This week, five celebrities
have been fighting it out
to become MasterChef champion.
This is hard work, this is.
God loves a trier.
Last time, model and TV personality
Christine McGuinness went home.
Good luck, everyone.
Now, the remaining four are back
to do culinary battle.
Tonight, they must step up and enter
the world of the professional chef...
It's mad! Aargh!
It's relentless. Aargh!
Honestly, how do they do this?
If you can't take the heat,
get out of the kitchen.
..before cooking for their place
in the quarterfinal.
It is addictive food.
That's what food trucks
are all about.
The flavours are great.
I'm glad I wasn't kicked
out on day one.
I'm growing in confidence
in the MasterChef kitchen.
I'm thinking maybe at some point
I might even use a deep-fat fryer.
Now, that is getting confident.
I'm terrified, to tell
you the truth.
But a little bit of excitement
at the same time.
I'm a kind of all-or-nothing person
in life, generally, so
we're here, we're doing it,
so let's go.
I've got no fingernails left,
but I'm still in with a shot.
And, while you're still in it,
you can still win it.
Three tough tests and we will
have ourselves quarterfinalists.
I'm loving the energy.
I'm loving the characters.
I want to see if they can build
on that good start.
OK. Gentlemen.
Here we go.
Excited.
We've got red today,
the colours of the Turkish flag.
So, what do you think we're doing?
We're Blue Team, J.
Welcome back to the MasterChef
kitchen,
and we'd also like to extend
a welcome to Max,
who is Jamie's sighted guide.
Welcome, all of you.
We call this the pairs challenge,
and this is a real lesson
in teamwork and communication.
So, we have split you into two
teams.
Red Team, Emma, Tamer.
I like the red.
Very good.
Blue Team, Jake and Jamie.
Jake. We've got this,
J, we've got this.
Each team is going to be tasked
with cooking a dish,
two portions of that dish,
and those two portions
need to be identical.
They need to taste the same.
They need to look the same.
But only one person on each team
has the recipe.
For you to be able
to succeed in this challenge,
you're going to have to work
as a team
and you're going
to have to communicate.
Reveal your ingredients.
Yeah. Ho-ho!
Oh! We got this, Ems.
Going to be amazing.
You're going to be brilliant.
You have one hour,
ladies and gentlemen.
Let's cook.
Each team leader has been given
basic instructions
for a different dish.
Easy, easy, easy, easy.
It's not easy, is it? It's not easy.
I am putty in your hands, Jake.
Yummy! Shall we go? Let's do it.
With separate trays of ingredients
for every element.
We won't rush. We've got an hour.
We'll smash it, mate, honestly.
Cool.
As leader of the Blue Team,
it's up to singer Jake to guide
comedian Jamie through a spiced
quail dish.
So, Jamie. Yeah.
The first thing we're doing
is the tray to your left,
which is the marinade.
So we're going to make
the marinade first. OK.
Then we just smash it in a blender.
Oh, great.
Spiced quail, yassa sauce,
cassava chips and rice.
So, it's 75 grams of the red pepper.
75. No worries, mate. Coming up.
ELECTRONIC VOICE: It is 91 grams.
Oh, hell. 91.
Now, this is a lot of work
to get done in just an hour.
They are going to have to truly
motor.
One clove of garlic.
Now, usually, in a challenge
like this, there is a little bit
of show-and-tell going on.
I was going to use this one.
But Jamie, of course, is blind
so Jake is going to have to rely
upon words only.
One small red chilli.
Coarsely chopped. Yep.
I'm quite good at talking,
so I suppose that's a benefit
for me and J.
Holy macaroni!
Fashion model and TV personality
Emma is leading the Red Team.
Oh! I'm really excited.
I mean, apprehensive.
Ask me again in ten minutes.
She will be instructing actor Tamer.
Yeah, I'm happy to be given
orders, I really am, today.
They need to make two identical
portions of a Caribbean favourite,
grilled jerk chicken, rice and peas,
mango slaw and dumplings.
So, what we're going to do first
is we are going to make
the jerk marinade.
Are you doing the garlic first then?
Yeah, yeah, we're going to do
it together, each step. OK.
The Red Team, made up of Emma
and Tamer.
I think it's a strong team. But
Tamer is going to have to listen.
Are we chopping these spring
onions up?
We're going to blitz it
anyway, so don't bother.
Really?
Is Emma used to giving instruction?
That's a question
we're about to answer.
Shouting all day.
Ems, talk to me.
What?
You've had 15 minutes, guys.
Quarter of your time's gone already.
15 minutes gone.
Jake and Jamie's spiced marinade
for their quail is made.
I've never seen a bird this small
in my life.
Their next job involves
some butchery.
Do you know how to spatchcock?
I... No.
They've got to cut down both sides
of the spine of the bird,
remove it and flatten it out,
so it's almost like the shape
of a butterfly.
Do you reckon we cut it right
in half, J?
There's a split in its arse. Yeah.
Do you think that's where
you start snipping?
Let's just snip down there, yeah.
OK.
Got it looking like that, Jake.
That looks lovely to me, mate.
It now says marinade the quail
with the marinade
that we've just made.
I'm just going to drop my
quail into a small bowl.
Yeah, I'm just putting it in
just now, mate.
That's the marinade on the quail.
Repeat, repeat,
the marinade is on the quail.
Jake and Jamie are working
really, really well as a team.
We are just so compatible, J.
Right now...
..seems to be going OK.
Early days.
The Red Team's jerk marinade
is also done,
and they next
need to prep their chicken
before it's ready to be coated.
How are you getting on?
We've got to separate
the thigh and the drumstick.
Separate the bits of meat?
And then score them on both sides.
GREGG: The drumstick has got to come
away from the thigh.
The thigh has got to be sliced
deeply,
so all the marinade can get in.
Skin on or off? Skin on, I think.
So, there, look. Yeah?
That was quick.
How many cuts have you done
on the thigh?
I did two. I've got two.
Yeah, and two on the leg?
I've done three. Three on the...
Doesn't matter. Doesn't matter.
It does matter.
GREGG: Tamara is working like a
steam train.
He's properly going for it.
He's having a workout.
Even though Emma's supposed
to be in charge,
she's struggling to catch up
with Tamer's pace.
So what do we do? Just leave this
in the marinade for now? Yeah.
Look, I've got it... I'm there.
Yeah.
GREGG: You birds of a feather,
you are halfway.
That is a tablespoon.
That is vegetable oil.
With their quail spatchcocked
and marinating,
the Blue Team can now turn
their attention
to making
their West African yassa sauce.
I've got my saucepan now, Jake.
Got it, buddy? Yeah.
The idea of yassa,
you slice onions quite thinly,
cook them for about 20, 25 minutes
till they're lovely and soft.
After that red Romano, you want
two garlic cloves, grated.
Grated garlic clove.
And then you add all the other
things into it,
some peppers, some spice,
some vinegar.
But everything's going
into the pot.
The good thing is they're both
doing exactly the same,
so it will taste the same,
but it's not the right way
to make yassa.
I'm following the instructions,
and that's all I can do,
because I've never cooked anything
like this in my whole life.
Right, we need to get
this quail in, bud. OK.
Ready? Let's go. OK.
Let's bang the little bad boy in.
Oh-ho-ho! Yeah.
Get out of it.
We're going to cook the chicken
in a pan to start.
With their chicken jerked,
the Reds still need to tackle
their rice and peas.
I might give the rice a rinse.
Don't worry about it, Ems.
I told you! Wash the rice.
Honestly. Just let's go.
GREGG: Tamer really wants to race
through this.
I don't know what you're asking.
What are you saying, Ems?
He wants to go at a much faster pace
than Emma does,
and it's causing a little bit
of friction.
EMMA: You going to put some oil in?
Olive oil?
It doesn't say that.
Huh?
That's kicking off.
We need to get the chicken
in the oven, you know.
What's your pot doing?
Nothing. It's just boiling.
Is that enough water for rice?
Don't put the water in it yet.
No? OK.
Empty it? Yeah.
JAMIE: Those two are arguing.
We're all right.
TAMER: No, we're not arguing.
I'm just taking orders.
We have so much to do.
I'm confident.
I just want the chicken to cook
so I've just got to get it
into the oven, I think.
Jerk chicken, pan-frying it first,
which is great,
to get some colour on the outside,
and then finishing it in the oven.
EMMA: Don't burn it!
Getting smoky.
Got plenty of work to do.
20 minutes.
Move it!
How are you doing, J? Good.
With their yassa sauce reducing
and their quail seared
in the marinade...
I'm a headless quail, especially
when I don't know what I'm doing.
I think we should put the quail in.
Yeah, let's bang the quail in, bud.
..Jake and Jamie can start
their rice.
Do you know how to cook rice?
No. I don't know how
to cook rice, no.
You should ask. I don't really know
how to cook rice. Do you know how?
I've just basically... Just stick
the water in the thing.
Yeah. Stick it in with the rice.
The Blue Team of Jamie and Jake,
I think the communication
is absolutely brilliant.
I think it's all going very well.
Jake is a very good team leader.
I'm bothered about J
because he deserves to stay here
for as long as he can.
So, I don't want to let him down.
Stop, stop. All right, give us your
best gangster look.
Yeah, that works.
Back on the Red Team, Emma and Tamer
are focusing on their cabbage,
red onion and mango slaw.
My partner's a legend.
He's doing really well.
He's good at chopping.
Hear that?
RAPID CHOPPING
With your mango... Mango, OK.
Let's do it like a hedgehog.
What's a hedgehog? Show me.
Do you want to do thin strips?
Is it cubes or strips? You've got
in front of you.
In the picture, it's strips.
Do the picture then. We'll stick
with the picture.
This is going to turn into an
argument, isn't it?
Yeah. That's exactly where I'm at.
Twins! OK.
You just have ten minutes left!
Huh!
With their dish almost complete,
the Blue Team have one final element
to get right.
Let's cut the cassava into the chip.
Do you peel it just with,
like, a tattie peeler?
I'm going to peel it
with a tattie peeler, yeah.
Yeah, that sounds fine.
Cassava has got arsenic in it.
They've got to make sure
they prepare that cassava
really, really well.
Wash off the starch, so it's no
longer milky water, at least twice.
Pat it dry and then put
it in the fryer.
Jake, watch out! It contains
arsenic, this thing. Oh, brilliant!
Yeah, so you've got to wash it twice
or you die.
You've got to wash the cassava
because it's got asbestos
in it or something.
Bring them to the boil,
get rid of the water,
and then we're going to
deep-fat fry them.
On the Red Team, it's a final push
to complete their dish.
Got to do our dumplings now.
So, what do we need?
200 grams of self-raising flour.
A Caribbean dumpling,
really lovely, quite hard,
made with self-raising flour
and butter
and then deep-fried.
Wait, how much butter?
25 grams.
You got that?
The hot butter, when you add
that to the flour,
will make that rising agent
actually react.
So they've got to use hot
butter, not cold butter.
I did it wrong, sorry!
It's melted butter.
What are we doing?
What have we got wrong?
Sorry. It's melted butter.
It's my fault. OK, don't worry.
Don't worry, don't worry.
We're all good. We'll start again.
GREGG: The dumplings
are just being made now.
They've got to be shaped.
They've got to be fried.
EMMA: How's your dough?
Is it very together?
Yeah.
We've got to go fry these.
Let's go, let's go!
You have just five minutes left.
We need to get this cassava
in, mate.
Let's get the quail on the p...
HE GIGGLES NERVOUSLY
Oh! Ho-ho-ho!
EMMA: They're not gonna be done
in time.
Shall we start plating? Yeah.
Let's start plating.
Check the chicken. I think
we can take it out.
Where's the plate?
EMMA YELPS
J, we need to get these chips
in now. OK.
Backs, backs!
That's what they say, backs!
Pick it up and drop it in.
There you go.
Fine. Your crisps are now cooking.
Oh, nice. OK.
I am an absolute slave to a hot
ball of fat.
EMMA: I think they're ready,
the dumplings.
GREGG: You've got 60 seconds.
Up the pace! Come on! Final push.
Let's get the chicken out quickly,
Quickly!
Where's the tongs? Tongs?
JAKE: So, your rice is on the left.
JAMIE: Yeah.
The chips are just above that.
The two pieces of quail
are spread-eagle. Yeah.
And then there's a sauce
in between the legs. Sort of.
EMMA: Are they out?
TAMER: We're in. We're good.
You didn't tell me! Teamwork.
We're ready, we're ready.
Right, six, the rice. Yeah.
Three, the thigh.
12, the drumstick.
Nine. Nine! Up there.
Nine o'clock, the pump...
Hey, I give up.
GREGG: Right, your time is up.
Well done, both teams.
Aargh!
TAMER: I don't care.
JAKE: Sorry, man.
TAMER: I cooked rice.
I've cooked rice.
Right, Blue Team, are you ready,
please?
JAKE: We are. Up you come.
Right, well, let's crack on.
I'll tell you what,
yours looks lovely.
It's delicious. Absolutely lovely.
Slam it down here.
There we go, buddy.
There we go.
You'll be pleased to
know they actually
look quite similar
to each other.
Very good job.
That's this guy.
That's this guy's direction.
GREGG: Jamie, we're going to taste
yours first.
JAMIE: I got most of the arsenic
off.
Good.
I hope you did.
Your bird is cooked really well.
There's nice, pink, juicy
flesh under there.
And, despite the incorrect method
of making your yassa sauce,
that is properly sharp and peppery.
I think that's great.
JAMIE: Excellent.
I love the fact that your crisps
are lovely and crispy.
Rice cooked really, really nicely.
You've done a good job, Jamie.
You followed along
really, really well. Thank you.
Jake, we're going to taste
yours now. Yeah.
The flavours on your quail, I think,
are absolutely fantastic.
The fact that they look the same
and they taste the same means
that you actually worked as a team
and you've understood each other.
Jake, I think you need to be really
proud of yourself cos that's
a really good dish.
Not only that, but you managed
to give
really good instructions
to your mate.
I'm loving these two dishes, boys,
I have to say.
I didn't want to let Jamie down.
You didn't, mate, you're fine.
Look at that little bit of emotion
in your eyes, Jake.
Don't, cos I will cry.
Thank you very much, gentlemen.
Thank you. Thank you.
GREGG: Well done. JAMIE: Cheers.
Clever boys. Well done.
For me, it's just
he's an incredible guy
and I think he's got probably
more chance of going further
in the competition than I have.
We've got the naughty kids
up the back.
CONTESTANTS GIGGLE
What a nice man.
I've chucked you under the
bus, man.
Red Team, come on.
EMMA: You can have a look.
OK.
We're close.
I've got to say,
they look so similar.
Shall we start with you, Tamer?
Yeah.
There we go. EMMA: Whoo!
Your chicken...
Ace. A-ha!
Ah! It's great.
The edges are all lovely and crispy.
There's that flavour of allspice
and thyme in there. Good.
The slaw is lovely.
You've got crunch in there,
and then you've got that lovely,
sweet, slippery mango. Thank you.
Your dumplings are properly
dense and heavy.
This is a great dish.
Thank you.
Right, Emma. EMMA: Hello.
Emma, you've really captured
the flavours of the Caribbean.
The rice is free-flowing, and
the little bit of black-eyed peas
and a little hint of coconut milk.
GREGG: The chicken...
You've used slightly more chilli
in yours than Tamer,
but they are very, very similar.
Your dumplings are superb.
They're doughy, as they're supposed
to be.
You've got a crust
on the outside of it.
There were times when I thought,
"This is going to fall over
in a minute,"
so well done, the pair of you.
Well done. EMMA: Thank you.
Off you go. Thank you.
Thanks, guys.
Yay! I wish it was always
a team effort.
It's much more fun doing
it with someone than on your own.
You was a great adult.
I do need an adult
in life as well, so you was
a great adult.
Thanks. Thanks for your directions.
They're still eating it. Yeah.
They're still eating.
Love you for that.
You've learnt a great lesson
in teamwork and communication.
CONTESTANTS CHEER
What you're doing next,
you're going to need it.
Off you go. Well done, guys.
Let's go.
It's day two and, still in their
teams...
Do you know where we're going? No.
No idea.
..the four celebrities are about
to get their first taste
of working in a professional kitchen.
Well, I'm in a white top
and black trousers.
What you got on?
Exactly the same as you.
Jake and Jamie will be cooking
at Lavo in London's Marylebone...
..working under executive
chef Stefano Lorenzini.
The type of food here is
Italian food.
I grew up in Italy. I'm Italian.
I come from a big family.
Reminds me of Sunday
at my grandmother's house.
I'm nervous.
This is going to be intense.
It's going to be brilliant.
Jamie will be responsible
for a pasta classic,
tagliatelle al limone.
During the service, you're going to
have our head chef come here
next to you. He's going to help
you out with all the cooking.
The head chef?
Yeah, but we want you to do
as much as possible as you... OK.
The dish is made up of fresh pasta
in an emulsified lemon-butter sauce,
which he will have to make to order.
Just a little ladle of water.
Just... Oh, wow.
That's kicking off, isn't it?
This dish means a lot to me.
A little bit of marjoram. OK.
Pink peppercorn. Oh, nice.
I remember my grandmother
making fresh pasta.
Got a grater here and lemon. Cool.
Here we go.
Tiny bit of fresh lemon juice.
That's it. And that's it?
That's pretty much the sauce.
Wow. Right? OK.
Pasta is going to be cooking for
around...I would say two minutes.
It's fresh pasta, so it cooks...
Will cook a bit faster.
..pretty quickly, yeah.
The challenges on the pasta
is we want to make sure
that the pasta and the sauce
are one thing.
Especially under pressure,
it's not an easy task.
And what you want to hear
is this noise here.
WET SLAPPING
Oh, right, a good squelch. Yeah.
And we're going to go in the plates,
and we're gonna add a small
quenelle of caviar on top.
A quenelle?
You're going to learn how to make
a perfect quenelle today.
Oh, lovely. And this is the dish.
Boom. Somebody's got a nice lunch.
You got it.
Well, let's get cracking then.
During prep time, Jamie has the
chance to have a few practice runs
on his pasta dish
before service begins.
Lemon zest. Thank you.
So it was, uh...
One, two, three, four, five, six.
There we go. Yeah.
I never worked with a blind
chef before.
So, you open it up a little. OK.
And after you put in the pasta ball,
which is...
Yeah, here?
Do I just drop it in? Yeah.
It's definitely a challenge
to not be able to see
in a professional kitchen.
And give it another wee stir.
OK, perfect.
It's got the squelch.
It's squelching.
But 100%, I think he can do it.
I've got my little station.
I'll be perfectly happy here,
I think.
Meanwhile, Jake is working
on portioning a whole salmon.
We can't waste any salmon, so we
just need to be precise here, OK?
Salmon is a little twist of some
memories I have as well.
You know, even in family, we used
to have, like,
a chickpea salad with vegetables.
We just add a fish
on to complement the dish.
You should be able to get 6 to 7
nice portions out of a fillet.
OK. That's great.
OK.
Pure stress.
If I didn't think my anxiety
could get any worse, it just did.
In service, Jake must master cooking
his salmon on the searing hot grill.
We want the salmon not to be dry
or undercooked.
It should be pink in the middle.
It's very important, you need to be
delicate when you flip the salmon.
Because if it breaks,
we can't serve it, OK?
It needs to be a nice whole
piece on the plate.
As well as perfectly cooking
each piece of salmon,
Jake's other challenge will be to
make an oregano sauce to order.
You can put a little bit of oregano.
Yeah. And we're going to go
on the stove here.
OK.
Be careful with the temperature
of the sauce.
If you see that it's started boiling
too hot, it's going to split.
Yeah.
The salmon is then topped
with a breadcrumb crust
and finished under the salamander.
Just a...a minute.
Make sure you don't burn the bread,
OK? OK.
So, next step is the plating.
Chickpeas puree.
OK, we're just gonna put
a little bit of the chickpea salad
here in the middle. Yeah. Got you.
Now, our salmon...
Oh, it sits on top.
..on top.
That looks beautiful.
That's the dish.
We're doing this. We're going to...
Bestseller today, this.
So, I used to work in a very
well-known fast food restaurant...
HE GASPS NERVOUSLY
..and I got sacked.
So this doesn't bode well.
Across the city in Kentish Town,
Emma and Tamer are arriving
at their restaurant...
EMMA: The Parakeet.
TAMER:
Hope we're not cooking parrots.
Oh, my goodness!
..a restaurant pub famed
for its cookery over fire.
It's the best flavour to get
out of meats or veg.
Seasonal, tasty food - whatever
we can get our hands on.
Thank you!
Even for us in the kitchen,
it's very hot.
You don't need to go to the gym
if you work here.
No, not at all.
Straight to the back?
Throw into the back right.
Whoops.
I nearly knocked your sauce over!
I'll be surprised if they can do
a whole service
without stepping out
for five minutes.
You learn not to burn yourself,
basically.
I'm an excellent lumberjack, too.
You need one, give me a call
any time.
SHE GIGGLES
During service, Tamer will be
juggling two different small plates.
So, all our dishes here
are mainly to share.
The first is a vegetable dish
of leeks, which are charred in prep
and finished over the intense heat
of a barbecue in service.
That's one of the most
important things.
Just chargrill a little bit?
Just chargrill them a little,
and that's it done.
The leeks are then topped
with a pecorino sauce
and finished with pickled
oyster mushrooms.
So, we cook these on the
fire as well. Yeah.
Keep spraying them with pickle
over the fire till they get nice
and crispy like this.
And then you've got the leek oil
from the tops of the leeks.
And that's the dish.
Wow, looks amazing.
I'd like to eat that.
THEY CHUCKLE
Tamer's other dish is confit trout
in a beurre blanc sauce.
This goes here on the fire,
right here.
We just leave it cooking
slowly here.
OK.
The trout is slow-cooked
in the oil over the fire
before being drained and flaked.
So nice, big and small bits.
Then we add the beurre blanc sauce.
So, this beurre blanc sauce
is notorious for splitting.
Yeah.
The dish is finished with fresh
radishes, sea beets,
kelp and parsley oil.
So, Ben, how many elements
on that dish?
About five. Five, OK.
Wow.
So, how do you feel
about doing this?
Are you ready? Ready as can be.
I don't want that going in the bin.
I'm going to finish that.
Go away. I want to eat.
I'm eating, go away!
Tamer's first prep job is
to char enough leeks
on the burning-hot coals
for his vegetable sharing plate.
Well, the leeks itself,
we chuck them straight on the fire,
let them char away.
Then you've got to peel them down,
break them down.
I'm used to being in front
of the barbecue anyway,
being a Cypriot. That's what we do.
I've got to do it.
There's no complaining, is there?
You've got to get people fed, right?
Cor, that is super hot, that is.
Emma is busy butchering
a whole duck...
It is like an anatomy class.
..for one of the restaurant's
signature mains.
It's been on the menu for a while.
I know.
So you've got crown of duck,
which you'll be cooking
in a wood oven.
Honey glazed, spiced with fennel,
coriander seeds and black pepper.
Yummy. Cooked in this blazing fire.
Cooked in this wood oven, right.
It's very hot in here.
My ears are singed.
THEY LAUGH
All right, so I'm just going to show
you the plating of the duck.
OK.
The honey-glazed duck breasts
will be roasted on the crown
ahead of service.
It's like carving marble.
So, it's half a breast per portion.
OK.
So that's one portion.
When an order is called,
Emma first needs to get Savoy and
pickled cabbage into the flames.
As you can see, we cook
everything in the heat.
It's very hot.
SHE LAUGHS
The duck, still got to serve it hot.
So we obviously carved it,
now we've just got to warm
it up again.
OK.
The wood oven gets to,
like, 350 degrees,
so you can easily burn
it within seconds.
The plate is then finished
with an apple puree,
the charred cabbage,
and a duck sauce.
That's it. That's the dish.
It's rustic, but elegant
at the same time.
I love the colours.
Obviously, you can burn
everything really quickly,
so you've got
to keep an eye on that.
Don't burn the duck
and don't burn myself.
Yes, exactly.
This is very serious.
I don't want to let the chef down.
And this fire is something.
I mean, my skin,
I feel like I'm getting a suntan.
It's midday.
Diners are arriving at both
restaurants.
How are we looking, guys?
We ready?
Yes, Chef.
We're about to start here.
Let's go guys. First order.
Let's go.
Two tagliatelle, one salmon.
Table 162.
Yes! Right? Yes.
It's kicking off.
HE YELPS MUTEDLY
The pressure is on for Jamie...
Right, uh, let's do this.
..to cook his first two pasta
orders perfectly al dente...
The pasta cooks very quickly.
But now I've got to dip into Satan's
swimming pool again
and get fricking this stuff up.
..and make his emulsified lemon
butter sauce without it splitting.
Not too much lemon juice.
And a wee dunk, and a wee dunk.
Yeah.
We're going to plate now.
Careful when you plate, Jamie.
Don't throw it on the plate.
So, get it in the middle there?
Yes. And just kind of gently...
Perfect, right. Is that better?
Beautiful. Almost.
OK.
OK, now we need to do the
quenelle, yeah?
Oh, "kin-ell" yeah. Yes.
Well done, Jamie. Thank you.
Pasta looks good.
We just need a little bit
of work on the quenelle, OK?
OK.
We got two more now, yeah?
Two more pasta. Yes, Chef.
HE SIGHS
Not stressful at all.
HE GIGGLES NERVOUSLY
With diners piling in, Jake's
salmon dish is proving popular.
And he already has several orders.
You got five salmon so far all day.
Right, am I banging this in?
Well, you got the salmon on?
Put the salmon,
the salmon is still not on.
Right, salmon's on.
As well as searing his salmon
to perfection...
Perfect.
Right, Jake, make sure it's
pink in the middle, huh?
Yeah, will do.
Do not overcook it.
..he must also keep an eye
on his oregano sauce.
Got to be faster, Jake.
I'm sure that sauce
is burning there.
It's stressful as hell.
Oh, you're destroying that salmon.
Sorry, it's hot.
Whoo!
Put another one on.
Seems like that one, you destroyed
the first one over there.
Sorry, I broke my fish.
It's so hot.
Honestly, how do you hold
your hands there?
I'm a cold man, that's why.
Across the kitchen, orders are also
flying in for Jamie's pasta.
It's...
HE LAUGHS
It's mad.
HE GROANS
It's relentless,
but I'm getting my rhythm in.
I know what I'm doing, when.
Beautiful. There we go.
Perfect. Push the plate.
OK, here we go, Chef.
Thank you very much.
All right. Thank you, Jamie.
Thank you.
Right, two more.
It's intense. It's very good fun.
Jake is still struggling
with the grill...
JAKE LAUGHS
What happened, Jake? It's hot!
Yeah, it's a grill.
Yeah, I know, but I'm not
used to this.
Meant to be hot.
..and is battling to get his first
orders out.
Salmon coming, chef.
Is it good?
Good one. Good one.
Good one, boy!
Come on!
Let's move on to the next
three of them, right?
You said it was good.
We are ready... Three more.
Three more salmon+s going on, Chef.
Whew!
Over in North London,
service is also underway...
All right, check on - leeks.
Tam, you hear me calling the checks?
Yes, Chef.
..and Tamer has his first
orders for his grilled leeks.
So, we're just getting this charred,
ready to go on the plate.
I feel good.
That heat's all right for now.
So these are the mushrooms that
are going to be going on the leeks.
This is vinegar we're putting
on there.
I'm trying to look like a pro,
but I am an actor,
so I can get away with it.
Emma is also underway
with orders for her duck dish.
Loads of people want duck
today, apparently.
Check on, two duck.
Is that five ducks, then?
You've got six ducks all day.
Six ducks.
I need to take this breast off
and then clean it like he did,
and then cut it in half
and put it in the oven.
There's a duck in the oven,
and I've got to keep an eye on it.
And then I've got to do four.
Tamer's main elements for his
leek dish are cooked.
It now comes down to the plating.
It's way too much oil.
Can we do that again?
Throw another one?
Yeah, let's do another one.
Let's do another one.
Sorry, Chef.
Chef wouldn't allow it to go out,
so we have to quickly get
another one going.
Is that enough mushrooms
on there, Chef?
Yes. Thank you.
Hope that's better
for you this time, Chef.
This one's much better.
Service.
How's it going, Tamer?
Good. How are you, Em?
I'm all right.
This fire is pretty serious.
Emma is also ready to plate.
So, you have to do that again.
The dollop of puree is too big.
God. That was perfect, right?
That was perfect, but we're going
to have to do this one again.
SHE SIGHS
Very difficult to get it right.
They're not going to let me
get away with that.
You ready on the duck?
Yep.
Yeah, so a little bit more sauce.
OK. Just put another leek on there.
Service, table nine.
So next time, just make
it a bit more centre. OK.
Other than that, it's all good.
Thank you.
You know what they say, don't you?
Yeah?
If you can't take the heat,
get out the kitchen.
Never!
Back in Marylebone,
the pace is showing no signs
of slowing.
So all day, I'm waiting for three
tagliatelle and three salmon, yeah?
Three tagliatelle, yes, Chef.
Jamie's still slammed with orders
for his pasta.
It's relentless, mate.
It's absolutely relentless.
And the caviar quenelle
is still proving to be a challenge.
Going to try and get this caviar.
In the middle, in the middle!
Ah, ah... Ah-ah. Oh, no.
How's the pasta looking?
Pasta looks good.
OK, let's just make
a perfect one now.
Aw, a perfect quenelle!
OK, let's just put the salmon on.
Let's go, let's go.
Jake's still struggling to master
the grill for his salmon.
Gyah!
He's still complaining
that it's too hot.
I don't know.
Argh!
Seems like that's the nature
of the grill.
Urgh!
Fighting with the salmon?
Yeah..
It's already dead.
It's very hot, Chef.
I've got a new-found respect
for you and your asbestos hand.
How long, Jake?
Yeah, a couple of minutes.
Argh!
Honestly, how do they do
this every day?
How's it looking?
Fantastic. You got two more.
Two more?
It's not easy at all.
Across town, there is no letup.
Tamer, another trout,
do you hear me?
Yes, Chef.
With two sharing plates to manage,
Tamer's got his work cut out.
Let's do that again,
cos it's the sauce.
Shall we use a clean plate, Chef?
Let's do the plate again.
You can see all the protein
coming out of it.
It means that it's cooked too much.
Change 'em?
So let's get another piece on.
Get another one on. OK,
I'll do one straight away for you.
With Tamer now wrestling orders,
Emma's getting a handle on her duck.
We're very much on time.
It's all under control.
Are these improving? Yes.
Much better. Thank you, Chef.
Service.
To be honest, I'm quite loving
the heat from this fire.
I might need to get one at home.
Two trout, two duck,
two potatoes and a beans.
Two minutes.
It's quite fun
just shouting numbers.
Yeah, a bit more sauce. Yeah?
Better?
Yeah.
Service.
It's like being a soldier, isn't it?
I imagine.
I've never done that either,
actually, to be honest!
Tamer's second attempt at his confit
trout is ready to plate.
Ready, Chef.
Yeah, thank you.
Yeah, much better. Cooked nicely.
Good to go. Thank you.
Service.
In Marylebone,
service is drawing to a close.
You've got two salmon and
two tagliatelle.
Let's go in five.
BOTH: Yes, Chef.
Jamie has one last chance
to perfect his caviar quenelle.
One more, Jamie. One more.
OK, now the quenelle.
Oh, the quenelle!
That's your favourite part, Jamie.
A little bit more on the right.
Perfect.
That's beautiful.
There we go, Chef.
Let's go. Well done, Jamie.
Thank you very much. OK, start
cleaning down the section.
OK, we're done.
Thank you.
Jake has finally got to grips
with the heat of the grill.
Last two salmon, let's go.
Any second, Chef.
There you go, Chef, last one.
How's it looking? All right.
Good one, Jake. Well done.
Fantastico! Woo!
Start to clean down the kitchen.
We're done. OK? Thank you.
These guys do it for eight hours,
longer.
Absolute animals.
Amazing.
I'm knackered.
Over at The Parakeet,
the last checks are in,
and Tamar is still trying to
perfect his two sharing plates.
Ready, Chef.
It's the last one. It's a good one.
Thank you, Chef.
Service.
There's one last chance for him
to impress Chef Ben.
Chef, this doesn't feel like
it's cooked.
Yeah, it needs a tiny bit longer.
Oh, OK.
Nearly there, Chef. Nearly there.
All right, that's the last
two trout. Well done.
Thank you, Chef. You did good.
Yeah? Thank you. Appreciate it.
Thank you.
Do I have to clean up now, Chef?
Yeah.
That part of the job? Yeah!
It's now down to Emma to end service
on a high.
That's the last two. Oh, yes!
That's the best news I've heard
in ages.
Let's go.
Good. Well done. Yay!
Did a good job. Thank you.
I might cry.
Am I doing the washing-up, as well?
Of course you are.
Cool. Let's go!
It's magic, it's alchemy,
it's science.
Like, you name it,
that's what they're doing in here.
It's art.
That was really good fun.
That was an incredible experience.
But these guys are champions
doing this every day, man.
I'm relieved it's over.
But I've got to say something,
it's a dream come true for me.
All you could hear was me in
the background going, "Ah!"
All the time.
I'm red raw,
my hands are killing me.
But we did well.
The boys are back in town, J!
Fresh air and sunshine! We're free!
Finally. We are free.
And I tell you, I've got the best
complexion I've had in years.
You have. You got steaming in the
kitchen. That's it.
THEY LAUGH
I wish.
Oi, oi.
Hey, hey, how are we doing?
Bonjour. G'day. Oi, oi.
Welcome to what we call
the street food challenge.
We want you to imagine that you
actually have a food truck.
We want to know, what are
you going to serve from it?
You'll have just one hour
to cook for us
two portions of your
incredible food.
But it has to be amazing.
Because at the end of this, three
of you will become quarterfinalists
and one of you is going home.
Let's cook.
What you want from the food truck
is food that's addictive,
that you just want to keep on
eating more and more of.
No messing around this round.
You want something fun, exciting,
but delicious.
What am I looking for?
Half a teaspoon of cayenne,
cos it's punchy.
I like these.
I've never done them,
but I've eaten them.
So, we'll see how it goes, baby.
I actually got a gritter named
after me in Scunthorpe,
called Jake Gritenden.
It grits the roads when it gets icy.
How cool is that?
I want to be here.
I want to make the quarterfinals.
Is that the freezer?
That's the freezer.
If I were to be a food truck...
Quick and Done!
Quick and Done Street Food.
Quick, you're in, you're done.
I'm going to be doing some
tempura prawn tacos.
First time I've ever done
tempura prawns,
but we're going to take a risk.
If you had a food truck, where would
it be? What does it look like?
I think it would be in London.
It would be very bright, big.
I'd maybe have some teeth on there,
cos I've got quite big teeth myself.
So, teeth on the front.
It's quite good at the back of
the studio right now,
because what you've got,
it's got Tamar, you got you -
if the lights go out, you both
smile, you can actually see
the back of the whole place.
Oi, I'll have you know
these are mine.
Yeah, you bought them.
Yeah.
They're mine now.
THEY LAUGH
Jake's really going for it.
He's making his own tacos out
of masa, which is cornmeal.
Too thick, and what will happen
is when you try and fold it up,
it will fall apart, it will crack,
and the whole filling
will fall out the bottom.
Do you have to take them out?
Don't know if you do.
That's a fiddly job,
to take a load of prawns
and deshell and devein them.
That's one done. 28 to go.
That's a lot of work from Jake.
I'm a new person.
I'm not even panicking, brah.
I am panicking a bit, actually.
It's good, it's progress.
And it shows he's really pushing
himself.
20 minutes have gone.
So much to do in this hour.
So, yeah, it's ambitious.
And fiddly.
I don't know if I'm a street food
person, really.
I think we automatically think
burgers and chips and hot dogs,
and all that sort of stuff,
but I wanted to make something
really satisfying, really delicious.
I could imagine dancing in
a summer dress, or a bikini,
with a drink in my hand,
and summer roll in the other one,
and just having a lovely time.
If you had your own food truck,
what would it look like
and what would you call it?
It's going to be called
Spice and Sunshine.
It's going to have speakers,
it's going to have drinks.
You need a drink.
So, what are you actually cooking
for us?
So, it's summer rolls.
And it's marinated chicken thighs
with some pickled vegetables
wrapped in a rice paper.
Something that's sweet, salty,
spicy, right? Crunchy.
You don't sound confident here,
Emma. I WAS confident.
Why are you nervy now? Is it because
there's a quarterfinal place?
Oh, gosh, yeah. If you mention
the word "quarterfinal",
I might burst into tears.
It's such an honour to be here
in this space
and to be doing this with you.
Whatever happens, it's been...
it IS incredible.
Vietnamese summer rolls.
Make a salad with a dressing, lots
and lots of shredded vegetables -
but she's usually using
spiced chicken -
all wrapped up tightly inside
a piece of rice paper.
Oh, my goodness.
It needs to be full of flavour.
This is a single morsel with
a bite full of spice.
Hot...!
Presentation is not easy
on a summer roll.
Guys, you have 25 minutes left,
please.
25 minutes left.
Where's my spoons?
You got the spoons? Thank you.
I love street food. I've done the
Edinburgh Fringe eight times,
and you come out and there's
just a suite of food trucks
kicking about, anything from crepes
to kind of high-end,
like, lobster and chips.
I think my one is going to be
the best bits of all
the nicest burgers I've tried.
That's me doing the rub on
my chicken.
It's going to be a kind of burger
thing, with chicken thighs
with a rub, and I'm going to do some
kind of mayonnaise,
make some mayonnaise up.
And I'm going to do you some
potato crisps.
So, tell me, if it was on a menu,
what would it be called?
Thighs Wide Shut.
Cos you kind of have it coming out
of the movies and stuff.
So, what would the food truck
be called?
Maybe I'd call it, like,
the Hungry Clucker.
Very good.
Now, a burger might sound quite
basic, but you look at all
the processes he's going through
there, there's a lot of work.
300ml of sunflower oil.
And my spoons.
Mayonnaise is not easy to make,
and it absorbs a lot of your time.
You've got to get the egg yolk
going, and then you've got to
drip oil into it bit by bit.
You can't throw it all in.
Is that starting to clag?
It will split and it will
stay liquid. It won't work.
Is it starting to catch?
It's still a bit loose.
It's all right.
There's plenty to go.
It's taking the oil.
It's not rejecting the oil?
It does look like it's emulsifying.
Oh, my God.
Oh, best thing I've ever tried in
my life. Right, here we go.
Confident today.
Finally, I understand this dish.
Everyone from my friends,
family, kids,
this is their go-to dish.
Whether they're hungover,
whether they're hungry,
whether they want something quick.
This is actually my street food
in my kitchen.
So I'm really excited to cook it.
I'm going to do some lamb, it's
going to go into the pitta bread
in the middle. And then I've made -
you guys call it tzatziki,
but we call it cacik.
You've got a kebab van going on!
I've got a kebab van going on, yeah.
I mean, who doesn't like the taste
of the Mediterranean?
And this food van of yours,
what would be it be called?
The Cypriot Cyclone.
Or the Turkish Torpedo.
One or the other.
Oh, that's got a nice kick.
We've got lamb which is marinated
with sumac, which is a sharp spice,
almost like sherbet,
but a little bit of chilli
and yoghurt and onions.
He's cooking the whole lot
with some mushrooms.
Fair game. That's all you, that is.
Do you want a bit of butter on it?
No. You sure?
A bit of salad?
Try a bit of that, go on.
Mate, you're not at home.
All right...!
I don't think he would have enough
time to make his own pittas,
but he could most certainly make
his own flatbreads.
All the cookery skill is the quality
of that lamb.
Excuse me, mate.
Excuse me, mate. Thank you.
Hiya, Jake! Hi, buddy.
Final ten minutes.
So I wouldn't stop and chat by
the fryer section, if I were you.
You've got ten minutes.
I mean, first time doing tempura.
They look all right, baby!
I've eaten a lot of these at home.
I think this oil's about
130 degrees.
You've only got a couple
of minutes left.
You really need to move, guys.
Oh!
They're so pretty!
I think they're done.
Final 30 seconds, guys.
30 seconds.
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
That's it, guys, your time is up.
Time's up.
Can I lie down?
It's very good.
It's just how I wanted it to be.
I hope the boys like it.
Jake!
Let's go. Come on.
Go on, son. Go on, mate.
Oh, gosh...
Jake's food truck dish is
prawn tacos.
Tempura king prawns,
pickled onions
and chimichurri on a
blue corn taco shell,
served with a sriracha sauce.
I like it, Jake.
Come on.
The flavours are great.
Those sweet, sticky pickled onions
underneath that lovely relish,
with all that coriander and chilli,
is great with the prawn.
I love the fact you've used the blue
cornmeal to make a blue taco.
That's great.
Your sauce is really, really tasty.
You've got good texture in there,
as well. It actually is crispy.
And you haven't overcooked the
prawns, you've got the crunch
of the prawn in there, as well.
It tastes good, it feels good.
You work hard, mate, don't you?
Thank you.
Street food and food truck stuff
is my favourite.
It was a good laugh.
I'm just ready for bed, man.
Emma has cooked summer rolls.
Chicken thighs marinated in ginger,
soy and chilli,
wrapped in rice paper, with bok
choy, carrot, coriander and lime,
and served with a satay sauce.
The chicken is seasoned well,
it's moist.
The major flavour in there for me
is coriander.
I don't pick up any chilli heat.
I would like a little bit of chilli.
Your filling is really good.
There's a sort of wonderful cross
between what I would call
a healthy salad sandwich - the
crispness of lettuce, the little
bits of shredded carrot - and the
chicken satay on the side.
The only thing I'll say to you is
that, when you do do them,
wrap them tighter. Yeah.
They're just starting to fall apart
a little bit.
Gregg would like more chilli.
But the colours are brilliant.
I feel like the comments were
exactly bang on, as usual.
The chilli should have been
in there.
One extra flourish was not there.
Jamie has served a chicken burger.
Roasted chicken thighs in paprika
and cayenne,
with a pancetta, tomato, red onion
and avocado salsa,
served with mayonnaise and crisps.
Obviously, the first bite is with
the eyes, and I never take
that, and blind people don't take
that, so, for you guys to take the
first bite without your eyes.
So, to where the eyes wide shut.
OK. That's a very, very interesting
experiment, actually.
All right, Jamie, bear with us.
I think not using your eyes maybe
actually heightens your senses.
Oh, good.
Can I thank you for that?
Me, too.
That was a fascinating experiment.
Oh, my pleasure.
Your burger is fantastic.
I got a sweetness of tomato,
I got the sharpness of lime,
and I got a nice finish of peppery
heat that made my lips tingle.
And I really, really enjoyed it.
Your mayonnaise you made
is delicious -
lovely and creamy and rich.
Your crisps are fantastic.
There's a perfectly puffed-up crisp.
Good work is not enough if it
doesn't result in something
that tastes great,
and your burger tastes great.
Thank you very much.
Thank YOU.
I'm feeling good after that.
I think that was possibly one of
my strongest rounds.
Yeah, I might open the Thighs Wide
Shut van, or the Hungry Clucker,
whatever I'm going to call it -
but I'd need to get a van,
and I can't drive.
Inspired by his Turkish Cypriot
heritage, Tamar's made a lamb kebab.
Shoulder of lamb spiced with sumac,
with mushrooms inside pitta bread,
served with cacik, and an onion,
tomato and cucumber salad.
I would have liked you to have made
your own flatbreads.
Sure.
Saying that, that is lovely.
Thank you.
Absolutely lovely. Your lamb is
cooked well, it's nicely seasoned.
It is the food that I actually
would order from a truck.
I'm enjoying it.
I think it tastes great.
Thanks.
You got the sweet tomatoes,
which have been marinated with salt,
they've become really juicy.
And then your cacik, which is great.
It is addictive food. That's what
food trucks are all about.
This is good, almost classic
Turkish kebab food.
It's really good.
I'm feeling OK.
I'm feeling good.
I could have tested myself a little
bit more with the pitta bread.
They like the flavours, they like
the food, the comments were great.
And I'm very happy about that.
I think we got served well, John,
I really do.
That was the nice bit.
The tough bit now is making the
decision, because three of these
go through to a quarterfinal. One,
of course, leaves the competition.
I liked the burger from Jamie,
I really did.
Made his own mayonnaise, and he
marinated that chicken properly.
I enjoyed it and I appreciate
the work that he put into it.
I agree with you.
The other person I believe
is pushing themselves
right now is Jake.
The batter from the prawns
were crispy.
He made his own taco.
It was sharp, it was hot.
It was good.
Emma - she made for us a
Vietnamese rice paper roll
with some roasted marinated chicken.
Nice crunch of vegetables,
nice flavour.
A little bit heavy on the coriander.
I just wanted some chilli.
She promised us chilli.
If I made it to the quarterfinals
of MasterChef,
I would jump up and down for joy.
And I can't even imagine.
Tamar - I really enjoyed that kebab.
Lamb kebab with salad,
flavoured with sumac.
I'm really happy.
It tastes good, but it would
have been nice to see him
actually make a bread.
For me to stay in competition
would mean a hell of a lot.
It's only going to better me.
I'm going to learn more, and the
experience is going to be amazing.
Thanks very much for all your
hard work.
Some really tough challenges
to get this far.
We have made a decision.
The contestant leaving us is...
..is Emma.
Emma...
Thank you so, so much.
Thank you. Really enjoyed having you
on here.
I really hope you've enjoyed it,
too.
I've loved every minute.
Thank you for having me.
Thank you so much, Emma.
So sorry. Thank you.
Good luck, everybody!
Thank you so, so much.
None of this has felt real at all.
At all. I can't believe I did it.
I'm proud of myself for doing
what I've done.
I'm happy to go home to my kids
and my husband and have a rest.
You are MasterChef quarterfinalists!
Come on!
Mate, I can't believe it!
I'm absolutely bewildered that I've
got through to quarterfinals.
I've made it so much further than
I thought I was going to make it.
I'm absolutely buzzing.
It is a little bit masochistic,
this show.
Like, I do want more,
but it is tough.
I'm going to try and put everything
I'm getting taught into making
myself better, and hopefully
progress as far as I can.
But delighted.
Do you know what? My kids are going
to be so proud of me.
I'm in the game,
I'm still in the game.
And I'm going to get to the end
of it and lift that trophy.
I'm telling you.
Next time...
Come on, man.
I could chew quicker than that!
It is what it is, mate.
..it's the quarterfinal.
Come on!
And Jake, Jamie and Tamar
are back...
Cheers!
..to battle for their place...
Sex on a plate! Ooh!
..in the semifinals.
The celebrity leaving us is...