♪ Sugar, yes, please
♪ Won't you come
and put it down on me? ♪
♪ I'm right here,
'cause I need ♪
♪ Little love,
a little sympathy ♪
♪ Yeah, you show me good loving,
make it all right... ♪
[screaming, tires screeching]
[knob squeaks]
[shower running]
[knocks]
Good morning,
Mrs. Valerian.
Mr. Valerian.
Happy...
tenth day anniversary.
[laughs]
I'll call in sick
if you will.
I can't.
He's coming
back in today.
It's his first day back
since the heart attack.
[elevator bell chimes]
Hey.
When's he due?
Couple of hours.
It's gonna be weird.
You know he's not going
to be the same guy.
Something like that,
confronting your own mortality?
That's got to change you.
A kinder, gentler Bull?
How could he not be?
DANNY:
Does he know we lost
those two cases yet?
Not unless
Marissa told him.
Marissa didn't
tell him anything.
Anything?
He didn't want
to be disturbed.
Until I got that text
from him on Friday
saying he was ready
to get back to work today,
I had no contact with him.
Wait, so he doesn't know
about you and your ex?
And by the way, do
you still call him
your ex, even though he is
no longer your ex?
Well, no. Now he's her ex-ex.
Her ex-ex?Better than her ex-lax.
[laughter]
Ah.
Okay. Guys? Guys,
I'm-I'm standing right here.
[phone ringing, vibrating]
[ringing, vibrating continue]
Hello?
MAN [over phone]:
Hi, this is EquiSafe Insurance.
Is Julia Summerfield there?
Uh, speaking.
I'm sorry. Did I wake you?
What time is it where you are?
Well, I'm in Elko, Nevada.
It's a little after 6:00
in the morning here.
[chuckles]: I'm sorry.
I-I'm in New York.
Sometimes I forget that anyone
lives in a different time zone.
I-I'm calling about your case.
Your review?
No. I-I know.
I, um, I know
why you're calling.
Um, I'm afraid
I don't have good news.
Uh, after carefully
reviewing the case
with almost
half a dozen specialists,
we just can't approve
your liver transplant.
I'm sorry.
["Happy Days Are Here Again"
by Barbra Streisand playing]
[sighs]
♪ Happy days
♪ Are here again
♪ The skies above
[sighs]
♪ Are clear again
♪ So let's sing a song
[elevator bell chimes]♪ Of cheer again
[cheering, applause]
♪ Happy days are here again...
There he is.
Here I am.
BENNY:
Ah, you look great, boss.
Haven't I always?Oh, my God.
I'm so glad you're back.
Your name again?[chuckles]
Believe it or not,
I am so happy to see you.
And believe it or not,
I am so happy to be seen.
[applause]
[sighs]
Oh, excellent.
[knock on door]
He's not back yet.
You look fantastic.
I'll bet you say that
to all the acute
myocardial infarction survivors.
And how are you feeling?
It's hard to explain.
Everything feels new,
and a little brighter, but...
familiar and old and maybe
a little worn at the same time.
It's good to be back.
It's good to have you here.
There's something
I think you should know.
Ooh. Surprises.
Love 'em.
And I have one for you, too.
I know while you were
in Arizona recovering,
you asked everyone to stay away.
Not reach out to you.
No e-mail, no visits...
Benny lost two cases. I know.
They had Internet.
It was part of
our recovery process.
They teach you how
to react to current events
and personal disappointments.
I got married.
Well, actually,
remarried.
Greg. Greg Valerian.
My first husband.
My only husband.
I was married to him while
I was working in Homeland.
12 years ago.
B.B., before you, Before Bull.
And, well, it
was Homeland.
I was always away--
Iceland, Caracas,
Budapest.
He works in
the restaurant business.
So he's never away.
And you can fill in the rest.
And it suddenly occurred to me:
I have a different job.
I'm in one place.
So I called him up,
we went for coffee,
and it was so... easy.
Got married in
one of his restaurants.
The gang was all there.
Except you.
And I want you to know
I regret that.
What's it like?
Everything looks new.
A little brighter,
but familiar and old
and maybe a little worn
at the same time.
What's your surprise?[knock on door]
Hey.
There's a Marshall
Hitchcock here to see you,
from EquiSafe Insurance.
That's my surprise.
Is Cable gonna join?DANNY: You know,
I actually haven't seen her
today. Maybe she called in sick.
Somebody give her a call
after we're through here.
Find out
what's going on.
So, who do we have here?
This is Julia Summerfield.
Lives in Nevada.
Married mother of
two preschoolers.
Works from her home
doing data entry.
During the birth
of her youngest,
doctors discovered
she had endometrial cancer.
Soon as the baby was born,
they put Julia on chemo.
Then they operated,
surgically removed the cancer.
Or so they thought.
It was only later
that they realized
the cancer spread to her liver.
She went back into
the hospital last year
for microwave
treatments,
and there was
a horrible accident.
The treatment left a hole in
her liver the size of an apple.
My God.
Given how badly her immune
system had been taxed
by her earlier cancers, her
prognosis was pretty dire.
Without a liver transplant,
she was given only a year
to a year and a half to live.
She filed a claim
with her insurance company,
EquiSafe Insurance,
to pay for the surgery,
which costs somewhere
in the neighborhood of $400,000.
That was four months ago.
This isn't gonna
end well, is it?
And they denied her claim.
In the meantime, she has filed
suits against the hospital,
the doctors,
the manufacturers of the
equipment that malfunctioned.
But as you might imagine, all
of those are going to take years
to make their way
through the courts.
And since, at this point,
she has little more than
three or four months to live,
she decided to file suit
against her insurance company,
EquiSafe, to pay
for the operation.
Okay. So when do we get
to meet our client?
He's already here.
He's in Bull's office.
He? I-I thought, uh...
We're not representing
Mrs. Summerfield.
We'll be working on behalf
of the insurance company.
♪
[whispering]: Hey. I left
three messages for Cable,
bunch of texts, and I
just fired off an e-mail.
If she doesn't make contact
by the end of the day,
I'll go by her place.
[shushing, chatter quiets]
BULL:
Anybody here know how much
two million dollars a month is?
Two million dollars
a month.
[chuckles]
Exactly right.
Two mil a month.
Roughly half a million a week,
that's a hundred grand a day.
Sounds like a lot, right? But...
when you got
30-some employees,
and you're renting
6,000 square feet
of prime Manhattan real estate,
when you pay taxes, insurance,
you have green drinks
to pay for,
your team loses a couple of
cases while you're convalescing,
a guaranteed two mil a month
makes a huge difference.
I only mention it because,
when I was in Arizona,
learning how to eat, not drink,
exercise and control my temper,
I met a man named
Marshall Hitchcock.
And for those of you
not familiar,
he is the CEO
of EquiSafe Insurance.
And watching him struggle
with his recovery
made a huge impact on me.
And apparently, I made some kind
of impact on him,
because he asked if my firm--
our firm-- would be interested
in a two million dollar
a month retainer.
[quiet murmuring]
And with that in mind,
I'd love you to meet our new
client, Mr. Marshall Hitchcock.
Thank you for that. [chuckles]
Crazy about your boss,
by the way.
[chuckles softly]
Listen, uh, I know people hear
"insurance company,"
and they, uh, roll their eyes.
But I have a secret.
We actually provide
an extraordinary service.
We actually do something great.
And I personally know that now
because I just went through
a horrible experience,
and like your boss,
I needed extraordinary care,
and I got it.
And my insurance
helped make that happen.
Yeah. So, uh...
Anyway, I-I'm gonna get
out of here and let you folks
do what it is you do,
but I just wanted to say hello
and, uh, tell you how much
I'm looking forward
to working together.
Thank you. Thank you. All right.
[clears throat]
BULL:
So, just to be clear,
moving forward,
EquiSafe Insurance
has first call on our services.
And while we're free
to take on other cases,
they are the only
insurance company
that we will be representing.
BENNY:
Boss?
We hear you. I hear you.
And, uh, this sounds like
a great thing for the company,
but this-this first case
is, um...
I sense some of you
are upset about it.
I suspect you think we should be
on the other side of this one,
that you'd rather be
representing the woman, who,
through no fault of her own,
lost the use of her liver
and almost certainly
is going to lose her life.
You want to go home at night,
feel good about yourself.
Plus, it's kind of a slam dunk.
I mean, it's not hard to find
a jury, let alone mount a case,
against a big, bad
insurance company.
Of course one problem
with that: she didn't hire us.
The big, bad
insurance company did,
and this is a business,
not a charity, so...
[quiet murmuring]
Yeah, that heart attack really
smoothed off the rough edges.
Turned him into
a pussycat.
[siren wailing in distance]
Maybe she just went out
to get some coffee.
Maybe.
If you want, you could
give me your number,
and then if she comes back,
I can let you know, or,
you know, if I hear anything,
I give you a call.
No?
And, you know, and then
I-I'll give you my number
if you need to get
back in here again.
It's simple.
It's not a problem.
Wait, so my friend is missing,
and you're hitting on me?
I-- No, I'm not hitting on you.
I just...
I mean, I know
nothing about you.
I mean, you know, you could be
married for all I know.
I got to go.
[phone vibrating]
Hello?
Marissa, sorry to wake you,
but I was laying in bed
reviewing everything
that happened today,
and I realized
I never said hi to Cable.
Was she even there?
No. She wasn't there.
I-I didn't want
to bother you with it,
but nobody seems
to be able to locate her.
Danny's on it.
The whole place is on it.
The second we hear from her
or get some explanation...
...I will let you know.
Well, I'll give her a call
the second you and I hang up.
Bull, everybody's been giving
her a call every ten minutes.
I-I'm sure there's
some kind of explanation.
And-and the second I have it,
I will share it with you.
[horns honking over phone]
Bull, it's 1:30 in the morning.
Where are you?
I'm in a cab.MARISSA: Heading where?
Nowhere, just
driving around.
That sounds a little strange.
Should I be concerned?
Well, like I said,
I couldn't sleep,
so I started to take a walk,
and did you know there's a bar
on almost every block
of this city?
Why, on some,
there are even two or three.
So, anyway... [sighs]
I realized walking
wasn't my safest option,
so I hailed a cab,
and what do you know, it works.
By the time I see a bar,
the car's already moved past it,
and, uh, I'm safe.
Too late. Can't go in.
Damn, I'm smart.
[clears throat]Don't you think
maybe you could use some rest?
You're still on the mend.
[sighs] Just say,
"I need to get back in bed
with my husband."
[whispering]: I need to get
back in bed with my husband.
Tell the team
we need to meet at 9:00.
Will do.
[sighs]
Found out late last night
that the plaintiff,
Mrs. Summerfield,
moved for
an emergency hearing
based on her declining
physical condition,
and the judge
granted the motion,
and we start voir dire tomorrow.
Okay. Talk us
through it.
Well, to begin with,
it's a civil trial,
which means we're only looking
at a six-person jury.
And for the plaintiff to win,
they require at least five of
those jurors to agree with them,
which means all we need to do
is convince two people
to side with us.
BENNY:
Oh.
Is that all?Yeah.
Ah. So here we are,
sitting in the courtroom,
Mrs. Summerfield behind
the plaintiff's table,
a dying mother
with a hole in her liver. Say hi to Mommy.
Who are these magical jurors
we're looking for,
who are gonna see past
a dying human being
pleading for her life
and sympathize with our client, the insurance company?
That sounds like a tall order
for voir dire.
BULL:
Maybe.
Maybe not.
So what would you have me ask?
I would have you say...
BULL:
Good morning.
You a mother?I am.
So I gather, like the rest
of us, you feel terrible
for Mrs. Summerfield?
I do.
You okay if we play
a game of pretend?
Okay.
BENNY:
So...
you're standing
at the edge of a dock.
You can't swim.
Two people in front of
you are in the water,
and they're drowning.
You only have
one life preserver.
Who do you throw it to?
Well, you haven't given me
any information
about the people
that are drowning.
I mean, how can you ask me
to make that decision?
You have to make that decision.
Two people in front of you
are drowning.
In three minutes,
they're going to be dead.
You can ask me a question,
I'll tell you what I know,
but time's a-wastin'.
Um, is one older than the other?
From where
you're standing,
one appears to be in their 70s
and the other one in their 20s.
Well, I kind of have to save
the 20-year-old, don't I?
I mean, he or she might have
50 or 60 more years.
The swimmer in their 70s,
maybe ten.
Then do it, do it.
Throw that life preserver.
Okay. I did it.
All right. [chuckles]
Good for you.
You just saved someone's life.
One more question.
Sure.
Would it be fair
if I prosecute you
for the murder
of the 70-year-old?
[chuckles]:
No, no, that's okay.
You don't have to answer that.
This juror is acceptable
to the defense, Your Honor.
You just got to do that
two or three more times,
and we got a jury
we can win with.
So having successfully
treated Mrs. Summerfield
for her endometrial cancer,
you realized the cancer
had spread to her liver?
Yes, we discovered it
in its earliest stages,
and really felt confident
that we'd be able to treat it.
And you used a technique
called microwave ablation.
Can you explain how that works?
MARISSA [over earbud]:
I know how hard it was
to put together
a jury that would
even consider the
possibility that our client
might be in the right,
but at the moment,
I am seeing nothing but red.
BENDRY: ...with pinpoint
amounts of microwaves.
The microwave creates
intense heat, just like
it does in an oven,
and that heat
kills the cancer.
But that didn't happen
with Mrs. Summerfield.
No.
Our instruments malfunctioned,
and we delivered
about 40 times the level of heat
that was required,
and ended up destroying
a vast portion of her liver.
And is there a way
to rectify that?
Not really.
Not short of getting her
a new liver.
Which you'd like
to see happen?
I would. In fact,
even though Mrs. Summerfield
is suing us for
malpractice, I...
my whole team has offered
to waive their fees.
Anything to make
her surgery possible.
And the hospital where
we performed the procedure
has indicated they, too,
would like to help out,
waive certain costs.
WRIGHT: So if everyone
is pitching in,
if everyone wants
to see this happen,
what is standing in the way
of Mrs. Summerfield
getting the new liver
she requires?
Well, you can't just
order them up on Amazon Prime.
They're harvested
from healthy people
who meet an untimely end
and whose families
are willing to donate them,
which makes their availability
unpredictable.
Also, not just
any liver will do.
The liver has to be carefully
matched to the patient,
or the patient's body
rejects it.
All of which makes the process
of finding a liver
and all the necessary
testing and follow-up
very, very time-consuming
and very expensive.How expensive?
Anywhere from
$400,000 to $500,000.
[gallery murmuring quietly]
And without that transplant,
how long is Mrs. Summerfield
expected to live?
[whispering]:
Honey, you ready to go?
Come on. Get you
out of here.
We love you.
Love you.
Come on, squirt,
you're with me.
Go with Daddy.We'll get you out of here.
Come on, handsome.[Lucas talks quietly]
MARISSA: I know it's not
technically possible,
but I'd almost swear
our six red jurors
got even redder.
Will the witness please
answer the question?
Without a transplant,
I believe life expectancy
is roughly four months.
Four months.
16 weeks.
No further questions,
Your Honor.
[Benny clears throat]
Thank you for your
testimony, Dr. Bendry.
Appreciate you taking
the time to be here,
and appreciate you offering
your services for free
to try to undo
the horrible situation
that Mrs. Summerfield
finds herself in.
You're welcome.
Just... one question.
What if it was
suddenly possible
for Mrs. Summerfield
to have the operation
you're saying she needs?
We find her a liver,
everything is paid for,
the operation's a success...
How long would you estimate
that she would live?
Ten years, 20 years,
30 years?
Objection. Counsel is
asking the witness to speculate.
The counsel
is asking the witness
for his expertise, Your Honor.
Objection overruled.
The witness will answer
the question.
Three years.
Maybe three and a half.
The first cancer took
a terrible toll on her,
and now this second one...
So 36 months, maybe 42.
And how much did you say
the operation would cost?
Between 400,000 and 500,000.
Half a million?
Got it.
No further questions,
Your Honor.
Nice.
MARISSA [over earbud]:
Chunk, Danny and I
all really thought it was
a huge mistake
to put a price tag
on the woman's life,
but then I just looked up,
and one of our red jurors
actually turned green.
Now the trick is not to lose
him or her along the way.
WRIGHT:
Let's talk about 42 months.
Some people might argue that
that doesn't seem like
a very long time,
particularly given
how scarce livers are...
how much it will cost
to do the surgery.
In 42 months,
my five-year-old son
will be in third grade.
If I get 42 more months,
I'll be able to see him
walk to school
through all four seasons
of the year
another couple hundred times.
I could help him
learn to read,
show him how
to tie his shoes.
And my little girl, Maura,
she'll be in first grade.
We'll get to buy
school supplies together,
make Halloween costumes.
I could teach her
how to brush her hair.
It's three more Christmases
and six more birthday parties.
Maybe I'll get to see them
ride bikes and ice skate
and swim with floaties.
Maybe even without.
But most of all,
I'll be able to
kiss them good night
over a thousand times more.
WRIGHT: We have no further
questions, Your Honor.
JUDGE:
Very well, then...
[sighs] ...let's take
a 20-minute recess.
[gavel bangs]
Hi, guys.
Come here.
Hello.
How are you guys?
I'll be right back.
I'm gonna pay for parking.Okay.
How are you guys doing?
Is Daddy taking good care of you
out here in the hall?
CHILDREN:
Yes.
Good.
I have to go to the bathroom.Right now?
Honey, Daddy just went to go
put money in the meter.
Can you wait till
he gets back?
No, I have to go right now.
But, honey, I can't
take you in the men's room,
and you're too big to go
in the ladies' room,
and this is New York City.
BULL: You know,
I can take him.
I couldn't help
but overhear.
I could take him to the men's.
I'll keep an eye on him.
You okay in there?
Yes.
Don't forget to flush.
[toilet flushes]
All right.
Wash your hands.
There's the soap.
Attaboy.
Are you a friend
of my mommy?
Uh... no.
Not really.
But you like her, right?
My daddy says my mommy's job
is to make sure everybody
in that room likes her.
I want to start the case
tomorrow by putting Hitchcock
on the stand, try and get
the jury to understand
what goes into making
a decision like this.
Okay.
I know what to do with that.
Then what?
Well, God may get me
for saying this, but...
do we go after the mother?
What do you mean?
Well, I'm just saying
maybe she contributed
to her current condition
somehow.
Drinking or drugs or...She didn't.
I checked.
She's a church girl.
Clean as a whistle.And even if she wasn't,
we don't want to go after
a dying mother
with a hole in her liver.
Not gonna win any hearts
and minds that way.
Hear, hear.
I'm just trying
to do my job.
Although...
...how many people our there are
waiting for liver transplants?
There are currently
17,000 people
waiting for
a liver transplant.
And, on average, how long
do they have to wait?
Last time they counted,
the average wait time
was 321 days.
Reach out to EquiSafe Insurance.
Get me the names of everyone
waiting for a liver,
how long they're
expected to live
and how long they've
been waiting.
And also, get me
the names of everyone
who was waiting for a liver,
but didn't make it.
How's it going
on the Cable front?
Uh, well, she's
officially on the FBI's list
of missing persons
as of today.
Her mom's, uh, a mess.
But, um, I have
one more idea
that I'm-I'm gonna
try tomorrow.
Well, let me know if there's
anything I can do to help.
Let her mother know.
MARISSA:
I can't reach anyone
at EquiSafe,
but I will jump
back on it
first thing in the morning.
How's married life
treating you?
Come on, let me have it.
I know you've been dying
to give it to me all day.
Married life is good,
thank you very much.
I highly recommend it.
Yeah, I really think
it's gonna catch on.
Are you mad at me
for getting remarried?
Mm. maybe a little jealous.
Not like that.
Not jealous of your husband,
jealous... of your happiness?
Well, I don't know what
to do about that, Jason.
You know, when I was lying there
on those courthouse steps,
with this elephant
sitting on my chest...
I kept hearing this voice
in my head.
It was my ex-wife, telling me
that I'm no good alone.
She said that to me a week
before she got married again.
I'm starting to think
she might be right.
You really hate this case,
don't you?
We all do.
We all keep thinking,
"What if it were us?"
Three more years with
the people you love.
How do you put a price on that?
No. I'm sorry.
You're being myopic.
It's about the greater good.
It's about resources.
It's about making sure that
there's something for everyone.
And the simple fact is that
everyone can't have everything.
I know,
'cause I just went through...
I knew what
you went through.
I cried for weeks.
I prayed for weeks.
But Jason,
what happened to you
has nothing to do
with the rest of us.
How could you say that?
'Cause you're rich.
And yes, everybody gets it,
everybody can't have everything,
but it sure seems like
people like you,
people like Mr. Hitchcock
always manage to get theirs.
I will do my best to get you
all that data from EquiSafe
first thing in the morning.
Look, I understand this
is a heartbreaking situation.
It is no fun to sit here
and look Mrs. Summerfield
in the eye and say no.
But according
to our actuaries
and our medical experts, the
chance for success is so low
and the chance for extended life
is so small
that it would be
irresponsible
for us to pay this claim
and allow this to go forward.
And can you explain that?
When you start
approving what amount
to Hail Mary medical procedures,
it inevitably drives up
premiums, so that people
with legitimate claims can't
afford to even buy insurance,
much less file a claim.
No further questions,
Your Honor.
JUDGE:
Thank you.
You may step down.
[sighs]
Do these people
give a damn about this?
They certainly don't appear to.
Got it.
And going forward, I'd
appreciate it if you'd reel in
your sense of self-satisfaction.
Mr. Toliver, how long have
you been waiting for a liver?
Going on 11 months.
So you've been waiting seven
months. And forgive me,
are you married?
No. Although I hope
to be, some day.
Obviously, no kids?Again,
maybe someday,
once I find my liver.
If they get to me, in time.
19 months.
So you've been waiting
19 months for your liver.
And what's your life expectancy
if you get one?
I've been told 30 to 35 years.
I've been told I could live
another 50 years.
I was told 50 to 60 years.
Talk to me.
I would, but there's
nothing to say.
SUPER:
Yeah?
Hi.
Um, I need to get into
my friend's apartment again.
Whoa, okay. You're just
going to take that?
I'm not taking anything.
I-I don't think
I can let you do that.
Yes, you can.
Technically, it belongs
to my boss; he paid for it.
Okay, but I'm-I'm supposed
to just take your word for it?
Hey, my friend has fallen off
the face of the Earth, okay?
She's vanished.
That doesn't just happen.
I need to look
through this computer
and I need to figure
out what's going on.
Okay, look, hey. Listen.
Do what you want, okay?
But for what it's worth,
it does happen, okay?
People do vanish.
They make themselves
disappear all the time.
[cell phone rings]Whatever you say.
Mrs. McCrory, hi.
You know,
I'm actually standing
in your daughter's
apartment right now.
I'm sorry, you want me
to turn on the television?
Channel three?
Okay.
Uh, Mrs. McCro...
NEWSMAN: If you are just joining
us, updating our top story,
once again repeating the New
Jersey state medical examiner
is now confirming that
there were 37 fatalities
in that I-99 bridge collapse
earlier this week.
Additionally, state
investigators now believe
they have recovered and
identified all the remains
from the bay and
are in the process
of notifying next of kin.
This is a late breaking
news story.
Keep it right here on this news
channel for all the details.
I'm Logan Crawford,
reporting live.
[gasping]
[quietly]:
Oh, my God.
Don't.
[gasping]
[crying]
BENNY: This is Powell.
23 years old.
Waited two years and
succumbed to his illness
before a liver
could be located
and the transplant
successfully performed.
This is Naomi.
After waiting 14 months,
a matching liver
was finally identified
and transported
to her hospital.
She actually, um, passed away
while in prep for her procedure.
Objection.
That's a tragic story,
but I fail to see the relevance.
Mr. Colón?
Your Honor, the defense is
simply trying to make the point
that livers, matching livers,
are limited commodities,
that many people
with greater life expectancies
have been waiting far longer
than the plaintiff
who seems to feel
that she's entitled...
WRIGHT: This isn't
about entitlement.
This isn't about
jumping the line.
If she doesn't get
the operation
in the next 12 weeks,
she is going to die.
And you know what?
If she dies,
these people save
a lot of money.
Make no mistake,
this is about money.
We should be identifying
livers right now.
We should be testing
What is insurance for
if not for that?
Exactly!
[gavel pounding]
[gallery mutters, quiets]
Mr. Colón, unless you have
something else
substantive to offer...
Oh, come on, Your Honor!
The plaintiff's lawyer just gave
a closing statement,
for God's sakes.
I'm going to ask you
to wrap this up.
Of course, Your Honor.
The defense rests.
I have a confession to make.
I'm not sure
I'm cut out for this.
It's not fun stuff.
People wonder why
it pays so much.
Obviously, it's to win,
but also it's hard finding
somebody willing to do it.
[chuckles]So, you know juries.
What are our odds?Not very good.
Anything can happen
during deliberations.
We have no way of monitoring
them, but in all likelihood...
Ugh. Well...
What's that?
Your fee for the month.
Well, the month's not over.
Case isn't over
and I'm pretty sure
I didn't do the job
you hired me to do.Take it.
You know, that lady's
lawyer isn't wrong.
Money is important.
And sometimes it can even make
you feel better about things
you might otherwise regret.
[elevator bell chimes]
Marissa.
What are you trying to do,
give me another heart attack?
Where is everybody?
They were all pretty upset.
I told them that
I'd wait here for you.
You remember that
bridge that collapsed
in New Jersey last week?
Cable was on it.
She was in a car,
car she rented.
Anyway...
they found her in the bay
under 30 feet of water.
And they identified her remains
this morning.
I need to sit down.
[sighs]
Everybody knows?
Her mother knows?
Everybody knows.
[exhales]
What are you gonna do?
I don't know.
Cry, maybe.
You want me to hang?
No.
I don't think I like the
idea of you being alone.
[sighs] I'm-I'm fine.
Are you sure?
You're not gonna do
something stupid,
like go get a drink?
I have a system for that.
Uh, as long as I have
taxi money, I have a system.
Seriously, I'm... I'm fine.
You can go.
I'll be all right.
JUDGE:
Has the jury reached a verdict?
We have, Your Honor.
We, the jury,
find for the defendant,
EquiSafe Insurance.
[gallery exclaiming][gavel pounds]
JUDGE: The court thanks you
for your service.
I got you, I got you.
It's okay.
No!
We'll fight this.
[cries]
BULL:
We got two jurors.
Not among the mirror jurors,
but among the ones actually
sitting in the jury box.
I knew it.
I knew you'd be great at this.
Look, I know you said
this wasn't for you,
but, uh, wow.
Hey, if you change your mind.
Well... I guess
I owe you an apology.
I said we couldn't do this
and I was wrong.
No, I think you said
we shouldn't do this
and you were right.
[sighs]
By the way, I've been
meaning to tell you
those two cases you
lost while I was gone,
I read the transcripts
last night.
You were great.
Those two judges
were morons.
[chuckles]
Well, thank you, Bull.
You want to go grab a...
[clears throat]
...fizzy water
or something or...?
No. Thanks.
I got to catch a cab.
Something I got to do.
BULL:
Mrs. Summerfield?
It's my friend.
What do you want?
We have a plane to catch.
I just wanted
to give you something.
I don't understand.
This is a check for $2 million
made out to some company.
My company. If you look on the
back, I signed it over to you.
What do you mean?
Why would you give me this?
I don't know.
I'm crazy. You can ask anyone
who works for me.
Also, I just lost somebody.
The truth is, it's EquiSafe
Insurance's money and...
[blows a raspberry]
...you know, you should use it
to get your operation and, uh,
put the rest away
for your family.
That's absurd.
Is this some kind of a joke?
No joke.
Get your 42 months, which,
by the way, who knows?
Might just be 42 years.
You should really get going. You
don't want to miss your plane.
♪ Happy days...
Thank you! Honey.
Bye, friend.
♪ The skies above
are clear again. ♪
Captioning sponsored by
CBS
and TOYOTA.
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org