I'm gonna duck into the diner,
ring it out.
I'm about to burst.
You want me to bring you
back something?
I'm good.
♪
Hey! This is
the ladies!
What are you doing?
Get out of here!
Wait, oh!
NYPD! Halt!
Let go of the gun!
Oh! Oh, my God,
you shot me!
You really shot me.
Precinct 55, this is Charlie
to Central. 10-13.
Shots fired
in the women's restroom
at Frankie's Diner,
46th and Third,
requesting a bus
forthwith.
Stay down.
SCOTT: Sorry to keep you
waiting, Dr. Bull.
Suffice it to say,
it's not a good night
to be a police officer.
Police Commissioner Scott,
I don't envy you.
It can't be easy.
I see you got my message.
You-you started without me.
Simply grilled fish
with some steamed vegetables.
Thought I'd leave
the good stuff for you.
Ah, I can't eat.
Don't have any appetite.
On my way over,
somebody threw a rock
at a squad car at 179th Street,
and just as I was
coming in here,
we heard about
a Molotov cocktail
being thrown at a station house
in Kings County.
An officer shot
an unarmed black man,
and it wasn't for
the first time.
Oh, come on, the guy bursts
into a ladies' bathroom
just as the officer
was about to do her business.
Well, he drank too much,
he knew he was getting sick.
Men's room was locked.
So he says.
I guess the real question is:
would she have shot him
if he were white?
Thanks.
We're talking about
a second grade teacher,
out celebrating his
Teacher of the Year award
who had a mimosa too many.
Hardly public enemy number one.
Where I come from,
you grab an officer's gun,
you should expect to get shot.
I don't care
what your day job is.
Frankly, he's lucky
she just winged him.
Frankly, the department's lucky
What can I do for you,
Commissioner Scott?
This, uh...
victim, this Cal Peterson guy
just hit us with a federal
civil rights claim.
Okay, City Hall has a floor
full of attorneys,
so I'll ask again.
Why are you paying for my fish?
I need more than a good lawyer,
Dr. Bull.
I need someone who can
really work a jury.
Anti-cop sentiment
has never been higher.
I'll give you
my best advice for free:
settle, and do it quickly.
We made Peterson
an offer this morning.
His attorney made it clear
that we were off by a factor
of at least ten.
Offer more.
Dr. Bull.
Listen.
I heard what
you said in there,
and in fact,
it may come to that,
but at least initially,
I owe it to the city,
I owe it to the force,
to go into a courtroom
and declare
in as full-throated
a way as I can,
that this had nothing
to do with race.
Nothing to do with some systemic
problem in the police force.
This was a woman
protecting herself
in a situation where
any reasonable person
would've felt threatened
and would respond
just as Officer Harris did.
And by the way,
Officer Harris?
She's Tonya Harris.
She's a real person.
She takes home maybe
47 grand a year,
and if she weighs 105
pounds, she weighs a lot.
Doesn't she deserve the
right to clear her name?
Right now she is the most
hated woman in New York,
and that's not right.
Could I at least get you
to meet her?
♪
SCOTT: You see that pep rally
down the street?
That's where
we're headed.
[chanting]: Don't shoot!
Hands up! Don't shoot!
♪
SCOTT:
My offer still stands.
We'd be happy to put
you up in a hotel.
[crowd shouting outside]
It's getting kind of
crazy out there.
Why would I move?
I've got
round-the-clock protection.
My boys aren't gonna let
anything happen to me.
[sighs]
Tonya.
[clears throat]
This is Dr. Bull,
the gentleman I told you about.
I think I'm gonna step out,
let you two have a chat.
CROWD: Hands up! Don't shoot!
Hands up! Don't shoot!
[door opens, closes]Hands up! Don't shoot!
[chanting continues]Nice to meet you, Tonya.
No, it isn't.
You're here because
I shot an unarmed man.
There's nothing nice about it.
Sorry. Figure of speech.
Your commissioner thought
I should spend some time
with you, see if...
I thought there was some way
I could help.
Can you undo it?
I don't think you can undo it.
This isall my fault.
Ah, you know, um,
whether or not I decide
to help you... I'd encourage you
not to say that out loud again.
But it's true.
Is it?
Blame is for the
jury to decide,
not you. Your job is
to tell me the truth
and let me guide you
through this process.
I am telling you the truth.
I hate that I hurt that man.
And I hate that every
police officer in the city
is three times
more anxious today
than they were
four days ago.
And I am disgusted with myself
that I have given people
who are inclined to hate another
reason to go on doing it.
[shouting continues outside]
Huh. Let's do this.
I know you're supposed
to go to court tomorrow.
Let me reach out to
Mr. Peterson's attorney today,
and see if there isn't some way
we can settle this
before we even get to court.
Are you serious?
Mm.
That would be amazing.
I make no promises.
Thank you.
DANNY:
Tell me it's not true.
Tell you what's not true?
TAC's not really gonna help
defend the police officer
that shot the unarmed
black school teacher?
Not that I'm aware of.
Where'd you get that idea?
Well, Bull just texted me.
"Find out everything you
can on Cal Peterson."
Cal Peterson is
the school teacher.
Yeah. First
that I'm hearing of it.
But would it upset you
if it were true?
I mean...
you were in law enforcement.
Did you see the bodycam footage
on the news?
He was going for her gun.
The guy was drunk.
He was going
for the sink to
puke his guts out.
Hmm...
And that gun should
have never been left
unsecured in the
first place.
The cop broke protocol
by removing it in an
unlocked public bathroom.
She created the threat.
True, but...
he tried to grab it.
She had to defend herself.
The police officer is the
one with the training.
There are a dozen ways
she could have de-escalated
that situation.
Hey, you may be right, but
I don't think it matters anyway.
As far as I know, we don't have
anything to do with this case.
[sighs heavily]
WOMAN: You're not gonna
take them all, are you?
Oh.
[laughs]
No. This is...
I just... Doesn't matter.
[chuckles]
Ms. Ford.
Mm-hmm.
I'm...
Dr. Jason Bull.
I know who you are,
and I know what you do.
How can I help you,
Dr. Bull?
Well, it's not me
that needs your help.
It's the City of New York.
They approached me,
and asked me to get involved
in this federal
civil rights suit
that you
and your client filed.
Frankly, I came over here
to see what I could do
to make the whole thing go away.
Well, you can get them to
offer my client $25 million.
[laughs]
What is it about that
figure that amuses you?
Well, that's a big number
for a flesh wound
that's probably gonna heal
before this case finishes
winding its way
through the courts.
And my bigger fear is that,
in the meantime,
jackasses will line up
on both sides of the argument
and use it as an excuse
to make more trouble.
Hmm.
I'd always heard
that you were this crusader
for civil rights, human rights.
I like to think I have
been a significant voice
in that conversation,
a meaningful advocate for people
whose rights have been violated.
And it may seem like just a
flesh wound to you, Dr. Bull,
but to me, it's a
bullet to the heart.
I'm reasonably sure if
that had been a white man
in that bathroom, there'd
have been no shots fired.
I've also learned over the years
that the only thing that changes
an entrenched institution
like the City of New York is a
big ding to their bank account.
And that's what
I'm really after.
Big change.
Then I guess
we're going to court.
I guess so.
You want the good news
or the bad news?
Just... give us the news.
We're going to trial tomorrow,
working on behalf
of Officer Tonya Harris
and the NYPD.
Oh, my God.
And our strategy is...?
Well, Malia Ford is obviously
gonna make this case about race.
So in choosing our jurors,
we are gonna do
everything we can
to make it about everything but.
And how do we do that?
Well, we want to concentrate
on the circumstances.
Not the people.
When you present
the circumstances,
there is a solid foundation
of facts
that supports the idea
that Officer Harris...
was reasonably in fear
for her life.
She shot Cal Peterson
in self-defense.
White or black, our ideal juror
is someone who would make
the same split-second decision.
Someone who doesn't take time
to think in a crisis
but reacts in a blink.
What I call a "Blink Reactor."
Okay. So now we're looking
for Blink Reactors.
Whatever those are.
BULL: We're not
simply relying on how
jurors tell us they'd react
in a crisis,
but also how long they take
to answer the question.
The main thing is we don't care
who these Blink Reactors are.
In fact, the more our jury looks
like a jury forCal Peterson,
the more we will have started
to convince everyone
in that courtroom,
most especially that jury,
that we're not trying a case
about race.
We're trying a case
about circumstances.
Hello, Miss Sloane.
I see that you are
a hair stylist.
Actually, I own my own salon.
That's terrific.
Now, let's say one day...
a gentleman comes
into your salon.
I don't know if he's crazy
or high on PCP,
and he grabs one
of your scissors,
and he starts
swinging it around.
Threatening you
and your customers.
What would you do?
Come on.
You a thinker or a blinker?
I want you on this jury.
MARISSA:
Seven seconds.
Eight seconds.BULL:
You can do this.
Throw bleach in his face.
Hit him with your hair dryer.
Move to strike,
Your Honor.
What we don't want
are people who lack
the confidence to take action.
Now, Mr. Sails,
you work the door
at a club.
Am I correct?
Yes, I do.Now, I bet when
it gets pretty late,
people have had
too much to drink,
gets kind of wild, huh?SAILS: It does.
BENNY:
So let me ask you:
what would you do if one of your
customers took a swing at you?
I would make it my business to
see to it that he regrets it.
Instantly.
Without hesitation?
We also want jurors who believe
people have a fundamental right
to protect what's theirs,
whether it's their property,
their life or the lives
of their loved ones.
Have you ever had your home
or apartment broken into?
Yes, a couple of years back.
And were you there at the time?No, thank goodness.
Thank goodness
because you suspect the robber
might have hurt you or...?
Thank goodness because if
I would have been there,
there'd be one dead
robber right now.
This juror's acceptable
to the defense, Your Honor.
Ms. Ford?
This juror is acceptable
to the plaintiff, as well.
Then it looks
like we've got our jury.
I saw your boss on the
front page of the paper.
Sitting in court beside that
cop that shot Cal Peterson.
Okay.
CHUNK:
You know, Anna,
it's my job.
I don't run the company.
I just work there.
You can hear how pathetic
that sounds, right?
Actually, I can't.
'Cause I know how hard
good jobs are to get.
And I know how important
my job is right now,
seeing as that you're
the one going to school.
And yeah, I know
all about your scholarships,
but somebody's got to pay
for books and housing...
Still pathetic.
[sighs]
I ever tell you what my dad
gave me for my 14th birthday?
He gave me "The Talk."
Sat me down and told me
all about how I should act
around the police.
"Don't attract attention.
"Don't make them mad.
Do whatever they say
the second they say do it."
[scoffs]
And it all made me
so angry.
I was embarrassed that he
was telling me those things.
I was embarrassed
that he believed those things.
And I was enraged
that he accepted those things.
But deep down,
I knew what he was
trying to do.
He was trying to...
tell me the truth.
And I knew my white friends
weren't having that talk.
[scoffs]
Not on their 14th birthday.
Not on their 40th birthday.
So, then, how can you go
and defend a white cop
who shot one of us?
Well, this is what
I tell myself.
For the justice system
to really work,
it has to be colorblind.
Look, I don't know what
really happened that night.
Who's right. Who's wrong.
But me being a part of it,
me being involved
in the fact-finding process?
Well, I have to believe
that somewhere,
my dad is smiling.
DANNY:
Veronica Hill?
Ms. Hill. Hi.
My name is Danny James.
I'm an investigator working
on the Cal Peterson case.
The unarmed schoolteacher
who was shot
by the female police officer.
Okay, but I don't know anything
about that
other than what I read online.
Isn't it true that Cal Peterson
was your driver last year
after you summoned a rideshare
service on your phone?
I'm sorry. I don't
have time for this.
I have to pick something up for
my boss and get it back to him.
But I saw that you filed a
complaint against Mr. Peterson.
Do you mind
telling me what happened?
Look, I really don't want
to get dragged
into a big case like this.
Or I can subpoena you.
SCOTT:
That's the jury you picked?
Are you sure you know
what you're doing?
Nope. A lot of this
is just dumb luck.
You still sure
you don't want to settle?
CAL:
I had been
to a big celebratory dinner
earlier in the evening.
Um, it was
a citywide celebration
honoring public education
and public schoolteachers,
and I actually received
a Teacher of the Year award
from the mayor.
And after this dinner,
what did you do?
Uh, went out
with some other teachers.
Had a few more drinks.
So, wait. Take us through this.
You're drinking with friends...
Well, uh...
this is embarrassing.
But the truth is I don't
normally drink very much.
So when I left my friends
and when I started to walk home,
I realized, um,
I was pretty messed up.
And then I started to get sick.
And I knew
I really needed a bathroom,
and there was that diner,
so I just ran in.
I tried the men's room first,
but it was locked.
I was feeling desperate.
I... I didn't want
to make a mess on the floor,
so I tried the door
to the ladies' room,
and it wasn't locked.
MARISSA: Surprise, surprise.
They like him.
Truth be told, I like him.
I don't recall anyone asking.
Okay, so, you open the door
to the women's restroom.
And what happened?
Uh, there was a woman
on the toilet,
but then I saw the sink...She was on the toilet?
Just about.
She may have been
unbuttoning her pants
or something like that.
This woman, is she
here in the courtroom?
Right over there.
Officer Harris.
[gallery murmuring]
So, you move toward the sink.
And next thing I know,
she pulled her gun
and was waving it in my face.
And then, uh...
then she shot me.
MALIA:
Now, Mr. Peterson,
after Officer Harris grabbed
her gun but before she shot you,
isn't it true you grabbed
the barrel of that gun?
I did.
Can you tell us
why you did that?
I guess it was just instinct.
Seems like every time
you turn on the news,
you hear about
some unarmed black man
being shot by a white cop.
[gallery murmuring]
So when this white cop
was pointing her gun at me,
I knew.
I knew she was gonna shoot me.
So I grabbed the gun and tried
to aim it away from me.
And thank God I did.
She only got me in the arm.
Who knows what she would've hit
if I hadn't.
I could be dead.
Objection! Speculation.
Overruled.
We have no more
questions at this time.
[clears throat]
So...
we've heard a lot about...
how much you had to drink
the night of the shooting.
But I was wondering if you
could also tell me about...
the illegal drugs
you also ingested
that evening.
[gallery murmuring]
I'm sorry. I apologize.
Must be me.
I didn't hear an answer.
I didn't offer one.
I don't have one.
I didn't take any drugs
that evening.
I don't take drugs. Ever.
Oh, I'm sorry.
[exhales] Forgive me.
My mistake.
Ah.
I see what the problem is.
I must have gotten thrown
off by this toxicity report.
Taken on the night
of the shooting.
See, they took you to
the hospital to stitch you up,
and they took some blood.
Remember?
Objection! I haven't seen
any toxicity report.
Defense didn't produce it
in discovery.
Again, I apologize.
I just got it
from the state lab last night.
They've been backed up.
That notwithstanding,
the plaintiff's counsel
had the same access
to this report
as I did, Your Honor.
I'll allow it.
Thank you, Your Honor.
Now, according to this report,
you weren't just drunk,
Mr. Peterson.
You were high on MDMA.
You know, MDMA?
Molly?
[scoffs]I need an answer, sir.
Is it still your testimony
that you didn't do any drugs
that evening?
And let me remind you
that you are still under oath.
No. I mean, yes.
I absolutely didn't take
any drugs that night.
All I can think of is maybe
somebody slipped something
in my drink, but I certainly
wasn't aware of it.
So someone slipped Molly
in your drink while you
were out celebrating
your Teacher of the Year award?
Objection. Argumentative.
Move it along, Mr. Colón.
Certainly, Your Honor,
certainly.
Th-The night that you charged
into Officer Harris's
bathroom...
that wasn't the first time
that you physically threatened
a woman,
was it, Mr. Peterson?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Isn't it true that last year,
at this time,
you used the evening hours
to work as a driver for
a ridesharing company?
And isn't it true that a
complaint was filed against you
by one of your passengers?
A Ms. Veronica Hill?
Objection.
Your Honor, relevance?
The plaintiff's counsel
has gone to great lengths
to present the plaintiff
as a model citizen.
An honored teacher
who could do no wrong.
She opened the door
to character, Your Honor.
Overruled.
BENNY:
Thank you.
Now, let me refresh your memory,
Mr. Peterson.
Isn't it true
that Ms. Hill became
so uncomfortable
with the aggressive,
sexual passes you made
while you were her driver,
that she demanded you pull over
three and a half miles
before she reached
her destination?
She did ask me to pull over.
But I wasn't being aggressive.
It was really just
a misunderstanding.
Oh, just a misunderstanding.
But didn't you chase her on foot
after she exited your car?
I was trying to reason with her.
You were trying to reason with
her while you were chasing her,
screaming at her,
threatening her.
I wasn't threatening her.
I just...
I just didn't want her
to file a complaint.
I really needed that job.
You're a big guy, Mr. Peterson.
How big would you say
Ms. Hill was?
Would you, would you say
that-that she was
a... large woman?
Or would you call
her average?
Or-or-or might you use
the word "petite"?
Petite.
She was definitely petite.
Got it.
No further questions,
Your Honor.
Let's take a 15 minute break.
Nice work.
You know...
...for the first time,
I think, uh,
we might actually have a
shot at winning this thing.
I think so, too.
And I think the plaintiff's
lawyer feels the same way,
which is why I would urge you
to authorize me
to use our newfound leverage
to try again
and broker a settlement.
Can you not feel the tension
in the air?
I don't think there is a good
ending for our city,
no matter which side wins.
Dr. Bull,
I hired you to clear
this officer's good name.
Why don't you worry about that
and let me worry about the city?
When my client came through
the door, what state of dress
or undress were you in?
I had unbuttoned my pants and
I was pulling down my zipper.
You must have been terrified.
I was startled.
My first concern was for my gun.
It was on the sink
and I needed to secure it.
So you weren't scared?
There wasn't time to be scared.
And besides, it didn't seem like
he was coming for me.
It seemed like he was going
for my gun.
And why would he be
going for the gun?
And how would he have even
known that the person
in the bathroom had a gun,
much less put it on the sink?
That's a terrific question, and
one I don't have an answer to,
except for the fact
that I could only deal
with the information
that was in front of me.
And the information
directly in front of me
was that there was a man
someplace he wasn't
supposed to be
and he seemed to be going
for my gun.
So that drove your
decision making?Absolutely.
It didn't occur to you that
he might have been sick?
That he might have been
going for the sink?
I had no way of knowing that.
He didn't look sick?
His head was down.
He stumbled, but...
Did he look drunk?
It was four steps between
the door and the sink.
Did he look black?
[sighs]
He was black. He is black.
Isn't that why you grabbed
for your gun?
No. That's ridiculous.
Without knowing what he
wanted, why he was there,
you grabbed for your gun
because a black man
was standing over you while
you went to the toilet,
isn't that right?With all due respect,
I was grabbing that gun
no matter who
was standing over me
while I go to the toilet.
[scoffs]
Did you struggle for the gun?
No. I got to it first.
I looked at the
bodycam footage.
Didn't look to me like he
was even going for the gun.
Is it possible
that you were wrong?
Is it possible that h-he
wasn't going for the gun?
You weren't there.
Did you think he had a gun?
It never crossed my mind.
My only concern was that
he didn't take my gun.
So I'm confused.
If you had your gun,
and you weren't thinking
about whether or
not he had one,
then why were you pointing
it at him at all?
Because...He was black?
No.
L-Look at the bodycam footage.
The second I had the gun,
he was on me,
trying to take the gun from me.
Because you were
pointing it at him.
Because he didn't
want to get shot.
So the question is: why were
you pointing it at him at all?
If all you wanted to do
was secure it,
then why did you end up
pointing it at my client?
Why did you end up
shooting my client?
And isn't the answer
because he's black?
Let's t-- let's
take a break.
You okay?
I'm thinking this is,
uh, about a tenth
of what you can expect
to face on the stand
when Malia Ford
questions you.
You can't let her bait you.
You can't let her anger you.
This is her technique.
It's what she does.
She's famous for it.
You okay?
Mm.
Great.
Let's go to court.
[crowd shouting]
TONYA [on video]:
Halt! NYPD. Halt!
W-What are you doing?
Let go. Let go of the gun!
[groans]
CAL:
Oh, my God, you shot me!
You really shot me. Oh.
TONYA:
Precinct 55. Charlie to Cent...
Wow. That's quite a tape.
I'm sure you won't forget
anything about that night
for years to come.
Burned in my memory.
So what color jacket
was my client wearing?
Excuse me?
What color sports jacket?
Was it black?
Was it blue? Was it brown?
The witness will please answer.
MALIA:
It's all right.
I withdraw the question.
But do you happen to recall
the color of his shirt?
I don't know.
Mm. White?
Mm.
Yellow?
Mmm.
It was a very light blue.
Mm.
Now how about his face?
Objection, Your Honor.
Counsel is...[alarm blares]
Ladies and gentlemen,
we've received a bomb threat.
We're gonna need everyone to
leave the courthouse right now.
CHUNK: According to
the commissioner's office,
the bomb threat was specifically
targeted to our courtroom.
Rather remarkable piece
of timing, actually.
You took the words
right out of my mouth.
That was not
great in there.
You... you were not
I know.
She makes me nervous.
Well, maybe you want to
come down with something?
So you don't have
to continue today?
Boss. We got the all clear.
Everyone's headed back in.
I'm fine.
Are you sure?
MALIA:
Now, where did we
leave off? Oh, yes,
I was asking if you remember the
color of Mr. Peterson's face.
It was black.
We all know it was black.
And it's your testimony that
that did not contribute
in any way to your decision
to shoot him?
Of course not.
So, then, logically,
what you're really saying is,
no matter who walked in
that room,
you were gonna react
the same way.BENNY: Objection.
Counsel is testifying.
Overruled.
You may answer the question.
Yes. No matter who
came through the door,
I would have reacted
the same.
An old woman?
Yes. I believe so.
You believe so?
What about a child?
A boy, a four-year-old boy?
Your Honor, these are all
ridiculous hypotheticals.
The attorney is badgering
the witness.
I sense the attorney is trying
to make a point; I'll allow it,
but let's get to it sooner
rather than later.
I was asking about a child.
A four-year-old boy,
you'd still point your gun?
Of course not.
Then it's not true.
Despite your earlier testimony
that no matter who walked
through the door,
you were gonna behave
the same way.
For some people
you point your gun,
for others, no.
And, frankly,
I think that's good.
You're a professional.
You should apply
critical thinking
to a decision like this.
So...
at what age do you start
pointing your gun?
If a person's 12?BENNY: Objection!
JUDGE STALDER:
The point, please.14?
It's a 20-year-old boy
instead of a 38-year-old man,
you point your gun?
What if it's a
20-year-old black boy?
Come on.
BENNY:
Your Honor?
[sighs]
You want the truth?
Well, that would be nice.
You always apply
critical thinking
before you point your gun.
But where does that
critical thinking come from?
Two places-- your training
and your experience.
And I'm sorry.
In my experience doing this job,
if I'm in a women's bathroom,
and a man--
yes, a black man--
if a black man
walks into it at 2:00 in the
morning, and moves for my gun...[gallery clamoring]
[gavel bangs]...I'm gonna get it first,
and I'm gonna
point it at him,
and anybody...[gavel banging]
...who does what I do
for a living
and says any different
is a liar!
[gallery clamoring]
I have no further questions,
Your Honor.
I'm so sorry.
So, so sorry.
I can't believe I did that.
I just...
I cracked.
How bad is it?
For our case?
I'd say it's
fairly catastrophic.
You want to tell me
what the hell happened
in court today, Dr. Bull?
No big deal.
It's just, your totally innocent
officer decided
to act on the stand
like she was... totally guilty.
It happens all the...
Wait. Actually,
it never happens.
Well, I'm glad you're so amused.
I've got reports that
my officers are being attacked
all over the city,
and right now,
I got a patrol car burning
in front of One Police Plaza.
We told you what to do.
Yes, you did.
You win. I give up.
You were right, so, let's
move to plan B, shall we?
Sit down and settle this thing.
Offer them
whatever you have to,
but just do it quickly.
We'll start making calls.
[line ringing]
On second thought, let's not
make any calls till morning.
What she said was indefensible.
I second that.
[sighs]
Indefensible. Absolutely.
The thing is, I'm not sure
I believe any of it.
What do you mean?
Well, in the car after court,
she was saying
how sorry she was.
She was shaking her head
the whole time,
and it's not an absolute,
but sometimes, that can indicate
a person doesn't believe
what they're saying.
Well, wait.
Why wouldn't she be sorry?
Her testimony basically
torpedoed the city's whole case.
I don't know.
It's just a feeling.
DANNY:
Please.
She's a racist.
Uh, people show you one face
when they know you're looking,
but the other one,
the real one--
it's always just peeking out
just a little bit,
laughing at you for getting
suckered by the mask.
If you say so.
It's not what I'm feeling.
Tomorrow?
Tomorrow.
[clears throat]
Danny, you have a copy
of that bodycam tape?
I want to give it another look.
Yeah, I'll send you the link.
One last thing.
Does anybody know where Cal
Peterson ended up throwing up?
Well, he was sick.
So sick he had to go
to the women's room.
But I don't recall hearing
about where he threw up.
You're right.
There was nothing about it
in the crime scene photos,
nothing in the notes.
I get the feeling
we're not making any
settlement calls any time soon.
I get the feeling
we should order in.
[crowd shouting]
SCOTT:
Gentlemen?
Where are we?
Why am I totally
in the blind here?
Have we commenced
settlement discussions yet?
We have not.I don't understand.
You want the good news
or the bad news?Oh, come on.
I have finally come to believe
this case isn't
about race at all,
and I think that is cause
for celebration.
I'm not following you.
I think it's really about good
old-fashioned American greed.
And isn't it great
to know there exists
at least two people
in this world who can finally
look past race or skin color
or religious differences
long enough to try and rip off
the City of New York
for a few million dollars?
Now, from your
tox screen report,
we know that not
only were you
legally intoxicated
the night of the shooting,
but you were also high on Molly,
as well.
Mr. Peterson, I'm wondering
if you might have been high
and drunk that night on purpose.
I'm sorry.
I don't understand the question.
Well, I'm asking if perhaps
you drank to excess
and took some MDMA
in anticipation
of getting shot that night.
[gallery murmuring]
A little something
to numb the pain.
Objection! Now counsel is making
absurd assertions
in the hopes
of confusing the jury
and obfuscating facts
already in evidence.
Mr. Colón, I think
this courtroom has already seen
enough drama.
I agree, Your Honor,
but I promise if
you'll bear with
me a moment longer,
I will substantiate
my allegations.
Well, you'd better, or I will be
holding you in contempt.
It's a simple question,
Mr. Peterson.
Did you barge into that
bathroom that night
knowing full well
that you were going
to get shot by Officer Harris?
[scoffs]
Why would I want
to get shot by a cop?
So we could all end up here,
with you suing the City
of New York for $25 million.
[laughing]
That's ridiculous.
Well, yes.
Unless of course,
Officer Harris was in on it.
[gallery murmuring]
MALIA:
Your Honor, do I even
need to cite an objection?
This-this is outlandish![gavel bangs]
[gallery murmuring]
Yes, it is outlandish,
Your Honor, but I can assure you
that I can prove that
Cal Peterson and Tonya Harris
are not the strangers
they've been pretending to be.
That, in fact,
they've been romantically
involved for months now.
[gallery clamoring]
What the hell is he doing?
You people are supposed
to be defending me.
Hmm.
Technically, the City of
New York is our client.
Since it seems you're
trying to swindle the city,
I fear you and I have a
serious conflict of interest.
[gavel banging]
Mr. Peterson, is this true?
Did you
plan this shooting
with Officer Harris?
Absolutely not.
Look at the bodycam footage.
I'm wrestling her for the gun.
Were you?
That's funny,
because the more I look at it,
the more it looks like you were
holding the barrel of the gun
to make sure
that the bullet went
into your arm
and not your chest.
[gallery murmuring]But...
that could just be me.
While you're thinking about it,
I'd like to enter
into evidence
this certified business record
of a history of Cal Peterson's
ridesharing customers.
And let the record reflect
that ten months ago,
he drove a Miss Tonya Harris.
Yeah. It's not surprising.
We all know he likes
to use the ridesharing vehicle
as his personal dating app.
I drive hundreds of women,
probably thousands.
[chuckles]
But in truth, I don'tremember
driving that woman.
BENNY:
Mr. Peterson,
would it surprise you
to know that the...
front desk clerk at the
Bridgecroft Motel in Astoria
remembers checking you in
at least 23 times
in the last
ten months?
No. It wouldn't surprise me.
My roommates can get loud.
Sometimes I rent a cheap room
to grade papers,
prepare lesson plans. Alone.
[inhales sharply]
Are you aware
that there is video surveillance
cameras in the hallways,
so the clerk can see if,
say, Tonya Harris decided
to join you
in your room?
I'd be happy to enter
the video surveillance cameras
into evidence if you'd like.
Or perhaps I can just call
Tonya Harris to the stand,
see what she has to say.
But...
you know,
as a former prosecutor,
I should tell you that
the person who confesses first
is usually the one
who gets the lighter sentence.
You are still under oath,
Officer Harris.
We were lying in bed one night
at the Bridgecroft Motel,
and he turned to me,
and he said...
"You know, darlin',
I'd take a bullet for you."
And the idea just grew
from there.
How many years you
think they'll get?
Whatever it is,
it's not long enough.
I'm not sure I ever
made it clear, but...
I admire the
hell out of you.
[chuckles softly]
[sighs]
Would you like to get a drink?
I would love to
get a drink, but, uh...
[inhales sharply]
I'm sort of between drinks
right now.
If that circumstance
should ever change,
you can be sure
that I will, uh...
I'll call you first.
Well, we don't have to drink.
Oh, trust me. If you're gonna be
spending any time
with me at all,
you are gonna need a drink.
I have that on good authority
from a great
many women.[laughs]
Well, don't look now, but...
I just might call you.
Don't you threaten me,
young lady.[laughs]
Captioning sponsored by
CBS
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org