[grunting]
DAVIS:
Come on, man!
Escape!
Roll out!
Get to your feet!
Come on!
[whoops]
[whistle blows]
[panting softly]
[exhales]
[breathless]:
Come on...
[retching]
We're heading over to the
dining hall. You coming?
Nah, I think I'm gonna
stick around.
Still over?
Yeah.
We'll catch you later, then.
[beeping]
DAVIS:
Antonio.
You got to be kidding me.
You're still three pounds over.
We talked about this.
You said you had it
under control.
I thought I did.
Well, I guess you thought wrong,
didn't you?
I'm sorry, Coach.Yeah, I bet you are.
But it's your teammates
you should be apologizing to.
If we have to forfeit
your slot, again,
do you know how hard it's gonna
be for us to qualify for state?
You got two hours
before weigh-ins.
Maybe you can still fix this.
You know what you got to do.
[horn honking]
[panting]
[wheezing]
Antonio!
Hey. Antonio.
Come here. Look at me, kid.
BOY:
Is he okay?
Call 911. One of
you guys call 911.
CHUNK:
What about Emmet?
Man, if anybody was gonna
go pro, it was gonna be Emmet.
Oh, um,
he sort of went pro.
He is a sportscaster in Atlanta?
Uh, beautiful wife.
No gray hair.
Ah, okay.I hate him.
Well, those are all
very hateable qualities.Mm-hmm.
Wish I had accomplished enough
for somebody to hate me.
What?
Mm-hmm.
What are you talking about?
Man, you work at one
of the snootiest prep schools
in America.
I mean, I'm sure there's
plenty of people out there
that hate you.Maybe.
I don't know.
I'm a guidance counselor, Chunk.
[both laugh]
So, what can I do
for you, Reggie?
Well, what makes you think
I want something?
"Makes you think..." Well,
you called me out the blue.
I haven't seen you
in, what, eight years?What...?
You bring
your briefcase with you.Oh...
What, are you gonna try
to sell me something?
I wish. Um...[laughs]
Uh, it's a 16-year-old kid.
Um...
One of the students
at my school, and he died
while he was training,
of a heart attack;
he's a wrestler.
Seriously?
He's a scholarship kid,
uh, Latino.
And the school,
they can't get his parents
to sign a legal waiver
fast enough.
The school wouldn't think twice
about firing me
if they knew I was talking
to a lawyer about this.
He used to come by my
office quite a bit.
He grew up poor in Newark.
Trust me, there are
not many kids like that
at Dartwell Preparatory School.
I just want to even up
the odds a little bit.
I mean, not that the school's
doing anything wrong.
Everything's
very polished,
very appropriate,
very respectful.
So, what is it
you'd like me to do?
I want you to get involved.
This boy's parents,
these are good people.
But they're in
way over their head.
I know how Dartwell operates.
They're just gonna keep throwing
their fancy lawyers at them
and pressuring them
to sign away their rights.
Do everything they can
s-so they got zero chance
of getting a fair settlement.
Just because these people
are poor
and their boy was there
on a scholarship,
that doesn't mean that his life
was worth any less
than any other kid there.
Let me see what I can do.
CLAUDIA:
He was always good at sports.
At games.
But wrestling,
that was his favorite.
Last year, he was a freshman,
he wrestled for the public
school down the street.
They got into a
state tournament.
First time it ever happened.
And everyone knew it
was because of Antonio.
That's when the calls started.
The calls?
Yes.
Schools wanting Antonio
to wrestle for them.
Expensive private schools.
Seven of them.
Three even offered
full scholarships.
That's very impressive.
We were thrilled.
This neighborhood
is not that safe.
The gangs,
they're everywhere.
Especially in the schools.
So why Dartwell?
We went and we looked.
It was beautiful.
[laughs softly]
But most of all,
it was Coach Davis.
He sat there, right
where you're sitting.
Promised us that he would
take care of our boy.
And has the school been
forthcoming with you
since your son passed?
Yes and no.
Manuel and I have been there
at least a dozen times.
I don't know how many
phone calls we've made.
They all tell us how sorry they
are but there are no answers.
And no one will explain
how this happened.
And I've yet to get
a call back from Coach Davis.
His lawyers have probably
advised him not to call you.
BULL:
We took a look at the
documents you sent over.
The proposed
settlement agreement,
the medical examiner's report.
And the examiner found that
Antonio died of heart failure
brought on by heat exhaustion
and extreme dehydration.
But he also mentioned a
juvenile mitral valve murmur?
Yes. That was something
he was born with,
but the doctors said that
that disappeared years ago.
That has nothing
to do with this.
BENNY:
No, I'm sure
you're right.
But in the agreement,
the school's lawyers reference
an "undisclosed
congenital heart condition."
It's clear they're trying
to use Antonio's heart murmur
to shield themselves from blame.
BULL:
Regardless of that,
they are offering you
a half a million dollars,
which is certainly
a respectable place to start.
The catch, of course,
is to get it,
or wherever we might land
money-wise,
you are gonna have to sign
a no-fault agreement.
That's what I don't understand.
What does that mean?
It means they're paying you
to go away.
Once you take
the money,
they don't want to hear
from you again.
You can't sue them,
you can't complain,
you can't go to the press.
The matter is closed.
Which means that I can't sleep,
I can't eat, I can't breathe.
No.
I don't care
about the money.
I want to know why this happened
and I want to know
how this happened.
My son was a healthy teenager.
And healthy teenagers
don't have heart attacks.
Well, then the choice is simple.
If you folks want to force
answers out of the school,
your only option is to sue.
BENNY:
What we'd do is file
a wrongful death civil suit
on your behalf.
We'd effectively be suing
Dartwell Prep School
and Coach Davis.
Just so everyone understands,
once you demand a trial,
all bets are off.
Maybe we'll get some answers,
maybe we won't.
Maybe we'll get
you some money,
or maybe you'll end up
with none.
So let me ask you, Dr. Bull,
would you accept half a million
dollars and silence
in return for your child's life?
No. Of course not.
Then we need to sue.
For Antonio.
♪
[muttering]:
Come on...
[grunts]
Around...
I mean, come on.
[whimpers, moans]
You look pregnant.
Taylor! Someone!
Help me!
Normally, don't you put on
your coat and mittens
and then your scarf?
It's a baby sling.
You had a baby, didn't you?
Yeah, but it didn't come
with one of those.
Never mind.
I was hoping you might be able
to help me a little.
Hey. Ju--
Uh...
just wanted you to know
we got the witness list.
Defense is calling
Sarah Barnes to the stand.
Wow. Playing hardball.
Mm-hmm.Who's she?
She is a brilliant medical mind
completely unfettered
by ethics and morality.
Excuse me?She's a gun for hire.
A very expensive
gun for hire.
The best or the worst,
depending on
what side of the courtroom
you're standing on.
Used to be New Jersey's
chief medical examiner.
Now she makes a fortune
providing her clients
with whatever medical
opinion they need to win.
[sighs]
Well, if Dartwell Academy's
hiring her,
we can assume they're going
all in on the heart murmur
as Antonio's cause of death.
We're gonna need to
get ahead of her testimony.
So, Taylor,
comb the Internet
for every word
this woman has ever uttered
or written
on the subject of heart murmurs.
If she's ever said anything
even slightly contradictory
to what she says about
Antonio's death,
I want Benny to be able
to pounce on it.
Let's talk jurors.
Oh, let's talk
authority bias.
Okay, what about
authority bias?
It's not good for our side.
People with an authority bias
are blinded by the power
of an authority figure,
or, for that matter,
an authoritarian institution.
They will always give it
the benefit of the doubt.
So they'll take
the school's word
that this was just
a tragic accident.
Exactly.
Mm.
And that's why we want
jurors who are distrustful.
Good afternoon, folks.
Let's start with
a hypothetical.
You are on an airplane.
The cabin doors close,
you've been instructed to
put your cell phone
on airplane mode.
But you are in the middle of
a very important text exchange.
What do you do?
Ma'am?
Uh, turn it off.
Safety first.
What do you think would happen
if you left it on?
What's the difference?
They want you to turn it off,
I'm gonna turn it off.
Blind faith
in a vague instruction
issued by an institutional
authority.
You seeing any signs of
rebellion below the surface?
Not a whiff.
Big joiner. Rotary Club.
President of her
alumni association.
[scoffs]:
No.
Your Honor, we'd like to thank
and excuse this juror.
And what about you, sir?
Me?Yeah. You hear
the announcement,
what do you do?I keep texting.
To be honest, I never turn
my phone off on the plane.
I just silence it.
They pretend like
it's about safety,
but really, it's just about them
not wanting us on our phones.
It's a control thing for them.
Tell me this man is
exactly who he seems.
Randy Grider, grandfather
and self-described cynic.
Manages a restaurant, and has
had what appears to be
a very public ten-year feud
with the health department.
Refers to health inspectors
as navel-gazing bureaucrats
whose only concern is
hitting a monthly quota
of violations.
Oh, my.
Welcome aboard, Randy.
I've been thinking
about tomorrow.
I think maybe we attack
the school's narrative
right from the jump.
Put our medical expert
on first to dispel any idea
that this supposed heart
murmur had anything to do
with Antonio's death.
Mm.
Uh, I'm leaning towards
making Claudia,
Antonio's mother,
our opening act.Why is that?
When Dr. Barnes
takes the stand,
the last thing we need is
for the jury to be wondering
why the Garcias didn't
fill in the school.
So we put Claudia on first
and have her speak
directly to it.
They didn't tell the school,
because the heart murmur
disappeared sometime after
Antonio's third birthday.
So they didn't inform the school
because it was a nonissue.
Exactly.
Ah.
And we'll drive the point home
with our own medical expert.
BENNY:
Mrs. Garcia,
at what age was Antonio
diagnosed
with the mitral valve murmur?
Shortly after he was born.
He was three months when
they first noticed it, I think.
And after you received
that diagnosis,
were you aware of it
manifesting itself
in any way on your son?
Did he exhibit any symptoms?
Was he suffering in any way?
No. Never.
But we weren't surprised.
At the time of the diagnosis,
the doctors told us
that in all likelihood,
it would have no impact
on him at all.
In fact, in most cases,
it actually disappears.
Or "resolves itself,"
which I think is
how they put it.
Mrs. Garcia,
do you recall submitting
this health questionnaire
to Dartwell
with Antonio's admission
materials?
Yes, I do.
And on the questionnaire,
it asks
if the student had ever
been diagnosed
with a heart condition.
And you answered no
to that question.
Didn't you?Yes, I did.
Why would you do that?
Why wouldn't you include the
information on the heart murmur?
When he was five years old,
the doctors told us
that it was gone.
He didn't have
a heart condition.
All right, I understand that.
But the question was asking
if Antonio
had ever been diagnosed
with a heart condition.
I guess that you can
read it that way.
To be honest, I just
didn't think about it.
When he was born, they said
that he had something,
and then they said
that he didn't.
So, in my mind, he didn't.
Every year, he had a physical.
And even when the Dartwell
Preparatory School's doctor
examined him, before
he began at that school,
he said that my son was
completely healthy.
But of course, none of these
doctors anticipated
that my son would be made to run
behind a school bus
in a garbage bag,
like some kind of a dog!
Your Honor, the witness is
being inflammatory.
She's speculating about
the thoughts of others.
She's assuming facts
not in evidence.
Sustained. The jury will
disregard that last statement.
No further questions,
Your Honor.
Mrs. Garcia,
before Antonio enrolled,
were you aware of
how competitive
Dartwell's wrestling team was?
We knew that they won a lot.
We knew that winning
mattered to them.
We knew that it was
one of the reasons
why they wanted our son.
And it's one of the reasons
that you wanted Dartwell,
because it was one
of the best in the state.
Well, yes, of course.
Every parent wants the best
for their child.
So you must have been thrilled
when you got an offer from them.
Yes. We thought we'd
won the lottery.
We?
Yes, we.
The whole family was thrilled.
Antonio was thrilled,
and we were thrilled for him.
Well, and not just because
he'd get to wrestle,
but he'd also get
a better education.
Maybe even a chance to go
to a superior college.
Yes, of course.
Has anyone in your family ever
attended college before?
CLAUDIA:
No.
Antonio would have been
the first.
So there was a lot riding
on Antonio's success,
or lack thereof
at Dartwell, wasn't there?
For him, for the family.
I would think
for any child, yes.
Now, regarding
the mitral valve prolapse,
the questionnaire was not
the only opportunity you had
to disclose this condition,
was it?
There was nothing to disclose.
You accompanied Antonio to his
preliminary physical exam
at the school.
Did you tell the doctor
about it then?
No, but...
You spoke to Coach Davis on
no less than a dozen occasions.
Did you ever bring it up
with him?
Objection, Your Honor.
Asked and answered.
Not with regard
to Coach Davis it hasn't been.
Objection overruled.
The witness will
answer the question.
There was nothing to bring up.
The condition no longer existed.
And that's why you chose
not to include it
in the questionnaire.Yes.
Even though you knew
how rigorous
the Dartwell
wrestling program was,
you never thought to mention
a heart condition?
That's pretty reckless,
don't you think?
But there was no
heart condition.
Wouldn't you have wanted Antonio
to have the most thorough
physical exam possible?
Wouldn't you have wanted
that doctor to know
everything about your son?Of course.
MOSLEY:
Didn't they ask you
whether he'd had
the measles or the mumps?
Yes, of course.
And even though he no longer
had those diseases,
you answered those questions,
didn't you?BENNY: Objection!
Relevance. Counsel is conflating
contagious diseases
with genetic...Overruled.
Ask the question again, please.
Even though he no longer
had those diseases,
you chose to answer
those questions.
Didn't you?
The witness will answer
the question.
Yes.
MOSLEY:
So you understood the question,
but intentionally
misled the school
because you feared
if they knew the answer,
they might withdraw
the scholarship.
Objection.
Argumentative.
Counselor's badgering
the witness, Your Honor.
I'm trying to establish
that the witness applied
different criteria
to different questions.
That the witness knew full well
what the intention
of the question was,
but when it didn't
suit her purposes,
she didn't answer it.
There was nothing to answer.
He didn't have
a heart condition.
You lied, and your son died,
Mrs. Garcia.
[gavel bangs]
Ms. Mosley, I have given you
a wide berth of latitude today.
Don't give me reason
to regret it.
I withdraw the question,
Your Honor.
Nothing further at this time.
[elevator bell chimes]
TAYLOR:
I've been going through
the last three years
of Dr. Barnes'
testimony transcripts,
and I've come up empty.MARISSA:
Good news/bad news
is she never met
a paying gig
she didn't like,
so we have four or five more
years of material to go through.
Do we know when
she's gonna testify?
BENNY:
It's hard to say.
We could rest our case
as early as tomorrow.
I'll read fast.
Danielle James,
you're next in the Thunderdome.
[sighs] You ever
heard the expression
"no news is good news"?
Never. Never ever.Hmm.
Well, then you won't find what
I have to say very comforting.
So, uh, Antonio's teammates were
not particularly forthcoming.
I've never been "no, ma'amed"
so much in my life.
They acted like
the team's regimen
was no big deal,
just standard practice.
Yeah, been there and done that.
They're circling the wagons.
Team first.
That's how competitive
athletes think.
Anything else is disloyal.
And you, Mr. Palmer,
you dragged us into this.
Have you any light to shed?
Actually, I did find
something interesting.
It was in the discovery packet
the defense sent over.
These are the wrestling
team's rosters
and body measurement stats
for the last four years.
And why are we
looking at these?
You see last year's?
Now look at the rosters,
then look at each kid's weight.
Now...
look at the year before that.
[clears throat]
They look almost identical.
What's your point?
Now go back one more year.
I'm sorry.
They look virtually the same.
You're losing me, Chunk.
Now look at their heights.
They're growing, but they're not
changing their weight classes.
Bingo.
BENNY:
Coach Davis,
you have had
quite a run at Dartwell.
16 years as head coach.
Four years as an assistant
at other schools.
I've been very blessed.
BENNY:
And I'm guessing,
in your two decades
of working with young athletes,
you have learned a thing or two
about sports nutrition?
All part of the game.
Ah. So tell me,
how is it possible
that during some of your
wrestlers' prime growth years--
now, I'm talking
between 14 and 18--
they don't seem
to gain any weight?
I'm sorry,
I-I don't know what you mean.
I apologize.
Let me get
a little more specific.
As it turns out,
I was able to get my hands
on the Dartwell wrestling team's
varsity roster
for the last three years.
Now, Coach Davis, are you aware,
according to your own
rosters and weight records,
from sophomore to senior year,
on average, only 12%
of the wrestlers on your team
changed their weight class?
Okay.
What-- You don't find that odd?
No. I don't.
A lot of it's genetics.
But wrestlers--
winning, competitive
high school wrestlers--
just tend to be
early developers.
It's the right body type
for wrestling.
So their growth just
isn't terribly dramatic,
because, by and large,
the bulk of it has happened
before they start
their work with the team.
Really?
Well, then,
how do you explain Lance Briles,
grew two inches in three years
and didn't gain any weight?
Clearly the bulk of his growth
didn't happen
before he joined the team.
Well, Lance, I mean, you're
talking about an outlier there.
That's not a typical situation.
I see.
And-and what about Ryan Tissen?
Grew four inches
but didn't gain a pound.
He an outlier, too?
What about Reese Nichols?
Grew five inches,
and no weight gain.
[chuckles]: I mean,
wrestler after wrestler.
Uh, these stats don't lie.
Although 80% of your wrestlers
grew at least three inches
during their time
on your team,
only 12% gained weight.
Now, I don't know about you,
but that seems
pretty strange to me.
Pretty scary, pretty dangerous.
Objection.
Counselor's testifying.
Mr. Colón.
Oh, that's all right,
Your Honor.
I'm gonna put a pin
in that for now.
Now, Coach Davis,
your success with the team
has started to wane
in the last few years.
You even failed
to qualify for state
in the last three.
Very tough competition.
Last three years
have been challenging.
Actually, in all three
of those years, you didn't have
a wrestler that qualified
in Antonio's weight class.
Am I right?
You had to
forfeit the slot.
Yes.
Probably didn't make
your bosses very happy.
Now, uh, were you aware
that the school's administration
had actually started
reaching out
to potential
replacement candidates
for your position?
I'd heard rumors.
But that's the nature
of athletics.
You don't bring home
the trophies,
people start to look elsewhere.
Yeah.
Well, it must have been
very exciting
when you were able
to recruit Antonio.
Great wrestler, perfect weight.
I had high hopes for Antonio.
Really believed in the boy.
BENNY:
So how did you feel
when he showed up
an inch and a half taller
and eight pounds heavier
than he was last May?
[chuckles]:
Obviously, I was surprised.
But... eight pounds
is not an insurmountable goal
for these kids.
BENNY:
Oh, I know.
Look at all
the athletes
you've worked with
in the past
that have grown
inches taller
and have gained
absolutely no weight.
And now here we are.
Let me ask you a question.
If you found out that some of
your athletes were doing things
that compromised their health
to keep their weight down,
maybe even put their lives
at risk, what would you do?
To stop them, I mean.
Objection. The attorney
is badgering the witness,
making up hypotheticals.
BENNY:
You're right.
Let's not be hypothetical.
Let's get specific.
What did you say or do
for Lance Briles?
Or Ryan Tissen?
Or Reese Nichols?
Or for that matter,
Antonio Garcia,
when you discovered
that they were getting taller?
Because let's be honest,
you can't get taller
and not gain any weight.
Did you tell them
to run behind
the team's bus
in a garbage bag?
Witness will answer
the question.
BENNY:
Oh, that's all right.
I'm making the coach
uncomfortable,
and I don't want to do that.
I withdraw the question.
Nothing further.
DALTON:
Let's take
a ten-minute recess
and then continue
with defense's
cross-examination.
Any news on our friend
Dr. Barnes?
MARISSA:
Actually,
Taylor is waiting outside
in the hallway for you.
She thinks she found something.
TAYLOR:
I've looked through
everything Dr. Barnes
has ever written or said.
Every medical journal article,
every FDA drug testimonial,
every speech, every
seminar, every everything.
And believe it or not, I found
nothing about heart murmurs.
How is that possible?
But when I looked through
her corporate accounts,
I noticed she almost always
tries to time her vacations
with European
medical symposiums.
And then it occurred to me,
could it be that Dr. Barnes
offers her opinions
and expertise in languages
other than in English
and in countries other than
the United States?
Long story long, my three years
of high school German paid off.
Dr. Barnes was a speaker at
a cardiology trauma convention
in Munich two years ago.
This is a transcript
of her speech.
What did it say?
I'll spare you
my terrible German accent,
but basically, she says
that mitral valve murmurs
have never-- I repeat, never
been shown to increase the risk
of myocardial infarctions,
regardless
of other externalities.
So in the words of the good
doctor, Antonio's heart murmur
couldn't have caused
his heart attack.
That's how I read it.
Ooh. Speak of the devil
and she will appear.
Jason.
Sandra.
Nice work, Taylor.
This is gonna be fun.
So, after examining
the original medical reports,
the toxicology results
and Antonio's personal
medical records,
what conclusions
were you able to draw?
Well, the first thing
to catch my attention
was Antonio's mitral valve
prolapse, his heart murmur.
That a girl, Sandra.
Come on in, the water's fine.
MARISSA:
Bull, you better watch out.
Your smug is showing.
MOSLEY:
So, in your
expert opinion,
you believe that
Antonio's mitral valve murmur
was the cause
of his catastrophic
heart event?
Actually, no.
[gallery murmuring]
No?No?
No?
And why is that?
The more I looked
at the medical reports,
the more I felt as though
something had been overlooked.
And then I realized.
It was lactic acidosis.
MOSLEY:
Lactic acidosis?
Could you explain to the jury
what that is?
Certainly.
When the body is under
extreme physical exertion,
as Antonio's was,
and it can't get enough oxygen,
it looks for alternate sources,
alternate pathways
to get its energy.
Anaerobic pathways.
The by-product
of this process
is lactic acid.
Lactic acidosis is simply
when this lactic acid
enters the bloodstream.
And why is this important?
Because in certain cases,
lactic acidosis can interfere
with a standard toxicology test.
Like the one performed
during the autopsy
in this case.
So I had some of the samples
rerun at a private lab.
And what were those results?
Objection, Your Honor.
This is the first
we've heard of these tests.
I'm going to allow this.
But I'll make sure
you have ample time
to conduct any confirmations
that you need, Counselor.
Overruled.MOSLEY:
And what
did these new tests show?
They showed that Antonio
was using amphetamines
at the time
of his death.
[gavel banging]
Now, how big a factor
would these amphetamines be
in causing
Antonio's heart attack?
Enormous.
In my opinion, it's the
amphetamines that killed him.
She's wrong. Antonio
would not use drugs.
I know my son.
BENNY:
We could go
to another lab.
An independent lab.
See if we get
a different result.
Benny, you don't understand.
My boy, he grew up around drugs.
Where we live,
there are drugs everywhere.
He grew up stepping over strung
out junkies on the sidewalk.
Does anybody honestly believe
that my boy would put in
all this hard work
to get to go to a
place like Dartwell
and then just throw it all away
just to get high?
I don't think they think
it's about getting high.
Athletes have been known to use
amphetamines to train harder,
to train longer,
to push themselves further.
Especially boxers and wrestlers.
Athletes looking to cut weight.
Well, then they made him do it,
because my son would never do
that unless somebody made him!
[Claudia crying]
[door opens, closes]
I think she's had enough.
I think we've all had enough.
Excuse me?
She'll just keep fighting
and fighting till it kills her.
Or kills us.
He was her everything.
He was my everything, too.
But the longer I think about it,
Antonio would've done anything
to stay in that school.
What are you trying to tell us?
Tell them we'll sign
the agreement now.
She'll hate me for the rest
of our lives together,
but I'll hate me
if I don't put a stop to this.
Manuel...Look,
I know money
won't bring back our son,
but at least it'll give Claudia
time to not work.
Time to heal.
Mr. Garcia, I sympathize.
But at the moment,
they're winning.
There's no reason
for them to settle.
And a "not liable" verdict
is gonna go a long way
to restoring their reputation.
Also, there's nothing
I can do without
Mrs. Garcia signing off.
You filed suit together.
There's no way for me
to negotiate a settlement
without her approval, too.
TAYLOR:
More?
Employment records for everyone
in the athletic department
for the last seven years.
Every notation,
every complaint.
If there's any history
of amphetamine use
in that department, I have
to believe I will find it here.
What are you two up to?
Taylor got me into Antonio's
e-mails for the last two years.
I'm-I'm looking
for something, anything.
I'm going through
the social media accounts
of every wrestler at Dartwell,
and by the way,
teenage boys need to be rounded
up and kept under lock and key
until their early 20s.
[quietly]:
Oh, man.
Hey, if I want
to print something out,
do I do it the regular way
even though this is
kind of a bootlegged file?
Just press Command-P,
and it will be waiting
for you in the printer.
Good talking to you.
[phone ringing]
Yes. Oh, yes.
Sure. Send him in.
Hey.
You come by to give me
a progress report on the trial,
or did someone catch you smoking
out behind the field house?
Why didn't you tell me?
Tell you what?
Been going through
some of Antonio's e-mails.
Found this one, from you.
"Antonio,
"I want to make sure
that I was crystal clear
"in our meeting earlier today.
"What you are doing is not only
unfair and unsportsmanlike,
"it is extraordinarily
dangerous,
"as well as grounds
for expulsion.
"I told you that your secret
"was safe with me,
but only if you stayed true
"to your promise
and never again repeat
this behavior as long as you are
a student at Dartwell."
You knew that that boy
was taking drugs?
You wrote this three weeks
before he died!
Yes, but that didn't
have anything
to do with his death, did it?
I mean, I got him
to stop, Chunk.
That's why I wrote the e-mail.
Okay, the
medical report--
the one I read said that kid
was clean when he died!
The school just ordered
a new toxicology report, Reggie.
Antonio was using amphetamines
when he collapsed.
Oh, man.
I'm sorry, Chunk.
I would've never reached out
to you had I known...
How did you find out?
I guessed.
And then he-he fessed up.
That kid,
he would come here
all the time, Chunk.
All he wanted to talk about
was how he was terrified that
he wasn't gonna make weight.
You see, in his mind,
if he didn't make weight,
he couldn't wrestle.
And if couldn't wrestle, then
they'd take his scholarship,
so he'd have to leave school.
[quietly]:
Right?
But you know, he was,
he was sweaty, he was jittery.
So I knew he was on something.
And... I made him promise
he was done.
And you just took him
at his word?
He's 16. He thinks his life
is on the line.
How could you just
leave it at that?!
I didn't. Yes, I didn't tell
anyone in the administration,
but I did tell
the one person in this school
who I thought
could make him stop.
I told Coach Davis.
DALTON:
Okay, Counselors,
we will proceed
to final arguments.
Actually, Your Honor, if I may,
the plaintiffs
would like to recall
defendant Wayne Davis
to the stand.
Objection, Your Honor.
The defendant
has already testified,
and the plaintiff has rested.
In light of the testimony
of Dr. Barnes, new evidence
has been discovered
that we did not have the chance
to introduce earlier.
All right, Mr. Colón.
I'll allow it.
I want to remind you
that you remain under oath.
You may proceed.
Now, Coach Davis,
I'm assuming
your team,
your school,
has some sort of policy
in place with regard to drugs.
Would you mind
sharing that with us?
Uh, it's simple.
No drugs allowed.
Okay.
And what if one
of your wrestlers
were to violate that rule?
Uh, immediate suspension.
Pretty
straightforward.
So let me ask you a question.
You ever drug test
Antonio Garcia?
No.
I don't test my wrestlers
unless I have a reason
to suspect something's going on.
Now, when you say
"reason to suspect something,"
I'm guessing you mean
unusual behavior.
Absences, maybe even
a worried teammate?
Yeah, sure. Any of those.
BENNY:
Now, Coach Davis,
do you recall
a conversation you had
with Reggie Baumann,
one of the school's
guidance counselors,
about Antonio Garcia
that took place about
two weeks prior to his death?
Um...
[clears throat]
It's hard to say
without knowing more
about the conversation.
BENNY:
Of course. My mistake.
Let me be more specific.
Let me see if this
will jog your memory.
Do you recall the conversation
you had where Reggie Baumann
told you that Antonio
was taking amphetamines
to drop weight
in order for him
to be able
to wrestle in the slot
that would be
most advantageous
for you and the team?
You told Mr. Baumann
that you'd take care of it.
That ring a bell?
The witness will answer
the question.
On advice of counsel,
I refuse to answer,
and invoke
my Fifth Amendment privilege.
[gavel banging]
You didn't take care of it,
did you, Coach Davis?
You didn't confront
Antonio Garcia,
a minor in your custody,
about his amphetamine use,
did you?
Because that would have meant
you would have had to bench him.
No. Instead you made him
run behind the team bus
because you needed him
to compete
if you had any chance
of making state.
If you had any hope
of salvaging the season.
If you had any chance
of keeping your job.
Isn't that what happened here?
Again, uh, I'm afraid I'm gonna
have to plead the Fifth.
[gallery murmuring]
[gavel bangs]
We the jury find the defendants,
Wayne Davis and Dartwell
Preparatory School,
liable for the wrongful death
of Antonio Garcia.
We the jury
award compensatory damages
in the amount of $300,000
to the plaintiff.
Wha-- That is less
than the settlement offer.
But wait, there's more.
JURY FOREPERSON:
In addition,
we the jury also award
punitive damages
in the amount of $5 million.
[laughs softly]
[inhales sharply]
Hmm.
All right.
Here we go.
[laughs]
Yeah.
CHUNK:
Oh, look.
You gave birth
to a sporting good.
What do you got, a
Wilson? A Spalding?
[laughs]
Can I help you?
Just thought you should know,
I just heard from Reggie.
The school officially
fired Coach Davis.
Sounds like the police
department is opening up
a criminal investigation
as well.
Hmm. And how's
your friend Reggie doing?
Mm.
[sighs]
He tendered his letter
of resignation today.
Said he feels like
he failed Antonio.
Well, let him know
he did his best.
I did. And I will.
And I appreciate you and
the firm diving in like you did.
Even though there wasn't
necessarily anything
in it for you.
For any of us. Thank you.
Getting ready to be a dad.
Trying to build some good karma.
[chuckles]
I hear you.
Hey. Let me play
with Bull Junior.
Oh-- Oh...
Okay, I'd like
my boy back, please.
Are you sure you can
handle this?
It's like looking in a mirror.
[laughs]
Nice.
[gasps]
[Chunk chuckles]
Captioning sponsored by
CBS
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org