Hey, Miguel!
It's been a long time, amigo.
You look good, Frank.
This is Mr Rico. He pays the bills.
How're you doin'?
That's Denning. And Erskine in the truck.
They're good men.
You didn't have to bring extra help.
We can take care of Dundee.
- You know him?
- I heard of him.
That's Teddy. He's a tracker.
Dundee went bush about a week ago
and Teddy'll help us find him.
The fella you're looking for,
is it Mick Dundee?
Yeah, so what?
For you.
Where's he going?
I don't know.
Denning, bring him back!
Come back!
He's gone!
Shit!
- This holds us up?
- No worries.
Maybe a day or two
to get another tracker.
What?
There's a quicker way.
This is the luxury holiday house?
Yeah.
- View's pretty good.
- Yeah, it's not bad.
Probably double the value of this place.
That'd be... two...
...three hundred dollars, minimum.
Well... you're the only one
I've ever brought here.
I'm so lucky to have a rich man like you.
What is it?
I think you'd better come with me.
Don't...!
Dundee!
I know you're up there.
Come down, or I shoot your friend.
Shoot the dopey bastard!
You shot Walter!
Yeah. It was all I could think of
to save his life.
- By shooting him?
- I only nicked him.
- Now we're all on foot. That's even.
- Seven to two is even?
I thought you two were mates.
So did I.
Garcia, kill him.
Wait.
Why would Dundee want you dead?
You know this country?
Well, of course, you see...
That's his backyard, up there.
And no man alive
knows this place better.
Except perhaps me. And so...
So he shot his best mate.
What a bastard.
This man thinks like me.
Garcia, let him go.
You stay up front.
Let's go.
There, that's what I'm looking for.
They've found the shack.
- Think they'll find us?
- Should do.
I left a trail even Wally could follow.
- Take your bra off.
- This is hardly the time!
Hey! Look at this!
You've lost 'em.
- You still know how to shoot.
- Yeah, feels great.
If he moves, kill him.
Mick, the gun's empty.
There's no more bullets.
But he doesn't know that.
Not much he can do about it anyway.
- Back soon. I'll check on Wally.
- Do you know where they are?
Yeah.
About 500 yards that way,
behind that ridge.
How do you know that?
Can't you smell it?
- Their sweat?
- Wally's aftershave.
Where are you going?
We're camping.
Do you want coffee or not?
- Come on!
- I'm coming!
- What's happened?
- Crocodile.
You're joking.
Yeah, it's a croc. Big one.
Sixteen feet.
See where he knelt
to fill his canteen.
You think he was taken by un cocodrilo?
Well, you could put it like that, yes.
Look!
There's nothing we can do here.
You, get some water.
Jose.
Stay with him.
- What's that?
- I'm gonna make a telephone call.
See who's about.
I think we're gonna need some help.
- Wanna give me a hand?
- Would Bonnie say no to Clyde?
Who?
That's the tree.
There's the bats.
Fill this up with those berries.
I'll be up on top of the ridge.
What the hell is that?
That is the mating call
of the jarra jarra bird.
It's a very large native bird, it's very rare.
Meat-eater. Has been known
to take small children away.
But don't worry,
it won't come near the fire.
Thank God you're back.
Did you hear that noise?
- What noise?
- I never heard anything like it.
Wind, maybe.
What's in the bag?
A little present.
Smell.
It stinks! Is it gonna work?
Oh, yeah. To a bat,
this is like that Channel No 5.
I'll be back for dinner.
Keep an eye on the kids.
Listen, boys,
you should be nice for the lady.
She's not here to guard you,
she's here to protect you.
You two aren't the only...
...crawling nasties in this place.
Dundee.
Tell me about him.
Well, there are bushmen
and there's Mick Dundee.
See, he's more like an Aborigine
than a white man.
He was adopted by Aborigines,
and he had to go through that initiation.
He knows about their magic.
Their...
...black magic.
You know, some people say
that he talks to the animals.
The Aborigines call him...
...Jabajada Arderdah, which means,
The crocodile who walks like a man.
If what you say is true,
it's lucky we brought the Kryptonite.
Look at that!
Get some sleep.
- Gonna be a long day tomorrow.
- Yeah.
Gonna be a long night, too.
Quick hands.
Shit!
- What is it?
- A bloody big snake.
It's a python, you big girl.
See how you like it if someone runs
out of the dark and throws one at you.
- Dundee was here, in the camp?
- He ran straight through.
You didn't even get a shot off?
Well, he came out of nowhere.
And he moved like lightning, and...
...and there was no sound.
No sound at all.
Dundee's some sort of a ghost
or something.
This Dundee likes to play games, Miguel.
Maybe we'll teach him
some good games when it gets light.
Come on, Jose, get up.
I told you. Black magic.
Crap magic.
Sweep the area, and stick together.
You!
He didn't fly in here and take Jose.
There must be tracks. Find them.
- You thinking what I'm thinking?
- We're headed in the right direction.
- Let's get out.
- You got it.
Jaba Point?
You want me to lead them
to Jaba Point?
Got it.
I got it.
OK.
Well, I think we'd better get the others,
now I know where he's headed.
Jaba Point, because there's
fresh water there and caves.
What makes you so sure?
Because I understand
how the bastard thinks.
I taught him.
And now I owe him one.
We'll see.
You stay in front of me...
...bushman.
- OK.
- How are you holding up, soldier?
- Tired. A little scared.
- But I wouldn't have missed it.
- Fun, isn't it?
- Fun?
- Yeah.
Now you can get some sleep.
Relief watch has arrived.
- Charlie, thanks for coming.
- Mick.
- Telephone call.
- Sue, this is Charlie.
And Diamond.
Crikey, you must have a tapeworm!
You've always got food in your hand.
We've been here since first light.
The two brothers are over there,
looking out for the others.
Watch this lot. I'll go after Wally.
OK, mate.
- Can I help?
- I really wanted to get ahead of Wally.
I know, a sheila would
only slow you down.
Be careful. This isn't a game.
It is to me.
No, mate. We just hold them.
What did he say?
He wants to know
if we're allowed to eat these men.
We made the right decision, mate.
Stuff the money.
Yeah, I've had a bad feeling about this
since that old black tracker walked off.
You know, I thought that greaser
really did turn into a goanna.
Erskine?
Don't fool around. Erskine!
He's headed for Jaba Point,
that's for sure.
We cross here.
You lead the way, we'll cover you.
Yeah.
We don't need him now, anyway.
He's already shown us
the way to Jaba Point.
We'll cross over here.
I knew it was you all the time.
First you shoot me,
now you try to drown me.
- You've been hit.
- It's only a scratch, mate.
Careful, there might be
real crocs down there.
Where do you think I got this fellow?
In here.
- Should have seen your face.
- What about it?
- You shit yourself.
- I did not!
- You didn't know it was me.
- I did!
G'day. Want a cold one?
- Who the hell are you?
- Nugget.
I've been looking for Walter Reilly.
Haven't seen him around, have you?
You should have brought a gun
instead of beer.
No, I don't need a gun. I've got a Donk.
You've got a what?
Donk.
Walter! Over here!
There you are! I was just
making sure nobody followed me.
- How d'you get away?
- It was a piece of cake.
It was just a question of timing,
'cause Mick and I had this plan.
- You were shot.
- No, Mick.
- What!
- He's all right. It's just a scratch.
- Where is he?
- He's leading those two to Jaba Point.
That's mountain goat country, so...
...he's gonna have a picnic
with those two!
What are you doing? Mick said wait.
Mick thinks it's a game.
Rico's no picnic.
Which way is it?
Well, I'll have to go with you.
Are you really enjoying that?
Nah. Needs garlic.
It's time we stopped playing
this bushman's game his way.
What do you mean?
This man can take us
any time he wants to.
No.
Now we finish it. Think!
When we were children,
did you chase a snake
into the cane fields?
Move to those rocks and wait.
G'day, amigo.
Take your pants off.
He's got Mick!
If Mick wants his clothes back,
he can climb down himself.
What?
Mick's clothes.
We swapped with that bastard,
to flush the other one out.
Plan was working
till you turned up and shot Mick.
That's... not Mick?
Course not. There's Mick over there.
Mick's bloody lucky
you can't shoot straight.
- You ready to go home now?
- I am home.