Bye, Alvin.
l'll be a-coming back.
Ma.
What are they a-fighting for?
l don't rightly know, child.
l don't rightly know.
Come on, you guys.
Hit the dirt and hit it hard.
Okay, Sarge.
Now look, Ross. That's not a teaspoon
you got there, it's a shovel.
-Lay into it.
-Okay, General.
Dig, soldiers, dig.
Dig your way straight down to China.
-Okay, Sarge.
-China?
What's the idea of going to China?
l thought this war was in Europe.
Parsons, Sergeant Early.
Yes, sir.
Which one of your men is York?
He is the big, lanky fellow,
fourth from the end, sir.
-Having any trouble with him?
-No, sir. Why?
He's down here
as a conscientious objector.
Keep your eye on him.
l want a weekly report.
Yes, sir.
That'll be a big help.
Dig. Dig. Dig.
l've been working in a subway all my life,
never thought about the guys that dug it.
But since l'm in the army,
l sure take my hat off to them.
-Subway you say?
-Yeah.
What's this here subway
you're talking about?
You mean to say you don't know
what a subway is? That guy kidding?
No, they don't have subways
where he comes from, l guess.
They haven't? Ain't they civilized?
Where you from?
Pall Mall.
Valley of the Three Forks of the Wolf.
-Where is that?
-Tennessee.
Ain't you ever even seen a subway?
-Ain't never even heard of one.
-You never... What? Heard?
Heard? What kind of talk is that?
Do they all talk that kind of English
where you come from?
Well, there ain't any English people
down our way, just Americans.
Well, look, a subway is a big hole
in the ground, see?
lt goes for miles.
-Straight down?
-Yeah... No.
lt doesn't go straight down,
it goes this way.
-Oh, this a-way?
-Yeah.
-Under the ground?
-Under the ground.
-And trains run through it.
-They run through it?
-Yeah.
-Steam cars?
Steam... No. Steam cars.
-They're electric, Alvin.
-l sure would like to see one of 'em.
You see, they have to run trains
under the ground in New York,
-because it's so crowded.
-Crowded? l'll say.
Look, it's the rush hour,
the Bronx Express is just pulling in.
l'm standing on the platform,
holding back the mob.
The doors open up and l...
You know what l'm talking about?
Just a word now and then.
Well, you see, the people are just coming
from work and they wanna get home, see,
and they wanna get into the cars
all together.
They start pushing,
l'm trying to hold 'em back.
Well, anyway, the doors open up and
now, buddy, this is where the fun begins.
''Move back in the cars,'' l yell.
Ain't no room in there, but l yell,
''Move back in the cars.''
Boy, how l used to push 'em in. l used
to pack them in like sardines in a can.
That's why they call me ''Pusher.''
All right, Pusher, that's mess call.
-Get a move on.
-Yes, sir.
This is the one bugle call
l ain't got no arguments with.
-2-4-1-8-0-0.
-Zaranopolis Nick.
2-4-1-8-0-1 .
-2-4-1-8-0-1 .
-Ross, Michael T.
Hey, this one's full of grease.
Ain't you got a clean one?
-Clean it, buddy. And keep it clean.
-Sure.
-2-1-8-1-0-2.
York, Alvin C.
Anything wrong with it?
Well, it sure is a fine rifle gun.
l thought maybe you might have
some conscientious objections to it.
No, sir, l ain't.
Careful you don't kill anybody with it
till we get to France.
-Next man.
-There you are, York.
-2-1-4-8-0-3.
Thomas, Bert E.
Boy, look at that shine,
is that clean or is that clean?
Look, Sarge, you can eat
right off the trigger.
Not bad.
You call that clean?
-What's the matter with it?
-Look.
-l don't see nothing.
-lt's full of grease.
Won't that make the bullet
come out faster?
Clean it.
That's a good job, York.
Did you ever clean a rifle before?
Ain't never cleaned one like that before.
l done clean my own, though.
So you've got a gun of your own,
have you?
-Yes, sir.
-l wouldn't think you'd have one.
Well, the next time get your sling
a little higher on your arm.
Okay.
Pull in your necks, soldiers.
Those rookies are gonna start shooting.
Now, remember, you guys,
you're using real, live ammunition.
A bullet hasn't got any brains.
lt'll hit whatever you aim it at.
So don't start murdering each other.
All right, let's go. Ready on number 30.
Ready, number 30.
Not yet, we'll try it first.
Relax, Ross, loosen up. Yeah, that's better.
Take a deep breath.
Blow, let a little of it out.
Hold it.
Remember, keep your sights
on the center of the bull's-eye.
Take up the slack in the trigger gradually.
Don't pull it. Squeeze it slowly.
Just like you were squeezing a lemon.
Ready? Aim.
l can't hold it no more.
All right, Ross, take another one.
Aim.
Fire.
Look, Ross, you had your thumb
sticking straight up in the air.
Just like that.
Oh, yeah. That gives me balance.
Oh, it does? lt gives you balance, does it?
-Yeah.
-Here.
Load.
Aim.
-Fire.
-Oh, my eye.
Maybe that will teach you
to keep your thumb down.
That's something
for the rest of you men to remember.
-A miss.
-Miss.
Ready on number 29.
Ready on 29.
Ready, 29.
All right, York. Let's see what you can do.
Aim. Fire.
l ain't much good at this here practicing,
Sergeant.
All right, next time get that sling
a little higher on your arm.
Press your cheek
a little closer to the stock.
Yes, sir.
Make sure that front sight
divides the rear sight in half.
l reckon l know about that, Sergeant.
You reckon you know about that, do you?
We'll see. Here.
Load. Aim.
Fire.
-A miss!
-Miss.
So you know about sighting, do you?
l sure thought l cut plumb center
that time.
You did, huh?
l can't no ways see how l can miss
that whole great big target.
Sharpshooter York requests a re-mark.
Re-mark for 29.
Re-mark, 29.
Oh, l didn't see that one.
-A bull's-eye, 4:00.
-Bull's-eye.
l can't figure out how l got
way down there on the edge.
Well, l reckon l can do a little better
when l get used to this here rifle gun.
Here's five chances to do better.
Fire when ready.
Hey, what are you wetting
that front sight for?
Why, it kind of cuts down the haze.
l always wet my sights
when l'm fixing to do some shooting.
Okay, do some shooting.
-Bull's-eye, dead center.
-Bull's-eye.
Okay, York. You're on your own.
Hey, look at this.
Right through the marker.
That ain't no rookie, that's Buffalo Bill.
Let's see that target, Sergeant.
Bring 29 to the firing line.
There's the first shot,
and here's the other five here.
l reckon that there gun
shoots a might to the right.
Where did you learn to shoot, York?
Well, l ain't never learnt, Sergeant.
Folks back home used to say
l could shoot a rifle before l was weaned.
But they was exaggerating some.
Now, supposing these here cartridges
is a flock of wild turkeys,
a-flying across the ridge
coming this a-way, see, right at me.
Now, which one of them
would you shoot first?
l'd take a crack at all of 'em
and trust to luck.
Well, you wouldn't have no luck
that way, Pusher.
No? Well, then l'd pick the motorman.
-The what?
-The motorman. The guy out in front.
Well, that ain't right either,
if you wanna get more than one turkey.
Now, which one of them's
got the most meat on him?
Yeah, what's the answer?
Well, now, if you shoot this one here,
the leader,
the rest of 'em will see him drop
and fly off, see?
So, you draw down
on the last turkey here,
and then the next one, see?
Kind of coming from back to front.
Then the rest of 'em won't know
they're being hit.
And, if...
Of course, they might flare off some
when the shooting starts,
but if a fellow's got himself
a repeating rifle,
he's got a good chance
of getting the whole flock.
-Sounds all right.
-Turkeys sure is dumb animals.
Seems you picked up a good bit
down in the hills, Alvin.
Oh, anybody that's done any hunting
knows that.
Alvin C. York!
Report to Major Buxton immediately.
-Yes, sir.
-What have you been up to now?
l don't know.
l've been aiming not to make no trouble.
lt's your move.
-Private York reporting, sir.
-Yes, York. At ease.
York, Captain Danforth has just
handed me a report concerning you,
made by your company sergeant.
Yes, sir?
You have a very excellent camp record.
Well, l'm mighty glad to hear that, sir.
You applied for exemption, l believe,
as a conscientious objector.
Yes, sir.
Well, l think we can disregard that.
York, Sergeant Parsons
recommends your promotion
to the rank of corporal with special detail
as instructor in target practice.
Captain Danforth and l heartily approve.
l congratulate you, York.
Well, l'm much obliged to you,
Major Buxton and Captain Danforth.
Well, l'll learn 'em fellows to shoot
the best l can,
like l already done Pusher and Bert.
l mean, Privates Ross and Thomas, sir,
but,
well, l don't want to be no corporal.
-What's that?
-l said l don't want to be no corporal.
-Why not?
-Wait a minute, Captain. Let him talk.
Well, you see, l...
ls it because of your
religious convictions, York?
Yes, sir. That's it.
You see, l believe in the Bible,
and l'm a-believing
that this here life we're living
is something the Lord done give us.
And we got to be a-living it
the best we can.
And l'm figuring that a-killing other folks
ain't no part of what he was intending
for us to be a-doing here.
Well, yes. ln a way l agree with you.
York, with your permission, Major?
Certainly, Captain. Sit down, York.
You... You say you believe in the Bible?
Yes, sir.
Well, l do, too.
But do you believe that the Bible means
that a man shouldn't fight
for what he believes to be right?
Well, it done said,
''Blessed are the peacemakers.''
Yes, l know, but...
You remember that verse,
l think it's in Luke,
where he says, ''He that hath no sword,
let him sell his garment, and buy one''?
He said that to Peter.
But he doesn't stop Peter
from using his sword.
He said, ''Them that lives by the sword
will be a-perishing by the sword.''
That were further on.
-Yes, l remember, but...
-No, go ahead, Captain, go ahead.
But according to St. John,
he said, ''My kingdom is not of this world.
''lf my kingdom were of this world,
then would my servant fight.''
Well, that's just the point, Captain.
He done said
his kingdom were not of this world.
And that... That is different.
-Yes, but...
-Just a moment, Captain.
York, have you ever read this?
''History of the United States. ''
lt sure is a lot of writing.
-Daniel Boone?
-Yeah.
You know about him?
Well, everybody down our way
knows about Daniel Boone.
First man into
the Valley of the Three Forks.
Yes, he was quite a man,
one of the greatest.
And that book's full of great men.
York, what do you suppose that
Boone was looking for
when he went out alone
into the wilderness?
Well, l never thought much on it.
Was he looking for new lands?
-Might be.
-Maybe.
Maybe for something more.
Something that a man just can't see
with his eyes or hold in his hands.
Something that some men don't even
know they have until they've lost it.
-Yes, sir.
-To be free.
Now, that's quite a word, freedom.
l think that's what he wanted.
l think that's what sent Boone
into your Tennessee country.
ls that what...
That what this here book's about?
Yep.
That's the story of a whole people's
struggle for freedom
from the very beginning until now.
For we're still struggling.
lt's quite a story, York.
How they all got together
and set up a government,
whereby all men were pledged
to defend the rights of each man,
and each man
to defend the rights of all men.
We call it a government of the people,
by the people and for the people.
Why, l never knowed
it was all written down.
-You're a religious man, York.
-Yes, sir.
You want to worship God
in your own way.
Yes, sir.
-You're a farmer?
-Yes, sir.
You want to plow your fields
as you see fit,
and raise your family
according to your own likes?
And that's your heritage and mine,
every American's.
But the cost of that heritage is high.
Sometimes it takes all we have
to preserve it, even our lives.
How you gonna answer that, York?
Well...
You done given me a powerful lot
to be a-thinking about.
Well, take your time.
Well, if l could only get home,
back in 'em there hills, l...
-What would you do?
-Well, l could...
l could figure something out.
l've done a heap of thinking
up yonder there once.
All right, take 10 days' furlough.
You mean l can go home?
And when you get back,
if you still can't see it our way,
l'll recommend your exemption.
-You will?
-Report to me as soon as you get back.
l'll arrange your furlough, York,
starting tomorrow.
-Thank you.
-Good luck.
l sure would like to read this here book.
Go ahead. Take it with you if you want to.
You can borrow it.
Thank you, Major Buxton.
Thank you, Captain Danforth.
Come on, boy.
Want me to be a-setting four places, Ma,
or just three?
Can't say, child.
Ma, ain't Alvin ever gonna eat again?
The Book says
man don't live by bread alone.
Well, what about that there hound dog
he's got with him?
He can't read the Book.
Get the table set.
He's up at the point. Been up there all day.
Want George to go get him, Ma?
Let him be.
Put your trust in the Book, Alvin.
But here's another book, York.
The History of the United States.
Them that lived by the sword,
will be a-perishing by the sword.
The government of all men
to defend the rights of each man.
And each man
to defend the rights of all men.
Remember, the Lord done said,
''Thou shalt not kill. ''
But the cost of that heritage is high.
Sometimes all we have to preserve it,
even our lives.
-Obey your God.
-Defend your country.
-Your God.
-Your country.
-God.
-Country.
-Country...
''Render therefore unto Caesar
''the things which were Caesar's,
''and unto God
the things that were God's.''
Caesar... The things which were Caesar's.
And unto God, God's.
-Private York reporting, sir.
-Have him come in.
Yes, sir. Go in, Sergeant.
l'm a-bringing your book back, Major.
And l'm a-thanking you.
Well, you're welcome, York.
l done what you told me,
l thought things over.
-Well?
-l'd like to stay in this here army.
l rather hoped that you would, York.
But there's just one thing, sir,
that l ought to tell you.
There's lots of things...
There's lots of things
l ain't figured out yet.
Lots of things still a-going on in my mind.
But it's...
Well, it's just like Pastor Pile done told me.
l reckon l can just be a-trusting in
something that's a heap bigger than l be.
York, as your superior officer, l don't feel
called upon to look into your conscience.
lt's enough for me that l trust you.
And l believe that when the time comes,
you'll conduct yourself as a soldier should.
Thank you, sir.
And l'm going to approve your promotion
to the rank of corporal.
Well, l'll sure take care of my men
the best l can, sir.
l know you will, York.
-That's all.
-Thank you, Major.
Aren't you...
Aren't you taking quite a chance, Major?
You mean as to whether he'll fight or not?
No, l don't think so, Captain.
l don't think l'm taking any chances at all.
''Dear Mom,
''am feeling just fine
and have taken in all the sights.
''And Bert took me to a church
called Notre Dame Cathedral.
''lt's big enough inside for a fellow
to plant a crop of corn.
''Pusher just come in.
''He's saying our outfit is moving up
to front pretty soon.
''l reckon that's so
'cause we got all our training
''and they ain't brought us here
for no sight-seeing tour...''
''Tour, nohow.
''Gracie wrote in her letter
she was a-worrying.
''Tell her, don't.''
l was feared. l'm a-feared for Alvin.
lt ain't right for us to be a-feared, Gracie.
Alvin's in good hands.
The Lord takes care of 'em
that's a-believing in Him.
-Any of you blokes got a cigarette?
-Yeah.
-Here you are.
-Thanks.
You know, you Yanks just got here
in the nick of time.
We're running shy of these.
Besides, we can do with some help.
Look out.
lt takes a while, but you'll learn
when to flop and when not to.
They say you never hear
the one that's hit you.
That's only half the truth.
No, the whole truth is,
if you hears it, you've got a chance.
Duck.
See what l mean?
-Heinie's got the range good.
-Yeah. A guy can get killed around here.
-Look out.
-Don't be afraid. This one'll pass over.
See?
Takes time, it do.
But you'll get the hang of it.
Duck again.
lf that was shrapnel, now,
we wouldn't be flopping at all.
You know, you only flop for...
Okay, Bert. The Express has gone through.
Hey, Bert!
lf one's got your name on it,
there's nothing you can do.
So you see, gentlemen,
the grave responsibility rests upon us.
This entire German salient,
holding up the Argonne advance
depends for ammunition and supplies
on the Decauville Railroad,
which as you know,
lies just beyond these hills.
lt must be taken.
This is all open country ahead,
but you can expect heavy machinegun fire
from these wooded ridges
on the right and the left flanks.
But we've got to get through.
Synchronize your watches.
Use as a mark, 4:32.
lt is now minus 10, eight, six,
four, two, mark.
Any questions?
What about artillery support,
Captain Tillman?
Artillery will lay down a rolling barrage
at 6:00.
Zero hour will be 6:10.
l'd like to know where that barrage is
that we're supposed to have.
Runners, notify the platoon commanders
that we go over, barrage or no barrage.
First platoon at 6:10,
second and third platoons to follow
in waves of 100 meters.
Yes, sir.
-6:10.
-6:10. All right.
Come on, men!
Halt and take cover!
We'll never get through.
We gotta wipe out those nests.
Early, take what's left of your section
and work your way back around that hill.
Maybe you can jump 'em from behind.
All right. Savage, York, Cutting.
Bring your men. Come with me.
Take cover.
Listen.
Heinie!
We're not far enough back.
Savage, keep the men quiet.
Cutting, come up here with that bayonet.
We're right behind their lines.
We'll skirt this ridge and flank 'em.
Look! Heinies!
Come on, get 'em.
Hold your fire!
Fall on down and keep 'em covered.
Spread out, men! Spread out!
Line 'em up and disarm 'em !
-Get back there.
-Get 'em up there.
Go on.
-l'm hit bad, Cutting.
-Me, too.
Savage.
Savage?
Where's Savage?
l seen him go down.
They like to cut him in two.
You're the only noncom left.
York, take over.
-Did you hear what l said?
-l heard you.
Watch this fellow.
The rest of you keep under cover.
Come back here.
-Where are you going?
-You done give me command.
Hey, Alvin!
Well, he cleaned out
that machine gun nest.
Zeekenny, Donahue! The rest of you guys,
keep your eye on them Heinies
so they don't try any rough stuff.
Don't try anything funny.
Belly to the ground, you babies.
We better get up there.
No, we better keep an eye
on these prisoners.
Five will get you 10 that guy knocks off
your whole sauerkraut army.
There are 25 machine guns on that ridge.
-Tell him it's useless.
-What did you say?
l said tell him it's useless.
You tell him.
You talk better English than l do.
Just like a flock of turkeys.
All right. Come on out of there! All of you!
Come this a-way.
Tell the rest of them fellows
to quit shooting and come on out of there.
Keep 'em hands up
and start a-going down the hill there.
Keep a-coming.
Go on. Move out of there, down the hill.
All right. Keep a-coming.
Hey, down there. Don't do no shooting.
All right, get on down!
Come on out and keep your hands up.
Boy, l told you.
Look at that mob.
Hey, we can't handle all that gang.
Sure we can. That's my mate.
Come on, step lively. Move forward.
Get going.
-Move forward.
-Move it, now.
Move forward, there.
Come on, step up. Step lively there.
Come on.
-All right.
-Get those hands up. Get in there.
-Come on.
-Come on, get going.
Nice going, York.
-Come on there. Come on.
-Come on, get in there.
Get those hands up.
Come on, move fast. Move.
-Hiya, Pusher.
-That was a good job, pal.
-Where's the Sergeant?
-Over there. Hurt pretty bad.
-How many men we got left?
-Eight, besides you.
Watch them fellows.
Get in there, you guys.
Move forward. Move...
Pusher.
This is where we change cars, Alvin.
The end of the line.
Who done that?
Who throwed that grenade?
Come on, you, put your hands up
and keep 'em up.
You know what l'm a-saying?
-You understand?
-Yeah.
Tell 'em men of yours
if any more of that happens
you and a lot more of 'em's
going to be mighty sorry.
Go ahead.
Tell 'em to drop their belts.
Look them fellows over good.
-You ready back there?
-Okay here.
-Okay. Ready here.
-Watch 'em.
Now, get going.
Tell 'em to halt.
lf you wanted to get back
to the American lines,
which way would you be a-going?
Up there.
We'll go this a-way. Go on.
Hey, tell 'em to halt.
What's up?
Sounds like them Heinies
is making a heap of trouble.
-What are we gonna do about it?
-Get 'em.
We got enough to take care of already.
And a few more won't make no difference.
Hey, you.
Signal up there
and tell 'em they're surrounded.
Tell 'em to drop their guns
and come down with their hands up.
Hey, this gun touches off kind of easy.
They sure are trained good, Major.
Hey, Sarge, look.
-Looks like Heinies.
-Stand ready.
Hello, there!
-A Yank.
-lt may be some kind of a trick.
-There's something funny here.
-Let 'em get a little closer.
-Hello there!
-Who are you?
Detail of the 328th.
We got some prisoners.
-Halt where you are.
-Halt!
That's a Yank, all right.
-Come out, let's have a look at you.
-Watch 'em, fellows!
Keep 'em covered.
Where you going?
Can you tell me where the 328th be?
lt's up that way someplace.
-Where did you pick up all this bunch?
-Back up the line a ways.
You couldn't be taking 'em off our hands,
could you?
What would we do with them?
Well, l don't rightly know.
-Can we be going?
-Sure. Go ahead.
Thank you.
Come on.
Forward!
All right. Halt!
Prisoners, hold right there!
Be a-watching 'em, Joe.
Beg your pardon, sir.
Yeah?
We all got some prisoners,
can we be a-leaving 'em here?
Put 'em right over there.
Wait a minute.
How many have you got?
Well, l done counted 132 heads, sir.
We haven't room for that many here.
Take them back up the line.
-Yes, sir, but...
-But what?
Well, sir, we can't find our outfit and we
tried to drop 'em off two other places.
And they ain't but only eight of us
to handle them.
-You should've brought more men.
-But that's all there were of us, sir.
You mean to say that you
and seven others captured all that bunch?
Yes, sir.
And we'd kind of like to get rid of 'em.
Well, good Lord.
l guess we can give you some help.
-Come on, Sergeant.
-Thank you.
Hey, Sarge! York by himself
captured 132 Germans.
Guy named York got 132 Heinies
all by his lonesome.
-How did he do it?
-Must have surrounded him.
-Guy named York.
-That's what they say.
Gee, he captured
hundreds of Boche and machine guns.
Guy named York! All by his lonesome!
Hey, what's that? How many?
A whole division and a lot of high officers.
-l'm telling you, York?
-Who's they?
Yeah, about half the German army
and a general.
-l don't know.
-One guy.
How could one guy...
-Guy named York.
-What's that?
They say he captured Hindenburg.
And the Crown Prince.
And brought them all back. They say...
Say, Sarge, did you hear?
York captured the Kaiser.
Now, as l understand it, York,
your detail came over that ridge there
and captured about 30 men,
right down in here.
Yes, sir.
Then you were forced to cover
by a machine gun
that was right up on this other ridge.
Yes, sir. Right up there.
Where were you?
Well, l was...
l was a-laying behind that log there.
They was machine-gunning us
pretty heavy, so l worked my way across
up behind that log there under the hill.
Rather incredible, wasn't it, York,
your being able to cross so much
open ground without being hit?
l reckon the good Lord
was a-protecting me, sir.
What did you wanna go over there for?
Well, l figured that was a good place to be
because they had to rear up
and show themselves
in order to shoot at me
and the rest of the boys back here.
And whenever they did,
l could touch 'em off.
l see.
So, l went up the hill,
up around that a-way,
then worked my way down the ridge
to a place where they was flanked
and couldn't show themselves
without being hit.
So, they... Well, they finally gave up.
How many did you kill?
l don't rightly know, sir.
l think Captain Danforth
is familiar with that, sir.
We counted about 20 bodies altogether
up around there.
What were your men doing
all this time, Corporal?
Well, l couldn't just answer that, sir.
l was pretty busy
and l reckon they was, too.
According to the statements of the others,
they were guarding the prisoners
and couldn't expose themselves
to the fire from the ridge.
All right, gentlemen. That's all, Corporal.
Corporal.
-There's something that l'd like to know.
-Yes, sir?
That night that you reported back to me
at Camp Gordon,
you as much as told me that you were
quite prepared to die for your country,
but not to kill.
What made you
decide to change your mind?
Well, sir...
Of course, if you'd rather not tell me,
why, it's quite all right.
Well, l'm as much against killing as ever,
sir.
But it was this way, Colonel.
When l started out l felt just like you said.
But when l hear them
machine guns a-going
and all them fellows
are dropping around me,
l figured that them guns
was killing hundreds, maybe thousands,
and there weren't nothing anybody
could do, but to stop them guns.
And that's what l done.
You mean to tell me
that you did it to save lives?
Yes, sir. That was why.
Well, York, what you've just told me
is the most extraordinary thing of all.
Sergeant York!
Thank you, sir.
And for conspicuous gallantry
beyond the call of duty,
you have been awarded
the Distinguished Service Cross.
Sergeant York, l am proud that
you are of the All-American Division.
lt's a privilege to command
such men as you.
Sergeant York,
as Commander-in-Chief
of the American Expeditionary Forces,
it is my pleasure to confer upon you
the United States
Congressional Medal of Honor
for heroism beyond the call of duty.
Thank you, sir.
l'm Cordell Hull, Sergeant York,
representative from
your district of Tennessee.
l'm mighty glad to meet you, Mr. Hull.
And this is Mr. Harrison
from the Tennessee Society.
Tennessee is indeed proud, Sergeant.
-Thank you.
-This way, Sergeant.
Well, Sergeant, what do you think of it?
Appears like everybody's
having a mighty good time.
So, Sergeant,
in the name of the people of New York,
may l present you with this key to our city
as a token of our very great esteem.
And may God bless you.
Thank you for what you said,
and l'm sure grateful to you
for this here key.
Well, thank you. And thank you all.
Now, Sergeant, the people of New York
would like to show their appreciation.
ls there anything we can do for you?
Well, there's just one thing
l'd like to ask you.
And that is?
Well, if it's all the same to everybody,
l sure would like to ride on the subway
on the Bronx Express.
l think we can arrange that.
Well, here we are.
l hope you will be comfortable here,
Sergeant York.
Well, if it ain't, l'd be pretty hard to please.
lf there's anything you require,
all you will have to do is ask for it.
Thank you. Thank you, sir.
An awful lot of room
for just one fellow here.
This here is mighty thoughtful of you,
gentlemen.
l reckon you know l ain't seen my ma
for quite a spell.
So we understand.
Representative Hull.
Oh, yes, yes. Are they ready?
Put them on.
-Somebody for you, Sergeant.
-Me?
Thank you.
Hello. Hello there.
What?
Who is it?
l... l can't hear you.
-Who is it?
-What's that you're saying?
l can't hear you.
Put it up to your ear, Mother York.
Stand closer, Ma.
When are you coming home, Alvin?
l said, when are you coming home?
Oh, l'm glad, Son.
l'll tell her.
She's right here.
He wants to talk to you, Gracie.
lt's me, Alvin. lt's me, Gracie!
We're all in here in Pastor Pile's store.
He's got this here phone in here now.
Oh, l just can't wait to see you again,
Alvin.
l can't wait to see you.
Yeah, yeah. l'll be coming home, Gracie,
right away.
Yeah.
-Goodbye. Goodbye, Gracie.
-Goodbye, Alvin.
Bye.
Sure was nice to talk to the folks.
-l'm a-thanking you.
-You're welcome, Sergeant.
Just like the electric signs
down the street.
How do you like New York, Alvin,
as much as you've seen of it?
-Mr. Hull?
-Yes, Alvin?
l wanna be a-going home.
When do you think l can go?
-You're pretty anxious, l reckon.
-Yes, sir, l am.
l've got to get to work.
Well, as far as that goes,
there's plenty to do right here, Alvin.
What do you mean?
l've been wanting
to talk to you about this.
You're a pretty famous man now.
And judging by all these offers
you've been getting,
it seems a lot of people realize it.
For instance,
two companies want you
in motion pictures,
Ziegfeld wants you in an act
in his new Follies.
And here's an offer to appear
at the Winter Garden, that's a theater.
And here's a breakfast food manufacturer
who wants you to endorse his product.
What does that mean?
Well, you've to tell him how much
you like it, how much good it's done you.
l ain't never ate
any of that there breakfast food.
Doesn't seem to make any difference.
Anyway, l've totaled the offers so far
and they amount to around
a quarter of million dollars.
They're offering me all that money?
lt's just a plain business proposition.
l sure could do a powerful sight
with that money.
There was a piece of bottomland
l was a-trying to get...
Here's your chance to get it.
Are they offering that money
because of what happened over there?
-Well...
-That's it, ain't it?
That's it.
What... What would you do, Mr. Hull?
Well, l think that's up to you, Alvin.
l reckon it is.
Take all the time you want to think it over.
l've done thought it over, Mr. Hull.
l ain't proud of what happened over there.
What we done in France
was something we had to do.
Some fellows done it ain't a-coming back.
So, the way l figure,
things like that ain't for buying and selling.
So l reckon l'll have to refuse 'em.
Would you be a-telling them that
for me, please?
And tell 'em l'm a-going home?
-l'll be more than glad to, Alvin.
-Thank you, Mr. Hull.
Here she comes, Zeke. Right on time.
Oh, there he is!
Alvin!
Oh, Alvin!
How are you?
Ma, l'm back.
l'm right glad, Son.
Hey, Alvin. How about your medals?
-What about 'em, George?
-l thought you'd be wearing 'em.
You'll be a-seeing 'em.
They better be a-something big.
As l was saying, Alvin,
of course, l always figured
on marrying you and Gracie myself,
but l ain't one to take the job away
from the Governor of the State.
Why, you're the dang-swangest hero
raised in these parts
since Daniel Boone and Andy Jackson.
Sure are, Alvin.
Hang on, Rosie.
Hey,
what about that there piece of land
l was aiming to get in Tomkins holler?
-lt's still there, l reckon?
-Yep, it's still there.
Somebody else has got it by now,
l suppose.
Well, l couldn't rightly expect Zeb
to hold it for me all this time.
l sure would like to see that there
piece of land, though.
l reckon ain't no harm you seeing it, Alvin.
l'd like to be a-seeing it, too.
l'll let you off at the fork and
you and Gracie can walk over to the holler.
Hang on, everyone.
Hey, look here.
-Somebody's done fixed up this old bridge.
-Yeah, they have.
Gracie, l... l gotta talk to you.
lt wasn't just the land
l was a-wanting to see.
There's something we got to talk about.
-Miss Gracie, l'm plumb worried.
-What about, Alvin?
Well, what with the governor fixing
to marry us
and all them people coming here
from all over...
Sure takes a body's breath away,
but l reckon we'll get through it all right.
-Well, it ain't just that l'm worried about.
-Well, what then?
Well, it sure looks like l ain't got nothing
to offer you excepting a big wedding.
Why, some girls don't even get that.
Well, l reckon you'd like a place to sleep,
wouldn't you?
Oh, l don't know.
l done a heap of sleeping
while you was away.
You sure ain't expecting
too much of a husband.
l'm expecting my husband to love me.
l reckon the good Lord
will take care of the rest.
Well, looks like he's done a heap already,
just a-having you. But...
Well, l was expecting to take over
from here myself.
l reckon you'll get to do your share.
No, Gracie, it can't be that a-way.
We got to wait.
Maybe in another two or three years,
if you're willing to wait...
Oh, but l ain't, that's the point.
-You mean you won't wait?
-There ain't no need of waiting.
Now, Alvin, you keep looking down
and don't you be looking up till l tell you.
Come on.
There! Now you can look.
What do you see, Alvin? Tell me.
lt's yours, Alvin. lt's all yours.
They give it to you.
The people of the state of Tennessee
for what you done.
-You mean...
-Only, it's 200 acres
and the house is bigger, with more
windows, and the kitchen's got a pump.
And it's for us.
The Lord sure does move
in mysterious ways.
Come on.