It was around 12 o'clock that night
I tossed and turned
I couldn't sleep
Then
My hubby is back
As soon as I saw him
I knew something was wrong
2 Characters
Pong
I could still remember his smile
There is something fishy
5 Characters.
You'd smell it if it is
And I did
5 Characters, Pong for me
Do you feel like crying?
"Mrs. Chan - suffering from depression”
I walked towards him
And I found it
A strand of long hair, stuck to him
That night
He said he went to play football with friends
All of them are bald
Where could it have come from?
Certainly not me
This is for you
8 Characters
Close to winning, aren't you
Pong again for me
- Again?
- Lucky I got it
Feel like crying yet?
It's already very difficult
And you are not making it easy for me
Last time
He denied about that secretary
And that model
And that nameless celebrity
He denied everything
Be honest
- 1 Character
- Does your husband treat you right?
Yes
That's what a woman really needs after all
- 6 Characters
- Pong
Pong
Pong again?
I win!
You thought you can have it your way?
What's mine will always be mine
Mrs. Chan, now you understand
What?
Husbands are like that too
What's yours will always be yours
They won't run away
Suspecting everything will only
make men try to avoid you
Would you rather cry after a broken family
Or smile at an intact one?
That's for you to decide
- Hey
- Hey! Hey!
Don't spray at us like this
Killing germs like that
It could kill us too
From what I heard, one of your F&B conglomerates
Is getting in on an IPO soon, right?
Screw it
Why even mention it?
I'm so pissed now
Those good-for-nothings
We planned to go public last year,
but nothing's been done
Imagine how much I lost
I want to kill them all
Rearrange the tiles
Don't mention it again
Alright
God, I'm pissed
"Mrs. Fong - suffering from mania"
Oh, Chow.
Pong
Excuse me
Why, you...
You always try to get what I'm after
Can you really keep up?
I like oversized challenges
Do you remember your best assistant, David?
Where is he working now?
Who would want those good-for-nothings?
I don't care if no one wants them
One betraying is all it takes
He won't dare do that
Look at you
- Let me get a snap
- He won't dare do that
I tell you
If I were David
I'd pack my bags when I see that face
Do you know why I don't get angry
Because a smile can resolve a war
What did I tell you
When you get angry
Thousands of nerves on your face get stimulated
When that happens
Even the best botox treatment won't reverse that
Oh... Let's continue
Mrs. Li
You were just back from Paris with your husband
I see that you had fun on social media
A full bounty of return
We were at Versailles
It was pouring outside
Waited for five whole hours
Wow, you must have long waited...
Everything must be closed by then
She's got OCD
What's a little shower?
She would wait even if there's a tornado
Look at her
She only goes after 13 Wonders in mahjong
"Mrs. Li - suffering from
Obsessive Compulsive Disorder"
Red Dragon, there you are
Now stay close
Not yet?
There are still two of those
I'll find them myself
Not yet?
Damn, did you bring your own tiles?
Be good now, I'm just one pair away
Sometimes
Did I Kill your parents or something?
Can't you go for other tiles
- Things just don't go the way you expected
- Four of them
All four 1 Characters are out
Green Dragon, why are you always late?
Why are you crying?
I'm already calling Mahjong
But you disposed all the 1 Characters
Sometimes, you can't force 13 Wonders
Just because you wanted to
West
Bad Flower tile
What is this, a florist?
- There's more
- Impossible
Wait a second. This makes six of them
Look, none of us have any
Right
Is it Mahjong with eight Flowers?
Yes
Mahjong with eight
This must be a coincidence
Yes
It really is
Flower again
One more to go
God of Mahjong, please make me happy
Flower Mahjong
It's wonderful
It really is a Flower
There's no such thing as
perfect planning in the world
You couldn't have 13 Wonders
But a Flower Hand is just the same
Congratulations, you deserved it
I still prefer 13 Wonders though
Hello, Hubbykins
Are you done playing football?
I'll come pick you up
Let's spend the night on a date
Dr. Bo, thank you very much
My wife no longer suspects me
The money is ready
I just need your account number
Tell everyone to come back
We will have a celebration feast
Tell that heartless David to come too
No...
Tell him
We will triple up his salary
So ask him to stay
Dr., thank you so much
For helping my wife to be happy again
I'll transfer the treatment fee to you
Thank you
Daddy
I got Mahjong finally
Not 13 Wonders
But a Flower Hand
Eight Flowers
Dr. Bo
It is impressive how you
made my wife get a Flower Mahjong
Thank you
I have made the transfer already
"Famous psychiatrist - Chung Ka Bo"
We got the reply on
when the renovation can be finished
It shall be done within our expected date
Our merchant acquirers gave us some comments
They asked whether if having
six toilets in our 18-storey mall
Would be too few
Customers might pee their pants
Do you remember what the boss said
With one less toilet
We can have two more shop spaces
Our company can receive more rent
Boss
You could hurt yourself
Put down the hammer
Where did you get the marble
We always get it at Old Fat's
Get it from Little Fat's from now on
I heard that Little Fai
Forged his late father's will,
and tried to steal his brother's share
Why stock up from that jerk?
Also
You lent money to Old Fai last year
If you give business to Little Fai now
Wouldn't it harm your business?
A one million-dollar question
I paid lots of money to hire you
And you only bring your empty bodies to work
Where are your brains?
Raise your hand if you know
You won't even try for a million
The correct answer is
From now on, you will all change your names
Do you know to what?
"Pigheads”
Because you don't have brains
Now Little Fai has a lawsuit
with Old Fai, am I right?
When we get things from Little Fai
We can bargain and slash the price
As for Old Fai
I lent him money
But I don't buy from him
Then he'd have nothing to pay me back
I can then merge both companies, bit by bit
My biggest desire
Is for them to fight each other
Running a business with no morals
He's doomed to have ugly offspring without asses
Are you cursing me?
No, boss
It's not what I meant
I...
What is your name
Tyson
How long have you been working here
Three years
Not happy with your job? Tell me
No, boss. I'm not unhappy
I'm very happy
You got a good-looking ass
Boss...
That means your mummy and daddy
Did great deeds in the past
For you to be so handsome
And you are still working under me
Being yelled at every day
You pighead
You can't even talk back
Go home and tell them
Even when they had done good things in the past
You are still working for me
Being scolded by me
Do you understand, pighead?
Do you understand?
Mummy
I want to go home
You pigheads dislike me
That's fine.
I don't care, I don't care at all
Does anyone want to resign
Raise up your hand
You can leave immediately
I have money
To hire some other piece of trash
No one?
Good
Get to work
Now take out your watches
From this minute onwards
Even if you are pigheads
You shall live as a greedy pighead
The golden rule of my business
"Greed"
"Simon Leung - famous tycoon, suspected manic"
"Valentine's Day - 13:26"
Funny, is there anything to eat?
What's with this?
It's just lunch
What's the big deal?
This one's for me
That is for you
What?
You get to eat this much
What did you make me?
What's this?
Last week you said you need to go on diet
Also
You will be attending
Dr. Yeung's charity ball next month
And ordered that gown for ten thousand dollars
To be made from Paris
You said you need to shine like a star on that day
Show me your hand
Don't play tricks on me, okay?
Boss, you should stop watching
Korean drama and sleep at night
What's that to do with you?
It harms your liver
Most importantly
You have bad Yin-yang balance these few years
Shut up
How rude
This herbal juice should be perfect
Seven cups a day
Helps you shed some weight and detox
If you keep on drinking
Ho
You'd live long and your beauty never fades
Is that true?
Bottoms up
Where did you get this?
Suffering today brings bliss tomorrow
It's going to be worth it
Hey
Eat if you will,
but don't make it so gross
Are you trying to scorn me?
According to conditioning mechanism in psychology
I am averting your appetite
The more aversive I making it look like
The more revolted you will be
For a cute preppy boy like me
It's a sacrifice to forsake my image and help you
You call yourself cute and preppy
I want to throw up
If you still have good conscience
You should increase my pay
Get out
A patient is waiting for you
I said
I will only work for the day's limit
I won't move even for the Chief Executive
Tell him to come again
But you really need her tonight
Congratulations, boss
The Asia Chamber of Commerce just called
They elected you as this year's
most successful entrepreneur
They want you to attend
the ceremony in Japan next month
You know how I hate to get under the spotlight
You go and receive the prize for me next month
Recently Penang's got some good property
We should think about how to get on good deals now
I got news that
Philip Lau lost by two votes
And he's outraged
He kept telling people it was all arranged
I've known him for 40 years
He tries to copy me in everything
When I do sun tanning, he goes indoor tanning
I live on Jardine's Lookout,
he lives at Jardine's Crescent
When I date Miss Hong Kong, he dates Miss Asia
No one can be as low-bred like him
I reckon he is for real this time
My friend saw him at karaoke
And he was really drunk
Damn you, Simon, you jerk
You bully me all the time
If I don't teach you a lesson
I'm gonna bleach myself white
I'm no longer Dark Fortune Philip
I'll look for someone to make you pay
Don't worry
His bark is bigger than his bite
He won't even dare to touch me
How much is his company worth now
3.6 per stock
Start buying him company shares bit by bit
You want to merge his company
Just to have a little fun
And give him some sleepless nights
3 o'clock, meeting at Four Seasons with Mr. Lee
"Valentine's Day - 14:30"
5 o'clock
Mr. Chan from Malaysia will come
"Valentine's Day - 14:30"
To explain to us their property
My idol
You look so much more handsome than on TV
Let us take a photo
We don't do photos. No photos
- Sorry
- Alright, alright
Just this once, I'll be leaving tomorrow
Didn't you say you hate the spotlight?
"Every step that you take,
you make a difference”
She's just a tourist
Be nice, shall we?
Let's take a photo
Almost time
Good
Thanks, Leo
You're going to be the best actor
of the year for sure
But don't tan yourself anymore
I support you
Now I just need to find Simon Yam
Then I'll have the full collection
I said no photos
Didn't you see that?
Why didn't you stop her?
Letting random people come near me
Boss
Don't run
Philip! You tricked me
I'll put everything in to play with you
Give me some tissue paper
Get the security guards
Are you alright?
- Yin
- Here
Give Chong a call
Tell him to forget about
buying the stocks bit by bit
Just buy the entire company
Yes
I will make Philip sleep on the streets
Yes, boss
"Valentine's Day - 15:09"
Michelle
What took you so long to call Mummy?
Mummy's worried
I nearly got caught
I ran a few blocks until I could escape
I'm still shivering
It's normal that you feel scared
Don't worry
I never thought I would do such crazy things
But when you do
Don't you feel a slight tinge of excitement?
Well, I do
Bingo! You are finally smiling
I forced you to do something
out of your character
So that your hidden characters can be discovered
Good for you
Now the journey to your healing
Can begin
Do I really have to go?
Today
Is supposed to be your anniversary
with that jerk Lo Jok
And it's Valentines Day
I booked a table at the hotel you often went
You must go and have dinner there
I'm done with him already
Why do I still need to go?
To forget someone
Is not as easy as you say it
To truly forget
Is when you meet him again
You are still be able to see right through him
I don't understand
That means, if you can finish today's meal
With complete peace and serenity
Then you have truly walked away
from this relationship
Can I really do that?
You are my dear daughter
You can do it
I'll wait for you to come home happily
And have Chinese New Year's Eve dinner
with the whole family
Mum
Did you get in touch with Sis?
Do you think she'd let me find her?
Speak up
What do you mean?
"Valentine's Day - 19:03"
The landlord wants to raise the price?
What on earth?
These necklaces
Are our newest designs
You can try and see which one you like
He wants a freaking raise?
Let him raise
If you like pink, Miss
This one would really suit you
I didn't say I like pink
Why do you say I like pink?
I tell you
Get his mother to talk to me
You can't? Then you go c--
- Do you understand?
- Sir
Can you speak quietly on your phone?
You are disturbing my customers
Now I can't even talk on my phone?
I can't buy things
Are you crazy?
Honey
Darling
I have what I want
Oh, have you given it a try?
Not yet
Then try it out
Is it hard?
Very hard! It's not fake
- Awesome
- Miss,
you can't bite our diamonds
Why not?
When I purchased gold in my hometown
I had to bite to see if it was real
If you sold me some fake jewelry
Then I will be fooled
Miss, all our diamonds
have the manufacturer's warranty
We don't sell fake goods
Couldn't you also forge the papers?
See if you can tell the difference by yourself?
You have been here for two hours
If you are not buying from us
Please shop at other places
Honey, she is mean to me
You go and tip her a lesson
Darling, it's teach, not tip
Did you hear that?
My wife is angry
Either you apologize,
or I'll mess up this place
If you dare! I'll call the police
Wow, you got some guts
Honey, leave it. Look at her face
She looks like she must have been dumped
by a man recently
That's why she is jealous of a cute couple like us
Let us go somewhere else
And you be stuck here your whole life
Here, for your whole life,
Here, for your whole life.
- Here, your whole life.
- What now?
Are you angry now?
Why are you glaring at me?
What, you want to fight? Come at me
Just try, I'll bring you to court and sue you
- You can't pay even with your body
- come on...
- come on. Try me,
Come on, come on. Try me, come on
- Come on...
- she must have been dumped by a man recently
Why?
I don't want you to leave
We are not right for each other.
I have another girlfriend
I was dumped. Does it have anything to you?
What if you are in love? What if you are rich?
You want to mess us up?
I don't have anything.
Go to hell with me
Help...
Stop, ouch, It hurts! Crazy woman
Stop, ouch, It hurts!
Calm down, calm down
Stop! Stop! Stop it!
Manager
What are you doing here?
They are causing trouble
Whatever the customers said,
we cannot treat them like that
We are people who provide service
And customers are always right, you know?
Manager Chan,
we schemed this "secret customer” project
Isn't it very effective to test out your employees
Well done
I shall put all the company's branches
under your team
To test out my employee's abilities
Thank you, Manager Chan
Manager, I haven't yet introduced myself
Slow Man, nice to meet you
Oh, here, let me introduce
Yes.
This is my work partner and girlfriend,
Kiki Cheung
We are both drama lovers
Yes, we are
Kiki, greet our boss
Hello, boss
Damn, you need to express more
Boss
Manager, what do we do with Susan?
Send that crazy girl home
She'll get her employment
termination through email
I don't want to see her ever again
What is wrong with him?
Turning against his own people
It's okay
Don't leave, please don't
Did you see that girl? She's out of her mind
She might even have rabies
She's crazy, to lash out like that
Are you kidding me? That guy is so stingy
I asked for medical reimbursement,
he refused
I'll definitely ask for a raise next time
Hey, you think we will be punished
for doing dreadful things?
Kiki, can you not pity others out there?
Think about it. We graduated from
Arts Academy for such a long time
We are passionate about acting. We have dreams
Did God give us any opportunity?
How long have we been jobless?
Now someone gave us a chance
And we can act in front of people again
How come we are giving up?
How can you tell people that we are actors?
Don't you feel ashamed?
My screenplay is finally done
Look,
the money that we made today
Is a big step closer for me
To bring this gem into the cinemas
I promise you
You will be the lead actress for my film
Will I be the cat or the dog?
You will be a lizard
Lizard?
Yes.
In this film, this lizard
Is the love interest of the cat and the dog
In other words,
it interferes in the relationship
between the cat and the dog
Now,
don't you think this character has lots of potential?
It won't be easy to handle
Of course it won't, I made it specially for you
So, you don't have to worry about anything else
If you have the time, just think
How to immerse yourself in the lizard's movements
and psychology
Bad Person calling! Bad Person calling!
What?
Your mum again?
Hey, not like she's my real mum
Come on, your little sister's
not as begrudged as you are
She is weak-minded, and believes easily.
I told you that.
My problem is that my memory is too good probably.
I will always remember who killed my dad
Is it that serious?
What kind of a psychiatrist
hooks up with a patient?
One day, my dad went out to sea
And he never came back
That doesn't mean she has to do with it
She knew my dad is hydrophobic,
and she gave him a yacht?
Giving him a plane
doesn't mean he could fly it too
What, why are you defending that woman?
If you hate that woman,
why don't we...
Make a plan
and steal all her money
Then you can star as the lizard very soon
Anyway, I said it.
I won't see that woman ever again
And I'm not playing the lizard anymore
Why not? I characterized it specially for you
Only you can do it
Honestly, why a lizard?
Is my tongue forked?
It isn't now, you know that
Dr. Bo, what took you so long?
Our boss has been waiting
Today is Valentine's Day, there's traffic everywhere
Did I speak to you?
"Valentine's Day - 20:33"
Stop barging into conversations, steward
Steward? Then what are you, a maid?
What are you calling me? Steward
- Maid,
- Steward,
- Steward...
- Maid...
Maid.
Stop.
What is the condition now?
Our boss is losing bad
Four words, like a sinking ship
Philip you loser, what are you waiting for?
What's the fuss? Just wait
Welcome
My Goddess
I've been waiting.
Please have a seat. Scram...
Please have a seat.
Hey, Philip
Need a chick to give you guts?
What are you saying?
You can laugh at me,
but not my goddess
Want me to burn down your whole family?
If you don't like it,
I can kill all of them
They are like that
Nothing good comes out of their mouths
I haven't looked at the cards,
I'm waiting until you come
Look at it, look at it
I won't if you don't look first
Hm, I like that. Deal the cards
Three 4s
It's gonna be a full house or a four-of-a-kind
5 million
Two identical suits,
this looks like four-of-a-kind
Well
Gonna be fun
Great!
Now, no turning back
If you win, I quit gambling for three months
If you lose
You will go out and have dinner
and watch a movie with me
Do you want me to win, or to lose?
Of course lose, am I right?
What is a few million dollars?
Just change to me
I won't even bother about it
You, on the other hand
Have never gone out with me
since we met
As a doctor, it is my principle
Not to have private meetings with a patient
Why do you come then?
The best way to treat a gambling addict
Is not to prohibit gambling
You need a visible goal to gamble
And my treatment is to help you win
So you will quit for three months
While it does not go to the heart of the problem
It will at least relieve your illness
right?
Admit it, you just want to see me, dummy
Look at your cards, do you think you can win?
I have calculated everything
Zodiacs, astrology, Tarot reading
And I got an unlucky spot fixed
by a Feng Shui master
With an lucky charm overhead
When you sat down, did you feel cold
And unsettled?
There are many spirits here haunting you
Bad luck turn and bad luck flee
Only good fortune, come to me
Today my worst day
I will lose every bet
I am confident in losing everything tonight
I can definitely have dinner with you tonight
I'm so clever
Why am I handsome
and clever at the same time?
Hearts, are you scared?
No
Three sides
It's 7
Hard to lose
Player with the strongest hand, please act
Don't mind if I decide on your part?
No
Any problem with that?
Five million
Five million it is
Mr. Lee, with such a big bet
Need to call your wife first?
What is it
It's just five millions
I call
Same
I am the youngest here
Can do nothing but call
Just a Flush hand, nothing to fear
Let's see
Full house, 4s over 9s
Open it, open it
Full house, Aces over 9s
Thank you
My Goddess
Full house
The 9s are all out, how do we win?
I said I have the worst luck today
You should think about where to have dinner later
You guys like 9s
Then take them
I'm waiting for this card all along
Amazing! A Straight Flush!
Why did I get a 47
No, why did you get a 4?
Isn't today my worst day of the year?
Silly, you have bad luck
But my boss is shining from within,
full force and unstoppable
Mr. Lau
I've done my part at least to
help you win the game
As for the treatment bill
Ask someone to pay it on time
Also
No turning back on your words
No gambling for three months
Funny
Let's go
Happy Valentine's Day, Silly Billy
What
You might need her tonight
I don't want to be a dealer anymore
Customers never tip me even when they won
When they lost, they take it out on you
I have insomnia every night
What can I do at night then?
Online shopping
My shopaholism is getting serious
And I'm high on credit card debts
With such low wages
I can't even afford for one session with you, Dr. Bo
So I told myself
I will find a new job
And I must be able to help others
And to do whatever I wish
Tonight, there's an event
Where you can really help me out
Help me cheat in this game
Best if you could control everything in the process
Most importantly,
you'll be satisfied with the payment
How satisfied?
One million in a lump sum
Is there more than one event?
"Valentine's Day - 21:16"
Happy Valentine's Day, Miss Chung
Manager, hello
Why are you waiting on your own?
Is your boyfriend late?
What a shame...
Did you break up?
My boyfriend won't come
He is dead
In a car crash
His car crashed into the hills in a "bang"
And the fire roasted him, burnt him
Burning, and, it's painful
Just before he died, he called out,
"Help! Help! Help!"
I'm sorry Miss Chung
Sorry for your loss
Just tell me if you need anything
Hey, manager
Yes
What's are your recommendations for today?
Oh, I'm sorry, Miss Chung
Since today is Valentine's Day
All our guests
Will be served "Two in Love" Dinner Set
Which might not suit you now
But it's fine
How about
We ask our chef
To prepare for you
Some Michelin-grade vegetarian dish
But a set costs less,
ala carte dishes are expensive
I'll stick with the set
"Two in Love"
I'll bring you champagne and the appetizer
But I'll also bring you a vegetarian dish
Thanks
What a good appetite after her boyfriend's death
Boss is coming back for a meeting,
clear out the floor
That's serious
I'm sorry for the inconvenience
Oh, Miss Chung
I'm very sorry
To tell you some bad news
Why is everybody leaving?
Our hotel
Has a spa
And a sewer pipe burst
But my colleagues
Without mentioning, went to mend it
But then, who knew
Even the sewer pipe at the gym bursted
But my colleagues didn't learn from the past
And they went to mend it
Which made the sewer pipe beneath
our kitchen to burst too
Now the sewage is gushing out
That's why, our restaurant is closing
But don't you worry
The meal is on us
And because you are our valued customer
We will give you some coupons for free
So you can go to our spa for free once
And to our gym for free once
And also enjoy a free tour around our kitchen
I guarantee you, there won't be faeces
But I haven't finished,
how can you tell me to leave
I'm putting it like this already, won't you leave?
But my boyfriend's dead
"Your boyfriend died",
this is in past tense
"Sewage is gushing out",
is present continuous tense
I planned to spend this Valentine's Day on my own
To think about my boyfriend
who was turned into charcoal
Seems like even a humble wish like that
Is impossible to be fulfilled
Miss Chung, how about this
Let me prepare you a VIP room
So you can have a mourning
banquet before you leave?
But the bill
is one us
And the coupons?
All free
The champagne
Is nice, right? It's Cristel
Give her a dozen to knock herself out
"Valentine's Day - 22:03"
Janet, you buy at $3.8
You, sell at $2.8
You, buy at $5.6
Sell at $6.5
You, sell at $13.3
Okay
Today is Valentine's Day
And you all put off your loved
ones for this meeting
It's not easy
When you leave,
get some snacks to make them happy
This time's reward is ever better
You were eyeing on that new car,
Now you can pay premium
I can take my whole family on holiday
I can buy diamonds
Boss
The boss has no time for you tonight.
Wait at home
Boss, you tipped me on 425 two days back
When the market opened today
it crashed and got suspended
I've lost all my savings
Please lend me five million to repair the damage
When did I gave you a tip on 4257
You eavesdropped on my phone call
Boss, you can take it that I was wrong or crazy
But you gotta help me! Just five million will do
I've waited for three years to get you
You still remembered
when I lead others to another company?
But last year you said you would let it go,
when I came back
You doubled my salary
You even lent me money to purchase a flat
I could bring you up high enough
to make you fall hard
I waited until you paid the premium for your house
Before I gave it to you
Boss, even if that's the case
Even if I'm in the wrong,
I beg you, please save me
Please help, just five million
George! If I were you
I'd sell your watch, and your car
And take the million dollars to hide in Dongguan
Stop showing your face for nothing
I beg you, you gotta save me
Big Keung and Small Keung,
- bring him away
- Boss, I beg you
I can't save myself even if I kill myself
Not even if I kill myself
Boss, please, Boss...
Yin, go home in my car today
Why?
You said Philip wants to ambush me.
See if that's true
What?
Boss
Aren't you fired?
What are you still doing here?
I really need money to save lives
Help me this once
I don't repeat my words
I beg you, just this once
If you do, I'll do anything for you
Why don't you go to Emperor Finance
You can get your property mortgaged too
You have to repay your loans though.
Don't pay any intermediaries
I owe you nothing now
Then I'm sorry, Boss
Philip said he'll pay for my debt
Hey, what are you doing?
How could they demand that I leave?
I haven't finished eating
Oh, the coupons
Richard forgot them
Hey
Bring that chick here
Come here
It's painful
George, it's me you want
Leave her out of this
You can't even save yourself
Girl
Step back, I'm here to protect you.
Don't' be scared
Take it
Are you done posing? Hit her
So you are good at fighting? Good at fighting?
Good at fighting?
Still want to fight?
You are lucky this time. I'll be back
Leave
Go, go, go.
Thank you
Did you steal someone's wife or owe them money?
You got a lot of enemies
Not many girls can fight like you do
Can't girls fight?
Are you discriminating against females?
No, I wouldn't dare
I am afraid you would beat me up
Don't worry, I only beat up bad guys
Never good guys
How do you know I'm not the bad guy?
You are so old but you still try to protect me
You can't be very bad
Richard is off work now
This is all your fault
If it weren't for you,
I would have gotten those coupons
What coupons? Are they important?
Of course!
The dessert buffet in this hotel is very delicious
You like it? I can treat you to one
It's closed, stop bluffing
I own this hotel
Is this enough? I can send for more if you want
Bring it on
You sure you don't want some?
"Valentine's Day - 23:02"
It's delicious
I don't like dessert
"Valentine's Day - 23:02"
You don't like dessert
Your life must be gloomy
Or you could try have a sip of wine, for a change
A sip of wine in times of weariness
Will make you more relaxed
I'm not weary
I'd rather him be dead
He should be happy now, and having great fun
Cuddling with another woman
Do you know who that woman is?
My best friend
My other boyfriends were even more ridiculous
Each of them, would go away, after a short while
And after that
They would get married
and have kids, just like that
Last year
I went for face-reading
He said it is in my fate, I'm like the Buddha
I get loads of admirers, and I bless them all
I'm more effective than a charm
He could have printed my face on paper
and worshipped me
This is what they call
"riding a donkey to find a horse"
Now they got the horse,
who would remember you, the donkey?
Why can't I be the horse?
Because you are used to being a donkey
Why won't you put your mind to being just a horse?
You got a point there
Why haven't I thought of it?
Cheers
To you
I'm the horse
Hello, friends up there
Do you see me?
Answer me, am I the most beautiful horse
You are a donkey
I'm a horse
Donkey
Horse
Dare say it again?
You are a donkey
Boss, weren't you assaulted by someone?
Seems like you are the one doing it
Am I in the way?
"Valentine's Day - 23:46"
Happy Valentine's to me,
"Valentine's Day - 23:59"
and to you
"Valentine's Day, is over"
This is Simon Leung.
Keep this phone.
Let's have dinner some other time
Our job today
is to help the real estates company
scare two elderly people away
These are our targets, Mr. and Mrs. Lui
The company is done acquiring all the old buildings
Except for theirs, they won't leave
That's why we are here to tackle them
I saw on a ghost rumours website
This place is super haunted. See for yourselves
Hello, this is Simon Lui. It has been a while
This is where a harrowing
family murder case was staged
A butcher living here
found out his wife to be cheating
And he grabbed a knife,
hacked her neck for 17 times
Until he chopped her head off
After that, he stood here,
and jumped from here
After the tragedy
The neighbourhood would see
Every night, the butcher with his wife's head,
wandering here and there
Saying the same thing
"Kill every soul. Give nothing back"
Are you sure?
How can you believe in Simon Lui?
It's better safe than sorry.
I'm not doing it
Since when are you such a sissy?
What about our friendship?
My zodiac offends Tai Sui this year.
I have bad luck
I quit
Hey
I will hold on to the clothes first
Holy shit
- You told us to come in the first place
- Go
Who else?
I am not afraid of anything.
I'm staying
A courageous spirit, you see
I have something to say
I'm afraid of ghosts,
but I'm afraid of being poor too
Now that he's gone
Can we split his share of money?
Anyway you like it
No problem with us then
We work as a team, don't we
Sure thing
Here's the plan
Lui returns every day at 8pm after running errands
You will hide in the lift,
and scare the crap out of him
With this outfit and some of your acting
Scaring him will be a piece of cake
Mrs. Lui comes out every day at 8:15pm
To throw garbage away in the stairs
Hung, that shall be your job
I am out of food
Can you burn me some more?
Lui's coming, be alert
Okay
This is bad.
If they take the shock badly at this age
And if anything happens to them,
we'll be condemned
We may be doing something bad today
But come to think of it,
when we becom famous
These will all be precious memories of
how we enriched our acting
What if we have to write autobiographies,
and go on TV shows
Like SNL, without anything to share? Understand?
Promise me this is going to be our last
We love acting, not scaring people
He's coming, get ready
Why is there no one? Where have they gone?
Hey
Are you taking the lift or not?
Don't block my way to hell
Run! Run
Chi, why are you like that?
The Observatory says it's 3 degrees today,
you aren't wearing anything
Coming
Granny,
I am out of food
Can you burn me some more?
Sure,
let us share mine
No one is answering the phone
I'll go and find them
Kill every soul,
- give nothing back
- The butcher, the butcher
Go, go, go, go, go
It's a ghost
Don't scare me
- Darn it, Let's go
- what are you saying?
Where to?
Downstairs
Ghosts downstairs, Upstairs
There's more up there
What should we do now?
In the middle, go
We had lots of fun today
This candy is actually delicious
I'm done,
how about you?
They wouldn't have guessed,
we hacked into their tablets
And changed up the screen
The young ones nowadays
Have no common sense with IT stuff
And no imagination whatsoever
When trying to be ghosts
Way too naive
to scare us
This city is hopeless
Thanks to my brother for making
this place sound haunted
For us to be this scary
Simon Lui...
is righteous at all times
Neighbours
around would see the butcher
with his wife every night
Cut.
Tell Simon to be more serious
I haven't been in Hong Kong for a while.
Recording work got slow
Check, check.
Lo Hoi-pang testing, one two three four five
Michael
This is too loud, just tune it down
How do you do it, just do it yourself
Quick...
Where are we going?
Quick
I'm scared, what do we do?
It's locked
What now?
Come
Jump,
there's no time to lose
It's high up here
He's coming, quick
It's gonna be alright, c'mon
Trust in yourself. One, two, three
It's fine...
I'm ready
Quick
I'm scared, carry me
Come, Kiki. Jump
- Jump
- No
We don't have time, they are coming
Almost there...
Kiki, Kiki
Kiki
- Sis
- Kiki
Hello, Auntie
You came to see your daughter?
You are very kind
Who are you?
[, I'm Slow Man
Kiki's boyfriend
Why is my sister like this?
I don't know,
I'm waiting for the doctor's diagnosis
What made her become like this all of a sudden?
I don't know anything about it
I came right after I knew
Are you sure you have nothing to do with it?
Nothing
You look nervous
Do 1?7 No, it's just warm in here
I'm sure you pushed her down
- Surely not
- Sure did
- Did not
- Look at me
- Look, look at you
- Scared?
- Not scared, not scared.
- Trying to run?
- Not trying to run
Look at me. Did you?
- May... maybe
- Did you or did you not?
- It must be you
- Is this the market or something?
This is the hospital, this is too noisy
Doctor, good timing
How is my daughter?
She?
Jumping from such height
Lucky that she landed on a canopy
which reduced the impact
Her limbs are intact
Though there was a slight concussion
- But then
- Doctor,
in the current circumstances
If you say "but", you make us nervous
Why don't you just tell us the truth?
I got X-ray scans for her, see
A blood lump the size of a fist,
seems dangerous
Dangerous?
Why didn't you operate on her?
I examined the patient, and interestingly
At this age, her cranium
is not fully developed yet
And the lump coincidentally filled that gap
If I operate on her
She might become retarded
But then
Darn you, I told you not to say "but"
Just say it
Exactly. The old geezer speaks recklessly
After examination
She shows slight memory loss
and retarded intelligence
How much has she got now?
Four Years Old
What?
What she needs the most now, is family support
Does she have a boyfriend or a husband?
Boyfriend? Me?
Not good, I should leave
She does, they are very much in love
Where's the boyfriend?
Where's the zombie?
Where did the zombie go?
Just ignore it
I saw that zombie
He left early
Doctor,
when will my daughter wake up
Fastest, it could be in three to five minutes
If things are slow
It might take several years
I own this hotel
Kiki
But then
Darn, how dare you say "but" again, jeez
I'll teach you not to,
I'll mess this place up
What did you say? I dare you do it
There can be miracles, though
Try saying that again,
and I'll get people to come
Boss, she's responding
Now I'm lying, am II? She's waking up
"Mess my place", you don't have a clue
Ignore him. What shall we eat today?
Mommy
- Kiki
- Mom
She remembers you
Yes
Sis
It's scary
Don't be scared, Mommy's here
Do you recognize me? Give me a hug
Yucky
Mommy, hungry
You hungry?
Mommy will get something for you
Mommy cook
What would you like?
I want Maotai
Maotai liquor? Who taught you that?
Brad Pitt and Tony Leung
Hello
I planned to throw this away
If you really wanted to,
you would have already done it
You won't keep it with you
Or have it charged to wait for my call
So? What's the matter?
I want to take you out for dinner
What are you eating?
You decide
Hey, wait for a bit
What up?
Hey, where are you?
Mong Kok. What's up?
Come to Wan Chai immediately. Intrusion mission
What intrusion?
I just heard
That stupid ex-boyfriend of yours,
Lo Jok, and that slut Anna
Are coming to my karaoke bar
to host a birthday party
And he is going to propose
I told King and Jen
to come crash the party.
We just need you now
Bring some friends too if you can
Who can I find in such a hurry
Oh, anyone will do
Get as many people as you can
We shouldn't be the minority there,
I'll be waiting for you
Hello
Made up your mind?
Let's go for karaoke before dinner, shall we?
Lo Jok
Yo
What's up
Michelle,
why are you here?
We were singing next door
Just to see a slut and a douchebag strutting in
I wonder if you saw them
Help us out, will you?
It's been a while
Now I see,
isn't that the douchebag
And that slut must be
Who's looking for me?
Baby, baby-boo-boo
Michelle, why are you here?
Long time no see
Care to tell me why you
You-you-you seem exhausted
Were you deprived of a man's love for a long time?
Ma'am, are you blind?
You should see that Michelle
is glowing from within
Her love fortune is running high
Who are you?
I'm nobody
I'm asking Michelle out
And ended up here
Then, how shall we address you?
Call me Simon
Uncle Simon
It's your birthday today, happy birthday
Thank you
Excuse me for not bringing a present,
I was too hurried
Don't pretend, you just don't care
It's fine not bringing a present
We take cash in substitute
Can't afford a few hundred dollars?
It would be stingy to talk about money now
It's your birthday
Do you have any wishes? I'll make them true
If my baby-boo wants to go to the moon,
could you take her there?
That's easy
I booked a rocket trip to go in 2029
If you like, I can give you my seat
But that's more than ten years,
let's talk about sometime closer home
Let me teach you an English idiom today
"Blow water don't wipe mouth”
What does it mean?
"All mouth and no trousers"
How about this
My Baby-boo shares her birthday
with the TV station
And it's their anniversary gala tonight
If you really can
Give my Baby-boo the Gala Prize
The Gala Prize it is
"Blow water don't wipe mouth", again
They are just kidding. It's just a joke
Go
No problem, trust me. I can handle it
Give me your number. The Gala Prize will be yours
He's so manly
Uncle Simon, my number is
67676767
Remember it
Excuse me for a second, I need to make a call
You idiot, getting her number like that
"Boss"
Hello, Boss
Is it hard to get the TV station's Gala Prize?
Their hotlines are usually full,
it's difficult to phone in
I want that prize tonight
It's a birthday gift for someone
I'll give you a number,
the Prize shall be hers
Boss, this is not going to be easy
If it is, I won't be needing you
Do everything to get it done, that's all
This is too much
Stop fanning me,
go find the director
- Where is my stuntwoman?
- Lily, be smart.
That girl is troublesome.
Shall we go dancing after work
Who is this?
Martial arts director
Oh, what's the matter?
Who is this?
The stuntwoman
For Miss Lok? That is a man
Man? She's a woman
You're crazy, he's a man
I am what you call a woman
Oh, Lily. You didn't shave for work
You asked for a stuntwoman all of a sudden,
you have to live with it
Hey, if you let that act as my boss
We will lose face
I don't care if you don't get off work today
If you don't find a girl as hot as me
I'm not filming
Get this solved
I am going to take a dump in the van. Useless shit
Hey... What is this?
Why are you in my van?
- Shut up, don't move! Be still
- Hey, let me go!
- Help! Why are you driving away?
- Don't move! Be still
Help!
"TV Station"
Hey, Patrick
- What?
- New arrangement
You are going to host the session
for our Gala Prize
Natalie is the one to do game shows
He's got diarrhoea and went home already
What about Eric?
His driver got into trouble for fighting
at Ian Kwai Fong
He's gone to bail him out
No way
Stop complaining, the producer said he wants you
It's your turn after the commercials, get ready
So fast
Boss, phone call for you
I'm going live
They say it's very important, you must listen now
Hello
That's me
Next is your turn
Man, stop trying to act cool
If you can't deliver
Just say it
What if I can? What will you do?
If you can make the TV station call us
I can do anything
If I don't, I shall get killed in a car crash
Choke on ice-cream to death
And even
Have my penis rot
Enough talk, let's switch on the TV
Welcome all to our most
exciting part of the show
Gala Prize Reveal
I will randomly pick out
one of our audiences at home
My Baby-boo did not enter for the lucky draw
Nor does she know the code
How could Patrick Dunn call us
Just give up
Since we're here, we'll see what happens
May I introduce a special guest
Who, supposedly, should be in Beijing
But because of our prize-giving ceremony
That's him, MC Jin
I came back to Hong Kong
to play games with you all
We are live now, on live
For the sake of impartiality, we also invited
Patty Wong Accountants
to monitor the entire process
Welcome, Patty Wong
So now, who will become our
lucky audience? You must be nervous too
- Let me do it, let me do it
- No need
Special guests don't have to do anything
Okay, let's see
Hello, our dear audience. It's through
Hello
Who are you?
I'm Chan, I'm so happy
We got bad reception here. Hello, hello
Everything is fine here
Oh no, it got cut,
better luck next time
But we can draw another of our audience at home
Mr. Patty Wong, please
Get me another number
Yes
Let me do this, let me do this
Special guests don't have to do anything
Let's see if this one
Is sitting by the TV
Hello, who are you?
My surname is Cheung
Mr. Cheung, are you watching us on TV?
Yes, yes
I'm going to ask you a question now
I'm going to ask.
Hello Mr. Cheung, can you hear...
Oh, hit or miss, just like this
He's gone, again
Patty Wong, the number
You hung up on all the calls, MC
There are no numbers left
We aren't like this usually
Not sure why all calls got hung up
Wait
Hello, my boss? It is I, your employee
Yes, sure, I see, I understand, okay
My boss says,
he'll give you one more number to call
If it doesn't succeed,
the prize will have to wait until next year
Then, what's the number?
Come on, get it done already.
I'm in a hurry to mahjong and dinner
I stand here every year looking at you make calls
And I don't get to share
I'm not coming next year
Okay, okay, I'm right at it, I'll call randomly
Pick up, pick up
Pick up
Hello
Who are you?
A... Anna
Anna, you must be watching TV
Patrick Dunn called me on TV
Anna Anna
I'm here, I'm here...
Your prize is worth $990,000,
and it depends whether
you can answer this correctly
I see
Listen carefully. The question is:
Are you male or female?
Anna
Female
Wow, accurate with speed
Congratulations Anna, the prize is yours
You will be contacted about collection details
Congratulations Anna,
We have given out all our prizes tonight
Thank you all for tuning in to our Anniversary Gala
We will see you next year, good-bye
Let's go for mahjong
Let's get started with the show
Hey, you lazy Patrick Dunn
You called it a day as if things are done
My freestyle is legit,
Who's that?
Still rapping?
- Yo, do you think I have much time to spare?
- Stop rapping!
Shut the lights and bring the dogs out
Let him rap all he wants
It's not okay, I don't feel dismayed
My freestyle game, it's staying so strong
I said make some noise if you love Hong Kong
I did everything you told me to
Release her
She is just beside the van
Why did this happen?
Get up, stand up first
It's impossible,
no one knows about our relationship
Did they harm you?
If this counts as harming
I wish they could do it again and again to me
I really enjoyed it
They said all of this is for me
I want to have half of it
Cheers
Congratulations
My voice was on TV
Patrick Dunn spoke to me
Lo Jok
You said if you lost, you would do anything
Don't act like you forgot
Why would I do that?
Here! I'll drink up three cups
No one told you to drink
Read it
Out loud
You are not a horse
What is wrong with you?
Have you gone mute? Read it now
Read it, or else you will
choke on ice-cream to death
Get killed in a car crash
Your penis will rot
Michelle, I am a jerk
I hooked up with your best friend,
I am sorry! Michelle
I am a jerk. I hooked up with your best friend,
I am a jerk, I took your money
and hooked up with your best friend
I am sorry! Michelle. I am a jerk,
I took your money
and hooked up with your best friend
I am sorry! Michelle
Okay, okay, okay... Are you done?
It says here for me to repeat 100 times
I fear that if I don't
I will rot down there
So you are not afraid that I won't forgive you
Well...
Will you forgive me?
No
Because you are not worthy to be
in my heart to begin with
From tonight onwards
I will forget you completely
Stop it,
play with your toys
Stop playing with my hair,
do you understand?
It takes me ages to do my hair
Hey, looks like you are having fun
Nice. Kiki
Mommy will go out for dinner today.
Funny, you take care of Kiki
No, that's not it, boss. No
I'm good at getting girls,
but not looking after them
I'm no good
You used to say that you have a big heart
Now is the time for you to demonstrate that
My daughter is a good girl
- Thank you
- No, she is...
Mommy, Mommy, let me open
Yucky
Kiki, don't say the truth out loud
Mommy knows her
Dr. Bo, this is bad
What's the matter?
My boss is losing and going bankrupt.
Please go and see him
Big sister, candy for you
Miss, no candy for her
Give her something nasty
I made the candy with my boogers
Dr. Bo, this time it is really serious, four words
Like a sinking ship
Wasn't it "like a sinking ship"?
You moron, you said your boss is nearly bankrupt
No one's gambling here, you tricked us
Not that no one's gambling
Just not yet
My goddess, it's been three months,
I missed you
Philip, what do you want
Nothing much,
I'm waiting especially for you tonight
And I invited my good old pal to gamble with you
That's crazy, you have your say either way
Boss, let's leave
How? We'll play by the rules
If she wins, I quit gambling for three months
That doesn't mean
I can't let someone play in my place
to make me lose
My goddess, I hope you aren't quitting now?
Your shifting standards are insufferable
Let's go, boss
You fat ass
I've put up with you long enough
Since when is it your turn to speak?
Now that we are here, let's do it
That's my goddess, bold and fearless
A big welcome to my good friend,
King of Cheats, Brother Tse
Isn't it too dark for shades?
His hair looks dry
Are we getting on? I'm a busy man
Don't waste the old man's time
Okay, deal the cards
My goddess always speaks
with such mighty aura
Deal the cards
Hey, what is she doing here?
She is not a dealer
Are you referring to May last time
Sorry, I sent her to Heilongjiang
Those who go against me will never end well
Dr. Bo
You had help last time
This time things won't go so well
If you lose this time,
it will be more than having midnight snacks
The night goes on
If I won this game
You shall also quit for the rest of your life
And never see me ever again
Impossible
I have the King of Cheats to assist me
What's to fear? Deal the cards
Lady, let me help you
Let me do it, let me do it
Can you?
I can try
Little girl, you are very talented
Why don't you be my student?
You be my student instead,
and I give you candy
Good stuff
Dr. Bo, what's are we betting?
One card each, the bigger one wins
Good
Ladies first
Kiki
Take one for mommy
No, you let her? She's retarded
What's the problem? She is my daughter
Who else should I ask? You?
You are right
Don't look yet
Wait
I win
Tell Fatty to get my yacht here
I will have fun with my goddess out in the sea
Oh,
Brother Tse, why is your card the same as mine?
No way
Hey,
we are playing from a blue deck
Why is yours a red card?
Your cheating is going too far
The kid must have changed our cards
You are crazy
You can see that she is retarded,
how could she do it?
- Being retarded doesn't mean she can't cheat
- Of course not
- Of course
Stop arguing.
It is pretty clear who won and who lost
Philip, you promised me
You will not gamble ever again
Thank you, godfather
Godfather? You are familiar with him?
And you kissed
Drinks on me tonight
Godfather
Stop talking about drinks
Explain this to me
You invited him over to defeat me
But he can make himself lose, too
You try to switch up the goal
But I also have a goalkeeper behind my back
Philip
You can't force love to happen
I'm leaving
My Goddess...
- Good boy
- What
I give you candy
- King of Cheats,
- This is good stuff
How do you style your hair
Made up your mind about dinner yet?
Are you thinking about how to thank me?
Don't bother, it's no big deal
I want to tell you something
You want to pledge your life to me?
How did you know? I want to marry you
I don't think I can ever meet someone
As handsome, cool
and as powerful as you
And you are not young anymore, right?
Let's not waste our time and get married
I'm impressed
I've been out there for a long time.
No one could ever guess what I want to do
But you got me there
I never thought you would propose
Very nice
It's fun
Wonderful
I'm not playing games, I'm serious
I need to fight for my own happiness, right?
Unless you tell me that
you have no feelings for me at all
You really have no feelings for me at all
I'm sorry, I must have shocked you
I'm not having dinner, I'll get going
If we are getting married
without seeing your parents first
It doesn't feel right
You just need to meet my mum
She is really nice, she's going to like you
Call her and invite her for lunch
Okay, I'll call her
Let's have dinner first, I'm hungry
My mum is a nice person. You don't have fear her
Here's you tea
Is there something you need to tell me?
You are really good at this. How do you know?
What does your mother do for a living?
So what is it?
Got dumped again?
Hold it, hold it, hold it
Of course not
Don't you tell me you are pregnant
I don't want to be a grandma soon
That's not it
That's good
I'm getting married
To who?
Who is that person?
How long have you met?
How did you meet?
Is he trustworthy?
- Why do you want to get married so suddenly?
- Calm down, calm down
I asked him to come and see you
And you didn't tell me beforehand
Surprise! He is here
Boss, they are here already
I had a meeting and it ended late
It's alright
My mother, Dr. Bo
My boyfriend, Simon Leung
Hello, Mr. Leung
Nice to meet you, Auntie
Have a seat
I'm hungry, shall we make an order first?
Sure
What do you want, Mummy?
Why don't you ask Mr. Leung, see what he likes
I am fine with anything
Auntie Bo, please have anything you like
- Then I'll decide
- OK
Mr. Leung
What did you see in Michelle that you like?
Mum, don't say it like I'm an old spinster
That's not what I mean
I mean, Michelle is a nice, beautiful girl
Why do have such an eye for good girls?
Probably because those I met in the past
were all bad women
Now I found a nice girl
So I'm not going to let go
You had bad experiences in the past
I never heard you talk about it
It's better to let bygones be bygones
As long as I am happy now
Sometimes,
one believed that they encountered bad people
But never considers the bad things
that they have done
Auntie,
for so many years
You had to bring up two daughters all on your own.
Was is difficult for you?
Ever thought of finding a good man
to take care of you?
Mummy has many admirers
Yin, go home in my car today
Is that so?
You are very demanding, and you look down on men
What sort of men do you like, I wonder?
Honestly, my requirements are simple
Being honest is most important
Simon is very honest
So you are not against us, are you?
Of course I don't.
What's important is what you like
Thank you Mummy
Say thank you
Thanks, Auntie
Am I still "Auntie"?
You should address me like Michelle did
Come on
Thanks, Mummy
That's more like it.
Have some food
Here
I never thought Mum would like you that much
You don't have confidence in me?
For my other boyfriends
She didn't like them much
But she had no negative comments about you
One word, "excellent"
I don't have any flaws for her to pick on
You're so conceited
"After tonight, let's meet and talk"
"The usual place, I'll wait for you"
What do you want, pretty?
Lard dregs noodles, little spicy, more vegetables
And you, handsome?
Lard dregs noodles, very spicy, no vegetables
What a unison. You practiced at home?
Food will be ready in no time
Here's some juice for free
It's been a while. You've lost weight
It's nothing, I'm getting on alright
I heard you are getting married
Yes
And you are still by yourself after these years
Are you really in love with my daughter
If you aren't, don't hurt her
She is a very simple girl
Why do you think I will harm her?
You know I'm not that kind of person
Because I know you too well
You like to cheat
Don't you remember?
You even went after my best friend
Why don't you believe in anything I say?
Your friend seduced me
But you still had to accept it
If you know me
You will believe that I did nothing at that time
Let's leave it, it happened so long ago,
nothing matters now
Isn't that so?
You men like to put the blame on others
And never admit what you did. And when you do
That's because someone was wrong in the first place
You did something wrong too
What?
You despised me for being poor
You thought I had no future,
so you went for someone else
I never said that,
you just saw me that way
You didn't say it but it showed on your face
Everyone knew you went after Alex
You had an affair
I said I did not, don't accuse me of that
But God is watching.
Alex got married last year,
and you are not his bride
As for me, I'm getting married soon
And my wife is very young
If you were lucky, you could have been her mother
Are you done speaking?
No, I came here especially to see you
To see how down-trodden you are
You are not young, fix yourself up
Or else no one will want you
Hey you, stay there
Young boys and girls nowadays
are really quick-tempered
We were like that too
Do you still remember?
That corner has never changed in decades
That broken brick is still there
I did that for you
Let's say you were violent
What violent?
That guy with glasses was harassing you
Don't hit me
Apologize to her
Sorry, boss
Let's go, you'll kill him. You're so violent
Violent? This is all for you
No one meddles with my girl
I think you had mood disorders back then already
What disorder?
Have you ever seen a psychiatrist?
Why don't you come to me, I'll give you a discount
You are so ungrateful
I fought for you
Hey, bro, you look familiar
I don't know you
Who are you?
I'm that guy with glasses
that you beat up in the past
I'm sorry, bro
For twenty years I come here every night
To see if I can see you again
I even got the bosslady here
Just to see you again
What a coincidence
Exactly
Guys
Go and get him
Don't run, don't run...
Why have you kept the pager?
You too
You never contacted me
How do you know it still works?
I asked the telecommunications company
As long as you pay,
they cannot cancel your number
Don't you know that?
In order for the pager to keep working
I bought the whole telecommunications company
Like an overnight billionaire
You splurge whenever you got money.
Vulgar tycoon
I have lots of money
If it is for the woman I love
I think it is worth it
What you do like?
I can buy it for you
I never despised you for being poor
You know what you did
I just didn't like how went around
and manipulate people with money
I want to tell you that
Money doesn't solve all your problems
I didn't know Michelle is your daughter
Now that you know, then what?
Don't even think about it
Cheers, son-in-law
Treat Michelle well
Or else I will not let you have it easy
Bo,
you missed me all along
Do you really want to know?
Yes
I will not tell you
Do you know what's the difference
between a man and a woman?
Tell me
Men is like bluetooth
If his woman is nearby, he sticks to her
If she's gone
He will go and connect with another woman
Women are different, they are like Wifi
Even if she has many
available connections around her
She will only connect to the strongest one
Then she latches onto him, and will never change
You men fall in love with women one after another
How can I believe you?
Hello
Where are you?
In a meeting
Did I interrupt you?
No.
Not going to sleep yet?
Nearly, take your time then
I'll sleep now. Good-bye
It's Michelle
Michelle?
Mummy, there is something I want to ask you
What?
Can we invite Simon over for
Chinese New Year's Eve dinner?
Of course
Sure, we are a family
Thank you Mummy
Sleep early
You too, goodnight
Goodnight
Michelle asks me to invite you over for dinner
Be early this time
Thank you
What happened in the past,
let it stay in the past
I think this is my last time meeting you privately
Take care
He's not picking up
He isn't like this usually
I think he must be in a meeting
Let me call him again
Michelle
Don't be so nervous,
he might just be caught in the traffic
Sit down
Oh, he is here
- Simon
- I'm sorry,
there's traffic everywhere
I was worried
Mum, see how much thought he put in?
You got this wine?
Thank you
Don't mention it
Yes...
- thank you
- You scared me for being so late
The first time you come for dinner,
minus points for you
Sorry
Are you hungry?
Eat
Happy New Year
Happy New Year,
wish you good health and good fortune
Simon, aren't you eating?
Michelle likes the drumstick
Thank you
Auntie, I think you also like drumsticks
I also like drumstick
Mummy will give it to Kiki
Good
Mummy is good, Kiki is a good girl too
As a mother, I should let my daughter have her way
Since we have everyone here,
I have something to announce
Really? Me too
What's with that? You agreed on this?
If you don't mind,
let me announce first
You go first
I accepted an offer from a university in the US
To be their guest lecturer,
I'll leave next week
So sudden?
For how long?
At least one year
That's a long time
Mummy, what about your clinic?
And your patients? Plus
Sis is stuck in this condition
The reason I'm going to America, is also to
Research on Kiki's condition with
medical experts over there
When things gets settled
I will bring Kiki over to see
if they can treat her
Mummy, I'm not going
Why
I'm okay now
I was nearly shot in the back, I'm scared
Kiki, don't be scared
Mummy will be with you
Mummy, what do I do when you're gone
I know my son-in-law will take good care of you.
I'm confident
But that is a long time
If you get married,
Mummy will fly back to be there
Future son-in-law, it is your turn
Don't you have something to announce?
Michelle and I are serious with our relationship
Auntie, I promise you
I'll take good care of her
Since you are so good to Michelle
Can you answer three questions?
No problem
First question
There is a 10-billion contract in front of you
At the same time,
Michelle calling you from the hospital
Needing you to transfuse blood to save her
Between the contract and Michelle
Which will you choose?
Easy, I choose Michelle
Second question
Is Michelle the last girlfriend you'll ever have?
Yes
Third question
Is Michelle the love of your life?
Yes
When you answered my first question
You right eye looked up towards the ceiling
According to psychology
You are not speaking the truth
Second question
You touched your chest twice
And said "yes" twice
Yes
Which covers up your untruthfulness
When you answered my third question
You pointed your chopsticks at the door
Meaning that you wanted to leave, to escape
Mummy, don't treat Simon like
one of your patients
Simon, I hope you don't mind.
My mother's just joking with you
There is really no big deal about it
So long as my daughter Michelle likes it, that's fine
Isn't that right? Future son-in-law
"One year later”
We are running late, the show is starting
Okay, I'll drive faster
Thank you
Lucky he's not here yet
You weren't this nervous
when you went out with me
That's different.
We broke up shortly before three months
I'm sorry
No need to be
I'm the one who should be sorry
Because I wanted break up soon
after when we got together
Although you were really handsome, cool and powerful
But you are just so boring
And you aren't actually my type of guy
Let's see what your type of guy is
Ah Ho
Michelle
Let me introduce you to my uncle
Uncle, good to see you
Ho, I see?
You spared time just to give her a ride?
My uncle pampers me a lot
Good girls deserve much pampering
I admit that I do
Uncle, We'll get going and not waste your time
Enjoy yourself
Ho
Yes, uncle?
I warn you, treat her well
Or else I won't go easy on you
Of course I will, uncle
Don't call me "uncle"
We are about the same age
Yeah, Simon
Thank you
I tell you
Mummy will be back in Hong Kong in two days
I know that look you have when you are in love
And I've seen it more than once
Last time Mummy asked you three questions
She had asked my other boyfriends too
It was really accurate
See you
Mr. Leung
What made you decide three months ago
To sell your companies at a high price
And to donate half of your personal assets
Together with 30% of the shares
in your conglomerate companies
To start up "Simon Leung Charity Fund"?
Money is outside the body
What's important is to help those really in need
You were entitled "King of Subdivision”
And were widely criticized
for your business ethics
For squeezing the best out of every deal
But why is it that recently
Your newly built 18-storey mall
Which had only six toilets to start with
Was changed just before sale
To having one toilet in each level?
And you also let the shops for cheap rent
To young people in support of start-up businesses
In this generation
It is very hard for the young to start a business
I was poor when I was young
I understand the struggle. I want try my best to help
My Leung
For such a drastic change to happen
Was it because of some sort of impact?
I hope your body is fine?
A good friend once told me
I want to tell you that
Money doesn't solve all your problems
She was right
So I learnt to solve problems using my heart
Once you put your heart into something,
you can do everything
What?
I nearly sprained my ankle
Don't yell for nothing
What do you think Simon asked me to come here for?
Boss, would it be that he wanted to Kill you?
You got someone to ambush him before
Maybe he lured you here to kill you
Shut it. It's fine
He told everyone around that
He didn't mind it. It's fine
Ow
Hey, what now again?
There are a lot of mosquitoes
Oh no
What kind of place is this?
Wait
Zika virus, Dengue fever
Simon is really evil-minded
No one would know if we die of poisonous mosquitoes
Let's leave
Philip
Here
Simon, you jerk, I'm here for lunch,
not to give out lunch
How could you ask an elite like me to do this?
You have seven days a week
to spend thinking about money
You have no wife, and no kids
What are you going to do with all that money?
Come volunteer when you are free
Are you possessed by a ghost?
You're speaking like a human
Are you cursed or something?
Yes, we both were cursed
What curse?
A curse to earn money non-stop
We labour every day
In this lifetime,
we missed out on a lot of things
But I am already released from this curse
I hope to release you too by asking you to come
Don't you hate me?
When did I ever hate on you
You bully me all the time
I'm like that to everybody
As good old pals
All those bad memories in the past
Let us press a "delete" button and let it go
Then I have misunderstood you
Sorry, Simon
I'll do as you say, let's forget about the past
Put your heart to it
I will do it with all my heart
Thanks, Simon
All hail Simon
Can I help you?
No need
I'm new here,
can you please teach me how to do it?
Oh, it's easy
How?
Put in some egg
Some egg
Yes
And some vegetables
Phew, this is complicated
That's it
I see
Give it a try
I'll try
Put in some egg,
I'm shaking
- Slowly, slowly
- Put in some vegetables
Is it like this?
More
Right,
- that's it
- Is it correct?
You are doing good
Thank you
What's your name?
My name is Philip
I'm Sze-yin
Sze-yin, you sound like a good girl
Hey, our clothes are matching. They're both pink
This is for girls
Girls?
Simon, you tricked me again
You are so nice
You always gave us a lot of delicious food, thank you
Don't mention it.
Being happy is what's most important
I'll ask the staff to
distribute red packets to everyone
Oh, thank you, this is so good of you
And you brought a friend
Wow, what a firm chest
Do you have a girlfriend?
Not yet, I don't have one
No girlfriend yet
That means I can...
No way
Although I am pretty
Yes
But you are not my cup of tea
Scaring me
I'm talking about my niece
- Auntie
- No
Auntie
Yin treats me the best
Really?
Hey
Act smart
I understand now.
Got it, Auntie
Auntie told me to act smart,
act smart
What now?
Helping people really brings joy
Are you helping yourself or others?
It's the same, the same
Simon is a good man
Of course he is
Some decades ago he beat me up badly
Is that so?
And I've forgiven him too
Thank you and your cha chan teng
For providing all the food today
No big deal, and you gotta pay for it too
Let's get to work
Yes
Don't be stingy, okay?
I won't be,
okay
Thank you, thanks a lot
Good, well done today
Let's take a selfie
Yay, selfie time
Okay, come on
My pager seems to be malfunctioning
Since you are the boss of the company,
can you give me a new one?
If not,
it is really a shame to your clients
who paid the monthly fees all along
You are my premium client
I'll give you a new number and a new pager
Available for life, and permanent warranty
But you can only contact me with that pager
Then I need to think about it
How long?
Still need to think?
Kiss her, kiss her, kiss her...
I'm just abiding by popular opinion
Spicy fish balls please
Jo... Joey
I love your songs
No changed needed
Thank you
Hey, Joey
This is for you,
it's got a lot in it
How much is it?
There's no need
Can we take a picture?
Oh, sure
Let me do it, let me do it. Here
Joey
Strike a cool pose.
One, two, three, there we go
Joey, you are really beautiful
I love your songs
You really do?
Of course
Sing it to me
Applause for yourselves
Thanks Joey
Dr. Bo
How are you? Are you full?
Fuller than last time
This means your pressure level is lowered
Artists like us live in hell
Every time there is a concert, I have to go on diet
How could I resist?
Plus, how could I enjoy these fish balls publicly?
Yes
That's why I'm really thankful
For this down-to-earth arrangement
I booked you in for revolving sushi too
You don't even need to go to Japan
Really
Joey,
you need to be on stage
in the Coliseum in 15 minutes
What? Oh no. Take this for me
Oh, before going onstage
Don't worry, I'm ready
Dr. Bo, thank you
Thank you
See you next time
Sure. Good show
- Good show
- Thank you
Tell me when you are free to see my show
Okay.
Remember to come back for sushi
Sushi
- Good show
- Here comes $88,000.
It's easy to earn a celebrity's money
Hey, Philip
What
Because Funny is on holiday,
and since you are good friends with Simon
I let you to come intern for a day
I'm surprised at how well you've done
Goddess, you know the situation I'm in
And you took care of me.
I can never repay your kindness
It's my fault for not checking up
on your illness regularly
Once I let you out of my eyesight,
You gamble more and more every day
Now you've lost everything
I wouldn't bear it if I did nothing
Goddess, since you are here
I'll tell you something. Don't be angry though
Why would I be?
Hm, look at the bill
Wow, why is it so long
$388,000
What is this? What did you eat?
This is all street food
What street food?
That shark fin soup uses real whale shark fin
Directly from Fook Lam Moon
Why whale shark fin?
It's for the queen of Cantopop,
how could we give her cheap food?
I hope the fish balls do not use abalone
Abalone cannot make fish ball paste.
It's from giant groupers
[t wouldn't cost that much even if that's the case
It's the cheek of giant groupers
One fish ball only uses three groupers,
That's a bargain
Philip,
You did really well
You didn't bring shame on me
I didn't
I tell you
Take all the food back home and eat it
What?
I tell you, you can start job-hunting
I can't take care of you anymore, that's it
Goddess
What's wrong?
- Why is she angry?
- Good that you are here.
Help me beg for mercy
- What's wrong?
- How can I pay the bill?
This $388,000 bill
There's no problem being poor.
No one can save you for being stupid
Don't say that
I think everything between us is over
What's over?
Pack your things and leave.
You'd be sued for blocking the road
Best of luck
Sze-yin, you weren't like that last night
Boss, let's go to see Joey's concert
What did I do wrong?
Kung Hei Fat Choi
MK Woody Allen's La Sing Land casting
is about to begin
No need to queue, but don't push
Why are you here?
Kiki
I thought I might be able to see you here
You loved MK Woody Allen
You must want to be
in his movie as his lead actress
Go away, I don't know you
Don't be like that, Kiki
Who left me at the hospital that day?
Kiki, you sound normal now. You got better
Your recovery is so fast
I got well a long time ago. I was just faking it
I heard that
the lead character is retarded in this movie
So I wanted to get into character first,
and get into method acting
Ladies and gentlemen, in the past 90 minutes
My retardedness was so on point that
it fooled everyone
Stop playing with my hair
I was nearly shot in the back, I'm scared
Such awesome acting, I won't say it's the best
But at least it is worth an award
You even sacrificed me for this character,
you must be able to get it
Why are you here?
I'm also an MK Woody Allen fan
Where there is a female lead,
there must be a male lead character
Kiki,
since we are both confident
If we do the casting as a couple,
it must help score more points
This idea is great, I've thought of it too
But not with you
Why?
Why don't I introduce my new boyfriend
Hi
You... why...
The movie's about to end
Let's not talk about what happened before
Simply put,
Kiki and I
It was love at first sight, like a spark of fire
No way, you must be acting again
Kiki, haven't you told him
We are so very in love
Wonderful. So scram
Scram? You scram
- You go
You go
Go where? Go where?
What? Go? Go where?
Stop, I'll go
- You go
- We aren't done
- Leave
- I'm not leaving
- Just go away
- You go away
Why don't you go?
Stop it.
Everyone's gone,
what is there to argue?
No one likes you here, go away
I'm back
- Kiki
- How was it?
Yeah, how was it?
I asked first, answer me
You just need to answer me
I did all that I could,
and I sang
What did you sing?
I'll sing it for you
"St Paul's, Buddha's Statue,
A-Ma Temple all beautiful views"
Well done
And I danced
What did you dance?
I'll show you
Sure
Wonderful
That's not it, there's more
Bravo
You must get the role
No
She said the role is not for me
Why?
You did so well, that's not right
"Fudge" it. The movie is in English
Nobody told me that
In English?
Western movies are in English, don't you know?
- Western movie?
- Yes
Since when is MK Woody Allen that good?
His movies are always kind of "western"
Why didn't you tell me,
I shouldn't have done method acting
I should have learnt English instead
MK Woody Allen is such a jerk
All of his movie names are the same,
who's going to remember
I won't tolerate it even if I'm a fan
Do you have any suggestions?
Let's go beat him up
Go
Okay
Peace and harmony to you
and your family in the Year of the Dog
May everything go well for you
Wish everyone a good morning, goodnight,
and good health every day
Wish you all an energetic year ahead
May all your wishes come true
Great fortunes and prosperity
Wish you a great start after good rest,
the best and the good jest
To good health and
a good future in the Year of the Dog