Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
Do you know him?
No.
He's the best French actor.
Louis Garrel.
He's the star of the film.
Can I ask what the film is about?
The director will tell you everything
himself. If you're selected.
There'll be two weeks of shooting
in Tehran and two in Paris.
Visa and travel will be arranged by us.
If you're selected, that is.
So when do you start?
Casting will be done today
or tomorrow.
The shoot begins in Tehran
in six weeks.
You're OK with nudity?
Flex your biceps.
This French actor...
Is he coming to Tehran too?
No. Your profile.
- Do you have a shooting permit?
- They'll get it.
Your back.
Flex it nicely.
Put your clothes back on.
Only 200 grams.
If you don't like the food
in your program,
we can change it so you get results.
No, I like the food.
- Then you're not exercising.
- I am.
All bodies differ. I promise you...
If you stick to it,
you'll get results.
What about liposuction?
DR. TAHERI'S BEAUTY CLINIC
Hi. I have an appointment at 11.
- And you are?
- Farhad Moslemi.
- Are you registered with us?
- No.
Fill this out. I'll call you.
FARHAD MOSLEMI
Keep your eyes open, Mr Houshmand!
It's dangerous not to.
- How many times were you champion?
- Three times.
I thought it was four.
I have a nephew. He's a bodybuilder.
He wants to compete for
a championship.
He wasn't happy with his trainer.
I told him he should see you.
- How old is he?
- He's 26.
You already did this one!
Sorry.
Sit up.
It's still sore here.
I'll tell him to call you then.
His name is Arshia.
Hello?
Yes?
Who's this?
Ah, how are you?
Really?
Is it confirmed?
Sure.
What time tomorrow morning?
That's good.
At the same office?
OK. Thank you.
So will I get the script now? Or...
OK, see you then.
- Enjoy.
- Thank you.
- Anything else?
- Do you have any puzzles of actors?
Actors...
We have Al Pacino's Scarface,
Marlon Brando's Godfather
and a few of the Rockys too.
- What about Louis Garrel?
- Who?
- Louis Garrel.
- Never heard of him, what's he in?
This is him.
Never seen him.
He's the most famous actor in France.
Mina, can you come a bit earlier
tomorrow to get the delivery?
- Sure.
- Thank you. Good night.
Good night.
FARHAD MOSLEMI
Hello? Hi, handsome Farhad.
How are you, baby?
It's Sara.
I want us to get to know
each other better.
Oh, baby...
Does it matter where I got
your number from?
Yeah, I have photos.
You have the Telegram app, right?
So I'll send them to you.
Bye.
It's a thousand pieces.
Give me those glasses.
At least have some fruit.
- You didn't eat your dinner.
- I had no appetite.
You shouldn't take those pills
on an empty stomach.
Yes? We're coming down.
Mina, are you ready?
The taxi's here.
Don't you want to put makeup on?
No.
Mina, for the love of God,
Don't embarrass me.
Auntie was telling me
about poor Manouchehr...
He's been waiting for us to visit
his restaurant since it opened.
It's not a restaurant.
It's a pizza joint!
Whatever it is, please be nice to him.
I don't like him.
You've never seen him properly!
Just give him a chance this time.
Come on, let's go.
She said they took Firouzeh to
one of those fancy fertility clinics.
And they paid a lot of money too.
But now they've told her
her chances are minimal.
She should've put her eggs in the
freezer when she was much younger.
There you go, ladies.
Thank you, son!
This is the frozen yoghurt.
It's fat free. Enjoy it without guilt!
- Thanks, Manouchehr.
- My pleasure.
I don't want it.
You didn't touch your food either!
I prefer ice cream.
You should've told me!
Ice cream coming right up.
Poor boy, he was so excited
that you were coming, Mina.
He would've made you "Pash Melba"
had he known you only like ice cream.
It's "Peche Melba".
Whatever you call it.
Excuse me,
I need to go outside for a bit.
Hey, Arash, you OK, baby?
I wanted to confirm our date tomorrow.
Let me know. Bye.
Hi, son. How are you?
I wanted to tell you,
we've finally got our tickets.
I can't wait to see you
and my beautiful daughter-in-law.
Love you...
OK, my love.
Call me when you're done.
I'll come pick you up for dinner.
Bye.
Vahid?
Must I chase after you every time?
Can't you be on time for once?
And you dropped this!
Please recite a prayer
for our beloved...
Yadollah Bagheri. The eldest of the
Bagheri family, kind father,
caring husband, and loving teacher.
They've mentioned here
that he loved walking too. Amen!
God bless Muhammad
and his descendants!
The sorrow of your departure
Haunts me forever
My eyes are forever on the door
Expecting your return
Hi.
How are you, buddy?
No. It's exactly what we thought.
She's a time waster!
No, the bitch doesn't pick up.
But damn, those sexy pics
were worth the effort.
I'll wait a little longer,
I'll come round if she doesn't show.
I still don't know
what this film is about.
Believe me, this director doesn't give
the script to anyone.
He will tell you all you need to know
when he arrives.
When I sent him your video yesterday
he loved it and chose you immediately.
You've really impressed our director!
I just don't want to get into trouble.
What trouble?
If you're worried about
the shooting permit,
I promise we won't do anything
without all the permits.
Seeing your beautiful face
Opens the doors of heaven
- Goodbye, Vahid.
- Goodbye, Uncle Khosrow.
We're going out for dinner with my
wife and her friends. Want to join us?
No thanks.
I'm having dinner with Arezou.
OK, then.
Let's get you to your fiancée.
What do you mean?
We had a plan.
My parents are coming
in three days to see you.
Tell them not to come.
We're not meant for each other.
We are.
We're not.
I've given it a lot of thought.
I should've told you sooner,
but I wanted to be sure.
These flies are driving me nuts!
Give me that!
Sorry. One second.
- Hi.
- Sorry I'm a bit early.
- No worries.
Go get ready.
I'll come and get you when I'm done.
The lockers are over there.
Thanks.
My legs are not as built as my
upper body. They need more work.
No. They're fine.
Take it off.
Flex your biceps.
I was much bigger two months ago
when I was with my old trainer.
He went off to Germany
and left me with another guy.
He was into steroids and stuff.
I didn't get along with him and
lost my groove. Now I've shrunk.
No, you have a good body.
If you train hard, you'll be ready for
the championships in three months.
- That's exactly what I want.
- Face me.
Arms up.
Down.
Flex both arms.
If you don't mind, I'll come for a few
trial sessions first.
Then we can fix it.
As you wish.
Sorry. It's because I had
a bad experience recently.
No problem. Fair enough.
- When shall we start?
- I'm ready whenever you say!
How about tomorrow, 11 a.m.?
Great!
Just remember to bring your exercise
and diet plan so I can take a look.
I've got them right here on my phone.
I'll send them to you now.
Hi. I have an appointment at 4 p.m.
- Your name?
- Hessam Fazli.
Here you go. Fill this out.
I'll call you.
HESSAM FAZLI
OK, open your eyes.
For Botox, you better start
as soon as possible.
You don't want those lines
to get any deeper.
Does it leave any marks?
No, none. Sit up.
Look here.
I'll take these for
the before and after comparison.
I mean, right after the injection.
Does it swell? Will there be a rash?
Not at all. What do you do for work?
I'm a personal trainer.
But I'm supposed to act in a film.
Look to your right.
What kind of film?
Any famous actors in it?
Louis Garrel.
He's the most famous French actor.
Arezou! Please pick up.
We can talk things through
if you give it a chance.
You can't just give up like this!
I love you.
Please talk to me.
Oh, my father! Oh, my father!
I know you will never return
But still
I keep the door open
and look for you everywhere
Say it again
Oh, my father, oh, my father
There you go, Vahid. Well done!
You gave it your all today.
I just spoke to your dad on the phone.
I told him your son made all of us cry
even though we hear him every day!
Thanks.
This is for tomorrow.
A 25-year-old died in a car accident.
Just don't go overboard with this one!
He was an only child.
The family is devastated as it is.
SOCIETY OF HEARTS
"Always have the strength to leave
behind those who harm you."
Oh, dear me!
Shall I bring you some water?
No. I'm fine.
Come in!
I'm Mina Shams. I called earlier.
Can I register for Dr Sami's class?
"Geometry of Love and Relationships".
Are you single?
Yes.
Perfect! Because this class
is for singles only!
I know.
Let me get you a form then.
"Today is the tomorrow
you've been waiting for. Smile!"
OK, love.
Fill this out for me.
And you know the cost, right?
It's such a fantastic course!
I know lots of couples
who have met through it.
Hello, Mum?
You OK?
I'm not bad.
I wanted to tell you
to postpone your trip to Tehran.
Arezou's grandpa is sick. She went to
her hometown with her family today.
Let's see.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, I'll let you know.
No, nothing's happened.
I'm just a bit tired.
DR TAHERI'S BEAUTY CLINIC
Hi, Farhad.
What happened, baby?
Are we still on for Thursday?
Bye.
Hi. I'm Sohrab Sabet.
I have an appointment at 11 a.m.
Sorry, I know I'm a bit early.
No problem. But the doctor won't be
here until 11 a.m.
I'll wait, if you don't mind.
Fill this out.
Excuse me! By previous illnesses, do
they specifically mean skin problems?
All of them.
We're definitely on
for tomorrow, sexy!
And if you are as hot as your pics,
we're so on for other things too!
You haven't even seen half of it.
Tomorrow...
Excuse me! Sorry to bother you again.
I was answering
the questions on your form.
I was just wondering... Do you use
anaesthetics for laser hair removal?
No.
So the pain is bearable then?
Depends on the person.
Some take painkillers.
Sorry, a little more here.
Yeah, that's it.
Great session, man!
I'm so pumped!
Yeah. Good start.
I went over your diet plan.
It's all fine.
You just need to add these supplements
and vitamins to it.
I'll take whatever makes me look like
those photos you showed me.
Back then we didn't even have access
to most of this stuff.
Now there's so much junk out there
you never know which ones to take.
I know this place.
They've got genuine products
and they give me a good discount.
We can go together.
I'll introduce you.
Sure, let's go.
No girl is going to put up with
this lifestyle of yours.
All this wailing, misery and death!
It's unbearable!
You seriously need some positive
energy and upbeat action.
What do you want me to do?
You know what?
I need to get you a job with
Uncle Mammad to cheer you up.
Let me give him a call.
Go!
My eyes staring out on the road
My pure and anxious heart is beating
The window opens onto
the autumn sunset
The pouring rain...
His voice is not bad.
But it's got this sorrow in it.
It's not fit for weddings.
It is, uncle!
Give him a chance.
If you don't like it,
I won't insist any more.
For you, OK.
I'll let him sing
a couple of songs during dinner.
Thank you so much, uncle!
I'm not made for this.
I only came because I didn't have
the energy to argue with you.
Come on! If you can't do it with
the voice you have, who can?
You need to get yourself
out of this misery.
You'll go,
sing a couple of happy songs
and everything will sort itself out.
There you go.
Only for our special customers.
Thanks, man!
Please keep this in mind,
we are getting Arshia ready
for the championships in three months.
- Please look after him.
- Sure. This place is all yours.
Thanks. I've heard a lot about you.
Cheers. Just like Hessam,
we are at your service.
Sorry, one second.
Hello?
Yes.
Who is this?
No, I don't.
Where did you get my number?
Does it matter where I got it from?
Miss! Please don't disturb me again.
Hello?
HESSAM FAZLI
- Thanks for the ride.
- No worries.
I love driving.
You've got nerves of steel
to drive in this madhouse.
Does your friend have a sore neck?
Aww, we know how to massage it.
- By the way, are you on Instagram?
- Yes. Hessamfitness247.
I'm not that active though.
Mostly use it for work.
- Cool. I'll follow you.
- Thanks!
Just a couple hours ago on TV...
They were talking about a 27-year-old
who died from drinking this crap.
Heart attack.
That's from steroids.
I was at this wedding last night...
The bride and groom's application
for immigration to Australia
was approved in less than six months!
I was like, lucky bastards!
Any news from yours?
- Special ice cream for you.
- I had the fruit salad.
Sorry!
- There's your fruit salad.
- Where's my umbrella?
Well, the fruit salad doesn't come
with an umbrella.
But I can get you one.
Thank you.
So, I called my lawyer right away.
This is so yummy. Can I take some?
So I called him and complained.
He kept saying that
it'll come any minute.
I'm like, just give me a rough date
so I can plan my life.
He kept saying
it could come any day now.
Enough about me.
What's happening with Mr Pizza Joint?
It was a disaster.
I was furious.
They need to...
just leave you alone.
They don't give up.
You should've applied
for Australia too.
We would've gone together
and we'd be rid of this place.
All for me? Thanks!
Since you're so kind,
can you take a photo of us?
Sure.
Mina, take your umbrella.
Ready? Three, two, one.
Why are you not answering your phone?
I got worried!
I was out of it.
You'll get back in it
when you sing at the wedding tonight.
- No way!
- Vahid! Don't be an ass!
I promised Uncle Mammad.
I've got three funerals
at the mosque today!
You don't.
You have food poisoning and
you're not going to the mosque.
I've sorted everything out with
Haj Agha. Sajjad is replacing you.
Have you lost your mind?
What did you tell them?
So let's see...
What will you wear tonight?
Everything's black here!
Is this your dad's suit?
I got this for my brother's wedding
a while ago.
Thank God your brother got married.
Made you get one thing
that's not black.
We might be able to sort it out.
Got any belts?
Sadegh, has your wife
spoken to Arezou?
- She's not answering my calls.
- I think so.
Put the belt on.
What do you mean? What did she say?
Nothing. The girl doesn't know
what she wants.
Forget about her.
Hi, Haj Agha.
Yes. I don't feel well.
I think it's food poisoning.
I don't know what it's from.
Must be some junk food I had.
It's all Sadegh's fault.
Yes, he told me.
I'll also call Sajjad to cover for me.
Sure. Sorry for the trouble.
See you later.
Now we're talking.
GEOMETRY OF LOVE AND RELATIONSHIPS
SINGLES CLASS
If you're here for anything else,
now is the time to run away.
OK. Introductions first!
Tell us about yourself and
what you expect from this course.
Reza! Let us start with our
new friends first.
Thank you.
So.
You, my dear.
Hi. I'm Mina.
Very well. Welcome, Mina.
Tell us a bit more about yourself.
Hi, Sara?
- Sorry?
- Sara?
- No.
- I'm sorry. My mistake.
I better go before my wife kills me.
You throw me in this mess
and now you go party!
You call going to my in-laws' a party?
Uncle Mammad said
he will come get you at dinner time.
I'm off. Call me when you're done.
Please give it up for our
handsome groom, one more time!
Thank you.
Our groom has to leave now
to get back to his bride
in the ladies section.
One more round of applause.
Thank you.
They're telling me dinner is served.
Please make your way to the buffet
and help yourselves.
I've also been told that
another singer named Vahid
is going to sing for you
while you eat.
But I promise
that I will be back with you
right after dinner
with some great songs.
One more round of applause!
What should I play?
This is what I know.
These? For a wedding?
You should've checked with me.
My eyes staring out on the road
My pure and anxious heart beating
The window open onto
the autumn sunset
The pouring rain in the street
Your memory beats in my heart
at every sunset
The sunset always reminds me of you
Got a light?
Thanks.
- Been singing for long?
- A few years now.
I wish you were singing after dinner
too. I can't stand that horny asshole.
But I screwed up.
No, it was all right.
Where did you sing before?
- I wasn't in Tehran.
- Ah, so you're a newbie here.
Yeah.
- Niloufar! Can you come for a second?
- Coming.
-I'm Niloufar. Nice to meet you
-I'm Vahid.
Are you singing on Tuesday too?
I am.
Great. I'll see you then! Thanks!
Can I sing on Tuesday too?
At dinner. Just like tonight.
And I don't want money.
Just like tonight.
- OK, come.
- Thanks!
Listen!
At least rehearse
some happy songs with Mohsen.
I will.
And fix those trousers.
Hi.
- How are you?
- Hi.
We met last week at the clinic.
I was a bit early.
Yes, of course. Sorry, I didn't
recognize you for one second.
No worries. You see so many people
at work every day. It's only natural.
I just saw you and thought I should
say hi. Didn't mean to disturb you.
No, it's OK.
Nice seeing you.
You too.
My next appointment is next week.
I'll see you then.
Sure.
Have a good day.
Thanks, you too.
Hello?
Hi. Sorry, I think I might have
the wrong number.
I was looking for Sohrab.
Can I speak to him?
This is...
Mina Shams.
Hi, Sohrab! How are you?
It's Mina. From the clinic.
We saw each other at the café today.
I'm good, thanks.
Sorry if I called at a bad time.
Your wife...
No, I just wanted to remind you
of your next appointment.
Yes.
Tuesday at 3 p.m.
Thanks. Bye.
The director insists you watch
these carefully.
Louis Garrel is in a couple of them.
Watch them to familiarize
yourself with him.
- When is he coming?
- Louis Garrel?
He's not coming.
I mean the director.
He'll arrive
in the next couple of days.
We start rehearsals next week.
Do you know the schedule
for rehearsals?
It's five days a week.
- Five days full time?
- Yes.
And shooting is definitely next month?
Yes. I told you all this already!
It's next month.
Is anything wrong?
No.
No, Mum!
Arezou isn't coming back
any time soon.
How can we talk about marriage
when her grandfather is so ill!
OK. I'll let you know.
Haj Agha is well too.
Bye.
Go take it off.
It'll be ready tomorrow.
I want it today.
- It will cost you.
- I'll pay.
Hi. I have an appointment at 1 p.m.
You are?
Hessam Fazli.
You don't have an appointment today.
I was here last week.
You gave me the appointment yourself.
It's for tomorrow. Not today.
I swear you said today!
I put it straight into my phone.
You must have made a mistake.
No, miss! I think the mistake
was made somewhere else.
I'm sure it was for today.
Mr Fazli! I tried writing your
appointment down on the card for you.
You said you prefer it on your phone.
Take this to avoid any
further confusion.
But I don't know
if I can make it tomorrow.
Would you like to change it then?
No. I'll call you if I can't make it.
As you wish.
Yes. They're good.
Don't worry, Mohsen,
we'll figure it out.
Just please practice that song
I told you about for tonight.
Look, I have to go now.
I'll see you tonight.
Oh! Which hospital?
I'm at work till 6 p.m.
I'll come right after.
OK. Bye.
Where are you going at 6 p.m.?
We got another one at 7 p.m.!
My friend had an accident.
He's in hospital.
His family... live out of town.
So again,
you're not performing tonight?
I'm here for the next one.
But I'm sorry about tonight.
I'll arrange for Sajjad to replace me.
The next one is an 86-year-old man.
Tonight's is a teenage cancer case.
I wanted you to sing for that.
Open your fingers.
Use your thumb as a pivot.
Bit further up. Good.
Aim at the middle of the white ball
and hit to the left of the red one.
You should only move
from the elbow down. Let's try.
Pretty good. You'll slowly get better.
You want to give it another go?
Let's do it.
- Arshia, shall we start?
- One sec.
I'll play a set with the guys.
Then I'll practice with you.
Sure, go ahead. I'll watch and learn.
Sorry.
Shall I break?
Go ahead.
We should never confuse
self-love with selfishness.
What we mean by self-love is
one's responsibility towards oneself.
It's only when we love ourselves
that we are able
to share this love with others.
Now, everyone close your eyes.
Concentrate.
Now think of something
you've done recently.
And see if you have done it
out of self-love or selfishness.
Open your eyes. Go ahead, Reza!
I've done something recently which
has changed people's opinion of me.
I put my mum in a nursing home.
Most people think of it
as a selfish act.
And I hurt myself for years
thinking the same.
But we got to a point where
both our lives were being destroyed.
That's why I think...
Thanks, Reza.
Very interesting example.
Now I want each of you to think
and say what would you've done
if you were in Reza's shoes?
Go ahead, Mina!
Mina! Excuse me!
I just wanted to say.
You were the only one who understood
where I was coming from.
- I was very touched.
- I only said what I thought.
That's what I mean.
I'd love to know what you think
about other things too.
Like what?
Many things!
Let me give you my number.
Maybe we can talk a little more.
One more game?
Let's do it!
Now that we're going
to train together full time,
you have to be careful
with your sleeping pattern.
Your body needs eight hours
of sleep per day.
Yeah, man, I'll be careful.
I've already adjusted
my work schedule.
I want to give this my all
until the championships.
I'll tell my family
not to bother me as well.
- Are you married?
- No! I meant my parents.
Good. You can focus better that way.
What about you? You married?
I've been divorced for a few years.
Thanks for the ride, again.
Don't mention it. We should get used
to seeing more of each other.
- We're going for the gold, man!
- One hundred percent.
If you just tell me about your fees,
we'd be all set.
No rush. We'll deal with that later.
- See you tomorrow.
- Good night.
Oh, my beloved and beautiful
My Niloufar!
You're asleep in your sweet dreams
You're asleep in your bed all alone
You've left me and my heart
in solitude
Lady of the desert Oh, Niloufar!
Oh, Niloufar! Oh, Niloufar!
Impeccable song choice tonight!
- You sing at private weddings too?
- Not yet.
I work with this private venue
out of town.
If you want, I can try and see
if they'll hire you.
They don't have a singer?
They did.
But I don't know what happened to him.
They were looking for one
up until yesterday.
Sure. No problem.
I'll call them and let you know.
Give me your number.
That's me.
I'll give you a missed call.
Hurry up! It just started.
I got work to do.
Auntie Behdokht invited us
for dinner tomorrow.
How many times do I have to say it?
I don't like that pizza guy!
Just see him once, at home!
You can talk to him
in a relaxed environment.
I have nothing to say to him.
I'm going to get ice cream.
Hi, Reza!
The director is arriving tomorrow!
What do I say to him?
It's out of my hands. I have to train
someone for a competition.
It's taking up all my time.
I did my best to make it work.
But you can't do this!
You've signed a contract!
I know. And I'm sorry.
Trust me.
This is not how I usually do business.
And I'm letting you know
the moment I found out.
So I don't waste your time.
- Do you have a keyboard player?
- I do.
Good. I've booked a DJ for tomorrow.
But since Niloufar referred you,
I'll let you sing after dinner
and we'll see how it goes.
Thanks.
OK, let's hear it.
Light it up, guys!
I doubt I'll make it to retirement.
There's so much stress
in our line of work,
people suddenly give up and go.
Just last week, someone suddenly left
to open a café in Laos.
- Where?
- Laos. Vang Vieng.
Now it's your turn.
After five years in this job,
nothing surprises me any more.
Come on!
What's the weirdest thing you've seen?
There was this woman in her 60s
who brought her cat's picture
and wanted to make herself
look like the cat.
Is that even possible?
It was.
But by the time all her surgeries
were done, she died.
- The woman?
- The cat.
You're joking?
I'm serious.
Desert menus.
My neck is so sore from sitting behind
the computer all the time.
Shall we have ice cream?
One, two, three, four.
The city is full of light and stars
Lovers' dreams are all coming true
What a beautiful...
Vahid, you need to be more energetic
for these private mixed weddings.
You're singing for a bunch of
men and women
dancing and jumping up and down.
It's not like "legal" weddings
with a bunch of grumpy old men
stuffing their faces with food.
Have you done this type
of wedding before?
That's how I started.
But then it got complicated
so I stopped doing them.
- What happened?
- Nothing. It's stupid.
Listen, it'll help if you stand up.
OK, now imagine the room is filled
with people dancing and screaming.
Lights going on and off.
Lots of energy.
Ready?
One, two, three, four.
The city is full of light and stars
Lovers' dreams are all coming true
What a beautiful night
He's a bit provincial,
but he's so sweet.
The second time he saw me,
he performed Niloufar on stage
in front of everyone.
Can you imagine?
Keep going. There's some more.
I'm helping him get into the
private weddings business too.
Poor guy is a beginner.
I felt sorry for him.
I met someone too.
Who? Where?
Why didn't you say anything?
We met in this class I go to.
What class? Is he nice?
What does he do?
He's nice. He's in I.T. and stuff.
Nice! Finally someone you approve of.
You've got to tell me all about it.
But guess who called today?
- Who?
- My lawyer!
My visa is here!
Nice.
So you're leaving for real...
Yeah. By the end
of the month, I think.
I'll miss you so much.
Wish you could come with me.
But we'll hang out a lot
before I leave.
You just wait here in the car.
I'll be back in a second.
Two more...
- One...
- One more...
Two.
I've got some DVDs
from the European championships.
We can watch them together
at my place tonight.
I can explain some of
the techniques to you.
Sure. Thanks.
It'll be good for you.
I'm off to bed.
Good night, Mr Fazli.
- Thanks.
- Sorry again.
I have to be somewhere, otherwise
we'd stay together until dinner.
We'll speak later tonight.
OK.
See you.
Hello? Hi, Reza. How are you, baby?
It's Sara.
You don't remember me?
I'm not going to remind you then.
But if you want, we can meet up
and I can refresh your memory.
How rude!
Just say you're not interested.
Hello?
Hello? Hi, Arshia.
You OK?
Where are you? You're not coming?
Oh.
Yeah, let's meet when you can.
By the way, I was comparing your last
measurements with when you started.
You've come a long way!
OK. I'll see you soon.
Bride, kiss the groom, yalla!
We want a kiss, yalla! Yalla!
Mashallah! Give it up for the bride!
Now it's the groom's turn!
Thank you all for coming, We
have a special guest among us tonight.
Now for the groom.
Groom, kiss the bride, yalla!
Give her an artistic kiss, yalla!
You really want to give up?
I swear I wouldn't if I could.
But it's out of my hands.
It'd be such a pity.
You know how much I wanted this.
But I can't focus
until I sort things out.
We can do late nights too.
If that helps.
I can arrange it with the gym manager.
That's nice of you.
But there's no way.
It's not the time that's the issue.
I just have to go on these work trips.
A few weeks in Europe, then China.
I don't want to waste your time.
Can I get you anything else?
Thank you so much, Haj Agha.
You were so kind.
Vahid was too ashamed so
I took the liberty to call you myself.
He is really lucky to have you.
God willing
they've learnt their lesson.
And I hope to see more of you
at the mosque.
Certainly, sir.
Be at the mosque at 5 p.m. sharp.
We need to talk.
I haven't mentioned anything
to your dad yet.
Yes, sir.
And you go find yourself a decent job!
Hello? Hi, Niloufar.
Yes, a friend managed to get us out.
No worries. It wasn't your fault.
Thank you. I just...
I was wondering...
If it's possible for us to meet?
I need to talk to you.
Open it!
Thanks!
So thoughtful of you!
For your neck.
I thought it'd be useful.
- Mina, dear.
- Yes?
I...
I'm a married man, with a son.
I mean, we are not together any more.
The legal process of the divorce
is taking too long.
But I wanted you to know,
before we go any further.
A deluxe double ice cream, please.
- Sure. And you?
- I'm OK. Thanks.
How old is he?
Abtin? He's five.
I was never a wedding singer.
Really? What were you then?
I performed at funerals. At a mosque.
You're serious?
Yes. Sorry, I should've
told you sooner.
It just never came up.
What were you doing
at the wedding then?
I was depressed
and was looking for a change.
I could hear the sorrow in your voice.
You tried to be happy for once
and look what happened.
- I'm so sorry.
- No, it's OK.
I mean now...
The reality is...
My real happiness is in seeing you.
You're sweet.
I'm leaving Iran in two weeks.
- Where to?
- Australia.
Vahid!
These are a couple of photos from the
wedding. Keep them as souvenir.
- Can I give you a ride?
- Thanks. I'm OK.
- OK. Take care of yourself.
- You too.
Bon voyage.
It's such a shame your schedule
didn't work with Arshia's.
I didn't know you were so busy!
He was lucky to find another
trainer so quickly.
I hope he makes it to the competition.
He really wants to be champion.
- How many more?
- Four more.
PROFESSIONAL BODYBUILDING COACH
HESSAM FAZLI
THREE-TIME CHAMPION
I want to change jobs, Haj Agha.
What do you mean? You don't want
to work here any more?
Yes.
What do you want to do then?
I'm not sure yet.
And your father...
- What are you going to tell him?
- I don't know.
Very well then...
You're asking me to tell
my dear friend of 30 years
that the son he's entrusted to me
all these years
has decided to become
a jester and an entertainer,
- and I let him get away with it?
- Yes.
Ms Shams?