1
00:00:00,500 --> 00:00:07,500
 本字幕由YYeTs人人影视修正制作
最新最快的HR-HDTV 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com


2
00:00:00,500 --> 00:00:07,500
■

3
00:00:08,000 --> 00:00:14,000
双字幕:  兔子   后期:  blueliongb

4
00:00:08,000 --> 00:00:14,000
■

5
00:01:02,800 --> 00:01:05,560
我们干掉了美索不达米亚人
We have killed Mesopotamians!

6
00:01:08,030 --> 00:01:10,190
我们干掉了亚述人
We have killed Assyrians,

7
00:01:10,260 --> 00:01:14,000
迈锡尼人  闪族人
Mycenaeans, Sumerians,

8
00:01:14,400 --> 00:01:15,590
但是...
but...

9
00:01:17,400 --> 00:01:20,760
我们一直没机会
we have never had the pleasure...

10
00:01:21,440 --> 00:01:23,140
干掉
of killing...

11
00:01:24,500 --> 00:01:25,840
阿卡得人
an Akkadian.

12
00:01:32,390 --> 00:01:34,750
先砍手还先砍脚
Which limb do I take first?

13
00:01:37,390 --> 00:01:39,640
希望神会怜悯你
May the gods have pity on you...

14
00:01:41,400 --> 00:01:45,000
因为我兄弟可不会
because my brother will not.

15
00:03:20,530 --> 00:03:21,960
我没事
You missed.

16
00:03:38,300 --> 00:03:40,170
能当我哥算你好运
You're lucky we have the same mother.

17
00:03:42,100 --> 00:03:47,700
蝎子王

18
00:03:49,590 --> 00:03:51,960
在金字塔时代之前
Before the time of the pyramids,

19
00:03:52,030 --> 00:03:54,620
东方崛起一支强悍的游牧部落
a fearsome horde came from the East...

20
00:03:54,700 --> 00:03:58,030
横扫古老世界的蛮荒大地
and swept across the barren lands of the ancient world.

21
00:04:09,150 --> 00:04:11,210
按照部落习俗
By the law of the horde,

22
00:04:11,280 --> 00:04:14,270
他们推举强者为王
their greatest warrior was proclaimed their king.

23
00:04:18,050 --> 00:04:20,780
他名叫曼能
His name was Memnon.

24
00:04:22,660 --> 00:04:25,680
曼能刀法如神  武功盖世
He was the greatest swordsman the world had ever seen.

25
00:04:45,910 --> 00:04:48,610
身边有一位巫师
With the predictions of a sorcerer...

26
00:04:48,680 --> 00:04:51,480
能预言每场战役的胜负
who could foretell the outcome of every battle,

27
00:04:51,550 --> 00:04:55,580
曼能大肆铲除异己
Memnon slaughtered all who resisted him,

28
00:04:59,260 --> 00:05:03,030
幸存的对手寥寥可数
until only a brave few remained.

29
00:05:16,410 --> 00:05:19,810
肃静  父王叫你们肃静
Silence! My father has called for silence!

30
00:05:20,180 --> 00:05:22,470
不要讲话
Hold your tongues!

31
00:05:29,190 --> 00:05:31,280
大家聚集在此
We are gathered in this place...

32
00:05:31,600 --> 00:05:34,380
就应该摒弃成见
to put our differences aside.

33
00:05:34,460 --> 00:05:36,800
趁着为时未晚
There is still time for us,

34
00:05:37,260 --> 00:05:39,600
残存的部落
the last of the free tribes,

35
00:05:39,670 --> 00:05:43,630
应该团结抵抗暴君
to stand together against this tyrant.

36
00:05:43,700 --> 00:05:48,800
他有巫师协助  谁也不是他的对手
With his sorcerer at his side, no mortal can defeat Memnon.

37
00:05:48,880 --> 00:05:54,280
巫师要是死掉  怎么办
And if the sorcerer were to die, what then?

38
00:05:54,350 --> 00:05:57,280
现在计划太迟了点
It's too late for your schemes, pheron.

39
00:05:58,250 --> 00:06:00,950
我袭击过曼能的车队
I have raided Memnon's caravans,

40
00:06:01,020 --> 00:06:03,350
截断他的补给线
broken the supply lines to his troops,

41
00:06:03,420 --> 00:06:06,790
但是他依旧势如破竹
but he still swept across the land like a plague.

42
00:06:06,860 --> 00:06:11,300
我不会派我的部下去白白送死
I will not send my people to their deaths in a battle that can't be won.

43
00:06:11,370 --> 00:06:14,700
你还有什么部下  巴煞
And what people would that be, Balthazar?

44
00:06:14,770 --> 00:06:17,290
你已经一无所有
You are the ruler of nothing...

45
00:06:17,370 --> 00:06:21,140
有的只是一堆石头和黄沙
but a pile of rocks and sand.

46
00:06:22,410 --> 00:06:27,140
我若不是帝王
If I'm no king,

47
00:06:27,210 --> 00:06:29,410
你又为何向我下跪
why are you on your knees before me?

48
00:06:29,480 --> 00:06:31,450
巴煞  卫士
Balthazar! Guards!

49
00:06:42,460 --> 00:06:44,530
阿卡得人
Akkadians.

50
00:06:44,900 --> 00:06:46,920
还以为他们早就绝种了
I thought they were wiped out long ago.

51
00:06:47,000 --> 00:06:49,100
他们是最后的阿卡得人
They are the last of their kind.

52
00:06:49,300 --> 00:06:53,260
他们会送巫师上黄泉
By their hand, the sorcerer will die.

53
00:06:53,340 --> 00:06:57,170
你相信这种为钱杀人的部族
You put your faith in a clan of cutthroats who kill for money?

54
00:06:57,240 --> 00:07:00,440
别小看他们  他们是世代相传
They are more than that. They are skilled assassins...

55
00:07:00,510 --> 00:07:03,640
训练有素的刺客
trained for generations in the deadly arts.

56
00:07:03,720 --> 00:07:08,520
他们开出什么条件  父王
And what price do these mercenaries ask from us, Father?

57
00:07:08,800 --> 00:07:11,390
二十颗鸡血红宝
Twenty blood rubies.

58
00:07:11,460 --> 00:07:14,690
-那是我们最后的财宝  -住口
- That's the last of our treasury. - Be quiet.

59
00:07:16,860 --> 00:07:19,890
要是他们铲除巫师
If these men kill the sorcerer,

60
00:07:19,970 --> 00:07:21,650
你们作不作战
will you fight?

61
00:07:34,650 --> 00:07:36,000
一言为定
So be it.

62
00:07:38,320 --> 00:07:40,380
只要我们还有一口气在
As long as one of us still breathes,

63
00:07:41,950 --> 00:07:43,890
巫师必死无疑
the sorcerer will die.

64
00:07:49,060 --> 00:07:50,060
刺客
Assassin!

65
00:07:55,250 --> 00:07:56,260
他...
Him...

66
00:07:56,670 --> 00:07:58,570
我们免费奉送
we'll kill for free.

67
00:08:05,080 --> 00:08:07,410
日落前会到曼能的大本营
We can reach Memnon's encampment by nightfall.

68
00:08:09,520 --> 00:08:11,680
你什么时候要把它换掉
When are you gonna get rid of that filthy beast?

69
00:08:11,750 --> 00:08:14,350
别理他  他不是有意的
He doesn't mean anything by it.

70
00:08:14,420 --> 00:08:17,690
-马比较快  -可是骆驼比较聪明
- Horses are faster. - But camels are smarter.

71
00:09:05,300 --> 00:09:06,470
那个交给我
That one's mine.

72
00:09:07,700 --> 00:09:08,850
活得自由
Live free.

73
00:09:10,810 --> 00:09:11,930
死得光荣
Die well.

74
00:09:15,020 --> 00:09:18,600
住手  听我说  我是祭司
Stop. Stop. Listen to me. I am a high priest of Set.

75
00:09:18,800 --> 00:09:22,890
放了我  我用五种语言赐福你们
Spare me, and I shall bless thee in five different languages.

76
00:09:23,750 --> 00:09:26,360
你会用五种语言尖叫
You'll scream in five different languages.

77
00:09:26,430 --> 00:09:28,220
马贼  等一下
Horse thief. Wait! Wait!

78
00:09:51,390 --> 00:09:54,110
喂  我没那么重
Hey! I'm not that heavy.

79
00:10:22,520 --> 00:10:24,850
小心那个胖子  他在你后面
Look out for the first one! He's behind you!

80
00:10:32,030 --> 00:10:35,760
不管你是谁  放我下来
Help me! Help me! Whoever you are, help me!

81
00:10:35,830 --> 00:10:38,920
谢谢你  好心的人  安静
Oh, thank you. Thank you, good sir. Quiet.

82
00:10:39,000 --> 00:10:41,260
我安全回去  你重重有赏
Surely you've heard of the enormous reward for my safe return.

83
00:10:58,800 --> 00:11:00,540
巫师的帐蓬
The sorcerer's tent.

84
00:11:12,050 --> 00:11:13,100
撤退
Back!

85
00:11:28,820 --> 00:11:31,940
-让开  -别让他跑了
- Make way! - Find the other one!

86
00:12:21,640 --> 00:12:23,690
你被出卖了  马沙亚斯
You've been betrayed, Mathayus.

87
00:12:25,310 --> 00:12:29,300
-你知道我的名字  -还有你来的目的
- You know my name? - And why you're here.

88
00:12:37,400 --> 00:12:38,870
他在帐蓬里
He's in the tent!

89
00:12:39,620 --> 00:12:41,350
你  到后面去
You! Move around back!

90
00:13:29,700 --> 00:13:31,400
生擒到阿卡得人
A living, breathing Akkadian.

91
00:13:32,100 --> 00:13:34,100
实属难得
This is a rare pleasure.

92
00:13:38,200 --> 00:13:41,340
听说你们的忍功一流
I hear you train yourselves to bear great pain.

93
00:13:41,410 --> 00:13:44,710
你要是不死  别忘了教我
You must teach me this, if you live long enough.

94
00:13:57,000 --> 00:14:00,960
你的威风现在跑哪去了
Not looking so full of yourself, are you now, assassin?

95
00:14:01,200 --> 00:14:04,490
你...  背叛自己的父亲
You... betrayed your own father?

96
00:14:04,570 --> 00:14:08,130
对  他当时非常震惊
Yes. He was very shocked.

97
00:14:08,340 --> 00:14:11,490
从他的表情可以看出来
You could tell by the look on his face.

98
00:14:13,380 --> 00:14:14,960
我以父亲的首级
By my father's head,

99
00:14:16,850 --> 00:14:18,610
向大王效忠
I pledge my allegiance.

100
00:14:19,350 --> 00:14:21,490
我相信你的忠心
You have proven your loyalty, Takmet.

101
00:14:21,490 --> 00:14:23,110
这个还没死
This one still lives.

102
00:14:38,370 --> 00:14:39,620
漂亮
Beautiful.

103
00:14:42,840 --> 00:14:44,350
带他过来
Bring him to me.

104
00:14:56,300 --> 00:14:57,640
活得自由
Live free.

105
00:15:01,290 --> 00:15:03,480
死得光荣  兄弟
Die well, my brother.

106
00:15:11,910 --> 00:15:12,710
现在...
So,

107
00:15:14,640 --> 00:15:16,000
要怎么处置他
how shall this one die?

108
00:15:16,410 --> 00:15:18,200
他今晚命不该绝
He shall not die tonight.

109
00:15:18,600 --> 00:15:19,530
是吗
Really?

110
00:15:21,500 --> 00:15:22,410
走着瞧 
We shall see.

111
00:15:22,410 --> 00:15:24,520
他不会死在你手上
Nor shall he die by your hand...

112
00:15:24,720 --> 00:15:27,140
也不会死在你部下手上
or any hand you command.

113
00:15:33,200 --> 00:15:35,190
你预见这样的景象
You have seen this in a vision?

114
00:15:35,400 --> 00:15:39,490
一意孤行只会招来横祸
To ignore this would bring great misfortune.

115
00:15:39,570 --> 00:15:42,470
神今晚眷顾他
The gods show him favor on this night.

116
00:15:42,540 --> 00:15:44,040
只有神
Just the gods?

117
00:15:50,380 --> 00:15:51,650
伤脑筋了
A puzzle then.

118
00:15:53,050 --> 00:15:58,050
要送你归西  又不能亲自动手
How to kill you without using my hand or any hand I command?

119
00:16:20,240 --> 00:16:22,070
厉害吧
Fascinating, isn't it?

120
00:16:22,140 --> 00:16:26,410
用烟把火蚁熏出巢穴
The smoke, it causes the fire ants to abandon their homes, you see?

121
00:16:34,020 --> 00:16:37,050
来享用我们的项上人头
All the sooner to feast on our naked heads.

122
00:16:38,890 --> 00:16:39,560
你觉得好笑?
You think this is funny?

123
00:16:39,630 --> 00:16:42,890
有一点  因为我逃得掉  而你呢
It's a little bit funny. Yes. You see, I am about to escape,

124
00:16:42,960 --> 00:16:47,330
只能等死  谁叫你昨晚丢下我
while you are about to die a horrible death for leaving me to die last night.

125
00:16:47,400 --> 00:16:48,570
那你还不逃
So what are you waiting for?

126
00:16:49,220 --> 00:16:50,600
看到那个守卫没
You see that one up there?

127
00:16:50,900 --> 00:16:54,900
他猛灌犁牛尿  要不了多久...
He's been drinking that Yak piss for about an hour now, and sometime very soon...

128
00:16:54,970 --> 00:16:57,030
看到没
Ahh. You see?

129
00:17:10,600 --> 00:17:11,800
马贼呢
Hey! Where's the horse thief?

130
00:17:41,590 --> 00:17:44,240
快点  快救我出去
All right. Come on. Get me outta here.

131
00:17:46,660 --> 00:17:49,570
你...  答应不杀我?
Do you, uh, promise not to kill me?

132
00:17:50,600 --> 00:17:51,930
好  我答应
Yes, I promise.

133
00:17:51,930 --> 00:17:54,280
记住  你是阿卡得人
Remember, you are an Akkadian.

134
00:17:54,550 --> 00:17:56,900
阿卡得人说话一向算话
You make an oath, you always have to keep it, right?

135
00:17:57,310 --> 00:17:58,250
没错
That's right.

136
00:17:58,800 --> 00:18:02,470
答应带我走  有好处分我一份
Promise to take me with you and share in the spoils of your adventures.

137
00:18:04,310 --> 00:18:07,660
什么  可以  我答应
What? All right. Fine. Yes, I promise.

138
00:18:28,640 --> 00:18:30,660
搞定  不要动
All right. Now hold still.

139
00:18:30,740 --> 00:18:34,150
这边有一只  好大一只
Oh, here's one. Ah. That's a big one!

140
00:18:34,870 --> 00:18:36,470
哇  这只是蚁后
My! Here comes the mother.

141
00:18:37,880 --> 00:18:39,970
我们要去哪
So, where are we going?

142
00:18:40,310 --> 00:18:43,480
去曼能的土地  替我哥报仇
To Memnon's kingdom to avenge my brother's death.

143
00:18:47,900 --> 00:18:50,900
-不准碰我的弓  -没问题
- Never touch the bow. - Not a problem.

144
00:18:52,400 --> 00:18:53,450
你在叫谁
Who are you calling?

145
00:18:53,600 --> 00:18:54,780
我的坐骑
My ride.

146
00:19:02,240 --> 00:19:03,610
不错的骆驼
It's a nice camel.

147
00:19:07,570 --> 00:19:10,240
后面很挤  麻烦你挪一挪
Not much room back here. Scoot up, please.

148
00:19:10,310 --> 00:19:13,770
嘿  我们说好的
Aah. Hey! We had a deal!

149
00:19:13,850 --> 00:19:16,750
没错  我没杀你...  还没
That's right. And I haven't killed you... yet.

150
00:19:25,560 --> 00:19:27,760
我的女巫今天看到什么
What news from my sorceress today?

151
00:19:56,820 --> 00:19:57,940
看到什么
What news?

152
00:19:59,060 --> 00:20:01,390
你的大军将会西征
Your armies will conquer in the West.

153
00:20:01,990 --> 00:20:05,370
大败依希丝女王的军队
Queen Isis's forces will scatter to the four winds.

154
00:20:09,300 --> 00:20:11,100
把消息传给各将领
Give the generals the news.

155
00:20:11,300 --> 00:20:13,570
准备打最后一仗
Have them make their armies ready for the final campaign.

156
00:20:13,640 --> 00:20:14,580
是的  大王
Yes, my Lord.

157
00:20:29,560 --> 00:20:31,320
你认为我不择手段
You think I'm cruel, don't you?

158
00:20:31,690 --> 00:20:34,660
也许你忘了外面的情形
Perhaps you've forgotten what it's like outside these walls.

159
00:20:34,900 --> 00:20:38,790
残忍  无知  野蛮
Heartless, ignorant and savage.

160
00:20:41,600 --> 00:20:43,300
但我能拨乱反正
But I can change that.

161
00:20:43,900 --> 00:20:46,790
我会平息数百年的动乱
I will bring order after centuries of chaos.

162
00:20:47,640 --> 00:20:49,730
为天下带来长治久安
An order which will last for a thousand years.

163
00:20:54,050 --> 00:20:56,740
血流成河换不来和平
Rivers of blood can never bring peace.

164
00:20:56,740 --> 00:20:58,550
却可以换来服从 
But they can bring obedience.

165
00:20:59,550 --> 00:21:01,950
那样就够了
That will suffice for now.

166
00:21:04,290 --> 00:21:07,050
一旦我完成霸业
And when I have become the king of legend,

167
00:21:08,390 --> 00:21:10,740
你将与我比肩而立
then you shall take your place beside me...

168
00:21:11,880 --> 00:21:15,100
共享王位  同床共枕
on a throne... and in my bed.

169
00:21:16,400 --> 00:21:18,900
但是  大王...
But, my lord,

170
00:21:18,970 --> 00:21:22,700
与你同床  我会失去预知能力
in your bed I would lose my gift of sight...

171
00:21:24,310 --> 00:21:27,560
你也会失去作战的优势
and you would lose your advantage in battle.

172
00:21:27,850 --> 00:21:29,690
那个时候
The day I speak of...

173
00:21:30,850 --> 00:21:32,840
我已经不需要你的预知
is the day I no longer need your vision.

174
00:21:41,160 --> 00:21:42,440
娥摩拉城
Gomorrah.

175
00:21:43,520 --> 00:21:44,690
听我说
Let me tell you,

176
00:21:45,030 --> 00:21:46,340
打家劫舍  辛苦了一天
after a hard day of looting and pillaging,

177
00:21:46,340 --> 00:21:48,660
最棒的就是去娥摩拉城玩
there is no greater city than Gomorrah.

178
00:21:48,740 --> 00:21:50,630
虽然所多玛城也不错
Except maybe Sodom.

179
00:21:54,030 --> 00:21:55,500
可惜我不能去
I wish I could join you.

180
00:21:55,980 --> 00:21:56,970
你不去?
You're not going?

181
00:21:58,480 --> 00:21:59,260
相信我
Believe me,

182
00:21:59,780 --> 00:22:03,050
我是很想找那些红卫队算帐
I'd like to even the score with a few of those Red Guards myself.

183
00:22:03,550 --> 00:22:05,300
可是我被通缉
But with the price I've got on my head,

184
00:22:05,300 --> 00:22:07,820
不可能进得去
I'd never make it through those gates.

185
00:22:09,320 --> 00:22:12,620
我有信心  我们一定进得去
I have faith in you, my friend. You'll get us in.

186
00:22:31,610 --> 00:22:32,020
看吧
You see?

187
00:22:32,020 --> 00:22:35,570
守卫森严到连苍蝇都飞不进去
They've got the city sealed up tighter than a crab's buttocks.

188
00:22:35,650 --> 00:22:38,500
我希望能帮得上忙  但我...
I wish there was something I could do to help, but I-I...

189
00:22:38,880 --> 00:22:40,100
你帮得上忙
Oh, but there is.

190
00:22:46,560 --> 00:22:47,920
你有什么事
What business do you have here?

191
00:22:48,900 --> 00:22:50,320
我来领赏的
I've come to collect a bounty.

192
00:22:52,330 --> 00:22:54,800
-马贼  -我认识他
- Horse thief. Oh. - I know this dog.

193
00:22:55,030 --> 00:22:57,130
这次一定让他脑袋搬家
They'll behead him for sure this time.

194
00:22:57,860 --> 00:22:59,690
他没头会比较好看
He'll be all the prettier without it.

195
00:23:06,310 --> 00:23:07,200
怎么回事
What happened?

196
00:23:07,200 --> 00:23:09,580
我就说靠你进得来
You got us in. I knew you could do it.

197
00:23:09,650 --> 00:23:12,620
给我朋友来杯最好的酒
A jug of your finest wine for my road-weary friend here.

198
00:23:13,650 --> 00:23:15,970
等一下  我好像记得
Wait a minute. The last thing that...

199
00:23:16,320 --> 00:23:18,590
你一记老拳
that I remember was this huge...

200
00:23:18,660 --> 00:23:21,420
-挥过来  -酒来了
- Akkadian fist coming straight into... - Here's your wine, sir.

201
00:23:21,950 --> 00:23:25,260
有什么需要尽管吩咐
Please, let me know if there's anything else you'd like.

202
00:23:26,900 --> 00:23:29,020
还是大城市好
Ah. It's good to be back in the big city.

203
00:23:30,000 --> 00:23:32,650
-帮我看着骆驼  -没问题
- Watch my camel for me? - Gladly.

204
00:23:33,300 --> 00:23:35,180
你在这里做了多久
Been working here long time?

205
00:23:36,770 --> 00:23:38,120
肉串好不好吃
How's the kabob?

206
00:23:49,060 --> 00:23:51,150
品质保证
Merchandise of the highest quality.

207
00:23:51,220 --> 00:23:53,490
由庞贝城僧侣铸造的纯钢
Virgin steel forged by the monks of pompeii.

208
00:23:53,560 --> 00:23:56,430
看啊  全世界最锋利的剑
Here! Here they are! The world's finest swords.

209
00:23:56,500 --> 00:23:59,090
在娥摩拉城就要佩戴好剑
Huh? You can't get respect in Gomorrah without a quality blade...

210
00:23:59,170 --> 00:24:01,330
观赏鸟  肉食鸟
Birds of paradise, birds of prey.

211
00:24:01,400 --> 00:24:03,670
世界上最漂亮的珍禽
The most beautiful birds in the world.

212
00:24:04,170 --> 00:24:07,230
阿兵哥  看你肌肉紧绷
Hey, soldier. Those big muscles look cramped.

213
00:24:07,510 --> 00:24:09,190
我来帮你松弛一下
Perhaps one of us can help you relax.

214
00:24:09,400 --> 00:24:11,030
或者我们一起伺候你
Maybe all of us.

215
00:24:39,910 --> 00:24:42,270
先生  我帮你带路
Mister, mister. Guide, mister.

216
00:24:42,340 --> 00:24:44,560
你需要向导带路
You need a guide to find your way in Gomorrah.

217
00:24:47,600 --> 00:24:50,550
好的向导会带我进曼能的宫殿
A good guide might be able to show me a way into Memnon's palace.

218
00:24:50,550 --> 00:24:52,550
聪明的向导就不会
But a smart guide wouldn't,

219
00:24:52,620 --> 00:24:55,850
不然你只会进曼能的地牢
or he'd be shown into Memnon's dungeon.

220
00:25:11,200 --> 00:25:12,320
不在我身上
I don't have it.

221
00:26:14,930 --> 00:26:15,980
想不想赚这颗
Do you wanna earn this one?

222
00:26:28,680 --> 00:26:31,480
准备动手  我一半  你一半
Get ready. I'll kill half, you kill half.

223
00:26:34,390 --> 00:26:37,020
好吧  都交给我
All right. I'll kill 'em all.

224
00:26:37,320 --> 00:26:40,190
干脆绕路走就不要杀人了
How about we go around them and not kill anybody?

225
00:26:45,870 --> 00:26:48,550
天啊  你是不是要杀我
Good Lord. Are you going to kill me?

226
00:26:48,750 --> 00:26:49,860
等一下再说
Maybe later.

227
00:26:50,400 --> 00:26:53,030
曼能动不动就要砍我的头
Memnon's always threatening to have my head.

228
00:26:53,560 --> 00:26:54,720
不要碰
Don't touch that.

229
00:26:55,200 --> 00:26:56,100
这是什么
What is it?

230
00:26:56,800 --> 00:26:59,300
那是我精心泡制的魔术粉
That's my special magic powder.

231
00:26:59,380 --> 00:27:00,910
魔术粉?
Magic powder?

232
00:27:01,910 --> 00:27:03,170
对  魔术粉
Yeah, magic powder.

233
00:27:03,380 --> 00:27:07,840
我花一大笔钱买来的中国配方
It's a Chinese formula that I procured at great expense.

234
00:27:07,920 --> 00:27:12,250
研制成功的话
If I get the recipe right, it'll move mountains,

235
00:27:12,330 --> 00:27:14,920
不但可以开山辟路
clear roadways in an instant...

236
00:27:15,190 --> 00:27:18,160
还可以造福人群
do great things, wonderful things.

237
00:27:20,270 --> 00:27:21,620
也可以为害人间
Or terrible things.

238
00:27:25,500 --> 00:27:28,440
我的发明都被曼能拿来作战
Like all my inventions, Memnon will try to use it for war.

239
00:27:28,510 --> 00:27:29,500
曼能在哪
Where is Memnon?

240
00:27:30,700 --> 00:27:32,100
你想杀他  是吗
Oh, you mean to kill him, do you?

241
00:27:34,880 --> 00:27:37,880
-对  -既然如此
- Yes. - Well, in that case,

242
00:27:38,120 --> 00:27:40,250
他在练武场
I'd say he was in the training courtyard.

243
00:28:54,060 --> 00:28:55,730
放手  放开我
No! Let me go!

244
00:28:58,500 --> 00:29:00,040
我又没做什么
I didn't do anything!

245
00:29:04,600 --> 00:29:06,990
你知道偷窃的下场
You know the penalty for thievery.

246
00:29:08,540 --> 00:29:09,490
不
No!

247
00:29:22,070 --> 00:29:23,060
不要
Oh, no.

248
00:29:36,370 --> 00:29:37,340
不要
No!

249
00:29:42,400 --> 00:29:43,310
有刺客
Intruder!

250
00:30:03,760 --> 00:30:04,770
跟我来
Follow me!

251
00:30:08,100 --> 00:30:10,500
-又是你  -我怎么出去
- You again. - How do I get outta here?

252
00:30:12,000 --> 00:30:13,070
穿过那扇门
Through that door.

253
00:30:14,500 --> 00:30:17,700
-那是什么  -我最新的发明
- What's that? - That's one of my latest inventions.

254
00:30:17,700 --> 00:30:19,900
快速运输机
It was meant to be a quick means of transportation,

255
00:30:19,900 --> 00:30:22,510
不过着陆有点问题
but there was a little problem with the landings.

256
00:30:23,290 --> 00:30:24,220
开门
Open!

257
00:30:26,270 --> 00:30:28,680
-开门  -别碰  会启动机器
- Open! - Don't touch that. You'll set it off.

258
00:30:29,050 --> 00:30:29,800
好
Right.

259
00:30:45,550 --> 00:30:46,860
我的天
Oh.  Oh, my!

260
00:30:49,340 --> 00:30:50,550
男人
A man.

261
00:30:51,440 --> 00:30:54,280
-这是什么地方  -曼能的后宫
- What is this place? - Lord Memnon's harem.

262
00:30:54,350 --> 00:30:58,230
不过他很少来  我们好寂寞
But he visits so rarely. And it gets so lonely.

263
00:31:02,760 --> 00:31:04,410
别烦我  行不行
Can't you leave me alone, Thorak?

264
00:31:04,410 --> 00:31:06,130
说话小心点
Watch your tongue, philos.

265
00:31:06,650 --> 00:31:09,610
小心  这些是精密的仪器
Careful with those! They're delicate instruments.

266
00:31:10,000 --> 00:31:13,100
曼能大人欣赏你  算你好运
You're lucky Lord Memnon has a taste for your "science,"

267
00:31:13,400 --> 00:31:14,900
老家伙
you old fool.

268
00:31:17,900 --> 00:31:21,330
要是我发现你和刺客有关系
If I find out you had anything to do with this intruder,

269
00:31:21,510 --> 00:31:23,140
我就要你的命
I will send the executioner.

270
00:31:26,050 --> 00:31:28,250
我们会让你满意
We know how to please.

271
00:31:28,750 --> 00:31:30,840
-我相信  但是...  -不要走
- Oh, I'm sure you do, ladies, but I... - Stay with us.

272
00:31:30,920 --> 00:31:34,110
-留下来嘛  -谢谢  我赶时间
- Stay with us. - That's nice, but now's not a good time.

273
00:31:34,190 --> 00:31:37,180
我们会让你美梦成真
We will make your every fantasy come true.

274
00:32:08,300 --> 00:32:09,270
放箭
Kill him!

275
00:32:29,400 --> 00:32:30,550
快追
After him!

276
00:32:47,090 --> 00:32:48,000
快追
Go get him!

277
00:33:20,920 --> 00:33:23,060
你是要杀我  还是就这样盯着我
Well, are you gonna try to kill me or just stare at me?

278
00:33:33,450 --> 00:33:34,560
吸气
Take a breath.

279
00:33:59,400 --> 00:34:00,950
赞美神
Gods be praised!

280
00:34:04,740 --> 00:34:07,500
你好大胆  敢碰我
How dare you touch me!

281
00:34:12,510 --> 00:34:15,890
我是阿卡得人  奉命来杀你
Sorceress, I am an Akkadian hired to kill you.

282
00:34:16,250 --> 00:34:19,590
不过现在  你活着对我更有用
Now, I find myself in a position where you are of more use to me alive.

283
00:34:19,800 --> 00:34:21,650
别让我改变主意
Don't make me change my mind.

284
00:34:25,090 --> 00:34:27,900
他说  大小不重要
And he said, it's not the size of the hump,

285
00:34:28,190 --> 00:34:30,130
重要的是能耐
it is the motion of the camel.

286
00:34:39,200 --> 00:34:42,270
可惜  我现在要走了
Alas, I must leave you now.

287
00:34:48,380 --> 00:34:51,280
-叛徒就在那  -我的天
- There's the traitor! - Oh, great gods!

288
00:35:03,900 --> 00:35:05,300
他死了
He is dead!

289
00:35:05,760 --> 00:35:08,440
认命吧  臭骆驼
Just admit it, you smelly camel!

290
00:35:10,000 --> 00:35:12,900
我才是你的主人  你要听我的
I am your master now! You belong to me!

291
00:35:13,110 --> 00:35:15,210
他死了  死了
He's dead! Dead!

292
00:35:15,570 --> 00:35:16,400
死了
Dead!

293
00:35:18,410 --> 00:35:21,340
你还活着  我就知道
You are alive. I knew it!

294
00:35:21,610 --> 00:35:22,380
对
Right.

295
00:35:23,520 --> 00:35:25,970
我才刚跟骆驼说
I was just saying to the camel,

296
00:35:25,970 --> 00:35:29,250
没人能杀死我们的马沙亚斯
"Camel, no one could kill our good friend Mathayus."

297
00:35:29,810 --> 00:35:30,770
上去
Get on.

298
00:35:30,960 --> 00:35:34,390
我干嘛要听你的  你不是要杀我
Why should I make it easy for you? You're sworn to kill me.

299
00:35:34,460 --> 00:35:35,990
其他人会比你先死
Others will die first.

300
00:35:38,730 --> 00:35:40,080
你真会安慰人
That's comforting.

301
00:35:42,030 --> 00:35:45,300
你朋友是谁  曼能的巫师
So who is your friend? Memnon's sorcerer.

302
00:35:45,900 --> 00:35:47,280
曼能的巫师
Memnon's sorcerer?

303
00:35:47,440 --> 00:35:51,000
你疯了  我们会被她害死
Are you insane? She's going to get us all killed!

304
00:35:51,300 --> 00:35:54,240
我要用她引曼能出来
Memnon will have to leave the safety of his palace to get her.

305
00:35:54,460 --> 00:35:57,250
所以你先利用我  再杀我
So you're going to use me first and then kill me?

306
00:35:57,320 --> 00:35:58,810
我觉得好过多了
I feel so much better.

307
00:35:59,520 --> 00:36:02,180
我也可以倒过来  先杀你
I could always do it the other way around and kill you first.

308
00:36:02,770 --> 00:36:03,960
我们要去哪
So where are we going?

309
00:36:05,620 --> 00:36:06,610
死亡谷
The Valley of the Dead.

310
00:36:06,780 --> 00:36:08,550
死亡谷?
The Valley of the Dead?

311
00:36:08,930 --> 00:36:10,760
哪有人去死亡谷的
Nobody goes to the Valley of the Dead!

312
00:36:11,460 --> 00:36:13,990
你以为那个名字是假的?
That's why they call it the Valley of the Dead!

313
00:36:14,940 --> 00:36:16,320
等我一下
Wait for me, please!

314
00:36:25,840 --> 00:36:29,210
你带十二名高手去追
Take a dozen of your best men, track him down,

315
00:36:29,400 --> 00:36:30,440
杀了他
kill him...

316
00:36:32,350 --> 00:36:34,000
把她带回来
and bring her back to me.

317
00:36:35,700 --> 00:36:37,400
得手立刻通知我
Send me news when he's dead.

318
00:36:39,020 --> 00:36:41,130
-是的  大王  -大王
- Yes, my lord. - My lord.

319
00:36:42,820 --> 00:36:46,590
军中传出巫师出走的谣言
There are rumors spreading to the armies that she's gone.

320
00:36:48,870 --> 00:36:50,800
-是吗  -是的  大王
- Is this true? - It is, my lord.

321
00:36:50,800 --> 00:36:52,710
那就想办法压制这种谣传
Then silence them!

322
00:36:52,710 --> 00:36:54,940
让士兵以为她还在这
They must believe she is here,

323
00:36:55,010 --> 00:36:56,480
必须尽快
if only for a short time.

324
00:37:03,450 --> 00:37:05,090
找到那个阿卡得人
And when you find the Akkadian,

325
00:37:13,260 --> 00:37:14,830
送这枝箭给他
give him this from me.

326
00:37:20,370 --> 00:37:22,200
我们是不是到了
Are we where I think we are?

327
00:37:24,000 --> 00:37:24,800
是
Yes.

328
00:37:27,600 --> 00:37:28,610
到家了
Home.

329
00:38:11,700 --> 00:38:13,690
你想去哪  巫师
Where are you going, Sorceress?

330
00:38:24,360 --> 00:38:26,300
急着回曼能身边
In a hurry to get back to Memnon?

331
00:38:26,370 --> 00:38:27,860
不  急着离开你
No, I'm in a hurry to get away from you.

332
00:38:28,000 --> 00:38:29,560
我也不会回到曼能那里
I'll never go back to Memnon.

333
00:38:29,690 --> 00:38:32,300
他从小就软禁我
He's kept me prisoner since I was a child.

334
00:38:37,340 --> 00:38:39,960
那晚在帐蓬  你为什么帮我
Why did you help me that night in the tent?

335
00:38:42,780 --> 00:38:45,840
我知道你可以帮我逃走
I knew you were the one man who could help me escape.

336
00:38:56,530 --> 00:38:59,850
要走就走  外面比这儿还危险
Run if you like. There are worse dangers out there than me.

337
00:39:20,020 --> 00:39:21,740
什么叫你找不到
What do you mean you can't find it?

338
00:39:22,700 --> 00:39:24,080
我知道就在附近
I know it's around here somewhere.

339
00:39:24,080 --> 00:39:25,600
你在找什么
What are you looking for?

340
00:39:25,800 --> 00:39:27,460
躲避沙暴的地方
Just a little place to get out of the storm.

341
00:39:29,050 --> 00:39:30,520
什么沙暴
What storm?

342
00:39:30,900 --> 00:39:32,150
你会看到的
You'll see.

343
00:39:44,110 --> 00:39:45,670
曼能是不是没来
Memnon didn't come, did he?

344
00:39:46,150 --> 00:39:47,800
他派了走狗来
Sent his maggots to do his work.

345
00:39:48,380 --> 00:39:50,410
他比你想的要聪明
He's smarter than you think.

346
00:39:51,200 --> 00:39:52,740
应该是懦弱
Or more cowardly.

347
00:39:53,030 --> 00:39:55,150
我可不可以回家
Can I go home now?

348
00:39:59,300 --> 00:40:00,190
待在这里
Stay here.

349
00:40:01,400 --> 00:40:02,500
盖住
Cover up.

350
00:40:03,010 --> 00:40:04,250
你们不会有事的
You'll be safe.

351
00:40:24,600 --> 00:40:25,980
快看
Look, sir.

352
00:40:29,970 --> 00:40:32,130
他单枪匹马来挑战
He's attacking! Alone?

353
00:40:32,280 --> 00:40:34,250
太阳晒得他神智不清了
The sun has fried his brain.

354
00:40:34,510 --> 00:40:37,240
取他首级者  赏金一千
A thousand duranas for the one that brings me his head.

355
00:41:23,490 --> 00:41:25,100
阿卡得混蛋
Akkadian bastard!

356
00:41:27,890 --> 00:41:29,180
他在哪
Where is he?

357
00:41:41,450 --> 00:41:42,550
这边
This way!

358
00:41:47,310 --> 00:41:49,970
你们两个先进去
You two first. Come on. Go.

359
00:42:31,960 --> 00:42:33,610
踩在石头上
Stay on the stones.

360
00:43:30,050 --> 00:43:31,310
跟我来
Come with me.

361
00:44:04,620 --> 00:44:05,630
不要碰
Don't touch that.

362
00:44:37,650 --> 00:44:38,670
懦夫
Coward!

363
00:44:40,490 --> 00:44:42,030
有种就出来
Show your face!

364
00:45:28,430 --> 00:45:29,600
阿卡得人
The Akkadian.

365
00:46:17,850 --> 00:46:18,910
你还活着
Ahh! You are alive!

366
00:46:18,980 --> 00:46:22,080
好像拍苍蝇一样  你太厉害了
You swatted them like flies! You are invincible!

367
00:46:50,000 --> 00:46:52,680
告诉我  有没有办法救他
Tell me. Do you think you can save him?

368
00:46:54,300 --> 00:46:58,340
他中了蝎子毒  在发高烧
His fever's high. The poison was made with scorpion venom.

369
00:46:58,340 --> 00:47:01,100
就算不死...  蝎子血
If he does live, the blood of the scorpion...

370
00:47:01,100 --> 00:47:03,110
也会永远留在他体内
will always flow through his veins.

371
00:47:43,740 --> 00:47:44,950
巫师
Sorceress.

372
00:47:57,410 --> 00:47:58,820
真是奇迹
It-It's a miracle.

373
00:48:00,400 --> 00:48:01,580
她救了你
She cured you.

374
00:48:01,690 --> 00:48:03,950
我就知道她有办法
I knew it! I felt her magic!

375
00:48:05,560 --> 00:48:09,150
她差点没命  还好有神的保佑
It almost killed her, but the gods, they were on our side.

376
00:48:14,900 --> 00:48:15,740
为什么
Why?

377
00:48:16,600 --> 00:48:19,030
为什么冒生命危险救我
Why would you risk your life to save mine?

378
00:48:20,170 --> 00:48:22,640
因为我相信你会拯救百姓
Because I believe you can save the people.

379
00:48:22,710 --> 00:48:26,510
他们不是我的问题  曼能才是
The people are not my problem. Memnon is.

380
00:48:27,540 --> 00:48:30,570
你和百姓有相同的问题
You and the people have the same problem.

381
00:48:58,110 --> 00:49:01,100
启禀大王  索瑞克有消息
Pardon, my lord. A message from Thorak.

382
00:49:03,980 --> 00:49:06,040
阿卡得人终于死了
Finally the Akkadian is dead.

383
00:49:13,160 --> 00:49:14,700
有事吗  大王
Is there something wrong, my lord?

384
00:49:16,430 --> 00:49:17,360
没事
Not at all.

385
00:49:18,900 --> 00:49:20,230
一切顺利
Everything is in order.

386
00:49:21,200 --> 00:49:23,290
事实上  因为非常顺利
In fact, things are going so well...

387
00:49:24,240 --> 00:49:26,400
所以我要把计划提前
that I'm moving up our plans.

388
00:49:27,300 --> 00:49:31,430
明晚我们设宴庆祝出师大捷
Tomorrow night, we feast to celebrate our impending victory.

389
00:49:31,510 --> 00:49:34,970
然后挥军扫平残余的叛逆
And then we'll drive the last of the rebels into the sea.

390
00:49:35,450 --> 00:49:36,850
下去吧
Now, go.

391
00:49:38,920 --> 00:49:40,050
大王
My lord,

392
00:49:41,190 --> 00:49:44,770
按照惯例  巫师应该出席会议
it is customary for the Sorceress to be present at these meetings.

393
00:49:45,290 --> 00:49:47,220
为什么她今天不在
Why is she not here today?

394
00:49:47,290 --> 00:49:48,810
她不舒服
She's indisposed.

395
00:49:49,100 --> 00:49:51,420
我希望不严重
It is nothing serious, I hope.

396
00:49:51,700 --> 00:49:55,260
严重的话  你自然会知道
If it were serious, then you would know about it.

397
00:49:56,970 --> 00:49:58,240
退下
Now, go!

398
00:50:04,110 --> 00:50:08,900
她还活着  跟他一起  在来的路上
She is alive. She is with him and he's coming here.

399
00:50:09,200 --> 00:50:10,190
去准备
Get ready.

400
00:50:23,500 --> 00:50:26,020
成功了  成功了
It works! It works!

401
00:50:28,100 --> 00:50:32,630
大人  能在荒郊野地看到你真好
My lady. How lovely to see you out here in this desolate place!

402
00:50:32,700 --> 00:50:34,970
你快来看  我成功了
Let me show you. It works!

403
00:50:35,040 --> 00:50:36,850
快点  快点
Come, come, come!

404
00:50:38,480 --> 00:50:39,630
巫师大人
My lady sorceress.

405
00:50:42,800 --> 00:50:45,770
你看  我成功了
You see? I worked it out.

406
00:50:46,680 --> 00:50:50,620
我的中国配方  我的魔术粉
My Chinese formula. My magic powder works!

407
00:50:50,690 --> 00:50:53,440
原来我需要的是硝石
All I needed was salt. Petered salt.

408
00:50:53,660 --> 00:50:57,390
硝石就在这里  这里多得是
It was here all the time. This place is just full of it.

409
00:50:57,460 --> 00:51:00,560
对了  你们谁有带水
By the way, do any of you happen to have any water?

410
00:51:09,170 --> 00:51:10,880
你觉得这水可以喝吗
What do you think? Is it safe to drink?

411
00:51:14,200 --> 00:51:15,500
本来可以
Not anymore.

412
00:51:15,500 --> 00:51:19,410
太好喝了  沙岩有天然的过滤效果
Delicious. The sandstone must act as a natural filter.

413
00:51:19,410 --> 00:51:20,330
安静
Quiet.

414
00:51:27,230 --> 00:51:29,820
我还活着  我还活着
I'm alive! I'm alive!

415
00:51:33,600 --> 00:51:34,830
目前是
For the moment.

416
00:52:01,290 --> 00:52:02,030
走
Move!

417
00:52:15,840 --> 00:52:19,510
刺客  神待我不薄啊
Assassin. The gods are good to me.

418
00:52:19,900 --> 00:52:22,470
上次见面  你想杀我
When we last met, you offered to kill me.

419
00:52:22,800 --> 00:52:25,120
现在轮到我报答你
Now I have a chance to return the favor.

420
00:52:25,880 --> 00:52:27,090
你们擅闯禁地 
You're trespassers here.

421
00:52:27,390 --> 00:52:31,050
我们能生存全靠这里够隐秘
Our survival depends on this place being kept a secret.

422
00:52:31,210 --> 00:52:35,350
只要你们活着  问题就来了
So we have a problem... as long as you're alive.

423
00:52:35,430 --> 00:52:37,720
没问题  我绝对守口如瓶
No problem. I can keep a secret like no other.

424
00:52:37,800 --> 00:52:40,960
我连怎么来的都不记得
In fact, I cannot remember how we got here. We took a left turn...

425
00:52:41,030 --> 00:52:43,650
-太迟了  -巴煞
- It's too late for that. - Balthazar!

426
00:52:44,340 --> 00:52:48,100
我们收留所有曼能的敌人
This place is sanctuary for all of Memnon's enemies.

427
00:52:48,170 --> 00:52:50,300
-你应该知道  -他是个危险人物
- You know that. - This man is dangerous.

428
00:52:50,300 --> 00:52:51,960
你判断错误
Your judgment is clouded.

429
00:52:51,960 --> 00:52:55,170
我的判断让大家活到今天
My judgment keeps all of you alive.

430
00:52:55,250 --> 00:52:57,770
这个人不可靠  我可以证明
This man cannot be trusted, and I'll prove it.

431
00:52:57,850 --> 00:52:59,530
把那个女人带上来
Bring the woman to me.

432
00:53:04,190 --> 00:53:07,250
谁敢碰她  就别怪我不客气
The first man to touch her will have to come through me.

433
00:53:14,770 --> 00:53:17,360
正合我意
I had hoped for nothing less.

434
00:54:29,140 --> 00:54:30,380
不公平
That's not fair.

435
00:54:51,530 --> 00:54:52,530
打他
Get him.

436
00:54:57,900 --> 00:54:58,710
不
No!

437
00:55:15,920 --> 00:55:19,550
-你服不服 那你是执迷不悟  -不服
- Do you yield? Then you're a fool. - Never.

438
00:55:20,100 --> 00:55:23,190
-我们是同仇敌忾的兄弟  -兄弟
- We're brothers in the same cause. - Brothers?

439
00:55:23,260 --> 00:55:25,280
你会连累我们
You brought death to my people.

440
00:55:25,650 --> 00:55:27,260
曼能一定会追来
Memnon will follow you.

441
00:55:27,750 --> 00:55:29,870
把他的巫师抢回去
He will come for his sorceress.

442
00:55:30,400 --> 00:55:33,540
没错  我认得她
Yes, I know who she is.

443
00:55:33,600 --> 00:55:36,400
曼能不会罢手  除非她回去
And Memnon will stop at nothing till she's returned.

444
00:55:36,470 --> 00:55:38,910
曼能有了她  会更锐不可当
He'll come swifter and deadlier once he has her.

445
00:55:39,200 --> 00:55:41,230
会更肆无忌惮
Memnon will stop at nothing.

446
00:55:41,400 --> 00:55:45,100
你们躲得了一时  躲不了一世
Hide here as long as you can, but believe me when I say he'll find you.

447
00:55:45,300 --> 00:55:49,750
要是不阻止他  他就会血洗这块土地
And if he isn't stopped, he'll sweep across this land and kill all of you.

448
00:55:52,420 --> 00:55:54,760
有谁可以阻止他
And who's gonna stop him, Akkadian?

449
00:55:54,830 --> 00:55:59,260
你  你敢挑战他的百万大军
You? Will you stand alone before the fury of his armies?

450
00:56:03,400 --> 00:56:04,150
敢
Yes.

451
00:56:25,560 --> 00:56:27,600
-男的应该让女的  -你就没有
- A gentleman always lets a lady win. - You didn't.

452
00:56:27,700 --> 00:56:28,890
三盘两胜如何
Best two out of three?

453
00:56:31,200 --> 00:56:32,280
尝尝蜜枣
Dates?

454
00:56:33,560 --> 00:56:34,920
谢谢
Oh, thank you.

455
00:57:23,080 --> 00:57:24,420
卡珊卓
Cassandra!

456
00:57:58,400 --> 00:58:00,000
我预见一个景象
I've had a vision.

457
00:58:01,450 --> 00:58:05,780
曼能会追到这里  大开杀戒
Memnon will follow me here and destroy these people.

458
00:58:06,150 --> 00:58:07,220
你确定
You know this?

459
00:58:16,570 --> 00:58:17,970
我预见的景象
The things I see...

460
00:58:18,850 --> 00:58:22,100
就像池面的浮光掠影
are like shimmers in a pond.

461
00:58:22,170 --> 00:58:26,130
时隐时现  忽暗忽明
Some are certain, and some remain shadows.

462
00:58:27,140 --> 00:58:29,080
不过有件事我确定
But I do know this...

463
00:58:29,300 --> 00:58:33,310
曼能会率领大军  踏平此处
Memnon will release his armies and ride straight through this place.

464
00:58:33,680 --> 00:58:36,080
曼能会死在我手上
Memnon will die by my hand.

465
00:58:43,190 --> 00:58:45,790
阿卡得人  看来神今晚眷顾我
It seems the gods favor me tonight, Akkadian.

466
00:59:03,310 --> 00:59:07,870
如果你跟曼能决斗  会死在他手上
If you face Memnon, you'll die.

467
00:59:10,250 --> 00:59:12,250
那是你命中注定
That is your destiny.

468
00:59:17,360 --> 00:59:19,450
我的命运由我掌握
I make my own destiny.

469
01:00:10,080 --> 01:00:11,600
我需要你帮忙
I need your help.

470
01:00:39,740 --> 01:00:42,300
你不能丢下我们
You can't leave us here.

471
01:00:42,750 --> 01:00:45,910
冷静点  听听原因
Mathayus, don't be so stubborn. Listen to reason.

472
01:00:45,980 --> 01:00:48,880
你一个人去  等于是去送死
You can't go alone. You're going to get yourself killed.

473
01:00:53,920 --> 01:00:56,190
你要骑我的马上哪去
Where do you think you're going with my horse?

474
01:00:56,550 --> 01:00:59,320
娥摩拉城  我们怎么劝都没用
To Gomorrah. Nothing we can say will stop him.

475
01:01:00,220 --> 01:01:01,690
不带你的巫师去
Without your sorceress?

476
01:01:01,900 --> 01:01:04,390
她回去了  怕连累你们
She returned to save the lives of your people.

477
01:01:04,470 --> 01:01:06,600
我不会让她一个人面对曼能
I won't let her face Memnon's wrath alone.

478
01:01:06,670 --> 01:01:08,600
-让开  -阿卡得人
- Step aside. - Akkadian,

479
01:01:08,670 --> 01:01:10,870
你这是去送死
you're riding to your death.

480
01:01:11,370 --> 01:01:13,120
如果让你单枪匹马去
If I let you ride alone,

481
01:01:17,620 --> 01:01:20,160
我就沾不到光
what glory will there be left for me?

482
01:01:51,280 --> 01:01:53,030
今晚我们热烈庆祝
So tonight we celebrate.

483
01:01:54,450 --> 01:01:57,700
大家尽情享用
Eat and drink your fill...

484
01:01:58,520 --> 01:02:01,170
明天我们奋勇杀敌
for tomorrow we ride into battle.

485
01:02:07,060 --> 01:02:10,410
我差点捉到他  可惜被他跑掉
I would've captured him myself, but he ran like a coward.

486
01:02:10,770 --> 01:02:12,850
连弓都不要了
He left his bow behind.

487
01:02:16,070 --> 01:02:16,840
大王
My lord.

488
01:02:18,380 --> 01:02:21,000
有件事造成军心动摇
There is something that is troubling our soldiers.

489
01:02:22,380 --> 01:02:25,370
那就麻烦了  请说
How distressing. Pray tell.

490
01:02:27,020 --> 01:02:31,220
传言女巫师已经离开了你
It's been said the sorceress is no longer by your side.

491
01:02:33,160 --> 01:02:36,320
士兵不应该轻信
Soldiers will fall prey to...

492
01:02:36,390 --> 01:02:38,330
无聊的宫廷传言
idle palace gossip.

493
01:02:38,400 --> 01:02:41,630
我向你保证  她十分安全
You have my word, she's perfectly safe.

494
01:02:41,700 --> 01:02:45,160
问题是出征在即
If the men are to fight, to die,

495
01:02:45,240 --> 01:02:46,840
士兵不要口头保证
they may need more than that.

496
01:02:50,040 --> 01:02:51,530
你怀疑我的话?
Do you doubt my word?

497
01:02:51,850 --> 01:02:53,370
不敢  大王
It is not that, sire.

498
01:02:53,580 --> 01:02:57,010
不过她是振奋军心的象征
It's just she is a symbol from which the men derive courage.

499
01:02:57,080 --> 01:03:00,350
-总要眼见为真才好  -大王
- Symbols are most effective when seen. - My lord.

500
01:03:07,950 --> 01:03:09,840
我奉召而来
I am here at your request.

501
01:03:11,070 --> 01:03:12,650
近来身体不适
pardon my absence.

502
01:03:12,800 --> 01:03:15,090
还望大王恕罪
I was not well.

503
01:03:16,730 --> 01:03:20,490
我军即将大捷  令我精神一振
But our impending victory has lifted my spirit.

504
01:03:21,870 --> 01:03:24,140
这样可以稳定军心了吧
Is this sufficient to placate your men?

505
01:03:26,650 --> 01:03:28,760
把你预见的景象告诉他
Tell them what you see, Sorceress.

506
01:03:34,120 --> 01:03:35,990
我看到我军大捷
I see a great victory.

507
01:03:38,020 --> 01:03:41,900
你的敌人会自动现形
Your enemies will reveal themselves to you.

508
01:03:51,140 --> 01:03:51,980
停
Halt.

509
01:03:54,470 --> 01:03:58,200
里面是什么  里面是什么?
What is in the cart? "What is in the cart"?

510
01:03:59,010 --> 01:04:02,170
里面...  是个惊喜
Actually, it is a bit of a surprise.

511
01:04:04,150 --> 01:04:06,700
为今晚的宴会助兴
A gift for tonight's festivities.

512
01:04:07,000 --> 01:04:08,910
泰克麦王子吩咐的
Prince Takmet's request.

513
01:04:10,400 --> 01:04:11,750
非常好
Very nice.

514
01:04:17,490 --> 01:04:21,260
让我看看...  这位姑娘
Well, now. Let's see that pretty little face.

515
01:05:12,050 --> 01:05:13,540
去我的寝宫
Now go to my chambers.

516
01:05:14,490 --> 01:05:15,970
我有事跟你谈
We have things to discuss.

517
01:05:21,690 --> 01:05:23,950
请大王恕罪
My sincerest apologies, my lord.

518
01:05:28,530 --> 01:05:29,900
我明白
I understand.

519
01:05:32,540 --> 01:05:35,770
你胆小  懦弱
You are fearful, weak.

520
01:05:42,150 --> 01:05:43,810
宴会结束
The feast is over.

521
01:05:44,550 --> 01:05:47,680
养精蓄锐  准备明天出征
To bed, men, for tomorrow we conquer.

522
01:05:52,060 --> 01:05:53,950
加强宫殿警戒
Fortify the palace guard.

523
01:06:10,670 --> 01:06:12,610
入城比较容易
All right. That was the easy part.

524
01:06:13,150 --> 01:06:15,470
-接下来怎么做知道吧  -制服守卫
- Everybody know what to do? - Cripple the guards.

525
01:06:15,700 --> 01:06:19,150
-点燃火药  -想办法保住小命
- Ignite the powder. - And try not to get killed.

526
01:06:20,950 --> 01:06:23,160
你怎么来了  你会受伤
What are you doing here? You could get hurt.

527
01:06:23,300 --> 01:06:24,410
你也会
So could you.

528
01:06:24,490 --> 01:06:25,700
待在车里
Stay in the wagon.

529
01:06:27,490 --> 01:06:29,290
阿卡得人  自己小心
You watch yourself, Akkadian.

530
01:06:31,260 --> 01:06:32,710
用不着担心  女士
No need for concern, miss.

531
01:06:33,380 --> 01:06:35,100
我会找他算帐的  走
Oh, he's gonna pay for that.

532
01:06:43,310 --> 01:06:46,220
关闭宫门  关闭所有宫门
Seal the gates. Seal all the gates.

533
01:06:52,650 --> 01:06:55,680
看到你安然无恙  我就放心了
Though I'm relieved to see you unharmed,

534
01:06:57,590 --> 01:07:00,080
奇怪的是  他竟然放过你
I am somewhat surprised the Akkadian didn't kill you.

535
01:07:00,080 --> 01:07:02,760
他要对付的是你  不是我
He was after you. I was merely a pawn.

536
01:07:02,760 --> 01:07:04,320
你怎么逃出来的
But you escaped his grasp?

537
01:07:04,500 --> 01:07:06,490
略施小计
I'm not without my wiles.

538
01:07:08,070 --> 01:07:11,210
这个我知道  带进来
Yes, I'm well aware of that. Bring them.

539
01:07:17,940 --> 01:07:20,900
你预见  我明天就完成霸业
Tomorrow my victory is complete. That is your vision?

540
01:07:21,000 --> 01:07:23,670
我说过  我有看到
As I said, I have seen it.

541
01:07:24,000 --> 01:07:25,130
你有吗
Have you?

542
01:07:27,500 --> 01:07:29,380
我感觉你变了
I sense a change in you.

543
01:07:29,900 --> 01:07:31,340
你看起来...
You seem somehow...

544
01:07:33,240 --> 01:07:34,620
法力变弱
diminished.

545
01:07:35,050 --> 01:07:38,860
我向你保证  我没有改变
I assure you. I am myself.

546
01:07:38,900 --> 01:07:39,770
那好
Good.

547
01:07:40,900 --> 01:07:43,800
一个小小的示范应该难不倒你
A small demonstration shouldn't trouble you then.

548
01:07:59,450 --> 01:08:01,050
一个简单的测验
A simple test.

549
01:08:40,660 --> 01:08:43,760
退下  全部退下
Now go. Everyone leave.

550
01:08:58,110 --> 01:09:00,500
-我应该去哪  -停车
- Where am I going? - Stop.

551
01:09:01,000 --> 01:09:02,080
在那里
It's over there.

552
01:09:02,680 --> 01:09:04,210
应该在那里
Should be just there.

553
01:09:16,750 --> 01:09:17,870
好家伙
Good man.

554
01:09:52,530 --> 01:09:53,850
瞧瞧
Well, well.

555
01:09:56,000 --> 01:09:57,370
是谁来啦
What do we have here?

556
01:10:09,120 --> 01:10:10,400
一次一包
One at a time.

557
01:10:23,730 --> 01:10:26,200
六个瓮  四条眼镜蛇
Six urns, four cobras.

558
01:10:26,360 --> 01:10:27,180
现在...
Now.

559
01:10:28,270 --> 01:10:30,200
看你看不看得到
Let's see what you can see.

560
01:11:02,930 --> 01:11:04,140
很好
Excellent.

561
01:11:04,940 --> 01:11:06,770
现在只剩一个空的
One empty pot left now.

562
01:11:14,300 --> 01:11:16,010
谁想送死
Who dies first?

563
01:11:33,900 --> 01:11:35,350
我们快到了
We're almost there.

564
01:11:45,110 --> 01:11:47,940
知道我看到什么  恐惧
You know what I see? Fear.

565
01:11:50,080 --> 01:11:51,870
你已经失去法力
You have lost your power,

566
01:11:53,120 --> 01:11:54,760
完全失去
thrown it all away.

567
01:12:12,140 --> 01:12:14,470
-这是什么法术  -我的法术
- What magic is this? - My magic.

568
01:12:14,950 --> 01:12:17,840
我看到你的下场  暴君
I see your fate, hollow king.

569
01:12:18,910 --> 01:12:21,170
你的气数已尽
And its time has come.

570
01:12:24,900 --> 01:12:26,910
看是法术厉害  还是剑厉害
You wish to test magic against steel?

571
01:12:40,300 --> 01:12:43,280
我要这个女人  还有你的头
I've come for the woman and your head.

572
01:12:45,300 --> 01:12:47,320
刺客和女巫
The assassin and the sorceress,

573
01:12:48,400 --> 01:12:49,900
多浪漫啊
how romantic.

574
01:12:50,900 --> 01:12:52,920
我一刀成全你们两个
I'll bury you both together.

575
01:13:51,670 --> 01:13:55,570
就是这里  宫殿的基石
And here it is, the foundation stone.

576
01:14:22,000 --> 01:14:23,410
快点  没时间了
Hurry, we're running out of time.

577
01:14:23,500 --> 01:14:25,200
我已经很快了
I'm hurrying, I'm hurrying.

578
01:14:58,640 --> 01:15:01,600
前无去路  后有追兵
Fire in front, palace guard at your back.

579
01:15:01,890 --> 01:15:04,440
看来我的头  你是拿不走了
Looks like I'll be keeping my head after all, Akkadian.

580
01:15:17,690 --> 01:15:19,020
杀了女巫
Kill the witch!

581
01:17:01,110 --> 01:17:02,830
这是为你父亲
For your father.

582
01:18:02,350 --> 01:18:04,040
死得好  刺客
Die well, assassin.

583
01:18:37,720 --> 01:18:40,310
阿卡得人  看来神今晚眷顾我
It seems the gods favor me tonight, Akkadian.

584
01:19:17,630 --> 01:19:19,080
-快点燃  -你点
- Hurry up and light it. - You hurry up and light it.

585
01:19:19,080 --> 01:19:20,400
这是你的发明
This is your invention.

586
01:19:27,600 --> 01:19:28,420
跟我来
Follow me.

587
01:20:11,650 --> 01:20:13,500
准备进攻
Ready! Weapons!

588
01:20:58,960 --> 01:21:00,850
这次完蛋了
So much for not getting killed.

589
01:21:08,300 --> 01:21:09,540
接箭
Catch this.

590
01:22:19,510 --> 01:22:23,170
王上万岁 万岁 万岁
Hail to the king! Hail, hail!

591
01:22:23,250 --> 01:22:25,410
我就知道
I knew it from the start.

592
01:22:25,480 --> 01:22:28,640
万岁  好耶
Hail! Yeah! Mathayus!

593
01:23:01,850 --> 01:23:05,110
巴煞  留下来  这里百废待举
Stay here with us, Balthazar. There's much work to be done.

594
01:23:05,300 --> 01:23:07,380
我要照顾我的族人
I have to look after my own people.

595
01:23:07,990 --> 01:23:11,670
我相信  你会是个好帝王
You're a king now, Akkadian, and a good one, I think.

596
01:23:12,330 --> 01:23:16,420
不要忘了自己的出身  背景
Don't forget how you got here or the people you came from.

597
01:23:16,500 --> 01:23:19,150
我不会让我的族人蒙羞
My people will live on through me.

598
01:23:19,870 --> 01:23:23,130
记住  这里随时欢迎你
Remember, there'll always be a place for you here.

599
01:23:24,370 --> 01:23:28,670
-活得自由  -好好统治
- Live free. - Rule well.

600
01:23:33,850 --> 01:23:38,980
记住...  努比亚人会看着你  蝎子王
Remember, Nubian eyes will be watching you, Scorpion King.

601
01:23:43,160 --> 01:23:47,000
我看见太平盛世
I see a time of great peace and prosperity ahead.

602
01:23:47,700 --> 01:23:49,100
你怎么看得到
How is it you see this?

603
01:23:49,700 --> 01:23:52,820
传说你会失去法力  一旦...
Don't the legends say you'll lose your powers if you...

604
01:23:55,000 --> 01:23:56,600
你能想到更好的藉口
Can you think of a better way...

605
01:23:56,600 --> 01:23:58,900
来避免帝王占你便宜吗
to keep a king from taking advantage?

606
01:23:59,290 --> 01:24:01,560
我的祖先也想不到
Well, neither could my ancestors.

607
01:24:03,350 --> 01:24:05,310
这样的盛世又能维持多久
And how long will this time of peace last?

608
01:24:08,800 --> 01:24:11,040
王上  世事无常
Nothing lasts forever, my king.

609
01:24:12,560 --> 01:24:15,920
王朝也躲不过世代交替的命运
That is the destiny of all kingdoms.

610
01:24:15,990 --> 01:24:19,190
那我们就自己开创我们的命运
Then we'll make our own destiny.

611
01:25:00,100 --> 01:25:03,770
我曾经告诉过你
I've told you this once before

612
01:25:03,840 --> 01:25:05,770
你无法控制我
You can't control me

613
01:25:05,840 --> 01:25:11,210
如果你想打倒我  省省吧
If you try to take me down you're gonna break

614
01:25:11,280 --> 01:25:16,680
你所做的一切根本伤害不到我
And I feel your every nothing that you're doing for me

615
01:25:16,750 --> 01:25:19,720
当我还手的时候
I'm picking you out of me

616
01:25:19,790 --> 01:25:22,350
你却逃跑了
You run away

617
01:25:22,430 --> 01:25:27,860
我独自站着那
I stand alone inside

618
01:25:27,930 --> 01:25:31,230
独自站着
I stand alone

619
01:25:33,970 --> 01:25:39,470
你总是躲在你的上帝身后
You're always hiding behind your so-called goddess

620
01:25:39,540 --> 01:25:45,310
以为那样我们就看不见你
So what you don't think that we can see your face

621
01:25:45,380 --> 01:25:50,680
在被灭绝前还能复活
Resurrected back before the final fallen

622
01:25:50,750 --> 01:25:56,920
找到出路前我不会停歇
I'll never rest until I can make my own way

623
01:25:56,990 --> 01:26:01,520
我不惧怕灭亡
I'm not afraid of fading

624
01:26:01,600 --> 01:26:05,970
独自站立着
I stand alone

625
01:26:06,040 --> 01:26:10,170
感觉到你蜇疼了我
Feeling your sting down inside me

626
01:26:10,240 --> 01:26:13,040
可我不会因此身亡
I'm not dying for it

627
01:26:13,110 --> 01:26:17,240
独自站立着
I stand alone

628
01:26:17,310 --> 01:26:24,310
我相信一切终将灭亡
Everything that I believe is fading

629
01:26:24,390 --> 01:26:30,090
我独自站立着
I stand alone inside

630
01:26:30,160 --> 01:26:34,390
独自站立着
I stand alone

631
01:26:40,270 --> 01:26:43,470
现在轮到我了
And now it's my time

632
01:26:43,540 --> 01:26:46,060
我的时代
Now it's my time

633
01:26:46,140 --> 01:26:48,910
我梦想的时代
It's my time to dream

634
01:26:48,980 --> 01:26:52,180
我梦想的时代
It's my time to dream

635
01:26:52,250 --> 01:26:54,980
梦想的天空
Dream of the sky

636
01:26:55,050 --> 01:26:58,040
梦想的苍穹
Dream of the sky

637
01:26:58,120 --> 01:27:02,850
让我相信这个地方已经
Make me believe that this place is invaded

638
01:27:02,930 --> 01:27:07,560
被我体内的毒素侵入
By the poison in me

639
01:27:09,770 --> 01:27:15,470
帮助我决定是否用我的怒火烧光一切
Help me decide if my fire will burn out

640
01:27:15,540 --> 01:27:19,500
在你复活以前
Before you can breathe

641
01:27:21,480 --> 01:27:25,940
先复活我
Breathe into me

642
01:27:34,660 --> 01:27:40,100
我独自站立着
I stand alone inside

643
01:27:40,160 --> 01:27:44,390
独自站立着
I stand alone

644
01:27:44,470 --> 01:27:48,870
感觉到你蜇疼了我
Feeling your sting down inside me

645
01:27:48,940 --> 01:27:51,500
可我不会因此身亡
I'm not dying for it

646
01:27:51,570 --> 01:27:55,740
独自站立着
I stand alone

647
01:27:55,810 --> 01:28:02,910
我相信一切终将灭亡
Everything that I believe is fading

648
01:28:02,990 --> 01:28:08,750
我独自站立着
I stand alone inside

649
01:28:08,820 --> 01:28:14,420
我独自站立着
I stand alone inside

650
01:28:14,500 --> 01:28:20,130
我独自站立着
I stand alone inside

651
01:28:20,200 --> 01:28:25,830
我独自站立着
I stand alone inside

652
01:28:35,320 --> 01:28:38,250
我从心里感到晕眩和疲倦
I'm dizzy and weary from the heat

653
01:28:38,320 --> 01:28:42,050
如同沙粒抹去时间的痕迹
As the sands erase the hands of time

654
01:28:48,900 --> 01:28:52,300
与你同在简直是种背叛
Do a job with you involved This is a betrayal

655
01:28:52,370 --> 01:28:55,390
我穿过山谷将他刺死
I walk through the valley and stab him to death

656
01:28:58,810 --> 01:29:02,340
见到那张几乎无法忘记的面孔
I see a face I can't seem to forget

657
01:29:02,410 --> 01:29:05,510
战争就是你得到的
The war you wage

658
01:29:05,580 --> 01:29:08,910
无论发生什么你都得付出
Whatever that happens you pay

659
01:29:08,980 --> 01:29:11,420
身体里的仇恨
Something wrong in you

660
01:29:12,990 --> 01:29:16,050
使你生机勃勃
Comes alive in your hate

661
01:29:16,130 --> 01:29:19,120
让你迷失自己
Lose yourself in some kind of hell

662
01:29:19,200 --> 01:29:22,860
你被仇恨点燃
Left you burnin'up where you are now

663
01:29:26,140 --> 01:29:28,830
你将永远无法摆脱
You'll never ever get out

664
01:29:28,900 --> 01:29:30,840
无法摆脱
No

665
01:29:30,910 --> 01:29:34,210
生命中的某处
Somewhere along the way

666
01:29:34,280 --> 01:29:37,840
时间改变一切
Time changes everything

667
01:30:04,470 --> 01:30:06,570
这场竞赛没有赢家
This race cannot be won

668
01:30:06,640 --> 01:30:09,740
时间长河或蜿蜒徜徉  或奔流湍急
Some days it crawls while other days it flies

669
01:30:09,810 --> 01:30:13,410
终将弥补一切  永不妥协
It feeds on our flaws It knows no compromise

