- So, answer me!
- If it were true, I'd tell you.
A woman can always find
an excuse not to make love.
- But you're really a jerk.
- Vulgar language doesn't suit you.
It doesn't suit me?
Listen to this...
Asshole. Cunt.
Shit.
Christ almighty.
Craphole.
Son of a bitch.
Goddamn.
So, still think
it doesn't suit me?
Why don't you want
to make love anymore?
All right. Let's do it, but fast.
I'd been thinking
Camille could leave me.
It was a possible disaster.
Now the disaster had happened.
We used to live
in a cloud of unawareness,
in delighted complicity.
Things happened with sudden,
wild, enchanted recklessness.
I'd end up in Paul's arms,
hardly aware of what had happened.
This recklessness was now absent
in Camille, and thus in me.
Could I now watch her coldly,
prey to my excited senses,
as she could undoubtedly observe me?
I deliberately made that remark
with a secret feeling of revenge.
She seemed aware
that a lie could settle everything.
For a while, on the surface at least.
She was clearly tempted to lie.
But she thought better of it.
Paul hurt me so much.
It was my turn now,
alluding to what I'd seen,
without really being specific.
But I was wrong. She wasn't unfaithful,
or at least not obviously so.
The truth remained concealed.
We needed to dig deeper.
I've noticed that the more we doubt,
the more we cling to a false lucidity,
in the hope of rationalizing
what feelings made murky and obscure.
I thought Camille might leave me.
It was a possible disaster.
Now the disaster had happened.
We used to live in a cloud of
unawareness, in delicious complicity.
Don't be like that.
- Don't be like what?
- You know very well.
It's your fault!
You seem to be searching
my expression
to decide the appropriate attitude.
"The private plane awaited
in the blue sky.
Rex noticed something about Paula
that he knew already, her face...
Her harmonious face,
now indecisive, seemed contorted.
Rex knew this trait of hers,
for it seemed that whenever Paula...
Whenever Paula
had to make a decision...
that went against her nature..."
What's got into you?
I love you exactly as before.
What would you do
if I stopped loving you?
- I already told you.
- I forgot what you said.
I wouldn't do the script
and we'd sell the flat.
But I love you.
I find this all so idiotic.
When Prokosch calls,
tell him you'll go to Capri.
- What about you?
- I love you. Don't make me repeat it.
I want to keep the flat.
If you don't want to do the script,
don't do it.
If you think I've stopped loving you,
you're wrong.
Kiss me.
We were just talking about you.
About your movie.
Yes, The Odyssey.
About that guy who travels.
In Capri,
can we go swimming?
I don't know.
Here's Paul. I'll put him on.
Mr. Prokosch? Yes.
No.
We're eating out?
I don't feel like
going out for groceries.
Fine. We're to meet Prokosch
and Lang at a cinema.
They want to see a singer
in the stage show. We can eat after.
It'll be late if there's a movie first.
It might give me some ideas.
Why not look for ideas in your head,
instead of stealing them?
- What's got into you?
- Let's get going!
I knew it. Since I said yes
to Prokosch, it's no more tenderness!
Right, no more caresses.
What was the phone call about?
- Our going to Capri.
- What did you say?
- That it was up to you.
- Are you nuts?
You know that it's up to you, not me!
- Then come to Capri.
- No.
Is there something
between you and Prokosch?
You're pathetic.
- Sit down. I have to talk to you.
- What about the cinema?
Camille, I need to talk to you.
All right, I'm listening.
I need... to talk to you.
Earlier, before the phone rang,
I said I didn't want to take this job
if I couldn't be sure of your love.
You said you loved me
and that I should take it.
Yes.
I'm sure you lied.
Why? I don't know.
Out of pity, self-interest...
- What self-interest?
- You holding on to this flat.
How can you know what I think?
In fact, I couldn't care less.
You can sell the flat, I don't care.
You said it was better than a hotel.
Not at all.
I said that to make you happy.
That's beside the point.
I want to know why you lied earlier.
Who said I lied? Stop it!
You did. You've stopped loving me.
What good will
knowing the truth do you?
See? You admit I'm right.
I'm not admitting anything.
Leave me alone.
It's true. I don't love you anymore.
There's nothing to explain.
I don't love you.
Why? Yesterday you still loved me.
Yes, very much.
Now it's over.
- There must be a reason.
- Yes, there must be.
What is it?
I don't know. All I know is
I don't love you anymore.
Since we were at Prokosch's?
When you saw me pat
Francesca Vanini's bottom?
Let's say it was that.
It's over now. Let's drop the subject.
Something's happened
since this morning.
It changed your mind about me,
and therefore, your love for me.
- You're nuts, but you're clever.
- Then it's true.
I didn't say that.
I said you're clever.
Was it something I said or did today
that you took the wrong way?
Maybe.
Don't talk to me like that!
I won't allow it!
Camille!
I despise you! That's what I feel.
That's why the love's gone.
And you disgust me when you touch me.
Wait for me. Don't be so dramatic.
Forget what I said, Paul.
Pretend nothing happened.
Good evening.
- Are you going to Capri, too?
- Maybe.
Are you okay?
Mr. Prokosch re-read Homer.
He found something
he had long been searching for.
Something as indispensable
to the movies as to real life.
Poetry.
- You remember...
- Oh, yes.
They say Ulysses came home
to Penelope,
but maybe Ulysses had been
fed up with Penelope.
So he went off to the Trojan war, and
since he didn't feel like going home,
he kept travelling as long as he could.
Do you think it was
an idea of his or...?
- Why do you despise me?
- Leave me alone!
Coming to Capri with us, Mr. Lang?
"Each morning, to earn my bread
I go to the market where lies are sold
and, full of hope, I line up
alongside the other vendors."
- What's that?
- Hollywood.
From a ballad by poor B.B.
- Bertolt Brecht?
- Yes.
Homer's world is a real world.
And the poet belonged to a civilization
that grew in harmony,
not in opposition, with nature.
And the beauty of The Odyssey
lies precisely in this belief
in reality as it is.
Thus in reality
as it appears objectively.
Exactly. And in a form
that cannot be broken down.
And is what it is.
Take it or leave it.
I shut up because I have nothing to say.
I'm not sure about going to Capri.
Where would we stay?
In Mr. Prokosch's villa.
- With your husband.
- And Mr. Lang too?
That's up to him.
Producers are something
I can easily do without.
- Madam.
- Goodnight.
If you don't want to come,
I'm not forcing you.
It's not you that's forcing me.
It's life.
What are you doing?
- What are you doing?
- Looking.
Don't stay by yourself. Join us.
- What were you talking about?
- The Odyssey.
- I agree with Prokosch's theory.
- What theory's that?
That Ulysses loves his wife,
but she doesn't love him.
Do you really think that?
I'm sure you don't.
- Please, you're in the frame.
- Places, everyone!
Are they going to strip off?
Marvellous business this!
You show women in dresses a camera,
and hey presto! They strip off!
Come with us, madam,
leave them here to talk.
No, I'll walk back later
with my husband.
He says you spend all day
with your husband.
Do you mind if you wife comes with us?
Not at all. Go on, Camille.
Go on.
I don't mind, go on.
I'll walk back with Mr. Lang
to discuss The Odyssey.
The girls are in the water, Mr Lang.
I should have done a scene
at the beginning
in which the gods
discuss man's fate, in general,
and the fate of Ulysses in particular.
A producer
can be a friend to a director.
But Prokosch isn't a real producer.
He's a dictator.
I think it's stupid to change
the character of Ulysses.
He's not a modern-day neurotic,
but a simple, clever and robust man.
I find his idea interesting.
It takes Ulysses
ten years to return home
because he doesn't really
want to return. It's logical.
It's logical, and the illogical
borrows from the logical.
Your Corneille said it
in his preface to Suréna.
Ulysses doesn't rush home to Ithaca
because he was unhappy
with Penelope,
but the trouble started
before he went off to war.
He never would've left
if he'd been happy.
The Trojan war was his excuse
to get away from her.
But he killed her suitors, didn't he?
That can be justified
by the fact that, at first,
Ulysses had told Penelope
to accept their gifts.
He didn't see the suitors
as serious rivals,
and didn't want to cause a scandal
by throwing them out.
Knowing Penelope to be faithful,
he told her to be nice to the suitors.
I think that's when Penelope,
who is a simple woman at heart,
began to despise him.
She found she'd stopped loving
Ulysses because of his behaviour,
and she told him so.
Ulysses then realized too late
he'd lost Penelope's love
because he'd been overly cautious.
The only way to win her back
was to murder the suitors.
Death is no resolution.
Camille!
- What a lovely yellow.
- Thanks.
I found this on the boat.
Children shouldn't play with firearms.
Drink?
I was there, outside. Nothing.
I decided not to write
the script you asked me.
Why?
Can I be frank?
Of course.
I'm a playwright.
Not a screenwriter.
Even if it's a fine script...
I'm only doing it for the money!
That's why I'm in a bad mood.
We all have an ideal.
Mine's writing plays. I can't. Why?
In today's world,
we have to accept what others want.
Why does money matter so much
in what we do,
in what we are, in what we become?
Even in our relationships
with those we love.
He is right.
We either do Homer's Odyssey
or we do nothing!
Mr. Prokosch already said it,
you're wrong.
You aspire to a world like Homer's.
You want it to exist,
but unfortunately it doesn't.
Why doesn't it?
You may be right,
but when it comes to making movies,
dreams aren't enough.
When do we eat?
- In an hour.
- Right. I'm going for a walk.
Mr. Prokosch wants to speak with you.
- Is that an order or a request?
- A request.
One must suffer.
That's for sure.
Camille!
It's me, Paul.
Looking at you just now,
felt like the first time I'd seen you.
- Mind if I stay?
- Stay if you like.
Why didn't you speak up earlier?
I don't get you! You always said
you loved that script.
Now you tell the producer it's for the
money, that your ideal is the theatre.
He's no fool.
Next time, he won't be asking you.
How can you not understand
something so simple?
- I bet you'll do it anyway.
- No.
Yes, you'll see. I know you.
I know you.
If I do it, it's for you.
To pay for the flat.
I'll let you decide
whether I do the script or not.
If you say no, we'll leave.
- You're so cunning!
- Not at all. Why?
- If you regret it, you can blame me.
- Not at all! I'm asking you to decide.
You want me to tell you what to do?
- Yes.
- Then do the script!
You signed a contract,
and you're boring me.
- I saw him kiss you earlier.
- I know you did.
- Why don't you love me anymore?
- That's life.
Why do you despise me?
I'll never tell you,
not even if I were dying.
- Tell me or I'll hurt you.
- Why hurt me more?
I have to know why you despise me.
It's crazy! I don't see why
you expect me to accept, anyway.
We need the money for the flat.
I don't want to go back to typing.
I can't accept that after what happened.
Obviously you do despise me.
You knew we kissed and you were
still ready to change your mind.
I turned the job down for you.
So you'd change your mind about me.
Don't touch me.
I don't love you anymore.
There's no way
I'll ever love you again.
Even if I turn it down,
you'll despise me?
- Yes, I will.
- Why? There must be a reason.
- You're the reason.
- What do you mean, me?
I don't know. You're not a man.
Anyhow, it's too late.
I've changed my mind about you.
I know why you despise me.
The other day, when I took a taxi,
you thought I wanted you
to go in his car with him.
And again on the boat earlier.
Don't be stupid!
I have faults, but that's not one.
I'll never forgive you.
I loved you so much.
Now it's impossible. I hate you
because you can't make me feel.
I can! You're almost in tears.
We're leaving! We'll pack up and go.
I'm staying. You go if you like.
Come on, Camille!
- No.
- Then I'm staying, too.
- But Prokosch will throw us out.
- Don't start again.
Dear Paul, I found your revolver
and took the bullets out.
If you won't leave, I will.
Jeremy Prokosch has to return to Rome,
so I'll get a lift with him.
Then I'll probably move
into a hotel alone.
Take care. Farewell. Camille.
What are you going to do in Rome?
Typist.
Me? No.
What... do you think... of me?
Get into your Alfa, Romeo.
We'll see about that later.
TAKE CARE
FAREWELL
Nathalie,
I'm leaving for Rome tonight.
Good-bye, then.
Mr. Lang,
I've come to say good-bye.
Good-bye. What will you do?
Go back to Rome, finish my play.
- And you?
- I'll finish the film.
One should always finish
what one starts.
What shot are you doing?
Ulysses' gaze when he first sees
his homeland again.
Ithaca.
- Good-bye, Mr. Lang.
- Bye. I hope we'll meet again.
We're ready, Mr. Lang.
Quiet on the set!
Camera!
Silence!
Download Movie Subtitles Searcher from www.OpenSubtitles.org