C'mon!
C'mon! I got a baby-sitter.
I don't wanna go.
I don't wanna go
on my own.
Trace!
You got some clothes here,
haven't ya?
C'mon, show us!
Hey, Tran, don't you reckon Tracy
should come to the school reunion?
Yeah.
Is that right?
Tracy never goes out.
Listen.
We'll have a look here.
You're alright?
Yeah!
Good.
Good Evening.
Can I have you bags, please?
What have you got there?
This one.
G'day.
How was it?
It was okay.
Did she behave herself?
Yeah, not a problem.
How was that?
It was alright.
Can we go?
I'll drive.
Can you give
me a ride home?
No. You can walk, fatso.
Excuse me.
Come here.
I had a message from
Lionel Dawson on my phone.
How did he get my number?
Hey, girl,
It's a new world
let's have a little fun
Don't stay hitting away
They play this one.
You should come.
I wish you were there.
You're gonna stay
very long?
Kind of got sick of this.
I thought you were dead.
I got my sun messy.
Mom was there.
I had to drive her home.
Well, I gave her another call
but no, she didn't call back.
You should go see her.
Yeah.
Yeah, I've been thinking
about that.
What's up?
Nah!
Someone's, you know,
dropping something off for me.
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
I didn't know
you were coming.
Go on, right on the front room.
Sorry, darling.
Just a moment, Steven.
Brad!
What an honor.
Lionel.
I'll get you a drink.
Working hard?
I've sold quite
a few jerseys this week.
Take the pressure off.
Li!
Lionel!
Tracy!
It's all yours now, mate.
Yeah, partnership's dissolved.
I understand.
It's all up to you now.
So, that's it.
Yeah, you're retiring.
That's great!
As to this
particular arrangement.
That's it.
The enamel packages.
This is not for me.
Yeah. Interesting timing. Like I've
been making arrangements for detox.
Yeah, I'm fine.
I reckon this will be good for us.
Clear the air.
Won't be so dependant
at last.
You'll have more time
not working.
We can take up golf.
Snooker.
Fucking bridge.
You're alright, then.
Yeah, I couldn't be happier.
It just began.
Good luck, mate.
Steven.
Fuck!
Sorry. I... forgot
you were there.
Yeah, you did.
It's you, ey?
Shinny girl.
I've gotta go.
I have to stay.
It was spectacular.
Jesus Christ, Lionel!
Don't get on
when I'm here, alright?
You wait till I go!
I thought
you'd go in there and-
Do you want this?
No.
I'll see ya.
See ya, love.
Trace, are you up?
Tracy, this business plan
Is good,
It's very good, You've
obviously done a lot of research,
It's very impressive,
And this address
where you live,
Is this rented property?
That's my mom's house.
It's rented, yeah.
In the last four years
there's steady employment,
but there's no savings,
no capital.
You don't own a car?
No, I've had some debts
to pay off.
We do a credit check
on all loan applications
and it is quite colorful
your file, Tracy.
This isn't really really
safe estimate.
Did you, did you see these?
We get people coming in
to the shop all the time
asking if we've got internet,
'cause we're so close to the station.
The nearest place is-
It's-
Tracy, this is not a personal
decision. This is the bank's policy.
I cannot approve
an unsecured line
against someone
with your history.
Sorry.
Look, if you can come back
with some collateral
we might be able
to talk again.
But the way it's currently
structured I can't approve that loan.
Okay?
What?
No, no, I won't do it.
No, Ray,
I said no.
Hey, Trace,
The manager said
the plan was, uhm,
What did he say?
It's impressive.
Impressive?
So, we'll sign off
our new shop on Monday.
That gives you a week.
Will the bank be able to
transfer the money by then?
By Monday?
Yeah!
Oh! Did you tell
your mom?
Trace... did you call
you mom?
Yeah, on the mobile.
Net one plan.
Do they have any computers
can we actually fit in there?
Some shoes
for your brother.
Ray gets his shoes done by that guy
of the street. I'm seeing him tonight.
How is he going?
Come on, kids.
Ray is Ray.
Grab your bags.
Hey, thanks for opening up
this morning.
No problem.
That'd be 12.
Sorry?
Computers.
Next door.
Cool.
I'll see ya.
See ya.
Girls!
Wait up.
Hello.
Ray Heart speaking.
This is where I work.
You get down here and get
the shit out of my shop.
Do you hear me, Ray?
Yeah. I'll get back to you in about five
minutes, alright? I'll call you straight back.
Shit.
Okay?
Forty'd be good.
What do you say?
See you tonight?
Yeah, give us a kiss.
Is it alright if I bring
a friend over for dinner?
Friend?
Yeah, I do have him.
Good. It's okay.
See you tonight.
Hi, Trace.
Don't hang up on me, Ray.
You get down here
and get this fucking shit
out of my shop
or I'll throw it
in the bin.
Just get here.
I have to get a bus. I've only got
ten bucks to last me 'till Friday
and it's Tuesday. Can you hold on
to it 'till tonight for me, Trace?
It'd be a birthday present.
Last time, Ray.
Sorry.
Your password?
Oh, Jesus Christ.
I suppose a cup of tea
is out of the question.
How's Ray?
He's good.
It's his birthday today.
There's milk if you-
No, still have it black.
Tracy's doing well?
Yes, she is. Lionel,
what are you doing here?
Just came round to
say hello, that's all.
Say hello.
Haven't been to a show
in years.
You and the kids
and me.
Had some times, ey?
Mainly in club
and races.
Beach.
I miss you.
Lionel, you gave my daughter
heroin.
Yeah.
She's clean now.
She's good.
This is for you.
I don't want anything from
you. You can call a cab.
It's Ray's birthday. I'm
cooking his favorite dinner.
Tracy will be home soon.
And you were never here.
Tran, I don't mind you
singing on the ship,
but you got to get
the work done, too.
Remember we got
that special?
Two DVDs and you get a pack of that
crap popcorn. Give it away, Tran.
Want me to pick him up
later?
No, mate.
I'll put him in a taxi.
Unless you want to stay
and watch the cable.
I gotta get home.
G'day, mate.
Over there.
Ray Heart?
Yeah.
Thanks for coming out here.
I got you a beer.
No, thanks.
So... is there a problem?
I got some money together
with a friend of mine.
We're looking
for opportunities to-
How much money?
About 30 grand.
No bullshit.
Why would I do that, mate?
We're good for it.
Fair enough.
Give us a call tomorrow
and I'll see
what we can do.
Thanks.
Well, he said a friend.
Isn't that what a friend means?
Could be someone he talked to
at the bus stop.
Look, it's his birthday.
Trace, get the door, will ya?
Why is he at the front-
You know where the key is.
Use it!
Shit!
Ray's not here yet?
I'll let you in the front.
Is that Ray?
It's Jonny.
Isn't he in Vancouver?
Not anymore.
Shit.
Janelle?
Oh, well,
what have we got here?
Come in.
Trace.
Duty free.
Do you still smoke?
Ray told you
I was coming here?
When did you get back?
A couple
of days ago.
Thanks.
Here.
This is for you.
Not real ones.
Why are you wearing
a suit?
Why I am wearing a suit?
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Hey!
How are you going, Ray?
Shit.
So, you know,
in Vancouver
people are making money 24-7
and that's all they do.
They work and sleep.
I don't suppose
they sleep much.
That sounds like shit.
You've been there, Janelle?
No. Overseas I've been in
New Zealand, Fiji, and Bali.
How long are you back for?
For good.
Yeah.
I've got a job offer here, so-
What sort of a job?
A trader
with a stockbroker.
I worked with my uncle
in Canada in his company.
They do the Asian market.
It'd be pretty good money,
wouldn't it?
Yeah.
It's alright.
I'm also thinking about importing
those flowers I gave you.
Thanks.
How are you going?
Good.
She's doing great.
She's opening her own shop.
Mom, I'm going into partnership with
Ming in my work at the video shop.
We're expanding into internet
on-line gaming.
And the bank.
Yeah.
The bank approved
my loan today.
That's great!
That's amazing.
No, no, really!
That is amazing.
Don't just drop them
in a plate.
How many times
have I done this?
Happy birthday.
Thanks.
Don't drink it all.
Anything but alcohol.
A speech, Ray.
Get fucked.
I want a big bit.
I'd like to say a few words.
Just a few, mom?
Ray's 30.
My baby's 30.
Five years ago
on this night,
I stayed in a hospital
emergency room
not knowing
if you were gonna live.
I never wanna go through another
night like that in my life.
It was a bad night.
Bad night.
And three years
of rehab for Ray and me.
People from the past
knocking at the door.
I suppose you think
about it. The accident.
Every day, Janelle.
So, when do you start work?
Friday.
In the city.
So I suppose now you'll be moving
out to Stratfield, somewhere.
I don't know.
I'm just staying with
Kim and June for now.
You probably have noticed this but
people have been running from this place.
Almost everyone. All the
houses have changed hands.
Or kicking themselves. Prices
around here have gone up.
People just want the best
they can for their families.
Oh, right,
and I don't!
That's not what I meant.
Five years ago one's nearly
killed in a car crash.
Other one is about to become a fully
blind junkie or find himself in jail.
Or maybe bloody both!
So, what do I do?
Can I send them off
to a rich family overseas?
No.
Can I get Tracy into the
clinics to get her clean? No!
Mom, sit down.
It'll be alright.
No matter what you do,
always someone's there
to smooth it over.
Need it?
Get it, sign the check.
That would be alright.
Maybe you shouldn't have married
such a loser asshole then.
You gonna blame your dad
for the rest of your life?
Probably yeah.
Janelle, you would have done the
same things if you had the money.
But I don't.
I didn't, I never did.
You say you don't understand
these people.
They're doing what you
would do if you could.
Oh, I've had enough.
Happy fucking birthday, Ray.
Should I take it?
So you can be all in.
Yes, thank you.
That will be very nice.
I'm fine, thank you.
Okay, there you go.
Darling.
It's alright now.
Ray.
Thanks for the shoot.
Good night.
Ray.
I'm gonna bed.
Trace, are we gonna fit
12 computers In here?
Yeah, easily.
Yeah, good.
This is cool.
Fix the place up.
Make a bit of money.
And you can refinance
and buy me out.
What would you do?
Oh, I'll be up at businesses.
Other things I wanna do.
No, no, no.
C'mon, Trace!
Why not?
You've been doing it
for four years.
You're a bloody great
manager.
You know, it's bad luck for tears to
fall in the ground of a new business.
Bullshit.
Just think about it, ey?
Yeah, right.
Thanks.
The whales aren't believed
to be In any danger,
But National Parks will stand
In guard to ensure proper traffic
as well as whale watchers
give the mammals
plenty of room to move,
You know, you should have told your
mom I was coming last night, prick.
Stay In memory,
Yeah, absolutely.
Give us a look
at that fun, will you?
This is weird.
What?
I don't know.
I just feel-
Seeing you again
we'll be more together.
What about this?
Did you speak to that guy?
Moss?
I told him we had 30 grand,
mate, and his eyes went like this.
C'mon, let's get out of here. I want
you to take me somewhere, will you?
Ray, I can't drive like this.
What's wrong? You're worried
you might have a crash?
Sorry.
Thanks, mate.
No worries.
Change those prices
for me.
No worries.
You're alright?
Yeah. I've just got a bit of a cold.
I'll drop in, uh, later in
the way. I'll give you a ring.
Hello?
Tracy, it's me.
Jonny.
How did you get
my number?
Ray.
Ray gave it to me.
It's hard.
It's hard being back.
It's harder than I thought.
Tracy, you're there?
I gotta go.
See ya.
Yeah.
Yeah, sure.
You're okay?
Yeah.
Yeah, just wanna get home.
And Jonny wouldn't speak.
He had just lost his parents.
A feeling
I will never forget.
As time goes on-
But Jonny has been
in Vancouver for four years.
He has been working
very hard.
And he has a new job here
in Sydney.
A stockbroker.
Today is 20 years
since I married June.
June, thank you.
I don't know, Lionel.
You've got to do something.
Never had to pay for it.
A straight price?
I never had to find it.
No, I won't stand up in front of a
bunch of people and say that I was wrong,
that my life was wrong,
because it wasn't. It isn't.
I gotta strip for this
Salbutan and just wait.
Really?
Yeah, I'll be fine.
One week and I'm clean.
One week?
Yeah, right.
M'mmmm.
How good is that?
Yummy.
Aren't you having any?
No.
Jonny's back.
Eh?
How is he?
He's great.
He's clean.
He's a stockbroker.
Let him on the phone
in the morning.
Most stupid.
No.
No boyfriend causes such a
commotion. What does that say?
It's okay.
Yeah.
Is it?
Yeah, it is.
It's great.
The look on your face
after you spoke to him.
And now it's beyond that.
I'd kill for that feeling.
You got your stuff?
Trace... I haven't been
to the beach for years
and what is all.
Like I'm on public.
I'll take you
to the beach.
You're my darling.
Eat something.
Bye-bye.
See you, darling.
Do you like trading?
Yeah. Yeah, I do.
It's fun playing with other
people's money, you know.
I'm impressed.
A car.
Mr. Cool C.
The car's me uncle's.
Tracy.
How you're going?
I'm good.
What are you doing?
Now?
Yes.
Nothing.
Do you-
Do you wanna meet up?
Yeah, we could meet
on the corner, you know.
I don't have a car.
I can, I can pick you up.
At 7: 00?
I'll take you
to the city.
This is a really
cool restaurant.
Yeah, right.
Alright.
Okay.
Bye.
Hey.
Hi.
You wanna drive?
Okay.
I've got to know
if this is the real sea
How are you going?
Good.
You look great.
You really changed
since I left.
Tracy, You know I-
I didn't have a choice.
My uncle sent me away
and my bags were packed.
I had no time
to see anyone.
Four years.
Yeah.
Anyway, look at you.
You look great.
Yeah, 32.
Living home with my mom
and work in a video shop.
Do you think
if I'd stayed,
you'd be clean now?
Fuck knows
where we'd be.
Scarlet for me
and scarlet for you
What do you wanna eat?
I bet the food
is pretty good here.
Is that what you heard? Like
you read restaurant reviews.
Certain times I do, yeah.
Are you ready to order?
What'd you like?
Take your time.
I'll come back.
You're okay?
I don't wanna be here.
I'm wanna go.
Tracy.
No, I just
wanna go home, okay?
This is a bad idea.
Where are you going?
I'm going home.
Let me drive.
No, no, no.
Don't grab me!
Don't think
you can fucking... grab me.
Tracy, c'mon.
What am I doing here?
This is so easy for you!
Is it easy?
What do you reckon, huh?
I want to drive you home, okay?
Mr. Bush spoke
to Mr. Howard
about getting at least
the understanding
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What?
Is that loaded?
Nah, it's my farewell present when
I sold the bar in the Philippines.
Some bastard
tried to impress me.
I never used it.
It's beautifully
handcrafted.
Why don't you keep it?
I'm retiring.
Oh, no.
No, I want you
to have it.
I'm not a collector, mate.
Do you want a beer?
I poured you one.
No, I might keep going.
There's some white wine
in the fridge.
Jenny's getting a bit jacked
up at me showing up late.
So, if there's nothing else,
I'll see you tomorrow.
Yeah, alright.
At 10: 00?
Sure.
Hey,
what ever happened
to that Barky couple
who ran the speed factory
for us?
Merv and Eileen.
Where did they go?
Kangaroo Valley, I think.
They've got some goats
up there.
Goats.
I just wanna get things
finalized.
Lawyer's on the case.
You understand?
Yeah, yeah, sure.
Steven,
just sit down
for a minute, will you?
I know you wanna get back
to your family.
Come.
I know some things about me
that you found... difficult.
I wanna say this.
I know what sort of man
you are,
and your thoughts about such
matters won't make things-
I'm not one
to judge, mate.
I just wanna...thank you
for your trust and discretion.
Okay.
Well, I'll see you tomorrow.
Yeah, alright.
Right.
Okay.
Bradly's got no idea.
He hasn't been down to
the speed factory in years.
He just wants to fuck boys
and play golf.
What if he goes down there?
Well, then he does.
Merv and Eileen can deal
with it. Honestly, Stevy.
I hurt my nose!
Is there any blood?
Is she alright?
Just a little bit.
My bunny, my bunny.
Oh, that's alright
'cause we've got him now!
We silly duffers.
These toys are shit.
Bloody dangerous, too.
You know, Tiny and Jean
have got a new floor.
You can just lay
straight over the slab.
Yeah? Good.
Here we go. It's okay, it's
okay, honey. There you go.
Sh, sh, sh,
There.
There we go.
So, this is what
we're doing.
So, we can save for a whole
new floor and we can have it.
It's worth it.
Yeah.
Move along the outside,
Now Springsfur is pushing up,
And now Camel has dropped
to the tall,
Springsfur by four,
Second Is Camel,
Tracy, you're brother's here,
C'mon, please,
He's not here.
Having a good perv?
You're losing your touch.
Why didn't you wake me?
I missed my swim.
I did try to wake you, but
if my memory says me correctly
you told me
to fuck off, mum.
Sorry.
Mum, just drop her off here.
She can get the train.
I'm late.
Here's the station, Trace.
Where're you going, anyway?
I don't know.
It's a surprise.
Yeah, it's just somewhere
never you mind.
Go right here.
Mum, mum? Go.
Oh, don't.
Stop it, for goodness sake!
We're going to take forever
to get back on the freeway.
I'll take Tracy to work.
Laura picks her up, right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Mum?
Just wait, please.
Trace!
Did you go out
with Jonny last night?
Yeah.
Okay.
Hey, mom?
Give us a kiss.
Oh, no, no, no!
Naughty girl!
Like the lesbians?
You have a good day.
Could you not clap lesbian-
Doesn't it go in the Ts?
No.
I'll look for it Ivonne
as a customer.
Would you?
When do you find out
about the bank?
This afternoon.
You told Janelle you got
the loan approved already.
Yeah.
Did you tell her
anything different?
No!
The party's right here.
It's right here!
Are you alright?
Yeah.
Just I didn't sleep much
last night.
You're racing or you
just watching some TV?
I went out with Jonny.
Are you alright?
It's a change.
Didn't you and Janelle
have a chitty chat about that?
Tracy.
Lionel Dawson. Okay, I can
buy that. He's an old friend.
Do you think
this is okay?
He's straight.
Straighter than you.
Do you feel okay
about being around him?
I can handle it.
You don't know him!
No, I don't.
He's a stockbroker.
Went to this really nice
restaurant in the city.
What?
You look scared. I haven't
seen that look for a while.
There's this big fucking
empty space.
Tracy, it's okay.
I'm fucking fine.
Take it easy.
Brad, It's Lionel,
If you're there, mate, please pick
up, I really need to talk to you,
Brad, It's Lionel again,
Please, call me, mate,
Okay?
It's the third time today.
Your wife's outside.
She's got a key.
Look at these fucking boxes.
There are people waiting.
Can I stay today?
Please?
If you want to arrange this,
you talk to me.
'Cause I fucking live here,
not her.
I co-owned, Bradley.
C'mon, Steven.
You fucking prick.
Do you know
whose house Is this?
Bradley Thompson's,
What?
Don't you want to have
a look inside?
Ray!
It's open for inspection, mom!
Look, anyone can go in.
How did you find out
about it?
I just ready it in the paper. C'mon.
Hi, my name Is Tracy Heart, I had
an appointment with Donna Suvani,
It's just that I need to secure
the loan as soon as possible.
No.
Okay.
No, that's great.
Yeah, yeah. I'll be there. Thank you.
Excuse me.
I've gotta close the shop.
Do you want anything?
I'm gonna get change.
I'll be two minutes.
It's Trace.
Oh, honey, I forgot
how painful this is.
It's fucking horrible.
I'll be back
in a couple of hours, alright?
I call Brad so many times but he
hasn't called back. I don't understand.
Sorry, Lionel,
but I gotta go.
I'll be back
really soon, alright?
Okay.
Hi. I'm here to see
Donna Suvani.
M'h-hm.
Take a seat.
Yeah, it's alright.
It's about half an hour trip.
Hi, Jonny. Steven Moss.
Steven, this is Jonny Nguyen.
How are ya?
Good, good, good.
I'm sorry, excuse me.
Hi.
Where are you?
With some friends at
the club. Where are you?
I'm just sorting out some-
Finishing up the bank stuff.
It's kind of hard for me
to talk right now.
Sure, sorry.
No, that's fine.
It's great you called.
I missed you.
I just, I wanted to say
that last night-
Tracy, listen,
I'll call you.
Okay?
I have to finish here.
Excuse me.
You can go in now.
I've gotta go.
G'day, Tracy.
How are you?
Sit down.
Wait me a second.
Bloody computers.
He's cute.
You want kids?
Don't know.
I've got a friend who's having
a second baby.
Really?
He's nice.
A lot of work.
Have you got
a boyfriend?
Would it help the loan
if I did?
Maybe.
Okay.
Now, the business loan.
I'm really sorry, Tracy,
but there's no way
I can approve this loan
for you today.
I think you probably
know why.
Okay.
But what if I reduce
the amount a little bit?
Instead of making it
40 thousand I made it 25.
The business is great but it's a lease
premises. There's no real capital.
If the bank did have to come in,
there'll be nothing to recoup on it.
The capital'll be built
into the new shop.
The computers, the stock,
the customer base.
Tracy, is there someone you
can get to help you out with it?
Maybe get your dad
to go guarantor.
That's not gonna happen. I'm
not asking for a gift here.
I'll be paying it back.
Tracy, we did a credit check
on you.
I'm paying it off.
I've organized it.
Di-di-
I'm paying it off!
Look here. "Have you been refused
credits in the last ten years?"
You ticked the box No
when you should've ticked Yes.