You just tell me when you're rolling.
We're rolling.
A lot of people--
have questioned what really happened.
And when the novel was first published,
it didn't take long
for there to be even more questions asked.
It's always remained a mystery.
And that's why I wanted to thank you
for coming in to meet with us.
To help shed some light on the events.
Okay.
He dedicated the book to you.
Can you tell us how much of his novel
was based on fact?
All of it.
It was 1969--
What can you tell us about that summer?
Question? What was the question?
What do you remember about that summer 1969?
It was hot. It was real hot.
God must have been sweatin', it was so hot.
Tell me about the murder.
Hey, how much, how much I'm gettin' paid for this?
Well, Sheriff Call was this evil, nasty,
disgusting son of a gun.
Black people hated Sheriff Call
because he killed so many of us
during his two terms in service.
Some of my family was included.
White people feared him too.
So somebody got fed up with his fat ass, and killed him.
That's what happened that summer.
They say he dragged his intestines
for a mile before he died.
Crazy white people even built a statue for him.
How did it come about
that you worked for the Jansens?
I was cleaning for them part time,
right when his mamma ran off.
And Ward and I, Ward was his brother,
he was in high school at the time
and we raised him together.
Little Jackie was five at the time.
Where was his father?
W. W. was just
chasing girls, you know.
And running the local newspaper.
The Moat County Tribune.
How's Ward?
He's good, he's good. Real busy.
Ward was a writer--
uh--for the Miami Times.
He used to write about, uh--
well, he was kind of famous, you know,
'cause he wrote about the Civil Rights Movement
and the poor and the unjustly accused.
That's how come that lady Charlotte
started writing letters to him.
Stuff like that.
Yeah.
And then Jack, like I said, he was a swimmer.
And, uh--
almost professional, very close but then
he got kicked off the swim team,
he got kicked out of college,
and he came back home to his papa's house to deliver newspapers.
He didn't want to come back home,
but he didn't have nowhere else to go.
# Yeah #
# Mmm #
Jack, you better turn that music down.
You know W. W. gon' be mad at you.
Dang it, Anita, can you please knock?
I could've been jerking off in here.
Please, it ain't nothing I ain't seen before.
What are you doing?
I'm picking up your stuff, like I do every day.
Oh come on, not today. It's too hot for that.
I'm just helping.
You're not helping me. You don't have to help me.
Come on.
Get off the bed so I can make it.
Go fix me some collard greens.
It's my bed.
I know it's your bed. Really?
Because it's your bed, you should fucking make it.
They cancelled "The Smothers Brothers."
Oh, no, that's your show.
Well, I love that show. I love Dick and I love Tommy.
Lay down. Let me be you for a second. Oh, yeah, right. Get me in trouble.
You want to be me, I get to be you? Okay.
Okay, I'll love this. Jack, may I come in?
Oh, good, okay. Go away, go out. Go back out.
Okay. I better start jerking off first. Okay.
Jack, sorry to interrupt your masturbation,
but I'm here to clean the bed!
I could've been jerking off. I'm gonna clean everything!
I could have been jerking off!
Get out! Clean my shit up!
...get all that we have received in return,
is just another smooth exercise
in political manipulation. Good girl.
Deceit and deception,
callousness and indifference to our individual problems,
and the disgusting playing of divisive politics,
pitting the young against the old,
labor against management, north against south.
Did you want to see me?
Have you spoken to Ward this week?
No. Hello, Jack.
He didn't mention anything to you about coming here?
I can't believe your father's making me report on this.
I mean, look at her.
... to open our society.
She plans to run for president next.
They want to talk to Hillary Van Wetter.
Don't you let that Pulitzer Prize fool you.
He don't know everything yet.
Ain't no reason to come up here
stirring up shit with that asshole.
I just wanted to say that it is very important
for all Americans to recognize--
Charlotte Bless loved her some dangerous men.
She wrote men in prison.
She finally fell in love with one.
She was determined to get him out.
Why y'all ain't got no ice in here?
You want ice, go to your house.
Charlotte.
Oh, that's my show. What you think, Charlotte?
I don't like it. Make it looser.
That's that nigger you've been writing?
No. This is my white man.
Ohhh.
What happened yesterday? I missed it.
Listen to this. He thinks I'm his angel.
His angel? Shhh. Shut your face.
Bitch, how old is he? Oh, my God.
He's a fine motherfucker that's trying to fuck you. "Ever there was an angel in the world,
"my angel, it must be you,
but no angel would do the things I dream that you want."
Your angel, his angel.
Mm-hm. That's hot.
He say, "If you truly exist, I may become a religious man."
Ah!
"All my life, my heart has tried to find a place
I cannot name...a home."
You need to find yourself a young one.
He'll fuck you real good.
He says I'm his home. Hm.
Got a hundred different men
writing her from the penitentiary.
That's her man.
Oh, no. This is my man.
This here's the one.
Mm-hm.
Ward came home to investigate
the conviction of Hillary Van Wetter.
The town wasn't too happy about it
and neither was his papa. Oh, shit. Ugh.
Ward--
there's a horse in the parking lot.
It's our ride home, Yardley.
Uh, where is everybody?
It's Sunday.
People's either at home or at church.
It's a shithole.
Hey, man.
Hey, you.
How you doing?
Jack, meet Yardley Acheman. Hey.
My little brother, Jack. The swimmer, right?
Yeah, he's our driver now. Right, good.
Here, let me get these.
That's my typewriter. You've gotten big, boy.
Just be careful with the typewriter.
Got all pumped up. Is that from swimming?
Not anymore.
No! No! No!
Yardley's real particular about his suits
and his typewriter. Well, it's very expensive.
Yes. Thank you.
How do I get in?
Watch your head. Watch your head.
Don't touch my head. Tell him where you're from, Yardley.
London.
Ah!
When I came here-- from New York,
I was interviewing for the job--
and I was in advertising in New York
and I mentioned that it was simply different in New York.
So how'd you get from New York City
to the metropolis of Lately, Florida?
Jansen residence.
So I came down South and I interviewed at the paper.
W.W., Miss Roberta's on the phone.
No, no, no.
We don't take phone calls. Anita...
Who's Miss Roberta? No calls, Anita.
What part of London you from, Yardley?
Um, all over London.
Is there a good dry cleaning here? Excuse me?
Dry cleaning.
Dry cleaning? Yes.
You ain't gonna eat that, are you? Uh-uh.
How you gonna win those swimming meets if you don't eat?
I'm retired.
Retired. Jack, you ain't even tired enough to be retired.
How is it exactly you guys work?
I mean, like that boy drowned at his initiation?
Well, Yardley's the writer--
And I'd guess you'd say Ward is the nuts and bolts.
Yeah. When I was a reporter,
we had rewrite men who took the stories over the phone.
No, no, no. I'm not a rewrite man.
I'm the writer.
I'm the one who puts the facts into perspective.
Oh!
Yes. It's a different world now, Mr. Jansen.
Clearly.
Times have changed a bit, sir.
What interest does "The Miami Times"
have in Hillary Van Wetter?
He murdered somebody in jail?
Even if he was guilty--
It was a lynching, pure and simple. --he had certain rights.
And even if he was guilty--
Hillary has rights that the process completely disregarded.
And that's why we're here.
I'm very sorry, everybody, but I'm going to have to leave.
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
I have early evaluations first thing in the morning.
Come here, sugar. I apologize.
All right, buddy.
Ward?
Good night, boys.
Seems mighty sure of himself for a colored.
Ward said they need a driver.
A driver?
What you do out there?
So you meet anybody new out there in Miami?
I met a few.
Oh, yeah. All types down there, you know?
You stay away from those rough ones.
Remember what happened the last time.
How your kids?
You look beautiful, babe.
They're doing good. They're doing really good.
As soon as I get out of here,
I'll go see them and make dinner all over again.
You should come to that dinner, too.
I'll come to that dinner.
I think Ellen is maybe number four--
since you left.
Yeah.
That's why I don't take them bitches too seriously.
They come and they go and they come and they go.
You know what I mean?
# At last My dreams come true #
# Today he said "I do" #
# Friends said It couldn't be done #
# But all his love I know I've won #
How you doing there, Yard? Oh, jeez.
# That's where he placed The wedding band #
Hey, close that door, boy.
I don't want your daddy screaming about all the flies
getting in the house.
Hmm.
Who is that, Jack?
Uh--
I'm looking for the office of Mr. Jansen.
Ward Jansen of "The Miami Times."
I said who is it? I work for the Times.
You do? Yeah.
Huh.
Well, I'm Charlotte Bless. I'm Jack Jansen.
Here, let me get that. Oh.
Hey. All my files.
The office is in the garage.
You look a little young to be a journalist.
I'm really just the driver. Oh.
But I do write.
So do I. I write letters. I'm pretty good.
Hey, guys!
This here is Miss Charlotte Bless.
Oh, not for long.
Hillary and I are engaged to be married.
Hello, Miss Bless. I'm Ward.
Oh, Mr. Ward, good to finally meet you.
You didn't mention the engagement in your letters. Go clean yourself up.
Well, it only just happened. He just proposed.
Oh, that looks nasty. Well, how did I do that?
Excuse me a second.
Get Miss Bless something to drink. I'm Yardley Acheman.
We thought you and Hillary hadn't met.
Well, only in pictures,
but we been writing each other for months
and we understand ourselves just perfect.
Ward, where should I put her files?
Everything you need to know about Van Wetter
that's been in the papers,
is here in these boxes.
Our exciting correspondence is in that box.
In case you're interested.
My desk, Jackie boy.
Mr. Jansen, I really just wanted to thank you.
I wanted to thank you for returning my letters.
And for helping me get Hillary out of that hellhole.
Well, I wouldn't go booking the honeymoon just yet.
But we are going to fight his sentence
and the way it came about.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
Nobody deserves the death penalty, Miss Bless.
Not even Hillary Van Wetter.
Um, excuse me. So, everything is ordered alphabetically.
I was telling, um-- what's your name?
Yardley. Yardley.
Um, that all of the files,
Um, everything that's been in the papers,
is in the top box. This is gonna be a great help.
He's an innocent man. You're gonna find that out.
Wrongly convicted.
This is gonna get us off to a great start.
I've done a lot of research. I see that.
In the meantime, you need to freshen up or anything?
Jack, show Miss Bless to the washroom. I think I'll just stay here.
You might have some questions that you need answered.
I can freshen up just here.
Cold beer for me, Jack.
You're adorable, Jack.
I will take an iced tea if you have it.
You want anything, Ward? I'm good.
You'll see, uh--
it's an enormous amount of work-- What's with the boxes?
I don't know what to do here. What's with the boxes?
Well, we're gonna start on it.
My Jack was in love with Charlotte Bless.
I could tell that horny little boy
wanted to jump her on first sight.
Everybody was confused why she was engaged to Hillary Van Wetter.
Nasty, white trash swamp.
"All the killers who have written me
want to press their mouths into my vagina
and some, even the crack of my behind,
except Hillary Van Wetter.
He has no such desire.
He wants to be sucked off himself.
I consider this psychological proof of his innocence. "
She is one nasty little nut job.
Think we've been taking her a little too seriously.
You sure get bored quick.
No. Can tell I'm not going to get laid anytime soon
in this Floridian shit pit, so--
Listen-- Hey, Kathy, it's me.
Hillary tells her that the knife
Yardley. and the bloodied shirt
that the deputies claim to have found in his house
somehow got lost before the trial.
Yeah, I miss you, too.
What?
Hello, Kathy.
Miss Bless wanted to look at the prison.
Jack's first assignment was to take her there.
I bet he knows I'm here.
See, people who fall in love outside--
of a normal relationship,
they have these powers-- telepathic powers.
Hillary and I have that kind of connection, you dig?
Now why ain't you in college?
Huh?
Uh, I was a swimmer when I was in school.
No kidding? Yeah.
I was a swimmer. You were?
Uh-huh. I'd swim like a mermaid
if it wasn't for my damn curly hair.
I think straight hair gives me class.
All right.
Good.
So?
Well, we was drunk one night, and, uh--
I just--
I lost my temper and just--
well, I emptied the pool.
At your college?
The University of Florida.
They called that vandalism, I guess.
It's actually not as easy to do as it sounds.
So you lose your temper often?
Mm.
This place is full of boys just like you
who lost their temper one day.
I'm getting horny being this close to him.
Oh, baby.
I bet he's horny for me all the time.
Yeah.
Mmm.
Oh, I can feel him.
Can I help you folks?
Oh, no.
Yes, Officer. Uh--hm.
We just wanted to sit in your parking lot for a little while.
What for?
His daddy's in there and we wanted to send him good vibrations.
Some good what?
Oh, these special things called good vibrations.
Sorry, ma'am. Y'all can't park here.
Oh.
Yes, Officer.
The story that Hillary told the deputies
was never investigated.
He simply told it once from the witness stand
and was never asked to elaborate,
not even by his own lawyers.
Good to see you again, Ward. Nice to see you.
Sir, this is my writing partner, Mr. Yardley Acheman.
Of course.
I suppose the best place to start
would be the beginning.
I was born in this county.
1897, to poor but proud parents.
Mr. Pine, could we skip 65 years,
save everyone some time?
Hillary Van Wetter, 1965?
Oh, I can't agree to talk to you about that matter.
Not without my client's permission.
He's entitled to his privacy, just like anybody else.
You have his permission. He wrote you.
I'll have to check that out.
I'm sure the letters would be in your files, Mr. Pine.
That's what you say, but I have a client to protect.
Look here.
If we have to get a lawyer of our own down here
to sort this out, then while he's here,
we're gonna have him look through every aspect of Mr. Van Wetter's case.
Including the competency of his defense.
There was nothing wrong with the defense Hillary Van Wetter got in court!
Then you have nothing to worry about from us.
We just want to talk to him.
Then we'll be out of your--
You don't know a thing about this person!
You've been in this world for five minutes, boy!
Now that's just not necessary, Mr. Pine.
Yes. I talk the way I want in my office!
All right. Then you'll arrange the meeting, will you?
Quick! We're gonna be late!
You get the marriage license?
I can't believe we're doing this!
Fuck! Jack, go knock on the door again.
There she is. Whoa, baby
Well, I say-- Good morning, Miss Bless.
Look at Daisy Mae.
Morning.
You look just fine.
Hope he likes it.
Uh--
Would you mind putting up the windows?
It's gonna muss my hair.
Are you serious?
I'm sweating like a pregnant nun back here.
Unbelievable!
Hi.
You got 15 minutes.
No physical contact of any kind.
No tape recorders.
No object may be passed to the prisoner.
I'll be right outside this door.
Mr. Van Wetter,
my name is Ward J ansen.
This is my associate, Yardley Acheman-- You look like your picture.
Mmm. I do?
Thank you.
These your paperboys?
Mm-hm.
What they gonna do for us?
They gonna save you.
They're gonna save us?
Mm-hm.
Shit. They can't even save themselves.
Mr. Van Wetter, we wanted to ask you
about the lost evidence in your case.
Shut up. Can't you see I'm busy?
Will you do something for me right now?
Oh. Oh, I wish I could.
Spread your legs open a little bit.
Mmm. Yeah.
Now tear off them pantyhose.
Rip those off.
Yeah. Mm-hm.
Move your hands away. Mmm.
Yeah.
Now open up your mouth--
you picture what you wrote me in your letters.
You bitch!
Oh, I love you.
What the hell's going on in here?
You're a good girl. I warned y'all! This visit's over!
I told y'all this visit was-- come on!
Come on, Hillary. No!
No! There's nothing going on!
Shit! No!
What the fuck? I didn't touch that girl!
No! No!
What the fuck you laughing about?
Come on now, Miss Bless.
Jack came home and threw up after that.
He couldn't believe he still loved her
after what he saw, but he did.
You're Ward Ward's boy? Mm-hm.
Most contrary man in all of Moat County.
What may I do for you gentlemen today?
It's about the murder of Sheriff Call.
I understand that there's some physical evidence
relating to the case that was lost?
Yes, sir. I believe there was.
Well, we was wondering what sort of explanation
the department might have.
I wish I knew.
Mr. Van Wetter once cut a deputy's thumb off.
Did you know that?
It was over a traffic ticket, if I remember.
You can't do much without your thumb.
It's what separates us from the primates.
For a little thing like holding your wife's titty.
You're not married, Mr. Jansen? No.
A little thing like that, you can't do it.
Maybe I'll just go talk to the deputies
who was involved in the arrest.
You can talk to whoever you want
as long as they'll talk to you. But they won't.
And why is that?
They haven't forgotten what Hillary did to one of theirs.
The judge allowed testimony
based on evidence that he never even saw.
He took the officer's word over Hillary's.
I can't say I blame him. Nobody does.
You got me in the face there.
So you've got to ask him.
Where was he between 2:00 and 6:00?
I'm gonna ask him about some things he wrote,
some letters to Charlotte.
H ere we go.
Hold.
Good morning, Mr. Van Wetter.
Hey.
Where's your dress?
You don't like me like this?
You know a prisoner by the name of--
Ward, Ward, Ward.
You know a prisoner by the name
of Mr. Bobby Valentine? Mr. Van Wetter?
Mr. Demarcus Williams, Mr. Bobby Hinton?
Another prisoner by the name of Jimmy Edwards,
another one, Demarcus.
I think his name is Curt. I forgot his last name.
Anyway, you know what they all have in common?
Hey, Martin Luther King.
You know what they all had in common? What?
They all wear pants.
Every goddamned man in here wears pants!
How am I supposed to tell you apart from them?
Don't talk to her like that! Sit down, Jack.
Sit the fuck down.
Mr. Van Wetter, we don't have a lot of time, all right?
We got to move on.
You're gonna move on one way or another, Ward?
Ward's in charge!
He's gonna get his way-- till he don't.
Maybe that's how he got his scars on the face.
You mentioned in one of your letters to Miss Bless
that you was working Turn around, bitch!
An Uncle Tyree-- Yeah, yeah.
at the time of the murder.
What kind of work you doing? Lawn work.
Lawn work.
You wear a dress in here next time
or you don't bother coming! Bitch, look at me!
And stop bringing that fucking nigger
think he Muhammad Ali with you!
Mr. Van Wetter, come have a seat.
Cassius Clay, nigger.
We can get a dress here in five minutes.
Why don't you have a seat?
Go home, boy!
I don't know--
Charlotte, where does one get pants like that from anyway?
Well, I think we got the case licked.
This is a fucking circus!
In this town,
Weldon Pine helped get Sheriff Call re-elected.
Tension was brewing in the house.
Jack was getting jealous of Hillary and Charlotte.
And he was getting jealous of Ward and Yardley, too.
Ward wasn't somebody who attached himself to just anybody.
Your dad's girlfriend, what's her name?
Jack couldn't understand why he was so attached to that Yardley.
No, you didn't.
What is the hottest temperature
that you've ever been in?
125.
How about you?
Just put your hand out and it burns off
The hottest was when I lived in Florida. How about you?
It doesn't bother me. I never pay attention to it.
Cold and wet just goes fucking through you like a knife
but--I don't know.
So how's Mr. Van Wetter today? He still innocent?
I don't know. If he is--
he sure as hell didn't have no help proving it,
not from that Weldon Pine guy anyway.
Could I have a fork or something?
The chicken legs, you eat those with your hands.
Maybe at your house.
This is the South, sugar.
Anyway, you know how I feel about that.
Do you eat your mashed potatoes with your hands? Do you really want to--?
Do you really want to--? Bring me some chopsticks, Anita.
Do you really want to take the shot--
on putting to death a man or a woman
when maybe they're innocent? I mean, I don't.
I don't want to try to have to live with that.
On the other hand-- Are you gonna eat that or torture it?
Told you, I'm not hungry.
That's'cause you're in love.
I know who you're sniffing around, too.
Anita, please don't tease him at the table.
On the other hand, if somebody's guilty,
well, you want to pay their room and board 365?
Absolutely. Ah!
Whoops.
I'm so sorry.
Anyway, it's just iced tea. It ain't even gonna stain.
You'da thought Jack woulda had a girlfriend by now,
but all he did was jerk off to the pictures
in those nudie magazines that was under his bed.
Now she was all he could think of night and day.
Oh, yeah, he was definitely in love.
He needed her.
What you reading? You give it to me.
What is this shit? " Lolita."
Porno, I bet.
Oh.
You need a girlfriend.
Look at them girls over there.
Go on and introduce yourself. Go on.
I'm just fine right here.
You want me to blow you, don't you?
You don't have to answer. I know it's true.
I'm not gonna blow a friendship--
over a stupid little blowjob.
You hear me?
Look, why you talking to me like that?
See that one in blue? She'll blow you.
I don't want someone like that blowing me.
It's a good thing you're not in prison
because you wouldn't have a choice there.
Fuck you.
Jack, come back here.
# Well, well #
# I passed the corner Where we first met #
# Yes, I did #
# Memories of our love Linger there yet #
# Oh, I'm sitting On top of the world #
# Just to know That you're my girl #
# I'm just lucky #
# I'm lucky, lucky, Lucky in love #
# Our love is here--#
# Lucky, lucky, lucky In love--#
# Oh, I'm sitting On top of the world #
# Just to know That she's my girl #
# That makes me lucky #
Oh my God. Pam.
# I'm so lucky lucky Lucky in love #
# Let me sing One more time ##
What is that? Is he okay?
Is he having an allergic reaction?
A jellyfish sting or something?
A fucking jellyfish did that.
You're supposed to piss on a jellyfish sting.
We're gonna have to do something embarrassing.
You got to hang in there. Hey!
Well, you're gonna-- You'll piss on him?
What are you doing to him?
Call an ambulance.
He's having a reaction! Shut the fuck up!
Don't push me! You're supposed to piss--
Get the fuck out of here! I can see this.
I can see he's poisoned. You don't pee on--
Don't push me! I will slap your face.
Get the fuck out of here. All right.
I said, I will kick your ass! I'm going to call the police.
Move it! Fine.
If anyone's gonna piss on him, it's gonna be me!
Fine, fuck you!
He don't like strangers peeing on him!
Come on. Come on.
Come on, baby come on! Wake up!
Come on! Shit!
# La la la #
# Zippeydoo da #
Come on.
Come on!
# No matter What people say #
# I know our love Is here to stay #
# And I'm so lucky #
You're gonna be okay!
# Lucky lucky in love #
# I'm mister lucky #
# I'm so lucky Lucky lucky in love ##
Jack.
What are you doing here?
What do you think I'm doing here?
Told you to knock on my door
before you come in my room.
Oh, hush up.
Here, I brought you something.
Take these pills.
I smell awful.
That's because that blond lady peed all over your face.
Ugh. Here, drink this.
Does it hurt?
I'm cold, I'm cold, I'm cold.
Congratulations, Jack. We're in the paper.
"Fast action saves Lately man at beach.
"Miss Charlotte Bless of Mobile, Alabama
apparently saved Mr. Jansen's life
by urinating over the areas of his body
where he was attacked.
These included the victim's arms, genitals and face. "
Jack, I had no idea.
I had no idea that your own father
would print something like that.
It made the AP wire.
You're famous all over the country.
"Home Remedy." Good title.
What's Dad trying to do to me?
It's called the newspaper business, Jack.
Oh, shit.
Let him go, Jack! You're gonna kill him.
Jack, let him go.
You put your hands on me again,
I will fuck you up! Yeah?
Fuck you, nigger!
He needs to get laid.
He needs a fucking straitjacket.
He's sexually repressed.
Sexually repressed is a 40-year-old woman
who's obsessed with prison cock!
That's not nice. Calm down now.
No, fuck calm down!
I'm not having some kid call me a nigger.
I want him out of here now!
Yardley?
Jack, let's go to the prison.
You two can stay here and keep arguing.
This time I'm talking to Hillary by myself.
Come on.
He's not even gonna look at you
if I'm not there in a pretty dress.
Well, that's too bad for him.
Ward.
You'll see.
I knew Jack didn't mean to say it.
But those were the times we were living in
and it was what it was.
Yardley, on the other hand, well--
# Get out of the cold #
# Take the night off #
# Be your own boss #
# When you're near me #
# Can you hear me #
# Or do I have to shout In your ear #
# Mmm #
# Take the night off #
# Turn the light on #
Forensic report says that the sheriff
was stabbed between 2 and 3 AM.
Yep. Like I told you,
I was with-- my Uncle Tyree doing lawn work
in Ormond Beach at the time.
Lawn work? Yes, sir.
You mean stealing? Yes, sir.
Stealing sod off a golf course.
A developer paid through the teeth for that shit.
We sold it and we didn't make it back
to the river till sunrise.
What kind of developers? Condominiums, man.
You got a name? No, I don't.
Deputies say they found the sheriff's body at 6 AM--
but it was the way he was killed.
That's what makes everybody assume it was you.
What you think? You tell me.
I ain't the only one carrying a machete around here.
True.
The deputies went to Tyree's house,
he said he'd been sleeping in bed all night
and had a whole bunch of family members there to confirm it.
Then they go to your house--
where they find the bloodstained shirt and knife.
Yeah, all right. Listen to me.
Every knife and shirt that I own is stained in blood.
It's what I do for a living.
I'm gutting alligators for their skin.
Okay? I was a bachelor.
I didn't have nobody to do my laundry.
You probably got somebody to do your laundry.
What you think?
I bet you do.
They never matched the blood to the sheriff's, did they?
Tell me how to find Tyree.
The arms of mercy are so wide
they will accept any man,
but they will not accept any man wearing pants.
Where is my woman?
Where's my woman?
The only one you need to talk to right now is me, baby.
The only one I need to talk to?
I'm the only one. I'm your mercy.
I'm your arms wide open, I'm your pants.
Ward's in charge!
If you wanna go see Tyree, I'll give you directions,
but you got to make that choice because he's a violent man.
Now stay with me now
because this is when it gets tricky.
Ward called Charlotte
and told her to drive Yardley to Ormond Beach.
He wanted to verify Hillary's so-called golf course story.
The boys went on to visit this Uncle Tyree.
Man, this is stupid. Where are we going?
No one lives out here. No one could live out here.
You talk to Anita about your--choice of words?
It was fucked up.
I know.
Goddamn it.
Sure you don't me to watch the car?
Goddamn it! This stuff ain't working, man.
It's like they like this shit.
Better than jellyfish, I bet.
Fuck! Oh, my God!
Watch it! You're way too close to him. Ward! Ward!
You better jump him.
It's better in here where we have to get lower.
Ward, you're sinking!
This whole place is just floating.
You ever think about Mama?
I wonder where she at.
She is in Tucson, Arizona.
You got a girlfriend?
Why?
You don't remember this, but Mom used to go on about, uh--
don't make love to a woman until you get married, right? Mm-hm.
I followed that until I was--
Oh, fuck that. We'll talk about it later.
Let's go.
Mr. Van Wetter?
Good afternoon, sir.
My name is Ward Jansen. I work for "The Miami Times. "
We're here on behalf here of your nephew, Hillary.
You lost a shoe.
You're lucky it was just the one.
Snakes all around here.
We need to talk to you about your nephew, Mr. Van Wetter.
Little late for that, isn't it?
He gonna be strapped to a chair and electrocuted.
Well--
you come all the way up here just to tell me that?
You could've saved yourself a trip.
He tells me that he was with you
the night Sheriff Call was murdered,
stealing sod, which you later sold.
Let's hope nobody believes him.
Stealing's against the law, ain't it?
Now he's still got time.
I don't much care for you.
Come up here in my home--
and call me a thief.
I ain't up here about thieving, Mr. Van Wetter.
I'm up here about whether a man's life needs to be taken or not--
for the murder of Sheriff Call.
But if you was with your nephew that night,
it's vital for Hillary that you admit it.
I don't think he likes you much.
I don't like him much either.
Where's the ice cream?
It's coming.
Keep that baby quiet.
What's wrong with that baby?
All right, well, sit on it.
Yeah.
You want--?
You want a little ice cream?
You don't want to have any ice cream.
You take this chair out here with me.
No sense you staying over there.
Thank you.
Little man, get yourself a chair there.
Get yourself a chair.
Was you with him?
Yeah.
Well, I--
I was with him.
Where?
Golf club.
Ormond Beach.
Stole sod, sold it--
to this one condo developer.
Where's Hillary live from here?
We didn't get back till the morning, sunrise.
He lives that way.
So why are you telling me now?
You seem like the only person thinks Hillary's innocent.
No, sir, Mr. Van Wetter. No, sir.
I didn't say that.
Your boy--
he's getting nervous over there.
Let's go. I'm done talking to you.
What you hiding? Ward?
I'm sick--
of your questions.
Eugene?
Ward, remember the first day when I was with Charlotte? Yeah?
We went and stopped at the prison.
We didn't go in. I saw him.
Tyree? Yeah.
What you think? They was getting their stories together?
I don't know.
I'll tell you this.
They ain't as dumb as they look.
Oh, shit, man.
Fuck.
What the fuck, man?
Leave me at the fucking hotel?
Jesus!
In Yardley's room, no less.
Fuck, man. Look at you.
You're becoming obsessed with this case.
Wake me up.
Come on.
You look terrible, Ward.
Those mosquitoes eat you for breakfast?
Yardley found the golf course.
You found the golf course? What's he doing in my clothes?
The car broke down.
we had to walk into town,
stopped by the motel to freshen up.
Get out of my clothes now.
Come on.
Come on, Jack.
What are you doing?
Miss Bless. Come on, stop it.
Jack!
On the morning of the murder
the grounds superintendent of the Ormond Beach Golf Course
phoned the Police Department
to report that four of his greens
had been stripped in the night.
You talked to the superintendent? No.
He died, but I found another guy who remembered
that the club called the governor
to ask him to declare them a disaster area
so they could get federal funds
to replace the greens.
It gets better.
I found the builder, too,
the guy who bought the stolen greens.
He remembered Hillary and Tyree.
They showed up at 6 AM in a truck.
He took one look at them and what they had
and thought they'd stolen it from a cemetery.
But of course, he doesn't want to be connected to this in any way.
And who was he?
Well, the only way he'd talk to me
is if I promised to keep him anonymous.
Come on now. What's his name?
No, no, no.
I've got to keep it anonymous. I gave him my word.
He's got, well, he's in a position
to get some work from the state, so you know.
But good, huh?
Outstanding.
How'd you find him?
Building permits.
Damn building permit.
Time to get out of Lately.
Did you sleep with Yardley?
You know, people like Yardley, you just--
got to get him on your side.
You know what I mean?
You fucked him for that?
Fucking a man is the most natural thing in the world, Jack.
It is.
I kind of like it out here.
This was a good idea.
Oooh!
Come on! Let's dance.
Come on! No!
Come on, Jack. Got to have fun!
You wanna dance?
Yeah! I wanna dance with you!
Woo! You're good!
This is not me apologizing, you dig?
I just don't like to see you sad.
Yardley told their editor about the new evidence
from Ormond Beach.
This was enough to show injustice in the legal system of Lately
and enough for a good story.
Yardley wanted to get out of town
and Ward knew it.
All these peanuts on the floor.
Pigs. Bunch of pigs living around here.
Sick of this shit.
I can't find Mama's ring.
Oh, well, a nigger must have come
in the middle of the night and stole it.
I'm sorry, Anita.
I didn't mean to say--
I didn't mean to say that.
And I'm really sorry.
You know, Jackie, you got to watch your mouth.
Somebody'll cut your little ass over some shit like that.
You understand me, boy?
Yes, ma'am.
And you miss your mother?
Sometimes.
It's a dis-damn grace the way she left you.
And I been here.
Well, let's find this ring, I guess.
No, that's all right. I can find it.
Ohhh. Sorry.
All right.
Okay.
I'm really sorry. Okay.
All right, Jack.
What's makes this story any different?
What makes your story different than the others, John?
What makes this case so different that you want to pull the plug now?
The facts. What's left to do?
You've been up there a month and a half.
I want your ass back here.
Save that shit for someone else.
I'm not comfortable with it and you shouldn't be either.
I'm going to Ormond Beach to get the facts.
I want to get some alligator shoes.
You run this article, this shit could hurt me.
I got advertisers to think of.
A dvertisers? You want me to be concerned
with the advertisers for your newspaper?
Ward, you don't know everything.
He knows what he's doing, Pa.
Shut up! I'm not talking to you.
He knows how to get stories,
but what he doesn't fully appreciate
is that the stories go out into a community.
They resonate.
Oh, like the jellyfish?
Like getting pissed on?
You notice Anita's been acting mighty bossy recently?
She's always been that way. Yeah.
Oh, shit.
Darling, let it go. Don't get yourself hurt.
Sit down. I'll get Anita. Anita!
Hey, I'll take care of it.
Anita will get it. Anita! Does she have children? I can't remember.
She got two kids. Oh, yeah.
How you doing, baby doll? Where you going?
Hoo. A baby shower.
Um, Anita, uh, before you go,
could you clean up this mess.
I said I got it. It's all right. Anita's got it.
I got it.
We're going to Ormond Beach.
Oh, just come right out and tell them.
I've named Ellen editor-in-chief.
And--
we're getting married.
It's an antique.
I know it is.
This belonged to my mother.
It was a gift from me. Give it back, Jack.
Just give it back to her.
It's all I got.
Ward never believed Yardley's story.
Building permits and anonymous sources.
He took Charlotte and Jack back to Ormond Beach
to get to the bottom of it.
Yardley went back home to Miami.
# That man is dangerous #
# Loving him is dangerous #
What is that builder's name, Charlotte?
What builder?
You know exactly what builder.
The one Yardley says bought the sod.
I don't know. He went alone.
I went to the hairdresser's.
Takes a lot to look like this.
Charlotte Bless, you is a mess.
And you'd do anything to get your man
out of jail-- wouldn't you?
Thirsty, huh?
Oh, yeah.
# That man is dangerous #
You keep staring like that,
we're gonna have a problem.
What really happened down there, Charlotte?
After you went to the hairdresser, what happened? Hm?
Jack, would you tell your brother to get his hands off of me?
Come on, man. Let's go somewhere else. Easy, little brother.
Just fucking relax, boy.
Miss Bless ain't got no answer, huh?
I didn't think so.
Your brother's acting strange.
Not used to drinking like this.
# Is this love affair for real Or is it just one and done? #
# I'm telling you #
A little more than that.
Why is Ward doing this?
We got 50 places to be tomorrow.
What is that?
It's beautiful.
Don't turn it down.
No one's ever given me something like this before.
Well, you just tell me when you want it back, huh?
It's beautiful.
You want me to fuck you, Jack?
Then I'm gonna fuck you any way you want.
Jack.
Jack!
I want to get some alligator shoes.
Mmm, Jack.
You wanted your ass whupped.
Is that what you wanted?
Tell me what you want.
You're a dirty pig.
I'll fuck you any way you want.
Little white pig.
Jack? Jack! Jack!
Jack, wake up!
Something's going on in Ward's room.
Hey! Hey!
Stop it!
What the fuck?
Help! We need help!
Where's the fucking keys?
Where's the fucking keys, you piece of shit?
Motherfucker, wake up!
Help!
Where are the fucking keys?
Ward, what's the plastic for?
What is the plastic?
What the fuck?
I've watched you so often.
You sit here, and I heard that you play a little drum.
You didn't get up and do anything. No.
I heard you could sing,
but with me you are going to sing.
He's gonna be fine.
You don't have to sleep all the way down there.
All right.
Just this once.
I can't fuck with this TV on.
Feels kind of awkward to be talking
while you see this.
But it's kind of awkward that they're doing it in the first place.
Most boys Jack's age fall in love
with their high school or college sweetheart,
but Jack never bothered much with girls
after his mama left.
I guess you could say he had abandonment issues.
With Charlotte, it was like he was getting his mama,
his high school sweetheart, and a oversexed Barbie doll
all rolled into one.
Anywho, I think y'all seen enough.
My hair looks like crap. Don't even look at it.
Oh, shit.
I got to go to the hairdresser.
My wig ain't acting right.
I don't understand what the fuck
you're doing with Hillary.
Oh.
Here we go.
You don't love him.
Really? Mm-hm.
You don't know that.
You don't know anything.
You're 20 years old. You're not that much older.
I'm a lot older.
It ain't gonna happen.
Look at me.
It's not practical.
I'm not as practical as the murderer?
He's not guilty, Jack. That's the point.
That's not the point. Fuck this. I knew it would happen.
What?
I give you some ass and suddenly--
Look--Hillary ain't so bad.
And I'm not so good.
I've got another side.
I got a fucked-up side,
and it gets along just fine with my man.
You can't split yourself into sides.
Sure, you can. Just ask your brother.
What the fuck does Ward have to do with this?
He has a dark side and I don't mean him being a fag.
Now these boys lived for each other.
Jack wasn't hurt by Ward being a homosexual
or the dark stuff that he was into.
He was just hurt that Ward never told him.
Hi. Hey, there.
H e's doing better. He's gonna be all right. Good.
So, I gotta go.
Go where? Where you going?
I'm going back home.
You don't have to go anywhere.
It's just the way it works.
You shouldn't go anywhere you don't want to go.
Who says I don't want to go?
Why do you have to go?
'Cause I do.
Take this ring back.
Yardley called the hotel.
Did you tell him?
I told him Ward got mugged and beaten on the beach.
Well, what'd he say?
Not much.
Wanted to know if he was gonna make it.
When I told him it wasn't serious,
he kind of just lost interest. He's not gonna be much help for a while.
Didn't sound like he needed much help.
He can't go write the story alone, Charlotte.
Well, we'll just have to see. He doesn't know enough about it.
This isn't about a newspaper article, Jack.
It's about a person's life.
That's the whole point we're here, okay?
So it's about someone's life.
Baby, don't go.
You're starting to screw with my head.
Look, you're a good kid, all right?
You're--
You got your whole life ahead of you,
and you want me?
Jack went down to "The Miami Times"
to try to stop Yardley from publishing the article.
He didn't want his brother's name on it.
Jack.
Hi.
Hey. How's Ward? How's your brother doing?
Been trying to get ahold of you since yesterday.
Good. He's obviously not doing so badly then.
Sorry, I didn't want any distractions. Come, sit, sit.
He wants to read what you're writing.
A s soon as I'm done, he'll be the first to read it, as always.
Damn it! I'm so sick of your shit, man!
His name is on that, too.
He wants to read it before it's published.
Okay? That's it. Uh-huh.
He just wants to read it before it's published.
You got to get those facts straight.
You got to get all the facts straight.
You're starting to sound like your brother.
Look, we have a deadline here.
I've told you, this is the newspaper business.
We don't have time to get all the facts.
We both know the town of Lately set Hillary up.
We've got the story. It's not the fucking truth!
You want to talk about the motherfucking truth?
You thought I was from London?
Ain't no Negro getting a job up in this spot
unless he's a colored motherfucking James Bond, you dig?
I got drunk once and let Ward suck my dick.
He got a taste for niggers and now he hates himself.
That's the truth.
Go back to your brother, boy.
I have got a deadline to meet.
Hello?
Put Ward on the phone.
Why'd you put his byline on that article?
How could you sign his name on that?
Tell him we got Hillary out.
The governor's gonna pardon him.
Hillary's getting out.
"I've had some time to think over the past few months
about me, about you.
I'm not sure I found what I want out of life yet.
All I know is that I don't want to live it without you.
Please take this ring back. Love, Jack. "
Get the door.
Get the fucking door, bitch!
Who the fuck are you?
I'm Hillary. What you want?
Get the fuck out! I'm with Charlotte.
That bitch took my-- I'll call you later!
Charlotte, you want me to call the police?
There she is.
I'm sorry.
I was gonna write you a letter--
No, I don't need your letters. Come here.
Uh--
Don't touch me.
Come on here. Don't touch you?
Don't touch you?
It's okay.
It's all right, baby.
Anything.
That's all right.
You told me you loved me in your third letter.
Do you love me?
Yes!
You always fuck like this?
Like it was the last time?
Do you think I'm pretty?
You fuck those niggers like this?
Gonna get all inside here!
Now pack your shit and let's go.
I don't think I'm gonna like living in a swamp.
I don't want to live in a swamp. I like it here.
And that was their declaration of love.
So Hillary took Charlotte to the swamp.
So did you hear about old man Henry? No.
He got drunk in his back yard by the water,
and the alligators came out and took a big chunk of his leg.
Ha. Just joking.
My daddy rooster, he got jumped
by three of his sons,
so I need to find a home for three of them.
So he's in my house sitting,
so I need--I know you only have hens.
That's why I was wondering, you know, if you want to babysit,
you know, adopt three of them for you.
But they'd be good though, because you have hens. No.
You're my only hope. No! I don't want any.
Come on, Charlotte.
I need you to do me a favor.
I need you to post this thing for me.
It ain't got a stamp on it.
What's wrong with you today? It's real important.
You think you can do that for me?
You're not acting yourself today.
Why's your door open, huh?
Smells like piss in here.
Ward Ward said you might show up.
Left him a note.
You stink.
I can smell you from over here.
Come here, boy. Come sit down.
What you doing back in Miami?
Yardley's gone.
He quit?
No.
He's in New York.
Signing some book deal.
Hero of the new journalism or some kind of shit. I don't know.
W.W. moved Ellen into the house, huh?
Whatever.
Whatever makes him happy.
There wasn't no developer, Jack.
All right, let's move.
Come on, go shower, Ward.
I'm tired.
Come on.
Jeez.
I keep thinking I missed something, Jack.
Like I missed something I was supposed to see
that was right in front of me.
Like what?
The point of it.
Doesn't matter.
Things got out of hand.
You got hurt,
Yardley got his fucking book deal.
Hillary got Charlotte in the swamp.
The idea--is that-- you run the water
while you're in there with it.
Come on, man.
Hey.
What if we didn't get it right, huh?
Makes no difference.
It makes no difference, Jack?
You don't know what it feels like
to get it exactly right now.
To get it down just the way it happened.
You're going back to see Hillary.
Fuck yeah, I am.
Do you ever hear from her?
No.
Miss Bless? No.
I wonder what she thinks of him now, huh?
Can't see her sitting on the porch stoop
holding a silver spoon
and waiting for the ice cream carton to come her way, can you?
I dug around.
There wasn't no proof, no how, nowhere
that they was ever stealing sod that night.
They want me to keep my mouth shut.
Don't want me to tell my story. Well, fuck them.
I'm gonna tell my story. I'm gonna write my story,
and they can publish it wherever the fuck they want to.
Yeah, Mama always said you better be--
right and be last before you gonna be first and be wrong, boy.
Be right and be last before you go gonna be first and be wrong--
Yeah, I know!
I heard-- They said things about--
Oh, yeah. It's all true.
Just kidding. You should see the other guy.
Smile. Smile.
Thank you.
Everyone, please. We're cutting the cake!
Where's the photographer?
Hey, Claire, can you hand me
that salt over there?
Thank you.
Hi.
You ain't supposed to be in here.
You gonna get me in-- I got you a drink.
You know W. W. fired me.
I'm gonna talk to your boss
and tell him you're a friend of the family.
No, Jack. Yeah.
All I ever did was cook and clean for you boys.
I wasn't never no family.
Anyway, go on back outside.
Well, Ward's out there. You gonna come see him?
Are you trying to get me fired?
I miss you.
I got something for you. Wait a minute.
This came for you about a month ago.
She told him to tell-
She told him not to let you see it.
"Dear Jack, I can't believe
I'm finally writing you this letter
or if it will get to you
or whether you'll even read it.
Jack, I think I've really messed up this time.
Don't misunderstand me.
Hillary lo ves me, in his way.
It's just me that isn't made for this place,
for this lifestyle.
I hope I can make it to your father's wedding
so I can hear you tell me, 'I told you so.'
Take care for now. Sweetly, your Charlotte. "
Is that from blondie?
Thank you.
Where's your hat?
Oh, I forgot. Get out of the kitchen.
I'm sorry.
Excuse me. I'm Jack Jansen. I'm the groom's son.
My father wants to know what exactly is taking dinner so long.
It'll be ready in a minute, sir. Thank you.
Put the hair under the hat.
I don't want your black hair in my food.
You can put your black hair in my food.
Cheers.
Bye, Anita.
Bye, Jack.
You wouldn't leave without me, would you?
Drop you off at the motel. I'm going somewhere.
Mind me asking where you're going afterwards?
Going to Charlotte's.
Well, it gotta be tonight?
I got to get her the fuck out of there.
I got to get her out of there!
Charlotte's acting on her own free will.
What do you want me to say? Move.
I got to go to the Van Wetters' anyway.
Come with me tomorrow morning.
We're going now. It ain't the right time.
Get the fuck out my way. You ain't driving drunk like this.
What the fuck are you gonna do about it, huh?
What?
Charlotte must be a good piece of ass.
You look like a pirate. I know.
Do this for me one time. Go "Aargh. "
Uh-huh.
Hey, you're driving all squirrelly, man.
Hey, Jack, sit on down. Hey.
You sure it's this way?
I'm sure it's this way.
Ain't a good time to be drinking too much out here, Jack.
Yeah, you're one to talk.
Keeping your promise to Dad, did you?
Not to drink on his big day?
How you holding up?
Let's see your hands. Are they shaking?
They shaking, Ward, huh? Don't drink.
Well, why do you take after the worst of me, Jack?
'Cause you're my brother.
Wedding party, Charlotte?
I'm going to the wedding.
Don't be difficult. I told you--
I don't want you to go.
No. I told you. I'm going to the wedding.
Watch out.
God, it smells like shit.
Electric fence. You all right?
You all right?
Goddamn.
You let me lead.
I don't want to quarrel with you.
You're my little pony.
I just want to climb up on you one more time.
I can't believe she'd live here.
Charlotte!
Charlotte?
What you want?
She not here.
She gone.
What is it you want with my wife?
Huh?
Just wanted to say hello.
A quick hello and a quick poke while you're at it?
How about you? What you up to, Ward?
I know what you came for.
I got what you want.
Where is she?
How should I know? I'm not leaving until I see her.
She not here. She gone.
Let's go. Where?
How should I know?
Last night she told me
she was going to your father's wedding!
You're a liar! We just come from there!
And that's where you should go back to, boy!
He's lying!
He's lying.
I got this. Go back to the boat.
Where is she? Where is she?
Stop provoking me, boy,
and do what your brother tells you!
I said I'm not leaving until I see her!
Goddamn it, he killed her.
He killed her, Ward.
You killed her!
You son of a bitch!
That's all you were good for is killing her!
Huh?
Run, Jack!
Come on, boy. Show me.
I'm gonna fuck you up.
Come on!
Jack!
Ward!
Is this what you wanted?
Yeah.
You got what you come for.
Paperboy.
Where you going, paperboy?
Ain't no way out of this one.
Fuck you!
Hillary Van Wetter was tried and convicted
in the murders of Charlotte Bless and Ward Jansen.
He died in the electric chair at the Florida State Prison.
Nobody ever found out who murdered Sheriff Call.
My little Jack finally saw his mama again at Ward's funeral.
He became a writer of some renown.
He never did get over his first true love.