So, we keep
headin' east?
Yeah, that's the idea.
Stay out of the big cities?
Uh-huh.
I think I'm tired.
Yeah.
Me, too.
Here.
Bring it on
up to the office.
I'm going to go
check us out.
All right.
♪ With the rushin'
that way ♪
♪ I had a feeling
it was my day ♪
♪ for one of those nights
♪ when you lose your cool,
and you're feelin' sorry ♪
♪ you're ridin' on sin
to the page of a story ♪
♪ of another great night
in the life of a fool ♪
♪ ow!
What took you so long?
Nothing.
I had a little trouble
with the maid,
but everything's
fine now.
Damn.
8:00.
It's already this hot.
Yep.
How are we fixed
for water?
Probably not enough.
Yeah.
There's a cooler
in the back
in the office.
Hey.
Shh.
Aah! Aah! Aah!
Sarah, honey,
what's wrong?
Huh?
What is it,
sweetie? Hmm?
Daddy.
Yeah?
Daddy's here.
There were monsters.
No, sweetie.
There's no such thing
as monsters.
You were just having
a bad dream.
What's wrong, dad?
Hi, kiddo.
Sarah's just having
a bad dream.
Oh.
I saw monsters, Jack.
Monsters?
What kind?
I don't know. They came
out of my closet,
and then they were
in the shadows.
Mmm, shadow monsters.
Well, they look
pretty scary,
but they really
can't do anything,
especially when
the lights are on.
They're scared
of the light.
What happened, baby?
You OK?
I'm OK.
Sarah had a bad dream
about monsters.
Oh.
And I was telling her
that there's no such
thing as monsters.
Oh.
I'm going to turn on
my night light just in case.
That sounds like
a brilliant solution.
Mmm.
Hey, Jack?
Hey, mom?
Morning.
Morning, baby.
Hey, hon, the pick up
still won't start.
You mind dropping me off
on the way in?
Sure.
Did you feed Burrow?
Yeah, I fed him.
All right.
Good.
The night light
worked, didn't it?
I got it, dad.
What do you got
going today, Jack?
Uh, nothing much.
A math test
in a few days,
and I think
we're playing baseball
in gym class today,
so I can look forward
to sucking hard
in right field.
Well, just remember,
don't let the hitter get
the ball over your head...
Unless it's
out of the park.
Well, yeah.
Bye.
I get off early today.
All I have
is the Watsons-Willard
day bride's tractor sale.
You want me
to pick you up?
Yeah.
Then we can go to the drive-in
and make out tonight.
There hasn't been
a drive-in here
since the early
seventies, but...
I love you.
Have a good one.
You, too.
Morning.
Derek.
Hey, Tom.
Morning, Joseph.
That's wild.
Hey, Tom.
Morning, Pat.
Hey, Mick.
Tom.
Charles is going to be
a little late this morning.
Is he drunk again?
Yeah, I guess.
Hey, who's the craziest
woman you ever dated?
Me?
Yeah. Mick and me,
we were talking
about some of the girls
we went with.
Uh-huh.
He once dated a girl
who used to attack him
in the middle of the night.
She what?
Yeah.
She used to have these
crazy goddamn dreams
where instead
of her boyfriend,
I was some kind
of demented killer.
I woke up one night,
she stuck a goddamn fork
in my shoulder.
You're kidding me.
No.
I'm spurting blood.
She's sitting there crying,
going, "baby,
I love you, I love you."
So, what happened?
You broke up
with her, right?
No, I married her.
Hey, it lasted 6 years.
Nobody's perfect,
Tom.
I guess not.
Strike this guy out.
We got 'em. Let's go.
Yeah.
2 out.
One winning run
coming right up, boys.
Go, Bobby!
Whoo!
It's all right, Billy.
Look alive, look alive.
Yeah!
Ball.
Yeah, that's it.
He's got
nothing. He's got nothing.
Let's go, let's go.
One more. Come on, now.
Come on, Bobby.
Yeah.
He's yours, he's yours.
Oh!
Whoo!
Easy, Jack.
Come on, Jack.
Don't drop it, Jack!
That's yours. Come on.
Jinx, Jackie boy!
Oh!
Game over!
Yellows win.
Let's go, guys.
Taylor, Dietrich,
you're on equipment.
Let's go.
Guys, come on.
Good try, Bobby.
You was robbed, Bobby.
Everyone
hit the showers.
Awesome.
Nice.
Good job.
Guess you think you're
hot shit, huh, Stall?
What?
No, I don't.
Little hero here, huh?
Little superstar here.
Little hero saves the day
at the last minute, right?
Bobby, it's just
a game, OK?
It's just
stupid gym class.
Who you calling
stupid?
Ahem. No, I said
gym class was stupid.
"No, I said
gym class was--"
listen to
this little faggot.
Yeah.
You're right.
I'm both little
and a faggot.
You got me
dead to rights.
Come on, chickenshit,
let's do this.
What would be the point?
I mean, you win.
You win, you win.
You've established
your Alpha male standing.
my unworthiness.
But doing violence to me
just seems--ahem--
pointless and cruel,
don't you think?
Let's do this,
you punk bitch.
Shouldn't that be
little punk ass
chickenshit
faggot bitch?
Chickenshit
faggot bitch.
Uh-oh.
God!
Bobby is
a chickenshit.
Hey, good looking.
Where are we going?
Well, Jack's studying
over at Judy Danvers',
and Martha's
taking care of Sarah.
Yeah?
Yeah.
So, where are we going?
We never got to be
teenagers together.
Uh-huh.
I'm going
to fix that.
What's going on
in there?
Keep your shirt on.
I'm coming.
Holy cow.
What?
Do you need some help
with that, big boy?
Uh...
Maybe.
Oh, my God.
What have you done
with my wife?
Ready?
OK!
Go, Wildcats!
No wives in here, mister.
Mmm.
Wow.
Shh.
Quiet. My parents
are in the next room.
Mmm.
You're naughty.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
You are such a bad boy.
Mm-hmm.
Rah, rah,
sis, boom, bah.
Oh.
There wasn't much
of that in high school.
Ah...
Mmm.
Uhh.
What is it?
Huh?
I remember the moment I knew
you were in love with me.
I saw it in your eyes.
I can still see it.
Of course you can.
I still love you.
I'm the luckiest
son of a bitch alive.
You are the best man
I've ever known.
There's no luck
involved.
You want to go down and
get some food or something?
You ever wonder
what kids did for fun
on a Saturday night
100 years ago?
I don't know.
I guess
I always figured
they got into
their parents' wagon
and went cruising up
and down their main drag
playing loud banjo music
and acting like idiots.
So, you think this is
as good as it gets?
For us?
Yeah.
For now.
Eventually,
we--we grow up,
we get jobs,
we have affairs,
and we become
alcoholics.
Ahem.
You know, sometimes,
you depress me.
Hey, that's what
I'm good at.
Give me that.
Hey, isn't that
that Stall faggot?
Yeah.
You should go
kick his ass.
I'm going to.
Who the fuck was that?
I don't know, and
I don't want to know.
Can I just say how sick I am
of these Podunk towns
and the goddamn Podunks
who live in 'em?
Do you think
if you keep saying that
it's actually going
to change anything?
I am so sick
of this shit.
Yeah,
you made that clear
about 10,000 Miles ago.
Now, if you haven't got
a better idea,
I don't want to hear
about it anymore.
We are so
goddamned broke.
Yeah, well...
That's easy to fix.
No way.
Come on.
Mm-mmm.
Are you going to go
shoot pool with Jerry?
Maybe.
Thanks, Tom.
Thanks, Mick--
good as ever.
There you go.
See you in church.
Yep. Have
a good evening.
You, too. See you
tonight, Charlotte.
Yeah.
See you.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Aw, it's all right,
old fella.
Just closing up,
fellas.
Coffee...
Black.
The same.
I'll have some pie--
some of that
lemon meringue pie.
Guys, guys, I'm sorry.
I'm--we're closed.
I said...
Coffee!
OK.
I guess
we can handle that.
It's not very fresh.
You can go home now,
Charlotte.
Just leave the pie.
OK.
Billy...
You're going to be sticking
around for a while, honey.
Tom?
Don't fuckin' move.
Sir, we don't--we don't
carry much cash here.
You gentlemen
are certainly welcome
to all of it.
Oh, I know that,
asshole, believe me.
I do know that.
Aah!
Shut up, bitch!
OK, Billy...
Let's show this asshole
we mean business.
What? Her?
Yes, her.
Do her!
Aah!
Uhh.
Unh.
I'm telling you,
those men were--
they were going
to kill us.
They were going
to kill us,
and if it weren't
for Tom...
He's a hero.
...in conjunction
with several murders
in those states.
Now, Tom Stall
is a family man
with longstanding ties
to this community.
Tom Stall was just
another hard-working
small business
owner and operator
in Millbrook, Indiana,
but now--
um, one of the guys
had a...
A gun to my head,
and Tom--
he was amazing. He--
Hi, baby.
Hey, honey.
How you doing?
How are you?
Uhh.
Are you as sick of
hearing about me as I am?
No, I kind of like it.
Look.
Your picture's
in the paper.
Oh, God.
Careful.
Hi, guys.
Mom.
Can I--can I
get up now?
You got it, dad?
Yeah.
Way to go, Tommy.
We're all
here for you, Tom.
Way to go, Tom.
Hi, sweetie.
Oh, that's so nice.
Thank you so much
for coming.
We're in Millbrook,
just outside the home
of American hero
Tom Stall,
who's just now returning
from the hospital
with his family.
Mr. Stall,
Jenny Wyatt, WRPK news.
I have a few
questions for you.
How did it feel
when you saw the guns
of those ruthless killers
pointed
directly at you?
How did it feel?
Yeah.
Not very good.
Were you surprised,
though,
by your own reaction
to the situation?
Uh...
What I did was...
I mean, anybody
would have done that.
It was just...
It was a terrible thing.
I think we'll all
be better off
when we get past it.
Yeah, but you really went
beyond what the average--
I--I need to--
I really need to be
with my family.
Thanks.
I'm Jenny Wyatt
in Millbrook,
and that was Tom Stall--
American hero,
man of few words.
Well, I guess that's all
we're going to get.
Man, it's good
to be home.
I hope there won't be
too much more of that.
Hey, dad, they all just
want to interview you
because of what you did.
You're a hero, dad.
Ha ha!
No, I'm not.
I just got lucky--
very lucky.
This will all blow over
as soon as they find
some other hot story.
Yeah.
Maybe the Lydons
will have
another 2-headed cow.
You guys aren't
thinking big enough.
You could probably do
Larry king live, dad.
That would be cool.
Stop it.
Look at this--
more reporters.
Are they
still there?
Yeah. Now there's some car
parked across the road.
They're just
sitting there.
Huh.
Does anyone want some tea?
I'll take some, mom.
Yes, please.
Unh.
Aw, jeez.
Hey, Edie.
Hi.
How are you?
Did you go
to the shop?
Yes, sir.
Hello.
Hey, bill.
Hi, honey.
Hi, baby.
How are you?
Oh, I'm all right.
What brings you by?
I just wanted to see
how you were doing.
Doing good.
Business is great.
Just can't keep up.
Yeah, it's busy.
Oh, look,
more reporters. Nice.
They don't look
like reporters.
Grilled cheese
is ready.
Got fries and
a strawberry shake.
Hello.
Welcome to Stall's.
Would you gentlemen
like some coffee?
You're the hero.
Uh, I don't know, sir.
I was just--
nah, you're
the big hero.
You sure took care
of those 2 bad men.
I really don't like
talking about it, sir.
We're trying to get
back to normal here.
So, can I offer
you gentlemen some coffee?
Sure. Give me some coffee.
Make it black...
Yes, sir.
Joey.
And--and
your friends?
They don't drink coffee.
It doesn't agree
with them...
Joey.
Who's Joey?
You are.
My name's Tom, sir.
Of course it is.
Mmm. That's
good coffee.
Thank you, sir.
If I were to find coffee
as good in Philadelphia,
but you know that,
don't you, Tom?
Heh.
No, actually,
I don't.
I've never been
to Philadelphia.
Pennsylvania? Is that where
you gentlemen are from?
Yeah, like
you don't know.
Sorry. Did--did we
know each other?
You tell me.
No.
We don't know
each other.
Come on, Joey.
Cut the crap.
My name is Tom.
Joey Cusack.
Your name is
You're from Philly.
Mm-hmm. OK.
Whatever.
Uh-huh.
Excuse me, gentlemen,
if you're not going
to order anything,
my husband and I
would appreciate it
if you would be
on your way.
We ate
on the road.
It's all right.
It's OK.
We really are
very busy here today,
as you can see.
Um, so if you gentlemen
aren't going to be eating,
I really should offer your
seats to paying customers.
Hmm.
Well...
Now we're
paying customers.
I can't take this.
It shouldn't be
any problem for you.
What is that
supposed to mean?
Mr. Fogarty's just making
conversation here.
Well, whatever you
want to call it,
this conversation
is over.
I think he wants us
to leave, Mr. Fogarty.
Do you know
what he does
when he don't like people,
Mr. Fogarty?
Yeah.
I'm scared.
We should leave before he goes
all dirty Harry on us.
I want to thank you
for the coffee, Joey.
It really is very good.
It's Tom.
My name's Tom Stall.
Excuse me.
What are you doing?
Who are you calling?
Hi--hi, Molly.
This is Edie Stall.
Is he in?
I'm fine, thanks.
You're calling Sam?
Yes.
Is there a problem
with my driving, officer?
Can I see
your license, sir?
Sure.
I thought I was
under the limit.
Is there some problem
I should know about?
What's your business
in Millbrook, sir?
We're tourists.
And what business did you
have at Stall's diner today?
We heard the coffee
was terrific.
Let me make something clear
to you and...
To Mr. Mulligan.
Uh-huh?
This is a nice town.
We have
nice people here.
We take care
of our nice people.
Do you understand me?
Yeah, sure.
Don't let me see you
around again.
You keep up the good
work, officer.
Charles Roarke,
Philadelphia.
Indicted on 3 counts
of murder.
Frank Mulligan,
out of New York,
indicted on one count
of murder.
Questioned in relation to
dozens of acts of violence
that you don't want
to hear about.
Both men work
for Carl Fogarty.
He's the fella
with the eye.
He spent 15 years
in prison
on several counts
of assault.
He's suspected in
half a dozen murders
and more disappearances.
Tom, these guys
are organized crime
from the east coast.
Now, they're
the real thing.
They're bad men.
Jesus.
Jesus, honey.
I have to ask you
a question.
Are you in some kind of
Witness Protection plan?
Sam.
Some kind of what?
This is no
laughing matter, Edie.
Of course he's not, Sam.
I'd just like to
hear Tom say that.
OK. No. No, I'm not
in a witness program.
Those men just have
the wrong guy.
They must've seen me on TV,
and I guess, uh,
I reminded them
of this Johnny guy.
Joey.
J-Joey somebody.
I mean, good lord.
The idea of me--
I never honestly
believed it,
but I had to ask.
I've done
some research
on this, uh,
Joey Cusack.
I didn't find
anything.
But there is
a Richie Cusack
in Philadelphia.
Apparently,
he's the head
of some kind of
crime syndicate
in that city.
Men like this
come to our town
and start harassing
a citizen,
we have to
take them seriously.
Sure.
All right.
So, if you folks
see them
coming around,
you let me know.
Will do.
I'm sorry, Sam.
Do you want a piece
of pie or something?
Ah, no, thanks, Edie.
I'd love to, but I've
gotta get back to work.
Thank you.
Thanks for coming.
Uh, Sam?
Thank you.
It's good to know you're
watching out for us.
Come on, Tom.
You know we look out
for our own here.
Good night.
See ya. Thanks.
Huh.
Don't worry.
They're as good as gone.
Sorry.
It's over
and done with.
OK.
Honey. Can you
get that, hon?
Come on, come on!
Hello?
The shotgun, Edie!
Get the shotgun!
Tom, Tom--
Tom, what's wrong?
They're coming
to the house!
Who's coming to the house?
Just grab it!
Do it and be ready!
OK, stop. Are you serious?
I'll be there
as soon as I can.
Shit.
Come on.
Oh, shit.
Oh, come on.
Come on.
Edie!
Oh.
Ohh, fuck. Tom!
Tom. Tom,
what's going on?
I--
huh?
I--I don't know,
baby.
Jesus.
What's going on?
I don't--I don't know.
Ohh.
Let me call Sam,
all right?
No, don't.
OK.
I--I don't even know--
I--I don't know why
I thought--
I--
mom?
It's OK, baby.
Yeah. Uh...Ha ha.
I--
I--I--I think
I'm losing my mind.
No, no, no. OK.
You're not
losing your mind.
You've been through
some serious trauma.
All right?
I'm here for you, baby.
We're all here for you.
It's all right.
It's gonna be OK.
Mom?
You haven't forgotten about
my new shoes, have you?
Gosh, no.
It's my top priority
for the day.
How could I forget?
You all right?
Yeah, yeah.
Hi--hi, sweetie.
Honey, just get ready
for school.
I'll speak to you
afterwards, all right?
OK.
Come on.
Let's go shopping.
Hey.
Careful. It's loaded.
Why was mom running
around the house with that?
What's going on, dad?
False alarm.
Nothing to worry about.
I am worried.
You're sweating.
You're soaked, dad.
What kind of
false alarm?
What did you mean,
you think you--
you think you're
losing your mind?
Some mob guys
showed up at the diner.
They saw me on TV,
and they came by
to take a look at me.
Yeah.
Yeah, I heard
about that. Uh...
So...
They thought
they knew me.
They thought...
I was somebody else.
Heh. That's weird.
Yeah. Weird.
And I guess, um...
Well, I guess
they don't like this guy
they think you are.
Apparently not.
And, um,
and I guess I--
I guess--
I guess they want
to kill this guy
they think you are?
See, that's--that's
the losing my mind part.
I mean, I have no reason
to think that.
It's just...
I was down at work,
and, you know,
suddenly I thought
maybe--
maybe...
They'd come
looking around.
You know?
And, uh...
And then you came running
back here to save us?
Yeah,
something silly like that.
I'm sorry.
What if you're right?
Then we deal with it.
OK.
Now,
look what I just found.
It's my last pair
in this style,
and it's exactly
your size.
Just try these on.
They should fit like a dream.
How do they feel?
Good. Yeah,
I think I like them.
I have a pair
of these myself.
They look great
and they really last.
Really? OK.
I'll take them.
And I needed a pair
for her as well.
Sarah?
Uh, ma'am?
The shoes--
I have to find
my daughter.
I can't let you leave
the store with the shoes.
OK, OK, OK. Sarah!
Sarah?
Sarah. Sarah...
Don't ever
do that again, OK?
I'm sorry, mommy.
But look. They have
the new Vespa dolls.
Nothin' to worry about,
Mrs. Stall.
I've been watching
over her.
You stay the fuck
away from my family,
you son of a bitch.
There's no need
for that kind of language,
Mrs. Stall.
Listen to me.
I don't know what you want,
and I don't really care.
You should care about
what I want, Mrs. Stall,
because I want something
from your husband
that might affect you,
might change your life.
My husband
does not know you.
He wouldn't know you,
somebody like you.
Oh, he knows
Carl Fogarty, all right.
He knows me intimately.
See?
This isn't
a completely dead eye.
It still works a bit.
The problem is, the only
thing I can see with it
is Joey Cusack.
And it can see
right through him.
Right through
your husband, Edie.
See what's inside him,
what makes him tick.
He's still the same guy.
No.
He's still
crazy fuckin' Joey.
And you know it,
don't you?
I know that my husband
is Tom Stall.
That's what I know.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Well, why don't
you ask Tom
about his older
brother Richie?
He doesn't--
ask Tom about how he tried
to rip my eye out
with barbed wire.
And ask him, Edie,
how come he's so good
at killing people?
If I see you
within 500 feet of me
or my children or my husband,
I'll have you arrested.
Heh heh heh heh.
Can I possibly make myself
any clearer than that?
No, no, Mrs. Stall,
you can't.
I thank you
for your time.
You have
an enchanting daughter.
And, Mrs. Stall...
Don't forget
your shoes.
Heh heh heh heh.
So,
how's your dad?
I don't know.
A little weird.
Well, after what
he went through?
I mean, actually
killing someone?
I mean, that's enough
to freak anybody out.
Yeah. I guess.
So, your old man's some
kind of tough guy, huh?
What's he think
of his wimp son?
You think
he'd take this shit?
he'd make jokes?
Go on, bitch.
Say something funny.
Bobby, leave him alone.
Shut up, skank.
Uh-oh.
He's gettin' mad.
Jack, let's just
get out of here, OK?
Jack, he's an asshole.
You know that.
He doesn't mean shit.
Let's just go.
Let's just
get out of here, OK?
Yeah, puss.
Run away.
Goddamn,
I bet your daddy
would be real
ashamed by you.
Go ahead, bitch.
Say something funny.
Make me laugh.
Uhh!
Ohh!
OK,
you motherfucker!
Get over there,
you son of a bitch!
Ohh!
Come here.
Are you laughin'?
Are you laughin' now,
you motherfucking
cocksucking piece of shit?!
What the hell
were you thinking?
I wasn't thinking.
Obviously not.
Bobby's been riding me
all year, dad.
He's a jerk.
He's a jerk?
Yeah. He's a jerk.
That's no excuse.
You stand up to him.
You don't put him
in the hospital!
Oh, big deal.
It's the best thing
anyone could've
done to him.
Besides,
I only got suspended.
It is a big deal!
His parents say
they might sue us.
There could be
assault charges.
We can't
afford that, Jack.
We don't have
that kind of money.
Oh, what? Mom's not
gonna take the case?
Oh, whatever, dad--
listen, smart mouth!
In this family, we do
not solve our problems
by hitting people!
No, in this family,
we shoot them!
Ah!
Jack.
Honey,
have you seen Jack?
What?
What's wrong, baby?
Fogarty and his men
followed us to the mall.
He what?
Call Sam. Should--
should we call Sam?
We should call--
I already
took care of it, honey.
I already took care of it.
Went down to the courthouse,
got a restraining order.
A lot of good
that'll do.
Well, it's something.
At least
we could have him arrested
if he ever
comes around here again.
You're right.
But I have
to tell you something.
What?
This man Fogarty
really believes
that you're
this Joey Cusack.
I mean...
The things that he told me
this afternoon--
what things?
Things. Just bullshit.
But he's, uh...
He's sure that it's you.
And we have to convince him
that it's not.
Well, I don't think
he's interested
in examining my DNA.
Get off our property.
We'll go, Joey.
We just want you
to come with us.
Come back to Philly,
see some people.
I told you,
I have never been
to Philadelphia.
Heh. You almost believe
your own crap, don't you?
You know, you're trying
so hard to be this other guy.
It's painful to watch.
Charlie.
Hey.
Look what we found.
Come on.
Yeah?
Ha ha ha.
Mom!
Jack!
No! Edie! Edie!
Mom!
Edie! No! No!
Jack!
Let go,
you son of a bitch!
Come here.
Wait.
Mom.
Don't make us
hurt the kid, Joey.
We just want you to come
for a little trip with us
down memory Lane.
Put the popgun down.
Come over and talk to us.
Baby, wait.
Edie...
I will get him.
I'll get him.
Please.
Go up to Sarah.
Go up to her.
Do it.
Put the gun down.
Put it down, Joey.
Come closer.
A little further.
Come on.
Go back to the house, Jack.
Go on.
You see how cozy
it can be
when you decide
to play nice?
Now, come on, Joey.
Get in the car.
You won't need
your toothbrush.
We'll take care
of everything.
I think it'd be better
if you'd just leave now.
Joey.
Come on, Joey,
let's go.
Ahh!
Uhh!
Uhh! Uhh!
Ohh! Ohh!
Uhh!
Tom!
Fuck.
Mommy, what's wrong?
It's OK.
You got anything to say
before I blow your brains out,
you miserable prick?
I should've killed you
back in Philly.
Yeah, Joey.
You should have.
Uhh!
Uhh.
Edie.
Honey, are you OK?
Tell me the truth.
The truth?
Please. You can
do that, can't you?
You can do that,
can't you? Please?
What do you think
you heard?
It's not what I heard.
It's what I saw.
I saw Joey.
I saw you turn into Joey
right before my eyes.
I saw a killer--the one
Fogarty warned me about.
You did kill men
back in Philly,
didn't you?
Did you do it for money,
or did you do it
because you enjoyed it?
Joey did, both.
I didn't--
Tom Stall didn't.
Oh, God.
Oh, my God.
Oh, God, it's
really happening.
Oh.
What are you,
like, some multiple
personality schizoid?
It's like flipping
a switch
back and forth for you?
I never expected
to see Joey again.
Oh, yeah. Joey.
What, was he in hiding?
Was he dead?
I thought he was.
I thought I killed
Joey Cusack.
I went out to the desert,
and I killed him.
Oh, my God.
I spent 3 years
becoming Tom Stall.
Edie, you have
to know this.
I wasn't really born again
until I met you.
I was nothing.
I don't believe you.
I can't believe
this is happening.
I can't believe this is
fucking happening!
You didn't grow up
in Portland.
And you never talk about
your adopted parents
because
you don't have any!
And our name.
Jesus Christ,
my name.
Jack's name.
Sarah's name?
Stall? Tom Stall?
Did you just
make that up?
Where did that name
come from?
I mean...
It was available.
Yeah.
I guess
I was available, too.
Hey, Jack.
What am I supposed
to call you now?
You're supposed
to call me dad.
That's what I am--
your dad.
Are you really?
So, you're some kind of
closet mobster dad?
I mean, if I go rob
Millikan's drug store,
will you ground me
if I don't give you
a piece of the action?
What, dad?
You tell me.
Please, son.
Don't.
If I talk to Sam
about you,
will you
have me whacked?
Jack.
Tom?
Hey, Sam.
How are you doing?
Good to see you
up and around.
Yeah.
You had her
runnin' yet?
Yeah,
for a second there.
She's coming back
to life.
Ah, shit.
Tom...
I got a problem.
Want to come inside
for a minute?
I've been running
through it all
for the last couple days.
It just doesn't fit.
What doesn't fit?
None of it.
Is that Edie
coming home?
Yeah.
Well, we don't have
to do this now.
Might as well.
Hi, Sam.
Edie.
How you doing?
I'm OK.
You want some coffee?
No, I'm good.
So, what brings you
out here?
Well, Tom and I were just
talking about that.
Mmm.
I'd like to hear it.
Well, it's just that...
None of this
makes any sense.
Mmm.
These are serious
secretive men.
I mean, they wouldn't have
come out here,
they wouldn't have
gone through all this,
exposed themselves
like this
unless they were dead certain
they had the right man.
So, what are you
saying, Sam?
I'm saying I think
I need to hear the truth.
The truth?
The truth.
Sam, you've got too much
time on your hands.
I'm sorry?
Tom is...
Tom is
who he says he is.
That's all
that really matters.
Sam, hasn't this family
suffered enough?
Well...
Goddamn.
Edie.
It's OK.
I guess I'll be going.
You folks give me a ring
if you need anything.
Anything at all,
understand?
Thanks.
You...
Edie.
Edie!
Get off of me!
Unh!
Fuck you, Joey!
Aah! Get off!
Uhh!
Ohh!
Ohh. Ohh.
Oh, my God.
Oh, God.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Mmm.
Uhh.
Hello.
Hey, Bro-ham.
You're still pretty good
with the killing.
That's exciting.
Richie.
Yeah, it's Richie.
What do you say, Joey?
Are you going
to come see me?
Or do I have
to come see you?
What's that
supposed to mean?
Uh, Jenny cream.
Bottle.
You ruben?
Yeah.
You Joey?
Yeah, I'm Joey.
So, what do we do now?
You finish your beer,
then I take you to see
Richie in the escalade.
Nice houses.
Richie's a very upscale
kind of guy.
Nice gate.
Yeah.
We're here.
Home, sweet home.
Got to frisk you.
Nah. I'll save you
the trouble.
I'm not packing.
I got to frisk you.
All right.
I don't smell very good.
I've been driving
pretty much non-stop
15 to 16 hours.
I'll hold my nose.
Can you believe
that place
is still standing,
the track and turf?
Didn't you bang
Jill Levy there
right on the bar
in front of everybody?
I never banged
Jill Levy.
Well, you should've.
She was--she was something.
How you doing,
Richie?
Mmm.
Yeah.
It's been a long,
long time, Bro-ham.
Yeah.
Come with me.
You want anything?
Nah.
So, you like
that farm life?
Milking cows
and shit?
I don't have a farm.
No?
Fogarty thought you lived
on some kind of farm.
Said you could
smell pig.
How that old fart
would know
what a pig smells like,
I don't know,
but that's what he said.
Ahem.
Do you like
being married?
What?
Do you like
being married?
Does it work for you?
I can't see it
working for me.
I never felt the urge,
you know?
A lot of great looking
women in the world.
I never met one
made me want to give up
all the others.
Sure, you can
fuck around,
but it's so much
goddamn work, you know?
Keeping it quiet.
It's not worth
the effort.
Don't see the upside.
You see the upside,
Joey?
Yeah, Richie, I do.
I do now.
I'm pretty pissed
at you, Bro-ham.
You could've called.
You could've dropped
a postcard in the mail.
We're brothers. What'd you
think would happen?
I thought that business
would come first.
Well, yeah.
Yeah, I know.
Tch. I know.
What am I going to do?
You bust up
a made man's place.
You killed
some of his guys.
You take his eye.
Jesus, Joey,
you took his eye.
Barbed wire,
wasn't it?
That's disgusting.
You always were
the crazy one.
Not anymore.
Yeah, I heard.
You're living
the American dream.
You really bought
into it, didn't you?
You've been
this other guy
almost as long
as you've been yourself.
Hey, when you dream,
are you still Joey?
Joey's been dead
a long time.
And yet here you sit...
Big as life.
You know you cost me
a lot of time and money.
Before you pulled
that shit with Fogarty,
I was a shoe-in
to take over
when the boss croaked--
a shoe-in.
It was made very clear
to me, Joey.
I had to clean up
your mess,
or nothing was ever
going to happen for me.
You got no idea
how much shit I had to pull
to get back in
with those guys.
You cost me...
A hell of a lot, Joey,
a hell of a lot.
Looks like you're doing
all right over here.
Yeah, I am, I am.
I'm still behind
the eightball...
Because of you.
There's a certain
lack of respect,
a certain lack of trust.
The boys in Boston
are just waiting
for me to go down.
You always were
a problem for me, Joey.
When mom brought you home
from the hospital,
I tried to strangle you
in your crib.
I guess all kids
try to do that.
She caught me,
whacked the daylights
out of me.
I've heard that story.
Well, what do you think?
Better late than never?
Richie...
I'm here to make peace.
Tell me what I got to do
to make things right.
You could do something,
I guess.
You could die, Joey.
Ooh!
Uhh!
Unh!
Oh!
Uhh!
Uhh! Ohh!
How do you fuck that up?
Uhh!
What are you going to do,
give him mouth-to-mouth?
Did you see my brother?
Fuckin' leave this
and let's just kill
that little fuck!
Jesus, Joey.
Jesus, Richie.