Jane!
You didn't take your pills again...
C'mon... be a good girl... drink up.
And now try and get some sleep.
Please, Richard, stay here with me.
I have to be in Oxford
at 10 in the morning.
I have to check out all the
forms... l'll be busy for a while.
No Richard! Please, don't leave, please!
Ok, I'll wait here
until you fall asleep.
I can't! I can't!
Jane! Please Jane, look at me!
Oh Richard, help me, please!
C'mon Jane... calm down!
No thanks... Oh damn, it's late!
I'm missing the 8:40 train.
I'm very sorry to leave you alone.
Barbara's supposed to call me later...
I bet she'll tell you about
her psychiatrist again!
She thinks he could help me...
Sure! He's a quack like all the
others, always spouting Freud.
Trying to pull you in
with the same old nonsense!
You shouldn't talk like
that about Dr. Burton.
After all Barbara works with him and
if she appreciates him, it means that...
Oh, sure. I have no
problems with your sister
but please Jane, leave
psychoanalysis out of it!
But Richard... you don't know what
happens to me when I'm sleeping!
It's just weakness. Your body is
still weak after the operation.
You don't think I know how you
feel about losing your baby?
The baby was also mine
and I suffered too!
Goodbye dear... come back soon!
Goodnight, love. It
was a fantastic evening.
All the same Richard should be grateful
to you. If you hadn't helped him
with that psycho-technical exam,
he would never have got his job.
Obviously he holds me responsible
for what happened after that...
What do you mean?
Having introduced him to you.
What's the stuff he gives to you?
A concentration of vitamins. I
feel sick when I take them but...
I think Richard takes
himself too seriously.
After all he's just a pharmaceutical
salesman, not a doctor.
Don't judge him badly.
He just wants to help me.
Giving you all those vitamins?
Taking so many vitamins without
medical supervision could be dangerous.
I don't know what to do... I know he
loves me, but he can't understand me.
Day after day, it's like
I'm falling into a pit.
This is nonsense, Jane! You
need a good psychiatrist.
That's why I set up an
appointment with Dr. Burton
Sit down dear, he'll
see you in a minute.
Jane, come in.
That woman was your mother?
Yes.
How old were you?
Five.
I don't know if you know
this, but you began treatment
right where it usually ends.
That is, from the trauma you
suffered during childhood.
Don't you think this is a good sign?
I'd like to believe you,
but is that really the case?
It's only an interview. Ever spoken
with your husband about this problem?
Well... Richard isn't... Richard
and I aren't married yet.
And that stops you
from confiding in him?
No but... you see, he wouldn't understand.
In his opinion everything comes
from the car accident that...
...where I lost my baby.
Stillborn?
Yes.
And from that moment you couldn't
have full sexual relations, right?
Yes, that's right, but it isn't
the car accident, or even the memory
of the baby that stops
me. It's the other thing.
The man with the knife?
Yes, but how can I tell that to Richard?
He'd probably end up hating me. His
life with me is already so difficult...
and I don't want to lose
him. I have to get better.
Are you afraid of the dark?
No.
Tell me, have you ever felt
you were living out your dreams?
Yes. In the waiting room, there
was a man... your patient I suppose.
He looked at me with the same
eyes that are in my nightmare.
Are you really sure?
He was sitting in the other room!
I'm sorry to contradict you, but I
never have my patients wait together.
Come with me please.
But... he was here. I'm
sure of that. He's gone.
Apparently.
You saw him, right? He was
here, sitting in this armchair.
Yes, sure. He asked for you, but
he wasn't one of your patients.
I told him to wait. Maybe
he was tired of waiting.
I must apologize, Miss. You
were right, there was someone.
However, the point is that, whoever
he was, you were scared of him.
In our next meeting we must
find out why that happened.
When can I come back, Doctor?
Barbara will take care
of the appointment.
For the moment I suggest that you
stop taking your husband's vitamins.
You are not ill by any means. You
must convince yourself of that.
Your worst enemy is loneliness.
Consider yourself neither crazy
nor someone who's seeing things.
Real madmen never think
of themselves as crazy.
What do you want from me!
Excuse me.
I can open the door if you want.
After you. I live on
the top floor, and you?
I live on the third floor, thanks. I've
only been here a few days. I'm Mary.
I'm Jane. Nice to meet you.
I've been living here for three
months and I hardly know anyone.
Here in the city it's
hard to make friends.
We people from the suburbs
haven't learned not to be nosy yet.
Would you like some tea? Tea
for me is still a social ritual
I hate having it alone.
I don't know. Maybe I shouldn't.
Waiting for someone?
You're very kind, but my husband
is tired when he gets home from work
and I have to make dinner.
Well I don't want to force you,
but it's early. It's only 5 o'clock!
Ok, I'll have some tea.
Make yourself at home.
Don't stand there, come in.
At the door you seemed
very scared, am I right?
It's true. Someone
was following me here.
Me, I'm scared of the time when
men won't follow me any more!
How do you know he was a man?
Men have been following
women since the world began.
With or without a club.
It's very nice here. How
did you fix it up so quickly?
It was already like this. I prefer them
already furnished. I just add the mess.
More cookies?
No thanks, I have to go.
I'd like to prepare something fro
Richard that's not out of a can.
Mary, why don't you come have
dinner with us? I'd like that.
Absolutely not! I don't want to
come between a couple of newlyweds.
Ok. See you tomorrow. Richard
goes to work and I'm all alone.
Would you like have lunch together?
Sure. Here at my place.
I can even make something
that's not out of a can.
We could go shopping together... OK?
Right. So... l'll see you
at 10 tomorrow morning.
Yes, thanks. Bye, Mary.
Hello?
Miss Jane Harrison?
Yes, who's speaking?
I'm Franciscus Clay, a
lawyer. I must see you.
See me?
Yes. Can you come to my
office tomorrow at 3:30?
Wait a second...
The address is Rolands House 5
So I'll expect you.
But... what about? Hello?
The eggs!
Jane! What's going on?
Good evening.
I would have preferred you ask my
advice before taking her to Dr. Burton.
I don't believe in psychoanalysis.
I've never seen anybody come out cured.
On the contrary I think it's just a way
of convincing people that the
world is populated only by madmen.
Go on... your logic is amusing.
You should take less care of Jane
and more of yourself, Barbara.
Sorry, could you pass me the
dress on the chair please?
Why do you hide yourself
under this stuff?
You surprise me, Richard. Think I can
still take your compliments seriously?
This time it's not even so you can get
a good recommendation
for a lousy salesman job.
You've never forgiven
me for that, have you?
Janet will continue with Dr. Burton
with or without your permission.
Have you ever asked yourself why
Janet hasn't agreed to marry you yet?
I've thought about it for a long time.
And I'm sure it's partly your
fault too. You treat her like a baby
who still can't make
a decision on her own.
Jane is still a slave to her
childhood. Maybe that's also my fault
but at the moment you don't give her
the reassurance she's looking for.
You and your stupid
psychoanalysis books!
Why are you blaming other
people for what's your fault?
It's all your fault even
according to your own crude logic!
If you hadn't hit that tree with your
car, Janet wouldn't have problems now!
I often walk in this
park. I like the solitude.
Hear the birds? They are
complaining about our being here.
They're very resentful, you know.
Not as much as men are. This
might sound strange to you, Mary
but I'm sure that someone is
chasing me. Someone coming very deep
from my childhood. Do you
believe in that sort of thing?
I believe in a lot more.
Don't worry about it... c'mon!
I had my problems too, not like
yours, but maybe more serious.
But I got rid of them.
How?
Do you know what a Black Mass is?
You're scaring me...
It makes sense to be afraid
sometimes. You have to find it
and it'll disappear.
But... what do you want from me?
Me?
See? You look like a scared
little baby without her mom.
Do you really want to get well?
It's all I want.
Don't think about psychiatrists
anymore. I know the right person for you.
Who?
My friends don't like questions. The
just want trust. They're waiting for you.
When?
Do you really want to come?
Even tonight if you want...
I have a meeting with a
lawyer who called me yesterday.
Make sure to be back home at
5.30. I'll be out at the door.
Why so late? What happened? We
can't be so late getting there.
But... what's the matter?
That man I was talking
about... he tried to...
Rape you?
Kill me!
I think it's better put off for
another time... let's go to my house.
No... l'm afraid I'm going crazy!
Let's go where you wanted, right now.
But you drive. I couldn't.
Ok.
Oh Richard, my love, my dear love!
Now everything's like before, Jane.
Yes but... I don't know... lt
doesn't seem real to me...
And me? Do you think I'm real?
Tomorrow I'll take the day off. We'll
go out to lunch. Would you like that?
When I told Barbara that I'm not
going to Burton anymore she hung up.
Let's not talk about it anymore.
Sorry, I have to phone a client.
You're here! Can you tell
me what happened to you?
What are you hiding behind you?
So now you rummage in my books...
And you? You read this stuff now?
I bought it in a used bookstore. Could
you explain why you ran away like that?
And where were you?
The phone was broken. I had a phone
meeting with a client in Liverpool.
I had to call him from another phone
nearby... what's so odd about that?
Nothing... nothing...
Welcome back, Jane.
We were expecting you.
She offers herself to you!
Free from her fears... forever!
You're free Jane.
Now that woman doesn't exist
any more. She gave you to us.
Now she's free not to exist.
No, Mary!
It's time to say goodbye Jane. Be happy!
No, Mary, I don't want to!
Now you're one of us, Jane.
You can't turn your back on us any more!
Come, he's waiting for you.
No, this can't be real! It's horrible!
Careful what you say!
What have I done?
Did you drug me?
Or is it just a nightmare...
It's all a nightmare.
Where's Mary?
With us you won't be alone any
more! You belong to us forever, Jane.
Where is Mary? I want to see her!
As you wish. Mary wanted to be free.
Anyone who wants to go away
has to bring a new adept.
Mary brought you and now she's free.
Permanently.
Take care of her.
You were sleeping so soundly
that I didn't want to wake you.
See you tonight. I love
you very much. Richard.
Mary! It's not possible!
It couldn't be real!
Where's Mary?
She lives here! She must be here!
Sorry? How dare you barge into my home!
A woman named Mary
lives here... Where is she?
Look, I don't know who you are and
what you want, but I won't answer
anyone who barges into my house
like this! But... Are you all right?
It's OK... it's over. I'm sorry,
but I was here with a woman...
The same furniture... Everything... I
couldn't have dreamt it!
I had the furniture put in last
week, but I got here just last night.
Maybe you met a person from the
agency... they took care of everything...
Wait!
Here's the address, you can ask them.
Thanks. Sorry for my behavior
but... I had no way of knowing...
You can stay here a while if
you want until you feel better...
No thanks. I've bothered you enough.
Hi, love, how are you?
Unfortunately we went on until late.
I'll be there tomorrow morning... Hello?
It's me, Richard... What's going on?
Oh Richard! Come home!
Jane? What happened to you?
Come back Richard!
Sure, sure, with the first train... are
you listening? Say something!
I can't now... but everything will
be all right if you come back!
Stay home, don't move. Wait for me!
Ok, but hurry!
Doctor's Burton's office?
Sorry. I'm Barbara's sister. Is she in?
I tried her house but nobody's there.
Barbara's out of town. The Doctor
sent her to take care of a patient.
Wait! Don't hang up!
I'd like to speak with Dr. Burton.
Call tomorrow morning after 8 a.m.
It's very urgent... please! I'm Dr. Burton's
patient. I'm not well, I need help.
Ok, hold on.
Yes, can I help you?
A man like the one in my dream is
following me! But it's not a nightmare.
He's really here!
Please help me, doctor!
Calm down, Miss. Come to my office.
You can explain everything in person.
I'm scared, I'm scared to death!
Well, I'll send the nurse with my
car. She'll be there in ten minutes.
Now calm down and wait for her.
OK, but hurry up!
Ten minutes, Jane.
It looks like a cabalistic symbol; like
that used by the Jews to indicate God.
It was used in the Middle Ages
by the witches and charlatans
for their black magic rituals.
In that castle that
symbol was everywhere...
So I wasn't dreaming... I
really killed that woman!
Don't be in such a hurry!
Everything could be just a nightmare...
Like what happened tonight. You're
in a clear state of emotional shock
so it's impossible to judge how much
is just a figment of your imagination.
So this is just a hallucination as well?
No, Miss, believe me! The only
thing you need is dreamless sleep.
Take two of these pills and tomorrow
we can talk about all this calmly.
But I am calm, Doctor! OK, I'm not
calm, but I have no intention of sleeping.
You treat me like a
mythomaniac, like a madwoman!
No, don't say that! Trust me and
I'll get you out of this. I promise.
Don't send me away! I don't
want to go home without Richard!
No, sure. I'll bring
you to somewhere quiet.
Are you cold?
Yes, a little bit.
Why does your husband
leave you alone so often?
You know... he works. He's a
salesman. He has to be on the road.
Any other problems between you and
him other than what you've said?
I don't know, money problems... sorry,
but indiscretion is part of my job.
This is my country house. It's closed
in winter. We're here in the summer.
Only the keepers are there now.
Good evening.
Let me introduce you to Mr. May. He
and his wife will be glad to help you.
It's my fault we're coming so late...
Don't worry Miss! You can get used to
it. I don't know if the Doctor told you.
Yes, don't worry about it. I think
you can find a room for tonight.
You're safe here. Unfortunately I
have to get back to my office now.
I have to check my notes for
a convention I'm going to.
Thanks, Doctor.
Call me tomorrow as soon as you wake
up. Tonight I'll be at my office.
OK, Goodnight.
There's a letter for you!
Nobody writes me...
To me neither! It's for my wife.
Stop it Boo Boo. We don't have
a chance with that man anyway!
Barbara? Is Jane with you?
Jane? No, I was out of town. I got
back at dawn. Why? What happened?
Last night I called and she was upset.
I don't know why. She wouldn't say.
You shouldn't leave her alone... Since
you don't believe in psychiatrists!
For God's sake Barbara! This is
no the time to make an issue of it!
Call your doctor and let me know as
soon as possible if he has any news!
OK. Don't worry.
Miss May?
He's here! He killed them!
What are you saying, Miss? OK, I'm
on my way. Calm down... Right away!
Sorry, I have to go.
Doctor... if you know anything...
I don't, but there's nothing
to be worried about yet.
Maybe she left early this
morning... She'll be back soon.
Wait a second...
It was your sister on the phone.
I understood that. What did she want?
She was scared. She's afraid
of being killed. I thought
it was better not to tell him
the truth. I don't like that man.
Maybe it's just a feeling,
but I don't trust him at all.
When Jane was with me she was
fine. Maybe he's the one who...
I don't know. Let me get to your sister.
After, we'll see what can be done.
But he has a right to know.
Try to make up something.
You can't repudiate us Jane! You
should have understood that by now!
Look at this knife... You recognize it?
It's the one that killed your mother...
Your mother tried to leave us years
ago. It's the one you killed Mary with!
No it's not true!
You've crossed the borders of
reality, Jane. You can't go back.
Now the truth is within you!
Go away, damn you! Go away!
So you have to die! It's the only
way to leave us... And you know it.
There's no escape now! You belong to us!
Doctor! Doctor Burton!
You have a mark on your skin... but
you've a deeper mark on your heart
in your flesh and in your
blood... like your mother!
Stop!
Who is it?
It's me.
What do you want?
So you know!
Yes.
How?
You shouldn't have shown
yourself naked that day.
What do you mean?
People marked like you shouldn't
ever show their naked bodies...
I wanted you to see me! I couldn't
allow that hysterical woman to take you!
You don't need that woman, you
need me! Look at me Richard!
I'm yours Richard... and you've always
known it. Don't worry about Jane...
She'll understand someday... She never
gave you anything... she couldn't.
She had to pay for
our mother's betrayal.
The roots of our faith lie far away.
You can be part of us if you want.
You won't be a useless salesman
going traveling from door to door.
You'll become whatever you want.
We're much stronger than you imagine.
This explains why you
wanted to get rid of Jane.
I'd like to have a word with that woman...
I'm sorry, Officer, but they're
administrating a sedative.
Just few seconds...
It's better she rests... She
can't listen to you now.
Jane? Do you hear me?
They didn't want me
to come in but I did.
We must escape Richard!
That man came back!
He's here, I've seen him!
Oh Richard... take me away!
OK, hold on to me. We'll go out
the main door... Nobody will stop us.
Get dressed!
C'mon... hold onto me.
Damn! They must have left
the door open. Wait here.
Help that woman.
You take care of the body.
What happened?
That woman... it seems
she killed her husband.
Make way...
A mysterious case...
Officer! Is that woman the killer?
Just some info...
Jane? Do you hear me? Answer me!
At last! The officer let me see you.
I don't know what's
real any more! Richard...
Maybe I'm dreaming right now and
you're not here... You're not here!
No Miss, you weren't dreaming.
But it's all over now!
George Harris, Glenda Scott, David
Means, Mark Corgan, Recognize 'em?
Betty Ryan, Sylvester Cole,
Clelia Morgan, also known as Mary.
Ex actress, but most of
all drug pusher and addict.
We thought she was dead years
ago but her body's been found
in the cellar of the castle
with the other victims.
What happened to the others?
In jail, except, of course, for the
dead ones, the story turns your stomach.
Unfortunately we're still missing
Gerald McBrian, the High Priest
a regular at all the asylums
for the criminally insane...
But don't worry, we'll catch him!
What about Barbara?
Barbara committed suicide. She was
the diabolical mind behind the sect.
She exploited their rites
for her own criminal purposes.
Send Clay in.
It seems the man who killed your
mother died months ago in New Zealand
and named you and your sister
heirs to a decent fortune.
The lawyer will tell you the details.
Good morning. I called you, Miss,
but you didn't come to the meeting.
I have also written to you... it was
easier to get in touch with your sister
but I also needed your consent.
We're talking about 300,000
pounds. Here's the will.
Now that my sister's committed
suicide... Do I get her share?
Of course.
So... lf I were dead...
Everything would have
gone to your sister.
Today we begin to look for another
house. What about Buckingham Palace?
Elevator! Damn! They left
the door open. Wait for me here.
Oh my God! I've already lived
this moment... Richard, stop!
You killed Barbara! You must die!
You killed Barbara... l've always
known that... I don't know why...
Like now, when I knew that man would
try to kill you in the elevator.
Oh Richard! I'm scared of not
being myself any more... Help me!