Now you're one of us, Jane.
You can't turn your back on us any more!
Come, he's waiting for you.
No, this can't be real! It's horrible!
Careful what you say!
What have I done?
Did you drug me?
Or is it just a nightmare...
It's all a nightmare.
Where's Mary?
With us you won't be alone any
more! You belong to us forever, Jane.
Where is Mary? I want to see her!
As you wish. Mary wanted to be free.
Anyone who wants to go away
has to bring a new adept.
Mary brought you and now she's free.
Permanently.
Take care of her.
You were sleeping so soundly
that I didn't want to wake you.
See you tonight. I love
you very much. Richard.
Mary! It's not possible!
It couldn't be real!
Where's Mary?
She lives here! She must be here!
Sorry? How dare you barge into my home!
A woman named Mary
lives here... Where is she?
Look, I don't know who you are and
what you want, but I won't answer
anyone who barges into my house
like this! But... Are you all right?
It's OK... it's over. I'm sorry,
but I was here with a woman...
The same furniture... Everything... I
couldn't have dreamt it!
I had the furniture put in last
week, but I got here just last night.
Maybe you met a person from the
agency... they took care of everything...
Wait!
Here's the address, you can ask them.
Thanks. Sorry for my behavior
but... I had no way of knowing...
You can stay here a while if
you want until you feel better...
No thanks. I've bothered you enough.
Hi, love, how are you?
Unfortunately we went on until late.
I'll be there tomorrow morning... Hello?
It's me, Richard... What's going on?
Oh Richard! Come home!
Jane? What happened to you?
Come back Richard!
Sure, sure, with the first train... are
you listening? Say something!
I can't now... but everything will
be all right if you come back!
Stay home, don't move. Wait for me!
Ok, but hurry!
Doctor's Burton's office?
Sorry. I'm Barbara's sister. Is she in?
I tried her house but nobody's there.
Barbara's out of town. The Doctor
sent her to take care of a patient.
Wait! Don't hang up!
I'd like to speak with Dr. Burton.
Call tomorrow morning after 8 a.m.
It's very urgent... please! I'm Dr. Burton's
patient. I'm not well, I need help.
Ok, hold on.
Yes, can I help you?
A man like the one in my dream is
following me! But it's not a nightmare.
He's really here!
Please help me, doctor!
Calm down, Miss. Come to my office.
You can explain everything in person.
I'm scared, I'm scared to death!
Well, I'll send the nurse with my
car. She'll be there in ten minutes.
Now calm down and wait for her.
OK, but hurry up!
Ten minutes, Jane.
It looks like a cabalistic symbol; like
that used by the Jews to indicate God.
It was used in the Middle Ages
by the witches and charlatans
for their black magic rituals.
In that castle that
symbol was everywhere...
So I wasn't dreaming... I
really killed that woman!
Don't be in such a hurry!
Everything could be just a nightmare...
Like what happened tonight. You're
in a clear state of emotional shock
so it's impossible to judge how much
is just a figment of your imagination.
So this is just a hallucination as well?
No, Miss, believe me! The only
thing you need is dreamless sleep.
Take two of these pills and tomorrow
we can talk about all this calmly.
But I am calm, Doctor! OK, I'm not
calm, but I have no intention of sleeping.
You treat me like a
mythomaniac, like a madwoman!
No, don't say that! Trust me and
I'll get you out of this. I promise.
Don't send me away! I don't
want to go home without Richard!
No, sure. I'll bring
you to somewhere quiet.
Are you cold?
Yes, a little bit.
Why does your husband
leave you alone so often?
You know... he works. He's a
salesman. He has to be on the road.
Any other problems between you and
him other than what you've said?
I don't know, money problems... sorry,
but indiscretion is part of my job.
This is my country house. It's closed
in winter. We're here in the summer.
Only the keepers are there now.
Good evening.
Let me introduce you to Mr. May. He
and his wife will be glad to help you.
It's my fault we're coming so late...
Don't worry Miss! You can get used to
it. I don't know if the Doctor told you.
Yes, don't worry about it. I think
you can find a room for tonight.
You're safe here. Unfortunately I
have to get back to my office now.
I have to check my notes for
a convention I'm going to.
Thanks, Doctor.
Call me tomorrow as soon as you wake
up. Tonight I'll be at my office.
OK, Goodnight.
There's a letter for you!
Nobody writes me...
To me neither! It's for my wife.
Stop it Boo Boo. We don't have
a chance with that man anyway!
Barbara? Is Jane with you?
Jane? No, I was out of town. I got
back at dawn. Why? What happened?
Last night I called and she was upset.
I don't know why. She wouldn't say.
You shouldn't leave her alone... Since
you don't believe in psychiatrists!
For God's sake Barbara! This is
no the time to make an issue of it!
Call your doctor and let me know as
soon as possible if he has any news!
OK. Don't worry.
Miss May?
He's here! He killed them!
What are you saying, Miss? OK, I'm
on my way. Calm down... Right away!
Sorry, I have to go.
Doctor... if you know anything...
I don't, but there's nothing
to be worried about yet.
Maybe she left early this
morning... She'll be back soon.
Wait a second...
It was your sister on the phone.
I understood that. What did she want?
She was scared. She's afraid
of being killed. I thought
it was better not to tell him
the truth. I don't like that man.
Maybe it's just a feeling,
but I don't trust him at all.
When Jane was with me she was
fine. Maybe he's the one who...
I don't know. Let me get to your sister.
After, we'll see what can be done.
But he has a right to know.
Try to make up something.
You can't repudiate us Jane! You
should have understood that by now!
Look at this knife... You recognize it?
It's the one that killed your mother...
Your mother tried to leave us years
ago. It's the one you killed Mary with!
No it's not true!
You've crossed the borders of
reality, Jane. You can't go back.
Now the truth is within you!
Go away, damn you! Go away!
So you have to die! It's the only
way to leave us... And you know it.
There's no escape now! You belong to us!
Doctor! Doctor Burton!
You have a mark on your skin... but
you've a deeper mark on your heart
in your flesh and in your
blood... like your mother!
Stop!
Who is it?
It's me.
What do you want?
So you know!
Yes.
How?
You shouldn't have shown
yourself naked that day.
What do you mean?
People marked like you shouldn't
ever show their naked bodies...
I wanted you to see me! I couldn't
allow that hysterical woman to take you!
You don't need that woman, you
need me! Look at me Richard!
I'm yours Richard... and you've always
known it. Don't worry about Jane...
She'll understand someday... She never
gave you anything... she couldn't.
She had to pay for
our mother's betrayal.
The roots of our faith lie far away.
You can be part of us if you want.
You won't be a useless salesman
going traveling from door to door.
You'll become whatever you want.
We're much stronger than you imagine.
This explains why you
wanted to get rid of Jane.
I'd like to have a word with that woman...
I'm sorry, Officer, but they're
administrating a sedative.
Just few seconds...
It's better she rests... She
can't listen to you now.
Jane? Do you hear me?
They didn't want me
to come in but I did.
We must escape Richard!
That man came back!
He's here, I've seen him!
Oh Richard... take me away!
OK, hold on to me. We'll go out
the main door... Nobody will stop us.
Get dressed!
C'mon... hold onto me.
Damn! They must have left
the door open. Wait here.
Help that woman.
You take care of the body.
What happened?
That woman... it seems
she killed her husband.
Make way...
A mysterious case...
Officer! Is that woman the killer?
Just some info...
Jane? Do you hear me? Answer me!
At last! The officer let me see you.
I don't know what's
real any more! Richard...
Maybe I'm dreaming right now and
you're not here... You're not here!
No Miss, you weren't dreaming.
But it's all over now!
George Harris, Glenda Scott, David
Means, Mark Corgan, Recognize 'em?
Betty Ryan, Sylvester Cole,
Clelia Morgan, also known as Mary.
Ex actress, but most of
all drug pusher and addict.
We thought she was dead years
ago but her body's been found
in the cellar of the castle
with the other victims.
What happened to the others?
In jail, except, of course, for the
dead ones, the story turns your stomach.
Unfortunately we're still missing
Gerald McBrian, the High Priest
a regular at all the asylums
for the criminally insane...
But don't worry, we'll catch him!
What about Barbara?
Barbara committed suicide. She was
the diabolical mind behind the sect.
She exploited their rites
for her own criminal purposes.
Send Clay in.
It seems the man who killed your
mother died months ago in New Zealand
and named you and your sister
heirs to a decent fortune.
The lawyer will tell you the details.
Good morning. I called you, Miss,
but you didn't come to the meeting.
I have also written to you... it was
easier to get in touch with your sister
but I also needed your consent.
We're talking about 300,000
pounds. Here's the will.
Now that my sister's committed
suicide... Do I get her share?
Of course.
So... lf I were dead...
Everything would have
gone to your sister.
Today we begin to look for another
house. What about Buckingham Palace?
Elevator! Damn! They left
the door open. Wait for me here.
Oh my God! I've already lived
this moment... Richard, stop!
You killed Barbara! You must die!
You killed Barbara... l've always
known that... I don't know why...
Like now, when I knew that man would
try to kill you in the elevator.
Oh Richard! I'm scared of not
being myself any more... Help me!