Axxon N., the longest running radio play in history
tonight, continuing in the Baltic region.
A gray winter day in an old hotel.
The stairway is dark
I don't recognize this hallway.
Where are we?
At our room now
I don't have the key
No, you gave it to me. I have it
What's wrong with me?
This is the room? I don't recognize it
- Take off your clothes.
- Sure.
You know what whores do?
Yes
They fuck
- Do you want to fuck me?
- Take off your clothes
I'll tell you what I want
Fine
I'm afraid
I am going to find out one day.
When will you tell him?
Who could have known?
What time is it
I have a secret.
There have been no calls today.
I hear someone.
I do not think it will be much longer now.
You are looking for something?
Yes
- Are you looking to go in?
- Yes
An opening?
- Look for an opening. Do you understand?
- Yes, I understand
- Do you understand I look for an opening?
- Yes. I understand completely.
Good. Good that you understand.
That's good!
You understand!
May I help you?
I am a new neighbor.
I live just down the street.
Ma'm?
Hello!
I don't mean to intrude
I am your new neighbor.
I hope that it is not being incovenient for you?
No, no.
Please, sit down.
Such a lovely home!
Thank you.
We enjoy it very much
Please
Uh, would you like uh, coffee?
That would be lovely.
Thank you.
And for you, ma'm?
the same, Henry,
thank you.
I've, I've been going around
meeting new neighbors.
I think that it is important
know one's neighbors.
To say "hello" to them.
Yes, it's very rare these days
but that's very nice.
Which house are you living in?
Just down the way.
Tucked back in the
small woods.
The brick house.
I think I know the one.
It is difficult to see it from the road.
Thank you.
Milk and sugar?
OH, yes, very good.
Will that be all ma'm?
Yes. Yes, thank you.
I'll be just close by
if you need me.
Thank you, Henry.
So...
You have a new role
to play, I hear.
Up for a role
But, I'm afraid,
far from getting it.
No, no, I definitively heard
that you have it.
Oh?
It is an...
Is it an interesting role?
Oh yes, very
Is it about marriage?
Um... perhaps, in some ways...
but... um...
Your husband, he's involved?
No.
A little boy
went out to play.
When he opened his door...
...he saw...
the world.
As he passed through the doorway...
...he caused, a reflection.
Evil was born
Evil was born,
and followed the boy.
I'm sorry...
what is that?
An old tale.
And a variation:
A little girl...
...went out to play.
...lost in the marketplace...
...as if half born.
Then, not through the marketplace,
you see that, don't you?
But through the alley
behind the marketplace.
This is the way
to the Palace.
But it isn't something you remember.
Forgetfulness, it happens to us all.
And me?... why, I'm the worst one!
OH, where was I?
Yeah.. Is there is a murder
in your film?
Ah, no, it's not part of the story...
No!
I think you are wrong about that!
No.
Brutal fuckin' murder!
Ah... I don't like this kind of talk
The things you've been saying,
I think should go now.
Yes...
Me... I.. I can't seem to remember if it's
today, two days from now, or yesterday!
I suppose that if it was 9:45...
I'd think it was after midnight!
For instance...
If today...
...was tomorrow...
...you would'nt even remember
that you owed on an unpaid bill.
Actions...
...do have consequences.
And yet
...there is the magic.
If it was tomorrow...
...you would be sitting over there.
You see?
Excuse me, ma'm?
Excuse me, ma'm,
telephone.
It's for you.
It's your agent.
Greg!
Oh my god! Oh my god!
My God
Nikki, it's we who are happy
and fortunate to have you on board
...on this film,
in this role.
I meant everything I said in
praising Devon.
And forgive me, I do love
making speeches.
I mean this too...
You have everything you need to soar
back to the top...
...and to stay perched there.
This film, you and Devon,
a great director.
Yes, do I hear?
The script is well, we're going to plunge into.
If all play our role,
do our best...
...if we work hard together
...well, this could be the one...
This is a starmaker, if ever I saw
one, you'll see
I think we have a chance
to pull it off...
what do you say?
Let's do it!
If you don't fuck it up Kingsley,
I'm sure we can!
I never felt better
in my life.
Champaign and caviar
is on its way.
Tonight, Nikki Grace
and Devon Berk.
Marsha, honey I know where you live,
do not pull my hair.
We're back in:
5,4,3,2,1.
Mamas, lock up you daughter's doors!
Nikki, really, this news, this
shocking revelation by Devon...
...must send a shiver down your spine!
Are you going to be able to be true
to hubby with a wolf in the den?
do with a bad wolf round you
Now, Marilyn...
I'm sure we'll get on famously,
in a professional way
and that's how it will stay,
professional.
And, Devon, your naughty boy,
are you hiding a smile?
Is your devilish mind scheming?
If you're looking for shock value Marilyn,
I suggest that you look in the mirror.
What a bitting wit!
But I tell you this:
Marilyn Levins is going to be watching,
and she will be reporting to you
everything she finds out!
There, and there, and there and beyond
around the world!
The Marilyn Levins Starlight Celebrity
show will be back next week
...from Hollywood, California.
Where stars make dreams...
...and dreams make stars.
How were you assholes thinking? That
was the biggest crock of shit I ever saw!
Show's popular!
Bullshit!
OH, you guys, how did it go?
Honey, you were great!
- You were amazing, how do you feel?
You were incredible. -Good...
You absolutely nailed it. Did you hear her?
Did you hear what Marilyn said?
She said you blowed! You were perfect!
So Devon, this one's off limits, right?
Don't even think about it...
...If I don't kill you, her husband will,
and he is THE most powerful guy around.
He knows everything. There is not a
thing he does'nt know.
I can tell you stories that
would color your hair.
So listen to me when I tell you.
Around Nikki, keep it in your pants.
What the fuck are you guys
talking about?
She's a nice girl, she's so far
from my style, it's not even funny.
Beautiful, Devon. Great.
We'll be able to sleep tonight
You gotta admit though...
She's got a nice ass.
It's good.
- Goodnight guys!
- Goodnight, I'll talk to you tomorrow.
- OK.
- Bye!
- Let's go!
Good morning
Mrs. Grace.
Fantastic.
It all in the beans!
And I'm just full of beans!
Is that our set?
Yeah
It's not finished yet
There's Smithie's House.
Smithie's House.
I should have guessed you two professionals
would be here early and beavering away...
We're just laying about drinking capuccino.
Devon makes a great capuccino.
Care for one?
Thanks, but Prey and I just had a cup of tea.
Actually, it was a terrible cup of tea
at the commissary.
"Terrible" is an
adequate description of it.
Well, I thought since we're here
and Smithie site's been started...
We might go over some of the scenes
that take place there.
Not the love scene, of course, but some of
the earlier scenes
that indicate so beautifully your character.
Lets take, for instance,
scene 35...
...the scene where Devon...
you arrive,
...Billy, at Smithie's house to find Sue,
- Nikki- looking out the window.
I remember the scene
Well...
...we'll go through it...
...and then we'll maybe take it on
the set and plug it out as possible
I guess we should just jump right in?
- That would be jolly good.
- Ok
And, I'll start it off...
...on page 57.
Nikki, this is just a rough run-through
So don't be hard on yourself...
- I am expecting from you, an Academy Award
performance, right out of the gate, so...
Thanks, Devon.
Get going, please
I didn't think you'd be here...
No, of course you wouldn't
...that's because you...
what
what do you want?
I said some things last night
as you know.
Yeah.
And I want to apologize
- Apologize?
- Yeah.
The things you said weren't the truth?
I didn't say that
Were they the truth?
Are you crying?
Uh huh...
Yeah
Are you sorry about last night?
Are you?
Why are you crying?
I'm sorry, Billy.
I'm so sorry
what?
OH, shit.
Look in the other room.
What is that?
Freddy!
No, someone's there.
This stage is ours and ours alone.
Well, let's have a look.
Who was it?
Disappeared where it's
real hard to disappear.
Maybe we should talk,
maybe this is the time.
Let's be serious for a moment
about something other than this scene.
why?
- what is it?
Sit down, I'll tell you.
It was Freddy who
first heard about it
If you have an assistant who can hold his
liquor, then...
...Freddy can do that with the best of them.
Somebody's got to do it,
Gable's dead.
Now, Freddy is purposefully out and about
gathering what in this business...
...is the most valuable commodity...
...information.
Information is indispensable.
You probably know this from your own lives..
...we all have people who gather...
agents, friends, producers...
And sometimes they share,
...sometimes not.
Politics, ego,
...fear...
Kingsley?
sometimes I just isn't told the whole story.
Kingsley, get to the point.
"On High In Blue Tomorrows"
it is, in fact, a remake.
It's a remake?
I wouldn't do a remake.
No, no no, I know, of course,
But you didn't know
The original was a differrent name.
Started, but never finished.
Now, Freddy has found out
that our producers...
...Know the history of this film and have takenit upon
themselves not to pass on that information to us.
Purposefully
Not on me, and I assume not the two of you...
True?
No, absolutely
Nobody told me anything.
No. Me neither.
I thought this was
an original script.
Yeah, well...
Anyway, the film
it was never finished...
Something happened before
the film was finished.
I don'tot understand.
why wasn't it finished?
Well, after the characters
had been filming for some time,
...they discovered something... something...
inside the history.
Please, Kingsley.
The two leads,
were murdered.
It was based on a Polish-gypsy folk tale.
The title in German was
"Fier Sieben".
"Four Seven".
And it was said to be cursed.
...so it turned out to be.
What?
Did you understand what I said?
I don't understand.
Hmm, you don't speak Polish.
No.
Half of it...
I think she understands more
than she lets on...
But I don't speak it.
Take a seat.
What's this all about?
I've been hypnotized,
or something
Hypnotized?
And I'm...
I'm...
I'm going to kill someone.
Oh, yeah?
Who you going to kill?
I don't know.
Who hypnotized you?
The saw him looking at me once when I...
...when I looked
around the bar, and...
He done moved his hands...
...and he said that I...
...which I would'nt know who I was.
How are you going to kill
this person?
With a screwdriver
Your wife...
I've been with her since
I was a little boy.
A little boy?
Nothin' little about you now...
As far as I heard, that is.
why are you doin this?
Doin what?
Don't play dumb with me, Billy.
I got husband.
You got a wife
and two kids.
why are you doin this?
'cause I never met you before.
what?
I didn't know you before
I never had this feeling.
You have it too...
Don't you?
I can't afford to, Billy.
All I see from this is blue tomorrows
OK, cuts.
That was brilliant
We're moving on...
Check the gate please.
Camera reload.
- Good, good.
- 27 for lunch.
- Did you feel good about
it? - Yeah, I felt great. - Ok
So we're going to leave this lovely weather?
- Freddy, did you have an ashtray..
- I had one...
Going well?
Very well, thank you, Freddy.
Very enjoyable
Enjoyable, yes,
thats is the word.
Are you enjoying yourself Freddy?
Well, there is a vast
network, right?
An ocean of possibilities
I like dogs.
It used to raise rabbits
I've always loved animals.
Their nature...
...how they think...
I saw dogs reason their way
out of problems.
watched them think through the
trickiest situation.
Do you have a couple of bucks I can borrow?
I've got this terrible landlord.
Thanks.
I got a lot of nerve, I know.
It seems like only yesterday
I was carrying my own weight.
is the 19 year old neice...
Ever since we went into pre-production,
she's been
...fascinated by Smithie.
Keeps going on and on about Smithie...
...asking in that ancient
foreign voice of hers
Who is playing Smithie?
Where did everyone go?
Sorry she taken
Mr. Berg upstairs
Alright.
I listen to you, but...
...I don't hear him.
Excatly sure what your getting in?
I am going to put my arm around you
I want to hold you close. You don't mind that, do you?
What do you mean?
Sometimes people don't say exactly
what they mean
And you have been guilty of
this all evening.
Now, I'll tell you something.
And I will mean,
...everything I say.
My wife is not a free agent.
I don't allow her that.
The bonds of marriage
are real bonds.
The vows we take,
...we honor and enforce them.
For our selves, by ourselves, or,
if necessary,
they are enforced for us.
Either way, she is...
...bound.
Do you understand this?
There are consequences to one's actions.
And there would, for certain, be consequences to...
...wrong actions.
Dark, they would be, and...
...inescapable.
why instigate a need to suffer?
Bucky J, are you there?
- Is he there?
- Yes, he is there.
I'd say we haven't still got the 2K quite in the right place
I think I'd say up about 2 feet, you'd know better than me.
But it's still...
Boss, you want the 2K down?
Want it down?
Yeah, I'd say about 2 foot down Bucky.
How much you want it to do down?
Yeah, a bit more...
- Keep...
- How far?
Another foot Bucky.
I haven't even touched it yet.
Well then put it 2 foot from where it is...
no, a foot down from where it is Bucky.
"... oss".
What?
Got it, boss.
Bucky, I... Bucky just lower it 2 foot, would you?
From there.
No, Bucky.
It's going up.
I want it down, Bucky,
Two foot lower.
This goddamn time I had a cramp
Just a minute, I'm getting on it...
Thank you Bucky.
Does we it in something else...
- go talk to him...
Just uh... relax for a minute.
Listen, get medics on the scene, and see what's behind this.
- Yes, but. who..
...Phil's on it.
- Phil's in... We got Phil up there now, Bucky J doin a deal.
- Ok
- Please guys, lets work on these lighting cues,
alright, we need to work together...
We're almost lit,
couple of minutets
Alright, Tim and Sally, five minute warning,
five minute warning.
Last looks on first team please,
Lockups go to place please,
lockups to place.
I'm heading out, you need anything?
Quittin time already?
Passed.
Wanna stay for a drink?
Naw, I'm late for gym.
- Gym?
Is that with a 'g' or a 'j'?
Oh, that's original.
'G'
what do you do...
...at the gym?
I exercise!
why would you do that?
See ya
Stay for one little drink?
I'm so lonely...
Oh, poor small infant child...
One?
Damn
Will there be anything else?
- No, thank you, Jim.
- My pleasure.
You want to stay for dinner?
Maybe
I think you should.
You do?
I really do.
This is a nice drink.
Nice fire.
wife and children gone..
You talk too much.
So sorry, baby.
Don't ruin this...
There's nothing to ruin Billy.
Done cut.
We copy cut.
Check gate.
Yeah, I was right. Did anyone else read
the script?
The light should fade after Billy's line, do you see?
Look.
Alright alright, we go again please!
Back to 1 everybody!
A car...
A click Al, it wasn't a car, it was a 'click'.
Guys on lockup outside, can we work on that please?
Really, I can't have cars going by without...
No, we had ITC...
I don't think it was... It's something in the wire...
Will you pick that up?
Thanks. I've got a lot of nerve, I know...
...it seems that only yesterday Iwas carrying my own weight.
Thanks, Devon.
My pleasure...
That is exactly what we need.
- Camera department, you guys ready?
- Yeah
- OK.
- Where you gonna go sir?
Can I have some coffee?
Yeah, coffee comming in..
After shooting, do you want to go get
something to eat with me?
I bet you know a cute little Italian resaurant.
Tucked away
Private,
Great food.
I do!
How did you know that?
Did I say a night?
They're ready for you.
Wait just a minute.
I'll see you after the shoot.
Good luck
and run...
And action!
Billy.
Is it this what you want?
I won't fall in love with you.
And cut!
Are you two happy?
What?
I don't know.
Tell me.
What?
Something's happened.
I think my husband
knows about you.
About us
He'll kill you...
and me...
He'll...
Damn... it sounds like dialogue from our script!
Cut. Cut it!
What's going on?
What?
What the bloody hell is going on?
And we just don't know the actual, real reasons.
...why this film wasn't finished.
Now, you know some stories,
But stories are stories.
Hollywood is full of them.
Thank God.
In this case, the same thing.
Stories which grew out of imagination.
And we're surrounded by these
old stories every day
And they shouldn't be taken as truth.
Or given creedence.
Or jeapordize Nikki's performance.
Unless the stories are true.
Devon...
There is absolutely no proof that anyting
bad happened around this film.
Tie me on and I'll come.
Wait, stop, stop baby...
OH, God! Oh yeah. Oh God Damn.
Ok, our first time...
...fuck and it's good.
OH, please
Babe, you talk too fuckin' much.
- Are you gonna talk through this whole thing?.
- Oh yeah.
It's time.
Remember...
Rembember that thing
When I said that thing
about me...
Remember that?
Yeah...
Remember I told you, about this thing
this thing that happened.
It's a story that
happened yesterday.
But I know that it's tomorrow.
That doesn't make sense
It was that scene...
...that we did yesterday.
When I'm getting groceries for you
with your car
And I was in that alley, and I parked the
car, there's always parking there.
...So there I am...
What?
Sue, damn!
It's a scene we did yesterday.
You weren't in it.
That one where I'm in the alley, I'm going to get
groceries for you with your car.
And I parked there 'cause there's always
parking.
You know the one?
I see this writing on metal.
And I started remembering something...
I'm remembering...
This whole thing starts floodin' in...
this whole memory.
I start to remember...
And I... I don't know...
I do not know what it is...
It's me, Devon, it's me...
Nikki...
That doesn't make any sense
What is this?
It's me, Devon, it's me...
Nikki...
Look at me, you fucker!
Please, please
Please
Forgive me.
Look in the other room...
What the hell is that?
Freddy!
No, somebody's over there.
The stage is supposed to be ours and ours alone.
I'll go look
- I'm sorry
- It's ok..
Billy!
Who the hell are you?
Hey!
Look at us and tell us
if you've known us before.
There was a man...
...I once knew
Was it like this.. look around.
Did he do that thing... you know
that little shaking thing?
While he was...
You know...
Wasn't that great...
Yeah
I'd let him do...
...anything
Strange...
...what love does.
So strange.
In the bedroom
- You'll be dreaming...
- The kind of sleep...
When you open the eyes...
someone familiar will be there.
This is the street.
Do you want to see?
Just down the way.
It was...
...to see...
Very pretty...
I know...
Pick a cigarette.
Erase him in the white silk.
Arrive closer
It approximate
And it look...
...through
of the hole.
Breakfast
I didn't mean anything by that.
I just asked a question.
Why did you ask if it means nothing?
Whatever you want, is that it?
No, whatever you want.
Oh... Now it's me!
Always you.
Lie to me, but don't lie to yourself.
So sly...
- Don't push me!
- I'll push you to hell!
Stop it!
I can't give you children, I know that...
- Are you listening to me?
- I'm going out now.
I'm not who you think I am!
I'll never let you have her!
Never!
- Excuse me, do you know the time?
- 9:45.
Thank you.
I don't really understand
what I'm doing here.
That's one hell of a fuckin' climb getting up here.
So I was told you could help me.
I guess I'll just tell you the thing..
I just know that am I.
There was this man...
...I once knew...
His name was...
It doesn't matter what his name was...
A lot of guys change.
They don't change, but they reveal
In time they reveal
what they really are.
You know what I mean?
It is an old story.
Well this guy...
...he revealed something.
Looking back on it...
All along it was being revealed.
He was planning something...
...planning something with me
in mind.
When I get mad,
I really get mad
I gouged a man's eye out when I
was 15 once, he was trying to rape me...
I mean, the fucker had it out
pushing my legs apart.
I got a finger on his eyes socket,
pretty quick, rape was quite a long
way off his mind.
He was crying and screaming like a baby.
"What a fuckin man you are," I said.
There was goo...
He still could still see
me with the one eye.
See me comin' at him, grabbin' his nuts
and tearin' at 'em.
He'd seen that alright, felt it too.
He was screamin' and wailin' like a little baby.
He sat in the corner cryin'
Alone and huggin' his nuts 'till the ambulance come
the ambulance guys, they say:
"What the fuck happened here?"
I say:
..."He come to a reapin' what he had been sowin', that's what. "
They say:
"Fucker been sowing some kind of heavy shit... "
It's the shits...
I really thought you would last, you two.
I saw it coming...
Sorry, I did!
You're full of shit Dorry...
Sucks... He was the one...
I really thought he was,
you know?
So what
He's gone
Find someone else
It is not easy
when you feel like shit...
OH, baby...
Tonight we'll change that.
Yeah. Tonight
it will be good.
There's always a chance
with tits like yours, Kerri.
Thanks
Tits
Tits and ass.
These are going to bring 'em
in like sin
- Pretty.
- Let me see 'em
They are pretty baby,
Nice.
Sweet.
Thanks guys
I started saving some money
- Oh
So now we rich?
so I drink this piss called beer.
What is the money for?
If it won't bring something like hope?
I'm pregnant.
Oh... Funny one!
I am pregnant.
What is this?
You don't seem too happy about it!
Your pregnant?
What is it?
What's wrong?
It just that it come as a shock to me
Hello?
Billy?
I seen a man come at me with
a crow bar once.
Guess he figured I was two-timing him.
I was coming home.
We were shacked up at the time.
He was waiting for me in the half-light.
Waitin' for me to come home.
I guess he worked himself
into some kind of frenzy.
I opened the fuckin' door.
And I seen his fuckin' shape burst out
of the chair...
and a crow-bar goin up
I screamed and turned
Fuckin' crow bar comes down...
...smashin' into that fuckin' door
...cheap piece of shit...
...it just splinters into 1000 pieces
...like it was glass, shit flyin' everywhere
I don't take this kind
of behavior.
I seen what this fucko is up to
Bam!
I kick him in the nuts so hard that
they go crawling into his brain
...for refuge.
He goes down like a $2 whore.
...cryin' and shit and tell me that he's
never done nothing but love me bullshit...
Were you in fact seeing another man?
I was screwing a couple guys for drinks,
no big deal.
This one guy, he was kinda cute
Fucker had a dick like a rhinocerous.
He'd fuck the shit out of you, I'll tell you what...
He'd buy me a couple of drinks after.
We'd talk.
He'd tell me about a town he grew up in.
All the little girls he'd fuck
There was a chemical factory in this town
and, uh...
Telling us it was putting so much shit
in the air you couldn't think straight.
I got to a lot of the people.
there was a lot of crazy shit going on there.
People having weird dreams, and...
...seeing things that wasn't there.
So one time, this one little girl...
...she was starin' off at somethin' one time...
...starts screaming
They.. the... people hanging around,
they come to her and
...ask her what's wrong, and uh...
She says she sees the end of the world.
...on fire, and smoke
and blood rain".
You know, like they say...
The wailing and the gnashing of teeth.
Hey!
Look at me!
And I tell me if you've known me before.
Yes,
we will do that.
Where is the paper towels?
They're behind you, on the table.
It removes myself...
from this sinful dream...
...which invaded
my heart.
Who is she?
I almost didn't recognize you
You startled me
Strange... to find you on the street
You seem upset.
Are you?
Should I be?
- No, but...
- So I shouldn't be?
No
But still, you seem so
I think you don't recognize me
I think you don't recognize my manners
That's true
- You seem different
- You too
I'm used to seeing you in our home,
not on the street,
at night
Me too
There was a murder
How awful!
- Where?
- Just down the way
I think...
...you knew the victim
- Who was it?
- Don't know the name
But I have seen you with this person
- You have?
- Yes
I think I've seen the two of you together
That's awful
Who are those people?
Hey, hello!
Good to see you.
Come in, come in.
Get some hot-dog.
You said 3 o'clock.
Yes, that's right.
You're right on time.
The situation is becoming dangerous
Give me my hammer.
Give me that!
Gives me now.
Did you see?
There is no paper.
For the toilet.
It is under the sink,
in the cupboard.
what?
They are a group that performs in
travelling shows.
In the Baltic region
What's that got to do with you?
I will care for the animals.
It was said that I have a way with animals.
Fucker went to some eastern
europe shithole
...with the fuckin' circus.
Can you fuckin believe that?
That circus...
...talk about carnies... Carnies, gypsies,
conmen, you name it.
A real fuckin' ball of shit.
There was this guy they had working there.
He'd start talkin'.
...you know, real regular.
Talkin' up the crowd.
They'd start listening...
...Pushin' in closer.
He did some sort of thing on people.
They all called him the phantom.
He got in a bar room fight one night...
All the bar was arrested.
A lot of them fuckin' circus clowns.
So when they take 'em all down to the station,
Guess what?...
...the Phantom's done gone and disappeared.
This is the kind of
shit I'm talking about.
He was a marine from North Carolina.
I had a sister with one leg.
...she had a sort of carved stick for the other one.
She killed three kids in the first grade.
This is the kind of shit.
Fuckin' funny.
People.
All got their own peculiarities.
Their own way of livin'
What about school?
One more day.
One more day?
Maybe two.
Susan?
What are you doing here?
What?
I thought you were gone.
Billy.
Something's wrong.
Bad wrong.
Do you feel it?
Sue?
Billy.
Do you love me?
what?
Billy.
Sue.
Don't you remember anything?
How it was?
I don't understand what you're talking about.
Are you kidding?
No.
You go on, Sue.
You go on now...
Would you like me to call the police?
No, we can handle this.
Billy.
Something is wrong
I love you, Billy.
I've had just enough.
I love you
Go away, Susan.
Sue!
I don't care
It's something more.
I do not care
Gordy
What do you want?
Where is he?
What's the point?
Are you blind? He's gone!
Everybody?
Why answer your stupid question?
You're nothing! You've done nothing!
Where did he go?
No idea. He talked... mumbled
something about Inland Empire.
I come about an unpaid bill that needs payin'
All right
Do you know a man who lives here?
Do you know him?
Yes. What is it? What do you want?
Which you want?
He has an unpaid bill that needs payin'
You already said that.
Do you know a man who lives next door?
Crimp is the name...
It was a funny name.
They was called Crimp.
Hey?
There's someone there
I have to tell you
There's someone
Do you recognize her?
I don't see her
You understand she was sent for you?
I don't know where I am
- I hear her now
- Do you see her?
No
It was...
...red
You work for someone?
Yes
The one she spoke of
Yes, I work for him
So you understand
The horse was taken...
...to the well
Take the pistol
Let's go!
Right away! It's past midnight!
I am going to find out one day.
It was red.
Where was I?
This isn't the way it was.
It was the man in the green coat.
It had something to do with
the telling of time.
I am a whore.
Where am I?
I'm afraid
Just a moment.
I need to make a collect call.
Look at me
And tell me if you've known me before
Someone is gonna fuckin' kill me...
You gotta let me in. I know
a girl.
Carolina.
I know Carolina.
- I don't really understand what I'm doing.
- It's one hell of a fuckin' climb getting up here.
There was this man...
...I once knew
I'm trying to tell you so you understand
how it went.
The thing is, I don't know...
...what was before or after.
I don't know what's happened first...
...and it's kinda layin' a mindfuck on me.
My husband...
...he's fuckin' hidin' somethin'
He was acting all fuckin' weird one
night before he left...
He was talkin this foreign talk and...
...tellin' loud fuckin' stories...
I'm not who you think I am.
Are you listening to me?
I know it for a fact.
I can't father children.
Like this... his face all red...
his eyes buggin' out...
I figured one day...
...I'd just wake up and...
...I find out what the hell yesterday
was all about.
I'm not too keen on thinking about tomorrow.
And today's slippin' by.
I guess after my son died,
I went into a bad time.
When I was watching everything go around me
while I was standing in the middle.
Watchin it, like in a dark theater.
before they bring lights up.
...I'm sittin there,
...wonderin...
..."how can this be?"
Hello?
Yeah, she's still here.
I don't think it will be too much longer now.
Yeah, the horse to the well.
Yeah.
Yeah, he's around here someplace.
Sure, I'm on it.
What have you been up to?
Where did you go?
Where 'you been?
Someone's there.
Look.
Hey, watch this move!
You' dyin lady.
what you say
about Pomona?
You asked about the bus.
Can't get no bus to Pamona.
You can get the bus for Pamona here.
If you get on the subway first.
I never can get no bus.
You can go all around Hollywood.
I was in Hollywood Irvine,
And you can get to Pomona
for 3,50.
From Hollywood, Irvine to Pamona
I never heard
of no bus there.
I ride on the bus
to Pomona...
.. last summer
to visit my friend...
.. who lives there.
Her name is Nico.
I stayed with her
two weeks.
My cousin comes from Pomona.
She has a place there, and said
I can stay there.
What time is it
I don' know.
It's after midnight.
After midnight?
My friend Nico, who lives
in Pomona...
...has a blonde wig.
she wears it at Paris.
but she's on hard drugs and turning tricks now.
She looks very good
in her blonde wig...
just like a movie star.
Even girls fall in love with her.
When she's looking so good...
In her blonde star wig
She blows kisses and loves
But she has got a hole in her vagina wall
She has torn a hole
...into her intestine
...from her vagina.
Shit baby...
you didn't tell us that shit...
She has a shitty doctor,
But it is too expensive.
And now she knows her time has
run out.
She scored a few more times,
And then, like that,
...she will stay at home, with her monkey.
It has a pet monkey.
This monkey shits everywhere,
But she doesn't care
This monkey can scream.
It screams like it in a horror movie.
But there are those who are
good with animals.
Who have a way with animals.
It's ok..
You dying is all
I'll show you the light now...
It burns bright, for heaven.
No more blue tomorrows.
You goin high now love.
And...
And.. Print it!
It was fantastic.
Check the gate.
check the gate please!
Lets go right now
for Nikki Grace.
Nikki Grace, everybody.
Bravo!
What's a matter with Nikki.
Nikki.
You were wonderful.
I guess after my son died,
, I went into a bad time.
When I was watching everything go around me
while I was standing in the middle.
Watching it, like in a dark theater.
before they bring the lights up.
Hello?
Yeah
She's still here
Yeah...
He's around here someplace.
That is right.
Heather?
Paul?
Sweet...