[Distant howl]
[Another howl]
[Whispering]:
savan!
Uri has ordered us
to turn back.
Savan!
Age has made him too cautious.
He's my father,
I can speak of him as i wish.
When you're chief,
you'll want respect.
It's not just
a matter of respect.
Now, stay close...
And tonight, yomak,
You will feast on the heart
with me.
Are you deaf, savan?
We do not separate, ever.
You may not agree
with my methods.
We haven't had
fresh meat in weeks.
Roots and berries
are not enough for us.
You've got
a lot to learn, savan.
I've proved myself
the best hunter in this tribe.
Hunting is not just
about courage.
You've got to be clever, too.
We are not the only
predators out here.
We are tired
of being hungry.
Let me lead this hunt,
and we will make our kill,
And tonight the village
will have reason to celebrate,
And the women will show
their gratitude.
[Laughter]
Very well, savan, lead.
Follow me.
Watch for my signal.
Shh!
Kaleb?
What's it to be then,
Roast kaleb or boiled kaleb?
You belong with the women,
Not with the hunt.
It's ahead.
I've tracked it.
Tracked what,
the deadly blueberry?
Enough!
That's beyond
our hunting grounds.
You know that.
It's out there,
Right in front of us,
Only 200 paces.
This is as far
as we go.
We already
pushed our luck.
It's too dangerous.
Maybe if we're quick--
[Distant growling]
200 paces, that's it.
[Growling nearby]
[Quietly]:
i tracked it!
Tracking's one thing,
Bringing it down
is another.
Stay back, or
you'll only get hurt.
[All roaring war cries]
[Sloth roars]
[Hunters shout]
[Sloth bellows and slathers]
Look out!
Get it!
[Cries out]
[Snarling and roaring]
[Shouting]
Pull!
That's it!
[Roars in pain]
[Shouting war cry]
[Wails in agony]
Evan, go cut
the heart out!
Yeah, cut it out!
The honor of today's hunt
is savan's
And kaleb's.
You will share
the heart tonight.
It was my kill.
Your blow brought it down,
But it was kaleb's skills
that led us here.
Is that not so?
Savan!
Yomak?
[Voice changing]: help me.
No! Stay back,
all of you!
[Screams]
He's been bitten!
[Screaming in pain]
[Human-Like again]:
savan!
Kill me, savan.
Don't let it take me...
[Voice changing]: please.
[Screams]
Savan...
Please!
Please...
[Groans in pain, beast-Like]
Savan!
[Snarling, spear thuds]
[Screams in pain]
No!
I'll kill you!
I'll kill all of you!
Don't do this!
We can't stay here!
I won't run!
Do you want to
kill us, too?
We can't beat them!
They killed him!
[Panting quietly]
[Tribe murmuring in excitement]
Savan!
Dorel.
Finally.
Tonight we feast.
We lost yomak today.
He was bitten.
Kaleb!
You don't
stand a chance.
What?
Oh, come on.
You can't keep secrets
from your sister.
We know you like dorel.
Well, you never know.
Maybe dorel
doesn't want to marry
A tall, handsome
Future chief.
Yomak's dead.
It was my fault.
What happened?
I led them beyond
our hunting grounds.
He was attacked by beasts.
The beasts are here.
It's only a matter of time
befores.
We must leave grey rock.
You saw them
with your own eyes?
Yomak was bitten.
That's all i needed to see.
Uri...
We've been safe here
all this time.
Did you go beyond
our hunting grounds?
The tribe needed meat.
There was none here.
Then we have no choice.
We have to leave.
And go where?
There is nowhere else.
We are the last survivors
of man.
God chose us
and led us to grey rock
And kept us safe here
for generations.
Are we to doubt him now?
We should not run,
or wait for them to come.
We should fight.
There are
too many to fight,
And you know the consequences
if we do,
Or have you forgotten
about yomak
Already?
Then we should continue
to live like cowards--
Careful what you say, savan.
If it's god's will
That they must
find us here,
Then we must
accept our fate.
The beasts are
a judgment against us,
A punishment
for the sins of our fathers.
Was it god's will
that my friend should die?
Why can't we choose
our own fate?
Hold your tongue.
You've got
no business here, kaleb.
My father spoke
of other tribes--
Your father didn't
listen to the elders
And suffered the same fate
as any man
Who goes beyond
our hunting grounds.
He went to look
for a better life...
For us all.
What kind of a man
abandons his children?
He sought the truth.
Our laws are the only truth.
He's right, kaleb.
There's nothing out there
but disease and death.
As you have
seen today.
The elders
will discuss this.
Savan,
for your disrespect,
You will take
guard duty tonight,
And the two of you will forfeit
the heart of the sloth
To the elders.
Why do you get yourself
into trouble
On father's account?
Should i not
question them?
Kaleb, it is the elders
who have kept us safe,
Not our father.
They don't like
to be questioned.
Anyway, it doesn't matter now.
He's not coming back.
He always came back before--
Yeah, well,
not this time.
It's been almost
three years, kaleb.
I've had enough of
living in hiding, miru.
I want to know what's out there.
Don't leave me, kaleb.
You're the only
family i have.
Then come with me.
Kaleb, listen to the elders.
There is no one else out there.
That's what
they believe.
What about all the things
he brought back?
Things from
the old world.
Those people died
many years ago.
It doesn't prove anything.
He told me he had met others,
talked to others.
Yeah?
Well, where are they?
Why haven't they come?
Why hasn't he come?
Well, i will come back, miru.
I promise.
[Snarling nearby]
[Gasps in fright]
[Large group approaches,
snarling and growling]
[Beast roars]
Beasts!
[Snarling and slathering]
[Tribe screaming in panic]
[Screaming]
[Shouting war cry]
[Snarling]
Protect the cave!
Go to the cave!
Go to the bat cave!
[Roars of battle
and screams of terror continue]
No...
[Roaring]
[Screaming]
No!
[Beasts snarling]
[Voice echoes dreamily]:
father!
Father!
[Echoing]: come on!
There's too many!
Savan,
what do we do?
Savan!
[Tribespeople scream]
Use the trees!
Circle the beasts!
Go! Close the cave!
[Beasts roar and slather]
Into the cave!
Kaleb!
Miru!
Everybody
in the cave!
Get into
the cave, miru!
Miru!
Get into the cave!
Everybody, get in here now!
[Roaring]
Quickly!
That's it!
Okay!
[Beasts roaring and snarling]
Close it!
[Blows thud, beasts snarl]
If you don't do it, we all die!
Do it now!
But others are still out there!
Do it!
[Beasts squeal in pain]
[Snarling]
[Screaming]
[Shouting war cry]
Are you okay?
[Beast grunts and snarls
outside]
How many?
Too many.
We have to distract them,
Get them away
from the cave.
Then what?
You have a better idea?
Go for help.
From where?
You're ranting
just like your father.
There may be people
who can help us.
The elders never spoke
of anyone else.
The elders are trapped
in the cave!
Those beasts will not give up
until they are all dead.
We are the only chance
to survive.
We should go to the mountains,
look for other tribes.
There are beasts
in the mountains--
There are beasts right here.
Shouldn't we at least try?
I'm not going to run away.
What if kaleb's right?
What if there are others?
If he is right,
Then everything
we have ever been told
Is a lie.
Do you really
take his word
Over the elders,
And the generation of elders
before them?
But if we stay here
and fight the beasts alone,
We will die,
And so will our tribe.
And so will you.
Come on.
One day.
You've got one day
to find some other people,
Then dorel and i
are turning back.
Kaleb, what is this?
It's a book.
What do you do
with it?
It's from the past.
People used to put
their thoughts and ideas
In books like this.
After the disease came,
Everyone was too busy
trying to survive.
Books died.
Where did you get this book?
My father brought it back.
He taught me to read.
Read?
To know what the pages
are saying.
"Monday morning
Tom sawyer felt miserable--"
Your father has corrupted you.
We don't have time for this.
Which is why
we kept it a secret.
[Snarling nearby]
Go.
Go!
[Beast grunting]
[Roars]
[Axe thuds, people scream]
[Roaring ferociously]
[Shouts, taunting]
[Roars]
[Hisses]
Kill it!
It's my father!
Your father's gone!
That's not him!
[Roars, snarling]
[Dorel screams]
[Axe thuds, beast screams]
It's all right.
This wasn't your father anymore.
Kaleb was right.
How...
How do you know my name?
I've been watching you
for a long time.
You can read.
Like your father.
You know my father?
I knew him.
What happened?
It was his wish
That i made sure
no harm came to you.
Were you bitten?
What?
Did it bite you?
No.
No bleeding through the nose?
What do you mean?
No...
We're not infected
if that's what you're asking.
Oh, yes, you are.
A mutant has only
to breathe on you
To infect you.
The bite is just quicker.
There is still time,
But there will be
more of them,
So follow me.
You're lying.
There's nothing
wrong with us.
Your mouth will go dry,
And your thirst
will be unquenchable.
Your lungs will tighten,
Your nose will bleed
and your eyes will sting,
Then your heart will race.
Now, follow me.
If we're infected,
Why did you get
so close?
I'm immune.
What's "immune?"
I can't catch
the disease.
How is that possible?
The cure is a powder,
A yellow powder.
There wasn't
much of it,
And what little is left
will be hard to get.
We have water,
but there's no food.
[Beast snarls and roars outside]
[They beat the barricade
with sticks and axes]
Don't worry,
they can't get in.
Yeah, but won't they leave?
They know we're here.
They won't stop.
They want to kill
like rabid dogs.
Then we must pray,
Put ourselves in god's hands.
We must have faith.
Gather round
And let us pray.
[Beast snarls
and slathers outside]
[Tribespeople chant]
Oh, lord, be with us,
Protect us
from this evil...
Are you taking us
to the yellow powder?
We must first go to my home.
There are things
we need to pick up.
How come the beasts
never found you out here?
They're frightened of water.
Helps keep them at bay.
Don't worry.
They'll never cross
this water.
Did you build this?
[Scoffs]
It's from the old world.
I just patched it up.
Neenah.
We have visitors.
Why?
He is jaret's son.
He doesn't belong here.
They need our help.
Their village
was attacked by mutants.
You brought
infected people here,
To our home?
They weren't bitten.
They still have some time.
Neenah!
He can read.
I don't care!
How can you be so reckless?
Don't you see what this means?
It means you've
put us in danger.
Look at him.
He's a boy.
How can he do what jaret did?
It's worth
the risk.
This is our son,
Persk.
It's been a while
since he's seen others.
Hi. I'm dorel--
Persk...
The beasts have gone.
I wouldn't be so sure.
It's so quiet.
Open it.
No...
Don't touch the door.
There might be other survivors
from our tribe out there
Who need our help.
No one else survived,
And neither will we
if we open this door.
No...
Kaleb is not dead.
I'm sorry, miru.
He isn't dead!
[Beast roars nearby]
Neenah...
Neenah, don't be angry.
I'm scared, amal.
I know what
you're going to do.
For what?
If kaleb can do
what his father did,
Think what that would mean.
But for you to go back there...
You were so lucky
to get out the last time.
Then think of persk.
Why should he have to
grow up in a world
Where people
live in hiding?
It's been good enough for us.
We're happy here, aren't we?
But what about his children,
And the others
who are out there?
They'll never be safe
Unless we can learn
to make the powder.
Are we going to look persk
in the eye
And tell him we never
took the one chance
That came our way?
What did your elders
teach you about the disease?
That god created it
As punishment
for man's sins.
The old world
was full of greed,
And men created machines
that got out of control,
And they meddled
with nature,
And only god
could stop them.
Men were trying to perfect
their own design.
They found a way to bring
extinct animals back to life
Like the mammoth
and sloth that you hunt,
But their science
also brought us the disease.
It wasn't long before
the whole world was infected.
The disease ate into
the human brain,
Turning men into mutants.
How do you know
all of this?
Because i met kaleb's father.
Jaret had the courage
To look for
the old knowledge.
He found out
what really happened.
It was your father, kaleb,
Who discovered
the cure.
The yellow powder?
It took him many years
To find the right mixture
of plants and fungus.
Once you inhale the powder,
You're protected.
What if you already have...
The disease?
Once you have turned,
then the powder is useless...
But if you get it in time,
then there is still hope.
So why didn't my father
bring the powder home?
He was doing just that
when he died...
And the secret of the powder
died with him.
But you kept
the powder.
So you're safe, while we--
No.
The powder was stolen,
And it will be hard
to get it back.
But you'll help us try?
Yes.
If we can keep
kaleb alive,
He will be able to carry on
his father's work.
They're all
from the old world.
My father would often disappear
for months at a time.
He told me that out there
Were answers
to all our questions.
I now understand
his fascination.
Your father
had this on him
When he died.
He said there'd be
more adventures.
[Chuckles]
I've only read
one book.
How will i ever unlock
the secret of the yellow powder?
You're the only one
who can read, kaleb.
But if we find
The powder that exists...
We only need enough
for our people.
Your father
risked everything
Teaching you to read
And leaving the safety
of his tribe.
Now...
I'm risking everything.
Saving just
a few people
Is not an option.
[Grunting with effort]
What are we waiting for?
That is not god's way!
Well, shouldn't we
at least try?
We will not scurry
Into the bowels of the earth
like animals
As our forefathers did.
They were punished
for their sins!
Would god punish us
for trying to survive?
We must have faith
And courage,
And wait for this evil to pass.
If i'd have had enough courage,
I would have listened to kaleb.
[Lovers gasp and moan
quietly nearby]
[Stones grind]
[Elder groans in his sleep]
We should wake them.
Give them one last chance.
[Grunting with effort]
They made their choice.
It's time to go.
Uh, w-We're ready to leave.
Washing my hair's
a simple thing,
But it makes me feel better.
Amal expects me
to perform miracles.
Well, you were the one
Who sought the knowledge
of the old world.
Yeah, and the truth,
And savan still isn't convinced.
Do not judge him.
All these things
we never knew
Have shattered everything
that we believe in.
He finds it hard to accept.
Okay, persk,
take care of your mom.
How deep
do you think it is?
The ceiling's gone.
It could've blocked
the whole tunnel.
No, it can't have.
I can still feel a breeze.
Well, you only need
a small gap for that.
What are you doing?
If it's a small gap,
You need a small person
to fit through it.
Miru!
That will stay
on top of the water?
It will,
And as long as you stay on,
you'll be safe.
Jump.
Come on.
It's okay.
I'm walking on water.
Yes, it floats.
This river will lead us
to the yellow powder.
That's a paddle.
Use both hands.
Here, let me show you.
That's it.
Good.
I think she's okay.
It's okay!
There's a way through!
Give me your hand!
[Screams]
Miru!
There's something
in the water!
Miru!
There's something
in the water!
What is it?
[Coughing and spluttering]
Get them off me!
Get them off!
It's okay.
Get them off--
Hey...
Miru, it's okay.
I'm getting them off.
[Coughing]
It's all right,
it's all right...
It's all right.
I think they're all gone.
Do we look for another way?
No.
We've come too far.
Right.
When i go through,
Just get them off me fast, okay?
[Splashing]
[She giggles]
[Splashing and laughing]
[Beast roaring on shore]
[Rocks splashing]
Paddle!
Get in the middle!
The middle!
Row to the middle!
[Growling and bellowing]
[Doral screams]
[Boulders tumble and thud]
I fear they will never leave.
Let's hope the others
aren't punished
For their doubts.
[Beast snarls]
[Screaming]
[Blows thud, spears stab]
[Snarling]
[Shrieks in pain]
There was a group of us,
A brotherhood,
That was formed to help protect
each tribe from the mutants.
After jaret discovered
the powder,
We thought if we could
immunize enough tribes,
People could come out of hiding,
Start to rebuild the world.
By one of our own.
A man called gagen
stole the powder.
But won't he help us
if he sees that we're sick?
[Chuckles wryly]
You don't know this man.
He turned an island
into a fortress,
His empire.
Gagen has hordes of followers
Who will kill for the chance
to inhale the yellow powder,
And kill they do.
You okay?
Those leech bites
really sting.
Yeah, well, not
as much as a beast bite.
If you put it that way,
I'm beginning to enjoy it.
Over here!
Looks like we got
our miracle after all.
[Miru laughs]
Half a miracle.
We've still got to climb it.
I'll go first.
Were you bitten?
No.
Did they
claw you?
We were fighting.
I don't know!
Maybe being close
is all it takes.
We don't
know that.
Yeah, but if it is,
then we're all infected.
Then we're all
going to turn.
Okay, we'd better get going.
Right.
Let's finish
what we started!
You know that kaleb
must find his father's work.
Above all else.
Do you understand?
Kaleb.
I never thanked you.
For what?
For saving my life
back at the village,
After the attack.
I haven't saved anyone yet.
Well, you saved me,
so thank you.
[Deep growling outside]
[More growling]
Oh, no. No...
Get down quickly!
[Rocks tumble, they scream]
[Grunting with impact]
[Screams in agony]
Go on!
Leave me!
[Beast snarling]
I'll carry you!
You two can still
get out of here.
I'm dead either way!
Move!
Go!
[Snarling]
[Distant screaming]
[Beasts roaring]
When the old world died,
how many survived?
It's impossible to say.
Each of the brotherhood
came from a tribe of 60 or 70.
Are they all
still out there?
Scattered, staying hidden.
We set up these beacons
as a warning system.
A beacon is lit, help will come.
That's the theory.
Let's see
who's up for the fight.
[Gasping for air]
[Snarling]
Run!
What did he say?
Mutants!
[Snarling]
Run!
[Flint rasps]
[Tires ignites]
[Snarling and slathering]
Run!
To the raft!
[Roaring]
[Shrieks]
[Cries out]
[Amal screams]
[Shouts in alarm]
[Snarling]
[Roaring]
We have to go back!
No, he's finished!
We can't just leave him.
We have to go!
No!
Come on!
Where are you going?
Get to the raft, dorel!
Without amal?
Come on!
[Snarling]
[Blade squelches, beast shrieks]
[Gurgling]
But what about
the brotherhood?
He lit the beacon!
He said others would come!
He said they might come.
Do you want to wait
along with the beasts?
The river is our only chance.
No.
The yellow powder's
our only chance.
[Horse whinnies]
[Tribespeople coughing]
[Baby cries]
[Weakly]:
if this is to be our time,
Let us leave this world
together.
We tried.
I never understood
your father before.
He would be proud of you.
Is it just us?
Let's hope not.
Have you seen amal?
Well, this is
his beacon.
He must be here.
Hey!
Who's that?
Well, that's not him.
That's garth
and his brother.
How are you feeling?
Okay.
Have we gone
too far?
Maybe we passed it
in the night.
I don't think so.
Here!
Over here.
[Amal groans]
Give me a hand.
[Coughing]
I wonder
how many people lived
In a village like this?
Come on.
Let's find this gagen
and get the powder.
But there's
only three of us.
We won't give him
a choice.
If we can't
reason with him,
We'll fight him.
We can't
fight him, savan.
We don't have to.
We'll convince him
we have something he needs.
[Hum of crowds]
What's the problem?
[Whip cracks, man screams]
I saw you!
Thief!
[Groans in pain]
Please...
Please, i won't do it again,
i promise.
I promise i won't do it again.
Please?
You won't.
Who are you?
It's all right.
We're not with them.
We came down the river.
Then you've got the disease.
Leave me alone.
We came for the yellow powder.
We all came
for the yellow powder.
How do we find it?
You find it...
Do you know a man called gagen?
Uh...
Gagen...
Savan, let him go!
Stop!
I only want to ask you
a question!
Jaret's son, kaleb...
He can read.
His village was
attacked by mutants.
There are survivors, trapped.
Kaleb and two others have gone
to get the yellow powder.
Against gagen?
They need our help.
Gagen's forces
are too strong for us.
This boy,
He could be the savior
of mankind.
It's too risky.
Is that not
worth the risk?
We are all immune,
and so are our tribes.
Not your children's
children,
And we have no powder
to give them.
What about their future?
Or the others,
way beyond our lands?
With the yellow powder,
We could come out of hiding
And join forces
against the mutants.
This could be our last chance.
Let go of me!
[Coughing]
Bring them.
[Coughing hoarsely]
[Coughing]
Sir...
We do not recognize them,
So we think
they might be infected.
We've come here
for the yellow powder--
I know why you're here.
[Coughing]
You're wasting
your time, giselle.
She's still a human being.
Not for
much longer.
[Coughing and spluttering]
My daughter
is a compassionate soul.
I'm afraid she doesn't
get it from me.
I can't help you.
Get them off my island
before they turn.
I've come to help you, gagen.
I didn't know i needed help.
When you took
the yellow powder,
You must've known
it wouldn't last forever.
That powder was a gift.
It was given to me.
A gift from
a dying man.
That man was my father.
Your father was jaret?
The one who discovered
the yellow powder.
His dying wish was that
it benefits everyone,
Not be hoarded by one man.
Is that true?
No.
My father could read.
So can i.
I don't believe you.
Hey!
"For abraham lincoln,
"There was no satisfaction
"Over his victory,
"For he had inherited a country
That was tearing itself apart."
I've come to carry on
my father's work.
I can make the yellow powder.
Give us some of yours
so that i will live,
Let us take some to our village,
Then i will make you
as much as you need.
If i fail you,
you can kill me.
You're dying already.
You'll say anything.
First, prove what you say,
and i'll give you the powder.
We don't have
enough time.
Well, then,
you'd better be quick.
What yellow powder
remains
Is for my children's
children.
Outsiders can stay
on the island.
We'll protect them
from the mutants,
But they must work.
We've seen them work.
Unless, of course,
they're infected,
And then i offer them
A quick death,
A courtesy i'll extend
to you and your friend
When the time comes.
If it wasn't for
his father,
We'd all be dead.
Let them have
some of the powder--
Giselle, enough.
Take him into
the library,
And you know
what to do with her.
Was he telling
the truth?
Did you steal
the yellow powder?
It wasn't his father
who kept us alive.
It was me.
There just wasn't enough.
Did you steal it?
You think i'm a tyrant?
I kept us safe.
One day, you will
have children...
And you will understand.
[Muffled scream]
[Quietly]: i know
you want to help us.
I'm not going to
hurt you.
All right?
[Panting in fear]
Show me where
the powder is.
I can't betray
my father.
How many has he betrayed?
Your friend said
he could make more.
Maybe, eventually,
but he's just stalling.
I'm sorry.
I can't--
Then you're killing us,
And all that's left of my tribe.
Is that what you want?
[Coughing]
I've spent my entire life
Clinging to
a small patch of rock,
Thinking we were
the only ones left,
And they deserve
the chance
You've been given.
I'll take you
to where the powder is kept,
But it won't do you any good.
Where do i start?
It's in there,
but we need the key,
Which is around
my father's neck.
Always.
[Coughing]
When is the last time
he got some powder?
Um... yesterday.
Then this isn't
where he keeps it.
This door hasn't been
opened in a long time.
It doesn't
make sense.
Whenever he
comes out of here,
He always has
the powder.
[Coughing and wheezing]
This is all my father's work.
You really don't know
what you're doing.
I can do this,
just not quickly.
It could take weeks.
If gagen gives us
enough powder for our tribe,
I'll come back and make him
as much as he needs.
Only to find out
this has all be a ruse.
You're out of time.
[Groaning and coughing]
[Sounds of sickness
intensifying]
[Groaning in pain]
Somebody,
End this!
Please...
Remi, do something!
He's an elder.
I can't.
Miru!
[Moaning]
[Gargled cough
becoming beast-Like]
[Shouts]
[He grunts in pain]
[Groaning]
[Panting with emotion]
When it's time,
I hope you do the same for me.
[Coughing]
As i thought.
Give me the powder.
Where do i draw the line?
Hmm?
You know how many people
Have asked me
for the same thing?
You know i can do this.
Or is that
what you're afraid of?
To lose your hold
on all these people?
Father!
There's someone
in the safe room,
Searching for the powder.
[Coughs]
[Gagging and shuddering]
[Gasps]
Don't kill him!
No!
When i tell you,
take a deep breath.
[Inhaling]
Give it
a few minutes.
Dorel doesn't have
Okay, okay.
Take me to her.
Open the door!
I wouldn't go in there.
She's starting to turn.
She needs more water.
Hey! What
are you doing?
[Yelps]
Breathe.
Dorel...
Breathe!
[Inhales]
Okay...
Okay, come on.
Let's go, babe.
You should
come with us.
I don't want to
leave the island.
And your father?
He'll forgive you
for helping us?
It's you he'll be after.
This is the future
of my people, too.
Tell kaleb to keep his promise
and continue his father's work.
Thank you.
[Gagging and wheezing]
[Kaleb coughs]
[Kaleb coughing]
He has to breathe it in.
Get it in front of
his face!
He's not breathing.
Watch out.
[Punches him hard]
[Winces, inhaling]
Kaleb?
Kaleb, can you
hear me?
Kaleb?
Kaleb, we have the powder,
But we have to
leave now.
Come on.
Hey!
Stop!
Stop them!
This way.
Come on!
They're getting away!
Move it!
Kill them!
I'll draw them away.
No, savan!
[Bolt whooshes]
Don't worry, i'll catch up.
After them!
[Bolt snipes]
[Groans in pain]
Let's go!
Go!
Did you lose them?
They'll want
their powder back.
We can't go
back upriver.
We'll be fighting
the current.
We'll have to
go inland.
How will we
find our way back?
We have kaleb.
He's a good tracker.
[Beasts snarling ferociously]
[Waterfall rumbles]
They've gone overland.
They're still alive.
They must have the powder.
Over there.
Keep going.
[Bolt snipes]
[Screams]
Gagen.
Go!
[Groaning in pain]
Kaleb...
[Kaleb wincing]
Can you run?
[Screaming]
Start picking the beasts off
from the tree line.
It's not much, but it might
give you a chance.
What are you doing?
Kaleb must survive.
I'm not leaving without you.
No--
I'm the chief.
Do as i say.
Savan. Savan!
[Bolt snipes]
Run, dorel!
[Shouting war cry]
Go back! Go back!
No! Savan!
[Screaming]
Oh, my...
[Panting with exhaustion]
We can't stop now.
Come on.
[Footsteps and clanking nearby]
[Horses whinny]
Amal!
Have you got the powder?
Yeah.
Then let's get it
to your people.
[Horses whinnying]
[Coughing]
Remi, please!
Please, you have to help me.
You have to, please!
Please end this now!
Please!
No, i can't!
End it, remi,
please!
[Sobbing]:
i can't take it, please...
[Horses whinny]
[Beasts snarl curiously]
[Growling]
[Squeals]
[Beasts roaring, arrows thud]
Let me in!
[Blows thud heavily]
It's dorel!
Give them the powder.
[Beast snarling]
[Miru screams in pain]
No!
Please, i need you to do it!
I can't stand it, please!
[Dorel]: help me!
I've got the cure.
Do it!
Miru!
[Beast roars in pain]
Lift her.
Sit her up.
Okay, miru, listen to me.
[Wheezing]
Take-Take a deep breath.
[Coughing]
[Spluttering]
Miru....
Dorel.
[Squeals]
Miru?
She's alive.
Hey!
I want my powder!
It's not yours.
It never was.
It was for my people.
[Groaning]
[Cranking winch]
[Grunts with impact]
[Gasps]
[Groans]
Ready?
Close your mouth.
Good.
Okay, you can lie back.
You're back!
I promised,
didn't i?
Let's get you
out of here.
You sure about this?
I'm sure about this.
To continue
my father's work,
I have to go back.
[Winces]
Take care.
And you.
Bye.
[Children recite]: "b"...
What's after "b"?
[Children]: "c".
Very good.
And what's after?
[Children]: "d"...
See you.
Take care of
yourself, okay?
Yeah. You, too,
brother.
What's this one?
[Children reciting]:
"h, i, j, k..."
Kaleb!
Bye, persk.