Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
COMMENTATOR 1:
...and Bannister has done it.
Now, he's out on his feet.
His coach and team manager tell
him
he's achieved his ambition, a
mile in three minutes 59.4
seconds.
COMMENTATOR 2: Jimmy Hines
is going to win the race!
Jim Hines is the winner! Lennox
Miller, second, Charlie Greene,
third.
Jim Hines is the world's
fastest human.
COMMENTATOR 3: He breaks the
world record by an astonishing
margin,
one minute and 17 seconds.
And history has been made in
Berlin in astonishing style.
CAPCOM:
You are go for landing. Over.
[RADIO BEEPS]
BUZZ ALDRIN: Roger. Understand.
Go for landing. 3,000 feet.
CAPCOM: Altitude, 1600.
1400 feet, still looking very
good.
ALDRIN: We're go.
We're go.
Contact light.
OK, engine stop.
CAPCOM: We copy you down, Eagle.
NEIL ARMSTRONG:
It's one small step for man,
one giant leap for mankind.
REPORTER: Welcome to a foggy
morning here in Vienna, Austria,
where one man will attempt to go
where no man has been before.
Pushing his body and
mind to the limit
with the aid of scientific
research and meticulous
preparation,
Kenya's Eliud Kipchoge will hope
to run 26.2 miles in under two
hours
and, in doing so, beat one of
the great sporting barriers of
our time.
Kipchoge! Kipchoge!
[INSECTS CHIRP]
[SINGING]
[DOG BARKS]
[SPEAKS SWAHILI]
[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
[IN ENGLISH]
[STARTING PISTOL]
COMMENTATOR: Hicham El Guerrouj
coming home,
Eliud Kipchoge, Kenenisa Bekele.
Kipchoge in the red.
Can he get to the finals? Yes!
Kipchoge edging out
Hicham El Guerrouj!
COMMENTATOR 2: Eighteen years of
age. Eliud Kipchoge.
You know, you hear about child
prodigies that can play the
piano.
How can you do this at 18, when
you should be a senior in high
school?
NDUHIU: You know, science
has it that the first man to run
42K
below two hours,
will do it in about 2075.
That is 50 years from now.
He wants to do it now.
His mind is... [EXHALES SHARPLY]
It's something you can't
describe.
Berlin, 2015,
he is running at kilometer-five
and the insoles are flapping
out.
And you're saying...
this guy will drop from this
because it will cause blisters.
But he went on,
and actually set his personal
best.
So you look at him and you say,
"OK, this is magical."
[LAUGHS] Because you were seeing
somebody here with a mind that,
if he puts it on something,
nothing will distract him from
it.
He will go for it.
COMMENTATOR:
Kipchoge puts his foot down.
The London Marathon
belongs to Eliud Kipchoge.
Eliud Kipchoge.
Eliud Kipchoge,
arguably the greatest ever.
This will be
the first sub 2:02 clocking,
and by a monstrous margin,
he is going to break the world
record.
Particularly in marathon
running, he is the greatest
ever, by a long way.
The quickest.
A man who knows how to win.
COMMENTATOR: Sang is second.
One, two, three for Kenya.
SANG: I was a fortunate guy
to have had help from so many
people throughout my childhood
years.
All the way to being a runner.
So, when I came back,
one of the things that I wanted
to do
was to give back
to the community.
So I was actively involved in
helping young athletes in this
country.
Somehow Eliud knew
that I was in this position,
and he came to me
like any other youngster
asking for a training plan.
I would give him a training plan
for two weeks,
and he would come,
religiously, every two weeks,
to ask for more.
But at one point he told me,
"I've made the regional team
to go to the Nationals.
I want to be guided."
He also told me that he took up
running because he used to see
me run
at the high school, and said
why don't I try, like this guy?
And that's why he was coming to
me for advice.
So that was the beginning.
COMMENTATOR:
He breaks the world record
by an astonishing margin.
One minute and 17 seconds.
Patrick Sang, his coach, his
companion
for run after run, race after
race, year after year.
SANG: It's just pure trust.
He never asks what are we going
to do next week, next month,
tomorrow.
And I think, without trust,
you cannot go far in this
business.
All of us in life, we go through
different phases.
And any situation
gives you lessons.
And it depends on how you
interact with that background.
Some will take it positively,
and use it positively.
[BIRDS CALL]
You know,
there have been so many theories
why we have this
rich pool of talent.
I believe strongly in the theory
of Darwin,
the survival of the fittest.
Most of our athletes
come from humble backgrounds.
You have to fight,
you have to be strong.
And I think in Kenya,
the strictures that were laid
down by the colonial government
to compete for the Empire
in the Empire Games
meant a tradition was formed
under that unfriendly regime.
And I think over time
they were perfected.
COMMENTATOR:
Keino making this crowd roar.
- [CROWD CHEERS]
- He is now 15 yards clear.
When you pass a place,
you leave some dust in your
wake.
And some dust can throw in
something glittering.
I think that would be something
that glitters
out of the unfriendly dust
that we experienced as a
country.
MAN: The people here in Kenya,
masses of the Africans here in
Kenya,
are probably
roughly at about the same stage
Great Britain was 500 years ago.
We do not think that the normal
forms of democracy are suitable.
COMMENTATOR: Simpson
in second place. O'Brien is
third.
Wilkinson is fourth, and surely
no one will catch the African.
SANG: People heard
through the radio
that there was this great guy
who could run so fast,
and his name was Kip Keino.
COMMENTATOR: And Keino
is going faster,
and Simpson is
going harder, too.
SANG: He was a household name.
There were songs sung about him.
When we were kids, we used to
say, "Run like Kip Keino!"
[CHILDREN CHATTER]
You get one person from an area
running very well,
then he becomes a mentor to many
others. There is an example to
follow.
[EXCITED CHATTER]
But then, there is dominance
on the Kalenjin group,
particularly where long-distance
running is concerned.
Every single time Eliud laces
his shoes and takes the guys out
for a run,
he doesn't have to say anything.
If you're in that camp,
all you have to do is see in his
eyes.
You know, his dedication
and his will to just keep
pushing every single time.
NDUHIU: For you to succeed
in the majority of these things,
you have got to get a team
that believes in your dream.
You are the vision carrier.
But the cast that supports you
have also to believe
and commit to the dream.
CHUMO: Eliud is super consistent
in whatever he does.
It's all about discipline.
It's a storm of conditions that
come together to make this man
who he is.
BRAILSFORD: He's got
an incredible physiology.
He's got incredible efficiency
as an athlete.
And he's got an absolutely
incredible mind. I mean, an
incredible mind.
COE: He is the perfect shape.
He has almost perfect posture.
He puts his feet down...
and it's a dream.
He almost floats.
Athletics is an individual sport
and Eliud is able
to make an individual sport
a kind of team sport
with the way he
does things in camp.
He feels it's a way of inspiring
people. That is something which
I see in Eliud
that you don't see
in almost any other athlete.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
SANG: Running is
a taxing exercise.
It takes a lot of energy
from the system.
The set-up we have in Kaptagat
is an ideal environment
where somebody
can have around them the right
people to give them moral
support.
CHOGE: Eliud has really helped
young people, and some of us
because what you see from him
makes you believe
that if this person can do this,
also I can do that.
He is a mentor
to so many young athletes.
Squat! Get into the
squatting position.
TRAINER: Open. Close.
Two. Close.
Three. Close. Four. Close.
[LAUGHTER]
NJOROGE: People look up to him
because he's not trying to be
something else.
He's completely sincere.
MAN: The camp is a
really special place.
The athletes organize everything
in camp themselves.
NJOROGE: It is very austere.
But I think you then get
connected with what really
matters.
You can get with very little.
All the other things are fluff.
[THUNDER]
CHOGE: There are so many things
that I've learned from him.
One of them is
really... be humble.
No matter what success you
achieve in your life, always be
humble.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
In his case, humility is
something that's absolutely
core.
He doesn't even think about it.
It's a natural thing
that emanates out from him,
really.
It's central to the way
that he operates.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
CHUMO: This is the best training
area for running.
Elite athletes.
For that person
who is aspiring to be the best.
AUGUSTINE: We believe in our
fitness, we believe in the team
that we have selected
to help Eliud.
We believe in the coaching
that's been provided for us.
So we have a strong team.
We do half squat.
CHUMO: At the end of the day,
all you can do is just
train, eat, rest, and repeat.
[SINGING]
[♪ "MESSAGE FROM KENYA"
BY THE HORACE SILVER TRIO]
[MUSIC ENDS]
NDUHIU: High-altitude training
does them a lot of good.
You develop a higher
red blood cell count
that transports the oxygen.
00:21