...and Bannister has done it.
Now, he's out on his feet. His
coach and team manager tell him
he's achieved his ambition, a
mile in three minutes 59.4 seconds.
Jimmy Hines
is going to win the race!
Jim Hines is the winner! Lennox
Miller, second, Charlie Greene, third.
Jim Hines is the world's
fastest human.
He breaks the world record
by an astonishing margin,
one minute and 17 seconds.
And history has been made in
Berlin in astonishing style.
You are go for landing. Over.
Roger. Understand.
Go for landing. 3,000 feet.
Altitude, 1600. 1400
feet, still looking very good.
We're go.
Contact light.
OK, engine stop.
We copy you down, Eagle.
It's one small step for man,
one giant leap for mankind.
Welcome to a foggy
morning here in Vienna, Austria,
where one man will attempt to go
where no man has been before.
Pushing his body and
mind to the limit
with the aid of scientific research
and meticulous preparation,
Kenya's Eliud Kipchoge will hope
to run 26.2 miles in under two hours
and, in doing so, beat one of the
great sporting barriers of our time.
Kipchoge! Kipchoge!
Hicham El Guerrouj
coming home,
Eliud Kipchoge, Kenenisa Bekele.
Kipchoge in the red.
Can he get to the finals? Yes!
Kipchoge edging out
Hicham El Guerrouj!
Eighteen years of
age. Eliud Kipchoge.
You know, you hear about child
prodigies that can play the piano.
How can you do this at 18, when
you should be a senior in high school?
You know, science has it
that the first man to run 42K
below two hours,
will do it in about 2075.
That is 50 years from now.
He wants to do it now.
His mind is...
It's something you can't describe.
Berlin, 2015,
he is running at kilometer-five
and the insoles are flapping out.
And you're saying...
this guy will drop from this
because it will cause blisters.
But he went on, and
actually set his personal best.
So you look at him and you say,
"OK, this is magical."
Because you were seeing
somebody here with a mind that,
if he puts it on something,
nothing will distract him from it.
He will go for it.
Kipchoge puts his foot down.
The London Marathon
belongs to Eliud Kipchoge.
Eliud Kipchoge.
Eliud Kipchoge,
arguably the greatest ever.
This will be
the first sub 2:02 clocking,
and by a monstrous margin, he
is going to break the world record.
Particularly in marathon running,
he is the greatest ever, by a long way.
The quickest.
A man who knows how to win.
Sang is second.
One, two, three for Kenya.
I was a fortunate guy
to have had help from so many
people throughout my childhood years.
All the way to being a runner.
So, when I came back, one
of the things that I wanted to do
was to give back
to the community.
So I was actively involved in
helping young athletes in this country.
Somehow Eliud knew
that I was in this position,
and he came to me
like any other youngster
asking for a training plan.
I would give him a training plan
for two weeks,
and he would come,
religiously, every two weeks,
to ask for more.
But at one point he told me,
"I've made the regional team
to go to the Nationals.
I want to be guided."
He also told me that he took up
running because he used to see me run
at the high school, and said
why don't I try, like this guy?
And that's why he was coming to
me for advice.
So that was the beginning.
He breaks the world record
by an astonishing margin.
One minute and 17 seconds.
Patrick Sang, his coach, his companion
for run after run, race after
race, year after year.
It's just pure trust.
He never asks what are we going to
do next week, next month, tomorrow.
And I think, without trust, you
cannot go far in this business.
All of us in life, we go through
different phases.
And any situation
gives you lessons.
And it depends on how you
interact with that background.
Some will take it positively,
and use it positively.
You know,
there have been so many theories
why we have this
rich pool of talent.
I believe strongly in the theory
of Darwin,
the survival of the fittest.
Most of our athletes
come from humble backgrounds.
You have to fight,
you have to be strong.
And I think in Kenya,
the strictures that were laid
down by the colonial government
to compete for the Empire
in the Empire Games
meant a tradition was formed
under that unfriendly regime.
And I think over time
they were perfected.
Keino making this crowd roar.
He is now 15 yards clear.
When you pass a place, you
leave some dust in your wake.
And some dust can throw in
something glittering.
I think that would be something
that glitters
out of the unfriendly dust that
we experienced as a country.
The people here in Kenya,
masses of the Africans here in Kenya,
are probably
roughly at about the same stage
Great Britain was 500 years ago.
We do not think that the normal
forms of democracy are suitable.
Simpson in second
place. O'Brien is third.
Wilkinson is fourth, and surely
no one will catch the African.
People heard
through the radio
that there was this great guy
who could run so fast,
and his name was Kip Keino.
And Keino
is going faster,
and Simpson is
going harder, too.
He was a household name.
There were songs sung about him.
When we were kids, we used to
say, "Run like Kip Keino!"
You get one person from an area
running very well,
then he becomes a mentor to many
others. There is an example to follow.
But then, there is dominance
on the Kalenjin group,
particularly where long-distance
running is concerned.
Every single time Eliud laces his
shoes and takes the guys out for a run,
he doesn't have to say anything.
If you're in that camp, all you
have to do is see in his eyes.
You know, his dedication
and his will to just keep
pushing every single time.
For you to succeed
in the majority of these things,
you have got to get a team
that believes in your dream.
You are the vision carrier.
But the cast that supports you
have also to believe
and commit to the dream.
Eliud is super consistent
in whatever he does.
It's all about discipline.
It's a storm of conditions that come
together to make this man who he is.
He's got
an incredible physiology.
He's got incredible efficiency
as an athlete.
And he's got an absolutely incredible
mind. I mean, an incredible mind.
He is the perfect shape.
He has almost perfect posture.
He puts his feet down...
and it's a dream.
He almost floats.
Athletics is an individual sport
and Eliud is able
to make an individual sport
a kind of team sport
with the way he
does things in camp.
He feels it's a way of inspiring people.
That is something which I see in Eliud
that you don't see
in almost any other athlete.
Running is
a taxing exercise.
It takes a lot of energy
from the system.
The set-up we have in Kaptagat
is an ideal environment
where somebody
can have around them the right
people to give them moral support.
Eliud has really helped
young people, and some of us
because what you see from him
makes you believe
that if this person can do this,
also I can do that.
He is a mentor
to so many young athletes.
Squat! Get into the
squatting position.
Open. Close.
Two. Close.
Three. Close. Four. Close.
People look up to him
because he's not trying to be
something else.
He's completely sincere.
The camp is a
really special place.
The athletes organize everything
in camp themselves.
It is very austere.
But I think you then get
connected with what really matters.
You can get with very little.
All the other things are fluff.
There are so many things
that I've learned from him.
One of them is
really... be humble.
No matter what success you
achieve in your life, always be humble.
In his case, humility is
something that's absolutely core.
He doesn't even think about it.
It's a natural thing that
emanates out from him, really.
It's central to the way
that he operates.
This is the best training
area for running.
Elite athletes.
For that person
who is aspiring to be the best.
We believe in our
fitness, we believe in the team
that we have selected
to help Eliud.
We believe in the coaching
that's been provided for us.
So we have a strong team.
We do half squat.
At the end of the day,
all you can do is just
train, eat, rest, and repeat.
High-altitude training
does them a lot of good.
You develop a higher
red blood cell count
that transports the oxygen.
So when you go and run now at sea
level, you find you have an advantage
because you're able to carry
the oxygen through
much easier than
the other person.
An elite athlete will be used to
having to capture the oxygen very well.
Their genomes are crafted
by the evolutionary process
to produce the proteins necessary
to capture the oxygen easily,
because the oxygen is thin.
But it can't be just that.
The elite performers in Kenya are
also inheriting the right epigenome.
That is, the ability to maintain
those controls
over, not only your muscles,
but also the rest of the body.
How we behave, the lifestyle,
the training,
the ways in which the body
tells the genome what to do.
I've been fascinated
throughout my career
by why certain ethnic groups
have excelled in sport.
If you asked me in 2000,
I would have said it's genetic.
But 20 years later,
it's very clear to me,
and it's actually
well accepted now,
that what we're observing is a
socio-economic cultural phenomenon.
The very best, or the very,
very unique individuals,
where genetics
plays a massive role
but genes alone
will not produce success.
You need that right environment.
You close your eyes
and you think about Kenya.
You think about athletes,
and you think about
extraordinary performances.
And there is an ambition, an
aspiration, amongst young Kenyan kids
to want to be great runners.
When we came out
of colonial administration,
we became independent.
And our first experience as a
country in international competitions
was so positive because
we won medals from the word go.
And that, in itself, set a tradition
that every young athlete coming up
has a bar that is already set.
And that bar is that
if you come with anything less
than a gold, you are not good.
The Kenyans train
to be the best.
And that's, like, a mindset
that is very strong for them.
Amongst all the Kalenjin
group that are running,
there are those that can have
a very low pain threshold.
That problem that would
actually make another athlete drop,
Eliud would finish with it.
His body is exceptional,
because he is able to block
that disruption, that irritation
that the pain is causing,
and put it at the back of his
mind until the race is over.
Actually, his biggest
asset, his mind,
carries him through
those very trying moments.
He is very
strong mentally.
He has really developed a way
of overcoming the pain.
He always smiles,
he always concentrates,
he always keeps focus
on what he does.
And I've tried and
it really works.
You smile a bit, and you forget
about the pain and just keep moving.
When you're exercising,
and you're competing
at a very high level,
you are doing much more
than just running.
You are also putting yourself into a
state of mind in which you can do it.
It's a meditative state.
You have to align the
mind and the whole body,
so that when you tell it to
move, it moves as you direct.
If you have a disconnect
between those two things,
that's when you start losing
the momentum,
and it becomes a nightmare
for you to sustain.
We are here
at the Autodromo Nazionale Monza
to see if we can really break
this barrier.
This is something that has been
in the making for two years.
Breaking the two hours
is incredible pressure.
He experienced that
for the first time in Monza.
That kind of pressure which is
different than going for Olympics
or for London Marathon
or anything else.
And I think in Monza,
he was learning to handle it.
It was really hard for him
to convince himself
that he was going to run
under two hours.
It took him six, seven months
to prepare physically,
but mainly, mentally,
to be ready on the starting line
that he had really internalized
that he was going to achieve it.
At that time he came from
a personal best of 2:03:05.
So he had to prepare his mind
to go three minutes faster than
he had ever had done in his life.
Believe me,
that's not just a first place,
that is a moment of
marathon history.
At Monza, it was very
clear it was a very big step.
I remember going to the
racecourse at Monza
and thinking to myself,
"Three minutes. That's a lot!"
Thirty seconds.
Nine, eight, seven, six...
He was courageous.
He said,
"I'm going to give 100 percent."
And he did.
The three most
important points from Monza were
that we didn't get enough
carbohydrates inside Eliud.
The drinks didn't
work as we wanted.
The weather was not ideal.
The rain. And it was very humid.
And the other thing for Eliud
was always the crowd.
There was nobody there.
But that's also part of sports,
you know?
If we can predict everything,
why are we here?
You know, this is life.
He almost succeeded,
but he missed by 25 seconds.
It was a
learning curve for me.
He showed me a different
character of himself.
That the mind that we thought
was, "He has a strong mind,"
was stronger than we thought.
The most successful people are
the ones that are not afraid of fear.
They try, and if they fail,
they come back again.
That belief that he has
that no human is limited...
It means, once you train your mind
on something, you will achieve it.
The difference
between the good and the great
is that your head may be telling
you you possibly can't do it,
but there is
something else there
that overrules
all those cautious thoughts.
And you think, "Fuck it, I can.
And I'm gonna go for it."
We're in a different era right
now
where people believe these guys
like Eliud are actually making sure
that the generation
that will follow
are going to think,
"We are going to be running 2:00
on an open marathon, or that is
not going to be good enough."
Haile Gebrselassie
writes yet another chapter
in the most astonishing
distance-running career in history.
In 2008, Haile Gebrselassie ran
for the first time under 2:04 in Berlin.
Then more and more people are
asking, "Two hours, when will it happen?"
If you look at the curve
of the marathon records,
it would take
another 30, 40 years.
To do the impossible...
and I almost still believe
that breaking a two-hour marathon
is impossible, because I run!
And the idea of running every
kilometer at two minutes 50
is impossible in my view.
That requires this combination of
an athlete that is truly superhuman,
but also incredibly meticulous
organization
to get him to the point
where he could break two hours.
It was that feeling of, "Holy
shit, this is the real deal."
We've got this responsibility
to this athlete
who's only going to
get this one chance.
When you're going into something
at the highest level,
you're really under
a huge amount of pressure,
you have to have
done the preparation.
You have to know in your mind
that you've done all you possibly can.
In the first instance, you pull
together a little team of people,
your safe team, as it were...
So, obviously, we got Tim in.
Tim's background was in rowing,
swimming, and he is now the
most decorated coach in cycling.
What he does have is a knowledge
of performance physiology
and an ability to apply that
to a range of sports.
One A and one B.
I met Valentijn,
who is a performance manager
and looks after Eliud and his team,
and we hit it off straight away.
One of the greatest challenges in the
first instance, was to find the course.
On that side we
had Hugh Brasher,
who many will know is the
director of London Marathon.
So you had Valentijn, Hugh and myself
as a sort of senior management team.
And then there were other people
in our team.
Fran Millar, obviously
who works very closely with me.
Peter Vint who was in charge of all
the cars and the lasers and the timing.
Spencer had got all the pacers
and Robby Ketchell who'd
worked on the Nike project.
I mean, a brilliant guy. A scientist,
meteorologist, aerodynamicist.
I mean, phenomenally bright guy.
And that's one of the challenges
when you take experts from
different fields and different sports
and you try and pull them together,
you've got to have the chemistry.
We're going to have to move fast,
we're going to have to have open minds,
and communicate really, really
frequently and move at pace.
Timothy and Emanuel, you just...
you start also behind.
Because we are all
on the starting line.
- We will not start in this formation.
- Oh, yes.
We are starting on the line
and then, boom, go...
Normally, we race to win.
We win medals, we win races.
We go to the Olympics, or the Tour
de France, we win stuff in competitions.
This event is different. This is
about breaking a human barrier.
So we had to really think about
this in a slightly different way
and make sure the philosophy
of the whole attempt was based
on a performance
-first mentality.
What's going to get us to that record?
What's going to help the performance?
And if we have to work harder,
invest more, find a different way,
find a different solution for all
the other aspects of the event
that will fit around it,
then that's what we'd do.
He had run a fantastic time
in the London Marathon,
and we thought, actually,
if he ran no worse,
the same physical performance
that he did in London,
then could we look for
the marginal gains?
The optimizers,
as we'd call them.
So, make sure the surface of the
road is absolutely perfect.
Perfect weather conditions.
We wanted the corners to be
more than 32 meters' radius.
What's the thermoregulation?
What's the fueling strategy?
What's the pacing strategy?
The aerodynamics?
All of those elements
were critical in essentially
what, for me, would
be marginal gains.
We improve shoes, we
improve drinks, all these things.
But that's natural.
In ten years, we will be again finding
out more things, and different things.
It's just a point in history
where we are at at the moment
and we are speeding up
a little bit of history.
I always wanted it
to be somewhere iconic
because it's such
a special event.
I didn't really want to be in an
airfield in Norfolk, you know?
Or somewhere in northern Germany
because those were a couple of ideas.
You get a flat course
and it's very manageable
because there's no people
around, there's no traffic.
You have to deal with all that.
If you're going to do this, it should
really be in an iconic location.
This course is actually
something really special.
When we came and saw it for
the first time, all of us looked at it
and said immediately,
"I think we found our place."
You come here and even before you
think about all of the physics around it,
and the environment
that you are trying to run in,
you get a feeling of, "This
is somewhere I can run fast."
It was June 13.
Thirteen minutes past eight,
I've got the call. It's Vienna.
It starts me crying a little
bit, just for a moment.
To have Eliud here,
and all those pacemakers?
It was the best that ever
could happen for Vienna.
So on this circuit, we have
a 4.3 kilometer section here
that we are walking on
almost perfectly flat.
It only has an elevation change
of about 2.4 meters
from one end to the other.
He's going to do 4.4 laps on it,
so that means that he is going
to do this about 8.5 times.
And there are roundabouts that are
located conveniently on either side.
Just having that circuit there
was enough for us to decide
that this is an
optimal location.
When you approach anything like
this, a big undertaking,
it's like being in a field where there's
mist and you can't see anything.
You don't know where the fence
is or where the edges are.
But you know there's a gate somewhere.
You know you can get out of the field.
But until the fog lifts, you're not
going to be able to find the gate.
And it felt like that at the
beginning of the project.
And as the fog lifted,
it was literally like all of the
elements started to fall into place.
An order fell across
the whole project.
People really seemed
to buy this concept
of, "We're doing something
that no one has ever done."
Like, that's special.
That's unique.
There was a genuine magic to it,
you know?
He is Zen-like in his
approach and his preparation.
And watching him
at close quarters develop
from the end of the finishing
line in the London Marathon,
in those few months coming up,
coming up to the level
of when he was ready
to execute that performance,
was something else.
How he approached
that was very special.
Not only did he believe in
himself, he had a brilliant way
of making everybody around him
believe in him, too.
The impact that has on everybody
else around him in a project...
Not only the other support
runners and the pacemakers,
but all of the staff,
the coaching staff, the experts,
everybody who was
working night and day
to try and bring all this
project together, that's special.
OK, good luck,
Gabs. Here we go.
Cameras, keep offering
what you can. Thank you.
Seven... six... five...
three... two...
one.
Well, the waiting
is over. The moment has arrived.
We are just moments away.
And there he is.
You know, thousands,
if not millions, of people
will be going out for
a Saturday run today.
Well, this could be the most famous
Saturday run the world has ever seen.
And it's all about this man,
Eliud Kipchoge from Kenya.
The sub two
hour marathon is considered
the Everest of distance running.
Something that people, for a long
time, thought was nearly impossible,
we wouldn't see
in our lifetimes.
And in the last few years,
it's suddenly hoved into view.
And we might see it today.
It's very exciting.
We've already got crowds
who are all expectant of history
being made today in Vienna.
He's done everything
there is to do in this sport.
This is the last barrier.
The two-hour marathon.
This would be his legacy.
Every i has been
dotted, every t crossed.
Is he going to do it?
The weather, the fact that it's
foggy, a bit foggier than expected,
throws another little doubt,
maybe, into the minds.
This is not a
foregone conclusion.
So we are into the final few
minutes before countdown.
- Fifteen seconds.
- Stand by, everyone.
Stand by three, stand by five.
- Here we go.
- Stand by ten.
From the president to the
simple Kenyan in a village,
we want to witness history
being made.
And we are confident that today,
God willing,
we will have a celebration
and 1:59 is going to be a
reality. Thank you very much.
We have lift-off.
Apollo Kipchoge is up and away.
The race, when it started,
it was beautiful.
As a coach, you know,
you look at the body language.
I saw the eyes of Eliud in the camera
and he was very focused and relaxed.
Everybody was psyched up.
The pacers were in high spirits
and I said,
"It's going to be a good day."
When he started
the race, I was nervous.
But when I saw how
he was running,
he was really in good shape,
and the pacers were also.
I was nervous... exciting...
And...
I had faith that he could do it.
We had a starting-race plan.
If everything went perfectly,
the plan was to go at the
first kilometer at 2:48: 0.
And every other kilometer
after that 2:50:45
which would give
a finish time of 1:59:50.
The speed
at which they are traveling
is quite extraordinary.
It's worth trying to put it into
some sort of layman's terms.
He is going to be running,
or trying to run, consistently
at 13 miles an hour.
Twenty-one kilometers an hour.
It's mind blowing.
I challenge people to go
to their local track
and just run one lap, 400 meters
of the track, in 68 seconds.
I bet you not many
people can do that!
This is crazy!
We can
break this down in so many ways.
One lap of the track,
at your local track, 68 seconds.
And he has to do that 105 times.
Each hundred meters in 17 seconds.
And he will be doing
that 422 times.
We are very familiar in cycling
with the concept of aerodynamics
and riding behind another one. A
teammate taking the brunt of the wind
and having to really
tire themselves out
so the person behind can be
fresher and then try and go for the win.
So Robby and the
aerodynamics team
set about looking at the formations
that were traditional in running.
And, also, throwing out
some creative ideas.
They ran their CFD models,
and their computer models,
and we made models, and the
miniature models went in the wind tunnel.
Positioned them all, et cetera.
Lo and behold, they came back
and they said,
"Actually, we found something
pretty interesting."
In a typical marathon,
if he was to run by himself,
he would have about
six Newtons of drag.
We've come up with a formation that
has reduced that to about one Newton.
It's a huge improvement in the
drag that he'll have when he's running.
So the pacers have a huge impact
on being able to help Eliud
break two hours.
Come on, guys!
I was there when he
did the test in the winter,
and it was fascinating to know.
We always thought pacemaking
would be like the birds flying in the sky
in the open-V formation.
But it turned out not to be a V.
It turned out to be a Y.
There are five runners in front
of Eliud and two behind him.
The front-runners will be
positioned over here on the sides
and there will be two of them.
But there will be a gap in
between them which is not natural.
That's part of the reason that training
them how to run like this was difficult.
Behind those two runners
will be two more runners
that are positioned further in,
so we're starting to create a V.
Then, behind them will be the
captain who runs in front of Eliud.
At some point, Fosbury
did his flop for the first time.
And people went,
"What? What's he doing?"
And yet it worked.
So we said, "Why isn't this
the Fosbury flop of running?"
We were maximizing what we call
the outwash around each runner.
So the outwash means that when
wind hits a runner on the torso,
it changes the direction of the wind,
and it's going to go out to the sides.
So, in effect,
what was happening,
the air was hitting the guy
that was on the outside.
Some of the air was coming
outside, some was going inside.
A guy on the inside of him,
on his shoulder,
was then getting the air coming
from guy number one,
plus the air hitting him. So
quite a lot more air, in fact.
And, of course, this is happening
on two sides of the funnel, as it were.
So the air, eventually, was
funneled right into the middle,
and the guy who was in the
center in the middle, took a lot of air.
He was getting
quite a buffeting!
And what happened was,
it created a big wake.
It actually created a nice little hole
where there was pretty much still air.
In that wake is where
Eliud needs to try to run
as close to the captain
in front of him.
Typically, you wouldn't run
there. Your visibility isn't the best.
You also don't want to trip.
So you don't want to step on the
runner in front of you.
They'll kick back and
vary a little bit.
The absolute trust
between all eight people at any
one time cannot be overstated.
Bernard Lagat there, right at
the heart of it, the initial captain.
And he will be handing over
shortly to the second team
and Eric Kiptanui
will be the second captain.
This event was always going
to have a bit of ballet about it.
You needed everyone to know what
they were doing, what their steps were.
We said, "OK, it's a big risk,
we haven't got much time.
We'll have to practice this
thing. If we go with this,
then we want to make sure, as
much as we can, that it's right."
It is kind of tricky,
but then, as a captain,
I need to keep my guys calm.
I want to make sure that they understand
the formation, to stay in their lanes.
At the same time, note that they are
the ones controlling the pace in the front.
The captain was the leader.
He was in charge of all the pacers
to make sure they executed exactly
what they were supposed to execute.
This is like the queen bee,
protected by the drones and the others
and it's that beautiful thing,
the exchange of the pacemakers!
And we're keeping
an eye out here
for the first change-over.
As I think Shalane was
likening... Here we go!
Shalane, talk us through this.
Yeah, I was likening it to, in
the US, a NASCAR pit stop,
where we change our tires,
fine tune the machine...
Same thing goes here for Eliud.
He's switching out
and getting fresh runners
that are hopefully smoothly
transitioning into formation
so that Eliud can just draft, and
conserve as much energy as possible.
Those changes
were not easy.
One slip, one wrong turn with a
trip-up, and it could all be over.
We wanted to maintain the pace
as well as the team exiting
and the team coming in.
So we want the team
that is going out
to really move out smoothly
and maintain the pace.
Then we also want the team going
in to come in smoothly,
not distracting Eliud.
We probably have 40 of
the top athletes on the planet
and they're all working
for a common cause
and one man, which is Eliud.
The man
at the heart of it,
he's already the
world record-holder,
and he is surrounded
by his band of brothers.
We've got 15 Kenyans, seven
Americans, six Ugandans.
We've got Australians, Norwegians,
Ethiopians and one Japanese pacemaker.
It really is
a truly international field.
They all idolize
and look up to Eliud.
I think they look at this as a
chance to be a part of history today.
It's a beautiful opportunity
to help someone
that we know can
transcend our sport.
You know, running is the
most natural sport in the world.
You grow up, you walk, you run.
I think that's why this sport
is so beautiful.
You can run without shoes.
You don't need anything to run.
From an
African perspective,
right now, there are young
Africans watching,
and just looking to see
what human potential looks like,
waiting to be the next Kipchoge.
This is so inspiring, not only
to runners all over the world,
but to everybody,
that no human is limited.
You can go for your goals
if you have that energy
and that strong mind
that you do whatever
you want to do.
So it's not about running.
It is about inspiring the world
everybody else in the world
that everything is possible.
And nothing is limited for you.
We are approaching the
first of the roundabouts here.
This is the Lusthaus. This is the
smaller of the two roundabouts.
In the middle of that
is a former hunting lodge.
The turn radius around
the Lusthaus on average
is about 27.4 meters.
Originally, when we came here,
the surface was pretty old.
We knew that we were
going to resurface.
When you're running
at 5.861 meters per second
at a 27.4-meter radius
you would, optimally, be looking
for about a ten-degree banking.
In a real-world condition, we
can't create a ten-degree banking,
but we can do something
to improve the current situation
of there being a negative two percent
of a camber going away from Eliud.
If you think of a track
athlete who runs indoors
you run on a 200
-meter banked track.
Now, if you're going fast,
if it was flat at 200 meters,
you're going to drift
towards the outside.
You're allowed to
step off the lines,
but you'd want
a little bit of a cushion.
- Yeah, I'm sure you saw me going...
- Yeah, yeah, I was, like...
It's a bit dangerous
when you arrive at such a turn,
when you run at a fast pace.
You might slip a little bit
outside or even twist your ankle.
They have actually raised it,
so that as you're running there,
you feel like you're running
an indoor track.
You're supported
and you're staying balanced.
It changes it from negative two
percent to a positive one percent
so we get a three
-percent difference.
We estimate that it can save him
up to three seconds per lap.
So that's 12 seconds
over the entire distance.
He won't save that time,
because he actually won't
run quicker because of that
but he will conserve
more energy.
That's going to allow him to run
at the sub two-hour pace for longer.
OK, you can see
the recent splits there.
The 2:50 mark in green
means that he is on schedule
for a sub two-hour marathon pace.
2:52 and 2:51 in the red,
means he's just outside.
He's been twice on target,
and twice just outside.
It just shows us, Ed,
even in these early stages,
just how challenging it is.
So, in what we call
the POC, on the day of the race,
the Performance
Operations Center,
we had representatives from the
aerodynamics team, the pacemakers team,
the car and the laser, the timing
system, the meteorology team,
and myself in communication
with Valentijn on the road.
Any information that needed to
come from any of those specialist teams
to Valentijn was
done through me.
Communication
taking place
with Valentijn on the bicycle.
He's giving instructions out.
I mean, it looks like one
smooth event, doesn't it?
But it's a million
miles from that, you know.
We had some interesting
situations in the race
where even the second kilometer,
we thought was out.
There were some kilometers that
were 2:48 and some that were 2 :52.
2:48! That's like...
They've gone out too fast.
That's the correction
from the 2km board. Over.
This is a major issue.
In our little
Mission Control pod,
it might have been looking like a
start to an event to everyone else.
"Oh, they're getting going,
getting warmed up."
We were, like,
"Whoa, OK, there's something...
What's going on?"
Tim Kerrison is sitting there
with his headphones on.
And he kind of nonchalantly
took one off
and put it on the side and said,
"All this timing you're seeing on
the telly, and that everyone can see,
it's wrong."
I was like, "What?"
He said, "Yeah, it's wrong.
They're on pace."
I said, "Are you sure?"
He said, "Absolutely. I'm right.
We're going to switch to our
back-up time and do it ourselves."
I was, like...
"OK, everybody. Forget the timing.
We're switching to back -up timing."
Two-51.
The target time
holding up pretty well.
We've been hovering
between eight and ten seconds
inside sub two-hour pace.
So, so far so good.
And, Ed, the next real milestone
will be the ten-kilometer mark.
And sub two-hour pace
would put him at, what, 28:26.
Yeah, which is
a pretty tidy 10K!
Just out of picture is Valentijn
Trouw the athletes' manager
handing now more drinks and more
gels to Eliud if he wants them.
He does take something
on board there.
How much he consumes
is actually closely monitored
by his nutritionist
who will be measuring
every time that he takes something
from his water bottle and tosses it.
They will pick it up
and hand it off to him
so he can weigh it
and know how much he consumed.
We had people just
there to grab that bottle
before it got in the crowd.
Get the bottle, get the bottle!
Right, get it in.
What's the measurement?
How much did he drink?
You feed it back in. He took
X amount of mls on that one.
OK, we need to
change the next one.
So they were modifying the
fueling strategy in-race, live.
To keep that same rhythm
for two hours...
That's a lot of things happening
in your body, your muscles.
Some muscles, especially the
hamstrings, will get very tight.
Because you're running
in the same rhythm.
Lactic acid is building up
in the muscles.
After one hour and a half, it
will be very difficult for him.
Everyone was stressed not to do
a mistake, not to make him fall.
That was the worst
that could happen.
And when it was my turn,
of course, I was stressed,
but I was so happy to be here
to help Eliud.
I think I am getting the mindset
of the Kenyans.
Believing that everything is
possible by just training every day
for months and months,
years and years.
When you go to race, you have
this self-belief that you can win.
I was more keen on
the body language
as the race progressed
because they never fell back.
But, as far as making the right
times were concerned,
they were being
guided by the laser.
Some people have criticized,
or maybe had a view about,
the role of the lead car, there.
We can see perhaps that that's
adding extra protection,
but, essentially, as far as the
experts have explained to us,
the only reason that car is
there is to project the laser pacer.
If you talked to Robby Ketchell
who designed the aerodynamics
he said, "If it were up to me,
I wouldn't have a car."
It doesn't seem like
that would be right
but all the computational flow
dynamics that they have been doing
have told them that the best
results would be without a car.
The car, obviously, had the
laser which set the pace-line
so they knew exactly
at what pace to run.
And it also had the lines to help
them stay in the corridor, if you like.
The reason that it's
15 meters in front of Eliud
is in order to throw the laser
at a significant distance.
Plus, in order to maintain the
pace precisely.
It doesn't help the runners
behind Eliud
and it doesn't help
Eliud's position,
but it helps those five guys
directly in front of him.
Let's just home in
here on Eliud Kipchoge.
This is a great shot for us
to see the cadence,
and the way the rhythm,
the natural rhythm...
From memory, correct me,
both of you, if I'm wrong,
but I don't think we've had
a kilometer outside 2:52.
I think that's the slowest we've had.
- Correct.
That's incredible.
If you really think about it,
that is incredible pacing!
Eliud has trained
himself incredibly well
to keep the same
rhythm for two hours.
And the rhythm of all those
different athletes is like a drum
hammering on the streets.
It reminds me of
that same feeling
of them running in the long runs
in Kenya.
A kind of silence where you
only hear the steps going on.
For me, ja,
it sounds to me like music.
There are people who are
a little bit cynical about this
and saying "Well, it's not
an official world record,
and there's so much technology, so
much science, why should we care?"
There is
something artificial about this
but that's because they want to see one
guy do what no one else has done before.
It would be incredibly hard
to achieve this in an open race.
And so, I think there is room
in the sport
for both events like this,
and also, like, open races.
London Marathon is fantastic,
and this is fantastic.
Obviously, we know
technology goes into sportswear
and has done for
a very long time,
but we shouldn't underestimate
what's going on on his feet,
and how important they are,
those trainers.
I don't think
we should kid ourselves.
I don't think it would've been
possible to try to go under two hours
five or ten years ago.
The technology has developed so
fast and he's in the latest innovation.
He's in shoes that no one else
has ever run before.
It's a step change from where we
were even two years ago.
So, we're talking about, maybe,
a few seconds
which in this context
is an enormous amount of help.
It could be vital.
World athletics are
reportedly getting ready to ban
Nike's Vaporfly shoes for giving
runners an unfair advantage.
The introduction of the Vaporfly
to the running community
really has changed what we think
of as possible.
In very simplistic terms, it's
almost like a mini pogo stick.
You put the shoe on and you're
immediately aware that it's different.
Nike Sports research labs
are working with Kipchoge
on enhancing his shoes
to break that two-hour mark.
But I guess the big
question comes down to,
if you're not wearing the Nike
Vaporfly, can you compete?
These shoes certainly are
game-changing and transformative.
The athletes typically are
sponsored, always sponsored,
by only the shoe industry.
So that industry
controls the sport.
Some of the biggest sponsors of
our sport are the shoe companies.
We don't really want to be telling
them what they can and can't do.
But there are obviously things
that we would be concerned about
if that technology started
to become the predominant story.
I think the research right
now shows actual innovation
that blurs the line
of enhancement.
It
enhances performance
because it's such
a technological sneaker.
The properties
of the carbon fiber plate and...
No society, no market
economy, has ever prospered
by trying to stifle innovation.
I think, whether
we like it or not,
technology comes into a lot of
sports these days.
I mean, look at cycling. The
advances we've made in the bicycle.
Does that take anything away
from Egan Bernal
or Geraint Thomas when they win
the Tour de France?
They still need to ride it.
The world of sport
needs to consider
that the effects of
technological doping
are vastly superior
than traditional doping.
So, therefore, you
and I, the public,
can no longer gauge
what you're watching.
For anybody who says this isn't
right, put the shoes on yourself.
Wear the same kit,
get yourself down to Vienna,
get a couple of people to run in
front of you, and see how fast you go.
Well, this is the sixth of nine
teams.
There are nine
rotations, if you like.
And, there we are, Eric Kiptanui,
who is having a busy old morning.
He's back on as
the team captain.
I tell you, that guy is in
shape!
Technology has a place,
and it helps.
But, at the end, it
is the human being.
And I think that's what I find
really amazing with Eliud.
At the end of the day, it is him.
And he knows what really drives him
and it isn't the technology
that will drive him.
Sub two hours has everything to
do with the changing of times,
changing of history,
changing of sports in general.
But what remains, there is a guy
a fantastic athlete, Eliud Kipchoge,
who is running 42 kilometers.
Yes, there is some
science involved
but it's still a person
that has to do this.
I think Eliud did not land
from another planet.
We know what he has done,
we know his potential.
He ran a world record in Berlin.
And I think the opinions of
people should be reflected in reality
of exactly the journey
he has come through.
I think there was a slight trip.
- Was there a trip?
- Yes.
I just saw Eliud have a little
trip-up in that transition.
12K to go, then.
This is where the critical stage
of the race starts.
We can make some comparisons
with how he was going in Monza.
Actually, up to halfway,
he was inside sub two-hour pace.
And at halfway exactly,
he was three seconds inside
and then at 25K,
he was still two seconds inside.
Even at 30K, he was only two
seconds outside sub two-hour pace.
And he admitted afterwards
that it was in the final 10K
when he really
started to feel it.
Literally no human
has tried to attempt this.
There's a lot of unknowns
physiologically
as to what Eliud can handle.
He's putting
himself through something
really, really extraordinary
here, and he will be emotional.
Thoughts bubble up. Thoughts
you think you suppressed.
Bad demons sit on one shoulder
and good angels sit on the other.
The way you think about pain,
is the way your life will be.
In this world, you need to undergo
pain in order to be successful.
If you understand
how marathon is,
at the apex of the pain,
that's where success is.
In training, he has
visualized these tough moments
and he's pushed through in training
and said, "This is the crucial moment.
This is when you have to execute
and push through the pain."
So, he has practiced
this over and over.
We've just detected the
slightest smile-stroke- grimace
on the face of Eliud Kipchoge.
When the smile appears, Shalane,
that normally suggests
that he's hurting.
Yeah, that's the classic Eliud,
when he is leaning into that hurt.
It means he's working hard.
He has to be thinking right now,
and I'm sure this is a version
of what he's thinking,
"If not now, when?"
He looked like
he came through that moment.
In the mission control, it was,
like...
This is on.
This is on now. This is coming!
And it was exciting, like, "Oh!"
It's just those moments,
what you live for in sport!
One and a half hours about
to click round on the clock.
We have just under 30 minutes
to try and get Eliud Kipchoge
into the history books,
here in Vienna.
And I can't stress enough,
the crowd out on the course
is absolutely phenomenal.
He gives energy
and he gets energy back.
And that is a wonderful
place to be in.
We Kenyans are very good
as a cheer squad.
It's all about the
support at the back
that comes out shining
to the whole world.
He has trained himself
incredibly well for what is going on
and what he takes in, and what he
shuts down from the outside world.
Here we go,
this is team number eight.
Wow. I think we just need to take a
pause, don't we, and just breathe?
I feel very nervous right now.
Because anyone
who has ever run a marathon
will know that the
last few miles,
anything can happen,
and the wheels can come off.
He looks really good. You're
just hoping that he's got this.
Here are the final team of
pacemakers, team number nine.
They will take them home from 38
kilometers right through to the finish.
And the captain, of course, he
was the captain in the first team.
It's Bernard Lagat.
There he is, itching to go,
Bernard Lagat.
And how fitting that the 44 -year-old,
the oldest pacemaker in the team,
the most experienced and
a dear, dear friend of Eliud,
should be the captain
on the final leg.
We're on the verge of history
here, folks.
We don't know what the
limits of human performance are.
There are people who
think they do know
and remarkable humans,
and teams of humans,
keep proving them wrong.
Our own individual performances
are nearly always linked to a
collective performance somewhere.
And I think for all of us,
in all walks of life, in fact,
we're stronger together.
It goes so much further than
running. So much further than sport.
It goes to show
that the preconceived limits that
everyone has on everything in life,
can be challenged.
It's incredible.
That line,
"No human is limited,"
I would impart it on any girl.
That no matter your gender, no
matter where you're born from,
you are not limited.
You are supposed to actualize
your dreams and your passion.
It means that you
should always work hard,
no matter what.
Not listening to negativity,
but listening to positive minds.
In most circumstances,
you and me limit ourselves.
It is not other people who limit
us. It is us who limit ourselves.
And I do believe the moment
we get over that hurdle,
then you have the whole world
outside there open for you to conquer.
I think the concept is spreading
in all sectors of our society.
It is a momentum that is,
to me, positive.
You meet teachers from different
schools that, when preparing students,
they are quoting
the "No human is limited" story.
And we can see
lives being changed.
I don't know about
you guys, but my heart,
I can feel it pounding in my
shirt this morning.
It's 500 meters to go,
he is almost there.
He has one hand on history
here in Vienna.
There was an
agreement, that if he felt good,
he was gonna tell Valentijn
and the other guys would peel off.
And, sure enough, Valentijn gets
the nod and they pulled off. Oh!
What a wonderful moment!
What an absolutely
brilliant moment.
Three hundred meters to
go, let's bring him home.
He's pointing.
"Come on!" he says.
Eliud Kipchoge has the hand of
history on his shoulder.
Neil Armstrong
we had on the moon in 1969.
We had Roger Bannister and
the four-minute mile 65 years ago.
Edmund Hillary, the first
man to climb Everest, in 1953.
Eliud Kipchoge is
on his way here.
It's overwhelming,
you know? It's a big deal.
People talk about these things,
they look at it.
"A guy ran a marathon."
He's the first bloke ever,
ever in the human race,
in human history, to do that.
And you think, "Oh, God."
And in a crazy little way
you've supported that, you know?
And it means a lot. It
means a lot to a lot of people.
It means a lot to me.