Simply Releases Toppers
Simply The Best
Proudly Presents: Alvin And The Chipmunks
CHIPWRECKED
Translated by Simply Releases Toppers Tokke
and Suurtje
One, two, three...
Boys.
Guys, stop.
Where's Alvin?
- Hi, Dave.
Where were you?
- I try to ships.
I already did.
I've also seen our room...
I made the bed closest to the window...
I ordered a pina colada.
And I have given to us parasailing.
- There you are too young.
I thought we went on vacation
to have fun.
For family vacations, only to
fun.
But first we need some rules to capture.
First, you should not go to bed
to everyone in the room.
This is a good, Simon.
This is our first line.
Will we go through the rest.
- Come on, Dave.
Rules is my middle name.
This is your captain.
Everything is permitted.
You do not get bored.
We had about rules, Alvin.
Sorry, I did not know we according to the present agreement should not make fun.
You can have fun.
If you act not like a child?
When you treat me more like a child?
- If you feel like an adult behaves.
I'm going to act like an adult,
like you...
Not now, girls.
- I'm sorry, Dave.
I must prepare for
dinner with the captain.
Do we eat with the captain?
- No, I. You stay here.
I have to apologize for everything
what Alvin did.
This is so unfair. Not for us, not for Dave
and certainly not for the captain.
This certainly looking forward to dinner with me
.
I'll go talk to Dave.
See if I can iron the whole thing smooth.
What is it, Simon?
- I would never say to Alvin.
It is really irresponsible.
I really want something.
You want me to propose something?
- I'm going crazy from him.
For far longer than he makes you mad.
What is it?
Imagine Alvin
a fiery race horse.
Is that your advice?
- I'm not done Dave.
Alvin is a race horse.
- And you are helpful jockey.
This is to place it on the racetrack
of life support.
But if you hold the reins too tight, then that
race horse fighting and goats.
That's not fun for anyone.
But if you hold the reins looser...
So he flies off the track into the fence.
I know you want to protect Alvin.
Sometimes children rise above himself,
if you give them confidence.
Room is on its way.
Lights out at nine hours.
Question.
If we in this room are held captive
...
By Alvin.
Can we at least see a movie?
Let's see what there is.
You choose just one film.
You are old enough to decide.
Really, Dave?
- Absolutely.
Dave looks so elegant.
- Have fun.
Dave, before you go.
I made you something.
... That's really - it is soft. You can sleep with it.
All colors are in process.
It fits everywhere.
Great. I do it after eating at.
- You can now belt.
That everyone sees it that
to the master table.
Nice, a real chip Madness.
Have fun, guys.
But not too much fun.
I am still very upset.
See you, Dave.
And hello, ladies.
I want my cocktail shaken, not stirred.
Where are you going?
- At the casino.
I'm Simon Rappy.
- No.
Dave said...
- he said, and I quote...
"We are old enough to decide for themselves."
We are old enough to choose from a movie.
Not so.
Look like what Theodore did.
What's wrong with this movie?
- That's for babies.
Why Dave treats us like babies
likely.
Come on, Theodore.
That's more like it.
Alvin, please.
I say, we're going out tonight
- in our pajamas?
I know already
I am the winner.
These dresses are great.
- You're so perky.
Thank you.
That's my job.
Sorry.
- What are you?
We are the Chip Juliettes.
- I'm Eleanor.
My sister tried to apologize.
What? The stairs at my girlfriend's toes
...
Or her silly silly dances.
You did not.
- Did they do.
Take the weird stuff out of my face.
Unless you want to meet my claws.
They are real.
Do you do that?
Captain, I'm really sorry
what happened to Alvin.
He is a child and wanted
but what fun.
There is nothing wrong with that. Our pelican
ensures that everyone has fun.
He goes on a hang glider around the ship.
It's really amusing.
The safety of passengers
is my priority.
Alvin or anyone else, must not be compromised
.
Believe me, I understand.
Alvin  If our lines again violate
Then there will be consequences follow.
We do not want anybody hurt.
Hot.
- I'm sorry.
Unbelievable.
Such a nice pants.
Do you have a problem with me?
- Yes.
Why?
- Either you do not know.
I do not know.
Ian?
What are you doing here?
I'm working, Dave.
- Is this your job?
There are not many record companies interested
a man to believe...
Who has messed with the Chipmunks, and the Chip
Ettes...
And Justin Bieber rejected.
Twice.
I'm sorry that you lost your job, and...
Your dignity. That you do not get back
by hot things to throw over me.
You're right, Dave. It's too late for me
to my old life back... more
But it's not too late
to ruin yours too.
Do you want to ruin my life?
- Let's start with this holiday.
If I see squirrels a line break, I go straight to
Captain Correlli.
You're in my house.
Technically it's not a house but a
ship.
The point is...
I love watching you.
If a hawk.
Please eat my brains on.
What are you looking at "Jungle Monster 4 '?
Alvin, how can you...
Girls?
No.
I'll be back.
It's dark.
You are nominated for the International Music Award
. That is fantastic.
Yeah, pretty cool.
I think.
If you hold a lot geslijm.
We fly immediately after the cruise go.
We hope 'album of the year' are.
Then you're the youngest ever winner.
- So young I am not.
I'm in a casino. Way past bedtime.
Not that I have a bedtime.
Nobody tells me what to do.
I wonder who "Alvin" is.
Anyway, it was a fun conversation.
But I must run.
You have big problems, young man.
You can follow me on...
I did not play.
Honest.
Your winnings, sir.
Busted.
I'm not running away. Actually, only to Alvin
stop.
Right.
- There they are, captain.
Captain.
- What will he do?
Should we walk the plank?
- Is there a board?
There is no shelf.
Disobey you again...
Then you put the ship, and
miss the International Music Award. Got it?
Yes, Dave.
- Absolutely.
Unless we have been disobedient.
- Why would you be doing?
Imagine that you say I
here to stay.
'Alvin, if you rid of that chair,
get punishment.
But, I see pirates.
Climbing ropes
along the side of the ship.
I would simply grab my Swiss army knife can
and cut the ropes.
But I must stay, right?
Yes, Alvin, that you need.
And what do you do with a pocket knife?
Any penknife you talking about?
Give it here.
You can hurt yourself.
So, I was able to save the whole ship...
Of 'steling' and 'roving'
And I still receive punishment?
Alvin, the word "steling 'does not exist.
And roving' either.
But, he does have a point, Dave.
There are times when you need us trust
things to arrange themselves.
I trusted you tonight, and see what
that brought me.
He's probably mad
a pretty girl.
Captain Correlli
You may still participate in an activity.
Is paragliding, wave boarding,
or bungee jumping?
No, shuffleboard.
According to my calculations is 10% and 90%
shuffle board.
That's funny.
Thank you.
Do you really?
Dave, I think I prefer the board wants.
- Sorry, Alvin. This should be done.
And I can do something, I did not have long
.
Absolutely nothing.
Britney approaching the PUK.
Fits her movement.
Look at me, quite irritated...
And wondering whether I will keep my mouth ever
.
Realizes that perhaps this is the case, and
slide.
Too short.
A costly mistake, ladies and gentlemen.
That will be its
the rest of her career pursuing.
Make jokes all you want, but even you can not
interesting.
Really? Would you make this interesting?
Then I can make this interesting.
What are you doing, Alvin?
Dave keeps an eye on us.
The poor man has had no rest since he
us has met.
He is exhausted.
About, three, two, one.
Lights out.
Time to sleep. Time out lines
into fun rules.
Do you understand? I took the rules of
penalty rules...
And set it to pleasure rules.
It works.
You want to trade?
This is a beautiful kite.
I can see everything.
Come on, Simon.
Forget it. I try always to save only
and I get in trouble.
This is good.
- Simon, do something.
Really?
- Now, Simon.
Alvin has problems, and Simon must rescue
it appears again.
Thank you, brother.
Thank you.
Sleep baby sleep in the nice chair
when you wake up, your hair falls
Dave, help us.
- Boys.
No.
No, if you want to hang gliding
put you on the list like everyone else.
You do not understand.
Oh yes. Dave Seville is so special,
that the rules do not apply to him.
Release.
- No, you let go.
No.
Awesome.
Well done, Seville.
I?
- Yeah, you.
Save your breath, Dave.
They come back to me.
Looking back,
this was a bad idea.
We're losing altitude.
I do not think I have more volhou.
I'm so hungry.
A bite it.
No.
- Just nibble?
Do not nibble.
- Maybe I can lick the icing?
The glaze keeps you alive, Theodore.
Its high fat content makes
a waterproof barrier.
I'm dying of hunger.
There are a lot of other things you
to die before you die of starvation.
Dehydration, heat exhaustion...
- An Island.
No, an island would be useful.
So you would really have to say.
We live.
I'll kill you.
- Nobody kills anyone.
Does not matter that he deserves it.
Thanks, Si, the bad impression that I do
.
We do not worry about it
Dave now knows that we're gone.
The whole crew looks to us now.
Let's go relax and eat donuts.
Did you that?
Can not you speed?
- We are here for two hours.
Thanks to my pilates move my legs
fast, but they are now slower.
Put ??your feet up.
Let me wait.
You can not. The costume is a whole.
No pick where you can pick up the feet.
Do this suit off.
I can not.
- Why not?
I have no bottom.
Look.
- No, it's good. I believe you.
No, look, an island.
Perhaps the Chipmunks washed up there.
Faster.
Come on.
Please.
It is not long until our rescue plane
SOS see...
And our flight back to civilization.
I can not hear airplanes or helicopters.
Maybe Dave in a hot air balloon.
They are very quiet.
Dave is established in a hot air balloon.
But he does anyway?
Course.
Only maybe not today.
Alvin is right. We must prepare for the night
.
What? You expect me to sleep outside?
I think squirrels live in the wild.
We lived in the wild.
It's just one night.
- A cold night.
Then we make a fire. We always
stabbing everything in the fire accidentally.
How hard can it be if you
think about it.
How do you do that?
I will make a spark, with my Swiss army knife on the stone
to...
Dave who has taken away from me.
You certainly have a better idea, smart boy?
Sure, smart boy.
As you can see the glasses captures the energy from the sun
, so get your fire.
Impressive.
- Thank you.
Thank you for that thought.
We have made a fire.
What do we do?
We need to go there.
From the top of the mountain, we can better oversee
the island.
Then we can see if they are here.
- Understood.
What are you doing?
- I make a fire.
The studio had no Snoop
more matches and we have made fire with two sticks.
How hard can it be.
- Forget the fire, we must climb.
It's dark and cold.
I make a fire. We're going tomorrow.
No, we are now.
- Do not talk to me in such a tone.
I'm not one of your chipmunks who can command
...
In a cage and stop whenever you want.
Did you, Ian.
- Calm.
Logical that it would prefer a ship
balls fly off then one day be with you.
They did not express.
It was an accident. They're just kids.
How long can they survive?
And you were worried.
Look at us now.
We are warm, a nice fire
fire.
A beautiful night sky and if
a rescue helicopter comes along, they see us.
Everything is good.
- Good night, boys.
Good night.
- Good night.
- Can I...
What? I always
the lights when we said goodnight.
That fire was the only thing that protected against freezing
death.
Can not light again?
- How?
With your glasses and the sun...
Great as the courage to hold back.
What can this be?
Breakfast.
- No, it's bark.
Yes, for breakfast.
- I think it's very nice.
It is not.
It is centuries since our last
"You can eat whatever you want 'buffet.
Idiot proposal. Let's go off this beach
, and to find real food.
If I still know my horticulture,
and that is true, that these are mango trees.
Where are all the mangoes, then?
Perhaps the jungle monster
eaten them.
I thought you were planning to share?
- Of course.
It seemed as if what you wanted to eat
alone.
What?
I would never do.
I do not believe you.
I got it.
My nuts.
Well done, Theodore.
- Take him.
Do not listen to him, Theo.
He eats everything alone.
I share it with you.
- No, they take you for a ride.
No, you're trying to trick him.
No, you. In saying that I
he wants to take the mickey.
He lies, Theo.
- What?
Theodore, very sorry.
My favorite.
Stop.
Look at us again. A day on this island and we're animals become
.
Do you hear that?
What was that?
- A jungle monster.
On your site, all of them.
Hold.
Fire.
- No. Why?
Please do not eat us up, Mr. Jungle Monster.
I'm not a monster. I'm Zoe.
And I'm obviously a girl.
Those have long on this island is that...
She imagines that squirrels can talk.
We Chipmunks.
- Yes, Alvin and the Chipmunks.
What?
You have probably heard about Chip Juliettes.
We are world famous.
Who?
- Maybe it helps.
Stop.
I do not know who you are.
- Strange.
How long have you here exactly?
I'm here on a Monday came.
So eight or nine years.
Have you been here nine years?
- It can also eight.
If we are now nine years to stay?
Here to stay forever?
I told you that Dave would come there.
I always thought that Dave would
happening.
And he never came.
What?
- Dave Henderson, my boss at UPS.
I flew cargo planes for them, until one day
I got dumped in the ocean.
We have also crashed.
However, our Dave will not rest until he found us
.
Still, Alvin?
- Absolutely.
I finally come out?
I must tell the others.
- Are there others?
Imagine being stuck here
and nobody to talk.
I thought I would go mad.
I want to introduce you to my friends...
This is Ms. Rowling, Fozzing, Caluwe Dinmar
and there Nerd.
You look good, friend.
They have also survived the crash.
I am Theodore.
Dave comes to pick us up.
No, not Dave Henderson.
I saw your face it. Another Dave.
You'll be thrilled.
We finally get to this island.
It's funny.
- In a strange way.
This is cause for celebration.
Who is hungry?
We are starving.
- Let's go to my house.
Is it far?
I can not move.
Who was talking about running?
That was cool.
- I know.
Come on, guys.
Is not that amazing?
No, it was not great.
It's a miracle that we arrived safely.
The chances of an injured squirrel
a sliding board is a six.
Why do I always right?
Is it?
- I sprained my ankle.
You have to do some ice.
I do not have ice.
I live there in that tree.
I thought perhaps you had.
No, we have no ice and no hiding
.
This is very annoying for you.
Do you like bungee jumping?
Yes.
- No, we do not like.
Maybe you should leave us alone, then
we concentrate more on survival...
And less on ourselves to murder.
That's a lot of nerves
in a small package.
I'm not nervous. I just do not want anyone else hurt
that...
What was that?
That was just a spider. Who live here, because this
nature.
This is not just a spider.
This is the "Benotrella Valensise.
Its bite contains neurotoxin.
Mr. rhetoric.
So what?
- Alvin, poison, neuroscience, brains?
This is not good.
Side effects are "changes in personality
liability, loss of vision, dry throat.
Take it easy. I do get bitten twice
and I'm very normal.
Yes, usually.
- No, anyway.
Simon.
- Fatty.
Come, fatty.
I hope all is well with them.
- What does it matter whether they are in order...
I want them here.
And here I thought you had changed
and not just self.
No, and that's good.
For the rage that I feel for you and the Chipmunks
keeps me going.
Shall we continue?
- Please note that if we find something to eat or drink.
Here.
- Where?
The thing around your neck.
- Not that I eat.
This was a gift from Theodore.
- That explains it.
I wanted to say, 'that's awful ugly.
It's not ugly.
The fit in anywhere and it is soft enough to sleep
.
And it is edible.
- You will eat my son not his chain.
He's your son, Dave.
He's just a Chipmunk.
Dave, where are you?
Where are you, Alvin?
I go to sleep.
Simon, where are you going?
Who is Simon
you talking about?
You.
- My name is not Simon, but Simone.
That's almost Simon.
And very different.
Do you want to go on an adventure?
- What kind of adventure?
The adventure called "The Law".
- Good.
Dave to show up.
Simon and Theodore are gone.
They are probably hiding
to the search.
They can only talk about have.
It's nothing for them to be so
getaway.
Can you please look for them?
- Why can not you do?
I have a problem I must solve
.
How is Eleanor?
With her doing well.
I'm talking about me.
I have taken two days no longer prayed,
and I'm not.
I can not be saved if I
so look.
Hello, my friend.
Simon, are you the bungee jumping?
His name is not Simon.
- Simone.
It seems a lot like Simon.
Yeah I thought so too.
But, he behaves very differently.
A spider bite.
That's it.
Do you have side effects?
Personality change, loss of vision...
Who are you?
Simone is very cool.
- It's Simon, Theodore.
No, he's not cool.
- Goodbye, Alfred.
My name is Alvin.
- Great, Simone.
Theo, you're allowed.
Really? I've never done anything like this.
- And you never will.
How can you let them do that?
What were you thinking?
I think, when my father
ashore on this island?
We have great fun. Why do you
show and so nervous?
I? Nervous?
I'm not nervous, but funny.
The one who is cool.
Just ask anyone.
Who do I ask?
You can not bungee jumping, Theodore.
You're afraid if you go to a movie.
Go, Alvin.
Can anyone help me?
This is much better.
These dresses are really great.
Thank you.
This I made for you, Eleanor.
Look how happy you're suddenly.
In case you get tired, I
a wheelchair for you.
Beautiful.
Meet you, ladies.
A kiss.
And again, a kiss.
What is his name now?
- A spider has bitten him.
He thinks he's some funny
French guy.
He thinks he's the most interesting man in the world
.
Yes.
- We must work to that shelter.
Why? I can not imagine a better roof
than the stars in the sky.
How about a roof that is truly one roof?
It's raining.
What is a little rain? We share the same aqueous feeds the flowers.
This is idiotic.
The shelter was your idea. From you.
Great.
Do not forget the shelter but I want everybody
going up.
I'll try, but I feel so useless
.
What do you do?
What I wanted to do when
I first saw you.
They do have a pneumonia.
So dance in the rain...
Zwier even if no mud around.
- Hello?
Someone can lose an eye.
Looks cool off.
Would you like to dance?
- Please.
Really
- Yes, Theodore.
I can not believe they all
attention.
I am handsome.
She is smart.
Do you see me hanging out clever?
- Yes, I am the funny.
And handsome.
- That's really slippery mud.
This is ridiculous.
They even listening?
Silence.
You start to sound like Dave.
No!
What do you do?
A shelter building.
Since I no longer
funny, I can just as well...
Are responsible.
Seriously?
Since I am no longer the handsome,
I can 't build shelter.
Good luck with that.
- Do you think I can not?
I did not say.
I think so, but said nothing.
So you want to play it so, huh?
Look.
It's so French-like.
Be careful.
Let's do it.
Was not that nice trip?
- Luckily I do not wear pants.
Come on, guys.
Is it really safe?
- Yes. I do this daily.
Hang.
Theodore is here.
No, look into my eyes.
You have nothing to fear.
Yes, very good.
You are safe. Bravo.
- You made it.
You are so brave.
Beautiful.
A double rainbow.
What does that mean?
In life they are superstars,
but they are dead legends.
Tribute albums, funerals on pay per vieuw
... - Wait.
Do you really think I do this for the money do?
If you do it to women
to pick up, you're not doing.
I do it because I love them.
Go ahead if you
life behind to walk spoiled brats.
If they are not.
- Not even Alvin?
You do not even know them.
Alvin may well be a nuisance...
But he means well.
Sometimes he's what...
Irresponsible. Nothing more.
Simon is the kid with the most responsibility
I know.
Sometimes he's too nervous.
And then little Theodore
... - Dave.
The first two were
I can barely cared.
The third me will not care.
Never mind. We are going through.
To the surface.
This is terrible.
- Had he not better than his?
Where are you?
Zoe, you have to do something.
Caluwé, go find Simon.
I know you can.
You do not believe it, huh?
If Caluwé not find him, no one can
.
See?
Sorry I worried.
I've got something for you.
Perhaps this is good.
It's beautiful.
Where did you find it?
Yes, it's beautiful.
Where did you?
In a cave behind the waterfall.
I thought you would be nice.
But now I realize that even a gem
your beauty can not match.
But there were
jewelry or diamonds?
When I struck gold, I was
too long away from my Jeanette.
What?
Boys, they found it.
And they do not even
what they found.
They think only one bracelet.
The rest of the treasure is for me.
At all for me.
What do you mean?
You're one of those "Honey Badgers"
who take what they want. Drop it.
If you are with me Dolte,
I'll go mad.
You can be in a stabbing or a cobra strike
...
But the squirrel can not care.
I'm ready.
I can help you...
This treehouse is great.
Maybe you're still smart.
Thank you, Alvin.
And yours is...
You did your best.
We can quite comfortably
and chic, right?
I think I know why Dave
not there yet.
Why?
Because he is not even looking.
Why should he find us?
Because he tired of me.
Just as Simon makes me crazy...
Make me crazy Dave for years.
No wonder he hates me.
Do not worry.
Dave really is.
It is certainly of Simon and Theodore.
Will Dave ever find us?
I mean Simone.
- Sorry, did you speak to me?
Yes, Dave.
Will we ever find him?
I see you're sad.
And I hate that.
I will help you find friend Dave.
Do you really think you can find him?
- I know I can t.
And I find that one Simon
what you're talking about.
Dave and I have never
met each other. Describe him.
He is very friendly and a good storyteller.
That really helped.
And it is about the size.
Is he by chance a large bird
that can not fly?
I do not think so.
Then those footprints
not his.
Sample of the jungle.
Did you hear that?
Yes, my stomach rumbling.
- No, maybe it's a helicopter.
Come face it, Dave, no one comes
save us.
My stomach always sounds louder
until they one day just stop.
Because I've eaten it.
Perhaps there really anyone
and the Chipmunks are not even here.
I'm talking really spoiled.
I really hate to say this, but...
You can really get along with them.
They love you.
I can know, because I
mistreats them. I hate them.
Whatever happens,
you've done nothing wrong.
Thanks, Ian.
Ian.
Get off me.
The monster of the jungle
is real and it is angry.
Or hungry.
It means letting go.
Great. A volcano.
Of course, why the water was so warm.
This is the underground magma chamber heated
.
How do you know?
- No idea.
The beauty sometimes I look at the science channel
.
Hi, does anyone fancy a trip to the waterfall
or something?
Not now. The whole island will explode.
- What?
We have this island.
We're building a fleet at once.
Now or immediately after
a trip to the waterfall?
I'm touched.
Dave his necklace?
Tell Janet that I always will watch over her
with the angels.
Dave?
Theodore.
Dave? I told him that we would find
.
Simon.
- It's Simon.
I'm sometimes confused by
that Simon guy.
Maybe we are like each other.
You thought it was chubby.
Do not worry, Theodore,
there is nothing happen. Yet?
What was that?
This is an active volcano.
Britney and I build the deck.
Eleanor, you tied the ropes.
Janet, collect as many coconuts and mangoes
if you can.
Who knows how long we are at sea.
- What can I do to help?
Dave!
You're touched.
I've missed you so much.
- I knew you would find us.
Eleanor, what happened?
Just a plain line.
- What?
It does only hurts when I try to explain
.
Do even.
The most important thing is that you are safe.
Everything will be fine.
What is it?
I thought you would never find us.
That you did not even it was looking for.
Why do not you search?
Because I'm such a nuisance.
I know you find me a nuisance.
No, anyway.
But I come anyway.
Patriot, fermez, Napoleon.
I don 't. You have a rich past.
We are all past when we go away.
Uncle Ian.
What is he doing here?
- It's a long story.
Do not worry, he does nothing.
- Yes, for a pelikaanman.
Yes, nothing cooler than a grown man in a
pelikanenpak.
Dave, how do we get here?
Do not know. I think
do you control this.
Theodore, Eleanor, and you do the rope.
Dave and Ian, we need oars.
- Simon, you and Janet provide food.
... And Zoe - I know, I'm gonna get my balls.
Who is that?
- Another long story.
Keep working guys, so we
of the island cope with this.
The fleet itself does not go together.
It's unbelievable, guys.
- Very impressive.
Now that everyone came together to
build it, I want to say...
It can wait.
Where are Janet and Simon?
Hopefully this is enough.
Have you heard anything?
- Who knows?
When I'm with you, I just
hear my heartbeat.
Someone: Help!
Guys, here. Come quick.
Simone, all goes well?
- Why do you call me, Simone?
Simon?
- Of course.
You're finally back.
- Why?
You were bitten by a spider.
Tampered with your brains.
I see why Dave and Ian half, half bird?
No, me and Ian are real.
- How you doing?
Where is Janet?
She was with you.
Do not know.
- I did. Zoe took her.
Simon, where did you find that golden bracelet?
- Which?
The one you gave to Janet.
- When did I do that?
During your date.
Are Janet and I together?
It is useless.
Theodore and Eleanor, you are the way.
I do not remember exactly the way.
I have.
Which way?
- Links.
No, right. No, left.
- You knew the way, right?
This is true. I sometimes forget what
left and right.
That way.
We just have to cross here.
Are you serious?
I can not.
Simon, that you have already done.
- No, it was Simone.
But you Simone.
He's there somewhere in your.
You have to just search.
Do it quickly, because Janet
needs you.
I just can not. Sorry.
Ian, bring everyone to the fleet.
The volcano explodes before I'm back...
...
Promise you - that I left without you. Roger that.
I'm with you.
- Absolutely not. Too dangerous.
Remember when I said I
one day you would not obey?
Sorry, Dave, but I will not obey.
Let's go.
You do not
up before you have all of that treasure.
But the volcano will explode.
Then you better hurry, huh?
Ahead.
Here we go.
Bags.
If so, keep going.
Keep going.
Pull me up.
I can not bear.
If you can still talk, still nothing
sticks in your mouth.
Pull me now but up.
- Yes, that sounds very good.
Janet.
They would be behind that waterfall.
For example, the.
That's what I mean.
Zoe.
- Not one more step.
Do not come closer.
All right, Janet?
I can not break free.
The jewelry tastes terrible.
Zoe, you should not do this.
- Ten years I searched for this treasure.
That's the reason I went
this stinking island came.
You are here not crashed?
- They found me crazy...
And they said this card is counterfeit.
Now is the treasure of mine.
Walk.
Come.
Ahead.
No, not yet.
- Janet.
No!
No, help.
You go back into that cave
to get more of that treasure.
Simon.
- It's Simon.
Alvin.
Quick!
- Forward.
Look.
Where is Dave?
Help me.
- Help you?
Do I do now, Dave?
All my treasures are gone.
Without that ruined my life.
And now you feel how it feels.
No, do not.
Dave blame is simple.
I did.
I could take revenge for all those years but
back. All that wasted energy.
All the pizzas to be sent home.
- Was that you?
Not now.
You can drop dead Dave and I can
to the raft with the Chipmunks...
And their manager again
and lots of money.
For me it does not matter.
But let me tell you something.
Hatred, anger and regret
are not members of a girl group.
They possessed me.
And they now take possession of you.
You can still do the right thing.
Again, for me it does not matter.
Your decision.
What are you doing?
Help him, please.
Help me save my father.
Hurry.
I bite you, Dave.
Come on, help me.
There they are.
Come on.
Come on. Hurry up.
Grab the oar.
Come on, guys.
Paddling.
Now we will never occur
during the International Music Awards.
Now we the suckers.
Janet, I do not know what to say.
I was apparently so obsessed
for that treasure, that I...
Crazy.
And I'm really sorry.
We both.
Apologies accepted.
I want you to get it.
Really?
Dinmar, it's a new beginning for both of us
.
Hope you do not mind.
Simone gave it to me.
- That's OK.
Not even the most beautiful jewel in the world
beauty can match.
Yes, Alvin?
I just wanted to say
now we...
So do...
I'm sorry.
Sorry that I acted childish
on the ship.
And I ruined our family vacation.
Sometimes a horse needs
place to walk.
Yes, that's right.
This is very wise.
How you doing?
No love for Uncle Ian?
You put us in cages.
Seriously? Still about?
New topic: I saved the life of Dave.
But I love you 'eye.
Do you have that knife?
Knife? Exactly, that I wanted to give back.
Keep it with you.
- Really?
You can
helicopter might be a sign along mail.
What?
We are here.
- Hello.
Okay. We see you.
Good to be back, huh?
- Absolutely.
I sold the story of Zoe
to Hollywood.
They offered huge prizes.
Kyra Knigt is interested.
There's also something in it for me.
Thank you.
We found the great giant.
Simply Releases Toppers
Translation: Suurtje & Tokke
This one is full.
We must charge you for this.
Thinkest you $ 25 per bag?
- No, $ 25 for first bag...
And $ 40 for each additional bag.
Do you want the fan off? I'm cold.
- Of course.
You have my paper crumples.
- Sorry.
Then I read this but.
She is beautiful.
Wait, that's me.
Just count.
Do you like that junglemonsterpak?
Eleonore has for me.
Yes, I have made.
- Nice.
Where's Alvin?
- Ladies and gentlemen...
This is your captain.
We will leave...
To Timbuktu.
If you do not need to Timbuktu...
Call then the stewardess
by pushing the button.
Thank you for Air Alvin chose.
Nice flight.
Please be seated.
We ascend.
Now sit.