Jack flack escapes.
How could he escape?
Look at the dice.
So what?
- Twenty-four. Jack's
agility is 24, he escapes.
That's not fair, I got killed
and you should've been dead,
- well, I'm not, Jack
flack always escapes.
Dumb game.
- You just gotta develop
better moves, Kim, that's all.
You're getting there.
- I don't believe it,
how can he do it, Morris?
I had 10 times as many
bullets as Jack flack.
- Yeah, but flack had the
ingenuity and the contacts, Kim.
Hey, don't feel bad, I
haven't been able to beat him
all summer, yet.
- What happens next, Morris?
- Let's leave it for now.
I wanna think of something
really good to get you with.
Anyway, I wanna get back to my game.
- Don't look at me, I'm
sick of getting killed.
I'll give you extra gas
masks and a bulletproof vest.
- No way, you never get hurt, it's no fun.
And Jack flack always escapes, anyway.
- Flack to lady ace, come in, lady ace.
- Hey, you guys, be careful
with those, I just got 'em in.
- This is Jack flack
requesting an assignment, over.
- Hello, everybody.
Come on, Kim, be serious.
- You guys want a real assignment?
- Yeah.
- You got your bus passes?
Okay, I want you to go over to textronics.
And pick me up some
catalogs for the new 4200.
- Come on, Morris.
Give us something exciting,
like cloak and dagger,
only for real.
- Okay.
I want you to infiltrate
their seventh level.
Then go to their vending machine.
Pick me up a pack of twinkies.
- Aw.
- There's a secret message inside.
Whatever you do, don't let
anybody see you. Anybody.
- You coming?
- Not if you're gonna be embarrassing.
- I won't.
Let's see, grenade.
- Now what are you doing?
- Jack flack says to always
keep your gun loaded.
Morris, could we try these out?
- Yeah, just don't break 'em.
- Time to go, Jack.
See you, Morris.
Oh, great.
- Flack to lady ace. Come in, lady ace.
- Yeah, what?
- Come on, Kim, play right.
- All right, lady ace to
Jack flack, do you read me?
- Loud and clear.
Prepare to penetrate the enemy
stronghold, follow me in.
- This is what I meant by embarrassing.
- Hey!
- You proceed to floor
7 for operation catalog.
I'll get the secret from the machine.
I think that sentry spotted us.
- Davey, put that thing away.
- Hi, kids. You lost?
If you tell me who you're
looking for, maybe I can help.
- We're looking for textronics.
- Ah, you're looking
for the game division?
- Thank you, officer.
- Take separate routes just in case
I'll take the fire stairs,
you take the elevator.
- Good, 'cause I'm not walkin' up.
- Sorry.
- That guy had a gun,
Kim, it was a real gun.
- Oh, Davey, will you stop it?
- Honest, I saw a gun!
- You're really being a jerk.
- Well, here, take this
grenade just in case.
- Thanks, anyway.
- Flack to lady ace. Come in, lady ace.
- Yeah, Davey, what is it?
I'm almost in
position, give me your location.
- I'm already up here
and I'm waiting for you.
- Textronics.
- Okay, start creating
- a diversion.
- Mr. Rice is in a meeting.
- Can I take a message?
- I'll sneak out the fire
- Davey, this is embarrassing.
- Maintain radio silence
from now on, over and out.
Murdock, don't let
him leave the building.
Rice moving. The
elevator, second floor.
- Will there be anything else today?
- Ah, do you have a food machine here?
Lady ace, lady ace, come in.
- Mr. Rice is in a meeting.
- I thought we were
- maintaining radio silence.
- As soon as I can.
- Did you hear them?
- No, I'm busy, now stop bugging me.
- The vending machines
are right over there.
- So, your friend cut off
radio contact, did she?
- 0h, hi, Jack.
- Well, some people just
don't know how to act
on a secret mission, I
guess we're better off
just handling this one on our own.
Like the maracaibo
assignment, remember that?
Back when I was known as agent x.
That was a close one.
- Yeah.
Yeah, there we were, surrounded by hordes
of angry mercenaries.
All you had was a ball
of string and a sealed
iou from the embassy.
- Yeah, that's 'cause I
told you not to trust 'em.
That's what I mean about working alone.
I guess you're right.
- Yeah.
- Help me.
Whatever happens, don't let them get it.
Tell the FBI.. One million...
Three-hundred twenty-nine.
- Davey, what are you doing?
- They just killed a man,
now they're after me!
- I got Morris' twinkie.
- Help, police, murder!
- What's the problem, kid?
- There's two men,
they're trying to kill me.
- They're up there,
they just killed a man!
- Charlie, call the police!
- He was right here, I saw him fall!
I had to run right by him!
You want to tell
me what is this all about?
- Well, these Nazis, or
some kind of bad guys,
they shot this FBI man.
Nazis?
- How should I know?
- Maybe they were Russians,
but they shot him.
And he was bleeding and he fell.
Look, I'm not kidding you!
I can prove it.
He gave me this secret cartridge.
- No, no, no, no.
Don't trust him, Davey.
That's the first rule of espionage.
Always stay true to your source.
- Secret what?
- What happened?
Well?
- Hi, Mr. Rice.
- Hi, Freddy.
Did you see
anybody on the terrace level?
- No, not a soul.
- We better hold him for the police.
- We better go talk to
the police, come on.
Okay, folks,
step back, clear the area,
thank you.
I better be going now.
You gonna be all right?
Yeah, I've got a key.
Okay.
- Davey, I've been calling
all over the place for you.
- Mr. Osborne, lieutenant
Fleming, San Antonio pd.
- Dad, I didn't do...
- Just wait a minute, okay?
Let him talk, come on in.
- Not at this time, I've
gotta keep an ear out
for the squawk box.
- Oh, well, go on to your room, Davey.
- But dad, I wanna hear what he has to...
- Just go to your room, Davey, all right?
- Well, your son created
quite a stir at the tower life
building this morning
when he reported a murder.
- A murder?
- That's right, sir.
We checked out his story
and found absolutely
then we tried to bring him
home, but he refused to divulge
the whereabouts of what
he called “headquarters."
Sorry, officer,
but he does do that
- we got 'em right where we want 'em.
- Let 'em think you're nuts.
See, if we're gonna be heroes,
we gotta keep a low profile.
No cops, no dads, we're on our own, pal.
There gonna be
any charges, or what?
- Not this time, sir, but we do think that
you ought to consider
getting him some help.
I have.
- For almost an hour, all he
would give us is his name,
rank, and serial number.
The tougher we got... - Good.
- The tougher he got.
If it hadn't been for the little girl,
we would've never gotten him home.
Officer, I...
- They'll sing a different
tune once you're a hero.
- Stuff like this with parents a lot.
He is a good boy.
He's just...
Going through a real tough time right now.
- He lost his mother recently.
- Oh.
- I guess we're both
having a little difficulty
making an adjustment.
- Well, I can say one thing for him.
If we were at war, I'd
want him on my side.
You ready to talk?
- They weren't murderers, they were spies.
They'd gone there to kill an FBI agent.
I just intercepted one
of their communications.
- Anybody else see 'em?
- If morn were here, she'd believe me.
- She probably would.
But she's not here and
she's not gonna be here.
You gotta get used to that.
- I miss her.
- I know.
I'll bet she can see us
right now, you know that?
Listen, I got an idea.
Why don't you and me call
up Dr. Sullivan tomorrow?
You just tell him what you saw today.
Just to see what he says about it.
- Jack flack was right,
you do think I'm crazy.
- Davey, you've got to understand
Jack flack is make believe
just like all these ridiculous games.
They don't make it any easier for you
to get a grasp on things.
See proof?
Show you it, this is
what the FBI man gave me.
Hey, come here, there's
something coming on.
- More cloak and dagger?
- What did I just get through
- telling you?
- Dad, this is important.
Just wait a minute and you'll see.
Oh, Davey.
- Just give me a chance, a
man was just killed for this.
Would you let me play it once?
- All right, play it. Play it one time.
- See, that's Dr. Boom
and that's Jack flack.
Going to the secret
underground bomb factory.
- You've seen this,
you've done this before?
- Yeah, I played it at Morris'.
Now, here we are, get the guards.
Okay, get the case.
Gotta light the fuse.
- Where's the proof you're talking about?
- I don't know, maybe
it's on the next level.
- All right, let's shut it off, all right?
- Come on.
- But I get another life.
- No, let's just shut
it off, that's enough.
- Dad!
- Why don't you
get ready for bed?
- Can I just play one more?
- Davey, I said no and I mean no.
Now get ready for bed.
I hate you.
- I know you don't mean that, son.
- You don't care about me.
- Davey, when I was a kid,
I was exactly like you are.
That's why I joined the air
force, so I could be somebody.
Let me tell you somethin', Davey.
Heroes don't just shoot bad guys,
they put supper on the table,
they fix bicycles, they do boring things.
Real things, not make believe.
I hope you'll understand that when you
get a little bit older.
I'm gonna put these games away.
I don't want you playing 'em anymore.
- Dad, if you'd just play
one with me sometime.
- Good night, Davey.
- Not too smart for a military man, huh?
- Shut up.
Will you get that for me, Davey?
Is this David g. Osborne?
- Yes.
Good.
- Dad!
- Yeah?
It's them, it's the spies!
Hurry!
They hung up.
What'd he say?
- He just asked who I was.
Dad, they know where I am.
- Oh, it's probably just a
wrong number, come on, let's...
- No, it wasn't, I know it was them.
- Come on, come on, take it easy.
Just go on to bed, it's
way past your bedtime.
- Can I sleep in your bed tonight?
- Well, I don't think those
guys'll come in when you're here.
- You don't, hey?
Okay, come on.
Everything's gonna be okay, son.
Dad!
- What is it, son?
- Well, I gotta go to work,
son, I don't have any choice.
- Well, they're just
waiting for you to leave
so they can get me.
- Yeah.
Listen, I talked to Dr.
Sullivan this morning and I made
an appointment for us to
see him tomorrow, okay?
- Humor him, Davey, this
Turkey's not gonna help us.
We're on our own.
- And I gotta work a double shift today
on account of that big
inspection I told you about,
but tomorrow I'm off, so I
can go to the doctor with you
and you can tell him
everything you told me
about those spies.
- Can't I go with you?
- Davey, come on, you're a big boy now.
I mean, you're old
enough to stay home alone
without making a fuss, aren't ya?
I'll tell ya what, maybe next week
we can get you in that baseball camp.
You'd like that, wouldn't ya?
If you need me, just call
me at the base, okay?
- Lady ace, lady ace, come
in. Kim, are you there?
Kim, come in.
- Yeah, what?
Listen, we got
an assignment for today.
- I don't want any more of
your stupid assignments.
Come on, Kim,
I'm really in trouble.
- Good, you got me in
trouble yesterday, now what?
- Remember the spies?
You mean the killers?
- Yeah, they're coming to
kill me, they want the cloak
and dagger thing back,
I need you to come over.
- What cloak and dagger thing?
Can't tell you
now, it's top secret.
- Tell him you're having your breakfast
and you'll call him back later.
- My mom says I gotta go now.
- Wait.
- I'm having my breakfast.
I'll call you back later.
- Is he always like that?
- Usually.
- Doesn't it drive you crazy?
- Nah, he's the only
boy in the neighborhood
who isn't boring.
- Did I teach you that?
Well, what's his father like?
- Forget it, he's not your type.
How on earth would you know
who is or isn't my type?
- He's in the army or somethin'.
- Oh.
- Guess you're right, we are on our own.
I'll get it.
- There's gotta be something in this tape.
- Probably encoded.
- Have it decoded, take it to
the FBI, and we'll be heroes.
- A good spy always knows when to bring in
outside expertise.
- Morris can do it, he can do anything.
Just enough to get the job done.
- But we can trust Morris, he's my friend.
Friendship is a
luxury a spy can't afford.
- What do you mean?
Well, okay, if you really think so.
Thank you.
- Morris.
Where's my twinkies?
- What, you made it to the
17th level of cloak and dagger?
- No, Morris, this is for real.
I got this real important
tape I want you to see.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah, it has some secret
code or something in it.
Will you take a look at it?
Morris, are you listening to me?
- Yeah, sure.
Hey, Davey, I wanna have the
twinkies or my money back.
- You tell me.
- Looks like a cloak and dagger tape.
- Well, it's not, take a look at it.
- What do you mean, it's not?
Who gave it to you?
- This guy, I can't tell
you any more than that.
- Top secret, huh?
What do you want me to do?
- I don't know, Morris,
you're the genius around here.
- All right.
This microchip doesn't belong here.
What?
Take a look.
Whoever put this in really
knew what he was doin'.
It could be used to store
information. Input, output.
What kind of information?
Government plans, maybe?
It could be anything, really.
I'll tell you one thing,
whoever put this in
really went through a lot of trouble.
- Think you can break the code?
The key is how
to get to it, I got an idea.
The guy who gave
it to me said something
What number?
One million
three-hundred twenty-nine...
I bet you anything
that's the secret code
that we're looking for.
Can you think of anything else?
- No.
Davey, are you alone?
- That reminds me,
Davey, I wanna get those
- sure, Morris.
Flack to lady ace. Come in, lady ace.
I'm here.
- Kim, where are you?
Your house.
- Get out of there, the spies are there!
Seems we each have
something the other wants,
don't we, kid?
- Yeah.
- We might consider a trade.
- Just leave her alone,
she doesn't know anything.
She does now, do you know
the Japanese sunken gardens?
- Yeah.
- Good.
We'll meet you there at noon.
If you tell anybody about this,
we'll break your little friend in half.
- Don't give it to him, Davey.
Rule number two: Never, never
play by the enemy's rules.
- I have to give 'em something.
It's called commandeering
necessary mission equipment.
- Just stop right there.
- Cut the crap, kid. Give me the tape.
- Come any closer and you're
gonna be diving for it.
- Now, are we gonna make a trade?
Or are we gonna start dropping things?
- Davey!
- Why do you want it so
bad? It's just a kid's game.
- Well, let's just say I'm a kid at heart.
- Why don't you go buy your own?
They don't cost much.
- Look, kid, don't outsmart yourself.
I got a couple of friends
and we play, too, you know.
If I don't hand that over to them by 5:30,
your little friend there is gonna die.
All right, just put it
down and I'll let her go.
- You let Kim go first.
- Sure, anything you say.
- Freeze, Turkey!
Take my advice, don't follow us.
Otherwise, I'll have to use this.
- You little punk!
- Boy, am I glad to see you!
- Come on!
- It's the wrong one!
Wonder what's going on.
Hurry up, let's get out of here!
Thank you.
- Thanks, Davey.
- What for?
- You saved my life.
- What were you doing in my house, anyway?
I thought you weren't coming over.
- I wasn't, but then I felt bad.
'Cause I hurt your feelings.
I was just mad 'cause you
got me in trouble yesterday.
And I thought you were dumb
'cause of all that murder stuff.
I never thought it could be real.
- I'm really sorry, Davey.
- That's okay, Kim,
it's gonna be all right.
Uh-oh!
I'm gonna get the tape now.
We have no further use for
the kid, do you understand?
Yes, I understand.
- We gotta get out of here.
I'll make 'em follow me,
you get to Morris as quickly
as you can and tell him what's happened.
- But they'll kill you if they catch you.
- No, they won't, I'm
the only one who knows
where the real tape is.
Sir, I gotta get off here.
- Sorry, junior, we're not
allowed to stop along here.
- But it's an emergency.
- It's only three blocks
to the bus station
and everybody gets off.
- Yeah, like I'm gonna throw...
Run, Davey, run!
- Why is he shooting at me?
- He must've found out
where the cartridge is.
- One million three-hundred twenty-nine.
That's it.
I'll be right there!
The following
material is for a-4 security
clearance personnel only.
It is a federal crime
to view such material
- without proper authorization.
- Bingo.
I said I'd be right there.
- You looking for something?
- Someone's trying to kill me.
Well, why don't
you kill them first?
- Don't encourage him, Henry,
your food's getting cold.
Would you please go away?
- Listen, I'm trying to contact
the FBI, would you help me?
- Get me a direct line to j. Edgar hoover.
This is an emergency.
Hoover's dead, Henry.
Oh, my god,
they've gotten hoover.
Now we're all goners.
Sorry, kid, can't help ya.
I need help with the tour.
The next day, you'll have
a lovely day for a tour
- stand still, Davey.
They wouldn't dare shoot at you
with all these people around here.
In fact, the more people,
the better. Over there.
Watch your step,
come on, move right in.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, enjoy your ride.
- One child?
- Yes, ma'am.
That'll be 50 cents.
Thank you, enjoy your ride.
Thanks.
- One adult, two children.
- I'll get him.
- No, just get in line.
Get in line.
- Hey, buddy, wait your turn.
- Let me get him out of there.
- No, no, just take it easy now, not now.
Well, just
don't bring it up again.
No, you bring it up.
Wish your mother'd come to this.
Tickets, please.
Ticket, sir, hey, here you go.
Sorry, sir, all full, you'll
have to wait for the next boat.
We want this one.
I'm sorry, I can't
take any more passengers.
There'll be another boat
in 10 or 15 minutes.
- Howard, Howard, my wallet's gone!
Are you sure?
Of course I'm sure.
- Don't panic, don't panic.
- Look, we'll go back over every
step we've been over and see
if we can find it somewhere.
- Come on.
- You know it's gonna be gone.
You know what people are like.
Come on, hurry, hurry, hurry.
- Welcome aboard, ladies and gentlemen.
My name is hal.
Now, our tour through the
downtown San Antonio river
shall take approximately 25 to 30 minutes.
If you have any questions or
anything you'd like to ask
me as we go along, please
do not hesitate to do so.
- I'm gonna get close to the boy.
When I give you the
signal, create a diversion.
- How?
- I don't care how, just as long as people
aren't looking at me.
- Which is the 10th
largest city in america.
With a population of
over one million people.
Famous world wide, the riverwalk
is the pride of the city.
Sir, would you kindly have a seat?
You're supposed to sit down.
- Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen, I'd
like to call your attention
to the building coming up
here to the left-hand side,
parties and fiestas are
held there almost every day
during the summer months.
- George.
- What?
- Look.
What's wrong, boy?
- You wouldn't believe
me if I told you, ma'am.
- Try me.
- That man over there
is trying to kill me.
Sir?
- Why?
- Because I said so, now move.
Looks like a pervert, if you ask me.
George, we've got to do
something about this.
The building here
to my right-hand side
is the old San Antonio library,
which contains the
huntsberg circus collection,
with over 20,000 exhibits
depicting American circus life.
The building that you see straight ahead,
the power and light building.
- Fire!
- Where?
- There, in the engine!
Please, everyone,
please, keep calm!
Everybody, please be seated.
Everybody, go back to your seats, please
and don't panic!
Go back to your seats, everybody, please!
Thank you.
Sir, you're all gonna have
to sit down, I'm sorry.
- Why don't you guys sit down and quit
- rockin' the boat?
- Sit down!
- Yeah!
For your own
safety, please sit down.
- Kim!
- What happened to you?
- Nothing, where's Morris?
- I don't know, but look.
Davey, do you think they...
- No, Morris is too smart for them.
- I think he's already dead.
- Shut up, you don't know that!
I'm sorry.
- No use calling my dad.
Why don't you call your mom?
And tell her rice is gonna do something
with the tape at 5:30.
Make her call the police, even
if she doesn't believe you.
We need a grown up.
- Okay, what are you gonna do?
- I'm gonna try to find rice and stop him.
- How?
- I don't know yet.
Well, you gonna
stand here all day?
- I'm waiting for the light to change.
- Come on.
They won't hit you if
you just keep moving.
Crazy kid!
- Means he'll probably take his car.
There, textronics.
No place to hide in there, open the trunk.
Oh.
Oh, tough.
It's now or never, come on.
In there?
- Oh.
- Hurry up.
Hold it down, don't close
it shut, just hold it down.
- Jack?
Agent x, help.
Help me. Get him off me.
- Isn't it crowded enough for you in here?
- He was my friend, how
could they do that to him?
I guess he
just wasn't good enough.
- Yeah, but they didn't have to kill him.
- When you've been playing
this game as long as I have,
you get used to this kind of thing.
- We've stopped.
What happens now?
- We just wait a couple minutes.
I'll walk over there and make the drop.
- So who gets the game?
We just leave the case,
we wait a few minutes,
take the money.
Only thing I know about
these people is one of 'em's
missin' a couple fingers
from his right hand.
Well, remember the alamo, boys.
- Sure as hell don't tell you much.
Enough.
- It's time to go.
Remember, you can win or
lose the game right here.
Blue drops
back, he rolls to his right.
He's looking for summers
in the end zone...
He took quite a lick on that play as well.
Summers, fully extended,
just couldn't reach it.
Second and goal, Dallas.
Taxation without representation.
In fact, they were quite angry,
but they did not want to fight Santa Anna.
Instead, they tried to negotiate with him.
Content being citizens of Mexico,
all they wanted was the reinstatement
in 1835, negotiations
broke down and the texans
- began to talk of revolution.
- Hi, could you tell us where
- we could get some postcards?
- General Santa Anna
- heard this rumor...
- We are closing soon,
but the souvenir shop
is right through there.
- Thank you.
- General Martin perfecto
de cos, with 1,200 men
- occupied the alamo...
- How much time do we have
- before that tour bus leaves?
- And end the so-called
- revolution.
- Oh, we've got time, honey.
- Let's stop on by the shop.
- At that time,
the Texas revolution was
nothing more than a rumor.
General cos had the roof
torn off the chapel.
Along the back wall.
The ledge is the original
height of the wall.
The upper section was
added in later years.
General cos laid three
cannons along the back wall.
He had a total of 21
cannons inside the alamo.
Approximately 300 texans...
- Well, look who's here.
The last time I saw you,
you were jumping off a boat.
Were you feeling a little seasick?
- General cos men surrendered.
- I'm hiding from that man
- over there.
- They were allowed to return
- to Mexico...
- Oh, it's somebody new
this time, now, isn't it
about time you told me
Returned to their
farms and their families.
Ladies and gentlemen, the alamo
will be closing in two minutes.
- Our young friend
seems to be in some sort
of trouble again.
Now, here, just a minute,
what is your name?
- Davey.
- Not Davy Crockett by any chance?
- I really have to go now, it's a matter
of national security.
- Will everyone please exit
through the front door?
- What do you think?
- I think the boy needs our help.
Hey, stop that kid!
Oh, he's stealing
somebody's bag, get him!
- You got a hell of a nerve,
kid, stealing inside the alamo.
- I didn't steal it!
- He didn't steal anything,
- officer.
- He took this.
- Well, that's just a simple mistake.
I sent the boy in to
pick up my camera case
and he took the wrong one.
- Oh.
This yours?
Well, come and get it.
- Why don't you take
the boy over to the car
while I straighten this out?
But that one has
the secret cartridge in it!
- Come on.
- It's got the secret
- microchip in there.
- Don't worry about it.
George will take care of everything.
The car's only over here,
now, don't you fret yourself.
George will take care of everything.
He's very good at that.
He's giving him the camera case!
- He is?
Well, if he did, he had
a reason for doing it.
Slide over, that's it.
- This what you're so worried about?
- No, sir.
It was the case you gave the other man.
That was the one with the plans in it.
- What makes you so sure I
gave the wrong case back?
- Why don't you open it and find out?
You got it!
- George always makes
things turn out right.
- But how'd you do it?
- Well, I just gave
that man my camera case
in its place, he never
noticed the difference.
Now, do you mind telling
us what this is all about?
After all, I sacrificed my good camera
to save your cloak and dagger tape.
- It isn't just a cloak and dagger tape.
There's an extra microchip in here.
- What was that man doing
with it at the alamo?
- Said he had to give
it to some foreign spy.
- Really?
Did he say what the spy looked like?
- Only that he had two fingers missing.
- How exciting!
May I see the tape, Davey?
- Sure.
- Something wrong, Davey?
- It's all right.
- Such a clever little boy.
Don't you think so, George?
I wish we could take him
to Mexico City with us.
- I made an arrangement with rice.
He's gonna take care of him for us
on the way to the airport.
- I don't like him and I
don't like his methods,
and I don't like those two thugs of his.
- I made it very clear to him back there.
We're very displeased
with this whole mess.
- I made that very clear.
What time's our flight?
- Midnight.
I'm afraid we won't be able to
use our dinner reservations.
- Wake up, someone's coming.
- Where are we?
I can't see a thing.
Right back where you put us.
Hey, pop the trunk, will you?
You better play
dead or you will be.
With five touchdown passes.
For Kyle, 19 completions
out of 23 attempts.
He had one high.
That's 318 yards.
- You wanna kill him now,
or wait 'til the chloroform
- wait 'til we get to the desert.
- What's taking rice so long, anyway?
It can't take him two hours
to divide up the money.
I think we should get
extra for killing the kid.
- You're right.
Let's go hurry him up.
We'll never get out of here.
Stay cool, I'm thinking.
What are we gonna do?
Open the door.
- What are you doing?
There's a phone here.
Let's get outta here.
- I'm calling Kim.
- We better get out of
here and find some weapons.
No, Kim, it's
me. Told your mom yet?
- No, she hasn't come home yet.
She left a note, but I
can't read her writing.
- Listen, you gotta get
to the airport right away.
The spies have the tape.
They're kinda old, a man and lady.
She only has three fingers.
- Where are you?
- I'm in a car.
Listen, they're catching a plane
to Mexico City at midnight.
- How am I supposed to get to the airport?
- Use your bus pass.
- Duck.
- I want you boys to pay
attention, you do what I tell ya.
Keep your mouths shut, there's a lot more
- what about the girl, you
want us to get her, too?
No, I already took care of that.
- Garage door opener.
- What are you gonna do,
crush her with a garage door?
- Not quite.
This is a trigger for a clock.
You can set off enough
plastique to blow up
her and half her neighborhood.
- You mighta told us, hell, we coulda been
blown up with her.
- That's why I use a timer.
I told that kid, if he
crossed me, she was gonna die.
So now, in exactly one
hour, our little friend's
gonna have a very short,
very loud nightmare.
- That'll be midnight.
- Yeah, I gotta call Kim.
- You go get the Van,
let's get these bodies
out of my trunk.
- Not now, you don't.
- Haverman's got the key.
I'll pop it open from
the glove compartment.
That's all right, I've got mine.
He was in
there five minutes ago.
- Great, Alvarez.
- Haverman, the kid's gone.
- All right, let's get outta here.
- You gotta tell me how
to drive this thing.
- I don't know, this is a real car.
Okay, so much for backing
up. Let's try forward.
Whoa!
Peel out, Davey.
- Don't shoot at my car!
- What are you, crazy?
- Well, that pretty well covers parking.
- Gimme me that, go get the Van.
- Let's go.
You're doing just fine, Davey.
Put the pedal to the metal!
Whoa!
- Take a right here, Davey.
Good, excellent.
Sweeper.
Left, Davey! The sweeper, the sweeper!
- Kim's already left.
She's safe, come on, let's go.
- What if they planted the bomb on her?
- How?
- Lady ace, lady ace, come in.
- Hello, Davey. Hello, can you hear me?
- Why won't she answer?
- She probably dropped her walkie-talkie.
Walkie-talkie.
- Cheap thing.
- We gotta save Kim!
- Right there!
- Uh-oh.
First, we gotta find some
hardware and blast these guys.
- Come on.
- I'm calling dad.
- That guy thinks you're
a nutcase, come on.
Let's get out of here, come on!
- He's gone.
- No kidding, Alvarez.
- Give me the case.
- All right, just stay with
the Van, we'll go on foot.
He can't have gotten very
far. Come on, let's go.
- This is starting to get good.
- Just like cloak and dagger.
- Trying to kill us.
- They can't kill me.
They can't see me.
- They can kill me.
- Not if you're good enough.
That's what this game is all about, right?
- Right?
- Kelly field.
- Yes, I'd like to speak to
master sergeant hal Osborne,
please, it's his son calling.
- Just a minute.
- Come on, you're wasting
valuable combat time, let's go, come on.
- Yeah, thanks. Hello?
Dad, you gotta help me.
- Davey, why aren't you in bed?
- The spies, they planted a
bomb in Kim's walkie-talkie
- hang up, let's go, come on.
- Wait a minute, son.
Look, I told you I didn't want
you to get in those games.
- Dad, this is no game,
now, I need your help.
Davey, look,
I've got a rush job here,
- I do not have time...
- Would you listen to me?
- For this kind of stuff.
- They're trying to take
the plans out of the country at midnight.
- Just calm down, okay, I
don't want you to get worked up
again, I'll be home just as soon as I can.
- What'd I tell ya, he's useless.
- Dad, I'm not home. Now
please, just listen to me
for once, I promise you
I'm telling the truth.
Now, you don't have to worry
about me, but get to Kim
before the bomb goes off at midnight.
- Wait a minute, what do
you mean you're not home,
where are you?
- I don't know, I'm in a telephone booth.
Davey, now listen
carefully, I want you to stay
right where you are and don't
get out of that phone booth.
What's the matter with him?
- One down and two to
go, come on, get the gun.
No.
- Davey, come on, get with
it, we can win this game.
You gotta take advantage
of breaks like this.
Get the gun.
- We gotta get across town
and get a bus to the airport.
- Davey!
- Along the river.
It's the fastest way.
- Play right!
11:35, I'm not gonna make it in time.
- You're gonna have to
take these guys out.
You know that, don't you?
- All right, it's time
for the heavy artillery.
- Let me have it.
- You got it.
- Now, just wait right
here and take 'em out.
- I don't wanna kill anybody.
- Davey, you know the rules.
You're supposed to take out the obstacles
before reaching the objective.
Can't just go right for the
objective, that's no fun.
- Fun?
We got 24 minutes before
the bomb goes off.
- That's why you have to take 'em out.
Look, how many people have I
killed for you over the years?
And now you're saying
you don't wanna play?
Now come on, this is
cloak and dagger for real.
It's what you always wanted.
- Yeah, but I don't have a
gun or a knife or anything.
- The crossfire gambit,
remember the crossfire gambit?
Now go back down there and hide.
Wait 'til the first guy passes you.
Then get rice's attention
and lead his fire.
Davey, if you don't save
Kim, who's going to?
- Okay.
- Hey, ricey, what's the
matter? Can't shoot straight?
- Good work, Davey, now pick up the gun.
He's dead.
- Never mind that, you're winning.
Pick it up, come over here.
- My dad was right, I
don't wanna play anymore.
- Davey, don't chicken out now, come on!
Hurry up.
Good boy.
Wait, Davey, it's a dead end!
- Don't come any closer or I'll shoot.
- Sure you will, with red ink.
Only this one shoots real bullets.
- I'm warning you, this
is not a water pistol.
I could turn you into
shredded meat in about
three seconds with this
baby if I wanted to.
But you've been a real pain in the neck,
so I'm not gonna be that nice.
You know what I'm gonna do to you, boy?
I'm gonna blow both your kneecaps off.
It won't kill ya, but it'll hurt worse
than any dying you can imagine.
Then you know what I'm
gonna do to you, huh?
- Shoot him, Davey.
- I'm gonna shoot you in the stomach.
And then when you beg
for me to finish the job,
I won't do it.
I'm just gonna watch you die slowly.
- Shoot, pull the trigger.
- Please stop, I don't wanna shoot you.
- But I wanna shoot you.
- Kill him. The guy's a jerk, kill him.
All right, I'll show you
what a real hero would do.
Just get him to shoot over here, okay?
Agent x will bounce the
bullets right back at him.
Come on, come on, Turkey, shoot, come on.
Right here, hit me, pull the trigger!
- Jack, don't!
- Good work, Davey, you won.
- You're not dead.
- No, he never touched me.
I guess this thing
doesn't stop real bullets.
He could see you.
- I doubt if he had the imagination.
Anyway, who cares?
You're a hero.
Hey, Davey.
Look, you killed the bad
guys, you won the game.
Well, how do you feel?
- That wasn't fair, you tricked
me, you made me kill him!
Now come on, let's go to the airport.
- I don't wanna play anymore!
I see.
Why do kids always say that?
- Your father said the same thing.
After all those games of
cowboys and Indians...
You get tired of make
believe, you break your toys.
- He did hit you.
- I'm okay, come on, let's go.
- But you're bleeding.
- I'm okay, come on.
I'll tell you what, Davey.
Maybe you better go on up
to the airport without me.
- No, I can't.
- No, no, no, listen.
You're a hero now, Davey.
You don't need an old jelly
blaster like me anymore.
- Don't say that, you'll be fine.
Leaving when they stop believing.
- Maybe I better go get some help.
- No, no, no, don't go.
They wouldn't be able to see me, anyway.
Well, fun while it lasted
anyway, wasn't it, pal?
But Jack flack always escapes.
- Wanna know something?
You're the best playmate I ever had.
You can't leave, Jack.
- I have to, kid.
You're growing up now.
Do me a favor, will ya?
Go get me a smoke.
- Jack, where are you?
Come back, I can't do it on my own.
Yes, you can.
You were always on your own.
Save Kim, Davey.
The white zone
is for the immediate loading and unloading
of passengers only, there is no parking.
- Hi, I'm David Osborne's father.
- Oh, yes, I know.
- Is Kim here?
- Isn't she at your house?
- No, she's not.
Look, I just got a call
- from David.
- Come here, I wanna show
you something.
I just got back here and look at this.
Is this another one of your son's games?
- No, I don't think so.
I need the phone.
- What is it?
- Operator.
- Operator, let me have the
police, this is an emergency.
- Police.
- Yes, my name is sergeant
Osborne, I'd like to speak
to lieutenant Fleming.
- Is it Kim? Is she...
- Lieutenant Fleming's
been trying to reach you.
- Why is he trying to reach me?
Two men are
dead down at the river.
They were shooting at a young boy.
- Jesus.
- What is it?
I'll have him call you.
- No, no, wait a minute, I'll hold on.
If you can connect me with the lieutenant,
I'll hold on, okay?
All right, hang on.
They were shooting at a kid Davey's age.
You and me gotta get to the airport fast.
- Sir, which is the airport bus?
- That one over there.
- Is this the bus to the airport?
- Uh-huh.
- I lost my bus pass.
- 75 cents.
- I don't have it.
- Have to get off then,
can't let you ride for free.
- But you have to!
Listen, I'll pay you when
I get to the airport.
- Sorry.
Flight 146 to Mexico City
is about to board at gate 15, concourse b.
- Thanks.
- Mister, take me to the airport.
- You got any money, son?
- Yeah, lots.
- I don't have that
much, but I have to get
- to the airport.
- Forget it, kid.
- Listen, I don't have any money,
but I gotta get to the airport.
I'll find some way to pay
you when we get there.
- What happened to your leg?
- Nothing.
- Look, maybe we better
get you to a hospital.
That leg doesn't look too good.
- I don't have time for that.
If I don't get to the
airport, a girl is gonna die.
- Get in.
I was going home that way, anyway.
- How long will it take?
- This time of night? About 10 minutes.
- But you have to stop them
from getting on the plane.
You see, they have the c and d tape.
- What?
- A cloak and dagger tape.
You know, a game cartridge,
only it has stolen
government plans in it.
- What does this couple look like?
- I don't know, kinda old, the
woman only has two fingers.
Maybe it was three, I forget.
Look, will you just stop
that plane from boarding
before they take off in it?
11:47.
Can't we go any faster? I
only have a few more minutes.
- Yes, sir, boss.
- You mind hand-searching that?
I don't want to put it through
that electrical doodad.
- That's all the description you've got?
- I told you, we got cut off!
Look, all you gotta do is
check their fingers, jeez.
Transcon flight 146
now boarding at gate 15.
- That's their flight!
- All right, let me
just get this down here.
- Wait here, I'll find
some way to pay you.
- Forget it, kid.
- Thanks.
Southwest flight 2
arriving from houston/austin.
- All right, thank you.
- Arriving at gate 12.
- How do I find somebody?
- Why don't you tell me their
name and I'll have them paged.
Kim gardener, please
report to the information
counter, Kim gardener to
the information counter.
- Did they just call my name?
- I don't know, I wasn't listening.
What's your mother's
name and phone number?
- I think they just said,
Kim gardener, that's me.
- Just a couple more questions, okay?
- Excuse me, have you seen
a little girl around eight?
Is she boarding on this flight?
- Stop them!
- Hey!
- Whoa, just a second, there, son.
But they have the cartridge!
Hey, I'm sorry,
son, you'll just have to go
around and wait your turn.
Who you with, anyway?
- Mom, dad, please don't leave me!
- They your folks?
Just a minute there, folks.
Would you mind coming back here, please?
- Plane's already boarding.
- It'll wait, let's get
this straightened out first.
Transcon flight
6 from miami/atlanta
is now arriving at gate 17.
- Is this your boy?
- Do we look like we
could have a boy that age?
- You putting me on, son?
- No, sir, I can prove they're my folks.
- How?
- Look inside that bag over there
and you'll find one of my game
cartridges, cloak and dagger.
- May I see that bag, please?
- Officer, this boy is lying.
I still would
like to see that bag.
Will you give it to me, please?
Okay, thank you.
- Kim!
- Davey!
Give me your walkie-talkie.
He grabbed the gun!
Eunice, grab the kid!
- No, you don't.
- The little boy!
Please stay back.
- Stay where you are!
- This thing has a...
Zone is for the
immediate loading and unloading
of passengers only, there is no parking.
- Here, lieutenant, take a look at this.
- What do you got?
- Come on.
- Passengers only.
There is no parking.
- We will begin boarding passengers seated
in rows one through 15.
What's going on here?
Ow, my leg!
Davey, Davey!
Out of the way, you!
- They're wanted by the FBI
for selling military secrets,
which were smuggled in
chi ldren's video cartridges.
- Well, what about my son?
- They've got divers down there now.
Did this belong to him?
Forget the luggage,
let's get out of here.
- Someone's been shooting.
- What's going on here?
- God.
- What's going on?
- Why didn't I believe him?
- Hijacking on 15, lieutenant Fleming?
- Hijacking at gate 15.
- Hijacking?
- We're going to code 3, code 3.
- Lieutenant Fleming, what happened?
- Two people kidnapped a
little boy, they have him
on the plane, they're holding him hostage.
- Kim!
- Mom!
- Oh, honey, I was so worried about you.
Give me some confirmation on that.
- They've got Davey out there.
As soon as you can, yes.
- What did they say?
- If they can't get a
pilot to fly 'em to Cuba
within five minutes,
they're gonna kill him.
- My god.
- What are you gonna do?
- The FBI is sending over
their resident agent.
- Well, how long before he gets here?
- It'll be a few minutes,
I just talked to him.
That may be too late, my
son's on that airplane.
- He says we got three minutes.
- He's bluffing.
- He's bluffing with my son's
life, let me go out there.
- What?
- I'm a staff sergeant out
at Kelly field, I've got my
- own ground crew.
- I'm sorry.
- I'm licensed to taxi airplanes.
- Forget it.
- I think he's flipping out, what do I do?
- Tell him a pilot's comin' out there.
- Wait a minute, wait a minute!
They might even buy the
uniform, but what happens
when they expect you to
take that plane in the air?
- I'll fake it.
- Fake it?
- One more minute, and I
blow this kid's brains out!
- But this thing has a...
- Go sit in the back, shut up!
Shut up, shut up!
George, remember
your blood pressure.
That darn kid's
messing everything up.
Calm down, as
long as we've got the boy,
they'll have to give us a pilot.
- Which one do I pull?
Here comes someone now.
- Oh.
Jack, please come back, I
didn't mean to throw you away.
I need your help.
Who are you?
I'm the pilot, I'm not armed.
Turn around.
- Where's the boy?
He's all right, he's back there.
He's clean.
Close the door.
Get in the cockpit.
No funny business, or
I'll blow your head off.
Watch him, George.
- Help me, Jack.
- What are you doin'?
- I have to pressurize the
cabin, the switch is over there.
I have to call the tower
now to get permission
to take off, is that all right?
San Antonio tower, this is flight 146.
- Jack, please come back,
I can't do this on my own.
- I need your help.
- Flight 146.
- Jack.
- Request permission to
taxi over to runway 15,
Jack, please come
back, I need your help.
- This is captain Jack
flack, David Osborne,
get up to the cockpit right away.
- What's the big idea? You
don't have to see the kid.
- They told me to make
sure the boy was all right
- Come on.
You're wanted up front.
- But the bomb goes off
in less than a minute.
- Come on, junior. Now!
- Davey, get up here right away!
- Dad!
- Oh, no you don't!
Let me go!
Look, it's moving!
- Okay, Davey.
- George!
Forget the boy and get back here!
Well, disarm it!
- I don't know how.
- It's still going, the door!
We gotta get you outta here.
- Not with the cabin pressurized.
- Oh, George!
Open up in there!
You'll never fit.
Never mind me, I'll be all right.
Dad, I'm not going without you!
Now take my hand.
Take my hand.
No, no, no!
No, dad, I'm not leaving without you!
Let go of my hands!
No, I'm not leaving!
When you hit the
ground, run away from the plane!
- Dad, come with me!
- Dad!
- Son!
- How'd you escape?
- Jack flack always escapes.
- I don't need him
anymore, I've got you, dad.