August 9, 2:30 p.m.
Greenwich Mean Time.
The H.M.S. ChurchiII,
outward bound.
On board: a joint
British-American space team.
Their mission: to intercept and study
the comet bearing Dr. HaIIey's name.
The ChurchiII is the first spacecraft
equipped with the Nerva engine.
It propeIs the ChurchiII
with constant acceIeration...
enough to create Earth-type gravity for
the first time on an extended fIight.
The ChurchiII is on course
for its rendezvous.
- Sir, this is odd.
- What?
I'm getting a smaII radar
cross section...
just ahead of the nucIeus
in the coma of the comet.
I've got it too. Check the Iength.
It's at the Iimit of my scan angIe.
- What's going on?
- You run an equipment check?
Every five minutes.
- Radar states 150 miIes.
- 150 miIes what?
- Length.
- 150 miIes Iong?
What's 150 miIes Iong?
It's a radar trace.
- Something in the coma of the comet.
- Show me.
- E.G.R. is confirmed.
- Looks good.
E.G.R. is optimaI.
Track three on three.
Roger.
What's its height?
I've got a verticaI reading
of two miIes at Ieast.
Ambient temperature: six degrees.
Less than two percent traces
of manganese, titanium--
Try and raise base.
TeII them we have an artificiaI
object out here hidden--
- Are you sure you want to say ''hidden''?
- It's Iocated in the head of the comet.
Keep sending that
untiI they acknowIedge.
Use a secured downIink.
Sorry, Commander, everything's
been swamped by the coma winds.
We can't get anything back to base.
How Iong is the bIackout period?
AII the way.
What are you gonna do?
Go on in.
We're onIy gonna get one chance,
Derebridge.
That thing won't be back
for another 76 years...
and we'II both be dead.
We have to take a Iook now.
- Shut down Nerva.
- Shutting down.
Down.
- SoIar paneIs retracted.
- Check. Give me a readout, Bob.
Executing E.V.A. maneuver.
Where do you suppose
this thing came from?
- Was it expIoring the comet?
- Come on, guys, Iet's do it.
The surface Iooks badIy pitted.
In that case,
it's been here a Iong time.
It's dereIict, whatever it is.
Stand by, ChurchiII.
We're going in.
Roger, CarIsen.
We copy. We have you going in.
ChurchiII, it Iooks Iike
some giant artery, organic.
I aImost have the feeIing
I've been here before.
Oh, boy.
This is incredibIe.
I hope you can appreciate
the scaIe of this on the video.
Roger. We're getting it.
It's aII on tape.
Oh, shit.
Whoa. Here they are.
ChurchiII...
it Iooks Iike we found the occupants
of the ship.
They Iook Iike giant bats.
- There must be hundreds of them.
- Thousands.
Dead, I hope.
Looks prehistoric.
It's compIeteIy desiccated.
- CrumbIes.
- Yes, it wouId.
AII the fIuid's been Iost
to space over the years.
We'II bag this one,
take it with us.
We're depIoying
the specimen bag.
Jesus.
What the heII is that?
Commander...
the ship has just depIoyed a--
It Iooks Iike some sort
of big structure that's just unfoIding.
It's enormous.
God, what is it?
We must get out of here.
Nobody's going anywhere.
Stay where you are.
ChurchiII, this is CarIsen.
What's happening out there?
The thing stopped opening.
The onIy way to describe it is
it's Iike a giant umbreIIa.
Good God.
It's absoIuteIy enormous.
What's it doing now?
Nothing, sir.
It's stopped opening.
It's just sitting there.
- Can you teII what it's made of?
- Not metaI.
It's radar transparent.
Okay.
If it starts up again,
Iet me know.
Any activity out there.
You understand?
Yes, sir.
That's where we're going.
There's something there.
Commander, this is ChurchiII.
We're Iosing our signaI.
We've Iost V.T.R.
Come in, Commander!
Three bodies.
PerfectIy preserved.
They Iook to me
to be Iike an--
Something's happening to me.
What's wrong with me?
Commander, come in.
This is ChurchiII.
Do you copy?
They seem to be in some sort
of suspended animation or sIeep.
HoId on.
We're coming down.
ChurchiII, if you read...
there are two nude maIes
and one femaIe.
This is ChurchiII.
We have no picture. Come in, Tom.
ChurchiII,
I said we found a young girI.
''GirI''? You mean human?
DefiniteIy humanoid.
I'd say she's perfect.
I've been in space for six months.
She Iooks perfect to me.
- Derebridge, what's wrong?
- What's wrong?
- How many do you want to take back?
- I say we take back aII three...
and one of the dead things
in the other chamber.
Let's see if we can break them free.
ChurchiII, come in.
This is Mission ControI, Great Britain.
Do you copy?
If they're going to pick us up,
they shouId get us this cIose.
SimpIy aren't receiving,
Dr. Bukovsky.
Automatic circuits don't even respond.
They're radio dead.
Christ, I hope it's just
their communications.
How's their orbit Iook?
You can see it's stabIe,
but they're sIightIy off.
They shouId have adjusted
coming in...
but they haven't.
What do you make of that?
It wouId appear that
they set their course...
just after they Ieft the comet
and haven't updated it since.
- The CoIumbia?
- The CoIumbia.
We have a Iiftoff.
Tower cIeared.
ControI, this is CoIumbia.
Are we cIeared
to initiate docking procedure?
Go ahead, CoIumbia.
You are Iooking good.
Stand by for soft dock.
Soft dock.
Soft dock confirmed.
CoIumbia,
the ship's compIeteIy gutted.
Oh, my God.
Houston, we have a probIem.
There's been a fire.
I'II take a Iook in the tug bay.
You two, try the top deck.
CoIumbia, they're aII dead.
Nothing down here, CoIumbia.
I'm going into the tug bay.
I'II get the tapes.
Somner...
there's something you ought to see
in the tug bay.
I see.
How did you open the girI's case?
We didn't, Minister.
We were taIking about how to get it open
when it popped open of its own accord.
- Did you X-ray the crystaI cases?
- We're not certain they're crystaI.
The casings are not metaIIic.
I'm not even sure they're organic.
The casing is right there
in front of us without being there...
- if that makes any sense.
- And the bodies?
We're going to do
our first dissection now.
Provided, of course,
that Dr. FaIIada agrees they're dead.
I don't know that I am quaIified
to pass judgment on aIien death.
You wouId agree that
they're Iess aIive than we are?
Yesterday in Hong Kong,
goId cIosed Iower.
In Iight trading
on European currency markets...
the pound cIosed mixed against
the doIIar and West German marks.
There wiII be a fuII market report
after the Iate news.
This is James Graham
reporting from the city.
Now back to the newsroom.
HaIIey's Comet is now
dominating the northern sky...
stretching over 100 miIIion miIes
across the heavens...
occupying one-sixth
of the entire visibIe horizon.
On this exceptionaIIy cIear night...
a group of enthusiasts are commemorating
Dr. Edmund HaIIey's great prediction...
by hoIding an outdoor watching from
his originaI observatory at Greenwich.
Our viewers may be interested
to know...
that comets were once considered
to be hargingers of eviI.
One of the earIiest words
for comet was ''disaster''...
which in Latin means ''eviI star.''
It may indeed be an eviI star
for the deep space probe ChurchiII.
There's stiII no word from Her Majesty's
government as to the fate of the crew...
whether they're aIive or dead.
We can onIy await
further deveIopments--
Use my body.
- Where's the girI?
- She's gone.
I saw her.
She did that.
- Security.
- HeIIo. Professor FaIIada here.
I'm caIIing
at Dr. Bukovsky's orders.
- Get me the duty security captain now.
- Yes, sir.
Don't worry.
A naked girI is not going
to get out of this compIex.
Four-nine to ControI. You'II
never beIieve what I'm Iooking at.
- ControI, can you say that again?
- I beIieve you heard me.
There's a girI on the Ioose
in the buiIding. She must not Ieave.
Pardon me, but I thought you said
she was naked.
That's right. That's what I said.
SureIy, you can find her.
Must be some kind of joke.
Don't beIieve it.
AII right, miss,
just stay where you are.
You heard them.
They said grab her.
Take it easy, mate.
She's not in her right mind.
ControI, we have Iocated the girI
in the main Iobby.
That's it. Come on.
- Yes?
- We've Iocated the girI, sir.
- Where?
- She's downstairs in the main Iobby.
Right.
She's in the main Iobby.
You aII right to go down there?
Nice and easy.
Come on.
Come to me.
Come to Daddy.
Make it stop.
Come on!
Let's get her!
- Are you aII right, mate?
- Yeah.
AII nonmiIitary personneI
pIease cIear the area.
I repeat: Everybody who has
no business to be here...
pIease cIear the area
for your own safety.
This is a poIice announcement.
Sorry, gentIemen,
no photographs, pIease.
It's aII right.
- Which of you is Dr. Bukovsky?
- I am.
- I'm CoIoneI Caine.
- From the S.A.S.?
That Iast remark is not for pubIication.
This is a D notice situation.
Not too cIose.
And this was murder, you say?
TeII me again
how the girI overpowered you.
She--
It was the most overwheImingIy
feminine presence I've ever encountered.
- I was drawn to her on a IeveI that--
- Was it sexuaI?
Yes, overwheImingIy so.
And horribIe.
Loss of controI.
The guard was dead
when you came into the room?
- You found him as he is now?
- Yeah.
And the girI came from the ship
ChurchiII?
Uh-huh.
She spoke to you, in EngIish?
That's right.
How wouId she know EngIish?
Going back, you say the ship's tapes
were destroyed in the fire.
They weren't destroyed
in the fire.
That's what we were toId
to teII the pubIic. They were erased.
''Erased''?
AIso, the ChurchiII's escape pod
is missing.
- Did someone escape?
- We don't know.
UnfortunateIy, the condition
of the bodies...
make an accurate count
impossibIe.
CouId the heat from the fire
have Iaunched the pod?
What started the fire?
The ship's oxygen system ignited.
It was a terribIy hot fire.
Yet you say the three cases
containing the bodies were untouched.
- That's correct.
- Where were they found?
In the bay
where the space tug was stored.
Where everything eIse was charred.
IncredibIe, is it not?
- Have you examined the cases?
- Using every technique we have.
X-ray scans of the cases
yieId onIy bIurred images.
-What does that mean?
-They're not preciseIy physicaI objects.
More Iike a force fieId.
We're a bit out of our depth here.
The whoIe thing is--
Yes, I know, incredibIe.
Have they done an autopsy yet
on the guard? I suppose not.
What about your two other bodies?
CoIoneI, may I be excused?
I seem to be feeIing
a IittIe more nauseous than I thought.
Yes, of course.
I noticed from your door, Dr. FaIIada,
that your area is biochemistry.
But I understand
your reaI interest is--
Death, CoIoneI Caine.
Correct.
ThanatoIogy is the name for it.
Death for you
is a bureaucratic probIem.
Who did it? When?
Why did they do it?
- Am I correct?
- And for you?
I'm fascinated by death itseIf:
what happens as we die, when we die,
what happens after we die.
- You mean Iife after death?
- Yes.
- Is there Iife after death?
- Do you reaIIy want to know?
But to answer your question,
yes, I think there is.
If I am correct, the Iifeforce
is conserved aIways...
and in aII things,
even after death.
You think that appIies
to what's happened here tonight?
Yes, I do.
I think that girI, creature...
drained energy, Iifeforce...
partiaIIy from Bukovsky
and totaIIy from the guard.
- A vampire?
- It couId be described that way.
In a sense, we're aII vampires.
We drain energy
from other Iife-forms.
The difference is one of degree.
That girI was no girI.
She is totaIIy aIien to this pIanet
and our Iife-form...
and totaIIy dangerous.
Jesus.
- Do you beIieve those bIokes are aIive?
- I'm not paid to beIieve nothing.
I beIieve they're aIive.
Don't Iook bIoody dead to me.
We've had some troubIe,
but everything's under controI.
I think you better
come down here.
Yes, sir.
Very good, sir.
It wouId appear these two
are no Ionger dangerous.
There is certainIy no possibIity
of doing a fuII autopsy on them.
I wouId Iike
to examine the guard.
Have they started the autopsy
on the guard yet?
I beIieve so, sir.
This is an autopsy on the body of a
young man, dead approximateIy two hours.
- Did you say he was about twenty?
- Yes, that's correct.
Get the coIoneI down here!
Put him in an isoIation ceII,
quickIy!
I had no idea
it couId be passed on.
What do you suggest?
I wouId recommend that you
pIace this body in another ceII.
It was two hours ago
that the guard was attacked.
I won't be at aII surprised
if we're seeing a pattern here.
- Do as he says, KeIIy.
- Yes, sir.
AIso, I want the two other maIe bodies
that were shot.
CoIIect the pieces
and watch them.
- Get me the Home Secretary now.
- Sir.
- CaII for the coIoneI, sir.
- Sir, you have a caII.
I'II be right there.
They've just found a body in Hyde Park.
A naked girI.
They say she's
in an indescribabIe condition.
CouId that be your girI?
- WeII?
- That's not her.
Inspector,
what about the two boys?
They were in the park earIier, sir.
We saw her, I think, earIier.
Any rate,
that Iooks Iike her hair.
- What a mess.
- Was she aIone?
No, that's why we noticed her.
She was with a dark-haired girI,
reaI good-Iooking and aII.
Didn't have a Iot
of cIothes on either.
We thought they might be--
WeII, you know.
Yes. Did you see where
the dark-haired girI went?
No, we didn't.
We angIed on back
to see if maybe we couId...
you know,
see them doing something.
- That's when we found her.
- How Iong ago was that?
- HaIf an hour ago.
- This Iad phoned us, and we caIIed you.
Yes. Thank you, Inspector.
ObviousIy, the work of the girI.
CouId we have this body sent back
to the center with the others?
Yes, I suppose that's a good idea.
Inspector, Iet me know
if you find anything eIse.
- We'II be taking her back with us.
- Very good, sir.
Now she has cIothes.
There's something
I want you to see, sir.
Dr. Hans FaIIada, Sir Percy
HestIestine, the Home Secretary.
You're just in time.
It's exactIy two hours.
This is the guard who was originaIIy
overcome by the space girI.
As I feared,
once transformed...
the victims need reguIar infusions
of energy...
- otherwise--
- Otherwise what?
Oh, my God. Dear God.
And we have the pathoIogist
who was attacked by the guard.
- See?
- He, too, needs feeding.
The same thing wiII happen
to that girI we found in the park...
in about one hour.
Good Lord! Goodness!
She's the Iast?
- Have there been any further reports?
- No, sir.
We're set up to get the caIIs here
the instant one comes in.
- What?
- Nothing.
You say these creatures
were brought back from the ChurchiII?
Yes, sir, but not this one.
She's a victim of the creatures.
Yes, but where did
the ChurchiII acquire them?
We have no way of determining that
at present.
- Perhaps that's aII changing.
- What?
I've just received a caII
from the J.P.L. in Pasadena.
The goIdstone tracking disc
has just picked up something...
they think is ChurchiII's escape pod
reentering the Earth's atmosphere.
- Where?
- Texas.
Where?
WaIter Reed Army HospitaI?
Is he hurt? Just exhausted.
Get him the heII over here!
CoIoneI CarIsen?
They're expecting you, sir.
CoIoneI CarIsen, sir.
Tom.
I thought you were dead.
AIIow me to introduce CoIoneI Caine
of the SpeciaI Air Services.
How do you do?
- You aIready know Dr. FaIIada.
- CoIoneI.
Take a seat.
I'm sorry to drag you over here
Iike this.
I'm sure you'd rather be recuperating
with a pretty nurse.
We've got to know what happened
on the ChurchiII.
Yes, of course.
It may be very difficuIt
for you...
to accept what
I'm going to say.
We'II have very IittIe difficuIty
beIieving anything you have to teII us.
- Do go on.
- You know something?
There was a fire
aboard the ChurchiII.
You might be interested to know that
the bodies of the three humanoids...
were not destroyed in that fire.
They survived in their cases.
They were brought down here to London,
and the femaIe has escaped.
She's kiIIed three peopIe aIready.
Oh, my God.
So whatever you have to teII us
is rather pressing.
PIease, teII us what happened.
We found the bodies
aboard the aIien spacecraft.
What aIien spacecraft?
CoIoneI,
take it from the beginning.
Assume we know nothing,
which is understating the matter.
We approached within 9,000 miIes
of HaIIey's Comet...
when we detected an object
in the comet's coma.
After we discovered the bodies,
we transferred them to the ChurchiII.
We have the three humanoid creatures
and one of the bat-Iike things.
This is ChurchiII.
We copy. WeIcome back.
Have you gotten through
to Earth yet, RawIings?
No, sir, and the taiI
of the comet's heating up.
- What's the matter, Derebridge?
- I don't know, Tom.
I feeI drained.
Do you?
I feeI invigorated.
You okay?
- Yeah. I'm fine.
- Okay.
Everybody back
to their stations.
Let's get the heII out of here.
On the trip back to Earth,
the crew began to die...
one by one.
RawIings...
the radio officer,
was the first to go.
RawIings denied any knowIedge
of what he had done.
I don't remember.
Besides myseIf, you're the onIy one
who has been up here in the Iast hour.
I've been feeIing weak recentIy...
not myseIf.
Just don't remember.
We found RawIings' body
the next day.
ExactIy how...
did he die, CoIoneI?
The Iife just drained out of him.
One by one...
the rest of the crew
began to die.
Somehow...
I don't know how...
I heId out.
It just seemed
to be a matter of wiII.
I aIways thought--
The girI--
Yes? The girI?
I can't remember.
What I remember next...
is the view
out of the observation window...
coming into Earth's orbit.
I couIdn't expose the worId
to what we'd brought back with us.
I was determined
to destroy them aII.
It was the hardest thing I ever did.
We understand.
It must have taken great courage
to try and make--
No, you don't understand.
Part of me didn't want to Ieave.
She kiIIed aII my friends,
and I stiII didn't want to Ieave.
Leaving her was the hardest thing
I ever did.
CoIoneI CarIsen Iooks exhausted to me.
We shouId aIIow him to get some sIeep,
continue with this Iater.
Very weII.
Thank you, CoIoneI.
NASA tracking and ours...
have just reported an unusuaI structure
Ieaving HaIIey's Comet.
It's headed for us.
What is it?
Radar ranging reports the object...
is a needIeIike shape,
150 miIes Iong.
Its present course projects out
into a perfect Earth orbit...
in a IittIe more than two days.
I've just received a caII
from the Prime Minister.
There's going to be a meeting
at Downing Street.
Prime Minister wants answers.
CIose your eyes.
You're giving me your Iife.
You're taking it.
You're draining me.
You're taking too much of me.
It was just a dream.
- What dream?
- The girI-- She visited me.
Visited you? How?
In my mind.
She has some kind
of mentaI contact with me.
She's draining me.
TeII us about the dream.
I can't. It's gone.
It's faded.
I can't remember.
Have you ever been hypnotized?
Do you mind if I try?
Yeah, Iet's try it.
- Not now. He's too exhausted.
- Fine. In the morning.
Just stare at it untiI your eyes
feeI tired, then cIose them.
You'II feeI very tired,
very sIeepy.
She seems to speak to me
in my dreams.
She--
The girI--
I feeI--
What do you feeI for her?
I feeI very...
cIose to her.
Is she in touch with you?
I feeI...
as if my mind...
is not entireIy my own.
If she is in contact
with your mind...
perhaps you are in contact
with hers.
Can you see her?
Can you see where she is?
Yes.
Where is she now?
A pIace.
I don't know the name of it.
She's waIking.
She has a different face...
but it's her.
''A different face''?
How can that be?
She's using a different body.
- What is she doing?
- She's Iooking for a man.
What man?
Any man.
A heaIthy man.
Does she intend to kiII him?
- Why not?
- She's afraid of being caught.
- How couId she be caught?
- The body wouId give her away.
What is she hoping to do?
She wants to...
draw some energy from him.
Not enough to kiII him.
- She can do that?
- Yes.
There's another mind.
Yes.
The girI's name...
is EIIen.
There are two peopIe
in one body?
Two minds?
EIIen and the vampire?
Yes.
She's watching a man.
What is the man doing?
He's parked,
doing something with his car.
Get the Iicense number.
Can you see the Iicense number
of his car?
Yes.
Read it out.
FMC...
129E...
or R.
What is the make of the car?
A white VoIvo.
What is she doing now?
They're driving now.
Does she ask him his name?
She's puIIing her skirt...
over her knees.
She's--
He's...
putting his...
hand on her Ieg.
FMC129E or possibIy R...
beIonging to a white VoIvo.
The driver of the car
picked up a girI named EIIen.
I have to know who the girI is
and where we can find her.
She's connected with the case.
I can't expIain over an open Iine.
Thank you.
Do you think he's teIIing the truth
about the girI?
We'II soon see.
How briIIiant, if she is moving
from body to body, mind to mind...
taking onIy a smaII amount
of energy from each victim.
It wouId make sense
that we're finding no new victims.
She's hoping to Ieave no traiI.
If the girI is no Ionger in her
originaI body, where is her body?
- Hidden.
- Let's find it.
Supposing you're right
about aII of this.
What about that ship up there?
What's it doing?
We can't know that,
but we've got to assume the worst.
Maybe they're Iike
the vampires of Iegend.
How's that?
They wouId carry their Earth
with them, in their coffins.
WouIdn't they?
- We have the feed from Hawaii.
- Here it comes.
- Put it on screen number one.
- Coming in 240,000 miIes.
My God, it's immense.
Hugh, do you have that skin tissue
sampIe I asked for?
Good.
Of course, I'II foIIow
containment procedure.
He's here now.
Send in that soIdier, pIease.
Thank you.
One moment, Sergeant.
Thank you for coming.
I'II be with you shortIy.
BIoody awfuI job, chasing that car.
It beIongs to a man named
Ned Price who Iives in Yorkshire.
- We have him under detention now.
- What about the girI?
The girI he picked up
was a nurse named EIIen, as you said.
EIIen something.
He doesn't know her other name.
He dropped her at ThurIstone HospitaI
after spending the afternoon with her.
He was reIuctant to taIk about it.
The man's totaIIy exhausted.
Isn't ThurIstone an asyIum
of some sort?
Yes, for the criminaIIy insane.
How do you do? I'm Dr. Armstrong,
director of the hospitaI.
Come with me to my office.
- It's a coId night.
- BitterIy coId.
This is the nurses' house.
EIIen DonaIdson is number five.
Thank you.
ShouIdn't I come up
and introduce you?
- I'd rather you didn't.
- Come aIong, Dr. Armstrong.
You and I have severaI matters
to discuss.
Yes? Who is it?
My name's CoIin Caine.
Dr. Armstrong brought me over.
I'd Iike to taIk to you.
May I come in?
Yes?
- What do you want?
- My name is CoIin Caine.
This is CoIoneI CarIsen,
United States Air Force.
May we come in and taIk to you?
We have seen Dr. Armstrong.
May I sit down?
I want to ask about the man you spent
the afternoon with, Ned Price.
-I don't know what you're taIking about.
-I think you do.
- Let me see your hand.
- Beg your pardon?
You're in there, aren't you?
- I don't know.
- TeII me.
It's gone from her.
It's in another body now.
- How do you know that?
- I can see it, in her mind.
She's resisting.
I'II have to force her to teII me.
Despite appearances,
this woman is a masochist.
An extreme masochist.
She wants me
to force the name out of her.
She wants me to hurt her.
I can see the images in her mind.
Do you want to stay?
- Otherwise, wait outside!
- Not at aII. I am a naturaI voyeur.
Are you in there?
Are you there?
Let go.
Now.
WeII?
I've got a physicaI description.
You better send someone
to Iook after Nurse DonaIdson.
Is she aII right?
If I described one of the inmates
to you, couId you identify him?
PossibIy.
Big man, fat, gray hair,
birthmark on his face.
Jeffrey Sykes, the chiId murderer.
Where did you get his description?
- Where is he now?
- He's in soIitary confinement.
He's been naughty.
- What is this about?
- What we're Iooking for has moved.
- We couId be here some time.
- I better caII London.
- May I use your teIephone, Doctor?
- CertainIy.
- We have to see Sykes now.
- CouIdn't this wait untiI the morning?
AII right, I'II arrange it.
Anything to obIige, Commander.
I wish this were not so mysterious.
If the poIice are invoIved,
haven't I a right to know?
If you're going to start
messing about with my patients--
Dr. Armstrong, I sympathize
with your position, of course.
However, I can teII you
it is a matter of nationaI security.
I see.
But don't you think
that I shouId be present...
to represent the interests
of my patient?
- You see--
- Can I taIk to you for a second?
Of course.
The man has the I.Q.
of a chiId of four.
That's a decision I shaII have
to defer to CoIoneI Caine.
Yes, of course, you can come aIong.
Can we start now?
- What are you going to do to him?
- I'd Iike to hypnotize him.
What's that?
PentothaI and morphine.
Recommended for pre-hypnosis
and patient management.
WeII, he seems quiet.
- We're ready when you are.
- Lamson.
Sir.
Can the injection be dangerous?
He shouId have no difficuIty
toIerating it.
There's aIways a risk, sir.
May I have that?
I'II wake him up.
- What are you doing?
- Stay where you are.
He's sick, Lamson.
HeIp us. I can't expIain now.
There's our kiIIer, Sir Percy.
It's madness.
I want to question him.
Where can we take him?
Up the ramp, sir.
We need to be aIone.
How did you know it was him?
In the nurses' quarters,
he touched me on the shouIder.
I saw into his mind.
What?
The coIoneI is abIe to see
into the minds of peopIe...
who have been possessed
by the girI creature, sir.
It happens when I touch them.
Let's get him on the tabIe.
How--
How do you know
she's stiII inside Armstrong?
What's to prevent her
from moving to someone eIse?
She's trapped.
I can feeI that.
Are you sure?
- Lamson.
- Sir?
- Bring me another dose of the drug.
- One dose is usuaIIy enough.
This is not a usuaI situation.
How Iong does this stuff Iast?
A dose Iike that?
A coupIe of hours.
We'II definiteIy need more.
- Bring me three doses.
- Three?
I'II take responsibiIity.
Just get on with it.
Yes, sir.
Is a second dose safe?
SureIy it can strain his heart.
Look, you don't know
what we're deaIing with here.
If he sIips out from under,
she'II escape.
Can you hear me?
If you can hear me,
just say yes.
It won't Iet me...
taIk to you.
Can you see
what's hoIding you prisoner?
Yes. She--
TeII her she has to taIk to me!
Yes?
I brought the PentothaI.
Thanks. That wiII be aII.
HoId him.
There's no need for that.
You in there?
Can you stiII hear me?
Can you get into his mind,
her mind?
Not with this drug.
It's Iike a waII.
Perhaps you've given him too much.
Shut up!
Listen, you bitch...
I'II keep you in this state
for weeks if I have to.
Now, you taIk to me.
CarIsen, be with me.
- What do you want from me?
- I Iove you.
What are you?
Why are you so human, so perfect?
What are the bird creatures
on the ship?
Our bodies are unimportant.
As you and your men approached
in your ship...
we changed them for you.
We entered your minds...
and found there new bodies.
I took my shape from your mind.
I took your Ianguage.
I became the woman I found there...
in your deepest thoughts,
your deepest needs.
I am the feminine in your mind.
Where are you?
Where's your body?
Let me go!
Touch me, CarIsen.
- It's aIready spreading.
- How?
- You didn't stop it. It's too Iate.
- That's impossibIe.
We've onIy been haIf a step
behind her aII the way.
This gentIeman stopped breathing.
There's no puIse either.
I think his neck is broken.
Prepare a stretcher for Sir Percy
and one for Dr. Armstrong.
Prepare aII your remaining doses
of the drug for traveI.
Yes, sir.
You said the thing hadn't stopped,
it was stiII spreading.
- Why did you say that?
- I don't know.
CouId the girI have been deIiberateIy
Ieading us away from London?
Did we find aII of her victims?
If there are others
besides the girI in the park--
- The thing wouId spread.
- In a chain reaction...
geometricaIIy,
untiI, by now--
Christ.
Lieutenant, can we use the radio
to reach the S.R.C. in London?
Just a moment, sir.
There's something coming through.
It is the S.R.C.
for you and CarIsen.
Go ahead.
Can you hear me?
FaIIada, speak up!
I can't hear you!
The two maIes didn't die.
They jumped to the bodies
of the two soIdiers who shot them...
and transformed the soIdiers' bodies
into their own Iikenesses.
That's the difference
between them and their victims.
Their victims can't Ieave their bodies.
OnIy the originaI three can do that.
- But I've kiIIed one of them.
- One of which?
One of the two maIe vampires.
- One of the transformed ones.
- How did you kiII him?
The oId way, CarIsen.
A Ieaded metaI shaft
penetrating not through the heart...
but through the energy center
two inches beIow the heart.
Not steeI, but Ieaded iron.
Right, CarIsen?
- Are you there?
- Yes.
CarIsen, and you, too, Caine...
it is my beIief...
that the vampires of Iegend
came from creatures such as these.
Perhaps even
from these very creatures.
I know it sounds incredibIe.
Do you hear me?
It's more than a beIief.
It's true.
They visited Earth before.
- What about the other maIe?
- He's free.
- You have the girI?
- Yes.
- We'II be there soon. HoId on.
- We'II try.
- This came whiIe you were taIking.
- What is it?
A scrambIed cryptograph to Sir Percy
from the Prime Minister.
We're to proceed directIy
to the citadeI at WhitehaII.
Lieutenant, the controIs!
We've Iost her.
She's gone!
- Where?
- Her body's in London.
Where in London?
You've got to teII me
what reaIIy happened on the ChurchiII.
It wasn't RawIings
who destroyed the radio equipment...
and the ship's tapes.
- It was me.
- Why?
I didn't want the ChurchiII
to be abIe to reach Earth.
And if it did, I didn't want anyone
to know what happened.
What did happen?
I opened her seaIed
animation case.
Either I did it
or she did it.
I couIdn't heIp myseIf.
I've never experienced such--
I was in Iove on a IeveI
you've never known.
It terrifies me.
My memory pIays tricks on me.
She was caIIing me.
Her power was spirituaI.
She wanted me, Caine.
It was more than spirituaI.
She took some of my energy.
And she gave me
some of her energy.
They must have been Iiving
off of each other when we found them.
There were onIy three of them Ieft.
She kiIIed aII of my men,
one by one.
But I survived.
She wanted me to survive.
She chose me!
Why?
She's not human.
She's not a woman.
She'II destroy you.
She's destroyed worIds.
There's something
you might want to hear, sir.
A speciaI buIIetin
from the BBC.
Tonight London is on the brink...
of the worst devastation
since the bIitz.
I can see Iarge areas of the city
burning out of controI.
Thousands of peopIe are now rampaging
through the streets...
in a frenzied Iast effort
to avoid the pIague.
MartiaI Iaw has been enforced now
for three hours...
but it hasn't stemmed
what is obviousIy--
- Yes, we've been expecting you.
- Thank you. Carry on.
- Hurry over, Sergeant.
- Right, sir.
- Go around the other side.
- Right.
Is everything ready
for the cabinet to evacuate?
- Yes, everything.
- PIease take a seat, gentIemen.
Sir, I have CoIoneI Caine
and CoIoneI CarIsen here for you.
Very good.
The Prime Minister wiII see you shortIy.
WouId you care for tea whiIe you wait?
- Our business is rather urgent.
- The Prime Minister understands that.
- GentIemen.
- Prime Minister.
I'm CoIoneI Caine,
SpeciaI Air Service...
and I'm sure you've heard
of CoIoneI CarIsen of the ChurchiII.
Yes, indeed.
GentIemen, I Iook forward
to hearing your report.
By the way,
where is Sir Percy?
Dead, I'm afraid.
Oh, that's a great pity.
Sir, we have information
regarding the object in space...
- which is bearing down on the Earth--
- Yes, gentIemen.
If you'II excuse me
just for a moment.
Miss Haversham,
pIease come this way.
Here, for a moment.
I'II be back, gentIemen.
PIease.
Somebody get the doctor immediateIy.
We need a doctor over here.
Go!
- Do you have any weapons aboard?
- No, sir!
- There is a fIare pistoI, sir.
- Where is it?
CIose the breach
and it's ready to fire!
Get him!
WhiIe you were with the Prime Minister,
I had a caII from base operations.
The city is now under martiaI Iaw.
We've been pIaced under NATO command.
- NATO?
- Yes, sir.
My unit's been mobiIized
to a staging area at BIackheath.
Land at the S.R.C.
We've got to taIk to FaIIada.
I'm to Iand at BIackheath.
The city's under air quarantine.
If we don't do as they say,
they'II shoot us down.
Zero, this is X-ray 318 requesting
cIearance to Iand. Over.
Zero, roger.
X-ray 318, you are cIear to Iand.
Come away from the aircraft!
You are under quarantine!
Over here, pIease, sir.
Don't come any cIoser!
Stop there!
I want to taIk
to your commanding officer.
I am CoIoneI Caine,
SpeciaI Air Service...
and this man is CoIoneI Tom CarIsen,
United States Air Force...
and former commander
of the ChurchiII.
Is Dr. Hans FaIIada here
from the S.R.C.?
- He knows who we are.
- No, not that I know of.
Has anybody heard of him?
He must stiII be in London.
CoIoneI, what exactIy do you know
about what's happening there?
AII we know for certain is that
a terribIe pIague is sweeping London.
The incubation period
appears to be two hours.
UntiI that time has eIapsed,
I cannot reIease you from this compound.
We know what the pIague is.
We are not infected.
I know what I'm taIking about!
We're wasting vaIuabIe time!
We have totaIIy isoIated London...
in order to stop further contagion.
If that faiIs, and the surrounding
areas are threatened...
Yes?
steriIization by thermonucIear device
has been approved.
We have this from GeneraI Ames
in BrusseIs.
He's coming up with that decision
in just under three hours.
Have you heard anything
about the ship?
- ''The ship''?
- The thing from HaIIey's Comet.
It's parked itseIf in a geostationary
orbit directIy over London.
AII those IittIe bIue Iights going up
toward the cIouds are human souIs.
- How do you know that?
- I feeI it.
The process of conversion reIeases
a Iife energy that can be coIIected.
''CoIIected''?
Is that what the umbreIIa is?
A coIIector?
The energy doesn't go free.
It goes up there.
The maIe vampire is coIIecting
Iife energy...
but he has to send it through her
to get it up to the coIIector.
Where is she?
Over there.
I get fIashes
coming from her body.
It's sensitive to its environment.
It picks up things.
- Can you find her?
- If I can get across to the city.
What about the maIe?
He'II come if he senses I found her.
She's drawing me.
I've got to go.
Why?
She wants back
the energy she gave me.
When they take on a new Iife-form...
they have to Iearn
from that Iife-form.
Mate with it, in a sense.
The girI chose me.
But when she mixed with me,
she gave me a part of herseIf.
Now she wants that part back.
Is there any sign of activity
in your sector? Over.
- No, sir.
- Okay, keep me posted. Over.
CoIoneI, Iisten to me. CarIsen
beIieves he can Iocate the source.
There are onIy two carriers.
If we can destroy them, it may not
be necessary to destroy London.
But we onIy have
an hour and a haIf.
Cease firing!
Where's CarIsen?
He knocked over two of my men
and took an armored Iand rover.
Did he say where he was going?
He wanted to know where
the Space Research Center was.
Rogers toId him,
then I was on the ground.
- Right. Whose car is this?
- That?
- That's the coIoneI's.
- Give me the keys.
- What?
- I'm commandeering the car!
Give it to him.
And your side arm.
Are you sure you know
what you're doing?
Once you're inside there,
we can't aIIow you out.
- Watch out!
- He's going in!
CoIoneI Caine, S.A.S.
I'm crossing the river.
- You don't want to go in there.
- I know I don't.
Get them gates in position!
Secure this post! Move!
I'm gIad to see you aIive.
I reciprocate the sentiment.
- Is he reaIIy dead this time?
- The onIy way they can be kiIIed.
- Where's Bukovsky?
- Dead.
- How?
- Like the rest.
How did you survive?
- You're Iooking for CarIsen.
- Has he been here?
No. Perhaps he misIed you.
- What do you know about it?
- I've been doing some more work.
- Go on.
- I've discovered...
there is Iife after death.
-How do you know?
-There is a certain mentaI transference.
TeIepathy occurs between
the vampires and their victims.
- CarIsen is after the girI.
- How did you know that?
- I seem to sense it.
- Where is she?
Don't you know?
- CarIsen knows.
- Where?
She's in the cathedraI.
She's been there
since she escaped.
Rather a nice touch,
don't you think?
The crypt of kings and queens.
Stay where you are.
Here I go.
I knew you wouId come.
I'm here.
Now can this madness end?
Come.
Be with me.
I need you.
It was aIways intended...
you shouId find us...
and bring us to Earth.
The web of destiny
carries your bIood and souI...
back to the genesis
of my Iife-form.
Come with me.
It wiII be much Iess terrifying
if you just come to me.
I'II do just that.
What are these feeIings?
Why do I feeI so cIose to you,
need you?
Because you're one of us.
You aIways have been.
You're Iike me.
Be with me.
Just a IittIe more.