Hey, Ash. Where are we?
Well, we just crossed the Tennessee border.
- Which would put us...  - Yeah?
Which would put us...
Right...
...Here!
Turn!
What the hell was that? Are you trying to kill us?
Don't blame me! It's your steering wheel!
Damn thing jerked right out of my hands.
I don't understand it.
I had this thing in for a tune-up yesterday
and they said they'd go over everything.
Well you better take it back
because the damn thing don't work.
The one thing that does work is this lousy horn.
Go to hell! I'm not honking at you!
Jesus Christ!
Hey Scotty! What's this place like anyway?
Well, the guy that's renting
it says it's an old place.
Little run down, but it's right up in the mountains.
Yeah, and the best part is that we get it so cheap.
Why are we getting it so cheap?
Well, I don't know. Might be in real bad shape.
You mean, nobody's seen this place yet?
- Well, not yet.  - Well, it might not be that bad.
- No.  - Actually, it might be kind of nice.
- Yeah.  - It's probably a real pit!
I think this is where we get off.
This is the bridge we're going to cross?
Jesus Christ!
The whole thing's falling apart on us!
Don't let the noise fool you girls
this thing's solid as a rock.
It's supposed to be one of these on here.
Come on!
- Hey  - Hey
Hey
Join Us!
Dead bodies in the cellar.
Dead bodies in the cellar
Will you stop it?
I would very much like to
make a toast for all this evening.
- Yeah  - It sounds good.
Ah, as a Greek friend of mine once said...
He said...
I...
Ok, Ok,...
Nis, nis...
...Tu, Tu, Tu... Tu, Ta, Rim.
Which means?
Party down! Yeah!
What is this?
Whatever it is, it's still down there.
I don't like cellars. Let's just close it up.
It's probably just some animal.
An animal? An animal?
That is the stupidest thing I ever heard of.
Jesus Christ!
There's something down there.
Maybe it is just some animal.
Yeah, you're probably right.
Probably just some animal.
Cheryl, why don't you go down and check, make sure?
Scotty! I'm not going down there!
Ok, Ok you cowards. I'll go.
Be careful.
Back in a minute.
Hey Scotty! You find anything?
Scotty!
Scotty?!
Scott!
He's just kidding around...
- Isn't he?  - Scotty!!
Scott!
Linda, get me a flashlight.
That's the only one we brought up.
Then get the lantern.
Scotty?!
Boo!!
Hey! Come here, I wanna show you something.
Look at all this stuff.
I bet this still shoots.
Probably does.
Oh!...God!
Oh God!
Look at this!
This kind of looks like your old girlfriend.
Come on. Let's take this stuff upstairs.
I'll grab the recorder...
...and you get everything else now.
This guy was a real turd... everybody hated him...
Like...Like you, kind of.
Yeah, just like me. I'm gonna break your face.
...also invented this western stuff
He makes all this little models...
Ok, shush!
Listen to this...
This is the tape I found downstairs.
It has been a number of years
since I began excavating the ruins of
Candar with a group of my colleges.
Now, my wife and I have retreated to
a small cabin in the solitude of these mountains.
Here I continued my research
undisturbed by the myriad
...distractions of modern civilization
and far from the groves of academe.
I believe I have made a significant find
in the Candarian Ruins.
A Volume of Ancient Sumarian burial practices
and funerary incantations.
It is entitled "Naturon Demonto"
...roughly translated, "Book of the Dead".
The book is bound in human flesh...
...and inked in human blood.
It deals with demons
and demon resurrection and those forces
...which roam the forest
and dark bowers of man's domain.
The first few pages warn that
these enduring creatures may lie...
...dormant but are never truly dead.
They may be recalled to active life
...through the incantations presented in this book.
It is through recitation of these passages...
...that the demons are given license
to possess the living.
What did you do that for?
It was just getting good!
I just don't want to hear it anymore, that's all.
Scotty, c'mon. Leave her alone, man.
Hey, come on...I just want to hear the rest of it.
No big deal.
Tatre-ah-mis-trobeen-ha-zar-ta
Tantir-man-ov-mansiz-onn-hazann-sobar.
Sum-unda-rop-sa Dar-his-hyk-err-duns-de-rod-sa
Kanda!
Shut it off!
Shut it off!!
Kanda!
Shut it off!!!
Oh my God!
Cheryl! Where're you going?
I can't believe this!
Scott, you knew not to play that!
I mean c'mon, you knew it was upsetting her.
You just don't know
when you're taking something too far.
Don't give me that!
You were playing it too.
You could've shut it off.
I mean... big deal!
She's nuts!
I mean it's just a joke, c'mon!
Jesus Christ.
She acts like she's three years old or something.
Listen. Why don't we stay up
for a while and listen to the storm?
All right, yeah.
Let me check on Cheryl first
to make sure that she's Ok.
Stealing from the blind, eh?
It's for you.
Ash, how sweet of you.
- Would you put it on?  - Oh, Sure.
I was going to give it to you
before we came up here, but...
...things got so hectic
this is really the first chance
we...we've had to be alone.
Take a look.
Oh, Ash! It's beautiful!
I really love it.
I'll never take it off.
Join Us!
Is anybody out there?
I know someone's out there!
I heard you.
I heard you in the cellar.
Join Us!
Ashley!
Help!
What the hell happened to you?
Cheryl, what's the matter with you?
Did something in the woods do this to you?
No! It was the woods themselves!
They're alive Ashley!
The trees! They're alive!
Ash. Why don't I take her in the back room
so she can lie down...
I'm not lying down!
I want to get out of here.
I want to leave this place right now.
Right now, Ashley!
Wait a minute!
I sure as hell am not leaving any place tonight.
- Cheryl.  - Cheryl.
Cheryl, there's nothing out there.
Trees do not attack people.
Ashley! Will you drive me into town or not?
Right now?!
Look, sure, sure
I'll take you into town
but just listen to what you're saying.
I don't care how it sounds.
I wanna get out of this place right now!
Ok, maybe you could stay somewhere in town tonight.
Come on.Come on.
I know it's not gonna start.
It's not gonna let us leave.
Why are you stopping?
Wait here a minute.
Do you see something?
Where're you going?
Ashley!
It's not going to let us go!
I told you! I told you!
Why won't you listen to me?
I know now that my wife
has become host to a Candarian demon.
I fear that the only way
to stop those possessed by the...
...spirits of the book is through the act of
...bodily dismemberment.
I believe now to avoid this horror
but for myself
I have seen the dark shadows moving...
...in the woods and I have no doubt that
whatever I have resurrected through this book
is sure to come calling...for me.
Ok, ah, let me think. Ummm...
It's a seven?
Oh! What suit?
Ahh... diamonds.
No wait! Ummm, hearts!
Oh My God! It's seven of hearts!
You're right!
Hey Ash! I guessed the card right!
Yeah... truly amazing, Linda.
I don't know,I don't know...
but I think it's really
some sort of extra sense or something...
- ...you know, like ESP.  - Ok, try this one...
Ok... It's a seven.
- I don't believe it!  - ...of Spades.
Queen of Spades.
Four of Hearts.
Eight of Spades.
Two of Spades. Jack of Diamonds. Jack of Clubs!
Why have you disturbed our sleep? Awakened us...
...from our ancient slumber?
You will die!
Like the others before you.
One by one we will take you.
What happened to her?
Did you see her eyes?
Oh Ash, I'm scared.
What's wrong with her?
Cheryl! Stop it!
- Oh, Shit!  - Join Us! Join...
Ash. I think we ought to get out of here.
Yeah.
We still have a few more hours before morning.
I don't think I can wait that long.
You have to. We all have to!
And then in the morning
we'll get in the car...
and we'll take the bridge. And...
Why does she keep making those horrible noises?!
I don't know!
And what about her eyes?
What about her eyes?
For God's Sake, What happened to her eyes?!
Everything's going to be all right.
Scotty. I think there's something out there.
Go to bed, and get some sleep. Ok?
Shelly?
I am on fire!I am on fire!
No!No!
Thank you,
I don't know what I would have done
if I had remained on those hot coals...
...burning my pretty flesh.
You have pretty skin.
Give it to us!
Join Us!
No...No...No...No!
Hit her!
Hit it!
No!No!No...No!
You love her!No...No!
No...You love her!
Scott?
Yeah?
What is...
What are we going to do?
We're going to bury her.
You...can't bury Shelly.
She's a... she's a friend of ours, isn't she?
Ash, she's dead.
Shelly's dead.
We gotta bury her now.
Linda's still sleeping.
I think once her leg...
I'm getting out of here.
Scott, we can't take Linda anywhere
with a leg like that.
We don't even know
if there is any other way back besides the bridge.
Well, maybe there's a hiking trail
or an old road or some other way around the cliff.
I mean there's gotta be
another way besides the bridge.
Listen to me.
Linda cannot walk with a leg like that.
She can't even stand up.
Well, then we'll leave her here.
Until we can send somebody back.
- What are you, crazy?  - Look! I'm getting out!
I don't care what happens to her.
She's your girlfriend
you take care of her.
I'm getting the hell out of here. Right now!
Soon all of you will be like me.
And then who will lock you up in the cellar?
- God  - Ash!
- Oh my God!  - Help me!
Help me, Ash.
Scotty. You're going to be Ok.
You're going to be just fine. You'll see.
Ash. It's not going to let us leave.
Cheryl...Cheryl was right.
We're all going to die here!
No, we're not going to die.
We're all going to die. All of us!
No, we're not going to die!
We're not going to die!
We're gonna get out of here.
Now listen to me, Scotty.
Is there a way around the bridge?
Scotty! Listen to me, please.
For God's sake! Scott!
Ash...Ash, I don't wanna die.
You're not going to leave me ,are you Ash?
Are you?
I don't wanna die.
You're not going to leave me here are you?
Are you, Ash?
Scotty! Now c'mon listen to me for God's sake!
Is there a way around the bridge?
There's a way. The trail.
But the trees, Ash.
They know.
Don't you see, Ash? They're alive!
Shut up!
Shut up, Linda.
Kill her!
Kill her if you can, loverboy.
God! Forgive me, Linda.
Oh, Ash. Help me, please!
Ash. Help me
please...Ash.
Oh, Ash.
Please, don't let them take me away again.
- Please.  - No, I won't. I won't. I promise.
Ashley. Ashley, help me.
Let me out of here.
Ashley? Ash, help me.
Let me out of here. I'm... I'm all right now.
I'm all right now, Ashley... I'm all right.
Unlock this chain and let me out.
Cheryl?
I'm all right now, Ashley!
Come unlock the chain and let me out!
I'm all right now.
It's your sister Cheryl.
You bastards!
Why are you torturing me like this?
Why?!
Shut up!
We're going to get you.
Not another peep.
Time to go to sleep.
We're...
It's Useless!
Useless!
In time, it will come for him
and then it will come for you!
Here.
Now,the sun will be up in an hour or so
and we can all get out of here together.
You, me, Linda, Shelly.
No,No...No...
Hmm...Well...Shelly...she...
We'll all be going home together.
Wouldn't you like to be going home?
I bet you'd like that, wouldn't you?
Scott?
Join Us!
Oh, Linda.
Come to me.
The door.
The back door.
Shells. Where did I see that box of shells?
We're gonna get you!
Shut up, Linda.
- We're all gonna die.  - Shut up.
- All of us.  - Shut up!
- How sweet of you.  - ...God! Forgive me, Linda.
...is through the act of...bodily dismemberment.
Hit her.
I really love it!
I'll never take it off.
Hit it!
Oh, Come on. Come on.
Why are you torturing me like this?
Linda.
Join Us!
Oh! No, God!
AAAAAHHHHHHHH!!!!