I'm gonna make damn sure
you spend the rest
of your miserable...
Ah!
...corrupt life in prison.
You are finished,
Dwayne.
You are done!
It's my hope to convince you
why Clearwater
is the best candidate
for the first naval shipyards
to be built in our country
in decades.
You want to break ground
next month,
but people are still living
on the very site.
It's not even cleared.
PRIDE: Well, I should've
stopped Hamilton
a long time ago!
He's killed people,
and more people are gonna die
if I don't do
something right now.
Pride.
He needs to be dealt with.
WADE:
It's not Pride.
Maybe he wants everyone else
to think he's dead.
Especially Hamilton.
Just wanted to make sure
you were still
breathin', Mr. Stone.
♪ ♪
(Stone panting)
Ah...
Who are you?
I'm Mr. Stone.
Yeah.
I know that's what you
call yourself,
but I want to know who you are.
Does it matter?
You tried to kill me.
Least you can do
is tell me
your real name
before we proceed.
If you think
you're gonna scare me
into some kind of confession
with all of these theatrics,
then by all means,
let's proceed.
(grunts)
Hamilton is
gonna empty
Clearwater and build
a Navy shipyard.
And I'm gonna stop him.
Ah!
Eliza West.
Javier Garcia.
Henry Morgan.
Five FBI agents.
(laughs)
Oh, you're not going
to scare me.
Or shame me.
Even if you could,
it wouldn't change anything.
Plan's in motion.
You can't stop it now.
(groans)
You know, you got a great
opportunity here, Pride.
Everyone thinks you're dead.
You got nothing to lose.
I mean, you can be anyone,
do anything.
You're right about one thing,
Mr. Stone.
I got nothing to lose.
(Stone screams)
(splashes)
♪ NCIS:New Orleans 3x24 ♪
Poetic Justice
Original Air Date on May 16, 2017
♪ Boom, boom, boom, boom ♪
♪ Bang, bang, bang, bang ♪
♪ How, how, how, how ♪
♪ Hey, hey ♪
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
♪ You gotta come on. ♪
SONJA:
What's going on here?
I don't have a clue.
I got word from Swanson
to come down here quickly,
so I called you.
SWANSON:
Lasalle, Percy.
Oh, my God.
I was just so shocked
to hear about Pride.
I mean I... I can't believe it.
Yeah, I know.
Yeah, we can't believe it, either.
You have any idea
who did it?
It's complicated.
Well, I might be able to help.
Victim took a flyer off
a nearby roof, we think.
Been told he's a person of
interest in Dwayne's murder.
Well, we appreciate the call,
but our team was suspended.
We can't, technically, be here.
Technically,
you're not,
otherwise my ass
is on the line,
but I was asked
to reach out.
Ms. Loretta.
This is not a Coast Guard body.
Okay? We're baby-sitting.
I'd say you've got
about five minutes
before the NOPD shows up.
Make the most of it.
LASALLE:
Thank you.
What's up with the cloak
and dagger?
You tell me.
(sighs)
Stone.
Hamilton's right-hand man.
And the suspect
most likely responsible
for trying to kill Pride.
What happened?
Ligature marks on the wrists,
contusions, bruising
of the face...
He was bound, beaten and
probably tossed off a roof.
So, not suicide.
No, but I found
some evidence that--
I don't know what
to make of it.
Right here.
A fingerprint.
WADE:
It's Dwayne's.
Does Swanson know?
Only the three of us.
Good.
Let's keep it that way.
Well, look, you guys. There has
to be a good explanation for this.
Pride's been pushed
to the limit, Percy, all right?
Going after Hamilton's cost him
his job, his team.
It's a lot of bodies.
And you weren't saying this
a few days ago, Lasalle.
In fact, you were
saying the opposite.
Yeah, well,
that was before Pride
decided to play dead
and disappear.
He had his reasons.
You know that.
Look, I don't want to jump
to conclusions.
I still have to get the body
back to autopsy, but...
I wanted you
to bear witness.
Because whatever Pride did here,
no one else needs
to know about it
until you find him.
I've never seen so many
condolence gifts in my life.
The entire
kitchen's filled up.
Half the restaurants in
New Orleans sent a platter.
Yeah. King's loved
in this city.
Well, I told Roy
to take some of the food home.
He's pretty broken up, too.
I just hate having to
pretend that Pride's dead.
Yeah, well, if we want to keep
him alive and find him,
that's what we're all gonna have
to keep doing.
Well, uh, how exactly are we
supposed to find him, though?
I mean, we don't have
any badges, no resources.
In fact, none of you should
be here in the first place.
What the hell is he doing here?
I asked him to come.
Pride's off the reservation.
Hamilton's declared war.
We're all gonna lose our jobs,
or better yet,
we're gonna be reassigned
to some backwater.
We need help.
So you called the
FBI agent that tried
to break us apart
in the first place?
Seems you've been able
to accomplish that feat
all on your own.
Look, you're right.
Isler's a pain in the ass.
Hey.
What? He's ambitious
and a rule-follower,
but you know what?
He's incorruptible,
and a man of his word,
and we can trust him.
Thanks, I think.
He's our only hope
at finding Pride,
stopping Hamilton
and saving Clearwater.
I hate it,
but it kind of makes sense.
Well, thank you for your
generosity of spirit.
Now, Gregorio downloaded
me on the case.
I've got it from here.
I will find Pride.
You can all go home now.
SEBASTIAN: W-Wait. What? No way.
Yeah, we're not sitting
on the sidelines.
That's precisely what you'll do
and it's non-negotiable.
All right, let's chat.
I agreed to take the reigns
and fix what your team broke.
I did not agree to allow you
to go rogue along with Pride.
No. You're 100% right;
we should not go rogue.
But you need to get
our badges back.
Your own Deputy Director
suspended you.
How am I supposed
to change that?
'Cause you got pull.
Yes. I do.
But I'm not about to waste
it for a former agent
who decided to give up her career,
Ah.
and run away to the circus.
Are you kidding me? You're still
mad that I came to NCIS?
I spent my life trying
to figure out where I fit in,
and it was not FBI,
it was here.
And I'm not about to let
that disappear because of...
That's really beautiful,
Gregorio,
but it doesn't change
a damn thing.
I'm not finished, Raymond.
If Dwayne Pride doesn't want
to be found,
he's not gonna be found.
I don't care how many agents
you have on the case.
You're saying that I need you.
No... Okay.
What I'm saying is,
if you really want to finish
what you started here,
who better to find him than
the team he personally trained?
(sighing):
All right.
I'll make some calls
and get your badges back.
Now, the case, where are
we with finding Pride?
We know he was with Stone
last night,
Hamilton's right-hand man.
Who he threw off a roof.
We are not sure about that.
We couldn't find
Stone's cell phone.
Pride probably has it.
All right, well, I'll work
on tracking the phone.
Hoping he's on the same network
as the other operatives.
LASALLE: All right, Stone's body
is in autopsy.
Since we've been reinstated,
Percy and I will
go talk to Wade.
See if she's got
any more evidence.
How about you?
Any clue as to where
your boss may be headed?
Nope.
But I know who he's after.
You cannot go inside.
The mayor's in a locked-door
meeting all morning.
No, sorry, ma'am.
We need to talk to him now.
This can't wait.
It's gonna have to.
And you...
you need to leave.
Who the hell are you?
Captain Estes, NOPD.
I'm takin' over the
mayor's protection detail.
Okay. Well, I'm
Special Agent Gregorio
and I need to get in there.
Yeah, I know exactly
who you are.
We believe the
mayor's in danger.
Yeah, from people like her.
Shoot-out in
the French Quarter,
car running into
a crowded restaurant,
all courtesy of
Dwayne Pride and NCIS.
Whoa. He's no longer with us,
okay? Have a little respect.
- Yeah? Well, he's not the only one.
- Yeah.
I just found out that the
mayor's private security
consultant was found dead
last night.
As well as
Congresswoman Angelou.
Chairwoman of the
Armed Services Committee?
Had some kind of stroke
at the airport, so no one
is getting inside,
especially NCIS, so let's go.
No, I'm--
Get off.
I'm not NCIS.
I'm FBI Deputy Director Isler.
Now, let me explain
the situation.
Screw this.
H-hey! Stop!
Stop!
He's not here.
He came in at 7:00, never left.
We have a code red,
the mayor is missing.
I need all units
to search the building.
What's this?
Navy shipyard
the mayor wants to build
in Clearwater.
The reason so many people
have died.
Including, it seems,
the congresswoman.
Yeah, and if we don't act fast,
a lot of others could get hurt.
The entire neighborhood of
Clearwater is getting razed.
The mayor's not in the building
and his car is missing.
We're gonna activate
the GPS now.
I'm gonna need to talk to
both of you after we find him.
Stone.
Stone!
Where the hell are you, man?
I got a schedule to keep.
Stone, where you at?!
(grunts, groans)
(groans)
Douglas... really?
Dammit. Dwayne, you shot me.
You shot yourself.
You're supposed to be dead.
And you're gonna end up that way
unless you do as I say.
Get in the car.
(Hamilton groans)
Gregorio and Isler are
being interviewed by NOPD,
but they sent photos
from the scene
where Hamilton was abducted.
Shell casings, blood.
Who got shot?
Hamilton.
Whoa.
I mean, at least, according to
NOPD crime scene techs,
but I, I can't believe
that Pride did it.
We couldn't believe he threw
that guy off the roof, either.
Hey, we don't know
that he did that.
You were just with me
at autopsy, Percy.
Doc Wade said
that Stone was forcibly
thrown off that roof.
Wait, what?
What is it with you, Lasalle?
You've known that man
for over ten years.
You always have his back,
and now all of a sudden
you think he's
gone off the rails?
Yeah, I don't want to.
But if Pride's got
a breaking point,
it's Hamilton.
So let's find him.
Look, uh, Wade...
got this foreign substance
off of Stone's clothes.
Can you analyze it?
Yeah, will do.
But, uh, look, I want to show
you guys something first.
It's the tire treads from
the Hamilton crime scene.
This could be the car
that Pride took him in.
Can you get us details?
Yeah, Firestone,
deep traction.
Probably from a late model
American sedan.
I'm thinking
a silver Chrysler 300.
So you got the color of the car
off of some tire tracks?
Well, I did
when I cross-referenced
the tire treads
to surveillance
that was taken
about a block away
from Pride's bar
after it exploded.
I'm guessing that
this was Stone's car,
and then Pride took it.
Ah, ah, ah, ah.
The man is under FBI
investigation for a hot minute,
and look how he's treated.
I was gonna mention you.
Mm-hmm.
I'm glad you're back, P.
And better than ever, baby.
Hasn't been the same
without you.
Of course not.
But back to business.
I accessed the city's surveillance cameras
for this footage.
And can you find more?
I'm working on it--
but that's a lot
of city miles to cover.
Boss man could be anywhere.
Not just anywhere.
Look, we all know Pride
inside and out.
And I don't care how obsessed he
is with bringing Hamilton down,
if that man is hurt,
he's gonna try to fix him.
Yeah, especially if he's got
information he wants.
(groaning in pain)
I need a hospital,
not a Band-Aid.
I know you're pissed,
but I never meant to
draw that gun on you.
You sent Stone to kill me.
Is that what he said?
He's a liar.
Stone's dead.
Add him to the list
of people who've paid
for your Clearwater plan.
(grunts)
I don't have a plan.
(yells)
(groans)
I am revitalizing...
a blighted neighborhood.
By razing the area
for a shipyard!
(phone rings) I literally have no idea
what you're talking about.
(beeps)
Hello.
Stone, it's Johan.
Team's in place.
Operation's a go.
Three-hour countdown.
Final confirmation.
Confirmation denied.
You're not Stone.
Who's Johan?
Huh? What's the operation?
Dwayne. You know, Dwayne...
Hey.
Dwayne...
You're gonna tell me.
Dwayne,
I'm gonna bleed to death
unless you get me to a doctor.
No, no, no.
Not just yet.
(phone rings)
Hello?
Loretta...
Dw... Hey.
What's going on?
Are you alone?
No.
The police are everywhere.
Did you kidnap the mayor?
No, I wouldn't call it
kidnapping.
Yeah, I would.
Okay, listen.
You can't let anybody know
that we're talking.
Is Hamilton okay?
Hamilton is not okay.
He's got a bullet
in his upper arm.
He's bleeding fast,
even with pressure.
He needs a doctor.
No, that's why I called you.
To help me remove the bullet.
Where are you? I'll come.
Stay with me.
Dwayne, what are you doing?
I'm finishing what I started.
Requires Hamilton to survive
a little longer.
Now, tell me what to do.
Okay, uh...
you need to put pressure
on the brachial artery.
It's just below the armpit.
Should help with hemostasis.
(groaning loudly)
Yeah, it's working.
Now you need to tie off the arm.
Tight enough
to stop circulation flow.
Which could cause further trauma
if he doesn't see a doctor.
(yells, groans)
(groans)
What are you doing?
Loretta...
What are
you doing?
Loretta, you tell anybody
I was on the phone?
Absolutely not.
HAMILTON:
Stop. Oh...
(panting)
(frustrated groan)
You've got a tracking device?
Of course I've got
a tracking device.
I got maniacs like you
following me, don't I?
Loretta, tell the others...
Stone has another team
in play in Clearwater.
Something's happening
in the next three hours.
Dwayne, wait. Dway... Dwayne!
Move! Move!
You go right!
(shouting indistinctly)
Clear!
We got problems.
NOPD used a GPS chip
hidden on the mayor
to track him
to a shuttered medical clinic.
He was gone,
along with Pride.
Need to know
where they are now.
Patton searched
surveillance cameras.
Stone's car was driving
away from the clinic.
Then it went off the grid.
I assure you
we're not the only ones
with that image.
It's only a matter of time
before NOPD
figures out that Pride's alive
and has Hamilton.
Yeah, he'll be harder to find
now that he knows
he's being tracked.
ISLER: The answer's simple.
We contact Captain Estes at NOPD
and tell him everything.
Uh-uh, we do that, they'll assume Pride
kidnapped the mayor.
He'll be public enemy
number one.
He did kidnap the mayor.
Look, you're under
the impression that Pride
went off the reservation
on some holy mission
to save the city--
perhaps he just went off.
He told Wade that there were
more operatives in Clearwater.
He's still trying
to save the neighborhood.
Problem is, we're no closer
to figuring out
Hamilton's plan
to empty Clearwater.
Actually, we're a lot closer.
I just analyzed the trace found
on Stone's clothing.
It's TATB explosives.
It's highly insensitive, which
means it's easy to transport,
and it's... very powerful.
Stone blew up Pride's bar.
Not with that.
That's used to
detonate warheads.
Stone's operatives have another plan.
SEBASTIAN: Yeah, well,
they're taking something out--
something big enough
to drive the residents
out of Clearwater for good.
Yeah, Clearwater
is big-- there's no way we find
those explosives on our own.
Then we loop in Captain Estes.
No.
(phone ringing)
NOPD can't be trusted.
But I know
someone who can.
That's Estes.
I'm done with this charade.
Captain Estes, we need to talk
about Mayor Hamilton.
Isler, wait.
I'm sorry,
somebody just walked
into my office.
Just hear me out. Please.
I'm sorry, I'll
call you right back.
Pride's out there
trying to get answers
from Hamilton.
If you really want
to sort this out,
you need to give us more time.
By abetting kidnapping?
Won't just be your ass
on the line,
target'll be on my back, too.
All right,
let's just be honest--
target's been
on your back since you got here.
I know why you wanted me here.
No.
You wanted your badges back,
and you wanted me to step aside,
but that's not how I work.
I'm calling Estes.
The minute you
tell them Pride's alive,
it'll be full-court press.
NOPD doesn't give a crap
about saving Clearwater.
You will undercut everything
Pride's fought for.
(whispers):
Come on.
Help me help Pride.
Please.
I'll give you two hours
to figure out
where those explosives are.
Okay. All right, thanks.
HAMILTON:
Dwayne.
Dwayne, we got to stop.
I need help.
(groaning)
Clearwater Baptist, huh?
(sniffs)
What is this,
another metaphor for...
my "come to Jesus" moment?
You're way past repenting.
And you're way out of options.
Who's Johan?
What is the plan?
Or what?
You're not gonna kill me.
Stone said the same thing,
and look what happened to him.
Well, he deserved
whatever you did to him.
You gonna tell me
that Stone's responsible
for all this?
Using drug money
to buy property in Clearwater,
the personal attacks on
my team-- Stone's responsible?
Taking advantage
of my desire to help
a struggling area
of this city.
Bringing in
thousands of jobs.
And the only thing I'm
guilty of is caring
about this city too much.
(laughing): Even you
are not that good a liar.
Then why don't
you come in?
Come on in, then!
And you tell your version
and I'll tell mine!
And who do you think
they're gonna believe?
Some... fugitive federal agent
or the respected mayor
of New Orleans?
You got no moves left here.
I got one.
I wasn't expecting
an epiphany.
Just betting
on the only motive
that's ever mattered to you.
(groans)
Self-preservation.
What are you doing?
(yells)
I didn't bring you here
as a metaphor to Clearwater.
This is ground zero.
Whatever's
about to happen here...
will happen to you, too.
Pride is alive?
You got to be kidding me.
I sent flowers.
Yeah, it was
a very tasteful arrangement.
And you can have them back
if you want.
Uh, no. I...
We would have told you
this morning if we could.
Is this some kind of
undercover operation?
Uh, sort of, yeah.
It's-it's a little complicated.
Listen, the more we tell you,
the more compromised you'll be.
The situation's
not exactly kosher.
Well, give me
the Reader's Digest.
Okay. Well,
we think Mayor Hamilton
has a team of operatives
planting an explosive device
in Clearwater.
Yeah, and I've been working on
a list of potential targets.
There is a chemical plant,
sewage treatment facility,
electrical grid station,
or it could be
a population center,
like a grocery store
or a school.
In other words,
we don't know jack.
Which is why I'm here--
you need Coast Guard tech.
You've got that FLIR camera
that can detect heat signatures.
Yeah, but it's got to be
hush-hush.
Because it's not exactly kosher.
And we got to move fast.
Well, I'll get the bird in
the air and boots on the ground.
You coming?
Yeah, I'll go.
Listen, I'm gonna stick around.
Try and locate Pride
and Hamilton before anyone else.
You got it.
(sighs)
MAN (over radio):
CGIS and NCIS ground, 6592,
overhead Clearwater, beginning
Sierra Sierra search pattern.
SWANSON:
Copy that. We are in transit.
MAN:
Wait a minute.
The FLIR camera's picking up
an abnormal heat signature
It's from a power
and water truck
parked off Adelaide and Fulton.
SWANSON:
We're on it.
(siren chirps)
SONJA: NCIS!
SONJA:
We got a runner!
NCIS! Stop!
(gunshot)
We got a body.
Some kind of security guard.
Explosives.
But I'm guessing there was
a lot more back here.
SEBASTIAN:
Guys, we got another problem.
That suspect just
sent out a Stuxnet worm.
None of us knows
what that is.
I-It's a malicious virus.
It infects programmable
logic controllers.
Uh, overrides
mechanical processes.
It was specifically designed
to take out
industrial computer systems.
All right, what's it targeting?
They just infected
the Industrial Canal.
(alarm blaring)
PILOT: CG 6592, we have a visual
on the south lock.
Gates are opening.
Water's rushing into the canal.
(alarm wailing)
Dwayne.
Dwayne, you hear that, right?
Flood warning sirens.
Don't change the subject.
Need to start talking.
But, uh...
we should leave.
Those sirens go off
twice a week in the spring.
Usually a drill.
Uh...
better safe than sorry,
though, right?
You nervous?
Nervous?
Well, I'm bleeding to death,
being held hostage
by a rogue federal agent, so...
And yet this is
the first time I've actually
seen you scared.
You're not gonna
push these people out.
You're gonna wash 'em out.
You're flooding Clearwater.
That's-that's...
ridiculous.
Devastate the area.
Relocate the residents.
Build your shipyard.
Look, if I say yes,
will you uncuff me?
You found a way
to make the river rise.
And yet
that's not enough.
After Katrina, they
strengthened the floodgates.
Few extra feet of
water wouldn't...
Dwayne, seriously...
we got to go!
You're taking out
the floodgates.
Where you going?
I'm gonna stop what you started
once and for all.
But if we get flooded here
I'll be under
nine feet of water!
Better hope I save the day.
Ah... aah!
Stone's operatives were able to
hack into city infrastructure.
Disable the lock systems across
the whole Industrial Canal.
That means water's
flowing freely
from the river
to Lake Pontchartrain.
Yeah, if one of those levees
breaches, then the water
would change course and
start flooding Clearwater.
That's what the explosives
are for:
to take out a levee,
then take out Clearwater.
Can you reverse the hack?
I mean, maybe with
Patton's help.
Get to it.
And based on the evidence
in the truck
there are more
suspects with explosives.
And the body of a security guard
who works riverside access.
Suspects are somewhere
on the water. Probably rigging
a levee.
But which one?
SWANSON:
We have patrols
sweeping the waterways.
It's a lot of miles to cover.
And there's no guarantee we find
the right levee before it blows.
Evacuating Clearwater just in
case, but it's gonna be tough.
We have to go house
to house to make sure
that people leave,
and we have no manpower here.
I'll get you
those reinforcements.
Find me those suspects.
King was part
of river rescue
for the first week
of Katrina.
Investigated levee
breaches afterward.
He has to have an idea which
levee's most vulnerable.
Oh, so you don't think
he's gone crazy anymore?
I never thought
he was crazy, Percy.
He has every right
to take Hamilton out.
I just hope he chooses
not to cross the line.
Let's head to the river and
see if we can't retrace
the truck's movements.
(indistinct
police radio chatter)
(tires screech,
siren starts wailing)
Oh, damn it.
Dispatch, this is unit 49.
I've got a visual
on a late-model sedan wanted
in connection with
the mayor's abduction.
DISPATCH: 10-4, 49. Any
available 6th district unit,
49 has a vehicle
matching the descript
of the mayor's abductors
in the 2500 block of Felicity,
turning onto Terpsichore.
That's got to be Pride.
NOPD just spotted him coming out
of Clearwater a minute ago.
No sign of the mayor.
How'd you get this feed?
Never mind. Don't answer.
The bigger issue
is NOPD's onto Pride.
And they're bringing in
the cavalry as we speak.
(indistinct radio chatter)
Driver, turn off the ignition.
Hands out the window.
You're surrounded.
Comply with our
instructions
or we will shoot.
What the hell is he doing?
He's heading to the river.
He must know about the levees.
That's a reach, Gregorio.
He's desperate.
We need to help him.
Seriously.
If we don't do something,
we're gonna watch him die
on that street.
Isler.
I know, Gregorio.
I know.
Let me think.
He's reaching for something.
I've got a clean shot.
Standing by for your go.
Hold this.
Who am I speaking with?
This is Deputy Director Isler.
You need to listen
very carefully to me.
If you and your men
don't stand down this moment,
all of our careers
will be over by tonight.
Dwayne Pride is in that car
and he's working
undercover for me.
All right.
We're standing down.
(sighs)
Thank you.
I truly hope we got this right.
(computer chirps)
I just got a text.
So did I.
It's from an unknown number.
All it says is
"Florida Street Levee."
Yeah, that's Pride.
It must be what the
operatives are sabotaging.
We need to call
Lasalle and Sonja now.
(birds squawking)
(indistinct conversation)
♪ ♪
(gunshots)
(gasping)
(birds squawking)
We've been exposed!
Set the
detonator now!
LASALLE:
We're on Florida Street.
We found Stone's car,
but no sign of Pride.
He's got to be somewhere there,
along with the rest
of Stone's men.
Yeah, we're gonna sweep the area.
All right, well, you better
hurry up,
because those explosives
could go off at any moment.
It would help if you could
close the locks,
keep the water from rising.
SEBASTIAN: Yeah, well,
easier said than done.
This is gonna take time.
So, in other words,
we're screwed right now.
Ball's in your court, Lasalle.
(gunshots)
Automatic gunfire
coming from up there.
LASALLE:
Let's move!
(gunshots continue)
(gasps)
(bullets ricocheting)
NCIS!
(gasps)
King! You're good!
♪ ♪
NCIS!
Drop your weapon!
(gunshots)
(gunshots in distance)
I got him!
Lasalle!
Don't shoot!
He's got the detonator!
(grunting)
Drop the knife!
(gunshot)
Percy.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm okay.
Really? 'Cause, uh,
you kinda got your ass kicked.
But I also got the detonator.
What'd you get?
Where's Pride?
Didn't think I'd forget
about you, did you?
What more
could you possibly want?!
(keys jangle)
Nothin'.
Clearwater is safe.
Your dream
of a Navy shipyard is finished.
(groaning)
No more innocent people
are gonna get hurt.
Now it's just...
time to settle up.
So, what,
you're gonna kill me?
And your reward,
ten years in prison
for assaulting
and abducting the mayor.
Life-- you pull
that trigger.
Unless we make a deal.
I don't think so.
You tried to...
kill me with this gun.
And that's the least
of your crimes.
Spent your entire career
hurting people
for your own personal gain.
And that ends today.
Just, please, listen to me.
Please.
I'd be within my rights
to take you out,
to kill you.
For everything
you've done to me,
my team, my city.
Our city.
'Cause no matter
what you think of me,
we both love New Orleans!
Did I make a deal with Stone
and his employers
to bring that shipyard here?
Yes, I did. I did.
For the good of the city!
(sniffles)
And mistakes were made!
And I regret that.
And people did die.
But only because I knew that
we could do something great!
You have no right to judge me!
I'm not gonna judge you,
Douglas.
Gonna let
the justice system do that.
Douglas Hamilton,
you are under arrest.
(indistinct police transmission)
Look at me. Look at me.
Look what he did to me.
He shot me, huh? He abducted me.
He threatened me.
I'm gonna press full charges.
Shut up, Mr. Mayor.
It's not over! It's not over!
Deputy Director,
I didn't realize
that you were in town.
I take it I have you to thank
for getting my team back
in the field.
And so much more.
We owe him big-time.
Hey, do me a favor,
don't do me any favors.
Lose my phone number.
How'd you track me down?
A little profiling.
Figured you'd take
Hamilton to the source,
make him face
everything he's done.
You know me well,
for a newbie.
Not that well.
I was wondering whether
you'd pull that trigger.
Crossed my mind.
What about Stone?
Do I really want to know
what went down on that roof?
He had a knife.
Was that before or after
you took his cuffs off?
Either way, you need
to get that checked out.
I will.
Right now,
I just need to sit.
You just bagged
the grand prize.
What's next?
Honestly...
I have no idea.
Says Isler ran a highly
classified undercover operation
to take down
Mayor Hamilton
in a conspiracy of
corruption and murder.
And not one
mention of us.
That's okay. 'Cause we took down
the mayor, saved Clearwater,
and got our team back.
- Let Isler have the credit.
- Huh?
You were investigating us a few
months ago, and now look at you.
Part of the family.
Well, I take family
very serious.
Well, so do I.
And we got to get going
if we're gonna get
this thing started.
Patton and Wade are
already on their way. Come on.
(quietly):
Hey.
Can we talk for a second?
Sure.
Yeah, it's just...
with all the craziness lately,
I never really got
the chance to thank you.
You really put yourself on the
line for me when I went to jail,
and you kept me safe.
You even got the judge
to let me out.
You would've done
the same for me.
No, no, no.
What I want to say is,
I appreciate it.
Your support means
more than I can say.
You know, before you do whatever
it is you're about to do,
just hear me out,
all right?
This thing
between us...
Ooh, who says that
there's a thing?
Well, I don't know.
Maybe it's nothin', but...
Yeah, it can't
really happen.
We just barely kept the team
from falling apart.
Yeah, I mean, we don't
need our personal stuff
getting in the way of that.
Yeah, we're a family.
All right? We need
to protect that.
For the good
of the team.
Yeah.
Okay.
(exhales)
(plays notes)
(chuckles)
(crackling)
(Bruce Springsteen's
"My City of Ruins" begins)
♪ There's a blood red circle ♪
♪ On the cold dark ground ♪
♪ And the rain is falling down ♪
♪ The church door's
thrown open ♪
♪ I can hear the organ's song ♪
♪ But the congregation's
gone... ♪
WADE: ...still a mess everywhere.
(indistinct chatter)
SONJA: Really good luck.
SEBASTIAN: ...piece of glass
I stepped on, so...
♪ My city of ruins... ♪
What are you guys doing here?
Hey, you know,
we got supplies, beer, food.
Yeah, respirators, too.
'Cause, honestly,
this place right now,
super toxic.
That's a lot
for the seven of us.
It's not just us.
I'm not really
in the mood for a...
for a party.
WADE: Well, that's good.
It's not a party.
It's a renovation.
We're gonna put your
bar back in shape.
Yeah, and a lot
more people's comin', too.
So sound like we have
to make another beer run.
I don't...
I don't know what to say. I...
Don't say anything, King.
You did everything
for this city.
They're gonna give you
a little something.
♪ Pray for the faithful... ♪
Hey. That's not all.
Oh, right.
It's a little worse for wear,
but I was able to clean it up.
I figured you gave me my badge.
I could at least give you yours.
♪ Come on, rise up ♪
♪ Come on,
rise up ♪
♪ Come on, rise up... ♪
Thank you.
♪ Come on, rise up ♪
♪ Come on,
rise up... ♪
All of you.
GREGORIO:
Hey,
we're a family.
It's what we do.
♪ Come on, rise up... ♪
All right, let's get
this show on the road.
Yeah.
Get this bar back up.
♪ Rise up ♪
♪ Come on, rise up ♪
♪ Come on,
rise up ♪
♪ Come on, rise up. ♪
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man