I'm sorry.
Alpha, I'm the last one left.
We must stop her!
Send the meteor to my coordinates.
Seek only those who are worthy.
Find only those who are strong.
With the Zeo Crystal,
we could have rulled the universe together.
That was never going to happen.
And because of that you will die, Zordon.
We will die together, Rita.
Where are we, Alpha?
I'm glad to hear your voice, Zordon!
I can see you, Alpha.
But I cannot see myself.
Where I'm I?
You are inside of the ship.
Everything is fine.
I saved your mind in to the machine.
Is the spaceship working?
The power coins have finally returned to the ship.
Where are the coins?
Where are the Rangers?
They speak in a foreign language called english.
You will find more about it
on the machines matrix core.
Yesterday you came home very late.
Take it easy, mom.
Lay down and rest.
I'm glad you here.
Are you going to school?
I want an awsner.
Make sure you take them.
They were five. They were warriors.
They saved Angel Grove.
Five warriors?
Were they good looking?