Shit!
Crazy-drivin' motherfucker.
-Shit.
-Come on.
Marvin, what are you doin'?
-He's mine. Get lost.
-He's yours? He's mine.
Eddie assigned him to me.
Then go talk to Eddie.
l'll collect the money.
l almost got killed tryin' to get this guy.
He shot at me--
Back off, goddamn it!
l said l'm takin' him, all right?
-All right, Marvin.
-This guy's worth $1,200!
Marvin. What are we fightin' for?
We're friends--
Nothin' personal, Jack, but fuck off!
Take it easy. Jesus!
Marvin, watch out!
What the fuck's goin' on?
You guys ain't cops.
No, we're ballet dancers.
Didn't your mother teach you
how to react to strangers?
Not shoot at them?
Thanks for the car.
You sleep,
and l'll bring it back a little later.
Got a delivery for you, Gooch.
Jack. The soda machine's been out
for a week and a half.
Check that for me.
What do we got here?
-Give you any trouble?
-Did you give me any trouble?
-Fuck you!
-He didn't give me any trouble.
Fuck you, too, man!
-Move!
-l know my motherfuckin' rights!
Slap it.
Moscone's Bail Bonds.
No, it's cash only. No checks, no cards.
l'm sorry, ma'am. That's the policy.
l wish l could help you out. Sorry.
Just dropped off Bouchet. ls Eddie in?
So you finally caught someone, Jack.
Jerry, is he in?
l think that's terrific.
l been tryin' to reach you.
What do you got for me?
Been tryin' to reach me? lt's Bouchet.
-Bouchet. Good. $900, right?
-No, it's $1,200.
No, $900.
That's $1,200. Come on.
No. Yeah, you're right.
My stomach's killin' me. l'm goin'
to Chin Loo's. l want to talk to you.
About what?
-l'll talk to you over there.
-Could l have my money first?
Of course.
Do you think l'm gonna stiff you?
You? Never!
He would never try and stiff me.
-Do l detect some sarcasm here?
-Never.
Where have l inherited this reputation?
l have never done business with anybody,
and Jerry is my witness...
...that l have ever, ever....
Has that phone ever rang
with a complaint about me?
Never. So let's go.
l'll buy you some breakfast.
-l don't eat breakfast.
-Then have an early lunch.
You ever hear of a guy named Mardukas?
-The Duke. l know who he is.
-What do you know?
He's an accountant that embezzled millions
from a Vegas guy and gave it to charity.
Only thing is, that it wasn't a couple
of million. lt was $15 million.
lt wasn't some Vegas wise guy.
lt was Jimmy Serrano.
l know. l can read the papers.
l don't want to bring up the past, but...
...isn't Serrano the guy who ran you out
of Chicago when he was runnin' things?
He didn't run me out.
Right. You gave up bein' a cop
to do this shit?
-What's the point?
-The point, Jack:
l bailed out the accountant.
l didn't know who he was at the time.
Had l known,
no way l would've put up the bond.
lt's only a matter of time
before Serrano makes this guy vanish...
...and l'm out $450,000.
You're out $450,000 on this guy?
-No.
Because l got you, and you're the best,
and you're gonna find him.
How do you even know this guy is alive?
Because this guy is crazy.
He sends postcards to Serrano.
He's tellin' him what a great time
he's havin' with his money.
How much time you got left?
Friday at midnight l default.
l eat the $450,000.
This Friday? That's five days.
-Forget it. Give me my money.
-Listen to me.
l'll give you.... l'll give you $50,000.
$50,000? l gotta chase you down
for $1,200. Forget it.
-No, please.
-Forget about it. What else you got?
l ain't got nothin'. lf you don't find
this guy, l'm out of business.
l'll do it for a $100,000.
$100,000? Are you out of your mind?
This is an easy gig. lt's a midnight run.
lf you haven't noticed,
l'm tired of gettin' shot at.
l'm tired of this miserable business,
every lowlife that l run into.
lf you're gonna pay me,
you gotta pay me right.
You want me for this job,
give me what's right.
First of all, the guy is an accountant.
He's not gonna shoot you.
All you have to do is find him.
You put him in a bag, bring him home.
That's easy for you to say.
lt's $100,000, no more, no less,
and l want a contract.
-Contract?
-That's right, and l want it in writing.
$100,000, and l'll have the Duke for you
by Friday.
Now, can l have my $1,200, please?
Man, you do worse than any crook
l ever put a bond up for.
Stanley.
Big Dog. How are you?
What are you doin' here?
Listen, l need a favor.
l need to see the booking slip
of a Jonathan Mardukas. M-A-R-D-U-K-A-S.
-Yes, sir.
-What's that?
The number he called
right after he was arrested.
212 area code.
Looks like l'm goin' to New York.
Are you Jack Walsh?
-Excuse me.
-Are you Jack Walsh?
Do l know you?
Alonzo Mosely, FBl.
That's a nice badge.
How can l get one of those?
-l want to talk to you.
-Why don't you call my social secretary?
You're very funny. l want to talk to you.
Take your hands off me!
Take it easy!
-You know it's a $10 fine for jaywalking--
-Shut up.
What l want to know is...
...are you working on anything
having to do with Mardukas?
Never heard of him.
l believe you have heard of him.
Let me tell you something, asshole.
We've been working on this
Jimmy Serrano thing for about six years.
Mardukas is my shot.
l'm gonna bring him into federal court...
...and l don't want any rent-a-thug
who couldn't cut it as a cop in Chicago...
...bringing him to LA
on some bullshit local charge.
Do l make myself understood?
Can l ask you something?
These sunglasses, they're really nice.
Are they government issued or do
you all go to the same store to get them?
Do l make myself understood?
Can't you take a joke?
Get him out of here.
No, let's talk some more.
-Get out of here.
-lf l hear anything, l'll tell you.
Good-bye. Have a nice day.
-Think l could have my sunglasses back?
-Here's your sunglasses.
Thanks. Thanks for this, too.
''Alonzo Mosely.''
How's that?
Looks fine to me.
Harold Longman, please.
Harry? Jack Walsh. How're you doin'?
You got that address check
on that phone number for me?
Thanks a lot, Harry.
Say hello to Julie for me. 'Bye.
You Jack Walsh?
-Who wants to know?
-Answer, ''Yes.''
We'd like to have a word with you.
-Yeah? What about?
-lt involves big cash, lot of prizes.
l'll make it short and sweet.
The people l work for are really interested
in your visit.
Who are the people you work for?
A friend of yours from the Chicago days.
You're here for the Duke. You think
he's in New York. We think you're right.
That's a nice jacket. What is it, goatskin?
Come on, Joey, please. Will you?
Never mind him.
The way l hear it...
...you didn't cooperate
with my boss a few years ago.
-ls that the way you heard it?
-But l got a news flash for you.
He'd pay a lot more for the Duke
than that bail bondsman.
-How much more?
-How about a one with six zeroes?
Are you gonna propose?
-Propose?
-Propose.
-'Cause if you're not, quit starin' at me.
-Starin' at you?
-You're staring at me.
-Joey, back off.
Mr. Walsh, your car's located
in space number 206.
You can catch our shuttle bus
just through these doors.
Here's my number, Jack.
Ask for Tony Darvo. That's me.
They'll put you through to wherever l am.
And be good to yourself this time. Okay?
Tell Jimmy l said hello.
-Hello?
-Hello? Mrs. Nelson?
Alonzo Mosely, Federal Bureau
of lnvestigation. How are you?
l'm fine.
Let me get right to the point, Mrs. Nelson.
An agent in LA discovered a detail
that was somehow overlooked until now.
lt seems that when Mardukas
was arrested...
...you were the first person he called.
ls that correct, Mrs. Nelson?
-Are you there, Mrs. Nelson?
-Yes.
This is a matter of great concern to us.
We'd like you to come down
tomorrow morning to 26 Federal Plaza.
Do you think you could do that?
-l suppose so.
-About 9:00 a.m.?
-Yes.
-Just ask for Agent Alonzo Mosely.
Thanks for your cooperation.
Have a nice day.
-Hello?
-Dana? lt's Helen.
The FBl called.
They want to speak to me about Jonathan.
-Oh, my God! Helen.
-Helen, what's going on?
The FBljust called. They know
we spoke the night you were arrested.
Hang up the phone, Helen. Right now.
Sweet music.
-What is it?
-l don't know.
Okay. Heidi.
Alonzo Mosely, FBl! You're under arrest!
Get this dog out of here!
Not you. You stay there.
Get the dog, ma'am.
-Do it.
-Get the dog!
Heidi. Come on, girl.
Don't move,
or l'll shoot you through the glass.
Get over here.
Put your hands up against the wall.
Spread your feet.
Relax. There won't be a problem.
Put your left hand behind your head.
You're taking me to the airport?
You don't look like an FBl agent to me.
Yeah? You don't look like a duke to me.
lf you're an FBl agent,
why don't you take me to the FBl office?
lf you don't be quiet, this is going
to be the worst trip of your life.
You work for Jimmy Serrano?
l don't work for that him.
Your bondsman hired me to bring you
back to LA, and that's what l'm doing.
-l got money.
-l'm sure you do.
-l'll give you whatever you want.
-Start by shutting up.
l've known you two minutes,
and already l don't like you.
That's too bad. l really like you.
l can't keep you cuffed
on a commercial flight.
l gotta check my gun with my luggage.
You fuck with me once,
l'll break your neck.
-l can't fly.
-What?
-You heard me. l can't fly.
-You'll have to do better than that.
l don't have to do better, 'cause it's
the truth. l suffer from aerophobia.
What does that mean?
lt means l can't fly. l also suffer
from acrophobia and claustrophobia.
l'll tell you what. lf you don't cooperate,
you'll suffer from ''fistophobia.''
Moscone's Bail Bonds.
Jerry, put Eddie on the phone.
Jack, what's the progress?
-l got him.
-You got who?
The Duke. He's right here.
You got him? Already?
Sure do. Want to say hello?
Say hello to your bail bondsman,
Eddie Moscone.
Hello.
There you go.
Jonathan Mardukas in the flesh.
Jack, l love you!
What happened? Where'd you find him?
l found him in New York.
We're at the airport.
This is wonderful news!
l'll be in your office by midnight
and l'm tellin' you...
...l want the money tonight.
Go empty out
one of your Swiss bank accounts.
You don't have to worry.
This is the best money l've ever spent.
-Okay. See you in a few hours.
-All right. l'll see you later. 'Night.
-So what's that all about?
-Jerry Walsh got the Duke!
-Walsh got the Duke?
-He got him! He got the Duke!
No kiddin'? This calls for a celebration.
l'll get some donuts.
How do you think Walsh found him so fast?
Tony, this is Jerry.
-Jerry who?
-Jerry Geisler.
-What are you doing?
-Eating dinner. What do you want?
Look, l hate to bother you
but l thought you'd like to know...
...that Walsh found the Duke in New York.
They're flyin' in tonight.
They should arrive around midnight.
-Don't forget me, babe.
-Yeah, kid.
Thanks. Good night.
Looks like your old friend
found the accountant.
They'll be flying into LA around midnight.
Have them met at the airport.
-You understand?
-Done.
-Can l take your coat?
-That's fine. Thanks.
-May l take your coat?
-No.
First class is nice.
l could make a habit out of this.
-Good evening, gentlemen.
-Good evening to you.
Would either of you like a drink?
Yes, we would like
one of your finest champagnes.
Certainly.
Let's see. Look at this.
Only in America. What a country.
Unbelievable.
l think l'm gonna have the steak.
How about you?
l'm not hungry.
Why don't you get the lobster,
because then l'll get a little surf and turf'.
l got a problem.
l can't fly. You're not takin' me seriously.
-l'm takin' you very seriously.
-l can't be on this plane.
You think l haven't heard this before?
Who do you think you're traveling with?
A novice?
Know what l'm talkin' about?
That's it. Settle in. lf you want to get up
and mingle with the other passengers...
...be my guest. You ain't goin' nowhere.
There's a couple
of nice-lookin' people here.
Better class of people.
Your class. Probably all embezzlers, too.
''Come fly with me, come fly away''
Why don't you just try and relax?
Just calm down.
Just relax and calm down.
-What are you gettin' so excited about?
-lt's not--
No! l can't! l can't.
Just relax! What did l tell you?
-Now, don't pull that shit on me--
-No. l'm tellin' you, l can't do it.
-These things go down!
-All right.
lt's too big! lt can't go up!
All right, everyone. Just calm down.
-What's the problem?
-lt's nothing, sir. lt's okay.
Alonzo Mosely, FBl. He's in my custody.
l'm taking him to LA.
-There won't be any more problems.
-l don't want to fly. l can't.
You can't make a prisoner fly
if he doesn't want to. You should know.
l do. l'm sorry. l thought he was bluffing.
l suggest you find some other mode
of transportation.
-What the fuck are you smilin' about?
-l love to travel by train.
Yeah? What do you think this is,
a class trip?
Are you always this angry?
Look. Right now l'm in a great mood.
Wait till l'm cooped up on that thing
and you won't be smilin'.
You'll be runnin' for that jail cell.
Still gonna make your schedule?
l'll make it, 14 hours to spare.
Nice. lt's a double.
-There'll be a lot of room.
-Glad you like it.
Thanks, 'Cause they're starting
to cut into my wrists. Thank you.
lt just gets the skin after a while.
-Get in there.
-What do you want? What?
Come on.
-Why would you do that?
-You'll enjoy yourself.
This is my room, and that's your room.
Good night.
-Can l help you guys?
-Special Agent Mosely, FBl.
-Mosely? Are all you guys named Mosely?
-What the hell are you talking about?
-You're here to pick up a prisoner, right?
-How did you know that?
He was afraid to fly,
so he got off the plane.
He left with an Agent Mosely.
Sir, that must mean that Walsh
has your identification.
Yeah?
ls this Moron Number 1?
Put Moron Number 2 on the phone.
Yeah, Jimmy. He's, right here. Hold on.
He's pissed.
You told me this guy
would be on the plane.
That's the information we got.
''That's the information we got.''
l want this guy taken out,
and taken out fast.
You two better start getting more involved
in your work...
...or l'll stab you in the heart with a pencil.
You understand?
You got it.
He ain't mad at me, is he?
Jack, l think this is illegal.
Jack, l don't think you can keep a person
in a bathroom like this.
-lt's very claustrophobic in here--
-Yeah, it is?
When we get to LA, you can tell
the prison psychiatrist about it.
There's no air.
There's no ventilation in here.
l told you l was claustrophobic. Come on.
What do you think l'm gonna do?
Jump off a train moving 90 miles an hour?
Good. Thanks.
Thanks a lot.
-Sit down.
-Yeah, that's great. Very kind of you.
Nice, much better. Thank you. Good.
What are you doing?
What am l doin'?
-Arithmetic.
-Arithmetic?
Maybe l can help you. l am an accountant.
You know what l was thinkin',
after l turn you in and collect my money...
...l'm gonna open a nice little coffee shop.
How much exactly are you getting for me,
if l may ask?
l don't think that's any of your concern,
but l'll tell you just to tell you.
-$100,000.
-$100,000?
Does that mean you'd take $100,000
to let me go?
Not by a long shot.
$200,000?
l never took a payoff in my life,
and l won't start with someone like you.
-Why not?
-Because you're a criminal.
You deserve to go where you're goin',
and l'm gonna take you there.
lf l hear any more shit from you...
...l'll bust your head,
l'll put you back in that hole...
...l'll stick your head in the toilet bowl
and make it stay there.
l have to tell you,
a restaurant is a very tricky investment.
More than half of them go under
within the first six months.
lf l were your accountant,
l'd have to advise you against it.
You would? You're not my accountant.
lf l were your accountant--
l told you, l took you out here--
No, l'm just saying that
it's a very tricky business and...
...if l were your accountant, l'd really have
to advise you against it, as an accountant.
-You're not my accountant.
-l realize l'm not your accountant.
l'm just saying if l were your accountant.
How the hell could he miss the plane?
He called from the airport!
All right. Time to bring in Marvin.
Call him up. He's in Pittsburgh.
-Marvin Dorfler?
-Yeah, Dorfler.
Under ''D'' in the Rolodex for ''jerk,'' Jerry.
Can l at least have some french fries?
l said no, pecker breath. Now shut up.
Dorfler.
Marvin? Sweetheart, am l glad l got you!
-Boy, do l have ajob for you!
-Yeah? l'm listening.
l gotta apologize,
because we were trying to find you...
...and it's an important job,
but l couldn't find you.
l had to give it to Walsh, but now...
...he's fucking it up--
Why do you keep hiring that guy?
l know. l apologize. You are the best
at what you do. You know that?
Do you know who Mardukas is?
-No.
-Jonathan Mardukas, the Duke?
-l never heard of him.
-That's not important.
What's important is that you find him
and bring him back.
Last l heard, he had him in New York,
and now l don't know where they are.
lfyou find him,
l'll give you what l'm givin' Walsh.
What's that?
$25,000.
You gotta have him back by Friday,
midnight, or the deal's off.
Don't worry, Eddie. For $25,000,
l'll bring him in on a silver platter.
Bring him any way you want,
but bring him.
Hey, scumbag.
My name's Carmine, fucko.
Carmine, today's your lucky day.
-Why is today my lucky day?
-Shut up!
Yeah, my name is Jack Walsh.
Excuse me. John Wesley Walsh.
Yeah, l think l lost my credit card.
Can you tell me the last place l used it?
Yeah, 731-483-9521-13.
The Amtrak office, Grand Central Station?
Yeah. l remember that now.
Okay. Thanks very much.
Maybe we ought to cancel that card?
Yeah. Thank you.
Familiar with the word ''arteriosclerosis''?
''Cholesterol''?
lf you want, l'll outline
a complete balanced diet for you.
Mail it to me from C-Block.
Why would you eat that?
Why? 'Cause it tastes good.
-But it's not good for you.
-l'm aware of that.
Why would you do something,
if you know it's not good for you?
Because l don't think about it.
That's living in denial.
-Living in denial?
-Yeah.
l'm aware of that.
You're aware of your behavior
yet you continue to do things...
...that aren't good for you.
That sounds sort of foolish.
Don't you think so?
No. Stealing $15 million
from Jimmy Serrano sounds foolish.
l didn't think l'd get caught.
Now, that's livin' in denial.
l'm aware of that.
You're aware of your behavior...
...and yet you continue to do things
that aren't good for you.
Sounds foolish to me. Don't you think?
lt was foolish.
But taking $15 million in mob money
and giving it to charity...
...was good for a lot of people.
You pissed off a Mafioso killer
to be loved by a bunch of fuckin' strangers.
That makes a lot of sense.
Don't you want to be loved?
Lots of people love me.
Really?
Who?
l got an ex-wife,
and l got a daughter in Chicago.
How do they put up with all your sarcasm?
Beautifully. l haven't seen either of them
in nine years.
Think maybe we should go see them?
No, l don't think maybe we should go
see them. Thanks for the interest, though.
The job must have been tough on them.
-l didn't do this then.
-What did you do?
-l was a cop.
-You were a cop in Chicago?
Then you must know
all about Jimmy Serrano.
Do you have the right
to ask these questions?
-l think l do.
-No, you don't.
Why not?
Dinner 's over. Let's go.
l can see this is gonna be some fuckin' trip.
l wouldn't worry about it.
l won't be with you much longer.
What do you mean?
With what l know about Serrano,
if l go to jail l'll be dead within 24 hours.
So sooner or later,
l'm gonna have to give you the slip.
Glad you find it humorous.
-Let's go.
-$2? That's all you're gonna leave?
-That's 15 percent.
-That's 13 percent.
These people depend on tips for a living.
Can l help you, sir?
Yeah, l'm lookin' for a buddy of mine,
Jack Walsh.
He told me he'd meet me on this train.
Yeah, Mr. Walsh.
He's in Bedroom D, next car.
-That next car?
-Yes, sir. That way.
-Thanks.
-Sure thing. Have a good night.
One word and you're dead, asshole.
-How did you find out where l am?
-l ain't tellin' you shit!
You'll force me to do something
l don't want to!
-What's going on?
-Everything's under control.
Take it easy. Alonzo Mosely, FBl.
Radio ahead. l want the police
at the next stop to place him under arrest.
-What are you talkin' about?
-That's enough!
Get on the horn and call the cops.
ls this good news or bad news?
Mardukas and Walsh
are on the Amtrak headed to Los Angeles.
Another bounty hunter was arrested
after he tried to take Mardukas away.
l want the jet ready in 20 minutes.
-Where's Jack Walsh?
-He got off with the other guy...
...two or three stops ago.
His real name's Mosely.
l'm Mosely!
l want to make a collect call
to Eddie Moscone from Jack Walsh.
-Moscone's Bail Bonds.
-Jerry, it's Jack. Put Eddie on.
-Jesus, Jack! Where have you been?
-Jack, l want to talk to him.
Where are you?
l want to ask you something.
How come Dorfler wound up on my ass?
Did you put him on this?
Dorfler? How could l put Dorfler on you?
-l don't know where you are.
-You had nothin' to do with it?
Where are you? You got the Duke?
-You're damn right l got him.
-Where are you?
Where am l? l'm somewhere
between Toledo and Cleveland.
-We're gettin' on a bus.
-Bingo.
Bus? What, are you out of your mind?
Shut up for a minute.
We're gettin' on a bus.
ljust wanted to let you know
we're on our way.
Don't hang up!
Shit! What the hell is this guy doin'?
l don't know.
Maybe l ought to get some donuts?
Two one-way tickets
to Los Angeles, please.
Still gonna make our schedule?
Don't worry. l'll get you there on time.
Don't have any illusions.
-lllusions?
-lllusions.
l'm sorry, sir. This card's been cancelled.
Has it been cancelled?
That's a mistake.
Would you please try it again?
-l checked it twice, sir.
-Please try it again.
-Did you pay the bill?
-Shut up.
l'm sorry, sir. lt's been cancelled.
That's impossible. l pay my bills.
lt could not be cancelled.
-lt's been cancelled.
-Shut up!
lt's cancelled, sir.
-Would you like to try another card?
-l don't have another card.
-Or cash.
-Would you just try that again?
-No.
-All right.
Alonzo.... Jack Walsh.
Federal Bureau of lnvestigation.
This is an official business.
This man is in my custody.
l'm taking him to Los Angeles.
So please try this once more.
Jack Walsh is not the name
on that badge, sir.
Would you like me to call the FBl?
Or would you like to pay cash?
-How much is it?
-$264 for two tickets.
$264.
Here's $100.
-Got any money on you?
-A lot.
You call that a lot of money?
lt's enough to get you
where l'm gonna get you.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven.
Got the whole fuckin' force after me.
Who the fuck are you?
Special Agent Mosely, FBl.
Goddamn it! l didn't do anything.
Relax. Just want to ask you
a few questions.
Yeah. Fucking A. Help yourself.
So, what do you know about Jack Walsh?
No. Come on. Cigarettes are killers.
So are women.
Not the right woman. My wife
and l have a wonderful relationship.
She's stuck it out with me.
Stuck it out with you and all your millions.
What a trooper.
l don't have millions, Jack.
l gave it all to charity, remember?
You didn't keep just a little for yourself?
l kept enough to get away and stay hidden.
We change buses in Chicago.
You're gonna have a couple hours.
l think you'd be a better man
if you looked up your ex-wife and daughter.
-lt's a perfect opportunity.
-Why don't you mind your own business?
Why is it you haven't seen them
in nine years?
-Why?
-Yeah.
l'll tell you why.
She married a police lieutenant...
...and l'm not popular
with the Chicago Police.
-Why aren't you popular with them?
-That's a whole other....
Do we know each other?
-Why?
What did you do?
Why aren't you popular
with the Chicago Police?
That's something that doesn't concern you.
-Did she hurt you, Jack?
-Yeah.
-l'm sorry.
-What are you sorry about?
-l'm sorry you're hurt.
-l'm not hurt.
-You said you were hurt.
-l didn't say it. You said it.
l asked you and you said, ''Yeah, l'm hurt.''
You made me say it.
You're startin' to put words in my mouth.
You're a grown man.
You have control over your words.
You're goddamn right l do.
Here come two words for you: Shut up!
Excuse me. Walsh called Moscone about
a half an hour ago from outside Toledo.
He's on an lnterstate Coach Lines bus
headed for Chicago.
Come on.
Sir, what do we do with this guy?
Let him go.
Son of a bitch stole my cigarettes.
When's the last time
you had a chest X-ray?
You know about secondary smoke?
You could give people lung cancer...
...who are innocent
and tryin' to live healthy lives.
Why don't you just go back to sleep?
Leave me alone.
-Do whatever you have to do.
-Put the cigarette out.
Why don't you shut up and leave me alone?
Put the cigarette out, Jack.
Put the cigarette out.
A pain in the ass this guy is.
Thank you.
-l thought you were putting it out.
-No, l'm not putting it out.
Why aren't you popular
with the Chicago Police?
Sid's downstairs.
-What's up?
-l think you and l should talk.
Why are you hangin' around? Take a walk.
-Somebody picked up Mardukas.
-lt's old news. We're on it.
Do you know what'll happen
if he becomes a witness?
-That will not be the case.
-l assumed you were taking that position...
...but l am to advise you
against such action.
Relax. Have a cream soda. Everything
will be all over with in a few minutes.
Who the fuck are these guys?
Hands on the bus!
All right, spread them.
lt's the feds.
Remember me?
Agent Foster Grant. Alonzo, aren't you
gonna thank me for doin' your job for you?
Thank you.
Let's get the fuck out of here!
-What the hell are you doing?
-Keep moving.
Wait a minute. Jesus Christ!
All right, l'm comin'!
-Come on!
-Goddamn it! All right! Wait a minute!
Walsh, you son of a bitch!
-My God!
-Shut up.
-What the hell was that?
-Why were they shooting?
-Those are Serrano's people.
They're not waiting for you to get to jail.
You're turnin' me in.
Why are we runnin' from the FBl?
l gotta bring you in myself, or l won't get
my money. l won't give you to the feds.
''Alonzo Mosely.''
lsn't that the name you've been using?
Let me see that.
-Look at this wealth of information.
-What?
They got a tap on Moscone's line.
Son of a bitch!
What are you doin'?
How far do you think we'll get
in a stolen FBl car?
What's that for?
An inside joke between me and Alonzo.
-Tony Darvo, line one.
-Yeah?
Sorry. lt didn't happen.
-lt didn't happen? Say that again, Tony?
-ltjust didn't happen.
There were cops everywhere.
There were a million fuckin' feds all over.
Jimmy, it was a mess.
-lt was a real mess.
-You'd better get off the line.
-lf they've got a tap on that line--
-Shut your mouth!
Now listen to me, dummy.
Do they have Mardukas in custody or not?
Jimmy, l don't know.
The cops are swarming all over the place.
-We couldn't see anything.
-Let me tell you two dummies something.
l better not get another call like this.
lf l do...
...l'll get on a plane,
and l'll blowtorch the both of you.
Do you understand?
Are you gonna stop? l'm on the phone!
What are you doin'?
l should've killed Walsh
in Chicago a long time ago.
Don't say a word to me.
Don't say a fuckin' word to me.
l'll get up and l'll bury this telephone
in your head.
l can't believe this.
l haven't seen them in nine years
and the first thing l say will be:
''Can l borrow a few hundred bucks?''
l have a feeling
this will be very good for you.
You look fine.
Who are you guys?
l'm your mother's ex-husband.
-Mom!
-Nice kid.
Hi, Gail.
-Hello.
-How're you doin'?
l'm doin' good.
They mentioned you
on the news this morning.
-They did?
-Yeah.
What did they say? Anything good?
No. Are you all right?
You're in a lot of trouble.
Can l come in for a few minutes, Gail?
Can l come in for a few minutes?
l won't stay long. l just need to borrow
some money to get to LA.
You know l'm good for it.
l don't think l have that kind of cash
in the house.
l'm so embarrassed. l'm just in a jam, Gail.
You look beautiful.
You don't look much like a criminal.
l'm a white-collar criminal.
Jason, go upstairs now.
You shouldn't be here.
lf Ted comes home,
he's gonna arrest you and him.
-Arrest us?
-Yeah.
Then we'd be in trouble,
'cause l'm a little short of bribe money.
All right, Jack, don't start. Please, don't.
How is Lieutenant whatever-his-name-is?
-lt's captain now.
-Captain? Royalty.
l don't want any trouble.
Do you understand that?
lt is not a good day for this. l mean it.
l'm sorry my fugitive timetable
doesn't coincide with your social calendar.
-She wasn't saying that.
-Stay out of this.
Your feelings get hurt
and then you hurt everybody else.
-l don't need one of your lectures!
-l'm not lecturing you! l'm protecting you!
-Come on!
-Ted will be home any minute.
We're going out. lt's an important night.
What's so important about tonight?
Let me guess.
-What's it, payoff night?
-That's it! Get out!
-Let's not fight.
-Gail, listen! l'm in a big jam!
l just need some money
so l can get this guy to LA...
...and l'm out of this business forever!
Can't you understand that?
Hi.
Denise?
You got so big.
-l'm sorry. l'm gonna go now.
-No, hold on.
l'm sorry, honey.
lt's just that we're havin' a....
What grade are you in now?
Eighth.
Are you in the eighth grade?
Here's $40. That's all l've got.
Here are the keys to my car.
lt's in the driveway.
-l'll tell Ted that it's in the shop.
-Okay.
And we'll worry about it
when you get back to LA.
So, does he take good care of you?
Yeah? Well, that's all l wanted to know.
So what's he gonna say about this?
-He'll understand.
-Yeah, that's love.
'Bye, honey.
Wait.
-lt isn't much. $180 baby-sitting money.
-Sweetheart, l can't.
-Take it.
-l can't.
Please.
-Take it.
-l can't, sweetheart.
Hello. l'd like to make a collect call
to Eddie Moscone from Jack Walsh.
Moscone's Bail Bonds.
Jerry, put Eddie on the phone.
Eddie, it's Jack.
Stop fuckin' around. Where are you?
Where am l? l'm in Boise, ldaho.
No, wait a minute.
l'm in Anchorage, Alaska.
No, wait. l'm in Casper, Wyoming.
l'm in the lobby at a Howard Johnson's
and l'm wearing a pink carnation.
What are you talkin' about?
l'm not talkin' to you.
l'm talkin' to the other guys.
What other guys?
Let me describe the scene to you.
There's these guys.
They've probably been up for two days.
They stink of B.O.
They have coffee breath.
They're constipated from sitting
on their asses for so long.
They're sitting in a van and they're
probably parked right up the street.
But now you're gonna have
to pack up and go home...
...because l'm onto you, you dumb fucks.
Your phone is tapped. l'm not going to use
this line anymore. Go to Chin Loo's.
l'll call you in five minutes.
They can't run a tap that fast.
So long, everybody.
Excuse me, buddy. l got it!
l think it's for me. Jack, that you?
l need you to wire me $500
to the Western Union office...
...in Amarillo, Texas right away.
What do you need with $500 on a bus?
And why the aren't you on a plane?
Has it occurred to you that
l am a professional and l have my reasons?
We're driving now, and l only have
enough cash to get to Amarillo.
We had to scrap the bus.
Fuck the bus!
What happened to the goddamn plane!
-He doesn't like to fly.
-He doesn't like to fly?
What the fuck does that mean?
Listen to me, Jack!
You gotta be back here
in less than two and a half days.
A half million dollars of my money!
What the fuck is goin' on there?
l swear. Don't start with me now
or l will shoot him...
...and l will dump him in a fuckin' swamp!
l am in no fuckin' mood for this.
Send me the money,
and l'll have him back on time.
-You hear me?
-Yes.
Let's go.
Wire $500 to Jack Walsh
in Amarillo, Texas right away.
Amarillo, Texas. Now, listen.
Get Dorfler down there!
Find him and get him down there, too.
-You got it, Eddie.
-Shit!
''Ninety-three bottles of beer on the wall''
Why were you so unpopular
with the Chicago Police Department?
'Cause of your personality?
What happened back at your house?
What was that all about?
Your wife married a corrupt police officer?
What was it all about?
That whole fuckin' department
was corrupt.
There's good and bad everywhere, no?
l'd say there's bad everywhere.
Good l don't know about.
What happened to you?
l wouldn't go on the payroll.
What payroll?
l was workin' undercover. l was posted
to a big heroin dealer in Chicago.
He supplied the whole city.
Took me a year just to get his confidence.
Just when l was about to nail
the son of a bitch, my fellow officers...
...mysteriously discovered seven pounds
of heroin in my house.
So this big-time drug dealer
gave me a choice:
Get on the payroll like everybody else,
get out of town, or go to jail for 30 years.
l didn't get on the payroll.
And that's why l do this.
When l find a criminal like you,
l bring him in.
l don't have to worry about takin' a payoff
because there's just me.
Why don't you get yourself a new watch?
l'll tell you when l know you better.
When will you get to know me better?
l'll get to know you better.
-You won't get to know me better.
-Will you shut up?
That's what l mean.
How much money do we have left?
-That's it?
-That's it.
We're starvin',
and you're buying cigarettes?
l need these cigarettes.
You can have your whatever. l'll have this.
What can l do for you boys?
Coffee, please.
-How much is the coffee?
-lt's 53 cents.
-How much is tea?
-53 cents.
l'll have tea.
Our breakfast special today
is chorizo and eggs.
-Chorizo and eggs?
-Chorizo and eggs. Yes.
-What is that?
-lt's a Mexican sausage...
...mixed with scrambled eggs.
lt comes with hash browns and toast.
Won't be havin' that. Thank you.
What time you got?
Ten to nine.
ln 10 minutes we'll be at Western Union,
we'll have $500...
...and l'll buy you a steak
or whatever you want.
Chorizo and eggs?
-Chorizo and eggs?
-l'll get you whatever you want.
You know...
...you're in this mess because you're
in this mess. l didn't put you in this mess.
Do you understand?
lf you had left Serrano alone,
this wouldn't be happening.
Thank you.
l had a way out of this, you know.
What's the thing Serrano's most afraid of?
Goin' cross-country with you.
Gettin' knocked off by his own people.
What l know of his financial transactions
would put him away...
...and every mob guy he did business with.
That's why he wants to kill me.
l was gonna put all his records
on computer disks.
l figured if things rough,
l could trade them for my life.
So what happened?
What happened was l got arrested
before l had a chance to do it.
Why didn't you just leave him alone?
You don't look like the kind of guy
who'd be involved in that--
Why didn't you leave
that heroin dealer alone?
l was a mob accountant.
l thought l worked in a legitimate firm.
When l learned l was managing accounts
for Serrano...
...l couldn't sit back and do nothing.
But, you still took
what didn't belong to you.
How can you be on the side of a mobster?
-l'm not on his side.
-You are if you're not on my side.
l'm not on anyone's side.
l got nothing to do with it.
You got everything to do with it.
You're takin' me to jail where l'll be killed.
-That's not my problem.
-lt's not your problem?
lt's not your problem?
Did you read about me in the papers?
-l did.
-Were you on my side then?
-Yeah, l was.
-Then why aren't you now?
-Because now you're in my way.
-l'm in your way?
What you want is the money
for turning me in...
...because that's all you're about.
You're just about the fuckin' money.
You think whatever you want to think.
Doesn't matter 'cause l'm gettin'
my $100,000 any which way you want it.
Let's go.
Tony, you got your camera?
Take a picture.
They got these at the airport.
Should l get one?
Come on. Put that away.
l'm not gonna tell you again.
There they are.
-How you doin', Jack?
-Shit.
Jimmy sends his regards.
Don't worry, Jack.
We're not here for you. We're here for him.
What are you starin' at?
Are you gonna propose?
Drop them!
l said, ''Drop them,'' assholes!
Who the fuck are you guys?
Who the fuck are you?
You're dead.
You know who you're fuckin' with?
No. Why don't you tell me about it?
Make sure you speak into the microphone.
Very clever, Jack. Now give me the keys.
Come on! Give me the keys!
Keys.
Looks like a package deal to me, Marvin.
Goddamn it. Come on! Both of you!
Who the hell were those guys?
-You did it this time.
-What are you talkin' about?
Those are hired killers back there.
-Hired to kill who?
-Hired to kill this guy.
-Me. Can you believe it?
-Hired by who?
Hired by who? Jimmy Serrano.
That's who.
Fuck. Why do they want to kill this guy?
Don't you read the papers, knucklehead?
-l read the papers.
-l can't take this.
They got away. Grey Dodge.
Get after them.
How did you know where we were?
-l can't take this.
-Did Eddie put you on this?
-Of course.
-That son of a bitch!
-l have a contract with him?
-You got a contract?
-l signed it on Monday.
-He called me.
-He said you were fucking this thing up.
-l'm not fuckin' anything up.
You should've been in LA two days ago.
Don't tell me how to do my job!
l'm thinkin' not to turn him in...
...just to watch Eddie go down the toilet.
-That's a good thought.
-What? Who the hell's talkin' to you?
Who's talkin' to you?
He's not yours to take anymore.
-He's mine.
-Do you hear that?
Fuck! Now who the fuck is this?
Jesus Christ!
Do something!
You guys are the dumbest bounty hunters
l've ever seen!
You couldn't even deliver a bottle of milk!
Will you shut the fuck up?
Where the hell did he go?
-Think we lost him?
-Don't know. l don't see anything.
l'm sure we're completely safe.
-You all right?
-Yeah, l'm fine. l'm enjoying it.
-Marvin, give me a gun.
-No fuckin' way!
-Will you give me a gun?
-Give him a gun!
Don't fuck me, Jack!
Shit.
They're not after me. Just kidding.
-Thought you threw those away.
-Always check the evidence.
Those were car keys.
Son of a bitch! There goes $100,000.
$100,000? He was gonna
pay you $100,000?
-Why? What was he gonna pay you?
-$25,000.
Son of a bitch!
Holy shit, Jack! You got him!
What the hell are you doin', Jack?
See you in LA.
Where the fuck are you?
Give me your hand. l'm slipping.
l can't hold on. Give me your hand.
Where are you goin'?
Good.
Promise you'll let me go?
Do you promise to let me go?
-Fuck you!
-Promise to let me go?
Fuck you.
You're making it very difficult for me
to do the right thing here.
All right. l promise l'll let you go.
Jesus.
-You all right?
-Yeah.
Thanks for saving my life.
Thanks for lettin' me go.
l'll let you go, all right.
The second you're in LA County Jail.
Come on.
Yeah, that's right. Down here!
Are you just gonna stand there...
...or are you gonna get me out of here?
This just came in.
ls this gonna upset me?
l think it's safe to say that.
Are you familiar with a dish,
a potato dish, lyonnaise potato?
lt's a kind of fried potato.
But it's got an onion in it.
lt's quite delicious.
lt really goes beautifully
with steak, chops...
...hamburger, cheeseburger,
any of your meat dishes.
lt's just a....
You know, l have enough money to buy...
-Look.
-...as much lyonnaise potatoes...
-...as you ever would enjoy.
-Shut up, will you, please?
l think you ought to think about it a bit,
because it's nothing....
Wait a minute.
Thank you.
Cover that.
Hi. Could you give us a ride
to the next town?
-Sure. Jump in the back.
-Thanks a lot.
Great. See? For every shit,
there's six nice people.
-''Yahey,'' everyone.
-What's that?
lt's ''Hello.'' l can say ''Hello''
in a lot of different languages.
Not yours, but a lot of them.
Welcome, sir.
-l'm not lookin' forward to this.
-Do you think l am?
l don't understand the problem
with you two. He's an accountant.
lt's been bad luck. This guy Walsh is good.
lf he's that good,
l should hire him to hit you.
l hope there's no chance of this
coming back to Jimmy.
No chance.
Rented the chopper out of Kansas City.
He's five times removed from you.
You're clear of this.
Clear as shit, you moron!
The guy is still out there, ain't he?
Let me tell you guys somethin'.
l'm not interested in seein'
you two alive again...
...until you get the accountant,
got the message?
lt's the end of the ride.
-This is it?
-This is it.
ls there a real town
around here someplace?
-Channing.
-Channing?
How far is that from here?
-Thirty miles.
-Thirty miles. Jesus Christ.
What the hell kind of town is this?
ls there someone that can give us
a ride to Channing?
-ls there anyone going in that direction?
-No, don't have a ride.
Excuse me a minute.
ls there a bathroom in there l could use?
Yeah, go ahead.
ls there a telephone here?
-Telephone.
-No telephone.
No telephone? Nothing.
Glad you're all havin' a good time.
Fear of flying, you son of a bitch?
Get over here!
Get back here, you son of a bitch!
Get over here! Stop!
Fear of flyin', my ass!
Get out of that plane!
You're a goddamn pilot, you son of a bitch?
l didn't feel it was appropriate
to share that with you, Jack.
l'm gonna appropriate your head.
How do you turn this thing off?
Turn it off!
Hang in there! l'm gonna let it down easy!
Shit!
Pilot? You're a goddamn pilot?
You're a pilot? Here, l'll show you pilot.
l'll tell you about the coffee shop
l'm opening after l drop you off...
...and get my $100,000. You'll love it.
All right, get back!
Everybody, back!
-Give me the keys to the truck.
-You can't steal their truck.
You were about to steal a plane!
-What are you talking about?
-l'm trying to save my life!
l should give them something.
Give me your watch.
My watch? Shit!
Keep it. lt's worth a lot of money.
Get in.
Stand back!
Jack, let's be fair about this.
You lied to me first.
-At the river.
-What? Get the fuck--
-At the river!
-You lied to me first.
-You got some fuckin' nerve!
-No. You lied to me first.
You lied to me first.
Yes, l lied to you first but you had
no knowledge l was lying about my fear...
...at the river, when you lied to me.
So as far as you knew, you lied to me first.
Can't even argue with you.
Don't know what you're saying.
l'm just saying you lied to me first
as far as you knew.
-What's the matter?
-l got an ulcer.
-An ulcer?
-Yeah, l got an ulcer.
l got a ulcer, and all your bullshit
started to make it bleed again.
You know why you have an ulcer?
Because you have two forms of expression:
Silence and rage.
Milk would coat it.
l need somethin' to eat, that's what l need.
What are we gonna buy it with? Dirt?
You drive to the next town.
l'll take care of it.
You'll take care of it? What do you mean?
Drive to the next town.
But you lied to me first.
-Now what?
-Give me that FBl badge.
-The FBl badge?
-Yeah, give me the FBl badge.
-Uncuff me.
-Uncuff you?
Want to eat? Want a nice meal?
Want some of that shit you eat?
Come on. Uncuff me.
-You fuck with me--
-You'll hit me on the head and drop me....
Right. Uncuff me.
-Who's in charge here?
-Who wants to know?
-Me.
-That'd be the manager.
l'd like to see the manager.
Yes, sir.
Alonzo Mosely, FBl.
We're tracking a ring of counterfeiters...
...passing phony $20 bills across the state.
Have you received any $20 bills
in the last couple of hours?
We get them all the time.
You get them all the time. Would
you mind taking two steps backwards?
Would you mind opening the register?
No, don't touch them.
Excuse me.
Contract two, Hank. Check them out.
Give him a pencil, please.
Do the litmus configuration.
Doing the litmus configuration?
-Litmus configuration.
-Yes.
You see any suspicious-looking characters
around here?
Nope.
-Do you live around here?
-Yep.
-How does it look?
-This one's bad.
Describe exactly what the last man...
...who passed a $20 bill to you looked like?
-Thirty. Tall.
-About 6 feet tall?
-6' 5''.
-Dark brown hair?
Light colored.
-Sounds like our man.
-That's him.
We're gonna take these bills for evidence.
Make them a receipt.
This one's bad, too.
Please notify the other establishments
in the area.
What's the name of yours?
-Red's Corner Bar.
-Are you Red?
Do you dye your hair?
No.
Why do they call you ''Red''?
lt's short for ''Red Wood.''
My last name's ''Wood.''
-What's your first name?
-Bill.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Hank.
These are all bad. Those are good.
-Come on. We're gonna get this train.
-What?
We're gonna catch this train.
l can't catch a train.
You also couldn't fly. Start running.
Wait a minute. Wait! lt's a freight train!
l can't do this!
l deeply feel l can't do this.
l thought you liked to travel by train.
Get up there!
-What are you doing?
-Promise to let me go?
-Open the fuckin' door!
-See you in the next life, Jack.
Son of a bitch!
You son of a bitch! Open that fuckin' door!
Glad to see me?
l guess we're in the next life.
-Don't overreact now.
-Don't overreact?
l won't overreact! Get over here!
React? You do this again,
l'll throw you off the fuckin' train!
Get down there! Put your hand in there!
-Easy, Jack.
-There.
You son of a bitch!
You shut up! l'm not talking to you
for the whole rest of this trip!
Are you gonna let me go, or what?
l don't know anything.
ls that a fact?
Shit.
Why don't you quit?
Be cheaper for both of us.
Where are they?
You got me.
-lnspector.
-Shut up.
Now you listen, you son of a bitch.
l want answers, right now.
What do you want from me?
l don't know nothin'.
lt seems that an Agent Alonzo Mosely
and his partner...
...were seen hopping a westbound
freight train near Channing.
Come on.
Jack? What?
How much further you think we have
to go? None of your fuckin' business!
l'm gonna have to go to the bathroom.
Shut the fuck up!
Did you ever have sex with an animal?
Remember those chickens
around the lndian reservation?
There's some good-lookin' chickens there.
You know, between us.
There were a couple there
l might have taken a shot at.
What's with you and that watch?
You said when you got to know me better.
You told me about your feelings
for chickens.
How private could the watch be?
What's the big secret?
Gail bought me this watch.
She gave it to me.
lt was the first thing she ever gave me.
She bought it because l was always late
by at least a half an hour.
So she bought it and set it ahead
a half an hour so l'd never be late.
ln the back of my mind
l keep thinking we'll wind up together.
l don't know why l'm still hanging on.
l'm still waitin' around.
l don't think she's comin' back.
Yeah, l don't either.
l don't either.
Sometimes you just have to let go.
Just get yourself a new watch.
You're okay, Jack.
l think...
...under different circumstances...
...you and l...
...probably still would've hated each other.
We probably could've been friends.
ln the next life.
Yeah, the next life.
Yeah, great.
Accommodations were wonderful.
-You got a smoke?
-Don't smoke.
That fed took my cigarettes.
You want your cigarettes back?
Then you'll have to go to Flagstaff...
...'cause that's where
your pal Mosely went.
Just might do that.
Where do you figure we are?
My guess would be Arizona.
We've been goin' west all night.
l think we're almost home.
l'm almost dead.
The Witness Protection Program
isn't so bad.
You'll get a new name.
You'll have a new life.
l won't make it
to any witness protection program.
-You don't know that.
-l know it. You know it.
Serrano will get to me before l get
to a Witness Protection Program.
Do me a favor.
Don't pretend you care about me.
lt really insults my intelligence.
Let's face it. The only important thing
about me to you...
...is gettin' your money.
l'm really tired of you makin' me out
to be a thug...
...whose only concern
is a big chunk of change.
You know Serrano's people
offered me $1,000,000 for you?
Why not go for the big money?
You're working for him anyway.
l'm workin' for him anyway?
You don't know what you're saying.
The reason l do this shit in the first place
is 'cause l wouldn't work for that asshole.
-What does that mean?
-Nothin'.
Doesn't mean anything.
Serrano is the heroin dealer
you told me about in Chicago?
Who owned your buddies
and destroyed your life? That's Serrano?
That's the guy that you're takin' me in....
That's the guy that's gonna kill me?
Hope it's a wonderful coffee shop, Jack.
-Come on. We're gettin' off.
-What?
We are getting off here, Mr. Railroad Man.
Come on.
-You should be good at this.
-What are you talkin' about?
Let's discuss this!
-Find anything?
-Not yet.
They could've jumped off the train
anywhere along the line.
Trains have regularly scheduled stops.
The reason is people plan to get off
the trains when they stop.
That's how, generally, people do it.
They don't throw each other off the trains.
That's the purpose of having stops.
What's this?
What are you gonna do?
What are you doin' now?
What are you doin'?
Christ! Come on!
Are you kidding? They're gonna come out
and shoot us, for Christ's sake.
What the hell?
Jesus. Great!
You get it started...
...and l'll run you over.
That's the best plan l can think of.
Congratulations. Another crime.
Come on.
l don't like this.
l don't like anything you do,
to tell you the truth. Nothin'.
Where are we going?
To the nearest airport.
l'm not the kind of guy that says,
''l told you so,'' but....
Shit!
They've been spotted 35 miles south
of here near Sedona.
There are officers in pursuit.
Let's take the chopper.
This is the kind of situation
where something bad happens.
Easy!
Goddamn it, l don't like this!
Truck!
-Where are you goin'?
-You'll find out when we get there.
l've come too far.
Too far.
l'm too close.
Okay. l'm coming. All right.
-Come on.
-All right.
Here we go.
Hello!
Am l lucky, or am l just good?
ls that Marvin?
Fucking A. l'm the best.
Hello, Jack, you dumb shit.
-Come on, you pain in the ass!
-What was that?
Wait a minute.
lf you move, l'll tear your fuckin' lungs out!
See you in LA.
Shit.
Afternoon, sir.
-You open?
-We're always open.
Hard day?
Hard week.
Yeah, l know what you mean.
l could use a cup of coffee.
-Thanks.
-You're welcome.
Keep it.
l been lookin' all over for these.
Thanks, Alonzo.
Marvin, l have to tell you,
l have this very serious fear of flying.
Why don't you just relax
and sleep through it?
Forget your deadline.
That's the way that one went.
l know my rights.
You owe me phone calls.
What should be important
to you is not the phone calls...
...but that you'll spend 10 years
for impersonating a federal agent.
-10 years?
-10 years.
10 years. How come no one's after you?
Give this guy his calls.
Thanks.
Can l have a little privacy, please?
Moscone's Bail Bonds.
lt's Jack Walsh. Put Eddie on.
lt's Jack.
Yeah. This better be good news,
because you got five hours left.
No, it's not. l'm callin' to let you know
that you're dead. You understand me?
Wait a minute.
You put Marvin on this case,
you piece of shit.
You're fucking deceptive. You vermin!
You serpent!
-Are you fuckin' done yet?
-You slime ball in a sea of pus! What?
You blew it, all right?
You had the guy four fuckin' days, Jack.
Four days!
You could've fuckin' walked him backwards
and not fuckin' blown it, but you blew it.
When have l ever let you down,
you fuckin' rat?
Are you fuckin' nuts,
tellin' Dorfler l offered you $100,000...
...when l told him l'd give him $25,000?
-When did you speak to him?
-Why?
When did you speak to him?
He called me 10 minutes ago...
...yellin' and screamin',
tellin' me to fuck off.
You're tellin' me,
everybody's tellin' me to fuck off.
Am l supposed tojust sit
on my fuckin' butt?
What are you talkin' about?
Look, you got five hours left.
Can you bring the Duke in, yes or no?
l thought he's bringin' him to you.
l just talked to fuckin' Dorfler.
He don't have the Duke.
-What?
-Where's the fuckin' Duke?
-Hello?
-l'll talk to you later.
-Yeah, Tony Darvo there, please?
-Who's calling?
-Marvin Dorfler.
Marvin Dorfler on the line.
Shall l put him through?
Yeah. Put him through.
Everything's still on schedule?
So Dorfler's workin' for you guys.
-Who is this?
-This is Jack Walsh.
Jack, what are you complainin' for?
We came to you first, didn't we?
lt's Jack Walsh.
Hold on. Somebody wants to say hello.
Too late for you, scumbag.
Too late for you. l didn't come this far
not to get my money.
You understand me, you motherfuckers?
l want the Duke back.
What are you tellin' me for?
What am l tellin' you for?
l'll tell you what l'm tellin' you for.
l got some of the Duke's belongings.
That's why.
lncluding some computer disks
that have every detail...
...of Serrano's businesses
and his money-laundering operations.
And if l don't get the Duke back
in the next two hours...
...l'm gonna turn the disks over
to the feds. Hear me?
Tell Serrano l'll meet him with the Duke
in two hours in McCarran Airport...
...where we'll make the exchange.
He's the only one of you
who won't try to shoot me in public.
lf l see one fuckin' single goon
within a mile of that airport...
...now listen to me...
...the deal's off, and l'll go to the feds.
l won't bother Jimmy with your bullshit.
You're not? Okay, fine. Fine.
After he's busted...
...l'll tell him
you knew all about it beforehand.
That's two hours from now.
Main terminal, McCarran Airport.
You got that, moron? Have a nice day.
Tell Alonzo l want to make a deal.
You want to make a deal with me?
What if l could deliver you Serrano?
What do you mean, ''deliver''?
For starters, conspiracy to destroy
government evidence.
What government evidence?
Will you let me take the Duke back
and collect my money?
Tell me more.
Tell you on the way 'cause we gotta be
in Las Vegas in two hours.
No, it's room service.
Here. Hold this up...
...so they know l took this today.
l amaze myself. l'm always thinking.
Got it all figured out.
-Now say, ''Cheese.''
-Don't do this, Marvin.
Adios.
All right.
There are no real computer disks.
-ls that right?
-Right.
So if you give him blank disks...
...and he accepts them
would that still be considered an overt act?
lf he just enters the airport,
he's committed an overt act...
...conspiracy to obstruct justice.
When he shows up with the Duke,
you add kidnapping.
Anybody with a gun,
conspiracy to commit murder.
The fact that it's an airport,
correct me if you think l'm wrong....
...you can slap an interstate transportation
aid of racketeering rap on him.
None of that means anything
unless you can get him to take those disks.
Don't worry. l'll get him to take the disks.
Get a wire on this man.
No hard feelings about
what happened back in Amarillo?
Just one of
those spur-of-the-moment deals.
-Where is he?
-Where's the money?
ln the car. Where is he?
Slight change of plans.
Now l want $2 million.
What?
l read the newspapers, you know?
The guy got you for $15 million, right?
So l figure he's gotta be worth
at least $2 million.
l'm a businessman.
How do we know you got him?
l want $1 million now...
...and l'll call you in 20 minutes...
...tell you where to drop off
the second million.
Once l know it's there,
then l'll tell you where he is.
-Not okay.
-Why not?
What are you, nuts? What will Jimmy say?
How will we get the Duke now?
-You got the answer right in your hand!
-What are you talkin' about?
When are you gonna learn
how to pay attention?
See what it says there?
All right. This is it.
Tonight is the night. You understand?
l'm sick of all of these screw-ups.
As soon as l get the disks from Walsh...
...you guys drop Walsh
and you drop the Duke. You understand?
l get the disks, you drop them. Okay?
-l don't think you should do this.
-Really?
What do you propose that l do?
Send somebody with a cash offer.
Don't do this.
l know Walsh.
He won't take any money from me.
He's a very self-righteous type of guy.
lt aggravates me.
ln his mind, this is clean.
He gets what he wants, l get what l want.
The guy's a fuckin' burnout, Sidney.
Sit down, relax, have a sandwich,
drink a glass of milk. Do something.
He's on his way.
He's heading north
on Las Vegas Boulevard...
...approximately two miles
from the airport. We're right on him.
Why are you smiling?
l feel like a cop again.
So l'm finally in the presence of greatness?
The Duke.
The guy that steals money from scum...
...and gives it to the unfortunates
of the world.
l wanted to meet you face to face.
Did you actually think you could steal
my money and get away with it?
l stopped by here to tell you two things:
Number one is: You're gonna die tonight.
Number two: l'm gonna go home,
have a nice hot meal...
...l'm gonna find your wife,
and l'm gonna kill her, too.
Wait here for my call.
The rest of you go in.
You got it.
Here he comes.
Long time no see.
You're still spendin'
all your money on clothes.
-You know....
-Listen, while you're in town...
...ifyou want to see a show
or you want a free meal or something...
...just let me know, all right? On me.
That's the kind of guy l am.
You're a real sport.
Just give him the disks.
How's your mother?
She's all right.
Daughter's gettin' big, growing up.
l was thinkin' if we would've done business
way back when...
...you wouldn't look like a guy
with a cup in your hand.
l'm tryin' to make a living.
You got those disks or did you lose them
like you lost your job?
Give him the disks, Walsh.
l see you, but l don't see the Duke.
-We'll worry about him in a minute.
-We gotta worry about him now.
Let me tell you somethin', Jimmy.
This isn't a reunion.
lf l don't see the Duke
in about five seconds, l'm walking.
You know, you're still way too serious.
Really. Listen.
Why don't you just hand them over?
We'll go get the guy together.
l'll see you at the arraignment.
Where the hell is he goin'?
You win, all right?
-l what?
-You won.
You want me to yell it all over the airport?
Where is he?
-He's on his way.
-You know l said no goons.
Never mind him.
You're gonna get what you want.
This thing is gonna give me a heart attack
before it's all over.
Since we have this moment together
there's something l want to ask you.
Doesn't it bother you that another copper
is fuckin' your wife?
Do you know
they made this guy a captain?
Can you imagine that?
Go figure it out. Made him a captain.
-Can l help you, sir?
-Give me a one-way ticket to LA.
One-way ticket to Los Angeles.
Will that be smoking or non-smoking?
Take a wild guess.
Smoking.
And how will you be paying for this, sir?
-Shit.
-What?
Look.
What the hell is he doing here?
We have a male Caucasian
with a green duffel bag...
...with his hand in his vest,
approaching the subjects.
Get him out of there as quickly
and as quietly as possible.
Shoot him if you have to,
but get him out of here.
-You okay, Jon?
-Yeah.
-Stand behind me.
-lt's all right.
Come on.
-How's everybody doin'?
-Get out of here?
Back off, everybody.
-Who are you?
-Are you writin' a book? Who are you?
Who is he?
You're missin' the bigger picture here.
Get out of here.
Wire's gone dead.
-Are you crazy?
-l didn't come all this way for nothin'.
-Serrano's leaving.
-Did he take the disks?
l don't know.
-Serrano's got the disks.
-Let him go.
He got the disks.
Did he take the disks?
l couldn't tell. There's too much goin' on.
Serrano's got the disks. He's got the disks.
Marvin, look out!
l'm not fallin' for that again.
You stupid fuck, will you look out!
Serrano's got the disks!
Move in.
Take it easy! Come on!
Goddamn it! Who the fuck are you guys?
There's somethin' l've been wanting to say
for ten years.
-What's that?
-''You're under arrest.''
We'll catch up to each other
one of these days.
Maybe we will.
-We still got our deal?
-We got our deal.
Wait a minute! What deal?
Why does he get special treatment?
See you in LA, Marvin.
Watch your cigarettes with this guy.
What's goin' on?
Sorry. l got an hour and a half
to get you back to LA.
Thanks, Alonzo.
Moscone's Bail Bonds.
Hello, Eddie. Where's Jerry?
Never mind Jerry. Where the hell are you?
Feds picked him up 20 minutes ago.
-What for?
-What's the difference, man?
l never trusted that guy anyway.
-Where the hell are you?
-Where am l? l'm at the airport.
And guess who l'm with?
l'm with the Duke.
You got him! l love you!
-You want to say hello?
-Yeah. Put him on.
-Say hello.
-Hello.
Hello, you son of a bitch!
We got you...
...you son of a bitch!
Now say good-bye, you lying piece of shit,
'cause l'm letting him go.
Would've been a nice coffee shop.
Jesus.
l don't get it.
l did what l wanted to do.
l got you to LA before midnight, so....
l don't know what to say.
Don't say anything.
Knowing you, you'll make me want
to put those back on you again.
Thanks.
-No. Thank you.
-Thank you.
Somethin' to remember our adventure by.
This better be good.
This is good.
This is very good.
When l was makin' my getaway,
l thought the FBl was closin' in on me.
Take it. l took some traveling money.
Take it.
lt's not a payoff. lt's a gift.
You already let me go.
You son of a bitch.
-You son of a bitch.
-Told you l had money.
l know you had money,
but l didn't know you had money.
How much is here?
Neighborhood of $300,000.
That's a very respectable neighborhood.
l don't know what to say.
Take care.
-Take care.
-See you in the next life.
-Do you know what time it is?
-Twenty-five to 12:00.
Twenty-five to 12:00.
l would've made it.
You wouldn't have change for $1,000,
would you?
What are you, a comedian?
Get out of here, you bum!
Looks like l'm walkin'.