[HONK]
WHAT THE HELL
IS THAT ALL ABOUT?
HEY, MIKE,
YOU IN A HURRY?
¶ DON'T YOU
REMEMBER THE DAY ¶
WHAT'S WITH THEM?
¶ THAT YOU WENT AWAY
MAYBE THEY'RE
JUST TIRED.
¶ AND LEFT ME?
¶ I WAS SO LONELY
¶ PRAYED FOR YOU ONLY
¶ MY LOVE
SORRY, BOYS,
THE KITCHEN'S CLOSED.
¶ LOVING YOU
¶ WHEN I KNOW
THAT YOU'RE NOT TRUE ¶
¶ AND WHY SHOULD I
CALL YOUR NAME ¶
¶ WHEN YOU'RE
TO BLAME... ¶
WE'RE STICKING
TO THE STORY
NO MATTER
HOW ROUGH IT GETS.
UNDERSTAND?
WHATEVER.
GREG?
GO AHEAD, MIKE,
MAKE THAT PHONE CALL.
WE'RE ALL WITH YOU.
GO ON.
THAT'S RIGHT, MAN.
THAT'S RIGHT.
GO.
[LAUGHING]
WORKING YOUR BOYS
KIND OF LATE TONIGHT,
WERE YOU, MIKE?
[COIN DROPS]
[RADIO STATIC]
THIS IS
SERGEANT REYNOLDS
FROM CRIMINAL
INVESTIGATIONS
CALLING LIEUTENANT
FRANK WATTERS.
ARE YOU THERE,
LIEUTENANT?
LIEUTENANT,
DO YOU READ ME?
I'M HERE, SERGEANT.
I'VE CHECKED
WITH SHERIFF DAVIS.
HE'LL GIVE YOU
ALL THE DETAILS
WHEN YOU GET
TO SNOWFLAKE.
WHAT'S HIS PROBLEM?
FRANK, IT SOUNDS LIKE HE'S IN
OVER HIS HEAD ON THIS ONE.
I HEAR YOU.
THIS IS A POLICE
INVESTIGATION.
THERE'S NOTHING FOR YOU
TO SEE OR TO HEAR.
EVERYBODY JUST GO HOME.
THERE'S NOTHING TO SEE.
GET IN YOUR CARS,
TAKE YOUR KIDS,
TAKE YOUR FAMILIES.
GO ON HOME.
LIEUTENANT WATTERS?
I'M FRANK WATTERS.
SHERIFF BLAKE DAVIS.
I KNOW A LOT ABOUT YOU
FROM THE PAPERS,
ABOUT YOU NOT HAVING
ANY UNSOLVED CASES
HERE OR IN MONTANA.
NOTHING BUT A MYTH,
BUT A DAMN FINE ONE.
WHY THE RADIO SILENCE
ON BRINGING ME HERE?
WELL, WE GOT A SPECIAL
KIND OF SITUATION HERE--
A MISSING BOY
ON OUR HANDS.
TRAVIS WALTON.
ABOUT AN HOUR AGO,
MY DEPUTY TOOK
A MISSING-PERSONS REPORT
FROM A FELLA NAMED ROGERS,
MIKE ROGERS.
I'VE KNOWN HIM
A LONG TIME.
HE'S A GOOD GUY,
A STRAIGHT GUY.
HE'S BEEN RUNNING A CREW
UP THE MOGOLLON RIM
NEAR TURKEY SPRINGS
FOR ABOUT A MONTH.
THEY HAD
A GOVERNMENT CONTRACT
TO CLEAR OUT THE BRUSH.
DENNIS. I WANT YOU
TO MEET MY DEPUTY.
SHAKE HANDS
WITH LIEUTENANT WATTERS.
DEPUTY CLAY.
HI, DENNIS.
IT'S AN HONOR,
LIEUTENANT.
I READ ABOUT THAT
WETBACK MURDER IN NOGALES.
DENNIS, TELL US WHO ELSE
IS IN THAT GANG
BESIDES MIKE ROGERS.
YEAH. WE GOT DAVID WHITLOCK.
26. LOCAL BOY.
ACTIVE IN THE CHURCH.
GREG HAYES. 17.
HIGH-SCHOOL KID
FROM WINSLOW.
THIS ONE'S
PRETTY SHOOK UP.
ROBERT COGDILL. 20.
FROM DURANGO.
JOINED THE CREW
A WEEK AGO.
ALLAN DALLIS. 25.
A DRIFTER.
ON THE CREW
JUST OVER TWO WEEKS.
BAD APPLE
IF YOU ASK ME.
HE'S GOT HELL
IN HIS EYES.
FRANK, UH,
I THINK THAT, UH...
I THINK THAT MAYBE,
UM...
MAYBE YOU'D
BETTER HEAR THIS
FROM THE HORSE'S MOUTH.
LEAD ME TO THE HORSE.
DENNIS, GET THESE FOLKS
OUT OF HERE.
FOLKS, GIVE THEM
SOME ROOM.
RESTAURANT'S CLOSED
FOR THE NIGHT.
WHAT IN HELL'S
THAT THING FOR?
IT BOTHER YOU?
YEAH, IT BOTHERS ME.
I DON'T WANT
ANY MISINTERPRETATIONS.
THIS WAY
THERE'S A CLEAR RECORD
OF EVERYTHING
YOU TELL US.
WELL,
WE ALREADY TOLD
THAT BARNEY FIFE
OF A DEPUTY
EVERYTHING WE KNOW.
[SHERIFF]
I'LL TELL YOU, FRANK.
CLAY WROTE DOWN
EVERYTHING.
WE'LL USE THE RECORDER.
A MAN
WITH NOTHING TO HIDE
IS A MAN WITH NOTHING
TO WORRY ABOUT.
HAH.
YOU'RE THE LEADER,
RIGHT?
YEAH.
YEAH, HE'S OUR
FEARLESS LEADER.
MAYBE I SHOULD BE
TALKING TO YOU INSTEAD.
OH, NO,
NO, SIR.
HE'S THE BOSS.
THERE'S NO DOUBT
ABOUT THAT.
TELL ME ABOUT
TRAVIS WALTON.
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED?
NO. ABOUT TRAVIS.
START BY TELLING ME
WHO HE IS.
HE'S, UH...
HE WAS MY BEST FRIEND.
WAKE UP, DADDY!
WAKE UP!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
IT'S THE TICKLE MONSTER!
OW!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
DADDY JUST
CRACKED HIS ELBOW.
HOW ARE YOU?
GOOD MORNING.
BREAKFAST IS READY.
WHO TOLD YOU
TO WAKE ME UP?
MOMMY DID!
WHY DID SHE TELL YOU
TO WAKE ME UP?
'CAUSE SHE WANTS ME
TO TICKLE YOU?
TRAVIS!
YOU SON OF A BITCH,
GET OFF THAT BIKE!
CATHY, WHAT
ARE YOU DOING?
NOTHING, MOM.
GET THAT THING
OFF THE SIDEWALK!
OH!
HERE YOU GO.
COMING IN.
YOU WANT SOME
BUTTER ON THAT?
OOH. CAN I HAVE
SOME FRENCH TOAST?
SURE.
I GOT SOME FOR YOU
RIGHT HERE.
I GOT TO GO.
I GOT TO GET
THE TRUCK RUNNING.
WAIT A SECOND.
LET ME TALK TO YOU
FOR A SECOND.
THE BANK'S GOING
TO CALL AGAIN TODAY.
SO?
WHAT SHOULD
I TELL THEM?
DO WE HAVE TO TALK
ABOUT IT RIGHT NOW?
YOU KNOW WHAT?
WE CAN WAIT
TILL THEY THROW US
OUT OF OUR HOUSE.
HEY, MIKE!
MORNING.
[SIGHS]
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
OH, YOU
AND KATIE AGAIN?
HEY, MIKE,
WANT A DOUGHNUT?
MAKE YOU FEEL BETTER.
ABOUT TIME
WE GOT YOURS
BACK ON THE ROAD,
DON'T YOU THINK?
UNLESS YOU GOT
SOME SECRET PLAN
TO LET IT RUST AND
SELL IT FOR SCRAP?
WE'LL START TONIGHT.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I GOT TO SHOW YOU
SOMETHING.
WHAT'S THIS?
THIS IS OUR FUTURE.
MT MOTORS.
SERVING ALL
OF NAVAHO COUNTY.
HARLEYS, NORTONS,
YAMAHAS,
YOU NAME IT.
WE'LL DO COMMERCIALS
LIKE THE GUYS
IN PHOENIX.
MT MOTORS.
OUR PRICES
ARE SO GREAT,
OUR SHOWROOM'S
ALWAYS ALMOST EMPTY.
GET IT?
EMPTY--M, T...
MOTORS.
EMPTY.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I THINK WE BETTER
JUST CONCENTRATE
ON FINISHING
THE CONTRACT.
THE FOREST SERVICE
WON'T EXTEND THE DEADLINE.
MIKE, DON'T WORRY.
THIS IS THE DEAL.
LOOK, TRAVIS,
MY MORTGAGE
IS ON THE LINE.
I GOT TO WORRY.
I GOT NO CHOICE.
WE'LL GET IT DONE,
OR WE WON'T.
HEY, WHERE YOU GOING?
LOVE AWAITS ME.
LOOK IT!
UNCLE TRAVIS!
GOD, TRAVIS, CAN'T
YOU USE THE DOOR?
NO!
GO--
MORNING.
GOOD MORNING.
BREAKFAST IN BED.
THANK YOU.
DANA, LET'S GET MARRIED.
I CAN'T WAIT ANYMORE.
TRAVIS.
DON'T ANSWER,
DON'T ANSWER.
JUST...
JUST THINK
ABOUT IT.
OK.
[TRUCK HOOD SLAMS]
CAN WE GET GOING,
PLEASE,
BEFORE I GET
SERIOUSLY SICK?
I'LL SEE YOU LATER.
OK.
[RADIO PLAYS
LOUD ROCK MUSIC]
THIS IS THE TUNE, MAN.
¶ BLINDED BY LOVE
HOW YOU DOING,
FELLAS?
¶ I CAN'T SEE
THE MORNIN' SUN ¶
GOOD MORNING,
TRAVIS.
¶ BLINDED BY LOVE
¶ I CAN'T SEE
TILL THE DAY IS DONE ¶
BOBBY, EVERY DAY
I TELL YOU
TO TURN IT DOWN
OR TURN IT OFF.
I'M NOT GOING
TO TELL YOU AGAIN.
[BOBBY] I NEED TO
LISTEN TO SOME BLUES.
YOU GOT ANY
DOUGHNUTS UP THERE?
WE DID,
BUT WE ATE THEM ALL.
HEY, LISTEN TO THIS.
"LADY IN BORNEO
GIVES BIRTH
TO A LITTER OF 13."
[DALLIS] IT'S A BUNCH
OF BULLSHIT.
IT'S RIGHT HERE.
READ IT.
GET OUT OF MY WAY!
HEY, LEAVE HIM ALONE.
SHUT UP AND MIND
YOUR OWN BUSINESS.
WHAT IF I MAKE IT
MY BUSINESS?
IS THAT WHAT YOU WANT,
WANT TO MAKE IT
YOUR BUSINESS?
CAN WE HAVE ONE DAY
WITHOUT YOU GIRLS
FIGHTING?
SHUT UP, DAVID!
HEY, HEY HEY!
KNOCK IT OFF!
NO, YOU KNOCK IT OFF.
[BOBBY]
THIS IS A GOOD SONG.
TURN IT DOWN, BOBBY.
I MEAN IT.
¶ BLINDED BY LOVE
¶ I CAN'T SEE
THE MORNIN' SUN ¶
¶ CAN'T SEE
¶ I'M BLINDED BY LOVE
¶ BLINDED BY LOVE
¶ I CAN'T SEE
TILL THE DAY IS DONE ¶
¶ CAN'T SEE TILL
THE DAY IS DONE ¶
¶ BLINDED BY LOVE
¶ I CAN'T SEE
THE MORNIN' SUN... ¶
ALL RIGHT, BOYS,
LET'S GET MOVING.
ALL RIGHT,
LISTEN UP.
IT'S GOING TO BE
A LONG DAY.
DAVID AND DALLIS,
YOU GUYS ALTERNATE
ON THE BIG SAW.
BOBBY AND GREG
ARE ON CLEANUP.
LET'S GET THE EAST SIDE
OF PINE MOUNTAIN
BEFORE SUNDOWN.
ALL RIGHT?
GET THE WATER.
LET'S GO.
ANOTHER DAY,
ANOTHER DOLLAR.
DOWN THE HILL!
GOT HIM LOADED NOW.
TIMBER.
ALL RIGHT, LUNCH!
NOT TOO BRIGHT.
CAN'T HEAR YOU.
KNOCK IT OFF,
DALLIS!
I SAID, LUNCH!
[STATIONS SCANNING]
¶ ROLLIN' ON BACK
JUST THE SAME ¶
¶ ROLL, BLACK WATER
¶ KEEP ON ROLLIN'
¶ MISSISSIPPI MOON
¶ WON'T YOU KEEP ON
SHININ' ON ME? ¶
¶ ROLL, BLACK WATER
¶ KEEP ON ROLLIN'
¶ MISSISSIPPI MOON
¶ WON'T YOU KEEP ON
SHININ' ON ME? ¶
¶ ROLL, BLACK WATER
¶ KEEP ON ROLLIN'
¶ MISSISSIPPI MOON
¶ WON'T YOU KEEP ON
SHININ' ON ME? ¶
¶ YEAH, KEEP ON
SHININ' YOUR LIGHT ¶
¶ GONNA MAKE EVERYTHIN',
PRETTY MAMA... ¶
HEY.
WHAT SAY WE DO
A LITTLE FISHING
WHEN
THE CONTRACT'S OVER?
WHEN THIS CONTRACT'S
OVER, HUH?
IT'S WHAT WE NEED--
ONE OF OUR
CAMPING TRIPS.
SOME HUNTING,
SOME FISHING,
CHASING BEARS.
OH, YEAH.
I REMEMBER.
YOU RAN THAT BEAR
UP THAT TREE.
JUST TRYING
TO MAKE FRIENDS.
SO, HOW COME YOU CAN'T
MAKE FRIENDS WITH DALLIS?
HE'S JUST JEALOUS
I CAN DO SOMETHING
HE CAN'T.
WHAT'S THAT?
READ AND WRITE.
SO, WHAT DO YOU SAY?
A LITTLE R AND R
THEN...MT MOTORS.
YOU THINK I'D LET
A FLAKE LIKE YOU
MARRY MY LITTLE SISTER?
A FLAKE FROM SNOWFLAKE.
HOW POETIC. I LIKE THAT.
THAT'S JUST MY POINT.
WHAT'S YOUR POINT?
YOU'RE A DREAMER,
AND YOU'RE NOT
READY FOR MARRIAGE.
NOT IF I GOT TO
TURN INTO YOU, MIKE.
WE WENT BACK TO WORK,
AND WE FINISHED UP
ALONG ABOUT DUSK.
THE DAY'S WORK
WAS DONE,
AND THE FIVE OF YOU
LEFT THE WORK SITE.
SIX. THERE WAS
SIX OF US.
TRAVIS WALTON
LEFT WITH YOU?
OF COURSE.
THE REST OF YOU BOYS
GO ALONG WITH THAT?
YES.
HOW ABOUT YOU,
MR. DALLIS?
DO YOU GO ALONG
WITH THAT?
OH, YEAH, I GO
ALONG WITH THAT.
YOU DON'T SOUND
TOO SURE.
WELL, I'M SURE.
WHAT'S IT TO YOU?
OH, IT JUST SEEMS
LIKE YOU HAD
THE BIGGEST AX TO GRIND
WITH TRAVIS.
WHAT WAS THAT WHOLE THING
WITH THAT CHAIN SAW?
I WAS JUST
HAVING SOME FUN.
THAT'S ALL.
ARE YOU GOING TO
ARREST ME FOR THAT?
WHAT HAPPENED
TO YOUR HAND?
UH...
I DID IT TO MYSELF
EARLIER TODAY.
JUST HAVING A LITTLE FUN?
YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT.
I WAS JUST HAVING
A LITTLE FUN.
YOU OUGHT TO BE
MORE CAREFUL, SON.
YEAH, WELL...
I'LL DO MY BEST,
DADDY.
I BET YOU WILL.
WHY DON'T
YOU FELLAS TELL
LIEUTENANT WATTERS
WHAT YOU SAW
OR WHAT YOU
THINK YOU SAW?
IT WAS DALLIS
WHO SAW IT FIRST.
WHAT ABOUT IT?
TELL US ABOUT IT.
WHAT'D YOU SEE?
WHAT DID IT LOOK LIKE?
IT LOOKED LIKE,
UH...
LIKE A FIRE.
¶ I WON'T BE
THE GUEST OF HONOR ¶
¶ AT YOUR PARTY
TONIGHT ¶
¶ YOU CAN FIND
SOMEBODY ELSE ¶
YOU AWAKE?
I'M AWAKE.
¶ ...YOUR PARTY LIGHTS
¶ AND I HOPE
YOU HAVE A GOOD TIME ¶
¶ I HOPE
THEY TREAT YOU RIGHT ¶
WHAT THE HELL
IS THAT?
¶ AT YOUR PARTY
TONIGHT... ¶
THAT IS STRANGE.
WHAT IS?
WHAT ARE YOU GUYS
LOOKING AT?
LOOKS LIKE
THE SUNSET TO ME.
NO, GREG.
THAT'S EAST.
THE SUN SET BEHIND US
20 MINUTES AGO.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
IT IS, THEN?
OH...MAYBE A FIRE
OR MAYBE A PLANE CRASH
IN THE WOODS.
YEAH, A PLANE CRASH.
IT COULD BE.
A CRASH, BOBBY.
HEY, WHAT THE HELL
IS THAT?
MAYBE WE SHOULD
JUST TURN BACK.
THAT'S--THAT'S GOT
TO BE A FIRE.
LOOK! IT'S MOVING.
I SAW IT.
IT ISN'T MOVING,
BOBBY.
LOOK, MAN!
IS IT?
[TRAVIS] THAT'S ONE
MONSTER FOREST FIRE.
[DALLIS]
YEAH, FIRE, MY ASS.
THAT AIN'T
NO FIRE, MAN.
WHAT ELSE
COULD IT BE?
[STATIC ON RADIO]
WHAT THE HECK'S
GOING ON HERE?
ARE YOU SCREWING AROUND?
NO.
MIKE, MAYBE WE OUGHT
TO DO LIKE GREG SAYS
AND JUST PULL OVER
FOR A MINUTE.
NO. I WANT TO SEE
WHAT IT IS.
THERE'S ONLY ONE ROAD
OUT OF HERE,
AND WE'RE ON IT.
IF THAT'S A FIRE,
AND WE CAN'T GET AROUND,
WE'LL BE SPENDING
THE NIGHT OUT HERE.
MIKE...
STOP! STOP THE TRUCK!
[DALLIS]
THAT'S WILD.
HOLY CHRIST!
TRAVIS!
YOU SON OF A BITCH!
WHAT THE HELL
YOU DOING?
GET BACK IN THE TRUCK,
ASSHOLE!
WHAT IS THAT?
WHAT IS THAT THING?
OH, MY GOD!
TRAVIS!
WHAT THE HELL'S
HE DOING OUT THERE?
WHAT THE HELL IS THAT?
TRAVIS! GET BACK
IN THE TRUCK!
GET OUT OF THERE!
WHAT IS THAT?
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT THAT IS.
HEY, MIKE!
GET OUT OF THERE!
LEAVE HIM HERE IF HE'S
GOING TO BE AN ASSHOLE!
TRAVIS,
GET BACK HERE!
TRAVIS!
RUN, TRAVIS!
RUN!
[RUMBLING]
WHAT THE HELL'S THAT?
YOU FEEL THAT?
TRAVIS!
GET OUT OF HERE!
GET BACK
IN HERE!
TRAVIS,
COME ON!
WHOA!
TRAVIS!
HE'S--
HE'S, UH...
HE'S--HE'S...
OH.
GO!
MIKE, HE'S DEAD!
HE'S DEAD!
OH, MIKE, HE'S GONE!
I'M NOT
LEAVING HIM.
HE'S DEAD!
GET OUT OF HERE. GO!
GET THE HELL
OF OUT HERE!
HE'S DEAD!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
COME ON!
HE'S DEAD!
GET THE HELL
OUT OF HERE.
GO!
AAH!
GET THE HELL OUT
OF HERE, MAN.
HE'S DEAD!
IT'S MOVING.
IT'S COMING AFTER US!
IT'S GOING
TO KILL US.
STAY DOWN. STAY DOWN.
EVERYBODY STAY DOWN.
SLOW DOWN, MIKE!
WHAT THE HECK
IS THAT THING?
I DON'T KNOW!
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT IT IS.
OH, NO!
OH, MY GOD!
WHAT WAS IT?
LOOK OUT, MIKE!
YOU'RE GOING TO KILL US.
IS IT FOLLOWING US?
I DON'T KNOW.
I CAN'T SEE IT.
SHUT UP!
OH, LOOK OUT!
UHH!
COME ON, MAN!
GET OFF ME!
OH!
WHAT THE HELL
YOU STOPPING FOR?
WE LEFT HIM THERE.
WELL, HE'S DEAD,
JACKASS!
WE GOT TO GO BACK.
NO WAY!
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
MAYBE WE DO
GOT TO GO BACK.
NO WAY!
WE GOT TO GO BACK!
WE DON'T KNOW
THAT HE'S DEAD.
GET OUTTA HERE.
IT'LL COME AFTER US!
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
I'M GOING BACK!
IF YOU
DON'T WANT TO GO,
GET OUT OF THE CAR NOW.
I'LL PICK YOU UP LATER.
YOU CAN'T
DO THIS TO US.
WHAT IF YOU
DON'T COME BACK?
GET OUT.
GO, MAN.
YOU GOT TO GO.
GET OUT.
IT'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
YOU STAY BY THE ROAD.
[BIRD SCREECHES]
SON OF A BITCH.
I, UM...
I SEARCHED
THE WOODS AND...
BUT HE WASN'T...
THERE WAS NOTHING.
THEY TOOK HIM.
YOU EXPECT ME TO BELIEVE
THAT A FLYING SAUCER
CAME DOWN
AND TOOK YOUR FRIEND AWAY...
TO OUTER SPACE?
THAT'S THE TRUTH, MISTER.
THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT HAPPENED.
IS IT?
ACCORDING TO YOUR STORY,
YOU NEVER EVEN WENT
BACK TO THE CLEARING,
SO YOU DON'T KNOW,
DO YOU?
I DIDN'T
HAVE TO GO BACK.
MIKE SAYS
HE WASN'T THERE,
YOU CAN TAKE IT
TO THE BANK.
YOU KNOW THAT, BLAKE.
WHY AREN'T YOU
SPEAKING UP FOR US?
WHY ARE YOU LETTING HIM
TALK TO US LIKE THIS?
DAVID, I--
IT SEEMS LIKE YOU'RE NOT EVEN
TRYING TO BELIEVE US.
WE ALL SAW THE THING.
WE ALL SAW THE GUY
GET ZAPPED.
YOU SAW SOMETHING...
AT LEAST,
YOU THOUGHT YOU DID.
AND WHAT ABOUT YOU, SON?
ME?
WHAT DID YOU SEE?
I SAW--I SAW THE SAME...
SAME AS THEY SAW.
WELL, THAT'S
QUITE A STORY.
YEAH, WELL...
I THINK
IT'S ABOUT TIME
TO GET OUT OF HERE.
WHAT DO
YOU BOYS THINK?
YOU'RE REAL BROKEN UP
ABOUT YOUR MISSING BUDDY.
OH, THAT'S VERY PERCEPTIVE.
THAT'S 'CAUSE
HE'S NOT MY FRIEND.
I GOT THAT...
CLEARLY.
DID YOU?
GOOD.
NOW ARE YOU DONE?
WE'LL TELL YOU WHEN.
I DON'T WANT
ANYBODY TO LEAVE
TILL I GET EVERYBODY'S
PHONE NUMBER
AND ADDRESS.
SHOULDN'T WE TRY
TO FIND HIM?
HE'S NOT ON THE MOUNTAIN,
REMEMBER?
THEY TOOK HIM.
AH, WHAT DO YOU THINK?
THINK WE OUGHT
TO HEAD UP THERE?
[BLAKE]
IT'S TOO LATE.
NOT ENOUGH MEN.
WE'LL HEAD OUT
IN THE MORNING.
WELL, DALLIS,
YOU SURE CAN TALK.
I TOLD YOU
HE WOULDN'T BELIEVE
YOUR STORY,
NOT A GOD DAMN
WORD OF IT.
THAT TRUCK LOOKS LIKE
IT'S BEEN TO HELL AND BACK.
WELL, THE SUN COMES UP
AT 6:00 IN THE MORNING.
WE GOT FIFTY MEN,
JEEPS, HORSES, DOGS.
I'LL CALL FLAGSTAFF
AND GET TWO HELICOPTERS.
WILL THAT BE ENOUGH?
THAT'S PLENTY.
MY HUNCH
IS TOMORROW
WE'LL FIND
TRAVIS WALTON.
I'D BE SURPRISED
IF WE FOUND HIM
IN ONE PIECE.
YEAH.
YOU RECOMMEND A GOOD
MOTEL, SHERIFF?
YEAH. CHAPARRAL.
JUST AFTER YOU GET
INSIDE OF SNOWFLAKE,
RIGHT THERE
BY THE WATER TOWER.
STILL, YOU
HAVE TO WONDER
HOW THOSE BOYS CAME UP
WITH SUCH A CRAZY STORY.
YEAH.
BACK ON EARTH, WE'RE
DEALING WITH A MURDER,
PLAIN AND SIMPLE.
GOOD NIGHT, SHERIFF.
YEAH. GOOD NIGHT, FRANK.
[RADIO PLAYS]
IT'S ALL OVER THE RADIO.
THEY'RE MAKING IT OUT
TO BE A BIG JOKE
OR SOMETHING.
IT'S NO JOKE.
YOU LEFT HIM THERE?
I DON'T KNOW
WHERE HE IS, DANA.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN, YOU
DON'T KNOW WHERE HE IS?
JUST WHAT I SAID.
WELL, HOW COULD YOU JUST
LEAVE HIM OUT THERE?
THE RADIO WAS
SAYING SOMETHING
ABOUT
OUTER SPACE.
I DIDN'T JUST LEAVE HIM,
AND YEAH. THERE WAS
SOMETHING OUT THERE, KATE.
I--I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
"OUT THERE"?
IS TRAVIS GONE?
THEY'RE GOING TO
SEND OUT A SEARCH PARTY
FOR HIM TOMORROW.
WHERE IS HE, MIKE?
MIKE.
IT'S OK.
HE'S GOING TO BE OK.
IT'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
[SOBBING]
MY FATHER IN HEAVEN...
I HUMBLY BOW BEFORE YOU.
I ASK FOR YOUR SPIRIT
TO BE WITH ME.
FORGIVE US, FATHER,
FOR WHAT WE'VE DONE.
[HELICOPTER]
[YELPING]
CHECK THE ROAD THERE!
I WANT TWO-MEN TEAMS
ON THAT RIDGE.
IF THAT BOY'S OUT HERE,
I WANT TO FIND HIM.
YOU GOT IT?
GOT IT.
LET'S GET GOING, BOYS,
AND GOD BLESS YOU.
OK.
YOU'RE CERTAIN
THIS IS THE SPOT.
I MEAN, IT WAS NIGHT,
BUT--BUT, YEAH.
THIS IS EXACTLY
WHERE HE FELL.
YOU SAID THERE WAS
AN OBVIOUS DEPRESSION,
THAT WE COULD
SEE IT CLEARLY.
THIS IS IT,
RIGHT HERE!
WHERE THE HELL WAS IT?
WAS IT OVER THERE?
WAS IT OVER HERE?
WHAT ARE WE DOING,
PLAYING GAMES?
I'M NOT SURE.
I SEE.
HEY, ED,
CHECK THERE!
ALL RIGHT!
HE DOESN'T
BELIEVE US.
WHERE'S MY BROTHER,
MIKE?
WHAT DID YOU GUYS
DO WITH HIM?
DAN, TAKE IT EASY.
BACK OFF, WHITLOCK!
HEY, WE'RE GOING
TO FIND HIM, DAN.
WHICH ONE OF YOU
IS ALLAN DALLIS?
HE'S NOT HERE.
WHAT ABOUT HIM?
I DID SOME CHECKING.
YOUR HIRED HAND'S
GOT HIMSELF A NICE
LITTLE CRIMINAL RECORD--
ASSAULT WITH
A DEADLY WEAPON.
LISTEN, MIKE,
IF ANYTHING'S HAPPENED
TO MY BABY BRO,
I'M HOLDING YOU
PERSONALLY RESPONSIBLE.
YOU GOT THAT?
UH, YEAH.
[DOGS BARKING]
GIVE ME A BREAK.
I CAME UP HERE
TO EARN MONEY.
NOW I MIGHT
GO TO PRISON.
MAYBE IT'S GOD'S WAY
OF PUNISHING US.
SPARE ME THE GOD TALK.
EVEN IF
YOU DON'T BELIEVE,
YOU KNOW
THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN
RIGHT AND WRONG.
WE ALL DO.
WE GOT NO EXCUSES.
WHAT?
WHAT IS THAT?
APACHE RESERVATION
STARTS RIGHT UP THERE.
RIGHT THERE.
HEY, WE GOT SOMETHING
OVER HERE!
OVER HERE THEY THINK
THERE'S SOMETHING.
[YELPING]
DO YOU
SEE ANYTHING?
DID YOU FIND
ANYTHING YET?
I DON'T KNOW.
WONDER WHAT
THEY'LL FIND IN THERE.
YOU GOT ANY IDEAS, MIKE?
THERE'S SOMETHING HERE,
SHERIFF.
IS IT WALTON?
IT'S HIM.
I KNEW IT.
THEY KILLED HIM.
WHAT IS IT?
QUIT DIGGING.
IT AIN'T HUMAN, FRANK.
SOME HUNTER
BURIED HIS DOG.
AW!
I THOUGHT
THAT WAS HIM.
DANA'S STAYING OVER
AT THE WALTON'S HOUSE.
SOME GUY FROM
THE A.L.I. CALLED TODAY.
THEY'RE TAKING
YOU OFF THE CONTRACT
AND HIRED
A WHOLE NEW CREW.
YOU DON'T SEEM
TOO SURPRISED.
I'M NOT.
WELL, WHY AREN'T YOU?
WHAT ARE WE
GOING TO DO
FOR A PAYCHECK
NEXT WEEK?
I'LL FIGURE IT OUT,
ALL RIGHT?
I DON'T GET THIS.
MY BEST FRIEND
HAS DISAPPEARED.
GOD KNOWS WHERE HE IS,
AND ALL YOU CAN
THINK ABOUT IS MONEY.
I'LL TELL YOU
SOMETHING ELSE.
PEOPLE IN THIS TOWN
ARE SAYING TERRIBLE
THINGS ABOUT YOU.
I DON'T CARE
WHAT THEY THINK.
I DO. WE LIVE HERE!
OUR KIDS LIVE HERE!
OF COURSE I CARE,
AND SO SHOULD YOU!
MOMMY.
HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY.
YOU KNOW WHAT? LISTEN.
GO BACK TO BED.
I PROMISE I'LL
READ YOU THAT STORY.
I PROMISE. OK?
OK. DON'T LET
THOSE BEDBUGS BITE.
WHAT'S SHE
GOING TO SAY, HUH,
WHEN EVERYBODY SAYS HER
FATHER'S A LIAR OR A...
GO ON. SAY IT.
A LIAR OR A MURDERER.
INCLUDING YOU?
ARE YOU SAYING THAT,
KATE?
NO.
OF COURSE NOT.
I JUST, MICHAEL--
I JUST WANT YOU
TO TELL ME
WHAT REALLY HAPPENED
UP THERE.
I--I TOLD YOU
WHAT HAPPENED.
I TOLD YOU
ALL I KNOW.
YOU BELIEVE ME,
DON'T YOU, KATE?
YOU DO BELIEVE ME?
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
HELLO? YES, THIS
IS PILOT 5-1-0-9-8.
WHAT IS IT?
YOU KNOW, MIKE,
THE WORD'S OUT.
WELL, WHAT WORD
WOULD THAT BE, TOM?
OH, I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S JUST I BEEN
GETTING CALLS ALL DAY
FROM HERE TO TIMBUKTU.
AS OF TOMORROW,
I'M ALL BOOKED UP.
WELL, WHO'S CALLING?
REPORTERS, SIGHTSEERS,
UFO BUFFS, AND THE LIKE.
HEY, MIKE...
WHAT'S REALLY
GOING ON HERE?
CAN YOU
KEEP A SECRET, TOM?
YOU BET.
DON'T TELL ANYONE
I'M HERE.
MR. ROGERS.
I FEEL LIKE ASKING YOU
IF IT'S A BEAUTIFUL DAY
IN YOUR NEIGHBORHOOD.
UH, RAY MELENDEZ,
ACTION NEWS, PHOENIX.
HOW ARE YOU?
LOOK, I JUST WOKE UP.
THAT'S NO PROBLEM.
I JUST NEED TO ASK A FEW
QUESTIONS. WHAT DO YOU SAY?
I GOT NOTHING TO SAY.
I FIGURED YOU'D WANT TO
SET THE RECORD STRAIGHT
WHAT WITH EVERYTHING
THAT'S BEING SAID
ABOUT YOU AND ALL.
YOU KNOW, IT'S--
WELL, YOU FIGURED WRONG.
IT'S FOR YOUR OWN GOOD.
JUST TALK TO THE PEOPLE.
LET THEM KNOW
WHAT REALLY HAPPENED.
WHAT DO YOU SAY?
COME ON.
COME HERE, GUYS.
I THINK IT'S HIM.
IS THAT HIM?
I THINK SO.
EXCUSE ME, MR. ROGERS,
MR. WHITLOCK.
I'M JARVIS POWELL
FROM A.F.A.R.
WE, UH, HAVE HAD A LOT OF
EXPERIENCE IN THESE MATTERS.
I THINK WE MIGHT BE ABLE
TO HELP EACH OTHER OUT.
AHEM.
WELL, UH, WE JUST
WANTED TO LET YOU KNOW
THERE ARE THOSE OF US
OUT THERE WHO KNOW THE TRUTH.
GO ON.
PLEASE GIVE US A CALL
IF WE CAN BE OF SERVICE.
LET'S GO.
ANYTIME.
HOW MUCH
I OWE YOU, EARL?
$3.00.
BETTY.
THESE BOYS KNOW MORE
THAN THEY'RE TELLING.
WHAT THE HECK'S
THAT LOWLIFE
BUCK MORTON
STARING AT?
HE KEEPS
LOOKING OVER HERE.
MIKE, THIS TOWN'S
GONE NUTS.
EVERYTHING'S CRAZY.
YEAH. NOW THAT
WE'RE TV NEWS.
THEY'RE GOING UP TO
LOOK FOR TRAVIS AGAIN.
THEY WON'T FIND
ANYTHING.
WATTERS COME BY.
AT 6 A.M.,
HE STARTS ASKING
ALL THESE QUESTIONS.
HE'S ALL OVER US, MAN.
HE SAID
IF WE COOPERATED--
COME ON.
IF WE CONFESS.
CONFESS?
YEAH.
IF WE CONFESS,
HE'S GOING TO TRY
TO HELP US OUT.
HELP US?
WHAT THE HELL'S
GOING ON AROUND HERE?
YOU GOT SOMETHING YOU
WANT TO SAY TO ME?
GO SIT DOWN, BUCK.
HOT FOOD
COMING THROUGH.
YOU BOYS WANT
TO REMEDY THIS,
WE CAN STEP OUTSIDE
RIGHT NOW.
YOU GOT TO BE KIDDING ME,
YOU FAT PIECE OF SHIT.
YOU LITTLE
SON OF A BITCH.
GET OFF OF ME! GET OFF!
CALM DOWN.
SON OF A BITCH.
BACK AWAY FROM THERE
AND LET MISS IDA
THROUGH WITH THAT FOOD.
GOD ALMIGHTY.
GET OVER THERE AND
DRINK THAT COFFEE
BEFORE IT GETS COLD.
HOW ARE
YOU BOYS TODAY?
ANYTHING, MIKE?
[BLAKE]
HOW'S MY BOY?
NO. THANKS, IDA.
SIT DOWN, DAVID. SIT DOWN.
COOL DOWN, FELLAS.
LISTEN, FELLAS,
I WANT YOU ALL TO KNOW
THAT THERE'S NOT A DAMN
THING PERSONAL IN THIS.
NOW, WHERE'S YOUR FRIEND?
WHICH ONE?
COME ON, MIKE.
THE ONE
WITH THE ATTITUDE.
IF YOU MEAN DALLIS,
I DON'T KNOW.
WE GOT A PROPOSITION
FOR Y'ALL.
I WANT YOU TO TAKE
A LIE DETECTOR TEST.
IF YOU'RE
TELLING THE TRUTH,
IT'LL SURE
STRENGTHEN YOUR CAUSE.
WE'LL THINK ABOUT IT.
I GOT A GOOD MAN RIGHT
HERE IN THE STATE.
TAKE IT TODAY, TOMORROW,
ANYTIME Y'ALL FEEL LIKE IT.
I SAID WE'LL
THINK ABOUT IT!
WHY DON'T WE HAVE
A LITTLE TALK, MIKE,
HUH...OUTSIDE?
YOUNG GREG
TOLD US THE TRUTH
ABOUT THE CUT
ON DALLIS' HAND.
IT WASN'T A PAPER CUT,
WAS IT?
HE HAD AN ALTERCATION
WITH TRAVIS
ON THE DAY OF
THE DISAPPEARANCE, TRUE?
I GUESS.
AND I THINK YOU'RE
STARTING TO GET
A PRETTY GOOD FEEL
FOR WHO I AM.
I'VE BEEN AT
THIS LINE OF WORK
FOR A LONG TIME.
YOU KNOW WHAT'S
STARTING TO BUG ME?
I THINK MAYBE YOU
DIDN'T KILL YOUR FRIEND.
BUT FOR THE LIFE OF ME,
I CAN'T FIGURE
WHY YOU'RE COVERING UP.
WHAT THE HECK'S
HE WANT?
I DON'T KNOW.
LET'S GO.
WHERE WE GOING?
TO FIND DALLIS.
DALLIS? I THOUGHT YOU
DON'T KNOW WHERE HE IS.
I LIED.
ALL RIGHT, I'M--I'M
GOING TO RAISE YOU 2.
I'M GOING
TO RAISE YOU.
CAN'T YOU SPEAK
AMERICAN, PLEASE?
[SPEAKING
SPANISH]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
WELL?
I HEARD
WHAT'S BEEN HAPPENING
IN THAT STUPID LITTLE
MORMON TOWN OF YOURS.
I TOLD YOU CHUCKLEHEADS
THAT STORY WAS NEVER
GOING TO WORK, DIDN'T I?
THEY TOOK AWAY OUR
LOGGING CONTRACT, DALLIS.
DO YOU KNOW THAT?
THAT FIGURES.
THEY'RE A BUNCH
OF CHICKEN-SHIT ASSHOLES.
SPEAKING OF
CHICKEN SHIT,
WHERE YOU BEEN?
I'VE BEEN AROUND.
YOU KNEW WHERE TO FIND ME,
DIDN'T YOU, MIKE?
DAVIS AND WATTERS
ARE LOOKING FOR YOU.
THEY KNOW ABOUT
YOUR CRIMINAL RECORD,
THAT YOU LIED ABOUT
HOW YOU HURT YOUR HAND.
YOU'RE JUST FULL
OF INFORMATION.
IT DON'T MAKE US
LOOK GOOD WHEN YOU--
IT DON'T?
THAT'S TOO DAMN BAD,
AIN'T IT?
NO, IT DON'T!
IT DON'T!
THEY WANT US TO TAKE
A LIE DETECTOR TEST.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
ABOUT IT?
YOU WANT TO KNOW
WHAT I THINK ABOUT IT?
THAT'S RIGHT.
I'LL TELL YOU
WHAT I THINK.
I THINK THOSE DEVICES
ARE VERY DANGEROUS, MAN.
THAT MACHINE SAYS YOU LIED,
IT DON'T MATTER
IF YOU TOLD THE TRUTH,
YOU LIED!
IT MIGHT CLEAR US,
THOUGH.
OH, IT MIGHT CLEAR YOU.
YOU KNOW, THEY DON'T
NEED A--A BODY
TO PRESS MURDER CHARGES,
DID YOU KNOW THAT?
AND THEY AIN'T NEVER
GOING TO FIND TRAVIS,
WE KNOW THAT, RIGHT?
THE PRESSURE'S ON
DAVIS AND WATTERS
TO SOLVE THE CASE.
WHO DO YOU THINK
THEY'LL ZERO IN ON?
WHAT, YOU, CHOIRBOY, HUH?
GOD WILL SEND A SWARM
OF LOCUST DOWN ON THEM.
YOU, MR. PILLAR
OF THE COMMUNITY?
NO. I DON'T THINK SO.
NO, THE QUESTION IS HOW LONG
BEFORE YOU BOYS DECIDE
TO SAVE YOUR WHITE ASSES
AND POINT THE FINGER AT ME?
THAT'S A LOAD OF CRUD.
NO! THAT'S EXACTLY THE WAY
IT'S GOING TO BE!
IF WE DECIDE
TO TAKE THIS LIE
DETECTOR TEST...
WE ALL TAKE IT.
DON'T YOU POINT
YOUR FINGER AT ME.
ALL RIGHT, MIKE!
COME ON!
ALL RIGHT!
ALL RIGHT.
STOP.
ALL RIGHT, DALLIS.
YOU JUST BE THERE.
THAT WAS NICE.
THAT FELT GOOD.
JUST BE THERE.
BE THERE.
THE STORY HAS DRAWN
INTERNATIONAL ATTENTION,
AND THE CONTROVERSY
SURROUNDING WALTON'S
DISAPPEARANCE
HAS REACHED
THE BOILING POINT.
I'VE HAD ENOUGH
OF THIS.
I'M GOING DOWN THERE.
IN THE FOUR DAYS
WALTON'S BEEN MISSING...
SURE YOU WANT
TO DO THAT?
HAVE DESCENDED
ON SLEEPY SNOWFLAKE,
AND THE LOCALS
AREN'T PLEASED.
RAY MELENDEZ HAS MORE.
THE WHITE MOUNTAINS--
APACHE LEGEND TELLS
OF EVIL SPIRITS
WHICH FREQUENTED
THIS PLACE,
DROPPING DOWN FROM THE SKY
TO KIDNAP CHILDREN.
THE FIVE MEN IN QUESTION
STILL HAVEN'T SPOKEN
TO THE PRESS.
LAW ENFORCEMENT AUTHORITIES
ARE DESPERATELY TRYING
TO GET TO THE BOTTOM
OF THIS MYSTERY.
IT'S BEEN FOUR DAYS NOW
SINCE TRAVIS WALTON
DISAPPEARED WITHOUT A TRACE,
AND THE CASE IS ATTRACTING
MAJOR INTERNATIONAL ATTENTION.
LAW CAN'T
GET THEM TO TALK.
I KNOW SOME FOLKS
THAT DAMN WELL CAN.
[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
IN THIS LOCAL
MOUNTAIN COMMUNITY,
THE OVERRIDING QUESTION
REMAINS--
WHAT REALLY DID HAPPEN
THAT NIGHT,
AND WHERE
IS TRAVIS WALTON?
A CONCERNED TOWN HAS CALLED
A MEETING TONIGHT
AT THEIR CHURCH TO DISCUSS
THESE VERY QUESTIONS.
THOUGH THEY WON'T
COMMENT PUBLICLY,
HOMICIDE IS A WORD
THAT IS HEARD ON THE LIPS
OF LOCAL INVESTIGATORS.
RAY MELENDEZ,
ACTION NEWS.
THANKS, RAY.
IN OTHER NEWS,
THE STOCK--
SHERIFF, WE'VE BEEN COMBING
THOSE WOODS FOR DAYS NOW.
THE TOWN'S GETTING
A BAD NAME.
MY KIDS ARE SCARED
FROM ALL THIS
SILLY UFO NONSENSE--
ALL THESE STRANGERS WANDERING
AROUND ASKING QUESTIONS.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING
TO DO ABOUT IT?
MA'AM, EVERYBODY'S AWFUL
CONCERNED ABOUT THIS.
NOBODY'S MORE CONCERNED
THAN ME AND MY MEN.
THEY'RE WORKING
24 HOURS A DAY
ON THIS MATTER.
WE WANT TO GET BACK
TO NORMAL IN THIS TOWN,
IF WE CAN.
ONE THING
I WANT YOU TO KNOW
WE'VE ASKED
THOSE YOUNG MEN
TO TAKE
A LIE DETECTOR TEST,
AND THEY
FLATLY REFUSED.
WHAT GOOD'S THAT
GOING TO DO, ANYHOW?
IF THERE'S BEEN
FOUL PLAY,
WE NEED TO KNOW NOW THAT
OUR TOWN'S SAFE TO LIVE IN.
WHY HAVEN'T YOU
MADE ANY ARRESTS?
COME ON, NATE,
THINK IT THROUGH.
THERE'S NOT ONE
SCINTILLA OF EVIDENCE
THAT A CRIME'S
EVEN BEEN COMMITTED.
EVERYBODY'S GOT A PRETTY
GOOD IDEA WHAT HAPPENED.
HEY, HOLD IT. YOU JUST...
HOLD IT RIGHT THERE.
WHAT ARE YOU PEOPLE
TRYING TO SAY?
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING,
GEORGE?
ARE YOU SAYING
I KILLED TRAVIS WALTON?
YOU REALLY
DISAPPOINT ME.
I WENT TO SCHOOL
WITH YOU, NATE.
MY MARY, SHE'S AT SCHOOL
WITH YOUR KIDS.
JACK,
LARRY,
MRS. PRATT...
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I MISS TRAVIS...
JUST LIKE YOU.
I--I MISS HIM BAD,
BUT I--I CAN'T HELP
WHAT HAPPENED.
I--I CAN'T CHANGE
WHAT I SAW.
I WISH I COULD.
I WISH--I WISH
WE HAD HIM BACK.
I--I WISH I KNEW--
I WISH I KNEW
HE WAS OK,
BUT THAT'S
OUT OF MY HANDS
AND SO IS WHAT
YOU THINK OF ME.
WE'VE BEEN TELLING YOU
THE TRUTH
SINCE THE BEGINNING.
AND NOW WE'RE READY
TO PROVE IT.
WE'LL TAKE YOUR DAMN
LIE DETECTOR TEST.
YOU SET IT UP. WE'LL
BE THERE. YOU GO AHEAD,
AND IF ANY OF YOU
GOT ANYTHING TO SAY
ABOUT ME OR MY CREW,
YOU SAY IT NOW,
AND YOU SAY IT
TO MY FACE.
THERE THEY ARE.
THAT'S THEM.
MIKE, WHOSE IDEA WAS
THE LIE DETECTOR TEST?
DID YOU KILL TRAVIS?
DID YOU REALLY
SEE ALIENS UP THERE?
DID YOU KILL
TRAVIS WALTON?
GIVE HIM SOME ROOM.
BACK OFF! BACK OFF!
YOU WERE TOLD
TO BE HERE AT 9:00.
YEAH, WELL,
WE WEREN'T.
FELLAS, MEET CY GILSON.
HE CAME
FROM PHOENIX
TO BE SURE YOU GET
A GOOD TEST.
HOW DO WE
KNOW THAT?
I GUARANTEE IT.
WORDS ARE CHEAP.
HOW DO WE KNOW
IT'S GOING TO BE FAIR?
I GIVE MY WORD.
WE CAN'T TRUST ANYONE,
MAN.
EVERYTHING WE SAY HAS BEEN
TWISTED ALL TO HELL.
THIS WHOLE TOWN
WANTS TO SEE US FALL.
BLAKE, YOU KNOW THAT.
I DON'T CARE
WHETHER
YOU PASS OR NOT.
IF YOU'RE LYING, MY
MACHINE'LL SHOW IT.
IF YOU'RE CLEAN,
IT'LL SHOW THAT.
HOW DO WE KNOW
YOU AIN'T BEEN BOUGHT OFF
TO MAKE US LOOK BAD?
CY GILSON'S
THE BEST THERE IS.
YOU'RE LUCKY TO HAVE HIM.
WELL, IF YOU SAY SO,
IT'S GOOD ENOUGH FOR ME.
THE POINT IS,
YOU CAN TRUST HIM.
WELL, I TRUST
YOU, BLAKE.
WILL YOU GIVE US
YOUR WORD
THIS TEST
WILL BE FAIR?
THAT'S EASY.
YOU GOT IT.
ALL RIGHT.
IS YOUR NAME
GREGORY THOMAS HAYES?
YES.
WERE YOU BORN
IN CORONA, NEW MEXICO?
YES.
ARE YOU CURRENTLY
SINGLE?
YES.
IS MY SHIRT WHITE?
FACE AROUND FRONT.
SOME OF IT'S WHITE.
YES OR NO?
NO.
FIVE DAYS AGO ABOUT
SUNDOWN ON RIM ROAD,
DID YOU SEE
AN UNIDENTIFIED LIGHT
JUST ABOVE
THE TREE LINE?
YES.
DID YOU SEE AN OBJECT
HOVERING ABOVE
THE CLEARING?
YES.
WAS IT SAUCER-SHAPED?
SORT OF.
I DON'T--
I NEVER SEEN
ANYTHING EXACTLY
LIKE IT BEFORE.
YES OR NO?
I'D HAVE TO SAY NO.
DID YOU SEE TRAVIS WALTON
APPROACH THE OBJECT
ON FOOT?
YEAH.
YEAH, I DID.
DID YOU SEE A BOLT
OF BLUE-GREEN LIGHT
ENVELOPE
TRAVIS WALTON?
YEAH. MAN.
I TOLD THEM
IT EXPLODED
ALL AROUND HIM.
DID YOU BELIEVE
TRAVIS WAS KILLED
BY THE RAY OF LIGHT?
NOW, HOW DO I KNOW?
I JUST KNOW THAT
I DIDN'T KILL HIM.
DID YOU PERSONALLY
DISLIKE TRAVIS WALTON?
WHAT KIND
OF QUESTION IS THAT?
HUH?
A SIMPLE YES OR NO
WILL DO.
YES...
AND NO.
HAVE YOU WITHHELD
ANY PERTINENT INFORMATION
REGARDING THE DISAPPEARANCE
OF TRAVIS WALTON?
NO.
DID YOU CREATE
THIS INCIDENT
TO GET OUT OF
YOUR LOGGING CONTRACT?
NO.
DID YOU
OR ANY OF YOUR CREW
MURDER TRAVIS WALTON?
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
¶ BAH BAH BUM BUM
¶ BAM
[DOOR OPENS]
WELL,
WHAT'S THE WORD?
WELL, THE RESULTS
OF ONE OF THE TESTS
WAS UNUSUAL.
IT'S INCONCLUSIVE.
WE'LL HAVE TO TRY
AGAIN TOMORROW.
WELL, WHAT ABOUT
THE OTHER ONES?
WHAT'S
THE WORD ON THEM?
THE PROCESS
IS STILL ONGOING.
WE NEVER
DISCUSS THE RESULTS
TILL ALL THE TESTING
IS COMPLETE.
SORRY, FELLAS.
COME BACK DOWN
IN THE MORNING,
9:00 SHARP.
NO.
WHAT?
I SAID NO.
LOOK, WE DID
WHAT WE SAID WE'D DO.
WE--WE CAME IN HERE
LIKE GUINEA PIGS
AND LET YOU TEST US,
BUT WE'VE HAD ENOUGH.
I AIN'T
COMING BACK.
YOU'RE SAYING
YOU'RE NO LONGER
WILLING
TO COOPERATE.
IT'S ALL WE DO
IS COOPERATE,
AND ALL WE GET BACK
IS GRIEF.
MIKE, WE NEED TIME.
NO, FRANK, I'M
SICK OF THIS SHIT!
YOU WANT
TO PRESS CHARGES,
YOU GO AHEAD.
YOU DO IT NOW.
WE TOLD YOU
EVERYTHING WE KNOW.
IF THAT'S NOT
GOOD ENOUGH,
THAT'S TOO DAMN BAD,
'CAUSE THAT'S
ALL THERE IS.
LET'S GET THE HELL
OUT OF HERE.
WELL, DALLIS' CHART
WAS ALL OVER THE PLACE.
HE MUST'VE BEEN
KEYED UP OR SCARED.
IT'S UNREADABLE--
COMPLETELY UNREADABLE.
AS FOR THE OTHER FOUR,
SEE FOR YOURSELF.
THEY'RE PRETTY MUCH
THE SAME.
WHAT ARE YOU
SAYING, SON?
WELL, BLAKE,
MY CHARTS DON'T LIE.
IF YOU ASK ME,
THOSE BOYS
ARE TELLING THE TRUTH.
[THUNDER]
[DOOR OPENS]
DO YOU PLAN
ON SPENDING THE NIGHT?
YEAH, I WAS THINKING
ABOUT IT.
WHY? IS THAT GOING
TO BE A PROBLEM?
NO. DO WHATEVER
YOU WANT.
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
[RING]
HELLO?
WHOEVER'S DOING THIS,
IT'S NOT FUNNY.
I CAN'T
BELIEVE THIS.
ANOTHER CRANK CALL.
WE'VE BEEN GETTING
TWO AND THREE IN THE DAY.
NOW WE'RE GETTING THEM
ALL HOURS OF THE NIGHT.
[RING]
NOW LET ME GET THAT.
YEAH. WHO IS THIS?
I HAVE A COLLECT CALL
FROM TRAVIS WALTON.
WILL YOU
ACCEPT THE CHARGES?
JUST HANG UP
THE PHONE.
I'LL ACCEPT IT.
GO AHEAD, SIR.
[HOARSE VOICE]
MIKE.
TRAVIS?
HELP ME.
I'VE BEEN THROUGH HEBER.
I DON'T REMEMBER
ANY PHONE BOOTH.
HE SAID HE WAS CALLING
FROM A GAS STATION.
ARE YOU SURE
IT WAS HIM?
WHAT'S THAT
OVER THERE?
MIKE, I THINK THIS
MIGHT BE SOMEONE'S IDEA
OF A SICK JOKE.
WAIT A MINUTE.
THERE'S
A GAS STATION
NORTH OF HERE.
I DON'T THINK SO,
MIKE.
WELL, I KNOW SO.
WELL, YOU WERE RIGHT
ABOUT THE GAS STATION
AT LEAST.
I KNOW
THAT WAS TRAVIS.
IT SOUNDED
JUST LIKE HIM.
STOP. WAIT.
WHAT IS THAT?
RIGHT THERE. PULL OVER,
MIKE. PULL OVER!
DAVID, GRAB
THAT FLASHLIGHT.
GOT IT.
TRAVIS?
IT'S HIM. TRAVIS!
TRAVIS, ARE YOU OK?
AAH!
TRAVIS?
TRAVIS.
TRAVIS, IT'S US.
HEY, MAN.
TRAVIS, WHAT'S WRONG?
HEY, TRAVIS,
IT'S MIKE.
HEY, IT'S YOUR PARTNER.
YOU REMEMBER ME?
TRAVIS, YOUR PARTNER--
MT MOTORS.
HARLEYS.
YOU COLD, MAN?
TAKE IT EASY, BRO.
TAKE IT EASY.
DON'T TRY TO TALK.
TRAVIS.
WATER! WATER!
SOMEBODY GET HIM
SOME WATER.
I GOT IT.
EVERYTHING'S GOING TO BE
ALL RIGHT, TRAVIS.
HEY, DANA'S RIGHT HERE.
TRAVIS.
TRAVIS?
AAH!
TRAVIS.
THIS MUST BE THEM.
THEY'RE HERE.
MIKE.
FIVE DAYS, MAN.
IT'S BEEN FIVE DAYS.
TRAVIS, EVERYBODY'S
BEEN LOOKING FOR YOU.
HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE.
COME ON. HURRY UP.
I THINK A LOT OF PRAYERS
HAVE BEEN ANSWERED.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
WE FOUND THIS PLACE.
WHERE IS HE?
WE'RE GOING
TO NEED A URINE SAMPLE.
A URINE SAMPLE?
MIKE, DON'T
LET THEM TOUCH HIM.
BACK OFF.
HEY, HEY. IT'S
A WISE THING YOU CALLED.
THIS IS A VERY
CRITICAL TIME.
COME ON IN. GET
SOME PICTURES HERE.
MR. WALTON?
MR. WALTON, MY NAME
IS JARVIS POWELL.
NOW,
CAN YOU TELL US
HOW LONG
YOU'VE BEEN BACK?
HERE. GET THIS
THING SIGNED.
LET'S GET HIM
TO A HOSPITAL.
SHH! QUIET, PLEASE.
MR. WALTON.
MR. WALTON, DID
YOU MAKE CONTACT
WITH ALIENS?
WERE YOU TAKEN
TO ANOTHER PLANET,
TO A MOTHER SHIP?
HOW DID THEY
COMMUNICATE WITH YOU?
STOP IT.
JUST LEAVE HIM ALONE.
OK, LOOK,
YOU'VE GOT
TWO CHOICES.
YOU CAN EITHER
BE QUIET
OR STEP OUTSIDE.
DAVID, GIVE THIS GUY
A CHANCE.
MR. WALTON, CAN YOU TELL
ME WHAT THEY LOOK LIKE?
CAN YOU TELL ME
HOW MANY OF THEM THERE WERE?
WERE YOU GIVEN FOOD?
INJECTIONS?
THAT'S ENOUGH, MISTER.
MIKE!
IT'S IMPORTANT
THE ENTIRE WORLD LEARNS
OF YOUR EXPERIENCE.
LOOK, I'M ASKING YOU,
JUST LET US
DO OUR JOB.
NO! HE'S NOT
ANSWERING, MAN.
YOU CAN'T COME
BETWEEN ME
AND MY BROTHER!
GET OUT OF HERE.
HE'S SAYING SOMETHING.
NO! NO!
HE'S SAYING SOMETHING!
[SHOUTING]
[SIREN]
ALL RIGHT,
HERE WE GO. READY?
YEAH. LIFT.
OK, LET'S GO,
GUYS.
THE DOCTOR'S DOWN IN ICU.
WE'LL PAGE HIM.
HANG IN THERE, PAL.
YOU'RE GOING TO BE FINE.
HE'S ROLLING THE EYES
A LITTLE BIT. WATCH HIM.
YOU'RE GOING
TO BE OK.
WONDER WHAT HAPPENED
IN THIS ONE.
OK,
WATCH THE CORNER.
ORDERLY, PREP TWO.
LAB TECH'S
ON THE WAY.
SECURE IT.
DID HE LOSE
CONSCIOUSNESS?
NO, HE DIDN'T.
RESPIRATION IS NORMAL.
PULSE?
ARE YOU OK?
HEY, CAN YOU TALK
TO ME?
[HEART MONITOR BEEPS]
HEY, MAN,
HOW YOU DOING?
HEY, I'M NOT SUPPOSED
TO BE IN HERE.
YOUR MA'S OUT FRONT.
SHE CAN'T WAIT
TO SEE YOU.
BUT THEY SAID
WE WEREN'T SUPPOSED
TO BE COMING IN HERE.
GUESS THEY DON'T THINK
YOU'RE READY
TO SEE VISITORS YET.
BOY, WAS I GLAD
YOU SHOWED UP.
I REALLY
MISSED YOU, BUDDY.
THEY HAD A SEARCH PARTY
OUT FOR YOU FOR DAYS.
THEY THOUGHT--
THEY THOUGHT THAT WE
HAD KILLED YOU, MAN.
THEY WERE READY
TO LYNCH US.
CAN YOU IMAGINE THAT?
THESE JERKS ACTUALLY
THOUGHT WE KILLED YOU.
KATE AND I AREN'T
DOING SO GOOD,
NOT THAT WE WERE
EVER DOING THAT GREAT.
BUT I DON'T THINK
WE'RE GONNA MAKE IT.
BUT DANA,
SHE SURE LOVES YOU.
SHE'S BEEN
A BASKET CASE.
I WAS PRETTY
BROKEN UP, TOO.
WHEN I CAME BACK
UP THERE
AND YOU WERE GONE,
I CAN'T TELL YOU
HOW AWFUL I FELT.
WHAT?
WHEN YOU CAME BACK?
TRAVIS, WE THOUGHT
YOU WERE DEAD.
I MEAN, IT BLASTED YOU
WITH THE LIGHT,
AND THEN THE GUYS,
THEY GOT ALL SCARED,
AND THEY STARTED HOLLERING
AND EVERYTHING.
YOU LEFT ME THERE?
WELL, COME ON,
TRAVIS.
I MEAN, WHAT DID YOU
EXPECT ME TO DO?
I CAME
RIGHT BACK FOR YOU.
YOU SON OF A BITCH.
IF YOU HADN'T GOTTEN
OUT OF THE TRUCK,
NONE OF THIS
WOULD'VE HAPPENED.
NO ONE IS ALLOWED
IN HERE.
YEAH. I WAS
JUST LEAVING.
YOU KNOW, TRAVIS,
I BELIEVE YOU.
MAYBE ONE DAY
WE'LL HAVE A TWO-WAY
CONVERSATION--
JUST YOU AND ME.
THANKS, DR. CAYLE.
I REALLY MEAN IT,
TRAVIS.
IF YOU NEED ME,
PLEASE CALL.
YOU CAN ALWAYS
FIND ME HERE.
REMEMBER THAT.
GOOD LUCK.
BYE.
LOOK,
HERE HE COMES!
MR. WALTON, PLEASE
GIVE ME A STATEMENT
ABOUT YOUR UFO.
GIVE ME A STATEMENT.
CAN YOU TELL US
WHAT YOU SAW?
MR. WALTON--
TRAVIS, GET IN THE CAR
AND LOCK YOUR DOOR.
WHY DON'T YOU
COME CLEAN?
WHAT IS THIS RUMOR
ABOUT THE CREW?
COME ON.
LOOK OVER HERE!
HE'S NOT ANSWERING
QUESTIONS TODAY.
CAN I BORROW
THAT LADDER OF YOURS?
TRAVIS, CAN WE HAVE
YOUR AUTOGRAPH?
AUTOGRAPH?
YEAH. YOU'RE FAMOUS.
YOU'VE BEEN TO SPACE.
GEE, THANKS.
COOL.
WOW!
THAT'S COOL.
AUTOGRAPHS, HMM?
YOU'VE BECOME
QUITE THE CELEBRITY.
YOU ENJOYING IT?
WORD IS THAT
TABLOIDS ARE
GOING TO PUT UP
QUITE A HUNK OF CASH
FOR YOUR STORY RIGHTS.
YOU'VE HIT THE BIG TIME.
CONGRATULATIONS.
WHO ARE YOU?
FRANK WATTERS,
STATE INVESTIGATOR
FOR THE C.I.B.
I'VE BEEN ON THE CASE
SINCE YOU DISAPPEARED.
WHERE YOU BEEN
THE LAST FIVE DAYS?
I--I CAN'T REMEMBER.
DR. WILSON
OVER AT THE HOSPITAL
TELLS ME... YOU WENT
WITHOUT FOOD AND
WATER ALL THAT TIME.
WAS IT WORTH IT?
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
YOU DON'T, HUH?
WELL, I CAN SEE
YOUR MEMORY ISN'T
QUITE THERE YET,
SO WHAT DO YOU SAY
WE JUST...
GIVE IT
A LITTLE MORE TIME, HUH?
I'M A PATIENT MAN.
I'M NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
YOU DECIDE YOU GOT
SOMETHING TO TELL ME,
I CAN BE REACHED THROUGH
THE SHERIFF'S OFFICE.
OH, UH...
WELCOME HOME, TRAVIS.
GOOD DAY, MA'AM.
WHAT WAS THAT
ALL ABOUT?
TAKE ME HOME...
PLEASE.
[ENGINE STARTS]
DID ANYBODY FIND OUT--
HEY!
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
YES. GOOD TO
HAVE YOU BACK.
I'M SORRY,
BUT MIKE'S
PROBABLY NOT COMING.
HEY, TRAVIS, MAN,
LOOK AT THIS.
WE MADE THE PAPER.
FRANK WATTERS WAS ON
THE RADIO THIS MORNING.
NOW HE'S SAYING POLYGRAPHS
ARE INCONCLUSIVE.
HE THINKS
WE'RE ALL LYING.
I BET WATTERS STILL
THINKS WE KILLED YOU.
YOU ALL RIGHT, GUY?
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
UM, EVERYBODY, COME ON.
LET'S EAT.
EVERYTHING'S ALL READY.
COME ON, TRAVIS.
COME ON.
LET'S GET SOME CHOW.
WHOA!
WATCH IT THERE.
OH!
THERE YOU GO.
HERE YOU GO.
DO YOU WANT
SOME OF THIS?
MARY, GET YOURSELF IN HERE
AND GET SOMETHING.
WHERE'S TRAVIS?
TRAVIS?
HONEY?
TRAVIS,
WHAT'S GOING ON?
UHH!
TRAVIS,
WHAT'S WRONG?
TRAVIS?
TRAVIS, ARE YOU OK?
TRAVIS,
WHAT'S WRONG?
TRAVIS?
TRAVIS? TRAVIS!
HUH.
AAH!
[PANTING]
AAH! AAH!
AAH! AAH! AAH!
[PANTING]
WHOA! AAH! AH.
UHH!
AAH!
SPACESUITS.
NO!
AAH!
[GLASS SHATTERS]
UHH!
AAH!
URHH!
UHH!
AAH!
[CRACKLING SOUNDS]
[MUFFLED SCREAMING]
AAH!
[GURGLING]
[MUFFLED SCREAMING]
IT'S DR. CAYLE,
TRAVIS.
YOUR BROTHER AND DANA
BROUGHT YOU TO MY OFFICE.
WE'RE ALL HERE.
I KNOW HOW DIFFICULT
THIS HAS BEEN.
TRAVIS...
ARE YOU OK?
I LOVE YOU, HONEY.
FIRST UNSOLVED CASE,
FRANK?
OH, I WOULDN'T SAY THAT
EXACTLY, SHERIFF.
I'M JUST WAITING
FOR THE REAL TRUTH
TO COME OUT.
WELL, THAT DOCTOR SEEMED
TO THINK IT WAS REAL.
UH, SHE'S FORGETTING
THE FACT
THAT TRAVIS
HAD FIVE DAYS
TO DREAM UP
AND REHEARSE
THIS COCKAMAMIE
STORY OF HIS.
WHAT ARE YOU
GETTING AT, FRANK?
IT JUST SEEMS TO ME
THAT THIS WHOLE THING
IS A VERY WELL-PLANNED
AND EXECUTED HOAX.
HOAX?
FOR GOD'S SAKE.
WHY WOULD THEY
WANT TO DO THAT?
TO GET SOME ATTENTION.
IT COULD BE
AS SIMPLE AS THAT.
I DON'T KNOW.
I MEAN...
WELL, ONE OF THESE DAYS,
THEY'RE GOING
TO SLIP UP.
AND WHEN THEY DO,
I'M ON MY WAY
BACK TO SNOWFLAKE.
ALL THE WAY
FROM MONTANA.
FROM THE FRIGGIN'
NORTH POLE IF I HAVE TO.
I'LL SEE YOU THEN,
SHERIFF.
[ENGINE STARTS]
[DOOR SHUTS]
[CHILD LAUGHS]
AREN'T YOU GOING
TO BE LATE FOR WORK?
COME HERE, YOU.
[LAUGHS]
I WANT...
WHAT?
I WANT DOWN.
NO. WE GOT TO
HAVE BREAKFAST NOW.
WE CAN'T
PLAY BALL ANYMORE.
GET YOUR LEGS IN THERE,
MICHAEL.
I'M PLAYING.
WE'LL LEAVE
THE BALL HERE,
BUT YOU HAVE
SOME CEREAL, OK?
I WANT DOWN.
MMM...
HOW'S MY GIRL?
WELL...OK.
YOU GOT TO
GO TO WORK.
YEAH. I'LL SEE YA.
OK.
BYE, SWEETHEART.
YOU GOING TO HAVE
SOME JUICE?
YEAH, JUICE AND CEREAL.
SAY, "BYE-BYE, DADDY."
BYE-BYE, DADDY.
BYE-BYE.
MIKE?
TRAVIS?
YOU'RE LOOKING GOOD.
YEAH, I HEARD
YOU MOVED UP HERE.
BEEN A LONG TIME.
WHAT IS IT,
TWO YEARS?
IT'S 2 1/2.
WE GOT TO TALK.
WELL, WHAT DO WE
GOT TO TALK ABOUT?
COME ON, MIKE.
LET'S GO FOR A RIDE.
YOU WANT TO GET OUT?
WHY'D YOU
BRING ME HERE?
YOU KNOW, I DON'T LIKE
THIS PLACE MUCH.
HEY, MIKE...
NEITHER DO I.
IN FACT,
I HAVEN'T HAD
A DECENT NIGHT'S SLEEP
SINCE...
SINCE I LAST SAW YOU.
YEAH, I KNOW
WHAT YOU MEAN.
SO IT BOTHERS YOU, TOO?
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I SAW YOUR GIRLS
THE OTHER DAY.
THEY'RE GETTING BIG.
THEY MISS YOU.
EVERYBODY MISSES YOU.
YOU KNOW, YOU'RE ABOUT
TO BE AN UNCLE AGAIN.
AGAIN?
YOU MEAN
YOU NEVER HEARD?
MICHAEL'S ALMOST 2,
AND...
DANA'S
THREE MONTHS GONE.
MICHAEL, HUH?
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
SO WHY ARE WE UP HERE,
TRAVIS?
I'VE BEEN DOING A LOT
OF THINKING ABOUT...
WHAT HAPPENED.
HELL, IT WAS
ALL MY FAULT, MIKE.
I NEVER SHOULD'VE
GOT OUT OF THE TRUCK.
DON'T BE RIDICULOUS.
WHAT HAPPENED HAPPENED.
WE CAN'T CHANGE THAT.
WELL...
WHATEVER YOU DID,
IT--IT'S OK.
UNDERSTAND?
IT'S COOL.
SAME GOES FOR YOU.
LET'S GET GOING.
YOU GOT TO
GO TO WORK, AND...
AND WHAT?
I'D LIKE TO GET
THE HELL OUT OF HERE
BEFORE THEY COME BACK.
OH, THEY WON'T BE BACK.
I DON'T THINK
THEY LIKED ME.
¶ YOU CAN'T STOP ¶
¶ RUNNIN' WATER ¶
¶ YOU CAN'T KILL ¶
¶ THE FIRE
THAT BURNS INSIDE ¶
¶ DON'T DENY ¶
¶ OUR FLESH AND BLOOD
¶ DON'T FORSAKE ¶
¶ OUR SONS AND DAUGHTERS
¶ I THINK WE ALL RUNNIN' ¶
¶ THINKIN' THAT
WE CAN HIDE ¶
¶ I THINK WE RUNNIN' ¶
¶ TRYIN' TO GET AWAY ¶
¶ FOR SOONER OR LATER
WE GONNA REALIZE ¶
¶ WE GONNA MEET UP
WITH THE TRUTH ¶
¶ FACE-TO-FACE
¶ YEAH, YOU CAN'T STOP ¶
¶ YOU CAN'T STOP ¶
¶ RUNNIN' WATER ¶
¶ YOU CAN'T KILL ¶
¶ THE FIRE
THAT BURNS INSIDE ¶
¶ FIRE THAT BURNS INSIDE
¶ DON'T DENY ¶
¶ OUR FLESH AND BLOOD
¶ DON'T FORSAKE ¶
¶ OUR SONS AND DAUGHTERS
¶ IT'S FREEDOM OF SPEECH ¶
¶ AS LONG AS YOU DON'T
SAY TOO MUCH ¶
¶ OOH OOH
¶ FOR SOONER OR LATER
WE GONNA REALIZE ¶
¶ OOH OOH
¶ WE GONNA MEET UP
WITH THE TRUTH ¶
¶ OOH OOH
¶ FACE-TO-FACE
¶ OUR SONS AND DAUGHTERS
¶ OOH OOH