Downloaded from
YTS.MX
This restoration was made
from the internegotive in 2013
by Eclair Group (image)
and L.E. Diapason (sound)
with the generous support of the CNC.
Official YIFY movies site:
YTS.MX
One of the challenges
posed by every restoration
is to differentiate accurately
between the imperfections
originally present on the negative
(which must remain uncorrected)
and those caused by wear and tear.
Inspired by Chris Marker's words of warning
"Do not believe more is befier"
we have left uncorrected the mishaps
of a temperamental lens,
the lens hood, and hairs in the gate.
LETTER FROM SIBERIA
Fox Lissa Potrikaievna
My beautiful fox
Little sister fox
Princess most wise
What was the use
Of creeping into the Ark
Since you'll end as the collar
Of the captain's coal?
Eagle, oh eagle
When you walk
We see your socks
You fill the goofs with terror
And yet they're befier than you
So why are you always crying out...
(untranslatable into English)
Oh reindeer, sweet and just
Friend of the birds and owls
They nest in your branches
Happy he who has ideas in his head
Happier still he who has birds
Brown reindeer
On a brown plain
Like an old spot of blood
On dead leaves
White reindeer
On white snow
Like the beloved's silence
In the midst of silence
When Yves Montand's voice
Comes over the short-wave
The branches of Paris chestnut trees
Come and peer into my window
When our distant friend sings
Warmth and joy spread everywhere
And distances shrink to nothing
When our best friend
Starts to sing
Lovers revolve in time
To the singer's voice
The music extends
The Boulevards of Paris
All the way to the parks of Moscow
Kora noet
Distances shrink to nothing
When my faraway friend
Starts to sing
Bear, bear, file ears
With a belly like a pope's
You give yourself airs
In your overcoat
But you don't look happy
You don't want to go home
You don't want to come to my house
You don't want to go to church
You don't want to go to school
You want to walk down the street
Giving candy to the little children