Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
Are you asleep?
Teresa?
That dog of yours will get rabies.
He's been bitten by a rabid one.
There is an epidemic.
They go rabid.
And piss in gateways.
Today's the first of September.
So what?
I'm in a hurry!
Haven't seen a penny since June.
Some want to pay
6 month in advance.
The wife gets paid.
She'll pay you.
Man, how are you driving!
What's up?
Hush, it's the police!
Silence, citizens!
People are asleep.
He slapped me!
Edzio, that swine slapped
your wife's ass!
Will you let this swine,
get away!
Who do you think we are!?
That's my husband. Every night
I have to drag this bastard...
And on top of that,
that swine slaps me!
Which one is it?
Man's to get up for work and this
rabble is still in a party mood.
- Had enough?
- Tell him to pick it up!
Edzio will show him!
Teach the swine a lesson!
He will get you, you swine!
Edzio will get you!
Get him, Edzio!
Had enough? Enough.
Let's go!
Pick it up, you jerk!
IDENTIFICATION MARKS: NONE
- Gentlemen, a new game!
- What is it?
Banknote planes.
The closest to the corner wins!
All right, go on!
- Like that!
- Well, throw one!
- Quiet!
- Good!
Not bad!
Gonna play, mate?
- I'll get it all!
- Go on!
I'll get it all, I will!
Will you give me a note?
There's some coppers short.
- Here. Go on, play!
- Guys, don't be like that.
Well! Watch out!
All right, go on!
Next!
Let's twist!
Quiet!
Eurydice, don't wait for me,
I'm forgetting you slowly.
Eurydice, Life is breaking us,
and you can never start anew.
- Who's that?
- Malicki.
- What about Leszczyc?
- He no longer lives there.
Let me through!
- Your name?
- Leszczyc.
Let's go.
Breathe.
A bit to the left.
OK.
Next.
- Your name's Leszczyc?
- Yes.
Leszczyc - no changes.
Sometimes they take you
straight away,
you only have time
to get your things.
- Leszczyc!
- Here!
Closer!
Come closer!
Well, don't overdo it.
There is a circle there.
Three steps back!
...oval face...
- Age?
- 24.
- Marital status?
- Single.
- Identification marks?
- None.
- Where are your certificates?
- Which ones?
You always bring
a suitcase full of certificates.
Troubles with kidneys, liver,
flat feet, crazy, six toes...
- Anything interesting this time?
- Nothing.
A new method.
Turn right.
Hand over the right eye.
A.
E.
K.
Open your eyes.
- Any ailments?
- None.
What's that scar on your leg?
It's from my childhood.
I was playing with a spade...
- All right.
- ...and somewhat unfortunately...
Fit and healthy.
So, Andrzej Leszczyc, the son
of Stanislaw, university graduate,
upon completing his studies
was due for 3-month
military training.
Andrzej Leszczyc
did not report for the training.
This can be classified
as desertion.
We enquired
at the faculty of ich...
...ich... thyology and were told,
that Leszczyc also failed
to report for the topic of his thesis
and was thus struck
from the student register.
Therefore, Leszczyc,
who was unwilling
to do the 3-month training,
is now due for
2-year military service instead.
He is not sick.
He is not the only family provider.
There are no grounds
for exempting you.
I want to join the army.
The new method.
How is it, comrade?
The State spent on you
a lot of money,
to give you the chance
to study your favourite...
...ich... thyology
so now you could pay that back
the State back by working as...
I was to work
in a provincial museum.
- As a deputy director.
- A director.
What's up?
Yeah. We don't have
many directors
...of ich... thyological museums.
All right.
And you refuse
to do it for the State.
No... it's not that... I enrolled...
to study to escape...
the military service.
I thought, that I'll lose 2 years
of my life in the army.
And... the discipline...
Somehow, I've always managed...
to lie low...
to do bulletin boards.
It's my invention.
I didn't have to study,
doing bulletins on Red Cross,
Women's League.
At school they said I have a
talent, but that it wasn't enough,
to study Art.
And my writing wasn't good enough,
to study journalism.
So, I no longer cared:
board bulletins at ichthyology
or doing bug science...
You should have forced
me to do my service then.
Watch out!
Why didn't you go
for those 3 months?
I couldn't.
I had to... somehow
arrange everything.
My life.
I thought I can't postpone it
for an hour,
let alone three months.
Leszczyc, what's this nonsense
you are telling us?
Has anything happened?
You all stand in this circle,
with bare bottoms,
and you want me to distinguish
a grown up man from just a squirt.
Now Leszczyc tells us,
that he is not ready for life yet.
But he showed us that
five years ago!
That's what you can do to me.
- When is the next transport?
- Today.
- Where to?
- Kolobrzeg, at 3.10 p.m..
Leszczyc, a small suitcase
with personal belongings.
At 1.00 p.m., assembling here,
understood?
Yes, Sir!
- And sober, understood?
- Yes, Sir!
Next.
- Fiszer!
- They've got you.
You've let them to pull
a fast one on you.
We were listening in.
Get going,
you don't have much time.
Say farewell to your loved ones,
have a drink and good bye!
The door!
You fiddled
with the alarm clock again.
You'll sleep when I'm gone.
Good doggie, good boy...
- I'm sorry.
- I can't go out naked!
I said sorry.
- The alarm was set
for before 8:00! - Sorry!
- I want to have all the time I need.
- Sorry!
I'm doing the shops behind
the sawmill today.
Near... your library.
You must look funny,
nose in a book.
I'd like to see it for once.
A diligent student.
I don't see anything funny in it.
I may be at the dean's office.
Just be there.
I'll find you.
A bit late for this idea.
Come here!
Jump!
Leave the dog,
or I'll hurt my eye.
- Good boy...
- The mirror is shaking.
The caretaker said that...
the dog's got rabies.
Nonsense...
these... small dogs...
Dog!
Good dog.
Yeah...
...these little dogs
don't get rabies.
Don't they?
Should've vaccinated him.
There's an epidemic.
- You won't fool them anyhow.
- About what?
That you have big eyes.
You'll make me late again.
You could be ready to leave
in three minutes.
I could be ready to leave...
...in one minute.
Once forever.
Forever...
Each time one leaves
it's forever.
- Do we have honey?
- I don't know.
...easy to remember.
Who wrote it for you?
Well?
Johann Sebastian Bach!
Johann Sebastian Bach lived
long time ago. And he died.
I'm off to work.
I'm not 19.
Must take care of my looks.
You are not 19,
You are off to work...
You are not 19...
What a sad song.
BACH!
What was that?
Your favourite mayonnaise.
Clean it up before you go to sleep.
Come here, come on.
Your mistress gave you breakfast.
Kiss your husband goodnight.
You could sweep the floor.
Look how messy it's here.
Three yoghurts.
A pot of honey.
Bread.
Fifty four.
I've only got fifty. I'll take
one cauliflower less.
That'll be fifty.
And radishes?
Here we are.
One loaf of bread, please.
- A dark one or a white one?
- Doesn't matter.
It's for a blind man.
My, you always come up
with things like that...
- Yes, dearie.
- Well, say something.
- Something.
- What?
You wanted me to say something,
so I said something.
Oh, go on, when you say
something...
Remember the address:
1, Pretty Street.
Mister! Your dog!
He's frothing at the mouth!
- Where're you going?
- It'll be all right here.
- The chimney's smoking.- Not here.
- And it will keep the wind out.
He must be at home.
What's the time? Ten.
He'll be asleep.
Nobody in. Look, his things are
packed. He must be going away.
- There's a suitcase on the bed.
- Wait, I'll fetch a blanket.
Well, now.
- Taking off you bra?
- Why not?
And if they come back?
She's working, and he's cooking dinners
or something. At this time he's asleep.
If he's packed,
he might be moving out.
- He's seen me already.
- I met him a couple of times as well.
- No, I mean naked!
- Never! You've been there?
No, just sunbathing. It's a nice
place. I come here often.
- Well?
- Nothing. He's seen me.
- And what? Did you know?
- What?
- That he saw you.
- Of course!
- Never!
- Who cares.
- But... his wife!
- What wife? They live together.
- And...?
- What? - With him.
They've live together
for two years.
- And then, when he saw you?
- Nothing, she arrived.
- Was there a fight?
- I don't think she's seen me.
I don't know, what's the score.
Who and whom...
I mean:
who cares more.
- What if she comes now?
- So what? Can't we sunbathe?
The chimney's smoking.
They're at home!
Quiet! Stop it!
Quiet! Go there!
Go there! Quiet!
- What a lovely doggie!
- Indeed!
The vet's gone to see horses.
- What's wrong with him?
- You'll have to wait.
Could I go in first?
I'm afraid
that he might have rabies...
You don't say!
Such a little dog...
- Did you vaccinate him?
- No.
Nice little doggie...
Oh, here's the vet now.
- He's coming.
- Yes.
I don't mind, you go in first.
- Yes...
- Follow the doctor.
Here, to the left.
What a long queue...
Doctor, I'm afraid
it might have been froth.
- Was he vaccinated?
- No.
Well, and you come now...?
Unfortunately,
he'll have to be, you know...
He'd only suffer.
- I'll put him to sleep now.
- How come?
Perhaps...
There's an epidemic.
It was in the papers.
Rabies doesn't happen often,
but now... Unfortunately.
Couldn't you do something?
There are some ways. Maybe...
...some...
What are you talking about...
- Did he bite anybody?
- No.
- Shall I get him ready
for injection? - Yes.
You'll have to take him
and bury him...
I could do it... but it'll cost.
I don't have any more...
Hello, get out, please!
Get out!
- Sorry!
- 0-9, 0-9!
Can't you see?
There's an accident!
A girl was hit by a car!
Come on, let me see.
- Hi!
- What's happened?
I don't know.
Don't like watching things like
that. Let's go for a drink.
I don't drink.
I'm meeting a guy
who owes me money.
Nice guy.
He's a car doctor.
If you have a car, he's your man.
Mundek?
You were the head of the Youth
Association in our school?
- What?
- Watch out or you'll get run over.
Hi.
All right.
Change it at the bar and
bring us some coffee. My friend.
Three coffees, please.
What was that stuff
with the Youth Association?
Old times.
You had better marks,
and never did a thing.
When I was little
I looked in a mirror
and imagined
that I'm a girl. Silly, huh?
- Naked?
- I wore my sister's stockings.
Silly, huh?
I was nineteen..., no twenty
when I first saw a naked woman.
I was bathed together
with my sister.
Go on.
The one with the stockings?
The younger one.
The other one was older.
She was crossed-eyed.
- Which one?
- Actually, both of them.
The older one was worse.
I'm squinting too.
You can see.
I don't know.
- Can't you see?
- No.
Like my father.
The theory of the genes.
He couldn't doubt his fatherhood.
- You can see it a little.
- When you look sideways.
They call me Picas.
Silly, huh?
Don't look sideways.
- 90...
- Why Picas?
One eye here, another there.
90 what?
- Bust! The one in a jumper!
- What?!
You've got an eye!
- The one in a jumper. See?!
- What an eye!
I can read what's written
over there.
A-man-at-the-station-who-says-
I-don't-know-why-I-came-here-
- ...after-many-years...
- Where?!
...or-after-something-
like-youth-or-love...
Over there, the green poster!
Is it an advert or what?
I thought you'd see double.
They didn't even exempt me
from the army.
I could read
the smallest letters.
You could've pretended, that you
don't see the largest ones.
Everybody expects that.
But I have better sight than others.
They thought you'd learnt
the letters by heart.
- 150.
- Where?!
These two. Together!
You could make one good one
from those two.
I'd marry her.
And you?
You've changed a 500 note but
didn't give the change back!
The change, mate.
I've married a 92.
- That's rare.
- True.
- Is the wife older than you?
- Why?
I presumed
that she's older and has money.
You don't look bad
and you don't work.
Maybe I'm on holiday.
Maybe I'll get a divorce.
My mate was on holiday. The wife
was gone when he came back.
- I'm doing my Masters.
- You're a fool.
You studied something, right?
Graduated in...
I had problems.
Now I'm writing my thesis.
- What is it?
- Well, ichthyology.
- Yes, ichthyol ointment!
- 95!
- Exaggeration!
- You'd bonk her!
Who wouldn't!
You don't sit in an office either.
I'm a hunter.
I hunt suckers.
I ring a bell and do my show bit.
The give me a photo
and some advance.
In 3 days they get a portrait
and I get the money.
And if the husband's out,
I may get something more.
Shit, I must make a call.
- The phone is over there.
- Wait, the number.
Well, I'll be...!
What a broad!
Yes, that's me...
This one's about a hundred.
L. Janczewska, 3, Pretty Street.
That's the one
he's calling now. Nice job!
- Janczewska?
- Yes.
No, her first name is...
You're a sucker. You'll graduate.
You're married. And what for?
I'll be a museum director.
A deputy director.
In the province?
Cinema once a week,
bridge with the pharmacist
and one hooker for the whole city.
If you don't marry for money,
you marry for the sake of others.
Thousands of guys like us
are sitting now in coffee bars
and thinking
how to bonk your wife.
And one's probably
doing it right now.
That Janczewska's not bad, huh?
Married one year.
I offer to do her portrait
and after an hour
she won't let me get my pants on.
- Nice job.
- C'est la vie!
- I'm off to work.
- To Janczewska?
I'm a bit weak in the knees
after yesterday.
Nice job!
But you've got the have the looks.
Damn it!
- Let's go. The coffee's been paid.
- Mundek!
Lend me a hundred.
You've got me.
Call me, the number's in the book.
Nice job, you've got yourself
a phone.
Others have degrees
and I've got a phone.
You'll pay me back
when you're a director.
She's called Janczewska now?
- Why?
- Just asking. She got married?
- Do you know her?
- No.
- What's that 100 for?
- I must buy an envelope.
10 groszy's enough.
I may need more.
- See you.
No business after eleven.
Hello, Department of ichthyology.
Why so late?
What is it?
I only wanted my record book.
I've been drafted.
No... it's only
in the interest of decency...
They've got you at last.
Can't give you your record book.
Only a certificate,
that you've completed something.
And that you've been expelled.
Explain to me, why?
How many years
have you completed?
Four.
You must've messed it up.
To get expelled
just before the degree.
I didn't report for
the thesis topic.
- Why?
- I don't like fish.
- I have the right to know!
- When are you to report?
- At once.
- Nonsense.
- Leaving at three. Going fishing.
- What do you mean?
Well, to the seaside...
They've assigned me
to the Marines.
I can understand everything.
I can forgive you a lot.
That's correct.
Since 1961 you didn't...
...report for your thesis topic.
Expelled.
I forgave you many things,
but this?
No, that's not possible!
What were you doing
those 2 years?
I have a huge favour
to ask you...
I told the wife,
that I'll be here at noon...
...about my diploma.
- She doesn't know...
- But this?
...I'm not studying any more.
Now I know, what you were doing
those two years.
She'll come here.
- Wait! Hello!
- I'll wait here for a while.
But, just in case,
don't tell her anything.
About the military service.
Tell her to go straight home.
- Have you got a pen?
- I do. Why?
Will you write something for me?
- Here?
- Here's not possible. Over here.
- What are you looking at?
- I knew a girl like you.
Go on then.
Start with "Darling", yes?
- No...
- "Dear Madame"?
"I'm going away for a long time."
I've explained everything
to my friend...,
...who'll give you this letter...
- What name should I sign?
- No name.
You'll put 3 crosses?
Now the envelope:
Lena Janczewska.
3, Pretty Street.
- Pretty?
- Number 3.
- I'm asking about Lena.
- I don't even know her.
And you're on first-name terms
with her? It's not you!
You wanted to kill me,
so it won't be revealed!
- I was kidding!
- Me too.
My friend fancies that Lena.
In this way he can get
to know her better.
I hope, he'll succeed.
Sign: Mundek.
Maybe not. Rajmund.
Not a nice name.
- I'm Basia. Barbara.
- What are you doing here?
I can't wait for the lectures
to start. I got enrolled.
- To read what?
- Ichthyology.
Do you know what it is?
Fish science.
I come from the coast.
I can't wait
for the lectures to start.
I was in the Highlands
and now I'm going home, to Slupsk.
You have a train at three.
How do you know?
I'm sure to surprise you
more than once.
Well?
- Maybe I walk with you?
- Well, surprise me!
Salmo salar pluviatikis:
an exceptionally rare salmon
that has most peculiar habits.
Once a year all fish swim
to one and the same place,
where they meet
as if they'd have an appointment
for a date or a wedding night...
This romanticism was their doom.
Fishermen...
discovered this place.
Grass consumption per capita.
If each man in the world
would eat...
Do you like dogs?
You looked
like a bulldog. Like this...
I can look even worse.
You win.
It's twelve o'clock!
Yes. I've only got an hour.
I have to hurry.
- Where are you going?
- I work here.
It's nearby so... sometimes I climb
over the fence...
to listen about fish.
You're making it up.
Where are you?
Well, where are you?
- Why are you following me?
- And why are you like this?
You pretend all the time.
You don't work here.
And such a salmon
as Salmo salar does not exist.
I wasn't listening
carefully to the lecture.
I'm a working man.
Tired and inattentive.
You are a working man?
My father...
I like watching people work.
I'd like to be a photographer,
and photograph people at work.
I always wanted to work
or take photos. Do you know?
We are not on first name terms.
Look: these logs
are pulled in through here...
These planks are cut further into
small bits - matches, toothpicks...
It's nice here, isn't it?
It smells nice.
Have you ever looked at a match?
Tonight... at dawn,
I struck a match.
It was like
seeing it for the first time.
The match?
- You're pulling my leg again.
- A match is a beautiful thing.
So are you.
The future is.
Generally, many things. Huge
logs. Matches made of them.
How do you know
what time is my train?
'Cos I work on the railway.
I'm the one who walks and taps.
Taps the wagon wheels:
knock, knock...
You're silly.
Wait a minute.
When you'll be leaving,
you'll see me at the station.
I'll be wearing a special uniform.
Or maybe not.
But I'll tap for you for sure.
It was you who run up the steps
after me!
You wanted to borrow a pen!
Why did you run after me?
- I wanted to borrow a pen!
- Well?
- I borrowed it!
- So what?
So what?!
I've got something in my eye!
My eye!
No, I'll do it!
Wait, stop fidgeting!
- No... It hurts!
- Wait!
There's nothing there.
And what?
I gave you the pen back.
I run up to you,
because I took you for...
...an old friend of mine...
She looked like you.
She did.
Where's she now?
I don't know.
She graduated in Art.
After...
She does some window dressing.
She thinks something,
does something.
She's no longer like you.
What does it mean "like you"?
Generally,
all girls are like you.
Even at the coffee bar...
my friend...
showed me a portrait of this...
- Banasiuk! Throw!
- Do you smoke?
- So, we'll meet at the station.
- No smoking here.
No smoking here.
Excuse me!
Does he come here often?
These students?
They come to earn some money.
Excuse me... My wife was meant
to be somewhere here.
He's asking about his wife.
What wife?
His wife. Must have one.
My wife.
She was to do these shops.
To do what?
Visit? Look at them?
No... She...
was to dress the...
...windows.
- Teresa?
- Yes.
She's go no husband.
Actually, that's me.
- Well, well..
- Well what?
Nothing. I didn't know.
So now you know.
Where... is she now?
I fired her.
What do you mean:
fired her?
You see, in our company
we have women artists
who dress shop...
Good afternoon.
...windows and so on.
Somebody has to employ them.
Somebody has to manage them.
Supervise them.
Assign tasks to them.
And fire them. That's me.
So, now you know.
You're welcome.
- Well... where did she...?
- She took her pay and went.
Must be something important.
She must've gone home.
Probably she did.
"Common Case" offers
foreign language courses in:
English, French, German,
Russian, Italian and Spanish.
Remember the address:
1, Pretty Street.
"Common Case".
...5, 6, 7, 8, 9... 80!
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9...
90!
100!
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9...
110!
- 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9... 120!
- Excuse me.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9...
130!
140!
Give me your hand, Sir.
I'll tell you the truth, your
fortune! Give me your hand!
Give me your hand, Sir,
I can see it in your eyes.
I'll tell you the truth!
For 10 zloties.
And if the Gipsy lies
you won't pay.
I'll tell you your name.
It is...
Andrzej.
You shouldn't have.
I'd have told you myself.
I didn't want you to be wrong.
Because then I wouldn't have
believed you.
Your mother's name is Maria,
and your father's in a grave, right?
- Is the Gipsy telling the truth?
- Yes.
Then give me 10 zloty.
You won't regret it.
- I haven't got any change.
- I'll change it for you.
- I will.
- That's not enough.
I'll give you more.
I can see in your hand...
no good.
- Probably a journey.
- No good, Sir.
I won't tell you anything.
I don't want anything from you.
I'm sorry, I'm in hurry.
You can see, isn't it?
That's all. Good bye.
Please, slam the door!
O, surprise!
Don't you recognise me?
Wait, it's me...
Do you remember?
On the beach?
You told me to call you "missus".
But you called me by name.
You were learning Spanish.
You've send me
to get ice-cream, right?
And whatever you wanted,
because you knew that...
Right?
Yes?
Yes!
So what?
So what?!
To start with he was cross-eyed.
Secondly, I've got here our...
You want to talk to him?
Just a minute.
Why're you looking at me like that?
It's not me who makes the bets.
I don't take money.
If Mundek bets,
it's his business.
Do you think,
that he wins every bet?
I don't bet.
Five hundred. It's the stake.
That mate of yours, that...
I kicked him out.
Mundek must be mad
for losing five hundred.
But he'll get it back from you.
I didn't bet.
If he bet five hundred, you must
do it too. That's the stake.
Mundek has these girls.
He shows them and says:
"She likes it".
"If you'd want, you could
have her straight away".
- "Shall we bet"?
- OK. Bet!
You don't risk anything. You win
five hundred from Mundek.
Or you give it to him gladly,
if you get what you want.
- Why are you...?
- I am what?!
And that husband of yours,
what if he did the same?
After all, there's as many
unfaithful as the cheated ones.
There must be a balance
in the end!
Wait on! What husband?
Well, the one here.
Janczewski.
The Janczewskis are abroad.
Mundek found it for me.
I can live here for a year.
Quite a debt of gratitude.
Supposedly a friendly favour,
and now these tricks...
With those bets.
Then... he calls
very annoyed.
Looks like,
it's not worth his while.
Do you know that...
...I liked your coming here.
It was nice... A joke...
Just... so simple.
Perhaps... that's how...
it ought to be?
That's not the way you wanted it,
your formula is spoiled!
"It's the balance,
the unfaithful and the cheated!"
If you had a girl you'd be sick
not knowing where she is.
Or you'd find a new telephone
number in her notebook.
Right?
Because you... You are...
Wrong number.
Let's pay for the whole year.
What if I get run over by a car?
- The course starts in a month?
- Yes, on the first of October.
So, what to do you think?
What language?
Is there a phone book here?
The phone is over there.
So what, shall we enrol?
- The full name and so on.
- There's no book here.
My colleague is using it,
wait a little.
- Have you got a pen?
- No.
I'm sorry...
can I borrow it from you?
Here.
- Wait, I'll go first.
- Go on, write.
May I speak with the director.
Yes, from the Central Board.
Yes, it's about...
...this conference. Exactly.
Hello? Is that the director?
Here's the Central Board.
That's about these...
...hold on,
what was it we wanted?
Mum? It's me.
No need for wanted posters...
Yes, I know.
No changes.
Blond, but not pig-eyed.
I called...
When I was there last time.
Before the holidays, but...
...you were...
at a conference or something.
I always come for a day
and then go back straight away.
Still at the lakes, with fish.
Collecting materials.
How? Not even a post office there!
I have. I earn money, mum!
I don't know what to do with it.
- I've got some in every pocket.
- You wanted the book.
Please, be quick.
My colleague needs it.
What're you looking for?
Kruszyski Rajmund.
No, sure, it won't be long.
Rajmund Kruszyski: 21-...
Just the address!
12, Armii Ludowej.
It's just here.
No, I was just talking here.
Well, when I come back,
I'll get myself a room or...
...arrange something
in the attic.
I can rent the attic from...
the caretaker.
I have to...
if I have some girls...
I couldn't do it with you there!
Get married.
Then I may do the same.
Let's have weddings
on the same day.
It's not on for a son,
to do it before his mother!
Are you going to be long?
- Pardon?
- Long?
He... He should be eighteen.
- That stepfather of mine!
- What are you smoking?
- Good ones!
- You might go astray.
You know, how it is.
I'm off to the coast.
- I'll write.
- Terrible!
That's materials from the lakes,
I'll add some from the sea.
Some fish swim to the sea
from the lakes.
Against the stream.
OK! I'll write. Yes.
Remember, you must get married!
You'll find some time...
Yes...
Bye!
- Have you finished?
- Yes.
That's for the call.
Have you got something smaller?
Yes, he's here with me!
Just went out for a while.
What languages do you have?
English, French,
Russian, German...
- Spanish?
- Yes.
And Italian.
We may also have Czech.
I'll take Spanish.
I'm telling you,
I'm not so sure about him.
Fill it in, please.
Are you paying for a year?
A month? A semester?
How much is it?
70 zloties for a month.
- Semester...
- No, just a month.
All right.
I gave you 20, here's... 50.
Yes...
- Shall I sign here?
- Yes.
Do you know
what kind of guy is he?
- All right.
- Is that all? - Yes.
Thank you.
Guys, put a jar to the wall,
you'll hear better!
What is she saying,
what is she saying now?
Let's put the fish in the bathtub,
we'll hear better through the...
Mundek.
Take you glasses off.
Leave him, he'll faint with fear.
You owe me something!
At least a hundred!
That did it.
- Who's this guy?
- An ichthyologist.
Trades in fish.
This... ichthyology
is to do with fish?
Little fish...
Maybe some warm water?
- We could warm some.
- Cold is better for bleeding!
We've a heater and fish...
We could apply
an ichthyologic torture.
Look, he's not worried!
He's occupied with himself.
The egoist.
Don't worry man,
the plug is broken.
We should mend it,
it might be useful.
You'll pay me back,
when you can.
When you're a director.
- Do you want to land on the Moon?
- I'm just going to the shop.
- Do you want to be a cosmonaut?
- What for?
- That's for TV?
- Radio! - Well, we have a TV.
What about you?
Can you introduce yourself?
No? Maybe you?
Would you like to be a cosmonaut?
Just like that? Maybe my daughter,
she's doing a dressmaking course.
By all means!
Great!
Sir! Would you like to
introduce yourself?
My name is An...
Antoni... See, I...
Don't be nervous.
Jasiski.
Excellent.
And now a question:
Would you like to be
an astronaut?
Yes.
I'd like for something
irreversible to happen.
So that you couldn't
go back on it.
But that you could still... decide.
After the launch.
To choose the direction, speed,
the way to destination.
That would be it.
It doesn't have to be
the Moon, because...
If I were a driver...
of, say... a lorry.
I'd drive... long distance...,
To Jelenia Gra, to Rzeszw.
- ...Koobrzeg... Shall I go on?
- Maybe's enough? - Go on, please.
I'd drive for several hours,
stop over, whenever I like.
But there's a task, one has to
be on time. Then...
on a day off
I'd walk in a strange city...
Behind every street corner
there's something...
You don't know this city,
you explore it.
It doesn't have to be the Moon.
Then you come back.
Or go on a different route...
The main thing is to be able
to give something from oneself.
Sometimes, conditions are hard.
One has to risk it.
That's the main thing.
Excellent, you put it very well.
Actually, why aren't
you a driver?
I don't know.
Maybe because I can't drive.
You could learn!
Yes, if I were called up,
I could've learnt.
They have various courses.
Driving as well.
But it's too late.
It's always worthwhile
to start anew.
- How old are you?
- What's the time?
2:30.
How old are you? 24?
It's too late, I won't manage.
It's always worthwhile
to start anew.
That would be an excellent end.
That was a rehearsal. So, maybe
we record it now, all right?
No, not now!
The music is swelling
to explode in a dramatic finale!
But before that it comes
to allegro con fuoco,
we hear the end
of the soothing...
The door's open!
- What is it?
- Have you any empty bottles?
Maybe something...
O! Here we are.
And this one...
Take it!
Cauliflowers for lunch!
I'll sit down for a while.
Now you've got it nice.
At your age
I was in the Uprising.
You were just a nipper in 1944.
I'd been hit
by a shrapnel in my leg
so I was no longer in actions.
But I was still killing the Krauts.
The caught ones.
Couldn't waste bullets,
so I used unexploded shells.
Sometimes they would explode
after the third go,
or wouldn't explode at all.
A Kraut dug himself a pit.
Lied in it nicely.
And I aimed
between his eyes: bang!
And nothing.
The Kraut screamed.
I hit again and again...
until I succeeded.
Those were the times...
You've got a dog.
Out for a walk?
Yes.
- You're going away?
- I intended to.
I had my share of travelling
as well.
After the war I drove a lorry
all over Poland.
When there was a need
I took corpses.
You know, money was scarce.
Not everybody could afford to
transport a corpse by railway.
In a coffin.
So I'd put the corpse with me
in the cab...,
pull his hat over the eyes
and go!
If I got stopped
by a police patrol,
I'd say: shush!
Don't wake him up,
he's tired after a conference.
Let him sleep.
And drive off.
How could you drive,
with... this leg?
Well... you know...
It was... with this leg,
it happened before the war.
Lost it under a tramcar...
But it's nicer to talk...
about the Uprising...
...and the truck, right?
Hey!
The bottles!
That concerns you!
"A man at the station who says
I don't know why I came here,
and after many years...
or after something like youth...
or love...
with his hand at the neck he wants
to put everything straight
and straightens his tie."
The poet already knew,
that the best ties,
are the "Forward" made ties!
Who are these people?
These names?
Who's Roman W.?!
I don't know them!
What's this cross?
What did you spent money on?
You're paid today!
Is that all?
Where's the rest?
I have holes on the elbows
and the wardrobe's full of these!
Not enough?!
Still not enough?!
And in the pockets...
Whose phone number is this?
My things take up...
My pay?
I paid the caretaker.
We owed for the rent.
Where have you been?
There're things which ought to be
discussed calmly and reasonably.
Not like now, not in this way!
What things?!
Being unfaithful, yes?!
It could be being unfaithful.
But also an illness, for example.
Or a child to be born.
Where have you been?
Listen. I'm staying with you
for as long as I want.
I can afford to be honest.
I wouldn't come back home,
do you understand?
If you can still call this a home.
Has my colleague
checked it already?
- No!
- Go away!
I'd like to know
where've you been.
60, Pretty Street, flat 21.
Didn't you see me?
An hour ago you nearly brushed
against me at Pretty Street.
Why have you packed
these things?
No reason.
Pull a face.
- What?
- Pull a face.
- Here's Warsaw Radio. It's 3 pm.
- The ugliest one.
- Or the funniest one.
- Here are the news.
Or any kind of face.
Today is the beginning
of the school year.
Once upon a time...
- ...you could do it.
- ...started their lessons.
At the beginning it's always...
...a speech to teachers and youth
gathered by radio speakers...
...this...
What's a reason for this fight?
I don't know.
On the occasion of the outbreak
of the Second World War.
In those two years
I didn't find out anything.
The memory of tragic events...
I want to know about you...
How much time have you
got for that? A year? 5 minutes?
No.
- At least I would like...
- 60, Pretty Street, fifth floor.
...the present state of armament
is sufficient,
to kill each inhabitant of the
Earth a few or several times.
I've sold the dog.
The scientists
analysing these numbers
for the subject of their research
adopted the name...
The stairs are dirty constantly
and you're fighting?!
5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 490!
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9...
Wow! It would be 500!
Sorry.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10.
Look, a sportsman.
You see him?
A sportsman.
Here.
He'll be jumping until
the tram shortens him by half.
Will he make it?
No, he won't.
He made it!
If I pay a normal fare, he should
pay an abnormal one.
I'm getting off just here.
A sportsman. Did you see him?
Here!
And here!
Two!
That was lucky!
How much could it be?
Well, it will be
in the region of...
You'll get money!
- Sorry, I'm late, I couldn't...
- Get in!
Have you got any cigarettes?
Guys,
who wants something to eat?
Eurydice, don't wait for me,
I'm forgetting you slowly.
Don't get in! Reserved!
For children
of the unknown soldier!
Eurydice, Life is breaking us,
and you can never start anew.
I don't even want to know
if you died.
Eurydice, don't wait for me,
I'm forgetting you slowly.
Eurydice, Life is breaking us,
and you can never start anew.
Eurydice, where will I find you?
The sorrow pushes the heart
into the throat.
Eurydice, don't wait for me,
I don't even want to know
if you died!
Eurydice, don't wait for me,
I'm forgetting you slowly.
Eurydice, Life is breaking us,
and you can never start a new.
Eurydice, where will I find you?
The sorrow pushes my heart
into my throat
Eurydice, don' t wait for me,
I don't even want to know
if you died!