Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
NARRATOR: Since biblical times,
man has witnessed and recorded
strange manifestations in the sky
and speculated on the possibilities
of visitors from another world.
[♪♪♪]
[TELEGRAPH TICKING]
NARRATOR: Today, from the skies
of California, the fields of Kansas,
the rice paddies of the Orient,
the air lanes of the world,
come persistent reports of UFOs,
Unidentified Flying Objects,
which we have come to know
as flying saucers.
[TRAY CLATTERS]
[♪♪♪]
NARRATOR: In Dayton, Ohio,
the Air Intelligence Command
gathers and sifts data from
all quarters of the globe.
Ninety-seven percent of the objects
prove, on investigation,
to be of natural origin,
while 3 percent still are
listed as unknown.
The Air Force is aware
of the widely held belief
that some of these could be
flying saucers from another planet.
While there is nothing
conclusive in the evidence,
the probing and digesting
of information about UFOs
continues unceasingly.
As a result, headquarters of the
Hemispheric Defense Command
in Colorado Springs issued an order:
All military installations
are to fire on sight
at any flying objects
not identifiable.
But even as they did so,
the military wondered
whether their scientific know-how
and their best weapons
would be effective in any battle
of the Earth vs. the flying saucers.
[♪♪♪]
July 16. To Internal Security
Commission. Re: Sky Hook.
Summary and progress report
from project director
Dr. Russell A. Marvin--
And Mrs. Dr. Russell A. Marvin,
without whose inspiration
and untiring criticism
this report could never
have been written.
Married two hours and already
she's claiming community property.
Now that you're married, Dr. Marvin,
you don't have to sneak up on me.
You always did have eyes
in the back of your head.
Besides, it's not safe
when you're driving.
But pretty.
I thought intellectual giants were
supposed to be backwards and shy.
My third-grade teacher,
Miss Hickey, said I was
a quick study.
You're starting something
you're not going to be able
to finish.
Yeah.
Yeah, today, I've got a hot date
with a three-stage rocket.
Now, please, no interruptions.
Because of recent
scientific advances,
it is now possible to realize
an ancient dream:
The exploration
of outer space.
To prepare for this great stride
forward, we are assembling data
on conditions at atmospheric
levels beyond those
hitherto explored.
RUSS: To collect the necessary data,
unmanned automatic observation
posts are being sent up
in multiple-stage rockets,
to a distance hundreds of miles
above the Earth's surface.
There, swinging in endless
orbits around our planet,
will be 12 tiny man-made
satellites, or moons.
They will report to us by radio, thus
providing primary information needed
to prepare the way for
our ascent into space.
The effects of gravitational loss,
showers of meteoric dust,
the fierce and undiluted heat of
the sun, the cosmic radiation.
All will be studied and analysed.
At the present time, we have launched
10 of the artificial satellites,
or birds, as we call them. We--
[WHIRRING]
Do you hear something?
Hear what?
I don't hear any--
Shh. Listen.
[♪♪♪]
Pull over.
[SAUCER WHOOSHING]
Russ, it was a saucer?
A flying saucer?
Well, we saw what appeared
to be a flying saucer.
That's all we can say.
We saw it.
We heard it, both of us.
What more do we
need to know?
Well, we have to have time
to think, to evaluate this,
before we sound off.
Let-- Let me have a light.
Of course, it wasn't
a saucer at all.
I just shake like this
all the time.
[♪♪♪]
Carol, I want you to transcribe
these notes for my report.
Yes, boss.
But there's one
little thing first.
Now that you're married,
Dr. Marvin, the first thing
you've got to learn
is no more passes at
the secretaries during
business hours.
All right.
RUSS [ON TAPE]:
--or birds, as we call them. We--
[SAUCER WHIRRING ON TAPE]
Russ.
The saucer sound.
It's on the tape.
You forgot to turn it off.
I remember now.
I turned it off afterwards.
[SAUCER WHIRRING ON TAPE]
Well, that's one piece
of concrete evidence.
MAN [OVER INTERCOM]:
Rocket Number 11 will be
launched in 20 minutes.
Well, we'll leave it for now.
Come on, we've just got
time to get to the bunker.
General Hanley reporting
to Project Sky Hook.
Make it fast, will you?
I'm in a hurry.
Nobody allowed in, sir.
There's a rocket taking off now.
That's what I want to stop.
Let me speak to
Dr. Russell Marvin.
West Gate to Bunker Number 2.
Dr. Marvin.
[PHONE RINGS]
Bunker Number 2,
Marvin speaking.
GUARD [ON PHONE]:
This is the West Gate, sir.
General Hanley wants you.
Oh, put him on.
Carol, it's your father.
Calling from Panama?
No, right here at the project.
HANLEY [ON PHONE]:
Hello, Russ?
Hello. Well, welcome home, general.
What's the news from Panama?
It's bad, I'm afraid.
I think you ought to hear what I found
before you send up another rocket.
Can you possibly put it off?
I'm afraid I can't, we're tied to a
definite schedule of launchings.
Wait a minute, uh, there's
something else I wanted...
Just a minute.
[WHISPERS]
It's your privilege.
Hi, Dad.
What is it, honey?
I just wanted to hear your voice
and tell you Russ and I
were married last night.
Married?
Forgive us for not letting
you know, darling.
[BUZZER SOUNDING]
I've gotta hang up. Let's have
dinner tonight. Can you?
Don't forget. Bye.
RUSS:
Fourteen, 13, 12,
11, 10, nine, eight,
seven, six,
five, four, three, two, one.
HANLEY:
I know how the designer feels
hearing a thing like this,
but Project Sky Hook hasn't
worked out the way the
Defense Department hoped.
Tell me, how many birds
have you sent up so far?
Eleven, counting today's.
And how many are you
in contact with right now?
Just one. Today's.
I admit we haven't been able
to track them visually so far,
but we'll correct that.
Don't be too sure
of that.
We can certainly tune them in
if they're up there.
What I'm trying to tell you is
that they're no longer up there.
That wasn't a meteorite
that fell on Panama.
It was the burned remains
of Number 7. I made sure
of that myself.
What?
And Intelligence has reports
now which convince us
that 1 and 3 fell over Africa,
Number 5 around the North Pole,
and 9 and 10 along the Andes.
The rest can be presumed to have
been lost some place at sea.
What happens to them?
Apparently they blow up
in outer space.
Why? There's nothing
explosive in them.
You can take it from me,
when a rocket's blasted off, it should
circle the Earth for a long time.
That is, unless--
CAROL: Russ? Dad?
Unless what?
Unless someone, something,
shoots them down as fast as
we set them up there.
Why, no gun in the world
can shoot that high.
No. No, of course not.
CAROL:
Bring spoons for your coffee.
Ah, my special barbecue.
Mm-hm. That's to make up for not
telling you about our getting married.
It was kind of sudden
for us too.
Sudden? I've only been
after him for a year.
I don't need to tell you,
both of you, how pleased I am.
Well, I'm glad of that. I wouldn't
like it very much if you weren't.
Thank you.
Russ, what were you
driving at back there,
about something shooting
down one of the satellites?
General, we saw a strange
thing this afternoon.
We saw what appeared
to be a flying saucer.
A flying saucer?
It nearly ran into us.
You're sure of it?
Both Carol and I are subject to
the same atmospheric disturbances
that may have affected
other observers,
but there is a qualitative difference
when you're a scientist.
We do have one piece
of supporting evidence:
An accidental recording
of the sounds it made.
The tape is in the lab at the project.
I'd like you to hear it tomorrow.
You both saw this?
Yes.
Excuse me.
From Captain Holoway, sir.
Oh.
Will you sign here, please?
Who's Holoway?
He's on monitor duty this evening.
[ENGINE STARTS]
[JEEP DRIVES OFF]
They've just lost contact
with Number 11.
Oh, Russ,
I'm sorry.
Is it still in range
of our receivers?
If it hasn't been knocked down.
Look.
What are those lights?
They're what the pilots
call foo lights.
St. Elmo's Fire,
in ancient times.
The superstitious
regard them as omens
of things to come.
The best science has been
able to make out of them is
that they're electric particles
agitated by moving air.
Same principle as
the aurora borealis.
There have been so many around
the project the last couple of days,
we all just take them for granted.
Bird 11 ought to be visible
in the sky right now, on its
second lap around the world.
Look, there it is.
[♪♪♪]
Was that it?
Yes.
Well, surely you're not going
to send up Number 12
tomorrow after this?
I have to.
Why?
With a television pickup,
cameras and microphone.
I should've done it before.
This time I'm gonna know
what's happening up there
and know the reason why.
Come on, let's finish
our dinner.
Checking TV pickup.
Getting a good image?
Fine.
TV's okay. I'll be down
in a couple of minutes.
Tell them to hurry it up.
Do you notice anything different
since you were here last?
Soundproofing?
That's right.
You could fire a cannon off
outside and you couldn't
hear a thing down here.
MAN [OVER INTERCOM]:
Number 12 okay for takeoff.
Well, as an old rocket man
from way back, I'd rather
watch from ground level.
MAN [OVER INTERCOM]:
Dr. Marvin. Dr. Marvin.
Marvin here.
You getting ready for a siege?
Well, Russ and I are gonna take turns
monitoring this one ourselves.
For days, if necessary.
Soundproof privacy and the last
word in scientific solitude.
Happy honeymoon, darling.
Thanks, Dad.
MAN [OVER PA]:
Prepare rocket for launching.
[WAILING]
MAN [OVER INTERCOM]:
Rocket Number 12 will be
launched in five minutes.
KIMBERLY [OVER INTERCOM]:
Four minutes to zero.
Check. Take it up at zero,
Major Kimberly.
KIMBERLY:
Okay.
Stand by.
EVANS:
Observation Tower A, come in.
Evans, Radar to Tower A.
Observation Tower A,
Sergeant Nash.
EVANS [OVER RADIO]:
UFO due west, approaching fast.
What does it look like?
EVANS: Can't tell yet.
I'll call when I get a better
reading on my scope.
Do that.
As you were, sergeant.
Unidentified flying object reported
due west, sir. Probably a buzzard.
[PHONE RINGS]
Sergeant Nash,
Observation Tower A. What?
Forget it, Walters,
this is no time for gags.
It's two minutes to zero.
Sentry at West Gate has
spotted a flying saucer, sir.
Evans, Radar to Tower A.
Tower A, Nash.
EVANS:
I got a better reading
on my scope, sergeant.
That UFO is over
the west sentry post.
It look like a flying
saucer, Evans?
EVANS:
Yes, it does.
[♪♪♪]
Sky Hook Control to
approaching object.
What is it?
I wouldn't know.
Connect me with Dr. Marvin's lab.
The line is dead.
Look at that, general.
It's landing.
[ALARM WAILING]
Battery, prepare to fire.
Fire!
[SHIELD PINGING]
They set up an electronic screen.
The artillery doesn't penetrate.
[GUNFIRE]
[♪♪♪]
Lines are out.
Abandon all
firing positions.
Mike's gone dead.
Try the phone.
The operator doesn't answer.
Look.
What's happening?
I don't know. I--
[♪♪♪]
CAROL:
I'm scared, Russ.
RUSS: They'll--
They'll dig us out.
[WHIRRING]
Where am I? What--?
ALIEN: We are speaking to you
through the translating device
above your head.
Can you understand us?
Yes, and I hope you
can understand me.
Whoever you are,
whatever you are,
you'll regret what you
did at the project.
ALIEN: Perhaps you can explain
why, after contacting Dr. Marvin,
we were met with violence.
You've contacted Dr. Marvin?
We spoke to him.
All he heard was meaningless sounds.
The same kind of sounds I just heard.
We had hoped a sufficient adjustment
for the time differential between us
would have been made.
I don't understand.
Evidently, you do not realize you
are in an interstellar conveyance.
You are already outside the
atmosphere of your own planet.
As a prisoner, all I am
required to tell you
is that I am General John Hanley
of the United States Army.
[HIGH-PITCHED BEEPING]
These are all the facts leading
up to the rocket explosion
at Operation Sky Hook.
To the best of our knowledge, my wife
and I are the only ones left alive,
since we have not seen or
heard anyone for hours.
The air is becoming toxic.
In the event of our death,
this report, together with
the recording of the
saucer sounds on this tape,
constitute all
the data we have.
The batteries are failing.
The recorder is not
running up to speed.
This is Dr. Russell A. Marvin.
[CLANK]
Russ? Where are you?
It's all right, honey. The gas
generator stopped, that's all.
CAROL: Please come close.
I'm afraid of the darkness.
ALIEN [ON TAPE]:
Dr. Russell Marvin.
The tape.
ALIEN [IN DISTORTED VOICE]:
It is very urgent that we meet.
We will appear tomorrow
at Operation Sky Hook
when your sun is exactly
over your local...
[VOICE GARBLES]
That's the sound of the saucer
we heard on the tape.
The message was sent
at an accelerated speed
so it just sounded
like gibberish to us.
When the batteries died,
the tape slowed down
and the voice
became clear.
If I'd only figured
it out before,
maybe we wouldn't have
been trapped down here.
[♪♪♪]
NARRATOR: What had snuffed out
hundreds of lives and leveled an
installation worth millions of dollars?
An aroused public
demanded an answer,
and the federal government dedicated
the strength of all of its branches
to the task of finding one.
However, when Dr. Marvin
and his wife were rescued,
the answer was to be found in
the experience of the only
two human survivors
and in a reel of tape recording
they carried to Washington, D. C.
and the Pentagon.
ALIEN [ON TAPE]:
--Operation Sky Hook.
RUSS: There can't be any
doubt about what it means:
A landing at the project
was proposed on the
day of the disaster.
There was to have
been a meeting.
If I couldn't keep the appointment,
a message was to be sent
on a designated wavelength by
ordinary shortwave transmission.
Does anyone want to have
the recording played again?
You've heard it a dozen times.
My wife and I, for three
days and nights, have been
telling what we knew.
We've been before every
committee, commission and
review board in Washington.
It's time we decided
to do something.
The tape is by no
means conclusive.
Certainly doesn't prove that your
so-called flying saucer caused the
destruction of Operation Sky Hook.
I grant you that.
A strange voice, a set of
instructions that might have
come from anywhere.
Well, has anyone a better
idea of what happened?
Personally, I'm inclined to accept
Dr. Marvin's conclusion
about the connection between
the message and the disaster.
All right,
so am I.
Then why not let me try to
contact them, meet them,
find out what this is all about.
If we are to be confronted with
a hostile and unknown power,
any decision to meet with them
must be made at the cabinet level.
Well, I just hope that while
we're waiting, another
disaster doesn't occur.
We're pressing for the
earliest possible action.
The secretary of state is
flying back from Europe,
the secretary of defense is
returning from the Pacific.
If a meeting could be
arranged in the meantime,
the only risk
would be to me.
I feel personally responsible
for what happened.
I was in charge.
Hundreds of lives were lost.
My own wife's father--
If I had the authority,
I'd grant it to you.
But we will have to wait.
But I promise you that we will
recommend that you be authorized
to make radio contact
and meet with...
With whoever
they are.
Are we through for the night?
Yes,
but we're going to ask you
to remain at your hotel.
You mean I'm under detention?
You may be needed
at any time.
Major Huglin
is assigned as
your liaison.
Good night.
HUGLIN:
Dr. Marvin.
Dr. Marvin, I don't like
this watchdog routine
any better than you do.
I'm under orders,
I have a job to do.
We're both on
the same side.
I'm sorry. I'm just tired and worried.
I know.
Well, you were in there.
You heard both sides.
Who do you agree with?
I agree with you as far as
the urgency is concerned,
but they're right too.
They're responsible to
a chain of command,
they have to be careful,
and this thing may be too
big to allow for mistakes.
[♪♪♪]
Russell Marvin calling on
225.6 megacycles. Over.
Dr. Russell Marvin calling on 225.6
megacycles as per instructions.
Are you listening?
If you hear me, please reply.
I am tuned in on the same
wavelength. Over.
ALIEN [OVER RADIO]: We hear you,
Dr. Marvin, and we understand you.
Do you understand us?
Yes.
Who are you?
Listen. It is now 9:30 a.m. Earth time,
Greenwich Meridian Time.
We will be waiting
at exactly 11:00 a.m. at the
shore of the Chesapeake Bay,
where the North Beach Road
reaches the sea.
Do not raise an alarm,
and keep this appointment.
Listen to me. I can't
keep the appointment.
I'm under orders. I'll be able
to meet you in a few days.
Do you hear me? Over.
Russ?
Hello, hello.
Dr. Russell Marvin calling
on 225.6 megacycles.
Do you hear me?
Please come in. Over.
Eleven o'clock Greenwich
time. It'll be 6:00 here.
I can just make it.
You're not going. I heard you
say you're under orders.
I didn't arrange this meeting.
I just asked them to wait.
Who ordered that radio?
I did, today. I was hoping
they'd give me the go-ahead
and let me use it.
You can't go.
I've already lost Dad.
You shouldn't have called them.
Well, maybe I shouldn't have
and maybe I should.
But it's started now and I've
got to go through with it.
But it's not your job alone.
Call someone! Call Major Huglin!
Room 312, Major Huglin.
Hurry, please.
[PHONE RINGING]
Hello?
Yes. Yes.
Thanks.
Well, call the garage.
Tell them not to give him a car.
Tell them he's sick,
anything, out of his mind.
I'll be right down to take care of it.
Sure thing, Mrs. Marvin.
Frank, may I have
my car, please?
Gee, Dr. Marvin, I can't.
I was talking to your wife on
the phone and she said that I--
But, Dr. Marvin, I can't
let you have the car.
Get out of my way, Frank.
Please, Dr. Marvin, I don't
want to lose my job. Ooh!
[♪♪♪]
There he is. See if you
can get him on the radio.
CAROL [OVER RADIO]:
Hello, Russ. This is Carol.
Russ, come in.
He won't answer me.
[TIRES SCREECHING]
CAROL [OVER RADIO]:
Wait for us, Russ.
Major Huglin and I
wanna talk to you.
[SIREN WAILING]
Russ, please come back
with us.
I'm sorry, but I have to do
my job. Let's go back.
ALIEN:
Please come in.
Come on, let's get out of here.
No, wait.
With your friends, Dr. Marvin.
[SAUCER WHIRRING]
I'm coming
with you.
Please come in. All of you.
I'm gonna phone
headquarters.
You'd better do
as they say.
[WHIRRING]
We must be thousands
of miles away
from the Earth.
And in a matter
of seconds.
ALIEN:
You are many miles away
from your planets,
but not in a matter of seconds.
Listen to your watch, Dr. Marvin.
It's stopped. It's supposed
to be antimagnetic.
We generate a magnetic field
stronger than the gravitational
field on your Earth.
This is the principle by which
we move through space.
We have adjusted the magnetic
field to compensate
for the normal loss of gravitational
effect and atmospheric pressure.
But your watch hasn't stopped.
Feel your pulse.
I haven't any.
Neither have I.
We operate in a very
different time reference.
You might say
all this is happening
between the ticks of your watch
or the beats of your heart.
And that's why we couldn't decipher
your message till it was too late.
It made it necessary for us to
defend ourselves at Sky Hook.
Then you shot down
our 11 rockets. Why?
At that time, we had no way
of knowing they were only
primitive observation posts.
We thought they might be
weapons directed against us.
Who are you? Where are you from?
Because of your leadership in
exploring the field of outer space,
we felt you could
best understand
that we are the survivors of
a disintegrated solar system.
At this moment, the remainder
of our fleet is circling your globe.
They're awaiting a signal
to tell them where to land.
What do you want with me?
Arrange for your world leaders
to confer with us in the city
of Washington.
They may not listen.
I'm only a scientist.
We will show you how important
it is to convince your leaders.
In an instant of
your time, we travel
from beyond your moon to
the surface of your Earth.
[GUNS FIRING]
There were 300 men on that ship.
Speed, maneuverability and force.
With a weapon like that, why don't
you just land and take over?
To do that would cause
worldwide panic.
Despite our power,
the few of us would
be busy indefinitely
trying to suppress a large,
hostile population.
In the end, we would be masters
of a wrecked and hungry planet.
What makes you think you'll
conquer us without a fight?
We felt it would be best to meet with
you so fighting could be avoided.
Such agreements have been
made on Earth before.
How do you know
so much about us?
We have the means of
accumulating information.
If you wish to convince yourself about
our detailed knowledge, test us.
Any question.
What's the size of the Armed
Forces of the United States?
HANLEY'S VOICE: It is approximately
3 and one half million men.
Well, what team has won
the most World Series?
HANLEY'S VOICE:
The New York Yankees.
Who was the first president
of the United States?
Washington.
I know that voice.
Who are you?
John Hanley.
My father. What have
you done to him?
ALIEN: You have been addressing
General Hanley's mind,
not General Hanley.
Look behind you.
Dad.
He will not recognize you.
He has been subjected
to a machine we call an
Infinitely Indexed Memory Bank.
We have transferred all knowledge
from his brain to our machine.
Thus, we have available and readily
accessible his total experience.
We can do this to as many as we like
and learn whatever we must know.
Oh, stop it,
please, stop it.
Put that gun away.
Don't look at that.
[HIGH-PITCHED BEEPING]
This is the beginning of the process
by which we read the brain
for the Infinitely Indexed
Memory Bank.
What have you done
with my father?
We will return him to you eventually,
and the police officer too.
Will you arrange
a conference for us?
We will tell the authorities you
want one. That's all we can do.
You're not going to cooperate
with these monsters?
It may take weeks or
months to set it up.
You will have two of your lunar
days, or 56 days Earth time.
Let them kill us now
and be done with it.
Please, Carol.
If our officials don't believe me,
I can't be held responsible.
When you tell of the
destroyer being sunk,
refer to latitude
30 degrees, 20 minutes,
longitude 45 degrees, 15 minutes.
They will believe you.
Well, suppose Major Huglin,
my wife, myself were all hysterical,
or hypnotized, or whatever
you're thinking,
that we never saw what these
fiends did to General Hanley
or the police officer.
How do you explain the destroyer?
There's word that the Atlantic
fleet has lost contact with
a vessel in the area,
but there's no confirmation
of a sinking. However,
we're continuing to check.
ENRIGHT: You realize, of course,
your contacting the saucer in the
first place violated our instructions.
This itself may have
placed the safety of the
entire country in jeopardy.
Now that the damage
is done, and assuming
your story is verified,
are you proposing that
we meet with these--?
These creatures,
and yield to
their demands?
EDMUNDS:
And why Washington?
If they want to parley with the
whole world, why do they choose
the capital of the United States?
They appear to be realists,
and Washington is one of the
centres of political power.
What about our atomic
and hydrogen weapons?
Wouldn't they be effective
against these saucers?
I'd like to answer that
question, sir, if I may.
Our atomic weapons might be
effective, if we could deliver them.
But to use nuclear power
when they land would
destroy our own cities.
And then we don't know whether
they are vulnerable or not.
In answer to your question,
Mr. Cassidy, I've learned a little
about their mode of operation
and I've got an idea for
a new kind of weapon.
It's only a guess,
of course.
A new weapon in
less than 56 days?
I have an idea for
an ultrasonic gun.
With enough scientific
and engineering help,
we could construct a working
model in a very short time.
Maybe it will work. If not,
we'll know soon enough.
And in the meantime,
you'll be working on every
other means of defense.
We have no choice but
to use every conceivable
weapon if they land.
Gentlemen, please.
"The destroyer Franklin Edison
was sunk at latitude 30 degrees,
20 minutes,
longitude 45 degrees, 15 minutes
at approximately 0600."
We are expected at the
White House in an hour
for a policy decision
that will probably involve
not only our own country
but the entire world.
Whatever the decisions,
you may be certain that you'll
be given every assistance
in testing your theory.
I suggest you start
to work right away.
ENRIGHT: Major Huglin will
make arrangements for whatever
facilities you may require.
Thank you.
HUGLIN: Hello.
Hi.
How's it going?
Well, instead of turning
electric impulses into
ultrahigh-frequency sound,
we nearly burned the place
up about an hour ago.
What?
RUSS: All right, let's try it
out on the cement block.
[WEAPON POWERING UP]
[WEAPON PULSING]
All the way.
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
Well, there goes your generator.
But it worked, Russ.
It worked, didn't it?
We know what
hit Sky Hook.
What?
Sound.
Sound? Ha-ha.
Having two small boys around
the house, I know that noise
doesn't do a man much good,
but burn him up,
knock his house down?
The sound I had in mind was of
a higher wave frequency than
we've ever been able to produce.
Then you mean we've
got the weapon?
No, I'm afraid not.
With the best materials
and circuits available,
all we've succeeded in
doing is pulverizing the
end of a cement block.
The theory is beautiful.
We don't have the tools and
the materials to make it work.
Maybe in 10 years,
five, even two.
How many days left?
Twenty-seven.
Russ, remember that report
from Dr. Patek in New Delhi?
He suggested a
different approach.
Instead of attempting to
duplicate the ultrasonic
devices of our visitors,
we try to interrupt
their magnetic field
by projecting a highly intermittent
induced electrical field.
Now, suppose we take--
Of course!
We cut the ultrasonic wavelength
into the circuit and knock them
down like clay pigeons.
Not so fast, Russ--
It can work. It can work.
Here, major, get on the phone.
HUGLIN: Yes?
We'll need the largest
portable generator that
Schenectady makes.
NARRATOR: From all parts of
the globe, under top priority,
came every facility
and scientific help
the governments of
the world could furnish.
Dr. Marvin and his staff assembled
these necessary materials
in a concealed laboratory,
where they were to translate a short
experience in a craft from outer space
into a formula, then plans,
and, finally, a functioning reality.
It's only a hollow steel ball,
but for our purposes
it's a flying saucer.
You can start up
the generator now.
[GENERATOR POWERING UP]
The magnet does that,
doesn't it?
The magnetic attraction above
is enough to counteract the
pull of gravity from below.
Go ahead, it was your idea.
You be the first to try it.
My idea?
Nonsense.
It was just as much yours, and
Dr. Patek's in India, and a dozen
other scientists' all over the world.
Come on.
[WEAPON PULSING]
It works.
It works fine.
Russ, look.
[DEVICE WHIRRING]
[EXPLOSION]
What was it?
The same kind of thing
that's watched us since
the beginning of the project.
Watched who?
Russ and all the developments
of the rocket program.
I always thought it
was St. Elmo's Fire.
I'll have to change
my mind about that.
Whatever it was, the
saucers sent it down to
find out what we're doing.
We have
television.
They may have some
totally different device that
serves the same purpose.
We'd better get to
Washington before they
decide to drop in on us.
Major, give Cutting a
hand and load that gun
on the generator truck.
Right.
Never mind the files, professor.
I'll take the diagrams.
We ought to be in Washington
in about an hour.
[♪♪♪]
I hope they haven't
spotted us.
Let's pull away from
the lab. Come on.
If that saucer stays
in firing range,
we may be able to give
the gun its first real test.
Saucer landing
near Belmont Lab.
Major Huglin calling for
aerial protection. Over.
They're sending
a bomber.
We ought to go on
with those diagrams
as quickly as we can.
I'll get them from Russ.
I'll go with you.
Fire up the generator.
We're gonna see if
this gun really works.
What's the matter?
I can't get this blasted thing started.
[GENERATOR STALLING]
They're looking
for us, all right.
[GENERATOR STALLING]
Russ, getting you and the
plans to Washington is more
important than anything else.
She's right.
She's right, if this machine
works. If not, it doesn't
make any difference.
[GENERATOR STARTS]
[WEAPON POWERING UP]
[WEAPON PULSING]
It works. If we just had
a little more power.
Russ, let's go, please.
Before it's too late.
[♪♪♪]
Keep the gun circling overhead
and the saucer will stay away.
Russ, be careful.
I think it's dead.
It's light as a feather.
Humanoid, and ancient.
These suits must serve
as an electronic and
mechanical outer skin
to take the place of their
atrophied flesh and muscles.
I must get this to a lab.
[AIRPLANE APPROACHING]
Don't go out there.
[CAROL SOBBING]
Oh. Here are Dr.
and Mrs. Marvin now.
Carol. Russ. We've
been waiting for you.
Thanks.
This is Dr. Alberts.
How do you do?
You know
General Edmunds,
Admiral Enright.
Certainly.
And Mrs. Marvin
is General Hanley's
daughter.
Mrs. Marvin.
Your father's death
was a great loss
to all of us.
Thank you.
Well, I see you've
been busy.
Oh, we've been
doing a little work.
Here, let me show you.
It didn't take too long to
break this thing down.
These helmets have a
language-translating
device in them.
Mrs. Marvin, would you say
something into the microphone?
The quality of mercy
Is not strained
[DEVICE SPEAKS IN
ALIEN LANGUAGE]
It droppeth as the gentle
Rain from heaven
[DEVICE SPEAKS IN
ALIEN LANGUAGE]
Shakespeare
wouldn't like it.
Professor Alberts said if
we read the dictionary into
the device, word by word,
we'd have a translation of those
words into their language.
By translating their
communications into our words,
we were able to decode them.
Professor Alberts requisitioned
the electronic translator which
his university had developed,
and the results, to say the
least, have been startling.
We've recorded a number
of their messages on tape.
One of the messages appears
to be a plan of attack.
ENRIGHT: The rest
were operational routine.
ALBERTS:
I'll show you how it worked.
Over here.
"We can expect trouble when
Mercury is in perihelion."
When will that be?
It happens twice
every three months.
The information is too vague
to be of any use to us.
And "the sun in
con Polaris"?
That implies an
orbital relation
between the star
Polaris and the sun.
We've never been
able to figure it out.
The blanks probably refer
to their time computation.
But these messages
do involve the sun?
Panama and the other
observatories are watching
it around the clock.
In the meantime, we have a
newer and stronger version
of our interference machine on
the drawing boards at Aberdeen.
Has there been any
determination of the
weapon's useful range?
There's a weakness.
Our instruments indicate that
the potential effect drops off
sharply after 1500 yards.
We'll have to hope
that that's enough.
Well, maybe we'll
be ready for them
when they come.
Has anyone tried
that helmet on?
Yes, we have.
I think you'd be
interested. Try it.
It weighs only
a few grams.
What's it made of?
We don't know exactly.
Solidified electricity is the
fancy name given to it by
the Bureau of Standards.
It resists everything we used
on it, including the most
extreme temperatures.
RUSS:
It makes me Superman,
for one thing.
Yes, we know.
RUSS:
I have a peculiar
range of vision.
I can also hear a young man
just outside that window,
discussing a problem
in advanced biology.
Carol, would you
see if I'm right?
MAN: --when I kissed her good night,
she slapped my face. I said:
"I didn't slap yours when you
ordered a $4 steak for dinner."
You know, just as we need
glasses and hearing aids,
these people need
electronic amplification
of all their senses,
especially sight
and hearing.
Does that suggest
anything to you?
They have their
weaknesses.
When will we
be ready?
We'll need at least
a couple of weeks.
ALIEN [OVER SPEAKER]:
People of Earth, attention.
This is a voice speaking
to you from thousands of
miles beyond your planet.
This is a voice speaking to you
EDMUNDS: Stop that.
From thousands of miles
beyond your planet.
Look to your sun for a warning.
Following eruptions on your sun,
there will be eight days and nights
of meteorological convulsions...
Turn it down.
They're arrogant enough,
announcing their
schedule in advance.
They're coming down to
take over, they made that
clear to us in the saucer.
They can move so fast and strike
so hard, they ought to be able
to sneak in and flatten us.
They expect to terrify us
with a display of power.
They're contemptuous
of our defenses.
If I'm right, they'll sail into
Washington in broad daylight
and expect us to capitulate
when they land.
ALIEN:
People of Earth, attention.
This is a voice speaking
to you from thousands of
miles beyond your planet.
This is a voice speaking
to you from thousands of
miles beyond your planet.
Look to your sun for a warning.
It's coming over
everywhere.
Following eruptions on your sun,
there will be eight days and nights
of meteorological convulsions.
Soon thereafter...
They'll panic
and immobilise
the whole country.
The whole world.
Let all nations be represented
in Washington to confer with us...
[ALIEN SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
[ALIEN SPEAKING IN
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[ALIEN SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN]
[ALIEN SPEAKING IN FRENCH]
[ALIEN SPEAKING IN
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
ALIEN:
People of Earth, attention.
NARRATOR: In every country of
the world, in every language,
every means of electronic
communication was jammed
with the message.
The warning was dinned into
the ears of the Earth's population
unceasingly for 12 hours.
And after the 12th hour, silence.
Then, a tremendous explosion
on the surface of the sun.
"Nine days."
That must be what
the missing words meant.
I get the picture. Thanks.
If I need any more information,
I'll call you back. Goodbye.
That was the Bureau of Meteorology.
As we know, sunspots
have a direct effect
upon our weather.
We can expect
heavy storms, tidal
waves, hurricanes.
When?
Beginning now and
continuing for eight days.
Just when we most need our
communications and transport.
We'll have to work under
the worst possible conditions
to prepare for an attack.
What's the schedule,
general?
You're working on the installation
of the interference units.
Our plans for evacuating the city
are already underway.
Then it's been decided
that we'll fight?
When an armed and
threatening power lands
uninvited in our capital,
we don't meet them
with tea and cookies.
There's the job of production
expediting waiting for me.
I don't believe further
discussion would
solve our problem.
Before we break up,
I remind you that we
have nine days left.
One of those days
is already half gone.
[♪♪♪]
What a nice
going-away present.
You might call it that.
Is my bag packed?
Mm-hm. Mine too.
What time do we leave?
I have to leave right now.
I'm going to Aberdeen to
supervise the interference project.
So that wasn't a hello kiss
at all. It was goodbye.
For a little while.
You're gonna have to leave town.
They're evacuating Washington.
Where am I going?
Palm Springs.
Remember the place
I told you about?
Mm-hm.
We were going there together.
I know.
Your plane leaves tonight.
Russ, let me stay.
Maybe I can help.
There's nothing more you
can do. Here's your ticket.
You'll arrive before
the bad weather sets in.
And I'll be there soon.
NARRATOR: The first of man's
vital communications to suffer
were the shipping lanes
and airways.
Then transport by rail
and highway ground to a halt.
When the telephone
and telegraph systems had failed
and the radio networks were
forced to bear the burden alone,
they, too, succumbed
to interference known to originate in
an increasing disturbance in the sun.
The world, crippled
by these events,
waited for the first sign of
an invasion from outer space.
Because of the atmospheric violence,
it was not until the ninth day
that an orderly evacuation of the city
of Washington could be attempted.
Although the authorities and
the military worked miracles,
when the 10th day dawned,
more than 60 percent of
the people of Washington
were still in the
metropolitan area.
Take these to CIC.
Yes, sir.
[KNOCKS]
EDMUNDS:
Mrs. Marvin.
Your husband told me you
were in Palm Springs.
The plane schedules
were canceled before
I could get away.
Have you heard
from Russ?
There's been practically no
communication with Aberdeen.
Wires are down, radio jammed.
But I'm expecting
a courier any minute.
[ALARM WAILING IN DISTANCE]
[PHONE RINGING]
A red alert.
[WAILING]
[♪♪♪]
[DOG BARKING]
[BUZZING]
MAN: Saucer heading in low
over the Atlantic, coming in fast.
They're breaking
through our defenses.
Ground all aircraft.
They'll be overhead
any minute. You better
get down to the shelter.
[PHONE RINGS]
Wait a moment, Mrs. Marvin.
Truck convoys from Aberdeen are
taking up positions in the city.
Your husband's section
is nearing the Pentagon.
Thanks.
[♪♪♪]
[WEAPON PULSING]
Mobile unit calling GHQ. Saucer
hit and down in the Potomac.
[SCREAMS]
Keep it in your field
so it can't fire at us.
[WATER BUBBLING AND HISSING]
[SAUCERS WHOOSHING]
Fire at the saucer
until it crashes.
Russ. Russ.
Carol, I thought
you'd gone to--
MAN [OVER RADIO]:
GHQ calling all HF units.
Saucer hovering vicinity
White House and Capitol.
Attention, all units. Saucer now
landing vicinity White House.
Attention, all units...
[RADIO GARBLING]
SOLDIER: Sounds like
they're jamming us.
[WEAPON PULSING]
[GUNSHOTS]
[SHIELD PINGING]
[WEAPONS PULSING]
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
[PULSING]
[WOMEN SCREAMING]
[WEAPON PULSING]
[SHIELD PINGING]
[PEOPLE SHOUTING]
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
[PULSING]
[EXPLOSION]
Dr. Marvin. Dr. Marvin,
we've made contact
with GHQ.
MAN [OVER RADIO]:
GHQ to all HF units.
Attention. Saucer has landed
in front of Capitol building.
All HF units, attention.
GHQ to all HF units.
[♪♪♪]
Keep firing at saucers.
[PULSING]
[SIREN BLARING]
MAN [OVER RADIO]:
The present danger is ended.
All units report to your commanders
for further orders.
The present danger is ended.
[♪♪♪]
Don't wiggle.
Here's what it says:
"The president has ordered
Project Sky Hook rebuilt,
and the space exploration
program continued
under the direction of
Dr. Russell A. Marvin.
The United Nations assembly Voted
unanimously today to award
a gold medal to Dr. Marvin."
And to Mrs. Marvin
goes a gold medal
from Dr. Marvin
for her love, courage,
devotion, et cetera,
et cetera, et cetera.
Russ, do you think
there are any more?
Will they come back again?
Not on such a nice day.
And not to such a nice world.
I'm glad it's still here.
And still ours.
[♪♪♪]