Pacha: ok.
Once we cross this bridge,
it's only an hour
to the palace.
Kuzco: Good, because
believe it or not,
I think I need a bath.
I believe it.
- What was that?
- Nothing.
Ohh!
Pacha:
Whoa!
Kuzco!
Pacha: Kuzco!
- Yeah?
- Quick, help me up!
No. I don't think
I will.
You're going
to leave me here?
Well, I was going to have
you imprisoned for life,
but I kind of
like this better.
I thought you were
a changed man.
Oh, come on.
I had to say something
to get you to take me
back to the city.
So all of it
was a lie?
Well, yeah.
No, wait.
Uh, yeah, yeah.
It all was a lie.
Toodles.
We shook hands on it!
[Echoes]
You know, the funny thing
about shaking hands is...
you need hands.
Ha! ok.
Buh-bye.
Aah!
Are you ok?
Are you all right?
Yeah.
Yeah. I think
I'm all right.
Pacha: Good!
That's for going back
on your promise!
Yii!
Yeah. That's for
kidnapping me
and taking me
to your village...
which I'm still gonna
destroy, by the way.
Ah ha ha ha!
No touchy.
Ooh!
Why did I risk my life
for a selfish brat
like you?
I was always taught that there
was some good in everyone,
but, ooh,
you proved me wrong.
Oh, boohoo.
Now I feel really bad.
Bad llama.
I could've let you die
out there in that jungle,
and then all my problems
would be over.
Well, that makes you
ugly and stupid.
Let's end this.
Ladies first.
- [Bell Dings]
- Aah! - Yaah!
[Both Grunting]
[Honks]
[Rope Snaps]
Ohh!
- Aah!
[Both Screaming]
- Ow! Ow!
- Whoa!
- Ohh!
[Alligators Roar]
Kuzco: What are we
gonna do?
Aah!
What are we gonna do?
We're gonna die!
That's it for me!
Pacha:
No, we're not
Calm down.
I have an idea.
Give me your arm.
OK, now
the other one.
When I say go,
push against my back,
and we'll walk
up the hill.
Ready?
Go.
Ow!
You did that
on purpose.
- Aah!
- No, I didn't!
Now, we're gonna have
to work together
to get out of this,
so follow my lead.
Ready?
- Right foot.
- Whose right?
Your right
or mine?
I don't care.
Mine.
Well, why yours?
OK, your right!
Ready?
OK, got it.
OK, right.
Left. Right.
Ha ha!
Look, we're moving!
[Roar]
Aah!
Don't look down!
Now, stay with me.
Stay with me.
Right. Left.
Right!
Now what, genius?
Working on it.
OK, here's the deal.
Stretch out your neck,
and I'll grab the rope.
How do I know
you won't let me fall
after you grab
the rope?
You're just gonna
have to trust me!
[Strains]
Kuzco: You know,
it's a good thing
you're not
a big, fat guy,
or this would be
really difficult.
Kuzco: Aah! Aah!
Almost.
Got it!
It's stuck.
Take your time.
No hurry here.
Scorpions!
Aah ha ha!
Kuzco!
Aah!
Oh, no!
Uhh!
Aah!
Ooh! Ooh! Ooh! Ooh!
Kuzco: Huh?
Aah!
Whoa!
[Both Laugh]
- [Rumbling]
- Huh?
Look out!
Ohh!
Pacha: Ohh
Whoo-hoo! Yeah!
Ooh, look at me
and my bad self.
I snatched you
right out of the air.
"Ooh, I'm
a crumbly canyon wall,
and I'm taking you
with me."
Well, not today, pal.
Uh-huh.
Uh-huh, uh-huh, uh-huh.
Kuzco: Uh-huh
You just saved my life.
Huh?
So?
- I knew it.
- Knew what?
That there is some good
in you after all.
- Kuzco: Oh, no
- Admit it.
- Wrong.
- Yes, there is.
- Nuh-uh.
- I think there is.
- Hey, you could've let me fall.
- Nuh-uh!
Come on,
what's the big deal?
Nobody's that heartless.
[Gasps]
Don't read
too much into it.
It was a one-time thing.
Right. Sure.
Well, we better get going.
With that bridge out,
it's a 4-daywalk
to the palace.
What?
You mean you're still
taking me back?
I shook on it,
didn't I?
Well, yeah,
but I hope you realize
that doesn't
change a thing.
I'm still building
Kuzcotopia
when I get back.
Well, 4 days
is a long time.
Who knows? Maybe
you'll change your mind.
Uh-huh.
4 days.
What are the chances
of you carrying me?
Not good.
Yzma: No, no, no!
We've searched
every village
surrounding the palace
and still
no sign of Kuzco.
Where is he?
Kronk!
Kronk here.
I'm getting tired.
Pull over.
Sure thing.
Kronk out.
Ooh! Aah!
Aah! Ohh!
[Straining]
Perfect.
These are my best shoes.
I hate this jungle.
[Insects Buzzing]
Oh, look.
A golden-throated
small-winged warbler.
Just one more
for exotic bird bingo.
Aah!
I am loving this.
[Gasps]
[Chatters]
Get away from me!
Yzma: Uhh
[Chatters]
Yeah.
Tell me about it.
[Chatters]
No, no,
it's not you.
She's not the easiest
person to get close to.
There's a wall there.
Trust me.
Are you talking
to that squirrel?
I was a junior chipmunk.
I had to be versed in
all the woodland creatures.
Please continue.
[Chatters]
Aah!
Why me?
Hey, it doesn't always
have to be about you.
This poor little guy
has had it rough.
Seems a talking llama
Kronk: gave him a hard
time the other day
Oh, a talking llama?
Ha ha ha ha!
Do tell.
Heh heh heh heh!
[Chatters]
Uh, he doesn't really
want to talk to you.
Well, then
you ask him.
[Sighs]
I hate being
in the middle.
Squeaky, uh...
squeak, squeaker,
squeaking .
[Chatters]
Aah!
Jaguars? No kidding?
Brutal.
[Chattering]
[Stops Chattering]
Uh, could you give us
a little room here?
Uh, sorry.
Uh-uh.
A little bit more,
please.
How is this?
- [Chatters]
- Yeah, that's good.
Now ask him which way
the talking llama went!
Uh, squeakity-squeak,
squeaking .
[Chatters]
Low blood sugar, huh?
Yeah.
It's a curse. Ha.
Well, as soon as we get
something to eat,
you're walking
the rest of the way.
[Sighs]
Welcome to Mudka's Meat Hut,
home of the mug...
[Giggles]
...of meat.
What'll it be?
Ahem. We'll have
2 specials.
Is that all right,
dear?
Oh, whatever you say, pumpkin.
You know what I like.
Hee hee hee. We're
on our honeymoon.
Bless you for
coming out in public.
So that's 2 specials.
And an onion log.
To split.
[Giggles]
Ordering!
I need 2 heartburns
and a deep-fried doorstop
on table 1 2!
[Laughing]
Pacha: OK, so I'll admit
this was a good idea.
When will you learn that
all my ideas are good ones?
That's funny,
because I thought you going
into the jungle by yourself,
being chased by jaguars,
lying to me to take you
back to the palace
were all really bad ideas.
Anything sounds bad when
you say it with that attitude.
Hot and crispy pill bug
for the happy couple.
Mazeltov
[Sniffs]
[Splort]
Oh, boy.
[Slurping]
Ooh. Ugh. Bluh.
Urp!
Pacha: Oh, here
Let me get that for you
Bleaggh! Uck!
Where are you going?
I'm just going to slip
into the kitchen
and have a word
with the chef.
You're gonna get us
thrown out.
Please.
With this disguise,
I'm invisible.
Heh heh!
We've been walking
around in circles
for who knows how long.
That is the last time
we take directions
from a squirrel.
I should have done away
with Kuzco myself
when I had the chance.
[Coughing]
Oh, you really gotta stop
beating yourself up about that.
[Squeak]
Kronk: Uh-oh I'll get you
another one there, Yzma
[Gasps]
You using
that fork there, pal?
Hey, don't I know you?
I don't think so.
Wrestled you
in high school?
Don't remember that.
Metal shop? I got it!
Miss Narca's interpretive
dance--2 semesters.
I was usually in the back
because of my weak ankles.
Come on, pal.
You gotta help me out here.
I don't think
we've ever met,
but I gotta go.
Don't worry.
I'll think of it.
Look, all I know is
the food looked iffy.
I'm not the only one
that thinks that, I'm sure.
Psst! Hey!
So I'm just
checking to make sure
you're going to take
the main course up a notch.
Is there anything
on this menu
that is not
swimming in gravy?
Hang on.
I'll go ask the chef.
It's a simple
question.
Is there or is there
not anything edible...
- on this menu?
- Gah!
[Gasps]
Hey, I didn't ask him
about dessert yet!
Hey, pal, what's your policy
on making special orders?
All right, buster,
that's it!
You want a special order,
then you make it!
I quit!
Yeah, but I--
I try and I try,
but there's no respect
for anyone with vision.
That's it!
There's just nothing
I can do about it!
Please don't go.
3 pork combos,
extra bacon on the side,
2 chili cheese
samplers,
a basket of
liver and onion rings,
a catch of the day,
and a steak cut
in the shape of a trout.
You got all that, honey?
3 oinkers wearing pants,
plate of hot air,
basket of
grandma's breakfast,
and change the bull
to a gill, got it.
What's going on?
No time to explain.
We gotta get out of here.
What is he
doing in there?
Unh! Come on!
In a minute.
I'm still hungry.
No, Kuzco!
OK, I'll make it simple
for you.
I'll have a spinach omelet
with wheat toast.
- You got it?
- Can do.
What's taking so long?
Pickup!
Kronk!
What are you doing?
Kinda busy here.
Yzma: Why am I
not surprised?
Your order's up!
Ohh!
Oh, well,
while you're at it,
make me the special.
And hold the gravy!
Check. Pickup!
You know what?
On second thought,
make my omelet
a meat pie.
Kronk:
Meat pie Check
Kronk!
[Screech]
Can I order the potatoes
as a side dish?
I'll have to charge you
full price.
Ooh!
Hey, how about a side
of potatoes, my buddy?
You got it. Want cheese
on those potatoes?
Thank you, Kronk.
Cheddar will be fine.
Cheddar spuds
coming up.
Spuds yes,
cheese no.
Hold the cheese.
Yzma: No, I want
the cheese
Cheese me
no like.
- Cheese out.
- Cheese in!
Come on,
make up your mind!
OK, ok,
on second thought...
Both: Make
my potatoes a salad.
- [Slurp]
Excuse me. You see
that woman over there?
[Mumbling]
No problem, hon.
We do that all the time.
Waiters: 1, 2, 3, 4
Happy, happy birthday
From all of us to you
We wish
it was our birthday
So we could party, too
Happy, happy birthday
May all your dreams
come true
Ha ha ha!
It's your birthday?
[Grunting]
What are you doing?
Look, there's 2 people
in there looking for you.
What?
A big guy
and a skinny old woman.
Wait. Was this woman
scary beyond all reason?
Oh, yeah.
That's Yzma and Kronk!
I'm saved!
Trust me, they're
not here to save you.
They'll take me back
to the palace.
Thanks for your help.
You've been great.
I can take it from here.
You don't understand.
They're trying to kill you.
Kill me? Their whole world
revolves around me.
No. I can't let you!
What? Wha--
Oh, I get it!
What?
You don't want to take me
back to the palace.
You want to keep me
stranded out here forever.
No!
This has all been an act,
and I almost fell for it.
Will you just
listen to me--
No, no,
you listen to me.
All you care about
is your stupid hilltop!
What?
You don't care about me.
Now, just get out of here.
- Go!
- But--
Go on! Get outta here!
Fine! Hmph!
Oh, this entire mess
is all your fault.
What'd I do?
If you hadn't mixed up
those poisons,
Kuzco would be dead now!
There'll be
no more diversions
until we track that
llama down and kill him!
Said I was sorry.
Can't just let it go.
Not even
on your birthday.
Yzma:
Kuzco must be eliminated
The empire will finally be
rid of that useless slug
Kronk: You got a point
Nobody really seems to care
that he's gone, do they?
Pacha!
Kuzco: Pacha?
[Sighs]
[Thundering]
[Thunder]
Kuzco:
So this is where you came in
See, just like I said,
I'm the victim here
I didn't do anything,
and they ruined my life
and took everything I had
Hey, give it a rest
up there, will you?
What? I’m just telling
them what happened
Who you kidding, pal?
They saw the whole thing,
they know what happened.
Well, yeah, but
Just leave me alone.
[Snoring]
[Gasps]
The peasant at the diner!
He didn't pay his check.
[Snoring]
He's the peasant
who I saw leaving the city
who disappeared
into the crowd
with Kuzco
on the back of his cart.
He must have taken him
back to his village,
so if we find the village,
we find him,
and if we find him,
we find Kuzco.
Oh, yeah,
it's all coming together.
Yzma!
What?!
Aah!
This had
better be good!
[Birds Chirping]
[Sighs]
[Sniffs]
[Gulp]
Yeech.
Pacha: So, there we were
standing on the cliff,
and the ground
started to rumble
And just as
it started to go,
he grabbed me
before I fell
Do you believe that?
You know, call me crazy
for following this guy
all the way out here,
but as much
as he tries to deny it,
I know
there's some good in him
Besides, I couldn't just
leave him out here all alone.
He's a lousy llama.
I mean,
a really lousy llama.
Hey, listen, Pacha,
you know, what I said to you
back at the diner,
that--that--
I--I didn't really...
So...you tired of
being a llama?
[Sniffles]
Ye-ee-ee-es!
[Sniff]
OK, we're just gonna
stop at the house
and get some supplies.
- Then we'll be on our way, right?
- Right.
Hey there, Pacha.
You just missed your relatives.
My relatives?
We just sent them
up to your house.
What did
they look like?
See, there was
this big guy
and this older woman
who was...
How would
you describe her?
Scary beyond all reason.
Yeah, that's it.
So, remind me again how
you're related to Pacha?
Why, I'm his
third cousin's brother's
wife's step-niece's
great-aunt. Heh heh.
Twice removed. [Sips]
Uh-huh.
Isn't that right, Kronk?
99 monkeys
jumping on the bed
One fell off
and bumped his head
You know, I am so sorry that
you had to come all this way,
but as I said to you before,
you may recall,
Pacha is not here.
I'll be sure and tell him
you came by.
Oh, would you, please?
That would be just great.
Oops. Silly me.
No, no. Allow me.
She's hiding something.
When I give the word,
we search the house.
OK, but I still have
94 monkeys to go.
Grr!
So, while we're
waiting for Paca--
Pacha.
Oh, yes.
Perhaps we can have a tour
of your lovely home.
You know, why don't
you just come back
when Pacha gets home?
I'm sure he'd love
to show you the...
[Stammers]
Excuse me, won't you?
I think I left
something in the oven.
This is my variation
of double-dutch.
On the signal,
we switch places.
Kronk, it's time!
ok!
Ohh!
So, we have to get
back to the palace,
find the lab,
and change him back.
Hi there!
Aah!
- That was him.
- Whoops.
You know what?
I don't believe you're
really my great-aunt.
You're more like
my great-great-great...
Go. I'll stall them
long enough
for you two to get
a head start.
Thanks, honey.
You have a lovely wife.
They're both very pretty.
Great-great-
great...
Grr! All right!
Are you through?
...great-great-aunt.
So, where were we?
Listen, sister, we're
not leaving until--
I show you the house.
Of course.
Was it a good idea to leave
your family with those two?
Oh, don't worry.
They can handle themselves.
What do you mean,
the door is stuck?
Try jiggling the handle.
There is no handle
in here.
There's not?
Are you sure?
All right, I've had
enough of this.
Tell us where
the talking llama is
and we'll burn your house
to the ground.
Uh,
don't you mean "or"?
[Sighs] Tell us where
the talking llama is
or we'll burn your house
to the ground.
Well, which is it?
That seems like
a pretty crucial conjunction.
That's it!
Kronk, break the door down!
Break it down?
Are you kidding me?
This is hand-carved
mahogany.
I don't care, you fool.
Get out of my way.
I'll break it down myself.
Yzma: A-one
OK, kids,
you know what to do.
Right, Mom!
3!
Aah!
OK, children,
on your mark,
get set, go!
[Giggling]
Ow! Ow! Stop it,
you little brats! Huh?
Yzma: Ow!
Oh, there they go, Kronk!
They're getting away!
Ha ha ha! Well,
I had a great time.
Let's not wait until
the next family reunion
to get together.
Yzma: Kronk!
I, uh, I gotta run.
[Thunder]
OK, why does she even
have that lever?
[Yelps]
Skull:
Please remain seated
and keep your arms and legs
in at all times
Aah!
Huh?
What does it look like?
I don't know.
Just keep looking.
Over here!
It has to be one of these.
Lions, tigers, bears...
Yzma: Oh, my
Looking for this?
No! It can't be!
How did you get
back here before us?
Uh...how did we, Kronk?
Well, you got me.
By all accounts,
it doesn't make sense.
Oh, well,
back to business.
OK, I admit it.
Maybe I wasn't as nice
as I should have been,
but, Yzma, do you
really want to kill me?
Just think of it
as you're being let go,
that your life's going
in a different direction,
that your body's part of
a permanent outplacement.
Hey, that's kind of like
what he said to you
when you got fired.
I know. It's called
a cruel irony--
like my dependence
on you.
I can't believe
this is happening!
Then I bet you weren't
expecting this
- No!
- Aah!
Aha!
[Sighs]
Oh, ok.
Ha ha!
Finish them off.
Kronk devil: Hey, you're
not backing down now,
are you, big guy?
Uh, where's the other guy?
Yo!
Sorry I'm late.
So, what'd I miss?
Well, Yzma just
tossed me this knife
and asked me to,
you know, take them out.
Then this guy popped up
and we waited for you,
and quite honestly--
Kronk! Why did I think
you could do this?
This one simple thing.
It's like I'm talking
to a monkey.
Whoa now.
A really, really big
stupid monkey named Kronk!
Ouch.
And do you want
to know something else?
I've never liked
your spinach puffs.
Never!
[Sobs]
That's it.
She's going down.
Now, now,
remember, guys.
From above, the wicked shall
receive their just reward.
All: That'll work.
Strange.
That usually works.
And so does this!
Ah. Should have
seen that coming.
Whoa!
Aah!
Give me that vial!
Oof!.
Ah! Ha ha!
Aah!
Oops. Clumsy me.
Yzma:
Which one? Which one?
[Alarm Sounds]
Better hurry
I'm expecting company
Yzma: Kill them!
They murdered the emperor!
No, wait! I'm the emperor!
It's me--Kuzco!
They're not
listening to me!
Just take 'em all!
- Yaah!
Get them!
Hey, I've been
turned into a cow.
Can I go home?
You're excused.
Anyone else?
All: No, we're good.
Get them!
We've gotta change you back.
Try this one.
Uh, Pacha?
A little help!
[Screech]
[Yelling]
Come on!
Kuzco: Aah!
Oh, please be
something with wings.
Yeah! We're flying !
Uh-oh!
[Guards Yelling]
We're not getting anywhere
with you picking the vials.
I'm picking the next one!
Fine by me!
Give me that one!
Don't you say a word.
- Aah!
Quick!
Drain the canals!
Pacha: Open up!
Yay! I'm a llama again!
Wait...
[Blorp]
- Aah!
There they go!
After them!
Come on, men!
Nobody lives forever! Charge!
Guards: Aah!
Grr!
Aah!
OK, only 2 left. It's
gotta be one of these.
No!
Ha ha ha ha!
Ah ha ha ha ha!
Meow.
I'll take that.
This is the one. This'll
change you back to a human.
Ow! Hey, get her off!.
Whoa!
Kuzco: Get her off me!
[Yzma Snarling]
Aah! Ow!
[Groans]
Drink the potion!
OK, ok! Aah!
Where did it go?
Where is it?
Yzma:[Squeaky]
Looking for this?
Is that my voice?
[Coughs]
Oh, well.
No! Don't drop it!
I'm not going
to drop it, you fool!
I'm going to drink it!
And once I turn back
into my beautiful self,
I'm going to kill you!
Ha ha ha!
[Grunting]
Aah!
Aah! Uh-oh.
Yzma: Aah!
Aah!
Aah! Aah!
Uhh! Whoa!
Uhh! Oh-oh-oh!
Kuzco!
Be right there!
Give me a minute!
Uhh! Uhh! Uhh!
Kuzco! Whoa!
Pacha:Kuzco!
Aah!
Oh.
The vial!
Aah!
For the last time,
we did not order
a giant trampoline.
You know, pal, you
could have told me that
before I set it up.
Aah!
Aah! Uhh--
Huh? Ha ha ha.
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Hoo hoo hee hee
ha ha ha--
Pacha: The vial!
You thinking
what I'm thinking ?
Ah ha ha ha ha!
I win.
Whoa.
Got it!
What are the odds of that
trapdoor leading me out here?
Yeah!
Uhh.
[Clears Throat]
Here, uh, let me
get this for you.
Well, see ya
on the other side.
Old man: Oh, now,
you--you
you stop being
so hard on yourself.
All is forgiven.
You're sure?
Oh, it's not the first time
I was tossed out a window,
and it won't be the last.
What can I say?
I'm a rebel.
Whoa-ho-ho, tiger.
Oh! Hey, I got to
use that arm later.
OK, buddy, take care.
Ha ha.
Ah, he's a sweet guy.
Kuzco:
So, you lied to me
I did?
Yeah. You said
when the sun
hits this ridge
just right,
these hills sing.
Well, pal, I was dragged
all over those hills,
and I did not hear
any singing.
Kuzco:So
I'll be building
my summer home
on a more magical hill.
Thank you.
Hmm. Couldn't pull the wool
over your eyes, huh?
No, no, I'm sharp,
I'm on it.
Looks like you
and your family
are stuck on that tuneless
hill top forever, pal.
You know, I'm pretty sure
I heard some singing
on the hill next to us.
In case you're interested.
[Chirping]
Ha! Boom, baby!
Theme song guy:
You'd be the coolest dude
In the nation
Or the hippest cat
in creation
But if you ain't got friends,
then nothing's worth the fuss
A perfect world
will come to be
When everybody here
can see
That a perfect world
begins and ends
A perfect world
begins and ends with us
" My acorn
is missing."
Squeak squeaking
squeak squeakity.
" Did you eat
the acorn?"
Squeaker squeak
squeak squeaking ?
"You owe me
a new acorn."
Squeak squeak squeak
squeak squeaker--
Squeaking .
I'm so proud of you guys.
Sting: In the quiet time
of evening
When the stars
assume their patterns
And the day
has made his journey
And we wondered
just what happened
To the life we knew
Before the world
changed
When not a thing I had
Was true
But you were kind to me
And you reminded me
That the world
is not my playground
There are other things
that matter
And what is simple
needs protecting
Or my illusions
all would shatter
But you stayed
In my corner
The only world I know
was upside-down
And now
the world and me
We know you carry me
You see the patterns
in the big sky
Those constellations
look like you and I
Just like the patterns
in the big sky
We could be lost,
we could refuse to try
But we made it through
In the dark night
Who would those lucky guys
turn out to be
But that unusual blend
Of my funny friend
and me
I'm not as clever
as I thought I was
I'm not the boy
I used to be because
You show me
something different
You show me something pure
I always seemed so certain,
but I was really never sure
But you stayed
And you called my name
When others would have
walked out on a lousy game
And look
who made it through
But your funny friend
and me
You see the patterns
in the big sky
Yeah, yeah, yeah
Those constellations
look like you and I
That tiny planet
and the bigger guy
I don't know whether
I should laugh or cry
Chorus: Just like
the patterns in the big sky
We'll be together
till the end this time
You don't know,
you don't know
Don't know the answer
or the reason why
We'll stick together
till the day we die
If I had to do this all
a second time
I won't complain
or make a fuss
Who would
the angels send
But that unlikely blend
Of those
2 funny friends
That's us