Aah!
Wee-be-be-bee.
Kuzco:
Will you take a look at that?
Pretty pathetic, huh?
Well, you'll never
believe this,
but that llama
you're looking at
was once a human being
And not just
any human being
That guy was an emperor
A rich, powerful ball
of charisma
Oh, yeah!
This is his story
[Crying]
Well, actually my story
That's right--
I'm that llama
The name is Kuzco
Emperor Kuzco
I was the world's
nicest guy,
and they ruined my life
for no reason
Oh, is that hard to believe?
Look, I tell you what
You go back away--
you know, before
I was a llama,
and this will all make sense
All right, now see,
that's a little too far back
Oh, ho! Look at me!
That's me as a baby
Waah!
Ahem! All right,
let's move ahead
Oh, yeah.
Theme song guy: There are
despots and dictators
Political manipulators
There are blue bloods
with the intellects of fleas
There are kings
and catty tyrants
Who are so lacking
in refinements
They'd be better suited
swinging from the trees
He was born and raised
to rule
No one has ever been
as cool
In a thousand years
of aristocracy
[Ship's Horn Blows]
An enigma and a mystery
In Mesoamerican history
The quintessence of
perfection that is he
Kuzco:
OK, this is the real me
Not this
- This
- Not this.
- Winner!
- Loser.
OK, see this palace?
Everyone in it
is at my command
Check this out
[Snaps Fingers]
Butler.
Chef.
Theme song guy.
Oh, yeah!
He's the sovereign lord
of the nation
He's the hippest cat
in creation
He's the alpha,
the omega, A to Z
[Snaps Fingers]
And this perfect world
will spin
Around his every
little whim
'Cause this perfect world
begins and ends with
Me.
What's his name?
Kuzco
That's his name
Chorus: Kuzco
He's the king
of the world
Chorus: Kuzco
Is he hip or what?
Yeah
[Tires Skidding]
Gow!
You threw off my groove!
Guard: I'm sorry,
but you've thrown off
the emperor's groove.
Sorry!
You were saying?
What's his name?
Kuzco
Chorus: Kuzco
Theme song guy:
That's his name
Is he hip or what?
Don't you know he's
the king of the world?
Whoa, yeah
Oww!
Ha!
Boom, baby!
Aah! Your Highness,
it is time for you
to choose your bride.
Kuzco: Allrighty
Trot out
the ladies
Let's take a look-see.
Hate your hair.
Not likely.
Yikes, yikes, yikes,
and let me guess.
You have
a great personality.
Is this really
the best you could do?
Oh, yes. Oh, no.
I mean, perhaps--
Kuzco: What
is he babbling about?
He's like the thing
that wouldn't shut up
Anyway, still wondering about
that llama in the opening?
Well, let me show you the people
responsible for ruining my life
First, there's Pacha
Uh, excuse me.
I'm here to see
Emperor Kuzco.
You see,
I got this summons--
Guard: Inside, up the stairs,
and to the left
Just follow the signs
Oh, great.
Thanks a lot.
Kuzco: Uh, and don't be fooled
by the folksy peasant look
Oh!
Old man: Pardon me
That's mine
Oh, here you go.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Aah! Oh, hey.
Are you all right?
Here. Let me, uh--
Oh, you're
so very kind.
What happened?
Well, I...
I threw off
the emperor's groove.
- What?
- His groove!
The rhythm in which
he lives his life,
his pattern of behavior.
I threw it off,
and the emperor had me
thrown out the window.
[Gasps] Oh, really?
I'm supposed
to see him today.
Don't throw off
his groove!
Oh, ok.
Beware the groove.
Hey, are you
gonna be all right?
Groove.
Kuzco: You see
what I mean?
This guy's trouble,
but as bad as he is,
he is nothing compared
to what's coming up next
Yzma: And why have you
come here today?
Peasant: Well
Your Highness--
I mean, Your Grace.
Kuzco: OK, gang
Check out this piece of work
This is Yzma,
the emperor's advisor--
living proof that dinosaurs
once roamed the Earth
And let's not forget
Yzma's right-hand man
Every decade or so
she gets a new one
This year's model
is called Kronk
[Fly Buzzing]
Yeah, I got
that there, Yzma.
- Kronk: Unh!
- [Buzzing]
Kuzco: Yep, that's Kronk
Now lately, Yzma's
gotten into this bad habit
of trying to run the country
behind my back,
and I’m thinking
that's got to stop
It is no concern
of mine
whether your family
has...
What was it again?
Um, food.
Ha! You really should
have thought of that
before you
became peasants.
We're through here.
Take him away. Next!
But I--
Oh, ok.
Ugh.
Kuzco: The nerve of some
of those peasants, huh?
Tell me about it.
Aah!
Hi there.
Ooh, Your Highness.
Ahem.
Oh, oh, oh,
ha ha ha. Um...
Uh, you were
doing it again.
Doing? Doing...
Doing what?
Doing my job.
I'm the emperor,
and you're the emperor's
advisor.
Remember that?
But, Your Highness,
I was only dealing with
meaningless peasant matters.
Kuzco: Whoa
Look at these wrinkles
What is holding
this woman together?
What the--
How long
has that been there?
Kronk:
Good thinking , Yzma
What do you say,
Kuzco?
Whoa! No touchy!
No touchy.
No touch.
Servant: Excuse me,
Your Highness
The village leader
is here to see you.
Oh, great.
Send him in.
Oh, and by the way,
you're fired.
Fired?
W-W-What do you mean,
fired?
Um, how else
can I say it?
You're being let go,
your department's
being downsized,
you're part of
an outplacement,
we're going in a
different direction,
we're not picking
up your option...
Take your pick.
I got more.
But I-- You--uh--
Uhh.
But--
But, Your Highness,
I have been nothing
if not loyal to the empire
for--for--for
many, many years.
Hey, hey, everybody
hits their stride.
You just hit yours
50 years ago.
So...who's
in my chair?
Kronk:
Oh, oh! I know!
Yzma.
Yzma's in your
chair, right?
Very good, Kronk.
Here. Get the snack.
Got it!
Unh! Oof!.
OK, you heard
the man.
Up, up, up.
Kronk: I’m ok
I'm fine
[Snarling]
Ah.
ok. Show him in.
Ahem.
Uh, afternoon,
Your Highness.
I'm here because
I received a summons--
Kuzco: Hey,
there he is!
My main village man.
Um, Pacha.
Anyway, I got
this summons--
Pacha.
That's right.
You are just the man
I wanted to see.
I am?
Word on the street is
you can fix my problem.
You can fix my problem,
can't you?
Sure.
I'll do what I can.
Good, good. That's just
what I wanted to hear.
Are you aware of
just how important
your village is
to the empire?
Well, I know
we grow the crops
that you use here
at the palace.
We also herd the lamas
that you--
My village?
Oh, yeah.
You got a pretty sweet
little setup there
on top of that hill,
don't you? Ha ha ha!
Yeah. My family has
lived on that hilltop
for the last
6 generations.
Uh-huh.
So tell me,
where do you find
you get the most sun?
Oh, I'd say
just on the other side
of those trees.
When the sun hits
that ridge just right,
these hills sing.
Well, that settles it.
Really?
Yep. Problem solved.
Thanks for coming.
That's it?
That's all
you wanted me for?
I just needed
an insider's opinion
before I ok'd this spot
for my pool.
Uh...your pool?
Boo-yah!
Welcome to
Kuzcotopia,
my ultimate
summer getaway
complete
with water slide.
What?
Isn't it great?
It's my birthday gift
to me. Ha!
I'm so happy.
Uh...uh...
um...I don't understand
how this could happen.
Well, let me
clear it up for you.
At my birthday
celebration tomorrow,
I give the word,
and your town
will be destroyed
to make way for this...
[Hums Carnival Tune]
So, if I were you,
I'd pick up some
change-of-address forms
on the way home.
But, um,
where will we live?
Hmm...
Don't know,
don't care.
How's that?
Oh, but wait.
You can't--
When I give the word,
your little town thingy
will be bye-bye.
Bye-bye!
Oh, w--wait. No--
Heh heh. Boohoo.
Kuzco: Oh, yeah
Everything was going my way
Kuzco: Or so I thought
He can't get rid of me
that easily.
Who does that ungrateful
little worm think he is?
Does he...
A little to the left.
...have any idea of
who he's dealing with?
How could he
do this to me?
Why, I practically
raised him.
Yeah, you think he
would've turned out better.
Yeah, go figure.
Well, it's better you're
taking out your anger
on these things instead
of the real Kuzco, huh?
[Gasps]
That's it, Kronk!
- That's it!
- [Crash]
I'll get rid of Kuzco.
Ha ha ha ha ha!
The real Kuzco?
Of course
the real Kuzco.
Don't you see?
It's perfect.
With him out of the way
and no heir to the throne,
I'll take over
and rule the empire.
Brilliant!
So how does that work
with you being fired
and all?
The only ones who know
about that are the three of us,
soon to be the two of us.
And I'm one of
those two, right?
To the secret lab!
Pull the lever, Kronk.
Yzma: Wrong lever!
[Splash]
Huh?
Why do we even
have that lever?
[Yelps]
Get out of my way!
Skull: Please remain seated
and keep your arms and legs
in at all times
Yzma: Whee!
Kronk: Faster, faster!
Yzma, put your hands
in the air!
Kronk: Whoo-hoo! Whoo-hoo!
Ah, how shall I do it?
Oh, I know.
Yzma: I'll turn him
into a flea,
a harmless little flea,
and then I'll
put that flea in a box,
and then I'll put that box
inside of another box,
and then I'll
mail that box to myself,
and when it arrives,
Ah ha ha ha!
I'll smash it
with a hammer!
It's brilliant, brilliant,
brilliant, I tell you!
Genius, I say!
Or, to save on postage,
I'll just poison him
with this.
Take it, Kronk.
Oh ho ho ho.
Feel the power.
Oh...
I can feel it.
Our moment of
triumph approaches.
Ah ha ha ha ha ha!
It's dinner time.
So...is everything
ready for tonight?
Oh, yeah. I thought
we'd start off
with soup
and a light salad
and then see how
we feel after that.
Not the dinner...
The you know.
Oh, right.
The poison--
The poison for Kuzco,
the poison chosen
specially to kill Kuzco,
Kuzco's poison.
That poison?
Yes! That poison.
Got you covered.
Excellent.
A few drops in his drink,
then I'll propose a toast,
and he will be dead
before dessert.
Which is a real shame,
because it's gonna
be delicious.
[Door Bangs Open]
Boom, bam, baby!
Kuzco: Let's
get to the grub
I am one hungry
king of the world.
So...no hard feelings
about being let go?
None whatsoever.
Kronk, get
the emperor a drink.
Drink. Right.
[Pouring Drink]
[Opening
Poison Stopper]
[Pours Poison in Drink]
[Explosion]
Your Highness.
[Sniffs]
Is something burning?
[Gasps]
My spinach puffs!
[Twangs Fork]
Ahem.
So... he seems...
nice.
Heh. He is.
He's what,
in his late twenties?
Heh heh. I'm not sure.
Saved 'em!
- That's great.
- Yzma: Great!
- Good job.
- Very good job.
Watch it.
They're still hot.
Ahem.
Ahem!
Heh heh heh.
Kronk.
The emperor
needs his...
drink.
Right. Oh. Right.
Hey, Kronky,
everything ok back there?
Well, heh.
Oh, uh...
Ooh. The drinks
were a bit on the...
hmm...
oh...ugh...warm side.
Heh heh.
Hey, did you see
that sky today?
Talk about blue.
Ha ha ha.
Yes, Kronk.
Riveting.
A toast to
the emperor!
Long live Kuzco!
[Under His Breath]
Don't drink the wine.
[Coughing] Poison.
Ah! Tasty.
Yzma: Finally!
Ha ha ha!
Good work,
Kronk.
Oh, they're
so easy to make.
I'll get you
the recipe.
Now to get rid
of the body.
OK! What were we saying?
Uh...we were
just making a toast
Yzma:
to your long and
healthy rule
Right. So what
are you gonna do?
I mean, you've been
around here a long time,
and I really mean
a long time. Um...
Ahem. [Humming]
Kuzco: It might
be difficult
for someone of your age
adjusting to life
in the private sector.
Hey, Kronk, can you
top me off, pal?
Be a friend? Heh heh.
[Yzma Muttering]
Kuzco: Now, about you
finding new work
Hit him on the head.
that's--that's
gonna be tough
More broccoli?
Because you're
you know
Let's face it
You're no spring chicken,
and I mean that
in the best possible way.
What? A llama?
He's supposed
to be dead!
Yeah, weird.
Let me see that vial.
This isn't poison.
This is extract
of llama. Ugh!
You know,
in my defense,
your poisons
all look alike.
You might
think about
re labeling
some of them.
Take him out of town
and finish the job now!
What about dinner?
Kronk, this is
kind of important.
How about dessert?
Well, I suppose
there's time for dessert.
And coffee?
All right.
A quick cup of coffee.
Then take him out of town
and finish the job!
[Kronk Singing
Jazz Scat]
Kronk: Cha cha
cha cha
Kuzco: Guess where I am
right now
Uh-huh. In the bag
Still think I'm
not the victim here?
Watch. It gets better.
Hey! Ba-da ba-da
ba-da-da
Kuzco: Ugh, he's doing
his own theme music?
[Holds Note]
Ba-da
ba-da ba-da ba
Ba-da-ba
Kuzco: Gig, dumb,
and tone deaf
I am so glad I was
unconscious for all of this
Kronk: Huhh!
Mission accomplished.
Kronk angel: You're not
just gonna let him
die like that,
are you?
My shoulder angel.
Kronk devil: Don't
listen to that guy
He's trying
to lead you
down the path
of righteousness.
I'm gonna lead you
down the path that rocks.
Oh, come off it.
You come off it!
- You.
- You infinity.
Uhh!
Listen up, big guy.
I got 3 good reasons why
you should just walk away.
" Number one..."
Look at that guy!
He's got that sissy
stringy music thing.
We've been
through this.
It's a harp,
and you know it.
Oh, right.
That's a harp...
and that's a dress.
Robe!
Reason number 2.
Look what
I can do.
Ha ha ha!
But... what does that
have to do with anything?
No, no.
He's got a point.
Listen, you guys.
You're sort of confusing me,
so be gone!
Uh, or, uh, you know.
However I get rid
of you guys.
That'll work.
Kuzco: Um, what's with
the chimp and the bug?
Can we get back tome?
Oh, boy.
Think, think, think.
What to do, what to do?
What do we do
with the body?
[Sighs]
What am I gonna
tell the village?
Come on, Kronky.
Come on, Kronky. ok.
Kronk: What do I
do? What do I do?
- Aah!
- [Mrreoww]
Kronk: Back!
Elbow! Shoulder!
- Unh!
- [Meow]
[Gasps]
Oh. Hey! Hey, you!
Kronk: Hey!
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Stop! Pardon me. Excuse me.
Sorry about that.
Coming through.
Hey, you with the cart!
Kronk: Uh-oh
This is not good.
Uhh. Hope that doesn't
come back to haunt me.
Tipo: Mom, Mom!
I think I'm still growing!
Measure me again!
Chicha: Ha!
All right, Tipo.
Stand still
and let's see.
Mom, you and I
both know
that it's
impossible for him
to have grown in
the last 5 minutes.
Mmm! Mmm!
Isn't it?
[Gasps] Look how much
you've grown!
What? Tipo, get
out of the way.
It's my turn again.
Measure me.
Dad's home!
[Kids Laughing]
Hey, ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha!
Pacha: Come here
[All Three Laughing]
Dad! I ate
a bug today!
Oh! Was Mom
baking again?
Heh. Don't tell her
I said that.
Chicha:
I heard that.
OK, everybody,
move aside
Lady with a baby
coming through.
Dad, Dad, Dad!
Look at
how big I am!
We were all
measured today.
Oh.
I'm going through
a growth spurt.
I'm as big
as you were
when you were me.
Mm-hmm. Sure are.
That's not as impressive
as my loose tooth. See?
OK, ok, you two.
Our deal was that
you could stay awake
until Daddy came home.
Now say good night.
Both: Dad,
do we have to?
[Whimpering]
No, you two can stay up.
We're just gonna be sitting
here telling each other
how much we love each other.
Right, honey?
[Coos]
- Ew!
- Blecch!
Both: Good night.
[Both Laughing]
So what did
the emperor want?
Ahem.
You know what?
He couldn't see me.
Couldn't see you?
- Why not?
- I don't know.
Well, that's
just rude.
Well, he is
the emperor.
I'm sure he's busy.
No, no, no, no. No.
Emperor or no emperor,
it's called common courtesy.
Honey...
If that were me,
I'd march right back there
and demand to see him,
and you know I would.
Sweetie, sweetie,
think of the baby.
Pacha, I'm fine.
This baby's not coming
for a while,
but even if it was,
I'd give that guy
a piece of my mind.
That kind of behavior
just--just--
Uhh! [Snarls]
I gotta go
wash something.
Pacha?
You ok?
Hmm?
Oh, yeah. I'm just
a little tired from the trip.
Um...I’m gonna go
put Misty away.
Uh, heh heh. Hi.
Excuse me.
2 seconds here.
Um, I'm the one
in the cart. Remember?
This story's about me,
not him.
ok. You got it?
All right.
We're gonna move ahead.
Sorry to slow you down.
Heh heh heh.
Huh?
Whoa.
Uhh. Oh.
Where'd you come from,
little guy?
No touchy.
Aah! Demon llama!
Demon llama? Where?
- Aah!
[Panting]
Oh, no! Oh, no! Oh, no!
Ooh hoo hoo!
Ow! Ow, my head.
OK, demon llama.
Just take it easy.
I mean you no harm.
What are you
talking about--
Oh, wait. I know you.
You're that whiny
peasant.
[Gasps]
Emperor Kuzco?
Yeah. Who do you think
you were talking to?
Uh...how did--
Um...
you don't...
look like
the emperor.
What do you mean I don't
look like the emperor?
Uh...oh...
do this...
What is this,
some kind of little game
you country folk like to--
Aah! It can't be! Aah!
Aah! Aah!
My face! Aah! My beautiful,
beautiful face!
OK, ok, ok.
I'm an ugly,
stinky llama!
Wait, ok,
Your Majesty.
- llama face!
- Shh!
What happened?
I'm trying to
figure that out, ok?
[Laughing Hysterically]
Ohh-ho!
I can't remember.
I can't remember
anything.
Wait a minute.
I remember you.
I remember
telling you
that I was
building my pool
where
your house was,
and then you
got mad at me.
Ohh!
And you turned me
into a llama!
What? No, I did not.
Yes, and then
you kidnapped me.
Why would I
kidnap a llama?
I have no idea.
You're the criminal
mastermind, not me.
What?
Hmm. You're right.
That's giving you
way too much credit.
ok. I have to get back
to the palace.
Yzma's got
that "secret lab."
I'll just
snap my fingers
and order her
to change me back.
Hey, you.
No time to waste.
Let's go.
Hey, tiny, I want
to get out of this body.
Wouldn't you?
Now let's go.
Build your summerhouse
somewhere else.
You want to run that
by me again?
I can't let you go back
unless you change
your mind
and build your summer
home somewhere else.
Hmm. I got
a little secret for you.
Come here.
No, closer.
I don't make deals
with peasants!
Then I guess I can't
take you back.
Fine.
I don't need you.
I can find
my own way back.
I wouldn't recommend it.
It's a little dangerous
if you don't know the way.
Nice try, pal.
No, really.
I'm telling you,
Pacha: There are
jaguars and snakes
and quicksand
[High Voice]
I'm not listening.
I'm not kidding.
Listen, you cannot
go in there.
La la la la
Oh. Heh heh.
Still not listening.
Aw, you...
Fine. Fine.
Go ahead!
If there's no Kuzco,
there's no Kuzcotopia.
Takes care
of my problem.
Hmm.
[Kuzco Laughs]
Scary jungle.
Right.
Ooh, a leaf.
Ooh, it might attack me.
Oh, it's a scary tree.
[High Voice]
I'm afraid. Ha ha.
Please. Never find my way?
I'm the emperor,
and as such,
I'm born with an innate
sense of direction.
OK, where am I?
- [Buzzing]
- [Gasps] Wha--
Help me!
[Crunch]
Uhh.
Fly: Too late.
OK, that was the freakiest
thing I've ever seen.
[Gasps]
[Animal Roars]
Aah!
Hmm.
What do you want?
[Chatters]
Oh, for me?
Why, I don't know
what to say.
[Laughs]
Ow!
Hit the road, bucky.
[Mutters]
[Raspberry]
Aah! Ow!
Huh?
[Snoring]
Kuzco: Huh?
Uh-oh.
[Chatters]
No, no.
No, no, no, no.
[Chatters]
No, no.
No, don't.
[Chatters]
[Loud Pop]
Ha! [Gasps]
[Jaguars Roaring]
Aah!
Kuzco: No!
[Jaguar Roars]
Kuzco: Aah!
[Roaring]
[Meow]
You killer jaguars...
Whoa!
Pacha:Aah-eee!
Aah!
[Pacha Screams Tarzan Yell]
[Jaguars Growling]
Pacha: Yee-aah!
Kuzco: Aah!
Don't worry,
Your Highness. I gotcha.
You're safe now.
Maybe I'm just new to
this whole rescuing thing,
but this, to me,
might be considered
kind of a step backwards,
wouldn't you say?
No, no, no.
It's--It's ok.
This--This is
all right.
We can figure this out.
I hate you.
- No!
- Yaah!
Kuzco: Aah! Ow!
[Both Scream]
[Bubbly Scream]
Kuzco:
Whoo hoo hoo!
Aah!
Ow!
Uhh!
[Both Cough]
[Spits]
I don't know about you,
but I'm getting
all funned out.
Uh-oh.
Don't tell me.
We're about to go over
a huge waterfall.
- Yep.
- Sharp rocks at the bottom?
Most likely.
Bring it on.
Boo-yah!
Whoo!
[Splash]
[Gasps]
[Inhales]
[Sighs]
Your Highness.
Your Highness,
can you hear me?
Oh, boy.
Come on, breathe.
Breathe!
Ohh. Why me?
Ooh!
All right.
[Inhales]
- Ohh!
- Aah!
[Both Spit]
- Ohh!
[Gargles]
Pacha:
For the last time,
it was not a kiss.
Well, whatever
you call it...
[Spits]
it was disgusting.
And if
you would've done
what I ordered you to do
in the first place,
we all could've
been spared
your little
kiss of life.
Pacha: Aw!
But now that
you're here,
you will take me
back to the palace.
I'll have Yzma
change me back,
and then I'll start
construction
on Kuzcotopia.
Oh, yeah.
OK, now, look,
I think we got off
on the wrong foot here.
Mm-hmm.
I just think if you really
thought about it,
you'd decide
to build your home
on a different hilltop.
And why would I
do that?
Because...
deep down,
I think you'll realize
that you're forcing
an entire village
out of their homes
just for you.
And that's...
bad?
[Laughs]
Well, yeah.
Nobody's
that heartless.
Mmm.
Now take me back.
What?
Wait, wait.
How can you
be this way?
All you care about
is building your summer home
and filling it
with stuff for you.
Uh, yeah. Doh.
Me.
Everyone else
in the kingdom gets it.
You're the only one
that doesn't seem to be
with the program,
eh, Pacha?
You know what?
Someday, you're going
to wind up all alone,
and you'll have no one
to blame but yourself.
Thanks for that.
I'll log that away.
Now, for the final time,
I order you to take me
back to the palace.
Looks to me like
you're stuck out here,
because unless
you change your mind,
I'm not taking you back.
[Imitates] Because unless
you change your mind,
I'm not
taking you back.
Me, me, me.
Moo, moo, moo.
Huh? What?
I didn't do anything.
I didn't--
Somebody's
throwing stuff.
You going to build a fire
or what? What's going on?
[Sighs]
He's never going
to change his mind.
Ohh. How am I ever going
to get out of here?
[Muttering,
Shivering]
[Stops Shivering]
Yzma: And so,
it is
with great sadness
that we mourn
the sudden departure
of our beloved prince...
[Sobbing]
taken from us
so tragically
on the very eve
of his 18th birthday.
Poor little guy.
His legacy will live on
in our hearts...
He never had
a chance.
for all eternity.
[Sniffles]
Well, he ain't getting
any deader.
Back to work.
[Blows]
Yzma:
Kronk, darling ,
I must admit
you had me worried
when you mixed up
those poisons,
but now that
Kuzco is dead,
all is forgiven.
Ah. Oh, yeah, yeah.
He's...
Heh. He's dead,
all right. Heh heh.
I mean, you can't get
much deader than he--
than he is right now.
Unless, of course,
we killed him again.
I suppose.
Hey, look,
the royal dresser's here.
Kronk...
I should tell you right now
I'm kind of hard to fit.
Kronk...
I wear a 66 long
and a 31 waist.
Kuzco is dead, right?
Tell me Kuzco's dead.
I need to hear
these words.
Do you need to hear
all those words exactly?
He's still alive?
Well, he's not as dead
as we would've hoped.
Kronk...
I just thought
I'd give you the heads-up
in case Kuzco
ever came back.
He can't come back!
Yeah. That would be
kind of awkward--
especially after
that lovely eulogy.
You think?
You and I are going out
to find him.
If he talks,
we are through!
Now let's move!
Dad, look out!
[Panting]
Tipo, what is it?
I had a dream that
Dad was tied to a log
and was careening
out of control
down a raging river
of death!
All right, all right,
it's ok.
- It was awful!
- Shh!
It's ok, it's ok.
Tipo, calm down.
It was just a dream.
Your dad's fine.
He just went back
to see the emperor.
Oh. Like you
told him to,
'cause you're
always right.
That's right.
Well, in my dream,
Dad had to kiss a llama.
Yeah, like that
would ever happen.
- It could.
- Nuh-uh.
- Yeah-huh.
Yeah-huh.
[Continue Bickering
Quickly]
Good night, you two.
- Night, Mom!
- Yeah-huh. Yeah-huh.
- Nuh-uh. Nuh-uh.
[Screeching]
Ooh!
[Coughs]
B-B-Brr!
Kuzco:
Uh, hey
Thanks.
Oh.
No problem.
Feels like wool.
Yeah.
Alpaca?
Oh, yeah, it is.
Oh, yeah,
I thought so.
It's nice.
My wife made it.
Oh, she knits?
Crochets.
Crochets?
Nice.
Thanks.
[Ribbit]
[Ribbit Ribbit]
So...
So, I was thinking that
when I got back to the city,
we'd, uh...
I mean, there's
lots of hilltops,
and maybe I might,
you know...
I--I might...
Are you saying...
you've changed
your mind?
Oh, well, I--I...
Because you know
that means
you're doing something
nice for someone else.
No, I know that.
I know.
And you're all right
with that?
Yes.
What?
Don't shake
unless you mean it.
All right.
Let's get you
back to the palace.
Oh, by the way,
thanks.
No...
thank you