I have a meeting in a
few minutes...
with some very jittery
stockholders, Mattson.
I hope you have
good news for me.
Yes, sir.
I do, sir.
Every tabloid’s running headlines
about Andy Barclay...
and his killer
Good Guy doll.
What about his mother
and the police?
The police were smart. They denied
everything. They can't hurt us.
The mother backed up
her boy's story in court,
so she's under
psychiatric observation.
Where's the boy now?
Midtown Children's Crisis Center.
Foster custody's pending.
My stomach hurts,
Mattson.
Is this what you
call good news?
No. I'm getting to that.
Our biggest problem
has been the rumors.
Good morning,
Mr. Sullivan.
People are saying
that some joker at the company...
must have tampered
with the doll's voice cassette.
''Hi. I'm Chucky.
''I'm the Lakeshore Strangler.
I'm going to kill you.''
Something like--
Well, something like that.
But the good news,
Mr. Sullivan,
is that now
we've got the doll.
We've rebuilt it
from head to toe.
A lot of it was
burned to a crisp,
but everything checks out--
voice cassette, servomechanisms--
We've found absolutely nothing.
This is a quality control report.
I'm sure it will make
the stockholders very happy.
I want to see the doll.
Absolutely.
Mr. Sullivan's here.
We ready?
Give us a minute. We're not
used to making them manually.
- What's wrong?
- I don't know. It's stuck.
Just--
They'll have this,
uh, worked out.
- Oh! Oh!
- My God!
Oh, Jesus!
Oh!
Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh!
Aah!
Andy, you still dreaming
about Chucky?
Sometimes.
- You want to talk about it?
- No.
Oh, come on, Andy.
Remember what I told you?
Talking helps make...
the nightmares go away.
Well, Chucky was trying
to take over my soul.
Why?
This bad man got
inside my Good Guy doll...
so he wouldn't
have to go to hell.
But then he wanted
to get inside me.
Why, Andy?
'Cause if he stayed
inside the doll too long,
he'd be trapped in there.
He needed me 'cause I was the
first person he told his secret to.
What secret?
That his real name
was Charles Lee Ray.
Boy, that's a scary dream.
It was.
You know,
dreams can't hurt you.
Dreams aren't real.
- Right?
- Right.
- In here.
- In there.
Let's hurry up.
I don't care what it takes.
Put a lid on this.
That's not a problem.
Listen to me.
You smuggle this error
out of here in 24 hours.
- Yes, sir.
- Now if you will excuse me...
I've got a meeting
I've got to get to.
As far as the stockholders
and I are concerned,
this matter is finished.
What do you want me
to do with the doll?
Stick it up your ass.
Naturally, he was badly traumatized
by the murders,
but they bounce back
pretty fast at that age.
- Poor kid.
- What Andy needs now...
is a normal family environment,
a fresh start...
and a chance
to forget the past.
Since you've done so well
with so many kids,
we were hoping you'd foster him
until his mother recovers.
- There's always room for one more.
- Mmm.
What does that mean?
Uh, well...
he seems... normal enough,
but how has all this affected him?
In order to come to terms...
with something he couldn't
possibly understand,
he turned it all into
a kind of fairy tale.
He insisted his doll
was responsible.
He said it was possessed...
by the soul
of Charles Lee Ray.
- Who?
- The Lakeshore Strangler.
He murdered a dozen people...
in this series of
ritual voodoo killings.
Are we even qualified...
to take care of
a boy like this?
I understand your concern,
Mr. Simpson,
but this is just a child's way...
of coping with
a difficult situation.
Andy's fine now.
He just wants
to get on with his life.
So, Andy, what
do you like to eat?
All kinds of things.
What's your favorite food
in the whole wide world?
Chocolate.
Besides chocolate.
My mom used to fix me eggs
for breakfast. I like eggs.
You got it.
Let's stop at the store.
- The one down here?
- Yeah, the organic one.
You're in luck, Andy.
Joanne's a terrific cook.
You like sushi?
You know what--
- Phil, look out!
- Jesus Christ!
Look out for the car.
Hey, wait up.
Make yourself comfortable, Andy.
Thanks.
Well, I have to get back
to the office this afternoon.
I thought that you'd
done everything.
Oh, I have--
Uh-uh-uh.
First rule.
Don't touch the old stuff.
- Sorry.
- Well, that's okay. No foul.
It's just that, well, we collect this
junk, and a lot of it's fragile.
- You like it?
- Uh-huh.
It's been in my family
for three generations.
My grandmother gave it to my mother
and my mother gave it to me.
And who are you
gonna give it to?
Why don't you take this upstairs and
explore. I'll be up there in a minute.
Okay.
What do you think?
Oh, I'll get used to him.
Jesus. Did you
ever hear of knocking?
Andy, did you find--
What, are you crazy?
Give them to me.
Come on, Joanne.
Phil will shoot you
if he catches you again.
Andy, this is Kyle.
She's staying with us too.
- Charmed.
- Kyle, what is this?
You've been here three weeks.
Why haven't you unpacked?
What for? I've never spent more
than a month in any home.
With that attitude,
I can see why.
Put these things away, then do me
a favor and help me get dinner started.
Can't. Got to work tonight.
Kyle, that's the third night
in a row.
I'd really like it if you'd spend
a little time with the family.
I need the money.
I'm gonna be on my own next year.
Yes, well, until then,
you're with us, ok?
- Come along, Andy.
- Bye.
I think you'll
be very happy here.
This is your room
right here.
I made those curtains
just for you.
I bet blue is
your favorite color.
Take a look around.
I'll start to unpack.
Wow.
I thought
you might like those.
Um, there's more
in the closet.
Before dinner,
we'll go explore the back yard.
Later I'll read
you some stories.
Would you like that?
There's lots of kids
in the neighborhood, Andy.
I'm sure you're going
to make new friends.
Aah!
Hey, hey, hey. Andy, rule number two,
no running in the house.
It's only a doll.
Andy, are you listening to me?
Oh, Andy, I'm sorry.
I didn't realize that was in there.
So many kids here, it's hard to keep
track of everything. I'll get rid of it.
Hi, I'm Tommy.
I'm your friend till the end.
Why don't we get settled in,
and then we'll have some dinner.
Aw, shit.
Ohh--
Hello, Gabriella.
Guess who?
That's right.
The vodka? Of course
I remembered the vodka.
Two-week anniversary.
You think I'd forget the vodka?
I know what that does to you.
Okay, well, wait for me.
On my way. Yeah.
Shit.
I want to play Red Light.
No, I don't want to play Red Light.
I want you to go back to bed.
But I'm scared.
There's nothing to be scared of.
It's just a storm.
Grace Poole.
Yes, I'm trying to
reach Andy Barclay.
Andy no longer lives here.
Who is this?
This is his Uncle Charles.
Sorry, uh, cash only.
But that's a gold card.
That's just as good as cash.
Not here, it ain't.
We don't accept credit cards.
I don't carry cash, okay?
Aw.
Oh--
- Don't move!
- Jesus!
God. Okay,
wh-wh-what do you want?
- No questions. Just drive.
- Okay, okay.
Keep going.
Now park this piece of shit.
Put your arms
behind the seat.
- What?
- Do it!
Okay. Take it easy. Take it easy.
Please, don't shoot. Don't shoot.
Look, I don't carry cash.
I got-- I got a gold card.
I'll give you anything you want.
Tell me what you want.
Freeze, asshole.
Take my-- Take the car.
You can drop me off,
but just, please, leave me alone.
- Please!
- Bang.
You're dead.
Aah!
No! No! No!
No! No! No! No!
Ha ha ha ha ha!
''The woodcutter argued
for a long time with his wife,
''but she was such a horrid,
frightening woman when she was angry,
''that in the end
he agreed to her plan.
''In the morning,
their stepmother called them.
''I think it would be nice if we
all went into the forest, she said.
''Hansel and Gretel did not reply, but
followed their parents into the forest.''
Where they all lived
happily ever after.''
- No, they don't.
- Well, they do for now.
We'll finish it tomorrow night.
- Don't go.
- What's the matter?
- I miss my mother.
- Oh, honey, I know you do.
- Will I ever see her again?
- Of course you will. I promise.
Don't worry. I'll stay with you
as long as you want.
My mother used to sing to me.
Will you sing to me?
~ Dee dee
dee dee dee dee ~
~ Hmm hmm hmm hmm ~
~ Hmm hmm hmm hmm hmm ~
~ Dee dee ~
~ Dee da da da ~
~ Da da da da ~
~ Dee da da da da ~~
- Shit.
- Hi. I'm Tommy.
Shut up, you idiot.
I like to be hugged.
- I like to be hugged.
- Hug this.
I like to be hugged.
I like to be hugged. I like--
- What was that?
- Nothing. Now go to sleep.
Nobody's going to hurt you.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Ha ha.
Eat dirt, Tommy.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Do either of you have anything
to say about this?
I think we should talk
to a lawyer first.
Kyle, that's not funny.
That statue was very important to me.
I think one of you
owes Joanne an apology.
I'm innocent.
- Andy?
- I didn't do it.
All right.
You leave me no choice.
Till somebody fesses up,
you're both grounded.
- But I have a date tonight.
- Sorry.
This is exactly how I wanted
to spend my day off. Thanks a lot.
But I didn't break
the statue. Really.
Yeah. Maybe it just fell, huh?
Hey. You want to hear me
say your name backwards?
Kyle.
Hold this.
Jesus. Give me that.
- What the hell are you doing?
- I wanted to taste it.
Get real. It tastes like shit, okay?
These things are very bad for you.
Then why do you do it?
Because grownups are allowed to do
things that are bad for them.
You're not a grownup.
You're beginning to get
on my nerves, Andy.
Why don't you
give me a hand over here?
Mr. Simpson is kind of
grouchy, isn't he?
He's not so bad.
I've had fosters that would shoot you
for staring at them cross-eyed.
- Really?
- Sure.
They figure you're not theirs.
You're just passing through.
The minute you screw up--
Grrr! They let you have it.
I got to tell you, I'm not happy
with this whole thing.
- Having second thoughts?
- Well, you have to admit it,
he's a very troubled
little boy...
that obviously has not come to terms
with this whole doll thing.
Look, all I'm saying
is that he may need more, uh,
attention than we can give him.
Phil, Andy's
been through hell.
You have to give him some time.
He'll settle down.
Besides, I like him.
I hate you.
Hi. I'm... Tommy
and I'm your friend to the end.
Hi-de-ho.
Ha ha ha.
Hi.
- Hi.
Kyle, do you miss
your mom and dad?
Can't miss someone
you never knew.
Where are they?
I have no idea.
My dad left before I was born.
My mom put me up
for adoption when I was 3.
Do you remember her?
I made it a point to forget.
It's easier that way.
Hey. Break time.
Move over.
- Want a push?
- No, thank you.
Come on. It's fun.
Come on, Andy, please,
I just want to sit here, ok?
Too late. There you go.
Andy, come on.
Give me a break. Stop it.
No. Ha ha ha!
Andy, I'll kill you.
Come on. Let me off.
Andy.
I'll get you.
- Andy, cut it out.
- Dinner!
- Come and get it.
- Ahh!
Mayhem. Come on.
I'll race you.
No fair.
You got a head start.
Excuses, excuses.
Don't forget your doll.
For Kyle.
Think she'll like it?
What do I know
about teenage girls?
- More than you did three weeks ago.
- I'm not so sure.
We should get something for Andy.
Make him feel more settled.
- Any ideas?
- How about a Valium?
Mm! Mm!
Surprise.
Did you miss me, Andy?
I sure missed you.
I told you.
We were going to be friends
to the end.
And now it's time to play.
I got a new game, sport.
It's called Hide the Soul.
And guess what? You're it.
Ade Due Damballa.
Give me the power, I beg--
This isn't over,
you little shit.
I'm not spending my life
as a plastic freak.
Next time you're alone,
you're mine.
Mm! Mm! Mm!
Oh, my God.
- It's Chucky. Look out!
- Shut up. You'll wake Phil and Joanne.
- Kill him!
- Stop it!
- What the hell is this, now?
- It's Chucky.
I told you he'd find me.
He tried to take over my soul.
- Andy, calm down.
- You didn't have to wait up.
Yeah? You know, Kyle,
I don't believe you.
You tied this child up
so he wouldn't tell on you.
- Oh, come on. Phil.
- Chucky did it.
- That's enough now.
- Chucky? I've had it.
- But you got to kill him.
- Andy!
Please, listen to me.
I'm not lying.
If you don't kill him,
he'll get me.
Andy, calm down.
I'm going to get rid of it.
There, see? He's gone.
He can't bother you anymore.
No.
I'm turning human again?
If I don't get out
of this body soon, I'm screwed.
Come on, Andy. We're late.
Andy. Don't forget your lunch.
Egg salad.
Mmm, yum.
Whatever you do,
don't act nervous.
They'll smell a new kid
a mile off.
Just act like you belong.
- What are you looking for?
- Nothing.
Is it Chucky
coming to get you?
Andy, how did you manage
to tie yourself up like that last night?
- I already told you.
- Yeah.
You're just like everybody else.
You don't believe me either.
- Kyle.
- Hi, Adam.
Why'd you leave so early last night?
You missed all the fun.
Story of my life.
Come on now.
Where is it?
Where-- Where-- Where is it?
Aha!
''Pinocchio jumped for joy, shouting,
I'm alive! I'm alive!
Then the talking cricket said--''
What'd he say?
''If you're very, very good,
and promise to tell no lies,
''then you will become
a real, live boy.
''Boys who are bent on following
their caprices...
and will have their own way,
sooner or later repent.''
- Get lost, microchip.
- Am I boring you, Andy?
No, Miss--
- Kettlewell.
I have precious little patience
for disruptive students.
But he just thwacked--
Especially new students,
whose utmost concern...
should be getting
on my good side.
I want those desks spick-and-span
before anyone leaves.
- Andy! You think this is funny?
- I didn't do that.
Go ahead, kids.
Don't forget the spelling test
tomorrow. Not you. Come over here.
Sit down and get comfy.
You're going to be here for a while.
- But I didn't do it, I swear.
- No? Then who did?
Don't even think about it.
No toys.
Head down!
Peekaboo!
Please, let me
out of here, Andy.
It's dark in here.
I promise I won't
kill anyone else. Okay?
Now open the goddamn door!
Let me out, you little dick!
Let me the fuck out!
Andy, I told you
to stay in your seat.
Come out of there!
Open this door right now.
Andy, come out
this very second.
Andy! Andy!
Andy?
Andy, this isn't funny.
Ohh!
Aah!
You've been very naughty,
Miss Kettlewell.
Aah! Aah!
Aah!
Andy, what's this all about?
Chucky followed me to school.
He tried to get me again,
so I ran home.
- Do you know what's he talking about?
- His teacher called,
said she was keeping him
after school for detention,
said he wrote an obscenity
on his paper.
Chucky did it.
All right, Andy. Come on.
This is going to stop, 'cause I will not
allow this foolishness in my house.
- Do you understand? Open the door.
- Oh, Phil--
Joanne, please.
Open the door.
Open it.
Open it!
Now, I want you to look down there
and tell me what you see.
It's Chucky, but--
His name... is Tommy,
and he's been there
since last night, hasn't he?
Hasn't he?
For crying out loud, Joanne,
the child needs professional help!
Stop pretending you're worried about
Andy. You never wanted him here.
- That's not true.
- So what are you suggesting we do?
- Send him back?
- Don't have to make it sound horrible.
Do you have any idea
how traumatic that would be?
For whom, Joanne,
for him or for you?
Look, if that kid stays here,
he's gonna tear this family apart!
Family? Is this
what you call a family?
Families don't just
give up on their children.
Joanne, he's not our child.
It's not the end of the world.
But they're going
to send me away.
You'll be okay.
Where will I go?
Andy...
I've lived with dozens
of different familes,
and they always
seem to send me away...
just when I'm getting comfortable,
but you know what?
- What?
- Every time it happens...
it just makes me stronger,
because it reminds me...
that the only one
I can count on is myself.
Okay, and you have
to learn that now.
I know it sounds tough,
but you'll deal with it.
It doesn't matter.
Wherever I go,
Chucky will find me.
Uhh!
Yaah!
...advances over the declines
by a 7-to-6 margin.
- More on today--
- What's wrong?
I thought
I heard something downstairs.
- It's one of the children.
- That's what I'm afraid of.
Why fight it, Andy?
We're going to be very close.
In fact, we're going to be
fucking inseparable.
Aah!
What the hell's
going on down--
Andy...
put down the knife.
But I need it for--
Just put the knife down,
and we'll talk about it.
Everything is going
to be just fine.
Aah!
How's it hanging, Phil?
No. Oh, God, Phil.
I'll call an ambulance.
Phil. Phil.
Oh, God! No!
Oh, God! Ohh!
Get away from me!
Oh, God!
I should have
listened to him.
He'd be here now
if only I'd listened to him.
It's not your fault.
I'll take care of this.
Andy, you'll be fine now.
Come stay at the center
for a few days...
until we can find you
a new family.
We've placed Kyle
with a number of familes.
Things always seem to work out okay.
Don't they?
Yeah.
There's your stuff.
Come on, Andy. Let's go.
He's still in the cellar, Kyle.
- Don't let him get you too.
- Andy.
We'll be out of your way
in just a minute here.
Did anyone besides the boy
witness the accident?
- No.
- Okay.
Let's go.
Joanne!
Joanne?
Rrah!
Ugh!
Bitch. You hurt me.
How much further
till we get to the kid?
- A ways.
- Step on it.
What's the rush?
If I don't get out of this body soon,
I'll be trapped in here!
What are you looking at?
- Floor it.
- Get real. This is a station wagon.
Shit!
Pull over.
Behave yourself.
I'll kill you if I have to.
Okay, honey,
let's see your license.
You were clocking 60 in a 45.
What's your hurry?
I have a date.
You're going to have to do
better than that.
That's one of those Good Guys,
isn't it?
- Yes, it is.
- I love these things. What's your name?
- Chucky.
- That's incredible.
- I'll say.
- What the hell's that?
You've seen dolls that pee?
This one bleeds.
Okay, look, uh...
just slow it down, huh?
And, uh, buckle up for safety.
Now, get going.
- You okay, honey?
- Mm-hmm.
Don't let the bedbugs bite.
Come on. Step on it.
Fine. We'll just get
pulled over again.
Just shut up and drive...
before I kick
your fucking teeth in.
Rrah!
You goddamn women drivers!
Fuck.
Fucking bastard.
Shit. Andy.
Playtime's over.
Andy, what are you doing?
We've got to get
out of the building.
Kyle, what's going on here?
You did this, didn't you?
He did it.
Get into my office.
Is this your idea of a joke?
Give me that.
Amazing, isn't it?
Aah! Aah!
Come on!
Okay, sport, we're going to have
a little game of Chucky Says.
Chucky says,
move your ass.
Snap out of it!
You act like you've never seen
a dead body before.
Andy, come on! Open it!
Andy! Open the door!
Come on! Everybody out!
Inside. Hurry.
Stop!
Come on.
Hey, lady,
slow down, will you?
~ Passin' by ~~
Say your prayers, Andy.
Goddamn it!
Pull over!
- What?
- Pull over!
Pull over!
What in the hell
do you think you're doing?
Let me go. Let me go.
What the fuck's
wrong with you?
Let go!
Crazy bitch!
We're home.
Close your eyes
and count to seven.
When you wake,
you'll be in heaven.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha.
This is it, world.
From now on,
no more Mr. Good Guy.
Ade Due Damballa.
Give me the power,
I beg of you.
Leveau mercier
du bois chaloitte.
Secoise entienne mais
pois de morte.
Morteisma lieu de vocuier
de mieu vochette.
Edenlieu pour
du boisette damballa!
Aah!
You little shit!
Do you know what you've done?
It's too late!
I've spent too much time
in this body!
I'm fucking trapped in here!
What the hell?
Andy, run.
Aah!
- Andy.
- Kyle.
Are you okay? Come on.
Shit!
Andy, hurry up.
Let's go. I'll go first.
Stay right behind me.
Come on.
Andy, step on it.
Reach! Give me your hand!
Andy! Stop yourself.
Grab the side.
- Aah!
- Andy!
- Hurry up! He's right behind you.
- You bastard!
Don't look back.
Come on. Hurry!
- You can't get away from me!
- Give me your hand!
Reach!
I'm going to kill you, Andy!
Aah!
Come on. Go! Go! Go!
Run down there.
I'm going to get you fuckers!
Aah.
G-- Oh, God!
Aah!
Oh, God!
Ohh--
Aah!
Come on. Do it!
Come on. Give me your hand.
Don't be afraid. Come on.
Closer. Closer so you can
grab my hand.
Andy. Now!
Aah!
- Can't open it.
- How will we get out?
We'll have to find another way.
Give me your hand.
I hate kids.
Terrific.
Aah!
Ugh!
- Hee hee hee hee!
- Duck!
Aah!
Aah! Aah!
Aah! Aah! Aah!
Do it!
Andy, please.
I was only playing.
Aah!
No, please!
No! No! God!
No! No! No!
Aah!
Holy shit.
We did it.
Let's get out of here.
- Let's see. Are you okay?
- Yeah.
- What's this?
- Thanks for coming after me.
Yeah, well,
you owe me one, squirt.
Kyle!
Aah!
I've got you now, Andy,
and you know what
I'm going to do to you?
I'm going to cut
off your legs too.
Huh?
No!
Aah!
Aah! Aah!
Kyle! Kyle!
Kyle! Kyle! Kyle, wake up!
Kyle!
Come on. Come on.
Ugh! God.
What did you do to him?
All right, Andy.
Aah!
Kyle! Kyle!
Aah! Aah!
Eat this, you son of a bitch!
Come on.
- Where are we going?
- Home.
Where's home?