["The right time" playing]
[Ray Charles] ♪ you know
the night time, darling ♪
[Chorus] ♪ night and day ♪
[Ray] ♪ is the right time ♪
♪ night and day ♪
♪ to be ♪
[Ray]
♪ with the one love, now ♪
[Chorus] ♪ night and day... ♪
[Glasses clinking]
[Man] You're doing
perfect, baby.
[Man 2 in British accent]
That's right. That's good.
- [Men and women laughing]
- [Shrieks happily]
[Man 3] Pour yourself
a little drink.
Yeah, I will pour myself...
Yeah, pour yourself
a little drink.
I will pour myself
[Women laughing]
[Man] Peg, focus.
Look at me and stay focused.
- [Man 3] Bunny...
- [Man] Right here, baby.
What are we seeing,
what are we seeing?
[Laughing deeply]
I'm trying to focus!
- Not too hard, peg.
- I'm trying to focus!
[Man 3] The tassels
are weighing you down.
I think you gotta lose them
and take them off!
Take the shirt off!
I have it, I have it,
I have it, I have it.
Focus. Right here.
- [Man 3] Tip it a little bit.
- [Shrieks]
[All] Oh!
That's not fair!
Peg made her drop it!
- [All chattering, laughing]
- [Man 2] That doesn't count.
[Man 3] Winner, winner,
cigarette dinner!
That wasn't my fault! Hang on.
- That is my drink.
- No, she pushed it off my head.
- I'll finish that.
- No, but I can win.
She just budged me.
It's not fair!
I know you can win.
- Mm-Kay. Are you sure?
- I know you can...
- Mm-Kay. Yeah.
- [Both laughing]
- You dropped it, or was it my fault?
- It got on my dress.
[Margie Hendrix] ♪ baby ♪
[Ray and Margie]
♪ night and day ♪
- Oh, don't set it on fire!
- [Both laughing]
- [Record stops, scratching]
- Deanie, sweetheart,
- can you please use an ashtray?
- [Dean] What?
Because if it gets on the rug,
it's impossible to get out.
Pete, your wife is drunk.
She's babbling
nonsense right now.
And she's pregnant,
and so she needs another drink,
get that baby healthy.
She should think about the baby!
[All laughing]
- Excuse me, excuse me!
- Whoa!
[Man] Did this come with
the promotion? You see this?
- Look at this man. Look at this.
- You know...
Frank did a ceremony.
It's just like the one he has.
- So gracious.
- Look at this. Look at this man.
- Kiss the ring, baby.
- [Men laughing]
["Bang! Bang!" Playing
on record player]
This doesn't get into bed.
Oh, my god.
Look at... look at this love!
Are you going
to kiss me right now?
- Yeah, is that...
- Mwah!
[Yelling]
- Time for upski downski!
- [All cheering]
Upski downski!
For you, and for you,
and for you, and for you.
Thank you.
- And these are for me!
- Those are all for you.
Drink 'em all. Drink 'em all.
[Animated chatter continues]
[Dean] You drink like a sailor
and look like a pin-up doll.
- [Bunny] Oh, baby.
- [Dean] Oh, god damn it.
You want to go for a ride?
[Woman shrieking, laughing]
["Where or when" playing]
[Woman] I'm slipping
out of the car!
[Both laughing]
[Woman] Oh, my god!
- [Man] You have to drive.
- [Woman screams]
It's your turn. Take the wheel!
- Take the wheel! Take the wheel!
- Oh, my god! What?
- No, I'm not ready!
- I've driven us...
- Oh, my god!
- I've driven us more than enough.
Alice, you're getting
so much better.
[Alice] I am. I feel better.
[Man] You're getting
so much better.
- [Alice laughing]
- Take me home, Alice.
Take me home.
- What if you're blind?
- [Shrieking]
- No, I can't! [Laughing]
- Now do it. Now do it.
You're doing so good!
- [Engine roaring]
- [Tires screeching]
- All right, now straighten up.
- Can you help me?
Straighten up.
- [Man laughing]
- [Alice giggles]
[Man] Good job.
[Sizzling]
[Alice] So then bunny said that
she wanted to play, which, mm...
She's never
played tennis before, ever.
She has a cocktail in one hand,
a racket in the other,
and, Jack...
She didn't spill a drop.
It was... [inhales]
Quite possibly the sexiest
thing I have ever seen.
I want to see you
in a tennis skirt.
[Laughing] God...
Do you think it's true
that frank actually has
a tennis court at his house?
- We'll find out, won't we?
- Yeah.
Oh, and babe, tell me...
How many people
are gonna be at this party,
because I need to know
how much tuna salad to make.
Mm.
- What?
- Frank doesn't like tuna.
- He doesn't like it.
- Are you being serious?
- Mm-hm.
Baby, why didn't you tell me?
I was planning on it being
the centerpiece to my dish.
- Alice, not the centerpiece.
- [Chuckling] Shut up.
- [Groans]
- [Loud rumbling]
[Alice] Oh, no! Shit.
- [Rumbling continues]
- [Glass clinking]
[Rumbling subsides]
Don't.
- Was that a big drill?
- Don't.
- Was that an explosion?
- Are those the progressive materials?
- Mm-hm.
You can tell me. I'm...
I'm really discreet.
- I can keep a secret.
- I'm going to be late.
No, wait, you... you can't...
You can't leave.
- [Clears throat]
- Why not?
[Whispering]
'Cause you're not feeling well.
- Oh, I'm not?
- Yeah, I'm so sorry.
I forgot to tell you, but
you're not feeling very well.
And the only way to cure it
is if we stay home all day,
and I tend to you
and kiss you and cook for...
- Mm-hm.
- No.
- Bye.
- Okay.
Oh... Jack, wait!
["Comin' home baby" playing]
Bye-bye. Make us proud.
[Chorus] ♪ do-do-do ♪
[Mel torme]
♪ I'm comin' home, baby, now ♪
[Chorus]
♪ do-do-do-do-do-do-do-do ♪
[Mel] ♪ I'm comin' home now
right away ♪
♪ do-do-do ♪
♪ I'm comin' home, baby, now ♪
♪ do-do-do-do-do-do-do ♪
♪ I'm sorry now
I ever went away ♪
♪ do-do-do-do-do ♪
♪ every night and day
I go and stay ♪
♪ I'm comin' home, baby ♪
[Chorus] ♪ come on home ♪
[Mel]
♪ comin' home, baby, now ♪
[Chorus] ♪ you know
I'm waitin' here for you ♪
♪ I'm comin' home now ♪
♪ real soon ♪
♪ you've been gone ♪
♪ comin' home, baby, now ♪
♪ you don't know
what I'm goin' through ♪
♪ I'm comin' home
I know I'm overdue ♪
♪ since you went away ♪
♪ expect me any day ♪
- ♪ now, real soon ♪
♪ I'm comin' home ♪
♪ come on home ♪
[Female voice on radio]
Victory project, day 987.
Security level, yellow.
All employees in transit
to victory headquarters.
All residents safe
and accounted for.
Enjoy the beautiful day, ladies,
and stay tuned
for frank's radio hour.
["The oogum boogum song"
playing]
[Brenton wood]
♪ oogum, oogum, boogum ♪
♪ boogum ♪
♪ boogum, now, baby you're
castin' your spell on me ♪
♪ I say, oogum, oogum
boogum, boogum ♪
♪ boogum, now, baby you're
castin' your spell on me ♪
[Faint laughter]
♪ Just look at me ♪
♪ when you wear
your high-heeled boots ♪
♪ with your hip-hugger suit ♪
[Peg] Peter made me swear
not to tell anyone.
So they're gonna build a whole
new row of houses behind us,
so we'll be much closer to town.
- [Alice] Really? Wow.
- Mm-hm.
So wait, how does that make you
closer to town?
We won't be furthest from town.
[Heavy door opening]
[Footsteps approaching]
[Door hinges creaking]
Good morning, ladies.
[All] Good morning, shelley.
I have some very exciting news.
The victory project has hired
a new employee, bill Johnson,
and I've invited his wife
to join us today.
Everyone, please give
a warm welcome...
To Violet Johnson.
[All] Welcome, Violet.
[Applauding lightly]
Let's begin. First position.
Remember, ladies,
there is beauty in control.
There is grace in symmetry.
We move as one.
[Gentle piano music playing]
[Shelley] Stomach in.
Chin up.
That's it.
[Bunny] Yeah, of course
Margaret wasn't in class.
I saw Dr. Collins
at their house again.
No!
Honestly shocked
Ted still has a job.
- Again?
- Unwrap it from her neck, Fred!
- Yeah.
- Oh, my god.
- [Bunny] Poor guy.
- Oh! I met her.
- Mm!
- The new wife.
[Whispers] Violet.
- Mm-hm.
- What's she like?
She's like a beautiful,
terrified, baby deer.
[Chuckles] Yeah. Apparently,
the husband's a real goober.
[Alice] Well, Jack better
recruit somebody soon.
Please! Dean says Jack's
about to get promoted.
- I hope so.
- Mm-hm.
You're gonna be right behind us.
What are you making
for the party?
- My deviled eggs.
- Oh, my god.
- Jack's gonna be ceo.
- [Laughs]
Hold this, please. That's it.
- I'm calling Santa.
- [Alice] Uh-oh.
- You give me no choice.
- Oh, no.
I have to call him. I have to!
That's why Santa
gave me his number.
He said I had to call
if you were bad.
I'm calling him.
I wish I had a choice.
- Give me that.
- But we stopped!
- Give me that. No. Give it to me!
- [Girl giggling]
[Alice humming simple melody]
[Inhaling deeply]
[Vocal sigh]
[Resumes humming, pauses]
[Hums melody tentatively]
[Man humming melody]
[Frank on radio] All that
matters is how you respond
in those moments.
I trust that you will prove
to yourself,
to everyone who has
ever doubted you,
that you are worthy
of the life you desire.
[Alice humming melody]
[Frank on radio]
Until tomorrow.
["Tears on my pillow"
playing on radio]
[Chorus vocalizing]
[Little Anthony]
♪ you don't remember me ♪
♪ but I remember you ♪
♪ 'twas not so long ago ♪
♪ you broke my heart in two ♪
♪ tears on my pillow ♪
♪ pain in my heart ♪
♪ caused by you ♪
[Chorus] ♪ you ♪
Oh, shit.
[Insects chirring]
[Frank on radio]
'Cause we choose to stay.
["Twilight time" playing
on record player]
Hi.
♪ In the sweet
and same old way ♪
♪ I fall in love again ♪
♪ as I did then... ♪
How was your day?
- So much better now.
- Mm-hm.
I made a roast.
- Mm?
- Mm-hm.
- What else?
- Mashed potatoes.
- Green beans.
What else?
Stuffed tomatoes.
[Whispering] What else?
[Panting]
[Moans deeply]
[Dishes clattering]
[Panting]
♪ As I did then ♪
♪ deep in the dark
your kiss will thrill me ♪
♪ like days of old ♪
♪ lighting the spark of love ♪
♪ that fills me
with dreams untold ♪
♪ each day I pray for evening ♪
♪ just to be with you ♪
[Moaning breathlessly]
[Echoing moan]
["Sh-boom" playing]
[The chords] ♪ life could be a
dream life could be a dream ♪
♪ do do do do, sh-boom ♪
[Man] ♪ life could be a dream
♪ -[Chorus] ♪ sh-boom ♪
♪ if I could take you up
in paradise up above... ♪
There's so much... skin.
[Bunny] Ooh, why don't you go
find your brother, okay?
[Alice humming melody]
Okay, you have to stop humming
that song.
- What is it?
- I don't know.
I was hoping you could tell me.
It's been stuck in my head
for days.
Maybe it's a children's song.
Something your kids sing?
Oh, no, I don't have children.
- Oh.
- Mm. Don't get me started.
It's just not what we want.
We're having fun.
I live next door. You wouldn't
believe the things I've heard.
It's like they're on
a perpetual honeymoon.
No, Jack and Alice
only have time for each other.
[Alice] It's not what we want.
Plus, bunny's kids
like me more than her, anyway.
[Bunny]
That's true, it's infuriating.
- [Laughs deeply]
- [Man humming melody faintly]
I think three
is a perfect number.
- Bill wants four.
- [Man continues humming]
Well, once you have one,
it's all the same.
- Having a second...
- [Sound fades]
- [Insects chirring]
- [Man continues humming]
[Bunny] Alice, how many babies
should Violet have?
Oh, at least seven.
["El merengue!" Playing]
- Christ. Where have you been?
- [Gasps]
I've turned avoiding
talking to other people
into an olympic sport.
- This place is incredible!
- You haven't seen half of it.
I could sleep in their bathtub
and they'd never find me.
I'm sure! Hi!
Hey!
[Kids] May we interest you
in a cocktail?
- Uh, yes, you may. Thank you.
- Yes, very interested.
- Bye-bye.
- Bye.
Thank you.
- They terrify me.
- They're so creepy.
I feel like they
sleep upside down.
- Do they wear matching outfits every day?
- Oh!
That little weirdo makes the
best Manhattan I've ever had.
We honeymooned in sea island.
- [Gasping]
- [Bunny] Oh!
- [Violet] What?
- We honeymooned in sea island.
Seriously?
Yeah, did you eat at Dominick's?
- I was a little nervous.
- [Bill chuckles]
Took a while
to get used to things.
Yeah. It takes a minute
to settle in.
- Yeah.
- But it gets easier, though.
- It does. Yeah.
- [Sighs] Well, it...
I'm just really excited
to be here.
- So excited, I can't even...
- We couldn't tell.
To be honest, I've been
out of it since we arrived.
Yeah.
- Bill says it's the jetlag.
- [Bunny] Mm-hm.
It's all just been
a bit of a blur.
It's the desert air.
You'll get used to it.
That's what
Dr. Collins said, too.
He was so sweet to stop by.
- [Bill] And, Jack, you're...
- [Jack] I'm a technical engineer.
She should come shopping
with us.
[Jack] A different department
than, uh, Dean and Ted.
Yeah, technically a worse,
less important department.
I haven't really gotten
to talk to frank very much.
Frank doesn't have to talk
to you.
Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't...
You have no idea
how extraordinary he is.
Or what he can do.
You're lucky to even know
who he is,
let alone be standing
in his house.
- [Bunny and Violet laughing]
- I'm just excited. I'm sorry.
I was just excited. Okay.
[Glass chiming]
- Oh! Guys, guys, guys. Go, go, go, go.
- [Dean] Ooh, here we go.
- [Violet] This way?
- Yeah, you should go in front.
[Light chatter, laughter]
[Shelley]
Gather 'round, everyone.
Now, usually,
we don't have the opportunity
to welcome couples in our home.
But on this occasion,
we just couldn't wait
to celebrate
our newest residents.
Bill, Violet...
I am so happy for you,
that you get to learn
from my husband...
And join this mission
and become a part
of this family.
Frank has built something
truly special.
What he's created out here,
it's...
It's a different way.
A better way.
- And we only have each other...
- [Woman] Why are we here?
[Man whispering tersely]
[Whispering]
Let's go, right now.
We shouldn't be here.
- [Whispering] What was that?
- [Faint chatter]
[Frank] Now, now.
Margaret and Ted are
going through a difficult time.
Margaret's question is right.
It is the good question to ask.
Why the hell are we here?
- [Chuckles]
- [Scattered laughter]
Why, when this landscape
can seem so...
Barren, so hard, so dusty, so...
Worthless?
Why not run?
Why not go back to safety,
status quo,
where it's safe,
where we should be?
No, I choose...
We choose to stand our ground.
Right?
To look harder, to dig deeper.
To mine that pure,
unbridled potential.
That gem of limitless
and unimaginable value.
It's just too easy to get
distracted by what seems.
Much more difficult, "braver,"
I would say...
To search for what could be.
- Dean...
- [Dean] Hm?
What is the enemy of progress?
- Chaos.
- Yes.
- [Shudders]
- [Dean chuckles]
Nasty word. Chaos.
Merciless foe, that chaos.
Energy unfocused,
innovation hindered,
hope strangled,
greatness disguised.
I see greatness
in each one of you.
I know exactly who you are.
- What are we doing?
- [All] Changing the world.
That's right.
I look around, I see
another reason why I'm here.
Once unfamiliar faces,
strangers, one and all, now...
One brave family.
Men like Dr. Collins.
One of our first, who built
this community with me.
Thank you,
Dr. Collins for your vision.
And adventurers like bill,
our newest intrepid explorer.
This brave,
young Robinson crusoe,
who's choosing to join us
on this adventure.
Bill, thank you
for being our partner in this.
And thank you, Violet,
for being his partner in this.
He could not do this
without you.
All of you wives...
We men, we ask a lot.
We ask for strength,
a shoulder to cry on...
Food at home, a house cleaned,
and discretion, above all else.
And that...
That's very difficult.
You are my rock.
I would not be here without you.
Thank you.
[Cheers, laughter]
- You're all dismissed.
- [All laughing]
[Whispering indistinctly]
["5-10-15 hours" playing
on record player]
[Ruth brown]
♪ baby, baby, baby... ♪
[Alice] Jack?
[Humming melody]
Jack?
- [Ted] Margaret.
- They're hiding me in here.
Oh, give us a second, Alice.
She'll be fine.
I'm not fine.
Nothing is fine.
- [Ted] She just needs to sleep.
- [Margaret] I don't sleep.
I have bad dreams.
Uh...
♪ I wanna love ya
love ya, baby ♪
♪ if I live to 99! ♪
♪ Just give me five, ten... ♪
[Whispering]
What are you doing?
I wonder why I chose this tie.
I like your ties.
[Whispering] No.
There are so many
people outside.
Jack, there are so many people.
There are so many
people outside.
[Alice laughs quietly]
[Exhaling]
[Panting]
[Panting quickens]
Wow him in a doubles game.
He'll 40-love this look.
[Bunny] Oh, yes, yes, yes.
Can you charge that
to Dean's account?
[Peg] I still can't believe
we can just charge, everywhere.
[Bunny] Yes,
but victory has things
- money can't buy.
- [Peg] Mm-hm.
It's true, you don't have to
worry about the weather
or learning to drive. Ugh.
- I love driving.
- [Bunny] No.
You love Jack
teaching you to drive.
That's foreplay.
Circle back to the guest list.
Were Kathy and Bob at frank's?
- I think so.
- Really?
Wow, so it just seems
very random, right?
Who is invited and who isn't.
It has nothing to do
with seniority, or success,
or even being well-liked, right?
Splish-splash. Who's ready
to dive into summer?
- Charge that.
- Hideous.
- I heard Margaret made a scene.
- Oh, my god.
Threw a drink in someone's face?
[Alice] What? No.
That did not happen.
[Sighing] She was upset.
It was humiliating,
and she's gonna get Ted fired.
Oh.
If Peter got fired...
I'd kill myself.
Not kidding.
Can't live anywhere else.
Margaret is just having
a really hard time.
Whose fault is that?
I know.
I still feel bad for her.
Of course.
It was a terrible accident.
It wasn't an accident.
Bunny, stop. Come on.
I don't want to be rude. I know
that she was your friend.
She was our friend,
when she was normal.
And then she lost her mind.
She took her son
out into that desert.
- She thought she saw something.
- [Bunny] She hallucinated.
[Alice] Well, it wasn't exactly
clear as to what... happened.
[Bunny] She knew how dangerous
it was, just like we all do.
The one thing
they ask of us is to stay here,
where it's safe.
But still, she dragged that
little boy out into the middle
- of god-knows-what.
- [Peg groans]
[Bunny] If they don't want us
going out there,
they have their reasons.
[Peg] So when they found her...
[Bunny] She was alone.
They never found him.
Oh.
I knew he died, I...
I just hadn't realized...
[Bunny] She claims
they took him to punish her.
[Loud rumbling]
Boys and their toys.
Least we know they're
getting work done.
What do you think
they're really doing out there?
- What do you mean?
- I mean, I know what they say...
You know, "development
of progressive materials,"
but, sometimes Peter insinuates
that they're
actually making weapons.
And that it's all
happening underground,
- because frank discovered...
- Peg.
Sorry.
We're all here because
we believe in the mission.
Yes.
We have jobs too, that are just
as important, just as vital.
What we do at home,
supporting them,
taking care of them.
Without that, they couldn't be
out there changing the world.
Mm.
[Gasping]
[Panting heavily]
[Frank on radio] Everyone
focuses on the sacrifices
you make by going
after what you want.
I want you to focus
on the sacrifices you make
by standing still.
By not going after what you
know you are owed by giving up,
and taking the smaller version
of your life.
Sacrifice doesn't just
take courage,
it takes faith, saying,
"I will stand this pain,
this hurt, this effort,
knowing that what I want
is waiting on the other side."
[Alice humming melody]
[Frank on radio] It's scary
to sacrifice something.
But you're sacrificing
something more
by sitting in that fear.
Until tomorrow.
["To know him
is to love him" playing]
[Bell clanging]
[Carol Connors]
♪ to know, know, know him ♪
♪ is to love, love, love him ♪
♪ just to see him smile ♪
♪ makes my life worthwhile ♪
♪ to know, know, know him... ♪
[Driver] No shopping today, huh?
What?
Oh, I said,
no shopping today, huh?
Oh, no. No.
Afraid that's
the end of the line for me,
I'm just gonna need
to loop around back to town.
That's fine, I'm...
I'm just here for the joyride.
I needed to get
out of the house.
Get some fresh air.
[Humming melody]
[Airplane droning overhead]
[Airplane motor sputtering]
Sir? Do you... do you see that?
You all right, miss?
Yeah. Do you see that plane?
Uh, I'm afraid I'm not sure
what you're talking about.
There's a plane, right...
Oh, no!
Oh, my god! Stop! Stop! Stop!
That plane! It just crashed!
Are you sure?
Yes! Yes! You...
You need to drive out there.
It just crashed. I...
I can show you where it is.
Drive? No, uh...
I don't go that way.
What?
We need to stay here,
where it's safe.
But I...
I can't go out there alone.
That's not my route. I can't.
But what if they need help?
Hey!
Oh, my god.
What's wrong with you?
[Wearily humming melody]
[Panting]
[Resumes humming melody]
[Breath rasping]
[Weakly] Hello?
[Breath hitches in throat]
I need some help.
There's been an accident.
A plane went down...
Hello?
[Frank muffled] We can let go.
We can let go of what society
has taught us to feel.
We can let go of the chaos
that reigns under the auspice
of equality.
We can fall deeper
into what we know is true,
that we crave order.
[Piano playing melody]
[Breath echoing faintly]
[Frank muffled, echoing] Allow
your consciousness to sink
into this world,
into this truth.
Sink deeper into the way
things are supposed to be.
[Jack] Alice.
[Panting softly]
[Light thudding]
[Soft thud]
[Thud repeating]
[Jack murmuring faintly]
[Muffled clattering]
["Little girl don't you understand"
playing on record player]
♪ That I want to be
your lover man ♪
♪ oh, yeah, now ♪
[Light thud, clatter]
♪ Whoo! ♪
- Jack?
- You're awake.
I didn't even have time
to set the table.
What's going on?
Well, I'm making you dinner.
Now, we were supposed
to have five courses.
Unfortunately, I think we're
down to about three.
That... don't look at that.
That course is officially
off the menu.
What happened?
I got a little aggressive
with the seasoning.
How long have you been home?
Uh, a few hours.
- [Liquid splashes]
- [Under breath] Okay.
Nope, don't look at that.
That's...
Okay, so I'm making that roast.
You know, the one you made
for my birthday?
[Exhales sharply]
Only with a few changes.
I was here when you got here?
Yeah. Asleep in the bedroom.
- [Fridge door opens]
- Do you put carrots in a roast?
How did I get home?
Trolley, I think.
Wait, so he came out and got me?
What are you talking about?
Jack, I got off the trolley.
I saw a plane crash.
Alice, I think I would've heard
if there was a plane crash.
- No, Jack, I saw it...
- They tend to be rather loud...
- And I started walking and...
- And hard to miss.
["Need your love so bad"
playing on record player]
Hey. Are you okay?
- No, I don't know. I'm not...
- What's wrong?
I had a really weird dream.
A really weird dream.
I'm sorry.
Do you know what
weird dreams make me?
What?
Hungry.
- Would you like some carrot?
- Yes.
Alice, I want to be honest
with you about something.
Mm-hm?
I don't think these mashed
potatoes are gonna work.
That's because you need
to boil them first, baby.
- [Laughing deeply]
- I knew it.
I knew there was a step
missing. Such an idiot.
Let me put a pot on.
No, no, no.
- Come on, let me just put the...
- Make us some drinks. Relax. Relax.
- Okay. Okay.
- Make some drinks.
I am your chef tonight!
[Sighing deeply]
- [Jack] Hey.
- Hm?
You love me?
[Whispering] The most.
The most.
♪ Boiling the potatoes
I'm... ♪
- ♪ Boiling the potatoes ♪
- [dishes clattering]
[Cars driving away]
[Insects chirring]
[Frank on radio]
Yes, there are always people
who will benefit
from the status quo,
and they will come for us.
- They're already coming for us.
- [Humming melody]
I am willing to sacrifice
everything for you.
I will give everything I have
to create this better world
for all of us,
but I can't protect you
without your loyalty.
[Continues humming]
When you promise something,
do you keep that promise?
Is your word your bond?
Is your word your truth?
Is it our covenant?
Until tomorrow.
[Quiet moan]
[Gasping]
[Crying out]
[Panting]
[Cracking]
[Gasping]
["The end of the world"
playing on record player]
[Telephone ringing]
[Skeeter Davis] ♪ why do
the stars glow above? ♪
[Telephone continues ringing]
♪ Don't they know
it's the end of the world? ♪
Hello?
[Margaret] You went out there.
You saw it.
Margaret?
They're lying to all of us.
I can't talk to you
right now, Margaret.
No one asks any questions.
We can't stay here anymore,
Alice.
[Crying] I'm not crazy.
You're being ridiculous
and you need to stop this.
- Alice, you know me...
- [Hangs up phone]
[Screams]
[Gasping]
No.
[Whimpering]
Margaret?
No. No, don't!
[Shrieking]
[Gasping]
Wait!
No! No, get off me!
Margaret! Get off me!
Margaret!
[Alice] Jack,
you don't understand.
I was right there.
- I watched the whole thing.
- [Jack] I'm tired, Alice.
- [Alice] I saw her fall.
- [Jack] I want to go to bed.
[Alice] I tried to go and help,
and then they dragged me away.
Why would they take me away?
- You have to stop!
- They...
There is no way
that she's fine, Jack.
No.
I don't know what to tell you.
Ted is with her
at the hospital right now.
- He said she needs a few stitches.
- Mm-mm.
She slipped cleaning
the window. It was an accident.
Nope. I saw her.
She cut herself.
You had a bad night.
- Don't! No!
- You weren't feeling well.
- She fell, and you imagined the worst case scenario.
- No, don't do that.
- She slit her throat!
- [Groans] That's crazy.
Crazy. It's crazy.
Jack, I saw it happen.
She cut herself open.
There was blood everywhere.
It's not just a few stitches.
- Please don't get hysterical.
- [Sighs]
[Voice trembling] Jack...
She was my friend.
And she came to me for help.
And I ignored her.
And then this happened.
And I feel like it's my fault.
It's no one's fault, Alice.
It was an accident.
No.
She said they would
come after her
because she knew something.
Why are they lying
about what happened?
- Please, just stop.
- What are they hiding?
Come on, baby, you have to
admit this is weird.
- Stop!
- There's something off!
What are you doing
at the victory project?
[Water shuts off]
You know what I do, Alice.
I'm a technical engineer.
Mm-hm.
I know.
But what are they doing?
Please...
What's actually happening?
Don't ask me that.
The development
of progressive materials?
- What does that even mean?
- You know we can't talk about this.
Come on, what does it mean?
What does it even mean?
Do you know?
Do you even know
what frank is actually doing?
It's classified.
We're not even allowed
to discuss our jobs
with other departments,
you know that.
What if Margaret was right?
Stop it, Alice.
What if this place is dangerous?
- What if...
- Stop it!
I'm part of
something important, Alice.
This mission,
what frank's doing, it matters.
I know that, baby,
but you're not listening to me.
No! Not everyone
gets this opportunity.
And if you keep
talking like this,
you're gonna put it all at risk.
You're worried about a demotion?
That's what you're
worried about?
Our life...
Alice. Our life together.
This.
We could lose this.
Please.
Just get a hold of yourself.
[Muttering] Fuck's sake.
[Insects chirring]
[Frank on TV]
Victory is safe and secure.
A perfect place
to raise the family
you've always wanted,
when you're not relaxing
with friends
or enjoying
the breathtaking scenery
of this sun baked paradise.
Although, you might find
the best scenery
at the club pool.
Here you can live the life
you deserve.
We can all live the life...
[Gasps]
["Sleepwalk" playing]
[Motor idling]
[Woman on radio]
If I could tell frank anything,
it would just be, "thank you."
Because I didn't know
- I could be this happy.
- [Alice humming melody]
Honestly, I don't even remember
my life before victory.
Frank gave us the opportunity
of a lifetime. I wouldn't...
[Woman continues on radio,
muffled]
[Gasping for breath]
[Woman on radio]
We are so lucky to be here.
[Panting]
[Air hissing]
- Hm.
- [Cuff tearing]
- Is there a bug going around?
- No, not that I know of.
Think this is just
run-of-the-mill exhaustion.
You had any new stresses
or pressures lately?
- Um...
- [Jack] She saw Ted's wife fall.
Thought maybe it might be shock.
[Dr. Collins] Boy,
that was quite a tumble.
She was so embarrassed.
It... it wasn't a tumble.
She slit her throat.
- [Jack] Alice.
- Uh, no, no, no.
Witnessing a trauma can often
lead to distorted memories.
Even nightmares.
It's...
I have some pills
I can prescribe for that.
Uh, I... I really don't think
that I need those.
Oh, they're precautionary.
Most of my patients have had
quite a bit of success
with them.
They will just keep you relaxed.
[Jack] She doesn't need those.
This isn't a problem.
We can handle it ourselves.
Well, I'll just
keep that on file.
What did you do to Margaret?
Pardon?
Ted's wife.
I'm sorry, I'm just... I...
I still don't understand
how she's okay.
You wouldn't want me discussing
the details of your treatment
with my other patients, now,
would you?
Mm... I wouldn't mind.
I would just... I would really
love to know the details of...
Of how you fixed her.
Well, as you know, we provide
both psychiatric
and physical care here.
And Margaret was
in need of both.
The good news is,
is that physically, she's fine,
but psychologically, she wasn't.
She was having
significant troubles.
Outbursts. Paranoia.
She made it impossible
for Ted to do his job,
so he no longer works
for the victory project.
She needed quite a bit of help.
Ah... not like you.
- [Jack] No.
- [Dry chuckle]
[Jack] It's not necessary here.
It's a totally
different scenario.
What is it that you brits say?
Ah! "Keep calm and carry on."
- [Laughs]
- [Both chuckle]
[Claps hands] Jack.
Walk me out?
Of course. [Clears throat]
[Dr. Collins] And remember...
- That I'm always a phone call away.
- Oh, thank you.
Thank you so much.
[Eerie instrumental
music playing]
[Intense instrumental music
playing]
Oh, come on.
[Locks click open]
You know our position on that.
So glad you came back.
You left this.
I'd forget my head
if it wasn't screwed on.
[Chuckles]
Jack, shouldn't you be getting
back to work?
[Jack] Yeah. Of course.
- See you tonight.
- Mm-hm.
Okay.
[Door shuts]
Oh, no. No. It's not...
[Fire crackling]
[Humming melody]
[Piano playing melody
in high register]
[Coughing]
[Gasps]
["Poor little fool" playing
faintly on record player]
[Ricky Nelson] ♪ I used to
play around with hearts... ♪
[Jack] Might ask shelley
to dance at some point,
if it feels like a good time.
You're still in the bath?
We're gonna be late.
You see the dress I got you?
Picked it out last week.
I couldn't stop
picturing you in it.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
You look incredible.
Been thinking we should
try something kind of crazy.
♪ She'd hold me close
and kiss me ♪
Let's have a baby.
♪ Poor little fool ♪
- What?
- [Chuckling] Not right now.
Look, I love you.
And I want more of you.
And I think I want a little you.
[Jack laughs]
I don't know,
I think it would be fun.
Just think about it, okay?
[Whispers] Okay.
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ I was a fool... ♪
Tonight's gonna be great.
You're gonna look beautiful.
♪ The next day she was gone ♪
♪ and I knew she'd lied to me ♪
♪ she left me
with a broken heart ♪
♪ and won her victory ♪
[People laughing, chattering]
[Drummer playing lively beat]
Good evening.
We've been waiting for you.
I'm so sorry.
You have the best table
in the house.
[Band playing "sing, sing, sing
with a swing"]
[Inaudible]
- Good to see you, man.
- Hey, guys.
Why are you two always
fighting? What's wrong with you?
- Always. Constantly.
- [Peter] We're fine. We're fine.
- [Alice] Hi.
- Oh! Finally! Hi.
Hello. Oh, my god!
Here, drink this.
You look just like
a little doll.
Spin, spin, spin! Ah!
This is me. This is you.
Here, go, go, go.
- All the way back.
- Just drink it all!
- [Jack] There we go.
- [Dean laughing] There we go!
[Shelley]
Here are the troublemakers.
[Bunny laughing]
I can't believe we're allowed
to put all of you at one table.
I think it's better for
insurance purposes,
- to be honest.
- [Bunny] That is true.
Alice, how are you feeling?
I'm... I'm well.
I'm doing well.
This is beautiful.
Thank you so much
for inviting us.
And if I hear glass breaking,
I'm coming right back here.
[Dean] Oh, don't tempt us
or we'll be breaking glass
all night.
[Dean laughing]
[Shelley] See you
on the dance floor later?
[Jack] Yes, ma'am. Of course.
[Band finishes playing]
[Shelley on pa] Can my
husband throw a party or what?
[Crowd cheering, applauding]
[Shelley] He does
so much for us.
More than we could ever repay.
But I have attempted
a little... gift for him.
- [Peg] Uh-oh.
- [Shelley] For all of us, really.
I hope you enjoy.
[Band playing "purple wail"]
[Cheering, applause]
[Whistling loudly]
Oh!
Let's go!
[Music fading]
[Jazz band fades completely]
You went out there.
You saw it.
[Dr. Collins]
She was having outbursts.
Paranoia.
- How 'bout that?
- [Jazz music returns]
[Audience cheering]
[Frank laughs]
There you are. I bow to you.
Now, make some noise! Come on!
[Laughing] You like that?
Did you guys like that?
Get off of your seats, come on!
How are you, sweetheart?
Good to see you.
All right, this is what
I'm talking about.
You work hard, you play hard.
What do you say, Jacko?
[Drummer playing lively beat]
- Jack, I want to go home.
- What?
I want to go.
[Frank] Come on, Tim!
Come on, Tim!
- All right!
- [Drummer stops]
- Whoo! [Laughs]
- [Crowd cheering]
How about that?
Put your hands together.
Please, we need to leave.
We need to leave right now.
Please.
- [Jack] We'll just pour you a drink.
- Please.
- No.
- [Jack] You'll be okay.
Only the best for victory.
My goodness!
All right, take a seat.
- [Cheers subside]
- [Chairs scraping]
[Frank] Uh, I have the burden
now of trying to follow that,
which will be hard, but...
- [Mouthing] Jack...
- I have to admit that I, uh...
I was planning...
A little presentation of my own.
- [Cheers, applause]
- I know. [Laughing]
[Chuckling] I know. Yeah.
All right. All right.
[Applause subsides]
Jack chambers.
If I could have you up here
for a minute.
Jack.
Jack, please, I need to
go home. We need to leave.
[Frank] Come on, everybody,
give him a round of applause.
- [Applause, cheers]
- Needs a little encouragement.
Big round of applause.
Let's give him
a big victory welcome!
Jack chambers.
[Clears throat]
Tonight is my favorite night
of the year.
I love seeing everybody
under one roof,
seeing how much we've all grown.
But few...
Few have grown as...
Impressively...
As this young man right here.
[Applause swelling]
[Chuckling]
I've debated long and hard
about this, lord knows. Whew!
It's certainly
out of the ordinary.
But you know what? This man
is out of the ordinary.
This man, I am in awe of.
Jack chambers, I am honored...
To invite you to join our...
Senior advisory board.
[Audience members exclaiming]
[Applause]
Are you the man
that you say you are?
It's a good fit.
[Light chuckle]
Thank you for your loyalty.
More good things to come.
How 'bout that,
ladies and gentlemen.
[Cheering, applause]
[Cheering continues]
[Panting heavily]
[Breathing deeply, shakily]
[Band playing
up-tempo swing music]
You wanna see the boy dance?
[Laughing]
Look at this boy dance!
Come on! Come on!
- [Crying quietly]
- [Music continues, faint]
[Frank faintly]
Look what he can do!
[Laughing]
- [Alice] Don't say that. You're gonna get another job.
- [Bunny whispering] Alice!
[Gasping]
Hey. What's wrong? Honey.
What happened? What's wrong?
[Frank] It's extraordinary!
[Frank laughing]
Everything's fine. It's okay.
Bunny, we need to go.
We need to get out of here
right now.
- No, no, no. We're okay.
- We need to go.
We're okay. Come on.
Tell me, what happened?
[Music increases in tempo]
How about that, huh?
You watching him dance?
Margaret was right.
She was asking questions
that they don't want us to ask.
And so they silenced her.
She didn't slip.
It wasn't an accident.
I saw it happen.
I saw her fall.
They're lying about everything.
[Frank] Dance, Jack!
Let's make him spin, shall we?
And so I went out there,
and I saw it.
You went... you went out where?
[Frank] Yeah, that's it!
Come on, boy, faster!
Keep it going! Come on!
Come on! Yeah!
That's it!
- [Music stops]
- [Frank] Ha-ha!
Doesn't that make you believe?
[Laughing] Stand up!
Stand up, take a bow!
Take a bow, you deserve it!
And when I touched it,
I saw something.
And I keep remembering more.
And I heard frank's voice,
and he's in my head...
It's more than just
a celebration
of our freedom from society's
arbitrary regulations,
it's a celebration
of potential unleashed!
It's a reminder of who we are!
Can I just show you?
Let's just go out there.
Everybody will be
distracted right now.
We can take Dean's car.
- We can head to...
- Stop. Stop. Stop it!
- Have you lost your mind?
- What?
You went to headquarters?
- Because I thought I saw a plane crash.
- It is the one rule...
- [Alice] No, I know...
- They ask us to respect.
You know how dangerous it is.
We are not going backwards.
We're pushing forwards, yes?
We move!
- You stole from Dr. Collins?
- Because Margaret can't be okay!
Get a hold of yourself, Alice!
You are behaving like a child.
Your husband is out there
having the most important night
of his life.
He's being celebrated,
and you're in here
trying to ruin it?
No! No!
You sound exactly like Margaret!
[Cheers, applause]
Whose world is it?
Ours!
Whose world is this?
[All] Ours!
- [Frank] Whose world is this?
- [All] Ours!
Whose world is this?
[All] Ours!
- Whose world is it? Ours!
- [All] Ours!
Whose world is it?
- Ours!
- [All] Ours!
- [Jack] Whose world is it? Ours!
[Sizzling]
["You belong to me" playing]
[The rovers vocalizing]
[Jack] They're calling it
operation extract.
It's higher security clearance.
I'm gonna be heading
the whole thing myself,
which is a real vote of
confidence from frank, I think.
[Bacon sizzling]
[Helen foster]
♪ see the pyramids ♪
♪ along the nile ♪
[Muffled knocking]
- Welcome!
- [Jack] Welcome!
There he is.
Oh, my. Those are beautiful.
Come on in.
[Bill] I want it for you.
Thank you.
[Peg] Are we late?
I feel like we're late.
[Peter] We literally
are arriving at the same time.
[Alice] What are
these platters? Wow!
Whatever's going on here,
I love. I love.
You like it?
- Yeah, the decor is...
- I'm glad, bill. I'm glad.
All right, buddy,
tell me the truth.
Is he really coming?
This is for you.
I think he's coming.
How the hell did you get frank
to come to your house?
It wasn't me. It was Alice.
These are the perks. I get it.
This is how you're living.
Is everything in this house
from the catalogue?
It's a house. Show me the ring.
Let me see it.
Did we beat bunny?
Uh, she... she's not coming.
- [Peg] Hm.
- Told you.
- Sorry, boys. Can I just get...
- Yeah, yeah.
You know, it's a good thing
you can dance,
'cause you're so hideously
unattractive.
- [Alice] They're here!
- How many secrets do you...
[Alice] Thank you.
- [Shelley] It's good to see you.
- Wow.
I knew it. I told peg.
It's gonna be a no-tie event.
- Frank.
- Jack! You crazy son of a bitch!
What do you want me
to do with this?
Hold on to it.
I told her it was gonna be like
a casual thing.
- Put that on ice.
- Wow.
- Thanks for coming.
- I'm proud of you.
- Thank you.
- What a lovely home, by the way.
Jack, could you make shelley
a cocktail?
[Jack] Of course.
Hey, frank, that was
a hell of a party last night.
It was.
I'm trying to get my wife
into a Martini glass.
[Laughs]
- He liked that.
- No, he didn't.
- [Peg] Where's your drink?
- [Alice] It's right here. Cheers!
[Violet] Cheers.
It's a wonderful home.
- How are you?
- Me?
- I'm amazing.
- Mm-hm.
After the night Jack had,
I'm incredible.
Right. Of course.
Cheers. Thanks for coming.
- You were a triumph last night.
- Oh! [Chuckles]
We haven't stopped talking
about you.
You guys go now
and enjoy yourselves.
I'm gonna go back
to the plates and finish up,
- and, um, I'll see you in...
- Can I help you?
- No, no, no, no, go.
- You sure? Okay.
Promise. Go snoop.
I love this record player.
- You do? You like it, bill?
- I love it.
At my house, I have a bench.
How did you get...
["Desafinado" playing
on record player]
[Peg] You can probably
tell by now
that appetizers are where
I really express myself
and buck convention.
[Violet] It's a skill.
Maybe you can teach me sometime.
Can't be taught.
[Humming melody]
[Frank] I learned something
very exciting.
[Exhales]
Oh, really? What's that?
Rumor is you and Jack
are trying.
Oh, well...
- We'll see. [Chuckles]
- Mm.
Hope we'll see a little boy.
[Both laugh]
[Smacks lips] I'm sorry
bunny didn't believe you.
[Frank chuckles softly]
But then again, you didn't
believe Margaret, so...
Why should anyone believe you?
My god, you fascinate me.
Because I've been waiting
for someone like you.
Someone to challenge me.
No great man has changed
the course of history
without being pushed
to the limits of his potential.
And you push me.
Yeah.
[Chuckles lightly]
I do hope you keep going.
And yet, here you are.
Preparing dinner.
Like a good girl.
[Chuckles softly]
- [Jack] Sit.
- [Frank] Absolutely.
[Violet] Do you know
if it's a boy or a girl?
No, I hope it's a boy.
Thank you.
- Can't get enough of 'em, right?
- [Groans]
- [Violet laughs]
- Girls are hard. They are.
- I'll be right there, all right?
- Thank you.
You know, Alice tells me you're
a hell of a tennis player.
- Oh, she does?
- Is that right? Yeah.
[Jack] She's being polite.
[Frank] Well, we're looking
for some fierce competitors.
If you're ever ready
to get out there, call me.
I've heard about that backhand,
though, it's famous.
[Frank] If you want a partner,
I'm yours, man.
That's a lot of pressure.
I don't know if...
Thank you.
[Chatter stops]
[Chuckles softly]
I'm having the fish. I don't
know what you guys are having.
- [Chatter resumes]
- [Clears throat]
[Peter] Nice to see
a familiar face.
[Bill] Um, so anyways,
those windows right there,
the slatted windows?
They're actually called
"jalousie" windows.
Did you know that?
- You didn't know why.
- [Peter] Oh, boy.
So, the etymology is...
[In French accent]
"Jealousy."
And you say,
"whose baby is this?"
And they say, "it's your baby."
And you say,
"how could that be?"
And it is your baby.
And I just do it every year.
- Violet, where are you from?
- [Chatter subsides]
- Pardon?
- I said, "where are you from?"
Philadelphia.
- Mm! I'm from Philadelphia!
- [Laughing] Are you serious?
- I didn't know that.
- I knew I liked you.
[Alice] Most of the women here
are from Philadelphia.
Or Baltimore. Or Chicago.
I've noticed.
[Jack] Mm. Can I
get anyone anything?
[Peg] I for one do not miss
the winters.
No, no, no.
I thrive in the sunshine,
even though
I'm alabaster-skinned.
I love the sunshine.
I love the beach.
- [Peg] Mm.
- [Jack] She does.
What was the last beach
you went to?
[Peter] Oh, fun fact
about the beach.
- I read this.
- Yeah?
Beaches are actually some
of the filthiest places
in the whole world.
- Just a sandbox of disease and...
- Peter! [Chuckles nervously]
Do not say "disease"
at the dinner table.
[Peter] It's true.
They need to know.
I can probably guess.
Hilton head? Cape Cod?
Or the Jersey shore?
And we all honeymooned
in sea island,
or the poconos,
or Niagara Falls.
I think those are popular
honeymoon destinations.
- Expensive.
- Mm-hm. Beautiful, beautiful.
Peter, you, uh... you haven't
finished your story.
[Peter] Mm!
Bill over here's probably
- one of the worst golf players...
- I'm sorry, Peter.
I'm not quite finished. Violet,
where did you meet bill?
Well, we met on a train.
- To Boston.
- [Violet] To Boston.
Yeah.
- Yes.
- [Both laughing]
You dropped your ticket.
And he bent down, picked it up,
gave it to you, right?
It is, yeah.
That's how Margaret met Ted.
And peg, am I right in thinking
that's how Debbie mcintyre
met her husband?
Yes, I am. That's how they met.
- Yes, that's true. I'm jealous.
- [Frank] Is it?
- Honestly, it's such a sweet story.
- [Frank] Wow.
- Yeah. Yeah.
- [Frank laughs]
Isn't that funny,
the way those coincidences...
Incredible.
[Alice] There are only so many
different stories we're told.
We're told what we remember.
Until...
We try to remember things...
That they want us to forget.
- Like Margaret.
- Alice...
No. Jack. It's okay.
I'm curious to hear
where she's going with this.
Frank is doing something to us.
Delusions, memory problems,
hysteria.
We saw these issues
with Margaret,
and know that it's, uh,
completely curable.
Dr. Collins prescribed you
a suite of medications,
which you are
clearly not taking.
The question is why...
He's lying to us.
He's lying to all of us.
Bunny, your best friend,
is worried about you.
She thinks that you need help.
Is that why she's
not here tonight?
Because you didn't want
to be reminded of that.
He's using you.
He's using all of us.
Do you even know what
the victory project actually is?
- Have you ever asked?
- Do you?
Is that why you went out there?
To headquarters?
What?
- I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
- Alice...
But you don't know
what he's doing.
[Frank] You wandered out
by yourself.
You ignored every rule.
And she put all your lives
in danger.
Yes, I did go out there
and I went to headquarters
and I saw what he's hiding.
- [Frank] What I'm hiding.
- [Alice] He's lying to us.
- [Frank] Oh, dear.
- [Alice] He's lying to all of us
about what the victory project
actually is.
- He's trapped us here.
- [Frank] Alice...
Trapped?
I hope no one feels trapped.
Do you feel trapped?
Violet?
- Peg?
- [Awkward chuckle]
This is your psychosis.
You are experiencing trust
as a feeling of entrapment,
yet you trust every day.
We all do.
Tonight, you've trusted us
in your home.
Just like I trusted you
in my bedroom.
Alice?
Do you remember that?
He's... he's trying
to create a world.
- If you want to articulate your own argument...
- He's using us.
- Try using your own words, Alice.
- He's using all of us.
- In your own words!
- What's in this food?
Let's talk about that!
- Where did it come from? Huh?
- [Frank] Oh, I'm sorry, everyone.
- I'm sorry.
- Let's just think about it.
- I'm sorry, Violet.
- [Alice] Victory milk.
- This is... this is an anomaly.
- [Alice] Victory meat. Victory eggs.
- It doesn't usually happen.
- [Alice] It all comes from him.
She's very sick
- and she will get the help that she needs...
- Everything we're told...
- I promise you both.
- Everything we are given
comes from him!
And it's all about control.
- It's all about control.
- [Frank laughs]
We wouldn't even...
He might be poisoning the food!
Enough!
We come to your house,
we sit at your table,
and you insult
and degrade my husband?
He invites you
to be a part of something
as extraordinary as he is,
and you sit there
like a spoiled brat,
demanding answers
to questions you've made up.
There's a pattern, isn't there?
A pattern of selfish,
pampered whining.
Or is it just a desperation
to be exciting?
Hm?
Spitting in the face
of this opportunity.
It's heartbreaking that your
sad, desperate paranoia
could destroy
what we're trying to build.
Hm?
Well, I won't listen to your
pathetic ranting any longer.
Frank, honey?
I'll be in the car.
- [Clicks teeth]
- [Door opens]
- [Sighing vocally] Well...
- [Door closes]
Jack, I think you may have
over served your wife.
[Chair scraping]
[Utensils clatter]
[Whispers] Thank you.
[Door opens]
[Sighing]
I was expecting
so much more from you.
[Fork clicks on plate]
Good luck, Alice.
Jack, let's talk.
[Door closes]
[Moaning angrily]
[Record crackling]
[Door opens, shuts]
Did you enjoy yourself tonight?
What?
No, I didn't
enjoy myself tonight.
You planned a whole evening
to sabotage me.
No! No, I would never
do that to you.
I would never do that to you.
I love you.
I'm trying...
I'm trying to save us.
You're trying to save us
by going out there.
Yes, because I saw
a plane crash. I told you.
But, Jack, everything I said
at that table is true.
Frank even admitted it to me.
He admitted it to me
in the kitchen.
That's why I did that. That's
why all of that happened.
He wouldn't have done that.
[Deep, shaky breaths]
Jack...
Everyone is acting
like I'm crazy.
And I'm not crazy.
And I need you to listen to me.
I need you to listen to me.
Hey.
Hey. Hey, look at me.
Look at me. Look at me.
To me...
You are...
You are bigger than all of this.
Mm-hm.
You are bigger than victory.
You are bigger than frank.
I believe in you.
I don't believe in him.
[Whispers]
And I don't trust him.
And I don't trust this place.
And I don't want
to be here anymore.
I don't want to be here anymore.
And we need to leave.
[Sniffles] We need to leave.
And we can go anywhere.
We can go anywhere and we can
create our own world,
and it will be you and me
and we'll be okay.
And it's not about where we go,
it's just that we're together.
Please? Please? Please?
Please?
[Whispering] Please.
Okay.
[Light gasp]
- Okay?
- [Breathing deeply]
[Sniffles] Okay.
[Voice trembling] Okay?
- Okay.
- [Sighs in relief]
[Whimpering]
I love you. I love you.
But we need to go tonight.
We need to go.
We can't be here.
- [Sniffles]
- Hey. Hey.
[Sniffles]
[Both chuckle faintly]
[Whispering] I love you.
Let's go.
I love you.
- Okay.
- 'Kay. Okay.
[Sniffles]
- [Door shuts]
- [Alice] Jack?
I packed us a snack in case
we drive all night long,
but I think I packed everything.
Let's go.
Baby, let's go. Come on.
[Sniffs] I'm sorry.
What?
I love you so much, Alice.
Baby, what's wrong?
I tried so hard
to keep this from happening.
- What? Let's...
- Please believe...
Baby, we need to go.
We need to go.
Baby, you need to drive.
We need to go. Go. Whoa.
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- No. No! No!
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry, Alice.
- No, Jack, please! I can be better!
- I can be better! I'm so sorry!
- Alice, I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
- Let me be better, please!
- I'm sorry!
- I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
- Baby, please!
- Let me be better.
- I'm sorry!
- Get off me!
- I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
- Let me be better!
- I'm sorry.
- I'm so...
- Jack, please!
- They're hurting me! No! No!
- [Sobbing]
No! Jack! They're hurting me!
They're hurting me!
Fuck!
[Sobbing]
[Crying]
No, please, please.
Please, don't...
[Faint, high-pitched whining]
[Muffled screaming]
[Intense groaning]
[High-pitched whine]
[Jack melodically]
♪ darlin' I ♪
♪ with you all the time ♪
♪ can't you see ♪
♪ I long to be ♪
[High-pitched whine continues]
[Jack humming melody]
[Strained, muffled gasping]
[Grunts]
[Jack in American accent] How
am I gonna take care of you?
[Alice] Don't say that.
You're gonna get another job.
It's okay.
[Jack] I'm sorry.
[Alice] I'll take extra shifts.
It's not a problem.
[High-pitched whine continues]
[Panting lightly]
- [Whine stops]
- [Monitor beeping]
[Surgeon] Done.
Resident, close her up.
[Alice] Needle holder.
Forceps.
- [Alice] All right, guys. 'Night.
- [Woman] 'Night.
[Man] 'Night, doctor.
[Groans, sighs]
[Woman 2] Good night,
Dr. Warren.
Good night.
[Door unlocks]
[Frank on computer]
I mean, I suppose
the primary question is...
[Jack] You're so late.
I thought you were gonna
be home by 10:00.
Yeah. So did I.
Surgery ran really long.
Well, I'm starving.
I haven't eaten.
Why not?
I wasn't sure what you wanted
and you never texted me back.
I don't have my phone
in the or, Jack.
Well, it'd be nice to know that.
Is the hot water
still not working?
Called the guy.
He couldn't come today.
Okay, well,
if I can't take a shower,
- I gotta go to bed.
- Come on.
I haven't gotten
to see you all day.
I know, I'm sorry,
but I'm really tired, baby.
- Dance with me.
- No. No, Jack. Just stop.
I just finished a 30-hour shift,
I sewed up 12 people,
and I gotta be back
in six hours,
and I'm so tired.
I... I just need
to go to bed. Okay?
[Frank on computer]
I mean, I suppose
the primary question is...
Do you know anyone
who's truly happy? Right?
Or satisfied?
Modern society
has smothered our true selves,
and driven us
from, uh, biological destiny.
I see that version of yourself
that you've buried deep
and that everyone else ignores.
That... that is the real you.
I know that you are the man
you say you are.
That's better.
[Shelley] Welcome home.
["You'd be so nice
to come home to" playing]
[English accent]
Look who's feeling better.
Oh, thank god! [Laughing]
[Alice] Okay, don't shout it
to the whole neighborhood.
- I'm here.
- Oh! I missed you so much.
I started writing gossip
in a journal.
You did? I should read it then.
- So sad. Hi.
- Hi!
- Wow, you look sensational!
- Thank you.
I feel better. I feel good.
- I'm so happy you're back.
- Me, too.
Hi, Jack.
- Wow! Look at this car.
- You like that?
Dean's gonna try to have sex
with this vehicle.
- [Cracking up]
- Where is Dean?
He's playing golf with bill.
Honey, you should go.
All you've been doing
is looking after me,
and you deserve
to have some fun.
Yeah, go. Leave her.
She's mine now.
- We're gonna garden.
- What?
Just look at plants and drink.
- Right.
- I don't have a garden.
- [Both exclaiming happily]
- Okay!
- Bye.
[Ruth] ♪ you'd be so nice ♪
♪ you'd be paradise ♪
- I'll see you later. Okay.
- Mm-hm.
[Bunny]
Violet would not stand up.
It was like her ass was glued
to the chair.
[Laughing] And peg!
Peg's face was so red,
I thought her head
was gonna pop off.
Mm.
Peg is, um... Peter's wife.
Always pregnant.
- Right. Yes. Yeah.
- Kinda... yeah.
Right, okay. Of course. Sorry.
My head's been a bit of a blur
since the treatment.
- Yeah. Okay.
- It's okay.
- It'll all come back to you.
- Yeah. Okay.
[Gasps] Oh, my goodness!
Uh-oh! Here they come.
Oh, my goodness! Hi!
[Girl] Did you see the sign?
It is the most beautiful sign
I've seen in my life!
Did you hire professional
artists to paint it?
- [Girl] We made it ourselves.
- You did? No, you didn't.
Quick, show me. Come show me!
[Gasping playfully]
[Girl] I did this part.
[Alice] Can you point to it?
Which bit? Go! Go! Go!
[Girl] I did the sunshine
and the letter...
[Alice]
You did the sunshine and...
[Shelley]
There is beauty in control.
There is grace in symmetry.
We move as one.
[Women]
There is beauty in control.
There is grace in symmetry.
We move as one.
There is beauty in control.
There is grace in symmetry.
We move as one.
There is beauty in control.
There is grace in symmetry.
We move as one.
There is beauty in control.
There is grace in symmetry.
[Shelley] We move as one.
- Hi.
- It smells amazing.
- Thank you.
- How was your day?
- I don't even remember now.
Good.
Well, you're a little early,
but I have...
So many things to finish.
So I'm gonna need to go
and get things out of the oven.
[Laughing]
No, it's gonna burn. No.
We'll eat first...
And that should build up
your stamina.
[Whispering]
Oh, my god, that's beautiful.
♪ Darlin' I ♪
♪ with you all the time ♪
♪ can't you see ♪
- [Alice humming along]
- ♪ I long to be ♪
♪ with you all the time ♪
♪ now that I ♪
- ♪ can't you see ♪
- [whispering] Can't you...
- ♪ I long to be ♪
- long to be.
- ♪ With you all the time ♪
- with you all the time.
[Jack coughing]
[Dr. Collins] Victory project,
applicant number 426.
Name: Jack chambers. Age: 29.
Blood type: O-negative.
[Man humming faintly]
[Keys jingling]
[Gasps]
[Dr. Collins]
Psychological evaluation: Fair.
Chosen nationality: British.
Chosen wife: Alice Warren.
Pre-existing relationship: Yes.
Do you understand
the discretion required
- to be a part of this community?
- [Jack] Yes.
[Dr. Collins] Do you understand
the consequences
- of indiscretion?
- [Jack] Yes.
[Dr. Collins] Are you aware
that you are responsible
- for preparing your home device system?
- [Jack] Yes.
[Sighing heavily]
[Dr. Collins] Do you consent
to the physical and medical
requirements for entry
to victory?
[Jack] Yes.
[Dr. Collins] Are you aware that you
are responsible for the physical upkeep
of your chosen wife?
- [Breath rasping]
- [Jack] Yes.
[Dr. Collins] Are you aware
that you must exit the simulation
through victory headquarters
every day,
and return only for your
allotted number of hours?
[Jack] Yes.
[Jack] ♪ darlin' I ♪
♪ miss you all the time ♪
♪ can't you see ♪
♪ I long to be ♪
[Alice whimpering]
♪ With you all the time ♪
♪ can't you see ♪
♪ I long to be ♪
♪ with you all the time ♪
[Beeps]
[Shelley]
Welcome to the victory project.
There are currently
72 active users.
Your reentry has begun.
[Tone dings] -[Frank]
The auspice of equality.
We can fall deeper
into what we know is true,
that we crave order.
Can we yield
to nature's hierarchy?
Allow your consciousness
to sink into this world.
Into this truth.
Sink deeper into the way
things are supposed to be.
[Pan clattering]
[Panting heavily]
[Moaning loudly]
- Alice?
- [Groaning] Don't!
[Panting vocally]
- Okay.
- [Alice yelling]
Baby, you're having
another episode.
Just take a deep breath.
- It's okay. Just breathe, Alice.
- [Groaning]
That's good. Just breathe.
- That's good.
- [Panting slows]
What did you do?
- Alice, please, just stay calm.
- [Gasping loudly]
[Jack] It's gonna be okay.
I can explain.
What the fuck is going on?
Look at me, you're my wife.
- What the fuck is happening?
- I love you. I love you.
Oh, no. No.
You can't say that.
You don't love me.
- No, don't do that. Don't do that!
- You don't love me.
Alice, just think!
Think about your life
and what you actually want.
- [Whispering] You're psychotic.
- Mm-mm.
I had a life.
You took my life.
No, I saved your life.
- That's not true.
- [Jack] No, listen to me.
You worked all the time!
I wanted to work!
I loved working! What?
[Jack] You were miserable.
You were so unhappy.
You hated your life!
It was my life!
My life!
You don't get
to take that from me!
I gave this to you!
I gave you all of this, Alice!
We are lucky to be here!
Frank built this world
so that we can live
the life that we deserve!
I have to leave every day
just to make enough money
to keep us here,
and I fucking hate
every minute of it.
I fucking hate it, Alice!
You get to stay here.
And you're happy!
You're happy.
That's okay.
Alice.
We're perfect in here.
Don't you want to be perfect
with me?
[Laughs angrily] No. No.
You made me feel like
I was crazy.
I came to you...
And you made me feel like
I was fucking crazy.
Alice, I'm so sorry.
[Sobs]
But I don't have to
lie to you anymore.
Alice...
- Alice, please, I love you.
- [Crying] I know.
You know I love you.
I would do anything for you.
You're my whole life.
I love you. Oh, god.
It's not about where we are,
it's just that we're together.
You said that.
You said that to me.
Alice.
- Alice, I'm so sorry.
- Oh, my god. [Sniffles]
Are there others?
Are there other people like me?
Where are their bodies?
- I don't know where they are.
- [Crying] Oh, god.
I don't know where they are.
I don't even know
who the men are. I swear.
It's not our business.
A man's responsible for his
own wife and nothing else.
So all the wives
are trapped here?
- [Whispering] Oh, my god, the kids.
- No.
- Oh, my god.
- No. No, Alice, the kids aren't real.
- Oh, god.
- They're not real.
Don't worry about them.
It's you and me.
- Look at me.
- [Crying] No, I...
Don't worry about them.
Look at me.
Look at me. It's you and me.
Okay? It's you and me.
- [Whimpering]
- Stay with me.
- I just need... mm-hm.
- It's okay. We're gonna be happy.
- I just need a second.
- We're gonna be happy here.
- I just need a second. Yeah?
- We're gonna be happy.
No, Jack.
No, Jack, please.
- [Gasping for breath]
- [Muffled] Stop. Stop. Alice!
[Breathless]
No, I need a second...
Get off me! I can't breathe!
I can't breathe!
- Get off me! [Yells]
- Alice, stop it!
- [Coughing] No! No!
- Stop it, Alice!
No. No!
- Stop!
- [Grunts loudly]
[Bunny] Alice?
Alice?
A-Alice?
What happened?
[Telephone ringing]
[Vinyl record crackling]
[Telephone continues ringing]
[Stops record]
What is it?
[Dr. Collins]
Jack chambers is dead.
[Bunny] Alice, listen to me.
No, I need
to tell you something, bunny.
No, you need to leave.
No. This world isn't real.
- Alice, they're gonna kill you.
- Frank created a program.
- And he created a world and its...
- I know. I know.
- And they're gonna kill you.
- What?
They're gonna kill you
in the real world.
- They're gonna kill your real body.
- What?
- You need to go.
Okay? Oh, my god.
Alice, if a man dies here,
he dies in the real world.
Jack can't put you
back in this time.
He can't put you back in
like he did before.
You need to exit again,
right now.
Alice, you gotta go.
You can drive. Take Jack's car!
- You need to go to headquarters.
- Bunny, answer me!
- You need to go right now!
- What do you mean, you know?
[Siren blaring outside]
[Panting] Listen...
I've always known.
I chose this.
My kids are here.
- Bunny, your kids aren't real.
- No, they are.
- Kids aren't real here.
- Nothing is real.
- They're real to me. They're real to me, Alice.
- Nothing...
- Because here they're alive!
In here, I didn't lose them.
Here, I... I can keep them.
Don't you see?
What... do they know?
What about the women,
do they know?
No.
They don't know.
[Crying]
Go.
You have to go.
Christ, Alice,
whose blood is that?
Jack!
[Peter] What's going on?
Where's Jack? Dean?
Go back inside, Alice.
Sweetheart? Stop.
[Peter] Where is Jack?
What is she doing?
[Dean] Jack!
[Bill] Honey, let's go inside.
[Peter] We have to go inside,
please.
It's the kids.
Where is Jack?
Peg. I need you to go inside
to the kids, peg!
Peg, she is unwell.
They said nothing like this
could happen!
Shut up, bill!
[Bill] They promised
it was safe!
[Peter] Jack!
[Frank on speakers] It's
a reminder of who we are!
We came to save the world
from itself.
We are a vanguard of a promise.
We are the future.
We are a brotherhood
of brilliance,
every single one of us.
[Dr. Collins]
Approaching victory portal.
Prepare to exit
in ten, nine, eight...
- Whose world is this?
- [Men] Ours!
- [Frank] Whose world is this?
- [Frank] Whose world is it?
- [Men] Ours!
- Whose world is it?
- [Bunny] Alice!
Go! Go, Alice! Go!
No, no!
[Panting]
- [Shrieks] Get off me!
- They'll find you!
[Tires screeching]
[Cars peeling out]
Please, please, please!
Don't be such a fucking...
They said it would not happen!
[Exclaiming angrily]
[Horn blaring]
[Indistinct chatter on radio]
[Gasping loudly]
Fuck!
[Yells]
[Cries out]
[Alice yelling]
Stop her, you idiots!
[Angry yell]
Stop her!
[Yells]
No, no!
[Gasping]
[Shelley on radio]
Security level is red.
We are under a shelter in place.
Stay inside and await
further instructions.
Attention, victory residents.
- Security level is red.
- [Telephone ringing]
[Frank] Where is she?
- [Man on phone] Huge crash.
- [Static crackling]
The two lead cars and Collins.
Collins is dead, sir.
[Frank] Listen to me,
you do not let her exit!
If she gets there,
she gets through.
Who's gonna put her back in?
- Frank?
- [Loud siren wailing]
Frank, what do we do? Sir?
[Knife stabbing]
You stupid, stupid man.
[Grunting]
It's my turn now.
[Panting loudly, gasping]
[Screams]
- No!
- [Engine roaring]
No!
Come on! Shit!
[Panting loudly]
[Yelling]
[Rocks clattering]
[Gasps]
[Yelling with exertion]
[Panting]
[Stops breathing]
- Don't leave me.
- [Exhales]
[Alice] You and me.
Always.
You and me.
[Piano playing melody]
[Gasping]
[Frank echoing] Once we
acknowledge that reality...
We can let go.
[Alice gasps loudly, panting]
["Where or when" playing]
[Peggy Lee] ♪ it seems
we stood and talked ♪
♪ like this before ♪
♪ we looked at each other
in the same way then ♪
♪ but I can't remember where ♪
♪ or when ♪
♪ the clothes you're wearing ♪
♪ are the clothes you wore ♪
♪ the smile you are smiling ♪
♪ you were smiling then ♪
♪ but I can't remember where ♪
♪ or when ♪
♪ some things that happened ♪
♪ for the first time ♪
♪ seem to be happening ♪
♪ again ♪
♪ And so it seems ♪
♪ that we've met before ♪
♪ and laughed before ♪
♪ and loved before ♪
♪ but who knows ♪
♪ where ♪
♪ or when ♪
["Sh-boom" playing]
[The chords] ♪ life could be a
dream life could be a dream ♪
♪ do do do do, sh-boom ♪
[Man] ♪ life could be a dream
♪ -[Chorus] ♪ sh-boom ♪
♪ if I could take you up in
paradise up above ♪ - ♪ sh-boom ♪
♪ if you would tell me I'm
the only one that you love ♪
♪ life could be a dream
sweetheart ♪
♪ hello, hello again ♪
♪ sh-boom and hopin'
we'll meet again ♪
- ♪ boom ♪
- ♪ ba-boom ♪
♪ day dong da ding-dong
a-lang-da-lang-da-lang ♪
♪ ah, whoa, whoa, bip
ah bi-ba-do-da-dip, whoa ♪
- ♪ life could be a dream ♪
- ♪ sh-boom ♪
♪ if only all my precious plans
would come true ♪
♪ sh-boom ♪ - ♪ if you would let
me spend my whole life lovin' you ♪
♪ life could be a dream
sweetheart ♪
♪ do do do do, sh-boom ♪
[Man 2]
♪ every time I look at you ♪
♪ something is on my mind ♪
♪ if you do
what I want you to ♪
♪ baby, we'd be so fine ♪
♪ oh, life could be a dream
sh-boom ♪
♪ if I could take you up
in paradise up above, sh-boom ♪
♪ you'd tell me, darlin' ♪
♪ I'm the only one
that you love ♪
♪ life could be a dream
sweetheart ♪
♪ hello, hello again ♪
♪ sh-boom and hopin'
we'll meet again ♪
- ♪ boom ♪
- ♪ ba-boom ♪
♪ day dong da ding-dong
a-lang-da-lang-da-lang ♪
♪ ah, whoa, whoa, bip
ah bi-ba-do-da-dip, whoa ♪
- ♪ life could be a dream ♪
- ♪ sh-boom ♪
♪ life could be a dream
sweetheart ♪
[Saxophone solo]
[Chorus vocalizing]
♪ Whoa, life could be a dream
sh-boom ♪
♪ if I could take you up
in paradise up above, sh-boom ♪
♪ you'd tell me, darlin' I'm
the only one that you love ♪
♪ life could be a dream
sweetheart ♪
♪ hello, hello again ♪
♪ sh-boom and hope we'll meet
again, boom ♪ - ♪ ba-boom ♪
♪ day dong da ding-dong ♪
♪ sha-lang-a-la-lang
a-la-lang-a-la-lang-a-la ♪
♪ whoa, whoa, bip ♪
♪ ah Bo da do da dip, whoa ♪
♪ life could be a dream
life could be a dream ♪
♪ do do do do, sh-boom ♪
[Ethereal instrumental music
playing]