Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
Produced by:
Fuji Television/TOHO
In association with:
Premier International/Cross Media
a MITANI Koki film
KARASAWA Toshiaki
TANAKA Kunie
TANAKA Naoki
YAGI Akiko
Excuse me, let me through.
Everything's OK, it's OK.
No pets allowed here.
You have it all wrong.
No more excuses.
You were walking a really huge one!
Don't be ridiculous.
A giant lizard with a huge tail...
bit the people in #301.
Don't ask me!
- It's a public nuisance.
- Go away!
- Stop it!
- Let me look!
I'll sue you!
Oh, look, it's a lizard!
That's my wife, my wife!
Stop it!
Don't! She hates flashes!
Don't!
Yes, yes.
Are you going or not?
Five more minutes.
It'll get dark.
Right, right.
Hello, it's Naosuke.
I really don't know about Godzilla,
it's just too far out.
We did all that monster stuff
to death before.
Just changing Godzilla
to Mechagodzilla...
doesn't change
the fundamental problem.
Oh, I'm sorry, I'll call you back.
Sorry, sorry.
Hey, what's that?
What is this?
It's a well.
The supermarket's behind the forest,
there's a school over there.
And a police box nearby
so it's safe at night.
So what do you think?
We're going to live here forever.
That's right, until we're
grandma and grandpa together.
What shall we build...
Something stylish.
Yeah.
ALL ABOUT OUR HOUSE
Plans are Everything
I think we ought to move away
from the monster motif.
No, no, not that.
Right, right, right...
Right. Right.
Sorry, sorry.
Now, what about the plans?
An architect?
What if we get someone
with terrible taste?
- A house is forever.
- That's right.
- Your father?
- Him? He's just a contractor.
He can't draw plans?
I don't think so.
A contractor's not an architect.
But he might know someone who can.
Excuse me.
Coffee.
He pals around with old guys.
Who knows what that bunch of
geezers would build.
Your Dad would love it.
We're not doing this
to make him happy.
Remember Yanagisawa,
the interior designer?
He created that table for us.
Huh?
How about him?
For what?
For our house plans.
C'mon, pay attention.
What?
His main thing is furniture but
he does interiors, too.
Really?
We could ask a regular architect,
but it might turn out stuffy.
Yanagisawa can give us
a contemporary feel.
That sounds good.
- Are you serious?
- Yes I am.
Your work's important,
but it's our house!
I think he'd be great,
let's hire Yanagisawa...
I mean, who else can handle it?
A Martian, yes, just go for it.
Bring in a Martian at the end.
What, you serious?
Yeah, yeah, yes...
Hello.
It's been awhile.
You look the same. Any children?
Not yet. I know you're busy.
Don't mention it.
For real?
I'm just on my way out.
A place I designed opens tomorrow.
Oh my.
Why don't you join me?
Why sure.
You sure I'm right for it?
Oh, yes, we want you.
But I've only done interiors.
We just know
you'll do a great job, right?
You know, I've always wanted
to design a house.
Really? So it's perfect, then.
You look awfully pale. Are you OK?
Are you sick?
I'm just...
You're carsick?
We're almost there.
- Here.
- Thanks.
Am I a wild driver?
It's not that.
I didn't get much sleep last night.
So?
You'll design us a special house,
something unconventional.
I mean, this place is great.
It's so cool.
My theme was the fusion of
tradition and modernism.
I tried to make it authentic.
Now I really want to do...
something based on
mid-century Modernism,
architecture of the '50s and '60s.
I'm most inspired by
Rudolf Schindler's Americanism.
But for the right fee,
I'd design anything, even this place.
Excuse me.
What do you think?
For a hot designer,
he's not that pretentious.
Don't have a clue
what he means, but...
I think he'll be fine.
No!
Why can't you do it like I said!
The intervals have to be equal!
This is just one big mess!
Do it over.
Tomorrow's the opening, you idiot!
I'd love to take the job.
There's just one problem.
I'm not a licensed architect,
so I can't apply for city permits.
You need a license?
Yeah, what if I design it, but
someone else draws up the final plans?
That much my father can handle.
He's licensed, after all.
That's right,
your father's a contractor.
Would you ask him?
Hello.
Oh, so you found it.
Why that's wonderful.
The thing is,
what would you think
if we asked Dad to build it?
He's an old man, now.
Is he still up to it?
I've heard his work is still meticulous.
I'm sure he'd be delighted.
Hold on a minute,
he's cutting his toenails.
It's Tamiko, your daughter, dear.
They found their land.
She wants to ask you a favor.
So the deal is, we're having
someone else draw up the plans.
But we want you to get
the permits and build it.
Sure.
Are you sure?
And build the house, too?
Someone else is drawing up the plans.
I'm not sure he gets it.
Yes. Good night then.
Did you accept?
How would I know?
Whether or not I'm doing it...
You'll be getting busier.
It's due at the end of the month.
The Martians OK?
How's your house? You find land?
It's in the country.
What do you want for a house-warming?
Thank you.
Call the maestro a taxi.
The plans?
I already told you,
we've hired a designer, Yanagisawa.
Who's that?
I knew him in college.
You'd trust a kid like that?
He's an interior designer now.
Specializes in Modernism.
Never heard of it.
Mid-century at that, Father.
Mid-sentence?
Are you up to this?
To what?
You actually have to talk to him.
He's a modernist, you know.
The hell with modernism.
Thing about a house is,
it's got to be sturdy...
Isn't that right, Naosuke?
Yes.
Wow, design a house!
Yeah, however I want.
Finally, your dream come true.
Wonderful.
Come let me show you.
What?
Thank you.
What, what?
And the Japanese style room?
That's what I'm worried about.
What do you say?
I think we can skip it.
We'd never use it anyway.
Do you think we need one?
But when you get older,
you'll really wish you had one.
Of course.
Instead of a Japanese room,
make a bigger living room.
What do you know, you brat.
Would you like some more potatoes?
Yes, I would.
When will the plans be ready?
Yanagisawa's thinking about them now.
What's your schedule?
Me? I don't really
have a definite schedule.
Get me the plans, the plans.
In any case, Naosuke.
I'm excited about it.
You think he's up to it?
He's certainly gung ho.
I'm really worried.
I think he was overjoyed
when you called to ask.
He started calling around
right afterwards.
Around?
His old crew.
Recently he's been sub-contracting
for sub-contractors.
Finally, he's got a job
he can sink his teeth into.
...makes a world of difference.
I see your point.
The thing about that place...
What about it?
Nothing blocks the wind.
It'll blow right at you.
Gotta build it to stand up to it.
I understand.
Since when are you the expert?
I already checked it out.
Got a problem?
You already went?
He's pretty into it.
Listen up, guys.
Yes.
Don't mess with that wind.
That wind.
Tamiko, Tamiko.
About that Japanese room,
your father's dead set on it.
What with the craze for
Western houses,
he hasn't had a crack at a real
Japanese room for some time.
Sounds good to me.
There you go, caving in again.
For years and years,
he's followed customers' orders.
Who knows how many years
he's got left.
Just this once,
can't you let him do as he pleases?
I can relate.
He's got something in mind
for that Japanese room.
Let's talk to Yanagisawa.
- Put it on hold.
- Think about it?
Why can't Dad tell us himself?
You know how he is.
See you.
- Good night.
- 'Night.
Let's let him build one.
For your Dad.
You sure have a soft spot
for him, don't you?
I love that old time craftsmanship.
Let's do it for him...
Don't be ridiculous.
Something with a razor sharp head
just attacked the people in #401.
Don't ask me!
- This is a public nuisance.
- Go away!
- Stop it!
- Let me look!
I'll sue you!
I see something!
Oh, look, it's a Martian!
That's my wife, my wife!
Stop it!
Don't! She hates flashes!
A big roof makes big snow drifts
- Afghani proverb
- Hear about the Japanese room?
- Yeah.
- Forget it if it's too much.
- Not a problem.
But...
But that's really not my domain,
so why not leave it to him?
Thanks for understanding.
I wanted you to get an idea,
so I came up with this.
Just an idea.
If you like it, I'll draw up plans.
Wow!
The basic concept is:
The Simpler The Better.
I went for perpendicular angles.
Let's go inside.
We can?
Not really.
It's just a general idea.
This is the entrance.
I want the living room to be open.
In contrast to the exterior,
the 1st floor's all about horizontal.
No unnecessary vertical lines,
in the Schindler Frame style.
As for wall colors, see this window?
Yes.
It maximizes both natural sunlight
and resultant shadows.
I want to draw out the inherent
texture of the materials.
What's called "soft monotone."
Steven Hall adapted
this approach from Schindler.
Onto the 2nd floor.
Haven't seen you since we built
that professor's mansion together.
That's right.
That was one sturdy house.
Put a lot of time and effort
into that one.
Who makes your hearing aid?
We built a professor's house?
You were out with a diabetes attack.
Who did the paint finishes?
It was Mori.
Oh, I remember Mori.
What's he up to now?
Died last year. His lungs...
Hey, who makes your hearing aid?
They're dying like flies.
Didn't Mori run the marathon?
That was old Kurosawa.
The old man, huh.
Brings back memories.
He died last month.
His lymph nodes...
The old man died?
I'm so happy to be working
with you again, chief.
I'm serious.
Me too, back with the old gang.
Makes it worth still being alive
all these years.
Hey, does your hearing aid work?
C'mon, man...
Listen guys, my heart actually
stopped beating last year.
I'm officially disabled.
Yanagisawa called to say he's late.
The traffic's really bad.
- Please.
- Thank you.
Suga will apply for the permits.
Not you, Dad?
I've got a second class license,
so I can't get any permits.
Suga's is first class.
Very nice to meet you.
I hope I can be of help.
His father's an architect, too.
I see.
My son-in-law writes TV scripts.
His scripts have a satirical touch.
Wonderful stuff.
Watch your sugar intake, Dad.
I'm fine.
Workmen need their energy.
- Yanagisawa!
- I'll get it.
Oh, chief,
have a look at our last job.
Great house.
It looks really sturdy.
These new houses are no good.
They only care how it looks.
Yanagisawa.
Sorry to be late.
May I introduce Yanagisawa,
he's designing the house.
My father.
I'm Iwata.
I'm Yanagisawa.
This is the architect.
I'm with Suga Architects.
He's handling the permits.
- Nice to meet you.
- Likewise.
Are they ready?
Let's sit here. Dad, take a seat.
Well, this is the general idea
I'm working with.
Such details...
Wonderful.
There may be some adjustments,
of course.
You drew these?
Yes.
Just what you'd expect...
from an Art school graduate.
What do you think?
It won't work.
What's the...
It violates construction code.
Violates code?
Your land is zoned exclusively
for Class 1 homes.
You can't just go and build
to any height you please.
You'll never get a permit for this.
What if we ignore that?
They'll tear it down.
I'm sorry, but...
You'll have to start over again.
This is giving me a headache.
Don't worry about me.
As long as I get a bigger study,
I'm fine.
Those plans are hopeless.
They'll never work.
Why are you so negative?
Yanagisawa said he'll rethink them.
What are you gonna do?
Suga's in a real bind, here.
Suga, talk to her?
Oh, no thank you.
We've already hired him.
We've made our decision.
Can't you try to be more patient?
In any case, these are useless.
Just in case, you draw up some plans.
But what about your daughter?
If it comes to that,
I'll talk to her.
I'll do my best.
You live in a house for decades.
You can't just throw it together.
Come in.
Thanks for coming over.
My wife wanted to join us
but she's got school now.
Unfortunately,
I'm on my way out, too.
I won't be long.
We can leave together in 5 minutes.
Come on in.
Hey, rise and shine.
Take a seat.
About yesterday,
I just hadn't done my homework.
Well, neither had we.
I need 3 days to draw up new plans.
That'll be great.
Say, you write that TV series
"Nutty Apartments?"
Well, yes.
Where do you get those ideas?
You could say I eke them out
of myself by sheer force.
That's hard work, every week.
It is.
Yanagisawa, hurry.
What?
She's about to roll...
You can't expose yourself like that
in front of a guest!
Hurry up and turn over!
Hurry!
Turn over!
I just restored this.
I'm on my way to deliver it now.
Can I give you a lift?
Sorry, be right back.
Go right ahead.
There you go.
Any problems since then?
The cabinet windows are
a little heavy.
That glass is kind of thick.
It's got its own charm, but...
I'll take a look. We can change it.
I think you should wear
that apron a little lower.
Oh.
This place too?
I know the manager,
so I just lent a hand.
It's great.
Sorry, call waiting.
I found this table in New York.
Really? It's got real heft.
How would I know? Find it yourself.
Are you the president?
I guess I am.
But you're so young.
I quit my former job and
started it with friends.
It's just me now. Excuse me.
Just go buy it, go for it.
Wait a sec. What?
Go outside, you're making a racket.
Hang up.
Gotta call you back.
Now!
Go gossip at Starbucks.
This place is all about atmosphere.
That's the whole concept.
I've never actually
worked for a company.
After college...
He told me to go
"gossip at Starbucks."
Which of you assholes
picked on my girl?
Use the phone outside.
Who the hell are you?
You don't belong here.
Oh, we'll pay their check.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
He says he'll finish the new plans
by Friday, so let's just wait.
I'm hungry.
Right up. Sukiyaki OK?
We have that nice beef.
Great.
Yanagisawa wasn't down?
Didn't seem like it.
Oh, good.
You stay on top of it, OK?
We can leave the rest up to them.
Aren't you worried?
Sure, but I've got
my own work to do.
Doesn't it matter to you?
That's not fair.
Whatever.
I'm doing my best...
This solves the permit problem.
It's looking good, isn't it?
You can see it
from different angles.
Looking good, looking good.
And your wife?
She's put me in charge.
Father?
Got a pen?
Yes, here.
What do you say?
Hey, wait, what are you doing?
- Central pillar.
- You don't need a pillar there!
What's a house
without a central pillar.
You need to rethink your ideas.
Central pillar?
Hey, what have we here?
What?
Look at this.
This way, the main door opens in.
You're right.
Good thing you caught it.
What a joke.
It's supposed to open in.
What... did you just say?
I want it to open in.
Hear that, Suga?
What, is it a huge problem?
I've never heard
of a door that opens in.
Most American houses...
Where the hell are we!
I thought this was Japan!
My inspiration is Americanism.
Then get yourself an American
contractor! I'm not up to it.
Father.
Naosuke.
Sorry but I just quit.
Please, wait.
I sympathize, but Western houses
are built on bigger lots.
Let me...
Japanese building is all about
how to maximize limited space.
And so our doors open OUT.
But take another look, Suga san.
I've added
extra space in the front hall
for just that reason.
Oh, I see your point.
Take a closer look.
Never seen such a thing.
I know, I know.
What if it swung both ways,
like a Western saloon?
That's not the point.
I've never seen one like it!
Oh, man.
It's really complicated, isn't it?
Building a house.
Maybe we should've just bought one.
Just kidding.
The chief's so serious,
he doesn't get my jokes.
- Naosuke.
- Yes, Father.
This maestro here.
Hasn't really been on
many construction sites, has he?
It's the first time
he's designed a house.
My specialty is furniture.
I don't care what
your damn specialty is.
You gotta know the nuts and bolts.
What a waste of time.
Excuse me, but I've got experience.
You do?
Part-time construction work
in the U.S.
Part-time...
Chief, you should learn more
about architectural styles.
Your way isn't necessarily
the only way.
Father, watch your salt intake.
Don't worry, Naosuke.
Workmen on construction sites sweat!
The way I see it,
Dad's only ever built houses
the old-fashioned way, so he's lost.
That chief...
But we want you to design
the house your way.
So you just go right ahead.
Right ahead.
And what about the door, then?
The truth is, it doesn't matter...
which way the door opens.
Well, if that's how you feel...
That's not what I...
Can't you save his pride?
Have it open out?
Well, I guess.
I'm sorry.
I don't...
Actually, Dad used to
do interiors, too.
I see.
Sorry...
Not design, but finish work.
Actually, the two of you
have a lot in common.
This is it, this is it.
This is the house I wanted to build.
Oh, don't trouble yourself.
Now these are what
I call professional drawings.
Much obliged.
This curving veranda.
Has that storybook feel.
I had to consider that
it's a home for a young couple.
I'll talk to Tamiko about it.
Your third house is the perfect one
- ancient Japanese proverb
So you found a great property.
- Thanks to you, Mother.
- Not at all.
Why?
Mother told us the feng-shui
on the property was good.
That land lies directly
south-southeast of here.
If you move south-southeast
by next year, you'll have great luck.
Show me the plans.
They're not final yet.
The front door can't face east.
Really?
Or your husband will
stop coming home.
Which way's east?
This way.
Fine, it's facing south.
Oh, good.
What's this, the study?
The study, the master's room,
should face northwest.
What'll we do?
That's enough. Go home.
But you're older than my son,
so maybe...
But really, his study should
be closer to the living room.
He's tends to brood,
so it's bad for him to be isolated.
Should've said so sooner.
Should've shown me sooner.
I'll speak to my father about it.
It's just an idea.
It's not such a big deal.
The thing is,
you build the house your way.
Our ancestors gave us feng-shui.
But take the advice you like
and then do what you want.
Sure.
But, since you're building,
might as well as make it auspicious.
Does the kitchen face south?
Great, you've thought it out.
And the bedroom faces... north.
It really should face west...
Oh, I know!
You need a small pond in the garden.
A heart-shaped pond
in the south brings luck!
Tell your father, OK?
Where's the washing machine?
"Build the house your way,"
with all those conditions?
They're just suggestions, you know.
Now she says
the bedroom should face west.
Forget the pond.
What a pain to clean.
Remember my friend Iriuchijima?
His parents had a pond
in their garden,
with a really big Mannequin Pis.
Huh...
In Belgium, it brings luck.
I don't believe it.
It looked so silly.
You can't take all
that stuff seriously.
So the washing machine should
face south, but in my study?
Hello.
Naosuke? Can I speak to Tamiko?
Just one more thing.
Hold on.
My Mom.
Hi, it's Tamiko.
Listen, about the toilet.
There's only one on the 2nd floor.
You really need one
on the 1st floor, too.
A house with no 1st floor toilet
lasts only 3 generations!
What a horrible thought!
I'm begging you.
Speak to your father about it, OK?
If you're going to
have a toilet, I'd say here.
It's near the entrance,
convenient for guests.
- What do you think?
- The end of the hall facing south.
Hey, hey.
You never make a toilet face south.
The trouble with amateurs...
Why waste sunlight on a toilet?
You don't get it.
You want it bathed in sunlight.
Bathrooms always face north.
Making a bathroom dark is outdated.
I'm taking a leak.
Excuse me.
Miss, where's the bathroom?
Which means... Due north.
Thank you!
On the northern...
boulevard of bars...
You really need one
on the 1st floor?
Without one, the house is doomed
after 3 generations, oh boy.
What am I supposed to do?
You decide.
It's your house, after all.
I know.
We'll have 2. One north, one south.
Who needs so many toilets?
It was the only way.
And the 2nd floor?
Another one.
What do we need
so many toilets for?
Just 3.
A house full of toilets! Yuck!
We can brag about them.
Further right.
That's it, that's it.
All right.
Shoot over here, over here!
What's that maestro doing?
He's never been on time.
He's no good, no good.
He's got lots of other work.
Here he is, he's here.
Can you get a table?
Right.
What the hell time
does he think it is?
The measurement here? Maestro?
It's there.
What's this "7" here?
7 inches.
Inches?
I've never built a house in inches.
Precisely the problem
with Japanese architecture.
C'mere.
The design's Western, but cut to
Japanese sizes, so it's miniaturized.
All wood here is cut
to Japanese measurements.
So if you re-cut in inches,
it's a lot of extra work.
Sure it's extra work,
but I say it's essential.
I know!
Who do you think you are?
Can't you use inches?
It comes down to money.
Inches cost more?
It's not economical.
If you cut a 30 inch plank
from a standard Japanese board,
you waste this much.
I see...
I can't!
Build a house in inches, dammit!
Sir.
Let's use the Japanese way.
- Chief!
- Yeah!
Gotta bury the well. Need you here!
Be right there.
And off I go...
Yagida san.
The wrong prayer...
You're really good to your father.
But all these disagreements.
Don't worry,
you can count on your Dad.
Here.
The wrong prayer...
We used to call a real priest.
The pipe?
So the water god can breathe.
Wow, that's neat.
OK, cover it with earth.
Tamiko, you look more and more
like your mother.
Is that supposed to make me happy?
Oh, no, no, no... Are you OK?
Building a house at your age
is something to be proud of.
We took a 30 year mortgage.
But these days, the banks...
don't like to lend money.
You have real credibility with them.
Impressive.
Naosuke, Naosuke.
Yes, Father. Excuse me.
Tamiko, Tamiko, he's my son.
He's your son?
I'm bringing him on this job.
Nice to meet you.
Where you goin'!
The W.C.
Not again.
About the maestro.
I hate to tell you.
He may be Mr. Modernism and all,
but he's a friggin' amateur when
it comes to construction, trust me.
At this rate,
you're never gonna
have a house, Naosuke.
So,
sorry for the maestro, but
I had Suga draw some other plans.
- Show him.
- Yes.
Won't you take it home and...
look it over with Tamiko?
Please.
Having fun?
Back already?
- What's this?
- No good?
Of course not!
The 1st floor's all tatami rooms!
It's not a houseboat, you know.
Why'd you even bring it home?
Is this what you want?
This is getting super complicated.
This house'll be great.
Nicely curving storybook veranda.
Very storybook.
Go ahead and apply for permits
early next week.
And the Ground-Breaking Ceremony?
It's Tamiko for you.
Sometime this month.
You work it out, OK?
My pleasure.
Yeah.
I want to build this house.
Listen, I hired Yanagisawa.
You can't just do
whatever you please!
This house belongs to me and Naosuke.
You just work for us.
If you can't listen to your client,
then we'll just have to...
hire another contractor.
Party's over. Go home.
Tamiko always was...
What?
She always was headstrong.
What's that about?
She always did everything
her own way.
Always independent.
Come to think of it,
this is the first time
she's asked me for anything.
Really?
And I haven't done,
a single thing to make her happy...
Now that my daughter finally
comes to me for help.
Oh, no...
No more toenails left.
Suga? It's me.
I'm awful sorry,
but about those permits,
can you hold off a little?
I'm really sorry.
Houses resemble the people
who build them -Italian proverb
Mind your manners!
Come over here.
How's the house coming?
Moving along.
I've never built my own home.
Is it as hard as they say?
Lots of twists and turns, I'd say.
Twists?
Meat's burning.
I told you not to play
with your food.
How're things... with the maestro?
No news from him?
You have to eat your food.
Come to Grandpa, Sweetie.
No word, recently?
Not a peep since then.
I'm sure he's hard at work.
- Who? Who?
- It's none of your business.
The designer we hired.
- There a problem?
- It's no big deal.
But originally, you'd planned
to be building by now.
And you aren't,
which means there's a problem.
Cut it out.
You know, I've got
my whole crew on hold.
Oh, really?
Better put 'em to work soon
or they'll all starve to death.
Your grandfather is not a toy!
Come over here.
- Are the plans delayed?
- No.
Come, let's all eat.
How are all the old guys?
They're fine.
You've got your hands full, Father.
I'm fine, but the guys
I have standing by...
What is it?
But that's terrible.
That's the worst.
When you have a chance,
check on Yanagisawa?
- Check?
- On the designer.
- Don't bother.
- Yanagisawa?
- Not so loud.
- Just ignore him.
Thank God, we're renters.
Recklessly build a house,
it's just a pile of worries.
OK, time to eat.
The chief's crew is waiting.
My philosophy is...
first an artist, second a craftsman.
Of course, you have to work to eat.
But I can't afford to
squander my talent.
Here's what I think.
The moment the artist bends
his principles, he's lost his art.
When the chief said
he couldn't build to inches,
frankly, my interest sank.
But I'm a big boy. Having taken
the job, I'll see it through.
But not as an artist.
From now on,
it's just another job to me.
Then meet your deadline!
Isn't that what work's about?
I sensed your passion so we waited.
But if that's your position,
then we'll reconsider ours.
You've got 'til the end of this week.
Otherwise, we'll find someone else.
I'm... a creative person too.
I can understand how you feel.
But you're wrong.
The artist and the craftsman
don't conflict.
Without passion, a craftsman
might as well be a machine.
And an artist who can't sell
his work, is just a weirdo.
It's a question of
where you compromise.
If you want to consider this
just a job, that's fine.
But I don't want to sacrifice
your artistic passion,
and it's not that difficult.
Here's what I want, OK?
Yes.
That you finish the work
as an artist,
by the end of the week,
like a craftsman.
On one condition.
The front door opens in.
On that, I will not budge.
Ground-Breaking Ceremony
I hereby undertake...
the ritual purification of this land.
Thanks for everything.
I think it'll be a lovely house.
- Hey, what are they up to?
- Purifying the land.
- What are they throwing?
- Rice, salt and paper.
Are they going to clean it up?
Um, excuse me.
Here.
Huh?
See that bamboo branch?
Dig under it with this.
Dig?
It's part of the ritual.
You go, "Heave, ho." Twice, please.
Be serious about it.
You, too, Tamiko.
Me, too?
Both of you, please.
Please proceed.
Here goes!
Ready, heave, ho.
Architect, the honorable Yanagisawa.
Your turn, maestro.
No, I...
Please.
Ciao.
- What the hell!
- The jerk!
Over, over, OK.
Jr.!
That's the last one, chief.
That's it.
It's no use, I'm blocked.
Can I go home and think it over?
They're starting to panic on set.
We should really stop wringing laughs
out of those monster suits.
How's the house coming?
I have my troubles
in that department, too.
Send the e-mail.
My juices stop flowing
when there's water north of me.
Could you move?
Got yourself some great pillars.
Yeah.
It'll be one sturdy house.
Be hard put to find a house
these days,
built of this quality lumber.
Just like you, chief,
giving it your best.
Should be ready for the Roof-Laying
Ceremony later this week.
Can't wait for the Japanese room.
Just between you and me.
Yes.
The plans call for 6 tatami mats,
but I gave myself
permission to make it 20.
Won't you get in trouble?
The maestro'll flip out.
The Japanese room's mine
to design as I like.
I gave in on paper, but hey,
we're the ones building it.
Roof-Laying Ceremony
What ceremony?
There's all kinds of ceremonies.
At the Roof-Laying,
you drink sake, show gratitude for all
their work, and pray for a good house.
But we just prayed the other day.
That was the Ground-Breaking.
We prayed to the gods to
protect our land, totally different.
You aren't a builder's daughter
for nothing.
He wants you to make a speech.
Me? A speech?
I hope Yanagisawa shows.
- About what?
- What a drag.
I sure hope they'll all listen.
I don't want a repeat of
that party at Mom's.
That was hopeless.
Of course they all watched
the Filipino dancer next to you.
Let's go to sleep.
That was the worst speech.
How many people?
Probably a dozen.
Will they have a microphone?
Once more.
You're in the way.
We'll be late, Mom.
Don't worry.
All done!
Bravo, chief!
You're the best!
Hey, hey!
What?
What are these guys doing here?
You said a dozen.
I've never seen half these guys.
It's the best being
on a job with you.
Thanks.
Time to toast your labors, chief.
Let me pour you one.
Drink up.
That's the way.
You're a good looking man, chief.
Don't egg him on too much.
It'll go to his head.
Mother, look.
Oh, here you are.
It's so far away.
Yes, it is, whatever.
What is it?
Well, I know it's a little early,
but you're making a pond, so
I thought you could use a statue.
This, is my...
house-warming present.
It's a Mannequin Pis, supposed
to be good luck in Belgium.
I never heard about a pond!
What the hell is this!
What's this about a pond here!
Naosuke, didn't you tell your mother
we gave up on the pond?
There's no pond here.
Is there a microphone?
Hello.
I came for his speech.
Thank you, the ceremony's over
and the party's heating up.
Please, take a look inside.
Where's the pond going...
- The pond?
- The pond, in the south.
I'm sure it's over there.
This way.
Just put it over there for now.
What pond is she talking about?
Everybody drinking?
Thank God it didn't snow, chief.
Is there a micro...
Oh, a microphone...?
Do you have a minute?
I just noticed, do you mind?
That's the Japanese room, right?
Yes.
It feels too big,
it's only supposed to be 6 mats.
It's not right. Hey, chief.
How many mats did
you end up going with?
How many what?
In the Japanese room.
The Japanese room has 6 mats,
of course.
Right, Suga?
It doesn't make sense.
Weren't you told?
The chief ordered a 20 mat room.
That huge?
Since when?
No turning back?
The structure's already up.
I'm so sorry.
I'm fine, but what about you?
I guess I don't have a choice.
Hey, folks, time for the man of
the house to say a few words.
Quiet down.
Here we go.
The word "house"...
What's that?
There they are!
You're late,
hurry up and get ready!
Folks, these are dancers
from my club.
A celebration dance...
Yanagisawa...
Oh, what the hell.
Who gives a damn!
Only you guys know how I feel!
Even the Arch of Triumph was built by
an architect and a builder -A builder
And the interior?
Chosen wall colors yet?
I'm sick of waiting for him,
so he's coming to the site,
making decisions on the spot.
That must be tough.
The Japanese room?
It's working out just fine.
How wonderful, Dad,
your dream came true.
You're good to your father.
What will it look like?
I want to go with "juraku."
Juraku?
What's juraku?
Never heard of it.
It's kind of rare these days.
I'll show you when it's done.
Makes me so nervous!
I bet it'll be a real problem.
You shut up!
I recommend this one.
I think it looks great.
Maestro?
No fluorescent lights.
Incandescents in the study.
This one, please.
I want the study to be austere.
Maestro, uneducated as I am,
I can't make this out, Chew...
Two, Too...
Tudor style, it's what
Frank Lloyd Wright preferred.
Don't know him.
You don't have to. Just order it.
Impossible.
Why not?
No time.
If we order it now, it's too late.
It's your job to
get it here on time.
If the maestro had made up his mind,
he could have anything.
Sorry, but you pick
from what's available.
Cut the bullshit and
pick one of these!
There's nothing here!
Let's order this one. Make a note.
I'm the designer!
I'm the contractor.
It's my job to finish the house
on time, maestro.
We use this one in the study.
A-45?
Now he's pissed.
Let him order you around,
it'll never get built, right?
Right.
The door won't open!
Pull it towards you.
Most doors open out.
Bye, teacher.
Bye.
Hello.
Great to see you, Tamiko.
It's coming along.
I brought you some snacks.
And now?
He's choosing colors
for the living room.
White walls are so great.
Ivory, not white.
To our way of thinking,
it's not a color we'd use.
White shows dirt,
so most people avoid it.
People use it and it shows wear.
That's what we call lived-in.
Sounds far-fetched to me.
People don't paint these days,
they use cloth.
Cloth?
Wallpaper.
But these days,
they've got great wallpaper.
Don't have to bother with paint.
I'd like a muted version...
of this chip.
That's a custom color.
Well then, make it.
Fine, then,
it's a good color, done.
Done, next.
That's 726-3.
It's always like this.
I feel bad.
My job is to compromise.
Maestro.
It'll be a great house.
Sorry, move over.
Maestro, about the bathroom tiles.
These are the only ones available.
Fine, you choose.
Oh, please.
Go ahead, the maestro says
it's up to you, so let's decide.
But the corners need to be,
what's it called, exactly?
The rounded corner that curves.
What's that?
What's up, chief?
Don't you know? The corner piece
has an oriental feel.
You better start making some sense.
Just wait a minute.
Now what?
If it's too specialized,
it'll take time to find.
You know the kind of tile I mean.
What the hell is that?
What the hell.
Go with what we've got.
Dad.
There's no time, c'mon, OK?
What exactly am I doing here?
Tell me!
This one and that one.
What is this pillar doing here!
The central pillar's
the heart of a house!
Ultimately, your Dad and
Yanagisawa are the same.
They're both craftsman,
who believe in themselves.
That's why they butt heads.
Maybe you're right.
If you ask me,
they're twins separated at birth.
He's useless.
What's his thing? He ask for stuff
we don't have on purpose?
Not necessarily.
All that fancy crap
and always in English, too.
Well, I don't like it.
We got lots of good stuff in Japan.
Chief, this...
This might just be "bamboo-tile."
What's bamboo-tile?
In old houses,
they usually used this tile
in bathroom corners.
Hardly see it, these days.
I'm impressed
the maestro knew about it.
Just might be, chief,
that he's the one stuck on
doing things the old way.
Wow, this tile brings back memories,
are you using it?
It's coming along.
White walls aren't bad,
are they, chief?
Not bad...
We're so used to wallpaper,
it'd never occur to us.
Father.
Chief, they need you
to check the juraku.
Right.
Here goes.
The chief seems to like it.
I was aiming for
a more muted shade.
I think it's neat the way it is.
This house is riddled with
compromises, everywhere.
I'll check out the Japanese room.
How is it?
It's uneven there.
Here?
Look, Naosuke.
That's what we call juraku.
It erases the boundary
between ceiling and wall.
That's how our ancestors expressed
the vastness of the universe.
Wow, I see.
Father, do you mind?
Yanagisawa seems kind of depressed.
If I recall, he specializes in...
He's an interior designer.
Where can I see a place he created?
I figure it can't
hurt to take a look...
Seriously?
OK, then I'll work in something
on the Mecha-mermaid theme.
Right, right, right, I understand.
What would you like?
Anything you don't eat?
Father, why are you so tense?
It's my first time
in such a fancy joint.
Yanagisawa designed this place.
He did?
Seems to be pretty popular.
It's really elegant, isn't it?
This table, too?
Is it?
That's what designers do, after all.
It's really well made,
and sturdy, too.
The chief wanted to see
a place that you designed.
What would you like?
Oh, excuse me.
Oh, I finally
spoke to him about that.
What's the specialty of the house?
Everything's good.
- You order.
- Not for me.
- Not eating?
- Not at night.
You need three square meals a day...
If you want to live a long life.
I don't especially want to.
That's what all young guys say.
Oh, right...
This what you had in mind, maestro?
It's called "bamboo-tile."
Scoured every tile dealer in Tokyo.
Finally found some
squirreled away in storage.
I'm impressed you knew.
I remember seeing it as a kid.
I'm startin' to get the picture.
Boils down to...
you like old stuff, right?
Nailed you, right?
Whenever we show you
new catalogues,
you always turn 'em down.
It's easy to find
cheap and convenient things.
So, everything ends up
being predictable.
Predictable lives, predictable homes.
I can't stand them.
What I'm looking for
isn't so special.
I just want the basics.
There aren't enough of the basics
in this country.
Is convenience so wonderful?
Is spending time and effort
really a waste?
You order?
What's that?
The kind I told you about.
Wow.
The chief managed to find it.
Really? Is that true?
So, you'll use it?
It costs a little more,
but my son-in-law will
have to live with that.
Guess I'll have to.
C'mon, let's order.
Something salty, salty.
All of these are salty.
This salmon carpaccia.
Carpacci O.
Carpacci A.
Oh, that's great.
Dad's got his sweet side, too.
What's wrong?
What's got you down?
Looks delicious.
Is that special salt?
No, people prize
Mediterranean salt,
but I don't think it works.
I use Japanese salt.
Mighty particular.
Cheers.
- I'll mix a new one.
- What?
I used too much salt.
But why!
It's my fault.
A real pro.
I'm only paying for one.
Of course.
No good.
Hurry up.
It's my problem.
A real pro.
No good.
What's no good?
It's my problem.
No good.
What is this?
Somebody got in last night.
Goddammit!
- But, who?
- The door was locked.
The windows weren't tampered with.
In other words,
it was someone who had a key.
Color's looking good.
You, you did this!
You asshole!
I don't give a damn
whether you like it or not.
But once we decide something,
you've got to live with it.
In this world,
you rarely get your own way.
And if you don't like it,
stay at home and paint pictures!
That's right!
If you're going to get
in my way, get lost!
Don't you ever show
your face here again!
Get lost!
Rain's good for a house being built:
helps it to grow roots - a wise builder
It's really raining.
They announced a storm warning.
I hope our house is OK.
Think it's covered well?
I'm stepping out.
Hi, Mom, is Dad there?
He went over
to check on the house.
What did he say?
He thought it'd be fne.
Just wanted to make sure.
OK, thanks, bye, bye.
My Dad went to check.
Says it should be fine...
Try his cell phone.
...you are calling
is out of range...
No answer.
Must be driving.
I was in the neighborhood.
I checked the 2nd floor.
I'll check the bedroom.
It's ringing!
Oh, hello, Dad? Where are you?
I built you a sturdy house, after all.
This little bit of rain's nothing.
Don't you worry.
Oh, thank goodness.
What! Yanagisawa's there, too?
Yanagisawa? Why?
What's he doing there?
Fixing me a cup of tea.
We both just ended up here.
How lovely.
What are they up to?
Apparently he was worried, too.
Got a soft side, too.
Let me talk to him.
Hello, what are you up to?
Thank you.
Really, both of you?
Why are you going?
- 'Cause, I'm worried.
- About what?
There's a storm watch.
Yanagisawa's there, too.
- It's not up to them.
- Why not?
It's our house, after all.
Naosuke. What's this about?
What's wrong with you?
We can't leave them alone.
But they seem to be getting along.
That's why I'm going!
You're not making any sense.
I don't get it.
I'm afraid those fellow craftsmen
might hit it off.
What's wrong with that?
What's the point of getting jealous?
Don't stop me.
And your deadline?
You haven't written a word!
We might as well wait
'til my son-in-law arrives.
Why's he coming?
I wonder...
I've got work to do.
Give him my regards.
Thanks for stopping in.
It's all my fault.
Why did you come?
They'll tow your van tomorrow.
- Sorry for the trouble.
- It's my fault.
No one's to blame, in this rain.
I'm just glad you're OK.
I feel bad for the chief.
Your house, then?
Stop, stop, stop!
He was moving a piece of furniture.
Furniture?
Headed back to repair it overnight,
when I hit him.
I see.
It belongs to a special client.
He's got to restore it by morning.
An Edwardian cylinder bureau.
Was it this much of a wreck?
Of course not.
The drawers stuck, that's all.
This is hopeless.
How much was it worth?
2 million yen.
Let's fix it!
It's impossible.
- But...
- I'll pay damages.
Who can afford it?
Even money can't fix this mess.
Get me my tool box.
You can't fix it.
Not if you don't try.
There's no way!
We've got all night to
put it back together, right?
I'll give it a try.
What do you know about it!
It's Edwardian!
And what do you know!
I'm a Japanese carpenter!
Been one for 51 years.
Besides, no matter what we do,
it won't get any worse than it is.
Let's trust Japanese carpentry.
A general idea...
This is how it should look.
That's no use.
OK.
Chief.
Let's remove everything
that isn't solid.
Dismantle?
Yes, melt the glue.
I need you to go boil some water.
Sure.
And I need a tube,
as narrow as possible.
Sure.
Here goes.
I think it's about ready.
Hot, hot, hot!
Hot!
It's hot, Father!
There.
Any usable nails?
- None.
- Any new ones?
Plenty of nails here.
But these nail heads are
vintage, unique.
Don't have any here.
Oh, no.
We'll make them.
Make them?
We do it all the time.
Line up all the pieces.
Right there.
That one next.
Hurry.
Losing your pants.
Start with the main frame.
Attach #18 to #34.
Right.
It's coming along.
Coming along.
Attach #23 to #38.
- #38.
- Right.
- Those pants.
What are you doing!
I just picked it up, really...
It's hopeless.
You said it couldn't get any worse!
It's turning into a disaster!
Let's just give it up.
I appreciate your spirit.
Let's find another plank.
I think I saw one
like it out there.
Don't be ridiculous!
This isn't just any old wood!
Then substitute a piece of wood
that doesn't show.
This one?
That's for the side,
you can't substitute it.
No good.
This one?
You only see #12 when you
open the drawer, it might work.
I think it'll work.
It works!
- No.
- Why not?
Different process.
Chief?
It's tongue-in-groove.
Tongue-in-groove?
Yeah, see this groove here?
Yes.
It's a method called
tongue-in-groove.
Guess carpenters come up with
the same ideas all over the world.
Bring my tongue-in-groove tool.
Sure thing!
Can you replicate it?
It has to be identical?
If possible.
That'll be tough.
I've never done such sloppy work.
Whoever made this piece,
wasn't much of a carpenter.
What's a tongue-in-groove tool?
I'm sorry...
But won't this reduce its value?
Old furniture isn't valuable
because it's old.
It's been cherished over the years
because it functions.
When it breaks, you fix it.
It doesn't hurt its value.
- Get me some varnish.
- Right.
Regular varnish'll give it
a Japanese sheen.
Sorry, there's French in the van.
- French...?
- French polish.
- Bring that.
- Right.
Todaiji Temple in Nara...
has the huge Nandaimon Gate.
Nandaimon Gate, of course.
Built in the 8th century, I think.
It's been restored several times.
After centuries,
they found an ink pot...
on one of the crossbeams.
We're talking
many meters up in the air.
An ink pot?
Yeah.
We use these to mark lumber.
Right.
Did a carpenter forget it?
No one knows the real story.
But the thing is,
we believe that a carpenter,
whoever he was,
intentionally left it behind,
you see?
Proof that he was the one
who built this Gate.
I get it! Sort of like a painter
signing his painting.
No, everyone sees a signature,
that's no good.
The ink pot is a secret...
between you and God.
That's the important thing.
That's the spirit...
of a true carpenter.
What a great story.
Juraku...
No line between ceiling and wall.
It expresses the eternity
of the universe.
Take a look.
What? Showing off?
Hold it to the light.
You can see right through it!
You're amazing.
Incredible technique.
It's like 0.2mm thick.
Been at it 51 years.
Excuse me.
Yanagisawa.
What are you?
I can plane a board.
Yanagisawa.
Better not.
Ouch.
Hey, yours is really thin, too.
Amazing!
But Father wins.
If I could use both hands...
It's plenty impressive,
but Father wins.
That's impressive.
Oh, no, that's nothing.
I'm impressed, too.
Now it's my turn.
It's really no good.
I'm really impressed, you're good.
- You beat me.
- Oh, not at all.
Hey, it's stuck.
I better stop bragging.
Next time, I'll beat you.
I swear I won't.
If only my daughter had
married a guy like you...
What an honor.
Who said honor...
Please, Father, c'mon...
It was a joke, a joke.
Why don't you join us?
Thank you!
Excuse me.
After all, it's your house...
Maestro.
- Chief, are you sure?
- Yup.
You, too, maestro.
Then, this.
Son-in-law?
Me, too? Sure it's OK?
It's your house.
Hurry.
This, then.
When were you born?
Hurry.
Stop running around.
I've seen you on that TV show.
It's been so long.
Nice to see you.
This way, Kent, hurry.
House-Warming Party
Cheers!
Thanks, Tamiko.
Enjoy yourself.
Your vegetable sign
is cauliflower...
Help yourself.
Your sign?
Mine is a "Manganji" pepper.
Manganji?
Don't you know?
It's a green pepper,
about this size.
It's delicious
if you cook it with...
I'd say the walls are
a little too white.
Oh, really?
You'll see once you settle in.
Pure white walls hurt your eyes.
Terrific, girls.
Oh, no, don't. Brother!
Girls, cut it out! No!
Can I get you anything?
Are you fine?
Fine.
Thank you.
Help yourself.
Thanks.
I always watch your show.
And your commercial!
Your show's coming up.
Oh, I remember this concept.
I saw this one.
You're serious fans.
Makes it hard to recycle ideas.
Really gotta watch it, OK?
He turned it off.
You can serve that.
Yanagisawa go home?
Oh, perfect. Take this outside?
- Your father?
- The Japanese room.
Excuse me.
Yes, oh, how exquisite.
Naosuke.
You did a wonderful job.
Mom, let me do that.
Maestro.
I don't especially like you.
But I like this house.
Thank you.
Nice job.
Eat up, everyone.
Thank you.
Have a drink, Naosuke.
Where's Father?
Isn't he around? I just saw him.
Where'd he go?
Down the hatch.
Down the hatch? Sure.
What's next?
Nothing.
But some day,
you'll do a big job, right?
Turned into a great house.
It certainly did.
Even if the door opens out.
Never heard of one opening in.
Most American homes...
Who cares. I say doors open out.
You old fart.
The Japanese room's too big.
You've got a point there.
You knew after all.