- Ally, can we get a recap?
- Remember the Kowolskis?
They want to set a record by
making Buffalo's largest cookie.
- You have to wear this.
- A hairnet?
H.ealth Department. If you're around
the cookie, you have to have it on.
I just did the hair.
The hair is perfect.
All right, give it to me.
God... why do you hate me?
We're rolling. And speed.
For three decades,
the Kowolski Bakery
has been a mainstay
in downtown Buffalo,
known for their sinfully sweet,
cream-filled Polski pierogies
and the occasional
sugar-induced coma that follows.
Today, in honor of their 30th anniversary,
they've invited us to ride along
as they go for the record
on Buffalo's biggest cookie.
Vol. Do you need
a tissue or something?
Can we get Vol a tissue? Or a spoon?
Good thing we're wearing these.
I wouldn't want any stray hairs
to fall into the booger.
- We doing this again?
- No. We can cut to B roll.
Moving on!
Tell me, Mama,
why make Buffalo's biggest cookie?
Well, man from Health Department
say he find rat pellet in our pastry.
But I say no, is big chocolate sprinkle.
But he shut store down.
So we clean up,
make big cookie
for to bring customers back.
Well, I admire your candor.
Let's try that again, shall we?
Tell me, Mama,
why make Buffalo's biggest cookie?
So the children of the neighborhood
will be happy.
It must be wonderful seeing
the smiles on their little faces.
I work in back. I see no smiles.
The previous record was 8 feet
7 inches, baked by Gladys Pelsnick.
If this cookie beats that, it will prove
the Kowolskis
have much more free time.
And the cookie is... 1 0 feet, 4 inches!
We have a new record!
Cue the cheesy inspirational music!
But what are we really looking at here?
Is it just a big cookie?
Or does this cookie represent
the pride of Buffalo?
Its hard-working citizens
the key ingredient -
with a few nuts thrown in.
And finally,
the love of our families,
which provides the warm center,
making our beloved Buffalo
the sweetest place to live.
And that's the way
the cookie crumbles.
I'm Bruce Nolan, Eyewitness News.
And cut.
So what do you think?
It's really good.
It sucks. It's a story about a cookie.
The Pillsbury Doughboy
would be riveted.
It made me laugh. Nothing wrong
with making people laugh.
I'll never be an anchorman.
The job's there, but I can't reach it.
Every time they make me do
this kind of stuff I have to act like a goof.
I have no credibility. Not good.
- Now you just sound silly.
- Forget it.
It's not important.
Let's watch it one more time.
- No.
- Once more? Please?
No! You promised to help me
with this photo album.
Now get your gooy butt over here.
Looking.
OK.
Just go through this stack
and pick your favorites.
Come on. This is fun, right?
Isn't this fun? This is nice.
Evan's going to get that anchor job.
- Bruce!
- He's the favorite.
You know what? Just forget it.
This is just our life.
We can always just
have some kid do it for us.
Hold the phone.
I like this one.
Our weekend at the lake.
That's supposed to be in our private stash.
- You look perky. Must have been cold.
- Give it to me.
I think I'll put this on my computer.
- Give it to me. Come on.
- No!
Fine. Do with it what you will.
I don't care.
- I will do with it what I will.
- Jesus.
I might even send this in to Playboy.
- Their layouts can be quite tasteful.
- Give that to me right now!
- Rough stuff.
- I'm going to hurt you.
Sweetie? Time to get up.
Good dream. No.
The Buffalo Sabres lost again last
night to the Toronto Maple Leafs.
Of course they did. They're my team.
That's the way the cookie crumbles.
There might be something
to this cookie line.
The greatest anchors have a signature
sign-off. Like Walter Cronkite.
And that's the way it was.
That's the way the cookie crumbles.
That's the way I like it
Oh, no.
- Grace, the dog!
- I'm in the shower!
No, Sam. Bad dog.
Inside, bad. Outside, good.
You're done now. Great.
B-E-A-utiful.
Come on.
Let's go back in and have a shit.
- What is the dillio?
- We are having a blood drive.
- Needles. Yuck.
- They need my blood.
I have a very rare blood type.
I'm AB positive.
Really? I'm IB positive.
I B positive they ain't touching me
with no needle. It's just so...
- Helpful and life-saving?
- No. It's blood.
Blood is supposed to stay
inside the body, where it's meant to be.
Besides, they stockpile this stuff
in a warehouse, it's all on ice,
and they say there's a shortage.
Where did you hear that?
From a friend of a friend
of a girl whose sister is going out with
someone in the government.
For your protection,
I cannot discuss it.
Now get out,
before they see us together.
Here. You need these more than I do.
What is "these"?
Prayer beads.
The kids made them for me.
- They will keep you safe.
- I hope they're powerful.
I'm going to need a friggin' miracle
to get to work on time.
This isn't happening.
Not now. Not during sweeps week.
Oh, God.
Yup, meeting started without me.
This is my luck.
Come on.
Jesus.
Get out of there!
"Are you blind?" No, but I'm late.
Is your child in dire jeopardy?
Find out tonight after the game.
Promos are approved.
Jack? Shouldn't we be focusing
on Pete's retirement?
- This is his last week.
- Any word on the anchor position?
Evan, when I know something,
you'll know something.
Sorry I'm late.
Traffic was...
Did you already play the spots?
Nice story,
but we're going with Evan's piece.
The sex scandal
in the mayor's office for sweeps.
Yeah. Sweeps.
And that's the way
the cookie crumbles.
I'm just messing with you, Bruce.
See, you just gotta remember that
the newsroom is like a big cookie.
Do you like jazz, Evan?
Let me play something for you.
- I can hold that note all day.
- Knock it off, guys.
We'll keep your story in reserve.
Can we get back to the board so we'll
have something to put on the air today?
Great choice, Jack.
The Cadillac of bolognas.
Jack, can I talk to you?
- Sure. What do you need?
- Sweeps.
Jack, hear me out.
I'm starting to get desperate.
I'm pushing 40
and what have I got to show?
I've hit a kind of ceiling. There's an
anti-Bruce barrier I can't get past.
And Evan is loving it.
He gets the stories, he gets on sweeps...
I should be more like Evan.
Don't be like Evan. Evan's an asshole.
- I can be an asshole.
- No, Bruce. You can't.
- You going to pick that up?
- Yeah. I'm sorry.
This anchor thing opening up
has got me nuts.
- Hi, Susan.
- Hi, Jack.
You're a good reporter.
You make people laugh.
All right. I'll tell you what.
Today is the 1 56th anniversary
of the Maid Of The Mist.
- I want you in Niagara Falls in an hour.
- The Maid Of The Mist is always live.
- Evan always does the live feeds.
- Now you and Evan get the live feeds.
I'm going live? During sweeps?
Watch your step.
I've seen your out takes.
Jack, you will not regret this.
And I won't forget you
when I go national.
Can you...?
Thanks, pal.
Can I have your wish now?
I'll put it in the wish jar.
Put your wish in.
- Me, too.
- Put your wish in.
That looks like a big wish.
No, Martin, don't eat that.
Don't put that in your mouth.
That's paste, honey.
- That must have tasted awful.
- Mommy!
Did you have a good time
with Aunt Gracie today?
- See how nice this is? Baby on the hip.
- It's amazing. You've become Mom.
The transformation is complete.
I'll get it.
- Small Wonders Day Care.
- Grace?
It's Debbie, the sister
whose life you're not wasting.
- OK.
- Bye, Debbie!
Hi. Sorry.
Debbie forgot to take her meds today.
Where are you?
A little place
called the winner's circle.
I'm at the falls, doing a live report.
Live? That's great!
Yeah! It's happening, hon.
I got sweeps and I'm live.
They're seeing if I can think on my feet.
Like I might have to do
in a live anchor situation.
Oh, my gosh.
Yeah! Jack practically came out
and told me.
Practically?
He didn't spell it out. Legally, he can't.
This is what happened to Susan Ortega
before they bumped her up to the desk.
It's good.
Well, honey, I just don't want you
to get too ahead of yourself.
- Bruce.
- I got to go!
- They're calling me in.
- OK, honey. Good luck. I love you.
Let's do it.
- They want you close to the falls.
- I'm going to get soaked.
That's the point.
They want you to put this on.
Part of the condition
of us getting the exclusive.
You know what?
Nothing can bother me today. Nothing.
Now remember,
it's their 1 56th-year anniversary.
1 49 capacity. They cater
to tourists, honeymooners...
And people who are insanely thirsty.
I get it.
You're going to interview
Irene Dansfield.
Irene, a pleasure to meet you.
You look beautiful.
Irene's mother rode on the maiden voyage.
- Rub that in my face!
- 90 seconds!
Holy hell.
Because of the fast response,
the chemicals were cleaned up
without incident. Susan?
Bruce Nolan is at Niagara Falls.
But before we go live to Bruce,
we have an announcement.
As everyone knows, after 33 years,
our beloved Pete Fineman is retiring.
Pete's shoes are virtually impossible
to fill, but the show must go on.
And we could think of no one better
than our very own Evan Baxter.
Oh, boy!
- Congratulations.
- I'm thrilled and honored.
As you said, no one can replace
Pete, but I will do my best.
I am so proud to be a part
of our local community of Buffalo.
I think, in a lot of ways, a great
city is like a great recipe, really.
You take hard-working citizens,
add some care-givers,
maybe a few nuts!
All sprinkled with the love
and support of our good families.
Ultimately, that makes
one sweet place to live.
- That was amazing.
- I wish I'd written something.
And now let's go live to that wacky
Bruce Nolan at Niagara Falls.
Hey, wacky Bruce!
- Talk, Bruce. Hello.
- Talk, honey.
- What's going on?
- A Walt Disney.
- It's frozen solid.
- Check the feed.
We may be having technical difficulty.
- The feed's good, Jack.
- Come on.
- Talk, Bruce, damn it.
- Get ready to pull the plug.
Come on, baby. Say something!
Bruce, talk.
- Hi, Susan.
- Thank you, God.
Bruce Nolan here,
aboard the Maid Of The Mist
in fabulous Niagara Falls, New York.
First, let me just add another
congratulations to Evan Backstabber.
Pardon me, Bastard... Baxter.
It is good to see what
someone with real talent can do
when great opportunities
are given to them instead of me.
Anyway, I'm here
with Katharine Hepburn's mom.
Why did you throw the Heart of the Ocean
jewel over the railing of the Titanic ?
Did you feel bad
letting Leo DiCaprio drown
while you were safe
floating on the door?
Could you have taken turns?
Or were you too afraid
to freeze your big fat ass off?
I guess that's how life is.
Some people are drenched, freezing
on a stupid boat with a stupid hat,
while others are in a news studio,
sucking up the glory.
Oh, well. No big deal.
The owner of the Maid Of The Mist.
Let's have a talk with him.
Come on in here, Bill.
No, let's have a talk.
What are you doing?
You've been running
the Maid Of The Mist for 23 years.
Why do you think
I didn't get anchor?
- I don't want any problems.
- Is it my hair?
Are my teeth not white enough?
Or, like the great falls,
is the bedrock of my life
eroding beneath me?
Eroding!
- Cut the feed. Go to black.
- I'm on it.
I'm Bruce Nolan, for Eyewitness News.
Back to you, fuckers!
- Oh, boy.
- Oh, my God.
That is perfect.
That is the motivation that I needed!
Right there! Thank you!
Thank you, WKBW.
Wimpy... Kitty Baby Whiners!
That's what that stands for!
I'll see you on Channel 5.
Where they do the real news!
Do I look blind to you?
Let's go, man. Come on.
What are you doing?
Come on. Leave the poor guy alone!
You OK, man?
Yeah, you better keep walking.
- What'd you say, ese ?
- Run, man!
Run!
Oh, God!
OK, I didn't mean it!
- I was just kidding!
- Hey, you forgot your things.
Say something now!
B-E-A...
..utiful.
That's what I get...
That's what I get
for trying to help someone.
Don't look at me, Walter.
Oh, no!
That's my payment, I guess.
That is my reward.
Just? Just get a clue!
Thank God you're all right.
God, yeah. Let's thank God.
For his blessings
are raining down upon me.
- Wait! That's not rain!
- Bruce, please don't do that.
Everything happens for a reason.
That I don't need. That is a clich?
That is not helpful.
"A bird in the hand
is worth two in the bush."
I have no bird! No bush!
God has taken my bird and my bush.
I see. So God is picking on you?
No! He's ignoring me completely.
He's busy giving Evan
everything he wants.
Great, Sam. But you missed
your target. I'm over here!
Don't get mad at the dog.
It's not his fault.
It's God's fault.
He gave him the wrong co-ordinates.
Enough!
Will you stop being such a martyr?
I am not being a martyr! I'm a victim!
God is a mean kid with
a magnifying glass, and I'm the ant.
He could fix my life if he wanted,
but he'd rather burn off my feelers
and watch me squirm.
Sweetheart, I know you're mad.
What Evan did was slimy and wrong.
This day could have been so
much worse. I'm just glad you're OK.
OK? News flash! I'm not OK.
I'm not OK with a mediocre job!
Or a mediocre apartment!
I'm not OK with a mediocre life!
Is that what you think we have?
A mediocre life?
Don't make this about you.
About me?
How could I make this about me?
It's about you. It's always about you.
Perfect.
I'll have the worst day of my life
with a side order of guilt, please!
OK, God. You want me to talk to you?
Then talk back.
Tell me what's going on.
What should I do? Give me a signal.
I need your guidance, Lord.
Please, send me a sign.
Oh, what's this joker doing now?
OK. All right. I'll try it your way.
All right. Lord... I need a miracle.
I'm desperate.
I need your help, Lord.
Please, reach into my life...
What the...? Where are you?
Got you!
Fine!
The gloves are off, pal!
Come on! Let me see a little wrath!
Smite me, O mighty smiter!
You're the one who should be fired!
The only one around here
not doing his job is you!
Answer me!
Sorry. Don't know you.
Wouldn't call you if I did.
Oh, God!
Hello, 555 01 23.
Oh, no! Sam, this has got to stop!
Get it straight. That's the house.
This is the bathroom.
House, bathroom. Bathroom, house.
What's the point?
555 01 23.
Denied that promotion?
Is life unfair?
Is someone less talented than you
reaping the benefits?
Is your name Bruce?
Then do we have the job for you!
We're located at 77256 23rd Street.
So come on down -
or we'll just keep beeping you.
"Omni Presents."
Oh, yeah. The glass is half-full.
Come on! Look! What is that?
Thank you again.
What the...?
You're looking for room 7.
- Yeah, I figured.
- Want me to even those up for you?
- How do I get to room 7?
- That'd be on the 7th floor.
- Stairs are over there.
- I'll take the elevator.
- Out of order.
- The stairs were my second choice.
Do you mind giving me a hand
with this floor?
What? That's good.
Are you serious?
I'm kind of busy. Rain check.
I'll hold you to it.
I'm free on the 7th at 7.00.
The 7th at 7.00 it is.
This looks promising.
Hello?
Another hug antic,
gnostic waste of my life.
Hello?
I'm looking for whoever runs this joint!
Be right with you. I'm fixing a light.
Tell me if it's working.
Yeah. Seems to be.
- Kind of bright, though.
- Yeah. It is for most people.
Spend their lives in the dark,
trying to hide from me.
The elevator's broken, huh?
Yeah, but I'll get around to it.
- You installed a clapper?
- No, but catchy jingle, isn't it?
Clap on, clap off
The clapper
Just can't get it out of my head.
Well, good luck with that.
- I'm going to go now.
- OK.
But the boss will be right out.
You must be Bruce.
I've been expecting you.
This is hilarious.
You're the boss,
electrician and janitor.
Must be a killer Christmas party.
Don't get drunk, though.
One of you might need a ride home.
You always were funny, Bruce.
Just like your father.
He didn't mind
rolling up his sleeves either.
People underestimate the benefit of
manual labor. There's freedom in it.
Some of the happiest people smell to
high heaven at the end of the day.
All right, what is this?
How do you know my father
and how did you get my number?
I know a lot about you, Bruce.
Just about everything there is to know.
Everything you've ever said or done
or thought about doing.
Right there in that file cabinet.
- Wow! A whole drawer, just for me.
- Yeah.
Mind if I take a look?
It's your life.
This oughta be good.
This last entry was a little disturbing.
"The gloves are off, God."
"God has taken my bird and my bush."
"God is a mean kid
with a magnifying glass."
"Smite me, O mighty smiter."
I'm not much for blaspheming,
but that last one made me laugh.
Are you spying on me?
Who are you?
I am the One.
Creator of the heavens and the earth.
Alpha and Omega.
I see where this is going.
Bruce... I am God.
Bingo! Yahtzee!
Is that your final answer?
Our survey says, "God!"
It was nice to meet you, God.
Thanks for the Grand Canyon.
Good luck with the Apocalypse.
And by the way, you suck!
It would have been more impressive
if you hadn't used
the cheesy file cabinet illusion.
Anybody with a brain stem
can tell that drawer
is being fed through the wall
from the other side.
All you have to do
is find the crease right around here.
There is a seam here, or a hollow spot.
Where?
Through the dry wall and concrete?
OK, that is a good one.
- How many fingers am I holding up?
- Thou shalt not tempt the Lord.
- If you can't do it...
- Three.
Two... four... nine.
Six... eight... one.
OK.
How many now?
Seven.
- How?
- You've been complaining about me.
- I'm tired of it.
- Don't come near me. Seriously.
I don't want to hurt you,
but I will out of instinct.
You haven't won a fight since
grade 5, and that was against a girl.
But she was huge.
She'd been held back.
And the sun was in your eyes.
Ah, the ego.
Anyway, I brought you here
to offer you a job.
- A job? What job?
- My job.
You think you can do it better,
so here's your chance.
When you leave this building,
you will be endowed with all my powers.
Sure. Whatever you say, pal.
OK. That did not happen.
No one needs to hear about it.
I'm deleting the program.
No.
I'm having a breakdown.
Everyday psychotic episode,
caused by a tumor, a brain lesion.
Come on. Start!
That was lucky.
Come on. Calm down.
You did not meet God.
You do not have his powers.
If that was God, I'm Clint Eastwood.
Holy hell!
Be careful what you wish for, punk.
Nope!
I am a reasonable,
sane human being.
With a .44 Magnum.
The most powerful handgun in the...
I'm not Clint Eastwood.
I'm Bruce Nolan.
I'm Bruce Nolan!
That was not real.
- Coffee?
- Coffee, yeah.
We have a special on soup today.
- No, thank you.
- It's tomato. I made it myself.
OK.
Excuse me, I need a spoo-...
It's OK. I found one.
Here's your soup.
Oh, soup, right.
Yeah, right.
Having fun?
Thy, thou...
Come. Take a closer walk with me.
- Let me explain the rules.
- Rules?
You left in such a rush,
I didn't get a chance to explain.
The two extra fingers
freaked me out a little.
I figured I'd get your attention.
I did the same to Gandhi.
He didn't eat for three weeks.
Anyway, here's the deal.
You have all my powers.
Use them any way you choose.
There are two rules.
You can't tell anybody you're God.
Believe me, you don't want the attention.
And you can't mess with free will.
- Can I ask why?
- Yes! You can!
That's the beauty of it.
- This is amazing.
- Speaking of amazing, excuse me.
Holy sh-... Cow.
Since you're through with these,
I'll keep them.
Might come in handy some day.
See you around, kid.
- Where are you going?
- I'm... taking a vacation.
God doesn't take vacations.
Does he? Do... ye?
Did you ever hear of the Dark Ages?
I'm covered. You can clear everything up
in five minutes if you want.
Right?
And he saw that it was good.
B-E-A-utiful!
Check it out.
Look, it's the hero.
- Whassup, homie?
- Yo, brethren, what up with thee?
- Blessings on your alley.
- Want another can of whup ass?
- You didn't get enough?
- He wants some more!
Surely, I say unto you dudes,
I do not wish to fight.
So as soon as you apologize and make
a reckoning of your transgressions,
I shall absolve you and continue
along the path of righteousness.
What are you talking about?
You talk kind of funny. I don't know
if you lost it up here or what.
You want me and the homies
to apologize? Cool.
We'll apologize the day a monkey
comes out of my butt. How about that?
What a coincidence!
Because that's today.
Did that monkey
just come out your crack?
This is some voodoo shit!
You guys leaving?
Don't forget your parting gifts!
Hey, little anal-dwelling butt monkey.
Time for you to go home.
I am Bruce Almighty.
My will be done!
What if God was one of us
Just a slob like one of us
Just a stranger on a bus
Trying to make his way
Home
- My God.
- Call me Bruce.
What happened to you? You seem so...
happy.
Why shouldn't I be? On a night like this.
Those are amazing. What are these?
A new breed. A cross-pollination
between tulips and daisies.
I call them todayzees.
OK.
Honey, these flowers are beautiful.
- But last night...
- Last night, I was only human.
Barry, help me out.
Honey? Hi.
- I've never seen the moon that big.
- Yeah.
We really shouldn't waste it.
Bedroom?
Five minutes.
Let there be light.
I'll be out in a minute!
Don't rush.
Sometimes anticipation
can heighten the...
pleasure!
Oh, God.
It's a funny thing about pleasure.
It can be quite... pleasurable!
Oh, my God.
Pleasuring, pleasurable.
Oh, good God!
In international news:
Japanese relief workers are staging an
effort to rescue hundreds of people
stranded by a freak tidal wave
that hit Kitamoto City.
Scientists say the tsunami
may have been caused
by what they are describing
as unusual lunar activity.
More on this as it develops.
Please bless my mommy, my daddy,
and especially my little sister.
Please help me, Lord.
Please get me through this one.
Thank you for everything else
in my life. Amen.
Good boy.
Forget something?
Good boy! There are girls in the house.
- Morning.
- Good morning.
- I made you grilled cheese.
- My favi.
- Honey, last night was...
- Heavenly. I know.
I mean, I woke up and I felt like
my boobs were bigger.
- Do they look bigger to you?
- What?
No.
- Bigger?
- Oh, come on!
Look at them.
Please. They are definitely bigger.
I mean, look. They feel huge to me.
I have to go.
But this has been the breast bek...
Thank you.
- Where are you going?
- To get my job back.
Yeah, yeah, I am great
Good grief! Is that what I'm driving?
Nice car, man.
Yeah, it gets me from A to B.
Darn. All this horsepower
and no room to gallop!
Hi-yo, Silver. Away!
I wouldn't want to be a fugitive
with Hank, Buffalo's number one
police dog, on the job.
Phil Sidleman at the police canine
training center, Channel 5 News.
And cut it.
Look what the cat coughed up!
Channel 7, right?
You're the guy that went crazy.
- I had a bad moment.
- What are you doing here?
- Looking for a story.
- No story here.
This pond is all fished out.
Pretty standard stuff, anyway.
My instinct tells me
there's something more.
Well, go with that.
It served you well in the past, right?
Hank found something!
We got a body!
Shit. Get the camera! Now!
- It's locked! The keys are inside!
- I guess every dog has his day.
- Kid, you want to make $1 0?
- Sure.
- Know how to use one of these?
- Duh.
Seems to be in tune. Let's do this.
The body of Jimmy Hoffa
was uncovered in a field today
outside a canine training center
in Buffalo, New York.
- Bruce Nolan was first on the scene.
- Thank you, Jane.
As you can see,
the body is being carefully exhumed
for transportation to a facility
where DNA can confirm the identity.
That, however,
merely a formality at this point,
as the body was found with a birth
certificate and dental records.
I'd call that a red-letter day
for any canine unit.
But was that enough for Hank?
No, siree.
Moments later, he busted
a local news camera crew
with 220 pounds of marijuana.
I never saw it before! I swear!
I'm Bruce Nolan...
and that's the way
the cookie crumbles.
Did you like that?
Thank you, thank you.
- Hi, Bruce.
- Hi, Susan.
Good work. I'm impressed.
- Did you need me for something?
- Bruce!
Just the man I want to see.
- Hoffa? What are the odds of that?
- What are the odds of that?
- Bruce, why don't you sit down?
- OK.
I'm going to be straight with you.
We want you back, Bruce.
But I want you to understand
it was not my decision to let you go.
- When the big guy gives the order...
- No harm, no foul.
I needed to reassess my goals
and get in touch with my true self.
- You did that in a day?
- Imagine what I could do with seven.
It is not in my power
to give you anchor.
As far as field reporting goes,
if you're looking for a bump...
Let's cut the crap
and get down to brass tacks.
I had you going.
Don't worry about it,
my old friend.
Just give me a camera.
I'll give you the news.
My secret is that I let the jalapenos
marinate in a spicy sauce
for at least 24 hours
before I stir it into the chilli.
Then I let it all come to a simmer.