- Hola!
- Hola.
What do you think my father would say...
...if I told him I didn't want to
be a lawyer anymore?
Nothing... He would just kill you.
How is it going with your new
roommate? What's her name?
She's alright, but I'm tired.
- Why?
We spent all weekend looking
for her doctor-boy.
How can a big time heart-guy
leave no trace of himself?
Don't know.
Maybe we're suing him for malpractice.
Where does he work?
I don't know. She said he
used to be at... Loma Vista.
What's his name?
David Ravell.
Loma Vista? David Ravell?
You're talking about the guy
on "A Reason to Love."
Tell me. Is your friend still trying
to find that soap opera guy?
Yes. I'd love to find that actor
so he could burst her bubble.
Here is your needle.
He's supposed to make an
appearance here tonight.