MYSTERY OF THE RESURRECTION
33 year Judaean Desert DC
Original text: dani67
Translation by: www.syedgakbar.com/projects/dst
editor: hidagamers
You are novel, huh?
E ring tribunes?
Gives.
Live far away?
Tenth Legion! Forward!
So! Come on !
For 30 years, the Roman Empire of Tiberius Caesar's
Judean desert and led his people.
Baraba ! Baraba !
As prefect Pontius Pilate's tribune,
my job was to keep order in a city killed by the riots.
In formation!
Jews pray their only god, Yahweh, until the Messiah appeared a mystic.
Meanwhile, the Sanhedrin tries to maintain a precarious peace.
Every day there are new government zealous that defies Rome
to bring freedom. Instead, we bring death.
Kill them!
Positions! Take!
Formation!
Hold the line!
Forward!
Tribunule !
I caught Barabbas!
Bring him here!
I know how it will end.
Then tell them that Yahweh live, courtesy of Mars.
You'll just find out that the only true god we chose us and not you.
But not today.
When the Messiah comes, Rome will not matter!
Until then...
Tribunule, has called Pilate!
- I'm dirty and bloody. - No matter, we have trouble.
Haide! Haide!
You won ?
They told me to hurry.
In reality, you're well-dressed for the job.
- What happened? - E Pesach! (Passover)
In all major holidays, fanatical idiots from Judea came to wreak havoc.
A madman has gathered a handful of followers defying doctrine.
Council decided to eliminate it.
He sent a handful of madmen who invokes his death
because he claims to be the Messiah.
We had to him crucified.
Do not look at me. They have made it and others.
The situation was risky, tribunule. You obviously can not understand.
King will arrive soon and expects to find order.
Order!
What you want me to do ?
Resume control of the territory and make orders.
This story has lasted too long.
And be merciful to one Nazarene.
Break his legs.
Clavius, he's your new aid.
Lucius Ticonius Enius. His father is my friend.
It's an honor for me, tribunule.
What's wrong with that? Now an hour the sun shone.
Poseidon s-a mâniat.
Sure some god was angry.
I hate when howling. I hate this.
It could take days.
Back!
Centurionule, how to proceed?
- It's a strange day, tribunule. - It was a small earthquake.
Not only that. It's too dark.
And King ... That's something wrong. Plebs feels.
Draw the sword and hit one.
Nazarene'm already dead.
After only six hours.
- It's not possible. - Spoke ?
- The man talked? - Just before the earthquake.
He said: "It is finished."
It's time to end this.
Finally.
Does not last long.
E mama nazarineanului.
You are!
Use spear.
That woman's mouth shut!
To shut up !
You are lucky or not.
This man was certainly innocent.
You must be strong.
Go and tell him that the prefect over.
Spread out! It's over !
Go to your homes!
Move! Out now! Out!
Bravo, free yourself! You must free yourself. Breathe deeply.
Breathe! So.
Come on, Let go!
Take claws!
I've never killed a king.
States !
Tribunule come from Pilate. Please read.
- You are Joseph of Arimathea? - I am.
Is your family tomb.
What is he to you?
Sabbath's close. I only have two hours.
Please.
It's yours.
Nicodemus, hurry!
Maria !
Out.
Sir?
Return to your centurion. Dealing them.
Please tribunule.
Be careful! Take care !
Vino, Clavius, relaxeazã-te si tu.
Put them in a glass.
What do you want? Food, a massage, a girl?
- Only this. - You're young.
After a night of rest you can get it at the end.
Your services are appreciated, tribunule.
I'm counting on that.
So I ask forgiveness if I was a little dry today.
Does not matter.
Nazareth was closed?
I helped pushed the stone over the grave. It was enormous.
- There were many disciples. - Hopefully will be buried with him.
It's a strange case. I've never seen a death so desired.
Even Him. As he will be sacrificed.
They're fanatics. Yahweh drives them crazy.
Yes, any other god.
For example, I just pray to Minerva.
For wisely. But you ?
- Mars. - It's normal.
Hopefully one of them listen to us.
We could use.
- Everyone does what you need. - Not loaded with yours.
Spare me. And you're stuck.
Your ambition was observed.
Where do you want to go ?
The Roma.
And?
- In a position of power. - What leads to ...
Welfare.
A beautiful family, a big house in the country.
Where did you find ...
End sacrifices.
A day without death.
Peace.
Yet for peace.
There is no other way?
Well, I go to sleep.
Tomorrow will be other punishments.
Nazareth ... did it seem different?
Mi death appeared.
Better.
- Pace, tribunule. Good night. - Good night.
A penny for the ferryman.
Good riddance to you, Gaius Elius.
Legion before!
Legion 10!
Tribunule, he called Pilate.
Ave, prefectule !
The smell of meat. Any celebration?
Funeral.
Here's the solution! Let it burn in public.
God forbids cremation.
It forbids you to work Saturdays and yet you are here
Tribunule.
- Who do you burn? - On Nazareth crucified.
What?
- It's unfinished business. - The man is dead, Caiaphas.
The disciples were hiding, no longer remains a threat to you.
But it remains a threat.
When live, the impostor said he would rise after three days.
He predicted that.
We demand that the tomb be sealed
that his disciples may not come at night to steal his body.
Not to say then that rose from the dead.
Would cause more chaos in the city that all blasphemies together.
- Have your guards. You can do it alone. - Are my words exactly.
To which I add that it takes Roman seal.
So that a decision may appear impartial prefect.
And not yours.
We want what he wants and Caesar.
Peace in Jerusalem, in Judea peace.
What you would lose if that body would disappear.
- This is why I'm here. - Take care of yourself.
Check you.
- Sigilati! - Sigilez.
None touch the seals before sunset tomorrow. It's clear ?
And Sacerdote say.
- But the centurion you? - Not good, not himself.
- That worries you? - No, tribunule, no way.
Only we have to be free tonight.
You will send rations.
And you are part of the council, huh?
Gives.
This man despise thy brethren, and you cry it.
It was very special.
A king?
Tribunule test me?
What was the name Nazarene?
His name was Jesus.
The or part!
A forgotten. And you know too.
If he had sent food, he had come before.
E de rang superior.
If you forget us, what we whips!
I kept for supper, but ...
- Great! You are great ! - Good !
I thought we broke even.
- Tribunule Pilate ... - he called.
A dispãrut !
Nazarineanul? Sigur nazarineanul!
- Tomb is empty! - Who broke the news? Garza?
Your guards are gone. We announced a local!
Who would you put the watch?
I want them found and flogged to death, of course!
Let me do research.
I want results to come here before Caiaphas and his flock of Jews.
Too late.
Tribunule.
How about you not lie?
- They come to you? - To seek refuge.
I know the punishment for he who sleeps in service.
- What happened ? - Exactly what I predicted.
Heretic disciples came by night and stole the body.
They proclaimed already risen from the dead!
- People will think? - The weak, yes.
Others will want to do this, so you have to robbery.
You believe?
If they believe Garza will not be killed.
- It never ends! - Robbery.
Prior to spread the news.
It's not enough !
Without a body to prove death, we have a potential Messiah.
I do not want to doubt, Tiberius must find no clutter!
We have to find a body definitely!
- Will you help me? - Of course, but you have to make the announcement.
My trust in you is moved, tribunule?
Maybe you prefer a place in hell.
You must find them all these disciples,
but especially to find the body of Jesus cursed!
Prior to rot.
Bring me the arimateean.
Come on, call your arimateean.
As if whipped!
Tribunule, look here!
- Where did he go? - That to tell me.
The body was embalmed?
I did not have time. I gave myrrh and aloe.
Here you see. Sweat and herbs. Get it!
Do not let anyone touch it. Controls roads.
Controlling what comes out of Jerusalem.
Arrest anyone who says he is alive and find out where he heard.
Since, tribunule.
Find the dead bodies in recent days.
Controlling them and check the signs of crucifixion.
You dig?
All !
And bring them to me immediately.
- Tribunule. - I asked in private.
Where's your boyfriend?
He does not want to come to speak.
Seriously ?
He had issues to talk about the theft of the Nazarene.
- He is afraid. Me too. - Very good.
M-Ati dezonorat.
Sleeping during the Guard is death.
But the prefect forgiven.
You can return to barracks.
- Unpunished? - If you are truthful.
I was attacked while asleep
by furious disciples of the Nazarene.
They took the body and they told us to say that rose.
Angry? How many were there?
- 8, 10 ... I'm not sure. - They were armed?
Yes Yes.
- I've seen while you were sleeping? - No, I ... we ...
We woke up when they cut the ropes.
- Did the Taiat. - Da. Da.
Then they rolled the stone.
- They took the body and fled. - While you look at them?
Yes, but they threatened us with a spear.
Soldier !
Ti was ordered to say something?
- You've been drinking. - No.
- No? - No.
What lies have you told?
Open the gates!
- It was stolen? - So they claim.
So what.
They're afraid that might be raised.
It might be the Messiah.
- That being said. - Arrest him!
Turn it!
- That when he died? - For at least a week.
- And these? - I am with thieves who died.
Let's go.
Over two days will be unrecognizable.
Wait to see how it will be on the battlefield.
Not.
It lacks a hand. See the hole in the other?
Not him. He has broken legs.
That's why we need you, tribunule.
And this tomb is done hastily.
- So. - I have questioned 40.
You should talk to about 11.
One of them might be a disciple of his.
- I apologize. - Eat chicory.
Over time, the stomach will get used.
- Put them inside. One by one. - Yes, tribunule.
- Who took the body? - I do not know.
It is said that you are an honest man.
And a disciple of Jesus.
The truth today you will not be fatal.
He was impressed by what he said and teaches.
I think not deserve to die like that.
They have opened the grave to steal a body
and to spread a lie that threatens Rome and the Sanhedrin.
There were followers of Jesus.
Not real ones.
They are desperate.
Who they say they are resurrected
to lead Israel against us.
Messiah.
You think ?
If Jesus were alive,
I think you should embrace as a brother.
Even if you disown you.
You can leave.
I will try other means before being forced to make cuts.
It's not something I said, tribunule.
I admit. You asked if he would be a king.
That's his crown.
Take a seat.
Why tremble?
Are you a novel.
They heard screaming: "Jesus lives!"
With joy, as report says.
- Why, just that you could not see. - I heard on the streets!
- From the past? - No, I heard his voice.
- Jesus. - Two days ago.
I recognize voices.
- I hear. - I do not doubt.
Erai o adeptã de-a nazarineanului
Miriam ?
Or just a follower, a follower?
He loved me.
An old woman ... I make me feel good.
In what sense?
If you had known, you could understand.
You have to stop saying that people raised from the dead.
Came.
- Do you want to know what he said? - Sure you do.
You are a seed that already bore fruit.
- It's too late. - Come on.
Next is important, tribunule.
Today I pray thee, Mars, the god of the Jews but, Yahweh.
Hear me!
Withdraw favor of defending those people
si dã-mi-o mie.
If you do the signs,
I high temples for you and I will devote games in your honor.
You know what I'm doing?
Gives.
Who told you that Nazareth crucified alive?
A friend...
of a friend.
A friend of Jesus. A disciple somehow?
Either way, do not lie.
This friend says that I was told ...
that they saw two women.
They went to the tomb at dawn that day and found him naked.
Then they saw Jesus on the road.
In life.
Their names.
Either way, we'll get the answer.
I know only one.
It's a slut.
Maria Magdalena.
It was last seen on the morning of theft.
Early. Then he disappeared.
As we found out, tribunule.
- Where does it work? - If you work? It's a street.
- You did not bring anyone recognize her? - But how? Who could?
Who knows one Maria Magdalena?
They were surrounded. We had to retreat.
A strategic withdrawal.
Many of us were captured and taken to the hills.
At night I heard screaming.
We looked up.
I put the stake to show us.
IALA why should not you pity for them.
Ea and?
Not.
She is !
Do not move!
Pace, Maria.
What were you running from us?
Instinct.
I had seen.
In my old life?
Jesus' death were there beside his mother.
She was with you to the grave?
If you know what happened there ...
- You're not thinking ... - Enlighten me.
It's beyond us ...
Spare me riddles.
Where have you gone to Jesus?
- Is here. - It's a ghost?
It's a spirit that returned to life?
- Open your heart and look. - It's a hallucination.
To keep alive a faith.
I can get what I want, to force you to say you threatened with death.
Does not matter.
- A martyr. - No!
Give me the others and I will restore freedom.
They are already free.
Show me the Messiah!
Dead or alive.
Go to His disciples.
Looking for something you will not ever find tribunule.
Looking wrong.
It's crazy. Refuses to think logically.
It could be a witch. Be stoned? Or so close?
Better ... let it go.
What?
Go ahead '. That woman is unwell.
You have not slept for two days, tribunule. The mind feels.
- When it ends, wake me. - Yes, tribunule,
Tu, Ridica-te!
Misca-te!
Tribunule, drained all the sand.
Pilate called you.
- You dug death? - Try them all.
Jewish graves?
Makes sense to me. He was a Jew and died.
Do not you realize how much anger you caused.
Over two days, no one will think about it.
Nature has its course.
Caesar's spies will find it.
An unfortunate circumstances.
For both, tribunule.
I want them body here! Until the night!
They are key disciples. If we find them, we will have on him.
For your help.
You will receive, if you do what you ask.
The disciples of the Nazarene.
How many are their names.
Their plans, where hidden weapons.
Where they meet, who now leads them.
Where they hid the body.
Just do it quickly.
There are 12.
No, there are now 11.
Circle of Jesus.
- They hid, but do not know where. - Do you have a name?
I will give you one.
- Who Bartholomew? - I am.
Take it.
- What do you get spread fantasies? - I saw with my own eyes, tribunule!
I walked with him, talked to me!
Of course, it's unbelievable but it's true!
Bring him here. Now.
Or looks my body.
Lo lost, snake skin.
God is not in my job.
God ?
Yahweh is manifested by a poor dead Jew?
So it seems !
What does rebirth?
Eternal life!
To all. For all those who believe.
Best means of recruitment.
Much better than assault. How many are you?
We are now few. The only weapon we have is love.
But this ... well, that changes everything!
What intentions do you have?
Why you is so afraid? Empire does not mean anything to him.
You must give to Caesar what is Caesar's. That taught.
And if ordering your crucifixion?
What? I could a serene face. I'm ready.
Have you ever seen a crucified man?
Not.
I do not think I've seen there.
Probably because you ran.
It is not like that ?
I'll tell you what you missed.
Ia-l !
Imagine that nailed this pierce your arms.
And then pierce your feet. Can you imagine that?
You will remain hanging from nails that will pierce your bones.
Now you need to decide if the agony is worse here
or here?
Your weight will torture all the time.
Then you discover that you can not breathe.
You will realize that you will not be able to breathe easy.
And that each breath the rest of your life
It will be like sucking a wet cloth.
He was lucky. He hung a few hours.
Many people have days on end.
And if he felt something in the end,
sure was spear that pierced his ribs to reach the heart.
There I looked around,
but all her ribs were broken as to give it away.
- Sometimes bury them with nails. - Please ends!
Reach.
Not to mention his body.
By now it be horrible.
Do I ever wonder once ...
Where are the other disciples? Stop wondering by now.
Tell me and I'll be free.
He assured me that?
You have my word.
Where am I ?
I'm everywhere !
There are more ?
Not those who can recognize.
I'm done here ?
The East ?
There are holes here, here and here.
- Rana side. - But the image? I do not recognize.
Nobody can.
We could say it was him.
At this point, any body can Nazarene.
But I find out who took it. That's the threat.
The threat is a creature with many heads.
Now I need you elsewhere. I have problems in Hebron.
But we must solve this. I need some time next week.
More than 7 days you have to be in Hebron.
You are dangerously smart, tribunule.
Can I trust you if you turn your back?
That's what I'm afraid most.
We are made from the same dough.
I remember the time when I was like you. So sure, so ...
I forgot.
- What difference can have reality? - What?
Over several years we will be so.
Open!
What happened?
It seems that went to Hebron.
I told the soldiers to prepare.
Guards were seen at the tomb.
- They left temple. - Where am I ?
It's not clear.
They say that they spent money.
I know you can win.
And I know that's gonna happen.
Your ambition was observed.
Bravo! Is wonderful ! Sing!
Sing them again! That before!
Sing them again! Please !
Yes, it's a beautiful song.
It's an expensive wine for a legionary.
Have you hidden! How do you win these coins?
Om the dead.
Sure you do.
Prefect forgave me.
She forgave me.
You can not give me anything.
I said what was proclaimed.
Say it again.
What?
Let's see if the same thing as your buddy said.
I was attacked at night while asleep, by a group of ...
The priesthood they were paid to say that.
They stole the body!
And they asked us to say that Risen!
How has reached 10 stone steps from the grave?
It took seven people, including myself, as it tumbling!
The ropes were not cut but were slapped as floss.
Seal melted butter. You want to go back there?
No!
What troubles you so much?
Do not lie !
How did they get?
Where the body of the Nazarene?
You have forgotten us two!
I had to eat.
For this wine she slept.
I stayed awake two days after the crucifixion.
What can happen when guards dead?
I slept on row until ...
Until ?
By the time he woke up a terrible ...
A terrible lightning.
Night ended ...
and was a burning smell and ropes as if exploded.
And stone flew like a leaf, and suddenly, the sun ...
He rose from the grave.
That was the sun.
Era...
It was everywhere.
And then a chip that appeared ... A face appeared and I could not look.
It was a terrible light and ...
There was a man.
It was not.
And there was a voice around us which we could not understand.
And we took her to flee. And I ran away until ...
Until I managed to think again!
Then we went to the priestly because you like you told us to do.
Caiaphas and will paid to say something else.
Tribunule...
I saw many in the service of kings.
Cannibals ...
I saw a man captured by a marine snake ...
but something I've never seen.
So...
Please explain this to me.
You were drunk.
Have you seen the sun.
A wine was poisoned?
Seriously ?
What you think?
Maybe there was opium, or even incense.
Maybe the disciples stole the body through witchcraft,
The priesthood as saying.
Or maybe our story is true.
That true?
I do not know.
So I drink.
Sir. Tribunule!
I've found.
Romans came!
Hurry! Hurry! Come!
That's home. I lost it there.
- Lost? - I think they went in there!
- Just think? - Yes, like that. When I came to tell you ...
I saw and other disciples who came from that.
Upstairs are my reward!
The Romans! Hurry!
Tribunule !
I six on this side. Check every home!
You five, on the aialaltã.
I want one or two in life! Come on! Move!
Move! I stuck out and go back!
Not.
Tribunule! You found something ?
Nothing.
Gather people back to camp.
Tribunule...
Withdraw!
Then come back.
Tribunule, we're close! I feel it !
Not that I need you.
I do not need you.
Sir.
Withdrawal!
Soldiers, we return to camp!
In mars !
Welcome, Clavius.
Join us, brother.
They are not enemies.
Do you take !
- God! - Thomas, where have you been?
Iarta-code!
Iarta-codes.
This mid-ceri Dispensa crumb? What?
We have to fear.
We are free.
Touch.
And here.
How?
Jesus!
- Jesus! - Where?
- Jesus! - Jesus!
- Returns ? - Where did he go ?
How will I know ?
And now ? Simon?
He said to stick to Jerusalem to receive the Holy Spirit.
- What have I got now? - I do not know.
- Galilee. - What?
When it appeared in the streets,
Jesus said:
go and call my brothers that go into Galilee.
There we meet. He told me.
I saw.
In Galilee you will see once.
Pay attention to them.
Simon !
Then let go.
- Let's go, my brothers. - Mary look after you.
- Goodbye, Maria. - Goodbye, brothers.
Forward!
Demand a ransom?
"Nu cautati code."
"Do not follow me or wonderful."
"There persecuted anyone in my name."
"I saw two things which they can not reconcile."
"One dead, no doubt. And the same man alive again."
"I'll follow Nazarene to discover the truth."
Clavius Aquila Valerius.
E seal of, sir.
- It must be epidemic. - My right arm comes back against me.
How Could a Jew to follow that?
Probable...
- It's true. - If it were so ...
kill him again.
Brothers let go.
In life, if you can.
And even if he were dead, would not mind less.
Will You Find at Caesarea.
Sir!
Leave. In north to Galilee.
Ten days later the King will be here.
Ten days.
Forward!
I brought water!
Water!
It will remain mark. I hope you know that.
Yahweh !
Hallowed be Thy name.
Give us the daily bread.
And forgive us our trespasses as we forgive our debtors.
And lead us not into temptation.
Deliver us from the evil one.
Amin.
A son of Yahweh be.
And you think?
Do you believe ?
After that, yes!
Raised from the dead, he eats, sleeps and then disappears.
It has a body.
Yahweh same body that it gives all people.
So he approached.
I have all the answers.
We marvel us.
Why did not showed all?
He could be killed again?
I do not know ! I do not know...
I wish I knew, but I do not know.
You will find in Galilee.
We are disciples. We follow him to reveal.
I think that prepares us.
For what ?
If.
Pilate will not stop looking for me.
We threatening.
After coming after me.
I can not know where we are.
I already know.
They are thirsty for blood.
We are not afraid.
We are not.
Should you have for what was entrusted.
Back!
Around here.
Come, we must hurry.
Grabiti-withdrawal!
Please !
Ruthless, tribunule.
- That's what I've learned. - It was a bad lesson.
I dub you the master.
But let them pass.
If nazarineanul?
A dispãrut.
They are not enemies.
You destiny of the world in your hands.
To know that.
I think that...
... Is in the hands of these men.
Today nobody dies.
None.
Now go away.
Does not say anything.
Remember that.
Why just here?
He told us to come.
Sometimes it's hard to understand.
Simon will to eat.
Where to fish.
To fish! Come!
He will find!
Come on ! The boat! FISHING!
We are here !
Brothers!
To fish!
Pull. Pull!
Try again?
Twice more.
Then sleep will wake up the sun.
You got lucky?
Try right again.
- My brothers, wake up! - What's happening?
Come on, brother!
Awake! Prepare dragnet!
Arunca!
What happened?
- Pull! - It's too hard!
- The water is not deep! - Shoot! Will go !
Something hanging it!
- It's over! - Pull!
It's over!
How did you know ?
Jesus!
- Jesus! - It's back!
- Jesus! - Jesus!
Jesus, I'm back!
- Thomas! - Thank you.
Did you know that he will rise again?
He told us, but ...
Frankly, I thought.
Why did you follow?
A leper! To leave ! Go away !
- To leave ! - Go away !
- To leave ! - You can not stay here! Can not !
- Blestematule! - Delete it!
Delete it from here! And never come back!
- I do. - What ?
He will heal the man.
Cum ?
Look ! Just look !
- Nobody wants to touch me. - A miracle.
I saw him do more.
Do you have faith?
Brothers!
Here's why.
What are you looking for ?
Trouble.
Will appear.
That's a threat to them. To Pilate, Caiaphas and Rome.
There will be trouble for us.
You must have faith.
Came.
Come to do two steps.
- Why ? - As to hang.
Simon loves me?
Yes, just know that yes.
- You love Me ? - Yes.
- Simon, you love me? - From all my heart.
You have to look after my sheep.
I do not know what to ask.
Speak to the heart.
Fail to reconcile all this
the world we know.
You saw with your eyes and you still have doubts?
Imagine that never saw the doubt. What should do?
Why are you afraid?
To be wrong.
To bet my immortality.
Then follow my father.
When you died...
I was there.
- I helped. - Know.
What are you doing, Clavius?
Certainty? Pace?
A day without death?
- Awake! - Brothers!
- Jesus! - He left !
My brothers, stand up!
Jesus!
Brethren.
I go to prepare a place for you.
Go into the world and preach the gospel ... all over
all nations.
You will be witnesses of Jerusalem.
In Judea to the ends of the world.
You know you'll always be with you!
Always!
My Lord.
It's not just about eternal life, but about how it is lived.
By sword or by love.
That it can change. Here.
It's time.
Farewell, my brothers.
A once more can you say.
Amin.
- God bless you, Peter. - Goodbye.
- Goodbye, my brothers. - Goodbye, Peter. Take care of yourself.
Farewell! May peace be with you.
You could join us tribunule.
Jerusalem only bring trouble.
Troubles ...
We were called to receive the Holy Spirit whom he promised ROMANU.
Your job is to fish.
Yes, but people.
How could I do otherwise?
You fish and you, Clavius?
Therefore...
Farewell, brother!
Farewell.
Lord to protect you.
I will carry with me ...
Forever.
Peter, come on!
- Come on! - My brothers !
- Grãbeste-you! - Wine!
Wait for me!
I doubt that we will have news about them.
Tribunule !
Pay with this.
Do you really believe in all this?
I believe...
It'll never be the same.
Readaptarea: Bubuloimare