In the name ofAIIah the beneficent,
the mercifuI,...
..aIIpraise is due to AIIah,
Lord ofaII the WorIds,...
..to the one God
to whom praise is due forever,...
..to the one who came to us
in the person ofMasterFard Muhammad...
..and raised up
The HonourabIe EIijah Muhammad.
- Aameen.
- (congregation) Aameen.
- As saIaam aIaikum!
- Wa-aIaikum saIaam!
- How do you feeI?
- Fine, sir!
- Who do we want to hear?.
- MaIcoIm X!
- Are we gonna bring him on?
- Yes, sir!
Yes, we gonna bring him on!
WeII, Iet us hear from ourminister,
MrMaIcoIm X!
Let us bring him on
with a round ofappIause!
(appIause and cheering)
Brothers and sisters, I'm here to teIIyou
that I charge the white man.
I charge the white man with being
the greatest murderer on earth.
- (congregation shouts)
- I charge the white man...
..with being
the greatest kidnapper on earth!
There is no pIace in this worId
that that man can go...
..and say he createdpeace and harmony.
Everywhere he's gone,
he's created havoc.
he's created destruction.
So I charge him. I charge him with being
the greatest kidnapper on this earth!
I charge him with being
the greatest murderer on this earth!
I charge him with being the greatest
robber and ensIaver on this earth!
I charge the white man with being
the greatest swine-eater on this earth!
The greatest drunkard on this earth!
He can't deny the charges.
You can't deny the charges!
We're the Iiving proofofthose charges!
- (cheering and appIause)
- You and I are the proof!
You're not an American,
you are the victim ofAmerica!
You didn 't have a choice
coming overhere.
He didn 't say
''BIack man, bIack woman,...
..come on over
and heIp me buiIdAmerica.''
He said ''Nigger,
get down in the bottom ofthat boat,...
..and I'm taking you over there
to heIp me buiIdAmerica.''
(appIause and cheering)
Being born here
does not make you an American.
I'm not an American.
You're not an American.
You are one ofthe 22 miIIion
bIack peopIe...
..who are the victims ofAmerica.
You and I,
we've neverseen any democracy.
We ain 't seen no democracy
in the... the cotton fieIds ofGeorgia.
Wasn't no democracy down there.
We didn 't see any democracy
on the streets ofHarIem,...
..in the streets ofBrookIyn,
ofDetroit, and Chicago.
Ain 't no democracy down there.
No, we've never seen democracy!
AII we've seen is hypocrisy!
We don't see any American Dream.
We've experienced onIy
the American nightmare.
(wiId cheering and appIause)
(congregation) We Iove MaIcoIm!
We Iove MaIcoIm! We Iove MaIcoIm!
We Iove MaIcoIm!
(fades)
We Iove MaIcoIm! We Iove MaIcoIm!
* Joe Turner: ''RoII 'Em Pete''
* WeII, I got a gaI
She Iives up on the hiII
* WeII, this woman's tryin' to quit me...
See that spot! Get it. The spot!
All right, Speedy, that's it.
* They shine Iike KIondike goId...
C'mon, Pee Wee.
* Every time she Ioves me,
she sends my meIIow souI
* WeII, you're so beautifuI
Butyou've got to die someday
* AII I want's a IittIe Iovin '
Just before you pass away
* Yeah!
* (piano scats)
Hey, ChoIIy!
Where'd you get that number you hit on?
Was that your girlfriend's address?
No, my grandma gave me that number
in my dreams, straight!
- Three, eight, four.
- You told me Sassy Frassy gave you...
Nah, that woman quit me.
After l hit the number,...
- ..that woman was no good to me at aII.
- No? What happened?
She said l was cheap
cos l wouldn't cop her a diamond ring.
- And on top of that, had the indignation...
- Whoo!
..to call me, of all people,
Good Time Cholly,...
..a cheap black son of a bitch!
- Sassy Frassy?
- Cholly, where's homeboy?
- Hey, Little!
- Yeah?
Your man out here waitin' on you!
There he is!
Hey! Fixin' to get that first conk laid on,
eh, homeboy? Be hot like hell!
Don't be a-scared, son,
you ain't got nothin' to worry about.
You in the hands of an expert!
My hair was just like yours.
Look what he did for me!
- (laughter)
- Heckle and Jeckle!
Don't scare the man
no more than he's scared already!
- Get his forehead and eyebrows, Shorty.
- Who's doing this?
- Y'all heard that.
Pull my coat-tail if it stings, this shit
could burn a hole through cement.
Hold tight, baby, and keep your eyes shut.
l thought you said this was gonna sting.
(chuckles) This ain't nothin'.
- Feel good, don't it?
- Yeah, reaI good, don't it?
- Yeah, it's all right.
- Gonna feel better than that in a minute.
lt is heatin' up a little bit there, Shorty.
Shorty, it's startin' to heat up there.
- lt's all right.
- Feelin' better and better, ain't it?
- Just hold on!
- All right, l'm holdin', but it's heatin'!
- We gotta make it straight.
- Well, all right.
- That's what he told me, too!
- (laughter)
- l gotta get this out now, it's startin' to...
- Uh-oh! Uh-oh!
- Hold on.
- l'm holdin', l'm holdin'! l'm holdin'!
- Well, hold on!
- l'm hoIdin'on!
- Cholly, gimme a hand! Help me out!
- Go on! Hold him! Hold him!
- Hold him!
- Shorty!
- C'mon, we're goin' to the sink!
- l got to get up! l got to get up!
- Cool it, baby! Cool it!
- Put some water on him! More water!
Hold on!
Wait, wait, you're getting it in my eye now!
How's it feel?
- Feel like l ain't got no skin on my head!
- lf you can talk, it's out!
- How's it look?
- l can't tell yet.
lt's straight, though, right?
l ain't doin' this again!
Yeah. Lemme dry it. Lemme dry it.
(chuckles) l can tell, it's layin' down.
(radio) Gets on down the Iine,
does it up so mighty, mighty fine.
- Don't take it off yet.
- All right.
That's the thing to do!
Come on in here and get through!
A moneymaker and a heartbreaker,
every step ofthe way.
You gonna fIip!
That's right, watch yourIip, dear...
Oooooo-ooh!
- (laughs)
- AII right! Go, Joe! He's the man!
- Looks white, don't it?
- Well, all right!
- Yes!
- Well, all root!
- Ow!
- Well, all reet!
* Yes, yes
Swing it!
- * Yes, yes
- Yeah, right now.
* Yes, yes
* Yeah, you know
* WeII, aII right, then
* WeII, aII reet, then
- Hit the brim with your left.
- * WeII, aII root, then
* WeII, aII rote, then
- Hey, girl!
- * WeII, aII right, then
Sweet thing!
* WeII, aII reet, then
* Bye, baby, bye
* Bye, baby, bye... *
When my mother was pregnant with me,...
..KIansmen on horseback surrounded
ourhouse in Omaha, Nebraska.
They brandished guns
and shouted formy father to come out.
- Earl Little!
- We know you're in there! Come on out!
My mother went to the door, where
they couId see herpregnant condition...
..and toId them my father
was in MiIwaukee, preaching.
Now, these hooded KIansmen
said the good white Christians...
..wouId not stand forhis troubIemaking,
and to get out of town.
- C'mon!
- Bring him out!
- (screaming)
- Come on!
- lt's all right!
- (children shriek)
- You and your family, Earl!
- We got no place for y'all here!
(shouting and screaming)
Mommy!
They broke every window
before riding offinto the night.
They rode offinto the moonIight
as suddenIy as they had come.
You see, my father
was not a frightened Negro,...
..as most were then,
and as many stiII are today.
He was six feet four, a very strong man,
and beIieved, as did Marcus Garvey,...
..that freedom, independence
and seIf-respect...
..couId neverbe achieved
by the Negro in America.
..on the object of building up
for themselves a great nation in Africa.
Therefore,
bIack men shouId Ieave America...
..and return to the Iand oftheir origins.
..to his original home, Africa!
My father dedicated his Iife to his beIiefs...
..because he had seen
four ofhis six brothers die vioIentIy.
Three kiIIed by white men,
and one Iynched.
There were nine chiIdren
in our famiIy.
My mother was a proud woman,
an educated woman, and a strong woman.
She was very fair-skinned because
hermother was raped by a white man.
One ofthe reasons she married my father
was because he was so bIack.
She hated the white bIood in herbody
and wanted her chiIdren to have coIour.
In fact, I think this had
a profound effect on me back then,...
..and on most Negroes today.
So many ofoursisters have been raped
or vioIated by the white man,...
..that the bIack men can't wait to get
theirhands on the white man's prize:
..the white woman.
Africa for the Africans!
(applause and shouts)
Say ''Roseland''!
(both) Roseland!
Showtime!
- Showtime!
- All right!
* LioneI Hampton: ''FIying Home''
Whoo!
Yeah! (laughs and whoops)
Whoooo-hooo!
- Yeah! C'mon, baby! C'mon!
- (gasps)
(laughs)
Hi, Shorty!
You're too big!
- l'm gonna come get you.
- Oh, no!
Whoo! C'mon, Shorty, l'm gonna dance!
- Red, hold this!
- Shorty, go get her, baby! l got your hat!
Yeah!
Hey!
- Hey! (laughs)
- Ah! Ah! Ah!
You in charge, boy!
Yeah! Whoo!
You like what you see, baby?
No! Shorty, get back here!
Go ahead, boy!
- Red, save me! Save me!
- Come back here! Gotcha!
Whoo! Yeah!
- Feels good!
- C'mon, Shorty, l wanna dance again!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Hey! Hey!
- Ho! Ho! Go on!
- Shorty, Shorty! Shorty!
Hey! Hey, hey!
Aow!
- Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha!
- Whee!
- Whoo!
- Whoa! (laughs)
Whoo... hoo!
- (laughs)
- Whoo!
Yeah!
- All right, then!
- Shorty! Shorty!
Whoo!
(laughs) Whoo!
- * (xylophone plays)
- (crowd responds) Whoo!
- * (xylophone)
- (crowd) Whoo!
- * (brass)
- (crowd) Hey!
Flyin' home!
Whoo!
- Whoa!
- Flyin' home!
- Yeah!
- Come on, Shorty! Come here, baby!
(music stops, crowd cheers)
You OK, baby?
(chuckles)
- Laura sure can go, can't she?
- Uh-huh.
- l gotta go freshen up.
- All right, baby.
- You come on back, now.
- All right, Malcolm.
Mmh-mmh-mmh!
That chick is fine as May wine.
Except she live up on the Hill
and got a grandmother, too.
Yeah, she a church girl,
so l don't know what l'm gonna do.
* Hoagy CarmichaeI: ''Stardust''
Wanna dance?
Yeah.
So what do they call you?
- Uh, Red.
- Red?
l'm Sophia.
- How you doin', Sophia?
- Very well, thank you.
l have an idea, Red.
Why don't you take that little girl home
and come on back?
What...?
Just walk, baby, don't run.
lt'll be here when you get back.
Well, l better not come in.
- l'm not stupid.
- What? l mean, it's late, baby.
No, l know where you're going, Malcolm.
l am not a total square...
- l know exactly what is happening...
- l'm not going anywhere! l gotta go home.
lt's late, l gotta get up...
..(fakes yawn) early in the morning.
You know l gotta work tomorrow.
So l call you tomorrow?
What for?
l'm not white and l don't put out,...
..so why would you want to call me,
Malcolm?
Good night, Mrs Johnson.
(lower) l'll call you tomorrow.
* The Ink Spots: ''My Prayer''
* Ooh
* My prayer
* Is to Iinger with you
* At the end ofthe day
* In a dream that's divine
* Ooh
* My prayer
* Is a rapture in bIue
* With a worId far away
* AndyourIips cIose to mine...
* ''My Prayer'' pIays on carradio
(playfully) Aww! Hey.
Am l the first white woman
you've been with?
- Huh?
- Hm?
No, you ain't! Shit, l done had plenty.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
That isn't a whore?
Hm?
(chuckles) You...
Mm... Mmm.
Take your time.
Sophia's not going anywhere.
Remember, l told you to walk,...
..don't run.
Shh!
l don't like women that talk too much. OK?
OK.
Who wants to talk?
* At the end ofeach day
* In a dream that's divine
* Ooh, ooh, ooh
- * Ooh
- * My prayer
* Is a rapture in bIue... *
- Yeah, Red! Bang!
- Naw, you missed me, flatfoot!
Here, try this one for size!
(mimics machine-gun fire)
- l ducked!
- You ducked?
- l got you right between the toes!
Man, l'm tired of playing the cops
all the time. l wanna be Bogart!
(as Bogart) Well, Shorty,
you're too small to be Bogart.
- l'm not too short to be Cagney. Boom!
- Aaaah! Why, you...!
- Oh! Aaaagh!
- Boom!
- You dirty, stinkin'...
- One more! One more! Boom!
- Aw, Jesus!
- (laughs and groans)
- (gunshot)
- Filthy, rotten, stinkin' copper! Aah...
He used to be a big shot.
(screams)
There is just nothing l can do.
- What do you mean, took his own life?
- l'm sorry, ma'am. You heard the verdict.
Verdict? A man takes a hammer
and bashes in the back of his own head,...
..then he lays down on the tracks
and kills himself(?)
We merely act on the verdicts,
we don't make them.
Well, do you pay or don't you?
Read the policy, ma'am.
lt clearly states...
C'mere, Sophia.
(radio)
* EIIa FitzgeraId: ''Stairway to the Stars''
- * Let's buiId a stairway to the stars
- You're the man.
- * And cIimb that stairway to the stars
- Sit down.
* With Iove beside us
- * To fiII the night with a song...
- What's your story?
You one of them white chicks
can't get enough coloured stud?
* We'II hear the sound ofvioIins
* Outyonder where the bIue begins...
Kiss my foot.
Go ahead. Kiss it.
* Can't we saiI away
On a Iazy daisy petaI
Now feed me.
* Can't we saiI away
On the IittIe dreams
* And settIe high on the crest ofa thriII?
Yeah.
(snorts) That's your story, girl.
So, when you gonna holler rape, sister?
Me?
Yes, you. You would if the time came.
Sure you would.
Malcolm, let me feed you.
C'mon.
While they're hot.
l sure wish your mother and father
could see you now.
And that ofay you gonna marry.
l sure wish Laura could see us.
* Let's buiId a stairway to the stars... *
Please, Malcolm.
There's nobody around.
Nah, this ain't right.
- Why?
- Because you...
No, it's...
- lt's because of the white girl, isn't it?
- No, it's not because of that.
- Folks say you two are running around.
- lt's not because of that.
Save it, all right, Laura?
Save it for Mr Right,...
..because your grandmother's
smarter than you think.
l'm sorry she raised me that way.
ls your mother alive?
Yeah, she's alive.
When l was a kid, l was so poor l used
to think ''Not For Sale'' was a brand name.
- l did knock.
- Did you hear me say come in?
There's no point in fighting about it.
l'm sorry.
- May l sit down?
- As you nice enough to ask(!)
lt's the same questions, Mrs Little.
Since the death of your husband,...
- Murder. Murder.
- There is serious question...
..as to whether or not you are capable
of raising these children on your own.
Oh, well...
These are my children.
They're mine.
And there ain't no question.
Sometimes, l think, Mrs Little,
candour is the only kindness.
All of your children are delinquent,...
..and one, at least - Malcolm - is a thief.
Get outta here!
Your control over your children
is therefore nonexistent...
Did you hear me?
You will regret this.
lf you don't move out through that door,
you're gonna be past regretting!
We were parceIIed out, aII ofus.
I beIieve that ifever a state agency
destroyed a famiIy, it destroyed ours.
I was sent to a detention home,
and Iived at this woman's house.
This is your room, Malcolm,
l know you'll keep it clean.
Mrs SwerIin.
Boys, this is Malcolm, our new guest.
We'll treat him like a brother.
I was speciaI.
The onIy coIoured kid in the cIass.
I became sort ofa mascot, Iike a...
Iike a pink poodIe.
In fact, I got caIIed a niggerso much,...
..I didn 't think there was anything wrong
with it. I thought it was my name.
(Mrs SwerIin) He's a fine athIete...
They taIked about me Iike I wasn't there,...
..Iike I was a pedigree dog or a horse.
- ..president ofhis cIass.
- Like I was invisibIe.
Now, the important thing is to be realistic.
We all like you here. You know that.
But you're a nigger, and a lawyer
is no realistic goal for a nigger.
But why, Mr Ostrowski?
l gets the best grades in class.
l got voted class president.
l wanna be a lawyer.
No. l want you to think about
something that you can be.
You're good with your hands.
Making things.
People would give you work. l would.
Why don't you become a carpenter?
That's a good profession for a coloured.
Wasn't your pa a carpenter?
Jesus was a carpenter.
People like you as a person.
You're doing real well.
Remember what we said? ''Nothing
succeeds like success.'' Let me hear it.
- Nothing succeeds like success.
- Right. As long as you're realistic.
lt's not the end of the world, Malcolm.
l said ''Don't...
..let 'em give that boy no pig.''
It wasn't the end forme, but it was
the beginning ofthe end formy mother.
(train whistle)
- (radio) A right cross to thejaw by Louis!
- (all cheer)
Conn is covering up now!
Louis takes Conn's head back
with a right uppercut!
He's reeIing around the ring!
Louis hits a Ieft and a right to thejaw!
And Conn is down,...
- (all roar)
- ..with a right cross to thejaw!
- And he's taking the count! Four! Five!
- Wait!
- Six!
- Seven! He's on his back! Eight!
- Seven! Eight!
- Nine! He's getting up at the count...
- Nine!
- No, the referee says it's aII over!
- (all cheer)
- The referee says it's aII over!
- l knew he was gonna get it!
- What in hell is going on?
- Uh, nothing, Mr Cooper.
We got a lot of hungry customers!
- Uh, yes, sir!
- Soup done finished, Mr Cooper!
- That's right, Mr Charlie!
- The name is Mr Cooper.
And don't you forget it! Mr Cooper.
Boy, what in the hell is the matter
with you? You want me to get fired?
- l got a wife and six kids!
- Mr Cooper is good white folk, boy!
You is a young fool!
Damn!
..not himseIf!
There'II neverbe another one Iike that...
Oh, yeah! He's got him!
He's done it! He's done it!!
By a knockout...
..and stiII the worId's
heavyweight champion!
- Joe Louis!
Ham and cheese! Excuse me, sir.
Ham and cheese here!
l got coffee, lemon meringue pie!
Hey, boy!
Gimme one of them ham and cheese.
Yes, sir, best in the house, sir!
- Mighty pleased with yourself, ain't you?
- l aims to please, sir, l'm pleased to aim.
- l like you, boy.
- Thank you, sir.
- Keep the change.
- Right, sir! Ham and cheese!
- * EIIa FitzgeraId: Drop me offin HarIem
- (hollers)
- * AnypIace in HarIem
- * Ho-oh! (laughs) Harlem!
* There's someone waiting there
Who makes it seem Iike heaven
- * Up in HarIem
- (car horn)
* I don't wantyourDixie
* You can keep yourDixie
* There's no-one down in Dixie
* Who can take me 'way
from my hot HarIem... *
(announcer) Joe Louis is back in HarIem!
They're ceIebrating! They're going crazy!
They're dancing and cheering,
they're hanging from the street signs!
Everybody's out!
Everybody's having a great time!
- Listen to them roar!
- (shouting)
- Joe! Joe! Joe!
- * IfHarIem moved to China
* I know ofnothing finer
* Than to stow away on a pIane someday
* And have them drop me offin HarIem *
(whistling and cheering)
(announcer) Joe's a credit to his race.
What a fine gentIeman!
But he's aIso a fine American!
The Brown Bomber, Joe Louis!
- Hey, sugar!
- Huh?
- Slow down, daddy. What's your hurry?
- Ain't no hurry.
- Lemme show you somethin' brand-new.
- Nah.
Look here, champ,
l got gold watches, diamond rings.
Any one of these.
Whatever you want. Whatever you need.
- No, l don't need nothin', daddy-o.
- You need somethin', baby.
- Well...
- Coupla these, then a player look good.
You know that. What you want, champ?
* LioneI Hampton:
''Hamp's Boogie-Woogie''
- Boy, you gotta see this.
- Yeah?
- My man!
- The word is ''Excuse me'', boy!
- ''Excuse me'' don't shine my shoes.
- Then you shoulda stayed out my way.
Old country nigger.
(laughs) What you gonna do?
Go home to your mama(?)
Nigger, don't you ever, in your Iife,
say anything against my mother!
- Let's get out.
- Man! What'd he do to my face?
Hurry up. Let's move it.
Give me a whisky.
(mouths)
l ordered a single, Jack.
The double's on that gentleman,... Jack.
Who is that?
That's West lndian Archie.
Yeah? What's his angle?
Some of this, some of that.
Come closer. l'm not fixin' to bite you.
You look like you're new in town.
From what l can see, you're...
you're pretty handy with a bottle.
- He had it comin'.
- Pull up a chair.
So what they call you?
Red.
Red, and l ain't no punk.
You better not be. Any cat toe you down
in this town, you stand up or make tracks.
- Man live by his rep.
- You better believe it.
- So what do you do for yourself, Red?
- Working on the trains, sellin'.
- Like that job?
- Keep me out the army.
When they're ready for your black ass,
nothing can't keep you out of the army.
Not this boy!
So, l hear tell you're a...
you're a good man to know.
- Where you hear that?
- Boston, where l'm from.
Kiss my neck!
l ain't never been in Beantown.
Well, like the man said,
a man's rep travels.
How 'bout that?
You bullshittin' me or what?
First thing my father taught me was you
never bullshit a West lndian bullshit artist.
- Your daddy is West lndian?
- My mama.
(lilting) She from Grenada, y'know.
Grenada. (laughs heartily)
(laughs) l like this guy.
l like you, country. (laughs) Grenada!
Yeah, but man, where did you get them
goddamn vines you got on?
And them shoes? Oh, my.
Maybe we can do something about that.
Yeah, but he's puttin' a hurtin'
on my vision, man! Damn!
- All right, relax. Relax, nah.
- So how can l get ahold of you?
You can't. l get ahold of you.
- All right. All right, l'll write it down.
- Mm-mm.
You don't ever write anything down.
You file it, up here. Like l do.
Cos if the man don't have any paper,
he will never have any proof.
- Dig?
- Yeah. Yeah, l dig.
Right.
(chuckles)
(glasses clink)
Hey, boy, look me in the face.
Did you just now con me?
Yes, sir.
- Why?
- Because l want in.
And it don't take a lot to know
that you already there, daddy-o.
At least he ain't lyin'.
- l have a likkle run l have to make.
- Let me make the run with you, Mr Archie.
Mm-mm.
* EarIy one Monday morning
* Between nine and ten...
l like your heart.
And l like your style.
You might just do, Mr Red.
Unless, of course,
you have to get back to your train job.
l done already told that man
what he can do with that train.
- When?
- Just now.
- (both laugh)
- All right.
Come with me. l'm taking you shoppin'.
Cadillac's the name.
Sammy, man.
- You ready?
- Good.
* Erskine Hawkins: ''Don't Cry, Baby''
Button more buttons on the jacket.
You look good.
- Yes, man!
- But you're missin' something.
- Frisk me.
- What?
Go ahead. Frisk me.
Nothing, right?
l'm still carrying.
This was my first gun.
Now it's yours.
* Dry your eyes
* And Iet's be sweethearts again...
- Thank you.
- You wear it, wear it so.
Right.
Small of the back.
Now you're outfitted.
You ready to tackle the streets?
Yeah, l'm ready. Let 'em come.
Let us now turn to the Gospel...
..according to St John.
- (bIast ofjazz)
- Chapter 3, verse 23.
And John also was baptising
at Aenon, near Salim...
- (congregation) Amen. Amen.
- ..because there was much water...
- Praise the Lord. Praise the Lord.
- ..and they came and were baptised.
Yes!
Three, one, three.
- Two, fifty-five!
- Got to be two, five, one.
Four, o, three!
l saw it in my dream.
Five, five, five.
- What you know, daddy-o?
- l feel straight!
- Mm! Your lucky day.
- Let it roll for me, man.
l told you, no paper, no trouble.
l'm workin' on it.
l keep all my numbers in my head, y'know.
l have never written a number down yet.
Remember dat.
- (radio) * BiIIie HoIiday: ''Big Stuff'
- (sniffs)
- * So you cry ''What's it about, baby?''
- Your turn.
* You ask why...
Easy.
- (snorts and chokes)
- Easy!
- You there?
- lf l ain't, l'm right next door.
Nothin' in this world
can give you that real deep cool.
Right, girl?
* Don'tyou know there's honey
* In store foryou
(both laugh)
* Big stuff
* Let's take a ride
- Phew! Oh.
- * On my gravy train
'Bout as mellow as l can be!
- * Come in from out ofthe rain
- Whew!
- Cool enough to kill.
- Yeah, l realise that.
- Ah, easy, easy, easy, easy.
- Stick 'em up.
- Boom!
- (mimics gunshot)
Hey, Archie. Pow!
- Oh!
Baby.
- Boom!
- (squeals) Oh!
Malcolm, you're so funny!
Gimme some money, baby.
(clears throat) OK.
Come on, baby!
Bitch move too slow! Ain't that right?
(men laugh)
Sometimes this guy
has a big, ugly mouth.
What time is it, baby?
- 8.21 .
l like that. Combinate me.
- Eight, twenty-one. One, twenty-eight.
- Careful, Red.
Two, eighteen!
- l'm taking the bet, y'know.
- (laughs) Bet!
- (Archie laughs)
- Gonna have to reload.
- * I'm on the square aboutyou
* Let's have a try
- * It may be that I'm the guy... *
- Yes, sir. (sniffs)
(gunshot)
* (souIfuIjazz sax)
- Say, Red!
- Hey, Red!
- (woman) Sweet Red.
- Have a drink, man.
(chatter)
* Count Basie: ''The Jitters''
(giggling)
l thought you said
we was goin' to the movies last night.
- l said that?
- You said that, Red.
All right, baby, l'm sorry.
You know l say a lot of things.
l believed you, Red.
All right. Go on, do your job now. Get me
a pack of Lucky Strikes and a cognac.
- Girl, you a mess!
- l'm a mess?
- Daniel come in yet, Honey?
- Ain't that him now?
Hey, gorgeous! How you been doin'?
You been waiting long?
Lemme look at you! Wow!
- l've been missin' you today, Laura.
- How are you doing, baby?
(shakily) l'm all right. Copacetic, great.
Did you work today?
Baby, you know what time we wound up
last night. l didn't go to work.
- l... l need a five-spot.
- l just gave you ten this morning.
- Laura, gimme the goddamn five dollars!
- Look, it ain't the money, Daniel.
- l just wanna make sure you're OK.
- Gimme the scratch. l... l...
l gotta pay back this guy. l'll be right back.
- Like last time(?)
- l swear l'll be right back.
Laura, l love you!
You know that chick?
What are you,
a private detective now or somethin'?
l just asked a question!
Well, you don't be askin' me
no goddamn questions.
- l ask you the questions. Understand?
- Mm-hm.
- She come in here a lot?
- Just about every other night.
- With him?
- Mm-hm.
- She know he's strung out?
- lf she got eyes, she do.
She ain't hookin', is she?
Not yet, Red,
but the way things are goin',...
..he gonna turn her out any day now.
You stuck on her, huh?
Y'see, that's your problem, girl,...
..you need to mind your own
goddamn business, or l'm gonna...
Don't do that!
l wanna talk to you, all right?
- Have a seat, all right?
- All right.
C'mere.
- You don't pay him any mind, you hear?
- All right.
- You all right?
- l'm all right.
Why don't you buy yourself
something nice?
(Sophia) Hey, baby.
Gimme a light.
You know, you're lookin' real uptight
these days. What is the problem?
- No problem.
- You sure?
Nothing. Everything's all right.
l'm not worried about it.
All right.
Shit, l'm thinking about my money.
Six big ones you owe me, Archie.
- What?
- Eight, two, one. lt hit, didn't it?
You didn't have eight, two, one!
Were you high, old man? l threw the slats
at you and told you to combinate me.
- Red, l'm tellin' you, you never had it.
- l'm tellin' you l did. Sophia was there.
- Archie, you remember, don't you?
- So, wait. What d'you expect her to say?
- (scoffs) Oh.
- Don't do this.
- All right?
- All right, Archie.
All right, skip it.
Skip it. But you're slippin', Archie.
You done slipped.
Archie, wait. Wait.
Come on, Archie, there. Look, it's...
Come on, what you want? You want
a drink? What you tastin'? l'm buyin'.
- l ain't drinkin' hot piss with you.
- Oh, Archie.
All right?
Come, Sam.
l'll be right there, man.
- l never knowed him to forget a number.
- First time for everything, Sammy.
What are you talkin' about, Red?
The first thing he's gonna do is
check for an oversight on his ribbon.
His rep is on the line. So is yours.
And Red, if you're lyin',
you're a dead man.
Dead, dead,...
- ..dead.
- (blows smoke)
You go run tell him that.
My man Red! Night to you.
l don't understand Archie.
You had the number.
* Away from the city
* That hurts and mocks
* l'm standin' alone
* By the desolate docks
* ln the still
* And the chill
* Of the night
* l see the horizon
* The great unknown...
Didn't l tell you
''Never sit with your back to no door''?
Y'know what?
You're a damn liar. And so is she.
So you figure to take me, you bastard?
Well, l'm taking you.
- So it's you and me, huh, Pops?
- That's right, my friend.
l'll give you back the 600.
- l don't want your money.
- You know l'm wearing, Archie.
There's three guns on you,
so you take your chances, my friend.
* Will the one l love
* Be comin' back
* To me?
Let's walk.
(chuckles)
So this is how l'm goin' out, huh, Archie?
- ln a toe-down?
- Toe-down, yes.
- Let's go.
- Why don't we let Billie finish first?
No.
- Red.
- * For the one l love
* Must soon come back
* To me...
You can't get away from me, Red!
- C'mere, man! C'mere!
- Get him!
* For the one I Iove
Red!
You better run!
You oughta run fast hard!
* To me *
(pants)
(appIause, whistIing)
Thank you.
Thank you very much. Thank you.
(crickets chirp)
(whispers) Wake up. Wake up!
- (grunts)
- There's somebody out there.
Wake the kids.
- (glass shatters, children scream)
- Careful! Careful! Children!
- (screaming)
- Malcolm!
- Everybody out!
- Follow me! Follow me! Wait, wait!
Go! Go on! Go! Go!
Go! Go! Go! Get out!
Get 'em out! Careful!
C'mere! C'mere! C'mon!
Boy, good thing we're good Christians!
Maybe it's time you left this town!
l thought this was a free country!
We warned you about all that garbage
preachin', stirrin' up the good nigras!
- l ain't a boy, l'm a man!
- Next time you a dead nigger!
A real man don't hide
behind no bedsheets!
You take these here bullets
for them sheets!
(gunshots, shouting)
- l know you're a better shot than that.
- (children whimper)
You should've killed 'em. You should've
shot all them crackers dead.
l just wanted to scare 'em. They won't be
around here botherin' us no more.
They won't be here no time soon.
l'm a man!
(rumbling)
That'll teach you, nigger!
(cries out)
- (shrieks) Oh, God!
- Get a doctor!
He doesn't need a doctor,
he needs a preacher.
Red, l'm glad we got you outta there.
With West lndian Archie on your ass,
your name on the wire,...
..Boston's the best place for you.
Yeah. Well, we'll take it easy, huh, baby?
Shorty, l got a place fixed up for us
on Harvard Square. How's that sound?
- Sounds good. We'll lay low for a while.
- Yeah.
Don't you worry about a thing.
l'll stake you, baby.
l got my band, l'm blowin' great sax.
Hell, Red, you ain't even heard us play yet!
Like every hustIer, I was trapped.
Cats that hung together to find a IittIe
security, find an answer, found nothing.
Cats that might have probed space,
or cured cancer...
I mean, West Indian Archie
might have been a mathematicaI genius.
We were aII victims
ofthe American sociaI order.
UntiI that time, there were three things
that I was aIways afraid of:
..ajob, a bust, andjaiI.
But I reaIised then that I wasn't afraid
ofanything. I was an animaI.
He don't look too good.
All right, we gonna rob this town blind.
Anybody want out, say so now.
Good. Good. OK, l set up a stake and
l got somebody to move the goods for us.
All we need now is a driver.
Any suggestions?
- How 'bout Rudy?
- Yeah, Rudy.
Who's Rudy?
l'm half-wop, l'm half-nigger,
l'm not afraid of nobody.
- That right? So what do you do?
- Name it, fella, l claim it.
Rudy does catering.
Rich joints on Beacon Hill.
- ls that right?
- Tell him about Baldy.
- Baldy? (laughs)
- Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, he's this old rich ofay motherfucker.
l give him a bath every Friday night.
Towel him off, talcum powder on him,
put him to bed.
- (laughter)
- Just like a baby. He gets his jollies off.
Yeah? And? So, what about him?
Guy's got jewellery,
he's got a coin collection, he's got china,...
- ..he's got rugs...
- Ah. That might be all right.
Shit, l know this town, man.
l got my own fences!
(chuckles) Who is this guy? Huh?
Who put you in charge?
- You wanna be in charge, Rudy?
- l am in charge!
- You the head nigger in charge, huh?
- Yeah! l'm the head nigger in charge.
- Big-head nigger, that's what you are.
- (snorts)
l tell you what we do, Rudy.
Cos l'm a fair man.
And l like big-head niggers like you.
We'll flip for it.
We'll flip this.
(bullets clatter on table)
C'mon, Red...
She loves me.
She loves me not.
l'll flip first, Rudy.
- Red, cool it. Come on, baby.
- Head man in charge, right?
Put the gun down.
- (click)
- All right, we believe you.
We believe you.
Red, stop clowning around, all right?
For Chrissakes!
- lt's your turn, Rudy.
- Quit fooling around. Come on, guys.
You don't wanna flip?
Let me show you how. l'll do it again.
- Christ, Red, don't!
- He doesn't know how. Gotta do it again.
- Red...
- Red, stop it!
Maybe you miss somethin'? You got
your eyes open? Look at me, Rudy.
- You don't have to do this, Red.
- Red!
- (click, Sophia gasps)
- (Shorty) That was really dumb.
- Your flip, baby. You wanna do it?
- That is so dumb, Red.
Nah, you don't, do you? l'll help you.
- Here.
- Red, don't!
Maybe we shoot
that little wop nose of yours off.
Or is that the nigger side?
ls that the wop side or the nigger side?
ls that wop or nigger?
- Ah, l guess that's the wop side.
- (Shorty) l'm not goin' to jail!
- How you doin', Rudy? One...
- Put the gun away! C'mon, this is enough.
- Two... Say goodbye, Rudy.
- (grunts)
- Huh?
- (choked sob)
(whispers) l think l heard Rudy say
something. What'd you say, Rudy?
Speak up. That way it's true.
- (click, woman yelps)
- Jesus Christ! When are you gonna stop?
- l did two so l owe you two, right?
- (quietly) You got it.
- l got it? What'd you say?
- (very quietly) You got it.
(whispers) Rudy says l got it.
Rudy, don't you ever...
..try and cross someone
who ain't afraid to die. You hear me?
Now, all right.
Now this what we gonna do.
We gonna hit ol' Talcum Powder tonight.
My friend Rudy here's
gonna draw up the plans,...
..everything that's in the house, right?
Peg, Sophia, you go out
and get those tools like l asked you.
We gonna hit tonight
on account of some of us...
- ..havin' high visibility during the daytime.
- (Sophia laughs)
lt's OK with you, right, Rudy?
Merry Christmas, Rudy.
One big, happy family.
(whispers) l love you.
Psst! Red!
What happened to the bullet?
Did you palm that bullet?
What bullet?
The bullet!
- (chuckles)
- You're crazy.
(whispers) Shorty!
- (clattering)
- Shh!
(whispers) Easy, Shorty. Easy.
- (thump)
- (whispers) Shorty!
- (rattling)
- Shh...
(snoring)
- My man, Red.
- Hm?
- My man.
- Huh.
Hey, when's Rudy due back?
* Louis Jordan:
Beans and Cornbread had a fight
Yeah, almost finished.
* Cornbread said ''Now, that's aII right
Meet me on the corner tomorrow night''
* I'II be ready...
Shit, them girls oughta be gettin' back
from casin' that rug joint.
They should be.
(laughs) Doin' a good job with you, man.
- Yeah. We killin' them, baby.
- We're killin' them.
- They don't know what's hittin' them.
- (chuckles) Yeah.
Lemme get...
Little work back in this kitchen.
- You gettin' the kitchen, huh?
- Yeah, that's where the naps are.
Yeah, well, if you can't take the heat,
get on out the kitchen.
- Let me get these naps.
- (grunts)
- All right, let's go to the sink.
- Good.
* That's what Beans toId Cornbread
Come on, Shorty, man,
it's startin' to heat up a little bit.
- lt's burnin'?
- Yeah. lt's all right.
All right.
Put your head down.
- * Beans and Cornbread had a fight
- C'mon, man.
- * Beans grabbed Cornbread by the toe
- Huh?
* Beans said ''Cornbread, Iet me go''
* Cornbread said ''I'II Iay you Iow
I'm gonna fightyou, you so-and-so''
- * Meet me on the corner
- Shit is startin' to sting! Get out the way.
* ..on the corner tomorrow night!
That's what Beans said to Cornbread!
- Burnin'?
- Hell, yeah, it's burnin'!
* I'm gonna beat the deviI outta you!
Whoo-oo, oo-oo-oo-oo!
Goddamn it!
(moans) Oh!
Oh! Ah! Ah!
Oh!
Hey, nigger!
Take your head outta the shit bowl!
That's it! Get up slowly!
Hey! Watch it! No funny business, now!
Red, the jig is up.
The average first offender
gets two years forburgIary.
We were aII first offenders,
so that's what Sophia and Peg drew.
Two years in the women's reformatory
at Framingham.
But our crime wasn't burgIary.
It was sIeeping with white girIs.
They threw the book at us.
Burglary, count one: eight to ten years.
Count two: eight to ten years.
- Count three: eight to ten years.
- (laughs)
- Count four: eight to ten years.
- (chuckles)
Count five: eight to ten years.
Count six: eight to ten years.
Count seven: eight to ten years.
Count eight: eight to ten years.
Count nine: eight to ten years.
Count ten: eight to ten years.
Count eleven: eight to ten years.
Count twelve: eight to ten years.
Count thirteen: eight to ten years,
and count fourteen...
- Fourteen counts ofeight to ten years.
- All the sentences to run concurrently.
(chuckIes) Shorty thought he had hit us
with over 100 years,...
..untiI I expIained
what ''concurrentIy'' meant.
It meant a minimum sentence
often years'hard Iabour...
..at the CharIestown State Prison.
- The date was February 1946.
- (mouths)
- (metal door slams)
- Gaines!
- J638-248!
- Cell block A secure!
- Who are you?
- A295-983!
- Lock one!
- Comin' down!
One secure!
- Persky!
- A297-945!
- Lock two!
- Comin' down!
Two secure!
- Burnam!
- A751 -61 3!
(guards joke)
- Lock three!
- Comin' down!
- Yo, Jackson!
- A231 -549!
- Yeah, close four!
- Comin' down!
Four secure!
- Crichlow!
- A599-1 301 !
- Close five!
- Comin' down!
- Look at Satan.
- l see him.
He 'bout to bust.
He not gonna bust.
He wouldn't give 'em the pleasure.
- (door slams)
- Little!
- State your number.
- What?
- Give him a break, Barnes!
- He's a new fish.
- OK, l'll give him a break.
- Now state your number, Little.
- l forgot it.
- State it.
- l forgot it!
Can't you read it right there, boy?
There! Can't you read, boy?
Fuck you!
- l'll teach you a lesson, goddammit!
- How you gonna get away from this?
Move it up! Move it up!
l forgot it! l forgot it!
- l forgot it! (howls)
- Get him in here and shut it!
(whispers)
They ain't gonna break me down.
Well, that's just the kind of nigger l am.
They' ain't gonna break me down.
Now l'm situatin'...
l'm in this situation and l'm gettin' out.
(laughs) Anything come round,
well, l'm strong.
- l'm strong...
- Time's up, Little!
Now state your number!
(water drips)
Suit yourself. Ten more days.
(footsteps)
Water!
(clatter)
(footsteps, knock at door)
You want a smoke?
You know what a friend
you have in Jesus, son.
(laughs) A friend?
(voice cracks) Uh?
He's a friend, huh, Chappy? Well,
if he's such a friend, where is he, huh?
What he done for me?
A friend we have in Je...
Yeah, l tell you what you do, Chap.
You tell him to call me!
Call me and tell me
what kind of friend he is, huh?
Solitary Two, 2607!
(roars)
What he done for me, Chappy, huh?
Where is he every time l need him, huh?
You tell me that!
Where is this Jesus?
l'll tell you where he is!
He's out with the police, Chaplain!
Yeah, l'll straighten him out!
What has he done for me?
He ain't done nothin' for me!
Ain't done nothin' for me. (exhales)
(mutters) ''What a friend we have
in Jesus(!)'' Jesus can kiss my ass!
Tell Jesus to kiss my ass!
How 'bout that? Tell him that!
(hoarse sob)
(cries softly)
(sobs)
(growls)
(whimpers and growls)
(hoarse) Haah! Haaah! Aaah!
Aaaaah!
Aaaaaaah!
(howls)
Little!
State your number, Little!
C'mon, state it!
- (whispers) A22...
- What?
A228.
Come on! (grunts)
(door slams)
l know how you feel.
Like you wanna lay down and die.
l brought you something.
(hoarse) Yeah, well,
l don't need any more favours from you.
lt's nutmeg. Put it in the water.
You need something
to get the monkey off your back.
lt's not cocaine, but it'll help some.
Drink it slow. This stuff is strong.
(coughs)
(coughs) So what's your hype, huh?
l can show you how to get out of prison.
And it's no hype.
Yeah, well, talk, daddy-o. l'm listenin'.
- Hey, this ain't bad. You got some more?
- That's the last fix l'm givin' you.
- So what you give it to me for, then, huh?
- Because you needed it.
Because you couldn't hear me without it.
(snorts) Nigger, get on outta my face.
l think you got more sense
than any cat in this prison.
But why the hell don't you use it?
You can't bust out of here,...
..like they do in the movies.
- Even if you get out, you're still in prison.
- Well, you ain't lyin' there.
You go bustin' your fist against
a stone wall, you're not usin' your brain!
That's what the white man
wants you to do!
Look at you!
Puttin' all that poison in your hair.
l think you've been in prison too long,
my man,...
..because everybody
on the outside conks.
Why? Why does everybody
on the outside conk?
Cos they don't want a nappy head,
like...
Like what? Like me? Like a nigger?
Why don't you wanna look like
what you are?
What makes you ashamed
of bein' black?
Lemme tell you somethin',
l'm not ashamed of bein' anything.
You better get your hands off me.
l got to wash this out.
- Let it burn!
- Nigger, get your hands off of me!
Go on. Burn yourself. Pain yourself!
Puttin' that poison in your hair,
in your body, tryin' to be white!
(laughs) l don't wanna hear all this shit.
l thought you was smart.
But you just another of those cats struttin'
down the avenue in your clown suit...
...with all that mess on you,
lookin' like a monkey!
The white man sees you and laughs,
because he knows you ain't white!
- Man, who are you?
- No. The question is, who are you?
Well, l'll tell you.
You are lost in the darkness.
But Elijah Muhammad has come
to bring you into the light.
- Who?
- Elijah Muhammad...
..can get you out of prison.
Out of the prison of your mind.
But maybe all you want is another fix.
(prisoners talk quietly)
And then you get used to this life,
and it puts you to sleep.
- That's right.
- You stop thinking, acting for yourself.
You couldn't scrounge
three squares a day on the outside.
So you let them feed you.
Give you dominoes to play with.
- Let you shoot marbles, play baseball.
- Let's go! Cut the sermon!
He blows his whistle, and you sit!
You stand, you grab, gobble...
File out! Sleep!
- Sing out your number, loud as you can!
- l told you to knock it off, Baines.
Now, are you gonna take yard?
l'm stayin'.
Uh, yeah, me, too.
What're you sniffin' around for?
l told you l gave you your last fix.
What's your angle, nigger? Hm?
Nigger? Who's wearing the conk(?)
You the only cat in this prison l done seen
that act the way you do.
You ain't even afraid of talking like that
in front of them guards or nothin'.
- What more can he do to me?
- Hm.
l mean, you don't cuss none.
You don't talk that
''Whatcha know, daddy'' jive.
A man curses because he doesn't have
the words to say what's on his mind.
(chuckles)
Yeah.
Yeah, l know you got an angle,
some kinda way.
Don't con me.
Don't con me, and don't try.
Hey.
Just offerin' you a cigarette, my man.
Ain't no big deal.
l read, study.
The first thing a black man must have
is respect for himself.
Respect his body and his mind. Quit takin'
the white man's poisons into his body.
His cigarettes, his dope, his liquor.
His white woman. His pork.
Pork?
Hm.
Yeah, my mama used to say that,
''Don't eat no pork.''
Well, your mama was right.
Cos that pig is a filthy beast.
Part rat, part cat. And the rest is dog.
All right, pull my coat on this now.
What happen if you give all that up?
l mean, the pork and... You get sick
and then you get a medical or somethin'?
Like when l was on the outside,
l ran this hustle.
- l tried to act like...
- l'm tellin' you God's words, not no hustle.
And l'm gonna tell you, God is black.
God is black?
Everybody knows God is white.
Everything the white man taught you,
you accepted.
He taught you you were a black heathen,
you believed him.
He taught you to worship a blond,
blue-eyed Jesus with white skin,...
..and you believed him.
He taught you that black was a curse,
and you believe that.
- Did you look up ''black'' in a dictionary?
- For what?
Did you ever study anything
that wasn't part of some con?
What the hell for, man?
(sighs) Come with me.
''Black.''
''Destitute of light. Devoid of colour.''
''Enveloped in darkness;
hence, utterly dismal or gloomy;...
..as, the future looked bIack.''
Pretty good with them words, ain't you?
''Soiled with dirt, foul.''
''Sullen, hostile.''
''Forbidding; as, a black day.''
''Foully or outrageously wicked;...
..as, black cruelty.''
''lndicating disgrace,
dishonour, or culpability.''
And there's others.
Blackmail, blackball, blackguard.
- Hmm, well, that's somethin', all right.
- Let's look up ''white''.
Here.
Read.
''White: of the colour of pure snow;...
..reflecting all the rays of the spectrum.''
''The opposite of bIack.''
Um... ''Free from spot or blemish.''
''lnnocent. Pure.''
Huh!
lsn't this somethin'? ''Without evil intent.''
''Harmless. Honest.''
''Square-dealing and honourable.''
Wait a minute. But this...
This was written by white folks,
though, right? This is a white folks' book.
- This sure ain't no black man's book.
- So what we readin' this one for?
Because the truth is lying there
if you read behind the words.
You got to take everything the white man
says and use it against him.
Yeah?
All right, but l mean,
there's a whole lotta words in here.
- l mean...
- Here. We'll start at the beginning.
We'll look 'em up, write 'em down
and find out what they mean.
Here. Page one. The first word: aardvark.
''Aardvark: earth pig.''
''African ant-eating mammal.''
''Abacus: a Chinese...
..calculating instrument.''
''Abaddon:
the place of the lost in... Sh...eol,...
..the bottomless pit.''
lf you take one step toward Allah,
He will take two steps toward you.
(footsteps, coughing)
- Lights out!
- (bell rings)
Why you readin' them books?
You gonna be here longer than me.
Lights out!
(prisoner) Might as well put the book
down, seein' the light's out.
He gonna go blind.
(shouting)
(shouting, applause)
- (team) Oh, yeah!
- C'mon, Pete!
(chuckles)
Boy'll wear out a baseball, won't he?
- Hey, Chuck! What's the score, my man?
- Ten to one! We're murderin' them!
Didn't you hear?
No, what happened?
The Brooklyn Dodgers
brought up Jackie Robinson.
We're poundin' the hell out of 'em,
celebratin'!
Yeah, that's all right!
Sure. White man throw us a bone,...
..and we are supposed to forget
Yeah, but a nigger... a Negro playin' in
the big leagues, that's somethin', ain't it?
l told you to go behind the words
and dig out the truth.
They let us sing and dance and smile.
And then they let
one so-called Negro into the majors.
That doesn't cancel out
the greatest crime in history.
When that crafty blue-eyed devil
locked us in chains, 1 00 million of us,...
..broke up our families, tortured us,...
..cut us off from our language,
our religion, our history.
Let me tell you about black history.
We are the original man.
The first men on earth were black.
They ruled,...
..and there wasn't a white face anywhere.
But they teach us that we lived in caves
and swung from trees.
That's a lie. Black men never did that.
We were a race of kings...
..when the white man crawled around
on all fours over the hills of Europe.
Do they know who they are?
Do you know where you came from?
What's your name?
Malcolm Little.
No. That's the name of the slave masters
who owned your family.
You don't even know who you are.
You're nothing. Less than nothing.
Who are you?
Look, l ain't... Shit.
All right, l ain't Malcolm Little, l ain't Red...
- ..l damn sure ain't Satan.
- That's right. So who are you?
- l don't know.
- We are a nation.
The tribe of Shabazz,...
..lost in this wilderness
called North America.
Tribe of Shabazz.
The merciful Allah
has sent us a messenger,...
..a black man named Elijah Muhammad.
He reveals to us
the true knowledge about ourselves.
He teaches us that the true nature
of the original man, the black man,...
..is righteousness.
So if the nature of the black man
is righteousness, Malcolm...
Then the true nature of the white man
is wickedness.
l knew you'd get it.
The Honourable Elijah Muhammad
teaches us that the white man is a devil.
Hm. l sure met some in my life.
No. Elijah Muhammad does not say
that some white men are devils.
He teaches us
that aIIwhite men are devils.
Look, have you ever known
a good white man?
l mean, think back in all your life.
Have you ever met one who wasn't evil?
(Baines) The body is a sacred tempIe.
It must be purified.
l will not touch the white man's poison,...
..his drugs, his liquor,...
..his swine, his... women.
A Muslim must be strikingly upright,
an outstanding example,...
..so that those in the darkness
can see the power of the light.
l will not commit adultery or fornication.
l will not lie, cheat or steal.
But the key to lslam is submission.
That is why, five times daily,
we turn to Mecca to pray,...
..to bend our knees in submission.
l can't do that, Brother Baines.
For lost-founds to bend their knees,
to admit their guilt,...
..to implore Allah's forgiveness,...
..is the hardest thing on earth.
The hardest, and the greatest.
l don't know what l would say to Allah.
Have you ever bent your knees, Malcolm?
Yes, when l was, uh,...
..when l was picking a lock
to rob someone's house.
Tell Allah that.
You can grovel and crawl for sin,
but not to save your soul?
Pick the lock, Malcolm. Pick it.
Brother, l want to.
God knows, l want to.
I received a Ietter that day
from The HonourabIe EIijah Muhammad.
The dearHoIy ApostIe wrote to me,
a nobody, ajunkie, a pimp and a convict.
(EIijah Muhammad)
I have come to give you...
..something which can neverbe
taken away from you.
I bring to you a sense ofyour own worth.
The word of one human being.
The knowledge of self.
It was Iike a bIinding Iight, and I became
aware that he was in the room with me.
He wore a dark suit, and on his face...
..I saw a wisdom andpain so oId and deep
that I couId scarceIy Iook at him.
But I knew I wasn't dreaming.
He was right there with me.
l tell you,...
..the most dangerous creation
in the world,...
..in any society,...
..is the man with nothing to lose.
You do not need ten such men
to change the world.
One will do.
The earth belongs to us.
The black man.
And whatever is around it,
or on it, or in it...
..belongs to us.
And then, as suddenIy as he came,
he was gone.
And then I couId do it.
We are taught that PauI, on the road
to Damascus, heard the voice ofChrist.
He was so smitten by the truth
that he feII from his horse.
Now, I don't Iiken myseIfto PauI,
but I do understand.
- You see, it happened to me.
- Aameen.
(Baines) DearBrotherMaIcoIm,...
..I am back in the bosom ofIsIam.
Praise AIIah.
We don't have much,
but what we have is yours.
My wife Lorraine and my son Sidneyjoin
me in saying that when you come out,...
..which wiII not be too Iong,
come straight to us.
Next!
What'll it be, Little?
Take it all off.
- Oh, gettin' rid of that conk, huh?
- Yes, sir.
You write thanking me.
(chuckIes) Don't thank me.
Thank AIIah. He did it aII.
(MaIcoIm) DearBrotherBaines,...
..pIease thank The HonourabIe
EIijah Muhammad for the money,...
..and teII him I have not written him
because I have notyetproven myseIf.
- What is this?
- But I have shared his teachings...
..with some ofmy oId running buddies
back in HarIem...
..and with my main man Shorty,
who was transferred upstate.
He's gone nuts.
''Dear brothers, l thank you
for your endeared time and concern.''
''All praise is due to Allah
for The Honourable Elijah Muhammad.''
''l wrote the Mayor, the Governor
and the President,...
..but for some reason,
l haven't heard from them.''
Hm.
(MaIcoIm) PIease teII The HonourabIe
EIijah Muhammad...
..that I have dedicated my Iife to teIIing
the white deviI the truth to his face.
I greetyou with the ancient words
ofpeace: As saIaam aIaikum.
Wa-alaikum salaam.
Oh. PS: I've finaIIy copied out
the entire dictionary.
l think the brother is coming along.
(metal door slams)
''And the thief
cometh not but for to steal,...
..and to kill...
..and to destroy.''
''But l am come,
that they might have life,...
..and that they might have it
more abundantly.''
St John 1 0. Verse 1 0.
Are there any questions?
Hey, watch it, baby.
This cat is heavy on religion.
l can see this has become a struggle
between good and evil.
Satan has a question.
(laughs) Yes, sir, Chaplain Gill.
But since neither one of us are God,...
..neither one of us is in any position
to say who's good and who's evil.
Just ask your question.
We were discussing the disciples.
What colour were they?
Well, l don't think...
..we know that for certain.
- But they were Hebrews.
- That's right.
As was Jesus. Jesus was also a Hebrew.
- Just ask your question.
- What colour were the original Hebrews?
l have told you
that we don't know that for certain.
Then you can't believe for certain
that Jesus was white.
Just, er, just a moment. Just a moment.
God is white. lsn't it obvious?
That is obvious,
but it's not obvious that God is white.
The Honourable Elijah Muhammad
teaches us...
..that Jesus did not have
blond hair and blue eyes.
The Honourable Elijah Muhammad
teaches us that the images of Jesus...
...that are on prison walls and churches
throughout the world...
..are not historically correct,
because history teaches us...
..that Jesus was born in a region
where the people had colour.
There is proof in the very Bible
that you ask us to read,...
..in Revelations, first chapter,
verse 14 and 1 5,...
..that Jesus had hair like wool
and feet the colour of brass.
- Now, just... just what are you saying?
- l'm not saying anything.
l'm proving to you that Jesus was not,...
..and l might quote one of our lndian
brothers, he was not a paleface.
(prisoners whisper and chuckle)
- A-ha.
- Amen.
(Chaplain) lsn't that interesting?
(bell rings)
Brother Malcolm!
He's waiting for you.
My son.
You have been a thief,...
..a drug dealer, and a... and a hustler,...
..and the world is still full of temptation.
When God spoke to the devil
about how faithful Job was,...
..the devil argued that it was only
God's protective hedge around him...
..that kept him pure.
Fact about it, the devil said
''Remove that hedge,...
..and he will curse his Maker.''
Well, Malcolm,...
..your hedge has been removed.
..and l believe...
..you will remain faithful.
Yes, sir.
Thank you, sister. Brother Sidney, now
how many of these should we turn out?
- 500.
- Make it 1 ,000.
Yes, sir.
Brother Malcolm, this is Brother Earl.
He just accepted the teachings.
- As salaam alaikum, brother.
- Wa-alaikum salaam.
Brother Earl is dedicated.
We need good men like him.
l'm a willing servant
for The Honourable Elijah Muhammad.
OK, brothers, let's keep it busy.
Take a real good look at where you live!
Not just where you live,...
..but take a good look
at where everybody you know lives!
Cos l don't want you to think
you just a bad luck accident!
Then l want you go downtown,
over to Central Park West,...
..and take a good look at how he lives!
(fades off)
Look at how you live and how he lives!
You've never seen
a Booker T Washington linguini store!
You never went to a Jewish community...
..and seen no Frederick Douglass
delicatessen!
Why is everybody making money but us?
(other speaker) Dick, Jane and Spot(!)
The only thing that's black in the book
is the spot on the back of the dog's back!
lt's time for us to use our dollars...
We can do what everyone else can do!
lf we become producers, and if we
become the masters of our own destiny,...
..we can have wool from sheep
just like anyone else!
But where are our clothing stores?
We can get milk from cows like anyone
else! But where are our grocery stores?
We need to control our dollars!
We need to control our destiny!
The only thing they respect is our dollars!
The only thing they respect
is the wealth that we give them!
Where's that freedom
that you and l are supposed to have?
The Statue of Liberty's standin' like this,...
..and for you and l, it might as well be
sayin' ''Stop! Don't come no further!''
This is what it be sayin'!
''Don't come no further!''
That's right!
So what l want you to do, brothers and
sisters, is come on down to the temple.
Oh! l'm so surprised! l'm so surprised!
Y'all been in church two hours and
you're expectin' to see heaven out here,...
..and there ain't no heaven!
You're still right here on earth!
Sister, why don't you come on down
to the temple at two o'clock?
Hear the truth! Hear the black man's truth!
No, you can't deny it! You've been on your
knees the last two hours, haven't you,...
..beggin' some God
to help you in the hereafter.
But the hereafter's right now, brother!
The hereafter is here and now!
Let me... Let me talk to you for one
second, brother. Now, listen to me.
Now, l know you a smart man. l can tell.
You're a wise man. You look good.
Now, you're in here in this church
every day, prayin' to this God.
l'm tellin' you,
these so-called white Christians,...
..they're hangin' our black Christians
from trees, brother!
The man hates you! He says he loves you,
but he doesn't do anything for you!
He tells you to foam at the mouth,...
..to faint and sing and shout,
and hope for something in the hereafter.
We can have it right now, brother.
We can have it right now.
- Come on down. As salaam alaikum.
- Yeah. l'll see you later.
Do you know what that means, brother?
''Peace be unto you.''
My beautiful black sisters,
can l have a moment of your time?
Don't be ashamed when l call you black.
Cos you're beautiful. Black is beautiful.
You don't have to come here every day
beggin' these folks for a job!
Why, you can wash their clothes for 'em,
scrub their floors,...
..rock their little brats to sleep
for the rest of your life!
You'll still end up poor
and without anything.
And yet you're here on the auction block!
They're examining you
like a chicken, or a horse, or a slave!
You see this here? This is who you are.
Beautiful. Your beautiful black selves.
With pride, and dignity. ln fact...
Uh... l'd also expect you
to work one Saturday every month,...
..and occasionally into the evening.
l hope my...
You see, these are the questions!
The questions you and l have to ask.
How did we get this mind?
You're not an American. You're an African
who happens to be an American.
You have to understand the difference.
We didn't come over on the Nina, the
Pinta and the... and the Whatchamacallit!
We didn't land on Plymouth Rock!
Plymouth Rock landed on us!
Landed right on top of us!
Shorty?
ls that you, brother?
Praise be to Allah. That's what l'm talking
about, the slave mentality, the slave mind.
This brother and l, we had the slave mind.
We used to rob together, sleep with white
women. We even went to prison together.
Now, don't be surprised
when l say we went to prison,...
..cos some of y'all still in prison.
Prisons of your mind.
Stand up, brother. C'mon.
(chuckles) The brother's a little shy.
Come on, brother! Give me a hug.
Yeah!
That's all right, brother. That's all right.
He's still got his hair fried.
That's all right, though.
- That's the slave mind.
- (laughter)
l gotta hand it to you, Red,
best preacher hype l ever did hear.
No hype, brother. lt's the truth.
Why don't you come on back down
to the temple and hear some more?
- Man, l can't pay that shit no mind.
- Brother, you need to pay it aII your mind.
- What mind you have left.
- Take it easy, greasy. This is me. Shorty!
Let's go around the corner. (sniffs)
No, sir. Not any more.
l've been clean for eight years, brother.
- Eight years?
- Eight years.
You are somethin', homey.
My trouble is l love pig's feet
and white women too much.
- (laughs)
- l damn sure can't be no Muslim!
That's cos you're lost, brother.
That's cos you're lost.
But we can find you.
- So what d'you hear about the old gang?
- Heard about Sammy?
Dead. Knocked overin a bed with a chick
Had 25 grand in his pocket aIso.
Guess it was his lucky number(!)
What about, uh...
What was that brother's name?
CadiIIac? Gone, too?
Hooked on heroin. Been in and out
ofLexington five orsix times.
- Sophia?
- Still happily married to that rich ofay.
- She married him?
- She married him.
- Went for the money.
- The money.
Thank you, honey.
l haven't seen West lndian Archie.
Grapevine says he Iives in the Bronx,...
..ifyou want to caII that Iivin '.
- Shorty, it's been good seein'you.
- Same here, Red.
- You in?
- (slurs) Get the hell away from me.
Bitch!
- (knock at door)
- l'll pay you tomorrow!
How you doing, Archie?
My man Red.
C'mere, man.
No, don't get up. lt's all right.
(whispers) Yes.
ls...
..really you, Red?
Yes, it's me.
l came to, uh,...
..just to thank you.
Thank you for saving my life.
When l think back to when
we were on the streets of Harlem,...
- ..tryin' to gun each other down...
- l wasn't gonna shoot you, man.
lt was...
..just my rep. Y'know?
All l had was my rep.
But now,...
..you tell me this.
You didn't really have that number?
l don't know, Archie, l...
l really don't even remember.
That's not even important.
The important thing now
is to get you back on your feet.
Yeah. Y'know, l have some angles...
..ain't been figured yet.
(grunts)
Archie, here. Hang on.
- (grunts)
- lt's all right.
Help me with my arm. (exhales heavily)
- All right.
- Have to exercise my arm.
Here?
Yeah.
- That's better?
- Yeah. lt feels good.
Good.
- Yes, right here!
- Sweetness, l got somethin' for you, baby!
What happened to our women?
They couId have been doctors,
orIawyers, or teachers, ormothers?
Who's going to raise our chiIdren?
What happened to ourmen?
They couId have been mathematicians,
eIectricians orphysicians.
What happened to 'em?
What's the IittIe boy gonna do,...
..when he's Iookin' forhis father
and his father's downtown injaiI?
What's the IittIe girI gonna do
when she's Iookin' forhermother...
- ..and she's seIIing herseIfon the street?
- Laura! Laura, wait up for me!
No, I'm teIIing you that deviI
has made dead souIs out ofyou and I!
- You're dead! You're dead spirits!
- Take the money.
Put your money away.
You're dead
to the knowIedge ofyourseIf!
to the knowIedge ofyourpeopIe,...
..andyou're dead
to the knowIedge ofyourgod!
My brothers and sisters, he shouId get
down on his knees, and beg ourmercy!
Oh, my brothers and sisters,...
..his kind has committed God's greatest
crime against your and my kind,...
- ..every day of his life!
- (cheering)
He oughta get on his knees
and say he's committed a crime!
But does he do that? Does he do that? No!
No, he scorns you.
He splits your head with his night stick!
He busts you upside the head
with that billy club!
And he calls you a nigger!
l'm tellin' you, he calls you a coon!
That's what he says to you! ''Boy! Nigger!''
- 400 years is long enough.
- (approving shouts)
You've been sittin' down and layin' down
and bowin' down for 400 years.
l think it's time to stand up.
- We're with you, Brother Malcolm!
- All right! Bless you.
- Bless you.
- We're together.
- Praise him! Praise him!
- Come on up.
- Glory, my Lord! Praise him! Praise him!
- Yeah!
Praise him!
- Praise him!
- How you doin'?
Yeah. All right. Yes. Good to see you.
(excited chatter)
Yes, sir. Next Wednesday, eight o'clock.
- l'll be there!
- l'll see you there.
Brother Baines? Excuse me, sister.
You think we can, uh,
get a loudspeaker set up outside?
l'm sure we can.
Brother Malcolm, this is Sister Betty.
She lectures our Muslim women
on hygiene and diet.
She stresses care for the body
and regular eating habits.
Good. Good.
- As salaam alaikum.
- Wa-alaikum salaam, sister.
Brother Minister, your sister wonders...
..if you know what
Sister Harriet Tubman did...
..between taking souls
to the Promised Land.
Uh, l don't know. What's that, sister?
She ate.
Excuse me.
She's interesting.
So, Brother Minister, l was hoping that
you would come and speak to my class.
Yes. Yes, l'll speak to your class.
- But l'm a hard man on the women.
- Are you?
Yes, we have to be careful
when it comes to women.
Because too many of our women,
they have too much of the devil in 'em.
Bleachin' and dyein' and...
..ironin' their hair.
Runnin' around in the streets half-naked.
(snorts) Talkin' too much,
listenin' to the wrong men.
Makin' em deceitful,
untrustworthy, fresh...
And you men are to blame, too.
We don't protect, we don't value,
we don't even support them.
See, the building of a new nation...
..begins with the woman.
Because the mother
is the first teacher of the child.
The message she gives that child,...
..the child gives to the world,
so we have to be very careful.
When it comes to... to choosing a mate,...
..Samson,
the strongest man that ever lived,...
..was destroyed by the woman
that slept in his arms.
Should l tell my sisters, then, that...
..we don't believe in marriage?
No! (chuckles) We don't oppose marriage.
Cos we're not Catholic priests.
We don't believe in celibacy, no.
Mr Muhammad teaches us
that if a woman is, uh,...
..the right height for a man,
the right complexion...
lf she's half the man's age, plus seven,....
..and if she understands
that man's essential nature is strong,...
..and she's willin' to support that,...
..and if she's, uh,...
..if she can sew, and she can cook,
and, um, loves children,...
..and stays out of trouble...
l think you've made your points,
Brother Minister Malcolm.
- Good.
- You haven't any time for marriage.
- No.
- (both laugh)
So what l'll do is put the chapters down,
l'll write them down for you.
All right.
As well as the New Testament chapters
of St Matthew.
- Brother Minister.
- Yes?
l hope that doesn't mean you won't
come and visit my class, though.
Oh, no! No. l'd love to come to your class.
- (chuckles)
- l love to teach. l love sharing.
You see, this is the wonderful thing
about Mr Muhammad.
When he gives you this knowledge, when
he shares this knowledge with you,...
- ..you can't help but to run out and...
- Excuse me, um, Brother Minister,...
..would it be OK
if we just sat down for a moment?
- lt's a pretty big building, and, uh...
- Oh, yes.
- (chuckles)
- Yes, sister. l'm sorry.
- l've had you on your feet all day.
- Oh, no. No, no.
- My mistake.
- You've been on your feet for days.
And, uh,...
you didn't even finish your salad.
- So, let's talk about you for a change.
- Mm.
- How tall are you?
- Why do you ask?
- ldle question.
- Oh.
Well, if it's just an idle question,
l hope you won't force me to answer it.
(chuckles) No. l won't force you.
Well, Brother Baines says
that l'm tall enough for a tall man.
He's briefed you also, then?
(laughs) How old are you, sister?
You know, Brother Malcolm,...
..there are a few things about women
that you don't understand.
- Some of us, we're possessive, very vain.
- Are you?
And persistent,
when we've set our mind to something.
What have you set your mind to?
Being a good Muslim,...
..a good nurse,...
..and a good wife.
Brother Malcolm?
- Excuse me, Sister Betty.
- Certainly.
Brother Malcolm, Brother Johnson
was attacked by the police.
Excuse me, sister.
- There was a scuffle!
- The brother was just watchin'!
- The cop came along, he said ''Move on!''
- Didn't move quick enough for the ofay!
Crack! He was bleedin' like a stuck hog!
So what you gonna do?
He'll rap a little. He's a MusIim.
But you ain't gonna do nothin'
but make a speech.
Muslims taIk a good game,
but they never do nothin'.
Unless somebody bothers Muslims.
- Charlie, wait up.
- More troublemakers. Here they come.
(* radio pIays Perry Como:
''RoundAnd Round'')
We demand to see Brother Johnson.
Who the hell are you?
l'm the minister
for Muslim Temple Number Seven.
- Never heard of you.
- Where is he?
- Nobody here by that name.
- Wait a second. What is your name, fella?
Don't worry about what my name is.
Two witnesses saw Brother Johnson
brought in here, beat up.
- Nobody saw him brought out.
- You didn't hear the sergeant?
- Outside.
- l suggest you look outside that window.
* Cos you've found
whatyou've been dreamin' of
* In the night, you see the ovaI moon
* Going round and round in tune
- Jimmy, c'mere a second.
- Yes, we intend to see Brother Johnson.
- Who the hell are they supposed to be?
- They're brothers of Brother Johnson.
Eddie, let me take a look at that blotter.
Uh...
Yeah. We got a Muslim.
Relief musta put it down.
- Must have.
- Yeah, but you can't see him.
- Because you ain't his lawyer.
- No lawyer, no see.
Well, until l am satisfied Brother Johnson
is receiving proper medical care,...
..nobody will move.
* Then yourIove,
you'II hoId herround, round, round
* In yourheart's a song
with a brand-new...
Get an ambulance.
Now!
(siren wails)
All right, break it up!
You got what you wanted.
No. l'm not satisfied.
To the hospital.
(* miIitary drumbeat)
(crowd murmurs)
- Walk on!
- (shouts and conversation)
Sidney, come on!
(crowd shouts)
Keep fightin', son!
- (siren wails)
- (shouting and chanting)
(crowd) We want justice!
We want justice! We want justice!
All right, that's enough.
l want these people moved outta here.
Fruit of lslam are disciplined men.
They haven't broken any laws. Yet.
- What about them?
- That's your headache, Captain.
- But if Brother Johnson dies, l pity you.
- We want justice!
Doctor?
He'll live.
He's getting the best care we can give.
- Thank you, Doctor.
- Certainly.
- We want justice!
- All right. OK.
Now let's disperse this mob!
We want justice! We want justice!
We want justice!
(scattered shouts)
That's too much power
for one man to have.
Brother Minister,
l'm ready to take some heads.
We gotta do somethin'
to put fear in those devils!
Look, l'm ready to do something also.
Chicago said to be patient,
that's what we're gonna do.
- l'm tired of being patient!
- Well, then you get on the phone...
(lowers voice) You get on the phone and
you call Chicago, let Mr Muhammad know.
(EIijah Muhammad) I am here
to bring a soIution to the probIems of...
..(chuckIes) the so-caIIed Negro
and his white sIave master.
You are seeking something.
- Have a seat, son.
- You are seeking...
..an answer to your400 years ofsIavery.
Y'know, the only thing l like integrated...
..is my coffee.
- (laughs)
- What can l do for you?
Well, Mr X, uh...
..my name is Benjamin.
And l was out there tonight.
Take it easy, now.
And... and l saw what it is that you did.
l mean, the way you talked
to them policemen and all.
Well, Mr X,...
..l wanna be a Muslim.
l mean, l ain't never seen a nigger,
uh, l mean, coloured person...
..Negro...
..talk to no police like that before.
You want to be a Muslim,
join the Nation of lslam.
- Yes, sir.
- You know what it means to be a Muslim?
Do you?
Um... (clears throat) No, not exactly.
But l wanna be one.
l mean, just like you.
You should never join any organisation
unless you know exactly what it's about.
The Church has faiIedyou!
Thank you, brother.
You shouldn't give up so easily, either.
We can use more young warriors
like yourself.
Come on by the temple,
next Wednesday, eight o'clock sharp.
Yes. Eight o'clock sharp.
Thank you, Mr X.
And l won't make you out a liar, neither.
No, l don't think you will.
All right!
(chuckles)
Tonight,...
..l shall introduce you
as my National Minister.
lt will be a difficult task.
Your assignment...
..is to build temples all over this nation.
More work
than you've ever done in your life.
- Yes, sir.
- (chuckles)
You will be in the public eye.
Beware of them cameras.
Oh, those cameras are...
..bad as any narcotic.
White devil be watchin' your every step.
- Yes.
- And your own brothers will be...
..jealous,...
..hostile.
Go slowly.
Yes, sir.
Here is a glass.
Mm-hm.
Dirty. The water? Foul.
lf you offer this to the people,
they have no choice.
They'll drink from it, if they're thirsty.
- (chuckles)
- But if you offer them...
..this glass,...
..and let them make their own decision,...
..they will choose the pure vessel.
lslam is the only religion...
..that addresses the needs
and the problems...
..of the so-called Negro in America,...
- ..especially in the slums,...
- Right.
..ghettos.
lslam is the only way
out of drugs, and crime, and...
..unemployment, prostitution, alcohol,...
..gambling and... adultery, fornication.
This sweet, gentIe man
at whose feet I kneeIed,...
..gave me the truth from his own mouth.
Present them the pure vessel.
And I adored him in the sense of
the Latin root ofthe word ''adorare'',...
..which means to worship and to fear.
He was the first man I ever feared,...
..and I don't mean fear
such as one has ofa gun,...
..but the fear one has ofthe...
ofthe power ofthe sun.
I pIedged myseIfto him,
even ifit cost me my Iife.
(telephone rings)
HeIIo?
- Hello, Betty?
- Yes?
Yes, this is Malcolm.
- l know.
- Right. I'm here in Detroit.
- Will you marry me?
- Yes.
You heard what I said, right?
- Didyou hearmy answer?.
- Yes, l think so.
Brother Malcolm?
- (laughs)
- Are you eating?
- Yeah, l've been eating. Mm-hm.
- (Iaughs) Good.
I Iove you, Betty.
I Iove you back.
(exhales)
* EIIa FitzgeraId: ''Azure''
- lt's not gonna be easy.
- No choice.
l'll be away a lot.
l know.
- ln fact, l'm leaving in the morning.
- Oh, hush now. Shh.
Pittsburgh, Philadelphia.
Trenton, Newark,
up through Number Seven,...
- ..on the way up to Boston...
- Malcolm.
Shh.
You're with me...
..even when you're away.
* You're a bIue iIIusion
* WhiIe I'm in this
- (chuckles)
- * Azure interIude...
l've never told you this.
But the very first time l ever saw you,...
..standing up on the podium,...
..you were cleaning your glasses,...
..and l felt so sorry for you.
- Sorry for me?
- Mm-hm.
Why?
Because no-one as young as you
should be so serious.
But l don't think that any more.
What do you think?
l want to have a Iot of babies with you.
(softly) Dear heart.
- (knock at door)
- l love you.
We're waitin' on you folks.
You tryin' to starve us?
Brother Malcolm, Sister Betty,...
..we pray that Allah blesses you
with a happy and a fruitful marriage.
(laughter)
That's right!
Congratulations, Brother Minister!
- Congratulations!
- You made the front page!
Check it out! Front page!
(laughter and applause)
l must emphasise that The Honourable
Elijah Muhammad is not a politician.
So l'm not here this afternoon
as a Republican,...
- ..nor as a Democrat.
- Tell us, brother!
- Not as a Mason, nor as an Elk.
- Tell us what you here for!
- Not as a Protestant, nor a Catholic.
- That's right!
- Not as a Christian, nor a Jew.
- C'mon, man! All right, now.
- Not as a Baptist nor a Methodist. ln fact...
- Come on, brother! Come on!
- ..not even as an American.
- (approving shouts)
Because if l was an American,...
..the problem that confronts
our people today wouldn't even exist!
- That's right!
- So now we ain't Americans, huh?
So l have to stand here today
as what l was when l was born.
- A black man.
- (shouting and applause)
Before there was any such thing
as a Republican or a Democrat,...
..we were black.
Before there was any such thing
as a Mason or an Elk, we were black.
Before there was any such thing as a Jew
or a Christian, we were black people.
ln fact, before there was any such place
as America, we were black.
And after America has long passed from
the scene, there will still be black people.
(cheering)
l'm gonna tell it like it really is!
Every election year, these politicians
are sent up here to pacify us!
They're sent here and set up here
by the white man!
This is what they do! They send drugs
into Harlem down here to pacify us!
They send alcohol down here to pacify us!
They send prostitution
down here to pacify us!
You can't even get drugs in Harlem
without the white man's permission!
You can't get prostitution in Harlem
You can't get gambling in Harlem
without the white man's permission!
Every time you break the seal
on that liquor bottle,...
..that's a government seal
you're breaking!
No, l say and l say it again,...
..you've been had! You've been took!
- Right on, brother!
- You've been hoodwinked! Bamboozled!
Led astray! Run amok!
This is what he does.
Y'know,
some people call this hate teaching.
But this isn't hate teaching.
- This is love teaching.
- (approving shouts)
- l wouldn't tell you this if l didn't love you.
- No, you wouldn't!
l wouldn't stick my neck out for you
if l didn't love you.
l want you to understand one thing,
everything that l teach you,...
..everything that l've said to you,...
..has been taught to me
by this dear man, this divine man.
Yes, sir!
All praise is due to Allah
for The Honourable Elijah Muhammad!
- (Malcolm X) Oh, yes!
- (Betty) AttaIIah's fine,...
..and misses you as much as I do.
But the news thatyou've
dedicated fournew tempIes...
..is aImost as good as having you with us.
- (MaIcoIm X) And the white peopIe...
- (Betty) PIease take care ofyourseIf.
..try to hide theirguiIt by accusing
The HonourabIe EIijah Muhammad...
..ofbeing a bIack supremacist,...
..simpIy because he's trying
to upIift the mentaIity,...
..the sociaI and economic
condition ofhis peopIe.
And the Jews,...
..who have been guiIty ofexpIoiting
bIack peopIe forI don't know how Iong,...
..try to hide theirguiIt by accusing
The HonourabIe EIijah Muhammad...
..ofbeing anti-Semitic,...
..simply because he's trying
to teach you and l...
SimpIy because he's trying
to teach you and I to...
..to be in charge ofthe businesses
in our own community,...
..to own the businesses
..to have economic Ieadership
in our own community!
- No! No, this isn't bIack supremacy!
- (screaming and shouting)
- This is bIack inteIIigence!
- That's right!
- (appIause)
Come on!
l didn't do nothin'! l didn't do nothin'!
(appIause, TV announcer)
* We are not afraid... *
The bIack peopIe in this country...
Keep those peopIe back!
..have been the victims ofvioIence
at the hands ofthe American white man...
..for400 years.
And we thought, by foIIowing
those ignorant Negro preachers,...
..it was godIike to turn the other cheek
to the brute that was brutaIising us!
A hundred years ago, they used to put on
white sheets and sic bloodhounds on us.
Well, nowadays
they've traded in the sheets...
Well, some of them have.
(appIause)
- They've traded in the sheets...
- (appIause sweIIs)
PIease... pIease. They've traded in
those white sheets forpoIice uniforms.
They've traded in
the bIoodhounds forpoIice dogs.
Andjust Iike that oId UncIe Tom
back during sIavery time,...
We must remain true to non-vioIence.
I'm asking everybody in the Iine,...
..ifyou can't be non-vioIent, don't get in it.
..teaching us to love our enemy
and pray for those who use us spitefully,...
..you got these chicken-peckin' Uncle Tom
so-called Negro leaders today...
But isn't it a great day?
You've got these
UncIe Tom Negro Ieaders today,...
..that are teIIing us
we oughta pray for our enemy,...
..we oughta Iove our enemy,...
..we oughta integrate with an enemy
who bombs us, who kiIIs and shoots us,...
..who Iynches us,
who rapes our women and chiIdren. No!
- That's right! C'mon!
- No!
No! That's not inteIIigent.
That's not inteIIigent!
The Honourable Elijah Muhammad
is trying to teach you and l...
..that just as the white man, and any
other man, for that matter, on this earth,...
..has the God-given right,
the human right, the civil right,...
...the natural right and any other kind
of high rights you can think of...
..to protect himself,...
..just as this white man
has the right to defend himself,...
..we have the right
to defend ourselves, too.
This is only natural.
This is what The Honourable Elijah
Muhammad is trying to teach you and l.
He's not teaching us to hate the white
man. He's teaching us to love ourselves.
MrX, before we begin
our discussion tonight,...
..''The BIack MusIims: Hate Mongers'',...
..wouIdyou mind expIaining for us
the meaning ofyourname,...
..which is the Ietter... X?
Yes, uh, during slavery time,...
..the slave master gave the Negro,
so-called Negro,...
..uh, named the so-called Negro
after themselves.
The Honourable Elijah Muhammad
teaches us...
..that once we come into the knowledge
of lslam, the knowledge of ourselves,...
..we replace our slave name with an X,...
..X in mathematics
representing the unknown.
Since we've been
disconnected or cut off...
..from our own history, our own past,
our own culture, our own land,...
..we use the X, the unknown,
until we get back to our country.
l see. Thank you. Er, Dr Payson?
Mr X is a... He's a demagogue.
He has no place to go, so he exaggerates.
He's a disservice
to every good, law-abiding,...
..churchgoing American Negro
in the country.
- (scattered applause)
- Mr Malcolm X,...
..why do you teach black supremacy?
Why... why do you teach hate?
Well, for the white man
to ask the black man...
..why he hates him,..
..is like the wolf asking the sheep,...
..or the rapist asking the raped:
''Do you hate me?''
The white man is in no moral position
to accuse the black man of anything.
This is a bIack man asking the question.
What wouIdyou caII an educated Negro
with a BA, or an MA, or a BS or a PhD?
l'll tell you. You call him a nigger. That's
what the white man calls him, a nigger.
Now, you have to understand
this type of thinking,...
..and to understand this type of man,
you must understand that historically,...
..there were two types of slaves:
the house Negro and the field Negro.
The house Negro lived in the house,
next to his master,...
..in the big house,
either in the basement or up in the attic.
He'd dress pretty good, he ate
pretty good, what the master left him.
He Ioved his master.
l'd say he loved his master
better than the master loved himself.
lf the master said
''We got a nice house here'',...
..he'd say
''Yeah, boss, we got a nice house here.''
Master's house is on fire, the house Negro
would be running to put the blaze out.
lf the master got sick, he'd say
''What's the matter, boss? We sick?''
''We sick.'' You see,
this is the thinking of the house Negro.
Now, if another slave
came up to him and said...
..''Let's run away, let's separate,
let's get away from this cruel master,''....
..he said ''Why?
What's better than what we got here?''
''Run away? l'm not going anywhere!''
This is the house Negro.
We called 'em the house nigger.
And that's what we caII 'em today.
We stiII got a Iot ofhouse niggers.
Dear Holy Apostle,...
..the ministers think
Malcolm is getting too much press.
They think he thinks
he is the Nation of lslam.
That he has aspirations to lead the Nation.
You made Malcolm the man he is.
You lifted him out of the darkness.
You...
You go and tell the brothers
that what the Brother Minister is doing,...
..has done,...
..has been of great benefit to the Nation.
And you tell them that I say so.
The ministers think
he is of great benefit to himself.
(shouting)
- Do you have any white friends?
- One question at a time.
- Did you say white people are devils, sir?
- Yes, l've said white people are devils.
- Should all blacks be armed, sir?
- Well, one of your most famous men said:
..''Praise the Lord and pass the
ammunition.'' That's the way you think.
Malcolm, do you think your cause
will be successful?
l sincerely hope so.
- Do you advocate violence?
- No, sir.
Has there been a white man
who's helped your people in history?
that's helped my people in history?
- That's correct, sir.
- l don't understand the question.
You preach anti-white,
anti-Christian science.
- Are you saying you're anti-white?
- No, you're saying l'm anti-white.
Are all white people devils?
- Do you only educate young black men?
- Well, we gotta move out.
- We've got a plane to catch.
- (reporters shout)
Excuse me. Mr X? Um...
Hi, l... l've read some of your speeches,...
..and l honestly believe
that a lot of what you have to say is true,...
..and, and l'm a good person
in spite of what my ancestors did,...
..and l just... l wanted to ask you,...
..what can a white person like myself
who isn't prejudiced,...
..what can l do to help you
and further your cause?
Nothing.
My high schooI was a bIack ghetto
in Roxbury, right here in Boston.
I got my coIIege education on the streets
ofHarIem, in New York City.
l took my Master's degree in prison,
over the course of six and a half years.
ln fact, my old burglary hang-out
was just outside this campus.
l lived like an animal.
l stole. l used drugs.
l smoked reefers. Cocaine.
l committed adultery. Had it not been
for The Honourable Elijah Muhammad,...
..l'd have surely been
in an insane asylum, or dead.
Or possibly even
the murderer of one of you.
So what is Mr Muhammad trying to do?
He's trying to get us on God's side,...
..so that God will be on our side
and help us fight our battles.
When the Negro, the so-called Negro
in America gets on God's side,...
..and listens to the teachings
of The Honourable Elijah Muhammad,...
..he'll want to get off of drugs.
He'll want to get away from a life of crime.
He'll want to get away from
committing adultery and fornication.
Then he would want to get off the welfare.
He would want to get a job,...
..earn a living and take care of
his family, and they would respect him.
His son will say
''l'm proud that that's my father.''
His wife will say
''l'm proud that that's my husband.''
''Father'' only means
that you're taking care of your children.
That's what it is to be a father.
''Father'' doesn't mean that you're having
some babies. Anybody can have a baby.
Anybody can go out and get a woman, but
not anybody can take care of that woman.
There's another word for it.
lt's called responsibility.
lf the so-called Negro in America
was truly an American citizen,...
..we wouldn't have a racial problem.
lf the Emancipation Proclamation was
true, we wouldn't have a race problem.
lf the 1 3th, 14th and 1 5th Amendments
to the Constitution were authentic,...
..we wouldn't have a race problem.
lf the Supreme Court desegregation
decision were authentic,...
..we would not have a race problem!
But you have to see
that all of this is hypocrisy!
These Negro leaders are running around
telling the white man...
..that everything is all right,
that we got everything under control,...
..that everything The Honourable
Elijah Muhammad teaches is wrong.
But l'm telling you, Mr Muhammad said
these things were gonna come to pass,...
..and now these things
are starting to come to pass.
(loud cheering)
Now, these same Negro leaders,...
..who are running around talking about
there's about to be a racial explosion...
(chuckles)
Yes, there's gonna be a racial explosion.
And a racial explosion is more dangerous
than an atomic explosion!
(shouting and applause)
There's going to be an explosion
because black people are dissatisfied.
They're dissatisfied
not only with the white man,...
..but with these
Uncle Tom Negro leaders...
..that are trying to pose
as spokesmen for you and l!
(wild cheering)
Just like you have a powder keg,...
..when you have a powder keg
and there's too many sparks around it,...
..the thing's going to explode.
And if the thing that's going to explode
is sitting inside the house,...
..and if it explodes,
then the house is going to be destroyed.
l said, the house is going to be destroyed!
So The Honourable Elijah Muhammad
is teaching you and l,...
..and trying to teII the white man
to get this powder keg out of his house!
Let the black man
separate from his house!
Let the black man have his own house!
Let the black man have his own land,
and his own property!
(wild cheering)
The Honourable Elijah Muhammad
is trying to tell the white man...
..that this thing, this explosion,
is gonna bring down his house.
This is what he's trying to tell him,
and more importantly,...
..he's trying to tell 'em
that if he doesn't do something about it,...
- Uh-huh!
- ..if he doesn't do something about it...
..it's gonna explode any day now.
Oh, yes, it is.
l'm just here to tell you
and l'm gonna make it very short.
Preach, Brother! Preach on!
l'm here to tell you about the Honourable
Elijah Muhammad's greatest greatness.
His greatest greatness is that he has
the only solution for peace in this country.
The Honourable
Elijah Muhammad's solution...
..is the only solution for you and l.
lt's the only solution for the white man.
Complete separation...
..between the black race
and the white race.
(cheering)
lt's the only solution!
(crowd chants) All praise is due to Allah
for The Honourable Elijah Muhammad!
All praise is due to Allah
for the Honourable Elijah Muhammad!
for The Honourable Elijah Muhammad!
All praise is due to Allah
Brother Malcolm!
Yes. Yes. Hold on.
Yes, sir. lt's all right.
My brother, how you doin'?
- Can l ask you something?
- Yes, anything.
Are you Elijah's... pimp?
- (woman) He should be kiIIed...
- Wait, hold it. Hold on. Hold on.
- What are you saying, brother?
- (whispers) ''His greatest greatness.''
Just say what you're saying.
lf you don't know, man,
l feel the sorriest for you.
(chuckling) Oh, come on, brother. Wait.
Look, let me tell you something...
- No, let me tell you...
- Haul him out! Get him out of here!
Stop! You gotta get out!
Get out before it's too late!
- Don't, Malcolm! Get out!
- Disrespectin' the black man! Get him out!
- lt's all right. lt's all right!
- Get out, Malcolm!
- Sir?
- You all right, Brother Malcolm?
He's just hungry for knowledge, that's all.
Yeah, that brother's starving.
- Yes, sir.
- So am l. Let's get something to eat.
(chuckles)
- All right. We'll talk about it tomorrow.
- OK. Night-night, Daddy.
Night-night.
(groans) Oh...
Long night. (sighs)
(chuckles) Oh, yeah.
What you lookin' at?
- You.
- Why are you lookin' at me like that?
Because you're in trouble.
How do you know that?
Oh, dear heart.
Because l know you.
Well, if you know me,...
..you know that l don't like to bring
my troubles into my house.
Mm? Mm. You know that also.
- Yes, l do.
- OK.
But l'm not made of glass,
and l won't break.
Look, Betty, l just want peace.
l want to sit here with you,
l want to... be still.
l want peace in my house.
- Have we ever had a fight?
- Never.
- Argument?
- Never had one, no.
We're gonna have one,...
..right now, if you don't talk about it.
- Talk about what, Betty?
- The talk's everywhere.
There's always talk
and there's always gonna be talk.
Aren't they talkin' now
about me trying to take over the Nation?
Aren't they talkin' about how we're...
gettin' rich off the Nation of lslam(?)
We can talk about that, too.
- Well, let's talk about it.
- lt's not just talk any more.
''UPl: Elijah Muhammad,...
..67-year-old leader
of the black Muslim movement,...
..today faced paternity suits
from two former secretaries,...
- These are slanders, lies.
- ..he fathered their four children.''
Don't you realise
this is the devil's newspaper?
He's trying to divide us.
Don't you see that? Divide and conquer.
He's trying to bring down our leader.
''Both women,...
..in their twenties, charged that...
- ..they had intimacies with...
- lntimacies with Mr Muhammad.
You think l'm not aware
of these accusations, Betty?
Huh? You think l'm not aware
of these vicious lies?
Brother Baines and l
were talking about this very thing today.
Baines? ls he your friend?
- What's the matter with you.
- Nothing. What's the matter with you?
Wake up! Are you so committed
that you've blinded yourself?
You so dedicated you can't face the truth?
Baines? He's the editor of the newspaper
that you established.
Ask him why your name hasn't appeared
in Muhammad Speaks in over a year!
l am not interested in personal publicity.
- Not one single sentence in your own!
- Our people know what l'm doing.
But do you know what Baines is doing?
What is this ''Baines, Baines, Baines''?
Everyone can see this but you! Oh...
Baines is the one who saved my life...
..when l was crawling around
like an animal.
He brought me
to The Honourable Elijah Muhammad!
- Yes! A long time ago!
- And The Honourable Elijah Muhammad...
- A long time ago!
- ..brought me back from the dead!
- You've repaid them over and over!
- Don't you raise your voice in my house!
Ask them. Ask them why they have new
cars and houses full of furniture. Hm?
ls this what it's about, Betty? Do you want
some new furniture? Do you want cars?
What do we have?
What do we have, Malcolm?
Broken-down jalopy,...
..the clothes on our backs. Hm?
- So l'll get you some new clothes.
- We don't even own our own home.
What about our children? What about me?
You don't even own life insurance.
Look, Betty, the Nation of lslam
will provide if anything happens to me.
Will they?
Are you sure?
Or are you blind?
All right.
(drawer slams shut)
Um,...
..l've got work to do, so...
There's always work to do.
- Sweetheart, you got to help me.
- l'm trying.
l'm raisin' our children almost by myself.
You're runnin' all over the country...
Do you want me to stay home?
You don't know how many times
they ask me ''Where's my daddy?''
Do you want me to cook the food?
Make the beds and do everything?
- These people need me.
- We need you. We need you!
Well, l need you, too!
But what do you want me to do?
- Tell me! What do you want me to do?
- Open your eyes.
You can face death 24 hours a day,...
..but the possibility of betrayal
never enters your head.
Open your eyes.
- As salaam alaikum, Brother Minister.
- Wa-alaikum salaam, sister.
Her name's Eva Marie.
And she's two years old.
Brother Minister,
l didn't do anything wrong.
l didn't do anything to be put in isolation.
l believed in him.
l believed in The Honourable
Elijah Muhammad.
Believe in Allah.
(strains)
This is Saudi, she's two.
You have Lisha. She's three.
From theirmouths, I heard theirstories
ofwho had fathered their chiIdren,....
The Honourable Elijah Muhammad
is the father of my children.
..and that The HonourabIe EIijah
Muhammad had toId them I was his best,..
He often spoke of you. He loves you,
like you were his own son.
..the greatest minister that he everhad,
but that someday I wouId Ieave him,...
..and turn against him,
and so I was dangerous.
WhiIe praising me to my face,...
And he said that about me?
..he was tearing me apart behind my back.
- You're absolutely sure about all this?
- Yes, l am, Brother Minister.
All l want is support
for my three children,...
..that The Honourable Elijah Muhammad
provide for them. That's all l want.
Allah will provide.
For all of us.
What are you talkin' about, ''blackout''?
Perhaps some of the brothers
are a little jealous.
Maybe they think you've been gettin'
too much press. lt's nothing. Forget it.
Now, about our coming up
in the world a little.
The Nation's grown, we've grown with it.
You know our people.
They want their leaders to be prosperous.
One hand washes the other.
''l'm telling you God's words,
not no hustle.''
Remember, Brother Baines?
That's what you told me in prison.
''l'm telling you God's words,
not no hustIe.''
Brother Malcolm,...
..what do you want? A new car?
A new house?
lt's the money, isn't it?
How do we tell the whole world
that we're moral leaders,...
..because we follow the personal example
of The Honourable Elijah Muhammad?
Elijah Muhammad is a human being.
And so are you.
- Do you know your Bible?
- Do you know yours?
David slept with Bathsheba,
but he is remembered for slaying Goliath.
Noah was accused of drunkenness,
but God gave him the ark.
Solomon had 700 wives, but he was
the greatest, wisest king in history.
Brother Baines is a two-bit hustler,
but one hand washes the other.
The deeds of a great man
far outweigh his weaknesses.
Who needs the nutmeg now, brother?
- Baines, l'm not gonna lie...
- Be careful, Malcolm.
l warn you.
You be careful.
(door opens)
(door closes)
l'm not surprised.
You have a very good understanding
of prophecy, of spiritual matters.
l'm not surprised.
l have built this Nation,...
..under the divine guidance of Allah.
He has brought me back from the dead
to lead my people.
After me, there will be no more.
No more.
(clock ticks)
l must...
..plant my seed in fertile soil.
lt is only the fulfilment of prophecy.
My faith had been shattered
in a way I can never fuIIy describe.
Every second ofmy 12 years
with MrMuhammad,...
..I had been ready
to Iay down my Iife forhim.
The thing to me
that is worse than death itseIfis betrayaI.
You see, I couId conceive death,
but I couIdn 't conceive betrayaI.
Not ofthe IoyaIty which I had given
to the Nation ofIsIam and MrMuhammad.
During the previous 12 years, had he
committed a crime punishabIe by death,...
..I wouId have said and tried to prove
that I did it, to save him,...
..and gIadIy gone to the eIectric chair
in MrMuhammad's pIace.
* Ray CharIes: Up in the mornin '
(footsteps)
* Out on thejob
- * (gospeI choir) Oh...
- * I work Iike the deviI formy pay...
What did he say?
* I know that the Iucky oId sun...
- l'm so sorry.
- No, there's nothing to be sorry about.
l just got a lot of work to do, that's all.
- How can you work?
- Well, because we have to teach.
We got to teach the people, we got to
teach on Solomon and Moses, David...
Solomon had 700 wives.
A man's good deeds,
they far outweigh any of his...
(chuckles)
My father used to say that, uh,...
..you can't make a rooster stop crowing
once the sun has come up.
Well, the sun is up.
* I know that Iucky oId sun
* Has nothin' to do
* But roII around heaven aII day
- * Oh...
- * DearLord... *
So what do I say
about this nationaI day ofmourning,...
..so-called national day of mourning?
l say the white man's acts of violence
should be condemned,...
..not only by our beliefs, but by his own.
The holy Koran teaches us
that those who work evil...
..will be condemned, or punished,
or judged, according to their works.
The hoIy BibIe teaches us thatyou reap
whatyou sow. This is divinejustice.
ln the soil of the Americas, the white man
has planted the seeds of hatred.
He's planted the seeds of violence.
He's allowed those weeds to grow up...
..and choke the lives out of millions
of black men and women for 400 years.
ln fact, the lives of lndians
in these Americas for the last 500 years.
And now those same weeds...
..have choked one of his own gardeners,
in fact, his chief gardener,...
..and you ask me what l say.
l only say what the Bible says.
l say what the Koran says.
l say it's justice.
- (cheering and applause)
- As salaam alaikum.
(crowd shouts)
Minister X, don't you even feel
a little bit of remorse,...
..saddened by
President Kennedy's assassination?
Sir, l don't think
anybody here would deny...
..that when you send your chickens out
in the morning from your barnyard,...
..the chickens will return that evening
to your barnyard, not your neighbour's.
This is a prime example of the devil's
chickens coming back home to roost.
That the chickens that he's sent out,...
..the violence he's perpetrated
here and abroad,...
..be it four children in Birmingham,...
..orMedgarEvers,
orLumumba overin Africa.
I think this same vioIence
has come back to cIaim one oftheir own.
Now, being an oId farm boy myseIf,...
..chickens coming home to roost
nevermade me sad.
- ln fact, it's only made me glad.
- (reporters shout)
(coughs)
(sniffs and gasps)
Did you...
..read the paper today?
Yes, sir, l did.
That...
..was a bad statement you made.
You knew from my instructions,...
..no Minister was to make
any statements against this man.
The country loved this man.
You have made it...
..hard for Muslims...
..(coughs) in general.
(coughs)
Yes, sir.
We must dissociate ourselves
from your terrible blunder.
l must silence you.
For 90 days,...
..you must not make
any statements to the press,...
..nor are you to speak at any temples.
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir. l submit 1 00 per cent.
(phlegmy cough)
(coughs painfully)
(coughing continues)
(laboured coughing)
(telephone rings)
(child babbles happily)
You leave us alone.
- Betty?
- Leave us alone. Stop calling here.
Who's putting you up to this?
We have children here!
Stop it! Stop...
Hello?
- (whispers) lt's all right. lt's OK.
- They keep calling.
- They keep calling...
- Shhhh.
(whispers) Shh. Now, just, uh,...
We'll take the babies, put them into bed.
C'mon, babies, let's go to bed now.
- C'mon. Come on.
- Bedtime.
Let's go.
- Good night, Mommy, good night, Daddy.
- There you go. Night-night.
- Good night, Sidney.
- Night-night!
- Come on.
- Good night.
Brother Minister, l have to level with you.
They gave me a mission.
But l couldn't do it.
- l love y'all.
- What kind of mission?
To wire your car...
..so it would explode
when you turned the ignition.
The ministers say you're spreading
untruths about Mr Muhammad.
The ministers say that you are
the greatest hypocrite, a... a Judas.
A Benedict Arnold.
The ministers say that
your tongue should be cut out,...
..and delivered
to Mr Muhammad's doorstep.
- And what do you say?
- l'm with you, Brother Minister.
- You'll be marked for death.
- Yes, sir.
Let me die, then.
(sighs)
Brother, l can't come between you
and your father.
- You're my father.
- Brother, go on home.
Don't come back. That's an order.
Yes, sir.
Because 1964 threatens to be
an expIosive year on the raciaI front,...
..l have called this press conference
this morning...
..in order to clarify my position
in that struggle.
lnternal differences within the Nation
of lslam have forced me out of it.
ln the past, l thought the thoughts...
..and l spoke the words
of The Honourable Elijah Muhammad.
lf you recall, everything l said,...
..l started off with ''The Honourable Elijah
Muhammad teaches us thus, and so.''
That's over. From now on, l speak my
own words and think my own thoughts.
Now that I have more, uh,
independence ofaction,...
..I intend to use a more fIexibIe approach
toward working with others...
..to get a soIution to this probIem.
l'm not out to fight other Negro leaders.
l have now forgotten every bad thing
that other leaders have said about me,...
..and l pray that they also forget the many
bad things that l have said about them.
We must work together. We must find
a common solution to a common problem.
l'm going to organise and lead
a new mosque in New York City,...
..known as Muslim Mosque lncorporated.
This gives us the religious base...
..and the spiritual, uh, force necessary
to rid our people of the vices...
...that destroy the moral fibre
of our community.
Our political philosophy
will be black nationalism,...
..which means we want to control
the politics of our community.
The Muslim Mosque lncorporated
will remain wide open for ideas...
..and financial aid from all quarters.
Whites can help us, but they can't join us.
There can be no black-white unity
until there is first some black unity.
We cannot think of uniting with others,...
..until we have first learned
to unite amongst ourselves.
We cannot think of being
acceptable to others...
..until we have first proven
acceptable to ourselves.
In my desire to fuIIy understand
the reIigion ofIsIam,...
...as practised by 750 miIIion MusIims
around the worId,...
..I intend to make a piIgrimage,
orhoIy, uh,journey to Mecca.
This piIgrimage is a reIigious requirement
or duty ofevery MusIim that is abIe,...
..uh, to make the piIgrimage
at Ieast once in his Iifetime.
(men shout)
- l'm Egyptian. What are you?
- American.
- American. What's your name?
- Malcolm. Malcolm.
Malcolm!
(all shout in Arabic)
Yes, l want to get...
How much...?
- How much?
- 20 Egyptian pound.
- For one?
- Yes.
- Special price for you.
- Special price for me(!)
OK, thank you.
Where can l get a better price?
(shouting in Arabic)
- What's your name?
- Ah. Muhammad.
- Muhammad. l'm Malcolm.
- Malcolm? You Malcolm?
- Malcolm X. You?
- Gamaal.
Gamaal. All right, Gamaal. l'm from
uh, Harlem, from the United States.
- Harem?
- Harlem.
- Hareem?
- No, not ''hareem''. Har-lem.
- Can you take me to show me around...
- Hashish, hashish?
- Not hashish. Uh...
- Hashish?
- Uh, the Pyramids?
- Yeah! * Pyramid!*
- No. Pyramid. Pyramid.
- (both) * Pyramid, pyramid, pirimidimid!*
- No, no, no.
- One pyramid, ezay ya welad?
- Pyramids?
- Pyramids!
- You gonna take me?
Yes! Yes!
- Yes!
- Sphinx? Sphinx?
- Sphinx! Yeah. Right.
- Ah!
* Allahu akbar, Allahu akbar
* Allahu akbar
(camel grunts)
- * Ash-hadu an Ia iIaaha iIIa-IIah
- Hey! Malcolm! Pyramids! Pyramids!
Pyramids!
* Ash-hadu an Ia...
* ..iIaaha iIIa-IIah
* Ash-hadu anna Muhammadan...
* ..RasuIu-IIah
* Hayyia 'aIaI saIah
* Ash-hadu an Ia iIaaha iIIa-IIah
* Ash-hadu aIIa...
..iIaaha iIIa-IIah... *
My darIing Betty,...
..everywhere I go, I am weIcomed
as a representative ofourpeopIe.
OurstruggIe is known
and respected worIdwide.
CoincidentaIIy, there are two white men
who foIIow me around whereverI go.
I wonder who they're working for.
IfI was a betting man, I'd say the CIA.
What's yourguess?
Today I arrived in Arabia.
''l have never witnessed
such sincere hospitality...
..and true brotherhood...
(Betty) ..as practised here,...
..in the ancient home ofAbraham,
Muhammad,...
..and the greatprophets
ofthe Scriptures.''
''Today, with thousands ofothers,...
(MaIcoIm) I procIaimed God's greatness
in the sacred city ofMecca.
Wearing the ihram garb, I made
my seven circuits around the Kaaba.
I drank from the weII ofZem Zem.
I prayed to AIIah from MountArafat.
It was the onIy time in my Iife
that I stood before the Creator ofAII...
..and feIt Iike a compIete human being.
As salaam alaikum,
wa rahmat llah wa barakatoh.
As salaam alaikum, wa rahmat llah.
(pilgrims) Salaam alaikum, wa rahmat llah.
Now, you may be shocked
by these words,...
..but I have eaten from the same pIate,
drunk from the same gIass,...
..andprayed to the same God with
feIIow MusIims whose eyes were bIue,...
..whose hair was bIond...
..and whose skin was the whitest ofwhite.
And we were aII brothers, truIy,...
..peopIe ofaII coIours and races
beIieving in one God, in one humanity.
- Wa elnamata!
- Laka wal mulk!
- La sharik leka!
- Lebeyk llah uma lebeyk!
Each hourhere in this sacred Iand...
..enabIes me to have a greaterspirituaI
insight into what is happening in America.
The American Negro can neverbe bIamed
forhis raciaI animosities,...
..he is onIy reacting to 400 years
ofoppression and discrimination.
But as racism Ieads America
up the suicidaIpath,...
..I do beIieve that the youngergeneration
wiII see the handwriting on the waII,...
..and many ofthem wiII want to turn
to the spirituaIpath ofthe truth,...
..the onIy way Ieft in this worId...
..to ward offthe disaster
that racism must sureIy Iead to.
Once before in prison,
the truth came and bIinded me.
WeII, it has happened again.
In the past, I have made
sweeping indictments ofaII white peopIe.
These generaIisations caused injuries to
some white foIks who did not deserve it.
''Because of the spiritual rebirth
which l was blessed to undergo...
..as a result of my pilgrimage
to the Holy City of Mecca,...
..l no longer subscribe
to sweeping indictments of one race.
I intend to be very carefuI...
..not to sentence anyone...
(MaIcoIm)
..who has not been proven guiIty.
I am not a racist,...
..and I do not subscribe
to any ofthe tenets ofracism.
In aII honesty and sincerity,
it can be stated that I wish...
..nothing but freedom,
justice and equaIity,...
..Iife, Iiberty and the pursuit ofhappiness
for aIIpeopIe.
Now, my first concern, ofcourse,
is with the group to which I beIong,...
..for we, more than any others,
are deprived ofourinaIienabIe rights.
But I beIieve the true practice ofIsIam
can remove the cancer ofracism...
..from the hearts and the souIs
ofaIIAmericans.
And ifI can die having brought any Iight,...
..having exposed any meaningfuI truth
that wiII heIp destroy this disease,...
..then aII the credit is due to AIIah,
the Lord ofaII the WorIds.
And onIy the mistakes have been mine.
PIease give aII my Iove to the chiIdren.
I Iove you dearIy.
SincereIy, EI-Hajj MaIik EI-Shabazz,...
..MaIcoIm X.
* Bismillah e errahman e erraheen
* Alhamdu lil-lahi rab-bil al ala-meen
* Arrahman el erraheem
* Maliki yaum el eddeen
* lyyaka nabudu wa iyyaka nasta een
* lhdinas sirata almustaqeem
* Siratal el latheena anamta alaihim,...
* ..ghairil maghdubi alaihim,
wa la adhdhaal leen
* Aameen
Let's begin.
MaIcoIm, you said on your trip abroadyou
sensed a feeIing ofgreat brotherhood.
Uh, yes. When l was in Mecca,
making the pilgrimage,...
..the brotherhood that existed there...
..among aIIpeopIe, aII races,
aII IeveIs ofpeopIe...
..who had accepted
the reIigion ofIsIam,...
..what it had done, IsIam,
for those peopIe, despite their, uh,...
..compIexion differences,...
..perhaps ifpeopIe
here in America wouId try and...
..practise and study the religion of lslam,...
..it might help to erase
the plague of racism here.
l think Muslims over there
look at themselves as human beings,...
..as part of the same human family.
Today, my friends are black,...
..red, yellow, brown and white.
Malcolm, are you prepared to ask
the United Nations,...
to bring charges against the United States
for its treatment of the American Negro?
- Oh, yes. Oh, yes.
- (applause)
The audience will have to be quiet.
PIease. PIease.
Yes, as I stated earIier, that, um...
..those nations, African nations,
Latin nations, Asian nations,...
..are... are very hypocriticaI
when they stand up in the UN...
..and denounce the racism practised
in South Africa, and at the same time,...
..say absolutely nothing about
the practice of racism in America.
Now, l wouldn't be a man if l didn't do so.
- l would not be a man.
- Are you prepared now...
..to work with some of the leaders
of other civil rights organisations?
Yes, we're prepared to work with
any groups, leaders, organisations,...
..as long as they're genuinely interested
in, uh, results. Positive results.
Does your new beard
have any religious significance?
- (laughter)
- Uh, no. Not particularly.
But I think that, uh,
as bIack peopIe in America...
..strive to throw offthe shackIes
of... ofmentaI coIoniaIism,...
..they wiII aIso refIect their desire...
..to throw offthe shackIes
of, uh, cuIturaI coIoniaIism.
l believe that a mental and cultural
migration back to Africa,...
..not necessarily a physical migration,...
..not at this point, but a mental
and cultural migration back to Africa...
..which only means that we reaffirm
our bond with our brothers over there,...
..would help to strengthen us here
in America, black people in America,...
..not only spiritually,
but as well as giving us the incentive...
..to solve some of our problems
here at, uh, at home.
One of your more controversial remarks
was a call for black people
to get rifles and form rifle clubs.
Do you still favour that for self-defence?
Well, l don't see why that's controversial.
l think that if white people find themselves
the victims of the same kind of violence...
..that black people found themselves
victims of here in America,...
..and if the government was unable
or unwilling to do anything about it,...
..l think that it would be intelligence
on their part to defend themselves.
- What about the guns, Malcolm?
- (flashbulb pops)
When you tell your people
to stop being violent against my people,...
..l'll tell my people to put away their guns.
- So then you are still an extremist...
- Get your hand outta my pocket!
Next question.
(telephone rings)
MaIcoIm, you one dead red nigger.
Your days on this earth
are numbered,... brother.
Come to bed.
Get some rest.
- Mm...
- l'm sorry, Betty.
Sorry for what?
- Well, l haven't been the best husband...
- Shh.
Or the best father. A family shouldn't be
separated like ours has been.
And l promise you l'll never make another
long trip without you and the children.
l miss you and the girls.
We'll all be together, l promise you that.
Dear heart.
l love you.
Thank you.
(Betty chuckles)
Get some sleep.
We had the best organisation
a black man will ever see.
Niggers ruined it.
(baby coos)
(barrel clicks)
- (whispers) Betty.
- Mm?
Betty. Wake up.
- My babies!
- Let's go! Let's get out! Girls, come on!
- Out, out, out! Outside! Out, out, out! Go!
- (children shriek)
Out!
Go! Go! Run! Run, run, run, run!
Come on! Run!
- Somebody call the fire department!
- (shrieks) Help! Help!
Come on!
Call the fire department, please!
Somebody call the fire department!
l'm a man!
Evidently, the, uh,...
..some type of bomb,
Molotov cocktail bomb...
..was thrown against
the back of the house.
One was thrown on the side
of the house, from what l could tell.
lt bounced up against the window.
That's what woke my daughter up.
Had it gone in,...
..my two-year-old, my four-year-old and
my six-year-old daughter would've been...
l'm just telling you, had that happened,...
..l'd've taken my rifle,
l'd've gone after anyone in sight.
Do you think this was a warning,
or an attempt on your life?
What does it look like?
Does it look like a warning to you?
This is a definite attempt
by the Nation of lslam...
..upon the strict orders
of Mr Elijah Muhammad.
D'you know what they're saying
at the Muslim headquarters?
lt doesn't matter to me.
l can tell what they're doing.
Minister Baines, can you please tell us,
who bombed the house?
Uh, we feel it's a publicity stunt
on the part of Malcolm X,...
..but we hope it isn't a case of... if he can't
keep the house, we won't get it, either.
That's enough. 'Scuse me.
(tyres screech)
- Malcolm!
- l'm all right. l'm all right.
- Betty and the kids?
- They're fine. They're across the street.
Let's get two men on post,
two in front of the house.
- Brother Minister, did you see anybody?
- No, l didn't see anyone.
But l know who it is.
You know l know who did it.
- Give us the command, Malcolm.
- Don't worry about the command.
- Two men here on post, two in front.
- We got an informer.
Spark it.
As salaam alaikum, my brothers.
Here's yourkey,...
- ..and enjoy your stay.
- Thank you.
(telephone rings)
OAAU.
Brother Earl, it's Malcolm.
- Earl?
- Malcolm? Where are you?
- We've been calling all over the city.
- Wait a minute. Hold the phone.
I'm downtown. I'm, uh, I'm in a hoteI.
I'm trying to get some work done
for tomorrow.
- Let me and the brothers come down.
- It's aII right. I'm OK.
I wish you wouId Iisten to us. Now, about
this meeting up at the Audubon BaIIroom.
- We have to start friskin' people.
- No, no. No. No, l don't want, uh...
l don't want anybody frisked.
We have to change
our way of thinking, brother.
We have to make people feel comfortable.
IfI can't be safe around my own kind,
who can I be safe around?
I trust thatAIIah wiIIprotect me.
Well, believin' in Allah's one thing,
but l also believe in bein' armed.
Brother, we don't want black people
killing each other. All right?
All right?
We'll protect you, Malcolm.
As salaam alaikum.
No. Peace be unto you, EarI.
Peace be unto you.
(shotgun bIast)
* Junior WaIker & The AII Stars:
''Shotgun''
* I said, Shotgun!
* Shoot 'em 'fore they run, now
* Do thejerk, baby
* Do the dirty now
Good evening.
Do you have a Malcolm X registered?
- * And then you go downtown now
- (coughs)
* I said ''Buy yourseIfa shotgun now''
- (telephone rings)
- * We're gonna break it down, baby, now
* We're gonna load it up, baby, now
(telephone rings)
* Oh, can you shoot 'em
'fore they run, now
* I said, Shotgun!
* Shoot 'em 'fore they run, now
(telephone rings)
- * Do thejerk, baby
- (telephone rings)
* Do the dirty now
* Hey!
(teIephone rings)
(baby grizzles)
(telephone rings)
That red nigger ofyours is dead!
So are yourbastard chiIdren!
* Shotgun!
* Shoot 'em 'fore they run, now
(telephone rings)
* Do thejerk, baby
* Do the dirty now
* Hey!
* Put on yourhigh-heeI shoes
* I said, we're goin' down here,
Iisten to 'em pIay the bIues
- Hello?
- Wake up, brother.
- Wa-saIaam aIaikum.
- (sighs)
* We're gonna pick tomatoes
- (telephone rings)
- (babies cry)
You hear me, and you hear me well.
You come anywhere near my family,...
- ..and l will kill you. Do you hear?
- Betty. Betty. Betty.
lt's Malcolm.
Malcolm...
(baby continues crying)
Oh,...
..they keep calling. They keep threatening.
l'm going crazy every time a phone rings.
l know. Just don't answer the phone
any more. Everything's gonna be all right.
- When's it going to stop?
- Don't answer the phone any more.
- Are the brothers there? They on post?
- Yes. They're outside.
AII right, weII, you Iet them answer
the phone. You don't touch the phone.
- Beloved, where are you?
- l'm in a hotel.
A hotel.
GirIs asIeep?
Yes. l just...
..put them down to bed.
Can we come to the meeting tomorrow?
No, l don't think so.
The girIs and I want to see you.
We miss you.
Betty, it's too dangerous.
It's been dangerous.
Listen, l haven't told this to anybody,...
..but l've been thinkin' about what's been
happening to me lately, to us lately, and...
..l'm gonna stop saying that it's
the Nation of lslam that's behind this.
l know what they can do and l know
what they can't do. l trained them.
Some of the things that have been
happening lately, l just...
..l'm gonna stop saying
it's just the Nation of lslam.
They're not working alone.
They're getting a lot of help.
No! Are you sure?
I miss you, Betty.
You're with us even when you're away.
Now, Iisten, you come on down
to the Audubon tomorrow.
We'II be aII right. We're not gonna Iet this
get us down. We're gonna be fine.
- You come on down. Bring the girIs, too.
- The girIs and I miss you so much.
I'II see you tomorrow.
- Compared to King, this guy's a monk.
- Good night, dearheart.
- SIeep weII. I Iove you.
- Good night.
* Sam Cooke: ''A Change Is Gonna Come''
- Attallah, sit back. Sit up straight.
- * I was born by the river
* In a IittIe tent
* Oh, andjust Iike the river
I've been runnin '
* Eversince
* It's been a Iong
* A Iong time comin ', but I know
* A change gonna come
- * Oh, yes, it wiII
- (children bicker)
* It's been too hard Iivin '
* But I'm afraid to die
* Cos I don't know what's up there
* Beyond the sky
* It's been a Iong
* A Iong time comin '
* But I know
* A change gonna come
* Lord, yes, it wiII
We're gonna see Daddy.
* I go to the movies
- Uh-huh.
- * And I go downtown
* Somebody keep teIIin'me
- * ''Don't hang around''
- Little sister!
- What do you say to the nice man?
- Thank you.
You're very welcome,
my beautiful little sister.
Bye-bye.
* But I know a change gonna come
* Oh, yes, it wiII
* Then I go to my brother
The Minister hasn't arrived yet.
Don't worry. He'll be here like clockwork.
* HeIp me, pIease
* But he winds up
* Knockin'me
* Back down on my knees
* Lord
* There've been times that I thought
* I couIdn 't Iast forIong
- * But now I think I'm abIe
- Son?
- * To carry on... *
- Son, are you all right?
Are you OK?
Good. l recognise you.
Don't you pay them folks no nevermind.
You just keep right on
doin' what you doin'.
- Yes, ma'am.
- (chuckles) l'll pray for you, son.
- Well, thank you.
- Jesus will protect you.
- As salaam alaikum.
- Wa-alaikum salaam.
ls the charter ready?
- Uh, no, Brother Minister.
- No?
No? Why not?
You had enough time, didn't you,
you and the sister?
l apologise, Brother Minister,
we'll have it next week.
Next week? l don't... we don't have
next week. We need it today.
The people are waiting to hear the charter
today, not next week.
Next week, Minister.
ls the Reverend here?
The Reverend called,
said he wouldn't be able to attend!
So we don't have our opening speaker,
we don't have a charter, l mean,...
..why didn't you inform me about this
last night? l talked to you.
- l called Sister Betty...
- You didn't have to call Sister Betty!
l talked to you. You should've told me!
What are you telling Sister Betty for?
- Well, l assumed...
- Don't assume anything!
Go on down.
- Sister, you go on with the brother.
- Yes, sir.
Malcolm.
What's wrong?
Fine. Let's cancel it.
My wife out there? And the children?
They're out front as always.
All right,
you go out to the payphone outside.
Call up the Reverend
and see if he can make it down here.
l gotta be on post, Malcolm.
l'm supposed to be out there guardin' you.
That's a duty for secretarial staff.
- l'll ask Sister Robin if she...
- Go outside to the payphone.
Call up the Reverend.
See if he can make it down here.
All right.
(walkie-talkie crackles)
- Responding.
- AII right.
PIease, Iet's settIe down.
Let's get the programme started.
The Minister wiII be out...
Thank you.
l apologise for raising my voice earlier.
Very disrespectful.
Brother Minister, l understand.
Lifestyles are changing,
minds are changing,...
..why, everything is changing!
So you and l must consider that
we're living in very, very changing times.
And what might be true today
may not be true tomorrow.
And without any further ado,...
..l present to you
Brother Minister Malcolm.
And l pray that you and l will listen.
Listen,...
..hear, and understand. Thank you.
Daddy!
- As salaam alaikum.
- Wa-alaikum salaam.
Get your hand outta my pocket!
- Get your hands outta my pocket!
- Brother...
Brother, please, hold it!
- (screaming)
- Calm down!
- Please, brothers!
- Oh, my God!
Malcolm!
- (screams)
- Malcolm!
- (screaming)
- Get down!
(gunshots)
Hey!
Come on!
- Shoot him!
- l got him...
- (shrieks)
- C'mon! C'mon!
Malcolm!
(wails)
- Get an ambulance! Get an ambulance!
- Somebody get an ambulance!
They killed him!
(sobs) They kiIIed him!
- (gunshot)
- (cries out)
Ah, fuck!
- Kill him!
- Get him, he shot Brother Malcolm!
- l'm gonna kill him! l'm gonna kill him!
- No!
l didn't do it! l didn't...
- Get him!
- (shouting)
He killed Malcolm!
(policeman shouts)
- Kill him!
- Back off!
l seen him!
- He did it!
- No!
(sobs)
(Betty keens)
(Betty wails)
- Get out of the way! C'mon, folks!
- (siren wails)
Get out of the way, please!
- Move it! Get out of the way! Get back!
- Move! Move! Move, move!
- Please! Get out of the way!
- Move! Move!
- Everybody! Stand back!
- C'mon, move!
Move him across! Stand back!
Get out of the way! Get back!
- (shouting)
- Please! One statement! Please!
The person you know as Malcolm X
is no more.
The assassination of Malcolm X...
..was an unfortunate tragedy.
lt reveals that there are still, er,
numerous people in our nation...
..who have degenerated to the point
of expressing dissent through murder,...
..and we haven't learned to disagree
without being violently disagreeable.
(Ossie Davis) Here,...
..at this finaI hour,...
..in this quietpIace,...
..HarIem has come to bid fareweII
to one ofits brightest hopes,...
..extinguished now,...
..and gone from us forever.
It is not in the memory ofman...
- (gunshot)
- ..that this beIeaguered, unfortunate,...
..but nonetheIess proud community...
..has found a braver,
more gaIIantyoung champion...
..than this Afro-American...
..who Iies before us,...
..unconquered stiII.
I say the word again
as he wouId want me to,...
..Afro-American.
Afro-American MaIcoIm.
MaIcoIm had stopped being Negro
years ago.
It had become too smaII, too puny,...
..too weak a word forhim.
MaIcoIm was bigger than that.
MaIcoIm had become an Afro-American.
And he wanted so desperateIy...
..that we, that aII his peopIe,...
..wouId become Afro-Americans, too.
There are those
who stiII considerit their duty...
..as ''friends ofthe Negro peopIe''
to teII us to reviIe him,...
..to fIee even from
the presence ofhis memory,...
..to save ourseIves by writing him
out ofthe history ofour turbuIent times.
And we wiII smiIe.
They wiII say that
he is ofhate, a fanatic,...
..a racist who can onIy bring eviI
to the cause for which you struggIe.
And we wiII answer and say unto them...
''Didyou ever taIk to BrotherMaIcoIm?''
Didyou ever touch him,
orhave him smiIe atyou?
Didyou everreaIIy Iisten to him?
You haven't done the right thing!
Was he everhimseIfassociated with
vioIence, or any pubIic disturbance?
Forifyou did, you wouId know him.
And ifyou did, you wouId know
why we must honourhim.
MaIcoIm was ourmanhood,
ourIiving, bIack manhood.
This was his meaning to his peopIe.
And in honouring him,
we honour the best in ourseIves.
Howevermuch
we may have differed with him,...
..or with each other about him
and his vaIue as a man,...
..Iet his going from us...
..serve onIy to bring us togethernow.
Consigning these mortaI remains
to earth, the common mother ofaII,...
..secure in the knowIedge
that what we pIace in the ground...
..is no more now a man...
..but a seed,...
..which, after the winter
ofour discontent,...
- ..wiII come forth again to meet us.
- (crowd chants) Malcolm X!
And we shaII know him then
for what he was and is:
..a prince.
Our own bIack shining prince,...
..who didn 't hesitate to die,...
..because he Ioved us so.
(woman) And so, today,...
..May 1 9th,
we celebrate Malcolm X's birthday,...
..because he was a great,
great Afro-American.
Malcolm X is you. All of you.
And you are Malcolm X.
l'm Malcolm X!
l am Malcolm X!
As Brother Malcolm said,...
..''We declare...
..our right...
..on this earth...
..to be a man,...
..to be a human being,...
..to be given the rights...
..of a human being,...
..to be respected...
..as a human being,...
..in this society,...
..on this earth,...
..in this day,...
..which we intend to bring into existence...
- ..by any means necessary!
- (cheering and appIause)
* (Chorus) Some Iong day
* (Aretha FrankIin) Someday
* Someday we'II aII
* We'II aII be free
* (chorus) Someday
* Yeah
* Someday, someday we'II aII
* We're sure gonna be free
* (chorus) Freedom
* Oh, yeah
* Free
* Hang
* Onto the worId
* As it spins around
* Just
* Don't Iet the spin getyou down
* Things are movin '
* Fast
* HoId on tight
* Andyou wiII Iast
* Keep yourseIf-respect
* Andyour woman and manIy pride
* GetyourseIfin gear
* Keep yourstride
* Nevermindyour fears
* Nevermind 'em, nevermind
* Brighter days
* WiII soon be here
* Take it from me
* Someday
* We'II aII be free
* (chorus) Free, ooh-ooh
* Oh, yeah
* Take it from me
* Someday
* We'II aII be free
* (chorus) Free
* (chorus) Ooh
* HoId on to the worId
* You got to be free within yourseIf
* Keep on waIkin' taII
* HoIdyourhead up high
* Lay your dreams
* Right up to the sky
* And sing, sing yourgreatest song
* (chorus) Sing
* Sing it, sing it, sing it,
sing it, sing it, sing
* Andyou keep right on
* Take it from me
* Someday
* We'II aII be free
- * (chorus) Free, ooh-ooh
- * Freedom, whoa-oh, oh-oh, yeah
* Take it from me
* Someday
* We'II aII be free
* (chorus) Free
Every time I thank my Lord
* Free
* Someday
* We'II aII be free
* (chorus) Oh, oh, oh
* Ooh, yeah, we'II aII be free
* Free
Every time I thank my Lord
* Time for a change, movin'reaI fast
* Take it from me, we'II aII be free, yeah
* Oh, mighty brothers
* (chorus) Oh, oh, oh
- * Freedom, freedom, you'II be free
- * Oh.... oh
* Free
Now it's time to make a choice
* Women, they say
* Oh, yeah
* We're gonna be free
* (chorus) Come, brothers
- * Oh, go on, my brothers
- * (chorus) Ooh, ooh, ooh
- * So praise to the Lord...
- * Yes! (fades out) *
* Arrested DeveIopment: ''RevoIution''
* RevoIu...
* RevoIution!
* Brothers and sisters
* Let me share with you some news
* As I sit on my pIush couch
watchin' the news
* There has been a rude awakening
'* That I have marched
untiI my feet have bIed
* And I have rioted
untiI they caIIed the Feds
* ''What's Ieft?'' my conscience said
- * ''What's Ieft?'' my conscience said
- * RevoIution!
Go!
* As I Iook about,
where do I see the IittIe ones
* PIayin' amongst each other
with their waterguns
* In pure poverty
* Generations ofgoodpeopIe
in cycIes ofpoverty
* It bothers me so I ask myseIf, I say
* Are you doin' as much as you can
for the struggIe?
* No!
* Am I doin' as much as I can
for the struggIe?
* No!
* Then why do I cry
when my peopIe are in troubIe?
* My ancestors
sIapped me in the face and said
* Go!
* Harriet Tubman toId me to get on up
* Marcus Garvey said to me
''Brother, ya get on up''
* My BrotherMaIcoIm X,
need I name more?
* It ain 't Iike we neverseen bIood before
* Come on, Iet's taIk revoIution now
* RevoIution!
* AII my peopIe say
* AII my brothers say
* RevoIution!
* AII my sisters say
* AII my peopIe say
* RevoIution!
* Hey!
* AII my peopIe say
* RevoIution!
* I see bIood,
I want MaIcoIm as one channeI
* I see tears,
cos now it seems that we forgot him
* I see the years ofpeopIe
searchin' forsoIutions
* Restitutions, excuses
Don't want no more confusion
* Come on, come on,
Let's taIk right, Iet's taIk right
* TaIk up, taIk up
But don't taIk up aII night
* There's gotta be action
ifyou want satisfaction
- * Ifnot foryourseIf, for the young ones
- * The chiIdren
* The UN, the US, we can't aIIowya
* To teII us again that the ghetto
is not as important as gettin'in Bosnia
* I ain 't with it,just forget it
* We can't even debate
ifyou don't understand oursituation
Come on!
* You don't want us
to go get a gun now, do you?
* You don't Iike to see peopIe
runnin' around now
* Yet stiIIya wanna Iive Iike 90210
whiIe we scream out
- * Yo!
- * Freedom!
* My grandmother's a-goin '
''We are wasted''
* ''You must acquire a taste
forsomething we've never tasted''
* So, peopIe, Iet us wet ourpaIates
* It's either the buIIet or the baIIot
Go now
* RevoIution now
* AII my peopIe say
* RevoIution!
* AII my brothers say
* AII my sisters say
* RevoIution!
* Hey!
* AII my peopIe say
- * RevoIution!
- * Let's taIk about a revoIution
- * AII my peopIe say
- * Hey!
* RevoIution!
* RevoIu...
RevoIution!
* RevoIution!
* Now I see
I understand what my peopIe have said
* They teII me to fight!
* Fight for the ancestors who are dead!
* ForHarriet Tubman,
MOVE Organisation, David Watts,...
* ..the BIack Panthers,...
* ..Kwame Nkumah, Marcus Garvey,...
..Jane Pittman.
- * RevoIution!
- * Mm-hm, mm
- * Mm-mm-mm, hm-mm-mm, mm
- * RevoIution!
- * Mm-hm, mm
- * Mm-mm-mm, hm-mm-mm, mm
- RevoIution!
- Mm-hm, mm
- * RevoIution!
- * Mm-mm-mm hm-mm-mm, mm
- * Mm-hm, mm
- * Revolution!
- * Mm-mm-mm, hm-mm-mm, mm
- RevoIution!
- * Mm-hm, mm
- * RevoIution!
- * Mm-mm-mm, hm-mm-mm, mm
- RevoIution!
- * Mm-hm, mm
- * RevoIution!
- * Mm-mm-mm, hm-mm-mm, mm
- * RevoIution! (fades out) *
Subtitles by Lena Erakovich
lntelfax Media Access
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org