My God, protect us now.
It seems that you are receiving
the most blows to the shoulders and arms.
We see that it sticks not strong
with the left.
EL RASTRO DE UN SUAVE PERFUME
That afternoon, connect say that Perkins
She kissed the canvas in the
2nd round, counting up to 8.
We come to the end of the sixth round!
Did you pay the phone?
We need money.
Who will give it?
My House is paid.
Almost.
Qu  dices?
Esa casa no vale nada.
- Es buena.
- S , maravillosa.
- Me prometiste encontrarlo.
- Te dije que lo intentar a.
Quisiera librarme de ella.
Por qu  no
se la das a alguien?
Tendr amos que trasladar
la oficina a mi coche.
Hay sitio para el tel f.
y el contestador autom tico.
- Es una buena casa.
- No para dos.
Quiero deshacerme de ella.
La conexi n est  pagada,
podemos recibir mensajes.
Nosotros podemos
recibir llamadas,
y quieres decirme c mo haremos
para poder contestadas?
Tenemos una cita para ma ana.
Para hacer qu ?
- No es para hacer nada.
It's just a date.
Already.
- You can go t ,  no?
- Yes.
Well, I'm going to see
if I hold it strong.
Yes.
Remember the money
of Pittsburgh?
- The one who cheated us.
-The one who disappeared?
Yes.
Last night, Bernie and I
We were having dinner
and a guy who danced,
he fell right next to me.
Is the woman.
The woman of Burning.
He has given one to each
concealer of the city.
As business cards.
Try to sell our pasta.
Is it dangerous?
Do not.
For us.
Warn the boys.
Mr. Hickey
Mr. Boggs?
Hickey
Mr. Boggs does not
Does he meet with us?
He is in the office. What can we do?
Do for you, Mr. Rice?
- Leave me.
-But if you do not know how to sign.
Do not say nonsense.
Say?
Yes.
Clear.
Agree.
T  warn Monte,
We'll go find the fat one.
Voucher.
Can I call my mom?
Clear.
It must be done delicately.
I have not seen her for a long time.
Only find it.
It's the only thing he should do.
I do not want you to talk
with her, understood?
I could be scared.
Discretion
You know what I want to say.
Only find it
and tell it to you.
Exact.
- Jack.
- S ?
I'm going to take the GTO.
The special one.
Mount, the keys are
in the rearview mirror.
These things may take.
I hope it is not too much.
The question of money remains.
200 a day more expenses.
I see.
Helping the inflation.
It was a joke.
Very good, the service number
that collects my messages
is in one of those
pieces of paper.
Call when you have
something to say.
500 dollars
As an advance.
A test of confidence.
Is it enough?
I think I am, Mr. Rice.
Well, "arrivederci", Mr. Hickey.
Try not to burn yourself.
- We have work.
- What a joy.
- I hate to bother you.
-So dont do it.
Do you see this girl?
-What does he teach?
- It's our job.
- Mary Jane Bowen.
-S .
Tell me about it.
An individual named Rice
He wants us to find it.
For what?
- A romantic relationship.
- It seems that the march is going.
Yes, and do not make fun of him.
We have 500 bucks to account.
You think the money
Does it drive me crazy?
Farrow, Shaw ..
Who is this last?
Burning
I think he's Hispanic.
When she saw Rice
by last goes?
3 weeks ago.
I will see Farrow
and you're looking for Shaw.
They were friends, but Rice already
he does not want to know anything about them.
- He only wants Mary Jane.
- It's your money.
And a part
it's going to be for us
In case you speak
with any of those guys,
Rice does not want
his name is mentioned.
How is Nyona?
What Nyona?
Whatever it is, I do not want
I do not care what he does.
The blinds are down,
He has not gotten up yet.
Men are all the same.
Who is it?
I could start
saying hello".
Hi.
How is it
the public servant?
I'm in a hurry.
Who is it?
I think his name is Farrow.
-What were you doing here?
Following the trail to a girl.
He was a clue.
Looking at the mailbox,
I found Mr. Farrow
lived in apartment 1338 A.
So making use of m
special deduction capacity,
I headed up the stairs towards
the apartment 1338 A.
No jokes
Note for the mechanic:
delete the last observation of Hickey
and my comment.
Get to the point.
Is there something?
It's been a long time
Do not see Mary Jane, years.
They went out with some brothers
called Burning.
Mary Jane's boyfriend
went to the moneybag for robbery.
Go item. Tomorrow we will go
to see the other Mr. Burning.
- Yes.
- Voucher.
-What about Farrow?
- He has eaten p lvora.
-He's dead?
- Yes.
Are you going to tell me something about him?
Looking at the buzzer, I deduced that Farrow
lived in apartment 1338 A.
What happened?
They have loaded a guy.
-  Robbery?
- Not seem.
As soon as I opened
the door, they liquidated it.
-Who has the report?
-It's in your office.
Shaw writes the statement
of Hickey, the one who found it.
Who is Hickey?
I was in the Hollen section.
Hello!
It does not have any grace,
dammit!
Your sense of humor is pathetic.
Go to the horn!
How timely!
Give me a towel
Go, get out of here.
Wait in another room.
I almost had a heart attack.
Everything you do is very funny.
- It was just a form of ...
- Wait in another room.
Do you feel better?
What do you want?
Want to see you.
- For the first time in 3 weeks.
- I have been working.
In what?
Come on, honey,
tranquil zate, will you?
I do not like this, you go
As if you still lived in this house.
- Viv a.
- But not anymore.
Now you live somewhere else.
You threw me out
I had to find another site.
With all the drunks
from the city.
You will be very happy
the 2 in that place.
Look, I'm tired of this.
I can not take it anymore.
Do you want me to leave?
Yes.
Voucher.
I will give you another chance.
Not tonight
I have it free, do you understand?
Ah rrame the drama.
A woman called Fine Sopp.
Although he has been
inactive lately.
A man named Bledsoe.
That is a good possibility.
My old partner,
Clifton Farrow,
I found out that he has entered
in negotiations with that person,
that woman.
They must have
Be very careful with him.
- We have it.
-Are they all?
There are not too many people
on the West Coast
able to do
big transactions.
How much is it really about?
In any case, these are
those who traffic with currency,
or buy it in this area.
We have got four cats.
Chandler is going to kill me.
I could call those people
for you and suggest
that refuse to enter
in dealings with that woman.
Do you want to hang up?
And he has not heard
of Mary Jane Bowen?
No, not now.
I am sorry.
But if I do ...
Perd n
If I can be of any help ...
We have already entertained you
Pretty, sir ...
Good evening, Mr. Rice.
Thanks for your sincerity.
- Lie.
- I know.
For now it does not matter.
Take care of this.
Now, tonight.
- No no.
- If it's lost, tell me.
- I have to present a report.
- Here it is.
HERE,  ve?
A key is nothing more than
a key until it opens something.
I have to take it to me
a traffic test.
I'll give it back to you
this afternoon or tomorrow.
If there has been a misunderstanding,
and I hope that is all,
It is my responsibility to clarify it.
An amateur less to the sport.
She is a good woman, she is
A little confused, that's all.
When you leave the apartment,
Would you mind telling us?
I would like to take a look,
just in case.
We also have
work to do
Yes, it's fine.
Do not forget
to return the key.
I need a little more sugar.
Something new?
No, the? Florister? A is closed.
Give me a puppy with chili.
- Two.
- Three.
Let there be four
and two coca-tails.
Found this where Farrow.
And also this.
Caramba.
Sorry to have to return them.
Yes.
Let's call Rice first.
I've already done it.
Cancel the service this morning.
I paid the bill and it has not stopped
another number, so let's eat.
"Averiado".
- In the drain pipe.
- Yes, in the kitchen.
-Do you hear the names?
- Do not.
Hickey?
We can not do
all for you
-How did you get in?
- Walking.
The apt is sealed.
Stop bullshit
and thanks.
- We would have found it.
- Yes, from here to a month.
- We are giving you a hand.
- It's fine, you've touched me.
Check it
Come on, get going.
Voucher.
- Do it well, boys.
- Av sanos if something comes up.
-Do you make a copy of the note?
- It's in my pocket.
Papadakis will go
ahead in this.
Fucks me giving these guys nothing.
Yeah, but if we do not,
leave us without a license.
Only
we're looking for Mary Jane.
I know, but still ...
You have a visit
-What do you want?
- Se or Burning?
The same.
We are private detectives,
Mr. Burning.
It means they are not police.
We're looking for Mary Jane Bowen.
Say, have you seen her?
We only look for it.
Nothing happens.
I have not seen
for 5 years.
I only sell flowers.
We do not have Mary Jane,
nor client.
This is what you copied
of Farrow's note?
There are three names
and directions behind.
It seems that they are plotting something.
Let's check these signs.
Tell us, where are you?
Wait.
The apartment is rented to a
such Mary Florida, or Florera.
They have not seen it for a long time.
Fourth floor, in the background.
- You have used your persuasion.
- Yes, and fifty bucks.
The cops have been this afternoon.
No one.
Go back
Yes.
You have invested your money well.
If someone appears,
will warn us?
I hope so.
With fifty turkeys.
- There are not many clothes.
- I would not have money.
S ?
Yes thanks.
They are here.
There are three types.
Eh, be careful!
Dammit.
Frank, do you want to come already?
My God.
"In reference to your request
of identification with respect
to thousand-dollar bills, with
serial numbers L41405982 C
and L41405983 C,
The above mentioned has not been
recovered from the theft
to the City Bank
15-10-71 ".
- Good morning.
- Hi, pir mano.
-Is there something?
- A certified cane.
Is it good news?
Not precisely.
Rice has given us a ballot,
It has left us untouched.
There may be
found Mary Jane.
It do not says that.
I think he is afraid.
- I like your style.
-What else can we do?
Listen, I'm going
to see the florist again.
T  oc pate de Rice, to see
if you can locate him
Are you going to put it on?
To the.
Have you ever killed
in the U.S?
Because I know what you're thinking,
but I know those people,
better than yourself.
They are bullies, nothing more.
Neither questions, nor time
to ask, or to talk.
The cops are more predictable.
If you wear a revolver, you should be
ready to kill.
I tell you it's better to run.
Have you finished?
You want to tell him
Papadakis last night?
Good...
I like your style.
Have you located Papadakis?
Tell him to come back.
No, it's something important.
Bob, distribute this.
Bring Al Hickey and Frank Boggs.
No, it's not an arrest.
What the hell is happening?
That money is red hot!
Stunning!
2 people killed,
another 6 in Pittsburgh.
Every time something happens,
you two are in the middle.
- I want to know everything.
- You'll stay af nico.
I warn you,
do not go for the branches.
Who goes by the branches?
We brought the money.
-What did you do there?
- Investigating a little.
- We have a license,  no?
- Yes, for now.
What did you need?
-What about the florist?
- It was a Rice track.
2 tracks,
2 dead men.
We live difficult times.
There is a lot of social agitation.
Have you found Rice?
- Not yet.
Wonderful.
-What's the matter with Pittsburgh?
-Last winter.
In the Federal Reserve Bank.
3 dead guards,
3 dead assailants,
the driver escaped with the money.
Big bills.
Almost four hundred thousand.
They riddled the driver.
They did not find the money
nor his companion.
-What was her name?
- We do not know.
Is reward offered?
Twenty-five thousand.
I want to review this.
From above.
If you need us ...
She can not
get rid of the pasta.
The bills
They're too big.
Do not worry about that.
Tomorrow we will go to the game.
Farrow was an intermediary.
She was trying to let go
that pasta under pressure.
I said that tomorrow we will go
to the match. Rel jate and enjoy.
-What a match?
- Rams and Falcons.
Your rugby-
I'm in favor of the Rams.
-  Was not everything sold?
- He is.
We have to look
to Mary Jane Bowen,
not a rugby player.
There are twenty-five thousand dollars.
How much do you want to bet?
To the Rams?
What a Mary Jane
is in the game.
I thought he would let himself be seen.
Go success.
Give me the envelope.
Farrow had the same written.
"Rams- Falcons
More 1 "
- In these seats.
-  More one what?
The person they expected.
More days?
Ma ana?
- I do not know.
-What will be the date?
The entrance is the key.
Time of the match,
these seats, more a day.
While.
Say?
God no. I do not want
talk, I want to sleep
You only remember my phone
at bedtime.
You had work in a party,
You could have taken me.
Of course, everything we have to do,
we can do it in the field.
Give it to me again.
It only takes two people
in a transaction.
Three is dangerous.
Why a third party?
-What is this?
- Nothing.
- It says "Edith."
- It has changed in number.
You have seen her again.
I stopped paying the pension
and it is without white. Need help.
What has become of the friend,
the one in the big house?
Whatever,
It has happened yesterday.
He was still there the night before last.
Maybe I found a bigger one.
A guy with
a bigger house
Do not.
He tried to go back to his old
I work, then he ech .
- I wonder why?
- It's fine.
Is it the only pot?
Voucher.
And this do not miss it.
What?
- My house was very small.
- I know, you told me.
Eh!
It's yours, Hickey!
How is it supposed to
are we going to explain this?
To the Rams?
To the cops.
I'll think of something.
- Thank you, sir.
- Good sound.
As soon as possible, thank you.
We have got one.
Did they take the girl?
She did not appear.
It was an enclosure.
The broker was loaded,
so we do not know with
Who was negotiating
I do not want him to run away.
Save this
Very good.
It's dirty,
but there is no alternative.
It belongs to us.
The first play was ours.
If I do not cling to principles,
I could not believe in anything.
Clear.
Boggs saw the note together
to telf. of Farrow.
We thought that he could
being Mary Jane,
that had been
cited with Farrow
Why did not you notify?
It was just an assumption.
How they discovered it
the thugs?
They forced Burning.
What is this?
You know
and we do not!
You call the stadium,
there is a shooting,
a man dies, there are cold cuts
All over Los Angeles!
And you are
in the front row!
You should have been there,
you had Farrow's note.
And what else?
You used us
- You know it.
-Do you accuse us?
- I would like it.
- If you played it again,
I warn you that I'm going
to make sweat blood.
Have you heard?
Yes, we have o dos.
If they find out about the hotel,
we are ready.
Yes.
We have to find
That fox before them.
Shoes seller,
kitchen piche ...
There is a lot of work
for ambitious young people.
- You take it with laughter.
- Do not.
Let me see it, I want to
check the other two names.
Come on.
Billy Bledsoe, Elena Could
and one Mr. Leroy.
Name (s.
Only names.
We will look at the telephone guide.
We have to find
That fox
So, when you're older,
You will know many things.
In addition, what will you do?
the day when the boys
go back to school?
No, I do not need a secretary.
But if ever
I need it, you will be.
My name is Boggs.
I wish you can see Mrs. Could.
Elena Could.
Can you tell me what you want?
I want to talk about Farrow
and Mary Jane Bowen.
Do you mind waiting, please?
No, for that you have
that put a tooth underneath.
Sure, you have to
put a tooth underneath.
Everybody knows.
More teeth, more pasta.
You can take it out with a thread
or with a pair of pliers.
There's no need, honey.
I love you too, but
It's harder for me to say, you know.
Tell mam  to call me.
Yes, look good.
Ok, honey.
Adi s.
Say?
Over here, please.
Boggs?
What name is that, brother?
- Irland s.
- Caf  irland s?
- More or less.
- It's fine.
Lester, bring chairs.
Sit down
Come on, be comfortable.
What can I do for you?
- I'll tell you.
-Direct to the corner.
Okay?
Prepared?
Now.
- The girl wants to negotiate.
-When?
Tonight.
Warn the troop.
You take it very calmly.
Yes.
Is there something?
I have not found Bledsoe.
So I went to see
to Mr. Could.
What did he tell you?
A freak of
justice and equality.
No children, widow ...
It's in the North,
trying to recover Alcatraz.
That costs a lot of money.
Keep Mr. Leroy
and a house full of people.
What does he do?
He is a leader for his people.
And where do you go
to those happy people?
In La Brea,
between Watts and Belair.
Leroy: bald, wears glasses
of sun to be at home.
-S .
A heavyweight
Superstar of the ghetto.
- So ...
- So nothing.
Farrow made a decoration
or something like that for Mrs. Could.
Nobody heard about Mary Jane.
We're fine.
We do not have anything.
No customer,
no suspects, no clues.
There are no clues, nothing.
Why do not you know
Who has called?
-Who?
-Mary Jane
He wants to see us tonight.
She says she's scared
and wants to leave.
If we help her, we could
get the reward
- Damned if ...
- Exactly.
- Of course he lies.
-How did you know our number?
You can only know it by Rice,
so he already found it.
The black community does not try
become something different.
In fact, it is still psychologically
white in his behavior.
And for that, my leader,
our leader,
keep saying one
and again that black power
can not be jealous
of white power.
He has to be fed up with him.
I have to be ...
Remember, the fourth car will be
behind the door 32.
At the beginning of the eighth inning.
In the back seat.
Yes, she will be there.
In point, as they say.
Exact.
It has strained.
All your contacts have been
driven away by those stupid ones.
They are not stupid.
She will have to negotiate
at our price. Tonight.
I told you I would do it.
That bitch is desperate.
The desperate foxes
They are dangerous, brother.
Will work?
I'll send Phillippe.
Disguised.
We're here
Hey.
It's her.
Come on!
Hi.
Mary Jane?
Watch out.
Close the door!
Shut the door, idiot!
Five hundred cars here
plasters bastards give him to mine.
Well, eye for an eye.
- Go with Mary Jane.
-What?
It's Bledsoe.
The one we did not find.
I need a rev lver
bigger I do not give one.
What are we going to say this time?
This time we need
a lawyer.
That bitch has played it for us.
S ?
Wait, wait a moment!
What are you talking about?
From Starsky and Hutch.
They just organized in the stadium
of the Dodgers. Another one dead.
We have got the money,
but not the girl.
The thugs have escaped.
And what excuse do they give?
They say the girl called them.
She said she would not appear
if he warned us
I want them made dust.
By concealment of evidence
and criminal behavior!
Mach cal the bones to both!
I'm going to call Sacramento
to denounce them!
They will take away the license,
I will tear them to pieces, lock them up!
They have some proof
so I can help them?
From what I've heard,
the thing has become ugly.
- Get the test.
-  May I get it?
How much do you have to pay him?
They caught you with
hands in the dough.
Move some threads.
Does not he have any cane?
I'm a lawyer.
Not a magician.
- We will have judgment.
- Unless the charges are dropped.
I do not know.
What?
It's time to leave.
Leave what?
There's nothing to do
in this profession, Frank.
Nowhere.
Has no sense.
He is right.
A private investigator
It is no longer what it was.
With the latest legislation of
Sacramento two years ago,
you are not more than
process meat.
It does not lead to anything.
Of course, he drives
Four hundred of the big ones.
Well, we have to
find that bitch.
They are putting you
against the wall.
Yes. Well, this is called
"a strong offensive".
What are you going to do?
I will have to counterattack
and move on.
I'll see you after work.
Are you coming?
I will wait for you.
Yes, that's fine.
Things are improving.
And you call them soldiers!
You call them soldiers!
They have failed!
Two cars to the fucking shit!
Eliminated by two handicapped people.
Tell me, how is it possible?
Show me!
I want to know why they failed!
What is it?
Stupidity?  cobard a?
Why the hell are you coming here?
For the music.
I think it
They have taken your beer.
Come on, I'm going to buy you a car.
First you were going to sell my house
and now you're going to buy me a car.
I'm going to buy you a car
if you forget the house
- It was a good house.
- Was.
It still is.
At least I do not know
It has fallen down a cliff.
Where are the papers
to be able to collect the insurance?
It's late, they've expired.
Timed out.
- Frank, Frank.
Listen out.
Everyone in this city
wants to finish with us.
We can not go worse.
Frank, do not you understand?
We went out in all the newspapers.
They are going to bury us.
One way or another.
Yes, it is here.
Edith is here.
It will go up right away
and then we will go.
Did not she get thrown out of here?
Someone owed him a favor.
Are you tough?
Thank you, Frank!
Muñerete
Where are we going?
On the street.
Mary Jane does not
he will call again.
Why would he do it?
The bosses and us
we press it.
He does not want to be near
if any of us dies.
Sacrificed two intermediaries.
That means he had found
someone to sell.
Mary Jane had a lot of deal
with the brother of the? florist
The one in prison.
I'll go tomorrow morning.
- You're still without a car.
- Ya, I'll find something.
What are you going to do?
I'll start with the beach house.
- The last assault.
- That's.
Are you okay?
-What is this?
- It's a bullet.
I'll take it.
S ?
Listen, the thugs have entered
in my house. They have destroyed it.
Also go for yours.
They were not looking for anything.
Bad business
They have destroyed it
just to get revenge.
They have been here.
Damn fans.
In the middle of the night.
He has come.
He says he wants to go home.
I think it is true.
But I also think that we
You owe a lot of interest.
I think he owes us a bonus.
We have to move forward in
the deal with Rice and the black man.
What are you doing here?
Nyona is not here!
She is dead.
And you know.
I do not want to see you
around here never again.
You're a garbage!
Two years ago that
you are rotten   Dead!
I do not want to see your face ever!
Never again!
- Come on kid.
- Come on.
- Come on, tell her.
- Come on, come on.
It has been missing!
-  Is everything ready?
- Yes.
Well, I do not want
that there are more failures.
Agree.
Are you okay?
Well, I've been in jail.
Burning came under the word.
Before yesterday a woman
He went to look for him.
Firm :
Mary Florida Burning.
Wife.
Bingo.
I took his address
to the official.
So let's go.
Get up.
I know you want the thugs.
We will find the woman.
They will not be far away.
Damn, they're not coming here.
It is an occasion.
Our occasion.
Okay, you quit.
Great.
Sit and spin around here.
You have chosen a good place.
At least, here
we will not stay dry.
Bob.
Put me a drink, please.
I will accompany my friend.
Oh, Frank.
Frank, you can not
leave me in the lurch.
They are going to bury us.
Only because you can not
get out of your head
to that stupid
and pitiful bitch.
And you're the one who says it.
You can stay here,
because I go for them.
I want twenty-five thousand.
If you want, you can stay
ah  sitting forever.
But you can not make her come back.
To the,
the only thing you can do is
Try to get over it.
Try it.
Now I'm going to go out there
and I'm going to catch them.
Tell me where you are.
Tell me where you are
or I will kill you.
I will do it.
Do not get depressed, because
you will not get anything.
It is very difficult to carry a l o
of four hundred thousand dollars
from prison.
You did very well.
You still have Mary Jane.
It must be a woman's devil.
I killed Farrow because
He wanted too much chop.
Represent the show
until you left.
He is a woman devil.
They will process you, but there is no evidence.
They do not want to get dirty.
So maybe you're going home.
There are things that could
be much worse.
Pi nsalo.
Mr. Rice,
Greet Mr. Boggs.
Mr. Rice.
Mr. Leroy,
Greet Mr. Hickey.
So he fell off the cliff.
A pity.
My partner has
a bargain for you.
Magnificent house,
great neighborhood.
Esc chenle.
Do only what
Mr. Hickey tell you.
We are going to do everything as
It was planned, okay?
- All right, Mr. Leroy?
- Agree.
-Why is this place?
- We used to come here.
It's okay, come out and get ready.
Make them know how
if everything went well.
Take the bag.
Nobody has shown up.
Who cares?
Thank you.
There is no need
It still does not lead to anything.
I know, you already told me.