NARRATOR:
In the criminal justice system
the people are represented by two
separate yet equally important groups,
the police
who investigate crime
and the district attorneys
who prosecute the offenders.
These are their stories.
Okay. Waiting room.
Deal is anything on the floor
or in the couch, we keep.
One time, I found a $50 bill.
My last trainee,
he told one of the doctors.
You notice
he isn't my trainee anymore.
Got it?
Yes, sir.
You see here?
Two quarters and a dime.
Now, the doctor's office,
that's a different story.
If you find a penny on the floor,
you vacuum around it. You got that?
Yes, sir.
Sanchez, I think
we're gonna get along fine.
(GRUNTING)
What the...
(CHATTERING ON POLICE RADIO) The victim is a shrink.
A Dr. Lillian Hampton.
She's on staff with the clinic. The
cleaning crew found her about 8:45.
Anybody else in the building?
There was another cleaning crew on
the fourth floor, but that was it.
We called the director
of the clinic, a Dr. Latham.
What about her family?
Well, Latham said
she had an ex in Westchester.
We called, but there was no answer.
Thanks, Joe.
Probably busy working
on his second wife.
Somebody tried to shrink her
head the old-fashioned way.
Three strikes, she was out. One on
the forehead, two on the left side.
We found blood on the walls.
The perp probably ended up
wearing some.
Cleaning crew entered the building at 8:20.
They didn't see anybody leave.
No sign of a struggle. Could've
been somebody she knew.
Somebody who didn't want her money.
Credit cards, $40.
Lady liked to sweat.
"Toughen-Up Gymworks."
Not tough enough.
Detectives,
looks like our murder weapon.
Bits of hair and blood
on the sharp edge.
(SIGHING)
"With gratitude from the Coalition
of Mental Health Clinics."
Should've given her
a plaque instead.
I'm still in shock.
It was a horrible loss.
Lillian
was a brilliant therapist.
We saw the diplomas
stacked on the wall.
Lot of talent
for a free clinic.
Well, she could have made a lot
more money in private practice,
but she preferred working here with
the schizophrenics and delusionals.
I mean, anybody our colleagues
on Park Avenue refused to take.
What time
was her last appointment?
I have
the master schedule here.
She had a 7:00.
With who? Client records
are confidential.
We just need the name, Doc,
not the whole work-up.
Megan Nelson.
But I believe Dr. Hampton had somebody
else in the office after her.
Why would you believe that?
Well, when I left a little after
8:00, I heard a man in there.
It was a very intense session.
He was yelling something like,
"How could you do that?"
Someone's yelling,
you don't check it out?
We hear a lot of that
in the clinic.
Well, if he was in the waiting
room, maybe Megan Nelson saw him.
You know where we can find her?
Yeah.
This is very upsetting.
Dr. Hampton
was everything to me.
A year ago,
I couldn't get out of bed,
forget about
holding down a job.
She gave me a new life.
We're very,
very sorry for your loss.
Yesterday,
you were her last appointment.
What time did you leave?
It was 7:50.
Dr. Hampton's very strict
about the 50-minute hour.
That was good for me.
The structure, I mean.
So, now, as you were leaving, did
you see anybody in the waiting room
or maybe hanging around
downstairs?
No. I was in a hurry to get to work.
I don't like to be late.
Try to remember, Megan.
We're thinking there might have
been a man waiting to see her.
A man?
There's Julio.
He works in the parking lot.
And there was a man in a green car.
He pulled in to park.
You remember anything
about this man?
He honked his horn at Julio.
He seemed very impatient.
That's all I remember.
The jerk in the green Jag?
Yeah, he was here.
Honked at me 'cause I didn't
take his money quick enough.
He drove in and parked in the
corner, like he always does.
Is he a regular?
He's been here a few times.
So, what's he do after he parks,
break out a deck of cars?
Usually the drill is Dr. Hampton
comes down to talk to him.
So, who is this guy,
the boyfriend?
Hey, none of my business.
Last night,
any change in the drill?
I don't know. I left at
8:00, before she came down.
Well, while you were
minding your business,
did you happen to notice
anything else about this guy?
Like height, weight,
color of hair?
Salt-and-pepper hair. Polo shirt.
You know, the golfing type.
He has a sticker on the visor.
Crestmont Club.
Okay, thanks.
Crestmont.
It's up in Westchester.
I got 5 bucks
that says it's the ex.
They got a couple of nice
par fives there.
Wonder how hard
he swings his driver?
Yeah, I was there last night. About 10 minutes.
I never left the car.
Why not? Do you like
the smell of exhaust?
I don't like psychodramas in the
middle of a skid-row outhouse.
I take it you don't approve
of your wife's job.
Pro bono psychiatry. Lillian thought
she was doing something good.
Maybe she was.
Which brings us back to what you
were doing there, Dr. Hampton.
I was doing penance for
missing two alimony payments.
Now I bring
the checks in person.
$10,000.
When she didn't come down
to get it, I left.
You never called up?
Why should I?
And no disrespect, but I jumped
through enough hoops for her.
Well, right now, it's only your
word that you never went upstairs.
I was on my cell phone to my
girlfriend the whole time.
I was still talking to her
when I drove out.
She has a very nice voice.
Must've been a lovely marriage.
A guy like that, she should have
been paying him to stay away.
You talk to his girlfriend?
Yeah.
She is Becky Price.
She does have a nice voice.
IUDs confirmed
they were on the phone.
Twenty minutes later they were
sitting at the River Cafe.
Doesn't give him much time
to smack his wife around and then
get the blood off his golf shirt.
Well, we know
about the girlfriend.
What about Dr. Hampton?
Any man in her life?
Yeah, but his name's Fluffy,
and he's been neutered.
Other than that, her social
calendar's pretty light.
Hey, look, if it's a choice
between work and play,
my bet is the work killed her.
(SIGHS) Yeah, but without
the patient records,
we have no way of knowing which
kernel was getting ready to pop.
Could be it's popped before
and got arrested.
Let's wait and see if Latent
comes back with prints.
(HORNS HONKING)
What are you smiling about?
We got hits
on two sets of prints.
Paul White, felonious assault,
and Edward Brennig,
attacked a police officer.
My kind of guy. Either one of them
leave a print on the murder weapon?
It was wiped clean.
So, which one of the mentally challenged
do you want to talk to first?
Brennig or White?
Oh, Brennig.
Let's see if he's changed his
opinion of police officers.
Edward Brennig?
Nice badge. What do you want?
For starters,
you could put the can down.
Any other tricks
I can do for you?
Yeah, instant recall.
Last Tuesday night,
between 7:00 and 8:30.
I was home, watching Court TV.
Picking up pointers for the
next time you beat up a cop?
Come on, give me a break,
all right?
I got into a bar fight.
I didn't mean to hit the cop.
I love cops.
Yeah, it shows.
Maybe you can tell us why we found
your prints at the Amsterdam Clinic.
What'd I do, forget to
vacuum underneath the couch?
Vacuuming?
Is that part of your therapy?
Therapy? Hey, I ain't one of
those fruit loops, all right?
The company that cleans the place,
they hire me when they're shorthanded.
Last time was two weeks ago.
We straight now?
Do I look like the type
to hit somebody?
As a matter of fact,
Mr. White, you do.
I just pushed the dude. I didn't
like the way he was looking at Alex.
Well, fill us in. Who's Alex?
My cat.
Dr. Hampton
at the Amsterdam Clinic,
I heard she looked
at Alex funny, too.
Alex and her don't get along.
So, you did see her recently.
Maybe it was Tuesday night.
No, that was the night
I got my prescription adjusted
at the outpatient pharmacy,
Bellevue Hospital.
Well, I see it says Tuesday,
but it doesn't say what time.
Oh, well,
I was there all night waiting.
They're not very organized there.
Alex was very upset with them.
Alex was upset
with Dr. Hampton, too, huh?
Yeah, yeah. That's why I called her
and left a message on her machine
to say I wasn't coming back.
Sounds good to us.
Meantime, why don't you
come on down to the precinct?
We'll get you a nice hot meal.
You got something for Alex?
Oh, sure, sure.
As long as he likes
day-old donuts.
Well,
nix on the donuts for Alex.
Bologna was a big hit, though.
Yeah, well, nix on
Mr. White as our suspect.
Bellevue remembers him
and Alex.
The orderly's
got the scratches to prove it.
White said he left a message
on Hampton's machine.
I didn't see a machine in her office,
so it must have been voice mail.
Okay. Now, our guy
isn't in the appointment book.
Suppose he needed an emergency
tune-up from Dr. Hampton.
He calls late, leaves a message.
Bingo.
WOMAN: Hi, Dr. Hampton.
It's Miss Schwab.
Another woman. Next.
MAN:
Lillian, it's Dr. Morris.
I have the speech sketched out for
the association. I'm faxing it over.
(TAPE REWINDING)
(SIGHING)
Hey, Mike, when we get to some
heavy breathing, I'll wake you up.
WOMAN: Hi, Dr. Hampton. It's
Jeanine at the Vertical Club.
Just confirming
your personal workout session.
Hey, wait a minute. Go back.
(TAPE REWINDING)
Hi, Dr. Hampton. It's Jeanine
at the Vertical Club.
Wasn't that gym bag in Hampton's
office from someplace else?
Yeah. Toughen-Up something.
You have the inventory
from the bag?
Here we go.
Sweatshirt, sweatpants,
socks, swipe card. No name.
Check with the club
and get a name.
BRISCOE:
We've got a swipe card.
This isn't the Y. Our members
expect a little privacy.
Well, this member may have
crushed a woman's skull.
Please don't make us
get a warrant.
Okay. Give me the card.
In case you're interested,
we got a two-years-for-the-price-of-one
special going.
You ought to think about that,
Mike.
I'm definitely
thinking about it.
Here he is. Bobby Walker.
He lives at 49-A
Horatio Street.
(BABY CRYING)
Detectives, I guess you have
some more questions for me.
Are you roommates
with Bobby Walker?
Not really.
Well, was Walker not really with you
at Dr. Hampton's the other night?
That's impossible.
MAN: Keep it down.
Okay, where is he?
He's not here right now.
We can see that.
Where can we find him?
He's in here. I'm Bobby.
Megan,
how long are we gonna have to
sit here listening to you say
that you're a guy named Bobby?
You think I'm making this up?
I think you have
a very unique imagination.
Bobby. Is that some kind
of nickname for Roberta?
No, Bobby is a he.
He's who I am sometimes.
Dr. Hampton diagnosed me with
Multiple Personality Disorder.
Okay. I'm gonna play along.
Now, tell me what Bob
did last night.
I can't.
When I switch, I don't remember
what the last alter did.
Alter?
Alternate personalities.
I have two of them, not including me.
There's Bobby and Nancy.
Dr. Hampton was helping me
integrate them.
Okay, can we talk to Bobby?
It's not like
I can turn a dial.
Believe me, if Bobby did something
terrible, I want to help you.
Why don't you tell us
what you do remember?
Now, you said you left Dr. Hampton's
office just before 8:00.
Yes. I remember
being in the office.
And then I saw the clock
in the lobby.
This is very stressful.
You're not kidding.
She got a Multiple Personality
Disorder diagnosis from her doctor?
That's what she says. This
only happens on Oprah, right?
It's a diagnosis that's
caused a lot of controversy.
Some doctors say that it's
caused by a childhood trauma.
Others say
that it's caused by ideas
planted in the mind of the
patient by the therapist.
Oh, the therapist tells her
she's crazy, so she acts crazy.
She's not acting. Give her a lie detector.
Chances are she'd pass.
She says she blanks when this
Bobby personality comes out.
That's probably true.
Unless the different personalities
are communicating with each other,
she wouldn't have any memory
of what each one's doing.
Well, do these personalities
talk to each other?
There are therapists who have
their patients keep a journal,
so that each personality can write
their thoughts during the switch.
That way, they can leave
notes for each other.
Yeah, fat chance Megan's just
gonna hand us her journal.
Well, we know we don't have enough
to get a warrant to look for it.
She said she went straight to
work from Hampton's office.
Yeah, Miss Punctuality.
With all that blood spatter
at the scene,
some of Hampton's blood
must've gotten on her clothes.
What'd she do, run through a
car wash on her way to work?
Megan's been working here
nearly a year.
Always on time,
keeps the orders straight.
Best of all, she doesn't burn up
the phone with personal business.
When she came in on Tuesday,
how did she seem?
She seemed okay.
Far as that goes for her.
Meaning sometimes
she wasn't okay?
Well, some days
she wants to be called Bobby.
Other days, it's Nancy.
All the same to me. Whatever
the name, she does great work.
So, Tuesday, did you notice
anything unusual about her clothes?
No. Coat and a dress.
She say anything? Yeah, she
said "sorry" a million times.
She was late.
Not normal for her.
Among other things.
So, how late was she?
She punched in at 8:52.
Excuse me.
Clinic's 15 minutes away.
That leaves about 45 minutes.
Sounds like probable cause
to search her place.
I'd like to know
which personality's into this.
That would be Nancy. She's a
personal favorite of mine.
I bet.
Your boss know you could be
charging for two roommates?
Hey, Miss Nelson, she pays her
rent on time. She's quiet.
Why should I make
trouble for her?
Hey, Mike, look at this.
Computer disks.
Look at the titles.
"Megan. Nancy. Bobby."
Let's put Bobby in.
Looks like some kind of diary.
Yeah. We'll get it printed up.
So, what is it she did, anyway?
We don't know
if she did anything.
You see her last Tuesday night?
No, I didn't.
You ever talk to her
when she calls herself Bobby?
Bobby, now,
he's a piece of work.
He chewed up that bunch upstairs
for playing the music too loud.
Anybody ever complain
about her?
No, like I said before,
she was quiet.
Except when her father
came around.
They had a couple of blowouts
right out here.
You happen to hear
the topic of conversation?
Yeah. She said
he was harassing her,
and if I ever saw him around the
building, I should call the cops.
She had a restraining order
against him.
It was all
her therapist's idea.
She thought I was interfering
with Megan's progress.
And were you?
I was trying to keep my daughter from
going completely off the deep end,
which is where Dr. Hampton
was sending her.
Well, no offense, but it looks
to me like she's already there.
My wife died when Megan was three.
I raised her by myself.
Granted, she was troubled.
Then a year ago,
she saw Dr. Hampton.
All of a sudden,
she was three troubled people.
I couldn't figure out
what the hell was going on.
That must've been
pretty tough to live with.
I could have managed,
but Hampton insisted
that Megan needed to move out
and be on her own.
At first,
I went along with that.
Then Megan refused to see me.
She wouldn't take my calls.
Another one of the doctor's ideas?
That's right.
She was controlling
my daughter.
Using her to prove
some quack theory.
Megan was holding down a job,
paying her rent.
Sounds like a solid citizen
to me.
Minimum wage, plus tips?
A dump in the West Village?
That is not a life.
Did you ever discuss your
feelings with Dr. Hampton?
I discussed them
with her answering service.
She refused to talk to me
about it.
Megan's a complicated kid.
Raising her by himself
can't be that easy.
Yeah? Well, I don't buy
that father-knows-best routine
that Nelson gave us last night.
Especially with
some doctor butting in.
Hey, when I was drinking,
my kid had a therapist
who kept telling her
what a lousy father I was.
I didn't like the message, but I
never thought about killing him.
Your kid didn't get a restraining
order against you, Lennie.
Why don't you find out
why Megan did?
I'll see if they got
her diaries printed out.
All right.
Bobby's diary,
the day before the murder.
"Nancy left a note for me.
She called me a liar."
"That bitch
better watch herself."
Sounds like a nice guy.
Nancy's diary.
"I can't trust Bobby or Megan."
"They promise to clean the kitchen,
and they don't. I hate liars."
Sounds like
one big happy family.
Got the court records
on the restraining order.
The judge issued two
the same day.
One to keep Mr. Nelson
away from his daughter,
and another to keep him away
from Dr. Hampton.
Why? Because he harassed
her voice mail?
Turns out he faced off with her a
couple of times outside the clinic.
I'm with Nancy. I hate liars.
Hey,
it gets worse for Mr. Nelson.
Here, in Bobby's diary,
the day of.
"I gotta make sure
Megan remembers"
"her old man has to be
at the appointment tonight."
Let's see if Megan remembered.
Here we go.
"I talked to Dad.
He promises he'll be there."
"I'm worried, but Dr. Hampton says
it's necessary for him to come."
Okay, so, if Nelson was there,
the screaming that the clinic director
heard could have been him, right?
Okay, Dr. Latham, tell us if you
recognize any of these voices.
Number one, go ahead.
How could you do that?
Number two.
Number three.
How could you do that?
Could he say that louder?
Number three,
say that again louder, please.
How could you do that?
That's him.
Thank you, Dr. Latham.
Well, that's a positive ID.
Of what?
A booming voice, originally
heard through a hardwood door?
Excuse me while I share
a good laugh with my client.
If it's not enough to hold him, is it
enough to get us into his apartment?
To find what?
Well, for openers,
how about some of Hampton's blood
on one of his Armani suits?
I'll talk to Judge Walters. He
should be back from lunch by now.
My second wife always wanted
a walk-in closet.
Now I finally got one.
Trouble is, I live in it.
I got something in the kitchen.
The luminol brought up trace
blood smudges around the sink.
There's two, each less than
five millimeters wide.
All right, is that enough to run a match?
No problem.
Mr. Nelson.
Excuse me, gentlemen,
I'm on a call to China.
You're gonna wish
you were in China.
Frank Nelson, you're under arrest for
the murder of Dr. Lillian Hampton.
You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you do say can and will be
used against you in a court of law.
You understand? You have
the right to an attorney.
Trace amounts of Jo.-negative?
By the time I'm finished
with your blood evidence,
I'll have the jurors convinced
it was their blood you found.
The fact is,
it's Dr. Hampton's blood.
His daughter's diaries
place him at the scene.
He was heard screaming
at Dr. Hampton.
He was heard
raising his voice, period.
You have this all wrong.
I had no reason to kill her.
She was worried enough about you
to get a restraining order.
She didn't want to be accountable for
what she was doing to my daughter.
And you care so much
for your daughter
that you'd kill anyone who
got between you, is that it?
You don't believe him,
then talk to his daughter.
They left together, and
Dr. Hampton was still alive.
I remember
leaving with my father.
Dr. Hampton was still alive.
Then why didn't you tell the
police your father was there?
I guess I forgot.
We read in your diary
that you were worried
about what might happen
at that session.
Why?
I don't remember
what happened in session.
Anyway, I don't have to tell you
anything that happens in therapy.
That's private.
You do,
if you expect me to believe that
your father didn't kill Dr. Hampton.
I'm not feeling very well.
I think you should go.
First she avoids him
like the plague.
Now she's lying to protect him.
Doesn't make a lot of sense.
It does if she's scared of him.
I didn't get the feeling
that she was.
She seemed more confused
than anything.
With three personalities
at the wheel, who wouldn't be?
Maybe the one who's running
scared is Frank Nelson.
He interfered with her therapy.
Could be he felt threatened.
I went through her diaries.
As far as churning up family secrets,
the sessions seemed pretty tame.
The juicy stuff would be locked
up in Hampton's medical records.
Which you can't get to
without her consent.
Was Hampton
her first therapist?
According to her father, she has
a history of mental illness.
But no one's volunteered the
names of the other therapists.
Until she moved out, her
father was paying her bills.
Including the medical ones.
Subpoena his bank records
and get a name.
Megan had already been through Freud
and Jung, with little result.
Well, you think your therapy
was more effective?
More flexible.
I use talk therapy,
rebirthing, hypnosis.
Whatever works
for the particular patient.
What worked for Megan?
You know I can't get into
that with you.
All I will say is she had
trouble with the therapy.
Meaning?
She had a bad session, and
then she just stopped coming.
Did you find out why?
I called her, but I only
spoke with her father.
He said she'd decided
to stop therapy.
Do you think he had anything
to do with why she stopped?
He just told me he wanted her
file sent to a Dr. Coleman.
Well, Mr. Nelson is the one
who retained my services
after he spent an hour
grilling me on my credentials.
What did he want?
Oh, anything that worked.
But it had to be conservative treatment.
No New Age therapies.
I fit the bill,
so he sent Megan here.
At that time, did she have
these multiple personalities?
No. I don't subscribe
to that kind of diagnosis.
Megan had one
very borderline personality.
We worked on it
once a week for two years.
I take it she wasn't cured?
We came close to a breakthrough.
Then Megan backed away.
She decided to stop coming?
Yes.
Sometimes dredging up a painful
memory can be too difficult to face,
even when a patient
wants the therapy to work.
This painful memory, did it have
something to do with Frank Nelson?
Even if I were free to tell
you, I don't know what it is.
But, yes, I believe it does have
something to do with her father.
A painful memory?
What are we talking about,
child abuse?
They wouldn't say.
I spoke to four doctors. I got four
versions of patient privilege.
All they would say was Megan's the one
who pulled the plug on the therapy.
This time it was Frank Nelson.
One doctor suggested he was
the cause of her trauma.
But unless Megan confirms it or
hands over her medical records,
that's as much
as we're going to know.
Maybe we could force her hand.
She's providing
her father with an alibi.
We could turn that
into a charge of conspiracy.
How does that
get us her records?
Her lawyer has a client with
Multiple Personality Disorder.
What defense does that suggest?
An insanity plea.
Right.
She puts her mental state at
issue, she waives privilege
and has to hand over
her medical records.
Let's pick her up.
Two of you?
We're getting something to go.
Sorry, folks, we're going
to need your waitress.
Megan Nelson, you're under arrest
for conspiracy to commit murder.
You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say can and will be
used against you in a court of law.
Nice technique, McCoy.
Squeeze my client's head hard enough,
maybe her memory'll come back.
Well, it seems to come and go.
She forgets
her father was there.
She remembers Dr. Hampton
was alive.
She forgets
what they talked about.
She has Multiple Personality Disorder.
She can't help it. She blanks out.
And we're supposed to
take her word for it?
Claire, you're going to have
a hard enough time
proving the underlying crime,
let alone a conspiracy.
And from what I hear, your case against
Frank Nelson is far from made.
I'll make it when I put her
on trial with her father.
Given her psychiatric history,
don't you think a trial
would be a waste of time?
Well, send her
medical records to our expert.
If she thinks she's insane,
we'll talk.
Here. February 22nd.
Hampton reports that Megan
has a recurring vision
of her father standing
at the top of the stairs,
quote "looking down at her
like a giant."
A memory of child abuse?
No. This isn't about
child abuse.
A couple of weeks later,
Hampton wrote
that the Nancy personality
was urging Megan
to tell the truth
about her mother's death.
And then this,
a week before she was killed.
"A painful session."
"Megan struggled, resisted."
"Finally,
the memory became clear."
"She's three years old.
She's in her bedroom."
"She hears her parents argue."
"She runs out of her room.
She hears a scream."
"She sees her father push her
mother down the stairs."
"She sees her mother lying
at the bottom, not moving."
She witnessed
her mother's murder.
At the very least,
she thinks she did.
And they dropped the bomb on
Mr. Nelson during the last session.
According to Dr. Hampton's notes,
that's what they intended to do.
So, two people
knew what he did.
One's dead, and the other
can be dismissed as a lunatic.
See what records you can find
on her mother's death.
I was the fourth officer
on the scene.
Carol Nelson
was on the bottom landing.
She'd gone ass-over-teakettle
down two flights of stairs.
Any indication
she got a little help?
Yeah, from a half quart
of 18-year-old Scotch.
Mrs. Nelson was one of the more
colorful characters on the beat.
So, she had a drinking problem.
Lovely lady. I mean,
really a very happy drunk.
She liked to sing show tunes in her
skivvies from her bedroom window.
Mr. Nelson must've loved that.
Well, I heard they had arguments.
Was he there
the night she died?
He was home,
best I can remember.
I wasn't the investigating officer.
Who was?
Arnie Wallace,
God rest his soul.
Fall in the home resulting in
accidental death. A hat trick.
Could've been filed under accidental,
homeowners, or through the life policy.
I'll need a year and name
of the insured.
1977. Carol Nelson.
Here you go. Carol Nelson.
$500,000 payout
on the life policy.
What was the cause of death?
Accidental fall.
Blood alcohol level was 0.18.
Is that all there is?
Once the claim is paid, we wait five
years, then we purge the files.
Adjuster's reports, witness statements,
medicals, they're all destroyed.
I pulled the files from the
police and the insurance company.
The death was ruled accidental.
Based on what?
Frank Nelson's say-so?
Who knows?
The police filled in the right
boxes then dumped their reports.
The insurance company cleans out
their files every five years.
Thumbnail version,
Carol Nelson had a blood alcohol of 0.18.
She tripped and fell.
"My wife's drunk.
She slipped on the stairs."
Haven't you heard that before?
SELIG: By now, I'm sure your expert
agrees my client was legally insane.
Your client's sanity
isn't relevant at this point.
I've dismissed the charges
against her without prejudice.
I'm waiting for the other shoe.
I want her to testify
against her father.
I've read your medical records.
I know why your father
killed Dr. Hampton.
I want to know
why you are protecting the man
who killed your mother.
That's what you believe,
isn't it?
I happen to believe it,
too, Megan.
You want to know what really
happened, you ask me!
Who am I talking to?
Bobby.
I'm Bobby.
You were there?
Yeah, I was there all right.
Tell me what happened.
It's all Dr. Hampton's fault.
Did Frank Nelson kill Dr. Hampton?
No.
Hampton was trying to get rid of me.
She wanted me to leave Megan.
She didn't give me a choice.
I had to kill her.
It's the father. It's the daughter.
It's Bobby.
You need a scorecard
to keep track.
This confession sound
right to you? No.
Male personalities
are protectors.
If Bobby's taking the rap,
he's trying to protect Megan.
From what?
A fate worse than prison?
Maybe he's trying to protect her from
having to testify against her father.
That'd make sense
if her father threatened her.
So, Bobby gives her a way out.
(PHONE BUZZING)
Yes?
Thanks.
Nelson's attorney.
He wants to meet.
Of course he does.
Satisfied, Jack? My client
did not kill Dr. Hampton.
Really? Did he kill his wife?
I did not kill my wife.
Megan saw you do it.
Dr. Hampton
uncovered the memory.
Talk to the police.
Read the reports.
We tried to.
There's nothing left.
I'll tell you the same thing I told
Megan and that therapist of hers.
Talk to my wife's sister
in Poughkeepsie.
She was there.
She saw what happened.
Fine. You're saying
what Megan remembers is false.
Of course it's false.
I told Megan
her mother was a drunk.
I am the only one who ever
cared about my daughter.
Seems to me
you just lost your motive.
On the contrary. Dr. Hampton
convinced Megan you were a killer.
Would it make you any less
angry that it was a lie?
You try explaining that
to the jury.
I'll settle
for Bobby's confession.
Bobby isn't competent
to testify.
You don't think so?
File a motion.
Multiple personalities?
Switching?
Forget competency, Mr. Weaver. Are
you sure your witness is even sane?
It makes no difference, Judge.
In Barker v. Washburn,
even if the witness is legally
insane, if they understand the oath
and can give a correct account of
what happened, they can testify.
That only begs the question, who
are they calling as a witness?
Megan, who may be insane, or Bobby,
a figment of her imagination?
It makes no difference that
Bobby confessed to the crime?
What matters
is that Bobby doesn't exist.
Our expert can establish that Bobby
can form and remember impressions
and can talk about them
intelligently.
That is the standard
for competency.
Mr. McCoy, isn't the only issue
here one of credibility?
It would be like asking a jury to
judge the credibility of a Martian.
It's beyond their experience.
That's why we have experts. Who I
want to hear from in the morning
before I decide if I'm going to
turn this witness loose on a jury.
DR. OLIVET: When Megan takes
on the persona of Bobby,
she's in an altered
mental state.
She uses it as a crutch to
cope with the outside world.
JACK: So, in your opinion,
Bobby doesn't exist?
Bobby is a distorted reflection
of Megan's inner feelings,
memories, fears.
The fact that she's
given him a name
doesn't make him any more real.
And would Bobby's testimony
be reliable? No.
Like testimony derived through
hypnosis or truth serum,
it's elicited from
a hyper-suggestible state.
Thank you.
When Megan switches, she's not
suddenly rendered unconscious, is she?
No.
Megan just takes on
a new identity,
which can walk and talk
like anyone else.
That's correct.
So, Bobby could go
to the movies, drive a car,
or even commit a crime.
But it would be Megan
doing all those things.
She just believes it's Bobby.
But there's no reason why Bobby couldn't
tell us about it, is there, Doctor?
In theory, no.
Bobby comes out during
the dissociative process.
He takes both physical and
psychological control of Megan's body.
Is Bobby aware
of what's happening to him?
Bobby is just like any of us,
a functioning person
with all of his faculties.
Bobby has a memory?
Oh, yes.
And if we could
bring Bobby out,
he'd be able to convey
those memories to us.
Certainly.
Thank you, Doctor.
Would you characterize Bobby
as a protector personality?
Well, that's the typical role of the
male personality in the female patient.
If Megan can't handle the stress
of a particular situation,
Bobby does the coping for her.
Yes.
Bobby would do whatever
it took to protect Megan.
That's his role,
as long as it helps Megan.
So, he would even lie for her,
wouldn't he?
I suppose he might.
In your opinion, Doctor, can
Bobby be brought out on command?
Switching can be triggered.
Mr. McCoy
inadvertently did it.
I believe we could,
using a comparable stimulus.
If you think you can bring
Bobby out, Dr. Cantrel,
then I want to hear from him.
You know, Megan, Mr. McCoy thinks
you're trying to protect your father,
a man who killed your mother.
I told him I'm not.
Well, he says you're afraid to
tell us what really happened.
I can't.
Come on, Megan.
What are you afraid of,
the truth?
Or is it something else?
Come on, Megan, admit it.
It's all an act, isn't it?
There is no Bobby.
There is no Nancy.
You're just hiding behind them
so we'll feel sorry for you.
So you can lie and do whatever you
want, and you won't be responsible.
Why don't you just
leave her the hell alone?
Is that you, Bobby?
Who does it look like?
I understand
you killed Dr. Hampton.
Is that true?
Yeah.
Like I told them,
Dr. Hampton wanted me gone.
She didn't understand
how much Megan needs me.
And that's why you killed her?
I'm the only one
who sticks by Megan.
Tell me what happened, Bobby.
How did you kill Dr. Hampton?
It's just me and that bitch.
She's rocking back and forth in her
chair, chewing on a pencil. So smug.
Telling me I'm bad for Megan.
What about her?
What did you do, Bobby?
That's when I did it.
I pounded her in the head.
I had to.
It was either me or her.
Thank you, Bobby.
I have one question
for the witness, Your Honor.
Go ahead, Mr. McCoy.
You said you struck Dr. Hampton
while she was seated at her desk.
Is that correct?
That's how it happened, yeah.
Thank you.
The witness is lying.
If that's what you think, you have the
opportunity to cross-examine at trial.
Dr. Hampton was struck while she was
standing at the door of her office,
not at her desk.
Bobby didn't know that
because Bobby didn't kill her.
Then how does Bobby know
so many details of the crime?
Maybe Bobby read the paper,
but not the case file.
As a matter of law, Bobby can't
testify because he wasn't there.
I have to agree with Mr. McCoy.
Judge.
If I allow this witness to
testify, I'd be suborning perjury.
That's my ruling.
I'm not letting Bobby testify.
I give Weaver an hour before
he calls looking for a deal.
What, it's not good enough?
We proved Bobby wasn't there.
What's bothering me is,
why wasn't he?
Megan has a restraining order
against her father.
They're having a confrontation
about him killing her mother.
It escalates
to the point of murder.
Where's Bobby, her protector?
Maybe her psyche's not as
fine-tuned as a Ferrari.
We assumed that Nelson
was furious at the doctor
for convincing Megan
he was a killer.
But suppose Megan
believed her father?
Then he'd have no reason
to kill Dr. Hampton.
What changed Megan's mind?
He told her to check out her story.
What was it he said?
Call the mother's sister
in Poughkeepsie.
Oh, that was a long time ago.
Things were bad
between Frank and my sister.
I mean, Carol was thinking
about moving out.
That's why I was there
that night.
Was Frank ever violent with her?
No.
I mean, they argued,
slammed a few doors,
but that was it.
Megan was just a little
three-year-old caught in the middle.
It's understandable
why she thought he killed her.
Megan called. She was so upset.
I mean, crying, you know.
I kept, you know, reassuring
her that I'd been there.
That Frank did not
kill her mother.
And she believed you?
Yeah.
I thought it would make her happy,
but she seemed even more upset.
She said she had to find
her father and apologize.
Where was her father?
I don't know.
Oh, she was
in her doctor's office.
Said she had to go
and find him.
I see. Now you're saying
the father didn't do it.
You ought to take this roller
coaster to Coney Island.
The sister confirms it.
Now we know Frank Nelson left Hampton's
office while she was still alive.
Maybe this Bobby
confession is for real.
We proved that personality
wasn't there.
In other words, you have no
idea who committed this crime.
It has to be Megan.
She was seeing Hampton
for over a year.
Do you have a motive?
Megan's unstable.
I'm not sure she knows
she did it, let alone why.
Find out.
We know you were alone
with Dr. Hampton.
That leaves only one person who
could have killed her. You.
JACK: We'd like to see you
get some help, Miss Nelson,
but you have to tell us
the truth.
I told you, I don't remember.
How about you, Mr. Nelson?
How's your memory?
CLAIRE: She must have gone to your condo.
That's how the blood got there.
Frank, don't say anything.
No one can protect you
anymore, Miss Nelson.
Not your father. Not Bobby.
Now, tell us what happened.
I can't tell you
what I don't know.
Jack, please,
the girl needs help.
Come on, Megan, talk to me.
No more lies.
I'm a liar?
You're calling me a liar?
She's the one who lied.
Who lied, Megan?
Leave Megan out of this.
You're talking to me.
And nobody lies to me.
Including that idiot doctor.
What did Dr. Hampton do?
She thought she could fool me.
Said she made a mistake.
Maybe Frank
didn't kill Megan's mom.
Did she think I was stupid?
What she meant was
she lied to Megan.
Megan trusted her.
And you killed her?
Yes. Me.
What's your name?
Nancy.
I saw that stupid award
she's so proud of.
She didn't deserve any awards.
So I gave it to her
with gratitude.
If we ever need to justify
letting people plead insanity,
Megan Nelson fits the bill.
So, she goes into the hospital
as three people,
and we hope that she
comes back out as one.
And regardless, her father
will be there waiting.