You need to dance.
This week, five celebrities
have taken on the challenge
to become MasterChef champion.
Ugh! That's not OK.
Last time, Traitors star
Diane Carson went home.
Now the remaining four are back
to continue their mission.
Ooh!
Tonight, they will have their first
taste of a professional kitchen...
Oh, mate, that looks great.
That looks really, really nice.
Oh! This is good! Hey!
This is stress like
I've never known it.
..before cooking for
a place in the quarterfinal.
I think this is great. It just
looks like a food truck takeaway.
I'm feeling excited to be back here.
Although, last night,
I had an anxiety dream
where I set a frozen pizza on fire.
I am having so much fun, you know?
And I would love, of course,
to go as much far as I can.
I feel like I'm just surviving
but I'm just going to give my best.
I've got my running sneakers on.
We're going to do this.
We think they may have potential.
Now we're really going
to start to push them.
It's time for them to blossom.
Welcome back to the
MasterChef kitchen. Good to see you.
This challenge is a fantastic test
of your teamwork and communication.
We are splitting you into pairs.
The Blue team -
Mutya and Dom, you are a team.
Hi, babes.
Aye-aye, captain.
And the Red team - Vito and OJ.
Ciao, ragazzi. Ciao!
Each team's challenge is
to produce, for us, a dish
and we want two portions of that
dish which need to be identical -
not just the way they look
but also in texture and in flavour.
However, only one person
on each team has the recipe.
Blue team,
please reveal your ingredients.
Ooh.
OK.
As leader of the Blue team,
it's down to singer Mutya
to instruct Glow Up judge Dom
in how to create a vegetarian kebab
made from tofu,
mushrooms and broccoli
in a Korean-style marinade
with flatbreads
and sweet potato fries.
You've cooked plenty of tofu
in your time, have you, Mutya?
Never in my life. It's my first.
OK. You good with
the mushroom, Dom?
Never worked with tofu.
Never made flatbread.
I love Korean food. Yeah.
So this is...
We got this. We got this. Yeah.
Right. Red team, could you please
reveal your ingredients?
It's like a magic show.
Ooh! Ooh-hoo.
Lots of stuff.
Strictly dancer Vito
is leading the Red team.
He'll be instructing Radio 2 DJ OJ.
They need to make
two identical veggie burgers
with a beetroot and chickpea patty,
onion rings,
spicy mayonnaise,
and a cabbage and coriander slaw.
Have you ever done any of these?
Yeah, some of them. Oh, perfect.
No, hang on, I've eaten it.
Doesn't mean I've cooked it.
You haven't cooked it?
No, of course not!
Oh, me neither. OK. We-we
communicate, yeah? Yeah, yeah.
That's it.
Ladies and gentlemen, the vegetarian
restaurant will open in one hour.
Two portions identical.
Let's go. Oi!
OK. Come on, then. So we're going
to start off with our flatbreads.
Yes. OK, so we need 300g
of self-raising flour.
Teamwork and communication.
That's what we're going
to test them on.
How good are they
at working together?
We got this, man. We got this.
OK. We start.
"Make the beetroot and
chicken-pea patty." Easy!
The team member with the recipe
has to give clear
and concise instructions.
150g... Yeah? ..of natural yoghurt.
150g.
Mutya and Dom are a team.
One tablespoon of vegetable oil.
We've seen flatbread
fail many times before.
Usually it's not cooked all the way
through because it's far too thick.
It's got to be the right thickness.
Let me know when you've done that.
Done that.
I'm feeling the vibes.
The communication is good.
I've never made bread
so, this is a first for me.
OK. So how are you doing over there?
I'm hot. You're hot? I'm getting...
Strip, baby, strip.
I'm stripping off.
Show me some skin.
We need to knead and divide and
rest until time to cook...
Until it needs to be cooked.
I didn't hear a word of that. What?
Vito and OJ are starting
with the veggie burger.
So, is this like a dance?
It's like a dance. Yeah.
We have to cut and move
at the same time. All right!
Vito's got the recipe.
Vito is a dancer.
He is used to following
strict commands.
But can he give clear instruction
when it comes to food?
"Add the chicken piece and
cook beetroot to a food...press..."
Hang on, the "chicken piece"
or the chickpeas?
Chickpeas.
I feel anxious because I have
to read the instruction, and I...
My English is not that good
and I have to communicate to OJ.
So I will try my best just
to be as expressive as I can.
"Add the onion and cook for a couple
of minutes, then add the garlic."
But the issue
I've got slightly here is
I've put everything together already
in the bowl. OK, so what to do?
We put together? Let's just put it
already in the bowl, yeah, yeah.
I've put my chickpeas in.
Yeah, but I think we should
make sure that it's dry, no?
OK. It's a bit late now.
Ten minutes have gone.
All right, the next part... Yeah.
..we need 500g of tofu.
The Blue team -
flatbreads have been made.
They're now making their kebab.
But they've got to work out how
big the pieces are going to be.
"Cut tofu and mushrooms
into strips."
Right. How? How does it look?
Something like this maybe.
Mutya is team leader and
Dom seems to be the follower.
The broccoli -
are you going to cut the stems?
I'm listening to you.
Cut the stem off a bit.
Dom is very much
waiting for instruction
and not taking any initiative.
How tough is this, Dom?
This is, this is tough
but I'm used to it.
I do work in an industry where
everyone shouts at you all the time.
You know, Fashion Week,
you've got stylists shouting at you,
you've fashion designers
having meltdowns
and you've got to
get a job done. So...
This is similar?
Oh, this is exactly the same.
Oh! My mushrooms are
literally falling apart.
So we go in...tofu?
Tofu, mushroom... Mushroom.
..and then... Broccoli.
..broccoli and then tofu.
Like that?
Yeah.
The kebabs that Mutya and Dom
are making are massive.
Shall I keep going? Yeah. Maybe
do one more. Maybe do one more.
One more. Right. OK.
So you've got lumps of tofu
in there, like that.
I mean, they're huge,
but they're both huge.
I'm pretty proud of that.
That looks good.
I think that looks pretty decent.
20 minutes have gone.
On the Red team, Vito and OJ
are still working on
their veggie burger patties.
Beetroot?
Yeah.
"Put in the food processor
and pulse until combined." OK.
The Red team of Vito and OJ
need to get a move on.
25g of breadcrumbs.
They have got to get
those patties made now
because they've got to sit
in the fridge to firm up.
How much when it comes
to potato flour? 25g.
So how confident are you, right now,
you're going to get a burger?
I...I am confident, yeah.
I'm going for it.
I don't know where I'm going
but I'm going somewhere.
Just going with,
going with the flow. Very flow.
OK. What do we do now?
So we shape them into patties. Yeah.
I mean, I would say this
mix feels a bit wet to me.
Yeah. So what do we do?
We add a bit of...?
I think a bit of
potato flour into this
because obviously we've got to fry,
we don't want it to fall apart.
I mean, we're almost halfway.
Do you feel like you're on time?
No. Absolutely not.
Keep on going but it's time
to motor, guys. OK, right.
Let's get these nice and floured.
Do you think it's like this?
Yeah, I think it looks good, man.
It looks the same as mine.
And let's get them in the fridge.
Let's go in the fridge.
OK. Red team, Blue team,
you are halfway. 30 minutes gone.
30 minutes left.
It's time to panic,
ladies and gentlemen!
Ah!
100g of tomato ketchup. On it. Done.
One tablespoon of maple syrup.
Right. We have made the kebabs.
We've made the flatbreads.
Although we still need
to roll them out.
We're in the midst of
doing the marinade.
I'm worried that
time is running out.
Yeah, I kind of feel like
we need to get a move on.
Are you chopping your...
spring onions?
OK. One sec. Let me find
out what we do with it.
Am I meant to have put the onions
in the sauce? Cos I just did.
It just says combine
the ingredients.
Yeah. I'm a bit all over the place.
I can't even lie.
Mutya is struggling. She's not
really sure what she's doing.
"Coat kebab and cook on
a griddle pan brushing."
Should we not do the potato?
Pota... Let's do the potato.
Let's do the potato.
Because I feel like
the veg will cook quickly.
Dom is finally
coming out of his shell
and is inputting into the team.
I think we should just strip it.
Yeah. Well, peel it. OK.
And then, if we slice it
and make some chips. Perfect.
You're not finding this easy at all.
I am not.
This is very, very hard for me
because I'm very laid-back.
So I kind of like to take
the pressure off myself.
Otherwise this is what happens.
What happens? This. Unorganised.
THEY LAUGH
Spicy mayonnaise.
Spicy mayonnaise, let's do that.
Two yolk eggs.
You've got two yolks, yeah?
Hang on, one sec. Two yolk eggs.
I think we are...
Possibly if we make any mistakes,
we're going to be
in real trouble here.
Mayonnaise - egg yolks, salt,
whisk that up together
and then drip the oil in, bit by
bit, while stirring vigorously.
Then, of course,
it will come together.
So I think just a little pour...
Whisk.
I put a lot. OK.
CHUCKLES
If it's split, I don't know if
you can get mayonnaise back again.
I've got no idea.
Ugh. I think I put too much.
So the problem is, this is finito.
OK. We can't save this.
Yeah, so, you have to start again.
You need a clean bowl. Ugh.
Vito's messed up
his first lot of mayonnaise.
He rushed the first one.
It's split. Absolutely gone.
He couldn't save it so he
had to start all over again.
You're getting one more egg.
You can catch this. Are you ready?
Oh!
Which means that
now he's running behind.
You've got just 20 minutes left,
everybody, 20 minutes left.
Burgers to cook, onion rings to
make, sweet potato crisps to make,
kebabs to cook, sauces to do.
There's so much to do, guys.
Woo!
Three, two, one - down.
All right, so the next part, babe,
we need to... "coat kebab
and cook on a griddle pan".
Oh, what! That's like,
that's really...
How do you do that
when that does that?
The Blue team, they are
just putting their kebabs on
and Dominic has realised
the wooden skewers don't fit
in the griddle pan.
Oh! Babe.
I'm going to chop the tops
and bottoms off the kebab sticks.
Oh.
How's it going over there?
Uh, getting there.
Ugh.
Mushroom down, mushroom down!
Dom is supposed to brush
his marinade across his kebabs.
He's poured it on to the kebabs,
meaning that his kebabs, right now,
are sitting in a marinade stew.
You have just ten minutes,
everybody. Ten minutes.
It's "whisk-y" business, Vito.
It's "whisk-y" business!
You're making mayonnaise, Vito,
did you ever think?
Never in my life.
Vito, we are tremendously behind. We
can do this though. I know, I know.
Vito, we got to go, go, go, go, go!
Right. I reckon we should
fry the burgers, man.
Come on, let's get them in. Let's
get these bad boys in. Wait, wait.
OJ and Vito have still
got to cook their burgers,
they've got to toast
their burger buns,
they've got to cook
their onion rings
and they haven't even
started their slaw yet.
They are really going
to have to push.
Grab your onion rings. Onion rings.
Let's... I don't want to burn this.
No, it's going to be fine.
We're going to keep an eye on it.
I've never fried anything
in a deep-fat fryer.
Dip it in the flour. Yeah.
That's it. That's it, man. Yeah!
Yeah. Go, go on. OK.
Dom... Yeah? We need to get our
flatbreads ready as well. Right.
Do we need to make
them the same size?
How big are you doing yours?
About a hand...hand-size.
Hand-size.
"Melted butter for brushing."
Do you...do you brush
them after or before?
I don't know. It doesn't say!
It doesn't say!
And now you can butter it.
Once you've done one side,
butter it. Right. Got you, babes.
You have five minutes left,
everybody. Oh, my!
Vito! What? Just keep an
eye on your burgers, man.
Oh, one is burned!
It doesn't matter.
A little bit of char, it's great.
We'll just pretend it's
char-grilled beetroot burgers.
Oh, man!
OJ seems to have taken control.
He's realised he had
to step up to the mark.
The thing is now they've
still got quite a bit to do.
We need to go to
the burger slaw bit.
Shred this cabbage.
Here, like this. OK.
OK. For the sauce, babe, we need
three long chillies, chopped. Right.
Three cloves of garlic chopped.
Coriander leaves coarsely chopped.
I think I'm just
going to crush them.
We haven't got time for chopping.
Blue team -
have you checked your fries?
How do I get the chips out?
Ooh! Argh!
With just ten minutes to go,
it has turned into chaos.
Oh, God. My patty has
fallen apart and it's burnt.
OK, so, it's going well!.
OJ! Yes? Argh!
OK, where do we put it?
The bin? I don't know!
It's mayhem in there.
Oh, my God,
they are absolutely rank.
They are...the worst chips ever.
You've got three minutes
so let's start thinking
about getting stuff on plates.
So, burger on first. You put...?
I put the burger on the bun.
Show me.
All right. Just try
and deal with the chaos.
Do you put this on top? I don't
know, man. What do you reckon?
I think that, and the slaw goes on
top. Yeah, yeah. Cool. Let's do it.
One and a half teaspoon
of lemon juice.
I have no idea if this is right.
Blue team, 90 seconds. You've got
to get something on a plate. OK.
90 seconds.
All right. We need to figure out
how we're going to plate our food.
So I've put the flatbread down
and then I've put the
kebab to the side of it.
Look at me.
Like this? Like that, like that.
A little bit more like that.
Wait, wait, wait. Show me, show me.
Like that. Like that. Vito.
Good. Yours looks great, man. It
looks good. Good, good, good, good.
Mine looks a bit of a... Has to be,
has to be similar? Yeah, yes.
Final 40 seconds. Make a decision.
Run with it. You've got 40 seconds.
One flatbread, two kebabs.
How full is the mayonnaise, more?
A little bit more
mayo in there, yeah.
We good? I think so, yeah. OK.
I don't know whether
my bread is done but, hey.
That's it! Your time is up.
Stop. Well done.
For crying out...
I'm going to have a lay down.
Vito, did we make the tomato
ketchup? What? I'm joking! Oh!
OJ LAUGHS
That was horrendous.
Red team, come on.
That looks beautiful. Did you put
this in between here? Yeah, yeah.
All right.
The plates look remarkably similar
but you have two
completely different burgers.
Vito - yours is the size
of a double-decker bus,
and, OJ - yours is half the size
and looks like it's falling apart.
Yeah, just like me!
First up is Vito.
That's not bad at all.
That's not bad? Yeah! Oh!
The sweetness there
of the beetroot.
There is a mealiness coming through
from the chickpeas. It's great.
Your onion rings are crispy.
They could be a little bit crispier
but, hey, that's not bad at all.
I love the smell
that's coming off that slaw
with that sesame oil
and the soy sauce.
Your mayonnaise is creamy
and silky-sharp with lemon
and a nice little bit of spiciness
coming from that sriracha
that you added to it. It's good.
OJ, your onion rings
are sensational.
Lovely and crispy.
Seasoned really, really well.
The burger itself -
when you emptied your
chickpeas into the mixer,
you put a lot of the liquid in,
it just made your mix
a little bit too wet.
The burger - yours is
definitely wetter and it's sweeter.
Your dressing is lovely but
it's got more soy and more chilli
because it's slightly
saltier and hotter.
Your mayonnaise is well-made.
You've done a good job, OJ,
but there are differences
between the two plates.
You fell behind with the mayonnaise
but you kept on going.
I've got to say, as a team,
I think you did really, really well.
I am more than happy, honestly.
Yeah.
I think we make a great team.
So, yeah. Look at that!
Blue team, up you come, please.
OK. OK. OK. OK. Uh-hm-hm.
Yes. Yeah. OK.
The striking difference
is the bread.
Apart from that, you've both
made absolutely gigantic kebabs.
First up is Dom.
Dominic. Your kebabs -
your tofu is lovely,
your mushroom's cooked
all the way through,
little bits of crispy broccoli.
Flatbread I like.
It's lovely and thin.
But if you look at these fries, you
can see they're a little bit soggy.
I like your marinade.
It's smoky, slightly sweet,
slightly hot.
Mutya brushed hers over her kebabs.
You emptied the bowl of marinade
into the griddle pan.
Love your marinade.
I love that sweetness, that heat,
that smokiness. It's lovely.
It's kind of barbecue sauce
meets chilli sauce.
There is nothing wrong
with your breads.
You just haven't rolled them
out flat enough. Yeah. OK.
They're not cooked in the middle
there. They're just doughy.
Kebab's great. There's a really
lovely sweetness that's coming
from that Korean chilli paste.
Your sweet potato fries have gone
too dark and they've gone soft
and a bit soggy
which is a bit of a shame.
I think you did very, very
well trying to teach yourself
and teach your partner
at the same time.
Dominic,
it took you a while to think,
actually, I've got a role
to play here as well.
And once you did,
things got a bit better. Uh-huh.
So, well done, the pair of you.
Thank you. Thank you. Well done.
Yaasss!
To be honest, it came out so well.
We've now made a dish
that we've never made before.
And we'll probably never make it
again. I totally agree!
You have learned
a really valuable lesson
in teamwork and communication.
You are going to need
every lesson you are learning.
Thank you very much. Off you go.
Thank you.
That was good.
THEY CHATTER, LAUGH
It's early morning
and, still in their teams,
the celebrities are about
to get their first taste
of a professional kitchen.
Just hoping it's not going
to be anything too crazy
because I know they do
all that fancy stuff on the plates.
Oh. I'm not...
These sausage fingers! I know!
They're not very good,
they're not delicate.
Mutya and Dom are
arriving at Fazenda
in the heart of
the City of London...
This looks nice.
OK. This looks fancy.
..a South American grill restaurant
that celebrates Brazilian
and Argentinian cuisine.
Running the pass is
executive chef Francisco Martinez.
Hello. Hello, chefs.
How are you feeling?
Good. Nervous. Nervous.
Yeah. Really nervous.
I have no idea what we're doing.
You should be! Don't say that!
That's not what we need to hear!
That's so mean!
We have about 140 people.
So it's going to be
a fun service for you.
Are you ready? Yes! Come on!
Then follow me and let's
crack on with the prep. Got it!
They have a difficult task today
because they're going to
be cooking with charcoal.
So, charcoal is not easy to manage.
There's quite a few elements
going into the dishes
that they're going to be preparing.
Anything that is not up to
standard unfortunately will go back
and we need to repeat
the dishes again.
For today's service, Mutya will
have to tackle a four-kilo octopus.
I love octopus.
The char-grilled tentacle
is coated in a squid ink stew
and a lemon mayonnaise.
Cook two, three minutes.
If we leave it here for
longer, it will get tough.
During service, you're going
to have a few at the same time
so try to get the timings right.
The other challenge for
Mutya will be plating.
Just making sure that we put
the squid ink stew all over. Yep.
So, slowly. No rush.
Once perfectly coated,
Mutya will have to delicately
place the tentacle
on a potato puree.
This is a coriander oil.
We just go all around.
And finish it with
smoked paprika caviar.
So this will explode
on the mouth of the guest.
It's a very complex dish.
It is about ten elements
with this octopus.
I know it's going to get really hot
but I'm definitely
going to see it through
and hopefully make him proud.
Yeah. I'm ready. I'm good to go.
I'll be really, really amazed,
to be honest,
if they know how to
handle a raw octopus.
I've dealt with octopus and squid
at home but not like this.
I'm not squeamish at all.
Mutya is not the only one
with her hands full.
Dom is busy prepping
a whole beef tenderloin.
The difficulty is trying
to cut them into equal sizes.
Very special product. It's an animal
that only eats chocolate beans.
Oh... This is a very,
very special product.
I feel like a kindred spirit.
Yeah? Yeah.
His dish is grilled beef skewers
with a truffle sauce
and a beef demi-glaze,
all topped with Parmesan
and fresh black truffle.
For me, this is a very,
very special dish in our menu.
We need them to cook medium rare.
So, a total of about four minutes.
OK? We get that caramelisation
on the outside. OK.
Charcoal is difficult to manage.
And as soon as they forget for 20
seconds, this beef will be ruined
and they will need to start again.
This is the charring
we're looking for, OK?
Once we've got this colour
all the way around, ready to go.
While keeping an eye on the beef,
he'll also have to heat
the two sauces.
This is a truffle sauce.
We go with the demi-glace.
Fresh Parmesan cheese.
Really, really nice amount of it.
Oh, wow.
For a touch of decadence, the dish
is covered in fresh black truffle.
Oh, my word.
It's expensive, this,
and I hope I don't need to
waste a lot of black truffle.
It looks amazing
and it smells beautiful.
I'm worried because
that beef is really special
and I don't want to mess it up.
I can do this.
I'm going to make you proud, chef.
Across town in north London,
Vito and OJ will be
spending the day at Supawan.
This is definitely too cold for me.
It is not a warm day
but I'll tell you what
is going to warm you up
and that is a day in the kitchen
of a... Oh! ..Thai restaurant!
Let's go! Go on.
Serving traditional Thai cuisine
inspired by dishes
from his childhood
is owner and head chef
Wichet Khongphoon.
Ah, hello. Hey, sawasdee
kha! Sawasdee kha, sawasdee kha!
My name is Wichet.
Do you like Thai food?
I love Thai food.
You've come to the right place.
We have a lot of
people coming today
so let's go to the kitchen
and let's see what we can do.
ALL: Let's go, let's go!
You need to laugh
a lot in the kitchen.
But I am, yes, quite strict
when it comes to producing food
because it's got to be precise.
Hi, Vito. Hi.
Welcome to our kitchen.
I am so excited.
So, you've got two dishes
today to prepare. OK.
Vito will be on starters.
He'll be making chef's
signature chicken wings
stuffed with Thai-spiced prawn
and chicken mousse
which is served
with aubergine larb,
a Thai-spiced grilled
aubergine salad.
You need to prepare these two
dishes at the same time... OK.
..so the timing, it's
got to be very precise.
Chicken wings is one
of the standout dishes.
I just love the complexities
of the flavours
and it's so labour-intensive.
So, we basically have to coat
the chicken wings very nicely.
OK. Now this one it goes into the...
The fryer. ..the fryer.
While the chicken wings cook,
Vito will have to quickly
prepare the aubergine laab
first by reheating
the grilled aubergine.
Make sure that you go for
about three to four minutes.
You don't want to get it too burned
because then it becomes
a little bit hard.
Slice the aubergine in half
and then you cut into three sections
like this, across like that.
One, two, three.
He'll also have to fry chillies
and heat up a tamarind sauce.
Oh, the smell is so good.
The larb dish is garnished
with fresh mint, crispy shallot
and the deep-fried chillies.
This is going to be
very, very spicy.
It's going to be quite spicy,
but very, very nice.
Finally, it's the chicken wings.
This is golden colour.
It's a golden colour.
If it's cooked too long
then it will be dry.
They are served with
a chilli and tamarind sauce.
Place the chicken wing, like that.
Wow!
You put a little bit
of this chilli in there.
We love chilli.
Perfect.
Thank you, chef. You're welcome.
Thank you so much. You're welcome.
You're welcome. Well done. Woo!
I am very, very excited
and I'm very, very focused.
So I will channel
all my energy, you know,
and I want to really do my best.
I promise I will do.
Vito's first big task...
I have never done
any of this before.
..is to debone and stuff
40 chicken wings
with a Thai-spiced chicken mousse.
That's my first one.
I'm so proud.
I will call this, in Italian,
il pollo gelato.
So, it means like
the chicken ice cream.
Yeah.
OJ, this is your station.
This is where I'll be?
The main station, this is
where you're going to be.
You've got two woks to play with.
OJ will have the pressure
of being responsible
for one of Thailand's
national dishes - pad Thai.
So we are going to
lightly fry this tofu. OK.
Give it a shake.
Yeah, give it a shake.
OJ's biggest challenge
will be mastering the art
of cooking in a wok.
OJ, have you been using
this kind of wok before?
No. We have a wok
but I think the kids stole it
and put it in the garden.
It's full of mud. Yeah.
The secret is that the wok
has got to be really, really hot.
So, onions in. And the onion in.
To cook pad Thai in the wok
is very challenging.
Make it like a scrambled egg.
OK.
So you need to be very,
very careful and very gentle
when you cook pad Thai.
And it can be burned so easily.
This is the dried shrimp.
Whoa!
It smells like a fishing bait shop.
To create the perfect pad Thai...
We are going to use these noodles.
Some tamarind.
..OJ will have to remember
the correct order...
So now it's time to do the tofu in.
OK. The big boys go in.
..of all 11 elements
that make up the dish.
Sauce.
And now you smell it.
Oh, that smells like pad Thai,
doesn't it? Yeah.
That absolutely smells like
pad Thai. Now you smell it.
Pad Thai is such an iconic dish.
Got to be quite a high standard.
How will I know
I've done this right?
You've got to have an instinct.
OK! That's how it works!
How many pad Thais have
you made in your life?
Not many.
I don't believe you.
Oh, I love it.
The dish is garnished with
chive stalks and banana flowers.
So banana trees, so these are the
flowers? These are the flowers. OK.
So, OJ, this is our pad Thai.
That is amazing.
Thank you so much. I'll see you
later. You've got to try!
Before service begins,
OJ has to get his hands dirty.
Ooh! Like this. It's like mud!
Yeah. It's like...
What is that? Is that one
of the tamarinds? Yeah.
I've found a lump.
We are squeezing the tamarinds.
They've been soaked in
water for a few hours.
It's one of the
weirdest sensations ever.
Imagine dipping your
hands into cold mud.
Never cooked Thai food in my life
but the idea of making that pad Thai
which is a famous, beautiful dish
is amazing.
It's almost midday
and, all across the city,
restaurants are preparing
for the lunchtime rush.
OK, team! Service is about to start.
Yes, chef. We've got 120 people in
so be ready, and have fun.
Yes, chef. Yes, chef.
Are you ready, babe?
I'm ready, babs.
All right. We got this.
We got this, we got this.
Check on. The first one for you.
One octopus on, please.
It's going in!
It's all happening!
Very nervous. I think,
after one or two, I'll be fine.
Check on.
One fugazzeta. One octopus.
Oh, Lord.
Check on, Dominic.
Two espetinhos going on, please.
Yes, chef.
I'm feeling so excited.
I'm pumped. I know what I'm doing.
At least I think
I know what I'm doing.
As well as cooking
the beef to perfection,
Dom must also make sure the coals
are at the perfect temperature
throughout service.
So far, so good.
Check on. One more espetinhos,
one vieiras...
It's a little bit...
..three espetinhos.
Argh...yes...
I don't know what the... Yes.
Mutya's first octopus
order is cooked
and she now needs to master
chef's intricate plating.
How long for the octopus?
Two minutes, chef.
It's very nerve-racking
but I'm trying my hardest.
Waiting for those octopus, please.
Yes.
Finished with that one?
It's my first one.
Yeah, I mean... OK?
..it's nearly there, getting there.
OK.
With the potatoes Parmentier,
a little bit less. Less?
More in the middle of the...
In the middle? OK.
So, do the next one better, I
promise. Thank you. Service, please!
This is not the easiest dish ever!
SHE LAUGHS
With Mutya's first dish
going out to the diners....
Look at me, multitasking.
..it's time for Dom
to step up to the mark.
So, the first of the day,
make sure that it is spot-on.
I will. I won't let you down, chef.
How long, Dominic?
One minute, chef. Thank you.
Everything's good.
I feel like...I'm under control.
Looking good.
So let's finish with that truffle.
A little bit less of
the demi-glace, please.
Less? Yeah, it's too powerful.
OK. Right. Less. OK.
The pressure is so on. I'm juggling.
I've got my meat. I've got my sauce.
I've got some oils.
I've just got to get it
in the right order.
Across town, the first
customers are arriving
and service is about to
start for OJ and Vito.
OK, guys. OJ, first order.
Vito, first order.
You have larb aubergine,
and you have one peek gai, please.
And then, OJ, you have one pad Thai,
please. One pad Thai. Yeah.
With Vito on the starter,
he'll be first to serve.
We are ready.
Timing is everything
as he has to simultaneously
cook his crispy chicken wings
and the aubergine larb salad.
He needs to fry. He needs to grill.
He needs to put things together.
Two dishes for Vito.
It's not going to be easy for him.
I'm feeling good because, at the
moment, I am managing quite well.
What's first, what's second, what's
third. Keep it under control, this,
while the aubergine is there.
Vito, you forgot your sauce.
My sauce? Ah. Yeah, the larb sauce.
I forgot the sauce.
Over on mains...
In she goes.
..OJ is about to get
his first taste of cooking
the 11 different
pad Thai ingredients
in the ferocious heat
of a professional wok.
There is nothing he can miss out
because, if he moves
away from his pan,
then his pad Thai will be burned.
Get the tofu in there.
It's getting burned now.
You need to move faster. OK.
Bean sprouts. Argh! Yes.
Bean sprouts... I think you need
to throw this one away, I'm afraid.
Oh, no! Yeah! No!
I think it's burnt! Oh, no!
Burnt the first one! It's burnt.
So, we start again. We start again.
We start again. OK.
It's tricky for someone who's
never cooked Thai food before.
Cos they've got to move quick.
Now stop!
Carrot. Carrots.
But it comes with experience.
He will cook 20 of these today...
He will be perfect.
While OJ starts again, Vito is
beginning to plate his first dishes.
The challenge is to make
everything with a good quality
but you have to
make everything fast.
And then drizzle all over it.
You need to work faster now.
I'm doing quite well, I think...
I hope, honestly.
Ready here!
I'm very happy with
these as a first time.
OK! So, ready to go.
Vito, we have another order of larb
aubergine and peek gai, please. OK.
I'm finding it so exciting,
so interesting.
Honestly, I'm having so much fun.
Wow.
OJ's onto his second attempt
at his first order of pad Thai.
Oh, it looks lovely. Look.
It looks like some noodles in a pan.
Come on. It's very good, actually.
Are you ready to plate? OK.
Some of these.
A little banana flower.
Food is coming. Food is coming.
Watch your back, man,
watch your back.
BELL PINGS
How does it look, Wichet?
For the second one,
after burning the first one,
I think this one is...better.
It's the chaos of it.
It's absolute organised chaos
because, constantly,
you've got something burning.
And if you're not watching at
any moment, then it all goes wrong.
Back in the City...
So, service, please. Table 51,
..all 140 lunch guests
are now seated.
Checks on, please.
One espetinhos, one octopus, please.
ALL: Yes, chef.
Yes, chef. On it, chef.
And the orders for
Dom's beef skewers
and Mutya's octopus keep coming.
One more octopus,
one more espetinhos,
one burrata going as well.
Yes, chef.
ALL: Yes, chef.
This is stress
like I've never known it.
You guys got a total of five each...
Five octopus. ..going on.
Oh, my God.
Mutya is beginning to struggle
with the fierce pace of the kitchen.
Waiting for those octopus, please.
Let's go. A little less
of the squid ink stew, OK? OK.
I'm still trying to get used to it.
Espetinhos. One octopus, please.
Oh, wow.
ALL: Yes, chef.
On the other side of the kitchen...
I need one a cab' on the pass,
please.
Yes, chef.
..Dom's also finding it hard to
keep up with the volume of orders.
Dominic. Yes, chef. I will say
I need your dishes in two minutes.
Two of them on the pass.
Perfect, chef.
If I'm honest, I don't know
which two he's talking about.
Is it these two?
Is it the two that I put on?
Dominic, ready?
Really good.
Again, a little bit less
of the demi-glace. Demi-glace. OK.
Back in North London....
Oh, mate, that looks great.
That looks really, really nice. OK!
Oh, this is good!
BELL RINGS
Come on!
Strictly come wok-ing!
..Vito and OJ are
in the thick of it.
One laab aubergine, and one
peek gai, and two pad Thai, please.
Yeah, come on. Two pad Thai?
Let's go!
Guys, we need to speed up. These
people need to go back to work.
Yes, chef. Yes, chef. Yes, chef.
Thank you so much.
OJ is juggling
multiple orders of pad Thai
over the ferocious heat
of two woks at once.
Oh, I've forgotten to
put the carrots in.
It's all gone wrong. He said
"well done" last time. Yeah.
And then I've totally
forgotten to do something.
I need carrots in there, don't I?
You need carrots now.
Go easy with the soy sauce. Easy
with the soy sauce. That's enough.
This one's done.
This one is ready.
Someone is getting
very perfectionist here.
Someone's getting
really, really good.
Come on, OJ! Someone is
really very good here. Woohoo!
BELL RINGS
Come on, pad Thai's up!
This is amazing.
I love the pressure.
Every time you turn one out,
this lovely man says,
"That was great."
It's like your heart jumps
a little bit. It's brilliant.
That is really nice.
It's very artistic.
BELL RINGS
Aubergine ready. Wait.
We love sauce. We do.
Balanced here, like two dancers,
you see?
Table 25. Ready!
BELL RINGS
It's OK. I'm good. I'm staying cool.
I'm having fun. Yeah!
With OJ and Vito revelling
in the fast-paced kitchen,
back in the city, the lunchtime rush
is finally starting to slow down.
Last check for lunch. We've got
two more going on of each, OK?
Again, speak to each other,
synchronise, please.
With two orders each
for the same table,
it's imperative
Dom and Mutya communicate
so the food is ready
at the same time.
How long, Mutya? Two minutes.
Perfect.
I've got so much respect for chefs.
Like, I will never
complain again, ever.
They have such a hard job.
Are you ready?
We're all good, babs.
Oh, look at that - tag team!
That's spot-on.
Exactly at the same time.
Thank you so much.
Ah!
SHE LAUGHS WITH RELIEF
Right. Hang on.
How many fingers have you got?
I've got... Still got...
Oh, my God!
Ugh, I'm very inky.
Back in North London...
VITO SINGS STRICTLY THEME TUNE
Cha-cha-cha!
..Vito and OJ continue to thrive.
Here we go. Last one. Last one!
Make sure it looks good.
BELL THUDS, THEN RINGS
Perfect.
I love to see how you just dance,
you know? It's like....
Yeah! We dance, chef.
That is beautiful. Boom.
BELL RINGS
Ready to go!
Thank you so, so much.
You're welcome. You're welcome.
Woo! You're welcome.
We've done it.
For the four celebrities,
their experience at a professional
restaurant is finally over.
That was brilliant. It was so fun.
It was just so energetic.
There was so much noise,
so much chaos.
I'm so happy I got through it
but today was definitely hard.
I'm... Yeah, I'm tired.
Was that two hours? Because
it felt like both 15 minutes
and about six months of my life,
both at the same time!
I do think I need
to lay down now, though.
I really loved this. Thank you.
I found this amazing.
I just love when people
do things with love.
Sorry. It's happiness tears, no?
Yeah. So good. Thank you.
You are amazing! Come, too!
Woo!
This is an experience, guys.
Oh, wow. Wow.
Come on.
Let's get out of here.
I am spent...mate.
Put it there. Bam.
I'm going home to buy a wok.
Welcome - not to
the MasterChef kitchen
but the MasterChef
street food market.
We want you to imagine
you are at a food market
with your own food truck.
What are you serving, and why?
At the end of this, three
of you will be quarterfinalists.
That does mean that one
of you will be going home.
Ladies and gentlemen -
one hour. Let's cook.
I'm feeling really good.
I've got a lot to do
but I think I'm on to a winner.
What's brilliant about street food
is that you can experience
all the different flavours,
different cuisines
from all over the
world in one place.
It's like the globe comes to you.
What are you serving, Dominic?
Dom's tasty toasties.
We're doing some cheese toasties.
We're doing three different types.
We're going to America to
do a Philly cheese steak,
Britain to do a cheese and pickle,
and then Korea to do
a barbecue chicken.
Wow. Yes.
I understand that you once had a job
in a fast food restaurant. I did.
But I was too much of a talker
so I wasn't very fast.
And so they put me
on the drive-through
and then I slowed everyone down
and I caused traffic jams
all along the M1.
So I was then removed
from my position.
You got sacked from a fast-food
burger joint? For being too slow!
I love what Dom's doing.
We've got three toasted sandwiches
and there's melted cheese
in every single one.
One is cheese and pickle.
He's made his own pickled onions
and it's made up of
four different cheeses.
The other one is
American Philly cheese steak
and he's got ribeye there.
It's got lots of fat running
through it
which means it can't be served rare
because the fat won't melt.
It's got to be at least medium.
I mean, what -
meat, onions, cheese... Mwah!
The Korean fried sandwich
sounds fascinating.
He's making crispy chicken and he's
making a chilli dressing as well.
He's got gochujang
which is peppery and smoky,
and he's got cheese
going on that as well.
What is it with Dom and cheese?
I mean, this is a relationship
that's bordering on obsession.
Bring on Dominic's tasty toasties!
Mm-mm-mm. Mm-mm-mm-mm!
So I feel like my
food fits the brief
because it's comfort food,
it's quick and it's filling.
I think that's what you really need.
Food that's going to make
you full and keep you moving.
SHE LAUGHS
Mutya, what are you serving
from your food truck?
I'm going to do, like, a shepherd's
pie but in a jacket potato.
Why have you chosen that?
Because I just love jacket potato
and I love shepherd's pie,
and I just thought
it might go really well.
Is that beef? Yeah. Beef.
That's a cottage pie.
It is. It's not a...
Because shepherds don't look
after cows! No, they don't.
You've got Scotch bonnets. I have
just to spice it up a little bit.
Is that you?
A little bit of eastern spice
and a little bit of
British home comfort?
Definitely. I think it's nice to
put everything together and just...
It's just comfort food.
The meat needs to be moist and
tender,
and bursting full of flavour.
And that jacket potato
needs to be soft all the
way through and buttery.
Thank you.
If I can get this right, and
the flavours are tasting amazing,
I think it could keep me
in the competition.
I'm praying for the best.
OK.
The good news is...
..there's 35 minutes left.
The bad news is
25 minutes already gone.
I love street food.
I love eating outdoors.
For me,
that's the point of eating.
You know, get messy, don't sit down.
I always find sometimes sitting down
in restaurants is a bit too intense.
So, doing this is absolutely
up my street, I love it.
So I am cooking, for you,
Borg's balls.
It's basically a sweet arancini.
So you've used risotto rice?
I've used pudding rice.
It's flavoured with
oranges and orange zest,
and a bit of orange blossom water.
So there will be
an espresso chocolate dip
and there's a berry coulis as well.
Wow.
And my daughter decided to
make me Borg's balls bags.
Fabulous, mate.
Yeah.
This sounds like a seller.
OK, good! For a second there,
I thought you were going to say,
"This sounds like a terrible idea."
It sounds like a seller.
I don't know if the name
would work on a food truck.
I think people might be a bit scared
of that, mightn't they? You reckon?
I like the idea of OJ's rice balls.
He's using rice that you make
for a rice pudding,
and he's sweetened it slightly.
If he doesn't cook the rice
properly, we're in trouble.
Undercooked -
it'll be really, really hard.
Overcooked -
it'll just be really, really gluggy.
I've chosen to make
this kind of food
because it's very my family style
and it's also very
Naples, Amalfi coast.
Oh! I cannot wait to prepare
and eat at the same time.
You're from Campania? Yes!
And they have a lot of
pizza on the street. Yeah.
Do you like street food?
I love street food.
If I should decide, like, you know,
to have something related to food,
I would probably have
a street food truck.
And where would you have it?
On the Amalfi coast. And while
you eat, you look at the beach.
Vito is going completely Italian.
Three completely different dishes.
We've got a deep-fried
mozzarella and bread.
It's going to be crispy
but good and tasty.
He's got a stuffed courgette.
You put it in the fryer.
Boom! It comes like, you know,
a little cloudy, very light.
Mwah! It's just so beautiful.
And I fill with a little bit of
ricotta in, you know. It's so good.
It has to be golden.
Not yet.
Oh, man, that looks beautiful,
though. Look at it.
Yeah, but this was raw. Look.
Ah, OK. That's not so good.
Then we've got a fried pizza.
So it's like a baby pizza.
And after, we put the tomato on top.
This could be delicious, but there's
lots of frying going on here.
I hope it's not all too greasy.
I will give my best, as always.
And I will do things with love.
Some good smells in here. You've got
ten minutes. Ten minutes, please!
I'm running out of time.
I gave myself far too much to do.
You have just three minutes, guys.
Three minutes. "Three"?!
That's it. Time's up! Time's up.
Ooh! Well done, guys.
CLAPPING
Just some fun, isn't it?
It's just some fun!
Dominic! Come on.
First up is Dominic,
who has served
a trio of cheese toasties.
A crispy Korean chicken toastie
with Swiss cheese and
a spicy Korean gochujang sauce.
A UK-inspired
cheese and pickle toastie
with four different cheeses
and pickled red onions.
And an American-inspired
Philly cheese steak toastie
filled with ribeye steak,
fried onions and mozzarella.
And on the side, a bearnaise sauce
and a Korean barbecue dipping sauce.
I think this is great.
It just looks like
a food truck takeaway.
The Korean one - crispy chicken,
lovely crispy bread.
Soft, sticky sauce on the outside.
Sweet but chilli hot
at the same time.
Cheese and pickle sandwich -
the pickles are fantastic
because they're sharp which help
to combat all that cheese.
I'm really, really impressed.
And I would go back to Dom's
and I would have
another toasted sandwich.
The Philly steak -
steak really well cooked.
You've put a load of pepper in there
offset by the sweetness
of the onions.
If that wasn't enough, let's sling
some mozzarella in there as well.
You're going to get knee-deep
in that because it's just fabulous.
Thank you very much.
I'm so chuffed.
I'm chuffed that I finished
but I'm even more chuffed that
John and Gregg loved the toasties.
I just... I'm blown away by that.
Hello.
Mutya has served a jacket potato
with a cottage pie filling
flavoured with Scotch bonnet chilli,
topped with Cheddar
and mozzarella cheese.
I'm really happy to say the potato
is cooked all the way through.
It seems to me like you've used
about a kilo of butter in there
as well that's melted into it! Yes.
Your beef is soft and it's rich,
and there is a chilli heat
emanating from there.
We know this stuff sells
because there are lots
of food trucks doing it.
I think yours is done
very, very well.
Lovely beef mince and vegetables,
lots of salty cheese, which is good,
and different types of cheese.
I really like the flavours.
But is it enough? That's my
question. Yeah, I hear that.
I'm feeling good.
But I feel like...
You just, yeah, you just never know.
Oh, my God.
It's kind of hard to know what's
going on in John and Gregg's head
but, I mean, they both
gave me great comments.
OJ has served sweet arancini -
deep-fried balls of pudding rice
flavoured with orange blossom,
espresso chocolate dip
and a berry coulis.
Very nice picture of you.
Thank you so much.
I like the texture on the outside.
You've used pudding rice.
Pudding rice goes nice and creamy.
It hasn't quite gone creamy enough.
The inside, for me,
is a little bit dry
and we don't have the flavour
of orange.
I'm enjoying both dips -
the chocolate one particularly,
because it's got a bitterness.
The raspberry is sharp,
that is sweet.
It's almost like a raspberry jam.
I am enjoying this. I think you
could have done a lot more.
I think you actually could have
stuffed something inside of them.
You know, that jam or that
chocolate could have gone inside.
Deflated, really deflated.
It's such an emotional high
being in that kitchen.
And then the not particularly
positive reaction to what I made...
..and you're like, "Ugh."
Finally, it's Vito...
Hello.
..with his trio of
Italian fried street foods.
Mozzarella fried in breadcrumbs
with a green olive dip.
Courgette flowers
stuffed with ricotta,
then deep-fried in batter.
And a fried pizza topped with a
tomato sauce, basil and anchovies.
Your mozzarella in the crispy
coating here is lovely.
Crunchy, not at all greasy.
You then put the salty olives
and the tangy basil
as a spread across it.
It's absolutely delicious.
Your little courgette flower ball -
creamy, a little bit salty.
This is unmistakeably
the flavours of the south of Italy.
This is wonderful.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
The little pizzetta which
you fried in oil - it's not greasy.
It's lovely and creamy,
and rich with tomatoes
but the saltiness of the anchovy,
right at the last minute,
just takes the whole thing up.
I think they are
three delicious little morsels.
There's a huge amount of work here
and I like it a lot.
Thank you so much.
Would you give us
a little celebratory dance
because we loved your food?
Go on.
Right away? Yes.
Bam! Hey!
I feel...overwhelmed.
And it was honestly
so amazing, so good,
because I was really
putting all myself.
Honestly, I'm very, very happy
and so satisfied about
the feedback from the judges.
Great round
with some really great cookery.
I mean, there were some absolute
brilliant show stoppers there.
We've now got a job to do.
I've got two people here whose food
I thought was absolutely fantastic.
I really liked Dominic and his
array of toasted cheese sandwiches.
I thought it was just outstanding.
Dominic's got himself a
place in the quarterfinal.
And the other person
who has got a shoo-in...
Oh, mate, it's our Italian dancer!
Vito's little fried pizza,
that lovely fritter
with the courgette flowers
and then that little
toasted mozzarella sandwich.
What's not to like?
Vito goes through.
One quarterfinal place left.
Mutya made baked potato
with cottage pie.
Really lovely potato
flavoured with butter.
The beef mince was delicious.
I'm a little bit concerned
about the ambition
BUT it was done very well
and it tasted very good.
OJ made for us sweet arancini.
Nice, crispy outside.
The issue was there was no
flavour of orange, unfortunately.
And the inside of
those arancini were dry.
I can't say I didn't like it.
I think just with a little
bit of push and desire,
it could have been so much more.
I want to prove that I can
make food they want to eat
and I absolutely can do that.
Or maybe I'm just a rubbish cook
and I need to realise it.
Why are you nodding?!
I'm very 50-50 about staying.
I don't know. I don't feel
as confident as I was before.
Some fantastic food,
some real courage
and great adventure.
That's what this
competition is all about.
It's been a difficult decision
but, sadly, one of you
is leaving us.
The celebrity leaving us is...
..OJ.
Thought so. Thought so.
Listen...you guys are amazing. Aw.
Loved it, loved it, loved it.
OJ, it's great to have met you.
Sorry to see you go.
Love you. Thank you so much
for all the advice. Loved it.
My MasterChef experience -
I would summarise it as this.
"Cook, cook, cook.
Cry, cry, cry. Goodbye."
I've loved every single moment.
But it is tinged with sadness.
And I'm sad my journey
has ended here.
Well done, you three!
Celebrity MasterChef
quarterfinalists.
Can you believe it?
LAUGHTER
Quarterfinal in MasterChef!
I honestly cannot believe it.
The feeling is like it's not real.
So I'm, like, pinching myself,
like, is it true?
This is amazing.
I never thought I'd be here.
So I prepared myself and was like,
"Oh, well, it's fine. I'm going
to go get my nails done tomorrow."
But, um, it seems
like I'll be here again.
Oh, my God, I am blown away.
I've had the best day.
It's been so much fun and I
just can't wait for it to continue.
Next time...
Boy...!
..it's the quarterfinal...
GASPS
MUTYA WAILS
..and Vito, Mutya and Dominic...
Look at that colour.
..are back to fight
for their place.
It's so exciting. I know.
Ready!
The first bite slightly disturbs me.
That is a very, very
colourful, creative plate.