Downloaded from
YTS.MX
MOSFILM
Official YIFY movies site:
YTS.MX
Experimental
Artistic Association
It's damp.
The air smells like a graveyard.
For six months I've been smelling
my own grave.
Hey, Chudra!
Why did you leave our camp?
Gypsies are no longer
what they used to be.
They give away a horse for gold.
They'll give away their knife,
and even their soul.
Tell me, Chudra, who knows more,
the fool or the wise man?
The fool.
The wise man doubts everything.
Then blessed are the fools, Chudra.
Too much knowledge
only brings sorrow.
What would you say to me if this
were to be our last meeting?
Do not love gold,
it will betray you.
Do not love women,
they will betray you.
Freedom is the headiest
wine of all.
Rise always at the break of day.
Remember, the sunset falls
when you don't expect it.
I wish you long life, Zobar.
Let your death come in time.
GYPSIES ARE FOUND
NEAR HEAVEN
Based on stories by
M. GORKY
Svetlana TOMA as Rada
Grigore GRIGORIU as Zobar
Cast:
Siladi – Ion Sandri SCUREA
Talimon – Pavel ANDREICHENKO
Bubulia – Sergiu FINITI
Old Gypsy Woman–Lyalya CHORNAYA
Bucha – Borislav BRONDUKOV
Rusalina – Nelly VOLSHANINOVA
Danilo – Vsevolod GAVRILOV
Nur – Mikhail SHISHKOV
Aralambi – Nikolai VOLSHANINOV
Balint – Vassily SIMCHICH
Yulishka – Yelena SADOVSKAYA
Gheorghe DIMITRIU
Belash VISHNEVSKY
Alyona BUZYLYOVA Dumitru MOCANU
Songs Performed by
Nikolai Volshaninov, Rada Volshaninova
Nikolai Zhemchuzhny,
Zhenya Savelyeva
Alyona Buzylyova, Tahir Bobrov
Zinaida Antonova
Dmitri Buzylyov, Lyalya Mihai
Written and Directed by
Emil LOTEANU
Director of Photography
Sergey VRONSKY
Cameraman Vladimir KROMAS
Production Designer
Felix YASYUKEVICH
Music by Eugene DOGA
Choreography by P. ANDREICHENKO
GYPSIES ARE FOUND
NEAR HEAVEN
Four kings.
To the new, twentieth, century,
gentlemen!
- To your health.
- Thank you.
- Schwabb!
- Yes, Lieutenant?
Can you dance the waltz?
No, I can't, Lieutenant.
Place your right hand
on my left shoulder.
Yes, sir.
- Propertsium.
- Yes, sir?
What will be the 20th century like?
Everything seems to be confused.
The Zodiac signs are contradictory.
The end of the world will come
in 16 years.
Mister Balint!
- What is it?
- Look!
Are you in your right mind?
Couldn't you wait until tomorrow?
I couldn't. Last night I set a trap
to see what the new year
will be like.
I know now that it will be
a magnificent year! Look!
Mister Balint,
on this side of the Carpathians
you won't find horses like these.
Nor on the other side.
Some light.
Let's have some light.
I don't take government horses.
- What about the others?
- I said, no government property.
It's up to you, my dear.
Tomorrow we'll take them
to the fair in Seget
and sell them for pure gold.
I take those that aren't the army's.
Wait. You still haven't paid
for the last ones we brought.
You're always at my throat.
Give me some time to breathe.
I wish to do honest business.
Honest business
selling stolen horses?
I'd like to offer my best wishes
to your honoured guests
and to your family.
May you all live long!
Thank you.
But it's bad luck to start
a new year with old debts.
Let's go.
Excuse us.
You wait here.
- Do you like me?
- Not much.
Come back at Easter
and I'll pay you the rest.
All right.
Don't be angry. You've got
the finest Bessarabian racers.
They're priceless. Farewell!
Get down!
Zobar, to the left!
Surround them!
Don't shoot!
I want them alive!
Capture them alive!
Run for it!
Let them have the horses!
Let them go! To hell with them!
We'll be caught!
They'll hang us!
Come on, come closer!
Come get me! Come on!
We'll finish up
on the end of a rope.
Hanging high from the oak branches!
Leave the horses, Zobar!
Leave the horses,
let's get across the Tisza!
Shut up and run for it!
You could at least pity the horses,
you Gypsy swine!
The crows will pick out
my violet eyes!
You'll be hanged!
- You will be hanged yourself!
- We'll hang you by your feet!
You'll have to catch me first!
Now run for it! Quick!
We'll go this way!
Son of a bitch!
After them!
This is the end of a Gypsy boy!
Who are you?
My… name is…
Zobar.
And what is… this?
Turn around.
It's moon dust.
As a child I drank moon dew.
Bullets have no power over me.
So I've seen.
Lower your left arm.
The pain will pass into the earth.
Where do you come from?
Galicia. Last night
we crossed over the Carpathians.
They're covered with snow. Here,
on the Tisza, there's still summer.
Close your eyes.
Everything will pass.
Where are you?
Oh, look at that!
It's Zobar, Zobar's back
Zobar is back!
You keep wandering around the world.
You've forgotten us.
Welcome back Zobar!
Rusalina! Wake up, you little fool!
Zobar is here with presents for you.
Luiku.
Do you think I've gotten pretty?
Pretty as death.
And our mama, was she beautiful?
She was so beautiful that the women
chased her from the villages.
Whenever they saw her,
they made the sign of the cross.
There was no other Gypsy
that could compare to her beauty.
- Then I'm beautiful, too.
- How do you know?
Everyone always says,
Rusalina's the picture
of her mother.
I'll find a master painter.
You'll be the model for a portrait
of our mother in miniature.
Greetings, father.
People say that you have
acquired great knowledge.
They say you know Russian,
as well as German,
Polish, and Rumanian, too?
That's right, father.
That's true.
And I only know…
how to read men's faces.
Do you think that's easier?
Not at all, father.
To read men's hearts as you do
is worth far more than books.
On your face
I see the shadow of death.
Send it away.
I only wish I could.
How many horses
have died under you?
Three.
I gave up after the second one,
and so should you.
No, father, I can't. I can't.
Get it.
For you.
- Thanks.
- I appreciate it, Zobar. Thank you.
- Godspeed you, Zobar.
- God bless you.
- God be with you, Zobar.
- Take Care
Yulishka, how do you manage
never to spill a drop?
I know by hearing where things are.
As I know you're coming
by your horse's hoof beats.
I drink to you.
And I drink to you.
Don't misunderstand me, my friends,
when I come to this house
it is with respect
and affection for you.
You just squander your money,
you rascal.
Your eyes are shining as at a feast.
Aralambi,
turn your back to us, dear.
Face the wall.
Play a lullaby for us.
Yulishka's eyelids are already
heavy with the evening mists.
You got no shame, Luiku.
You should know
that what is sweet
is always shameless.
I am your wheat field, Zobar,
whose grain you come to harvest
once a year
and leave again.
Are you all right?
You have a fever. Are you ill?
No.
I'll bring you some fresh water.
Buy cocks, my beauty.
You're asking too much for them.
A Swiss watch, Mister Gypsy,
you won't find one like it.
Listen to that sound!
Sweet-smelling hay!
Haven't you looked enough?
Beautiful Swiss watches!
Everything for you, Madame.
Or maybe for your gentleman?
Fine Swiss watches!
Get your fresh sweet loaf!
Fresh sweet loaf!
Get him away, he eats my hay!
Do me now.
Me, too.
Ah, Shukar, that is lovely!
I can do everything,
but that beats me!
I'm selling it cheap.
Here's a black beauty!
This is a young, healthy animal!
Buy a young black horse!
He is not young.
Just look at his teeth.
- When will you pay your debt?
- You'll get it!
Come, my treasure,
come, my lovely, I will tell you
what your future holds.
- A handsome horse.
- An Arabian race horse.
Yeah, I see.
Do you remember last year, the horse
I bought from you in Mishkolts?
- From me?
- Yes.
Stand still!
You died this hack with ink,
bastard! Here, look!
I've looked for you
for a whole year, you dog!
Come on, come here.
Come, come here.
I'll kill him!
Ah, Gypsies, why should we kill each
other? There aren't many of us left.
All right, calm down, everybody!
Take off that sheepskin!
If I do, I'll be cold.
You must clean up our town
and throw out all this riff-raff!
Allow us, Officer,
and we'll drive him out...
You can't take
the law into your hands!
He's also a human being, ladies and
gentlemen! He almost bought a watch.
Why, there's the chicken
I thought I'd lost!
I would have him whipped here now.
Don't you think I'm right, dear?
Of course you are, dear.
I'd give you a gold piece
if you'll let him go.
Don't try to sweet-talk to me.
I'm doing my job.
This one should be whipped too.
They're all the same.
Who wants to try
giving me the stick?
You?
Your Honour, if we're not supposed
to steal chickens
or steal geese
or a loaf of bread,
how are we to live in this world?
Get out of here!
I don't want to see you anymore!
You'll never see me again.
I'll never forget your kindness.
Where are you from?
We came from Galicia.
We just got here.
I'm very grateful to you.
Don't steal anymore
chickens or geese.
- What should I steal?
- Girls.
And horses.
And if you can't steal, work.
You dishonour our people.
Would anyone hire me to work,
with a mug like this?
- What's your name?
- Bucha.
- Who is your headman?
- Old Nur.
Nemcho Nur?
Yeah, he can't seem to die.
And who are you?
Zobar.
Can you remember?
Luiku Zobar?
May you live for all eternity!
Let all your wishes be granted!
What a fortunate man I am
to meet Zobar at last!
Where have you come from?
Come and visit us,
it would give us all such pleasure.
Our camp is not very far,
on the banks of the Tisza.
You'll like our tribe, they're
the bravest.
Only I am a rotten apple.
For you.
From my heart.
Our girls are
as lovely as icons.
Get out of the way,
you spawn of the devil!
Turn back!
Let's turn!
Go on!
You're an extraordinary girl!
Good day to you, young ladies.
You look like a smart man, sir.
Only your driver's a fool.
May I apologize for us both?
Here's my hand. I'd like you
to tell my fortune if you will.
If you wish,
I can tell your name.
What is it?
I see it all here, my Lord.
Antal is your name.
You'll have a long life, my Lord,
only I must tell you something.
Your life will be a miserable one,
because the devil of desire
dominates you,
but you're made of wax.
Have you nothing good to tell me?
Tell your driver to give me his whip
and I'll drive for you.
Didn't I tell you, my Lord,
that you've got a lot of wax in you?
Apolodor, give her the whip.
- Wait at the inn.
- Yes, sir.
Well, ladies, go into the coach.
All right, get in.
Let's ride!
Come and live in my house,
I'll give you everything you want.
And have to bow to all your wishes?
You'd better get lost, my Lord!
Giddap, darlings!
Oh, good afternoon, my Lord.
We've just received the most
fabulous models from Paris.
The latest thing in fashion.
Please come right in.
Let me show you, my Lord.
Look, my friends,
our honoured guest has arrived!
The day we welcome you,
is the greatest day for us all.
Your eyes are
like wells emitting light.
Out tribe has grown strong.
Chudra is back with us.
We also have Danilo,
a great soldier.
He bears scars that show
how bravely he fought.
He brought with him
his daughter, Rada.
And the sky above our camp
has become brighter than before.
Speak to us, Zobar,
words from your heart.
When you are gone,
your words will stay with us.
Stay away from her, Brother Luiku,
she'd be the ruin of you.
And nobody will be able
to help you, not even me.
Beware, Zobar, she's a witch.
- Don't you remember me?
- No.
You were in the forest,
your hair was in braids.
No.
You healed me with moon dust,
remember?
Giddap! Go on!
Rada, I'm made of granite,
like the mountain.
- Good.
- What's good?
Your words are good,
but your lies are bad.
What an old jade you've got!
I'll bring you
a beautiful white mare,
as fiery and wild as you are.
I'm going to be your destruction,
my friend. Your destruction.
I want that white mare.
You can have the rest.
You're lost, Zobar, you're in her
power, that beautiful witch.
Oh, my pretty sweethearts!
Where is Zobar?
Where's Luiku Zobar? We'll find him
anyway, and we'll hang him.
But that will be tomorrow.
And today any one of you
can make money on him.
You hear me, Gypsies?
One hundred gold pieces for him
alive and fifty for his body!
Don't touch His Majesty
the Emperor
Franz Joseph the Second.
Please, Your Honour,
don't take him from me.
Where is Luiku Zobar?
Where is Zobar?
You don't know
where Zobar is either?
We'll shoot every last one
of your horses and bears!
Where is Luiku Zobar? You hear,
Gypsies? A hundred pieces of gold!
Don't touch the wheels!
May you burn in hell
together with these wheels!
Don't touch them, I said!
Get out of here!
You just wait! I'll show you
what a Gypsy can do!
So you've got claws,
you stray cat!
Your Honour, don't touch
the Emperor Franz Joseph II!
General,
I'm at your service, sir!
Get out of here!
What are you laughing at, you fool?
I'm not a fool,
I am Zobar's sister.
You're the fool
to look in the trunk.
My name is Rusalina.
I'll see that you remember me.
Where's your brother?
You know what, policeman?
I'm gonna steal horses too.
- We'll catch you and hang you.
- No way.
- Why not?
- We have drunk the moon dew.
Bullets can't stop us,
the forest gives us shelter,
the night saves us.
Sergeant, I've found Napoleon!
Look, Sergeant,
I've found Napoleon!
Ready… aim!
Don't shoot, please, Sergeant,
you must not do this!
Don't shoot!
I'll give you my son.
I'll give you Luiku Zobar.
Why did they do that?
We came too late. They're gone.
Who are they?
Are they crazy or what?
No, brother, they're artistes.
I asked around.
The camp left two days ago.
They were seen heading for
the mountains.
They seemed to be
going back to Galicia.
All right.
You'll go for nothing.
Go to Balint.
The money he owes me for
the Bessarabian racers is yours.
Why are you giving everything away
as if you were dying?
Share it with Bubulia.
Oh, I'm going to collect everything,
don't worry.
I don't want it, Zobar.
I'm going to Galiсia with you,
all right?
No, brother Bubulia.
Go and find my people.
Give this to my sister.
Take it, brother Bubulia.
I give it to you.
Let's drink to our farewell.
What is this, brother?
Are you going to die?
To our brothership.
Goodbye. When you get enough
of loving, you'll come back.
Go now. Go.
My son…
Forgive me.
- Are you Luiku Zobar?
- Yes.
You're under arrest.
Put your hands on your head.
Stand up.
Just a second, you haven't paid.
All right,
you can keep my horse till I return.
Good enough.
Offer my respects to the young lady
and give her the dress.
Yes, sir.
A gift for you from my master.
Get up please, my dear.
Come on, rise!
Will you give me your daughter,
Danilo?
I'll pay. I'll give you whatever you
want.
Only rich men buy
and sell everything,
from pigs to their own souls.
You insolent nobody!
Why do you have dealings with
a nobody like me, your honour?
I'm sorry, soldier, I didn't mean
to offend you or your daughter.
Old habits die hard.
I came to you, Gypsy,
with my respect. And you?
Where's your generosity, soldier?
I have no generosity, my Lord,
I have nothing.
I have only my daughter, Rada.
Nothing else!
Listen to me, my Lord,
I do have a favour to ask you.
Whatever you want.
Anything?
- Anything.
- You swear?
I swear.
I want Bucha to put on the dress.
Go on, Bucha, put it on!
I'm sorry, my Lord.
Come to my house tomorrow.
I invite you all. We will talk.
Here, soldier. It will come handy.
My name is Antal Siladi.
Bucha, go return his money.
Quickly!
Why?
Get out of my sight!
Excuse me for my audacity, my Lord.
You seem to be a kind and good man.
Don't come here again,
stay away from these people.
You can see that they only
know how to speak with knives.
My son, Almighty God
has commanded us
to work for the salvation of souls.
But it is not here on earth that
the sinner may find his redemption.
You've eaten the bread of the outlaw
and drunk the wine of stealing.
Do you know, Father,
how delicious stolen wine tastes?
Who are you?
A devil or simply a foolish child?
I am Zobar.
The greatest horse thief
in the world, Father.
Is there anything more you'd like
to say?
I wish I could bid farewell
to my people.
Stroke my horses and spit on them
to protect myself from the evil eye.
I wish I had a little
of that stolen wine to drink.
May God in heaven save his soul.
And the body too, Father.
Pray to the Lord to save me
and I'll bring you
the best horse in the world.
- Shall I open up?
- Yes, do it.
Greetings, brother Balint!
I've come to get the money
you owe us, sir.
If you'll forgive my intrusion.
That I owe you?
That's right, your honour.
An old debt,
brother Balint, very old.
You're no brother to me,
remember it.
Don't get angry.
Zobar's gone away
and he sent me for the money.
I was not dealing with you, and
I'm not going to settle it with you.
Why are you so rude, brother Balint?
You should've asked me into your
house, offered me some wine.
It's no time to be drinking wine.
You know, brother Balint,
unless you pay up,
I'll take the horses back.
I can easily sell them to Rumanians
or Guzuls across the river.
Perhaps you can even lose some
of your own. That's the man I am.
Go on, take them.
Oh, what a mistake, my Lord!
There they are, my darlings.
One, two, three,
four, five, six.
There you are, my sweethearts!
I'm gonna get married now,
with a dowry like this.
My lovelies!
Let's go home.
There you are…
Come along…
What are you doing, sons of a…
Keep him hidden, and tonight
throw him in the Tisza.
Aren't you glad to see me?
Good day, Gypsies.
An honoured guest is always
welcome here.
Welcome, my Lord.
Good people!
I speak to you as to my peers.
My conscience is clear
before God and you.
Let Rada marry me.
I'll share all with you, everything
I own!
I'm very rich, Danilo.
Why don't you say something,
old men?
Speak, daughter, what's your answer?
He's waiting!
You're welcome, my Lord.
Think about it, my Lord.
Your nest is for
doves and birds of prey.
What will I be
if I enter your nest?
I've given it a lot of thought,
before I came here
for the third time.
It would be better
if you didn't come.
I wish you a long and happy life.
- Where are you going?
- To the end of the world, my Lord.
- Why?
- To go there and come back.
What kind of people are you?
What do you want?
Nothing, my Lord.
Nothing but the road.
Let's go!
Don't take it too hard, my Lord.
Time will heal all.
May you burn in hell!
Let the devil's fires
spoil your beauty and your life!
Burn in hell!
Pardon this sinner, heavenly Father.
I wish we had the drummers here,
in gold doublets, as in olden times.
I recall a hanging in Magdeburg.
That was a real spectacle!
It was unforgettable!
Almost like a coronation.
We can't begin to compare to it.
What we're doing is vulgar!
We're in the provinces, gentlemen.
They don't even know
how to strangle a man here.
They write anonymous letters
full of errors in every line.
The local beauties here smear
goose fat over their hair.
Mister Mayor,
shall we read the sentence?
To whom? It's just a waste of time.
It's not Copernicus,
it's only a miserable horse thief.
Let me through!
Mister Mayor, please pardon him!
I beg you, Mister Mayor!
- Take her away!
- Have pity!
No! No!
Please, have mercy!
Pardon him!
Guards, forward march!
One, two!
One two, one two! Left face!
Halt!
Stop sneezing, you idiot!
Of course, Mister Mayor!
I promise.
Mercenary dogs!
Mister Mayor, I did it for you,
because he annoyed you
with his sneezing.
Tell them to release me
and I'll do everything myself.
All right.
Step back!
I'm waiting for your orders.
- Just get it over with quickly!
- Yes, sir.
Come on, my dear, get on with it.
Want some soap?
It makes it slide easier.
Save it for yourself.
Look, Mister Mayor.
What is he doing there?
I don't know, Mister Mayor.
- How did it get here?
- It's very odd.
Get rid of it!
Yes, sir.
Get rid of that horse.
Shoot!
Don't stand there!
Bubulia, this way!
You fat pigs!
You eat too much!
It spoils your aim!
Thank you, heavenly Father!
Save my sinful soul.
Bubulia!
Bubulia…
Zobar!
Break it, Chudra.
I brought you
the white mare!
Zobar!
Look, Zobar, the cards always
say the same thing.
There were four of us.
It was as if we held the whole
earth in our hands.
Two of us were killed.
Talimon has vanished into thin air.
Now it's my turn.
Well…
You see?
I'm always wherever you are.
This is your road
and there you are,
and I am always
crossing your path.
That's a fine pipe you have.
A Polish prince gave it to me.
I was like gold, he said.
Yes, you all are. Ready to cut
each other's throats for gold.
Two of your tribe
have come over to ours.
So your good-for-nothings
have got two more.
Or maybe it's
because I'm really like gold?
Oh, you really love yourself.
Who should I love then, Zobar?
What man will make
my heart vibrate
like a fine steel blade?
Hey, stop smoking.
But why?
There are saints here. You shouldn't
smoke in their presence.
What made them saints?
They suffered a lot.
All their lives, understand?
I suffer too.
I can't tell you how much I suffer.
So that makes me a saint too.
Zobar, why don't you build a fire
so I can dry my clothes?
Don't look at me that way,
Zobar. Don't look.
It will make your head spin.
I've never loved anybody.
But I love you.
And I love liberty, Luiku.
I love it more than you.
But you couldn't live without me,
as I couldn't live without you.
Will you be my body and soul, Luiku?
Your words are like clever snares,
Rada.
They're spread out all around me.
Wherever I set my foot,
I'm bound to be caught.
But what would happen
should I escape your net, Rada?
Perhaps you're blind, Zobar?
The earth is covered in nets.
Everybody sets up nets.
Some are subtle and honest,
others crude and brutal.
No one can avoid them.
Ah, I'll offer you my lips
and my caresses, Zobar.
Ah, my love will be so sweet.
You'll forget the whole world.
You won't miss those wild
gallops over the plain.
Tomorrow you will submit to me
like to your elder.
You'll bow down before me
in front of my people.
And you'll kiss my right hand.
When you do, I'll become your wife.
And then…
Then we'll have our night.
I will come to you,
naked as a newborn child.
And we shall be reborn together,
Luiku.
Come here.
May your love lie heavy
upon your thoughts,
and upon your heart
and on the hands that caress me.
Drink!
Don't be afraid of me,
Luiku, don't.
I was… I was even more
beautiful than your Rada.
Where is she? Where's Rada?
Your Rada's gone away,
she left, my dear.
They set out at sunrise.
- Why have you stayed?
- I'll wait for the first frost.
I must gather herbs,
then I'll join them.
Just before winter kills herbs,
their poison is strongest.
- Where did they go?
- Toward the mountain pass.
They'll stop in Bucovina
and make camp.
Vanity…
It's all vanity.
And your suffering is vain, too.
I'll give you a potion,
it will make you stronger.
And you'll forget
your love for Rada.
Ah, Zobar…
You'll go there for your death.
What will you have?
Nothing.
I'll rest a little, then I'll go.
Go on, rest if you like.
Everyone only wants to rest today.
That cursed Friday.
What's the matter, Zobar?
Why do you look so sad?
Go wash up.
Wake up, man!
Hey, Innkeeper,
fill up four big jugs
with wine and hang them
on my saddle.
Right away, Zobar.
Today we're going to celebrate!
Drink, my friends!
Take me to her.
You'll be my best man.
You've forgotten.
I told you to have
three locks on you.
One for your lips, one for your
heart, and one for your thoughts.
They've all been broken.
Take me to her.
I know, Zobar, you've broken
many a wild horse,
only so far they've always
been easy ones.
That's so.
You are right.
Listen, Danilo,
a wild horse needs a strong hand.
Will you give me your daughter
in marriage?
Take her, Zobar, if you can.
No one can escape his destiny.
The fastest horse in the world
cannot help you
run away from yourself.
I take you for my wife, Rada,
upon my honour,
before your father,
before all our Gypsy
brothers and sisters.
He got a bridle on her!
He's got her! What a man he is!
- You're an idiot!
- Why do you say that?
We'll see
who's got a bridle on whom.
I warn you, Rada,
don't go against my will.
Remember, I was born free
and I will go on living as I will.
Oh, Zobar!
What did you do that for?
It isn't funny, is it?
I think you're safer on horseback.
Yes, I think you're right.
What are you doing that for, girl?
He's my best friend!
- Please help me…
- Get away!
Last night, brothers, I looked
into my heart.
And I discovered that the old free
life no longer matters to me.
Only Rada matters.
Only she is in my heart.
And so I have decided,
brother Gypsies,
to bow down in front of her,
as she asked me to, to show everyone
that her beauty's conquered Zobar.
I who until now went to any woman
as a stallion goes to a mare.
Ah, Zobar, Zobar…
No, don't go, Chudra.
Stay and watch how Zobar
bows before your Rada.
What a long speech you're making,
Zobar.
Never mind.
Don't be in a hurry.
Now witness this… brothers.
Your hand.
Your hand!
No, Zobar,
you must bow down before me
and kiss my right hand,
as you promised.
Your hand.
No.
Zobar!
Mama…
I knew that…
Danilo!
Rada…
I didn't want to…
The End