She scares me so much.
Just count with me.
VIENNA, AUSTRIA. DECEMBER 1877
How long? - 40.
Nonsense. It was a whole minute and eleven seconds, Majesty.
Fetch Lotti.
The Emperor and Empress will arrive to the last bars of the national anthem.
You leave the carriage simultaneously
in front of the main entrance of the new Museum of Art History.
You will be greeted by the architect Baron von Hasenauer,
mayor Felder and minister-president Prince of Auersperg,
who will join you in the topping-out ceremony.
Since you haven't seen him in a while, Your Majesty will permit me to remark
that the Prince has been critical of the Double Monarchy from the very start.
He seems to keep a precise record of how many days
Your Majesty spends on Hungarian soil.
At the Emperor's side prevails
He related by common sense
Rich in charm that never outdated
Our gracious Empress
What fortune to be praised as highly
Stream from the sky on them
Hail Franz Joseph
Hail Elise
Blessing to the entire House of Habsburg
Majesty.
Watch out for your back, Adolf.
A magnificent building. You must be proud, Carl.
As though your ink drawing came to life and made its way to the Ringstrasse.
What a rare honour, Your Majesty.
My wife read recently in the papers that you were struggling with your weight.
These tabloids are a veritable plague.
Your Majesty, what a delight to welcome you in person.
Being appreciative of art, I know of course the depictions of your gracefulness.
Luckily, there are plenty because here in Vienna
we almost think of Majesty as a phantom.
You sway back slowly and then...
And then the eyes. At the right moment, you do this...
Like this and then...
That did not look quite right, Ludwig. - Show me again then.
You remind me of my dogs.
I'd love to be your dog, then I wouldn't vex your husband so much.
You would. He's jealous of my dogs.
Is he? - He is.
But actually,
you much rather remind me of my wallpaper.
They were inconsolable.
They want to assure themselves of your existence occasionally.
I really felt... so weak.
Those cheekbones. - He is sweet, isn't he?
Is your dear cousin staying much longer?
He is leaving tomorrow. He has obligations.
I have never met a more fickle person. - Haven't you?
People will gossip that you are sick again.
Well, it does make me sick
to stand there with a kilo of tin on my head, while everybody gawks at me.
What will you do about the Serbians? What does Gyula say?
General Beck and I have been in contact.
Andrássy's opinion is of minor importance now.
As is mine.
Stop that.
See what Hungary has brought us? - Yes.
A kingdom.
I asked for your opinion back then.
And I am despised for doing so to this day.
"A lion doesn't lose sleep over the opinion of sheep."
Nobody loves nobody.
Everybody loves what he wants from others.
And we love anybody who loves in us that which we would like to be.
Let's go on a journey.
Majesty, it's Christmas in two days.
"The large assembly organised by the Independence Party
was attended by over 5,000 people.
Vehement speeches were held in opposition to Minister Andrássy..."
Mama, the trees are being decorated. They are the biggest ones we have ever had.
You have to see them. - I do not care much about dead plants.
The child looks pale.
Yes, Majesty. - You must get some fresh air.
When was she last outdoors? - I have so much studying to do, Mama.
Studying is good, but breathing is even better.
Send for Hunyady.
The child is reading too much in German. - Yes.
A young idealist has of course no idea
of the duties and devotion that mark the lives of the aristocracy.
But it's quite amusing to leaf through his newspaper.
I sometimes do it in secret.
It must be the audacity of youth
that gives him these republican ideas.
These newspaper people are quite infatuated with Her Majesty.
She is always a source of stories, your Mama, isn't she?
More of rumours, I would say.
Long may she live Long may she live
And yet more so
Long may she live
Beautiful may she remain
And yet more so
The candles, Mama.
A steady breath like a 20-year-old.
Here's to you, my darling.
Happy Birthday.
At the age of 40 a person begins to disperse and fade,
darkening like a cloud.
For example, we intend to place the two sections,
for peaceful and for restless patients, further apart,
so the emotional mood swings of one group
do not trigger attacks of hysteria and panic in the other.
And in line with Your Majesty's valuable remark on your last visit,
which put the medical staff in a flurry,
the installation of modern bathrooms is being considered.
Especially since the healing power of warm baths,
with various substances or even electricity added to the water,
is proving of increasing importance in this treatment.
Hello. Candied violets.
You will like them.
Paralytic imbecility.
Triggered by secondary syphilis.
Don't you remember me?
Last time you told me I was beautiful.
Most of the women here are by nature melancholic.
Jesus.
A fairy.
Valerie.
Come on, get dressed.
It's night time.
We are going on a little trip. Just the two of us.
Is it allowed? - I allow it, my dearest.
Come.
Your horse is falling asleep. - I can't see anything, Mama.
And I'm so cold.
Darkness is beautiful. It's protection.
Valerie.
"... saw a large fish flapping around,
trapped in a thorn bush, unable to move.
As soon as the fish saw Sepp on his horse, it addressed him:
God bless you, please free me from this thorn bush.
I have been trapped here for seven years..."
Over 40 degrees? - 39.
She is quite fine.
Papa!
It's beyond my comprehension that you of all people would risk our child's health.
Will you always blame me?
We didn't know it better. We should never have travelled with Sophie.
She could have fallen ill here, too. - No!  - Yes!
I don't want you to pass on your restlessness to our child.
The task of raising the children is mine alone.
You committed yourself on paper.
I do not believe that you see more in them
than their position in the succession to the throne.
Papa!
Hello, princess.
She would be 22 years old now.
She wasn't that droll and chubby at all.
But she did have that serious look.
He captured that well.
At least we leave behind a pretty picture of her.
The room needs to be cleaned.
My husband is not joining me?
I was ordered to serve your dinner only, Majesty.
Good evening, Your Majesty.
Has His Majesty gone out?
No, Your Majesty. His Majesty has already gone to bed.
Is he unwell?
His Majesty is quite well, Your Majesty.
You arsehole.
Forgive me for disturbing you so late. - The later the disturbance, the better.
You are leaving so suddenly. - I always go away after New Year.
My sister will be joining me.
Well, Papa is surprised that you...
Howsoever... I would like to accompany you.
Lovely.
Now they're checking if I've grown old.
NORTHAMPTONSHIRE, ENGLAND. JANUARY 1878
Thank you.
Bay will never marry Charlotte.
You know very well why.
Don't you want your sherry?
I do not see the attraction of alcohol. - It helps to relax.
Remember father after seven tankards of beer?
You exaggerate.
I believed every man spoke that way after dark.
He slurred his speech after dinner.
My sister is tired.
Yes, Your Highness.
Your Imperial Highness.
You have good eyes. - Yes, I do.
Majesty, Mr Louis Le Prince, resident in Leeds.
He asked to meet you. The Earl felt his request might interest you.
You have a request? - Your Majesty.
It is said that your interest in technical innovation is unusual for a woman.
And what I have to present is indeed an exciting new invention.
But you don't appear excited. - No. I am even-tempered by disposition.
I would like to film you, Majesty.
What would you like?
I have developed an apparatus that can capture moving pictures.
Like photography?
The difference is that photographs don't move.
I don't think much of photographs.
They claim to be objective. But nothing is ever objective.
Well...
the accounts of your beauty and your grace are not objective either.
But I can now tell that they are true.
Come back tomorrow.
All right. Thank you.
Goodnight. - Goodnight.
Monsieur, can your device hear me?
What a wonderful idea.
But no, alas.
No.
So I can say anything I wish as long as I smile?
Yes, Madam. You just say whatever you wish.
Say whatever you want.
What does your father say about this?
He allows her to do as she wishes.
But he is naturally concerned.
All by yourself today?
Not any longer. Come, let's ride together to the other end of the forest.
I am not in the mood.
I need to talk to you, Mama.
You are too close to your riding instructor.
Bay is not my instructor. I ride just as well as him.
People talk about you. And I don't want Papa to hear what they say.
If you're bothered by gossip, you're hardly cut out to be Emperor.
You should maintain more distance to him.
It's not fitting.
I shall not allow my children to tell me what is fitting.
With all due respect, Mama, you are the one acting like a child.
You abandon yourself to every whim, without considering your position.
It's a miracle that you are unharmed. - Why?
Why can't I be dead instead of my horse? - It's sacrilege to talk like this.
He was the most intelligent and the strongest horse.
Bay will find you another horse. - I don't want another horse! I want mine!
And I shall never see Bay again.
Why?
Some gossip has imputed an affair to us and set my son against me.
I never want to see my sister again.
A little milk?
We shall help you with this.
You are back. - Yes.
VIENNA, AUSTRIA. MARCH 1878
I wasn't expecting you so soon.
I am busy after this. I shall come and see you later.
Mr Blümlinger, we will find a solution for your family.
Your wife shall not be forced to become a washerwoman. We feel for you.
You must be very tired after the exhausting journey.
I was told about your fall.
Good to see that you are unharmed.
Come over here now.
You can stop being angry with me.
I am too old for another child.
Look at me.
Don't stop looking at me.
Ida, darling. Nobody is watching, so you could try it today.
No, thank you, my dear.
I order you.
Come. There is no finer place in the whole world.
No. - Help her mount.
No, really. - Yes.
Good. Hold on tight.
Your dress.
One, two, three.
Okay.
I am holding you. Okay? - Okay.
Don't be afraid.
It's a docile horse.
Continue. Faster.
Attack.
Now! Now!
And... allez!
Bend your knees.
Move forward.
And back.
Two steps forward.
Two steps back.
One step.
Lunge.
Anna Nahowski, née Nowak.
Resident of Schönbrunner Strasse 8. 18 years old.
Married to Franz Nahowski, her second husband. An official of the South Railways.
18 years old?
Her first marriage to the silk manufacturer Johann Heuduck
was arranged by her parents.
Heuduck indulged in alcohol and was addicted to gambling.
And he was unable to get her pregnant.
They say she copies your hairstyle.
She is young. That counts more than a nice hairstyle.
Her second marriage is also grounded on financial reasons.
It seems she is longing for romance now.
As if she could find that with FJ.
Hanni, lend me a dress.
Majesty, I am Fini.
Well, Fini then.
And a few mushrooms. Not too many.
I'll get some meat.
Hello. How is your husband? - He's very busy.
I want some of this. - How much would you like?
Is it tender? It has to be tender. - Very tender, Madam. See for yourself.
Let me try. - Of course, Madam.
Exquisite.
You should take it. Your husband will like it.
Thank you. Okay. Two servings.
Advice from an experienced woman is very precious.
Your complexion has changed, Majesty.
I have been out in the fresh air a lot.
No, that's not what I mean.
No worries, I won't look. I want to be surprised.
That's wonderful after so many years of marriage.
Good morning, my darling.
Have you been smoking, Fini?
This is Hanni.
No, my darling. This is Fini. Hanni is skinnier.
Am I right, Fini?
We're dining with Latour and Rudolf. He is leaving for Prague early in the morning.
We will keep it short, as his mind will already be on his journey.
Right. Carry on and enjoy yourself. Bye.
Have you heard of the technique of moving pictures?
No, Majesty, I'm afraid I haven't.
It will replace painting.
I hope not, Majesty.
Have them bring you all my portraits hanging around the house,
and copy them.
And be careful with my complexion.
The academy in Prague is tightly organised.
And I know all the gentlemen there, of course.
I assure you, Your Majesty, I will keep an eye on Rudolf.
I am confident
the best place for the Crown Prince's military education has been found.
You know my views: Discipline is essential.
But curiosity is more important.
So go through life with your eyes wide open.
You are young and Prague is a pretty city.
Gather experience, get to know the people.
Well, well, Mr Teacher. I hope you are not referring to the young girls!
Here's to Prague.
Cheers, Father.
It breaks my heart that you're leaving.
I'm doing my duty, Mama.
Don't let Papa hurt you.
I once gave you that advice.
Did you? I think you can use it yourself, too.
Papa has his own idea of us.
And he cannot accept any other idea.
Tighter.
Tighter, I said. Don't you have any strength in your hands?
The horoscope says it's going to be a lovely day.
What do I care? Ida!
Ida!
Majesty? - I don't understand.
They travel to the North Pole now, but it's still impossible to find girls
who master their simple duties without ruining my day with their ugly visages.
She gives her best, Majesty.
Well, that's not enough.
Tighter.
Don't laugh at me.
You know exactly that I am stronger. - The plan was to cheer you up.
Then you would have to send me on a very long journey.
It's most odd.
You miss him here, but you never want to be here yourself.
You would feel the same if your only duty was having your hair braided.
If you feel like leaving, I won't hold you back.
I am very busy, anyway.
You shouldn't be working so much.
You should go for a stroll every now and then.
Schönbrunn is quite pretty in the spring.
Your new portrait is quite lovely.
I wonder how you managed to look like a young girl.
It will remind me of you when you're gone.
I'm taking Valerie with me. - I don't know.
Unlike you, she enjoys being at home.
Valerie's home is Hungary. - You are projecting, mon coeur.
Leave her here.
Look.
You see?
A series of successive pictures that produce the illusion of movement.
People will love your invention.
I don't know. So far...
... everybody just laughs at me.
Really?
People fear the ephemeral.
A beat of an eyelash, and life has passed by.
They would do anything to hold on to it. Isn't that so?
Are you different?
Yes. - How?
I have nothing to hold on to.
Except myself.
And sometimes even that seems like
an incredible effort.
He didn't want to see her. He just sent the doctor.
A hairline fracture of the right calf bone. You truly have a guardian angel, Majesty.
Consider your health a gift from God to be cherished, Majesty.
BAVARIA. MAY 1878
I had resolved to die.
I just didn't have sufficient expertise.
Stay as long as you like.
Maybe forever, then.
Won't that be too long for you?
It's not that long.
Bring me an orange. Sliced wafer-thin.
What an idea. The same for me.
And bring a little pot of melted chocolate and a bowl of whipped cream.
Very well, Majesty.
For all I care, we could have four desserts. The rest doesn't interest me.
You should enjoy your trophies, Majesty. You shot more than all the men together.
And it would be good for you, if I may be so bold.
You are even slimmer than in the portraits. - Am I?
All this is to turn us into beetles, lying on our backs and kicking our legs.
But the ability to enjoy
is an achievement of human civilisation, Your Imperial Highness.
Or to put it another way, what poor creatures would we be
without the delights of a good wine and its wonderfully relaxing effects?
It would be unfitting to consider lust in the same manner,
Your Imperial Highness.
So please allow me a little drunkenness.
I envy you.
I really do.
Open your mouth.
Isn't it comforting?
Forgive me, cousin.
We are one, my dearest. The animal instincts could never compete with that.
So the rumours about the stable boys are true.
I love you.
But you don't want me.
You don't want me either.
Quite beautiful, this double-headed eagle. - Indeed.
But I find it a little bit eerie. - You have many of them in Austria.
The manor stretches across the hills over there.
How do you like our region, Countess Festetics?
Or may I say Marie?
I like it here. It's very pretty.
Is it? - Yes.
Would your mistress mind if I called you Marie?
Most likely.
You look unwell.
You should eat something.
I hadn't expected such banality from you.
Forgive me. I have passed on my lunatism to you.
It's not your lunatism. I haven't been sleeping for quite some time.
Do you want me to leave? - No. On the contrary.
But please put that death wish out of your mind.
I thought I could share that with you.
I forbid you to drown in my lake.
It's my lake.
I prefer the sea anyway.
Count von Holnstein proposed to me.
I know you consider him coarse.
But he is a good-looking and smart man.
With considerable influence and wealth.
And he is from Bavaria.
It's most likely my last opportunity, Elisabeth.
By no means.
You are the only one who loves me the way I am.
VIENNA, AUSTRIA. JULY 1878
Come here. My darlings. Hello.
Hello, my darlings.
Come here.
My dearest darling.
We were concerned.
Papa says you can't even look after yourself.
She is like a book to me.
A riddle on each page.
Her soul is like a chaotic museum.
Full of treasures that cannot be exploited.
She doesn't know what to do with all that.
She lives in a different world, where she is walking a path
so narrow that only one person can walk it.
The summer is unbearable. Does the humid air bother you too?
Someone should invent a machine that turns the heat into cool air.
Like an oven, but the other way around. Wouldn't that be marvellous?
With all due respect, Highness, an astounding idea.
I heard there are even women who invent things.
Of course.
You don't wish to put to bed the old rumour about you and Andrássy.
I simply wish I was allowed to talk as well.
Do you follow Sarajevo? - Of course.
But when I look around here, everything seems unchanged.
Crayfish, champagne and conversations about the weather.
The monarchy is in decline.
Don't let your father hear that.
He knows what I think. And he blames you for it.
Your father believes God puts everyone in the place He considers right for them.
God certainly made a mistake with me.
With me, too.
It's very early for a conversation.
I am told that you don't sleep anyway.
What is so urgent?
It's my duty to control the fate of our Empire.
Your duty is merely to represent.
That's what I chose you for, that's what you're here for.
You liked it as long as you enjoyed the beautiful clothes and the admiration.
But pleasure has no role to play in the tasks assigned to us.
I was really tired.
Von Widerhofer will be in your chambers at 8 o'clock to examine you.
Never forget, no matter if bronchitis or head-ache,
you are the Empress.
I'm sorry that you are suffering.
I don't know what to say, Majesty.
I would kill for a cigarette.
Make way, please.
FJ sits at his desk all day and complains about the load of work.
But no word about the thousands of wounded.
Get me the numbers, please.
My dearest darling, you shouldn't have seen that.
We'll have Demel send up something.
Do you still like their cream cake?
Mama, smoking is unfitting.
You embarrassed me.
How can you think of cream cake now?
Thank you.
Gyula and you underestimated the occupation.
Well...
It was very nice of you to visit the wounded.
Is there anything I can do? - You have already done a great deal.
It means a lot to soldiers if one shows interest in their fate.
Yes.
Confide in me.
What are your plans for Sarajevo?
I have the impression, the situation there is still unsteady...
Enough!
You see what Hungary has brought us.
Well, a kingdom.
Well, this conversation doesn't get any better by repetition.
Do you have a wish?
Mon coeur? Anything at all.
Allow me to bring you some joy. Just tell me what you want.
A Bengal tiger.
Or an extension to the lunatic asylum.
You have ample choice now.
Your Majesty, what a surprise!
I like it here with the women.
Have the bathtubs arrived yet?
What's wrong with her? - Adultery, Majesty.
She seems harmless, but she is a real hussy.
The warm baths have a temperature of approximately 32 degrees centigrade.
They are applied for up to 25 minutes
and are indicated for all forms of mental agitation.
They have a powerful soothing effect on the entire organism.
She looks as though she wants to weep but can't.
Very well observed, Your Imperial Highness.
Did something bad happen to her?
One of her children died. But she has three others.
Too bad that she can't find consolation in them.
What is this? - It's called heroin.
A semi-synthetic opioid. An absolute novelty on the market.
It suppresses pain and has a soothing effect.
I have no pain. - It could do you good.
It's absolutely harmless.
In the interest of your health, may I advise you to take care of yourself.
At the age of 40...
I may remind you
that 40 is the average life expectancy of your female subjects.
SUMMER RESIDENCE OF THE EMPRESS. AUGUST 1878
Very well. Again.
Press here.
Marie.
You shouldn't have dinner this evening.
You're serious about it.
You have already given me your life.
Marie.
At the Emperor's side prevails
He related by common sense
Rich in charm that never outdated
Our gracious Empress
Mama is very serious today, isn't she?
She misses the Emperor, Princess.
He has never been absent on his birthday before.
Fini!
Come!
Quick. We have to unlace the corsage.
Take this off. - It's all right.
I'm sorry. - Fini, come!
Quick.
Help me... - I'm sorry.
Everything's fine. Fini, open the front.
They will say I have put on weight.
But they probably will have liked it.
You're getting it tangled. Give it to me.
I've been wondering for years why you put up with this.
Ida, you have to weigh me. I feel weightless all of a sudden.
First, this must go to the wig-maker in Vienna as quickly as possible.
Fanny, pull yourself together.
This was my life's work.
Well, now you have completed it.
What touching devotion. She has set her heart on your hair.
She is foolish, but she had the patience of an angel with you.
No!
None for you.
Three orange days a week.
Clear beef broth in the evenings. Lean meat, if you want. Nothing more.
No potatoes, no bread, no dumplings. And no pastry, for God's sake.
Mama?
Come in, darling.
Forgive me, Mama.
It's all right.
Mama, I feel like crying.
But that would be bad manners.
But Mama!
Let me hold you.
Just one last time like my little chick.
It's as though a part of you has died.
Stay.
What an honour to be invited for coffee with Your Majesty.
VIENNA, AUSTRIA. SEPTEMBER 1878
You know the Emperor.
It's funny.
When I met him, I thought he was just a simple soldier who had lost his way.
I want you to be his mistress.
May I have some sugar?
According to my information,
your husband is hardly ever home during the week.
So you will receive the Emperor regularly.
He...
has little time and no patience.
Expect him in your bed, without your corsage.
And...
talk to him.
Just be kind to him.
It's a matter close to my heart.
You like him, don't you?
The day I met him was probably...
... the happiest day in my life.
We have an agreement then.
It will not be to your disadvantage.
55.9.
What a surprise, my darling.
Would you like to eat cream cake with me? Would you like a hot chocolate?
I have drawn something for you, Mama.
You were very dignified that day.
Minny says you are leaving tomorrow?
Yes.
Then you should have an early night. Adieu.
We can also wait until morning. - Let's go.
ANCONA, ITALY. OCTOBER 1878
Your Majesty, I must urge you to go under deck.
The wind is getting stronger.
In a minute, signore.