‘Seolgyeong’is a weaponized
‘talisman’that seals vile spirits
with Buddhist sutras and patterns.
Dong-woo!
Grandpa…
I’m here, don’t worry.
You’ve reached your destination.
This is a no parking zone,
don’t park here.
How did you wake up on cue?
Were you pretending to be asleep?
Man…
I heard the GPS say we’re here.
In-bae, I mean, Apprentice Kang.
It’s our first gig in a while,
let’s do it right.
Stop with that Apprentice Kang,
a technician should
stick to technical things!
I know all about
your technical prowess,
startups like us
have to wear many hats.
I’m not asking for the impossible,
Apprentice Kang is capable
of multi-tasking,
so, you’re the only one
whom I fully trust.
Multi-tasking?
What’s wrong with the madame here?
She said her daughter’s
possessed or something.
A middle schooler.
Are you allowed to park there?
They can’t tow that.
Holy cow…
I got a half basement room
with 3-year savings,
I’ll have to work 250 years
to live in a place like this.
I’d be so old in 250 years.
That again?
Why bother ringing that?
it never rings…
In-bae, be quiet.
Nothing much here.
No need to get nervous,
stick to what we do.
Stupid concept and freaks,
you live tough lives.
It looked so fake on YouTube.
You must be the middle schooler.
Hey!
What are you doing there?!
Where are your manners?
Allow me to apologize.
She’s usually…
She’s usually not like that,
but she changed suddenly.
It’s as if she’s possessed.
Do you feel anything
seeing her in person?
Shhh!
The child is not the problem.
Stench is all over the house.
Stench of rotting corpse…
is piercing my nose right now...
Morons, what a load of shit.
It’s coming from inside too,
let’s all go inside.
Apprentice Kang, make preparations.
Never cross…
this straw rope, please.
Mister, this is all bullshit, right?
You’re embarrassing us!
I’m the one embarrassed!
Shit!
Did you know what this was
before putting it here?
I was told it's a totem from a noble
house protecting its boundaries...
It did belong to a noble family,
but not home…
it’s for a tomb.
As in grave?
Yes.
This is called a tomb totem.
A totem that protects the deceased.
This totem is
creating the stench,
and turning this home
into a grave!
That’s why you’re restless in bed!
That’s right…
When you lie down, your legs itch
as if bugs crawl all over them,
pit of the stomach feels stuffy,
and even when you fall asleep,
you wake up from bad dreams!
- Yes!
- Yeah!
The business is booming,
but income is down!
- Yes, yes…
- Moron!
Hiking and golfing all weekend,
but he’s always sick…
- That’s right!
- So right!
And the daughter suddenly
became bitchy,
not only that, her grades
are dropping, am I right?!
What are you staring at?
You’re right, so right,
how could you be so accurate?
This is all because of the totem!
What should I do, doctor?
What else?!
We must exorcise
the spirit from the totem.
Raise the god of the five directions!
Drive god of the South and the East,
help us get rid of this vile spirit!
Put your phone down!
Go away!
Vile spirit, go away!
Holy shit…
Did you see that?
He stabbed it…
Phone down!
No way.
Oh gosh…
Enough!
It was haunted by a rude spirit!
What the hell?!
Gosh!
You’ll be fine behind the rope.
The spirit shall return
to the afterlife!
It has stopped.
Return at once!
Return!
- Did it return?
- Eh?
Divine wifi, divine wifi,
wifi, wifi…
- What is it?
- Come on!
What happened…
Get down!
Do you see it?
Pardon?
What should have gone that way,
came this way instead.
These are what pulled the totem.
You have a very strange taste.
That’s why you’re intrigued by these.
From here on, if something
intrigues you, avoid it at all costs.
If you get the urge to buy,
let your wife decide.
Yes, I’ll take that to my heart.
Respect.
Very well.
Because of recent events,
your daughter’s feelings were hurt,
let her take it easy for 2 weeks.
Don’t let her go to school
or other tutors,
and just let her do
whatever she wants.
I’m so sorry for not realizing your
greatness and calling you fakers!
Oh my…
Anyway, these should be cleaned up...
Please get rid of them
as you see fit.
Apprentice Kang?
Sure.
Buddha, are you okay?
It’s not an easy task,
but I’ll do it at no charge.
Only peace will remain
in this household.
DR. CHEON AND THE LOST TALISMAN
In-bae, parking…
How could they tow that?
And go easy with explosives,
that’s all money!
How could a technician not
control a rock properly?
Are you possessed by
the totem spirit?
I gotta control the music,
explosion, theatrics,
and tug all heartstrings
as Apprentice Kang…
I can’t do this alone,
hire someone!
In-bae, I really was going to
hire someone this time,
but I’m too nervous to do it,
look at what happened today,
I'm too busy cleaning up your mess,
how can I handle another newbie.
You should've gone with
an easy target.
There were so many light things,
why pick this heavy rock?
You see?
You’re not ready for an assistant.
What’s this?
This is the kid’s Instagram,
a birthday party a month ago.
Good, next question,
how is that different
from today’s?
Did she cut her hair?
The totem’s not there!
The color of the dirt on it is different,
and moss is on the side
facing the sun.
It hasn’t been a few weeks
since it was bought.
Then why keep a new totem
out of view?
Because it was an eye sore
for the madame.
She must’ve hated seeing
her husband’s things.
So, you used the totem
as an excuse to make her happy,
and keep her at bay
from that weird looking husband
and bratty kid?
Right.
According to DSM-4 of
American Psychiatric Association,
Koreans suffer from 2 disorders
stemmed from culture-bound syndrome.
One is ‘anger syndrome’
and the other…
Hey, be careful!
Buddha, sorry.
The other must be
ancestral spirit possession, S-H-I-N…
Very good.
Anyway, you're saying that
we don't deal with ghosts,
but a person's mind, soul, etc...
Yes, yes, yes.
The ghosts we tackle are in...
Gosh.
Our divine toad.
Hold on tight.
Shit, goddamn rock…
Very nice.
Jeez.
I know the market price for gold,
don't even try.
Melting and molding it
will cost me quite a bit.
You can put it there
sell it as is.
You’ll go to hell
if you scam me too often.
You’ll go to prison before hell
when you sell things with seals.
Is that all for today?
This damn rock is too heavy!
You guys raid tombs now?
Was this really guarding a grave?
I saw tons of these at
restaurant gardens.
Dr. Cheon, how long will you
live like this?
Why do you continue
scamming people?!
I told you, it’s psych treatment,
not scams.
Do you honestly think, if I tell
my clients that there aren’t
any ghosts, would they just nod?
They’ll curse at me,
and run to the next shaman.
I’m preventing them from losing
tens of thousands of dollars.
How did the grandson
of a chief shaman...
Always with that chief shaman crap…
That’s ancient history,
why do you still bring that up?
Why are you so desperate
to bring that up again?
What happened to the gold price?
Reminder, reminder,
they sure can sniff money.
So many reminders…
Doc, I got gifts for you.
Are we good?
Are you the boss?
Stop worrying and focus on editing.
Hurry up!
There’s my reminder.
Medical License
Pyeongchang-dong
Madame Song
Yeah, mom.
The deaconess showed you what?
Heavenly Cheon TV’s apprentice?
I said that bastard’s not me, prick!
I’m not cursing at the deaconess.
Don’t you know where
your son works at?
I work at a very specialized
high-tech psychiatry.
Why turn me into a cult fanatic
when I have a perfectly ordinary job?
And why is a church deaconess
watching Heavenly Cheon TV?
Mom, I may have a date
on Christmas, I gotta go.
What a load of crap…
Apprentice Kang?
Yes, I’m Apprentice Kang.
You can just call me In-bae.
Kang In-bae.
Pardon me.
We’re fully booked for the year.
Sorry about that.
What a load of crap…
One sec, I’m the VP here,
I’ll talk to him.
Doc, we had bookings?
Get it together, Apprentice Kang.
I’m very much together,
thanks to her.
This is definitely a pro bono case.
Our company isn’t UNICEF.
Didn’t you see her diamond ring?
It’s gotta be at least 2 carats.
If it’s on the left hand,
is it a wedding ring?
That’s the right hand.
I told you not to miss details.
She wore it out of anxiety.
It’s an old design and wrong size.
Handed down from her mother,
she’s wearing it like a talisman.
In-bae.
I told you we shouldn’t
take on lonely and desperate…
You see?
Stop!
I heard you charge
$10,000 per job.
It’s not the money
that I chase, pursuing…
$50,000 for coming with me now,
another $50,000 after the job.
Miss!
Hm?
Where is the job?
Gwechun, Chungcheong province.
Gwechun County
Do you want to flirt with her
or get rejected?
Yoo-kyung is the first person
to offer her hand to me.
Yoo-kyung is also the first person
to unload
that much money on me.
In her 20s, dad’s car,
mom’s ring,
no parents in sight.
Resides in the country.
Looks like a student,
maybe taking some time off?
No, no, look…
Dozing off behind the wheel?
I should've driven that car for her…
Fog?
I got the thumbnail title,
‘The Lady in the Fog’.
Great concept,
I got a good feeling.
Beautiful eyes,
I sense a ton of views.
Good.
Is everyone moving out?
Is he a shaman?
Funerals everywhere,
this feels weird...
What happened here?
Who is that?
They came to give us
a quote for the move.
You look terrible,
make sure to eat.
Always call me
if you need my help.
Thank you for your concern.
Pardon me for intruding.
Can’t leave because of your sister?
What about her sister?
There’s nothing here.
It’s okay, please open.
Yoo-kyung…
Why are you doing this to me?
Doc, what’s going on here,
can we chat outside?
I’m getting a call…
Jeez!
What’s wrong with this place?
Doc, we have to get out,
let’s just bail.
How do you abandon the first person
who reached out to you?
There were others actually, and
I definitely didn’t take her hand!
In-bae, a child is tied up,
how could you say
you want to bail
after seeing that poor girl?
Then let’s call the police,
what are you doing?
In-bae.
Think carefully.
Why do you think
Yoo-kyung came to us?
She was compelled by videos
made with your technique and editing.
Your videos spawned
a $100,000 faith for us!
What if she witnesses it live?
Her faith will explode.
“My sister is back,
she’s finally exorcised!”
We get $100,000, and you can
finally take her hand.
Look.
See? There’s nothing here.
Don’t be nervous,
just do what we normally do.
Who are we really after?
Right? Go, go, go.
Excuse me!
Yes?
Why do you have that?
Who did you want to tase?
Jesus…
Don’t ever cross this line.
How do you do it, In-bae?
What?
I saw it on YouTube.
You can see things
that aren’t human too.
Well… I, uh…
Either I ward them off,
or reason with them,
I mean, we’re pros…
Apprentice Kang’s ability to see
spirits has to be the greatest in…
I’ve seen a ton since
I was a child.
So, I got used to them
for the most part.
Even some seen on your videos
felt very ordinary.
Actually, it feels good to see them.
It’s like spotting rabid dogs
and avoiding them.
But this time it’s about my sister,
so, I can’t just run away.
God of the five directions,
ward off vile spirits!
You can see it too.
Anyone you can see
who aren’t alive
will be exorcised.
Mister.
Are you a shaman?
I’m a doctor, actually.
I came to fix your sister.
Oh, this?
You know what?
This is fake.
Keep this a secret from her.
My sister’s lying about
seeing ghosts, right?
She said a ghost is inside me.
A famous shaman used this
a long time ago,
he said when a bad ghost
is inside a person, it’ll ring.
But it has never rung so far.
Even now.
The bell is ringing.
What are you?
Who are you?
What’s going on?
It’s not me!
No!
It’s you.
What a fresh scheme,
a scam pretending to be a scammer?
Dr. Cheon...
in front of me!
Master.
Are you all right?
She saw me.
She looked straight at me.
Are you inside, sir?
Enter.
Both men left,
and 2 girls remained.
We messed up the entire village
to find the eye…
What’s with the girl
master couldn’t possess?
What about her?
I mean, if we just get her eyes,
he’ll be unchained,
and we can all leave Gwechun, right?
That’s right.
But the Chilsung sword
wielder showed up.
Didn’t the master eliminate
all of them in the past?
I guess there was a leftover.
Mr. Hwang.
Doc is acting weird.
He’s been weird for a while.
No, he’s really weird this time.
Come on, doc…
All right, I'm sorry...
You should’ve said so,
why did you suddenly
decide to drive yourself?
Dr. Cheon?  Doc!
Go to Mr. Hwang
and tell him the bell rang.
Bell?
What bell?
No!
Dr. Cheon, in front of me…
Where are you?!
Keep it down, will you?
Whatever you’re planning,
don’t do it.
Just walk away
and get out of there!
Answer me!
Do you remember the diner
on Taeahn-bound route 29?
See you there.
Cheon Dong-sik! Dong-sik!
What’s this about?
What are you doing?
What is he carrying?
It looked like you were grabbing
a trident to kill someone.
“Where are you?!”
But you grabbed a drum?
Are you joining a cheerleading squad?
Watch your mouth,
you’ll go to hell.
This is a holy object.
From a bell to a drum,
what’s the big deal?
You don’t even explain
a damn thing.
How long have you worked
with Dr. Cheon?
He contacted me when I uploaded
a ghost prank video, so 3 years?
You must know that he’s from
a chief shaman family.
Of course, shaman this,
chief shaman that...
I don’t exactly know
what that means though.
Know what a deity shrine is?
It’s the name of the famous bakery.
Bak…
You’ve been freeloading
all this time?
I’m just a technician.
Even if you are, oh man…
Those big totems at
the entrance of a village?
Sure.
That’s called a deity shrine,
it’s where the village guardians reside.
The chief shaman’s job is
to protect and maintain that site.
And Dr. Cheon’s grandfather
was a chief shaman.
Did you know
Dr. Cheon had a brother?
Is that right?
He inherited his grandfather’s skills,
and made incredible Seolgyeongs.
Seolgyeong?
It’s a talisman that traps ghosts.
But Dr. Cheon had no interest
in becoming the chief shaman.
So, the role of chief shaman
was handed down
to his brother instead.
One day, his brother disappeared.
The chief shaman was desperate
to get the boy back,
and performed a ritual for 4 days
without eating or sleeping.
He’s here! He’s finally here!
The Great Chilsung deity is here!
Of course! I’m here!
I came down since you
called for me so earnestly!
We’re trying to find Cheon Dong-woo,
the chief shaman’s grandson!
Please point us
to his general direction!
The binding curse must be undone
for the boy to live!
So, did he find the boy?
He’s dead, because of Dr. Cheon.
What?!
At least that’s what he believes.
That’s when we realized,
his grandfather was hunted down.
His brother was used
as a bait to kill the chief shaman.
Afterwards, I raised Dr. Cheon
in secrecy by changing his name,
but there’s no way
he grew up properly.
In an attempt to find the one
who killed his family,
he chased after so many shamans
only to become one himself.
That’s why he’s so hard
on people, especially me.
Hm?
Huh?
Mom…
Who is it?
Yoo-kyung!
Mr. Foreman, good evening.
One moment.
This was delicious.
Is the moving prep going well?
Yes, thanks to you.
Not at all.
So, you’re playing dumb
even after seeing me?
Such clear eyes…
Damn…
Are you okay?
Yoo-min!
Yoo-kyung!
I’ll get the car.
Tie me.
Kill the broken sword wielder.
Dr. Cheon!
This way!
Who’s there?
Mi-soon?
Shit...
Dammit!
Step on it!
How dare you wimp out?
You should be thinking about
filling up the damaged goods.
Who’ll step up?
Bring it.
What took you so long?
Didn’t clock out yet?
Our company could go belly up
because the boss is acting out,
how could the VP just go home?
Jesus Christ…
VP my ass, you could
at least not pass out.
Pass out? Yoo-kyung tased me…
Shoes, your shoes…
Say hello.
This is Mr. Hwang,
he came to help us.
And here, you heard about her?
Ms. Oh Yoo-kyung.
Thank you for coming.
Sure.
Yoo-kyung, put this on,
let’s go sit down,
come up the stairs.
Wait, I need a word.
Are you nuts?!
Even your grandfather
couldn’t do this.
What if you get killed
in the name of revenge?!
This isn’t about revenge.
We’re doing a job for our client.
You always nagged me for being
the grandson of a chief shaman.
You know I’ll go to hell
if I do not accept my fate.
You got no spiritual energy,
but got a tongue instead…
I got no spiritual energy,
but sword energy though.
I shouldn’t have given it to you.
This was used by him
until a few hours ago.
Jeez…
You know where we can go
to find out who wrote this.
I’ve been called a scammer
for 10 years in pursuit of him,
and I finally got on his trail.
Celestial Maiden
After predicting accurate
general election results,
everyone including prosecutors,
VPs, and their wives all visit him,
it takes 2 months to
get a reservation.
You gotta be at my level
to get a reservation instantly.
Some of us drive all over
the country to put on shows,
but he managed to
raise a building sitting down.
It’s to pay your salary.
Let’s head inside.
Do I get paid that much?
Yoo-kyung, I mean, Yoo-min,
$25,000 for her location,
another $25,000 after finding her.
Mr. Hwang, you’re too much.
You saw how people
dropped dead chasing this thing.
Go on.
Please ask the celestial maiden
where they took her.
Where this talisman
is linked to,
just give us a cardinal direction,
and we’ll leave.
I’m begging you.
Begin.
Here she comes!
I feel her!
The maiden is coming!
Welcome!
She’s coming!
The maiden is coming!
Celestial maiden!
I feel her!
Here she is!
Here she comes!
I told him to throw
this tacky thing away!
I see it, I see it…
I see it!
I see those bastards!
This vile thing snuck in
because you brought this dirty thing.
By the way,
kid, you there.
You saw me earlier.
We locked eyes, right?
Yes.
You can see the dead,
souls and deities…
No wonder the mage wants them.
I get why he wants to pull
those eyes out for keepsake.
Why’d anyone pull her eyes out
for no reason, what a lunatic...
You don’t know?
It’s because of his grandpa.
To get rid of
the old man’s Seolgyeong,
he wants this child’s eyes.
She possesses eyes
that can evaporate Seolgyeong.
To become a deity,
the mage that you’re chasing,
has been hunting down shamans
for their spiritual powers.
And your grandfather was
caught in his trap.
Dong-woo!
Grandpa…
I’m here, don’t worry.
He puts severed fingers
in bamboo tubes,
and uses their spiritual power
to possess humans.
He possessed your brother
and bit down on your grandfather.
But who was your grandfather?
The only shaman who could
trap the mage inside a Seolgyeong.
That’s what your grandfather
was capable of.
But the mage held off
the Seolgyeong chains.
He had no choice but to
break the Chilsung sword,
and tried to save your brother.
That’s how the Seolgyeong
was cut in half…
and your grandfather was stabbed.
But thanks to Seolgyeong,
a binding curse was in place,
limiting him to Mt. Jukak
to the North,
and Mt. Geumak to the South.
he was essentially locked up
in that tiny village.
Since then, he’s been desperately
trying to get rid of the Seolgyeong,
but this can’t be destroyed
by ordinary means.
A potent talisman like this
can’t be ripped up,
or burned either.
This has to be read backwards,
and you...
should be able to see
what’s written on it.
Your eyes are capable of it.
What’s supposed to be there?
Is this all bullshit?
Quiet!
Very good.
You saw it, you did.
So?
Can’t read it?
If you can’t...
draw it.
Good.
Incredible.
You must read this backwards
to get rid of the talisman.
“Jigae jimoon ahhoryung.”
That’s enough,
he’s using you as a puppet.
Even if you save her sister,
the mage will come after you.
Then I must complete
my grandfather’s Seolgyeong,
and seal him up for good.
You?
Boy, that bastard’s
already half ghost.
You don’t even have
a guardian watching over you!
Even your powerful grandpa failed
and he’s now floating the afterlife,
you think you can do something
by swinging your sword?
As if seeing your grandpa
and brother dead...
Holy shit!
Excuse me.
No one can see you besides me.
It won’t work on him.
Huh?
What is everyone looking at?
What’s going on?
- Hey, hey!
- Is something there?
- Hey, stop!
- Right here?
Here?
Why was I lying down?
Look at this guy.
Yoo-kyung has the eyes,
I got the sword,
we can do it.
Working together in unison?
We’ll put two halves
of the Seolgyeong and insert this.
Just tell us where the mage sealed
the other half of the Seolgyeong.
Mt...
Yong…
wol.
Mt. Yongwol!
They’re going after
the other half of the Seolgyeong!
In-bae, wake up!
This is big, so big…
What’s going on?
Where am I?
We’re very close to the spot
that the celestial maiden told us.
There’s nothing here,
did we get scammed?
In-bae, light it up,
with the biggest one.
High and wide.
Okay!
Okay?
You guys carry around
so much crap…
How do you bring just a drum
on a job like this?
It’ll be like when you were
looking at the talisman.
Imagine a big talisman
hiding somewhere out there.
Ready?
Yes.
1 minute.
30 seconds.
Over there!
Let’s move!
Wait a minute!
Shit, I should’ve just clocked out…
You are all screwed.
It’s okay.
Hey, hey!
- Doc!
- In-bae!
My foot! Why is my foot like this?
My foot! Oh my god!
- What’s wrong?!
- In-bae!
- It’s gone!
- You got a foot!
- My foot!
- It’s there!
- My foot’s gone!
- It’s okay, In-bae!
It’s gone!
Snap out of it,
it’s a mirage!
My foot’s gone! Gone!
Grandpa...
Dong-woo...
What about Seolgyeong?
Did you find it?
Damn pests...
Eh? My foot.
My foot’s back.
Doc, my foot came back!
In-bae!
Shit!
Mt. Jukak to the North,
Mt. Jukak
Mt. Geumak to the South,
that’s his boundary.
Mt. Geumak
Kangryung Tunnel
This is where the celestial maiden
told us about,
Mt. Yongwol.
The mage’s location is...
here.
What are you doing?
Come to Seoul with me.
What’s with you all of sudden?
The master will be freed
when we pull her eyes out.
He’s bound to do great things
when he reaches Seoul.
Why run away now?
Do you know what happened
just now in Mt. Yongwol?
The shrine collapsed.
What do you mean?
You know what that place is,
the master plastered it
with talismans.
And he killed so many people
to make those talismans.
What happened to
the Seolgyeong inside?
Don’t be mistaken,
it wasn’t me.
Mom…
Step on it!
Doctor!
Give me your eyes, bitch!
I just need your eyes!
Doctor!
Yoo-kyung!
Stop right there!
Dr. Cheon, get in!
Many lives could have been spared,
had you shown up earlier.
Why was I so blind?
You were right in front of me.
So cruel.
I’ll pull them out painlessly,
and keep them in a special spot.
Rig the cave entrance
with explosives,
and when Yoo-kyung comes out
with her sister, blow it up.
If you don’t come out,
you’re gonna die?
Shush!
It’s our last chance
to seal the mage inside.
Whether inside the cave,
or the Seolgyeong...
That’s not right!
In-bae.
Let’s do it properly this time.
I’ll come with you.
I’ll see you when I see you.
Dr. Cheon!
You resemble your grandfather
more than your dead brother.
So, this is your real face.
Did you want to see me so badly?
Yoo-kyung...
The Cheon clan seems to be
full of futile men.
We’ll have to see about that.
Close your eyes!
Shit, shit!
Go, go!
Doctor!
Seolgyeong! Seolgyeong!
Stab the Seolgyeong!
Where is it?!
We have to go!
You couldn’t come sooner?
Look at that crazy bastard!
Dammit!
He’s coming after us!
Mr. Hwang, run!
Hwang! In-bae, push the button!
What is it?!
Push it!
I told you to go easy
with explosives!
The Seolgyeong...
Christ...
Here, pierce it with your sword.
So hot! Shit!
What’s happening?
GANG DONG-WON
HUH JOON-HO
ESOM
LEE DONG-HWI
KIM JONG-SOO
PARK SOI
AND PARK JEONG-MIN
DIRECTED BY
KIM SEONG-SIK
Yoo-kyung, great work.
Yoo-min, listen to your sister,
and be healthy.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Hope your move goes well,
and give me a call
when you see anything weird.
Thank you, doctor.
Let’s get going,
it’s almost rush hour.
Let’s go.
Yoo-kyung,
I believe that it’d be a travesty
to waste your incredible talent.
I’d like to formally offer you a job.