xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx
You know that.
It's beautiful.
This message is for Maricruz.
I'll be there in the airport
in Ixtapa waiting for you.
Hi, my name is Sara,
and I'm an addict.
Hi, Sara.
(applause)
I'm just looking to do my time;
I don't any any trouble.
Hey!
Break it up, convict!
No, no, this isn't fun--
what was fun
was when Caroline and I
would talk about you
and the schoolboy crush
that you had on her.
He proposed to her.
Hey!
Terrence!
I'm leaving!
Terrence, listen to me.
Just listen.
So many people
have suffered because
of this, because of you.
When the press get here,
you can tell the truth.
You can end this.
Sorry.
(yelling)
We interrupt this program
for a special news bulletin.
It's breaking news
out of Cutback, Montana.
Lincoln Burrows and Michael
Scofield, two of the prisoners
who broke out of Fox River State
Penitentiary in Illinois
have continued to allude
the authorities,
leaving a trail of crime
in their wake.
And today, they left behind
something else.
My name is Lincoln Burrows,
and I'm innocent.
We're done.
There's no other
way out of here.
Next time you decide to hold
a press conference,
do it from a room
with a back door.
Just let me think.
MAN (over bullhorn):
Montana Highway Patrol.
Michael Scofield
and Lincoln Burrows,
you'll need to exit
with your hands in the air.
This is a warning.
Exit with your hands up.
What about him?
He's useless.
A dead body?
We got fingerprints everywhere.
Are you worried someone's
gonna pin a murder on you?
So what's your plan,
leave the body
walk out the front door?
Yes.
That's exactly
what we're going to do.
Michael Scofield
and Lincoln Burrows,
you need to exit
with your hands up.
FBI. Hold your fire.
MAN:
FBI?
Start rolling.
I have Burrows and
Scofield in custody.
We're coming out.
Hold your fire.
Hold up, who are you?
Federal Bureau of Investigation.
We're going to Billings.
Wait a minute,
let me see that ID again.
Okay.
Drop the gun!
(yelling)
Don't do it!
Everybody calm down,
and this won't get ugly.
MICHAEL:
All right, you!
I want keys to both
of cop cars now!
Do not do it!
Don't listen to him!
Get the keys!
Linc, get in the car.
What's going on?
We're getting out of here
before anyone else gets hurt.
Lincoln, start it.
Come on! Come on!
Come on!
Stay there or I
will drop him.
I'm not gonna tell you again.
One more step and I drop him.
Come on!
(tires screeching)
LANG:
Welcome back.
You feeling...?
Much better.
Update?
Okay, you got it.
Get a lead on something?
One of the COs from Fox River,
Brad Bellick,
got locked up last night
for the murder of another guard.
Wait, we're looking for COs now?
What about the escapees?
Scofield?
Burrows?
Nothing on them currently.
Also, Franklin's wife...
(phone rings)
was taken
into custody
in North Dakota.
His wife?
Line two.
This is Agent Mahone.
How long ago?
I'll make you a deal--
if you don't move a muscle,
I won't blow
your head off.
No one's gonna hurt you, Greg.
Where are we going,
Michael?
Can't keep driving.
We lost Steadman.
Sara's in
the wind.
Shh!
Turn it up.
(over radio):
...are armed and dangerous.
Burrows was sentenced to die
for the murder of
the president's brother.
The president could not
be reached
as she continues
to tour the Midwest.
REYNOLDS:
I want to thank all of you who
have supported me in the past,
and I appreciate
your continued support
in the upcoming year.
REPORTER:
Reynolds travels
to Colorado tomorrow
for a scheduled appearance
in Denver this evening.
Pull over.
What for?
Just pull over.
Want to drop
off this kid?
Later.
We should get rid
of Kellerman, too.
We don't need him.
Actually, we do.
We still have assets.
It's just a question
of how we use them.
-= http://www.huodidao.com =-
Nurse.
Nurse!
You ain't no nurse.
You right about that.
(medical device beeping)
Oh, that's a pretty shiner
you got, Captain.
Must make you think
about all the times
you walked around here
in your fancy guard outfit,
turning a blind eye
to everything you saw
that was wrong.
"Who me?
Oh, I didn't see nothing."
How that blind eye feel now?
You son of a bitch.
Get used to it.
Hear old one-eyed jack's
gonna be getting screwed
in the socket.
Over my dead body.
No.
A dead man can't feel
a beat-down.
And you got a lot more
coming your way.
(door opens)
Come on now,
let's go.
(chatting indistinctly)
It'll take the feds a while
to figure that out.
What time is it?
A little after 9:00.
It's gonna be tight.
450 miles
in six hours.
What do you think?
Got to move now
if we're going to make it.
Eyes front.
Hey, look at this.
It's perfect. You ready?
Yep.
(clucking)
Puerto Rico.
(chickens clucking)
(rustling)
Ugh!
Here, Larry, that's for you.
What about this?
This is too small.
Why didn't it float?
Why didn't it...?
I need more wood.
Wood floats.
This will work.
Hey, man.
We were just wondering
if you could buy us some beer.
Huh?
Yeah, sure.
Can I get some food
for my dog, too?
Do whatever thing
you got to do, man.
You can even keep
a beer for yourself.
Huh? Oh, no.
My dad used to drink.
You're going
to want to see this.
LANG:
We've shut down
every freeway
in central Montana.
So far, no sign of them.
Go wider.
Get troopers on and 90 and 94,
all the way
through Wyoming,
and call Whitefish.
Have him lock down the
Canadian border at 15.
REPORTER:
Recapping our top story
on the Fox River Eight, we will
now bring you exclusive footage
shot by
a cameraman who was kidnapped
by the escapees.
My name is Lincoln Burrows,
and I'm innocent.
I escaped
from Fox River Penitentiary
because I was sentenced to death
for a crime
I did not commit.
I did not murder
Terrence Steadman.
He committed suicide last night
in the Cutback Motel, 30 miles
outside of his home
in Blackfoot, Montana.
He killed himself
out of fear.
Fear of the people
who have been hiding him
for the past three years.
The same people
who want my brother dead.
They don't want you to know
who they are, but know this:
They've stolen billions
of dollars
and murdered dozens
of innocent people.
And yet they plaster
our faces on the news,
and tell you to be afraid.
They are a group
of multinationals
with corporate interests.
Together, they're known
as The Company.
MICHAEL:
They are working
with the highest levels
of government,
including the president
of the United States.
Damage control immediately,
before this hits page one.
It's already
airing, sir.
Start a wildfire in Florida!
Find a lost storage unit
full of Arabs!
I do not care!
As long as it's not
about Lincoln Burrows!
And they operate with impunity
Go!
under the cover
of the Secret Service,
少几句字幕，听一下，一起写到这里来
xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx
xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx
xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx
XXXXXXXX
XXXXXXXXXXXX
XXXXXXXXXXXXX
XXXXXXXXXX
XXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXX
XXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXX
Dr. Sara Tancredi.
Do we know how long
the videotape lasts?
26 minutes, beginning to end.
It's all online.
I know I can't ask you
for another chance.
I can only hope that,
by now,
you've found
your safe haven.
Start a transcript.
I need every word.
...your commitment to help
others, and I put you in a place
that's every
doctor's nightmare.
I wish I could
do things differently...
Call Montana, have them
send an agent to talk
to the cameraman-- I want to
know what he saw, what he heard,
what they were wearing--
anything he can give us.
...people murdered
by government operatives.
One man, Special Agent
Alexander Mahone,
is responsible for multiple
deaths. He murdered
not only John Abruzzi
and David Apolskis,
but also the last fugitive
he was assigned to chase:
a man named Oscar Shales.
A man who escaped from prison
two years ago,
who remains one
of this country's most wanted
despite the fact
he will never be found.
The guy's nuts.
LINCOLN:
He'll do whatever it takes to
make the deaths look official--
like they happened
in the line of duty--
disappearances, accidents...
Hey, thank you.
Sure. Here you go.
What's the wood for?
I'm building a raft.
I need more wood if I'm going
to make it to Holland.
Holland?
Yeah.
Want to see it?
The raft?
||
GIRL:
You're going to try to get
from here to Holland in that?
Uh-huh.
Yeah, good luck,
Gilligan.
I'm going to
take a leak.
How are you going to
know where you're going?
Do you have, like,
a map or anything?
Yeah. I do.
It's-it's right...
Oh, it's right here.
That's your map?
Uh-huh.
Well, I really hope you make it.
You know, every morning,
I wake up
and wonder what it would be like
to just disappear.
And you're just going to do it.
I think it's great.
(both laughing)
Okay. Well...
What happened to your arm?
My dad drinks, too.
What's going on?
Oh, nothing.
No, no. No, no, don't...
Let me go.
I just want to fix it.
No, I just want...
Stop!
Matt, will you
take me home, please?
No, I...
Freak.
All right, now, Brad,
how we doing?
I could be better.
Yeah, that's
a nasty contusion,
but it should go down
in about 24 hours.
I got your paperwork here
for your transfer
back to Gen Pop.
Already?
Move 'em in, move 'em out;
you know the policy.
Katie...
Mm-hmm?
You look nice today.
You worked here over
tenyears, right?
Something like that.
That's a long time
we've been friends.
Brad, if you think I can pull
some strings to keep you
out of Gen Pop, I can't do that.
Please. Please,
You can't send me back there.
Do you want that responsibility,
knowing what they'll do to me?
Just listen, please.
One more night.
Just let me stay here tonight.
I know you
can do that.
And when you go home,
just leave that door open
for me.
(door closes)
REPORTER:
They hung a sheet
behind their heads on the wall.
One of them--
the guy with the gun--
he found it
while Burrows and Scofield
were talking
about how far they had to go.
Uh... Scofield said something
about 450 miles in six hours.
450 miles to where?
I don't know.
MAHONE:
450 miles in six hours.
Any point on this circle
could be their final
destination.
75 miles per hour,
stopping for gas.
It's doable.
Yeah.
Where are they?
I'm not sure.
I still need more time.
This can't happen fast enough,
Mr. Mahone.
They've already
done irreparable damage.
Scofield made the video
in a storage facility somewhere
between Great Falls and Helena
not long after sunrise.
From there, the witness said
they had 450 miles
to get where they were going.
There's Seattle,
Portland, Salt Lake, Denver...
Denver?
Yes. What?
The president is speaking there
this afternoon.
3:00.
Six hours from when
they made the video.
by escaped convicts Lincoln
Burrows and Michael Scofield
was immediately dismissed
by the Justice Department
as entirely baseless, which
brings us back to the story
(over radio):
we'll be continuing
to follow throughout the day.
The terror threat
has been raised to Orange
as a storage unit rented
by several Arab Americans
was suddenly...
(radio shuts off)
They buried it, dumped it off
the front page and buried it.
It's what they do.
They can spin it
all they want,
it's out there now.
Give it time;
the tape is going to work.
This is a Hail Mary, man--
if we don't get to her...
Getting to her
is the easy part.
It's what we do after
that's the problem.
Which is why this has
to happen quickly.
Once anyone knows we have her,
the curtain comes down.
Well, I'll notify the
White House to cancel
the President's speech.
No. If there's any change
to her itinerary,
the brothers will know
something's up,
and they're gonna go
right back into hiding.
We've found them before, we can
certainly find them again...
These are not pets,
Agent Wheeler.
Yeah, thanks,
I'm pretty clear on that,
but if you're going to use
the commander-in-chief
as bait, it's certainly
not going to...
You have a problem with the way
that I do things?
Yeah.
And I'm not the only one.
Is that right?
Internal Affairs has asked me
to run all your moves
through them from here on out.
Then get a pen
and make sure
you get this word-for-word.
The president's day
does not change.
The only lead we have is that
we know where
these men are headed.
So we're gonna keep
quiet about this
and let 'em come.
Now, get out
of my office.
They're two of the most
recognizable faces in America.
How do they think
they were going to get
anywhere near the president?
Because it's not just
the two of them anymore.
I'm gonna go take a closer look
at that video.
If I may, sir, the president...
Are you certain we should keep
her in the dark on this?
Because there is
a scenario where...
she could be useful.
It is... her ass
on the line, sir.
And I think we're all pretty
clear she's been known
to get her hands dirty
when that line gets too close.
We should
let her know
just how close it is.
(silverware clinks)
XXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXX
(engine starts)
They did a good job
masking the room.
No reflections,
no flares.
Audio markers--
church bells,
construction, traffic, anything?
The room tone tells us
they were in a large space--
about 100,000 cubic feet.
So the kid with the camera--
his story matches up?
We clocked
the quality of light
with the time of day,
and it pretty much fits
his wheres and whens.
All right, content.
The usual tells--
eyes, hands, feet.
Burrows, we were able
to baseline him
off the footage
from his trial,
so we got even more
clarity there.
I escaped from
from Fox River Penitentiary
because I was sentenced to death
for a crime I did not commit.
I did not murder
Terrence Steadman.
Okay, there.
The eyes.
See it?
Yeah, slight shift
to the left, then up.
Yeah, blink rate's up here
versus the pattern.
LINCOLN:
He committed suicide last night
in the Cutback Motel
30 miles outside from this home
in Blackfoot, Montana.
He's lying.
Seems so.
(tape squeaking as it rewinds)
Okay, here,
Burrows,
arms folded.
He's protecting himself.
We'll do whatever
it takes...
Not a lot of confidence
in these words.
...like they happen
in the line of duty.
Okay, that means something
other than what he's saying.
(computer keys tapping)
Like our father
Aldo Burrows...
Posture, shoulders in,
for emphasis.
Really wants your
attention here.
Our attorney,
Veronica Donovan...
I was on the phone...
Right there.
...when they shot her
like an animal.
Adam's apple.
Zoom in, zoom in.
We made this tape
to let the world know...
That's a lie.
Yeah.
His behavior
is textbook.
If there's anything in here
about what they plan on
doing in Denver,
they're gonna tell us.
If you say it that way,
it plays too earnest.
'Course it will--
it's the truth.
Okay, but the truth sends them
home to the wife and kids.
Lies will keep them busy.
I'm not telling a lie
to the whole country.
It's our one chance
to say it out...
Yeah, say whatever the hell
you want--
tell them
you're the Green Lantern--
but I know
how they break down these tapes.
I've done it.
Every detail matters.
Bin Laden crosses his legs--
right over left--
tells us something completely
different than left over right.
It's not the same message.
To them, it is.
If you want this
plan to work,
whatever you say
with your mouths,
you need to be saying
something different with
your bodies and your eyes.
Slightly up and to the left.
Yes.
Much blame has been placed
on another innocent person...
LANG:
President's motorcade
is rolling in.
So far no sign of the brothers.
Right there. Right there.
What's Scofield doing
with his hand?
(computer keys tapping)
We've been throwing them
a bunch of fast balls.
What do you say
we mix it up a little?
Like what?
(keys tapping)
We think it's Morse code.
For what?
Right now we've got a phrase,
"The water is warm."
Any idea
what that might mean?
What the hell does that mean?
Nothing.
But it'll take the Feds a while
to figure that out.
TECHIE:
We have teams checking
the surrounding counties
for the water temps.
It might be a message
to an accomplice.
(tape rewinding)
The North Platte river
runs through the city.
Maybe they're trying to use...
It doesn't mean anything.
He's traveling with
an ex-Secret Service guy.
I'm guessing they're
spoon-feeding us every lead
they want us to follow.
So all this is
just a distraction
while they go after
the president?
They had to know
the tape would be discredited.
that we'd talk to the cameraman.
Much blame has been placed
on another innocent person,
Dr. Sara Tancredi.
Sara, if you're listening,
I know I can't ask you
for another chance.
I only hope by now
you've found your safe haven.
I took advantage of you,
of your commitment
to help others
and put your in a place
that's every doctor's nightmare.
(tape rewinds)
Sara, if you're listening,
I know I can't ask you
for another chance.
I only hope by now
you've found your safe haven.
I took advantage of you,
of your commitment
to help others
and put your in a place
that's every doctor's nightmare.
(tape rewinds)
...of your commitment
to help others
and put you in a place
that's every doctor's nightmare.
I've considered many ways
to apologize,
but I must arrive at one.
There's more
of the same here.
Uh, body language,
his tells...
If you ask me, it doesn't look
like he means this at all.
I don't care what it looks like.
Play it again.
I don't see...
(keys tapping, tape rewinds)
I only hope by now
you've found your safe haven.
I took advantage of you,
of your commitment
to help others
and put you in a place
that's every doctor's nightmare.
His voice-- would you say
he sounds sincere
when he's talking to her
as opposed to when he's
talking about their crimes?
I... I guess
you could say that.
I did say that.
Would you say that?
I wish I could do
this differently,
but it's too late
for that now.
Yeah.
It's too late for you
and for others.
People murdered
by government operatives...
This isn't
about Terrence Steadman,
and it's not about
their innocence.
What do you mean?
They're not going
after the president;
they're going after the doctor.
I want everything
we've got on Sara Tancredi--
friends, families, pen-pals.
If anybody so much as wrote her
a thank-you note,
I want to know where the hell
they arenow!
XXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXX
Sara Tancredi.
Dad dead, mom dead.
E-mail account shows
a minimal list of contacts
with very little activity.
Credit cards used
mostly for groceries,
sporadic clothing
shopping and, uh,
the purchase
of single movie tickets.
And ob-gyn records tell us she's
had very little in the way
of sexual relationships
recently.
To tell you the truth,
I would say the bulk
of her life was her work.
Excuse me, sir,
where are you going?
Apparently,
we took out a janitor.
When it all comes down,
all of this will get cleared up.
Well, it ain't coming down
if we don't get Sara.
She'll be here.
I want to speak
to my brother.
We got to start thinking
about what to do
if she doesn't show.
Or if she does.
What if the only reason
this guy's helping us
is to get whatever
information Sara has?
What if this is
just one giant setup?
Well, good night.
It's about time you come home.
Been out with
that Feytek boy again?
Sasha.
You may
look like me...
but you take after your mom
when it comes to boys,
now, don't you?
Hopefully,
with a little better taste.
Damn it, girl, you are gonna
show me some respect.
(grunts)
(blows landing)
MAHONE:
I know Sara didn't have
many friends.
She's sort of a loner.
But you were her friend.
I like to think so, yes.
And you have no idea
where she is now?
No.
This is a transcript of
the Scofield-Burrows videotape.
I highlighted the part where
he talks directly to Sara.
Mean anything to you?
No.
You have no idea where
she might meet him, if...
that's his plan?
(sighs):
No.
(bell rings)
Is Brad Bellick still here
in the infirmary?
Yeah. Why?
You must be loving this.
(chuckles softly)
I didn't drive all this way
to gloat.
Well, then what the hell
you come here for?
(sighs)
First, I really...
got to tip my cap to you.
You've managed
to draw a bead on the convicts
more often than my own staff.
Well, thanks for the
"attaboy," but...
as you can see,
the correctional system
doesn't share your gratitude.
I won't take much of your time,
but I do have a few questions.
About...?
Sara Tancredi.
She listed you
as a reference
on her job application
to work here.
You know her well?
I'd know her a lot better if you
can get my ass moved to Ad Seg.
(chuckles softly)
I have no influence
with the D.O.C.--
you know that.
If you want my help, you do.
I'll talk to the warden
and see what I can do--
right after you give me
some answers.
Scofield likes to communicate
with Sara via coded message.
Do you recognize anything here?
Anything that he may be
trying to tell her?
No.
I mean, he's saying
he's sorry.
Not that that's gonna do any
good with Dr. Cold Shoulder.
But...
What?
Ad Seg.
(sighs)
Yeah.
All right, you see here,
where it says this stuff
about "another chance."
"Safe haven."
That's out of the big book.
What big book?
Alcoholics Anonymous.
Sara's in recovery.
Yeah, I'm aware of that.
Those are the names
of some of the chapters
in the book they use in AA.
Do you have a copy of
the Alcoholics Anonymous book?
MICHAEL:
Sara, if you're listening,
I know I can't ask you
for another chance.
I can only hope by now
you've found your safe haven.
I took advantage of you,
your commitment to help others
and put you in a place that's
every doctor's nightmare.
I've considered many ways
to apologize,
but I must arrive at one.
It's getting late.
I know.
She's not here.
I know that, too.
There is a chance
she didn't get the message.
Or maybe she's just sick
of all this.
The girl bailed on you
back in Gila.
What makes you think she's
gonna come running back now?
The same thing
that's been keeping us going
for the last three months:
faith.
Yeah, well... reality's
kicking faith's ass, man.
Look...
Wait, wait.
Wait? Man,
we can't wait anymore.
(over P.A. system):
Once again, Michael Crane,
Listen, listen.
please report to the front desk.
You have a telephone call.
Michael Crane to the front desk.
Yeah. Sara Tancredi.
That's right.
She might be with them now.
Just... Yes!
Just call the local police
in Akron and tell them
to get everyone they have
over to St. Thomas Hospital now.
Um...
Michael Crane. I think
you have a call for me.
Thank you.
This is Mr. Crane.
It sounded better
than "Origami."
Even if you got the message,
I wasn't sure you'd respond.
I-I couldn't get to you in time.
This is the only thing
I could think of.
I swore I'd leave you alone,
but I had to contact you.
Because I have something?
How'd you know?
Michael, back in Gila
I was coming back to you.
Somebody... grabbed me,
and they, um,
they told me that my father
had given me something.
Did someone hurt you?
I-I got away.
Uh...
(sighs)
Michael,
I want for this to be over.
That makes two of us.
Do you think that's possible?
With your help, yes.
It's just a question of looking
at whatever it is
your father gave you.
It's just...
It's just a key.
Well, we'll figure it out.
Together.
I like the sound of that.
Me, too.
(phone ringing)
REYNOLDS:
Hello, Paul.
Madam President,
it's been a while.
I know.
I'm calling to apologize.
Okay.
It all just got away from me,
and I ended up hurting
the one person
who's always been at my side.
I want you to come home, Paul.
We can fix this.
Together.
But not with those brothers
running around the country
tearing down the very office
you helped me build.
Caroline...
Bring them in, Paul,
and everything can go back
to the way it was.
That is what you want, isn't it?
I have to go now.
I'll see you soon.
Did you talk to Sara?
In a few days,
this should all be over,
one way or the other.
KELLERMAN:
Absolutely.