That's the overpase, we arrived.
- Let's wait here?
- Da.
- Are you sure?
- I'd say so.
Now what we do?
Let's pray.
< In the coming election
vote Beniamino Spano,
the force of the future...
< In the coming election
vote Beniamino Spano!
< Vote Beniamino Spano!
< The force of the future!
- Hi, Daddy.
< Daddy's little girl, hi!
Debby, aren't you cold?
Here's your jacket.
< Come and get your jacket.
Come here, sweetheart.
< Where are you going?
Marta!
Come on.
< Put it down, he'll tell us when.
Girls, stay in line.
< Santa!
< Everything OK?
- Long live Mary!
They'll drive me crazy.
Debby, you're here!
I want you to meet my nieces,
they're back from Switzerland.
- Did you know that? - No.
- Come on!
We're a little messy,
we walked all night!
- You did the night pilgrimage?
- Da.
Rosa and Alfredo, her boyfriend.
He's from here.
A pleasure, Santa.
- How beautiful!
- And the younger one, Marta.
Where is she?
- Marta!
- Here she is.
Hi, beautiful.
- How old are you?
- Nearly .13
Really? You'd never guess.
You know, with the kids
your age that I teach...
< Santa, come here a minute!
- Excuse me.
The loudspeaker's not working.
- It worked a moment ago.
- And now it's not.
- I wanted to tell you
it doesn't work sometimes.
- Let's get things going!
- Reverende, could we spread a tarpaulin
in case it rains?
- OK, spread a tarpaulin.
Quick, a tarpaulin.
Let's cover the Virgin.
Testing, testing.
It's working.
Dear brother and sisters,
your attention please.
We're gathered here, like every year,
to renew our faith...
... and the love four our community.
< This year is special, though -.
Bishop Giorgio
will take part in our procession.
I here that His Excellency's car
is about to arrive,
let's wait for him in silence
and welcome him...
... with warmth and joy, our community
is capable of showing.
< Here it is!
< (Rosa) It's an order!
< Open it!
< Marta!
< Let me in!
Marta!
- What time is it?
- Relax, your mother's sleeping!
You're uglier than before.
< Welcome.
- Hello.
- You're late.
They're waiting for you.
Do you know where to go?
I'll show you.
You can get
through the rear door too...
... but I suggest you come this way
to say hello to Jesus first of all.
< Who invented the Church?
The Pope and priests, non-Europeans,
the people of God or the plant world?
Come on, the p...
The p...
- Sara.
- The p...
The p...
- The Pope and priests
- Are you sure, is this your final answer?
- That's my final answer.
- Tell her, Anna.
The people of God.
Good!
< Kids, more energy!
More energy!
< What's the name of Lazarus' sister
who listens to Jesus attentively?
< Mary, Martha, Sabrina or Jessica?
Want to answer, my dear Marta?
Don't be scare, listen...
Mary, Martha, Sabrina or Jessica?
Come on, a name you know very well.
Martha?
Mary, the good sister is Mary,
tell her!
Go and sit down.
Did you go to catechism
where you lived before?
Don't sit down here.
Sit here, next to Anna who's good.
What did they teach you there?
Did you take tests?
< Can I go to the toilet?
< No.
So, we were saying that Confirmation...
... confirms, meaning it's the final confirmation
of Christian values.
< It's guarantee, a certainty.
Without Confirmation
the doors to heaven are closed...
...and marriage too.
After a short reading
you'll understand bearer.
You need to learn this by heart,
it's formula of the Holy Ghost.
Natale, stop clowning around!
Now pay attention and listen
to what Marco reads to us.
Marco, on you go.
< "You are growing and it's
an amazing experience for you."
< "How many new things each day:"
< "your voice changes,
your body transforms."
< It transforms.
- It transforms!
"You feel useless, bored, depressed,"
"you don't know
your place in the world."
- "But we know, the Church
is the answer you're looking for."
- The Church!
"Feeling the Holy Ghost is like
wearing wonderful sunglasses,"
"that allow you to see things
in a different way."
"It is through the Holy Ghost
that you must see the world."
- See the world!
< It's hard to feel at home.
< How long were you in Switzerland,
ten or eleven years?
Ten years.
Can you pass me your plates?
Take it off, you'll stain it with sauce!
< Leave me alone!
Holy Mother,
I can't get that dress off her.
You know kids,
they like to dress up.
< She's not eating?
- Tell her, she won't listen to me.
- Voila!
- Stuffed calamari!
- Thanks, Aunt!
- I don't know if they're good.
- You always say that!
It's from the ocean.
- I'm not buying Mediterranean fish any more
- Why?
< You never know what you're eating.
With all the corpses in the sea...
Nino's cousin in the navy told us.
All the bodies they find!
They're illegal immigrants.
< They're Moroccans.
< What should the fish eat?
< Exactly. It's best to buy ocean fish.
- Come on! - No!
That's enough gloom.
A toast.
It may be thanks to God,
or maybe to the sea,
a toast I make, to these calamari!
Cheers!
To the new house!
- Me too!
- Only for the toast?
Just a drop.
- How did you do them?
- Breadcrumbs, parsley, garlic...
Is Mum your bin?
- Mum likes calamari.
- Then take them from the pan.
- Don't eat her leftovers.
- I didn't touch it.
< Louder, let us here!
< Excellent, Debby!
Wonderful!
- You should have seen her in church, fantastic!
- Debby, what's the church one like?
< Hallelujah.
Hallelujah.
Hallelujah! Hallelujah.!
< Good!
< Come to Daddy!
- Just a drop.
< Is our Martha ready for Confirmation?
Yes, she was already attending
Sunday school in Switzerland.
Here she's just started catechism,
Father Mario insisted.
He was right to insist!
It's a way to make friends too.
- You do it now and then forget about it.
< Cake!
< What a beautiful cake!
- Thanks.
- Happy Birthday, Rosetta dear.
< Did Marta make it?
< Yes, by herself.
Blow?
- Greetings! Greetings!
- Thanks.
- Who wants some?
- Me!
- No.
- You, Uncle?
< No thanks, I'm really full.
- I'm stuffed too.
Enough!
Let's taste it!
Mm! Delicious!
You don't know what you're missing!
Delicious!
< I just eat and eat and leave no room for desert!
- Is that my bra?
< Rosa, not now...
- If she takes my stuff, she has to tell me!
Don't argue, it's your birthday.
- What's she need a bra for?
Look at her! She's a child
< Stop!
-She runs off! Where's she going?
-She doesn't accept criticism.
- It's easy just to run off!
< Enough!
"Holy Ghost, in times of trouble
I seek you and call you."
"Eli, eli, lema sabachthani."
"Like water flowing
from the font of the sea,
"I entrust myself to you.
"Free me from
the temptations of the world,
"give me wisdom, intellect,
counsel, fortitude,
...knowledge, mercy, fear of God.
"Holy Ghost, in times of trouble
I seek you and call you.
"Eli, eli, lema, sabachthani..
"Give me...
"wisdom, intellect,
"counsel, fortitude,
"knowledge.
"Fear of God."
- Is he completely naked?
< Yes. - And how big??
Life-size?
- Yes, yes...
- Even down there?
Children, you don't understand,
Jesus' body is different
from ours,
it is a spiritual body,
heavenly, holy.
- Can I go to the toilet?
- Jasmine, listen to me.
It's important.
It's a figurative crucifix,
meaning you see
the whole figure of Jesus.
- When will they bring it?
- The day of Confirmation.
< On a donkey!
It's Father Mario's idea,
our reverend parish priest.
He wants to organize
a grandiose ceremony...
...for when this gift is unveiled.
I'm tuning into God.
He's the right frequency...
I'm tuning...
- Have you seen Ignazio?
- No, sorry.
- Thank you.
- Father Mario, excuse me!
Would you like to hear
the children's Confirmation song?
- Yes, OK.
- Thank you.
< Children, keep the tempo!
I'm tuning into God.
He's the right frequency.
He's a goal for me.
I want to choose Jesus.
I listen to His voice.
I listen to His command.
He teaches me so much.
He teaches me what I'm worth.
I want to choose Jesus.
< I found something!
March elections are, for Calabria,
a testing ground...
What treatment!
- Go to bed, Mum.
- No, I'm fine here.
I dreamed my teeth were falling out.
Bad sign, right?
Fairly.
Come here.
Are you Confirmation
classmates nice?
- Normal.
- That's good.
- What?
- That they're not abnormal.
- What do you do?
- We sing.
- Let me here.
- I don't remember.
Come on, a little bit!
- No, come on...
- Are you embarrassed?
You're embarrassed.
Come on, a little bit for your Mum
who has to go to work.
OK, but close your eyes.
Really close them!
I want to choose Jesus!
I want to choose...
- Oh, Gad!
< Why are you so selfish?
< Let Mum sleep.
- You sleep at night, don't you?
- Rosetta, I can defend myself.
< That's not true,
you don't realize
she's devouring all your energy.
< She's sucking all you have left inside!
< What are you saying?
These are your Confirmation clothes,
they're Alfri's sister's,
they have to be returned intact.
You're welcome!
- Rita, where've you been?
- Sorry, the girls...
It's OK now.
The dough's getting over-risen!
Help him out.
It was Jesus' very hands...
... that revealed his holiness to people.
Placing His hands,
the Savior performed His first miracles, like this...
Has she frozen?
We too can experience
this energy of faith...
... that issues from our hands.
And we'll do it with a game called
"The dance of the man born blind."
- Who can say who he was?
< Me! < Me!
< Anna?
- The man born blind was a man who'd never seen,
so Jesus Christ gave him sight.
-Good.
< How did he to that, Jasmine?
< I haven't clue!
< Cinzia?
- With His hands?
< His hands. How, Sara?
- He put them on his face.
I'll explain what He did exactly.
Jesus used spit, saliva on His hands...
... and then He placed them
on the man born blind.
Wait, I remember one.
< Which?
Jesus, take me in Your hands tonight,
watch over me till morning light
- Doesn't count, it's not a prayer.
< What is it? - A phrase.
They remember
every prayer that exists:
the Credo for the Agonizing,
the Credo for the Dying,
the Credo for the Suffering...
- How wonderful!
< Mum?
Get under.
- Yes?
< Rest, don't get over-tired.
< I'm going to Alfri's.
- I'm a sufferer...
- Come on, stop!
Come on, stop!
Come on, She might come back!
Let's sleep.
- I pray for the moribund...
That's enough, real rest now.
Crisps, pastries, cookies, crackers...
drinks are missing.
If we have to buy drinks,
expenses increase, don't they?
< Father Mario?
- What?
Sorry if I interrupt this idyll
of drinks and crackers.
We're worse than kids!
All they think of is clothes.
- Who comes back after Confirmation?
- Grown-ups.
The church is always full.
Of course, there aren't many youngsters.
But we're always here.
< If these kids get to Confirmation,
< it's no small thing.
... They have to study, grow...
- Grow, that's the right word!
- I didn't mean anything.
- The church has become a place...
... for toddlers, women, old ladies,
people who have nothing to do.
- I think you're a pessimist.
- Sorry, maybe I didn't express myself very well.
Let's look around and see
what the world offers today:
Uncertainty, instability.
< The Church has to become
a protagonist again,
< it has to propose
extraordinary events,
... like ours,
a new Confirmation, renewed.
< And the crucifix will be
the gift for our community.
- It's a figurative crucifix.
- Right, we have to get this crucifix...
... before the Bishop comes.
< Sunday morning.
- Is that time enough?
- I can't before that.
- He can't before that.
At 3 Confirmation, Holy Mass
and presentation of the crucifix...
- Cristiano, come here.
- At 5, dance of the little virgins...
They need good beating!
Kids have to obey.
Obey in the name of what?
Calm down.
I'll be right back.
Where's he getting
this figurative crucifix?
It's in an abandoned church
in Father Mario's town.
- What's this exercise called!
- "Lining up for God".
When would it be?
For Confirmation, excellent.
No, I'm sorry, I can't before that.
< 70, all reliable people,
< don't worry.
< About the other thing,
tell His Excellency I fell ready...
and I could give much more
if I were transferred.
- Hear that?
- What?
- They're transferring him.
- What's that mean?
- He just said so, he wants to
have a bigger church. - Why?
In a more important church...
he might be made bishop.
< Good for his career,
even if he doesn't pray well.
"Now, Master, let your servant
go in peace, according to you word."
"For my eyes..."
"... have seen your salvation, which you
prepared in sight of all the peoples,"
"a light for revelation to the Gentiles..."
"...and glory for your people in Israel."
"In waking waking save us,
in sleep abandon us not..."
I brought the next few day's meals.
- Is it true you'll be transferred?
< I wish!
What do you mean "I wish"? And me?
Even if they transferee me,
I'll never forget the community.
Besides, you should be glad,
I'd be offered great responsibility.
< I know that.
But who knows
who they'll send in your place.
Maybe some foreign priest.
It's late,
they're waiting for you at home.
< No. I brought sheets,
I'll go and change the bed.
- Will you be eating?
- No, thanks.
< Look!
< It'll fall on your head.
- Let's go to the beach.
< Mm?
- I wish I could!
- But you said?
- Come on, please?
- On foot?
< Yes.
- No.
< Come on!
< Good evening.
< Good evening. The rent!
May I?
- Our Confirmation girl!
- Here I am.
Excuse me, it's untidy.
You're eating,
I'll come buy later?
No, no problem,
our schedule's all out of kilter.
- Go ahead.
- Thank you.
< This is the rent.
- Everything all right?
< Yes.
- How's work?
< Fine.
< At least it's a job.
< If it weren't for the early start,
it'd be perfect.
Every job has its drawbacks.
Mine's a job too,
it's just that my task is much greater.
< I have to protect you...
... act in the parishioners' interest.
That's why I need to know
if I can count on you,
on your family.
This isn't a god period,
there are so many bad types around.
- The elections!
- Of course.
- What can I do?
- You should put a signature her,
name and surname.
- Name: Ventura.
< Yes.
Ventura Rita.
Here you go.
- Here?
- Yes.
< Your other daughter?
- Rosa?
< (Is she 18?
- Yes, just.
< Rosetta!
< What is it? < Come here!
< What is it?
I have to study.
< Name and surname.
You'll be voting
at the primary school in Via Manzoni,
voting station B.
I think so.
This is the candidate to vote for.
For you, too.
< Signora Agata, everything all right?
< Yes, please come in.
< Did you resolve that problem?
< Yes.
< Sara, start from further back.
< Far enough, come forward.
< Sara, stand up straight..
< You're going towards God!
Kids...
Confirmation
is your spiritual battle,
you are now soldiers of Christ.
< You all look like mummies!
< Come on, come forward!
Stop, the formula.
< Holy Ghost, I entrust myself to you.
< Eli, eli...
- Eli, eli, lema sabachthani.
- Good girl. < What's it mean?
They're God's words, Marta.
- But what do they mean?
- It's not the time.
Sara, continue.
< I entrust myself to you like water
flowing from the font of the sea.
Free me of every sin,
forgive me and give me...
< Energy, Sara! Energy!
Think of Rambo, do you know him?
Come on!
Continue.
< A cat!
Flavia, a cat's got in.
< Children, catch it!
< Natale!
< Good, Marta. Catch it!
< Like that.
No, kids...
Miss Marta Ventura, come with me.
The formula.
Holy Ghost,
in times of trouble I seek you.
Give me the fear of God...
- Do you believe in God...
... the Father, Almighty, Maker of heaven and earth,
of all things visible and invisible?
I so believe.
Do you believe in the Holy Ghost,
which is the Lord and gives life,
the Holy Catholic Church,
the communion of saints,
the forgiveness of sins,
the resurrection of the body...
... and the life everlasting?
I so believe!
This is our faith,
the faith of our church...
... and we glory to profess it
in Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen!
At this point, the bishop
will mark you with a cross...
... and give you a symbolic slap,
like this!
< When I grow up I want to be a saint,
so everyone will give me gifts.
Want a gift?
I'll give you my hair.
- Cut it.
- I don't know how.
Try.
Cut it.
Then you can attach it to yours.
I can't do it.
Here.
- How do I attach it?
- You've got your dress all dirty, look!
Where did you get this?
I don't want to see.
What have you done?
Show-off.
< Let's go to the hairdresser's.
< No. She stays like that.
< She wants to be noticed.
< Come on, both of you.
- What did you do?
< Debby, let's go!
Maybe I'd better not take Confirmation.
Don't add more problems,
Marta, pleas.
Sit up.
You were right to cut it.
It'll grow out stronger.
After Confirmation
we'll go to the beach.
Beautiful.
Like a bride! Your hair to...
Is it a custom in your country?
< The big day is here,
< everything has to be perfect.
You, go and hang this in the hall.
You, take care of the tables.
You, spread the rug
and take care of the stage.
You, go to the storage room
and get the decorations.
Come on, dear. Go.
- No.
< Under the red veil?
< No, maybe under there.
< Move stuff.
< What have you found?
< Oh, yuck!
- I want that!
< Come on!
< Yuck!
< They're cute. What do we do with them?
- Let's take them home.
< No way, we have to drown them!
My grandpa put them
in bags and boiled them.
-We'll boil you, not the cats!
-Put them down, you'll hurt them.
What's going on?
Don't touch them, they carry disease.
-Come on, out.
-What disease?
< All sorts! All of you, out!
You too, don't touch them,
come out of here.
Gennaro, call Ignazio for me, please!
Ignazio!
< Come!
What are you doing here?
This leads nowhere.
< Marta, isn't that right?
< Is everything all right?
< What are you doing here?
You should be getting ready.
Entryway of the...
Yes, Marta.
Think about it.
- How did you get here?
- I walked.
< Walked.
< Santa? No one...
< Her mother's mobile number?
< I see. All right.
- Get in the car.
- No, thanks. I'll go on alone.
- Get in the car!
- I was going home.
No one's in.
Stop.
< Can you tell me what you were doing?
- Taking a walk.
Taking a walk. On the motorway?
< Anyway, I really need a hand.
- Where are we going?
< A village close by.
The village I was born in.
We're going to get the crucifix.
<We're on a mission.
< Wait for me in the car.
< Your participation shows the faith...
< ... in our community..
< Thank you.
< Long live Father Mario!
Let's start over,
music!
For the signatures, over here.
- There's only a handful of them.
- There's flu around.
Thank you.
Do you understand me when I talk?
If I tell you to wait in the car,
there's a reason.
Hello? Yes, she's with me.
< What should I have done?
< Go looking?
- Eli, eli, lema sabachthani.
- Yes, I know. I won't get tired.
< Eli, eli, lema, sabachthani.
- Keep me informed.
- Like something to eat? - No, thanks.
< I was expecting more people.
< I'm just here for signatures.
- Sure.
A sweet for the little girl?
- A nice bass?
- 15 minutes, no more.
Get it ready.
- Signora Angela...
- Welcome.
I don't want to disturb you,
but I'd like a favor.
Pray for my sister,
she has a disease that won't go.
I'm praying so hard.
If you could pray for her too?
- Of course.
- This is her picture.
- Her name's Caterina.
- Mum.? - Just a minute...
- Give her a kiss.
- Caterina.
- I'll pray for your sister.
- Thank you, Father Mario.
< Excuse her, that's just how she is.
But she cooks great. < I know.
- You're not eating?
- I don't eat fish.
Too bad.
Know how much calcium it contains?
No, stay right here.
Marta, how did you get dirty?
< Miss?
- Occupied.
< Is everything all right?
< Take this.
< It's the first time, huh?
< It's a good thing,
even though it seems bad.
I need the toilet.
You can go where you want,
there's not soul here. OK?
I'll wait for you in the church.
What are you doing? Leave him!
< I didn't recognize you.
< I don't see very well these days.
I'm taking it away,
to warmth, safety.
Have you seen the state
you've let it get into?
Hello?
- How are you?
< Fine.
- Wait, where are you going?
- I'm late, I need to let them know.
< Hello, Santa?
Are you a priest?
< Yes.
- You study like priests do?
What does,
"eli, eli, lema sabachthani" mean?
"Eli, eli..."
It's a cry,
it's Jesus crying out...
"My God, why have you forsaken me?"
- Why is he crying out?
- Because he's angry.
How do you imagine him?
- Good.
- Smiling?
< Yes.
- With blue eyes?
Ready to hug you?
- Yes.
- But he's angry, furious.
He's alone,
running from one place to another.
Everywhere they ask him
for healing, miracles...
... and he runs to them all.
With ignorant disciples around him.
... who don't understand a thing,
and always ask him for explanations.
They don't have a crumb of imagination.
And they're scandalized.
Read.
"When his family heard this,
they went out to restrain him..."
"... for they said:
He is out of his mind."
- He's here. - Who?
- The Bishop.
Now what do we do?
He shouldn't have waited till the
last minute to get that crucifix.
- He had other business.
- So what are we supposed to do?
We look like a disorganized parish,
just making it up as we go along.
- I'd say...
- Let's start with the dance.
Marta, let's go, come on!
Give me a hand.
- Hello.
- Hello, dear.
- This is my mother.
- Hello, signora. - Good morning.
- A pleasure, Santa.
- Marta?
Didn't she tell you?
Father Mario chose her
for a very important thing,
they've gone together
to get the new crucifix.
When? She didn't tell me anything.
I don't know. I'm sorry.
Pleas, have on.
Wouldn't you like to join us?
There's the dance of the little virgins....
... we've organized lots of nice things.
I'll go then, duty calls.
May I ask a question?
Where exactly will Father Mario
be transferred?
Why this bizarre question?
Since there's a certain degree
of familiarity between us,
he told me he might be transferred
to a more famous parish.
Signora, who are you?
< Santa! - Yes, but who are you
for our Holy Mother Church?
What do you represent?
- His Excellency would like a handkerchief.
- I'll see to it right away.
After Confirmation,
what else do we do?
Nothing, we go into church, that's all.
- Do you read the Gospel?
- Every day, at Mass.
You know what they said about Jesus?
- What did they say?
- He was mad.
< Nonsense!
Yes - angry, furious.
- Can I eat them?
- Yes. - One piece.
< These long hair!
I'm sorry, it's all ready.
So, have you decided?
Will you transfer or stay with us?
Where could I go?
There's a stain.
Everything's ready.
It hurts ... I bit myself.
- What have you done?
- I bit myself.
- I was curious to see that crucifix.
- You know what happened?
That little girl Marta cut the ropes
and the crucifix fell.
Don't badmouth my sister.
< My brothers and sisters,
first of all
I apologize to the whole community.
< Today our children grow up.
Thanks to our Bishop Giorgio,
who...
with his presence...
Want to see a miracle?
Look.
It's still alive.