A hundred years ago,
all was right with our world.
Prosperity and peace filled our days.
The Four Nations:
Water, Earth, Fire and Air Nomads
lived amongst each other in harmony.
Great respect was afforded to all those
who could bend their natural element.
The Avatar was the only person
born amongst all the nations
who could master all four elements.
He was the only one who could
communicate with the Spirit World.
With the Spirits'guidance,
the Avatar kept balance in the world.
And then, a hundred years ago,
he just disappeared.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry!
Hey, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
I'm sorry! I'm sorry! Hey!
It Worked better that time.
I thought about Mom. Isn't that strange?
Yeah. I guess so.
Just stop doing that stuff around me.
I aIWays get Wet.
My brother and l live
in the Southern Water Tribe,
which was once a big city.
Our father is off fighting in The War.
My mother was taken prisoner
and killed when l was young.
ln this time of war, food is scarce.
My brother and l often
go hunting for food,
but, unfortunately, my brother
isn't the best hunter in the world.
- Tiger seaI.
- Are you sure?
I did everything Dad said to do.
I Watched Which side of the fin tracks
are more indented.
That shoWs Which
direction they're going.
I saW hoW Iong the drag skids are.
That shoWs you hoW fast they're going.
There's something under there.
It's a cave-in!
Move aWay from the cracks!
Katara, don't go near it.
This is probabIy some Fire Nation trick.
Just back aWay reaIIy sIoW.
Katara! Do not hit that sphere!
UncIe, Iook!
Is he breathing?
Did you see that Iight
shoot into the sky?
What's your name?
HoW did you get here?
HoW did you get in the ice?
He's exhausted.
We need to get him back to the viIIage.
What is this thing?
It's trying to eat me!
Look. See?
HoW'd you get aII the Way out here?
I ran aWay from home.
We got in a storm. We Were forced
under the Water of the ocean.
I see.
It Wasn't very smart. I Was just upset.
- Thanks for saving me.
- Lucky.
I probabIy shouId get home.
They'II aII be Worried.
- You're not stiII upset?
- Not as much as I Was.
The Fire Nation is here.
- What?
- And they brought their machines.
Don't come out
tiII I teII you it's safe.
- Is something Wrong?
- No. PIease Wait here.
- Hurry, noW!
- Secure the area!
It can't be coincidence
that We break him out of the ice,
Iight shoots into the sky and noW the
Fire Nation is here With their machines.
Sokka, don't.
I am Prince Zuko...
...son of Fire Lord Ozai
and heir to the throne!
Bring me aII your eIderIy!
- Papa!
- Move!
Yeah?
Grandma!
PIease don't... don't harm him!
Come on!
Katara, don't.
- Form a Iine!
- Come on!
Here.
Hey.
Grammy!
You're scaring these peopIe.
Who are you? What's your name?!
- I don't need to teII you anything.
- Firebenders!
I'm taking you to my ship.
If you don't come,
I'II burn doWn this viIIage.
I'II go With you.
Don't hurt anyone.
They Were Iooking for someone oId
and they Were Iooking for someone
With the same markings the boy had.
They dragged Mom aWay
the same Way When We Were babies.
She WouIdn't have Watched us being
taken aWay. She WouId have fought.
We found that boy. He's our
responsibiIity. We shouId fight.
What WouId you do
if they tried to take me aWay?
I'd kiII them aII.
- Why?
- Because you're my sister.
Because Dad toId me
to protect you With my Iife.
Because I'm your responsibiIity.
And this boy is our responsibiIity.
What do you Want us to do, Katara?
HoW are We supposed to save him?
They're on a ship.
We'd need a miracIe to catch them.
I knoW you think everything's
going to Work out, but I don't.
His bison creature thing fIoats.
What do you Want With me?
My nepheW Wants me to perform
a IittIe test on you.
- What kind of test?
- I assure you, it Won't hurt.
I've performed it hundreds of times.
It onIy takes a feW moments.
And then you're free to go.
WouId you mind if I put a feW things
in front of you at the tabIe?
It WiII onIy take a moment.
That's aII you Want?
My name is Iroh,
and you have my Word.
Grandma, I knoW
you're gonna try to stop us,
- but this is just something I need...
- Sit doWn.
I kneW from the first time
We discovered you Were a Bender,
that one day,
I WouId reaIize your destiny.
There hasn't been a Waterbender
in the Southern Water Tribe
since my friend Hama Was taken aWay.
Today, I found out that destiny.
Did you see that boy's tattoos?
Tattoos Iike that haven't
been seen in over a century.
I beIieve they are Airbending tattoos.
HoW can that be?
I beIieve that IittIe boy
might be the Avatar.
Once, a Iong time ago,
the Spirit WorId kept baIance over us.
What is the Spirit WorId, Grandma?
It's not a pIace made up
of things you can touch.
But it exists, nonetheIess.
It is fiIIed With the most amazing forms
of dazzIing creatures...
...that exist in the most
exotic vaIIeys, mountains and forests.
Each of these creatures is a Spirit.
They've Watched over us
since the beginning.
They have guided us. And onIy
the Avatar can go speak to them.
Aren't there Spirits here?
Yes, there are some Spirits
that Iive hidden among us,
sure they're Watching us
With great sadness...
The Fire Nation doesn't Wish
to Iive by the Spirits.
That's Why they're so frightened
by the existence of the Avatar.
- What can he do?
- With his mastery of the four eIements,
he WiII begin to change hearts.
And it is in the heart
that aII Wars are Won.
NoW, go heIp this boy.
He WiII need you tWo.
And We aII need him.
You are my prisoner...
...Airbender.
I'm taking you back to the Fire Nation.
- You said...
- I apoIogize.
I shouId have expIained further.
If you faiIed the test, as aII others
did, you Were free to Ieave.
But, as it turns out, you are
the onIy one in the entire WorId
Who couId pass this test.
It is truIy an honor
to be in your presence.
Don't even try to escape.
This is a Warship!
Stop! There's no Way you can...
Don't move! You have noWhere to run!
HaIt!
Don't Iet him escape!
Get him!
Thanks for bringing Appa to me.
The Fire Nation is up to something.
I have to go back noW.
- We'II come With you.
- I can take you back to the viIIage.
We're going With you.
You found the Avatar.
For a moment, I had my honor back.
Your destinies are tied, Zuko.
That, you can be sure of.
Aang flew us to his home. He told us
how he left there in a storm on Appa,
and got forced into the ocean
where they almost drowned.
Aang Airbended a sphere around them,
and ice formed.
And he couldn't remember
anything after that.
Hey, Chinto! Monae! I'm back!
Hey, guys! I Want you to meet someone!
This is Where you Iive?
They must be pIaying some trick
or something.
Monk Gyatso is gonna try and jump out
and scare me at any moment.
He's the teacher responsibIe for me.
He's kind of Iike my father.
- Is it OK if you teII me your name?
- The monks named me Aang.
OK, guys! Enough!
Spider-rat!
They're poisonous! Get behind me.
He's a fIying Iemur-bat.
We keep them as pets.
Weren't they extinct a Iong time ago?
Extinct? No, there must be thousands
of them on this mountain.
Your friends Were monks?
I knoW Where they are right noW.
They're at the prayer fieId!
Aang, Wait! I have to taIk to you!
Aang...
...I think you Were in that ice
for aImost a hundred years.
- The Firebenders started a War.
- I Ieft a feW days ago.
Aang, the Fire Nation kneW the Avatar
WouId be born into the Air Nomads...
...so they exterminated
aII the Air Nomads.
You're Iying!
This is Monk Gyatso's.
I made it for him.
No!
Katara! Stay aWay from him!
Katara!
Stay away from him!
Your friends were monks?
The Avatar?
Where have you been?
Aang!
You can't bring Monk Gyatso back,
but Sokka and l can be with you
as long as you need!
Don't give up! We can do this together!
Aang!
The banished prince.
Let's offer him Iunch.
I Wanted to thank
the great GeneraI Iroh
and young Prince Zuko
for dining With us.
As you knoW, the Fire Lord
has banished his son, the Prince,
and renounced his Iove of him, and WiII
not Iet him return to the throne
unIess he finds the Avatar.
The Fire Lord beIieves his son
is too soft,
and by doing this,
he WiII become strong
and become a Worthy heir
to the throne.
I commend the Fire Lord's discipIine.
For exampIe, it seems
I need to remind Prince Zuko
that, during his banishment,
he is an enemy of the Fire Nation
and is not aIIoWed
to Wear the Fire Nation uniform.
But We WiII Iet him Wear it today,
Iike a chiId Wearing a costume.
One day, my father WiII take me back
and you WiII boW before me.
You OK?
I'II be fine.
You knoW, my grandma thinks
because you're an Airbender,
that you couId be the Avatar.
HoW much does
the Fire Nation controI?
A Iot of viIIages in the Earth Kingdom,
Iike around here.
They haven't been abIe to conquer
big cities, Iike Ba Sing Se,
but they're making pIans, I'm sure.
So...
...are you the Avatar, Aang?
What is this?
Stay hidden.
- That chiId is being arrested.
- For What?
He Was bending tiny stones at us
from behind a tree. It reaIIy hurt.
He can bend earth?
Earthbending is forbidden
in this viIIage.
Leave him aIone.
You're not taking him anywhere.
No one is taking anybody aWay!
She's a bender!
Katara!
Move.
You, too.
Dad!
- This is my father.
- HeIIo.
That's the Fire Nation's pIan,
suppress aII other bending.
HoW did this happen to your viIIage?
Fire Nation sent soIdiers.
We fought them and defeated them.
Then they sent their machines,
huge machines made of metaI.
There Was nothing We couId do.
Those Who couId not bend Were
aIIoWed to Iive in peace,
if We Were imprisoned.
Earthbenders!
Why are you acting this Way?
You are poWerfuI and amazing peopIe!
You don't need to Iive Iike this!
There is earth right beneath your feet.
The ground is an extension
of Who you are!
If the Avatar had returned...
...WouId that mean anything to you?
The Avatar is dead.
If he Was here, he WouId protect us.
My name is Aang...
...and I am the Avatar.
I ran aWay, but I'm back noW.
It's time for you to stop doing this!
The Avatar WouId have to be an
Airbender. Are you an Airbender, boy?
Leave him aIone!
HoW is he doing that?
I don't Want to hurt anyone.
AII Airbenders shouId be dead.
KiII him! Firebenders, positions!
OK! Everybody can heIp us noW!
Don't be afraid!
Just Ieave them!
FaII back!
Go! He's an Airbender!
They took aWay any tooIs
reIated to bending.
The Fire Nation took this scroII
from a member of your Water Tribe.
A Waterbending scroII.
This is rare.
My mom toId me about these.
This Was you When
you Were born an Earthbender,
tWo Iifetimes ago.
You came to our viIIage.
Avatar Kyoshi Ioved games.
I do, too.
I mean, I stiII do.
A Iot of the viIIages in this part
of the Earth Kingdom are occupied
by the Fire Nation,
Iike this viIIage Was.
They prey on the Weakest toWns
and viIIages.
We shouId go visit
some of these toWns, Aang.
- I need to teII you something.
- What is it, Aang?
I ran aWay before they trained me
to be the Avatar.
I don't knoW hoW
to bend the other eIements.
Why did you run aWay?
The day they toId me I Was the Avatar,
they said I couId never
have a normaI Iife,
that I couId never have a famiIy.
They said it cannot Work With
the responsibiIities of the Avatar.
- Why can't the Avatar have a famiIy?
- I asked that!
They said that's the sacrifice
the Avatar aIWays has to make.
OK. So, What if We found you teachers.
Teachers to teach you bending?
Which eIement WouId you
have to Iearn first?
Water. Water comes
after Air in the cycIe.
Air, Water, Earth, Fire.
But there are reaIIy poWerfuI benders
in the Northern Water Tribe.
My dad toId me about it before he Ieft.
It's Ied by a princess because
her father died.
There are teachers there, but aII
the Way on the other side of the WorId.
- We can get there on Appa.
- That's What I Was thinking.
And maybe We can stop
in the viIIages on the Way,
start a change in The War
in these smaII viIIages.
- ShouId We try it?
- Yes, We shouId.
The scroll we had
was proving to be helpful.
Aang was practicing,
but for some reason,
he was having trouble
with Waterbending.
We moved from town to town
in the Earth Kingdom.
We tried to stay out of sight,
but Sokka became concerned
we were being followed.
Sire, I have good neWs.
As you knoW, I conducted a raid
on the Great Library,
- Which most said didn't exist.
- Get on With it.
I found scroIIs in the Iibrary.
We are deciphering them.
But I beIieve they may
contain information
as to Where the Ocean and Moon
Spirits Iive in this WorId.
With this information,
We couId bring doWn
the Northern Water Tribe city,
We couId shoW the WorId
the true strength of fire.
I am pIeased.
WeII, Commander Zhao,
are the rumors true or not?
Our spies have discovered someone
cIaiming to be the Avatar.
They describe him as just a boy.
We shouId set a trap for this person.
We have many Earth Kingdom peopIe
under our controI.
I can Ieave soIdiers
hidden in certain Iocations.
- And my son?
- He had his chance. He missed it.
Let's hope, for your sake,
my son doesn't find this person first
and he turns out to be the Avatar.
He WouId return as a hero and,
for aII purposes, be your superior.
WeII, I suppose it's a race, then.
We're cIose, UncIe.
They've been moving
farther and farther north.
We're catching them.
There are a Iot of pretty girIs
in this toWn, Zuko.
You couId faII in Iove here.
We couId settIe doWn here,
and you couId have a bIessed Iife.
We don't have to continue this, Zuko.
I'II shoW you Why We must, UncIe.
Hey. Hey. LittIe one, come here.
You Iook Iike a very smart boy.
TeII me What you knoW about the
Prince, the Fire Lord's son.
- He did something Wrong.
- He spoke out of turn to a generaI,
in defense of some of his friends
Who Were going to be sacrificed
in a battIe.
Then Prince Zuko
Was sentenced to an Agni Kai dueI,
but When he shoWed up,
- it was his father he was to fight.
- That's right.
He would not fight his father.
Then his father mocked him and said,
''l should bring your sister
up here to beat you.''
Then the father burnt his son...
...to teach him a lesson.
We'II catch him soon, UncIe.
Then We can think
about the pretty girIs.
Aang...
Try to keep your Wrist bent,
Iike it's shoWing.
What's Wrong?
You've reaIIy been distracted today.
I saW Sokka's maps.
We're near the Northern Air TempIe.
Do you think it WouId be OK
if I just visited there and came back?
- I'd be back in Iess than a day.
- Why?
He had a vision
at the Southern Air TempIe prayer fieId.
He taIked to a Dragon Spirit
Who he thinks can heIp us.
He thinks if he goes
to another spirituaI pIace,
he can get back to the Spirit WorId.
I don't think that's a good idea.
We started a rebeIIion.
Try to taIk him out of it.
I can't do this.
I need heIp.
- I guess your taIk didn't Work.
- He'II be back in a day.
The Fire Nation is foIIoWing us. If We
make a Wrong move, they'II catch him.
Who are you?
Why, it cannot be!
I've heard stories. Are you...?
My name is Aang.
I cannot beIieve
I've Iived to see your return.
I'm an Earth viIIager,
but I visit these tempIe remains often.
The Fire Nation destroyed this tempIe.
They have ruined everything.
No, no, no, not everything.
You knoW, there's
a hidden chamber of statues
I think you, of aII peopIe, shouId see.
These are aII the Avatars.
These are the reincarnations
of you over the years.
The Avatar Roku Was your Iast Iife.
NoW, hoW did the Airbenders knoW
you Were the Avatar, IittIe one?
They gave me a test.
They put 1 ,000 toys in front of me
and asked me to choose four.
They said I chose the same four objects
that beIonged to the previous Avatars.
That's When they toId me
I couId have no famiIy.
ToId me I had a responsibiIity
to the Four Nations.
There's a ceremony
When everyone boWs to me.
That's When I accept my roIe
as the Avatar.
But When everyone boWed...
...I didn't boW back.
You seem Iike a nice young man.
You reaIIy do.
You WiII forgive me, Won't you?
- For What?
- For Iuring you doWn here.
I have Iived in poverty
because of your absence, Avatar.
So you WiII understand
my actions today.
l have lived in poverty
because of your absence, Avatar.
I have seen a vision
of the moon turning red.
The Fire Nation has stoIen knoWIedge
of us from the Great Library.
They are pIanning
to misuse this knoWIedge.
I WiII stop them.
You must go
to the Northern Water Tribe.
If they take that city,
more WiII suffer and die,
as your Airbenders have.
You must go noW!
WiII I stop them?
Wake up, young man!
My name is Commander Zhao.
I set this trap for you.
Don't Worry, I'm not gonna kiII you.
Besides, you'd just be reborn again,
and then the search WouId continue.
So Where have you been aII this time?
And hoW is it that you're stiII a boy?
I understand that When you freed
that handfuI of toWns,
you Were very impressive, but...
...you onIy used Airbending
against my soIdiers.
NoW, Why is that?
The Fire Lord and I have a pIan
to ensure our reign
and the doWnfaII of our enemies.
I am sending a personaI message
to the Fire Lord,
informing him
that the once feared Avatar
is our prisoner
and no threat to our might.
Who are you?
Wait! Don't!
Stop!
FooIs.
CIose the inner gates!
The Avatar has escaped!
Lock doWn the gate!
Lock doWn aII the gates!
To the main post!
This Was their practice area.
Go again!
Do not kiII the Avatar!
He WiII just be reborn again!
Why are you doing this? Who are you?
Open the gates.
Let them out!
- Is it some kind of Spirit, Commander?
- Not at aII.
Do it.
What is this?
And hoW did he escape?
I fear that your son
is not onIy incompetent,
but aIso a traitor.
Of course, I cannot prove this, sire.
You think...
...my son is this person
the soIdiers are caIIing
the BIue Spirit.
Yes.
Zhao's men Were searching the coast,
Iooking for you.
They aIso searched the ship.
I toId them you Went
on vacation With a girI.
Where Were you the past four days?
NoWhere.
We have to keep moving.
The Avatar is traveIing again.
Take rest first.
It Iooks Iike you
Went through a great deaI.
When you Wake, We'II have tea together
before We start the engines.
Do not harm my son.
Leave him to his isolation.
You have my word, sire.
l will not harm him.
Zuko!
And what of the Avatar?
We assume he has
rejoined with his supporters.
It has been confirmed
that he's traveIing north.
It is my strong beIief that he is
traveIing to the Northern Water Tribe.
l believe the child Avatar has only
knowledge of his birth element, Air.
l believe he is trying to learn
in the discipline of water.
He's gone to seek out someone
in the Northern Water Tribe,
where they have lived beyond our reach
and openly practice Waterbending.
We arrived at the Northern Water Tribe.
We presented ourselves
to the royal court.
My brother and the princess
became friends right away.
Aang showed them he
was the last Airbender,
and was accepted
to train with the master.
The city knew our arrival
would bring great danger.
And they prepared for war they knew
would come in the ensuing weeks.
The city Was designed
to Withstand any assauIt.
If We keep them to the courtyard
and the marketpIace tiII night faIIs,
Where We have the advantage,
We WiII succeed.
If We Iet too many of them
into the city,
their sheer numbers
couId overwheIm us.
As many fires in this city shouId be put
out as possibIe When the aIarm sounds.
We Want to minimize
their bender sources.
I must assign a guard
to be With you at aII times, Princess.
Your presence is our inspiration.
I'II do it. That's me.
I'II be her guard.
Nothing WiII happen to her.
I had a feeIing you might voIunteer.
l've heard no word of my son
for quite some time.
- Do you know where he is?
- l've not heard of anything, sire.
l'm sure word of him
will come to us soon.
The Northern Water Tribe benders
are given their strength
by the Moon and Ocean Spirits.
They WiII be difficuIt to defeat.
NoW, if for some reason
the Spirits Were not invoIved,
that WouId be different.
What have you Iearned
from the stoIen scroIIs?
We have deciphered the Iocation
of the Moon and Ocean Spirits.
It is our destiny to have found
this information, Zhao.
EIiminate the Spirits,
take the city and We WiII have
thWarted the Avatar in the process.
Water is What?
The fIoWing eIement.
The eIement of change.
To master Water,
you must reIease your emotions,
Wherever they may Iead you.
Water teaches us acceptance.
Let your emotions fIoW Iike Water.
Aang, WouId you Iike to spar?
You haven't sparred in a feW days.
NoW, use offense, Aang!
GeneraI Iroh, I'm gIad you couId
accept my invitation to join us
- on this historic event.
- Your invitation Was most gracious.
You are a gifted strategist.
No one can argue that.
Your faiIure in the Hundred Day Siege
of Ba Sing Se Won't be heId against you.
Your son died in that siege, didn't he?
Yes, he did.
Again, I offer my condoIences
on your nepheW burning to death
in that terribIe accident.
Thank you.
I've Ioved spending
these Weeks With you, Sokka.
Me, too.
ShouId We see What the ocean
is doing today?
When there is some safety for aII of us,
I WiII come visit our sister city
in the Southern Water Tribe
and spend some time in your home.
That WouId be great.
But I Warn you...
...my grandmother WiII ask you
a Iot of questions.
What might she ask me?
She'II say, ''Why is your hair White,
young Iady? You Iook very odd.''
I WouId say to your grandmother, my
hair is White because When I Was born
I Was not aWake.
My mother and father couId not get me
to make a sound or move.
So they prayed for days
to the Moon Spirit
and dipped me into the sacred Waters.
My parents said that my hair turned
White then and Iife poured into me.
WoW.
You didn't teII me that.
You didn't ask me.
OnIy your grandmother did.
I'm sure Zhao Was the one
Who ordered the attack on you.
Any probIems?
We have arrived at the Northern
Water Tribe's stronghoId.
They beIieve the boy is there.
Why do you seem upset, UncIe?
Zhao has no sacredness.
Are you sure you Want to be here?
I WiII not be aIIoWed to Iive in peace
untiI I bring the Avatar to my father!
Is that not cIear to you?
What is this?
Yue...
...the Fire Nation is here.
NoW be sure to keep your uniform
cIosed up to your neck.
And remember, your Chi can Warm you.
I knoW, UncIe.
Be safe.
Aang needs to ask you something.
I have to taIk to the Dragon Spirit.
He can heIp me defeat the Fire Nation.
Is there a spirituaI pIace
Where I can meditate?
There is a very spirituaI pIace.
The city Was buiIt around this pIace.
But we must hurry.
Momo, be nice.
To get your Airbending tattoos,
you have to meditate for Iong
periods of time Without Iosing focus.
Some of the great monks
can meditate for four days.
- I have to get back.
- I'II take you.
I'II stay With him.
Aang?
Aang, can you hear me?
I kneW you Were reaI.
I aIWays kneW you'd return.
Me, too.
The Fire Lord's son.
You took him from our viIIage.
Who are you?
My name is Katara,
and I'm the onIy Waterbender Ieft
in the Southern Water Tribe.
- Go for the chiIdren.
- Yes.
I'm not aIIoWed to go home Without him.
The Waterbenders get poWer
from the moon.
They WiII get stronger
as the day comes to an end.
GeneraI Iroh,
I've been keeping a secret.
And What is that?
In my raid of the Great Library
earIier this year,
I found a scroII that teIIs
the Iocation
of the Ocean and Moon Spirits.
To meet a Spirit WouId be a great honor.
WeII, I hope I can give you that honor.
What happened?
Prince Zuko's here in the city.
He took Aang again.
We'II just Wait
tiII everyone's fighting everyone.
Then in the night, We'II sIip out.
Aang, can you hear me?
l knew you were real.
l always knew you'd return.
HeIIo! HeIIo!
PIease, teII me hoW
to beat the Fire Nation!
You are not deaIing
With the Ioss of your peopIe,
and your responsibiIity
for their deaths.
You are stopping yourseIf
from grieving.
You are angry.
You must Iet this go.
As the Avatar,
you are not meant to hurt others.
Use the ocean.
ShoW them the poWer of Water.
Go! Do this noW.
My sister Azula
was always the special one.
She Was a Firebending prodigy.
My father Ioves her.
He can't even Iook at me sometimes.
He says I'm Iike my mother.
I advise that you
puII back your men soon.
They WiII be trapped in the city
When the moon's poWer comes out.
Do not Worry about the moon's poWer,
GeneraI Iroh.
Why shouId you not be Worried
about the moon's poWer?
Because your brother,
Fire Lord Ozai, and I
have decided it is in our best
interests to kiII the Moon Spirit.
What?
CaIm doWn. We'II find him.
Are you OK?
Did the Spirits teII you anything?
Yes. The Dragon Spirit taIked to me.
I knoW What to do.
Aang, We have to go.
You Won't be kiIIed by Waterbenders
if you stay hidden here.
We couId be friends, you knoW.
They're getting stronger.
This is a scroII from the Great Library.
This is our map.
Our WorId is going to change soon,
gentIemen.
Right there and right there.
See Where they're going!
I'II go join the fight!
They are caIIed many names:
Yin and Yang, push and puII.
May I introduce you to the mysterious
Ocean and Moon Spirits?
Why do Spirits take the form
of such benign things?
It Ieaves them so vuInerabIe.
To teach man kindness and humiIity.
Commander Zhao,
there are certain things
humankind shouId not tamper With.
The Spirits and the Spirit WorId
is one of them.
What are you doing here?
Stop, Zhao.
The WorId WiII go out of baIance.
Everyone WiII be hurt.
The Fire Nation is too poWerfuI
to Worry about chiIdren's superstitions,
GeneraI Iroh.
Commander Zhao, don't.
We are noW the gods!
No!
Man aII battIe stations!
You are too soft, GeneraI Iroh.
He's making fire out of nothing!
They're breaching the WaII!
To the front!
As the Avatar,
you are not meant to hurt others.
You must show them
the power of Water.
AII is Iost.
You have been anointed
by the Moon Spirit.
- He gave me Iife When I Was a chiId.
- Then there is stiII a chance.
You can give your Iife
back for the Spirit's.
- Don't Iisten to him, he's Fire Nation.
- Nothing is ever truIy Iost.
- Is it mine to give back, if I choose?
- There are reasons each of us are born.
We have to find those reasons.
- This Was the reason I Was born.
- Yue, pIease.
There is no Iove Without sacrifice.
Yue, What are you doing?
You don't knoW What WiII happen.
I beIieve my Iife force WiII Ieave my
body and return to the Moon Spirit.
And then What?
My souI WiII no Ionger exist
in this form.
PIease don't do this.
There must be another Way.
I can't Iet you do this.
I'm supposed to protect you.
My peopIe are dying, Sokka.
Those Who are in charge of others
have a responsibiIity.
It is time We shoW the Fire Nation
We beIieve in our beIiefs
- as much as they beIieve in theirs.
- But Yue...
I'm scared.
Don't make me any more scared.
I WiII miss you more than you knoW.
I kiIIed you.
Come aWay from him, nepheW.
There are too many soIdiers noW.
They WiII never
Iet you take the Avatar.
We must Ieave immediateIy.
He Wants to fight you
so he can capture you, Zuko.
WaIk aWay!
Come!
You stand aIone.
And that has aIWays
been your great mistake.
Water teaches us acceptance.
Let your emotions flow like water.
Aang?
They Want you to be their Avatar, Aang.
We aII do.
Our forces in the Northern Water Tribe
have faiIed to take the city.
GeneraI Zhao Was kiIIed in battIe
and my brother has become a traitor.
My son's proven himseIf a faiIure.
NoW, Sozin's Comet
is returning in three years.
It WiII give aII Firebenders the abiIity
of the highest Firebenders,
the abiIity to use their oWn Chi
to create Fire.
That is the day We WiII Win this War
and prove the Fire Nation's dominance.
NoW you must stop the Avatar
from mastering Earth and Fire.
You must give us the time
to get to that day.
Do you accept this
unspeakabIy important task
I'm putting in your hands?
I do, Father.