I spent my life traveling
in one direction.
Driven by greed, narcissism, arrogance.
And a slight obsession
with Steve McQueen.
You see I'm what I call
a professional criminal.
But back in the day
you'd have called me a gangster.
I was blood-tied to the second most...
...powerful crime family in Los Angeles.
Then, well, one decision changed it all.
See that girl?
That girl happens to be
the daughter of the boss...
...of our bitter enemy, The Romanos.
But first, the most powerful
crime family in California.
Talk about star-crossed lovers.
But right now, here...
We're about to cross
that wonderful line in the sand.
That glorious mark of no return.
As Steve McQueen said...
I live for myself...
...and I answer to nobody.
In 1972 McQueen fell in love
with his co-star in The Getaway.
And at that point she was married
to studio chief Robert Evans.
When a divorce was mentioned,
Evans found incriminating
information on McQueen...
...and the divorce was settled quickly.
To this day, the nature
of that evidence is unknown.
I mean, what did those
private investigators dig up...
...on McQueen that was so volatile?
I want you to think about that.
Because what's
happening in here is private.
And I don't want you imagining...
...anything that's going on.
There's moments of calm
that you remember.
Not the actual storm itself.
How quiet. How soulful.
How without pretense she is.
You think of all the magical
things you want to say to her...
...and you go to speak
and nothing comes out.
So you just smile.
She smiles back and it's all fine.
The girl's in the truck. Let's go.
I've known you since...
For how long now?
Since before you were
in the army, right?
Since you were a kid.
I'm your friend Carl.
I'm your people, Gabe.
Gabe, buddy.
It shouldn't be like this, man.
It's undignified.
Man, I know what you're capable of.
No need to labor the point.
I heard about Sebastian.
You're famous, man.
Yeah. Big man on campus, huh, Gabe?
Just tell him what you heard, Carl.
What I heard...
Oh, well...
I heard that Sebastian was into
Caterina for, like, ten large.
What you did to that poor man...
And how you left him.
It's the stuff of legend, Gabriel.
It really is.
But if you've got a heart...
I was hoping I could reach you
with my observation.
And I now fully appreciate
my position here, so...
I am happy to pay, Gabe.
But I need it to be known...
That it wasn't without resistance.
That you broke me, okay?
It's all here. Every bit of it.
He's good.
I'm good.
I don't think you're as bad
as your reputation, Gabe!
But I'm happy to let that be.
Glasses like this were made
to hide some awful pain.
They were designed to disguise
some deep psychological trauma.
I feel like Peggy Cummings in Gun Crazy.
About to embark
on an interstate robbery spree.
You want some of me, Copper?
You'll never take me alive.
That's fifteen for the wing tips...
...and six hundred
and fifty for the Presols.
Six hundred and fifty for a pair
of second hand shades, Gabe?
Six fifty and tax.
They're worth every penny.
714 Persol, folding sunglasses.
Blue glass anti-glare lens.
And the handmade Italian leather case.
Steve McQueen owned a pair.
Yes, he did.
- Keep the change.
- Thank you.
He also wore M43 rough outs in
the Great Escape.
Fashionably tapered white chinos.
A button up woolen cardigan
over a sport shirt.
It's not that I don't have
my own sense of style.
It just seems that my life
is that much easier...
...dressed like the man.
You ready, blondie?
Now remember, you can't smile
wearing these glasses.
No. Of course not.
And it's absolutely essential that...
...we wear them inside
in the darkened hallways...
...of a shady apartment
building somewhere.
But that will all change
when we get the package.
- Is that right?
- Mm-hmm.
From who? The big fat scary man?
You bought those shades because...
...Steve McQueen wore
the same make, didn't you?
Why does it always have to be
Steve McQueen?
Don't you think it's a little...
- A little weird?
- What is?
How obsessed you are over some actor.
I mean I can only name
maybe one of his movies.
Have you seen Papillon?
Sounds riveting.
See, that comment
right there just killed...
...any chance of
a long-term commitment from me.
So when I take her home and
I tell her I'm going to call her,
I won't.
And that will be the end of that.
You ready?
Thank you.
For the drive...
The glasses.
Gabriel, I'll call you.
She used to walk around my apartment...
...in these black stockings.
Just those and a T-shirt.
Oh my God, those legs.
I'd watch her make coffee
just pretending to be asleep.
Just watch her march,
doing that tip toe walk
that girls do in their socks.
You see how white her skin is?
That juxtaposition of white
against black on her thigh.
You want to put your mouth there.
Like a baby on a milk bottle.
Do I respect her?
Yeah, of course.
But if it came down to keeping
or discarding her...
That wonderful thigh swinging bounce...
Farewell, my love.
Farewell.
There she is.
When McQueen met McGraw
in The Getaway...
...he said she was the kind
of woman you would cheat...
...and then kill for.
I ask myself that question
every time I see a woman I like.
It just kills me.
I should stay but...
My family... You don't want to be early.
And I sure as hell
don't want to be late.
See, my family,
they're dangerous people.
And they expect punctuality
from their employees.
And as such they demand that
the family set a rigid example.
So I work for my aunt Caterina.
And presently that means
that I run with the enforcers.
See she put me on this detail
because she figured...
...it was a good way
to get me back into the game.
Knock away any aspirations
I may have picked up...
...while in the Middle East.
My delightful companions for
the afternoon.
Listen, if you're looking to correct...
...the imbalance of justice in
the world...
...then this is not your line of work.
Because like the man said...
Justice is for one and all...
The same way the Ritz Hotel is.
We don't want to be here just as
much as you don't want us here.
All right? But Caterina has got
a reputation to uphold.
And if you fail to acknowledge that...
...then where does that leave us, huh?
So, listen to me, brother.
Before this goes any further, tell me...
Are you going to pay or not...
...because I've got
some decisions to make.
- Yeah.
- You sure?
It's in the dresser.
Top drawer. Grocery bag.
You all right?
That wasn't so hard now, was it?
Looking a little pale there, Gabriel.
It's been awhile, Casper.
I heard you were playing
castrati in a quartet...
...for the Aryan Brotherhood.
How's your singing voice, champ?
That's very funny.
Now don't trip over yourself when
you see what I've got for you.
A little present from up north.
Like them apples, twinkle toes?
Real elephant ivory grips.
I had them fashion me a type and match.
You're pretty tough with the steel...
...for a mealy-mouthed faggot.
You want to see what you are
without it, huh?
Big man, thinks his war record
is something special,
but what does it mean?
I'll tell you what...
Some phony medals
and a hillbilly heroin habit.
I know you better than you think.
Don't forget that.
Now while you were away...
Learning to polish your boots...
I was learning the ropes.
Tony's been grooming me.
Which means, one day you and I
will go head to head.
Or...
Or what?
Are you willing to play nice
and share your toys?
You can come over, man.
Be like old times.
You've just got to say it.
Just say I'm sorry.
You know what the problem is?
You let your ambition outweigh
your ability, Casper.
You'll only ever be the odd man out.
You won't mean shit as a chief.
You may wish you'd have taken
my advice there, sunshine!
My aunt Caterina runs a club downtown.
It's an ugly little place.
From there she manages at least a
dozen more questionable v