- Ian
- Adam, man, how are you?
- Hey. Is this the Supra?
- Yeah. It's a beautiful one, man
I really hope you're gonna like it 'cause these Supras
are getting harder and harder to find you know what I mean?
You get one and pick up and it's got something and then the neck is messed up or something
Oh shit!
Adam, do you want me to take off my shoes, man?
I think I got stucked with some mudders.
- I really wouldn't bother
- Okay
- The Supra.
- 1959, man.
- Really nice, Ian. Thank you.
- Cool.
All the electronics, everything, are original.
Of course, I plugged them in, and they're all work.
Just what the doctor ordered.
As they say.
I should call it William Lawes.
It's a male?
This one is, yeah.
Who is William Lawes?
He was just a 17th century english guy.
Wrote some great funeral music.
And during the english civil war
he was casually shot dead by a parlamentarian.
That sucks.
Adam, check this one out, man.
- This one...
- It's a very strange Hagstrom, from 1960.
- Sweddish.
- Yeah.
Look at this thing.
Look at the back
Mother of toilet's seat.
Seriously, man.
And this one...
Check this out.
It's Silverton, in the very early 60's.
With an amp fit into the case.
- Fantastic.
- Right?
- Yeah
- And...
Oh, that's a lovely Gretsch 'Chet Atkins'.
6120. Double cut away.
I once saw Eddie Cochran
playing one of these.
But it had the front pickup modified
to a Gibson P-90.
Wait. You actually saw Eddie Cochran play?
Yeah, on YouTube.
Right, of course man.
- Hey, I've got something very special for you.
- We have what you need.
I know you don't wanna play live,
I know you want to remain completely anonnymous
But, you being so reclusive and everything is...
...probably gonna make people to be more interested in your music.
Yeah...
What a drag.
Listen, Ian
There is something you could do for me
Anything.
Anything man, what is it?
I need a bullet.
A very special bullet.
Really?
I got you that pack of shells of the 38 last year.
I know, the 38.
I need a 38 caliber bullet
- but made of wood.
- What, wooden bullet, seriously man?
Made from the hardest and most dense wood that you can find.
I'd suggest guaiacum wood, Lignum Vitae,
maybe snakewood, Piratinera Guianensis,
Or posibly african black wood,
Dalbergia Melanoxylon.
- You think you could find than someone who could make it for me?
- Yeah, but... could you just repeat the last couple.
guaiacum wood, Lignum Vitae,
snakewood, Piratinera Guianensis,
black wood, Dalbergia Melanoxylon.
Okay. Yeah, I think I know someone but...
what the hell for?
It's for a...
a project.
- A secret art project.
- Ok, cool, cool.
Alright, let me think.
Thank you, Adam.
The shellcase should be -metálico-
but the bullet has to be wood.
- Just want one?
- Just the one, yeah.
Okay, cool.
Anything else weird...
Interesting you may need?
There's a warehouse that sells this kind of
softake amps
some german resistances, soviet tubes
I thought you may go there and check it out
No, I'm good. Thank you.
Okay.
Can I use your bathromm before I get out?
Ah...
I'm afraid it's still out of order.
Still?
I'm gonna get someone...
- No, don't bother.
- It's really no bother...
No!
Look, Ian... I'm gonna fix it myself
I just haven't gone around to it yet.
Please, feel free to piss in my garden.
Bilal.
(you look beautiful in french), madame Eve.
(Gracias.)
So... Tell me, how is he?
Really.
My teacher is fragile.
But he has a strong spirit.
He is in such good hands.
He's my family.
And I protect...
Protect his secrets.
And yours too.
Mistress mine.
It's just an hour before sunrise
I'm well aware of that, my dear.
Is that the really good stuff?
Yes, Eve.
From the french doctor?
Precisely.
So...
How's the fabulous Christopher Marlowe tonight?
I told you this! Never call me that name in public.
You nutcase.
I can keep a secret!
You should know that.
But I'm asking,
what most outrageously delicious literature scandal in history?
Dear Eve, that was 4 centuries ago.
You've been wearing that westcoat for 4 centuries.
I was given this in 1585. It's one of my favourite garments.
So, are you saying you're never gonna let the cat out of the bag?
Couldn't we...
drop a hint here and there?
It would cause such a thrilling chaos.
I think the world has enough chaos
to keep it going for the minute.
Spoilsport.
Jesuschrist!
You scared the shit out of me.
I've sort of been expecting you recently for some reason,
doctor...
- Doctor Faust.
- It's good to see you again, too, doctor...
Doctor...
Watson.
You know, uh...
This whole setup is a bit unnerving for me.
Would you consider meeting somewhere
outside the hospital sometime?
Instead of just appearing
unexpectedly, like a... Phantom.
That would require pretty arrengement.
Yeah, and it would be safer for me.
I'd like to come to the source.
Besides, the mutual jeopardy makes me feel safer.
Now, If you excuse me. I haven't any spare time.
Right, well then,
let me get you what you desire.
doctor... Strangelove?
type O negativo.
By the way,
that stethoscope of yours?
It's for all practical props an antique.
It's from the 1970's.
- Even the 60's.
- Is it?
That guy gotta have to be from Cleveland.
- Yeah?
- Adam.
- Eve.
- Hey, darling.
- Hang on a second, I want to see you.
- Oh, I want to see you too.
What is that? Are you scrabbling about your
wires and knots, my old pet rat?
Yeah, one second I just...
- Hello.
- There you are.
Hello sweetheart.
What is it? You look tired.
Do I?
I guess I am...
Any supply problems?
No.
So, what is this, then?
Can't you tell your wife what your problem is?
It's the zombieism.
The way the treat the world.
It does feel like I'm the sands at the bottom
of an hourglass, or something.
Time to turn it over, then.
Oh my liege lord...
We've been here before...
Remember?
And you missed all the real fun like
the Middle Ages, the tartars, the inquisitions...
The floods, the plages...
How about your music?
I seem to be
writing a lot of funeral music.
Oh, my darling, why don't you just come here
and kiss me?
You used to love Tanger.
You loved the music.
Oh fuck.
Alright. I'll come
But I can't believe you're doing this to me again.
It's the travelling what's such a drag.
Eve...
I love you so much.
I'll take that, for the journey.
Fucking hell.
Yes. And is there a posibility of a night flight
from Tanger to Paris?
Yes, that would work.
And then flying the following night from Paris to Detroit?
Is that correct? Wonderful.
Name of Fibonacci.
Hey, man, I hope this isn't a bad time.
I wanted to come right the way cause
I have a thing for you.
Wooden bullet. 38 caliber.
It's cocobolo.
Dalbergia Retusa.
For your art project!
The guy made it for me no questions asked.
He said the wood it's so dense
that it sinks on water.
I think thet make guitars out of it too.
Both are true, yeah.
It's perfect. Thank you, Ian.
No problem, man.
You know, for a zombie...
You're alright.
Thanks.
Please.
Oh, no man. You already paid me so much the other time.
It's okay.
Ian, please.
Bought my car and everything.
Thank you, Adam.
Anything else you may need, man?
Anything you want me to get you?
There was some rock 'n roll kids here last night.
Ringing my doorbell.
- Really?
- Yeah.
How do they know where you live?
No one fucking lives out here.
- I don't know but it's not cool. We've talked about this.
- I know, I know we did, man. It's not cool at all
It's completely fucked up.
How did they...?
Alright. I know
Don't worry.
I will spread some rumours
very cautiously about where you might live
and I'll just throw away them off track.
Whatever you need to do. Please, do it.
Just take care of it.
- I'm on it.
- Okay.
Look, I see you later
There's something I need to do.
You know
I had a dream
About your infamous little sister last night.
You had a dream about Eva?
What's sort of dream, Kit?
Kit?
What?
Oh sorry! I...
Sorry, I just flew away for a minute.
You are miles away!
In Italy, actually.
Few hundred years ago.
Was he painfully good-looking?
What?
Look, I know I don't have to say this to you but
Please, be cautious.
I couldn't bare that
something happened to you.
Frankly, I don't understand why you don't live in the same place
Because you can't live without eachother.
Anyway,
give him my regards to that...
suidicial romantic scoundrel.
- Do you really think he is?
- Scoundrel?
Well, let's hope he's just romantic.
Even so I mainly blame Shelley
and Byron
And some of those french arseholes
you saw him around with.
Oh, I wish that I'd met him before
he wrote Hamlet.
He'd provided the most perfect
role model imaginable.
"Love alters not
with its brief hours and weeks"
"But bears it out even
to the edge of doom."
"If this be error
and upon me proved"
"I never writ,
nor no man ever loved."
Marlowe...
Ouch! Oh man...
I'm a mess.
- Excuse me
- Oh no, let me get you something.
Thank you.
Damas y caballeros, empezamos el descenso
al aeropuerto Metro de Detroit.
Thanks for flying with us on Air Lumiere.
And we hope to see you again soon.
- I appreciate
- No problem.
Mephitis Mephitis.
My lady.
May I?
I love what you've done with the place.
I love your newest music too.
It makes me think of when you gave that string quintet
to Schubert. Remember?
- And he presented it as his own.
- Yeah, but I asked him to do that.
I only gave him the adagio.
Just to put something out there.
Is that why you release this new stuff?
I needed a reflection.
See if it would echo back before...
Before what?
Oh, Adam.
You always have the convenience of the zombies
to blame when you get low.
What about all your heroes?
- I don't have heroes.
- No?
- What about your blessed scientists?
- The scientists?
Look what they've done to them.
Pythagoras, slaughtered.
Galileo, imprisoned
Copernicus, ridiculed.
Poor old Newton pushed into secrecy in alchemy.
Tesla, destroyed.
His beautiful possibilities completely ignored.
And still bitching about Darwin.
Still.
So much for the scientists.
And now they've succeeded in
contaminating their own fucking blood.
Nevermind the water.
Yeah, well
If we're gonna have a letany in
all the zombie atrocities in history
we would be here until the sun comes up.
The sun is coming up.
Should I tell you again about the
'Spooky action at a distance'?
Einstein's theory of entanglement.
I love the way you tell it.
But not now.
We don't wanna be up all day.
Eve?
Could you tell me how old this guitar is?
I think is an L2, but...
I've never been able to date it exactly.
Ah! She's a pretty one.
A Gibson. 1905.
She is old.
Yes, my darling. But you know your dressing gown
is at least a century older.
Is it?
So this is your wilderness.
Detroit.
Everybody left.
- What's that?
- It's a Packard plant.
Where they once built the most beautiful cars in the world.
Finished.
But this place will rise again.
Will it?
Yeah
There's water here.
When the cities in the south are burning.
This place will bloom.
Do you want to see the Motown museum?
Well, there's not much to look at from the outside.
I'm one of the stag(?) girls myself.
Actually there is something
I could show you.
It's not far.
There. It's Jack White's house
It's Jack White's house.
- Aah! I love Jack White
- It's where he did grow up
Aw.. Little Jack White. Nice
You know he's actually his mother's seventh son?
Haha. I bet he is
And this is the famous Michigan Theatre.
They built it back in the 1920's.
It was huge on the money.
It was built ironically on the exact same site where
Henry Ford made his very first prototype.
It used to be seats for over 4000 people in here.
It's fantastic.
For what? for concerts?
Concerts and as a movie house, can you imagine?
Mirrors used to reflect the chandeliers...
And now...
A car park.
There goes your queen, playboy.
By the way, your hero Christopher Marlowe sends his love
I don't have heroes.
I know what you're doing.
You're trying to distract me
Now no more talking.
- Did you play chess with Byron?
- Eve! Please...
No, I want to know...!
You love telling me these things and I love to hear them.
- So what was he like?
- Frankly, he was a pompous ass.
Why am I not surprised?
And what about Mary?
What was Mary Wollstonecraft like?
Come ooon! Tell me, what was she like?
She was delicious.
I bet she was.
Talking of delicious, I have a surprise.
An experiment.
- That doesn't work by the way.
- Nono it does, I plentied in.
- What is that?
- O negative.
- That's delicious.
- Blood on a stick.
On a stick.
- It's not bad.
- It's very refreshing.
Specially when you're in a hot spot.
Checkmate, my darling.
Eve, you're ruthless. You're brutal.
I'm a survivor, baby.
That's all the bloody talking.
You gotta hear this one.
Charlie Feathers.
- You know it?
- 1956.
'Can't Hardly Stand It'
Yeah.
Shit!
Oh! What a lovely place!
Vitis Vinifera, hello.
Look at that.
Fucking zombie shit.
In greed.
It's so antiquated. What century is this?
Tesla had lightbulbs and not even a plug-in in 1895.
- But it's not even connected!
- Yeah I disconnected it all out.
Oh!
What a hidden treasure, my darling! Did you make that?
- Well, I cabled it together from bits and pieces.
- How beautiful! You're an alchimist!
I just need to check the charges and the connections.
This may need a callibration.
- Are these the antennas?
- Yeah
They're receiving
electrical information from the athmosphere
- From outer space?
- They (?) into energy.
(?)
Hang on. Let me just see this
Amanita Muscaria.
How odd.
- Adam?
- Yeah?
Have you noticed these?
Yeah.
Fly garrack. They're behaving very strange though
- But this is not the season!
- I know.
They kind of appear and then disappear and reappear those caps.
I guess they're receiving information of the atmosphere I might have tell them.
This puts to show we don't know shit about fungus.
Maybe the life from the planet couldn't live without them
You know you guys shouldn't really be here.
Not until the Autumn.
- Evening.
- What's going on, my love? Are we playing doctors?
I am.
I've got to go after our source.
- Am I not included?
- Not this time.
1968. you could do with a new one.
Have you ever used this on anyone?
doctor... Faust? Right
What is it, my darling?
I had a dream
about your sister.
- Not a good one, then.
- Well I suppose it could've been worse
But not that much.
- Back in a flash.
- Hope so.
Good luck with the surgery, doctor..
June 23rd. 1868.
Our third wedding.
We look so young!
Marlowe...
Dalbergia Retusa?
This has been newly made.
You're looking awfully pale, doctor... Caligary.
Maybe you need to get a little more sunlight.
Vitamine D deficiency can have serious consecuences.
Fresh blood, baby.
What's this about?
Just tell me that you haven't been in trouble
with one of the others
Please tell me that.
I don't see any others.
Ever.
Okay.
Don't ever fuck around like that.
Just playing a part in your story.
It's the zombies I'm sick of...
And the fear...
of their own fucking imaginations.
My darling! That's true
Meanwhile...
Just tell me what's so not frightening about that?
How can you have lived for so long
and still not get it?
This self-obsession, is a waste...
...of living!
It could be spent on surviving things
Appreciating nature,
nurturing kindness, and friendship...
and dancing!
You've been pretty lucky in love, though
If I may say so.
It's a full moon.
Did you know that there's a diamond out there
of the size of a planet?
It's a white dwarf of compressed heart of a star.
And it's not only a radiant diamond
but also it makes the music of a gigantic gong.
A diamond...
That it makes the music of a gigantic gong.
- Where is it?
- It's just... 50 light-years away.
In the constellation Centaurus.
Mmh...
I wonder what it sounds like.
I have to tell you something.
I... also had a dream about my sister.
As did Marlowe before I left Tanger.
I think she's looking for us.
Fuck!
Well... I mean, it's been quite sometime
Yeah, not long enough.
Shouldn't she be sleeping in a fucking coffin somewhere in her own?
Probably with a wooden stack sunk in?
- Adam, she's my sister.
- Is she now?
Well, we are...
Related by blood
I didn't leave these lights on.
That's your music?
Eva.
What the fuck are you doing here?
Oh my god! It's so great to see you!
You're still so beautiful.
May I?
My amazing sister,
I missed you.
- Did you get my message?
- I think I might have. I had a dream.
Aw, how cool! It works!
There's your "spooky action at a distance".
Yeah, well spooky action anyway.
What are you guys talking about?
You do know that is very bad luck to cross a threshold without being invited.
- Are you still afraid of garlic?
- I'm not talking about myths here, Eva.
You know it's also bad luck to listen to someone's private music
without invitation?
My god, I love it Adam! It's totally brilliant.
Can I get a download?
No.
So? Were you just passing through Detroit?
Yeah!
No! I mean I came to see you!
I've been living in LA.
Great.
The zombie central.
Are you alone?
No...
I'm here with you guys!
Fuck.
Well, you can't stay here
- Adam!
- No fucking way! Not after last time
Oh, Adam, It's been 87 years.
What? When?
Are you still upset about the Paris thing?
Well, are you okay?
Yeah but I'm...
I'm really really really hungry
Do you maybe have something?
Did you smell it all the way from LA?
Go on.
- Eva...
- What? I just wanna see where you keep it
No!
Well, it's so amazing to see you.
We're gonna have so much fun together.
She drank a whole bottle of O negative.
I know.
But she's been travelling and that fries you, you know?
We'll all be alright.
It's always a bit weird with family.
- Where is she sleeping now?
- I put her in that little bedroom downstairs.
- Which little bedroom?
- You know, the little one down the corridor.
I'll have to put my tapes in the bloody safe now.
Don't worry. Go to sleep now.
She's out god and it's getting light out.
We can talk when we will get up tonight.
Just think of that magic gong musical diamond in the sky
Above us now.
Eve! Adam!
- What is it Eva?
- Can I come in?
Mmmmh... no.
Isn't time to get up?
Darling, can we sleep a little longer?
But it's dark out already.
Starving.
Go away, we're still sleeping.
In a little while we'll all get up and have breakfast together, alright?
- Some of the good stuff?
- Sure.
Where do you keep it?
- You could and get dressed and we'll bring you some, alright?
- Okay.
Peek-a-boo!
I see you!
What the hell is this?
Oh! This is from french television in 1975.
Hey!
You're pushing your luck, Eva.
Why did you turn it off?
I love that, I found it on YouTube.
Yeah, of course she did...
I don't feel well.
What is this sweetheart?
You think is all the travelling?
Maybe.
It's probably blood-poisoning.
- Don't joke Adam.
- I'm not!
Are you taking care of your nutrition?
You know you've got to be very careful.
There's a lot of contamination around
I try.
Hey! You guys fed without me!
Take it easy! Shit!
My god, that is good I want more.
No, even more that enough.
This is pure shit,
and you're drying out all our fucking supplies. So take it easy.
Fine.
Then I wanna hear some of your music.
No, I told you, it's private.
Oh yeah?
Well, how could I heard it in LA, then?
What do you mean you heard it in LA. Where did you hear it?
At some underground music club.
I don't believe you.
So don't.
- How did you know was mine then?
- Oh come on, I could tell inmediately!
I might have been born in night but I wasn't born last night.
Fine.
But I'm gonna go out.
- I wanna hear some music
- Good idea. Go out
But I wanna go with you two!
No.
You're so fucking boring!
I bet he never takes you out. Ever, right?
Well, no. We do go for a drive sometimes to time.
Oh! a drive!
That's exciting.
I mean, go somewhere!
Where there's music.
- Don't you wanna go, Eve?
- Well, I wouldn't mind
We are in Detroit.
- Yeah!
- No!
Adam is going to take us out!
No! Adam is not going to take you out.
- Awesome!
- They were great
You guys have awesome gloves, man
Where did you get them?
- Hey, Ian.
- Scott, how are you man, it's nice to see you.
- Yeah, the last time I saw you were with Daniel
- I think so, yeah
I've got something to you.
I'll be right back.
- That's great
- I know. So good
- So, you remember that 12 inches?
- Oh yeah yeah.
- So check it out, man. Triple pack
- Yeah
- 180gr vinyl?
- 180 grame, man.
- Amazing.
- No printing anywhere.
yeah that's awesome.
So misterious.
Thanks, man.
Wow, man, this is so great you know?
I...
I couldn't get this guy just to come out
and see some live music, you know?
- Do you like it, Adam?
- Yes
- Adam! You wanna meet White Nails, man?
- No.
Cool, then.
Oh, I'm so sorry! So rude,
can I get you a beer or anything, Eve? some drink?
I'm Eva, she's Eve.
I'm so sorry.
Eve, can I get you something? a beer?
- No, thank you, nothing
- Eva?
Oh! Very nice.
You brought your own, what is that?
- Jagermeister?
- Where did you get that?
- I found it at home before we left.
- At home? You mean at my house?
- Yeah, want some?
- No.
I'll have some.
- Do you think that I can get some of it?
- Sure
Cool.
Wow, man.
That was like martial arts top shit
And this guy is just.. amazing man, you know?
- He's brilliant.
- He is brilliant.
You know I can't tell anyone about him?
How weird is that!
I had to sign a confidentiality term and everything.
That's your music.
- Hey, you wanna dance with me, rock 'n roll star?
- What now?
Yeah.
Eve, we gotta go.
Right now.
Alright. Just cool and (?) yourself
Just... Go easy.
Hey
Eva.
- Adam, I think we could hear some of your new stuff?
- No it's not a good time.
Seems like a great time, we're all here you know?
Yeah I got you, I'm sorry I'm sorry I'm just...
...deadly excited.
Me too.
Adam?
Adam, can I have that flask back, please?
No, Eva. No more tonight.
- I'm just really thirsty.
- I'm think we just could go to bed.
I mean it's getting light out.
- I think it's time to retire.
- Oh, do you wanna share some of this?
Ian. I think, uhm...
I think it's time for you to go.
- Yeah
- He's gonna go as soon as he's finished his little beer
Yeah, I should, I should get going
- Yeah, he's just going in just a second.
- That's an excellent idea. Goodnight, baby.
Goodnight Ian, very nice to meet you.
I hope yo see you again.
Yeah, I sure hope so.
- You're leaving soon, right?
- Yeah, I'm going then.
Yeah, that's I'm getting out here.
Really?
Peek-a-boo!
I see you!
Peek-a
Don't even dare...
Shit
- It's all dark outside?
- Yeah
- What are you doing with this?
- I filled a little something for Eva.
Oh, fuck...
I'm gonna check on her.
But you're alright, darling.
She's gotta go.
I need you all to myself again.
Good idea.
Before it's too late.
I'll get some getting up then.
Eva?
Eva!
Fuck!
- Eve!
- This is the bloody 21st century.
Ahh I didn't mean to!
He was just so cute and now I feel sick.
What did you expect?
He's from the fucking music industry!
Oh, back off!
You drank Ian.
Adam!
You drank...
...Ian.
Sorry!
We can solve this. Eva is leaving.
Just get off me, Eve!
- How many times!
- I don't mean to!
Let go!
What the fuck? That's my stuff!
Get the fuck out of my house.
Where am I supposed to go?
Go back and rot in fucking LA.
You know what you guys are?
You're condescending snobs!
You've no fucking idea.
Fuck you!
Go fuck each other!
Oh, my love
He seemed such a lovely fellow.
Why couldn't she just have turned him?
- Can anybody link you two?
- You joking?
- We were all together last night.
- So much for that confidentiality agreement.
- Where's his car?
- He left it down by the club.
Yeah, well. Then, it'll be gone in a day or two
- Look what she did to my Gibson
- The 1905.
Wow...
Look how beautifully made is inside!
Yeah.
- Have you got a bit of old carpet?
- Behind the sofa.
- Shall we?
- Yeah...
- Hang on
- That's it.
- You got it?
- Yeah
- His feet first.
- yeah, his feet first.
Careful with his head
What are we gonna do with him?
I mean it's not like the old days
when we could just choke them in the Thames alongside the
rest of the tuberculous floaters.
Any other ideas?
Canis Latrans, how lovely.
- I think they're clocking you.
- Yeah. They're all over Detroit
Come on, Eve.
Don't even ask. Ready?
That surely was visual.
Hello? Good evening
I'd like to book
two flights from Detroit to Tanger.
Travelling at night.
Who is it?
Some rock 'n roll zombie kids.
- They're on to me.
- Yes, but be grateful is not the police.
Yes, I'm still here.
Thank you.
Yes. Two tickets. First class.
Leaving and arriving at night, please.
Yes, I'm sorry.
I know it's complicated.
Connecting through London?
Nono I'm sorry, London is not good.
Yeah.
Is there another connection?
Madrid?
Madrid's fine.
Yes, two travellers.
And no lugagge.
- What about all my instruments?
- My darling! The world is full of beautiful instruments.
I'm gonna find you the magical instrument in Tanger.
- Yes. Just carry on.
- Can we carry on blood?
Kit has the best stuff
As soon as we arrive.
Yes, credit card, which would you like?
Yes. The names of...
Stephen Dedalus and Daisy Buchanan.
Chet Atkins...
Dates of birth...?
You need something?
Mosieur? Madame? J'ai quelque chose spécial por vous
I have something very special for you.
Not far from there now. Come on.
Shit, Marlowe, where are you?
Adam!
- What was that for?
- Come on.
Where are we?
- Did you find Marlowe?
- No, we gotta go find him. You gotta get up, come on
Fuck, can't even fucking walk.
I've got something very special for you
I have what you need
Not what I need.
Oh fuck, Kit!
- Bilal.
- Madam Eve?
- Pleasure.
- Bilal.
Come in, come in.
Madam Eve, my teacher is not well.
This is a very, very bad situation.
Very bad.
Maybe your visit can do good
Please
Well, well...
Look at the cat that dragged in.
I look like shit.
My old darling..,
Ohh yeah
"What a piece of work is a man!"
"What are these acquantainces of dust?"
What happened, Kit?
This is the very last bottle of good stuff.
No more good french doctor.
They got some bad stuff.
Contaminated.
Avoid the hospital here.
Still been scratching away, though, Kit?
Oh, yeah.
Here and there over the centuries.
Bilal.
Bilal's an excellent writer in his own writing
- Maybe not yet.
- Humility...
Get you nowhere.
There's the proof of that
Humility zombie philistine.
The game paid off though, Kit.
You still got the work out there.
Never had much choice
It's all...
Very political.
Anyway, I was supposed to be...
Dead.
And now, at last...
I shall be.
Oh, Eve.
Oh, look at that shit.
- What are we gonna do?
Well, I know what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna get you that present.
Give me all your money, baby.
Come on.
Now.
Look, you stay here. Okay?
And I'm gonna go around the corner.
Just for a minute.
No funny business.
OK.
Eve, this girl is fantastic.
Jasmine, she's libanese.
I'm sure she'll be very famous.
God, I hope not.
She is way too good for that.
Come on, baby.
Look at the bow.
Dalbergia Retusa?
It's beautiful.
Thank you.
82% of human blood is water.
Have the water was started yet?
Or they're still with the oil?
Yes, they're just starting that.
They'll only figure out when it's too late.
How much of the human body is water?
55 to 60%.
And how much the Earth surface?
Up 70% is ocean and...
then they're lakes,
and the rivers...
Fuck.
I'm barely still here.
We're finished, aren't we?
Tell me now about entanglement.
Einstein's spooky action at a distance.
Is it related to quantum theory?
No. I mean
It's not a theory. It's proven.
How is it all again?
When you separate an entwined particle
And move both parts
away from the other
Even at opposite ends of the universe
If you alter or affect one,
The other will be identically altered or affected.
- Spooky.
- Even at opposite ends on the universe?
Yeah.
Is that what we're thinking?
Adam, really.
So fucking 15th century.
But they're deliciously beautiful, though, ain't they?
What choice do we have, really?
But, we're going to turn them, right?
How romantic of you.
I'll get the girl, though.
Excuse moi?