Hi there, everybody.
Welcome to the movie.
Hey, we're so glad you came.
Ernie, Ernie, listen.
I'm going to take a shower.
Have you seen my
antibacterial soap?
No, Bert, I haven't.
Oh, now where...
Now this movie you're about
to see is all about Elmo.
Who are you talking to?
The audience, Bert.
They're right there.
Wow, look at all those people.
Hey, nice cardigan.
Now in this movie, Elmo
is going to ask for your help.
He wants you to talk
and play along.
- How do we start?
- It's easy.
Just count backwards from 10.
See Bert, that's how you
start a movie, Bert.
Can you all help us count
backwards from 10?
- Yeah.
- Ready? Yell real loud.
Ten, nine, eight,
seven, six, five, four,
three, two, one!
Heya Bert, don't you think
you ought to put
some clothes on now?
Ahhh!
Enjoy the movie, everybody.
Wake up!
Ahhh!
Elmo's up, Elmo's up! Elmo up!
Wow. Hello, everybody.
It's so nice to see you.
Hey, since you're here, Elmo
wants to show you something.
It's Elmo's favorite thing
in the whole world, yeah.
Elmo's blanket!
Come on over
and meet everybody, Blanket.
Blanket? Blanket?
Blanket, where are you?
Elmo wants to show
you somebody.
Are you under here, Blanket?
Blanket?
Blanket, where are you?
Blanket? Blanket?
Oh hey there, nice people.
Have you seen Elmo's blanket?
Yes.
Where? Over there?
No.
No? Where is Blanket?
Blanket?
Is it over here?
Yes.
Really? Oh, there you are.
Thanks everybody for helping.
Blanket. Hey, you come
down from there.
Blanket. Oh, Blanket,
Elmo's so glad he found you.
Elmo doesn't know what he'd do
without his best friend.
Stop, that tickles!
* Blanket, do do do
* Who's Elmo's best friend
always by his side? *
* That's you, Blanket, yeah
* Elmo's best friend,
Elmo finds you when you...
* hide
* Elmo's blanket, a carpet,
the magic kind
* Elmo never would
ever leave you behind
* Elmo's best friend,
let's go for a ride
* Whee
* Who's Elmo's best friend?
Who helps Elmo try?
* You, Blanket
* Elmo's best friend
won't let Elmo cry *
* Together forever
in rain or sun
* We do things like two
but we're really one
* Elmo's best friend...
Uh oh, time to wash you *
Sir, sir, sir?
There's something wrong
with this.
Listen.
It's working!
Hey, you hear that?
Let's groove.
Haha!
Blanket, you're wet.
Time to dry.
* Together forever,
the world seems fine
* We never would ever
leave you behind
* Together forever,
the world seems fine
* We never would ever
leave you behind *
Whoa!
Thank you, Blanket.
Hey, let's go home.
Hi, Zoe.
Zoe?
What's wrong?
I really, really wanted
to go to the zoo today,
but my daddy had to work,
so he couldn't take me.
Oh.
Elmo has an idea.
Since Zoe can't go to the zoo,
Elmo will bring
the zoo to Zoe.
Huh?
Watch, watch, watch.
What are you, a lion?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Watch this!
Oh, that's a monkey!
I know, I know, I know.
It's a pig!
No, Elmo has something
in his nose.
Oh. Hahaha.
That's funny. Thanks, Elmo.
You always make me feel better.
You're welcome, Zoe.
Wow. Oh, what a great blanket.
Yeah, it's very special
to Elmo, Zoe.
That's why Elmo's going
to take it home.
- Soft.
- Oh, Zoe,
Elmo has a nice washcloth
at home you could hold.
Well, don't worry, Elmo.
I'll be careful.
But Zoe, Elmo wants
his blanket back now.
Well, in a minute, Elmo.
No, not in a minute,
Zoe, now, now.
Elmo wants his blanket
back now.
-Wait.
-Elmo wants his blanket
back now.
It's mine, mine, mine!
Zoe, look what you did.
I didn't mean it.
It was an accident.
Zoe's not Elmo's
friend anymore.
What? I'm not your friend?
I can't stop!
Stop Telly, that's Elmo's
blanket!
Elmo?
This is so delicate.
Coming through!
Blanket!
Sorry, Ruthie. Blanket!
Cookie...
Look out!
Blanket!
- Oh waiter?
- One second, sir.
Oh.
Elmo wants his blanket back!
- I can't stop!
- Telly!
- Hi, Telly.
- Hello.
Blanket!
Yes, sir?
Oh no, not you again.
Well listen, I'd like...
Blanket! Blanket!
This looks like a job
for Super Grover.
But what about breakfast?
No thank you, sir. I cannot
fly on a full stomach.
Oh.
Huh? But...
Blanket!
Huh?
Look out!
Could somebody please get up?
My little super body cannot
take this much weight.
Sorry, Super Grover.
They crashed.
They couldn't stop.
Everybody's okay.
But where's Elmo's blanket?
Oh, I saw it.
It fell out of the sky,
and Oscar sneezed in it,
and he dropped it in his can.
Oh, it fell out of the sky,
Oscar sneezed in it,
and then Oscar threw it
in his can.
Elmo sees. But...
Elmo?
Elmo, are you okay?
How many fingers
am I holding up?
Huh?
That's two, two fingers,
ah ah ah ah ah ah.
Excuse Elmo, make way.
Oscar, please
bring back Elmo's blanket.
Oscar, Elmo really needs
his blanket back.
Oh Elmo, it's okay.
Oscar, bring Elmo's
blanket back!
Elmo needs his blanket
back now!
Oscar, Oscar, Oscar, Oscar!
Okay, okay, okay.
Elmo, take it easy,
take it easy, calm down.
It's okay. I don't think
Oscar's home right now.
Not home? But Gina,
Elmo needs his blanket back.
I guess you'll just have
to wait for Oscar to get back.
Elmo?
Elmo doesn't want
to talk to you, Zoe.
All Elmo wants is his
blanket back.
I didn't mean to...
Don't worry, Zoe. Elmo's just
a little upset right now.
But Bob, I didn't mean to rip
his blanket.
And then Telly came
and you saw...
Everybody, break it up.
Nothing to see here.
Move along, just
a little monster trying to get
his blanket back, thank you.
Elmo can wait. Oscar will
probably be
back at any second.
Any second now.
Waiting...
Elmo's waiting.
Elmo can't wait anymore.
Wow, Elmo didn't know
Oscar's place was this big.
Blanket, there you are.
Oh, Elmo's so glad to see you.
Elmo missed you.
Come on, let's go home.
Ahhh!
Blanket!
Hey, Elmo.
Haha. Have a nice trip.
Blanket! Wow.
Wait, wait, stop the film,
stop the film.
Ernie, Ernie!
What's the matter, Bert?
What's happened to Elmo?
Oh, don't worry, Bert.
That's just the way
to get to Grouchland.
- Oh.
- Roll film.
Neighbor, duck.
Ahhh!
Whoa. Blanket, where are you?
Blanket!
Very colorful.
Ahhh!
Wow, that was a fun ride.
Gee, look at this place.
Where's Elmo's blanket?
And where is Elmo?
Elmo doesn't think he's on
Sesame Street anymore.
Hey, mate,
you're in Grouchland.
Just happens to be
the greatest place on earth.
A place where you can
kick off your shoes
and smell your stinky socks.
Oh no, I think I feel
a song coming on.
Wow, this is great.
Watch your toes,
musical number coming through.
* Hear the steady beat
of sweaty feet
* On the greasy streets
of Grouchland
* Smell the stinkweed gag,
the waving wheat
* What a perfect day
* Bring in the noise,
bring in the junk
* Step on a crack,
step in the gunk *
Home of the world's worst
traffic jam!
* Welcome To Grouchland,
now scram
* If there's gum and goo
beneath your shoe
* You can bet
you stepped in Grouchland
* It's against the law
to use shampoo
* So we wash with cheese
You like me,
you really like me!
Now get out of here.
Get my good side.
Oh, that's right, I don't
have a good side.
* If you're growing old
and love the cold
* Spend your golden
years in Grouchland
* Where the streets are paved
in solid mold
* And the stinkbugs sing
* Bring in the noise,
bring in the junk
* Step on a crack,
step in the gunk *
Our motto? I Grouch,
therefore I am!
* Welcome to Grouchland
* Now scram
Wow, Grouchland sounds
like fun.
What?
Fun? You obviously don't
appreciate Grouch culture.
Let's sing him
some greeting cards.
Air mail!
Have a rotten birthday!
Happy grouchness.
Yeah, get sick soon!
Happy sour 16.
Elmo doesn't know
how to read yet.
Oh, isn't that...
What's happening?
Oh no, it's Huxley again.
He'll take anything.
- What's going on?
- I'll take that.
Hey, you're taking
his greeting card.
Mmm, I'll take that.
Hey!
* Soggy Sandy was so wet
* That's why they
call her Soggy
* Watch her do her soggy dance
and after you'll get wet *
Hey little girl,
is that your new
Soggy Pants Sandy doll?
Yeah.
You're wrong.
Guess whose doll it is now?
Oh no!
He can't do that.
That's not nice!
Ahhh!
Put me down, you rotten Huxley.
Wow.
Ahhh!
Stop!
Oh, I bet that hurt.
Oh yeah.
Are you okay?
Did someone say stop?
All right, who said that?
Which one of you dares
to question my evil ways?
He did.
Elmo said it.
Hey boss,
he's the one who said it.
I heard him.
It's the cute little red guy.
He's the one questioning
your evil ways.
I know that, Bug.
It's not nice to take things
that don't belong to you.
He also says,
"It is not nice to take things
that do not belong to me."
Isn't that just precious?
Haha. Yeah.
Let me tell you
about something.
It all belongs to me.
If I touch it, I own it.
Bug!
You see this tennis racket?
I own it.
This hammer? I own it.
This velvet painting of Elvis?
I didn't really want it,
but I own it.
And this.
Elmo's blanket!
You're wrong. You see,
I didn't borrow this blanket.
I didn't rent this blanket.
I didn't even take out a
36-month lease
on this blanket.
I own it.
I think it's made
of all-natural fibers,
maybe 100% cotton.
Very lovely.
Bug, you really know
how to ruin a villainous
moment, don't you?
Now get in the cartoonishly
evil vehicle and drive.
Sir, yes sir!
No, wait, Blanket, Blanket!
You know, I would really love
to stay and chat,
but I have to get home
to take a nap with my
brand new wooby.
Woo!
Say, "Bye-bye, wooby."
Bye-bye.
It's a blanket!
- Wooby!
- Blanket!
Mine!
Blanket!
Wait!
Stop the movie, stop the movie!
What's the matter, Bert?
Ernie, did you see
what Huxley did?
- Yeah.
- He took Elmo's blanket.
Hold on, I can't look.
But don't worry, Bert.
It'll be okay,
right everybody?
Because we know Elmo won't
give up until he gets
his blanket back.
Roll film.
Let's watch, Bert.
Okay, Ernie,
but I can't see anything.
Bert, you still have your
hands over your eyes, Bert.
Oh. I knew that.
Sure you did, Bert. Come on.
Please, someone help Elmo,
please? Excuse Elmo...
Sir, can you please help Elmo
get his blanket back?
I'd love too,
but I don't speak English.
Can someone please help Elmo?
Excuse Elmo, that mean old
Huxley took Elmo's blanket.
That makes me feel
so bad inside.
Oh wait, I think
that's just gas.
No, please.
Now what is Elmo going to...
Hey, you're the girl
with that doll.
Shh, my name's Grizzy.
How come all the Grouches just
let that mean old Huxley guy
take everything?
Well, because the only way to
stop Huxley
is all the Grouches
would have to work together,
and Grouches hate that.
But Elmo has to get
his blanket back.
Shh, shh, okay, okay.
Look, maybe I can help you.
Follow me.
Okay.
Elmo? Elmo? Elmo? Elmo?
Sorry, Cookie.
Me having a bad cookie day.
Oh, me head!
Hey, everyone, hey!
What's going on?
Oscar said that Elmo is gone.
He probably went down into
Oscar's can for his blanket,
but instead of getting
the blanket, he got
sucked away
into some far-off and grouchy
place and he's
never going to...
Telly, easy Telly.
Oscar probably just meant that
Elmo went home, that's all.
No, actually
the worrywart's right.
What?
Say what?
Yep, Elmo got sucked down
through a door in my can
to Grouchland, USA.
Grouchland, USA?
- Where's that?
- This is terrible.
What are we going to do?
Here's what we're
going to do, Telly.
We're going to go down to
Grouchland, whatever that is,
and get Elmo back.
Yeah!
Well, all right,
but be careful.
I just had the rugs dirtied.
Oh joy, fruity goodness.
Come on, come on, Elmo.
Oh!
Come on, hustle, hustle.
- Are we there yet?
- Almost.
Hold your horses, kid.
Gee.
Well Elmo, there it is.
Greedy Huxley's house on
the top of Mount Pickanose.
That's where your blanket is,
all the way over there,
far, far away.
Well, Elmo has to get it back
by tonight.
Maybe you're not hearing me.
It's far, far away.
Oh, well that's okay, Grizzy.
Elmo's done harder stuff
than this before.
Like what?
Elmo learned to tie
his own shoes.
What are you, crazy?
If you go there, you might
never make it back home again.
Oh well, I think
I've helped enough.
Good luck to you, kid.
But Grizzy...
Elmo's going to make it,
you'll see.
Elmo's going to get to that
Huxley's house
and get his blanket back.
Is Elmo kidding?
Grizzy is right.
Elmo will never get there.
I'm stuck, I'm stuck.
Okay, here we go, Telly.
One, two, three, push.
Thank you.
We're coming, Elmo.
That place is so far, far away.
You'll never get there, huh?
Who's talking to Elmo?
Oh, just a little green plant.
Me! Hahaha.
How come nobody ever
thinks their shrubbery got
something to say, huh?
But I do because I know
exactly how you feel.
- You do?
- I do.
You feel like you're stuck.
Yeah.
Well, at least you've got
your legs. Am I right?
- Yeah.
- Well then,
all you've got to do
is take the first step.
Now lend me your ear.
* Elmo, get your chin up
Things could be worse
* You could have your feet
stuck down in the earth
* I don't see no roots growing
from your toes
* Just two furry little feet
And they're revving, revving
* Revving to go
* And soon you will see how
brave your heart can be
* Look on up to the sky
* Take that first step
and kiss your fears goodbye *
Now get up there, my little
red muppet,
and take that step.
That's it. Now look at that,
look at that.
I knew he could do it. Yeah!
Wow.
* Destiny is calling,
so listen up, please
* You can feel the rhythm down
deep in your knees
* One foot, then the other,
your journey has begun
* Elmo, believe it, you're
ready, ready, ready to run
* Take that first step
* Soon you will see
how brave your heart can be
* Look on up to the sky
* Take that first step
and kiss your fears goodbye *
Look at that. There he goes.
Hey, I knew he could
do it, yeah!
Look at him go.
That's it, that's it,
just keep on going.
Take another step.
* Take the first step
* Soon you will see just how
brave your heart can be
* Look on up to the sky
Take that first step
* Elmo, we believe in you
Take the first step *
You better watch out,
Mr. Huxley.
Elmo's coming
to get his blanket.
Oh, that's rich.
He's little and he's coming
to get his blanket.
Excuse me, boss.
Didn't you hear
the little guy?
He's taking his first step.
Shouldn't we do something?
Well, normally I wouldn't,
but I am feeling a bit
saucy today, huh?
A little parmesan.
Perhaps I should toy
with the little red monster.
But how?
No, let me think, let me think.
Wow, his eyebrows are huge.
Those aren't eyebrows.
That's my aunt and uncle.
Maybe if I look at it this way.
I know. I think it's time for
Elmo to take a little trip
to the tunnel, if you know
what I mean.
Yeah?
What'd you say, boss?
Bug, what are you doing?
Just having a little snack.
Hard to do your evil bidding
on an empty stomach.
Oh, sure. Listen, Bug.
Listen good.
Are you listening?
Get back to work!
That was a wild ride.
Wow, so this is
Grouchland, huh?
Yeah, land of 1,000 stenches.
Yeah, and I think I can smell
a number of them right now.
Look who it is.
- It's Oscar.
- Oscar?
You look like a million yucks.
- Yeah, go away.
- Get out.
Take your friends with you.
Who says you can't
go home again?
Oscar, maybe you can get
your friends to tell us
where Elmo is.
In a minute.
First, I have to look at
the old neighborhood here.
Hey, I wonder where
that old septic tank is.
Oscar, we've got to
find Elmo first.
Elmo? Elmo?
Have you seen Elmo?
Stop bothering us. First,
the little red guy, now you.
Oh look, there's
a police officer.
Yeah, let's ask him for help.
It's against the law to
ask for help in Grouchland.
You have the right to scream
your head off.
Should you give up the
right to scream your head off,
someone who screams their head
off will be provided for you.
Me innocent!
Hello, me needs cookie!
Okay, Sydney, Little Ricky,
Howard.
- Present.
- Listen.
I'm going to get the
trap door ready.
You turn the arrow on the sign
so it points in the tunnel.
- Got it.
- Ready?
Break!
Howard? Howard? Howard!
Coming.
Oh, man. Oh, ow, ow.
Your tushie bone
is crushing my skull.
Here he comes. Everybody hide!
Oh, hmm.
Oh well, this must be the way.
Is he in yet?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Wow, a tunnel, cool!
Whoa, it sure is dark in here.
A little help.
Dark and dirty and dusty.
The boss is going to be
so proud of us.
Are you guys still here?
Elmo can't see you.
If you're still here,
yell Elmo.
Elmo!
What?
Are you saying something?
Elmo still can't hear you.
Please yell louder.
Elmo!
Elmo heard you that time.
Hey, Elmo's glad
you're still here.
Elmo needs some lights.
Wow, fireflies.
Hello, fireflies.
Oh fireflies,
can you help Elmo?
Can you help Elmo
get out of here?
Wow, thank you, fireflies.
Oh, nice hat.
Whee, this is fun.
Whee!
Uh oh.
Oh yay! Thank you, fireflies.
Don't worry, Blanket.
Elmo will be there soon.
Impossible. He's still coming?
I'm walking.
The boss is walking,
the boss is walking.
Ow, hot rocks, thorny rocks.
Should've worn shoes.
The boss is walking.
Ahhh!
Baloney sandwich again?
Get back to work!
Why is that little red furball
so determined
to get this blanket?
Maybe because it's so
devastatingly cuddly.
What do you think you're doing?
Just hugging Elmo's blanket.
Whose blanket?
I mean your blanket.
Hahaha. That's right,
my blanket.
And I'm the only one
who can hold it.
Oh, hey tissue, maybe you
can be my blanket.
What do you think you're doing?
Just... Just holding
this tissue, boss.
Whose tissue?
Your tissue, boss.
That's right. Mine.
Come here, Bug.
It belongs to me.
* The issue at hand
is the tissue at hand
* And I wish you would hand,
or I'll squish you at hand
* The tissue at hand
to the man who can prove
* He can be the most
deserving he
* That's me, me, me, me, me
* Me, me, me, me, me
* Me, me, me, me, me,
me, me, me, me *
Thank you, Bug.
Oh, I want that.
Bug, give me that lollipop.
That's mine.
* Look at all I got,
this lamp, this yacht
* But what makes having fun
is knowing you have none *
Come on, Bug.
* Some may call it greed
It's not, it's need
* A need I love to feed,
the need to have a lot
* I give my all
to all I see, see?
* And all I see I give to me
Take it, boss.
* I see it, take it,
then I make it mine
* My little stamper adds
a pinch of perfection
* On every middle
is my little sign
* I ache to make it mine
* He sees it, takes it,
then he makes it mine *
I truly care.
* His little stamper adds
a pinch of perfection *
I give and give.
* On every middle is his
little sign
* He aches, he aches
to make it mine *
Oh, my favorite teddy bear.
My yo-yo. I love my yo-yo.
* Something old, something new
* Something borrowed,
something blue
* Things that once
belonged to you
* Like this plastic telephone
* I love this highway
traffic cone
* This wedding cake
for Joan and Jake
* this rake,
this giant rubber snake
* This Chippendale,
don't let it break *
Oops, it's true, love is a
many-splintered thing.
* He sees it,
takes it, then he
makes it mine *
You better believe it.
* Oh, what an honor
to be in his collection *
It's such an honor.
* It's like a number
that you can't define *
An offer you can't refuse.
* He aches, he aches
to make it mine
* You say you love
your old Atari
* I love it more
He loves it more
* You say you love
your new Ferrari *
Mine!
* I love it more
He loves it more
* Look at me, I'm on safari
* Things I want, my only quarry
* I love what is yours
far more than you
* And if love means never
having to say you're sorry
* Well, I never do
The lights, somebody turn off
the lights!
* I see it, take it,
then I make it mine
* I snap a valentine,
a sign of affection
* Four little letters
make a word so fine
* I ache to make it...
* I see it, take it,
then I make it mine
* I give a stamp that says
goodbye to neglection
* I've got an offer
that you can't decline
* When it broke,
disappeared, they're not lost,
they're all here
* The things you cannot find
because they've been
left behind
* Got them locked up in a box
with a million missing socks
* Everything I've got here
I long to make it mine *
Here's your drink, boss.
Oh, thank you.
So did you think of a plan
to stop that Elmo pest yet?
Not yet, boss. I was too busy
listening to you sing.
You've got a lovely
singing voice.
Oh yes.
Why, thank you.
I always fancied myself
a singer.
I almost performed in
the bus and truck tour
of West Side Story.
They said I wasn't
right for Maria.
What do they know?
- I feel pretty.
- Oh, very pretty.
Very pretty.
You should take a weed whacker
to those eyebrows.
What'd I say?
Anyway, I digress.
Right now, I need you
to take care
of my new arch-enemy, Elmo.
- Elmo.
- Elmo?
Maybe you should arrange
a little introduction for him
to the Queen of Trash.
Queen of Trash?
But nobody ever
escapes her dump.
Stop the movie,
stop the movie.
Ernie, Ernie, Ernie!
- What's the matter now, Bert?
- It's just not good.
Huxley's being mean to Elmo.
It's just not fair.
Why would anybody be
so mean to our little Elmo?
Well, gee Bert, maybe
Huxley just hasn't learned
how to share yet.
Well Ernie, do you think
he ever will?
Maybe, Bert. I sure hope
that he does, don't you?
Now come on,
Bert. Let's go find out what
happens to Elmo.
Okay, good, great.
Ernie? Problem.
This way, Bert.
Oh boy.
Elmo didn't know it
would take this long
to get his blanket back.
Oh!
Excuse Elmo.
Excuse Elmo!
Sorry, Mac, this whole area is
closed for construction.
- Huh?
- Yeah.
Bring it in, boys.
Slow, slow, slow.
What's going on?
Slow, slow, slow, slow, slow.
Stop.
Nice work, Charlie!
Thank you.
You see, we're putting in
a new Tarbucks
because there
just ain't enough
of those places around
when you want a nice latte.
But Elmo has to go that way to
get to Huxley's house.
Hey, look, you're making me
fall behind in my work here.
But you look like a good kid,
so I'll tell you
which way to go.
- Follow me.
- Okay.
In order to get to Huxley's,
you've got to
go down the path,
through the dump over there.
Really? Thank you very much
for your help.
You're very nice.
Nice? You think I'm nice?
Yeah, very nice. Thank you.
You're welcome.
He hugged me.
Ice cream, anchovy swirls
right here, ice cream.
- I'll take one.
- Okay.
Hey, where's my topping?
Oh, right.
That's disgusting.
And delicious.
No problem. Have a rotten day.
Ice cream, anchovy swirl
ice cream.
Oh, ice cream. Anchovy swirl?
How I long for a lick.
Oh, Oscar, get over it.
We've got to think about Elmo.
Cookie.
This is hopeless.
Maybe this'll cheer you up.
* A, B, C, D...
No, let me out of here.
It's torture!
Let us out, please.
That's it, that's it.
I can't take it anymore.
I demand justice.
I want a lawyer.
Call the media.
Start a defense...
Calm down, Telly.
Let me get you some water.
Hey, can we get
some water in here?
Thanks.
I didn't get any.
Thank you.
Whoa, this shortcut
is very long.
Very smoky.
Ahhh!
Halt! You are trespassing
on soiled ground.
Yeah.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Elmo has to get
to Huxley's house.
Oh, no way, Bucko.
You're going to see our queen.
Queen?
Oh yeah, and this is
her kingdom.
Oh, kingdom.
Kingdom? This looks like junk.
You said the "J" word.
You'll find out
the difference between
what's junk
and what's beautiful.
What's that?
What's going on?
Who is that?
* Listen up because this
is all I have to say
* This could be the thing
to get you on your way
* Just imagine what is old
is new again
* Maybe then you'll understand
* I dare you, take
a look around and tell me
that you don't see
* Just a worthless pile
of garbage and debris
* I see a kingdom,
shining bright
* I can see the colors
coming through, yeah
* You'll find the beauty if
you look at something right
* It's all about your point
of view
* In life, it's all about
your point of view *
Yeah, you go, girl!
* Everywhere you look
a story can be told
* And the tales they tell are
worth their weight in gold *
Hey, hey, that's very
inappropriate! Settle down.
Sorry.
* Rotting castaways,
and broken bits of glass
* I dare you, take a look
around and tell me that
you don't see *
Watch this part.
This is good.
* Just a worthless pile
of garbage and debris
* Because I see a kingdom
shining bright
* And if you try,
then you can see it too, yeah
* You'll see the beauty if you
look at something right
* It's all about your
point of view
* In ife, it's all about
your point of view *
It's our turn.
Come on.
Okay, let's go.
* I see a kingdom
shining bright
* I can see the colors
coming through
* You'll find
the beauty if you
look at something right
* It's all about your
point of view
* In life, it's all about
your point of view
* Your point of view,
your point of view *
Where do you think
you're going? Stay right here.
So who is this
who trashed my dump?
This is him, your majesty.
He's a trespasser.
Yeah.
No, no. Elmo's not
a trespasser, Miss Queen.
Silence, trespasser.
He says he's on his way
to Huxley's.
Huxley's, eh?
Yeah, and maybe,
maybe he's a Huxley spy.
Elmo's not a spy. Elmo just
wants to get his blanket back
from Huxley because it's mine.
Well, you certainly sound
like Huxley.
No, Elmo doesn't.
Elmo's not like Huxley.
No, no, it's Elmo's blanket.
It's mine, mine, mine, mine.
He says he's not like Huxley.
Make him prove it,
your highness.
Yeah, prove it.
- Yeah, prove it.
- Well, I think it's time
for the ultimate challenge.
Oh, goody, goody!
What's the ultimate challenge?
You have to give me something.
You see, Huxley could
never give anyone anything.
That's true.
Now if you're able to give,
then you pass
the ultimate challenge
and are free to go.
What does Elmo have to give?
Well, you have to give
her royal majesty,
and that would be me,
100 raspberries.
Ooh, the ultimate challenge.
Elmo doesn't have any fruit.
No, no, no. It's not fruit,
dear Elmo.
Like this, watch.
Oh, that sends shivers
down my spine.
Well, Elmo can do that.
Elmo knows how to make
that sound.
Good. Now I want you
to give me 100 raspberries
in 30 seconds.
Now let me go get
my raspberry counter.
- I'll get it, I'll get it.
- No, my turn. I want to get it.
30 seconds to do 100?
Well, that's why it's called
the ultimate challenge.
Ready, set, go.
- Oh no.
- Hurry, you're wasting time.
How can Elmo do this?
Oh wait, wait, wait.
Can you please help Elmo
do raspberries like this?
He's getting help.
Is that legal?
Come on. You can do it.
You're doing great.
He's never going to do it.
No way. Never been done.
We're doing it.
Oh, he's doing it.
Good, keep going.
You better move it,
you better move it.
90!
Oh, I love raspberries.
Wow!
We did it! Thank you.
Well, you did it.
- Yeah.
- Well, no one has ever
passed the ultimate challenge
before, and you did it.
-Well...
-He did it, he did it,
he did it.
Since I'm queen of my
word, you're free to go
and pursue the blanket
or bedcovering of your choice.
Thank you, Miss Queen.
And Elmo's sorry for calling
your dump junk.
It's very pretty.
Thank you.
- Bye-bye.
- Bye-bye, Elmo.
- Goodbye, Elmo.
- I'm going to miss him.
Bye-bye.
* It's all about your
point of view
* In life, it's all about
your point of view *
Go, team, go.
Go, team, go. Go, team, go.
Excuse me, boss.
Don't you want to play?
This usually takes two.
Eh, why should I play when you
can do it for me?
Besides, I think I'm winning.
- Huh?
- Yay!
I told you.
This time I'm keeping it!
Hey, Bug.
That was the last ball.
Hey, let's try boxing.
Oh no.
Aha!
Come on, let me see you
do your stuff, Bug.
Come on, give me a
right, come on!
Oh, that little red bathmat.
Bug, Bug, Bug!
Stop playing games.
Come look at this.
Huh? Wow.
Would you look at that?
Boy, that Elmo's
something, huh?
What guts, what spunk,
what chutzpah.
Bug? You are really beginning
to bug me.
Probably because I'm a bug.
What is it with this blanket?
That's it. It's time
to take care
of that little red fuzz wad
once and for all.
Oh no. No, no, no.
Out of my way. It is time
to release the secret weapon.
No, boss, anything but that.
You can't do it
to the little guy.
Oh really?
Well, I've had enough toying
with that little red lintball.
Just watch.
Hello, Tiny.
Come on, rise and shine.
We have work to do.
Yes, we do.
Elmo, you'll make it.
Just be strong, little guy.
* I see a kingdom...
What's that?
It's getting closer.
Chicken!
Elmo's not afraid
of a little chicken.
Why should Elmo be afraid
of a little chicken?
That's why.
Yikes!
Hey, you dinner, stop running
away from me.
I'm trying to eat you.
Leave Elmo alone.
Elmo doesn't want to be eaten.
Will you stop jumping around
so much? You're going
to make me gassy.
Leave Elmo alone!
You see what I mean?
Now stand still
like a piece of corn.
Hey, this is not
how eating works.
You stay still
and then I sneak
up on you and then I eat you.
So come on, I'm ready for
a nice, juicy worm like you.
No! Wait, wait,
Elmo's not a worm.
Excuse me, I'm not stupid.
- Elmo knows you're not stupid.
- Good.
But worms aren't red, are they?
Oh, well sometimes...
Well, no.
- Well, couldn't they be?
- No, no, no.
Worms aren't fuzzy.
Well yes, but if...
Will you just be quiet
so I can eat you?
Wait! Worms can't do this.
* Elmo's a little teapot
short and stout
* Here is his handle,
here is his spout
* When you tip me over...
Hey, wait a minute,
you're not a worm.
That's what Elmo was trying
to tell you.
You're a teapot.
I can't have tea.
I haven't had my din-din yet.
Ahhh!
Well, not quite
what I had in mind,
but effective nonetheless.
This is not fun.
Ow!
Oh no.
Are you guys
still here with Elmo?
Yeah.
Oh, good. Elmo feels a lot
better with you here,
but Elmo still misses
his blanket.
Wait, wait, wait,
stop the movie again.
- Ernie, Ernie!
- What now, Bert?
Well, Ernie, this is terrible.
Elmo didn't get
his blanket back.
How can it end this way?
- It's so sad.
- Oh, no, no.
Bert, Bert, Bert,
no, Bert, listen.
- Don't Bert me.
- No, it's okay, Bert.
The movie's not over yet.
Oh, you mean good things
could still happen?
Of course they can, Bert.
In fact,
I'm sure good things
will happen
because who'd want
to see a movie with
a sad ending, Bert?
- Titanic.
- What?
- Titanic had a sad ending.
- No, Bert.
Roll the film.
Come on, Bert. Come on.
- Gone With The Wind.
- No, Bert, No.
- Doctor Zhivago.
- Shh, quiet, Bert.
Chocolate covered fish cakes.
Hey you, Tangerine.
Maria? There's a Grouch.
No, no, no, wait.
I really want to help.
Well, who are you?
All right, all right,
all right.
I'm Elmo's friend, Grizzy.
Now wait, shh!
Don't let it get around
that I'm helping Elmo.
So where is he?
He went to Huxley's.
What, Huxley? First this guy
ruined my
beautiful Grouchland,
and now he's messing with my...
Oscar, were you going
to say friend?
No, I was going to say
french-fried fish heads.
Right, sure.
All right, so the little
stinkball is my friend.
I've got to go do something
about this.
Hey, listen up, you
Grouch-potatoes.
Come on over here.
Listen to me.
Why should we listen to you?
You're going to get
my ugly rash.
Go soak your head.
You call yourselves Grouches.
Look at you.
This Huxley character's
taken everything that makes
Grouchland so disgusting,
and you're not doing
anything about it.
We've got to fight
for our trash,
stand up for our slop
because when they take our goo,
we've got to do.
Yeah, that's right.
We've got to do.
When they take our goo,
we've got to do.
I love goo.
When they take our goo,
we've got to do.
Hey you, get up.
You're in my spot.
Get out of my spot now.
Huh? Elmo's sorry.
Oh hey, don't cry.
I can get a new spot.
Elmo's not sad about that.
Oh. Well, what then, huh?
Come on, my friend,
tell me what's wrong.
Elmo didn't get
his blanket back.
Elmo can't do anything.
Elmo's just a little monster.
Little? Hey, look at me, huh?
I'm just a little, tiny
caterpillar, right?
- Yeah.
- Wrong.
One day, I'm going to be
a butterfly.
- You are?
- Oh yeah, yeah.
I'm going to change
into a beautiful butterfly.
Yeah, I will because
I have what it takes
right here, inside.
You know what, kid? So do you.
You proved it by
getting this far.
Just look inside.
Yeah, you're right. Inside.
Elmo can do it.
Elmo can get to Huxley's house.
Yeah, I knew you could, kid.
Thank you, Mr. Caterpillar,
thank you.
Don't worry Blanket,
Elmo's coming!
Go ahead, eat it.
Don't you
think he'd mind?
-Eh, he wouldn't mind.
-Hey, that bacon's
for the boss.
And besides, Howard,
your cholesterol level's
way too high.
Hey.
- Morning, boss.
- Morning, Bug.
I made you some poached eggs,
I pressed your favorite
pair of slacks,
the ones that make you
look thin and villainous,
and I brewed you some coffee.
Anything about me in the paper?
Check page six.
What's it say?
You know I can't read.
It says you're a greedy,
no-good...
I mean, a lovely man.
Hahaha.
Thank you, Bug.
It's a wonderful day.
My sun is shining,
my birds are chirping,
and my humongous chicken
has defeated Elmo.
No!
Yes! And the wooby is mine
for keepsies.
The wooby is mine for
keepsies, the wooby is
mine for keepsies,
the wooby is
for keepsies, for keepsies.
Give me those.
The wooby is mine
for keepsies.
The wooby is mine for keepsies.
Poor little Elmo.
Somebody can't see what's
so special about this
stupid blanket.
Why didn't he just get
a different one?
Maybe he loved that blanket.
Aw, maybe he loved
that blanket. Maybe he loved
that blanket.
You don't know
what you're talking about.
Blanket!
Elmo wants his blanket
back now!
The little piece
of macrame lives.
Blanket!
Pesties, pesties!
Don't let him escape with my
wooby!
Dirty rascal!
We'll get him, boss.
Um, boss?
Oh boy. What are you doing?
Too high, too high, too high.
Hey, you let Elmo
and his blanket go!
I don't think so. You
and your blanket
are both mine now.
- No! No!
- Yes!
- No! No! No!
- Yes! Yes!
Stop right there,
you mean old Huxley.
Zoe?
Yeah, come on.
Elmo, are you okay?
Ah, you do have friends, huh?
And don't they look sweet.
I bet you all just have
a grand old time together,
just saying the alphabet
and counting all day long.
- Yeah.
- Hahahaha.
It's over, Huxley.
Get him.
Huxley don't pay me
enough for this.
What do you mean pay?
I want my mommy!
Grouches cooperating?
How are you going to get out
of this one, Huxley?
- I've got a plan.
- Oh yeah? What?
I don't know, I haven't
figured it out yet.
Not real villainous, is it?
They may save you,
you annoying red monster,
but they can't save your wooby!
No, no, no!
That's not a wooby!
That's Elmo's blanket!
Be careful!
That's it.
Wait, wait,
wait a minute.
Wait, wait, wait!
Where's Elmo's blanket?
No, Blanket!
Haha, that's my Bug.
Give me back my wooby!
No, boss. You're nothing
but a basket case.
What?
This blanket belongs to Elmo.
Blanket.
Thank you, Bug.
You're welcome, Elmo.
How could you do this to me?
I thought we were friends.
No, you're a greedy,
selfish villain,
and nobody likes to be
friends with a greedy,
selfish villain.
Come on, Bug. Be a bug, huh?
I mean, just be a bug
just for a second.
Give me another chance.
Let me give everything back.
I'll give back all the yo-yo's
and all the rollerblades
and all those bicycles
and all the kids' toys,
all the dolls, everything.
I'll give it all back.
- No.
- Bug, Bug,
I'll give back every
single teddy bear.
I'll give back the sun
and the moon
and the earth and the stars.
Less talking, more giving.
You're tired. You're not
in your right frame of mind.
This isn't when you make
an important decision, Bug.
Bug, Bug, listen to me...
Oh, Blanket.
Oh, thanks for helping,
everybody.
Elmo sure is
lucky to have friends
like you.
We're really proud
of you, Elmo.
Yeah, way to go, Elmo.
You're one brave
little monster.
Oh, thanks, Big Bird.
Let's hear it for Elmo!
Let's go back to Sesame Street.
I know a shortcut.
Ready, guys?
Let's go, Blanket! Yay!
Zoe, Elmo's sorry
for hurting your feelings.
Can we still be friends?
Well... Yeah.
Friends forever.
Yeah.
Wow, I can hold it?
Sure. What could happen?
* Together forever,
the world seems fine
* We never would ever
leave you behind
* Together forever,
the world seems fine
* We never would ever
leave you behind *
Elmo just wanted to say
thanks for helping.
Elmo couldn't have
done it without you.
Elmo love you.
Bye-bye.
* Together forever,
the world seems fine
* We never would ever
leave you behind *
See, Bert?
Just like I told you,
Elmo got his blanket back.
Yeah, a happy ending.
Yep, and thank you all
for helping.
Oh yeah, yeah.
You deserve a big
round of applause.
Oh yeah, everybody clap for
yourselves. Come on, come on.
Okay Bert, time to go home.
Yeah, I knew everything was
going to be okay.
-Sure you did.
-I knew Elmo would get his
blanket back.
-Yeah, right.
-I knew there'd be
a happy ending.
- Of course, Bert.
- See ya!
Oh, look, look,
look, look!
Ernie, credits!
Oh, I want to see
who did the catering.
Yeah, that was really
good toast.
You know, they cut off
the crusts and everything.
Bert?
Time to feed your pigeons.
Oh, thank you. Bernice?
Bye-bye.