Previously on "The Good Doctor"...
I'm your neighbor.
I'm in the middle of "Uncharted," And I'm dead.
Can I borrow some triple A's?
It's kind of silly, isn't it?
Our relationship... that we're hiding it.
We don't have a relationship.
We have sex.
- You're late. - No, the bus was late.
I did nothing wrong. The bus...
Yeah. This is gonna work out great.
So you're treating him like anybody else?
You have any idea how many patients he's scared the crap out of today?
So teach him.
I'm teaching you both that he doesn't belong.
I hear you got Shaun off scut and back into surgery.
You figure you'll give him a little authority,
he'll screw something up.
Either way, if he succeeds,
I'm the guy who just backed him.
And if he fails, I'm the president.
Hello. I've looked everywhere.
All right, I'm here now. We'll...
we'll just keep looking until you find it.
Why is the furniture in the middle of the room?
I know I packed it. I made a list.
"Star-tip screwdriver."
Look, it's checked.
It's checked.
Maybe you... you threw it out with the newspapers
you used to pack the dishes?
I packed with bubble wrap.
It's safer. And you can see through it.
Of course you did.
Shaun, there's a hardware store up the road.
You can buy a new one.
I don't want a new screwdriver!
I want my screwdriver!
Stop it!
It's the middle of the... I'm sorry.
I just shouldn't have yelled. J-Just...
Let's just take a moment. Sit down, please.
You know what? We can use this for now, okay?
I can't stay here.
Of course you can.
- It'll be fine. - I can't stay here.
The...dishwasher doesn't dry,
the shower drain has someone else's hair in it.
And the crisper drawer keeps coming off the track?
I assume that's what you were fixing.
I forgot.
Of course you forgot.
It's understandable.
You've been working your ass off.
You're exhausted. You're under a lot of stress.
There's a super in the building.
You can call him anytime.
Just make a list of the things you need repaired.
Later, Shaun. Later.
Later, Shaun!
Leave it now. Go to bed.
36 years old, 22 weeks pregnant.
Ultrasound at 16 weeks revealed a tumor on the fetus' tailbone.
Mom's got antiphospholipid syndrome.
Makes surgery high risk.
Also makes pregnancy high risk.
She's had three miscarriages.
We need to do an ultrasound and MRI
to measure the tumor's growth rate.
Late bus doesn't explain why you're showing up tired
after you just had 12 hours off.
We're all tired.
Our last shift was 36 hours.
I'm not interested in debating the shift schedule with you.
But I am curious why you always feel the need to defend him.
Well, we're all on the same team.
Yes.
But you're all quarterbacks.
And when training camp is over,
there's only gonna be one starter.
The crown-rump length of the fetus is 21.5 centimeters.
The diameter of the tumor is...
10.6 centimeters.
Half the size of the fetus.
The tumor's grown.
It's not cancer, but it is monopolizing the blood supply,
which is weakening the fetus' heart.
I'm sorry, but there's no chance it would survive long enough to be viable.
The safest course is to terminate the pregnancy.
If we were interested in the "safest course,"
we wouldn't be on our third "second opinion."
Please, Dr. Melendez,
we want whatever will save our baby.
Dr. Wright told us you've done fetal surgery
to remove this type of tumor before.
And without the tumor, our baby would be healthy.
Your antiphospholipid syndrome
makes a long surgery extremely dangerous.
There's a high chance for blood clots,
which could have fatal consequences for you.
We're willing to take that risk.
Saving the fetus doesn't do any good if the mother dies in the process.
I've had three miscarriages.
If I have to go through that again, I might as well be dead.
- Barb. - It's true.
No, it's not.
You're the strongest woman I've ever met.
We'll get through this.
We will. And... and then we'll try again.
We could manage clotting risk pre-operatively
with an infusion of unfractionated heparin.
Never contradict me in front of a patient again.
I didn't.
I agree with your assessment of the risks.
I suggested a way we could mitigate them.
Not in front of the patient.
We're not in front of the patient now.
I was just reading about a new technique
for transesophageal echocardiography monitoring.
If there's a cardiac issue,
it would give us an early warning.
Let's get her prepped. ASAP.
I want J.L. on anesthesia.
And let the neo-natal nursing supervisor
know that I want to do a full run-through.
Damn it.
Yes?
Well, we're a little busy up here, too.
All right. I'll send someone.
Andrews is covering for Lim in the ER.
He has a patient who needs a boil lanced.
A plastic surgeon can't lance a boil?
Plastic surgeons can. Chief surgeons don't.
You and Murphy.
What?
It was our ideas that convinced you to do the fetal surgery,
and now you're punishing us with Andrews' scut work?
You're not getting punished.
He is.
For being late. Again.
But I don't trust him alone with a patient.
And since you like to defend him
and seem to know how to communicate with him...
Hurry back.
Olivia Hartman?
Yes, ma'am.
I mean Doctor.
You're 18?
Yes, ma'am.
Where's the boil?
It's... It's down there.
Down where?
Shaun. It's, um, on her labia.
Is it painful?
Like I used a bowling ball for a tampon.
Okay. Boils shouldn't hurt that much.
Okay if we take a look?
Okay.
If you just scoot down,
put your feet in the stirrups...
Great.
The swelling is fairly localized.
Extreme pain that's out of proportion to the visible injury
could mean you have necrotizing flesh-eating bacteria.
What?!
I'm gonna use the heparin pre-operatively
and a T.E.E. monitor.
Still not enough.
The risk of a heart attack or stroke was thoroughly explained.
The patient still wants the surgery.
She wants it? Or you want it?
Yes,
saving a fetus' life would be good news for me.
Any other questions?
Or insults?
Relax. I'm not insulting you.
Of course you want to do the surgery.
But you do surgeries like this,
some patients are going to die.
And then our department's success rate goes down,
and then our funding goes down,
and then you can't do surgeries like this.
So if your judgment is clouded in any way, just --
It's not.
Okay.
I'm sorry. I know this hurts,
but I really do need to insert a speculum for this part of the exam.
If I really have what he says,
does that mean you have to cut off my --
No. No, as I said,
the abscess is most likely the result of an untreated chlamydia infection.
We'll drain the abscess,
give you antibiotics.
You'll be fine.
I'm -- I'm sorry.
The inflamed Bartholin gland is causing the ischiocavernosus muscle
to spasm and pinch the labial nerve.
You need to start with a more upward angle.
Can I try?
I think it's better if I do this.
Yeah, okay. Fine.
Can we, uh, call your parents? Let them know --
No.
I'm 18. I'm an adult.
Even adults need emotional support.
Someone to drive them home after surgery.
Uh, I'm gonna take a taxi.
I have money.
There's nothing to be embarrassed about.
25% of college students contract an STD before graduation.
I'm not embarrassed.
And I know all about STDs.
I get tested every 30 days.
There's no necrosis on the vaginal wall or cervix.
You got it in already?
Yes. It's definitely not flesh-eating bacteria.
- I was wrong. - Thank God.
You do need surgery to drain the Bartholin gland abscess.
Why do you get an STD test every 30 days?
I have to. For work.
I do porn.
The umbilical is 19 inches,
which will allow us to remove the fetus via Caesarean
and rest it in its mother's lap while I excise the tumor.
Now, the hard part
will be reinserting the fetus afterwards.
We can't overstretch the uterine wall,
and we must be certain that every suture is tight enough
to handle four more months of kicks and thrown elbows.
Do you have a minute?
Can it wait?
No.
I don't want to do it.
Have you talked to your wife?
Yes, but she's not thinking rationally.
You heard her say she'd rather die than lose this baby.
I'm sorry, but husbands don't have veto power
over their wife's medical decisions.
A husband can't stop you from operating on his wife.
But a father can stop you from operating on his child.
What kind of porn?
I'm sorry.
I was too busy doing all the labs and imaging she needed for surgery.
I forgot to ask for her résumé.
I just mean, is she an actual actress,
like in stuff with a story, or...
Do they even make porn with stories anymore?
Sometimes.
You watch porn?
Why wouldn't he?
I don't know. He just seems...
He's a guy. All guys watch porn.
You finished with Andrews' patient?
No. It wasn't a boil.
It's a large Bartholin gland abscess that's pressing on her pudendal nerve.
Which apparently does interest a chief surgeon.
We're gonna assist Andrews when he drains it first thing in the morning.
We just thought we'd check with you.
Go home. And sleep.
Not play video games or whatever it is keeping you up.
I don't think it's video games.
You can head out, too. It's been a long day.
- But what about... - Fetal surgery's been put on hold.
What? Why?
Go home.
Once the fetus is removed from the uterus,
one could argue that it becomes a child.
That's ridiculous.
There are numerous legal precedents...
That guarantee the mother's right to choose.
It's her body. It's her control.
I'm completely comfortable going ahead with this surgery.
As am I.
I never was, and I certainly am not now.
I'm sorry. Until we're certain there is no liability
connected to parental consent, neither am I.
Well, the one thing I think we can all agree on
is that the mother has the power to do nothing.
And if she doesn't terminate
or have the surgery to remove the tumor...
A fetus with a massive tumor will die...
inside a patient with APS.
Then the mother would die, too, right?
So we do nothing, and they both die.
Or we can do something that's legally and ethically complicated,
and maybe they both live.
The board has approved the surgery.
Thank you.
- Barb, please... - Mark, stop.
- If you loved me... - No.
- No, do not say that. - No, it's true.
If you really loved me...
I'm trying to protect you because I love you.
I don't need your protection.
I need your support.
We'll start prepping you first thing in the morning.
Try and get some sleep.
Thank you.
I still can't believe it.
That 18-year-old college students do porn?
She's just not the type.
How do you know what "type" she is? You just met her.
Did one medical history and pelvic exam.
What?
Nothing.
No, go ahead.
Tell me all the reasons why I'm wrong.
I volunteered at a shelter for runaway teens when I was at high school.
Got to know a lot of sex workers.
They're not all the same, but they do have the same...
armor.
I don't believe it.
- You think I'm lying? - No.
No, I think you just opened up to me,
actually shared something personal.
It was high-school community service. It's not a big deal.
Oh, no, it's a big deal. This is huge.
- I am peeling the onion. - Shut up.
Actually, it's more like hacking through a coconut with a dull machete, but...
"Dull" is right. Very dull.
It feels good, doesn't it?
You should do it more often.
How about you stop worrying about what I won't do
and just enjoy what I will?
Do you think she's of sound mind?
You really want to talk about work right now?
She's basically threatening to commit suicide.
She's not suicidal.
She's... She's just desperate to have a child.
This is probably her last chance.
She could adopt.
- It's not the same. - Really?
You don't think there's a difference?
No, I don't.
Carrying a fetus in your body for nine months.
You don't think that creates a unique relationship?
I think every relationship is unique.
Yeah, of course.
What are you saying?
I just think it's selfish.
I mean, for her to go through so much,
to put your husband through so much,
just so you can have a certain experience
when there are other ways.
Yeah, okay.
But...you want children, though, right?
We've talked about this before.
Yes, I-I want children.
But our children.
Like, from you getting pregnant.
Yes.
But what if that doesn't happen?
What if I couldn't get pregnant
or if I decided that I didn't want to?
That I wanted to adopt instead?
Is there something you're not telling me?
Actually, there is.
When we're in meetings together,
don't ever call my ideas "ridiculous."
Come on, I'm being serious.
So am I.
You're right. I'm sorry.
It won't happen again.
Geez, you scared me.
- What're you reading? - Nothing.
- Can I read it? - No.
- Why? - Because.
Why?
Because.
Because there's nothing to read.
Just pictures.
Where'd you get this?
Colleen Myers.
Her dad has so many in his closet,
he doesn't even notice when she takes a few.
She's pretty.
She sure is.
It's bedtime. That means lights out.
I missed my stop.
I missed my stop!
Lynwood Place!
I need to get off at Lynwood Place.
Well, then you should've been paying attention
when I stopped at Lynwood Place.
Next stop's gonna be even further away,
so if I were you...
Shaun?
Are you okay?
Yes.
Are you waiting for someone?
No.
I'm horrible at directions, too.
Every time I exit a BART station,
I walk like three blocks before I realize
I'm going the wrong direction.
You're lucky I actually made it to the gym.
I like to go when it's not crowded,
but it's so hard to motivate after work.
Half the time I end up not...
You stink.
I know. I'm disgusting.
But I can't shower there.
I'm terrified of foot fungus.
Hey, you know, as long as we're tossing out truth grenades,
you suck at being a neighbor.
First, you take back your batteries,
and then you wake me up in the middle of the night
stomping around and banging on pipes.
What the hell's up with that?
My sink drips.
I couldn't sleep, so I tried to fix it.
Then I couldn't find my screwdriver, which made me anxious.
You kept me up because you were anxious about a screwdriver?
Yes. I was very anxious.
You're funny.
I stink. You're anxious.
You always say exactly what's on your mind.
It's the total opposite of most guys.
It's nice.
Good night.
And don't go fixing any faucets tonight.
That's Armen's job.
This is a list of repairs I need for my apartment.
Number 33.
What the hell is your problem?
Sorry. Hello.
My name is Shaun Murphy. It's very nice to meet you.
No, it's not nice to meet me at 12:40 a.m.
Yes.
Dr. Glassman said I can call you any time I need something fixed.
Who the hell is Dr. Glassman?
He's the president at San Jose St. Bonaventure Hospital.
I'm a surgical resident there.
Well, I don't care if you're St. Bonaventure himself.
Unless it's a fire or flood,
I only work 9:00 to 5:00.
I'll...
try and come back tomorrow between those times.
You already woke me up. Just give me the damn list.
It's my fault.
I should've known you would take what I said literally.
It's okay.
Actually, you know what, Shaun?
It's not my fault.
It's your responsibility. You're smart.
You should be able to use your common sense.
When somebody says something,
you should figure out what they really mean.
And when things don't go exactly how you expected them,
navigate that.
There's a thing called a Personal Support Worker.
Think of it like a home health aide.
No, thank you.
I can take care of myself.
Everybody needs a little help now and then.
I-I'm thinking of asking them to give me one.
I've lived by myself a long time.
In Casper, Wyoming.
Everybody looked out for you in Casper.
Everybody looks out for everybody in Casper.
This is San Jose. It's a big city.
And residency is a whole lot more demanding than medical --
I don't need an aide.
We're just talking, Shaun.
- I don't need an aide! - Okay, okay.
- Okay. - Okay.
Okay.
We'll table it for some other time.
Let's enjoy our breakfast, okay?
Mr. Allen?
I'm trying to convince her to save herself.
I don't want to roll the dice with my wife's life.
But she does.
We're gonna start prepping her now,
and she goes into the O.R. in a few hours.
I understand why she's desperate.
But not why you are.
If she dies, it's your fault.
And what if she lives?
You're gonna have a wife and child who need you,
and you keep driving her out of your life.
I'm not desperate.
I'm confident.
Which should make you feel better.
Retraction.
I'll make the incision,
and then I want you to insert the Word catheter.
Good job on the pelvic exam, Dr. Murphy.
With all this swelling, it couldn't have been easy.
Thank you.
How do you know who...
Oh, I have my ways.
Like Santa.
I told him.
No presents for you.
Insert the drain.
But I'm curious.
How could a guy who can't even shake a co-worker's hand
be comfortable doing a pelvic exam?
People squeeze too hard. It hurts.
Send this to the lab for culture.
So, I'm guessing you're not that into hugs.
I don't like to be squeezed.
Well, what if it's somebody you like?
Or somebody you love?
Have you ever had a girlfriend?
I almost kissed a girl. Once.
Well, you know what they say --
If at first you don't succeed...
Are you trying to mock me or encourage me?
I'm trying to get to know you
so I know when I should mock and when I should encourage.
When's the right time to mock you?
Press harder on that abscess.
It should have drained by now.
Something's wrong.
The gland's evacuated, but the swelling's not going down.
Heart rate and BP are stable.
Can I get a little more light, please?
- Damn. - What is it?
The swelling isn't going down because there's a mass beneath the abscess.
And it's not just pressing on the pudendal nerve --
It's totally engulfed it.
That's bad.
Very bad.
You're done already?
We were able to drain the abscess.
I already feel better.
That's only because of the pain meds.
The reason the pain was so severe
was because it wasn't just an abscess.
There's perineal myoma underneath.
What's that?
A fibroid tumor.
It's not cancerous, but it is wrapped around the nerve.
We need to remove the tumor,
but to do that, we will have to sever the nerve.
You'll lose all feeling in your genitals.
I'm so sorry.
I knew it.
God's punishing me.
No, absolutely not.
This is just a random growth...
You're religious?
Yes.
Or at least I used to be.
I haven't thought about God in a really long time.
But being in here...
You sure you don't want us to call your parents?
No. I couldn't bear to see the look on their faces.
Especially my dad's.
Well, that's what parents are for.
So you don't have to do these things alone.
Could you tell your father you're a whore?
You made a mistake. That is all.
- Patient vitals? - Stable.
- Fetus? - Stable.
Okay.
Is everybody ready?
Knife.
Retractor.
Okay.
Cutting into the uterus.
T.E.E. is showing anterior wall hypokinesis.
Systolic pressure 90. Get me a Swan.
I.V. function is decreasing. She's having a heart attack.
I need you to close the incision.
- On it. Needle driver. - Get a fluoroscope in here!
I'm gonna prep her for a balloon pump.
Barbara?
There was a complication during surgery.
A blood clot blocked an artery in your heart.
We were able to catch it in time.
And my baby?
The fetus is stable.
The M.I. happened before we opened the uterus.
So, we're right back where we started?
You just had a heart attack.
I don't care.
There is no other option now.
If we don't terminate and the fetus dies in utero,
the resulting clots will overwhelm your heart and brain.
Which is exactly why we need to try again.
What're you talking about?
You need to remove the tumor.
You begged me not to do the surgery before.
I thought I could talk her out of it then.
Now I know I can't.
Either you do it, or she dies.
Before, if we got sued,
we'd at least have one of them on our side,
but now, with them both aligned --
Can they sue us for not operating?
They could argue that we abandoned care.
We're still offering care.
Just not the care that they want.
Which is your fault.
If you hadn't offered her hope to begin with,
we might have been able to reason with her.
How's the pain around the incision?
5 out of 10.
I'll up the dosage.
Any chest pain?
No. My heart actually feels fine.
Good.
If she doesn't want to terminate, there's nothing we can do.
So we just send her home to die?
It is her decision.
We could tell her we were going ahead with the fetal surgery.
But once she's under --
I'm gonna pretend you never said that.
If it's the only chance to save her life --
This is exactly what I'm talking about.
You wouldn't lie to convince a suicidal person to climb down off the ledge?
Knowingly lying to a patient about a major medical surgery --
Okay, okay! Hey!
Lying to a patient is one thing.
Performing surgery without their consent --
It's unethical and illegal.
And insane.
I just...
I don't want to do this.
It's not our only option.
You want me to attempt the fetal surgery again?
If it's the only way to save her life.
The first time, it was the only way to save her life.
But a second heart attack one day after the first
- will kill her. - Maybe not.
I am so sorry to interrupt, but I...
I have an idea.
What if we kill her before she kills herself?
We'll stop your heart
and put you on a bypass machine for the duration of the surgery.
You can't have a heart attack
if your heart's not beating to begin with.
It takes the most significant danger off the table.
But aren't the clots a danger to her brain, as well?
This doesn't completely eliminate every risk,
but it does reduce the biggest one.
Thank you.
We'll do it first thing in the morning.
You fixed my sink!
Do you know how to tell time?
You're welcome. Now go away.
It was not on the list!
The faucet. It was not on the list.
You weren't supposed to touch it.
So after I fix everything you woke me up for,
then I go out of my way to fix something el--
It was not on the list because I'd already fixed it.
Well, you fixed it wrong.
Because it was still dripping.
I need it to drip.
At the same rate as my sink in Casper.
It was too slow before.
Now I have to fix it all over again.
It's not fair.
I'm done.
If you don't like your faucet
or anything else in your apartment? Move.
If you knock on this door again after 5:00 p.m.,
I'm gonna knock your teeth out.
BGM: Down In The Valley by The Head And The Heart
♪ I wish I was a slave to an age-old trade ♪
♪ Like ridin' around on railcars and workin' long days ♪
♪ Lord, have mercy on my rough and rowdy ways ♪
♪ Call it one drink too many ♪
♪ Call it pride of a man ♪
♪ But it don't make no difference ♪
♪ If you sit or you stand ♪
♪ 'Cause they both end in trouble and start with a grin ♪
♪ We do it over and over and over again ♪
♪ I am on my way ♪
♪ I am on my way back to where I started ♪
♪ California ♪
♪ Oklahoma ♪
♪ And all of the places I ain't ever been to ♪
♪ Down in the valley ♪
♪ With whiskey rivers ♪
♪ These are the places you will find me hidin' ♪
♪ These are the places I will always go ♪
♪ Theses are the places I will always go ♪
- Nerves are like pipes! - Shaun, th-- this --
We need to sever the pudendal nerve to excise the myoma,
but if we reconnect the ends...
The tumor is 4 centimeters in diameter.
That's way too wide of a gap to reconnect the ends,
and nerves don't stretch.
We don't need to stretch it.
We can connect the distal end of the pudendal nerve
to the branch of the femoral cutaneous nerve from her inner thigh.
Would you rather lose feeling in your thigh or genitals?
Thigh, definitely.
Is he right?
Can we do that?
It probably would've been better to discuss this prior
to meeting with the patient,
but, yes, I think it could work.
Cut the suture.
Grafted nerve's in place. Let's see if it will conduct.
Conduction electrodes are in position.
Send a pulse.
Again.
- Again. - Okay, Murphy, we get it.
Your idea worked.
Good job. Both of you.
- Thanks. - Thank you.
I'm guessing Melendez doesn't let you know this enough,
but you both are doing a great job.
And if either of you needs anything, even just to talk,
my door's always open.
4-0 Vicryl.
Yes doctor.
She's on bypass.
Cross clamping the aorta.
You ready?
- Flush the heart. - Flushing.
Let's prep her for C-section.
Dr. Andrews.
The operation went perfectly.
But I don't feel anything down there.
You're still on the meds, so it's gonna --
It's going to take six months to a year to regain complete sensation.
It'll take a while for your brain to figure out what we did.
But the grafted nerve is fully conducting.
You're gonna be fine.
Thank you.
- Can you do me a favor? - Sure.
- Call my parents. - Absolutely.
- Knife. - Knife.
Bovie.
How're we on bypass?
- Dr. Kalu, you still with us? - Yeah.
Central venous pressure's good.
Bypass oxygen tension's 200.
Good. Repairing the fetal sacrum.
Gonna put this baby back where it belongs.
Baby?
That's the first time you didn't call it a fetus.
Just an expression.
I told you.
Yes, you did.
You're gonna need to stay in bed for the next four months...
but both you and your son's prognosis is excellent.
We wanted it to be a surprise.
Rookie mistake.
Yes!
We are definitely celebrating tonight.
Screw sleep, Murphy.
You are coming with us.
Where are you going?
- Out. We're gonna drink. - I'm not thirsty.
Don't be an idiot.
I just meant...
Come on, mate.
You just saved an 18-year-old girl's sex life.
And I saved two lives.
We are drinking.
Come on, Shaun.
Okay.
Cool.
BGM: There's Nothing Holdin' Me Back by Shawn Mendes
♪ Baby, there's nothing holdin' me back ♪
♪ There's nothing holdin' me back ♪
All right.
I have to go home now.
♪ Just picture everybody naked ♪
It'll be okay. Don't worry.
♪ She really doesn't have to wait ♪
We won't stay long.
♪ Not really into hesitation ♪
♪ Pulls me in enough to keep me guessing ♪
Hi, Shaun.
Hi, Colleen.
I heard Steve showed you my dad's magazine.
Did you like it?
Don't worry. I'm not gonna tell anyone.
It's nothing to be embarrassed about.
All guys like that kind of stuff.
You want to know a secret about me?
I think you're really cute.
You smell like bubble gum.
I know. It's my lip gloss.
Come here.
Come here, silly.
Do you think I'm pretty?
I like you, too.
I'll show you mine if you show me yours.
Come on. I'm curious.
You must be curious.
Can I have a kiss?
I want to know what it feels like.
I'll give you a kiss...
if you show me.
Show you what?
You know. Pull down your pants.
No.
Come on, Shaun.
No. I gotta go.
Oh, my God. I can't believe you were about to pull it out.
No, I wasn't!
And like I'd ever kiss a creepy weirdo like you.
Leave him alone! Come on.
♪ Baby, there's nothing holdin me back ♪
All right, guys, a toast. To us.
'Cause we rock.
Nothing else need be said.
- Cheers. - Cheers.
♪ When you're with me, baby ♪
♪ Baby, there's nothing holdin' me back ♪