Now!
See anything?
You think it's deserted?
If they've gone off with the treasure,
Richard won't be pleased.
If there ever was a treasure.
One more flight.
- John.
- Cease firing!
I speak for Richard Lionheart...
...King of England, lord of half of France...
...and thereby overlord of this domain.
I'm up here speaking for myself.
- Where are your soldiers?
- Ran off.
- Where is the Lord of Châlus?
- He led them.
Ask if he knows about the treasure.
Left me with all the women and children,
and no weapons anyplace.
Here am I with only half an eye,
collecting arrows.
And you think I've got a bow
to shoot them with.
My king thinks your lord
is keeping treasure from him.
It's my orders to get it.
That'll be the treasure people say
was found by Jean the ploughman.
- Great gold statue, 3 foot long.
- That's the one.
I was with him when they found it.
What we dug up was a rock.
Now we're fighting for a rock.
You want to look?
Out there in the turnip field.
We couldn't lift it, so we left it.
What I've come to say is...
...if there's to be a fight,
I'm all there is. Come and get me.
You're a mad old man.
What now?
I want to give that rock to Richard.
Let's find the turnip field.
John.
What kind of siege is this?
- Where's Lord Châlus and my treasure?
- Gone.
My treasure? Gone?
The lord is gone. Your treasure never was.
A gold statue, 3 foot long. I want it.
- Captain.
- Yes, my lord.
I ordered you to take this castle.
- Well, take it.
Bring it down and get my statue.
They surrender, and your statue is a rock.
I want it done.
- There is no treasure.
- Do it.
There are no soldiers,
just some children and a mad old man.
And what's that to me?
Well, it should mean something.
Is that disapproval, Robin?
Am I in the wrong?
I followed you 20 years.
I fought for you on the Crusades,
and here in France.
Show me a soldier and I'll fight him now...
...but I won't slaughter children
for a piece of gold that never was.
I ordered it.
I command you.
You do it! You're a bastard, you'll enjoy it.
Damn right I'll do it! Mercadier!
Arrest those two! Lock them up.
I'll have their heads on pikes.
I want these walls down.
I want every damned head in that place!
Lionheart.
Lionheart!
You are a pig!
Good God!
Well...
...so it was a stone.
- Is this a barber-surgeon?
- Yes, my lord.
I only look after your men, sir.
- With much success?
- Yes.
- You've seen to John and Robin?
- Under guard, on their way to Châlus.
Come on, come on.
The patient's cold, and the doctor sweats.
The arrow will be hard to reach.
That should make it
all the more worthwhile.
Well, you heard it, Mercadier.
I told him to attack, he told me no.
I ought to kill him for it.
- Will you?
- I don't know. It depends on my mood.
I killed them all this afternoon
except the old man. I let him go.
I liked his eye.
But, Robin...
We've been friends, you see, for 20 years.
I met him in Nottingham for the first time.
I needed men for the Crusade.
Robin was the best that ever came to me.
Well, get on with it.
I'll die of old age at this rate.
So off we went to do great things.
We led 300,000 men to the Holy Land,
and came back on a boat with 50.
Not at all what we intended.
Christ!
I do what has to be done. I have no choice.
But Robin judges me. He always does.
The peasant bastard!
Judge a king!
Butcher.
I'll show you how it's done.
King's blood.
Remember it.
It's cold.
I don't like the dark.
Mercadier, how long to Châlus?
Half a league?
Sire.
A little rest and then I'll attend
to John and Robin.
What would you have done?
Killed the old man, women and children?
You didn't save them.
They're all dead and we're in here.
- I didn't force you to come.
- You looked at me.
You nodded.
What do you want me to do?
I don't know.
What did I get us into?
I could have talked to Richard.
I could have tried.
Well, he is a bloody bastard.
Are we any better? We serve him.
He's our king.
I took him for a great king.
There we were in Sherwood,
robbing abbots, giving pennies to the poor.
It didn't seem much
compared to rescuing the Holy Land.
How can you eat?
I'm hungry.
They reckon it's a good life
to have reached 40.
We've both passed it, and look at us!
My poor old dad,
and all the dads before him...
...lived in Barnesdale.
All they ever knew was one small town.
I've known a king...
...traveled half the world, seen Jerusalem.
The sand was blowing
and the walls were miles away, but...
I think I've had a good life.
Do you think Richard will kill us?
I don't know him anymore.
I don't know the man.
Well, if we go, we go.
Is that your idea of dying?
I don't know.
You'd think I'd learn.
I've seen enough of it.
I'll tell you something. I won't go quietly.
Come here.
Bend down.
If I had not met you,
think what I'd have missed.
The King will see you now. Come on.
Your Majesty.
We are celebrating our demise.
I always fancied leaving
from a rather larger stage.
But my physician, a funny fellow...
I've already had him hanged.
It seemed a fair exchange.
Wine! A bucket of it.
But you're not for hanging.
You're for cutting up.
I would've done it already but for this.
- Will that be all, my lord?
- All?
Damn your "all"!
All done.
All over.
My father cursed me when he died.
I killed him, and he felt resentful.
He'd have loved all this.
I said a bucket.
A bucket!
John's the next king.
You remember John.
John Lackland they called him.
Now he gets all the land.
Christ, why did I have no children?
Never gave a damn about England.
Never really there.
Not even as a corpse!
They're planting me in France,
by my father!
Take something, Robin.
Nothing, sire.
He sulks.
He pouts. He gives his life to Richard,
and he's sorry.
You don't know what sorrow is.
I was a king.
My mother...
She'll be 80 soon, the bitch.
I've sent for her. Do you think she'll come?
Bucket.
Clever fellow, death is.
I've tried to find him on my terms.
God knows I've tried.
Ask for something, damn you!
It's too late. There's nothing left.
There's still your life.
You take me as an equal. You always did.
I'll carve you yet, you peasant bastard.
Mercadier!
My sword!
While I'm still King of England, I'll...
Richard!
Richard, it's me.
I know it's you.
You couldn't leave me, could you?
You're free of me.
I'll let you go.
What will you do without me now,
jolly Robin...
...now I'm dead?
That's that.
What now?
We watched him die. He saw us there.
He won't mind if we miss the funeral.
Where do we go? Which way?
North.
Why north?
England's there.
Let's go home, John.
There she is!
I'll race you. Come on!
- You sure?
- Of course I'm sure.
This way.
- A lot of thorns can grow in 20 years.
- I know these woods.
Good place to pass the night.
We're going through.
What's that?
- Deer.
- Deer?
Someone's seen us. Come on.
I can see it!
- I can't even see you.
- That's the top of my tree.
I told you this was the way.
There's nothing left.
What did you expect to find?
I don't know. I never thought...
John!
Quick, Robin. There!
All right, boy.
Jesus, Rob, mine's an old man!
Robin?
It's me, Tuck. Tuck and Will!
Will? Will!
Robin! You've come home!
"And evil Prince John
Took one look at his sword
"And fled to his castle
And prayed to the Lord
"Follow him, follow him
Bloody and brave
"I'll follow bold Robin
From here to the grave"
They've turned us into heroes.
You didn't make it up?
I don't know where these songs
come from. They're everywhere.
- We go from town to town.
- What do you do for a living?
While I take confessions...
...he takes the horses.
Everywhere we go,
they want to hear about the things you did.
We didn't do them.
I know that.
I think I'll go to Barnesdale in the morning.
See my dad.
He died, John. Years ago.
Wouldn't have known me anyway.
What happened here after we went off?
Did Marian... Is she still alive?
Last time we passed Nottingham.
She lives down Kirkly way. Not far.
Lovely girl.
Haven't thought of her in years.
And the sheriff?
He still rules the county,
he's as powerful as ever.
Those were good days, fighting him.
What about the rest of us?
They died or went away.
When the Crusades ended, we were sure
you'd come. When you didn't...
...we took you to be dead.
Like Richard.
Aye, Richard, well...
I mean, King John must be mad.
His own kind have turned against him.
The kingdom is falling apart.
His queen is 12 years old,
and all he does is stay in bed with her.
And you know he's fighting with the Pope.
You can't hear Mass or take
Holy Communion anywhere in England.
If ever there was a time for us, it is now.
The people would come to you
if you called them.
Fight the King?
Then why did you come back?
Not to fight.
Sing us another song, Will.
One that really happened.
About Marian.
About Marian? Oh, aye.
Marian, now let's see...
Still, it would be something,
wouldn't it, Rob?
Not at my age.
No!
All right, come on, you.
You, too. Hack the post.
My arms are getting tired.
Dolt, get up!
They never learn.
No. Put your body weight behind it.
All right!
I'll take two men at once.
The rest of you, pay attention.
You...
...and you.
Any questions?
Take that rope over there...
My Lord Sheriff!
Yes, my lord.
It's time to go.
Sir Ranulf.
In my domain, never tell me, always ask.
Taxes, what you got?
Tom the ploughman, one egg. Put it down.
What else? Your tax?
- One chicken, Sam the herdsman.
- Slow down a bit.
She won't be able to pay...
If you want to work with me,
you must pay your taxes like anybody else.
Hey! He's taken my egg.
He can't do that. What am I going to do?
Now what will I do? Where do you think
I'll get another egg from?
Watch it.
- Aren't we going to Nottingham?
- I thought we'd go by Kirkly first.
- Kirkly's this way.
- Aye, but Marian's up there.
- Up there?
- Well, aye.
- That's Kirkly Abbey.
- Aye, so it is.
What's she doing up there?
She's lived there for 18 years or more.
A nun! She can't be! Not my Marian.
You'll see.
- I won't know what to say to her.
- She'll think of something.
This will help the pain.
Hello, the abbey!
Damn!
Forgive me. It's the sheriff.
I have a busy day.
Hello?
John, you go in.
I never said goodbye, she might be angry.
Better yet, leave it for another day.
You, there!
What in hell do you want?
This is Kirkly Abbey?
Yes, and I'm the abbess. Who are you?
Good God, it's Marian.
Robin.
- What are you doing in that costume?
- Living in it.
Well, I've come home to you, Marian.
The wars are over. I'm here.
It's Mother Jennet now.
You can trot right back to Jerusalem.
You're angry.
I haven't thought of you in 20 years.
Give me a smile. Invite me in.
Come back tomorrow. I'll be gone.
- The sheriff's coming. I'm off to prison.
- Off to prison?
Marian! What did you say?
Damn the man!
- Mother Jennet...
- They'll be here for me soon.
- You're in no danger, carry on.
- But...
No services, but you must help
all those who come as best you can.
Marian.
- What happened? Explain.
- I haven't time.
- But why the sheriff? What did you do?
- God's work. That's what I do.
- lf you're in trouble, I can save you.
- I have nothing to be saved from.
- I don't want you.
- You've got me.
- I like the way you look.
- More than I can say for you.
So this is your room.
And I thought I knew you.
What's happened to you?
Good things.
I work hard. I've studied herbs and
medicines, I till the fields. I love my life.
I won't give it up.
When the sheriff comes...
What's he coming for?
I'm the abbess.
The King's ordered the higher clergy
out of England. I'm not going.
When he comes,
he'll find me doing what I do.
- You mean to let him take you?
- God's with me.
- He didn't help us on the Crusades.
- Rob! Horsemen!
- Wait there.
- But it's my life, Robin.
You're a fool.
How many are they?
- Six!
- I like the odds.
My Lord Sheriff.
Robin.
Still not dead?
Not for want of trying.
You look well, all things considered.
- How was the Crusade?
- A disappointment.
After all these years, look at us.
I'm nothing but a former captain.
You're still the sheriff.
No advancement.
I can read and write.
It makes you suspect.
Not a duke in 20 reads a word.
Correct, my lord?
Books are for clerks.
How's Mother Jennet?
You find her changed?
I didn't find her. She'd gone off.
Two decades, and I missed her by a day.
That's odd. I sent her warning
and she answered, "Come and get me."
Well, we've both come for nothing.
- So be it.
- I'm ready.
- That's the woman, is it?
- It is.
- By my authority...
- Who is this oaf?
- Sir Ranulf de Pudsey.
- I'm your prisoner.
- Come back!
- Let me go.
Release her!
- Can't you grow up?
- I'm saving you.
- Arrest them all.
- Not enough men.
- I'm here. I'll do it.
- You'll what?
In King John's name, I charge you. Yield!
I'm trying to.
- Give her to me.
- Here.
I warned him not to.
Oaf or not, he serves the King.
You're still a free man.
- Let me have her and you can go.
- I can't do that.
- Then I shall have to hunt you down.
- Good hunting, Sheriff.
- God help you, Robin.
- lf he will.
So that's Robin Hood.
He's a dead man.
Yes.
But not just anyone's. He's mine.
Can you get on your horse, Sir Ranulf?
- I didn't mean to hurt you.
- Nothing hurts.
I couldn't let them take you.
Take me! I was going.
I'll save you from prison.
- That I can do.
- It's none of your affair.
I don't know how I look,
but I'm not your Marian.
I can't imagine living in the world again,
or even wanting to.
- Come morning, I'll go to the sheriff.
- Why? Who would it serve?
There's always God.
- You went crusading, didn't you?
- Some things are worth dying for.
They had souls too,
the heathen that you killed.
If I should die in prison...
I'd rather not, but if it comes...
...it's for a reason.
I'll have stood for something.
But I won't have taken another life to do it.
What will you do now? Fight the sheriff?
More corpses?
Aren't you sick of it?
On July 12, 1191...
...the mighty Acre fortress fell to Richard.
His one great victory in the Holy Land.
He was sick in bed and never fought.
On August 20, John and I were standing
on the plain outside the city, watching...
...while every Muslim left alive
was marched out in chains.
King Richard spared the richest
for ransoming, took the strong for slaves.
And he took all the children
and had them chopped apart.
When that was done,
he had the mothers killed.
When they were all dead,
3,000 bodies on the plain...
...he had them all opened up...
...so their guts could be explored
for gold and precious stones.
Our churchmen on the scene,
and there were many...
...took it for a triumph.
One bishop put on his miter
and led us all in prayer.
And you ask me if I'm sick of it.
Why didn't you come home then?
He was my king.
Come. Walk with me.
That's where the kitchen was...
...and over there we stored the ale.
And this...
Was this our house?
As small as that?
The door was here.
I tried so hard to keep it clean.
I was right to love you all those years ago.
It's odd, I know I loved you, but...
...I can't remember how it felt...
...or who I was.
Of all things,
I found peace most difficult to come by.
I suppose I took the church up
out of anger.
It's a blur now, but I think I thought...
...of all men, you would mind most
if I married Jesus.
Not a good beginning.
For months, when it was time to sleep,
I'd think of you.
My confessions were the envy
of the convent.
I said endless prayers.
Did dreadful penance, but...
...nothing helped but time.
I have found peace.
I don't dream about you anymore, Robin.
I'll see you back safely
into Nottingham tomorrow.
I think one of my teeth is loose.
I never mean to hurt you...
...and yet it's all I ever do.
You never wrote.
I don't know how.
Jesus!
Did you sleep well?
- Did you?
- To Nottingham then.
The abbey first. My things
were left behind, in the confusion.
- Well, you'll have to ride with me.
- I always did.
If you still know how.
- I won't be long.
- Mother Jennet!
They've been taken.
We were in the garden, where you left us.
- The men came in.
- The sheriff and the oaf?
We ran. I ran the fastest,
but they caught the others and took them.
- They took them all away!
- lf you'd kept out of this, they'd be here.
You believe that?
You think it's you he wants? It's me.
It's John and me.
He's in his castle waiting for us.
Take me to Nottingham.
- No, not you, we're going.
- I'll walk there if I have to.
Take them to camp. We'll join you later.
I wish to God I were a man.
I'd knock you down.
Now that's my Marian.
Nottingham.
There she is, John.
You look ridiculous.
He'll never come.
I know him.
He's a little bit in love with death.
He flirts. He teases.
I can wait.
They haven't changed a thing.
- Shall we go on?
- Why not? See what there is to see.
No harm in that.
- See anything?
- Not yet.
He knows we're coming.
He'll be waiting, watching.
- Not a soldier anyplace.
- So far.
- Robin.
- Where?
You can't see anything. Just a crowd.
I see a wagon with three horses.
One to pull, but two to push?
I'm almost sorry.
Now. At once.
Aye, sir.
What now?
We set up shop. Do you see a table?
- Why not go out and get him?
- Why go out when he'll come in?
There we are.
- It's no good being inside all day.
- What?
Walk where you like.
I don't understand what he means.
Hey, there! You, lad!
- That's not your table. It's ours.
- It was empty.
Makes no difference. What's mine is mine.
Now, get off with you.
- I need it. I'll buy it from you.
- It's not for sale.
I'm good at faces. I know you, don't I?
I could have sworn that...
That's not your wagon.
Fat man, been here all week from Bristol.
He left this morning.
Be you thieves?
Take the lot.
- Fair's fair, and that's too much.
- Listen.
If you don't move,
I'll have to split you from here to there.
John.
It's madness going in there.
There's only one way in.
They'll bang the gate down on us.
We could always come back tomorrow.
Look.
Skillets, pipkins! London-made!
Just pots and pans.
Pots and pans!
Pots and pans, Sisters?
- There's a yellow wagon beyond the gate.
- You're not supposed to be here.
- Can you see it?
- We can't buy your pots, we're prisoners.
- God almighty! Can you see the wagon?
- You've profaned the Lord's name.
- Who are you?
- Jesus Christ!
I'm a friend of Mother Jennet's,
and if we don't get out, we'll all die.
Cut it, for Christ's sake.
Move!
Up.
Where in hell are your crossbowmen?
Get them out here!
This is murder.
Those bloody nuns.
After them!
God!
- There's Robin Hood.
- Which one?
Him.