Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Now!
See anything?
You think it's deserted?
If they've left with the treasure,
Richard won't be pleased.
If there ever was a treasure.
One more flight.
- John.
- Cease firing!
I speak for Richard Lionheart...
...King of England.
Lord of half of France...
...and thereby overlord
of this domain.
I'm speaking for myself.
- Where are your soldiers?
- Run off.
- Where is the Lord of Chaluz?
- He led them.
Ask if he knows about the treasure.
Left me with the women
and children and no weapons.
Here am I with one eye,
collecting arrows.
And you think I've got a bow
to shoot them with?
My king thinks your lord is keeping
treasure from him.
It's my orders to get it.
People say it was
found by Jean the ploughman.
- Great gold statue, 3 foot long.
- That's the one.
I was with him when they found it.
What we dug up was a rock.
We're fighting for a rock?
You wanna look?
Out there in the turnip field.
We couldn't lift it, so we left it.
What I've come to say is...
...if there's to be a fight,
I'm all there is. Come and get me.
You're a mad old man.
What now?
I want to give that rock to Richard.
Let's find the turnip field.
John.
What kind of siege is this?
- Where's Lord Chaluz and my treasure?
- Gone.
My treasure? Gone?
The lord is gone.
Your treasure never was.
A gold statue, 3 foot long.
I want it.
- Captain.
- Yes, my lord.
I ordered you to take this castle.
- Well, take it.
Bring it down and get my statue.
They surrender, and your statue
is a rock.
I want it done.
- There is no treasure.
- Do it.
There are no soldiers, just some
children and a mad old man.
And what's that to me?
Well, it should mean something.
Is that disapproval, Robin?
Am I in the wrong?
I followed you 20 years.
I fought in the Crusades and France.
I'll fight a soldier...
...but I won't slaughter
children for gold.
I ordered it.
I command you.
You do it! You're a bastard,
you'll enjoy it.
Damn right I'll do it!
Mercadier!
Arrest those two!
I'll have their heads on pikes.
I want these walls down. I want
every damned head!
Lionheart.
Lionheart!
You are a pig!
Good God!
Well...
...so it was a stone.
- Is this a barber surgeon?
- Yes, my lord.
I look after your men, sire.
- With much success?
- Yes.
- You've seen to John and Robin?
- Under guard.
Come on, come on.
The patient's cold,
and the doctor sweats.
The arrow will be hard to reach.
That should make it all
the more worthwhile.
Well, you heard it, Mercadier.
I told him to attack, he told me no.
I ought to kill him for it.
- Will you?
- I don't know. It depends on my mood.
I killed all of them this afternoon
except the old man. I liked his eye.
But, Robin...
We've been friends, you see,
for 20 years.
I met him in Nottingham
for the first time.
I needed men for the Crusade.
Robin was the best.
Well, get on with it.
I'll die of old age at this rate.
So off we went to do great things.
We led 300,000 men to the Holy Land,
and came back on a boat with 50.
Not at all what we intended.
Christ!
I do what has to be done.
I have no choice.
But Robin judges me.
He always does.
The peasant bastard!
Judge a king!
Butcher.
I'll show you how it's done.
King's blood.
Remember it.
It's cold.
I don't like the dark.
Mercadier, how long to Chaluz?
Half a league?
Sire.
A little rest and then I'll attend
to John and Robin.
What would you do?
Kill the women and children?
But they're all dead
and we're in here.
- No one forced you.
- You did.
You nodded.
What do you want me to do?
I know.
What did I get us into?
I could have talked to Richard.
I could have tried.
Well, he is a bloody bastard.
Are we any better?
We serve him.
He's our king.
I took him for a great king...
...when we were robbing abbots,
giving pennies to the poor.
It didn't seem much compared
to rescuing the Holy Land.
How can you eat?
I'm hungry.
I reckon it's a good life
to have reached 40.
We've both passed it, and look at us!
My poor old dad and all
the dads before him...
...lived in Barnesdale.
All they ever knew was one town.
I've known a king...
...travelled the world,
seen Jerusalem.
Oh, the sand was blowing and
the walls were miles away, but...
I think I've had a good life.
Do you think Richard will kill us?
I don't know him anymore.
I don't know the man.
Well, if we go, we go.
Is that your idea of dying?
I don't know.
You'd think I'd learn.
I've seen enough of it.
I'll tell you something.
I won't go quietly.
Come here.
Bend down.
If I had not met you,
think what I'd have missed.
The king will see you now.
Come on.
Your Majesty.
We are celebrating our demise.
I fancied leaving from a
larger stage.
But a funny fellow, my physician...
I've already had him hanged.
It seemed fair.
Wine! A bucket of it.
But you're not for hanging.
You're for cutting up.
I would've done it already
but for this.
- Will that be all, my lord?
- All?
Damn your "all"!
All done.
All over.
My father cursed me when he died.
I killed him, and he felt resentful.
He'd have loved all this.
I said a bucket.
A bucket!
John's the next king.
You remember John.
John Lackland they called him.
Now he gets all the land.
Christ, why did I have no children?
Never cared for England.
Never really there.
Not even as a corpse!
They're planting me in France,
by my father!
Take something, Robin.
Nothing, sire.
Oh, he sulks.
He pouts. He gives his life
to Richard, and he's sorry.
You don't know sorrow.
I was a king.
My mother...
She'll be 80 soon, the bitch.
I've sent for her.
Do you think she'll come?
Bucket.
Clever fellow, death is.
I've tried to find him on my terms.
God knows I've tried.
Ask for something, damn you!
It's too late.
There's nothing left.
There's still your life.
You take me as an equal.
You always did.
I'll carve you yet,
you peasant bastard.
Mercadier!
My sword!
While I'm still king of England,
I'll...
Richard!
Richard. Richard, it's me.
I know it's you.
You couldn't leave me, could you?
You're free of me.
I'll let you go.
What will you do without me now,
jolly Robin...
...now I'm dead?
That's that.
What now?
We watched him die. He saw us there.
He won't mind if we miss the funeral.
Where do we go? Which way?
North.
Why north?
England's there.
Let's go home, John.
There she is!
I'll race you. Come on!
- You sure?
- Of course I'm sure.
This way.
- A lot of thorns can grow in 20 years.
- I know these woods.
Good place to pass the night.
We're going through.
What's that?
- Deer.
- Deer?
Someone's seen us. Come on.
I can see it!
- I can't even see you.
- That's the top of my tree.
I told you this was the way.
There's nothing left.
What did you expect to find?
I don't know. I never thought...
John!
Quick, Robin.
There!
All right, boy.
Jesus, Rob, mine's an old man!
Rob, Rob... Robin?
It's me, Tuck. Tuck and Will!
Will? Will!
Robin! You've come home!
And evil Prince John
Took one look at his sword
And fled to his castle
And prayed to the Lord
Follow him, follow him
Bloody and brave
I'll follow bold Robin
From here to the grave
They've turned us into heroes.
You didn't make it up?
I don't know where they come from.
They're everywhere.
We go from town to town.
How do you make a living?
While I take confessions...
...he takes the horses.
Everywhere we go they want to hear
about your deeds.
We didn't do them.
I know that.
I think I'll go to Barnesdale
in the morning. See my dad.
He died, John. Years ago.
Wouldn't have known me anyway.
What happened here?
Did Marian...?
Is she still alive?
Last time we passed Nottingham.
She lives down Kirkly way.
Lovely girl.
Haven't thought of her in years.
And the sheriff?
Still rules the county,
as powerful as ever.
Those were good days, fighting him.
What about the rest of us?
They died or went away.
When the Crusades ended
and you didn't come again...
...we took you to be dead.
Like Richard.
Aye, Richard, well...
I mean, King John must be mad.
His own kind have turned on him.
The kingdom is falling apart.
His queen is 12 years old and
all he does is stay in bed with her.
And you know he's fighting
with the pope.
You can't hear Mass or take Holy
Communion anywhere in England.
The time for us is now.
The people would come to you
if you called them.
Fight the king?
Then why did you come back?
Not to fight.
Sing us a song, Will.
One that really happened.
About Marian.
About Marian? Oh, aye.
Marian, now let's see...
Still, it would be something,
wouldn't it, Rob?
Not at my age.
No!
All right, come on, you.
You too. Hack the post.
My arms are getting tired.
Dolt! Get up.
They never learn.
No, no, no.
Put your bloody weight behind it.
All right!
I'll take two men at once.
The rest of you pay attention.
You...
...and you.
Any questions?
Tie that rope over there.
My lord sheriff!
Yes, my lord.
It's time to go.
Sir Ranulf.
In my domain, never tell me,
always ask.
Taxes, what you got?
One egg. Put it down.
- One chicken, Sam the Herdsman.
- Slow down a bit.
She won't be able to pay...
You have to work and pay taxes
like anybody else.
Hey! He's taken my egg.
He can't do that.
What am I gonna do?
Now what am I gonna do?
Watch it.
- Aren't we going to Nottingham?
- I thought we'd go by Kirkly first.
- Kirkly's this way.
- Aye, but Marian's up there.
- Up there?
- Well, aye.
- That's Kirkly Abbey.
- Aye, so it is.
What's she doing there?
She's lived there for 18 years.
A nun! She can't be!
Not my Marian.
You'll see.
- I won't know what to say.
- She'll think of something.
This will help the pain.
Hello, the abbey!
Damn!
Forgive me. It's the sheriff.
I have a busy day.
Hello.
John, you go in.
I never said goodbye,
she might be angry.
Better yet,
leave it for another day.
You there!
What in hell do you want?
This is Kirkly Abbey?
Yes, and I'm the abbess.
Who are you?
Good God, it's Marian.
Robin.
- What are you doing in that costume?
- Living in it.
Well, I've come home to you, Marian.
The wars are over.
I'm here.
It's Mother Jennet now.
You can trot right back to Jerusalem.
You're angry.
I haven't thought
of you in 20 years.
Give me a smile.
Invite me in.
Come back tomorrow.
I'll be gone.
- The sheriff's due. I'm off to prison.
- Off to prison?
Marian! What did you say?
Damn the man!
- Mother Jennet...
- They'll be here for me soon.
- You're in no danger, carry on.
- But...
No services, but help all those
who come as best you can.
Marian.
- What happened? Explain.
- I haven't time.
- But the sheriff? What did you do?
- God's work. That's what I do.
- I can save you.
- I have nothing to be saved from.
- I don't want you.
- You've got me.
- I like the way you look.
- More than I can say for you.
So this is your room.
And I thought I knew you.
What's happened to you?
Good things.
I work hard. I've studied herbs
and medicines. I love my life.
- And when the sheriff comes...
- What's he coming for?
I'm the abbess.
The king's ordered the clergy out
of England. I'm not going.
When he comes he'll find me
doing what I do.
- You mean to let him take you?
- God's with me.
- He didn't help us on the Crusades.
- Rob! Horsemen!
- Wait there.
- But it's my life, Robin.
You're a fool.
How many are they?
- Six!
- I like the odds.
My lord sheriff.
Robin.
Still not dead?
Not for want of trying.
You look well,
all things considered.
- How was the Crusade?
- A disappointment.
After all these years, look at us.
I'm just a former captain.
You're still the sheriff.
No advancement.
I can read and write.
Makes you suspect.
Not a duke in 20 reads a word.
Correct, my lord?
Books are for clerks.
How's Mother Jennet?
You find her changed?
I didn't find her. She'd gone off.
Two decades and I missed her by a day.
That's odd. I sent her warning
and she answered, " Come and get me. "
Well, we've both come for nothing.
- So be it.
- I'm ready.
- That's the woman?
- It is.
- By my authority...
- Who's this oaf?
- Sir Ranulf.
- I'm your prisoner.
- Come back!
- Let go...
Release her!
- Can't you grow up?
- I'm saving you.
- Arrest them all.
- Not enough men.
- I'm here. I'll do it.
- You'll what?
In King John's name,
I charge you. Yield!
I'm trying to.
- Give her to me.
- Here.
- I warned him not to.
- Robin.
Oaf or not, he serves the king.
You're still free.
- Let me have her and you can go.
- I can't do that.
- Then I shall have to hunt you down.
- Good hunting, sheriff.
- God help you, Robin.
- Lf he will.
So that's Robin Hood.
He's a dead man.
Yes.
But not just anyone's. He's mine.
Can you get on your horse,
Sir Ranulf?
- I didn't mean to hurt you.
- Nothing hurts.
I couldn't let them take you.
Take me! I was going.
I'll save you from prison.
- That I can do.
- It's none of your affair.
I don't know how I look,
but I'm not your Marian.
I can't imagine
living in the world again.
- Come morning I'll go to the sheriff.
- Why? Who would it serve?
There's always God.
- You went crusading, didn't you?
- Some things are worth dying for.
They had souls too,
the heathen that you killed.
If I should die in prison...
I'd rather not, but if it comes...
...it's for a reason.
I'll have stood for something.
But I won't have taken another life.
What will you do now?
Fight the sheriff?
More corpses?
Aren't you sick of it?
On the 12th of July, 1191...
...the mighty Acre fortress
fell to Richard.
His one great victory
in the Holy Land.
He was sick and never fought.
On August 20th, John and I were
outside the city, watching...
...while every Moslem left alive was
marched out in chains.
King Richard spared the richest for
ransoming, took the strong for slaves.
And he took all the children
and had them chopped apart.
When that was done,
he had the mothers killed.
When they were all dead, 3000
bodies on the plain...
...he had them all opened up...
...so their guts could be explored
for gold and precious stones.
Our churchmen on the scene,
and there were many...
...took it for a triumph.
One bishop put on his mitre
and led us all in prayer.
And you ask me if I'm sick of it.
Why didn't you come home then?
He was my king.
Come. Walk with me.
That's where the kitchen was...
...and over there we stored the ale.
And this...
Was this our house?
As small as that?
The door was here.
I tried so hard to keep it clean.
I was right to love you
all those years ago.
It's odd, I know I loved you...
...but I can't remember how it felt...
...or who I was.
Of all things, I found peace
most difficult to come by.
I suppose I took the church up
out of anger.
It's a blur,
but I think I thought...
...of all men, you would mind
most if I married Jesus.
Not a good beginning.
For months, when it was time to sleep,
I'd think of you.
Oh, my confessions
were the envy of the convent.
I said endless prayers.
Did dreadful penance, but...
...nothing helped but time.
I have found peace.
I don't dream about you
anymore, Robin.
I'll see you back safely
into Nottingham tomorrow.
I think one of my teeth is loose.
I never mean to hurt you...
...and yet it's all I ever do.
You never wrote.
I don't know how.
Did you sleep well?
- Did you?
- To Nottingham then.
The abbey first. My things
were left behind, in the confusion.
- Well, you'll have to ride with me.
- I always did.
If you still know how.
- It won't be long.
- Mother Jennet!
They've been taken.
We were in the garden.
- The men came in.
- The sheriff and oaf?
We all ran. They caught
and took the others.
- Took them all!
- Lf you'd kept out they'd be here now.
You think it's you he wants? It's me.
It's John and me.
- He's in his castle waiting.
- Take me to Nottingham.
- No, not you, we're going.
- I'll walk if I have to.
Take her to camp.
We'll join you later.
I wish I were a man.
I'd knock you down.
Now that's my Marian.
Nottingham.
There she is, John.
You look ridiculous!
He'll never come.
I know him.
He's a little bit in love with death.
He flirts. He teases.
I can wait.
They haven't changed a thing!
- Shall we go on?
- Why not? See what there is to see.
No harm in that.
- See anything?
- Not yet.
He knows we're coming.
He'll be waiting...
...watching.
Not a soldier anyplace.
So far.
- Ah, Robin.
- Where?
You can't see anything but a crowd.
I see a wagon with three horses.
One to pull, but two to push?
I'm almost sorry.
Now. At once.
Aye, sir.
What now?
We set up shop. Do you see a table?
Hey!
- Why not go out and get him?
- Why go out when he'll come in?
There they are.
It's no good being inside all day.
Walk where you like.
I don't understand what he means.
Hey, there! You, lad!
- That's not your table.
- It was empty.
No difference. What's mine's mine.
Now get off with you.
- I need it. I'll buy it from you.
- It's not for sale.
I'm good at faces.
I know you, don't I?
I could have sworn that...
That's not your wagon.
Fat man, been here all week
from Bristol. He left this morning.
Be you thieves?
Take the lot.
- Fair's fair, that's too much.
- Listen.
If you don't move, I'm gonna
have to split you from here...
...to there.
John.
It's madness going in there.
There's only one way in.
They'll bang the gate down on us.
We could always come back tomorrow.
Oh, look!
Skillets! London-made!
What? Just pots and pans.
Pots and pans!
Pots and pans, Sisters?
- There's a wagon beyond the gate.
- You're not supposed to be here.
- Can you see it?
- We can't buy pots, we're prisoners.
- God almighty! Do you see the wagon?
- You profaned God's name.
- Who are you?
- Jesus Christ...
A friend of Mother Jennet's,
and if we don't leave, we'll all die.
Cut it, for chrissakes!
Move!
Up.
Where in hell are your crossbowmen?
Get them out here!
This isn't much better.
Those bloody nuns!
Hey!
After them!
God!
- There's Robin Hood.
- Which one?
Him!
- Mother! There's barely time...
- Go on!
Do as they ask!
- Robin!
- Jump!
- I'll hurt myself.
- For chrissakes.
That's him.
I should have taught you better.
Two old men, for Jesus' sake,
two old men.
This one's still alive.
Take care of him.
As for the rest of them...
...take up their limbs and bury them.
You there!
- Raise it! Raise the gate!
- I can't, my lord. How?
I ought to let you go.
I'll bring him back.
Bring him back from Sherwood?
You won't even find him.
- I can do it.
- In full armour, in the woods?
You'll sink in the bogs.
I've tried it.
I've gone in after him.
I never even saw his archers.
Just the arrows in my
soldiers' bodies.
I can get him, and you failed.
And you don't like it.
All right, get some men.
Raise the gates.
Here. Take this.
Give me your bow.
Get up there, keep watch.
Come on. Come on.
Come on!
I can't keep doing this
kind of thing anymore.
Turn left!
- Turn left!
- No, no.
She never did have the
touch for driving.
Do you think they'll come after us?
We'll hear from Will if they do.
There's not another Mother
Abbess like you.
Amen to that. You're a marvel.
Blood!
Oh! You fool.
You've put on weight.
Was this a day! I haven't had one
like it since we left.
Neither have I. Did we really
used to do this sort of thing?
All the time.
How did I bear it?
When I saw you on that wall,
I thought you were dead.
Why did I ever leave?
Let's take a look at you.
- Just a few bumps and bruises.
- All the same.
So many!
You had the sweetest body
when you left.
Hard, and not a mark.
And you were mine.
When you left I thought I'd die.
I even tried.
I walked out into the woods...
...and laid down by a stream
and cut myself.
Some damn fool forester came by,
took me to the abbey. So they say.
No more scars, Robin.
It's too much to lose you twice.
I've never kissed
a member of the clergy.
Would it be a sin?
They're coming in!
Tuck, we'll need your bow.
Right!
- Hasn't there been enough?
- I'll meet you at camp.
- Don't go.
- I just want to see who's hunting me.
Next time you ride into Sherwood,
keep your visor down.
John! Wait.
I hold my office from
the king himself.
I never liked your king.
You're his subject and his servant.
He's not king here. Not in Sherwood.
You're the ruler? Should I bow?
I wouldn't have you in my service,
nobleman.
I've known your kind all my life.
You're everything I meant to fight.
You're the enemy.
You gobble red meat
and we get bread and cheese.
The laws can't touch you and there's
no crime you can be punished for.
We can shoot a deer and have
our eyes put out.
This is my forest.
I'll live here as I like.
You come in again and I'll kill you.
Good.
- Was there fighting?
- Some.
You said you were only going to look.
My father worked honestly for years.
He left a pot, a blanket and a spoon.
The sheriff?
No, the oaf.
- You didn't kill him?
- No.
I told him this was my forest
and I want to live here with you.
What are you looking for?
Some trace of Marian.
Or Mother Jennet.
Either one.
Good woman, Jennet.
Years of diligence it took to leave
the flesh behind.
She could look at men
and feel nothing.
See? She looks at you.
Touch her hand. Hold it.
Just as well.
She wouldn't feel anything.
I think of what I did and it
makes no sense.
To want to die from wanting you!
Some other girl it must have been.
Let me hold you.
Robin...
Were there many women
on your great Crusade?
- Lots.
- Don't tell me.
- As you wish.
- How many?
But they all looked like you.
Am I old and ugly?
Am I anything you'd want?
I've felt so little for so long.
Robin...
Hurt me.
Make me cry.
I can't stop smiling.
I don't mind.
Could there be two rooms to our house
next time?
- And something for a floor?
- All right.
I'd like that.
And a bed with blankets?
And a chest for clothes, and...
Do you hear that?
Jesus Christ almighty!
Don't...
You do be Robin Hood, yes?
I'll be damned!
I told them in the market it was you.
It's Robin.
I told you so!
Robin's back in Sherwood, I said.
I led them since I knew the way.
They're mostly from farms
round about here.
They're here to serve you
and fight against that king.
Tuck! Give them all food.
So be it, then.
Go fight your sheriffs and your kings.
I love you and you make me proud.
If there were a way to turn time back
just five minutes, I'd give my soul.
- You ladies there, where is the king?
- In the largest tent, of course.
So you go to the pope
and you tell him...
...if his archbishop puts one foot
in England, I'll cut his head off!
What's next?
John...
- Aren't you ever coming?
- Soon.
I clean all over. Want to look?
The court is here.
I don't mind.
I think you're pretty.
What in God's name do you want?
- Men, Your Majesty. Two hundred men.
- Two...!
- What for?
- To fight an enemy.
- What enemy? There are so many.
- Robin Hood.
I thought the man was dead.
He's back in Sherwood.
Can't the sheriff manage it?
Must I waste my time?
My army waits for me in Dover.
Good God, man!
These people have made a hero of him.
They're flocking to him.
He's become a legend.
Have you tried to fight a legend?
- Just my brother.
- But, sire...
...they mean to rise against you.
Do they?
Be in Dover in the morning.
I'll give you men.
And you tell the sheriff I'll have
Robin's head, or I'll have his.
Either way, I'll win.
Are you sure these berries
make it green?
Keep your bow arm straight
and pull it to your chin.
- Like that.
- Which arm?
All right, two!
Three!
The king was generous.
He sends a message.
He wants Robin's head.
Or mine.
- Follow me.
- These troops are my command.
Not in my county. Follow me!
This way!
- What, here?
- This is close enough.
- How many?
- Enough.
And they're making camp.
There in the field?
- I'd thought they'd come in after us.
- They'll come.
- Will! Tuck!
- What's wrong?
The sheriff's here with an army.
A hundred soldiers.
- Where are they?
- Near Kirkly.
They'll be coming in at dawn.
I want us in position tonight.
These pears are absolutely delicious.
Damnedest thing.
He's still eating breakfast!
Still?
What's he waiting for? More men?
You'd think he had enough.
What do we do?
We wait and see.
Come on.
No, thank you.
Come on, come along!
Now!
Let's go!
Call your men to sword!
It's an attack, my lord.
Call to arms, foot soldiers!
What happened?
- Nothing.
- Nothing?
We attacked. No one followed.
Are we to fight them in the open?
That seems to be the plan.
We'd be slaughtered.
Does he think we're fools?
That's what he's waiting for.
He's the fool, then.
He can sit out there forever.
He can't put a forest under siege.
That's how I see it.
He comes in, we've got him.
- We stay here.
- The man's mad.
You haven't asked what I think.
I think one madman's enough.
He's out there, Marian.
He expects me.
Let him.
The mist is rising.
You look so cold.
It's so beautiful, this place.
The woods just now. Full of noises...
...everything so alive.
I kept thinking...
...of all the death I've seen.
I've hardly lost a battle,
and I don't know what I've won.
"The day is ours, Robin. "
And then it was tomorrow.
But where did the day go?
You're so beautiful.
Come and sit by me.
Do you love me?
Say it.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
- You're going, aren't you?
- It's a possibility.
You heard John, and Will and Tuck.
They said it was madness.
Well...
Is that all being dead means?
"Well... "
I'll have more to say when the
time comes.
Let it be God's time.
He'll take you soon enough.
Then it's all in his hands.
You think I'm gray and old.
Well, I'm not.
Oh, Robin, I'd be 20 for you
if I could.
I'm all I ever was.
You saw me on the wall.
Yes.
And if you come back there'll be
another morning, won't there?
And each time you'll be less.
Not Robin anymore.
- And then one day...
- You'll see.
No, I won't see.
Or hear the songs about bold Robin.
I'll be gone.
Leave? Why?
Because I'll do everything for you
but mourn.
Go fight your sheriff,
and may God go with you.
May the sun shine
and the day be great.
But, Robin...
...I never want to know.
John.
I'll do anything you say.
I'll leave here.
I'll go as if he never found me.
Only stop him from this thing.
- What thing?
- His march against the sheriff.
- What?
- Didn't he tell you?
Fight the sheriff? Don't be mad.
It's four to one. We'd be slaughtered.
These are boys we've got.
They're farmers.
Tell him! You're the only one.
He'll listen.
Me? Say no to Rob?
Just this once.
We've always been together.
I'd be nothing without him.
I want him safe, that's all.
I'll leave.
What more do you want from me?
I haven't asked for anything.
You never liked me much.
- You're Rob's lady.
- Go on, say it.
You're Rob's lady.
Lf...
...you'd been mine,
I never would have left you.
Oh, damn you.
You've had him with you. You've had
years! And I'm going to lose him.
- No, you won't.
- Oh, John!
Oh, John...
John.
I'll watch over him.
Don't cry.
He'll be back.
We're going out.
Yes, I know.
She told you?
Yes.
Well?
She asked me not to go.
And you decided what?
It's mad, Rob.
And?
Well...
I told her you'd be lost without me.
This may be the hardest part
of the day.
I doubt it.
- Goodbye.
- What?
God keep you well.
If he so chooses.
Move!
All right, you men, put
it here. And hold it!
Sit still!
Await your orders.
I knew you'd come.
Of all men, just for you.
I know.
- I want to settle this with champions.
- One of yours against mine?
The winner takes the day.
Why should I, Robin?
The odds are four to one.
Why should I make them even?
I'm one champion.
And I'm the other?
If I lose, my men are yours.
- Without me, they won't trouble you.
- And if I lose?
Your soldiers leave the field.
Those are my orders.
Are they clear?
I let this rabble go?
Just march away?
Those are my orders.
Leave the field!
I promised I'd watch out for you.
I promised her.
She's gone, in any case.
- I'll kill him, Rob, if you don't.
- No!
What you do is keep my word.
I'll see you, Johnny.
Off you go.
God be with us, Robin.
Come on.
Whoa!
Will you not yield?
No!
I'm tired.
Marian!
I couldn't stop him.
For the love of God, Robin!
All right?
We've got to get the
men into the woods.
You're a stout lad.
- What's your name?
- They call me Little John.
Well met.
Let's see how tall you are.
Robin!
- Look at you.
- You came back.
Can you hold him?
We'll take him to the abbey.
My medicines are there.
I thought I'd seen the last of you.
A woman of your word.
I'm glad you came back.
Up there.
Stand still!
I wonder where the day went?
Vespers it must be.
What kind of abbey is this?
No one rings the hours.
Are you in great pain?
A little weary.
I've had worse.
He went down well, the sheriff did.
Brave man.
And the better one today.
The years...
The years, they whittle at you.
I should give it up, you know.
I doubt I'll have a day
like this again. And yet...
John!
- Lf they should follow us...
- I'll wait outside.
- I did my best.
- I know.
This will help the pain.
He's something, John is.
No one's gentler in the world...
...nor half as terrible.
Did you see him?
I should go and tend my men.
Brave boys, all of them.
I meant to...
I like your medicine.
There's no pain at all.
We'll have a time in the forest.
You'll tend me till I'm well again.
And then...
...great battles!
We'll have a life to sing about.
My...
...legs are cold.
I know.
They're numb.
I... I said you would have no pain.
What have you done?
John!
I'm poisoned!
Help me!
No one can help you now.
Jesus, Marian!
Why?
I love you.
More than all you know.
I love you more than children.
More than fields I've
planted with my hands.
I love you more than morning
prayers or peace or...
...or food to eat.
I love you more than sunlight...
...more than flesh or joy...
...or one more day.
I love you...
...more than God.
I'd never have a day like
this again, would I?
Well, it's better this way.
Marian.
It's all right.
Rob.
Look at you.
It's all right.
No.
Give me my bow.
Where this falls, John...
...put us close...
...and leave us there.
Subtitles by
SDI Media Group
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org