RESTORATION BY
IN CONJUNCTION WITH THE
SCUOLA NAZIONALE DI CINEMA,
THE CENTRO SPERIMENTALE
DI CINEMA TOGRAFIA
and
THE ROBERTO ROSSELLINI INSTITUTE
WITH ADDITIONAL CONTRIBUTION
FROM THE CITY OF ROME,
THE COUNCIL FOR CULTURAL POLITICS,
ENTERTAINMENT DIVISION,
AND WITH SUPPORT FROM
THE COUNCIL OF MINISTERS,
ENTERTAINMENT DIVISION
Restoration Done at
STUDIO CINE AND VIDEORECORDING
Technical Advisor
MANRICO MASINI
Under the Supervision of
VINCENZO VERZINI
Praise be to you, O Lord,
and to all your creatures.
Especially Brother Sun,
through whom you light our days.
He is beautiful and radiant
and resplendent,
and derives all meaning from you.
THE FLOWERS OF ST. FRANCIS
Praise be to you, O Lord,
for Sister Moon and all the stars,
which you cause to shine
clear and bright.
Praise be to you, O Lord,
for Brother Wind,
and for cloudy and clear skies,
and all kinds of weather,
which bring sustenance
to all your creatures.
Praise be to you, O Lord,
for Sister Water,
so useful and humble,
precious and chaste.
Praise be to you, O Lord,
for Brother Fire,
with whom you light up the night
and who is beautiful and playful,
robust and strong.
Praise be to you, O Lord,
for Sister and Mother Earth,
who sustains, governs
and brings forth the various fruits
with their colorful flowers
and leaves.
Praise be to you, O Lord, for those
who forgive out of love for you,
and who withstand infirmity
and tribulation.
Blessed are those who live in peace,
for they will be crowned by you,
the Most High.
Praise be to you, O Lord,
for our Sister Bodily Death,
from whom no mortal man
can escape.
Woe to those who die in mortal sin.
Blessed are those who abide
by your holy will,
for death shall not harm them.
Praise and bless my Lord.
Give thanks and serve him humbly.
"God chose the foolish things
of this world to humiliate the learned,
the weak to humiliate the strong."
St. Paul
So Francis, to vanquish the world,
made himself contemptible
and humble.
He became a child in order
to be worthy of the kingdom of heaven.
The world laughed at him
and called him mad,
but Pope Innocent had faith in him
and gave him permission
to bring among men
his faith in meekness and poverty.
Here is Francis, returning to Rivotorto
from Rome with his companions.
Their hut is occupied, so they retire
to St. Mary of the Angels,
whence they will spread
the power of their meekness
and their sweet love of peace.
If I were to preach to the people,
I would begin thus:
"I've come among you to tell you
a secret that will make you rejoice.
I will teach you what you must do
to find true peace."
- Joy.
- Exactly.
Because joy, like true peace, begets
ardent desire in the human heart.
If I were to preach,
I'd speak to men of glory.
Did he not say we must find in ourselves
the spirit of the perfect knight?
He was referring to the ardent love
with which we should preach
God's word.
My brother, ardor springs from a heart
steeped in the joy
of which Brother Ruffino just spoke.
I say all Christians
should aspire to do battle.
Especially when the battle is followed
by possession of the desired object.
You mean the battle for virtue?
The joy I referred to
is that felt by the soul
when it tames
the passions that tormented it.
Don't you remember?
We lived in a state of perfect calm.
In those clear, starry nights,
dreams enchanted our youth.
But his conversion broke that spell
that could have been our ruin.
Now, with the blessing
of his Holiness the Pope,
we should spread the knowledge
of this new divine reality.
The joy which we possess today,
Brother Pietro,
is the result of this struggle
divine goodness has inspired within us.
Brother Bernardo, why do you not
explain in your own sweet way
how creatures are to attain
such peace of the spirit?
Would you follow Christ in poverty
and humility as he has done?
- Welcome, joy!
- O comforting glory!
May all find sweetness
in the struggle for it!
May all men rediscover love's joy!
- Careful, brother. Are you thirsty?
- Help him.
But why you? Why you, I say!
Why you?
- What do you mean?
Why, Francis,
does the world follow you?
Every man wants to see you,
hear you, obey you.
You are neither handsome,
nor great, nor noble.
Because God found
no more humble creature on earth.
Because he saw among sinners
no one more vile than me.
So that men would see that every
virtue and good comes from Him.
Glory be to God forever.
And that's why
I follow you too, Francis.
- Go in.
- We can't.
Our hut is occupied.
Come, a little chivalry won't hurt you.
Good evening.
- What do you want?
- Brother, we must rest a while.
Bring the donkey back in here.
I'll give you rest!
But we built this hut
with our own hands.
- Well, I need it now!
- We'll make room as best we can.
Get out!
- But that's not charitable.
- Nor civil.
Out, out!
Enough yammering!
I'll show you,
if you keep bothering me.
Out, vile thieves!
I'm talking to you! Move!
Matteo, Bernardo, Leone,
lambs of the good Lord, come.
- Where will we go now?
- I know where to go.
- What will we do?
- It's cold!
Don't you see that our hearts
have reason to rejoice?
It's the first time providence
has made us useful to others.
Father, what's upsetting you?
May God forgive me for taking
advantage of your obedience.
Bernardo, come here.
I command you to do what I ask
in holy obedience.
I'm prepared to obey,
if you promise to do what I ask of you.
- I'll do as you wish.
- Tell me, Father, what you wish.
I command you
to punish me for my arrogance.
As I lay flat on the ground,
place one foot on my mouth
and the other on my neck,
and moving your weight
back and forth three times, repeat,
"Lie there, wretch,
son of Pietro Bernardone.
Whence this arrogance
that imposes on your companions
such severe penance?"
The joy you see on our faces
is the most beautiful answer
God can give you.
Now we are truly beginning
to love our vocation.
We truly understand that
in following you, we follow God.
Thank you, my children.
The Lord is always good to me.
How Brother Ginepro returned naked
to St. Mary of the Angels,
where the brothers had finished
building their hut.
I can't wait to go preach.
Brother, this work brings you
ever closer to God.
Perform the most humble tasks
with your own hands,
and you'll know life to the fullest.
Put your heart into each stone,
and each stone will make you greater.
Who gave you such a wonderful gift?
- What shall we do with those bells?
- Now we need a flock of sheep.
How beautiful!
Who gave that to you?
- A benefactor.
- Let's put it on the altar.
Finally we have bells
to call us to prayer.
Yet another wonderful
surprise awaits you.
We've finished our little house.
Do you want to see it?
It's so beautiful!
Come, children.
- It's lovely.
- How will we all fit?
- It's too small.
- We'll manage.
Brother Ginepro,
what happened to you?
The poor thing's shivering.
- Quick, cover him up.
- Get a blanket.
This one too.
What happened?
I gave my tunic to a poor man
asking for alms.
You mustn't give away your tunic.
Didn't you say
we must help the poor?
I command you not to give away
your tunic without my permission.
How Giovanni, known as "the simpleton,"
asked to follow Francis
and began imitating him
in word and gesture.
Leone.
I'm coming.
Francis, we're leaving.
Yes, go.
My Father,
help me to form,
with the help of my children,
a new and humble people.
May this new age resemble that which
witnessed your son's humility on earth.
May mankind live in peace.
In the name of the Lord,
go forth in humility and honesty,
praying to God in your hearts,
avoiding all vain speech and action.
Let each help the other.
If on the road you meet someone
who needs you, set aside all else,
for he who will not bring
peace on earth to his fellow man
can hope for little reward from God.
Brothers, beware of wasting
the precious gift of time,
nor should any of you appear idle
in your brothers' eyes.
I want my brothers to work honestly.
Let none be a burden to the others.
May he who is ignorant of the gospel
learn from your example.
Brothers, Ginepro cannot go
with you clad as he is.
He'll prepare a nice meal for you.
I will obey.
And we shall bring him
a nice tunic of silk from Provence.
Good-bye, brothers.
Until tonight.
- We shall bring back joy.
- And greetings from the poor.
O Lord, make me
an instrument of your peace.
Where there is hatred,
let me bring love.
Where there is discord,
let me bring harmony.
Where there is pain, let me bring joy,
and where there is despair, hope.
O Master, grant that I may not
so much seek to be loved as to love,
and may all on earth learn
the secret of your peace,
which is the fruit of justice
and brotherly love.
Sing a bit more softly.
Our Father who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done ！
My little brothers,
you can praise God so easily
because you're free to fly
through the air so pure.
Now allow me some peace
in which to sing his praises.
Thy will be done
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread,
and forgive us our trespasses
as we forgive those
who trespass against us.
Lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
There's nobody here!
What do you want, brother?
How beautiful you are!
What do you want?
- I want to speak to the leader.
- Speak to me. It's the same thing.
I want to stay with Francis.
What will you do with this ox?
I'll give it to the brothers.
Well...
Grandpa's gone mad!
- He's gone senile.
- That's our cow.
We can't give it away.
Yes, keep the cow.
We don't need it.
I'll look after him. Go.
You can keep the old man!
- Here we're close to Jesus Christ.
- Jesus Christ.
- And the Virgin Mary.
- The Virgin Mary.
- Do you know how to pray?
- Yes. "Hail Mary..."
See how beautiful it is.
Do you like it?
We'll always come here to pray.
- To pray, always.
- Do you like them?
- They're beautiful.
The flame went out.
We'll light it tomorrow.
What are you doing?
Oil is beautiful.
Let us pray.
Father, Son and Holy Spirit.
- Listen to the wonderful quiet.
- Wonderful quiet.
And this is the hut where we'll sleep.
It's very nice.
- Nice.
The fire's going out. Ginepro!
The fire.
The fire's so beautiful!
What's going on?
What are you doing?
Why were you stingy with Brother Fire?
I love him because he's beautiful
and playful, robust and strong.
God be praised for Brother Sun in the day
and Brother Fire at night.
But fire can also do harm.
And why do you want
to harm Brother Fire?
- Father, allow me.
- No, let go.
Why aren't the others back yet?
- I don't know, but they'll return.
- They'll return.
- I want to be like Francis.
- But you have a wife and children.
Why did you leave them?
Did they harm you?
No, I want to be like Francis.
But with us you'll have
to work even harder.
- I want to work.
- Your family will be as if dead to you.
You'll have to preach
and work among the poor.
Preach, work. Everything.
Wasn't it hard for you
to leave your loved ones?
- Everything.
- What do you want from Francis?
- I want to be a saint like Francis.
- But I'm Francis.
- Here they come!
- Let's go.
This is how those who will be
your brothers return after a day's work.
- Who's this dear old man?
- Our new brother.
What bounty from our Lord!
Here, Ginepro.
Sister Clare gave us this tunic
for Brother Ginepro.
She hasn't seen you in a long time
and wishes to dine with you.
Will you accommodate her?
- Do you think I should?
- Yes, we do.
Then tell Sister Clare
that we await her here.
Here, Ginepro. God does not abandon
those who serve him.
Why so sad?
- We are terrible sinners.
The Lord didn't grant us
the consolation of receiving alms.
Never fear. Those who do their duty
shall want for nothing.
What our brothers brought
belongs to us all.
We have a new brother.
- What's his name?
Giovanni's his name.
Of the wonderful meeting
between St. Clare and St. Francis
at St. Mary of the Angels.
- What will we do?
- Don't worry. There's still time.
Don't break the branches.
Just pick the flowers.
- Want to get on my shoulders?
- If you'll hold me.
How great is the Lord.
And we thought we had nothing
to offer Sister Clare.
Pick lots of them.
- Shall I help you?
- Yes, Father.
Quick, let's make
a nice carpet of flowers.
Smell their wonderful perfume.
Good children,
let us make our house
worthy of a maiden devoted to God.
Now hurry and shave.
Take the basins.
- Right away.
- Aren't you going?
- I don't need to, Father.
- My turn.
- Let's clean you up nice.
You're hurting me.
Gently.
That hurts. Gently.
She's coming.
Am I doing all right?
- Sister Clare is coming.
- She is? Really?
Sister Clare is coming!
Sister Clare is coming.
Sister Clare!
There she is.
Good day, Sister Clare.
Come.
So many memories.
This is the chapel in which
Sister Clare devoted herself to God.
Beautiful Sister Clare.
Hail Holy Queen,
Mary, mother of God.
You were chosen to be a virgin
by our heavenly Father,
who consecrated you
with his beloved son and Holy Spirit.
In you every grace and virtue
finds its fullness.
Hail to her tabernacle,
hail to her vestment.
Hail, daughter and handmaid
of our heavenly Father,
mother of our beloved Lord Jesus Christ,
and spouse of the Holy Spirit.
- He took my cape!
- Be quiet.
Be quiet! Brother Ginepro is naked.
But he took my cape!
...for St. Michael the Archangel
and all the saints,
his beloved Lord, Jesus Christ,
who abides with the Father
and reigns forever. Amen.
My cape!
What have you done?
Didn't Francis command you
not to give away your tunic?
Yes, but today I met
a poor man who asked for alms.
I had some ricotta,
but I couldn't give that to him.
So I said, " I have nothing
to give you but my tunic.
But my Father has ordered me
not to give it to anyone.
But if you took it off my back,
I wouldn't resist."
Let's go.
My cape!
Have pity! You saw he was naked.
They covered him up.
My blessings!
Take it to a poor brother.
No, you take it.
Let's go.
Last night
I was visited
once again by the devil.
But he left empty-handed,
because I have a very simple means
of driving him away.
When I feel him drawing near
to enter inside me,
I immediately shut
the door to my heart
and seek shelter
in holy contemplation.
When he knocks on the door,
I call out from inside,
"Stay out, evil one.
This inn is occupied
and there's no more room."
So the devil, defeated, leaves not only me
but all the area around me.
- My God.
- God.
And the people of Assisi
saw a fiery red horizon.
They ran to St. Mary of the Angels,
thinking there was a fire.
The sky had been set ablaze
by the words of Clare and Francis
inflamed with the love of God.
How Brother Ginepro
cut off a pig's foot
to give to a sick brother.
I always have to stay home.
That's all right.
Today we also have Brother Amarsebello
here, weak from fasting.
I made him this soup.
- Soup?
- It will do him good.
- Good!
Taste it.
Don't you think it smells good?
I doubt he'll be able to eat it,
but I'll take it to him anyway.
Brother, I've made you something
fit to revive the dead.
Thank you, Brother.
I understand, but in your condition
you shouldn't fast.
If our Father Francis were here,
he'd order you to eat it
out of holy obedience.
It's not for self-mortification
that I refrain from eating.
That's not true.
We all know you're always fasting.
I know what would do you good.
A nice boiled leg of chicken,
or a river trout
with some roasted sausages,
a fresh egg and some ricotta.
Then what do you want?
What can I get you?
A pig's foot would be
of enormous comfort.
You'll have it in no time.
He wouldn't eat it,
but he expressed
a desire for pigs' feet.
Can you find some?
If only God would help me find
a pig who'd offer his foot.
- You'll find one.
- Give me the knife.
- It will be as God wishes.
- Let us hope in God.
Brother pigs,
the Lord has placed you on my path
to help me.
Listen to me.
Brother Pig, listen to me, please.
Most handsome pig,
with your succulent foot
would you grant
my sick brother's wish?
I promise I won't hurt you.
The Lord will help us in need.
Think, brother, of the
few opportunities we have to do good.
Thank you, Lord, for the good that
that pig and I will do with this foot.
- I got one!
- You got one!
- Listen. He's thanking the Lord too.
- Thanking the Lord.
Amarsebello, I got a pig's foot.
- What is it, Brother Ginepro?
- Nothing.
What a wonderful smell!
Thieves!
Criminals!
You cut off my pig's foot!
You call this doing good?
Calm down, brother.
What happened?
One of your friars
cut off my pig's foot.
I'm sorry, but did you see him do it?
If I had, I'd have
cracked his head open!
I know who it was.
You're up to your tricks again.
And you call yourself a simple friar!
I did a good deed.
Ginepro, why did you commit
such a scandalous act?
No, Father, Brother Pig and I
have done a good deed.
The pig was happy too.
Isn't that true, Giovanni?
I command you to run after that man
and beg his forgiveness.
Promise to make it up to him
so he'll have no more quarrel with us.
I'm on my way.
And don't be stingy
with your penance.
We'll need a lot of hair, won't we?
That would be nice.
All for God.
Listen to me.
You too, Brother Swineherd,
can rejoice with Brother Pig...
because he granted
my sick brother's wish.
Rejoice! Please listen.
We helped a sick brother.
Aren't you glad?
Here, you vagrants. Eat!
Just don't let me see you again
or I'll break your skulls open!
I'll break your skull open!
He threw Brother Pig on the ground!
- I told you I appeased him.
- O merciful God!
He threw Brother Pig on the ground!
- What shall we do with it?
- We could give it to the poor.
It's the right thing to do.
- I'll take care of it right away.
How Francis,
praying one night in the woods,
met the leper.
My Lord and my all.
My God...
nailed on the cross.
To love you in the company
of my brothers.
Nailed on the cross.
My God.
My God!
My Lord and my all!
O great God.
How Brother Ginepro
cooked enough food for two weeks,
and Francis, moved by his zeal,
gave him permission to preach.
I have an idea.
Now that we have all this food,
shall we cook it all at once?
That way it'll last two weeks.
Or even more.
- More.
Then we can go preach too.
Wouldn't you like that?
- Sure.
- I hope Francis will be glad too.
- Of course.
- And the poor.
- Sure.
Where will we find a pot
big enough for all this?
Ask the shepherds.
- Good idea.
- They'll have one.
I'll find one there with God's help.
May it be to Francis's honor.
Get lots of greens.
Lots of greens.
What are you doing? Not that!
Get more wood.
- What are you doing?
- The wood.
Another one.
No, the rest of the greens!
The greens!
Ginepro!
Come quick!
The fire's going out!
Hurry!
Come quickly!
The fire's going out.
Ginepro's making broth tonight.
Don't let it go out!
We have to make the broth!
What are you doing?
- I don't want the fire to go out.
Don't put so much wood on the fire!
You'll ruin everything!
- I'm going crazy!
- No, that's enough!
- That's enough!
Don't put that on.
- Why not?
What are you doing?
Beautiful Francis!
What's going on?
I'm cooking two weeks' worth of food.
Then we can all go preach.
My God!
This soup will be good for the brain.
There are hens in it
that will make our bodies humble.
Free of cares for dinner and supper,
we can all go preach.
Ginepro, come here.
I grant you permission
to go and preach.
But you must begin
each sermon with these words:
"I talk and talk
yet accomplish little."
It's better to preach by example
than by words.
How Brother Ginepro
was judged on the gallows,
and how his humility vanquished
the ferocity of the tyrant Nicolaio.
- Get off, little girl.
- I don't want to.
Get on the other end.
Where did you get that thing?
- Nicolaio's soldiers left it.
- Who's he?
- The tyrant laying siege to Viterbo.
- Since when?
- Three months ago.
- Are they still there?
- Yes.
This is a good chance.
I'll go there right away.
Little girl, come here.
Good-bye. Have fun.
You wanna bet he's going
to win again?
No, his nose may bleed easily,
but he's not as full-blooded as I am.
I bet he can't fill the cup.
I say he can!
I say he can't!
I talk and talk,
yet accomplish little.
My God, I thank you,
because I finally understand
that it's not by words but by example
that souls are won.
- What's going on?
- They're playing around.
Something must have happened.
Let's go and see.
- What's going on over there?
- What's happening?
They're playing with a beggar.
Bring him here!
Go and get him.
Silence!
Search him.
- An awl and a flint.
- Very well.
Club him over the head
and kill him.
Enough! Let me try.
What have you done
with this damn armor?
It's wearing out my neck!
Bastards, take this off!
Let me do it.
No! With your poor aim, you nearly
chopped off the last one's rump!
- I'll show you.
- Wait.
Would you kill him without even
calling one of their priests?
That's right. Let's call one.
- Who will go?
- I will.
Call the man who follows behind us
and buries the dead.
Why bother with a priest?
He has to die anyway.
Give him some wine instead,
or play some music ！
he'll die quite nicely either way.
Cute little mouse!
So small, yet so intent
on killing our master.
Leave us.
My son,
I've come to offer
the consolation of our faith.
In the name of the Father,
the Son and the Holy Spirit.
Tell me:
Who are you?
A sinner.
What sins do you have to confess?
Very many.
- Where are you from?
- Assisi.
- What is your name?
- Ginepro. Why?
The same Ginepro
who is a companion to Francis,
who is as kind as a mother?
And meek as a lamb.
Listen to me, by God!
I know this man.
He is a friend to all.
I'm going to speak to Nicolaio.
O lord! O lord!
O Nicolaio!
You're making a serious mistake.
You're killing an innocent man.
What are you talking about?
Who are you?
Nibbio, pull up my face plate.
Open this thing!
What innocent man?
The man you just condemned.
That slug meant to kill me.
Nibbio, show him the weapons.
No, these are work tools.
With this he lights the fire,
and the awl is for fixing his sandals.
I got word a killer would come
from Viterbo in beggar's clothing,
and that I would
know him by those tools.
This is a diabolical conspiracy.
I know him.
He's a disciple of a poor man,
a friend of the church.
Francis, the son of a rich man.
He gave everything to the poor
and lives in the woods with his friends,
as free as a bird.
His followers are many,
because he loves the humble.
He who despises the world
has a heart full of hatred.
Ergo, he's a venomous being.
I deny your assertion
and make a distinction.
Aristotle also says, does he not,
that he who despises the world
protects himself from pain, ergo ！
I know the world too,
and this is how the poor are.
They preach poverty
only to steal and kill.
I've also heard that
they refuse everything,
and that they're incapable
of harming anyone.
Ergo, bring him back here.
I want to question him myself!
Get back, the rest of you.
Tell me, who are you?
A terrible sinner.
Take my helmet off.
Nibbio, where are you?
Hurry up!
Quick!
Is it true
you would betray us
to the men of Viterbo?
I am a terrible traitor
and unworthy of all favor.
But did you want to kill me, Nicolaio,
with that flint,
and then set fire to the camp?
Me?
I was just ！
I'm a terrible sinner.
I'd do far worse
than those things you say
if God weren't watching over me.
If this is Ginepro, imagine Francis.
See what truth there is in his words.
Before God we are always more guilty
than men could ever say.
First of all, because we're not
grateful to God in the slightest.
Secondly, because we have little
or no love for our neighbor.
And we would be
even more vile and guilty
if God in his mercy didn't assist us.
- I don't understand these words.
- Nor do I!
Get this armor off me, now!
Quick!
- But, Nicolaio ！
- Get out of here.
Take him to my tent.
Not you!
Hurry!
Go away.
Sound the rally!
We're lifting the siege!
How Brother Francis
and Brother Leone
experienced those things
that are perfect happiness.
Leone, my brother, lamb of our Lord,
even were we able
to restore sight to the blind,
straighten the limbs of the crippled,
banish all demons,
restore hearing to the deaf
and speech to the mute,
and bring the dead back to life,
that would not be perfect happiness.
Thief! Thief!
Murderer!
- He's dead.
- Did you see that, Brother?
He wanted my gold,
but I punished him severely.
Brother, what have you done?
Is a bit of gold worth a man's life?
Take this offering.
May he rest in peace.
Brother Leone,
lamb of our good Lord,
even were we able to speak
the language of the angels
and know the secrets of the heart,
even that would not
constitute perfect happiness.
O Leone, even were we able
to predict the future
and know nature's secrets,
even that would not be
perfect happiness.
O Brother Leone, even were we to convert
the infidels to the faith of Christ,
it would not
bring us perfect happiness.
Please, Brother, where does
perfect happiness reside?
Look, a house.
Let us go and see if people there
wish to praise Jesus with us.
God in his mercy will show us
where perfect happiness lies.
Who is it?
Would you give us alms, brother?
We're poor friars who wander
for the love of people's souls.
Hear us, brother.
We'll show you how to serve Jesus Christ.
Serve Jesus Christ with us.
Why won't you serve
Jesus Christ with us?
I told you scoundrels to get out of here.
Stop bothering people!
Brother, give us alms.
Serve Jesus Christ with us.
I'll show you how I serve Jesus Christ!
Get out of here!
Thieves! Lazy bums!
Swindlers! Out!
Take that! Get out!
I'll take care of you! Get out!
Get out!
Be gone, you knaves, scoundrels,
good-for-nothings!
- We just asked for charity.
- I'll show you charity with my club!
I'll beat you as hard as I can,
one knot at a time.
You'll feel every knot in my club.
Take that! And that!
- Think of your soul.
- Think of your own soul!
And if you want more, just keep
bothering people in their homes!
O Brother Leone,
lamb of our good Lord,
now that we've borne all this
for the love of our blessed Christ,
know that in this resides
perfect happiness.
Because above all the gifts
Christ bestows on his servants
is that of triumphing over ourselves
and bearing every evil deed
and tribulation out of love for him.
In this alone lies perfect happiness.
How Saint Francis left
St. Mary of the Angels with his friars
and traveled the world
preaching peace.
They're coming, Francis!
Come, Francis!
Here they are, Francis.
They're here.
We didn't find many.
No one would accept our alms.
They say we're poor.
Come. We're leaving and want
to leave you our gardens.
I'm 84 years old.
In April I'll be 85.
Many happy returns.
Our little chapel is lovely, isn't it?
Come.
Our oil, bread and nuts.
These are simple things,
but we bequeath them to you.
But you must take care
of our little chapel,
for we're going out into the world
to preach, aren't we?
- I can't go.
- Why not?
I can't go with my cape.
You're right.
An apostle wears neither cape nor shoes.
You have more than you need.
Good for you.
Shall we give it to the poor?
- Yes, to the poor.
My cape and shoes to the poor.
- Happy now?
- Yes.
- He needs a hood.
- Right away.
God bless you, children,
and good-bye.
I take only my faith with me.
My heart stays here with you.
Good-bye, Brother Nightingale.
Good-bye, Brother Tree,
who sheltered us in your shade.
Good-bye, blessed earth.
Good-bye, Brother Birds.
- Good-bye, dear little home.
- Good-bye, St. Mary of the Angels.
Peace unto you, brothers.
Peace.
We'll give some to the poor...
and keep some for ourselves.
- Thank you, brothers.
- We'll give you what we have.
Here, take my cane as well.
Peace unto you.
Come, Father, come.
May God reward you.
Giovanni, bring the gifts to Father.
Thank you, and God bless you.
- God bless you all.
- Peace unto you.
Brothers, I'm left with nothing.
Me too, and I have
15 children to support!
Calm down.
Now that we've given you everything,
let us go and thank the Lord.
Keep calm, for the love of God.
Father Silvestro, you who are a priest,
bless us in God's name.
- Lord, save your servants.
- O Lord, we place our trust in you.
- Send us, O Lord, your help from above.
- Protect us from the devil.
- Be our salvation.
- Against our enemies.
- Lord, show us the way.
- And teach us your path.
- May you guide our steps.
- In the way of your commandments.
- Good-bye, Sister. God bless you.
- Peace.
We're here.
Giovanni, we're waiting for you.
Giovanni's coming.
My children, the time has come
to go our separate ways.
From now on, each will travel
and preach on his own.
- Father, which way should we go?
- The way shown by God.
And how will we know God's will?
I command you, out of holy obedience,
to spin around where you stand,
the way children do at play,
and don't stop spinning
until you're dizzy.
Aren't you dizzy?
Still not dizzy?
- Are you all right?
- Now I'm dizzy.
Come, Giovanni.
My head's spinning!
Amarsebello, which way
were you facing when you fell?
Toward Siena, like me.
- And you, Bernardo?
- Toward Florence.
- Ginepro?
- Toward Arezzo.
- Elia?
- Toward Pisa.
- Ruffino?
- Toward Spoleto.
- Egidio?
- Toward Foligno.
And you, Giovanni,
which way were you facing?
That way, where that sparrow
hops among the trees.
Then you will follow that sparrow,
as it's surely the path
the Lord has shown you.
Now, my children, go forth
into the world and preach peace.
end
唹頭儿崙Alaundo
忖鳥崙恬jj117