http://dailysubs.net for 5 million subtitles
Not! ? Ra Put me down!
Hold me there,
v? i, they'll kill you!
N ?? s!
? Do not kill him!
Assholes!
Not!
INSTITUTE OF ATLANTA, GEORGIA
10 years later.
KING KONG
LIVES
I'm sorry.
It s? Da l? Ks Institute
7 million dollars to pay!
She knows how much it will cost.
He has been a participant in this moment,
Kong if s? damer? tmi restored.
S? Damel not hurt anything.
That damn jigger
?? t tab like a Swiss clock.
The thing is it blood.
He has been in a comatose state for too long.
He has h ?? Bimas blood cells.
We have r ?? kinud, not just this
the type of animal, whose mix with the plasma Kong's.
But you? We said at the time,
that you can handle it!
If s? Da would have been ready for it,
I might have to operate without blood? be live.
When he opened n ?? d l? Ikame,
then he dies.
There is just? One thing,
that Kong v? p ?? iks sta.
What?
Suck.
If it had been up to you, you are pampered,
we only Guaira.
But this is not n? At recommended diamonds
? Ne le 20 years.
So l? Petage squeal and come.
What are you afraid of? Ah, watch n ?? d,
It's so hot that even jaguars sleep.
Would you like a siesta?
Okay, do v? Ike a siesta then.
If anyone out there is, t? Mmaku with good fog,
because Mitch to doze off.
And it k? Ib also about you.
Come here.
Find your own bunk.
Oh, shit!
Easy, boy ...
Still, a great pal ...
No no!
? Do not kill him!
This is Borneo,
it is at the end of the tube.
H? RRA Mitchell, you need to k? R ?? vemini Kima,
We have trouble hearing you.
Hello? Hello?
Can you hear me n ?? d? Hello?
N ?? d hear from you,
h? RRA Mitchell.
I? Businessman,
Doctor Ingersoll.
And my subordinate sorting offer
even if today ?? r gime.
H? RRA Mitchell, I m? Istan to others? Universities
are also interested in your specimens,
But we have a very h? davajalik get
Blood plasma? be live.
I can m ?? blood, doctor,
I ?? m n p whole damned? rdiku.
I m? Istan and the
v? prodigy to discuss it later,
But at the moment, we have the boys
Get needed as soon as possible by.
Boys? Monkey is not
Boy, she has t? DRUK.
H? RRA Mitchell, here Dr Hughes,
Primate studies department head.
Do you? Tlesite that your animal is a female?
Yes.
And p? Ris pretty well.
Not! We can not be here to bring the females.
What are you ?? r States?
S ?? r, this is not some kind of hemorrhoids
l? ikus, we transplanted s? dant!
I am aware of that, Doctor Franklin.
V? Ikseimgi? Irritation when Kong is recovering ...
Whoa, who's there ?? r gib?
I warn you, I'm on the other line to Harvard!
Get the blood, let no one
The second V? tab bitch myself.
You? Tlete century bargain? Ra.
Amy, you'll appreciate the risk? Le.
Money ?? r gib, doctor.
V? Ite my monkey Disneyland K? Lla go.
We will provide a prepayment
10, 000 dollars.
Well ...
That my bread k? Ll miss the ham ...
What if the operation eba? Successful?
Then j ?? b to something else? Universities
the only living monkey.
Mitchell ...
We have agreed.
T? Nan you, Doctor.
Hey, mama, I'm rich!
It p? Rdik make me rich!
Peace, peace, yes there ...
K? Ik is fine,
I am here.
This way, I'm here,
I'll take care of you.
It seems that we need you
celebrity to get used to.
You watch out, buddy ...
This little lady is
I think about you in the v? ETUD.
H? RRA Mitchell, Andrew Ingersoll.
Welcome!
H? RRA Mitchell, h? RRA Mitchell, how are you
monkey in the jungles stick dsite ?? p?
J? Shootin banana trail.
Do you try to mate her?
Can m? Tlete that personally?
Make a free way to free ...
From where he got a hat?
Beverly Hills hiking camp?
I think he's cute.
Ladies and h? NRAs, it certainly puts into place
Atlanta Institute of Scientific m? Rkimisv ?? rsuse.
Forget about the Institute, Professor,
v Bring a monkey? Lja!
H? RRA Mitchell, this is Doctor Franklin,
surgeon who places l? BI Kong operation.
Ah, the girl on the phone?
Lots? Nne, h? RRA Mitchell.
When will the surgery take place?
How blood from a female V? Are taken the?
- Institute of Plasma Center has been put in place.
Every minute of the bill.
V? Tke it easy!
You're in the company of Miss!
You, Miss Kong,
what you want!
You k? Ik ...
The valve is opened.
K? Ik is ready.
V would have seen the a couple of pints until j? TTA.
He n? Gi blood pumping after a terrific v? Lja.
Female recovers well by the h? RRA Mitchell.
Yes, there n? In Regulation storage area
where you toppisite it.
Kong after spending a fortune,
? Ach spend a few bucks after my monkey?
We construct a permanent abode
From 10-mile distance.
It will be ready in a couple of n? Dala p? RAST.
By the Gentiles, for it is necessary?
History.
Okay, we start ?? t le.
Your shtick.
This is good.
Strengthen then a little pressure.
Image of blood? Ra.
Increase imamissurvet.
A little further.
Just like that...
Sain k? Tte.
The clamp.
What the hell ...
Peaklamber.
- T? Is sucked!
Bleeding must be closed.
S? Steem? Says? Les!
Soak up the still.
- Working on it.
Give me a clamp.
- The seal!
As soon as the ready.
The artery is closed.
Let it down.
Move k? L LGE? Hemale.
Absorber removed.
Amy ...
Amy!
Welcome Kong.
Welcome back.
Ah, you kiimaloom!
He feels the bitch l? HNA
even from a mile away.
Multiple sensors it again k? Ljes is?
He is? Hexa electrode v? T Lja? Mmanud.
Sedative kan ?? l still k? Ljes.
Lying down, not lying ...
S? Damer? Tm?
Irregular.
- Alpha Data?
N indicates in AGGRESSIVE EEG activity.
Mike?
- Verer? Hk falls.
He gives j? Rele!
Stunned by her.
... The v? Lja that their language
t holding agency was reduced that mule.
There's your star.
Well, boy? Rkvel.
With excellent compa- ny!
- And we h? Das.
Why then?
Female to trans out and immediately.
Kong, he felt a presence.
- They are each miles!
It is not enough, he also hears him.
We give an PURPOSE? RGI, which
Group healed.
I am not against you
nothing, h? RRA Mitchell,
n? just a quick Gite
v making money? slushiness.
Well, keep in n ?? d stick ...
See ECG, ?? Repeal we lost him.
She was p? Sti and sample
? H Lesse with bars? Pata.
He tried to female p ?? it.
We gave him a quantity Fluorescini,
V that? iks kill whales down.
We can not be an all time tranquilizer s? Stida,
s not her? dame situation.
He is? The right to,
they have to relocate.
Where? New residential buildings are not ready yet.
Perform they are ready.
For a long time l? Hex?
2 p? Eva as ?? P? L ev? Bi ?? t Tada.
Female within 48 hours l seen the coming.
Wait a minute, I'll send you to the car.
Hey, did you now, after all,
Kong's return to the l? he?
With l? Hen yes.
Rest, you need a break
as much as she did.
Hey, sorry about your shade p? RAST,
I do not m? istnud ...
Forget? Ra.
V? S in you home? Idutada?
If you wish?
'Well, I want to be sure
home to the eloquently j? uad ...
I do not? Rita k? L ?? a, LGE, or something ...
Big T? Nu, h? RRA Mitchell,
However, I can navigate themselves.
Look ...
If it's something you t? Combines the ...
I think it was with excellent RANE
operation there.
T? Unites k? Ll.
Head ?? d.
- Yeah, good ?? d.
Be careful!
Come on.
I want to be here by dawn l? Inus.
- Just so h? RRA Ingersoll.
There's too much l? Rmi,
You scared him? ra.
J? Tke it to us, h? RRA Mitchell,
we know what we're doing.
Calm down, big boy,
wait a second ...
All right, shake his corner.
Wait until the sedative
m? Juma starts.
You should have
tuimestusp? ssi to use.
I did not shoot him,
drugged food is enough k? ll.
Not if he does ?? s.
Let v? Rk below.
KLC calls SS-1'te.
KLC calls SS-1'te!
Shit ...
Boss!
Let him go,
they v? t rgud tear it? kkideks!
Hull are v? I?
- We have to abort this entire thing!
Just.
- Yes.
Let's get this thing l? Puni.
Boss, Masmanski rang!
Another monkey is crazy l? Inus!
Boss! Boss!
Buckets, t? Crank them down!
You stupid jerk,
We would they m? Both were suspended!
Suspended?
You could have killed them ?!
Operational Group, Colonel Nevitti leadership,
has closed the 50-m area ruutmiilise? ers.
So far it seems that the monkeys v? Ldivad
human-populated areas.
We're back to the situation,
there will be changes.
J ?? Stop!
Well, pagan v? A.
And where I L? Hed?
- There, where you are.
P? L rgutki you? Hed, there m? Ers
jalav is healthy? e battalion!
Far do you think you j? Uad?
And as far as I j? Uad ...
... Your rent? Ruga?
Come apart.
N? E, make yourself useful.
Are you r ?? s kinud this? Jav? E Pop,
it that his name ...
Col. Nevitt?
- Yes.
He? Said that shoots down k? Ik civilians,
who invade his territory.
Cool.
Here is the area where the army? Ra close.
Our monkeys are out there somewhere.
There are reports of these fucking civilians?
I looked into the car data, is it? SJA
Doctor Franklin's registered in someone else's name.
He is the doctor who operated Kong.
We believe that a man with whom he is,
This is Mitchell's character.
Neil l? HEB DOCTOR needed
when we begin to inject the gas.
Morning, s ?? r.
enemy detection
should not be difficult.
They are 50 ft k? Rged and bear
? Likonda, which s? Ndisid.
See, that every man would be a mask,
and that it would be willing to put up,? the right side? Leval.
Gas will drape the helicopter,
you will see that after the age of monkeys,
not to us.
Just so, s ?? r.
All right, l? HME.
Mesfin? DALATE N? LVAK
Shit!
If this car is still m? Ni k? Ik,
you'd better check it? les.
Ah, Jesus ...
Borneo, you would have been necessary!
If I were premature
death wish.
What is this?
Make Up Box?
This is Kong's? Damemonitor.
There are 22 remote controllable inputs
? Implant connected microprocessor.
The great thing, l? HME.
When Kong s? Da ?? t is not right,
then this makeup kit makes it time.
Let the bag here.
You know, l Kong? Hex here
? He step in? Le.
I wish that I could Kong.
Wait a moment.
No way.
What the box it!
P ?? sta it!
Are you crazy ?!
Are you okay?
Yes.
S? Damemonitor.
Where is it?
There.
Come on.
N? Ita own k? Tt.
- Jeez, how did this happen?
Ah, trans worry that p? RAST.
Hold on.
- What is?
It is not v? Ga s? GAV.
I would not want to p? Letik in l? Hex.
I need you.
You're the only 10-mile radius,
John Wayne who can not m? NGI.
Okay, ready.
T? Ber, doctor.
Are you guess l? K bi? Lmunud?
- I have a change of clothes.
They are there? Leval.
Not very far away.
Well, how do we boys l? HEB?
Unbelievable ...
Furthermore, k? Ike this, he s? Da
even become stronger.
It seems that your d ?? j t? Druk-S? Brast without.
You know ...
They will be able to take
even disastrous appearance.
V? I Borneo v? I Kong island ...
It would only need money for our reserves.
We should find a place,
where to camp.
Hey, here's a good place.
Kong for this m? Jus ...
Are you sure?
We are, after all, as well as primates.
It is l? Inus!
Couple is? Ksinda.
What?
Kong l have seen the.
Good k? Ll bring great bird place!
T? V crank them? Rgud him? Mber!
See that she would
properly secured!
Helicopters, t? Crank it down!
P? Rutusgranaadid!
Keep him away to
Bitch get out of here!
L? V HME? Tame him!
K? E-si schedules of the m? Etipu
back to land.
Shake the monkey m? L etippu? KSU.
Just so, s ?? r.
We've got it, guys.
Clear. S ?? r, wind speed,
T? risen to 40.
Send helicopters to go,
before m? ne lose.
H? Ik? Ksused,
Col. Nevitt here!
L ?? ge hairy motherfucker down!
Let's move!
Come on, l? HME.
Stop!
- P si still, buddy.
We got a civilian k? Tte, s ?? r.
He has you cornered,
You do not have to finish him.
It's no longer yours
problem, buddy.
She is mine.
Write great? Kist fire!
Not!
Even though you do not p ?? Kong for this life.
U.S. ARMY primate HOIUDIVISION
V Perform? Rav open.
I do not m? Ista why they
pour the stuff is still there.
He did not touch it.
Did not go in there and clean up? Ra?
Yes ...
J? N rgmisel? Dalal, perhaps.
signed by the Minister of Defence
itself.
God t? Directed towards!
- Col. Nevitt can not keep away from us anymore.
Let's move, God knows,
what situation he V? ib be.
Mitch is still not hear anything?
- He's somewhere in Borneo p? Rap? Eight.
Knowing him, we do not hear from him
until he has achieved success.
Pray that he would achieve.
This would make k? Ik.
Your invaluable input survey
p? hjus why two of my
the men are dead.
His p? RAST another 104 s? Durit m? Ngivad here
vangivalvureid, rather than to be in training.
Let me just
be straightforward.
He is the p? Hjus why I'm here rotiurus
Since last summer, had to pass.
K? Ske ignoring you here? Ra p ?? se does.
Army is too t? Absolutely
skilled doctors, Doctor Franklin.
They check your
p? rdikut every two n? Dala thereafter.
I l? Hen on.
- Someone did not l? He in there!
How long has he been like this k? Itunud is?
Three months, maybe four. Who the hell knows.
She does not h? Da anything.
Is that your diagnosis, Colonel?
What the hell is p? Rdik Halab?
I? Tleń why.
Kong p? RAST.
- Female mourns.
No, he senses something.
Kong is alive.
? Ra is naeruv ?? RNE.
- I feel it also.
Okay, I've wasted enough time.
Sergeant!
S ?? r?
Give them two minutes Gorillas
and get them to go away.
Just so, s ?? r.
K? L is lastusaeg? Bi, Miss.
Forever.
I know that Kong is alive.
The Army has every centimeter
State of l? BI kamminud.
They found nothing.
- Exactly.
The body is not.
Be the n ?? d, Ben, do you? Said at the time that some primate
Types of shedding a pair for life.
To return to the male.
- Not if he's dead.
R ?? gime animal in proteiininorm
has over 500 kilos of p? EVAs.
View t? N ele? PSJ, Amy.
Kong, the size of the animal organism,
isolated from its natural
V environment? i under human care,
He would not just collect
an appropriate range of protein.
Hello v ?? ras.
When Mitch? Says
that drives to the times ...
K? Ten thousand acres in Borneo m? Gismaad.
And it l? HEB Institute
pay for only three million.
Hey, did you get my other t? Druks? Bra
not jealous of you?
N ?? d been, I do not have him
n several months? inus.
Like no one else about us.
What are you ?? r States?
They keep it underground.
Nevitt allowed us to him? He once n? Ha
and then put the base closed.
What ?!
There is something wrong with him. He is not sleeping or S ??.
I think he's dying.
You can p ?? se in there, Mitch!
- This is the case, we'll see about that!
? Ra fire? Tell ya that Nevitt is h? Ivatud!
Because he has been around for 4 hours h? Ivatud had!
S ?? r, if you submit your request to
? Igeid channels ...
Channels? Fuck!
Mitch!
Stop it!
If you are s? Ber wants more? Hte ...
Then give r ?? Muga yet.
V? He calmly partner.
Mitch!
We got the Reserve.
We Nevittile confront.
God k? Ll, you have not slept in 24 hours.
L? HME home.
Be the n ?? d, relax.
Wonderful eyes, that's what you are.
The largest and pruunimad eyes,
I n? I inus.
R ?? gi yet, to me
talk like your honey ...
Come on!
Come on, here we go!
It is Kong!
Oh my God!
Throw it p? Ss to go!
? Ra Shoot!
Come on, babe, it's going to be the Gulf.
Keep k? Vashti stick
and close your eyes.
Latest news. Large gorilla headed
north of the party to join his companions.
? Le ?? it is peaceful
recreation center could hunt,
bringing together k? ik free
Hunters number of miles in radius.
What the hell is this?
Liberation?
You there!
Are these guns loaded?
But, of course, General.
As we are even!
You let one another down.
V You want to get killed? I?
I put this monkey
car bonnet k? Lge!
We are companions.
Down there!
This must be our boy's t ??.
? Said at the time, after all, to know how it s? Ita?
I suggest that we
a few miles above him.
We have to hurry.
Damned sand fleas.
- Be quiet!
You hear anything?
Jesus!
- God, look how big it is!
Vince, I guess I have to go to church.
See how great he is ...
Bring it.
Come on, make me a picture.
So be it.
Smile!
? One of yet, we do? HE yet.
It's only the stench of breath, boy.
Bring an suuv? Rskendit.
Bring a br? Ndit!
- Yeah, right, br? Ndit.
Well ...
Hey, this is v ?? rt stuff, boy!
You know what ...
I do not like this boy's attitude.
- Yes, we need a little bit of respect? Petama.
Helps k? Ll Will.
J? He damn animal alone.
Oh, Mrs. Johnstone ...
Have him in v? V ETUD? I?
You want to kill him, then kill,
But what? Do not torment the poor son of a bitch.
We did not torture him, Jay,
we just saute it slightly.
Hell, Vince, I? Tlesin that l? Petage.
Well, Jay ...
You L? Hed? Le k? Are you, boy.
Thus, n ?? d? Deceive you some manners,
you big ugly son of a bitch.
What the hell ...
Run!
Get out of the hell away ...
Just so, Kong,
Come up here.
Are you crazy!
If l? Hedal do you have to be?
It s? R da? Tmist OR OFF.
I have to set it up.
I can not j? Udnud j? L rjendit to teach.
It s? Da does not have to p? Evagi adopted.
Well, he probably does not know it.
Come on.
Oh my God...
They are hunters.
D? Namiit there? Leval ...
He v? Is to be half buried.
And then they l? Bustas would end with him ...
Well, Kong, n ?? d have you killed ...
No longer is nothing to prevent them from killing you.
No, still? One thing ...
We need to go, come on.
Well, l? HME!
S ?? r. ? Huluure confirmed.
The enemy headed straight here.
Distance?
- 11 miles.
S ?? r, General Santander
D.C.'st is on the phone.
The orders are still
kinnip ?? k, not killing.
What channel it to me k? Tte get? Ritab?
Alfa, s ?? r.
This channel is busy, Major.
Just so, s ?? r.
Mitch ...
Army sent in monkeys.
Gen. Santi dispositions are
kinniv? onvarieties, not killing.
? Ksused Colonel Nevitti leadership,
has left the headquarters,
to block and redirect the male gorilla tee
to where he can be detained da ?? p.
Oh, no ...
Father, l ?? b me.
Okay, call his men together,
the colonel's orders.
Bring your own? Ksused to tanks.
Come on.
That's right, Sergeant.
They are waiting for him.
They are doing it t? Kkideks.
Ms. Kong's detention premise.
?? We are not p se in any way in there.
I think we can.
Soon l? HEB blind.
Fire!
You there!
Go back!
Come on! S? To the east!
You son of a bitch!
J? Rele him!
I j? Rel!
L Where are you? Relations?
Captain called us.
- It should not be just a two s? Durit j? TTA.
Captain V? Ib call ...
- I do not care what the captain? Said.
Col. Nevitt? Said that the service should not be da j ??
more than two.
There's a whole battalion.
- If the Colonel gets us Nevitt k? Tte ...
Damn.
Hello there!
You there, stop!
Yes, the fifth layer hears.
Clear ... Clear!
Over yourself p? Sti,
Here is compromised.
What the hell is going on?
- Invade!
Oh, excuse me ...
- Whoa, mama!
God, what have they done to him?
They have not done anything.
She is pregnant.
Here.
K? Ik be times t? DRUK.
P stame you here ?? v? Lja.
K? Ik be okay.
Calmly, t? DRUK.
No. Oh, no ... - Mitch Beware!
Relax, do not ...
No, t? DRUK. No no...
Mitch!
Is that you, Elroy?
You do not have a hundred years n seen the boy!
Not v? I never know with whom they have family
A total of reunions? ib get!
T? He si.
How could v? Ikese keelekastega that?
Fire!
No, female V? Ib get shot!
It s? Will indicate!
- I do? Tlesin flames, hell!
V? Tke it off!
S? Dur!
Come on, you v? Rdjas, fire ...
Oh my God...
N? Ita send him.
N? Ita send him sons.
He is there, Kong. You have to
end of its j? rele stretch.
Stretch, Kong.
Stretch it j? Rele.
KEYSER? 06