Not tomorrow. The day after. Right.
You, me, Gary, Brad. We'll be teeing off at...
- I like Gary.
- Doctor, I'm in a hurry...
We'll tee off at 7:30. If you're not there
because of Gary, come on. I gotta go.
Am I missing something?
Why a head X-ray
when the man was bitten on the hand?
The patient was in a bar fight.
He was admitted at six.
That's 6:00am.
That's when I started my shift.
Where is he now? I'd like to see him.
- They moved him. A night nurse...
- Page me when you find him.
Sure.
I'll do that.
Cora, can you locate a patient for me?
Hey, Ana. Sure.
- Edward Solomon?
- Yep.
- Aren't you off?
- An hour ago.
Here he is. They had him backwards.
Solomon Edward. He's in ICU.
- From a bite?
- I don't know what from.
Toxicology's working him up tomorrow.
- I'm going. Can you let Dr. Dandewar know?
- Sure.
- Thanks.
- Did you talk to Luis about Sunday?
- I will. Night, Cora.
- Night.
- Hey.
- Hey, Ana.
- Let's go. It's starting early.
- Great. Later.
Let's go, let's go!
'... an unconfirmed... '
'... not an isolated... '
Hey, Vivian.
- Look, I can go backwards.
- Let me see.
Hey, that's amazing.
Maybe tomorrow I'll do
a few backward laps with you.
- OK.
- Careful, now, I gotta pull in.
- Say hey to your mom for me, OK?
- OK.
- Hey.
- Hey, you.
You missed it.
They just cut the mailman loose.
No, Richie? The chubby one?
He had such a sweet voice.
I can't believe that.
Hey, you.
Hey, you. Come here.
- How'd it go today?
- Not bad. You?
Good. I'm trading shifts with Cora
so if I take Sunday,
I'll have a three-day weekend
at the end of the month.
- Is that OK?
- Yeah.
I think Cora has a new guy
she's keeping secret.
Really? Wow. Lucky her.
I thought maybe you'd gone out with the girls.
What, and miss date night?
'I decided to take action.
'I went to see Harvey
at the men's weight loss farm... '
'27 horsepower, turbocharged... '
'Stay tuned to this special news bulletin.
'We will return to our regular programming
following this report.'
Vivian's here.
Vivian, honey. Sweetie, are you OK?
Oh, my God. Oh, fuck.
- Call an ambulance!
Vivian!
Luis, Luis, Luis. Let go! Let go!
- Let go! Let go! Let go!
I can't get it!
Hold it! Hold it!
Let go. Let go!
I'm going to call for help.
- 'All circuits are busy at this time.'
- God, no. No.
- 'All circuits are busy... '
- Don't do this to me, please!
911.
- 'All circuits are busy... '
- Luis? What are you doing?
Luis?
Help!
Get back, Ana.
- Get back!
- Just tell me what's going on!
- I told you to get back.
'... emergency broadcast
here in the Milwaukee area.'
'The following is information
for local evacuation centers.
'If you live in Waukesha County... '
Help! Can you help? Please!
'... 22 Robin Lane.
'If you live in southern Milwaukee County,
there's a shelter... '
- '... 1353 Henderson Road.
'If there is no activity where you live,
stay inside and lock all doors.'
- 'If you live in Jefferson County...
'This is the Emergency Broadcast System
for the greater Milwaukee area.
'If you live in Racine County,
there is no information available at this time.
'Please stay inside
and lock all doors and windows.
'Miller Park is no longer
considered a safe haven.
'Please avoid the stadium
and proceed to other locations.
'Meanwhile, civil unrest is still being
reported in the area of the RiverWalk.
- 'Please avoid traveling to... '
'There are unconfirmed reports
that several military personnel... '
'The following locations are still listed on
the Milwaukee Emergency Safe Haven list... '
Give me your car!
Get off me! Get off!
'I'll take your questions.'
'Is it a virus? '
'We don't know.'
'How does it spread? Airborne? '
'Airborne is a possibility.
We don't know.'
'ls this an international
health hazard or a military concern? '
'Both.'
'Are these people alive or dead? '
Hold him down!
- 'We don't know.'
- 'These shelters have been compromised.'
- 'I've lost the teleprompter.'
'... shifted from containment to... '
- 'I've just spoken with the President.
- 'He's in contact with CDC and FEMA.'
- 'No more questions.'
'A US offi...
- 'God, they're here! '
Say something.
Please.
All right, OK. Put the guns down!
What are you doing? He's a cop!
Come on, put the gun down.
I thought you were one of them.
- You do not want to go that way.
- What's that way?
Officer. Sir? You do not want to go that way.
- It's pretty bad.
What about Fort Pastor?
If you had wings.
The road's thick with those motherfuckers.
- How do you know?
- We just tried. Come on.
Back when there was eight of us.
We're going to the mall.
Shit.
Damn.
Hurry up!
Back up.
Open the door.
Lights.
Here.
- No?
- No.
Come on.
Sit right there.
We need to make sure this place is safe.
I'll see if the doors this way are locked.
I'll check down there.
Maybe, Officer, you could go check...
All right. OK.
Maybe it's better you stay here with the gun.
Andre and I will check around.
Baby, I'll be right back.
No, just stay right here. Stay right here.
Shatterproof, asshole.
Shit.
- What happened?
- Come on, move.
Move!
- Which way?
- Here. Elevators.
Let's go, let's go!
Can I see that arm?
I need to suture that.
- Are you OK?
- Yeah.
- Find someplace else.
- We just need a place...
- Maybe you didn't hear me.
- There is no place else.
Tough shit. This is our place
and you can't stay here.
Yeah. And you already trashed Metropolis.
- My wife is pregnant. We can't run.
- His arm...
- Those things are down there.
These are your problems, not mine.
If I put my foot up your ass,
would that be your problem?
Hey, asshole, I'm the one
pointing the gun at you.
He is a cop, CJ.
- So what?
We're not gonna cause any trouble.
Just let us stay here
for a little while. Please.
OK. Come out slowly
and give your weapons to Bart and Terry.
- Don't do it.
- You must be crazy.
You can take your ass on over
to Quality Inn, Shaq.
Huh? You want to do that?
Let's go.
Hey, don't give him that gun.
Fuck.
Smart move.
'Nobody knows what's going on.
There's a lot of blood and bodies.
'There's a slew of fires.
We're going back to a live picture now.'
'One second. Ma'am, are you American? '
All right. Let's go, guys.
Come on. Get your own little TV.
Come on. Let's go.
Excuse me.
Please. Is there a restroom?
No. You're staying here.
Then tell us where in here you'd like us to piss.
It's around the corner, that way.
Whoa, where are you going?
She's not going anywhere alone.
"She's not going anywhere..." This is a
fucking nursery school! Go with them.
'I'm Bill Vibert for 23-V Cable News.
'I'm at one of the collection depots
to interview Sheriff Cahill.
'How do you kill these things? '
'Just shoot 'em in the head.
'They go down permanently when you
shoot 'em in the head. Then burn them.
'Danny! Put another round in that woman!
'Look! She's a twitcher! '
Twitcher!
Now, that is one cool motherfucker.
He's still bleeding. I need to stitch his arm.
- You a fucking doctor?
- No, I'm a fucking nurse.
- 'I know some of these people.'
- First aid kit's in the office.
'What are you gonna do? It's gotta be done.'
- Huh? What did I tell you boys?
- 'Get those bodies off the truck! '
America always sorts its shit out.
You're lucky. He could have bitten it off.
'You're referring to a report
that came in this morning.
'That report was completely... '
'What can we tell people
that don't know what to do? '
'I would suggest
that you come to Fort Pastor.
'If you can't get here,
our search-and-rescue teams will find you.'
My brother's there. He's waiting for me.
What's the holdup, darling?
Hm?
So what's the plan?
The plan is you drink a tall glass
of shut-the-fuck-up.
- OK. That's one idea.
What about locking this place down?
Sooner or later, they'll get in.
That's good. I hadn't thought of that.
No doubt. You probably already thought
about putting a sign up on the roof
cos there's still planes in the air.
Might be good to let them know we're alive.
We can get paint from Case Hardware.
Use doors to board up the weak spots.
That's a solid plan.
CJ, is it?
- Yeah.
- All right, CJ.
Listen up. I'm giving
everybody a job and I expect you to do it.
I don't want to see any half-assin'.
You can start by cleaning up
that mess you made in Metropolis.
Hey, CJ, look!
Terry.
Look at Ben Cozine.
Hey, Ben. Ben!
Christ. Look at him.
Look, he's a twitcher.
TV says you gotta shoot 'em in the head.
TV said a lot of things.
Fuck the fucker.
I told him not to go downstairs.
Let's go. Let's get to work.
Holy shit.
Let's do it.
All right, let's pick him up, then.
Ready? One, two, three.
On two. All right?
One, two.
What are they?
I don't know. Why are they coming here?
Memory, maybe. Instinct.
Maybe they're coming for us.
Look over there.
There's someone on the roof.
His name's Andy. He's alone.
He may as well be on the moon.
Poor guy.
What's he pointing at?
- Helicopter.
- Hey, it's coming.
Fuckin' A, man!
Hey!
- Hey!
- Where's he...?
Please... What's he doing? Where's he going?
No. I mean, they saw us, so...
They'll be coming back, baby.
Don't worry. They'll send somebody.
It's safe here.
We'll just wait for them to come back.
I don't want anybody
sneaking around and stealing shit.
Comprende?
Sweet dreams.
Those assholes are gonna get us killed.
We have to do something.
I'm not doing anything
to create problems for Luda and me.
- The helicopter's coming back soon.
- I hope so.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- It's means it might come and it might not.
What do you mean?
You said it was coming back!
- We have to get to hospital.
- Baby, listen. Don't worry, OK?
This guy, he doesn't know shit.
All right? It's coming back.
My man, I hear you talking a lot,
you're always saying something,
who the fuck are you that we should listen?
Were you like in the Marines?
What the fuck do you do?
I sell televisions at Best Buy.
Wow.
Hey, Officer, how do you like
following a guy that sells TVs?
About as much as I like
following a guy who steals them.
I'm not following anyone.
I'm going to Fort Pastor to get my brother.
'They seem to need to feed on warm flesh.
'Some basic skills remain.
'They don't seem to have much,
if any, reasoning power.'
- 'And how does this spread? '
- This is shit. The same thing all day.
Tell me something I don't know, asshole!
- 'We're going off the air... '
- Wanna hear something that sucks?
'... and switching to
the Emergency Broadcasting System.'
- You know that chick at Dairy Queen?
- 'I don't know when we'll be back.'
- The fat one?
- Yeah.
She was coming over tonight.
I would have tapped that shit.
Bart, dude, everybody's dead, OK?
Your mom's dead. Your brother.
That fat chick at Dairy Queen.
Dead.
- Yeah.
- 'God bless America.'
That sucks too.
'Hell is overflowing
'and Satan is sending his dead to us.
'Why?
'Because
'you have sex out of wedlock,
'you kill unborn children,
'you have man-on-man relations,
'same-sex marriage.
'How do you think your God will judge you?
'Well, friends,
'now we know.
'When there is no more room in hell,
'the dead
'will walk the earth.'
What the hell?
- Hey, dumb-ass.
- Hm?
It's the timers. It's eight o'clock.
Terry.
- Go shut 'em off.
- It's Bart's turn.
You're the trainee, man.
Shit rolls downhill.
I wish somebody
was working at Hallowed Grounds.
How hard is it to make coffee?
I wanted a soya mocha latte with foam.
Faggot.
What are you doing?
What's the news?
Bad.
Hey! Hey!
Hey.
What?
The bathroom in here is fake, it doesn't work.
- I'll tell CJ.
- I'm telling you.
You're the type of cat that goes to church
and all that shit, right?
Yeah, I do all that shit.
So what do you think?
What is this? Is this the end of times?
Cos if it is, I'm fucked.
I'm serious. I've done some bad things.
Oh, I get it. You saw hell yesterday,
now you're scared of going to hell
for all the bad things you've done.
Go in the stall, say five Hail Marys,
wipe your ass,
and you and God can call it even.
You think I feel like I deserve to be here?
- Yeah.
- Well, I don't.
And I'm cool with that.
But that's not it.
I feel like I'm here for another reason.
I feel like I'm here
to bring that baby on this earth
and give it everything that I never had.
I just want the opportunity to change things.
Shit!
CJ!
How did you get out?
Who said you could loot the stores?
- What are we going to do about that truck?
- Nothing.
- There's people in it.
- How do you know they're not fucked up?
- For one thing, they're driving a truck.
Oh, and shooting guns.
We might let the wrong ones in.
Then I'm dead. And I don't want to die.
- Who are the wrong ones?
- Nobody here is sick. It stays that way.
- I think...
- I did not ask for your opinion!
- If you want to argue, argue with this.
- Relax.
Shut your fucking mouth.
- Move the gun.
- You can't turn them away. They'll die.
Tough shit. Self-defense.
- I won't kill anybody.
- I'll kill you.
- Stop it, CJ. Don't do this.
- Shut up!
I'll kill all of you to stay alive.
Get the fucking gun out of my face!
- Oh. You got a mouth on you.
- Somebody should show her how to use it.
- Is there a holding cell?
- Yeah. Back of the security room.
That's real good.
You're gonna get us all killed, dumb-ass!
Fucking traitor.
Get off me.
I hope you got a good plan.
Come on.
- Hey!
- Through here.
- I can't see a damn thing.
- Me, either.
Why is he backing up the truck?
- Through here!
- Hey!
Shit.
What the fuck?
- We gotta go out there.
- Throw that bullshit out of your head.
That's not part of the plan.
Change of plan. I'll open the door.
No.
OK. One, two...
- Don't do it, man.
...three.
Come on, man.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
Shoot them in the head!
I don't see anybody.
- Get back inside!
- Here you go.
- There are six more people in the truck!
Andre!
Thank God. I couldn't stay
in that fucking truck anymore.
Anybody who's injured,
go to Metropolis. I'll take a look at you.
Let me take a look at her.
Can you help me? What's your name?
Glen. Yeah, sure.
Just give me a second to collect myself.
- Thanks.
- OK.
Wait in there. I'll look at your leg.
- Can you hold this?
- Yeah.
- We're just going right there.
- Oh, my arm.
We'll make you nice and comfortable.
We got plenty of food and water.
- Help should be along soon.
Help? You hear that from the same jackass
who said to go to St. Verbena?
- The church downtown?
- Yeah.
It's the first place I went. Some dipshit on
the radio said it was safe. He was wrong.
That's where you got them?
I got a call on the CB from Glen
saying these folks were in the chapel.
- He's a priest?
- No, he plays the organ.
I was in the neighborhood so I picked them up.
- Well done.
- Thanks.
Excuse me, when you two fellows
are done blowing each other,
maybe Davy Crockett can tell us the deal.
Since the TVs went down...
- Excuse me. Whose rig is that?
- It's mine.
- You mind if I borrow it?
- I'm not using it.
- Keys?
- They're in the cab.
- The truck won't make it to Fort Pastor.
- Forget it. That place is fucked.
- Bloodbath city.
- How do you know?
We just came from there.
- Is everyone there dead?
- Dead-ish.
- Yeah.
In the sense that
they all sort of fell down and then...
- I have to see.
- You won't make it.
...got up and...
- I'll get as far as I can.
- One foot.
...started eating each other.
- I'll take my chances.
- Don't be an idiot.
Please. The people here could use your help.
Fuck y'all.
It's nice to see
you've all bonded through this disaster.
- Hey. You need anything?
- No, we're fine.
He's got a bite on his hand.
- She's cold.
That's good, right?
I don't know. It's weird.
An infection this bad
usually comes with a fever.
That guy's arm looks pretty bad.
You should check it out.
- All right. Stay with her for a minute.
- Let me take a look at that.
- I'm fine, really.
They don't hurt much. Tucker could use you
more than me. His ankle's cut pretty bad.
I'll just clean it up a bit.
- You OK?
Ma'am, can I get you something?
Like a glass of water?
Ana! Ana, come here!
Anyone know her name?
Died without a name?
Damn.
You wanna use the other room?
Holy shit!
Holy shit.
I think it's the bites.
Frank said she was walking on her own
five hours ago.
The bites killed her.
The bites brought her back.
How do you know?
I watched it happen.
I felt her pulse, she was gone. Then...
Yesterday I saw the same thing.
I think that's why it spread so fast.
All right.
So who else in the group is bitten?
- Frank for sure.
- And the one with the foot?
Tucker? He says no, he fell.
So it's Frank. Tall guy, right?
Right. So we have to quarantine him.
Where do we do that?
There must be a place in here.
Then what?
I don't know. But...
It's too dangerous to keep him here.
What are we talking about?
Are we talking about killing him?
You'd rather wait for him to die
and then he kills us?
Yes. No. You can't kill him.
He's got a daughter!
I'm sorry.
There's no other choice.
He's right.
Michael, no. What if I'm wrong?
You've seen it happen before.
Frank.
Michael's coming to shoot you.
- What?
- You're infected.
You're going to become one of them.
Is this true?
Are you here to kill me?
- You were bitten. It's only a matter of time.
- No. No. No.
Leave my dad alone. Go away.
You can't do this.
You have to understand
that she's lost everyone.
Her mother, her two brothers.
I'm all she's got.
Well, Michael, what are you waiting for?
- Go ahead. Kill him.
- Hey, kill Tucker, too.
- Wait a minute. I was never bit.
We can't be sure. Do it, Michael.
Are you sure it's the bite?
No.
She's sure.
I'm sorry.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- Are you OK?
- Mm.
Let me see your arm.
It hurts.
It's already starting to heal.
Andre, I can't have baby here.
Why not? People have had babies
for millions of years,
all on their own, no hospitals.
- Wait.
- Oh, yeah.
- It's moving.
- I felt it.
We gotta come up with a name.
- I want Russian name.
- Don't start that. African name.
- Please?
- Come here and give me a hug.
Sweetie.
I'm so proud.
I couldn't ask for anything more in a daughter.
I love you.
I love you too.
- Time to go, honey.
- No.
Terry, come on. Open the door.
- Shut up.
- Don't tell me to shut up. Open the door.
I got you this job. Come on.
You want...
every...
single second.
Ana.
I'm glad you didn't do it.
- Fuck me harder.
OK, here's a good one. Top ten ingredients
to a successful relationship.
I'm gonna skip to the top three.
Number three. "He listens to me."
Number two. "He tells me he loves me."
And number one.
It's trust. Number one is trust.
Holy shit.
He got him.
- So, who do we have next?
- Er...
Yeah. Burt Reynolds.
Tell him to get Burt Reynolds.
My goodness.
- Man, he's good.
It barely even looked like him.
Oh, oh... er...
- Rosie O'Donnell. Tell him Rosie.
- Yeah, Rosie.
Nah, too easy. Give him something hard.
You guys had rough childhoods?
A little bit rocky?
Hey, sweetheart, let me tell you something.
You have my permission -
if I ever turn into one of those things,
blow my fucking head off.
Oh, yeah, you can count on that.
I guess the first time
I knew I was gay I was 13.
This guy,
Todd,
he was building a deck in our backyard...
OK! Just, please, stop.
He had the most astonishing blue eyes.
Oh, my God! I'm in hell.
How's Luda doing?
She's fine. Hey, where's that lemon stuff?
It's all gone. Steve likes to put it in his booze.
Try the vanilla stuff.
All right.
I'd like to check on her, see how she's doing.
No, thanks. She's fine.
- You sure?
- Yeah, I'm sure.
It's OK, hon. We understand.
Thanks.
And before that, I worked in a stationery store.
And I drove a snowplow. Fixed copiers.
It's a shame this whole
end-of-the-world thing's holding you back.
OK, worst job.
I know which job I was the worst at -
it was being a husband.
- That's not a job.
- It sure is.
You guys just haven't met the right girl.
I tried it three times and...
I got pink slips every time.
What were you best at?
Being a dad.
I think I was best at that.
Calm down.
Are they in?
No. Are there generators?
- Shh. OK, shh.
Shhh... It's all right, baby.
Baby, please. You got to be quiet, OK?
It's gonna be all right.
Our baby is on the way. It's coming.
That's it.
It's in employee parking level 3.
They're in a pen near the parking shuttles.
- Have fun.
- Wait a minute. You're coming too.
No, I'm not. I said I'd tell you
where the generators are, not show you.
Did you think I'd just leave you two up here?
You come with me or go back in the cell.
All right.
I ain't going anywhere without a gun.
- You're not getting a gun.
- Trust.
The primary ingredient in any relationship.
Have at 'em, cowboy.
Asshole.
Bart, get the chains.
- You ready to roll?
- You're coming with us?
No, you're coming with me.
I've done this before.
Know how to use that?
This one's the dangerous end, right?
- Now it is.
This is level 1. We gotta walk down to 3.
What the fuck was that? I just saw something.
You didn't see shit. Shut the fuck up.
Oh, shit. Here it comes.
Jesus Christ.
It's a fucking dog.
- Come here, boy.
Nothing's here or it would've eaten him.
- See? I told you I saw something.
- What's wrong, boy?
- There's nothing wrong.
That dog's just fucked up.
Run!
Wait, CJ! Wait up! Wait!
It's locked! It's fucking locked!
Come on, let's go!
CJ!
I'm out!
CJ! Matches!
Breathe. You're doing good. Breathe.
- You're doing good, baby.
I'm sorry.
- Thanks.
- OK. That's the last.
I'm gonna go check on Luda.
- I'll go.
- You sure?
- Yeah. I'll take them some candles.
- OK.
- Let me know if they need anything.
- I'll have a smoke on the way.
- See you.
- Bye.
It's coming.
I see it.
Guys?
Oh, my God.
It's a girl.
Oh...
You want to kill Luda?
You want to kill my family?
Norma! Come on, Norma.
What happened?
The son of a bitch shot me.
- Get away from her.
- Wait. Just wait.
She died of the gunshot.
She wasn't bitten.
But she'll wake up, right?
No.
No, if she was one of them,
she'd be up by now.
- Terry?
- Yeah.
Hold this.
Oh, God.
- Somebody should say something.
- Yeah.
Glen?
No.
You worked in the church.
I played the organ.
You must have heard the priest say
something about life and death.
It was a job. I don't believe in God.
I don't see how anyone could.
Somebody should say something.
There's nothing to say.
I've been to a lot of funerals.
I've folded the flag and given it
to a lot of wives and fathers and kids
and told them how sorry I was.
But that's not what I was really feeling.
In the back of my mind,
I was always saying, "Better them than me."
But I don't believe that now.
Now I realize there are some things
worse than death
and one of them is sitting here waiting to die.
I don't want to die here.
I saw a couple of buses in the garage.
We could reinforce them,
then get as far from here as possible.
- And then what?
- I have an idea. Um...
Why don't we swing by the marina
and hop in my boat and take it
for a pleasure cruise, you jackasses.
Wait. There's islands in the lakes,
there's not a lot of people on them.
I was kidding.
- How far is the marina?
- Oh, my God!
- You're serious?
- I think it's a damn good idea.
How about the rest of you?
- Kenneth?
- Yeah, it's a good idea.
We have to pick up Andy.
He's part of the group.
Excuse me. Not to shit on anyone's riff
but let me see if I grasp this concept.
You're saying we take the parking shuttles,
reinforce them with aluminum siding
and then head to the gun store
where our friend Andy plays some
cowboy-movie, jump-on-the-wagon bullshit.
Then we drive across a ruined city
through thousands of dead cannibals,
all so we can sail off into the sunset
on this fucking asshole's boat?
And head for some island
which may not even exist?
- Yeah.
- Pretty much, yeah.
Yeah.
OK.
I'm in.
We have 12 of these shotgun shells,
26 of those pussy.9- Mils,
and 16 of the.357 Magnums.
Yeah? That's still not very much,
so hopefully there won't be
too many of them at the dock.
Nice to see you busting your ass.
Oh, that's sarcasm. That is awesome.
You know, I would love to help but, er,
a captain never works alongside his men.
You guys have a good 'un.
What a total dick.
Guys, where did Chips go?
- Chips?
- I can't find him. Chips? Come on, Chips!
"Come on, Chips!"
- Where'd you go, honey?
There you are. There's my boy.
Don't you ever leave me again, OK?
Ever, ever.
Hey. Kenneth wants a meeting upstairs.
Come in here first. I want you to see this.
When those things are on
the side of the bus, this'll get them off.
Cool, huh?
Wow.
That might be the most romantic thing
anyone's ever shown me.
I'm trying here.
Yeah, I know.
It's not just about him starving.
If we pick him up and he doesn't have
his strength, we'll be carrying him.
She's right. He's a hell of a shot. We need him.
- I'm not saying we don't.
- There's no point in arguing.
We need to get some food over there.
I know. We draw straws and the loser runs
across the lot with a ham sandwich.
- Could you be a bigger prick?
- Yes, but that's irrelevant.
My question is, what's your plan?
- Come on!
- I got it.
- Shut up!
...more ammunition.
I have an idea.
- It's hurting him! It's not safe!
- They're not interested in him.
They want us, OK? Chips is gonna be fine.
See? Look, they're not even
paying attention to him.
The walkie's in the bag?
Yeah.
Let me see. Let me see!
- There he is.
Good boy. Good boy, Chips.
- OK, he's there, he's in.
- Give me those.
Oh, man.
- What? What?
- No.
No. Oh, man. They got him. They got him!
I'll try him on the radio.
Andy. Andy, do you copy?
Andy, can you hear me?
Andy?
'Can you hear me? Hello?
This thing working?
'I'm dinged up pretty bad but I think I'll be OK.'
- Where are you hurt?
- 'Goddamn, those bastards bite hard.
'I just have to stop the bleeding.
It's really going.'
- 'Easy, boy. Easy. Is this Ken?
'Is that you, man? '
- Yeah, it's me, brother.
- 'Hey, man, good to hear your voice.
'I guess we'll meet up-close pretty soon.
'Shit, hang on.
'Ah, Jesus. He got me good.'
You just hang in there. You got the food, right?
- 'Yeah.'
- Do we tell him?
- 'Hey, this dog got a name? '
- See, Nicole, Chips... Nicole?
- What the hell's that?
- Oh, my God, it's Nicole!
Shit.
That idiot's going after the fucking dog.
She made it! She's in!
'Guys, I found Chips!
I got him. He's OK! '
Nicole, how's Andy looking?
'I don't know. There's a lot of blood in here.
There's blood everywhere.'
Wait, I see him. He's on the roof.
- He's writing something.
- What's it say?
'Guys? '
- Tell her to get out!
- What's wrong?
- Nicole, how's the truck?
- 'I'm not going back out there.'
- 'Chips, be quiet! '
Tell her to get the hell out!
- You need to hide. Can you do that?
- 'What do you mean? What's going on? '
- Nicole?
- 'Here's Andy.
- 'Oh, my God! '
- Tell her to get out!
Nicole, listen to me.
'I'm in a closet
but he's outside trying to get... '
Nicole? Nicole?
'Help me. Please, you have to help me!
I'm gonna die! '
We need to do something. Now.
Tucker, when we come back
we may have company.
Stay here and make sure this door stays open.
Wait, wait. I'm sorry. Why does he stay here
while I go on the suicide mission
to rescue Terry's already dead girlfriend?
- Fuck you.
- We don't know that.
Either way, we need the guns
to get out of this parking lot.
- Michael, it's OK. Let him stay.
- Yeah.
- Steve, don't fuck this up.
- Yeah. Totally.
- All right. That's it.
- Are you sure?
I'd say we're at the end of the line.
Go! Go!
- Through here!
- Hurry up!
- Hurry up, hurry.
.357,.357. What do you need?
.38,.38.
Here.
- Damn it.
Hurry up.
All right.
Oh, shit.
Nicole?
- Andy.
I'm sorry, brother.
Nicole, are you in there?
- I'm here, I'm here!
Get as much ammo as you can.
- You got a plan?
- Uh-uh. You?
How about a barbecue?
How do we know if he hits it?
CJ! Over here, hurry up!
Over here!
Go! Get down! Look out!
Come on, Tucker!
- Shit!
- Ah, my leg!
- I got you, Tucker.
- Go! Go!
Shit!
Go!
Shoot me! Shoot me!
Hurry! Come on!
Hurry, hurry!
Goddamn Steve Markus!
- Steve, come on!
- Open up!
- Open the door! Open the door!
- Steve!
- I'll fucking kill him!
- Open the door.
- Steve!
Let's go.
Goddamnit!
Move!
- Go!
- Move it, guys, move it!
- Where are you going?
- Just go right now!
Go! Go!
- They're right behind us!
- Go!
Come on, move! They're right behind us!
Get in!
Close the door!
I like this song.
- Everybody in!
- What the hell happened to you guys?
- Prick.
- I'll deal with you later, motherfucker!
- Wait a minute! Nicole!
- Get in!
I'll take the gun. OK.
OK, let's get out of here!
Hold on!
Oh, Christ!
CJ, now! Go!
They're trying to turn us over!
Hit 'em with the saw!
Give me a shotgun!
Holy shit.
There's still one hanging on.
- Which fucking side?
- Right side!
- I got him.
- You gotta drive faster, man.
Hard left here!
Whoa, stop! Stop, guys.
- What?
- We lost them.
- Back it up!
Kenneth, are you there?
'Kenneth, are you there?
'Kenneth, are you OK? '
What the fuck?
- What are you doing?
- Fucking nursery school.
CJ!
Ana, no! Everyone's dead.
- Steve took off.
- What?
Let's go! Come on!
Steve!
- I got him.
Damn.
Look out!
Come on, come on!
Go, go, go!
- Open the door! Hurry up!
- Come on!
Guys, get in!
Let's go.
Where's Ana? Ana!
Ana!
Get in.
What the hell were you doing?
Hold on!
Come on, boy.
Kenneth. Here. Get out on the end of the dock.
- CJ, come on.
- Do it! I'll catch up.
- There it is!
- Terry, get the bowline!
- Shit.
CJ!
Damn! Fuck!
Come on!
Bitch! Shit.
Come on.
I'll blow every fucking thing up.
OK, let's go, let's go.
- I can't go.
- What?
- Downtown when they jumped on us.
- Oh, no, Michael. No.
- I have to stay here.
- You can't. No, you...
- I'm sorry, Ana.
- I can help you.
No, you can't. You can help them.
Stay on the boat.
I can help you.
It's OK. It's gonna be all right.
No.
- It won't.
- Hey.
It will.
You sure you wanna do this?
Yeah. I think I'll just stay here a while.
Enjoy the sunrise.
'I run a tight ship.'
- 'Where did you get that? '
'I found Steve's camera.'
'Put that down and help us.'
'Ah! Kenneth, fucking shoot it! '
'Christ! '
'Oh, shit! '
'Get your damn camera out my face.'
- '... if there's anyone there.'
'Terry, put the camera down
and help us off the boat.'
'Nicole, what is it? '
'Chips, no! '
'Oh, shit! '
'Stay behind me.'