Glengarry Glen Ross《拜金一族》1992
Sync & Encoded by Owen Lee
看电影学英语 看美剧学英语
智能手机、IPAD、MP4学英语，请观注：
=-www.en580.com-=『英语我帮您』
2306, please.
Hello, honey. How are you doing?
Good.
Oh, what did he say?
Uh-huh. Is he still there?
How long ago did he leave?
Uh-huh.
I'm stopping here, then I've got a little meeting. Then I'll...
I would if I could.
As soon as I can. Let me get off and...
Let me get off and I...
I promise you it'll be OK.
MOSS: What a bunch of bullshit.
Waste of a good man's time.
Hi, could I speak to Dr Lewenstein, please?
It's rather important. Could you get him for me?
It's bullshit trying to make a living on these deadbeat leads.
I swear to God, Shel, I'm on a sit today. This...
Hello, Mrs Swaboda. This is Dave Moss. Yeah, we spoke yesterday.
Now, on the Rio Rancho Estates we've had a situation just come up.
The president of our company is in town just one day and he has certain parcels...
Er, Doctor... Oh, well, could you get?
What do you mean? He's not there? I have to speak to him.
Yes, it is fairly urgent.
Mr Levene.
No, I can't be reached. I'll get back to him.
But we have certain parcels, certain choice parcels,
which he's given me a hold on for the next 48 hours.
What's the best time to get you and your husband together?
Say tonight at... at ten?
Or tomorrow at eight?
OK.
OK, what would be the best time to do that?
Look, you sent in the... No... No, listen to me now.
I've got 48 hours to make you a lot of money.
Well, when will he be home?
Fine, I'll call you back in ten minutes.
They don't give you the leads, they don't give you the support, they don't give you dick.
Then they're yanking us in on a sales conference.
When did anyone make a dime or learn a goddamn thing?
All it does is some jerk shoots his mouth off.
Yeah.
I swear to God, Shel. I've got half a mind to go across the street.
I've got half a mind to go with you if they'd take me.
Well, you never know. I'm talking to Jerry Graff last week.
I gotta call these deadbeats back.
Baby, I can't make a goddamn dollar with these leads.
- You're killing my ass on the street. - I'm sorry you aren't happy here.
That's cute, but you run this office like bullshit.
You're on an override. You make money, we make money.
- I'd like you to make more. - Give me a lead and don't waste my time.
- Sales conference? - The strategy comes from downtown.
Oh, the strategy. The strategy?!
- I think I'll pass. - I wouldn't.
- Why's that? - When you come, then you'll see.
- Shelley. - Yeah?
Are you ready to do or die tonight?
Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah, John. Always ready, John.
One thing. We were talking about the leads. I understand we got some new ones.
- We're talking about that at the meeting. - We are?
Cos I'm running into a little bit of a snag.
- Yes, I've seen your sales figures. - John, give me a better lead...
- That's what we're talking about tonight. - I'm in a personal bind. I could use a leg up.
- After the meeting. - The Glengarry leads...
After the meeting, Shel.
- Hi, Ricky. - Hello, John.
- Wet out there tonight. - Huh?
Wet out there tonight.
Maybe it'll break the heat.
Al, give me a quick J&B, huh? A double.
Cutty.
They say...
LEVENE: Huh?
They say it was so hot downtown this afternoon...
...grown men on the street corner were going up to cops
begging the cops to shoot them.
They say you should not drink alcohol when it's so hot.
Who says that?
Something I read.
For they say it dehydrates you.
They say you should drink water.
But I subscribe to the law of contrary public opinion.
If everyone thinks one thing, then I say bet the other way.
Added to which, you know they're wrong.
Well, that's what I'm saying.
- Slow tonight. - Huh? Oh, yeah.
I guess everybody's staying home, huh?
If my daughter calls, if anybody calls, I'm over at the office. Thanks.
Got a woman in White Plains on the hook.
Five units, Mountain View. What happens?
She... She has to check with her lawyer.
You let her check with her lawyer?
- What could I do? - I don't know.
Shelley. Who's the guy?
Couldn't tell you.
I don't like the whole thing. Cos all I need is a lead. They won't give out...
Uh-huh. The rich get richer, that's the law of the land.
Who belongs to the BM?
WILLIAMSON: It is 7:30.
So who is that?
WILLIAMSON: And where's Mr Roma?
Well, I'm not a leash, so I don't know, do I?
Let me have your attention for a moment.
Cos you're talking about what? You're talking about...
Bitching about a sale you shot. Some son of a bitch don't want to buy land.
Somebody don't want what you're selling. Some broad you're trying to screw.
Let's talk about something important. Are they all here?
- All but one. - I'm going anyway.
Let's talk about something important.
Put that coffee down.
Coffee's for closers only.
You think I'm fucking with you?
I am not fucking with you.
I'm here from downtown.
I'm here from Mitch and Murray.
And I'm here on a mission of mercy.
Your name's Levene?
Yeah.
You call yourself a salesman, you son of a bitch?
- I don't gotta listen to this shit. - You certainly don't, pal.
Cos the good news is you're fired.
The bad news is all of you've got just one week to regain your jobs, starting with tonight.
Starting with tonight's sit.
Oh, have I got your attention now?
Good.
Cos we're adding a little something to this month's sales contest.
As you know, first prize is a Cadillac Eldorado. Anybody want to see second prize?
Second prize is a set of steak knives.
Third prize is you're fired.
Do you get the picture?
Are you laughing now?
You've got leads. Mitch and Murray paid good money.
Get their names to sell them.
You can't close the leads you're given, you can't close shit. You are shit!
Hit the bricks, pal, and beat it, cos you are going out!
The leads are weak.
The leads are weak?
The fucking leads are weak? You're weak.
I've been in this business 15 years.
- What's your name? - Fuck you! That's my name.
You know why, mister? Cos you drove a Hyundai to get here tonight.
I drove an $80,000 BMW.
That's my name.
And your name is, you're wanting.
You can't play in the man's game? You can't close them?
Then go home and tell your wife your troubles.
Because only one thing counts in this life.
Get them to sign on the line which is dotted.
You hear me, you fucking faggots?
A... B... C.
A - always, B - be, C - closing.
Always be closing.
Always... be... closing.
AIDA.
Attention, interest, decision, action.
Attention - do I have your attention?
Interest - are you interested?
I know you are, cos it's fuck or walk.
You close or you hit the bricks.
Decision - have you made your decision for Christ?!
And action.
AIDA. Get out there.
You've got the prospects coming in. You think they came in to get out of the rain?
A guy don't walk on the lot unless he wants to buy.
They're sitting out there waiting to give you their money. Are you gonna take it?
Are you man enough to take it?
Incredible.
What's the problem, pal? You - Moss.
You're such a hero, you're so rich.
How come you've come here to waste your time with such a bunch of bums?
You see this watch?
Yeah.
That watch cost more than your car.
I made $970,000 last year. How much did you make?
You see, pal? That's who I am. And you're nothing.
Nice guy? I don't give a shit.
Good father? Fuck you. Go home and play with your kids.
You wanna work here? Close!
You think this is abuse?
You think this is abuse, you cocksucker?
You can't take this, how can you take the abuse you get on a sit?!
You don't like it? Leave.
I can go out there tonight with the materials you got and make myself $15,000.
Tonight! In two hours!
Can you?
Go and do likewise. AIDA.
Get mad, you son of a bitches! Get mad!
You know what it takes to sell real estate?
It takes brass balls to sell real estate.
Go and do likewise, gents.
The money's there. You pick it up, it's yours. You don't, I got no sympathy for you.
You wanna go out on those sits tonight and close - CLOSE - it's yours.
Not - you're gonna be shining my shoes.
And you know what you'll be saying, bunch of losers sitting around in the bar?
"Oh, yeah. I used to be a salesman.
It's a tough racket."
These are the new leads.
These are the Glengarry leads.
And to you, they're gold.
And you don't get them.
Why?
Because to give them to you is just throwing them away.
They're for closers.
I'd wish you good luck, but you wouldn't know what to do with it if you got it.
And to answer your question, pal... Why am I here?
I came here because Mitch and Murray asked me to. They asked me for a favour.
I said, "The real favour - follow my advice", and fire your fucking ass.
"Because a loser is a loser."
(Train rumbles)
Bunch of fucking nonsense.
Treat people like that.
The fuck is he gonna get off?
Mickey Mouse sales conference.
He didn't mean it. I'm sure he didn't mean it about trimming down the sales force.
Where's Roma?
Where the hell's Mr Ricky Roma while we sit here and eat this nonsense?
Hello? Uh, Mr Levene. How's she doing?
Uh-huh. Yeah. Is she awake?
Oh, the doctor came by? What did he say?
Uh-huh. OK, look, I can't come in tonight.
Yes, I know she is. I know that she is. I gotta go out.
Will you please tell her when she wakes, I've got to go out?
And tell her I'll call her from the road. Thank you.
Gentlemen, you heard the man.
MOSS: What is this in aid of?
- As of tonight... MOSS: What is this? Excuse me?
- It's in aid of Mitch and Murray... - Fuck Mitch and Murray!
Fuck 'em! I'm doing my job. I gotta put up with this childishness?
I don't make the rules. I'm paid to run the office. You don't like the rules?
There's the door!
Two lead cards for tonight. Two lead cards for tomorrow.
As you heard, end of the month, top salesman gets the Eldorado.
- How about the good leads? - The leads I've given you.
These leads are shit. They're old.
- I've seen that name a hundred times. - Leads are assigned randomly.
What about the new leads, huh? The new leads.
- The Glengarry leads. - I've got them.
I'm gonna hang on to them. They'll be assigned to closers.
Based on the sales volume, first to Roma.
- Where is Roma? - Don't you worry.
- He'll get his leads. - He's top, so he's not here for this shit?
That's correct - and as the hour is waning,
I suggest those of you who are interested
in a continuing job with this organisation get to work.
Garbage. Worked-over bullshit.
- Thank you for your attention. - Bullshit! How am I supposed to close these?
Look at this. I've had this guy before. I've been to his house twice.
I can't... I... I... I can't close this stuff.
Shelley, how am I supposed to?
They're going to bounce me out of a job.
AARONOW: Hello. Mr Palermo?
I'm sorry.
Mr Speece? Mr Robert Speece?
This is George Aaronow. I'm with Rio. I spoke with your wife earlier.
Yeah, I'm the Vice President of Rio Rancho Properties in Furman, Arizona...
Yes. I'm calling from the airport
and, consulting my map, I see that you and your wife live near the airport.
I have some rather unusual, rather good information
on the property we've been discussing. - Hello! This is Sheldon Levene.
Please listen closely, I only have a moment or so.
I can speak only to a Mrs Nyborg.
Oh, this is Mrs Nyborg. Please listen closely, Mrs Nyborg.
I'm calling from Consolidated Properties of Arizona.
Our computer has chosen you from all of the many thousands who write in
requesting information on our properties.
Now, by federal law, as you probably know,
the prize must be awarded to you,
even if you are not engaged in our land development plan.
The only stipulation, of course, is that you and your husband must sign at the same time
for the receipt of your prize.
Now, I will be in the area tonight, possibly tomorrow.
What do you think might be a convenient time to meet with both you and your husband?
Of course I'll hold.
- Bunch of fucking nonsense, huh? - I can't close 'em.
- Nobody can close 'em. - They're old.
They're ancient. A bunch of fucking nonsense. Get some jerk to come in here.
Sometimes I just think... I wonder if I belong in this business.
Send a guy out there, no support, no confidence.
Then I say, "Nobody can close 'em." Then I look at Roma.
Roma. Fuck Roma. Had a freak couple... You know, a run of luck.
The leads are garbage.
Then I say, "Why give him the good leads? He doesn't need 'em."
- You going out? - Yeah. I have to go out.
- I can't make a sit. - Have you tried?
Yeah. Something's... Something's wrong with me.
- I don't know what it is. I can't push through. - Get your coat, you're coming with me.
- Something in me. - Forget it.
- I try, I try. - I said forget it. Come on.
I can't close 'em.
Life. I swear to God, you know. You work all your life.
- Forget it, George. - Fellas... Roma, so on - so gifted.
Gifted, my ass! Guy gets a string of luck.
Oh, no, no. Not.
The thing of it is, money's tight.
Times are tight. It don't do no good throwing this fodder at us - "Go out and sell."
Threaten a man all you want. You can't whip a dead horse. All this garbage.
Sell 10,000, you win a Cadillac. You lose, we're going to fire your ass.
- It's... medieval. - Yes.
- It's wrong. - Yes.
- Yes, it is. And you know who's responsible? - Who?
You know who it is. It's Mitch and Murray. It don't have to be this way.
Look at Jerry Graff, he's clean. He's doing business for himself.
He's got that list with the nurses. See? You see? That's thinking.
Why take 10%? A 10% sales commission?
Why are we giving the rest away? What are we giving 90% for?
For nothing.
For some jerk in the office to tell us, "Get out there and close. Win a Cadillac."
Graff goes out and buys. He pays top dollar, you see, for the leads.
That's thinking.
Now, he's got the leads, he goes in business for himself - that's what?
That's thinking. Who?
Who's got a steady job? Couple of bucks nobody's touched. Who?
- Nurses. - Graff buys a fucking list of nurses. One grand.
He paid two, I'll eat my hat. Four, five thousand nurses. He's going wild.
- He is? - Yeah, he's doing very well.
I heard they were running cold.
- The nurses? - Yeah.
You hear a lot of things. He's doing well. He's doing very well.
- With River Oaks? - River Oaks, Brook Farms - all that shit.
Somebody told me - you know what he's clearing himself? 14, 15 grand a week.
- Himself? - That's what I'm saying.
Why? He's got the leads. He's got the good leads.
What are we? We're sitting in the shit here.
Why? Cos we've got to go to them to get them, huh?
90% of our sales we're paying to the office for the leads.
There's our leads, the overheads, the phones, there's a lot of stuff.
What do you need? A telephone? Some broad to say good morning? Nothing.
It's the leads. The whole thing is the leads. You understand me?
You can't sell to a void. You've got to get a goddamn person.
With a lead, you get a person. I'll go and sell. Otherwise, what do they want from my life?
LEVENE: Hello. Uh, Danny?
Danny, it's Shel Levene.
Yeah, we spoke last... May. I called you. I was in town from my estate in Rio Rancho...
Arizona. I wish we could've gotten together at that time.
Danny, that piece of property I had for you has increased in value...
Grace, Grace... what was that figure?
$76,000.
Oh, Danny. I wish you could've been in on it with me.
I'm here overnight, I have to go home tomorrow,
and I thought after the interest you showed on the last trip...
Hold it, Grace.
Danny, I know that you're serious,
and because of that I am going to shove my appointments around and make sure...
Oh, gee... I wish that... Uh-huh.
All right, Danny. Yeah, all right.
Going out tonight, Shelley?
What is this bullshit with the sales promotion?
- It isn't bullshit, it's the way it is. - You're firing the bottom men on the list?
That's how it is. I don't make the rules. They come from downtown.
I've got a little bit of a problem here, John.
- I'm closing up the office. - Come over and have a drink with me.
I gotta get home.
- Do me the courtesy, huh? Five minutes. - I am trying to get home for two hours.
I gotta grab an hour with my kids, come back,
see if anyone closed a contract, take it to the bank.
How about one minute? Huh?
What is it?
- I can't close these leads. - Then move on.
Don't jump...
Don't jump out of your manager bag, huh? It's just two guys talking. Am I right?
We're just talking. You've got the new leads. If you... Just hold on a second.
The Glengarry leads are to be assigned only to closers.
Hold on a second. If you give me the good leads...
- You blew the last good one I gave you. - No.
Hold on a minute, please. I did not blow 'em.
One kicked out, one I closed.
- You didn't close it. - Would you listen? I closed that cocksucker.
His ex, John, his ex. I didn't even know he was married. The judge invalidated it.
- Shelley... - What was that, John, huh?
Bad luck, that's all it was. I pray in your life you never find that it runs in streaks.
That's what it's doing, that's all it does. I pray that it misses you, and that's all I have to say.
(Sighs) I've got to eat, Williamson.
Look at the sheets. Look at the sheets.
1987, '88, '89. Six months in '89 - who's on top?
- Roma. - Under him.
- Moss. - Oh, bullshit. Bullshit, John!
April to September, it's me. It's no fucking Moss.
Due respect - he's an order taker. Oh, talk. Ooh, talks a good game.
But go look on the board. It's me.
- Not lately, it isn't. - Not late... Well, lately...
Kiss my ass, lately. You call Murray and you call Mitch.
When we were on Peterson, who bought the new car, huh?
Call Mitch. The Seville? Oh, he came in here - "You bought that for me, fella."
And out of what? Hey, look at me!
Out of what? Nothing! Cold calling.
You wanna talk about a sale. You are really beginning to burn my ass, kid.
I can't get a lead...
and you...
It was skill, John. It could be working for you.
- You want to throw it away. - It isn't me.
It's not you? I wonder who it is.
Who the fuck am I talking to?! Now, look, I need the leads to...
After the contest. After the 30th.
Bullshit after the contest!
If I'm not on the board by the 30th, they'll can my ass.
I need those leads and I need 'em now, or I'm out.
You're gonna miss me.
(Mutters) I swear to you, you will miss me.
Let me tell you something, Shelley.
I do what I'm hired to do. You might do the same.
Jesus.
Now, wait a second.
I'm hired to watch the leads. To marshal my sales force. I'm given a policy.
- My job is to do that. - You're going to marshal your sales force?
Anybody falls below a certain mark, I'm directed.
I'm not permitted to give them premium leads.
How do they rise above that mark? With dreck?
With this toilet paper that you're giving me?
- You give me a premium lead... - Do you know what they cost?
Do I know what the premium leads cost? Yeah, I know what they cost.
I generated the sufficient dollar revenue to buy them.
But I cannot sell shit!
Jesus. I've seen these before. Christ, I saw these back... Homestead.
We pitched these cocksuckers Baywater. They couldn't buy a fucking toaster. They're broke.
They're deadbeats.
Hey, just give me some leads don't come out of a phone book, huh?
Give me something hotter and I'll close it.
It's just a streak. I'm gonna turn it around. Hey.
I need your help.
Huh?
I can't do it, Shelley.
(Train rumbles)
Hey, John.
Give you 10%.
- Of what? - My end. What I close.
You give me the premium leads, you're in for 10% of what I close.
- What if you don't close? - I will close.
- What if you don't close? - I will close!
What if you don't? You understand?
Then I'm fucked. You think you're the only guy with a family? You see what I'm saying?
I step out and you don't close, then I'm fired.
I will close! Now, 10%, John. I can get hot. You know that.
- Not lately, you can't. - That's defeatist. Fuck it.
Go with me. Get on my side and let's do something.
You want to run this office? You heard what the man said - attack!
Let's do something. Huh?
20%.
- All right. - And 50 bucks a lead.
- (Snorts) - No?
Oh... (Chuckles)
Oh, shit.
(Engine fails to start)
Listen, er...
I gotta talk to you.
Permit me to do this a second. I'm older than you.
A man acquires a reputation on the street.
What he does when he's up, what he does at other times.
I said 10, you said no. You said 20, I said fine.
Now you want to throw this 50-buck thing in. Now, John, a good deal...
- A deal has got to be one where both parties... - (Engine fails to start)
OK, OK, fine. 20%, 50 bucks a lead. It's done.
Let's go out. We make some money. I've got bills to pay, huh?
I want two sits tonight and I want the good leads, the Glengarry leads.
Two. Two, John. Because I am gonna close 'em both.
It's a long road with no turning, pally. Huh?
OK. Now, let's go.
- I've gotta go back to the office to get 'em. - Go on, let's go, huh?
You see, this is what I was saying, John.
All you need is a little boost. You turn the streak around. Right? Good, huh? Huh, good?
What?
- What? - Two leads, 100 bucks.
- Now? - Now, yes. When?
Oh, Christ. Shit, John!
- I wish I could. - You fucking asshole.
I don't have it. I... I... I don't... I'll bring it in the office in the morning.
- I'll be coming in with the sales. - Nope.
I don't fucking believe this. All right, here's...
Er... 20... 30.
And... Come on. Jesus. Here's the 30 and I'll bring the rest in tomorrow.
We've gotta do this, huh? For Christ's sake.
No.
My daughter...
I can't do it, Shelley.
I gotta tell you something, fella.
It wasn't so long ago I just pick up the phone and I call Murray. I got your job.
"Hey, Murray, the kid is burning my ass." "Shelley, he's gone."
You are gone before I'm back from lunch.
Bought him a trip to Bermuda once.
- I've gotta go. - All right, hey.
Give me er...
- I'll take two more of the old leads. - I gave you two today.
Christ, one is a bust-out and the other ain't home.
- Shelley... - I've been on the phone, I know.
No more leads today. Two per day. You've got yours.
- All right? - Sure.
We will do that er... other thing.
I left my wallet in my room.
Deadbeats. Deadbeats - all of them.
MOSS: My mistake. I shouldn't have took the leads in the first place.
AARONOW: You had to. MOSS: Why?
To get on the...
Get on the board. How am I going to get on the board trying to sell a doctor?
Two regular, two chocolate doughnuts. And the same to go.
- And don't ever try to sell an Indian. - I'd never try to sell an Indian.
These names come up. You ever get 'em? Patel. You ever get 'em?
I think I had one once.
You had one, you'd know it. Patel.
They keep coming up. I don't know - they like to talk to salesmen. They're lonely.
They like to feel superior. Never bought a fucking thing. I don't know.
Come down the line. Doctors, lawyers, Indians.
Times are tight. It's tight. Pressure's just too great.
A man can't work. All of them.
You go in the door - "I gotta close this fucker or I don't eat lunch or win a Cadillac."
We work too hard, George.
Remember when we were...
...when we were selling Glen Ross Farms?
- Ohh. - Didn't we sell a bunch of that?
Yeah, they came in.
- They fucked it up. - They did.
- They killed the goose. And now... - Stuck with this.
- This fucking shit. - This shit.
- It's too... - It is.
- You get a bad month... - You're on a...
- They put you on a board. A contest board. - I... I... I...
- It's not right. - Not right to the customers.
I know. It's... Hey.
What did I learn as a kid on Western? You don't sell a guy one car.
You sell him five cars over fifteen years.
- That's right. - Goddamn right.
Guys come in - blah, blah, blah.
"I'll go and rob everybody blind and go to Argentina, cos nobody thought of this before."
They kill the goose. A fucking man's worked all his life, he's gotta...
- Cower in his boots. - True, his boots. Yes.
Some fucking "Sell 10,000, win steak knives."
- What do you do? - What can you do?
What can you do if you don't have the leads?
If you do not have the goddamn leads.
Mr Spannel? Oh, Sheldon Levene.
I was speaking to your wife earlier.
Come in.
Cats and dogs, huh?
Oh, yes. (Chuckles)
Ooh, I see you're interested in fishing.
Oh, I fished myself. Many years. Muskie, Wisconsin.
Oh, a beauty.
- Where's the missus? - Out at the PTA.
- Oh... - What was this in reference?
I spoke to your wife earlier on the phone. I'm in town with Rio Rancho.
Yes, yes, I'm sorry. She said you had some sort of award...
I was speaking to my sales organisation, my representatives in this area.
Now, Mr Spannel...
Your name is Larry. Do you mind if I call you Larry? Huh?
All right, Larry. We had a consultant and he made me an offer. (Chuckles)
He offered me $230,000
to promote a sales plan, you see.
A plan to present our investment opportunities at Rio Rancho to the public.
Well, I said, "Hell, let me save you the 230 and pass the savings along to the investor."
My people immediately said, "Whoa! How do you do that?
How can you present investment opportunities without television, without magazine ads?"
I said, "You take something this good, you go to a man has invested in the past.
You go to him direct and offer the money to him. Rebate!
And don't give it to this expert."
So you're here to sell me some land?
No - I wouldn't try to sell you land. I leave that to the salesmen, you know,
and people who want to own land.
I think something has to be fed, watered and painted, you know. But don't invest in it.
And that motto has stood me in good stead.
- Mr... - Just call me Shelley.
I have never been afraid of familiarity.
- I'm walking out the door to pick up my wife. - Let's take my car. We'll go together.
I spoke to the little woman on the phone. Can't wait to meet her.
- No, we're going to our relatives. - She didn't mention that.
- I'm sure she forgot. - I'm on a plane to Florida.
- I'm sorry if we put you out... - You didn't put me out. I'm just trying to think.
You know, that's the only parcel that I've got. You know what I'm gonna do?
I'm gonna go to the computer and pull another one and speak to your relatives, too.
- No, no. Nope. - Come on, you're a busy man and so am I.
- Listen... Lis... - My God, I'm giving a gift away!
Look. I don't wanna buy land, I don't wanna invest in land. I have nothing.
She took the call without my knowledge. I have no business that I wish to transact.
I can't tell you how to handle your wife.
My wife filled in a form and we have been plagued for the last year by...
- That's the situation I'm trying to alleviate. - No, no. Do you understand?
Thank you, no.
OK.
- Roma, man, Roma. He don't care. - He don't care.
He's on top of the world. He's got the good leads, good prospects.
Sales, sales.
- Sales contests. - That's what I'm saying.
Times turn hard, they bounce you out.
- And if they bounce you with no confidence... - That's what I'm saying to you.
You know, if they get you on a bad beat...
They get you on it, and you gotta go out. Get a new job.
- With no... With no... - With no confidence.
- Yes. - I'll tell you what the hard part is.
Stop thinking like a goddamn slave.
You say, "The Nazis in Europe. If they came in my door, I'd..."
Bullshit, the time is now. What do you do now?
Some guy pissing in your face - cocksucker. Wants to break your rice bowl.
Mitch and Murray - fuck you. What I say - fuck you.
Sitting on the good leads.
George, we're men here.
Yes.
I'll tell you. I'll tell you what the hard part is.
- What? - Starting up. Standing up.
Breaking free of this bullshit, this enslavement to some guy because he's got the upper hand.
(Sighs) This is the difference. Listen to me, George.
Now, Jerry Graff went in business for himself. He said, "I'm going on my own."
And he was free. You understand me?
I'll tell you what somebody should do.
- What? - Somebody should stand up and strike back.
- Somebody should do something to them. - What?
Something to pay 'em back. Someone should hurt them - Mitch and Murray.
Someone should hurt them? How?
Someone should hurt them where they live.
- What? - Someone should rob the office.
- Huh! - That's what I'm saying.
If we were that kind of guy - to hold up the joint, trash it. It looks like robbery.
We take the fucking leads out of the files and go to Jerry Graff.
- We take the fucking Glengarry leads. Huh? - (Chuckles)
Yeah, Mr Nyborg?
Ah, Mr Nyborg - Sheldon Levene. I was speaking to your wife earlier. That's right.
I'd like to speak to you about your prize - awarding you your prize.
We're coming to the end of our fiscal year. I'd like to get it off the books before...
Yes, the prize for Consolidated Property.
Yes, the information you requested on Rio Rancho.
Now, I'm in town only for a couple of... Let me see, I suppose I could swing by tonight.
Oh. When do you think it might be more convenient?
As I said, I could swing by tonight.
Of course, yes, you speak to your wife.
Grace! Gonna need a first-class seat.
Er... passport, 10,000 in cash - put that with the negotiable papers, if you would.
And put me on the telex hook-up with... Yes?
Well, when do you think Mrs Nyborg might be back?
All train compartments smell vaguely of shit.
It gets so you don't mind it.
That's the worst thing that I can confess.
You know how long it took me to get there? A long time.
(Chuckles)
When you die, you're gonna regret the things you don't do.
You think you're queer? I'm gonna tell you something - we're all queer.
You think you're a thief? So what?
You get befuddled by a middle-class morality? Get shot of it. Shut it out.
You cheat on your wife? You did it. Live with it.
Fuck little girls? So be it.
There's an absolute morality? Huh? Maybe.
And then what?
If you think there is, go ahead, be that thing.
Bad people go to hell? I don't think so.
You think that? Act that way.
A hell exists on earth? Yes.
I won't live in it.
That's me.
Did you ever take a dump made you feel like you slept for 12 hours?
- Did I? - Yes.
(Chuckles) I don't know.
Or a piss?
Great meals fade in reflection.
Everything else gains. You know why?
Because it's only food.
The shit we put in us keeps us going. It's only food.
The great fucks you may have had. What do you remember about them?
- What do I remember? - Yeah.
I don't know. For me, I'm saying what it is...
It's probably not the orgasm.
Some broad's... forearm on your neck.
Something her eyes did.
There was this sound she made.
Or it's me in the... I'm telling you.
I'm in bed the next day and she brought me café au lait, gives me a cigarette.
My balls feel like concrete. Hey?
What I'm saying... What is our life?
Our life is looking forward or it's looking back.
That's it. That's our life.
Where's the moment?
And what is it we're so afraid of?
Loss. What else?
The bank closes. We get sick.
My wife died on a plane.
The stock market collapsed. What of these things happen?
None of 'em. We worry anyway. Why?
What could we get for 'em?
- For 'em? - For the leads.
What could we get for the leads?
I don't know. Ten bucks a throw. 15, maybe.
I don't know.
For the leads, you're saying? Say somebody took 'em and went to Jerry Graff.
Yeah. How many leads do we have?
The Glengarry? The premium leads? I gotta think they've got 500. Say 500 leads.
You're saying a fella could take those leads and sell them to Graff?
The leads to Graff, yes. I was saying...
Yeah, a guy could take... Like anything else that is negotiable - a guy could sell 'em.
- How do you know he'd buy 'em? - Because I worked for him.
- You didn't talk to him? - No.
- What do you mean? Talk to him about this? - Yeah.
- Are you just talking about this? - We're just speaking about it.
- Speaking about it as an idea? - Yes.
- We're not actually talking about it? - No.
Talking about it as a robbery.
As a robbery? No.
(Moss laughs)
Well...
Hey.
So all this... You didn't actually call Graff? You didn't talk to him?
- Not actually, no. - You didn't?
No, not actually.
- Did you? - What did I say?
- What did you say? - What the fuck do you care?
- We're just talking. - We are?
- Yes. - Because er... Because it's a crime.
Robbery - that's right.
It is a crime.
It's also very safe.
- You're actually talking about this. - That's right.
- You're gonna steal the leads. - Have I said that?
- Are you? - Did I say that?
- Did you talk to Graff? - What did I say?
- What did he say? - What did he say?
He'd buy 'em.
- You're gonna steal 'em? - (Woman laughs)
You're gonna steal the leads and sell 'em to Graff?
- Yes. - What's he gonna pay?
He figures there's 500 leads at, say, ten bucks apiece - that's $2,500 each.
Each?
- Each? - That's right, George.
- What are you saying - me? - You and me. Yeah.
That's exactly what I'm saying.
$2,500 apiece - you and me for one night's work
and a job with Graff working the premium leads.
- A job with Graff? - Is that what I said?
- He'd give me a job? - He could take you on, yes.
Hello... I was dialling the direct line to my daughter's roo...
Sheldon Levene. Yes, she's in twenty-th...
Well, yeah, I'm sure she's asleep, but...
Well, where's the duty nur...
They cancelled her?
Well, then, let me talk... Who am I speaking to?
I'll have the money there tomorrow.
That's a big decision, George.
Times a guy's gotta make one.
It's a big decision and it's a big reward.
$2,500 and a job. It's a big reward for one night's work.
- Yes. - You know, sometimes a guy...
Sometimes a man, if he wants a reward...
That's absolutely right.
To do one thing, one thing on one night.
- The thing is that it's gotta be tonight. - What?
What what? The leads ain't gonna leave?
They bring the leads, wave 'em under your nose, tomorrow they take 'em downtown.
A guy wants those leads, he'll have to go get 'em tonight.
Tonight is the thing. Talk about a chance. It's when a chance presents itself.
- So you've gotta go in there tonight? - You.
- I'm sorry? - You.
- Me? - You have to go in.
- You have to get the leads. - I do?
It's not something for nothing, George. I took you in on this.
You have to go. It's your thing. I've made a deal with Graff. I can't go in.
I've spoken out on this too much.
I got a big mouth. "The fucking leads, fucking tight-assed company."
They'll know when you go to Graff.
What will they know? That I stole the leads?
I didn't steal the leads. I'm going to a movie. Then I'm going for a drink at the Como Inn.
- Dave. - Yes?
You want me to break into the office and steal the leads?
- Yes. - No.
- Oh, yes. - What does that mean?
Listen to this. I have an alibi. I'm going to the Como Inn.
Why? Why?! The place gets robbed, they'll come looking for me.
Why? Because I probably did it. Let me ask you this - are you gonna turn me in?
- What if you don't get caught? - They come to you, will you turn me in?
- Why come to me? - They'll come to everyone.
- Why would I do it? - You wouldn't. That's why I'm talking to you.
- Are you gonna turn me in? - No.
- Are you sure? - Yeah.
Uh-huh.
George... when they come to me...
If I have to go in there and I get caught, they come to me.
- You don't have to go in. - I have to go in. That's something I have to do.
- Why? - Why? Are you gonna give me $7,500?
I thought we were splitting five grand?
I lied, all right? Your end's 25, my end's my own concern.
Stick with me here, George.
They come to me, I'm caught. They're gonna ask who were accomplices.
- Me. - Absolutely.
- It's ridiculous. - You're an accessory before the fact.
- I didn't ask to be. - Tough luck, George. You are.
- Because you told me about it? - That's right.
Why are you doing this to me, Dave?
Why are you talking this way? I don't understand.
- Why are you doing this at all? - None of your fucking business, pal.
In or out? You tell me. You're out, you take the consequences.
- I do? - Right.
- And why is that? - Because you listened.
Well, when will Mrs Nyborg be back?
I hate to keep calling you this late, Bruce, but I feel a responsibility, I must say.
When you have a...
You know...
...they say you don't buy it, you rent it. - Huh?
The thing.
You really er... What do you keep?
I mean, you don't keep anything really.
(Chuckles) No.
Security... Things. Things.
- You know? - Mm-hm.
It's just... you try to stave off insecurity.
You can't do it.
- No. - No. That's what I'm telling you.
Stocks, bonds, objects of art, real estate. What are they?
An opportunity. To what? To make money?
Perhaps.
To lose money? Perhaps.
To indulge and to learn about ourselves? Perhaps.
So fucking what? What is it?
They're an opportunity. That's all they are. They're an event.
A guy comes to you. You make a call. You send in a card.
"I have these properties I would like for you to see."
What does this mean? What do you want it to mean? You see what I'm saying?
Things happen to you.
Glad I met you. I'm glad I met you, James.
I want to show you something.
It may mean something to you, it may not. I don't know. I don't know any more.
What is that? Florida.
Glengarry Highlands. Florida.
Bullshit.
And maybe that's true,
and that's what I said.
But look at this.
What is this?
This is a piece of land. Listen to what I'm gonna tell you now.
- What happened? - You. Where do you work?
I work... Yes, I work here. What is it? What happened?
Robbery.
Williamson. Williamson.
Did they get the contracts?
- Tell me. They stole the contracts. - Excuse me, sir.
- Did they get mine? - They...
- Fella... - Did they?
Don't fuck with me. I'm talking about a fucking Cadillac that you owe me.
- They didn't get your contract. I'd filed it. - They didn't get my contracts?
They got... Excuse me.
Fuck!
Fuck. Fuck! Fuck! Williamson!
- Williamson, open the fucking door. - Who are you?
- They didn't get the contracts. - Did they?
Listen to me. Listen to me. They got some of them.
- Some of them? - Who told you?
Who told me? Who told me we had a robbery? We got a fucking board up on the win...
Who is this? Yes.
Yes, I confess. I did it.
Now, leave me a second here, please.
- OK. Now, talk to me. - We're still trying to sort it out.
Talk to me, talk to me. They got some of the contracts.
- They... - Lingk.
James Lingk, which I closed last night.
- You closed it last night? - Yes.
- I filed it. It went down. - You filed it?
- James Lingk. - Yes.
It was sent downtown?
Yes, all right? I filed it last night. It went to the bank, it went downtown.
You filed it, then I'm over the fucking top. You owe me a Cadillac.
- I don't think... - I don't wanna hear any fucking shit.
I don't give a shit. Lingk puts me over the top, you filed it.
It went downtown, now you owe me the car.
- The robbery makes difficult... - Fuck you, you owe me the car! See?
Cos this is how we keep score, Bubby.
You told me close thus and so you get the car. I got it.
Would you excuse us, please?
You hear what I said? Do you hear what I said?! Hey, pal!
Your excuses are your own.
(Dials phone)
(Reads) Recontact James Lingk. Haircut, 6pm Morton Grove...
Uh-huh. Yeah, well, when do you expect her in?
This is Ricky Roma from last night.
She'll remember me. Just... Wait a minute. Wait a minute!
Just to say... To thank her for a wonderful time.
Thank you. I'll call back later. Thank you.
They should check if we're insured.
Uh-huh.
10pm... Batavia.
DETECTIVE: Please don't leave.
I'm going to talk to you. What's your name?
Are you talking to me?
- That's right. - My name is Richard Roma.
I... You know... They should be insured.
What do you care?
- Well, then they wouldn't be so upset. - Uh-huh?
- They wouldn't be so upset... Mitch and Murray. - Yeah, you're right. That's right. How are you?
I'm fine.
What, you mean the board? You mean on the board?
I... Yes, OK. The board.
I'm fucked on the board. I can't... I can't...
See, I can... My mind must be other places, cos I can't...
What? You can't do what?
I can't close 'em.
Well, they're old. Look, look. Look at this shit they're giving you. Huh?
- Yes. - Huh?
- They are old. - They're ancient.
- Clear Meadows. This shit's dead. - It is dead.
- Waste of time. - Yes.
- I'm no fucking good. - Hey! Fuck that shit, George.
- You had a bad month. You're a good man. - I am?
Yeah. You had a bad streak...
Look at this. 15 units, Mountain View - fucking things get stole.
- He said he filed... - He filed the big one.
He filed the guy from the bar. That I closed last night.
All the little ones... I gotta go back.
Ah... can you believe this? I gotta go back and close again.
I mean, talk about a fucking beat that would sap anyone's self-c...
Wait, wait. Where are the phones?
- They stole 'em. - They stole...
- What kind of outfit is it... - They stole the phones.
...when criminals come and they steal the phones?!
They stole the leads, they stole the phones, they stole...
Oh, Christ.
What am I going to do this month?
Shit.
You think they... Where are you going?
Down the street.
Where are you going?
To the restaurant. What do you fucking care?
Aren't you going out today?
With what, John? With what?
Well, answer me. They stole the Glengarry leads. They stole Rio Rancho.
- I have the stuff from last year's file. - Oh, oh, oh. Your nostalgia file. Oh!
- Great. That's great, cos, you know... - Do you want to go out today?
...I don't have to eat this month.
Great. Give 'em to me.
Bring 'em. Come on.
Fucking Mitch and Murray are gonna shit a brick.
What am I going to do all month?
The thing of it is, is, you know...
Were the leads insured? Do you think?
What?
- Were the leads insured? - I don't know, George. Why?
Cos if they weren't, I know Mitch and Murray...
- What? - They'll be upset.
That's right.
You're right.
- He said we all have to talk to the guy. - To...
- The cop. - Great. We've got to talk to the cop.
Another waste of time.
A waste of time? Why?
Why? Because they're not gonna find the guy.
- The cops? - Yes, the cops.
- No. - The cops aren't gonna find the guy?
- Nope. - Why do you think so?
Why? Because they're stupid. Where were you last night?
Where were you?
- Where was I? - Yeah.
- I was at home. Where were you? - At home.
- Were you the guy who broke in? - Was I?
- No. - Then don't sweat it, George. You know why?
- No. - You have nothing to hide.
When I talk to the police, I get nervous.
You know who doesn't?
- No, who? - Thieves.
But I don't know what I'm gonna tell 'em.
The truth. Always tell them the truth. Easiest thing to remember.
Oh-oh-oh... Patel?
Ravidam Patel?
How do I make a living on these deadbeats? Where'd you get this, the morgue?
- Look, I'm... - Oh, come on! What's the point?
What's the fucking point? I gotta argue with you? I gotta knock heads with the cops?
I'm busting my balls to sell your dirt to deadbeats. Money in the mattress.
I come back, you can't even keep the contracts safe. I gotta go out... Fuck this shit.
- I'm gonna go and reclose last week's stuff. - No. The word from Murray is leave them.
- He needs a new sig, he'll go out himself. - Murray is gonna go out?
He'll be the president of the company, just come in from out of town. All right?
- OK, OK, OK. Give me this shit. - There's three leads.
- Three? I count two. - There's three.
Patel? Fuck you.
Fucking Shiva handed this guy a million dollars, told him, "Sign the deal", he wouldn't.
And the god Vishnu, too. Fuck you, John!
You know your business, I know mine. Yours is being an asshole.
I find out whose fucking cousin you are, I'll go to him and figure out a way to have your ass.
Fuck you!
I'm waiting for the new leads.
Get the chalk! Hey, get the chalk! Get the ch...
I did it! I closed him. I closed the cocksucker. Get the chalk, put me on the board, John.
Put me on the Cadillac board, huh?
Williamson?! Hey, pick up the fucking chalk!
Rick, eight units, Mountain View.
You sold eight Mountain View?
You bet your ass. Who wants to go to lunch?
Who wants to go to lunch? I'm buying. Hey, Williamson.
$82,000.
12 grand in my commission.
- On deadbeat magazine subscription leads. AARONOW: Who?
Bruce and Harriet Nyborg. Read it.
- What the hell happened? ROMA: Fuck! I had them on River Glen.
- What happened? WILLIAMSON: Somebody broke in.
ROMA: Eight units! - Wh... Yeah!
- Shelley! - Ah, big deal. I broke a bad streak.
Shelley "The Machine" Levene! That's great.
Thank you, George. Hey, grab the phone. Call Mitch.
- They took the phones. - Aaronow.
They took the leads, took the cash, took the contracts.
AARONOW: We had a robbery. - Last night, this morning.
They took the leads?
- Fucking asshole. - What? He beat you with a rubber bat?
Cop couldn't find his dick with a map. Anybody talks to this asshole's a fucking asshole.
- You gonna turn state's? - Fuck you, Ricky.
I ain't going out today, I'm going home. Nothing's accomplished here.
- Anybody talks to this guy... - Guess what The Machine did.
- Fuck The Machine. - Mountain View, eight units.
Cop's got no right to talk to me that way.
- I did not rob the place. - Did you hear what I said?
- Yeah, he closed a deal. - Eight units, Mountain View.
- You did that? - Yeah.
- Fuck you. ROMA: Guess who.
- When? - Just now.
- Guess who. - You... Just this morning?
Harriet and blah-blah Nyborg.
- You did that? - Yeah. $82,000.
Those fucking deadbeats.
My ass. I told 'em. Listen to this.
- I don't wanna hear fucking war stories. - Fuck you, Dave.
I said, "You have to believe in yourself."
Give me a lead. I'm going out, I'm getting out.
Oh, fuck the leads. I'm going home.
LEVENE: "Fuck me, Bruce. Believe in..." - We haven't got a lead.
- Why not? - They took 'em.
They're fucking garbage.
- The whole goddamn... - "You say this one has so-and-so.
- I got nothing. Why don't I get opportunities?" - Did they steal the contracts?
- Fuck you care. - "Harriet, I'll tell you."
- Fuck's that supposed to mean? - Shut up. I'm telling him something.
Can we get some coffee?
- How are you doing? - Fine.
Uh-huh.
If anybody's going out, I could use some coffee.
"You do get the opportunity."
- Fuck is that supposed to mean? - You do get the opportunities.
Ricky, that I don't care they stole the contracts?
- We're in the kitchen eating crumb cake. - What does that mean?
It means, Dave, you haven't closed a good one in a month.
None of my business. You wanna push me to answer you.
So you haven't got a contract to get stolen, and so forth.
- You got a mean streak, Ricky. - Let me...
Shut the fuck up. You got a mean streak. And what the fuck are you babbling about?
You bring that shit up, of my volume?
If you were on a bad one and I brought it up to you, you'd harbour it a long, long while.
Who said "Fuck The Machine"?
Fuck The Machine? Fuck The Machine?
Fuck The Machine!
What is this - courtesy class? You're fucked, Rick.
Are you fucking nuts? You're hot so you think you're the ruler of this place.
- Hey... - Shut up!
You want to decide who should be dealt with how, is that it?
I come to the fucking office, get humiliated by some jagoff cop.
I get accused of... I get the shit thrown in my face by you, you genuine shit,
because you're top name on the board!
Is that what I did, Dave? I humiliated you. Oh, my God, I'm sorry.
Sitting on top of the world. Sitting on top of the world. Everything's fucking peach fuzz.
And I don't get a moment to spare for some bust-out humanitarian, down on his luck.
- Oh, fuck you. - Fuck you. You know you got a big mouth.
You make a close, this whole place stinks with your farts for a week. How much you ingested.
Ohh, what a big man you are!
Let me buy you a pack of gum.
I'll show you how to chew it. Ooh.
Your pal closes, all that comes out of your mouth is bile. Eugh! How fucked up you are.
Who's my pal, Ricky? Hm?
What are you?
And what are you, Ricky, huh? Bishop Sheen?
What the fuck are you, Mr Slick? What the fuck are you, friend to the working man?
Big deal! Fuck you!
You got the memory of a fucking fly!
I never liked you anyway.
Is this your farewell speech?
- I'm going home. - Your farewell to the troops?
- No, not home, I'm going to Wisconsin. - Have a good trip.
Oh, fuck you!
Fuck the lot of you! Fuck you all!
You were saying?
Huh?
Come on.
Come on, you got 'em in the kitchen.
You're in your shirtsleeves. You got the stats spread out.
You can smell it. Come on, snap out of it.
You're eating her crumb cake.
- Yeah. I'm eating crumb cake. - How was it?
- From the store. - Fuck her.
"Bruce, Harriet, what we have to do is admit to ourselves
that we see that opportunity and take it - and that's it."
- Now, we just sit there. I got my pen out. - Always be closing.
God, that's what I've been saying. The old ways, right?
Convert that motherfucker. Sell him, make him sign the cheque.
Their money's in government bonds. I said to myself, "Fuck it. Let's go all the way, huh?"
I take it and plat it out. Eight units, 82 grand.
And I say to them, "This is now.
This is that thing that you have been dreaming of.
You are gonna find the suitcase on the train.
The man walks in the room, that bag is filled with money.
Harriet, this is it. And, Bruce, I don't want to fuck around with you. No, I don't.
I don't want to pussyfoot around, huh? You think you gotta look back on this? I do too.
I'm here to do good for you and me. The both of us.
What is the point of some interim position?
The only arrangement that I will accept is full investment, and I mean it. That's it.
All eight units, period."
I got the pen in my hand, Rick.
Hey, I turned that contract around. That's eight units. 82 grand.
And I said, "Now, I want you to sign."
I sat there five minutes.
And then I sat... 22 minutes by that kitchen clock on the wall.
Ricky, not a word, not a motion.
And what am I thinking? Is my arm getting tired? No.
I did it! Just like the old days, like I used to. Like I was taught. I did it!
- Like you taught me. - No.
Hey, no, nobody ever... Well, if I did, I'm glad.
No, what I did, I locked on 'em.
I locked all on them. Nothing on me, on them.
And, oh, God, I am holding my last thought - "Now is the time."
They signed. Ah, that was great.
It was... It was so fucking great.
It was like they wilted all at once.
- (Chuckles) - No gesture, nothing. Just together.
- Honest to God. - (Chuckles)
They both kind of imperceptibly slumped.
Then he reached, he took the pen, and he signed.
Passed it to her and she signed.
It was solemn, fucking solemn.
I let it sit, you know.
And then I nodded. I said, "Harriet, Bruce."
Then I pointed into the living room, to the sideboard.
I didn't know there was a fucking sideboard. He went over. He brought us back a drink.
Little shot glasses with a pretty design in the little...
And we just toasted in silence.
Great sale, Shelley. Great.
Ooh, fuck. Fuck! Hand me out. Come on! Give me leads. Williamson!
- Send me out! - The leads are coming.
I talked to Mitch and Murray an hour ago.
- They're coming in. They're a bit upset. - Did you tell 'em my sale?
How could I? I didn't have a tele... I'll tell them your sale when they bring in the leads.
We had a little... You closed the deal, you made a good sale.
- Better than a good sale. - I have a lot of things on my mind.
They're coming in, they're upset. I'm trying to...
All I'm telling you is you can tell them it was a remarkable sale.
- The remarkable thing is who you made it to. - What the fuck does that mean?
If the sale sticks, it'll be a miracle.
If the... Why shouldn't the sale st? Oh, fuck you!
That's... You do not know your job, you know that?
A man is his job. You are fucked at yours. You hear what I'm saying to you?
Your end-of-the-month fucking board.
You do not know how to run this office. You haven't got the sense or the balls.
Have you ever been on a sit? Has this cocksucker ever been on a sit?
- Ever sit with a customer? - If I were you, I'd calm down.
Oh, my God, what are you going to do, fire me?
- (Roma laughs) - Ooh, Rick. Ooh!
- It's not impossible. - Oh, really? On an $80,000 day?
- It's not even noon yet. - You closed today?
Oh, I got up early, I tracked him down and I closed it.
What I'm saying to you, is that things change.
That's where you fuck up because you don't know. You can't look back.
You don't see who's coming.
Maybe it's someone new, huh? Maybe it's someone else. But you don't know.
You can't look back - you don't know your history.
When we were on Rio Rancho, who was the top man?
For what? Two months? Three months?
How about eight months for three years in a row, huh?
And on what? Luck? Was that it, John? On purloined fucking leads? It was talent.
- Yes. - Door to door.
It's called cold calling, John.
Shit, I don't know their name, they don't want to buy what I've got. Soft sell.
- Shit, we did it before we had a name for it. ROMA: You're right, Shel.
You wouldn't know, you... (Laughs) He doesn't even know what a streak is.
What the hell are you?
You're a fucking secretary. Fuck you!
Yeah, that's my message to you. Fuck you and kiss my ass.
If you don't like that, baby, I go across the street
and I speak to Jerry Graff. Period. Fuck you.
Now, listen to me. You put me on that fucking board and I want three promising leads today.
I don't want any bullshit about them and I want them close together,
because I am gonna close them all.
And that's all I have to say to you.
He's right, Williamson.
LEVENE: I'm sorry, but it's wrong. And you know whose fault it is? Mitch and Murray.
Ah, to hell with him. Let's get some lunch, huh, Rick?
The leads won't be up here till later anyway.
You're a client. I just sold you five waterfront Glengarry farms.
I do this with my hair - throw me the cue Kenilworth.
- Which is it? - Kenilworth.
I... I own the property. My mother owns the property. I put her into it.
You look on the plats when you go home. You'll see.
A-3 through 10. 26 through 30.
- Take your time. If you still feel... - Oh, I won't need more time, Rick.
- I've bought a lot of property. - Can we talk?
Jim! What are you doing here?
Jim Lingk, er... D Ray Morton.
- I'm glad to meet you. - I just put Jim into Black Creek.
- Are you acquainted with er? - Black Creek? No.
- Oh, in Florida! - Yes.
- I meant to speak to you about that. - We'll do it this weekend.
- My wife suggested I look into it. - Beautiful rolling land.
I was telling Jim and Jinny. Ray, I gotta tell you something. Ray.
You eat in a lot of restaurants, I know you do.
Ray is with American Express.
- Can I tell Jim what you do? - Sure.
Ray is director of all European sales and services for...
What I'm saying is you haven't had a meal until you've tasted...
I was at the Lingks'... What was that service feature you talked about?
- Which? - "Home Cooking." What did?
- Er... - You had a tag phrase you used.
- Cooking... - Home Cook...
- The monthly interview. - The magazine.
- Yes. - Oh, well, I...
Is that something I can talk about?
Well, it won't be out until the February issue, but go ahead.
- Are you sure? - Go ahead.
Ray was eating at one of his company men's homes in France. The man is French.
No, but his wife is.
Ah, his wife...
Ray... what time do you have?
- 12:15. - I gotta get you on a plane.
- Oh, didn't I say the two? - No.
One o'clock. That's why we can't talk till Kenilworth.
Ooh, you're right, the one - let's scoot. A pleasure.
- Uh... I gotta talk to you. - I gotta run Ray to the airport.
Let's hustle. John! Get on the phone to Pittsburgh, American Express - for Mr Morton.
Tell them he's on the one o'clock.
I'll see you. Oh, Christ, I'm sorry. You came all the way in.
I'm running Ray to the airport. You wait here and I'll... No.
I can't. I'm meeting your man at the back.
- I wish you'd phoned. - Well...
- Wait. Are you and Jinny home tonight? - I don't know.
LEVENE: Rick? - What?
- Kenilworth. - Sorry?
Kenilworth.
Oh, God. Excuse me, Ray, just a minute...
Jim, I told you who he is. He's the Senior Vice President of American Express.
His family owns 32...
Over the past years I have sold him... I can't tell you the dollar amount, but quite a lot of land.
I promised him five weeks ago that I'd go to the wife's birthday party in Kenilworth tonight.
I have to go. You understand? I have to... They treat me like family. I have to go.
It's funny, you get a picture of a corporation-type company man, all business.
This guy... I tell you... We'll go to his house someday.
Let me see... Tomorrow...
I'm in LA. Uh...
Monday. I'll take you to lunch. Where would you like to eat?
- My wife said... LEVENE: Rick...
I can't talk now. I'll call you tonight. Sorry. Coming, Ray.
My wife said to cancel the deal.
It's a common reaction, Jim. Let me tell you what it is. That's why you married her.
One of the reasons is prudence. It's a sizeable investment. One thinks twice.
It's also something women have.
Reaction to the size of the investment.
Monday - invite me to dinner again... She can cook.
- I'm sure she can. - We're gonna talk.
I wanna tell you something. Something about your acreage
I want you to know.
I can't talk about it here. I really shouldn't.
And by law I c...
The man next to you bought his lot at 42, phoned to say he already had an offer.
Rick.
I'm coming, Ray. What a day. I'll call you this evening.
I'm sorry you had to come all the way in. I'm sorry. Monday lunch.
- We really have to go. - Monday.
She called the Consumer... The Attorney...
- The Attorney General? We have three days. - Who'd she call?
The Attorney G... It was some consumer office.
Why'd she do that, Jim?
I don't know. No, but they said we have three days.
- They said we've got three days. - Three days.
Three. You know...
No, I don't know. Tell me.
- Well, to change our minds. - Of course you have. Three days.
Well, so we can't talk Monday.
Monday. You saw my book.
Jim, Jim...
I can't. You saw my book. I can't.
We have to to get our money back.
Three business days, they mean. Three business days.
- Wednesday, Thursday, Friday. - I don't understand.
They're the three business... We wait till Monday, my time limit runs out.
- You don't count Saturday. - I'm not.
No, you don't include Saturday in three days. It's not a business day.
I am not counting it.
Wednesday, Thursday, Friday - so it would have elapsed.
- What would have elapsed? - If we wait till Monday, it would have elapsed!
- When did you write the cheque? - Yesterday.
- What was yesterday? - Tuesday.
- And when was that cheque cashed? - I don't know.
What's the earliest it could've been cashed?
I don't know.
Today? Today?
Which it was not, as there was something on the agreement I wanted to go over with you.
It wasn't cashed?
- I just phoned downtown. It's on their desk. - Rick...
One moment. One point, in fact,
of which I spoke to you, of which...
- I can't talk about it here. DETECTIVE: Levene.
LINGK: Listen...
Listen. The statute is for your protection. I have no complaint with that.
In fact, I was a member of the board when we drafted it - so quite the opposite.
You can change your mind three working days
- from the time the deal was closed. - Levene.
- Wait! That's not until the cheque is cashed. AARONOW: I'm through with this meshugas.
Nobody should talk to me that way. How are you talking to me that way?
DETECTIVE: Levene. - How can you talk to me that way?
LEVENE: I'll flag a cab. - I didn't rob.
Shelley... Shelley, get in the office.
Where were you last... Is anybody listening to me?
- Where's Moss? Where, where? - Levene. Is this Levene?
Perhaps I could assist you in that. Excuse us, will you?
Come in here... I work here.
- I didn't come in here to be mistreated. - Go to lunch.
I... I... came in to work today.
- If the leads come in, I'll tell you. - That's why I'm here!
- Go to lunch. - I don't wanna go!
Go to lunch, George.
- Where does he get off? I'm a working man! - Go outside. People are trying to do business.
That's what I came in for. It's what I'm trying to do.
- I meet Gestapo tactics! - Excuse me.
I meet Gestapo tactics!
I meet Gestapo tactics. That's not right.
No man has the right...
No man has the right to...
"Call an attorney" means you're guilt... You're under sus...
Cooperate. He says, "Cooperate or we'll take you downtown!"
That's not... As long as I've...
Will you get out of here? Will you get out of here? Will you?
I'm trying to run an office here. Now, will you go to lunch?
Go to lunch.
Will you go to lunch?!
- Will you excuse me? - Where did Moss?
- Excuse me, please. - Did he go to the restaurant?
Will you excuse me, please?
I'm sorry, I...
I apologise to you. It's um...
It's not me, it's my wife.
- What is it? - Well, I told you.
- Tell me again. - What's going on here?
Tell me again. Your wife.
- I told you, she... - Tell me again.
Well, she wants her money back.
Well, we're going to speak to her.
No. No, she told me, "Right now."
- We're going to speak to her, Jim. - No, she won't listen.
Roma.
She said if I don't get my money back,
- I have to call the State's attorney. - No, this is something she said.
- We don't have to do that. - No, she said I have to.
- No, Jim. - I do. I do... Listen, I do.
- If I don't get my money back... - Roma. I'm talking to you.
Listen...
Will someone get this guy off my back, please?
You have a problem?
Yes, I have a problem. Yes, I do, my friend.
It is not me that ripped the joint off.
I'm doing business. I will be with you in a while. You got it?
Where are you going? Where are you going?
This is me... Jim.
This is Ricky, Jim.
Anything you want. You want it, you got it. You understand?
This is me.
Something upset you. Yes.
Sit down, now. Sit down.
You tell me what it is.
Am I gonna help you fix it?
You're goddamn right, I am. Sit down.
Tell you something.
Sometimes we need someone from outside.
Sit. Talk to me. Come on.
I can't negotiate.
- What does that mean? - Well, I...
- What? - (Sighs)
What? Say the words.
I don't have the power.
OK? I said it.
What power?
To negotiate.
To negotiate what?
This.
- What this? - The deal.
- The deal? - (Sighs)
Forget the deal, Jim.
You got something on your mind. What is it?
What?
I can't talk to you.
You met my wife. I...
What?
Oh...
I met your wife, what?
(Sighs)
What, Jim?
Come on, let's go. Come on.
Let's go. Let's go get a drink. Come on.
No... she told me not to talk to you.
We're going round the corner for a drink. Who's going to know?
- She told me to get the cheque or I have to... - Forget the deal, Jimmy. The deal is dead.
You know me. The deal's dead. Am I talking about the deal?
That's over.
Please, let's talk about you.
I'm gonna tell you something.
Your life is your own.
You have a contract with your wife, you have certain things you do jointly.
You have a bond there.
And there are other things, and those things are yours.
And you needn't feel ashamed.
You needn't feel that you're being untrue
or that she would abandon you if she knew.
This is your life.
Yes?
Now, I wanna talk to you because you're obviously upset...
- No... - And that concerns me.
Now, let's go. Come on. Right now.
Let's go. Come on.
DETECTIVE: Roma. - What?
- Uh... - What?
The cheque, it's...
What did I tell you? No, look. What did I tell you about the three days?
DETECTIVE: Roma, I'd like to get lunch.
Er... I am talking with Mr Lingk. If you please.
I will be with you... in a while. Just check with Mr Williamson.
- People downtown said to check... - Call them again. Mr Williamson.
Yes?
Mr Lingk and I are gonna go to the...
Oh, yes, please. The police can be...
- What are the police doing here? - It's nothing.
- What are the police doing here? - We had a slight burglary...
- It's nothing. I was assuring Mr Lingk... - Mr James Lingk? Your contract went out.
- Don't worry. ROMA: John.
- Your contract went to the bank. - You cashed my cheque?
- Mr Williamson... - The cheque was cashed,
the contract was filed and deposited in the bank.
- And we're completely insured in any case. - You cashed the cheque?
Not to my knowledge, no.
I'm sure we can...
- Not to my knowledge. - Christ. I...
Oh, Christ. Hey, don't follow me. Just don't follow me, OK?
I've let you down. I know I've let you down. I'm sorry. Forgive me.
I... I've...
I don't know.
I don't know any more.
(Sighs) I'm...
(Sighs) Forgive me.
You stupid fucking cunt.
You, Williamson. I'm talking to you, shithead. You just cost me $6,000.
$6,000.
And one Cadillac. That's right.
What are you gonna do about it?
What are you gonna do about it... asshole?
You're fucking shit.
Where did you learn your trade, you stupid fucking cunt? You idiot.
Whoever told you that you could work with men?
DETECTIVE: Could I er?
Oh, I'm gonna have your job, shithead.
I'm going downtown. I'm gonna talk to Mitch and Murray. I'm going to Lemkin!
I don't care whose nephew you are,
who you know, whose dick you're suckin' on - you're going out.
- I swear to you, you're going... - Hey, fella. Let's get this done.
Anyone in this office lives on his wits.
I'm gonna be with you in a second.
What you're hired for is to help us.
Does that seem clear to you?
To help us... not to fuck us up.
To help men who are going out there to try to earn a living, you fairy.
You company man.
I'll tell you something - I hope you ripped the joint off.
I can tell our friend here a little something might help him to catch you.
You wanna learn the first rule?
You'd know if you ever spent a day in your life.
You never open your mouth till you know what the shot is.
You fucking child.
You are a shithead, Williamson.
Hmm.
Can't think on your feet, you ought to keep your mouth closed.
Can you hear me? I'm talking to you. Can you hear me?
Yes, I hear you.
Ricky's right. Can't learn it in an office, gotta learn it in the street.
- Sure can't buy it. You gotta live it. - Mm.
Yeah - "Mm." Yeah, precisely. Huh?
Because your partner depends... I'm talking to you, trying to tell you something.
- You are? - Yeah.
- What are you telling me? - What Roma told you.
What I told you. You don't belong in this business.
- I don't belong... - Listen to me.
One day you could say, "Hey, maybe the guy..." Oh, fuck it.
Listen to me now. Your partner depends on you.
Your partner, the man who is your partner, depends on you,
and you go with him and for him or you're shit.
- Huh? You are shit. You can't exist alone. - Excuse me.
Excuse you nothing. Be as cold as you want.
You just fucked a good man out of $6,000 and his goddamn bonus
because you didn't know the shot.
You can do that and you're not man enough to say it gets you?
If you can't take something from that, then you're... scum.
You're fucking white bread.
A child would know it. He's right.
If you're gonna make something up, John, be sure that it helps. Hm?
- Or keep your mouth shut. - Hm.
I'm done with you.
(Shelley mutters)
How do you know I made it up?
What?
What are you talking about? Huh?
You said, "Don't make something up unless it's sure to help."
Mm.
How did you know I made it up?
What are you talking about?
I told the customer his contract had gone to the bank.
Mm. Well, had it?
No, it hadn't.
Don't fuck with me. Don't fuck with me! What are you getting at?
Well, I'm saying this, Shelley...
Usually I take the contracts to the bank. Last night I didn't.
Last night I stayed home with my kids.
How did you know that?
One night in a year, I left a contract on my desk.
No one knew that but you.
Now, how did you know that?
You wanna talk to me or you wanna talk to someone else?
- Oh, for... - Because this is my job.
This is my job on the line and you are gonna talk to me.
How did you know the contract was on my desk?
You are so full of shit.
- You robbed the office. - Oh, sure. I robbed the office! You asshole.
- What did you do with the leads? - Wh...
You wanna go in there? I tell him what I know, he'll dig up something. You got an alibi?
- Yeah... - You better have one.
What did you do with the leads? If you tell me what you did with the leads, we can talk.
I don't know what the hell you're talking about.
If you tell me where the leads are, I won't turn you in. If not, I'll tell the cop you stole them.
Mitch and Murray will see that you go to jail, believe me. Where are the leads?
I'm walking in that door. You've got five seconds to tell me or you go to jail.
I don't care. You understand?
Where are the leads?
- I... - All right.
I sold 'em.
(Chuckles nervously)
Jerry Graff.
How much did you get for them?
- How much did you get for them?! - Five...
Five grand... I... I got half.
- Who got the other half? - Do I have to tell you? I...
Moss.
Well, that was easy, wasn't it?
- His idea. - Was it?
I think he got more than five, actually.
- Uh-huh. - He told me my cut was $2,500.
Mm.
Wait a minute. OK, John. Hey, hey. John. Wait. OK.
Hey, John. Hey, Johnny. Listen.
Come here.
Hey, John...
Last night...
I gotta tell you, I'm ready to do the Dutch. I'm done.
Moss gets me, "Do this, we'll get well." Why not? Big fucking deal.
I'm halfway hoping to get caught. Hey, put me out of my misery.
It taught me something, John. What it taught me...
...you gotta get out there.
I'm not cut out to be a thief, I'm cut out to be a salesman, and I am back. I got my balls back.
Now...
...you got a slight advantage on me here.
But whatever it takes, John, to make things right, we're gonna make it right.
We are going to make it right.
- I want to tell you something, Shelley. - Uh?
You have a big mouth.
What?
You've got a big mouth. And now I'm gonna show you an even bigger one.
Where are you going?
You can't do that. You don't wanna do that.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait. Huh?
It's $2,500. Go ahead and take it. Take it all.
I don't think so. I don't think I want your money.
I think you fucked up my office. I think you're going away.
Are you nuts?! I'm gonna close for you. Take...
I'm gonna make this office and I'm gonna be number one on that board again.
(Laughs derisively)
Wait, John. John...
OK. Uh...
This is what we're gonna do.
20%. I'm gonna give you 20% of all my sales.
20% as long as I'm with this firm.
50.
50% of all my sales.
- What sales? - What sales?!
By God, I just closed 82 grand. Are you out of your fucking mind? I'm back.
- This is just the beginning. - The beginning? Where have you been?
- Bruce and Harriet Nyborg! - Ssh.
You want to see the memos? They're nuts. They used to call in every week.
When I was with Webb we were selling Arizona. (Whistles) They're nuts.
Did you see how they were living? How can you delude yourself?
- I got their cheque. - Forget it. Frame it, it's worthless.
- The cheque is no good? - If you stick around, I'll pull the memo.
Wait. The cheque is no good? They're nuts?
Want to call the bank, Shelley? I called them four months ago when we first got the lead.
The people are insane.
They just like talking... to salesmen.
Don't.
I'm sorry.
Why?
Because I don't like you.
My daughter...
Fuck you.
Asshole.
Guy couldn't find his fucking couch in the living room.
ROMA: What a day. Whooh!
I haven't even had a cup of coffee.
(Train rumbles)
Jagoff John opens his mouth, blows my Cadillac.
(Sighs) I swear it's not a world of men.
It is not a world of men, Machine.
- Huh? - A world of clock-watchers.
Bureaucrats...
Office-holders, what it is.
It's a fucked-up world.
No adventure to it.
A dying breed.
Yes, it is. We're the members of a dying breed.
ROMA: That's...
That's...
That's why we gotta stick together.
Shel.
- Huh? - I wanna talk to you.
I've wanted to talk to you for some time. For a long time, actually.
I said, "The Machine...
There's a man I would work with.
There's a..." You know?
I never said a word. I don't know why I didn't. I should've. I don't know why.
And that shit you were slinging on my guy today...
That was so good. That...
Excuse me for saying this. It's not even my place to say it.
That was admirable.
It was the old stuff.
Hey, I've been on a hot streak.
So what? The things I can learn from you.
- You eat today? - Me?
Yeah. You want to swing around the Chink's, watch me eat? We'll talk?
I think I'll stay around a while.
Hello, Mrs Schwartz.
This is Richard Roma - Premiere Properties.
You or your account requested information on a land investment
which would offer you depreciation
and the chance of a substantial return on a small investment.
- I'm in from Florida for one day... DETECTIVE: Mr Levene?
So I only have that one lot left.
DETECTIVE: Could you come in here?
ROMA: I don't have much time. I'm on the midnight plane back.
So if you or your husband are truly interested...
Cos I can't hold this parcel ba...
ROMA: Yes? Well, what would be better for you - six or eight?
Well, go ask him... Shel.
Let's talk. I'm going to the Chink's. Come down and smoke a cigarette.
- I er... DETECTIVE: Get in the room.
Hey, hey... Hey.
Easy, pal. That's The Machine.
- This is Shelley "The Machine" Levene. - Get in the goddamn room.
- Rick, I... - OK, I'll meet you there.
- Ricky... - Ricky can't help you, pal.
- All I want is... - What do you want?
- You want what? - Rick...
- Rick... - Hello?
Excellent.
ROMA: 8pm.
6947 Euclid.
Not at all. Thank you very much.
They find the guy that broke into the office?
No.
I don't know.
Did the leads come in yet?
No.
Oh, God, I hate this job.
Anybody wants me, I'm at the restaurant.
Hello. Mrs Delgare? Yes, you requested some information about Rio Rancho properties.
* Blue skies
* Smiling at me
* Nothing but blue skies
* Do I see
* In the morning there's bluebirds
* Singing a song
* Nothing but bluebirds
* From now on
* I never saw the sun shining so bright
* Never saw things going so right
* Never seen the days hurrying by
* When you're in love, my, how they fly
* Blue day, all the day long
* Nothing but blue skies
* From now on...
* Blue skies
* Smiling at me
* Nothing but blue skies
* Do I see
* In the morning there's bluebirds
* Singing a song
* Nothing, but nothing, but bluebirds
* From now on
* Let me tell you I never saw the sun shining so bright
* Never saw things going so right
* Never seen the days hurrying by
* When you're in love, my, how they fly
* Blue skies
* Smiling at me
* Nothing but blue skies
* Do I see
* In the morning there's bluebirds
* Singing a song
* Nothing, but nothing, but bluebirds
* From now on
* Let me tell you, I never saw the sun shining so bright
* Never saw things going so right
* Never seen the days hurrying by
* When you're in love, my, how they fly
* Blu-u-ue days
* All of them, all of them gone
* Nothing but blue skies
* From now on
* Now on
* Nothing but blue skies