They're off, ladies and gentlemen!
There they go!
Classic World War II aircraft.
The Axis versus the Allies!
The Spitfire
Group Captain Nigel Palmer
versus the Messerschmitt
of Major Ernst Leichman.
And Japan's Colonel
Sue Horikoshi in the Zero
versus our own Colonel Chappy Sinclair
in the P-38 Lightning!
- Hello.
- Hey!
I wouldn't have thought
she has the power for the snap roll.
Stockman has spruced it up a bit
and added a few other little goodies.
Still not much for the Spit,
I'm afraid.
Her guns have been updated
by Dassault,
and her snout's been
re-engined by Rolls Royce.
Oh, really? Well, don't look now,
but her butt is about to be
reamed by Lockheed.
Regret to end
the contest so soon.
Looky here,
looks like Tokyo's hot to trot.
Appears your shooter
had a case of premature ejection.
Very unusual maneuver.
Don't you remember?
Zeroes were famous for it over Midway.
And P-51s used to counter
with this move.
Uh-oh.
Whoo!
Ha-ha.
Ha. Ha. Ha. Ha.
Another spectacular victory
for Colonel Chappy Sinclair,
as Colonel Sue Horikoshi
is acknowledged in defeat.
Let's hear it
for the Red, White and Blue.
(crowd cheering)
And now the Spitfire's Battle
of Britain, Pilot Nigel Palmer,
versus Germany's Ernst Leichman,
flying the Messerschmitt 109.
We haven't seen the likes
of a struggle like this since the 1940s.
They're begging for a spectacle,
you bloody Kraut!
- Let's give them one.
- All right, Limey.
Mind your elbows,
mein Herr.
Yeah, by the looks of this
it could be a close one.
Hold on to your hats!
Those boys are gonna give me
a heart attack.
Ladies and gentlemen, I swear
I didn't know they were gonna do that.
Walk up for another kill
for Major Ernst Leichman.
Tomorrow is our last show of the season,
ladies and gentlemen.
The Axis and the Allies
fly again.
We certainly hope
you all can join us.
We still have a few tickets
for tonight's End of the Season Party.
Your chance to meet the Aces,
so hurry.
Ha. Ha. Ha. Ha.
Now, don't go committing
hara-kiri, Sue.
- You'll get me next time.
- No. You're too pretty to die.
Excuse me.
- Colonel.
- Yeah.
Ramón Morales
just crashed in the Gulf.
- Is he all right?
- He's dead, Chappy.
Dead?
- When? How?
- I don't know.
All I know is a whole bunch of suits
just flew in from Houston.
General Simms
wants you back on the base.
Now.
Sue. You tell Stockman
that there's been an accident.
- I'll try and be back tonight.
- Oh.
- Enzo!
- Si, mi capitán.
I want more trucks, more jeeps,
50 more armed guards.
We move again so soon?
A small incident has transpired.
DEA may become bothersome.
So I take the risk. We simply move
higher up into the mountains.
Más fuego aqui, apúrale.
Apúrese, vieja.
- Apúrese.
- Escovez.
Ask the mayor when they'll finish
packaging this consignment.
Quiere saber cuánto tiempo
toma empacar todo.
Como en dos dias.
Y ya he estado trabajando
muy duro para ustedes.
Por favor, senor,
le suplico que suelte a mi hija.
Yeah yeah yeah.
He says very quickly.
Perhaps two days.
But he pleads with you
to release his daughter.
Tell him unless he gets back
to work quickly,
I will kill his daughter
in front of him.
Dice que si no vuelves
a trabajar enseguida...
Up in the mountains,
good workers are hard to find.
Maybe this time
we should take them with us.
Impossible. They've seen
the markings of the planes.
Though these people
have served this land well, Juanito,
in five days time
we shall bury them in it.
Flight Commander
Finley report to operations.
...that's part of the tail section,
let's put it over here.
Coast Guard
find the body too?
Most of it. The medics
are doing an autopsy.
His personal things are over here.
Do you know
these people, Colonel?
- I didn't catch your name.
- Well, I'm Warren Crawford.
Henry, bring that over here.
It's his family.
Kid brothers, dad, sister.
She went to UCLA
on an athletic scholarship.
This picture was taken
the day she graduated.
He's from a little village
in the Peruvian mountains.
His father's the mayor.
He has an aunt
living here in Brownsville.
That's all in your files.
Anybody's told her?
She's been informed, yeah.
Poor people, aren't they?
Very poor.
They worked their butts off
to make something of themselves.
We think he was shot down
by the Colombian cocaine cartels.
Well they had to get to one of us
sooner or later.
We're out there tracking them
all the time.
Morales was in competition with him.
They don't like that.
What the hell is that
supposed to mean? Who are you?
I'm the station chief,
DEA, Houston.
Chappy, I think you better
take a look at his auxiliary fuel tank.
Damn! I don't believe this.
Where is his flight report?
Who was with him?
I was, Colonel. It was just a routine
interdiction mission.
Over Sector Seven he said he had orders
from you to fly a classified pattern.
He would rendezvous
one hour after break-off.
I never gave those orders.
I wouldn't know about that, sir.
He broke off over the Yucatan.
I got his mayday 45 minutes later.
By the time I got there
there was nothing but wreckage, sir.
- GULFSTAT confirm this?
- They were off-line for EV tests.
DEA intends to run
a full investigation on this, Colonel.
We'll want to talk you again soon.
The DEA isn't running
any full investigations on my command,
and it's God damned well not
gonna harass any of my senior officers.
Well, sir, there's no way Morales
was operating alone,
not with a quarter of a billion
worth of cocaine in his tank.
Maybe, maybe not.
But this kind of scandal
makes headlines the Pentagon
doesn't like one damn bit.
Services prefer to clean
their own houses, Mr. Crawford.
I'll lunch my own little look-see
into this matter.
Excuse me, sir, but DEA
does have jurisdiction in this case.
You're on a military installation, son.
The only thing
that has jurisdiction around here
is the star on my shoulder.
Take your people back to Houston,
and I'll see you get a full report.
(telephone ringing)
You're late.
We're clear, but GULFSTAT
reports that DEA
is tightening surveillance
on fighter aircraft in the entire area.
Your moment of madness could've
place the entire operation in jeopardy.
I had no choice.
Morales was running scared.
He threatened
to go to Colonel Sinclair.
Just as well I have a contingency plan,
isn't it, Captain?
Give me the code numbers.
Lima-Romeo-654.
They have to touch down by 0500.
Escovez.
The Jackhammer flight leaves
for Lethridge at midnight.
We must begin
loading immediately.
Use all available personnel.
(En Vogue singing
"Boogie Woogie Bugle Boy")
Give me a blazing sun,
occasional clouds for cover,
and I'll shoot the ass
off any aircraft flying.
Well maybe next year Arthur'll send you
up against an F-16 or a Mirage.
Call it The Battle
of the Generation Gap.
Agh. Flying computers, Captain.
In our day, it used to be the man,
not the machine.
Technology is no match
for seasoning.
- Damn shame you missed it, chap.
- Don't hold my youth against me.
By the time
I was old enough to join up,
there was nothing but missiles
and Mach speed.
Very fine beer.
May have to import it
for company cafeteria.
I was told you work
for an aerospace firm,
but I didn't fancy you as caterer.
He's chairman of the board.
What do you say, we press
a little flesh, gentlemen?
You know, mix and mingle,
work the crowd!
You know this little party
could line us up to real supporters
- for next year's show.
- Well, count me out.
When I retire, I'm gonna buy myself
a little ranch, and a big hammock,
I want to sit around
all day working on my tan.
Ha. Ha. 10'll get you 20,
that'll last about a week.
When this batch is dry, use these people
to help with the packaging.
Five kilos in each pound here?
(struggling)
(Choking)
Este no es mi trabajo.
- A trabajar.
- Yo soy el Mayor de la ciudad.
- ? Aqui?
- Si.
- Trabajan todos.
- Mande.
- Muchas gracias.
- Bien, muchacho.
Buenas.
Detente.
Cuidado.
- Rápido, rápido, rápido.
- Vamos.
Mira. Amo, amo.
- A la plataforma.
- Atención.
Más rápido!
Vamos.
Papá.
Papá, voy a Lethridge
a buscar a Ramón.
Siganme.
Vamos, rápido.
Acá.
Come on, move it.
Finish loading and be gone.
Nobody is gonna stop you at the gate.
You're Anna Morales,
Ramón's sister.
What the hell happened to you?
I need to find my brother,
where is he?
Anna, I'm Chappy Sinclair,
Ramón's friend.
There's something
I need to tell y...
There's no time to talk,
I need to find my brother.
My whole village
and family is in danger...
- Anna, Ramón is dead.
- I need to find...
He was shot down in the Gulf.
He was carrying cocaine in his tanks.
No es cierto.
Ramón, Ramón.
Ramón.
They told Ramón they would kill us all
if he didn't help them.
Who?
Who told you that?
A German called Kleiss.
He's going to kill everyone
in four days, my family...
- Slow down, slow down.
...everyone.
Now, how did you get here?
I escaped on the plane that brought
the drugs here to your base.
Drugs are being brought
here to this base?
Yes, they're unloading now.
They're in the barrels.
Kleiss called it the Jackhammer
flight to Lethridge.
Give me the key.
You stay right here.
I'll be back as fast as I can.
You keep this door locked.
You don't open this door
for anyone.
Hold it. Hold it!
- Hold it.
- Stop right there.
Let me see your orders.
- What are you bringing in?
- Hydraulic fluid, sir.
A milk run.
Next stop is San Diego.
This plane ain't stopping nowhere
until I see what's in those barrels.
- Get me a crowbar.
- Yes, sir.
Don't stand there, get another crowbar
and open up the rest of those barrels.
What's going on here, Colonel?
I think there's drugs
in this plane, sir.
The DEA was right.
Morales wasn't just a lone eagle.
Offload the rest of this cargo
and have it checked.
Where are you getting
your information, Colonel?
Morales's sister.
She's in his quarters.
She'll lay the whole thing
out for you.
It's all right, Anna.
It's Chappy Sinclair.
Anna?
She's gone.
Why don't you take a little water
with your booze, Colonel?
I thought... she was here,
General, I swear.
This base is going to close
in three weeks.
My base for 12 years.
My men, my planes, my equipment
transferred to other commands,
all over this country.
I wanna go out with honor, Colonel.
I don't want a trumped-up scandal
and I don't want gossip and talk.
Have you got that?
Yes, General.
I've got that.
How do I know that you're not
running a line of bullshit
just to save
your own ass, Colonel?
You don't,
until I find the girl.
This guy Kleiss she talked about,
does he mean anything to you?
Gustav Kleiss has been
on the Fed's books for years,
dealing arms, heroin,
chemical weapons in the Middle East.
He uses the money to finance
hate groups all over the world.
Can you get
any information from Peru?
That's not such an easy thing
to do, Colonel.
You know how much corruption
there is down there?
These are poor countries
surviving on narco bucks.
They don't want
to hear from DEA.
So, what about
this Jackhammer?
I'll tell you what,
you get her to pinpoint
the location of Kleiss,
and I'll see what I can do.
Well she's got an aunt in Brownsville,
maybe she's there.
Now, that's a rough neighborhood.
You watch your ass, Colonel.
Always do.
(Dance music playing)
Want some action?
Oh, come on.
(baby crying)
Excuse me.
315?
Lotto game was last night,
brother.
- Mrs. Del Prado?
- Si.
I'm Colonel Sinclair.
Please, please,
I must speak with Anna.
Váyase. Váyase.
Wait! Anna.
I just wanna talk to you.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Wait, hey!
I'm getting too old
for this shit.
Hey, don't...
What kind of shit
are you looking for, lady?
Blow...?
Uh-uh!
Put it down.
Now.
See? This homeboy don't dig
any piece carrying by non-members.
Now, baby,
wanna leave it to brother?
Or you want to stick around here?
Leave, thanks.
Hey, maybe
you should just say no.
I owe you one.
You better start trusting me.
How can I? A soldier came
to arrest me after you left Ramón's.
Abre la puerta,
es Anna.
A soldier?
Did you just see his face?
Just his gun.
I ran off the back and I came here.
My aunt has been waiting
for me to return.
Estoy bien, tia.
No se mortifique.
There's nothing you can do alone.
I've been to the DEA
and they're willing to help.
I need for you to point out the exact
location of Kleiss' set-up.
It has to be accurate.
Do you think you can do that?
I think so.
But I'll need a little time.
All right.
I gotta go fly.
There's something I have to do.
I'll be back soon.
Look, everything
is gonna be okay.
But no more running out.
All right?
No more running out.
Look, boy.
$50.
You keep an eye on the girl.
Deal?
Deal.
(Dance music playing)
Oye, vato, put that shit
back in the van.
I'm paying the house all day.
You cover my ass.
Comprende?
Comprende.
Thank you, Jesus.
Archie, bring them down now.
Chappy's here.
Oh!
Permiso senora.
Oye, digame
if the old lady comes back.
(struggling)
Bitch!
- Now, get your ass in the bedroom.
- No.
(struggling)
- I told you to stay outside, vato.
- You can't do this.
Watch me.
I'm afraid I never miss twice,
Colonel.
Oh my God!
Tower, this is Chappy.
Clear the runway.
I got problems.
(crowd voicing concern)
(coughing)
Chappy!
Oh, man.
Thank God you're all right.
Somebody must've
fooled around with the ammo.
I'm damned grateful
you're such a lousy shot.
Who in the hell could've made
a mistake like that?
That was no mistake,
Arthur.
There is some deep shit
going down here.
And if they tried for me, they're damned
sure gonna try for Anna. I need a car.
Thank you for your cooperation.
- Who's Anna?
- I'll let you know later.
We go with you.
If you're in serious deep shit,
maybe you need some help.
Chappy Sinclair is unhurt.
Let's go.
Let's hear it
for a great piece of flying.
Baby, take us for a ride.
Wife say
travel in America...
...very dangerous.
He tried to take her out.
And I don't mean for dinner.
Where's Anna?
Yo, baby, come on in.
The coast is clear.
- Are you all right?
- I'm fine.
- You know him?
- Oh, yeah.
He's a heavy homeboy
from the hood.
My ass ain't gonna be worth a shit.
Nobody's ass is gonna be worth anything
if we don't find her a safe place.
You can take her back to my place.
We could stay with her.
What are you gonna do with him?
Well I'm gonna get some of my brothers
to help me dump his ass.
You can't hang here, brother.
I mean, the police are gonna
be happy that he ain't breathing,
but his homeboys
are gonna come look for him,
like inquiring
minds wanna know.
All right.
And how about your aunt?
She's gone
to stay with friends for a few days.
Did you manage to finish that map?
- Yes, I did.
- All right.
Here it is.
We've got enough time to get to
the DEA office before they close.
Come on, let's go.
No help.
Peruvian justice people say
there's nothing in the area except
coffee growers. SATS confirm.
Oh no. Kleiss' set up
is camouflaged.
- You have to come in low with a plane.
- Izquitos airbase is in the same grid.
They'd know if anything was going on
without visual confirmation.
I have to take their word for it.
- That's bullshit.
- I don't make the policy.
DEA will get Kleiss.
It may take a while,
but we will bring
the bastard in.
A while?
That's a whole lot of comfort
for those people who are
gonna die in a couple of days.
People die in the drug world
all the time, Chappy.
There's nothing more
that can be done right now.
Don't you read
the papers, Sinclair?
Peru's big
on territorial sovereignty.
No surveillance, no interdiction,
no nothing without their permission.
An F-16 can go so fast, it could aim
from Bogotá and end up over in Lima.
Faster than you can say
"My God, I'm in the wrong airspace."
And get back out,
just as fast.
I don't believe I'm hearing this.
Come here, Chappy.
This is my whole life
here on the wall.
Take a good look,
Korea, Nam, the Philippines.
You're asking me
to put it on the line
by authorizing a low-level
reconnaissance mission?
I wouldn't involve you, sir.
You bet your ass you're not gonna
involve me. You're grounded, Sinclair.
This Morales affair
has screwed all of us.
Whatever your involvement is,
bury it
along with him.
Dismissed.
Te suplicamos humildemente
por el alma de tu siervo Ramón,
que has sacado hoy
de este mundo.
No la entregues
en manos del enemigo,
ni la dejes
en perpetuo olvido.
Manda a tus ángeles
que la reciban
y la lleven
a la patria del cielo.
Para que pues, ha esperado,
y criado... creido en mi,
no padezca
las penas del Infierno,
sino que es unir las voces
sobre los votos eternos...
I tried everything, Anna.
It's important that you understand that.
You're everything
Ramón said you were.
But I've been
depending on you too much.
Now I have to do something myself.
Like what?
A few men escaped
to another village.
Maybe we can mount
some kind of attack.
With just a few guys?
I have to try.
My family's lives
are at stake.
You have to understand that.
(Country music playing)
Hardly a proper attendance
for a wake, Chappy old chap.
- May we join you?
- Be my guest.
Chappy, we come
to say goodbye.
No. Not before
I buy you all a drink.
Where you all going?
Well, Sue
has a business to run.
I have grandchildren
to terrorize.
And I'm sure Leichman here
has Nazi hunters to evade.
Bottom line is... there's not
a lot of calls for arthritic pilots.
At least we were all pilots,
before they bastardized the bloody word.
With all due respect
to the deceased, of course.
The only thing that was bastardized
is the way this kid went down.
The way they're handling
this damn thing.
He was a good pilot.
Oh, sure he was, Chappy.
Look, I don't mean any offense, but you
have to admit that the kids today
do it all with terminals
and the monitors and what have you.
Now, as Ernst
is so fond of saying,
"It used to be about the man,
not the machine."
Yes.
Hey, how would you like
to prove that theory?
I would.
What makes you so ready
to go after this Kraut?
All Krauts weren't Nazis,
you know?
But this Kleiss
was the worse kind.
He even killed his brother,
for refusing to shoot down
enemy pilots parachuting to safety.
And then he had the gall to steal
his dead brother's Medal of Honor.
Well, why not?
Can't have you Yanks and Jerries
dukin' it out all over
the Peruvian jungles
without a representative
of Queen and country.
I would be honored.
Gentlemen.
- To Ramón.
These planes
are priceless antiques.
They are not battle gear.
Pound for pound, flown
by the right men, they're lethal.
Hell, you modified them.
You know what they can do.
What about air-to-ground
ordinance?
These... these laser units.
How do you think
you're gonna get all that...?
I got a hold card at the base.
They can get us outfitted in a day.
Anna leaves 12 hours earlier,
and hooks up with the local resistance.
Oh, that's a real comfort.
All they've got to do is to line up
the lasers with the targets,
and leave the rest to us.
Now,
if they can get in there undetected,
a two-year-old
could operate the unit.
- And what if they don't?
- Well, then we abort.
Either way, I'll have these fighters
back in this hangar by Sunday morning.
Yeah, in how many pieces?
Damn, Arthur.
Men like you
helped to build this country.
And men like me
helped to defend it.
Now I'm willing to risk my career
and my life for what I believe in.
Come on, Arthur,
take a risk.
Cocaine is killing
our country, man.
Wouldn't you like to have a nice story
to tell your grandchildren?
Something more than
beating out other wildcatters,
or finaglin' the bond market?
Wouldn't you?
I'm taking Polaroids.
Not a scratch on those paint jobs.
Are you clear on that, Chap?
I'm clear.
Hi.
So, uh, how are
we gonna pull this off?
If you mean "we,"
as in you and me,
then you got
the wrong definition of the word.
Oh, wait.
Come on, Chappy.
Excuse me.
- You can start contacting your people.
- How long to prepare, Chappy?
We're airborne in 36 hours.
Let's go, guys.
I can't even tell
if the systems are compatible, Chappy.
Units were designed for jets.
Traveling at Mach I.
We're about to find out.
Commencing approach.
You have to hold the unit
really steady
all the way through
target termination.
She's all yours.
We are gonna
need some seeker heads.
Fins too. Couple of other things.
Anna has the list.
- You've a list?
- Hmm.
- When do you want this stuff?
- Tonight'll be fine.
If you want miracles,
why don't you call the Pope?
SATS. Compliments
of Warren Crawford.
Okay, Anna. Let's take
a real good look at this village.
Okay. The guns are concealed
here and here.
There are more guns
hidden in the bushes,
and on the water tower, here.
The village is very close by.
- Hmm.
- That's a bit tight.
But with Anna and her men
in place to direct the lasers,
we should be able
to knock out their artillery
without doing any harm
to the villagers.
With bedlam going on there,
and Kleiss' pistols concentrating on us,
Anna should be able to get
the villagers out of that factory.
Then, on the second time around,
we bomb their dope.
We each line up
on one target, right?
- Correct.
- Piece of cake, old boy.
Piece of cake?
I don't want to hear
any more of this.
Let's get our gear
stowed, Anna.
We're gonna go.
We're gonna be out of here early.
Oh, by the way, I'm gonna put
a super booster on the P-38.
Strike leader could always
use a little extra power.
Much obliged.
All right.
We divide into pairs.
Strike and Wingman.
We cover each other's ass.
Who wants to team with whom?
Leichman?
Well, Nigel chose me last time, so...
it would be impolite
not to return the favor.
Fine.
Sue, that leaves you and me.
We've been tangoing
pretty good together.
Regret to say...
I cannot go with you
on mission.
Why, Sue?
What's wrong?
I have deceived you.
- Deception?
- I'm not famous, Ace.
That was my brother.
He died 40 years ago.
I served only at the end of war.
Never in combat.
Always in his shadow.
I would jeopardize
your safety.
Forgive me.
I'm...
very dishonorable man.
You're not dishonorable.
You told the truth.
That's a damn hard thing to do.
Thank you.
Bloody hell.
I was just getting
fond of the idea.
God damn it, Chappy!
Don't you think we can pull this off?
- Just the three of us.
- No.
They told them
these were defective.
Said I had to hand carry 'em back
to the manufacturer to work...
the bugs out.
Uh-uh.
- Evening, Sir.
- Sir.
I might as well walk here.
It'd be safer than flying this crate.
Christ, it doesn't even
have a HUD!
Sue'll have you
checked out soon.
If there're any other options,
I'd take them.
If I had a suicide pill,
I'd take it.
Sir, you can't go in there.
That's all right, Sergeant,
thank you.
I followed Ames to Avra.
He and Sinclair got something going on
with those antiques fighters.
Those old shit buckets.
They can't be that stupid.
Wings are loaded with ordinance.
They're not planning a charity ball.
Where the hell are they getting
that stuff?
Ames, he's stripping our storerooms
of everything that isn't nailed down.
I'll fix that bastard.
- Sergeant.
- Sir?
Get the chief of security
in here.
We'll change our plans.
Take our plane down first thing,
turn around and transship immediately.
Contact our people
at the other bases.
Tell them to be prepared
for accelerated delivery.
Yo, ho-ho. Ha-ha.
Santa Claus is here.
Santa went straight to the ghetto.
Check this out, man. I got enough stuff
in here to outfit a whole army.
What is all of this?
Well, I took a little green out
of the homeboy's sock, right?
So Anna's dudes got something
to kick a little ass with.
Ha-ha.
Check that out, brother.
- So am I in now or what?
- We already discussed this.
No, no.
We ain't discussed nothing.
All right? If the shit hits the fan,
I'll be there.
You could get killed
in that place, boy.
Hey, I can get killed in my own
neighborhood, man.
It ain't nothing new to that.
Look, your personality
just doesn't fit my team profile.
So forget it.
Captain, I'll need to see
inside the vehicle.
Fourth of July.
- Good luck.
- Thanks, Chappy.
I guess we finally understand
each other, don't we?
Yes, we do.
Chappy...
watch your ass.
I always do.
Chappy.
Ames was gonna check my laser control.
Now, where the hell is he?
We don't have our full complement
of missiles yet, you know?
Chappy.
It's Ames on the phone.
He's in trouble.
Muévanse.
Arranquen.
Muévanse!
I'd better get to a radio
and call them back.
We'll never make it with three aircraft
and half of the ordinance untested.
Suggest we leave.
We're half hour
behind schedule.
Sue, are you sure?
I'm sure, but...
the decision is yours.
Perhaps, your lives
will depend on me.
- We...
- Would be honored.
- Mamá!
- Ahi va, hijito.
So where are your people?
They'll be here.
(clamoring)
Aah... ooh... aah...
ooh... aah.
Ah!
My legs! My legs. I can't feel
my legs, they're dead.
- What do you think you're doing?
- What am I doing?
Yo, baby, that was my best
Eddie Murphy imitation.
Hey, how are you doing?
It's show time.
So let's get busy.
He goes back with you.
No way, baby.
We're a team now, huh?
We're like Jazzy Jeff
and the Fresh Prince.
I mean, we're like
Milli and Vanilli.
We're like Michael Jackson
and the Elephant Man's bones.
Yo, are they still together?
No, they are not together,
and neither are we.
- You're history.
- Oh, let's talk history, baby.
Now, if I do recall,
I saved your butt twice.
And I'm trying to save yours.
Oh, we don't go dissing me baby.
My butt is covered. The rest of your
posse will be happy to have me along.
- By the way, where are they?
- Behind you.
Qué bien, aqui están.
Damn, homeboys around here
got some bad-ass disguise.
Fernando,
? dónde están los demás?
- No vinieron.
- Pero tengo todo listo.
Ya sé,
pero lo aceptaron...
- What's happening?
- ? Cómo?
Uh?
Usted dig rap?
You know,
like my name is Tee Vee
and I am here to say that I am a rapping
brother and I'm here to stay. Huh!
No?
Let's see.
You got MTV around here?
You got an opinion
on 2 Live Crew?
I guess not.
Hey, where is your posse
going off to?
- Back to their homes.
- Oh, hey. Can I get a rewind on that?
Kleiss' security has been increased.
They say we don't have a chance.
Well, I make it a point
to never argue with the locals.
- I have got to roll.
- Make that "we."
The party's over. Look, you're crazy if
you think you're going in there alone.
It's much too dangerous.
Ordinance?
Check.
- Check.
- That will do it.
We've got three hours till refuel.
Take it easy.
It gets uglier from there on in.
Rápido!
...borregos!
- You're pulling out?
- As soon as you're airborne.
Cause for celebration
by the local people, I'm sure.
Oh yes. They'll be having
a special mass.
It'd be most uplifting.
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha.
Make sure
everything's ready to go.
A little overkill,
don't you think?
- Never hurt Stallone.
- Not so fast.
Maybe I better follow you.
The deposits have been made
just as we agreed.
This final shipment
should be worth another 50 million.
Perhaps more.
Dispersed to bases all over the country
along with the Lethridge surplus.
No questions will ever be asked.
And you are a very rich man.
Don't you want
to drink to that?
I'll drink to paying back
those bastards in the Pentagon.
I gave them 27 years,
God damn it.
And they closed me down.
We're getting close
to the village.
Here.
(Horse whinnies)
Let's go.
We don't have much time.
Hold this.
Stay here.
(Burro haws)
Shh.
Cayeron en la trampa.
Manuel, allá.
Aah!
- ! Cuidado, cuidado!
- Está minado el camino.
Llévatelo al camión.
Agarra la bolsa.
? Trajiste las bolsas?
Aah!
? Qué pasó, condenada?
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha.
Miras...
Buenota, muy buenota.
(Laughs)
Si te mueves te mato,? Huh?
Te mato.
Súbelo.
Siéntese.
We're getting close.
Panther One?
This is Strike Leader.
Do you copy?
Dame el radio.
Panther One?
This is Strike Leader. Do...
Panther One.
This is Strike Leader.
Do you copy?
Over.
- Maybe we're still out of range.
- Chappy: Lmpossible.
We're only a half hour
from the target.
I'll keep trying.
It's dangerous to break radio silence
repeatedly at this point,
isn't it, Chappy?
We've got no choice.
We're flying blind
without the ground unit.
Panther One, this is
Strike Leader. Come in.
Yo, man,
watch the threads.
Jesus.
This is a laser interlock unit
from my base.
Sinclair!
Patrón, Sector Cinco
interceptó la transmisión
de cuatro aviones
en esta dirección.
Sector Five has just
picked up the transmission
of four aircraft headed this way.
Call lzquitos Airbase.
I'm getting airborne!
Get him out of here.
Atención, atención.
Estamos en estado de alerta.
Apúrate.
Más pronto, ya casi
acabamos con la iglesia.
Mete eso alli.
Eso atrás.
Pronto.
Muévanse, muévanse.
Bogeys, 10:00 and closing.
Shit.
Gustav?
Aircraft in Peruzco Pass.
Identify.
Identify?
Shoot them down.
What do I pay you for?
That is Kleiss.
He's pretty good
at buying off pilots...
...split up fast
and pull them in close
where we have the advantage.
Bank out of there, Nige.
He's gonna get your ass.
Hardly, old boy! Remember
"the man, not the machine"?
Whoa!
Mayday,
Chappy!
Mayday!
Mayday, Chappy.
Hang on, Nige.
Hang on.
What the bloody hell
does it look like I'm doing?
Ohh!
Well done, old chap.
? Qué me traes aqui?
(Laughing)
Ahi les traen la comida.
Am I glad to see you?
You know, I got tired of hanging around
here all by myself.
You know what? I should just
leave you here, you know that?
Cuida la puerta.
Los demás,
vamos conmigo!
I hope these things still work.
Vamos, a prisa.
Looks like your posse
had a change of heart.
Ayúdame.
Vamos, ale, ale!
Sue, use your counter measures.
Deploy your foil
and get out of there.
Rápidamente.
A la linea de fuego.
Rápido.
I'm going to the airport.
You got to keep things moving here!
Muévanse.
Yo. Strike Leader,
this is Panther One.
We're loose, we got the juice, and we're
ready to blow the shit outta this goose.
Tee Vee, is that you?
None other, baby. I flew in
for the surprise party.
- Baggage class.
- Where are you?
We're up in the bell-tower
at the church, man. You should stop by.
- We got a beautiful view.
- What about the lasers?
Anna's setting them up
as we speak.
You better jam, man. Kleiss
is pumping some major drugs
into the belly
of a big bird on the runway.
Well, line up on the artillery.
We're 20 miles out and closing.
Gotcha.
Dame eso.
Ayúdame.
Come on, baby. Get some
big dudes on that sucker.
This ain't Pee Wee's
Playhouse.
Muévelo.
Despacio.
? Lo miras?
Perfecto.
Leichman?
Panther One is in position.
Can you hold out while me
and Palmer go in for target?
I'm good.
Horikoshi, what about you?
Never better.
(Beeping)
(Alarm sounding)
- Ernst, are you all right?
- Yeah, he got the message.
So much for your
damn air cover!
Get those engines
started now!
Get those drums loaded!
- Lock them in, now.
- Check.
You hear the man?
There he is!
Palmer, take
the northwest gun.
- Fire when you get a lock.
- Roger.
Aah!
The bloody tracking unit
isn't working!
Guillermo,
no es tu culpa.
We better switch positions.
Leichman?
Get down here.
Palmer's laser malfunctioned.
Afraid mine has too.
It doesn't even light up.
- Sue, do you read me?
- I'm on my way.
Déjalos, déjalos,
como si fuera su vida, muchachos.
Muévete.
Yo disparo.
Ahh!
Recoge eso!
Muévanse!
- Get airborne now!
- Where the hell am I gonna go?
Go to Salvador.
I've friends there.
You may lose the flags and the military
bands when you retire,
but you won't lose the money.
I need gunners.
You! You!
Here.
Hold on northwest position
and line up on southwest,
- you got it?
- We got it.
Palmer,
are you okay?
As I said, technology's no match
for seasoning. We're going back down.
Smug bastard!
So much for seasoning!
Only one bogey left.
And it looks like we lost Palmer.
Damn it!
We're all lined up.
We're coming in.
Ahh!
Yeah!
Woo!
Cuidado! No!
Asesinos, desgraciados!
Line up the southwest gun for Sue.
I'm saving my missiles for the factory.
Tell Anna to get her people
out of there and into the church.
You copy?
We copy, Chappy.
We're lining up now.
Manda más hombres enseguida.
Necesitamos ayuda,? Me entiendes?
Ayúdenme, por favor!
Rápido, la mesa!
Ahi vienen de nuevo!
Atentos!
Ahi viene otro!
Ahh!
You suckers!
Apúrense todos!
Apúrense.
Rápidamente.
Rápido!
Apúrense.
Anna's people are doing good.
But the trucks
are starting to split.
I think they got
Kleiss' equipment on them.
That's my call.
- Corre, corre.
- Auxilio, corran!
All right, the big bird
has taken off.
Shit.
- Sue?
- I would be honored.
Corran a la iglesia!
Agárrenlo. Sáquenlo.
Sáquenlo, váyanse, agárrenlo.
Okay, Anna's getting
her people into the church.
That's perfect. When the church blows,
the Americans will be blamed.
Que lo deje ahi, que lo deje ahi.
Ya vuélvanse!
You're clear. We're going to get
a line on the factory right now.
Tell me when you're set.
Take this truck out of here
and put the other one in.
Okay, we got to lock.
- Otro!
- Ahi viene.
Al suelo!
Air force, baby. When it absolutely,
positively has to be.
Ha-ha-ha-ha.
Whoa!
Blow the church!
Get the men up
into the mountains.
Basta!
Basta, tú.
Mayday! Mayday! Kleiss is pulling in
two choppers' worth of backup.
We're history.
Let's get out of here.
Strike Leader,
this is Warren Crawford.
Do you copy?
Warren?
Those choppers yours?
DEA's finest.
ETA five minutes.
Panther One,
these choppers are friendly.
Stay put until the DEA
can give you help.
Aah. We copy that, baby.
Apura, apura.
Damn.
I knew this was too easy.
Va a explotar la iglesia,
sálganse de aqui! Rápido, ya!
Vámonos de aqui!
Vámonos!
Ahh!
Tee Vee, come back!
(Church bell ringing)
Tee Vee, are you okay?
Nice hat!
One more pass.
You take care of it.
I'm worried about Sue.
Ahh!
Get him out of here!
Knock that bastard
out of the sky!
Hold your fire.
Hold it!
Chappy.
Kleiss is airborne.
Repeat.
Kleiss has escaped.
What's he flying?
It's the weirdest damn jet
I've ever seen.
Guns all over the wings.
- Which direction?
- North!
Jackhammer,
this is Wolf Seven.
Come on up,
the skies are clear.
Not quite.
Two fighters remain.
They're flying shit buckets.
Let them take their best shot.
Sue. Come in,
this is Chappy.
Sue.
Pull out!
Yaa!
Sue!
Shit!
Good God!
It survived!
- What?
- Messerschmitt 263.
The plane that was going
to win the war for Germany.
Don't take him on alone.
Chappy, I didn't fly
all this way to run.
Break it off, Leichman.
I'm 10 seconds out.
Leichman?
Is that you, Ernst?
You've disgraced
our family's name
and you've disgraced
our country.
Huh!
One last chance for you
to do something for the Fatherland.
You've got that just exactly right.
Leichman, bail out!
Hardly the Aryan ideal, are you?
Afraid I didn't get a chance
to grab my swastika
and get a lobotomy.
You only have seconds to live.
I smell the kill.
What you smell is in your pants.
Take a whiff of this.
Kiss my ass.
Damn!
Bastard never dies.
Warren,
this is Strike Leader.
Kleiss has bailed.
We spot him.
Dispatching a unit now.
I'm coming in!
Can't seem to recall your name.
Morales.
Like my brother Ramón.
But more intelligent, perhaps.
What do you want for the jeep?
Six figures? Seven?
I don't even talk
about a full tank of gas.
Very sensible.
I have a lot of friends here,
and there are
no extradition treaties with the US.
! Qué alegria!
You know what movie
they're showing on the way home?
You all right?
- I'm gonna make it.
- I know you will.
Confounded Palmer
is going to haunt me
until I'm an octogenarian.
You mean
you found the wreckage?
Not the wreckage...
Palmer!
The devil's alive!
Ha-ha!
(Laughing)
I think this calls
for a celebration, Chappy!
Yeah. I know
just the place for it.
(Country music playing)
Hey, what's with the Stetson?
Well, let me tell you, partner,
I'm switching
from urban to suburban.
Kind of like you,
brother.
You want to put
these steaks on?
All right.
And don't burn them
like you did those chops.
Those aren't burned,
- they're extremely well done.
- Oh, shut up.
- Hey!
(Chappy chuckling)
So, where's Dad and the boys?
They wanted to be here
more than anything to thank you,
but they knew you'd understand.
We'll never forget
all you've done for us.
Aah.
Oh, the DEA, they wanted
sole credit for the bust
and I wanted all of Kleiss' cash
to go to the villagers.
So we made a compromise.
They did it my way.
(All chuckling)
I have something
that I think belongs to you.
Welcome home.
Thank you, Anna.
Well, you know,
I didn't come out so bad either.
The Air Force gave me
a nice little fleet
of moth-balled F-86s
to keep my mouth shut.
Uh-huh.
Leichman and Palmer
are gonna fly them for me next year.
Well...
if we can work out
the percentages.
What about a guest shot from you
next season, Chappy?
Now that you got your own plane,
What are you gonna call her?
Son of a bitch.
That's not much of a name.
You know,
I think I'm gonna call her...
"Shadow Warrior,"
named after Sue.
Yep, better get 'em
while they're hot!
Get what?
What is that?
- You cook?
- I'll fly the plane! How about that?
SubRip by TraceR