Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
They're off, ladies and
gentlemen! There they go!
Classic world war ii aircraft!
The axis vs. The allies!
The spitfire of capt. Nigel Palmer vs.
The messerschmitt
of major Ernst leichman!
And Japan's
jiro horikoshi in the zero
vs. Our own colonel
"chappy" sinclair
in the p-38 lightning!
Hello.
Hey, I wouldn't have thought you
had the power for a snap roll.
Stockman has goosed it up a bit and
added a few other little goodies.
Still, no match for
the spit, I'm afraid.
Her guns have been
updated by dassault
and her snout's been re-engined
by Rolls-Royce. - Oh, really?
Well, don't look now, but her butt
is about to be reamed by lockheed.
You read and countered so soon.
Ha, looky here. It looks
like Tokyo is hot to trot.
It appears your shooter had
a case of premature ejection.
Very unusual maneuver.
Don't you remember?
Zeros were famous
for it over midway
and p-51s used to counter
with this move.
Whoo! Ha-ha!
Another spectacular victory
for colonel "chappy" sinclair.
There's colonel jiro horikoshi
acknowledging defeat.
Let's hear it for
the red, white and blue!
And now the spitfire
battle of britain
pilot Nigel Palmer
vs. Germany's Ernst leichman,
flying the messerschmitt 109!
Reenact the life and death
struggle above england
in the 1940s.
They're begging for a
spectacle, you bloody kraut!
Let's give them one.
All right, limey!
Mind your elbows, mein herr.
By the looks of this,
it could be a close one.
Hold onto your hats!
Those boys are gonna
give me a heart attack!
Ladies and gentlemen, I swear,
I didn't know
they were gonna do that.
Chock up another kill
for major Ernst leichman.
Tomorrow is our
last show of the season,
ladies and gentlemen.
The axis and the allies
fly again.
Really hope y'all can join us.
We still have a few tickets for
tonight's end-of-season party.
Your chance to meet
the aces, so hurry.
Now don't go committing
harakiri, su.
You'll get me next time.
No, you are too pretty to die.
Excuse me.
- Colonel?
- Yep.
Ramon morales just
crashed in the Gulf.
Is he all right?
He's dead, chappy.
Dead?
When, how?
I don't know. All I
know is a whole bunch
of suits just
flew in from Houston.
General Simms wants you
back on the base, now.
Su, you tell stockman that
there's been an accident.
I'll try and be back tonight.
I want more trucks, more jeeps,
and 50 more armed guards.
We move again so soon?
A small incident has transpired.
The DEA may become bothersome.
So, why take the risk?
We simply move higher up
into the mountains.
Ask the mayor
when we will finish
packaging this consignment.
He says, "very quickly,
perhaps two days."
But he pleads with you
to release
his daughter.
Tell him unless he gets
back to work quickly,
I will kill his daughter
in front of him.
Up in the mountains, good
workers are hard to find.
Maybe this time,
we should take the loss.
Impossible. They've seen the
markings on the planes.
No, these people have served
this land well, Juanito.
In five days' time, we
shall bury them in it.
Flight commander findlay,
report to operations.
Coast guard find the body too?
Most of it. The medics
are doing an autopsy.
His personal things
are over here.
Do you know these
people, colonel?
I didn't catch your name.
Oh, I'm Warren Crawford.
That's his family.
Kid brothers, dad, sister.
She went to ucla on
an athletic scholarship.
This picture was taken
the day she graduated.
He's from a little village
in the Peruvian mountains.
His father's the mayor.
He has an aunt living
here in brownsville,
but that's all in your files.
Anybody tell her?
She's been informed.
Uh, poor people, aren't they?
Very poor.
Had to work their butts off
to make something of themselves.
We think he was shot down by
the Colombian cocaine cartels.
They had to get to one
of us sooner or later.
We're out there tracking
them all the time.
Morales was in
competition with them.
They don't like that.
What the hell's that supposed to mean?!
Who are you?
I'm the station chief,
DEA, Houston.
Chappy,
I think you better take a look
at his auxiliary fuel tank.
Damn! I don't believe this.
Where's his flight recorder?
Who was with him?
I was, colonel.
Just a routine
interdiction mission.
Over sector seven,
he said he had orders
from you to fly
a classified pattern.
We would rendezvous
one hour after break-off.
I never gave those orders.
I wouldn't know about that, sir.
He broke off over the Yucatan.
I got his mayday
45 minutes later.
By the time I got there,
there was nothing
but wreckage, sir.
Gulfsat confirm this?
They were all flying
for ev tests.
DEA intends to run a full
investigation on this, colonel.
We'll want to talk
to you again, so...
The DEA isn't running any full
investigations on my command!
And it's god damn well not gonna
harass any of my senior officers!
Well, sir, there's no way
morales was operating alone,
not with a quarter of a billion
worth of cocaine in his tank.
Maybe, maybe not,
but this kind of scandal
makes headlines
the Pentagon doesn't like
one damn bit!
The services prefer to clean
their own houses, Mr. Crawford.
I'll launch my own little
look-see into this matter.
Excuse me, sir,
but DEA does have
jurisdiction on this case.
You're on a military
installation, son!
The only thing that has
jurisdiction around here
is the star on my shoulder.
Take your people
back to Houston,
and I'll see you
get a full report.
You're late!
We're clear.
Gulfsat reports that DEA
is tightening surveillance
on fighter aircraft
in the entire area.
Your moment of madness
could have placed
the entire
operation in jeopardy.
I had no choice.
Morales was running scared.
He threatened to go
to colonel sinclair.
Just as well I have a contingency
plan, isn't it, captain?
Give me the code numbers.
Lima-Romeo-654.
They have to touch down by 0500.
Escovez!
The jackhammer flight leaves
for lethridge at midnight.
We must begin
loading immediately.
Use all available personnel.
But then his number came up
and he was gone with the draft
he's in the army now
a-blowin' reveille
he's the boogie woogie
hip-hop boy of company b.
Give me a blazing sun,
the occasional
cloud for cover,
and I'll shoot the ass off
of any aircraft flying.
Well, maybe next year
Arthur will send you up
against an f-16 or a mirage.
Call it the battle of
the generation gap.
Ach! Flying computers, captain.
In our day, it used to be
the man, not the machine.
Technology is no match
for seasoning.
Damn shame you missed it, chap.
Well, don't hold
my youth against me.
By the time I was
old enough to join up,
there was nothing but
missiles and mach speed.
Very fine beer.
May have to import it
for company cafeteria.
I was told you worked
for an aerospace firm,
but I didn't fancy
you were its caterer.
He's chairman of the board.
What do you say we press
a little flesh, gentlemen?
You know, mix and mingle.
Work the crowd.
You know, this little
party could line us up
some real supporters
for next year's show.
Well, count me out.
When I retire,
I'm gonna buy myself
a little ranch
and a big hammock.
I'm gonna sit around
all day working on my tan.
10 will get you 20
that will last about a week.
When this batch is dry, use these
people to help with the packaging.
Five kilos in each barrel, yes?
Ahh!
Come on, move it!
Finish loading and you're gone.
Nobody's gonna
stop you at the gate.
Ohl
You're Anna morales.
Ramon's sister.
What the hell happened to you?
I need to find my brother.
Where is he?
Anna, I'm chappy sinclair,
Ramon's friend.
There's something
I need to tell you.
There's no time to talk.
I need to find my brother.
My whole village and
family's in danger.
Ramon is dead.
He was shot down in the Gulf.
He was carrying
cocaine in his tanks.
Ramon!
They told Ramon
they'd kill us all
if he didn't help them.
Who, who told you that?
The German called kleiss.
He's going to kill
everyone in four days.
- My family, everyone!
- Slow down.
Slow down, slow down.
Now, how did you get here?
I escaped on the plane that brought
the drugs here to your base.
Drugs are being brought
here to this base?
Yes, they're unloading now.
They're in the barrels.
Kleiss called it the jackhammer
flight to lethridge.
Gimme the key.
You stay right here. I'll
be back as fast as I can.
You keep this door locked.
You don't open this
door for anyone.
Hold it!
Hold it! Stop right there!
Let me see your orders.
What are you bringing in?
Hydraulic fluid, sir. A milk run.
Next stop, San Diego.
This plane ain't stopping nowhere
until I see what's in those barrels.
- Get me a crowbar.
- Yes, sir.
Don't just stand there.
Get another crowbar and open
up the rest of those barrels.
What's going on here, colonel?
I think there's drugs
in this plane, sir.
The DEA was right. Morales
wasn't just a lone eagle.
Off-load the rest of this
cargo and have it checked.
Where are you getting your
information, colonel?
Morales' sister.
She's in his quarters.
She'll lay the whole
thing out for you.
It's all right, Anna.
It's chappy sinclair.
Anna?
She's gone.
Why don't you take a little
water with your booze,
colonel?
But she was here,
general, I swear.
This base is going to
close in three weeks.
My base for 12 years.
My men, my planes,
my equipment transferred to
other commands
all over this country.
I want to go out
with honor, colonel.
I don't want
a trumped-up scandal
and I don't want
gossip and talk!
Have you got that?!
Yes, general, I've got that.
How do I know
that you're not running
a line of bullshit
just to save your
own ass, colonel?
You don't, until
I find the girl.
This guy kleiss
she talked about.
Does he mean anything to you?
Gustav kleiss has been on
the feds' books for years,
dealing arms, heroin, chemical
weapons in the middle east.
He uses the money
to finance hate groups
all over the world.
Did he get any
information from Peru?
That's not such an easy
thing to do, colonel.
You know how much corruption
there is down there?
These are poor countries
surviving on narco-bucks.
They don't want
to hear from DEA.
What about this jackhammer?
I'll tell you what.
You get her to pinpoint
the location of kleiss and
I'll see what I can do.
Well, she's got an aunt in brownsville.
Maybe she's there.
Now, that's a
rough neighborhood.
You watch your ass, colonel.
Always do.
Want some action?
Aw, come on.
Excuse me, this 3157
lotto game was
last night, brother.
Mrs. del prado?
Si.
I'm colonel sinclair.
Please, please,
I must speak with Anna.
Wait! Annal
I just wanna talk to you!
Whoa, whoa! Hey, hey!
I'm getting too old
for this shit!
Hey, don't...
What kind of shit you
looking for, lady... blow?
Ahh!
Ah-ah...
Put it down, now.
See, these homeboys
don't dig any
piece carrying by nonmembers.
Now, baby, you wanna
leave it to brother,
or you wanna stick around here?
Leave, thanks.
Hey, maybe you
should just say no.
I owe you one.
You better start trusting me.
How can I?
A soldier came to arrest
me after you left Ramon's.
A soldier? Did you see his face?
Just his gun. Ran out the
back and I came here.
There's nothing
you can do alone.
I've been to the DEA and
they're willing to help.
I need for you to point out the
exact location of kleiss' setup.
It has to be accurate. Do
you think you can do that?
I think so.
Great.
But I'll need a little time.
All right, I've gotta go fly.
It's something I have to do.
I'll be back soon.
Look, everything is
going to be okay.
But no more running out,
all right?
No more running out.
Hey, boy...
$50, you keep an
eye on the girl.
Deal?
Deal.
Put that shit back in the Van.
I'm paying a house call today.
Cover my ass, comprende?
Comprende.
Thank you, Jesus.
All right, you can bring them down now.
Chappy's here.
Oh...
Let me know if the
old lady comes back.
Uh! Oof!
Bitch!
Ohl
Now get your ass in the bedroom!
I told you to stay outside.
You can't do this.
Watch me.
I'm afraid I never
miss twice, colonel.
Oh, my god!
Tower, this is chappy.
Clear the runway.
I got a problem.
Chappy!
Oh, man! Thank god
you're all right.
Somebody must have fooled
around with the ammo.
I'm damn grateful you're
such a lousy shot.
Who in the hell could've
made a mistake like that?!
That was no mistake, Arthur.
There's some deep shit
going down here, and
if they tried for me,
they're damn sure gonna try for Anna.
I need a car.
Who's Anna?
I'll let you know later.
We go with you.
If it's serious deep shit,
maybe you need some help.
Chappy sinclair is unhurt.
Let's go.
Let's hear it for
a great piece of flying.
Ooh, take us for a ride, man.
Wife say travel in
America very dangerous.
He tried to take her out,
and I don't mean for dinner.
Where's Anna?
Yo, baby, come on in.
Coast is clear.
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
You know him?
Oh, yeah, he's a heavy
homeboy from the hood.
My ass ain't gonna
be worth shit.
Nobody's ass is gonna be worth anything
if we don't find her a safe place.
You can take her
back to my place.
We could stay with her.
What are you gonna do with him?
I'm gonna get some of my brothers
to help me dump his ass.
He can't hang here, brother.
The police are gonna be happy
that he ain't breathing,
but his homeboys are gonna
come looking for me.
You know, like, inquiring
minds wanna know?
All right.
How about your aunt?
She's gone to stay with
friends for a few days.
Did you manage
to finish that map?
- Yes, I did.
- All right.
Here it is.
We've got enough time to get to
the DEA office
before they close.
Come on, let's go.
No help.
Peruvian justice people
say there's nothing
in the area except coffee
growers, that's confirmed.
Oh, no, kleiss'
setup is camouflaged.
You have to come in
low with a plane.
Esquitos air base
is in the same grid.
They'd know if anything was going
on without visual confirmation.
I have to take
their word for it.
That's bullshit!
I don't make the policy!
DEA will get kleiss.
It may take a while,
but we will bring
the bastard in.
A while?
That's a whole lot of comfort for
those people who are gonna die
in a couple days.
People die in the drug war
all the time, chappy!
There's nothing more that
can be done right now!
Don't you read
the papers, sinclair?
Peru's big on
territorial sovereignty.
No surveillance,
no interdiction,
no nothing without
their permission.
An f-16 can go so fast,
they can aim for Bogota
and end up over Lima
faster than you can say,
"my god, I'm in
the wrong airspace."
And get back out just as fast.
I don't believe
I'm hearing this.
Come here, chappy.
This is my whole life
here on the wall.
Take a good look.
Korea, 'nam, the Philippines.
You're asking me to put it
on the line by authorizing
a low-level
reconnaissance mission?
I wouldn't involve you, sir.
You bet your ass you're
not gonna involve Mel
you're grounded, sinclair.
This morales affair
has screwed all of us.
Whatever your involvement is,
bury it along with him.
Dismissed.
I tried everything, Anna.
It's important
you understand that.
You're everything Ramon
said you were.
But I've depending
on you too much.
Now I have to do
something myself.
Like what?
A few men escaped
to another village.
Maybe we can mount
some kind of attack.
With just a few guys?
I have to try.
My family's lives are at stake.
You have to understand that.
I'll take you with me
if you just send me
love letters
till I return...
Hardly the proper
attendance for a wake,
chappy, old chap.
May we join you?
Be my guest.
Chappy, just come
to say goodbye.
Not before I buy
you all a drink.
Where you all going?
Well, su has a business to run.
I have grandchildren
to terrorize.
I'm sure leichman here has
Nazi hunters to evade.
Bottom line is,
there's not a lot of call
for arthritic pilots.
At least we were all pilots.
Before they bastardized
the bloody word.
Mm, all due respect to
the deceased, of course.
The only thing
that was bastardized
was the way that
this kid went down
and the way they're
handling this damn thing!
He was a good pilot.
Oh, sure, he was, chappy.
I don't mean any offense,
but you have to admit
that the kids today
do it all with terminals and
monitors and what have you.
Now, as Ernst
is so fond of saying,
it used to be about the man...
- Not the machine!
Damn right.
Hey...
How would you like
to prove that theory?
I would.
What makes you so Randy
to go after this kraut?
All krauts weren't
Nazis, you know.
But this kleiss
was the worst kind.
He even killed his brother
for refusing to shoot down enemy
pilots parachuting to safety.
And then he had
the gall to steal
his dead brother's
medal of honor.
Well, why not?
Can't have you yanks and Jerrys
duking it out all over
the Peruvian jungles
without a representative
of queen and country.
I would be honored.
Gentlemen...
To Ramon.
Ramon.
These planes are
priceless antiques.
They are not battle gear!
Pound for pound, flown by the
right men, they're lethal.
Hell, you modified them.
You know what they can do.
What about air-to-ground ordinance?
These laser units.
How do you think
you're gonna get...
I have a card at the base.
I can get us outfitted in a day.
Anna leaves 12 hours earlier
and hooks up with the
local resistance.
There's a real comfort.
All they've got to do
is line up the lasers
with the targets and
leave the rest to us.
If they can get in there
undetected, a 2-year-old
can operate the unit.
And what if they don't?
Well, then we abort.
Either way, t'll have these
fighters back in this hangar
by Sunday morning.
Yeah, in how many pieces?
Damn, Arthur!
Men like you helped
to build this country,
and men like me
helped to defend it.
I'm willing to risk my career
and my life for
what I believe in.
Come on, Arthur, take a risk.
Cocaine is killing
our country, man.
Wouldn't you like to have
a nice story to tell
your grandchildren?
Something more than beating
out other wildcatters
or finagling the bond market?
Wouldn't you?
I'm taking polaroids.
Not a scratch
on those paint jobs.
Are you clear on that, chap?
I'm clear, I'm clear.
Hi.
So, how we gonna pull this off?
If you mean "we"
as in you and me,
then you got the wrong
definition of the word.
Aw, come on, chappy.
Excuse me.
Start contacting your people.
How long to prepare, chappy?
Airborne, 36 hours.
Let's go, guys.
I can't even tell if these
systems are compatible, chap.
The units were designed for
jets traveling at mach 1.
Well, we're about to find out.
Commencing approach.
You have to hold
the unit really steady
all the way through
target termination.
She's all yours.
Gonna need some seeker heads.
Fins too. Couple of other things.
Anna has the list.
You have a list?
Mmm.
When do you want this stuff?
Tonight will be fine.
Look, you want miracles, why
don't you call the pope?
Sats, compliments
of Warren Crawford.
Okay, Anna, let's take a real
good look at this village.
Okay, the guns are concealed
here and here.
There are more guns hidden in the
bushes and on the water tower here.
The village is very close by.
Yes.
That's a bit tight,
but with Anna and her men
in place to direct the lasers,
we should be able to
knock out the artillery
without doing any harm
to the villagers.
With bedlam going on there and
kleiss' pistols concentrating on us,
Anna should be able to get the
villagers out of that factory.
Then, on the second
time around...
We bomb that dope.
We each line up
on one target, right?
Correct.
Piece of cake, old boy.
Piece of cake?
I don't wanna hear
any more of this.
Let's get our gear stowed, Anna.
If we're gonna go, I wanna
be out of here early.
Oh, by the way,
I'm gonna put a
super-booster in the p-38.
Strike leader
could always use
a little extra power.
Much obliged.
All right,
we divide into pairs,
strike and wingman.
We cover each other's ass.
Who wants to team
with who, leichman?
Well, Nigel chose me last time,
so it would be impolite not to
return the favor.
Fine.
Su, that leaves you and me.
We've been tangoing
pretty good together.
Regret to say...
I cannot go with you
on mission.
Why, su?
What's wrong?
I have deceived you.
Deception?
I'm not famous Ace.
That was my brother.
He died 40 years ago.
I served, but only
at the end of war.
Never in combat.
Always in his shadow.
I would jeopardize your safety.
Forgive me.
I'm very dishonorable man.
You're not dishonorable.
You told the truth.
That's a damn hard thing to do.
Thank you.
Bloody hell...
I was just getting
fond of the idea.
God damn it, chappy!
Don't you think we
can pull this off?
Just the three of us.
Nah.
I told 'em these were defective.
Said I had to hand
carry them back to
the manufacturer to work the...
Bugs out.
Uh-uh.
'Evening, sir.
I might as well walk there.
It'd be safer than
flying this crate.
Christ, it doesn't
even have a hood.
Su will have you
checked out soon.
If there were any other
options, I'd take them.
If I had a suicide pill,
I'd take it.
Sir, you can't go in there!
That's all right, sergeant.
Thank you.
I followed ames.
He and sinclair got something going
on with those antique fighters.
Those old shit buckets?
They can't be that stupid.
Wings are loaded with ordinance.
They're not planning
a charity ball.
Where the hell are they
getting the stuff?
Ames, he's stripping
our storerooms
of everything that
isn't nailed down!
I'll fix that bastard.
- Sergeant.
- Sir?
Get the chief of
security in here.
We'll change our plans.
Take our plane down first thing,
turn around and transfer
immediately.
Contact our people
at the other bases.
Tell them to be prepared
for accelerated delivery.
Yo-ho-ho, ha-ha!
Santa claus is here.
Santa went straight to the ghetto.
Check this out, man.
I got enough stuff in here
to outfit a whole army.
What is all this?
Well, I took a little green out
of the homeboy's sock, right?
So Anna's dudes got something
to kick a little ass with.
Ha, check that out, brother.
So, am I in now, or what?
We already discussed this.
No, no, we ain't
"discussed" nothing.
All right, if shit hits
the fan, I'll be there.
You could get killed
in that place, boy.
Hey, I can get killed
in my own neighborhood, man.
There ain't nothing new to that.
Look, your personality just
doesn't fit my team profile.
So forget it.
Captain, I'll need to
see inside the vehicle.
Fourth of July?
Good luck.
Thanks, chappy.
Guess we finally understand
each other, don't we?
Yes, we do.
Chappy,
watch your ass.
I always do.
Chappy.
Ames was gonna check
my laser control.
Now, where the hell is he?
We don't have our full complement
of missiles yet, you know.
Chappy!
It's ames on the phone.
He's in trouble.
I better get to a radio
and call him back.
We'll never make it with three aircraft
and half the ordinance untested.
Suggest we leave.
We a half hour behind schedule.
Su,
are you sure?
I'm sure, but decision is yours.
Perhaps your lives
will depend on me.
We would be honored.
So, where are your people?
They'll be here.
Ahh!
My legs, my legs!
I can't feel my legs!
They're dead!
What do you think you're doing?
What am I doing? Yo, baby, that was
my best Eddie Murphy imitation.
Hey, how you doing?
It's showtime,
so let's get busy.
He goes back with you.
Oh, wait, baby!
We a team now, huh?
We like jazzy Jeff
and the fresh prince.
I mean, we like
milli and vanilli.
We like Michael Jackson
and the elephant man's bones.
Yo, are they still together?
No they're not together,
and neither are we.
You're history.
Now, if I do recall,
I saved your butt,
twice.
And I am trying to save yours.
Ho, ho, well, don't
go dissin' me, baby.
My butt is covered.
The rest of your posse be happy to have
me along. By the way, where are they?
Behind you.
Damn!
Homeboys around here got
some badass disguises.
What's happenin'?
Como?
Uh, usted dig rap?
You know, like,
my name is tee vee
and I'm here to say that I am
a rapping brother
and I'm here to stay.
Nah?
Let's see, uh, you
got mtv around here?
You got an opinion
on 2 live crew?
Guess not.
Hey.
Where's your posse going off to?
Back to their homes.
Hey, can I get a rewind on that?
Kleiss' security
has been increased.
They say we don't have a chance.
Well, I make it a point to
never argue with the locals.
I have got to roll.
Make that "we."
The party's over.
Look, you're crazy if you think
you're going in there alone.
It's much too dangerous.
Ordinance.
Check.
That'll do it.
We've got three hours
till refuel.
Take it easy.
Gets uglier from there on in.
You're pulling out?
As soon as you're airborne.
Cause for celebration by the
local people, I'm sure.
Oh, yes, they'll be
having a special mass.
It will be most uplifting.
Make sure everything
is ready to go.
A little overkill,
don't you think?
- Never hurt Stallone.
- Not so fast.
Maybe I better follow you.
The deposits have been
made, just as we agreed.
This final shipment should
be worth another 50 million,
perhaps more.
Disbursed to bases
all over the country,
along with
the lethridge surplus.
No questions will ever be asked.
And you are a very rich man.
Don't you want to drink to that?
I'll drink to paying back those
bastards at the Pentagon.
I gave them 27 years, god damn
it, and they closed me down.
We're getting close
to the village.
Here.
Let's go.
We don't have much time.
Hold this.
Stay here.
Shh.
Ahh!
We're getting close.
Panther one?
This is strike leader.
Do you copy?
This is strike leader. Do...
Panther one,
this is strike leader.
Do you copy? Over.
Maybe we're still out of range.
Possible.
We're only a half hour
from the target.
I'll keep trying.
It's dangerous to break
radio silence repeatedly
at this point, isn't it, chappy?
We're flying blind
without the ground unit.
Panther one, this is
strike leader. Come in.
Yo, man, watch the threads.
Jesus!
This is a laser interlock
unit from my base.
Sinclair!
Sector five has just picked up
the transmission
of four aircraft
- headed this way.
- Call esquitos air base.
I'm getting airborne!
Get him out of here.
Bogey.
10 o'clock and closing.
Shit!
Gustav.
Aircraft in path, identify.
Identify? Shoot them down!
What do I pay you for?!
That is kleiss.
He's pretty good
at buying off pilots.
Split up fast and pull them
in close where we
have the advantage.
Bank out of there, Nigel.
He's gonna get your ass.
Hardly, old boy.
Remember, the man,
not the machine?
Ohh...!
Ah! Mayday, chappy!
Mayday!
Mayday, chappy!
Hang on, Nigel, hang on.
What the bloody hell
does it look like I'm doing?!
Ohh...!
Well done, old chap.
Am I glad to see you.
I got tired of hanging
around here all by myself.
I should just leave you
here, you know that?
I hope these things still work.
Looks like your posse
had a change of heart.
Su, use your countermeasures
deploy your foil
and get out of there.
I'm going to the airport.
You get things moving here!
Yo, strike leader,
this is panther one.
We're loose, we got the juice, and we're
ready to blow the shit out of this goose.
Tee vee, is that you?
None other, baby.
I flew in for the surprise
party, baggage class.
Where are you?
We're up at the bell
tower in the church.
You should stop by.
We got a beautiful view.
What about the lasers?
Anna's setting them up
as we speak.
You better jam, man.
Kleiss is pumping
some major drugs into
the belly of a big
bird on the runway.
We'll line up on the artillery.
We're 20 miles out and closing.
Gotcha.
Come on, baby. Get some
big dudes on that sucker.
This ain't
"pee-wee's playhouse."
Leichman, panther one
is in position.
Can you hold out while me
and Palmer go in for target?
I'm good.
Horikoshi, what about you?
Never better.
Ernst, are you all right?
Yeah, he got the message.
So much for your
damned air cover!
Get those engines started now!
Get those things moving!
Lock them in now.
Check. You hear the man?
Palmer, take the northwest gun.
- Fire when you get a lock.
- Roger.
The bloody tracking unit
isn't working!
We better switch positions.
Leichman...
Get down here.
Palmer's laser malfunctioned.
Afraid mine is too.
Doesn't even light up.
Su, do you read me?
I'm on my way.
Get airborne, now!
Where the hell am I gonna go?!
El Salvador.
I have friends there.
You may lose the flags
and the military bands
when you retire, but you
won't lose the money.
I need gunners!
You!
You! Herel
hold the northwest position
and line up on southwest,
you got it?
We got it!
Palmer, you okay?
As I said, technology
is no match for seasoning.
We're going back down.
Smug bastard.
So much for seasoning.
Only one bogey left.
And it looks like
we lost Palmer.
Damn it!
We're all lined up.
We're coming in.
Ahh...!
Yeah! Whoo!
Line up the southeast
gun for su.
I'm saving my missiles
for the factory.
Tell Anna to get her people out of there
and into the church. Do you copy?
We copy, chappy!
We're lining up now!
You suckers!
Anna's people are doing good.
But the trucks are
starting to split.
I think they got kleiss'
equipment on them.
That's my call.
All right, the big bird
has taken off.
Shit.
Su?
I would be honored.
Okay, Anna's getting
her people into the church.
Oh, it's perfect.
You're clear. We're gonna get a
line on the factory right now.
Tell me when you're set.
Get this truck out of here
and move the other one in!
Okay, we got a lock.
Oh, ho! Air force, baby!
When it absolutely,
positively has to be!
Whoo!
Blow the church. Take the
men up into the mountains!
Mayday! Mayday!
Kleiss is pulling in two choppers'
worth of backup. We're history.
Let's get out of here.
Strike leader,
this is Warren Crawford.
Do you copy?
Warren, are those
choppers yours?
DEA's finest.
Eta, five minutes.
Panther one, those
choppers are friendly.
Stay put until the DEA
can give you help.
We copy that, baby.
Damn, I knew this
was too easy.
Ahh!
Tee vee, come back!
Tee vee, you okay?
Nice hat.
One more pass.
You take care of it.
I'm worried about su.
Get him out of here!
Knock that bastard
out of the sky!
Ahh!
Hold your fire! Hold it!
Chappy, kleiss is airborne.
Repeat, kleiss has escaped.
What's he flying?
It's the weirdest damn
jet I've ever seen.
Guns all over the wings.
Which direction?
North.
Ahh!
Jackhammer, this is warp seven.
Come on up. The skies are clear.
Not quite.
Two fighters remain.
They're flying shit buckets.
Let 'em take their best shots.
Su, come in, this is chappy.
Su, pull out!
Ahh...!
Sul!
Oh, shit!
- Good god!
- It survived.
What?
Messerschmitt 263.
The plane that was going to
win the war for Germany.
Don't take him on alone.
Chappy, I didn't fly
all this way to run.
Break it off, leichman.
I'm 10 seconds out.
Leichman?
Is that you, Ernst?
You've disgraced our family's name,
and you disgraced our country.
Ha, one last chance for you
to do something
for the fatherland.
You've got that
just exactly right.
Leichman, bail out!
Hardly the Aryan ideal,
are you?
I'm afraid I didn't get a
chance to grab my swastika
and get a lobotomy.
You only have seconds to live.
I smell the kill.
What you smell is in your pants.
Take a whiff of this.
Kiss my ass!
Damn!
Bastard never dies.
Warren, this is strike leader.
Kleiss has failed.
We spot him.
Dispatching a unit now.
I'm coming in.
Don't seem to recall your name.
Morales.
Like my brother Ramon.
But more intelligent, perhaps?
What do you want for the Jeep?
Six figures, seven?
I don't even talk about
a full tank of gas.
Very sensible.
I have a lot of friends
here, and there are
no extradition
treaties with the U.S.
You know what movie they're
showing on the way home?
You all right?
I'm gonna make it.
I know you will.
Confounded Palmer
is going to haunt me till
I'm an octogenarian.
You mean,
you found the wreckage?
Not the wreckage, Palmer!
The devil's alive!
I think this calls for
a celebration, chappy!
Yeah, I know just
the place for it.
Hey, what's with the stetson?
"Well, let me
tell ya, pardner..."
I'm switching from
urban to suburban.
Kind of like you, brother.
Well, put these steaks on.
All righty.
And don't burn them
like you did those chops.
Those aren't burned, they're...
- Aw, shut up.
- Extremely well done.
Hey!
So, where's dad and the boys?
They wanted to be here more
than anything to thank you,
but they knew you'd understand.
We'll never forget
all you've done for us.
Ahh...
Hmm?
Well, the DEA,
they wanted sole
credit for the bust
and I wanted all of kleiss'
cash to go to the villagers.
So, we made a compromise.
They did it my way.
- I have something that
- I think belongs to you.
Welcome home.
Thank you, Anna.
Well, you know, I didn't
come out so bad either.
The air force gave me
a nice little fleet
of mothballed f-86s
to keep my mouth shut.
Ah-ha!
Leichman and Palmer are gonna
fly 'em for me next year.
Uh, well...
If we can work out
the percentages.
What about a guest shot from
you next season, chappy?
Now that you got your own plane.
What are you gonna call her?
Son of a bitch.
That's not much of a name.
You know, I think
I'm gonna call her
shadow warrior, named after su.
Yep, better get 'em
while they're hot.
You cook.
I'll fly the plane.
How about that?