I want more trucks, more jeeps,
and 50 more armed guards.
We move again so soon?
A small incident has transpired.
The DEA may become bothersome.
So, why take the risk?
We simply move higher up
into the mountains.
Ask the mayor
when we will finish
packaging this consignment.
He says, "very quickly,
perhaps two days."
But he pleads with you
to release
his daughter.
Tell him unless he gets
back to work quickly,
I will kill his daughter
in front of him.
Up in the mountains, good
workers are hard to find.
Maybe this time,
we should take the loss.
Impossible. They've seen the
markings on the planes.
No, these people have served
this land well, Juanito.
In five days' time, we
shall bury them in it.
Flight commander findlay,
report to operations.
Coast guard find the body too?
Most of it. The medics
are doing an autopsy.
His personal things
are over here.
Do you know these
people, colonel?
I didn't catch your name.
Oh, I'm Warren Crawford.
That's his family.
Kid brothers, dad, sister.
She went to ucla on
an athletic scholarship.
This picture was taken
the day she graduated.
He's from a little village
in the Peruvian mountains.
His father's the mayor.
He has an aunt living
here in brownsville,
but that's all in your files.
Anybody tell her?
She's been informed.
Uh, poor people, aren't they?
Very poor.
Had to work their butts off
to make something of themselves.
We think he was shot down by
the Colombian cocaine cartels.
They had to get to one
of us sooner or later.
We're out there tracking
them all the time.
Morales was in
competition with them.
They don't like that.
What the hell's that supposed to mean?!
Who are you?
I'm the station chief,
DEA, Houston.
Chappy,
I think you better take a look
at his auxiliary fuel tank.
Damn! I don't believe this.
Where's his flight recorder?
Who was with him?
I was, colonel.
Just a routine
interdiction mission.
Over sector seven,
he said he had orders
from you to fly
a classified pattern.
We would rendezvous
one hour after break-off.
I never gave those orders.
I wouldn't know about that, sir.
He broke off over the Yucatan.
I got his mayday
45 minutes later.
By the time I got there,
there was nothing
but wreckage, sir.
Gulfsat confirm this?
They were all flying
for ev tests.
DEA intends to run a full
investigation on this, colonel.
We'll want to talk
to you again, so...
The DEA isn't running any full
investigations on my command!
And it's god damn well not gonna
harass any of my senior officers!
Well, sir, there's no way
morales was operating alone,
not with a quarter of a billion
worth of cocaine in his tank.
Maybe, maybe not,
but this kind of scandal
makes headlines
the Pentagon doesn't like
one damn bit!
The services prefer to clean
their own houses, Mr. Crawford.
I'll launch my own little
look-see into this matter.
Excuse me, sir,
but DEA does have
jurisdiction on this case.
You're on a military
installation, son!
The only thing that has
jurisdiction around here
is the star on my shoulder.
Take your people
back to Houston,
and I'll see you
get a full report.
You're late!
We're clear.
Gulfsat reports that DEA
is tightening surveillance
on fighter aircraft
in the entire area.
Your moment of madness
could have placed
the entire
operation in jeopardy.
I had no choice.
Morales was running scared.
He threatened to go
to colonel sinclair.
Just as well I have a contingency
plan, isn't it, captain?
Give me the code numbers.
Lima-Romeo-654.
They have to touch down by 0500.
Escovez!
The jackhammer flight leaves
for lethridge at midnight.
We must begin
loading immediately.
Use all available personnel.
But then his number came up
and he was gone with the draft
he's in the army now
a-blowin' reveille
he's the boogie woogie
hip-hop boy of company b.
Give me a blazing sun,
the occasional
cloud for cover,
and I'll shoot the ass off
of any aircraft flying.
Well, maybe next year
Arthur will send you up
against an f-16 or a mirage.
Call it the battle of
the generation gap.
Ach! Flying computers, captain.
In our day, it used to be
the man, not the machine.
Technology is no match
for seasoning.
Damn shame you missed it, chap.
Well, don't hold
my youth against me.
By the time I was
old enough to join up,
there was nothing but
missiles and mach speed.
Very fine beer.
May have to import it
for company cafeteria.
I was told you worked
for an aerospace firm,
but I didn't fancy
you were its caterer.
He's chairman of the board.
What do you say we press
a little flesh, gentlemen?
You know, mix and mingle.
Work the crowd.
You know, this little
party could line us up
some real supporters
for next year's show.
Well, count me out.
When I retire,
I'm gonna buy myself
a little ranch
and a big hammock.
I'm gonna sit around
all day working on my tan.
10 will get you 20
that will last about a week.
When this batch is dry, use these
people to help with the packaging.
Five kilos in each barrel, yes?
Ahh!
Come on, move it!
Finish loading and you're gone.
Nobody's gonna
stop you at the gate.
Ohl
You're Anna morales.
Ramon's sister.
What the hell happened to you?
I need to find my brother.
Where is he?
Anna, I'm chappy sinclair,
Ramon's friend.
There's something
I need to tell you.
There's no time to talk.
I need to find my brother.
My whole village and
family's in danger.
Ramon is dead.
He was shot down in the Gulf.
He was carrying
cocaine in his tanks.
Ramon!
They told Ramon
they'd kill us all
if he didn't help them.
Who, who told you that?
The German called kleiss.
He's going to kill
everyone in four days.
- My family, everyone!
- Slow down.
Slow down, slow down.
Now, how did you get here?
I escaped on the plane that brought
the drugs here to your base.
Drugs are being brought
here to this base?
Yes, they're unloading now.
They're in the barrels.
Kleiss called it the jackhammer
flight to lethridge.
Gimme the key.
You stay right here. I'll
be back as fast as I can.
You keep this door locked.
You don't open this
door for anyone.
Hold it!
Hold it! Stop right there!
Let me see your orders.
What are you bringing in?
Hydraulic fluid, sir. A milk run.
Next stop, San Diego.
This plane ain't stopping nowhere
until I see what's in those barrels.
- Get me a crowbar.
- Yes, sir.
Don't just stand there.
Get another crowbar and open
up the rest of those barrels.
What's going on here, colonel?
I think there's drugs
in this plane, sir.
The DEA was right. Morales
wasn't just a lone eagle.
Off-load the rest of this
cargo and have it checked.
Where are you getting your
information, colonel?
Morales' sister.
She's in his quarters.
She'll lay the whole
thing out for you.
It's all right, Anna.
It's chappy sinclair.
Anna?
She's gone.
Why don't you take a little
water with your booze,
colonel?
But she was here,
general, I swear.
This base is going to
close in three weeks.
My base for 12 years.
My men, my planes,
my equipment transferred to
other commands
all over this country.
I want to go out
with honor, colonel.
I don't want
a trumped-up scandal
and I don't want
gossip and talk!
Have you got that?!
Yes, general, I've got that.