Happy birthday to me.
How in hell did I end up here again..
Fuck off.
My birthday actually began
the way of all my birthdays.
Hello darling. Just ringing
to wish you a happy birthday.
Mom? It's six a.m.
I'm doing the FaceTime.
Una taught me. It's really marvellous.
Mum, the point of FaceTime is that you
haven't got to put the phone to your ear.
Oh, please.. Oh, there you are.
This time, 43 years ago...
I was having a lamb beriyami in an
attempt to coax you out.
23 hours of labour.
Never been the same down there.
It's a miracle, the gift of childbirth.
- Here it comes.
Penny Husband-Bosworth's son
sells his sperm on the internet.
You don't need a man, Bridget.
Some people have marvellous lives
without them. Look at you.
Nice flat, lovely job...
Nice flat...
- I'm putting the phone down now, mum.
Say happy birthday to Bridget. Colin?
Happy birthday to Bridget.
Thank you.
I love you darling. Now don't forget...
I'm counting on you to head up
my media campaign.
It's the parish council elections, mum.
Not the US primaries.
The annual phone call from mum reminding
me to take my ovaries out of retirement.
The truth was that by now I thought
I would have had a little baby to love
with the chisel jawed love of my life.
But sometimes life gives
you shallower compensations
and at least I was finally down
to my perfect weight.
Good morning, Ms. Bridget.
You look beautiful again today.
There was life in the old dog yet.
Haven't exactly been put out to grass.
Hah! Ding dong..
But this year all these things
were brought into sharper focus...
by an event I hadn't expected
to attend quite so soon.
Hi.
So how are you feeling? Are you ok?
Mm. Yeah.
I just can't believe he's gone, really.
His death seems to have
hit the eastern European
teenage modelling community
particularly hard.
They found the flight recorder
but still no bodies.
Strangely fitting that he should
have died going down in the bush.
We are gathered here
to celebrate the life...
of Daniel Vivian Cleaver.
Daniel was a kind and wonderful son...
Fuck. What the fuck is he doing here?
You know what he's like,
wanting to do the decent thing.
Is that his wife?
Did I ever get over losing Mr. Darcy?
Was he my Mr. Right?
Oh Christ.
A man of outstanding charm and charisma.
Just a bit emotional.
- I would like to invite his loved ones up...
to share some of their
memories of Daniel.
Daniel could be very sensitive ...
Make you feel like you were
the only woman in the world.
I first met Daniel in Moscow.
He once took me rowing on the
Serpentine and quoted Keats by heart.
He could quote Keats by heart.
- Where be ye going, you Devon maid.
And what have you there in the basket?
- Where are you going, you Devon maid.
You tight little fairy,
just fresh from the dairy.
Will you give me some cream if I ask it?
He did it to everyone.
Anybody else like to say a few words?
Say something for his mum.
Come on.
Daniel was a man ...
who touched many of us here today,
including me.
Oh dear.
This is when Daniel would say,
"Shut up, Jones."
And he would be right,
because all I really need to say is...
Dear Daniel, I will miss you terribly.
We all will.
Give you a call?
- Yes very good. Bye bye.
Bridget.
- Mark.
This is Camilla.
- Hello.
Bridget, an old friend.
Well, less old, more childhood.
So...
Nice memorial, as memorials go.
Almost makes one look
forward to one's own.
Yes, well...
Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
Maybe that's the reason Mark
Darcy and I never made it.
I always felt like a verbally incontinent
old maid, even when we were together.
Still, I wasn't going to
dwell on the negatives.
At least no-one at work
knew it was my birthday.
Or indeed, how old I was going to be.
Surprise.
Congratulations, Bridget.
Or so I thought.
Who told you?
It's so hot. So many candles.
Isn't there some sort of statute
of limitations about the
number of sodding candles on a cake
once you get to a certain age?
Josh, I need you to see what Reuters
is saying about the attacks on Ramallah.
We might need a live link. And Laura...
I may have been another
year older and still single...
but I could always take consolation
in my job as top news producer.
So,
how will I be changing the world today?
Well, our main feature is the
exclusive interview...
with the Foreign Secretary about NGochi.
Oh, gee. How did you do that?
- NGochi.
NGochi.
- You're good at that.
I know. I've been practising. NGochi.
It's harder than you think.
Plus, have great new 30
something work colleagues
who are not obsessed with
children and marriage.
How do we plan on celebrating tonight?
Well, night out with the gang.
- Please say that involves group sex.
Gangbangs? Ooh, we'd like to do that.
I know a smashing little club
in the back of Berwick Street.
Chance would be a fine thing.
I'm beginning to think I'm
past my sexual sell by date.
No. There are names for women
like you now, Bridge.
You're a cougar. You are a MILF.
I'm not a MILF, I'm not even a mum.
I am a spinster, I'm a SPILF.
Three minutes 'till we're on air.
- It's called Voyeurz with a 'z'.
You tell them that Cathy sent you.
If you go on a Thursday there's a Chinese
buffet. All you can eat, as it were.
But whose advice was, never the less,
sometimes a tad too modern for me.
It's me, checking talk-back.
- Yep.
You didn't freeze your eggs
by any chance, did you?
No,
I imagine they're hard boiled by now.
You know what, Bridge? This weekend...
you and me need to go out,
and get stuck into some serious...
"Binge drinking,
a dangerous scourge on society."
Is new legislation needed?
Bridget, Miranda, I've told you,
don't talk between the bongs.
Stick to the questions on the cue cards.
Miranda. Cue.
The Foreign Secretary will
be live in the studio...
to talk about the looming
crisis in Muribundi.
You can always try online dating again.
The other night I was on Tinder. Half
an hour later I'm having a 3-way with...
Prince Andrew, the Royal Special
Representative for Trade and Investment...
He did that on purpose. ...has just
written his first children's book.
He had a massive cock.
Live in the studio I'm joined by
Foreign Secretary George Wilkins...
who has just returned from
war ravaged Muribundi...
Miranda, I'm in your ear.
Just follow my lead.
...Where the assassination of
bloody dictator Charles NGochi...
has resulted in civil war.
- One shot, come back to four. Four.
Minister, was this a military coup?
- Well, the signs are that NGochi's
own generals did take him out...
Hi, Tom. I can't talk.
How was Daniel's memorial?
- It was just sad.
I can't believe he's gone.
It's sad.
I can't believe he's gone, actually.
Ah... I don't think there was any
particular sadness in his passing.
His persecution of the Ubuntu
people amounted to genocide.
And that is well documented.
- I know he had his flaws.
Well, I know he had his flaws.
- He could be a massive asshole.
He could be a massive asshole.
But I miss him. We all do.
- But I miss him. We all do.
Well, he was certainly a very colorful
character on the world stage Miranda...
I grant you that,
but I think the genocide...
resulting in the deaths of over 10,000 of
his own people, men, women and children...
probably rather put him on
the wrong side of history.
At least he was never boring.
Well, at least he was never boring.
One, two, three clear.
Do you think a spirit of democracy can
carry over into West Africa...
Now that's NGochi's dead?
Do you think, minister,
that the spirit of democracy can
carry over into West Africa
now that NGochi is dead?
Well now, that is an
interesting question. Finally.
We're running out of time.
- Miranda, wrap it up.
Briefly, please, Minister.
- Well it is a complicated issue.
A 'yes' or a 'no'.
Miranda, make it the last answer.
- Let's hope so.
I'll take that. Thank you for
joining us on the sofa today.
Over to you, Toby.
Thank you, Miranda, Bridget.
You couldn't just behave yourselves when
the new management team were here?
They're the new management team?
That is Alice Peabody,
new brand manager.
Apparently 'Hard News'
is too old fashioned, too serious...
and she is the smiling assassin, brought
in to sack anybody older than her.
Everybody's older than her. I've got tins
of soup in my cupboard older than her.
Look at them all.
With their apps and their ironic beards
Maybe one of them could
get Bridget some sex.
What?
- Bridget? Do you need sex?
No.
- Yes.
That's why I'm taking her on an a girls
weekend to beat all girls weekends.
Bridget, isn't it?
Yes, nice to...
- Team meeting tomorrow morning.
We can do introductions then.
Nine a.m.
We should all start an
hour earlier from now on.
Do you think she saw that?
- Quite possibly not.
And you're sure you don't want to
come out with me and my crew?
Thanks, but can't let the old gang down.
They're stay at home moms now.
They'd be disappointed.
Thank God for the gays.
Now, whatever fears you're
bringing in the room with you today...
I want you take those fears and I want
you to tell them to fuck the fuck off.
Yeah!
Are you ready for this?
- Yes.
Then ride, you sexy bitches! Ride!
Look, I'm so sorry, Bridget, but I'm
actually going to have to blow you out too.
I didn't want to have to tell you this
today, but Eduardo and I are adopting.
Adopting?
What, a baby?
- Yes, a baby.
Or gayby, in our case.
That's fantastic news, Tom.
I'm going to Bogota tomorrow to start
the paperwork so I've got to go and pack.
Wonderful, go.
Happy Birthday. Have fun.
Congratulations.
- Thank's darl.
Fucking excellent.
And that was how I wound
up back here again.
The last barren husk in London...
and of the two loves of my life,
one is married and the other is dead.
Right, new birthday resolutions.
I, Bridget Jones am done
with affairs of the heart...
and dedicating my autumn
years to the pursuit of hedonism.
Will hang only with new free
spirited friends like Miranda...
and when the going gets tough,
the tough go on a luxury spa weekend.
What the fuck.
Love the shoes.
I didn't tell you,
because you wouldn't have come.
Seriously, it's been five years.
You've gotta shake yourself out of this
self imposed purge you've been in...
ever since you split up with your
precious Mark Darcy.
Rubbish. I barely think of him.
What you need is a good shafting.
You need some good old fashioned,
lie back and think of England bonking...
and festivals are sexual free for alls
like Sodom and Gomorrah with tofu.
First man you meet you've
gotta sleep with.
The first man?
I'm not taking no for an answer.
I'm gonna find our backstage passes.
You get the maps.
Maps.
I may be old and inappropriately dressed,
but at least I look fucking amazing.
That's exactly why I
didn't wear my heels.
Ding fucking dong.
May I?
Thank you.
It fits.
Bridget.
Is that your wicked stepmother?
- Yes.
I better go before she has me
sweeping fireplaces all day.
Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Ah ha. Birthday resolution number two.
Must remember the way to a man's heart
is not through beauty, sex or love...
It's Jack.
But merely the ability to
fall arse over tit in the mud.
By the way.
Right.
Which one's ours?
- Let's try up here.
And anyway, it's not camping,
it's glamping.
Putting a G L in front of it
doesn't make it any better.
Calling him Gladolf Hitler wouldn't suddenly
make you forget all the unpleasantness.
Oh... fuck me!
NGochi.
It's 2:30 in the afternoon.
I should be Hoovering.
This is incredible.
We've got to get a photo.
Excuse me?
Do you mind if we ask you
to take a photo of us?
Yeah, sure.
- Thank you.
Alright. Are you ready?
Hey. What're you doing?
I was taking your photo.
I thought you guys wanted a photo.
- Yeah, we do. Of us.
Yes. Terribly sorry. We thought it'd
be really fun to get a photo of us...
backstage among all
these glamorous people.
I think that's the guy from
'Bargain Hunt'.
It'd be great if you could get him in the shot.
- Quick. Quick.
So you don't want me in the photo at all?
- No, and you can lose the attitude, babe.
Is it really that difficult?
They let any old riff-raff
backstage nowadays.
I don't know. I thought he was
kind of cute. He looks familiar.
I think he works
at the Starbucks at Balham.
One, two, three, singing.
Oh my God.
I know. It's the guy from Starbucks.
Crowdsurfing.
Miranda.
Miranda?
Hey, Miranda.
Oh, God.
I have to admit, that was fun.
And you're right ...
What I need is a good shafting...
some good old-fashioned,
lie back and-think-of-England...
bonking.
Well, sign me up.
Oh my God.
What are you doing in my yurt?
With all your clothes,
and luggage and possessions.
Yeah, it's as if I've come in,
made it my own.
Wait, it's you,
the creature from the Black Lagoon.
Yes. Sorry.
You don't really expect me to believe that
you accidentally crashed into my yurt, do you?
Since you're here, maybe I can help you.
Well, he is the first man I met...
and his yurt is one heck
of a lot nicer than mine.
Bridget, where the fuck are you?
Bridget, I'm so pissed.
Bridget.
I'm zorbing with Ed Sheeran.
Oh, God.
I just slept with a complete stranger.
I'm nothing but a feckless prostitute.
No, no. I'm an elegant older woman
taking men for my own pleasure.
Or am I just a deluded middle-aged fool?
Oh, fuck it.
Miranda?
Good morning.
So it lasted six hours?
What lasted six hours, mum?
A puppet show that
Auntie Bridget went to.
A six-hour puppet show?
- Hello.
Tell me, were they little puppets or...?
Very nice size puppets.
And did he...
put his puppet in your mouth?
God! I feel like my days
of puppet shows are behind me.
I've had finger puppets.
And has he called?
- It doesn't work like that any more.
You just hook up with rugged
troubadors at music festivals...
and there are no strings.
Puppets with no strings.
Take the wings off.
They're for little girls.
Hello?
- Where the fuck are you?
Speeding through lovely countryside
on our way to your christening.
No we're not.
Why is auntie Bridget lying?
Bridge, I thought you should
know after Tom dropped out...
Giles asked Mark to be the godfather.
- What?
He did what?
Yes I know. He really is a useless cock.
Did it without asking me.
Oh my God. Mark Darcy again.
Twice in the space of a week I turn
up at church as rent-a-spinster.
Where the fuck were you?
Sorry.
Good morning and welcome.
Well, this isn't embarrassing at all.
Mark Darcy and I at the altar with a baby.
That's lovely.
Ok, now, nice big smiles.
Look at me. Thank you.
Lovely.
Ok, can I just get
the godparents now please.
How are you?
- Very well, thank you. How are you?
Well, thank you. Mm.
Are you here with your wife?
I can't remember her name...
Camilla.
No, eh, no, she couldn't make it.
Are you here with anyone?
- No, no. Not today, no.
Come on, it's not a funeral.
Can I get a couple of
smiles out of you two, please?
Maybe give her a little kiss you know,
on the forehead, there.
Ah, I was talking about the baby.
Lovely.
Alright.
I'll see you later, shouldn't wonder.
Yes, unless I make a break
for it with this thing.
Could this day actually get
any more awkward?
Just keep walking, keep walking,
keep walking. Keep walking.
Hello.
- Hello.
How are you?
- Very well, thanks.
- I'm fine.
So am I.
Well, goodbye.
- Goodbye.
A glass of wine.
- A whiskey, please.
Big, big glass.
- Double.
Thank you.
I'd ask you to join me, but I'm pretty sure
you're not a big Gangnam Style kind of guy.
I was only there very briefly.
- Where?
Gangnam.
What are we talking about?
- Gangnam, dancing.
Not the suburb of Seoul?
- No.
I'm not familiar with Gangnam, the suburb.
- It literally means south of the Han River.
It was inhabited as early as
the Paleolithic period.
Suddenly seems so much less catchy.
Now something for you lovers out there.
We are entering the erection section. Don't
say fucking erection at a christening.
Would you like to get some air?
I mean, some more air.
Sure.
I don't suppose you happen to have a cigarette?
- No.
I gave up 1891 days ago.
Not that people're counting.
Since when did you smoke?
- I don't.
It's been a tense time.
Maybe I'm nervous.
Why?
You have a train in your hair.
I'm aware of that.
Courtesy of one of my many godchildren.
Seems to be stuck.
And this would be...
Cake?
- Profiterole.
That's technically more of a dessert,
I suppose.
What're you doing? You're married.
- No, I'm not.
I mean, I'm getting a divorce.
That's why she's not here.
Why were you together at the memorial?
She was just being supportive.
She's gone back to The Hague,
where she's now living, and I'm not.
Oh, I'm so sorry, Mark.
At this precise moment
I'm not sorry at all.
How the fuck am I
supposed to get in here?
Again?
Mr. Darcy, wow.
Bridget?
God, I've missed you.
Are we on schedule?
I have a flight to Khartoum tomorrow.
I'm so sorry, Mark. Had to leave.
It probably sounds pathetic,
but I got scared.
The fact that we went 'round and 'round
for the best part of ten years...
without ever making it across the
finish line leads me to think...
we did the best thing
by ending it when we did.
Sometimes it feels scary
still being on my own at 43.
But you and I have
been here once before.
We always loved the fantasy of us...
But the reality,
as we both know, is quite different.
We could both come up with a 100
reasons why we didn't make it...
but in the end I always felt that you
were never there and I was mostly alone.
No, can't go back and keep
making same mistakes.
Must keep moving forward
and make new ones.
And will lodge myself into
frenzied keep fit regimes.
And allowing 4 weeks to reduce
thighs circumference...
to squeeze largy ass into
teenage skinny jeans...
Obviously not meant
for women of a certain age.
All this bloody cycling is pointless.
I'm putting on weight.
Let's rule out some of the other options,
shall we? You're not pregnant, are you?
Of course not.
A lady is always prepared and
I always carry these in my handbag.
Oh, God!
You didn't use those, the vegan condoms?
Biodegradable and dolphin friendly.
If I'm going to be slutty, it's nice
to think I'm helping the environment.
Christ, Bridget.
I remember when you bought those.
That was decades ago.
Sell by dates don't mean anything.
Do they?
They were a gift. Don't ask.
Tumbling rapids, frothing waterfalls...
babbling brook.
Oh, come the fuck on, Bridget.
How long do you think it takes?
I think that's a positive result.
Pregnant
I'll just make sure.
- Don't shake it.
You'll hurt the baby.
- The baby is not in the stick.
I think this is when you're meant to...
jump for joy.
Oh my God.
- You're pregnant.
I'm pregnant.
- You're going to have a baby.
I'm going to have a baby.
- Yes.
If you've got footage of her
punching a horse, I want it.
Bridget, do you want a baby?
- I don't know.
I mean, I'm 43.
It might be the only chance
I'm going to get.
One broken, out of date condom I might
have believed was an acciddent.
But two?
You wanted it.
Maybe I did.
Can we get a medic please?
Oh my God. I'm pregnant.
This is it.
More to the point, whose is it?
This is not how I thought
this moment would be.
I always imagined myself in 'OK!'
Magazine with the man of my dreams.
Oh Christ! Too many dilemmas to ponder.
Not least of all...
Who was that man I shagged in a tent?
And so you're age will be 43?
So, umm...
Which of the times with my wonderful
man do you think we got pregnant on?
Does it matter?
Well, yes, it's such a special moment.
We'd like to know which one
it is so we can treasure it.
Can't you treasure both of them?
- Yes, we will, we do.
But surely one of those days is
more likely than the other?
Well, actually, day 10, which was
his birthday, is a little early.
And day 16 which was the...
- Anniversary dinner.
Oh yes, the Osso Buco, I recall,
is a little late.
Are you sure there wasn't another
treasurable occasion in between?
Yes, I'm quite sure. He was away.
So which of the two would you go for?
Couldn't say. They're both equally likely.
It could have been after the event.
Because as you know, sperm can live
for several days after ejaculation.
Couldn't you just have a guess for me?
- No.
What about the first scan? Would
that show when conception took place?
No. Ring this number to fix a date.
And do bring along the father,
if you can work out which one he is.
Right.
Just out of interest... If someone did have
an element of confusion about the father...
Well, you can get a DNA sample at the
amniocentesis, and I do recommend that you have
the amniocentesis, because there are
always more risks with a geriatric mother.
Geriatric? Hmm.
That's outrageous.
- Indeed.
Unless you can sign on for your child
support and pension at the same time.
That's hilarious.
It's called "news"
'cause it should feel new.
Otherwise, it be called "olds".
Sorry.
Last night. Top stories.
Earthquake in Asia, seen it before.
Car crash on the M5... Blah blah blah
We're making 'old's.
We need to flip the switch, mix it up.
I want a new triple on the shit out.
- She's on the warpath.
Susan, the floor manager's gone.
- She's six months pregnant.
We've got to grab the attention,
get the eyes on the screen.
I want to see headlines like:
"Is Your Sofa Bed Giving You Cancer?"
"Is Your Freezer Giving You Alzheimers?"
- Oh my God. Are they?
Literally no evidence whatsoever, but you're
missing the point. You're intrigued, aren't you?
I want to reload 'Hard News'
with a clear new objective.
We have a presentation in twelve
weeks at the London Media Show...
and I'm looking for someone dynamic,
innovative, focused...
to lead the charge. Any volunteers?
Whatever happens now,
must hold on to job.
Must prove to fascist boss
that I may be single mother...
but am willing to roll with the
ironic bearded hipsters.
Anybody at all?
Do you need to leave, Bridget?
- No, I want to volunteer.
Hashtag: "Let's do this!"
It's me. Turn on your TV now. Look at
your TV. Now. Now. Now. Turn on Channel 4.
Bridget, I've found him.
He's the dating website guru.
See, you have to trust the science.
Algorithms don't lie.
You slept with a fucking billionaire.
So, tell us, Bridget.
What was it that initially attracted you
to the billionaire Jack Qwant?
Was it his face, or his body? Big dick?
- I'd do it with him, obviously.
If I were you I wouldn't
tell either of them.
All you need is a DNA sample from one of them and then
you can eliminate the other one from your enquiries.
What would I say to Mark? "Hello Mark,
I know I just left you asleep...
but do you have any blood,
sperm or old fingernails lying around?"
How do you even get in touch with Jack?
Yeah.
He is a bloody mogul.
Can't just ring him up.
I may have just figured out how
to win favour with new boss...
and eliminate one father
from my enquiries.
I have to say, Bridget,
I'm actually excited by this next guest.
Relevant, relatable, extremely fuckable.
Good work.
Welcome to CSI Hard News.
Thank you my love. If you could
just fuck off that'd be great.
Jack, this is Cathy.
She'll get you ready.
Hi, Cathy, nice to meet you.
- I was thinking, just a simple magenta eyeshadow...
to make your eyes pop
and a little bit of rouge, maybe?
Kidding.
- You funny.
You do happen to have
a little stray gray hair.
Oh, Jesus.
- That's it.
Actually, there's a whole gray patch.
Shall I just... let me see?
Yes, my hair is full of gray hair.
- Well, that's sorted.
Jesus Christ.
- All gone, that's lovely.
These fingernails on this silver fox could
do with a bit of a trim, couldn't they?
These hands haven't experienced
much manual labour, have they?
No, I'm a mathematician.
- They're silky soft.
Tell me, Jack.
Do you happen to like Chinese food?
Jack, let me take you to the set. Great,
thank you. I do sometimes. Thank you.
I don't think she put any makeup on me.
- It's fine. You're looking radiant.
Ok, coming out of ET in five, four...
And remember the gear change.
And Miranda, cue.
- Now, though, I'm joined by Jack Qwant.
Raised by a single mother in Baltimore, he
created the matchmaking website Qwantify...
and he claims to have found
an algorithm for love.
And he's here today to tell us all about
his number one bestseller Qwantum Leap'.
It is absolutely wonderful to have you on our sofa today.
- Thank you. It's great to be here.
Now, we'll talk all about your new book soon, obviously.
- Yes. But first let's talk about romance.
Qwantify has found
true love for millions.
Monitor two.
- Does it work for you?
Now if I answer that can we
go back and talk about the book?
Maybe.
Can you please try not
to shag him on air?
This is dynamite.
Tell her to flirt with him more.
Some people had their first
crush on Farrah Fawcett.
My first crush was an algorithm.
- And we've lost him.
If he carries on talking about algorithms I'm
putting to the VT of cats who look like Hitler.
Back to four. Love it.
He's avoiding the question.
Get him off maths.
Ask him if he's with someone now.
For someone so good at match-making...
is there a special someone in your life?
Apart from Lady Mary on 'Downton Abbey'?
Now can we go ahead and talk about the book?
Cue the Hitler cats.
- Don't be evasive.
Well, don't be evasive.
It's apparant you have everything.
Why have you chosen to have no family?
Why the decision to have no family?
- No children.
And no children?
Brilliant. Zoom in on four.
And in on four.
- Love it.
Look, I love kids...
but I've always found the idea of being
a father myself kind of petrifying.
Which is why I've been drawn to algorithms.
- Cue the Hitler cats.
They're rational, reliable,
predictable, everything a kid isn't.
So, can you have children?
- Can you have children, though?
Are the soldiers working?
- Are the soldiers working?
Well I believe so.
The barracks are in pretty regular use.
Really? - Really?
- Yes.
Because for someone with a
supposed algorithm for love...
Isn't it odd that you've never found it?
Well, I think in order to find something
you have to be actively looking for it.
I've just been too busy; I haven't...
What about the Qwant family bloodline?
- And what about the Qwant family bloodline?
Are there any skeletons in the closet?
- Sexual deviants? - Sexual deviants?
Sorry, I don't know where
we're going with all of this...
but I have to tell you,
I can attract the wrong type of women.
That's really great.
Thank you for sharing that with us.
Bridget, what are you doing?
You wouldn't believe some of the
weirdos that cross my path.
Really?
- Get up.
Can you tell me what she's doing?
Ask him something about algorithms.
- Have to be the last question. Have to be.
Lastly, algorithms.
- Yes.
What first attracted you to them?
- The logic and...
Wonderful, Jack Qwant,
thank you for coming on my sofa.
I hope you've had as much fun as I have.
- Jesus.
That's it from me. Goodbye.
That was great.
- You look really familier, outside of being on the show.
Are you on Tinder?
- What?
Then we won't have met.
- No, okay.
Well hey, how about seeing you here.
- Hi.
Great to see you.
- Good to see you too.
I was going to come and find you to say hello,
but you know how live TV can be, so chaotic.
Well, you know, there are easier ways to get in
touch with me without inviting me on national TV...
and asking me about my sperm.
- What? No, that's not what...
I would've liked to have heard from you.
I was disappointed when I came
back that morning, and you were gone.
You were?
- We had an amazing night.
And I thought you were great.
At least I did until I became a clip...
of the 15 most embarrassing chat
show moments of all time.
Really sorry about that. Yes that...
I don't know how to explain.
I'm pregnant.
- Wow. Okay.
It's so much better than you
being mentally unbalanced.
I'm about twelve weeks.
Oh. Right. Wow.
So you mean that... it's the music festival?
- Yes.
I know, it's quite a surprise.
Yes but...
I'm fine, and umm...
you should know that...
I don't...
I'm not looking for anything from you.
Except for a complete DNA check and a
review of my medical records.
Well, the thing is, I didn't mean
for you to find out about this.
And, umm, I'm feeling a bit foolish.
Mortified, actually. Yes, mortified.
I'd like to just retreat, gracefully?
Mr. Qwant, will you sign my book?
Oh God. I didn't even tell him that he
may not be the only daddy.
Christina.
- I find this amazing book.
Hey, Kitty Kirk, I need to talk to you.
What if this DNA turns out to be Jack's?
I don't want the father to be Jack.
I don't even know Jack.
And what if it's Mark Darcy's?
Christ. I'll have to confess to him that
I've been a whore with dolphin condoms.
Good.
So the baby's ok?
- Perfect.
See?
- Oh my God. Is that it?
And it's alright?
- Sound as a bell. Cooking Nicely.
Have a listen.
There you are.
I've recorded that for you.
You can watch that for a moment.
So glad you decided
on the amniocentesis.
Hello you.
Is that your ear or your foot?
You have got very big feet.
Oh, look at you. Waving already.
You're the best thing I've ever seen.
I promise I'll try my best.
So just stay safe and snug in there...
while I try and sort the mess out here.
And hopefully...
What the fuck is that?
- It's the amniocentesis needle.
We just pop it in, take a little amniotic
fluid, test it for any abnormalities...
and also the DNA sample
that you require.
Now, there is the slightest risk of miscarriage
so you'll have to stay very still indeed...
because we don't want the needle to come into contact...
- What?
No, no. I'm not taking that chance.
It's enormous.
It'd go straight through the other side.
Come on, I'm taking you home.
Your mother will be over the moon.
- Will you promise not to tell her?
Just not yet.
- No, of course. I promise.
I'm really sorry, dad,
not to know about the father.
Don't be daft.
I know dozens of people who could have been anybodys.
- So you're not disappointed?
You don't think I belong on Jerry Springer?
- Not a bit, I'm thrilled.
Actually I'm not sure if you're mine or that nice
lieutenant colonel who's 'round the bowls club.
Only joking.
You've got my feet.
I've always had very dainty feet.
Just tell the truth, Bridget. You can't
go too far wrong, telling the truth.
Mark, I have some exciting news. Mark,
I have the funniest story to tell you.
Mark, I'm up the duff.
My lords, my ladies.
There is only one fraud committed
here today and it is this.
To use the laws of one country to
destroy the freedom of speech of another.
A cynical political expedient to take away
the right of these brave young women...
to speak the truth about
the country they love.
Now you may not like their
music and for that I cannot blame you.
They may not have mastered the fundamentals of melody...
or even the most basic tenents of musicianship.
But this is the land of Shakespeare,
Orwell, Lawrence ...
I'd forgotten just how hot
he is in that wig and gown.
...to any country, any ruler, any despot,
that here in the United Kingdom...
we will always defend and protect women such as
these who have selflessly and courageously...
risked their liberty and
quite possibly their lives...
to tell the truth.
The court will now adjourn
and judgement will be given...
Poonani! Poonani! Power to the Poonani! Power to the Poonani!
- Christ.
Looking forward to going back
to some good old fashioned genocide.
Order.
Right. How to do this?
I didn't expect to see you again
after the events at the christening.
Crap. He's dived right in.
No, right. I understand.
Maybe flattery will work.
You were very impressive in there today.
- Thank you.
Although dealing with them over the last month
has given me a certain amount of sympathy...
for the totalitarian dictator who
wants to silence them.
Okay, jokes.
I'll laugh harder next time.
There's only a certain number of
times that one can listen to the...
resolutely un-catchy "Menstruation,
Castration, Liberation."
Mark, that's hilariously funny.
Please.
So.
- So, Mark.
Yes.
The gardens look lovely. Autumnal.
- Yes.
Is that a conker tree?
- Bridget.
I am pregnant.
Right. Well, congratulations.
How can I help?
I'm three months pregnant.
Oh.
You mean the christening?
Yes.
Would you excuse me for just a moment.
I think that this is quite
possibly the most wonderful
piece of information I have
ever received in my entire life.
Oh!
Ok.
Of course I've got no expectations about how things
should work out. I just thought you should know.
No, of course.
I mean, how do you feel? Are you happy?
- Yes, I am.
So much has happened in the past
ten years. A lot has changed.
I mean, you've been married,
and I've been...
on a number of long haul holidays.
But... So here goes on Jack.
I mean...
- I know about it.
It's just right now I can't bring
myself to feel gloomy about it.
God, how can I tell him now.
State of emergency. Cannot sleep. Looping
thoughts going round and round in head.
It's surely weird that tou can do
something as complicated and important...
as growing a baby or invading
Iraq without any instruction at all.
I keep thinking all the alcohol
I've drunk over the years...
will give the baby
fetal alcohol syndrome.
These are the things I could do.
Tell Mark about Jack...
but risk hurting him so badly
I couldn't live with myself.
Not tell Mark about Jack, but I'd
never be able to go through with it.
Tell both of them the other one is the father and then
if the one who isn't the father is upset about it...
Oh Christ.
Tell no-one and make a run for it.
Hello?
- Hey, it's the father of your child.
Jack?
- Yeah, who else?
Come up. Ok.
Oh fuckfuckfuck. He's probably employed a
team of Google Earth detectives to find me.
Okay, just act naturally.
Hi.
Come in.
- Okay.
You found it.
- Try it on, see if it fits.
Wow.
I didn't expect to see you.
- I wasn't expecting to come.
I'm not used to being rejected. Twice.
I hope you've got cake in that bag.
Yeah, I've been doing a lot of thinking.
Bridget, the whole baby situation threw me initially.
We've squashed an entire relationship into one night...
and skipped straight
to starting a family phase.
We never even had a real second date.
Just so you know if we did,
I would have taken you to Ottolenghi.
You would have had the grilled
salmon and pine nuts salsa.
Unbelievable and healthy.
And we would have come back here...
have incredible sex...
spent the next couple of days
sending each other filthy texts.
I would not have let you
do that on a second date.
Why not. You let me on the first.
And then we'd go on a
naughty weekend to the seaside...
and I would prove my manliness by
winning you a cuddly toy...
at the pier.
I really wanted the giant Scooby-Doo.
- Oh, no-body wins that.
The coconuts are glued on.
What are those for?
- To apologise.
We had our first fight.
I was not flirting with that waitress.
She means nothing to me.
And then I would have...
bought Swedish furniture for us to make.
If we can get through this, we can get through anything.
- Anything.
I find it adorable how your neck gets
all blotchy when you get nervous.
And I know you'd be the greatest
possible mother to my child.
Oh no, can not fall in love
with shiny new American.
I'll tell them both tomorrow,
definitely.
Hi. I just wanted to connect, check how
the presentation is shaping up.
Yeah, totally on top of it,
Neutra Bulleting the shit out of it.
I'm relying on you, Bridget. I need
you to get this right. Understand?
100 percent. You can count on me.
- Great.
You alright?
- I'm fine.
Big party.
I'm so glad to see you back together.
It certainly is Gianni.
- Wonderful news, huh?
Cheers.
I was thinking about Jack.
If it's a boy, after my grandfather.
It's a good strong name.
You can rely on Jack.
Yes, one for the list.
To Jack.
- To Jack.
So this is dad, I presume.
So glad you're here.
It's a unique and wonderful moment.
Dr. Rawlings, I wonder if you
could maybe do me a little favor.
So this is dad, I presume.
Pleased to meet you.
I'm so glad you could be here.
This is a unique and wonderful moment.
Before we start, would you like to know the sex?
- We should be prepared.
I'm not sure...
- It's a boy.
A boy.
- Our boy.
My boy.
Okay, right. This time I have to
tell them. We'll start with Jack.
Have invited him for big scary work
presentation and will explain all afterwards.
Welcome.
In a digital age where every cell phone
is a camera, we are all broadcasters.
"Hard News" is partnering
with the London Media Show...
so you can use your smartphone to create
your own news broadcasting channel.
Simply download the new 'Hard News' app
and broadcast directly to our studios in...
where Miranda is waiting for
our first ever live simulcast.
Hello everyone,
live at the London MediaShow.
And welcome to the new look of
'Hard News' studio.
We are live and yes,
our viewers are broadcasting.
Right. Let's now go to the Grampians...
where Adam Wollaston is leading a team of
Venture Rangers to the top of Ben Nevis.
Hello, Adam Wollaston.
- 'Hard News' sucks balls.
Jesus.
- Oh dear.
Well, let's put that news
story firmly behind us.
Technical glitch.
Of course it's never been easier
to email or text the show.
Just search "Hard News" or simply H.
Because...
Be... cause...
Holy fuck. What's he doing here?
Because at 'Hard News', we believe...
We believe that we are ready
and on the front line...
asking the questions
the world wants answers to.
Turn around.
Thank you. Okay. Career down the toilet.
Both men in the same room.
What could possibly go wrong?
I hope you don't mind me just
showing up and surprising you.
No.
- Well done. It was very...
Yes.
- Technically adroit.
Mark, I would love for you to meet...
Ariyaratna Sithamparanathan.
Ariyaratna's is the area manager
for DTC Technological Solutions.
Aren't you, Ari Sinatra?
Hi.
- Hello.
Hey.
What the hell was that?
What'ere you thinking?
I've got four voicemails from David
Cartwright that I dare not listen to.
I'll be right back.
- You call that a presentation?
I don't know whether I've the right
people around me because you're not...
Alice, I'm so sorry.
Yeah well sorry isn't good enough.
Excuse me. Look at me when I'm talking to you. Excuse me.
- I'm so sorry, but I really...
What?
Bridget, I'd like you to meet Jack
Qwant. He's rather extraordinary.
I was just reading a profile of him in The New Yorker.
- Right, yes.
We actually know each other.
Yes, we certainly do.
Good job. Why didn't you
introduce me to this man before?
He's brilliant. You know, he represents
the punk rock band that's being extradited.
That's right.
- Yes. Yes. I knew that too.
Hi, we've met fleetingly before as well.
I'm in charge of data management
for most of Daventry.
Oh. Well, umm...
I must say it's fantastic that you're getting
on so well because you have a lot in common.
Shall we get out of here, and find a place a bit quieter?
- Yes, why not. I booked Gianni's.
Great.
- That sounds lovely.
You might have to sit this one out,
Arinuth. I'm sorry.
So do you actually believe that mathematics
can... how did you put it in your book?
Help us analyze behavior
previously invisible to science?
Well, my dating algorithm is to help people
find love, not necessarily replace it.
Oh no, is incredible idea.
- Have you ever tried it out?
You're single, right?
- Well, I'm... Yes, I suppose so.
How did you two meet?
Yeah.
- It's umm...
It's sort of a funny story. Sort of.
You see, umm...
a few months ago, on the fourth of the
month, I met Jack at a music festival.
Right.
And we got on very well
and sort of had... relations.
And the next week, that is to say, on the eleventh of
the month at Jude's baby christening to be exact...
following the consumption of a large amount of
alcohol, Mark and I, well, we had similar relations.
And, um, this is the funny part,
I suppose. Owing to these relations...
the resulting life form currently residing in my
tummy, could actually, in fact, be either of yours.
I know I should have told you both
before but... I just didn't.
You both seemed so happy.
So correct me if I'm wrong, but did you just
say that the baby could be either of us?
So you have no idea which
of us is actually the father?
I know, it's all very confusing.
I'm sorry.
So however we choose to do this...
the most important thing now is this.
Bridget, I'm not going to
pretend this isn't a shock.
I want you to know whatever
the circumstance...
The most important thing is the baby.
Who knows,
this could be a great adventure.
I'm afraid you're going to have
to excuse me. I have a meeting.
Good night
- Mark...
Gianni, can we have the bill please?
- Subito.
And if I thought that was tricky...
how would the news go down at mum's
parish council election campaign?
Honestly, we started half an hour ago.
Where have you been?
You said it was an emergency. Well, The
Gazette wants to take a family portrait.
What are you wearing?
Oh my God. Bridget, you're...
- Yes.
Why didn't you say anything?
- I didn't want to upset you.
Why would you?
Oh no, Bridget. Who's the father?
It's not Mark is it? Oh, do say it is.
- There's at least a 50 percent chance.
A 50 percent chance?
- Mark and this really nice American called Jack.
Oh no, Bridget. An American?
Did you have a three-way?
Mrs Jones.
Here, take this and pretend everything is fine.
- Everything is fine.
Ms. Jones, can we...
Here's a lovely place for you to stand.
Are you ashamed of me?
- No darling. It's just the circumstances.
I'm running for high office. See?
If you love family and you
love values... it's so long.
It's not the 1950's.
Look around you.
Two lesbians just adopted at number 32.
If you don't change the way you look at things,
you're going to lose your precious election...
and perhaps your daughter.
Bridget, so lovely to see you.
Are you...?
- Yes, I am.
How wonderful.
We thought you'd just got all fat again.
I'm now the Mary Magdalene of middle
England. Have alienated Mom and Mark Darcy.
Am like tropical female insect that shags
men to impregnate self and eats them.
The question is: will Mark even turn up
and engage in a polyamorous family?
Hey. Hello.
First pre-natal class.
Exciting, huh?
- Yeah.
You look great.
Hello.
I'm so glad you came.
- Yeah, me too.
I brought you a nice tea.
- Oh, wow. Thank you.
It's off 'till this evening. But there's
a heck of a lot of caffeine in that tea.
I brought you a... super juice.
Thank you. Shall we go in?
Why not?
- Sure. Let me carry that for you.
Thank you.
- Can I carry your phone, please?
Okay.
Thank you.
And who do we have here, then?
I'm Bridget and this is Jack ...
and this is Mark.
Oh. Lovely.
You're our second same sex couple today.
No, actually we're ...
- Absolutely.
We just need the gift of a baby
to make us feel complete.
You must be the surrogate?
- Exactly, yes.
Just helping this wonderful couple
make their dream come true.
Mark is very nervous about all this.
All new to you, isn't it, lamb chop?
Like all visionaries,
we encounter bumps along the road.
How would you like to give birth to your placenta?
- Quickly.
Are you okay? Are you sure?
And of course massage can have
many benefits throughout pregnancy.
Can we name some of them?
- It relieves stress and promotes feel good hormones.
And is also to be avoided in
cases of high risk pregnancy...
For example,
when there is a geriatric mother.
Right, excellent,
someone's been reading up.
Would you like to have a go?
- No, I think I'll let Jack get on with it....
I think he seems to have it covered.
- That's very sweet of you.
That's why I love you, my little teacup.
What if we ask the right questions
and apply the laws of mathematics...
so that the science of courtship
could be quantified?
May I please make an application
to lead to an appeal...
in the case of Her Majesty's
Government and Saddiq Al Bashir.
As Your Lordship is aware,
Mr. Al Bashir has lost.
So everything's alright?
- Yes, well, it's this combination...
gherkins, anchovies,
banana juice and Pringles.
So essentially...
- It's wind.
Right, so, going forward regular
Pringles, not hot, spicy barbecue?
Or possibly no Pringles at all.
Try that.
Is everything alright? Is Bridget okay?
- Yes, perfectly fine.
She's in there with... That's Dr. Pringle.
He's testing her blood. This is interesting.
This is a new bedside technique we're
testing out of Oslo. It's Norwegian.
It's alright. I know about Jack. Thank you doctor.
- Oh, thank God. Why didn't you tell me?
She's fine. He's calmed her
down completely, actually.
I'm sorry, I got your messages.
I was in court.
Hi. It's alright. Can't be helped.
You should get it. It might be work.
Don't worry. I got it covered.
- Yes, I can see that.
Wow. Okay, you need to chill out.
We have to do this together.
You know, in Peru the Um Bat Do, consider paternity
attach shared responsibility among the many tribesmen.
Unfortunately, we Um Bat don't
live in Peru. I live in Ealing.
Negative energy is just
so bad for the baby.
Stop it. Both of you.
This isn't a competition.
She's right. We should take this
toxic energy out of the room.
I won't be a minute.
What's up? Come on, buddy.
Why are you so angry?
You know what?
I'm really not your buddy.
I don't know about vibes or negative
energy or prenatal wind...
and even less about algorithms...
so I will confess that the laws
of attraction are somewhat beyond me.
In fact,
Bridget defies comprehension generally.
But despite, or perhaps owing to the
bewildering litany of catastrophes
I've witnessed over the last 40 years, I
feel I've come to know Bridget rather well...
and I've spent those years
caring for her very deeply.
And that may defy automated reasoning,
but there's nothing I can do about it.
Nothing you can do about it?
Maybe you should try and stay around a little,
instead of saving the world by cellphone.
I make her happy, Mark.
And I suppose your algorithm tells you
you're destined to be together, does it.
Actually it does.
The fact that you've been trying
and failing for the past ten
years tells me you are not.
No...
- I don't want to fight with you.
We should think about
Bridget and the baby.
For better or worse,
fate has brought us together.
It wasn't fate, it was condoms.
- What do you mean?
Those ridiculous dolphin friendly things
from the bottom of Bridget's bag.
I'm sorry, I have no idea what you're talking
about. When Bridget and I got it on, I was...
I was not dressed for the occasion.
No Mark today?
- No.
We must thank one person who
was prepared to fight for us...
when no one else would,
and we say to that person...
with all our hearts...
"Freedom!"
Bridget, we're back.
I still can't believe Mark
ducked out like that.
Well, it's not really his fault.
I suppose we just have
to hope it's Jack's, right?
I mean, let's face it, things could
be worse. He's pretty fucking amazing.
He's richer than God and he
has a very nice sized puppet.
He does,
and we match up very nicely on paper.
Well, how do you know?
- You just have to have faith.
You just have to ask yourself:
can I see myself growing old...
with this guy, and not Mark Darcy?
There it is. Here we go.
Oh, hey!
You know, first few months,
they only see black and white.
This will help stimulate
spatial awareness.
Or early onset motion sickness.
I got him one of these. A bouncy chair.
Not quite sure where
we're going to put it.
About that... It's kind of
cramped in here, don't you think?
It's cosy.
You know, I've been thinking.
Might be nice if we moved in together.
You think we're ready for that?
I'm just tired of living in
hotel rooms and airport lounges.
We could be a family. Me, you and him.
What do you say?
What if it's not yours?
- What?
What if the baby turns out to be Mark's?
Well, I mean,
it'd certainly change things.
Is that what you want?
For it to be Mark's?
Are you in love with him?
I have been in the past.
And me?
I could be, one day.
Bridget,
I haven't been totally honest with you.
Mark thinks the baby isn't his,
and I let him believe it was mine.
That's why he disappeared.
Why would he think that?
- Because I let him.
Because I wanted you for myself.
We could be so good for each other.
97 percent.
- On paper.
But falling in love
doesn't happen on paper.
Sometimes you love a person because
of all the reasons they're not like you.
And sometimes you love a person
just because they feel like home.
I've got to find Mark.
Hello, Pierce. It's Bridget.
I'm trying to get hold of Mark.
He just got back from a trip, Bridget.
He's in a taxi on his way home.
Hi.
Approximately eight weeks to go.
You don't really need them, you know.
All they're good for is fitting
car seats, and blaming things on,
they really just get
in the way after that.
You're absolutely capable of
doing this on your own.
I did.
You know what? I can do this on my own.
We can do this on our own.
One of the perks of being pregnant is I no
longer feel like a tragic lonely spinster.
Because of a miniature
miracle growing inside.
Hello. Hello!
Mum's throwing a
Christmas party / political rally.
It's like the G8 summit with
Scotch eggs. Be brave. Go in.
Hello darling.
- Hello.
Sorry, I didn't realise everyone
was here. I'll just pop upstairs.
No, nonsense. Nonsense.
Una's had all the posters reprinted.
You've inspired me.
- Still so long.
You were quite right, as it turns out.
This place is teeming with single mothers,
single fathers, bisexuals, surrogates.
And they're all lovely and so normal.
Do you know, I've even got two homosexuals on the team.
- No, thank you.
Who knew?
- Everybody.
I'm so proud of you, darling.
You know that?
What you're doing is not easy, but
if anyone can make it work, it's you.
That child is the luckiest boy on
earth to have you as his mother.
And he's going to have the love of
a million fathers with you by his side.
Come on.
We've got some campaigning to do.
Make way. Make way.
Single pregnant mother coming through.
Laura, Josh. We need to give six
minutes to General Lu Tong, ok.
It's a huge scoop.
- Yeah, Alice wants to pull the interview.
She's got a feature on
"Is The World Really Ending On Tuesday?"
Well it may as well if we lose Lu Tong.
Lu Tong stays.
Six minutes. Let's do this.
General Lu Tong, hi.
Sorry it's so chaotic in here today.
Thank you for coming on.
We're on, live, in two minutes.
Miranda will probably want to start with
what's going on in Naypyidaw.
Go three.
- Miranda, back to General Lu Tong.
Keep pressing.
- So let me ask you one more time, General Lu Tong...
will you take responsibility for the
human rights abuses...
perpetrated by your own government?
He's on the rack. Tight on 4.
Get those beads of sweat.
In you go, 4. Push it.
- I'm sorry, I can't answer that.
Can't, or won't, Lu Tong?
- Can't, or won't, General Lu Tong?
On balance, I'd suggest "can't",
considering
I've just found General
Lu Tong in the lobby,
and his chauffeur is currently
live on air answering
questions about Far Eastern geopolitics.
No? Any comments you want to make
about the use of sexual torture...
by your own military?
Ask him about London traffic.
- London traffic, General Lu Tong,
anything to say about that?
No comment there. Unbelievable.
That's it from General Lu Tong.
We'll see you after this short break.
Good job.
Unfortunately, you leave me no choice.
It is actually illegal to fire
somebody for being pregnant.
I'm not firing her for being pregnant.
I'm firing her for gross incompetency.
Bridget is the beating heart of this
show. How could you want to fire her?
How about for interviewing a
chauffeur instead of a general?
Using a TV interview to determine if a
guest might be the father of her child...
and being responsible for the
broadcast of six bare arses?
It's okay. It really okay, Richard.
I was going to quit anyway. Probably.
Believe it or not, I was a little
like you when I started here.
A little chunkier and much less makeup,
but I wanted to make my mark too.
But I don't want to be
part of your re-branding.
I haven't got the right haircut anyway and
I don't drink cocktails out of jam jars
or post photos of my lunch on Instagram.
And I suppose it's become
unfashionable to care
about wanting to make
something worthwhile.
But I would rather be old-fashioned
and unemployed...
than part of a show that
celebrates the inane.
Then maybe when my boy
is old enough to understand,
integrity will be fashionable again.
What have I done?
It's all very well fighting
for your principles
when there's no food in the fridge.
I mean, how difficult can
it be to find another job...
when you've just been fired
and your nine months pregnant?
And whatever happens now, I'm going
to get you one of those bloody Bugaboos.
Birthday?
Oh God, brains gone to mush.
First shag?
No.
Bugger.
I'm very sorry.
I've gone all crap, all of a sudden.
Right.
No, no, no, no. Fuck.
Okay, new pre-birth resolutions.
I, Bridget Jones, am going to
be the best mother in the world.
I'm going to try not to
leave you in a shop...
or put you in the washing machine like
the woman in the newspaper with her cat.
Look, I know I made you a promise to
get things sorted before you got here.
Well the truth is, I haven't,
but you and me can do this together...
because knights in shining armour
don't exist any more.
Or do they?
Hi.
Bridget. Good God, what are you
doing there? You're all wet.
Yes, I locked myself out,
and left my bag...
Lost my keys, phone, my mind.
What are you doing here?
It seems I can always find time to
save the world, but you're my world.
I thought you were back with Candida.
You know perfectly well her name's Camilla.
- Camilla.
I came round your house to find you,
and she was there.
She came to collect her bags.
Gone back to The Hague.
Just taken her to the airport.
Thank you.
Bridget...
You know I find
emotional declarations...
difficult.
But the truth is ...
Why are my trousers warm?
My waters must have broken.
- Oh Jesus.
So sorry. I'll get a cloth.
But you're not due for another
two or three weeks.
That's a contraction. I think we
should get to the hospital quickly.
Absolutely.
- Let's take your car.
I came in a taxi.
- Oh, for fucks sake.
Well, how was I supposed to know?
- No, not you. The contractions.
No, we'll take your car.
- We can't. The car keys are in
my bag with everything else.
Five, six, seven, eight...
- Just pant, and breathe, and count.
...Nine, ten.
- It's what your supposed to do, isn't it?
You should get that. It might be work.
No don't!
- Oi! What the fuck?
That's really sweet,
but we've got to call a cab.
Oh, shit.
Right, what do we do?
I'll think of something.
Watch out.
- Out of the way.
We go to the hospital.
We're going to make a baby.
Let's go.
God, this is...
This is really happening.
I'm going to be a mother.
Maybe I'm too old for all this.
Wait, wait. Why're you stopping?
A margarita with onion and pineapple.
Number 17, thank you.
What?
Who is ordering onion with pineapple,
huh? Some people they're crazy, no?
Yes. Okay. Here we go.
Do not worry, Ms. Bridget.
We get you there.
There is no traffic this time of night.
It's okay, eh?
Vagina. Power to the vagina.
My God. Unbelieveable.
Is a bloody women's rights march.
Oh gees, not now.
- Christ, it's those women I defended.
It's those infernal Russians.
Just hold my hand.
We really need to get there.
We need to get there.
Right, we're getting out. Ready?
- No, I don't think it's a good idea.
No, Bridget... Bridget.
Call Jack.
- I'll come behind with the bags, Mr. Mark.
And I call Mr. Jack.
It's all right, Bridget. We'll find a way.
- I don't think I can walk.
It's alright. I'll carry you.
Good God, Bridget. You're immense.
- I can't help it.
I think my lungs collapsed,
but this is not about me.
The contractions are starting again.
I'm going to have the baby in the street.
- I tell you what,
we'll rest for ten, and we'll walk for ten.
- Okay.
It's not much further.
- No.
I think it's about a mile and a half.
- Don't think...
Are you okay?
It's probably best if I don't talk too much.
- Yes.
Okay, I'm here. Okay.
I can take it from here.
I'm here. Okay. I got this.
- Thank you.
Jesus.
This is a two man job.
- I'm here.
Take her. Take her.
- I got her.
Jesus. Don't drop her.
Just inside.
- This way?
Yes, there.
- No, this way.
Okay, squeeze in.
Are you squeezing?
- Get her.
Squeeze in.
- I'm squeezing.
Push.
Closer.
No, no, that's fine.
We're out.
- Nurse.
Carol, Carol, wheelchair. Wheelchair
One two three.
- Yes, over here. Please. Thank you.
You okay?
Which of you is the father?
- I am.
Right.
Breathe out the pain.
Oh, good.
- Hey.
I was wondering how many fathers
we'd get. A full house. Bingo.
Bridget, how do you want do this?
An epidural?
No, you can do this. A positive mental
attitude is stronger than any drug.
Okay? Just think away the pain.
- Oh bollocks to that. No, I want everything.
Gas, air, injections, morphine.
Bridget, remember your yoga.
- Fuck yoga.
Oh, I couldn't agree with you more.
It's supposed to relax one...
but I just spend the entire time clenching
my sphincter in an effort not to fart.
Can we turn you over?
I just need to check your cervix.
You're doing very well.
Turning around. Turn to me.
Just a little rummage.
Okay, ready? Rummaging... now.
Yes. Oh, good, good..
You at eight centimeters already.
That's excellent. That means
you can't have any drugs at all.
What?
- You're too far gone.
Well done. Ooh, another contraction.
I'm not sure how much there is to gain from
you two being at the coal face if I'm honest.
My ex-husband said it was like watching
his favourite pub burn down.
So. Your choice.
Maybe dad should go and
fetch mum a cool flannel.
I know. I know.
It's okay. You can do this.
Just, think away the pain.
Mother fucker.
Just think away the pain.
- Get out, both of you.
Where are you going?
I've changed my mind.
You can do this.
You can. We can do it together.
Just think what lifes
thrown at you already.
You've turned disasters into triumphs...
with your sheer, joyful, indefatigable,
infectious lust for life.
You've managed this entire pregnancy
almost entirely on your own...
despite a lunatic mother, repressed men and
cheating boyfriends who don't deserve you.
Just a last few moments.
Just a last few moments, my love,
and then you'll see your beautiful baby.
What if it's not yours?
- I'll love him anyway, just as I love you.
The way you were, the way you are,
the way you always will be.
I think you better go and have that seen to.
- Thank you.
I'll handle it from here.
Think the pain away.
You're pushing an entire human
being out of your vagina.
I'd like to see them thinking it away.
And, with 367 of the votes...
the winner is Pamela Margaret Jones.
- Pamela, honey, it's Bridget.
Not now, Colin.
- It's about the baby.
I hereby declare that
Pamela Margaret Jones...
I'm so sorry. You'll have to excuse me.
We are about to become a grandmother.
Well, that's it for the special late
night edition of "Hard News".
25 seconds to off air. 25.
- Standby.
Bridget's in labor.
Bridget's in labor!
Except to say Bridget
Jones is in labour!
Yes.
- Run the credits.
Credits.
I hope I'm bloody godmother.
- Cue the fucking weather.
Listen I...
I owe you an apology.
I know I haven't behaved
very well in all of this.
No, it's okay.
Hello.
Say hello to our beautiful boy.
Go ahead.
- Thank you.
Let's see who you are.
Isn't he perfect?
- Yes.
Hello.
I'm so sorry I'm late, Bridge.
Some lesbians are having
a stupid all night march.
Actually,
they're marching in aid of free speech.
It's rather important.
- My God, look at him.
Bridge.
I'm so sorry that we weren't here.
There's an unbelievably long march.
Actually, the march is critical...
- Can I be godfather?
Oh, I'm depending on you.
Oh, congratulations.
- Well done.
Thank you very much.
Well done, both of you.
- To all of you.
Where is she?
I'm so sorry we didn't get here on time.
Daddy's parking the car.
There's some march for women's rights. I
mean, honestly, do we need any more rights?
Mom, meet your new grandson.
The darling. He looks just like...
Not that it matters, but...
do we know who the daddy is yet?
Shall we find out?
Come on, you two.
Time for a little test.
It's so exciting, isn't it? It's like
the final of the X Factor or something.
Dial 01 if you want it to be Mark and
02 if you want it to be Jack.
Well, good luck.
- You too.
Please.
- Thank you.
You look beautiful.
Hello darling. Hello.
Hello.
- Hi.
We're really doing this.
- No going back now.
We are gathered here to celebrate the
union of Bridget Rose Jones...
and Mark Fitzwilliam Darcy.
Aand by the powers vested in me,
I now pronounce you...
finally, husband and wife.
Jack,
what on earth are you doing with my son?
Well,
don't leave me alone with him again.
I have no idea what I'm doing.
- Is he traumatized?
Hallo, William Jones-Darcy.
Are you ready?
Some champagne for you?
- Yes please.
Dear Diary. And so, I, Bridget Jones ...
am a singleton no more. Married? Yes.
Smug? Well, it's about time, so...
maybe just a little.