Happy birthday to me
How in hell
did I end up here again?
Ugh.
Fuck off.
My birthday
actually began the way
of all my birthdays.
Hello, darling.
Just ringing to wish
you a happy birthday!
Mum? It's 6:00 a.m.
I'm doing the FaceTime.
Una taught me.
It's really marvelous!
Mum, the point of FaceTime
is that you haven't got
to put the phone to your ear.
Oh! Silly me!
Oh! There you are!
This time, 43 years ago,
I was having a lamb biryani
in an attempt to coax you out.
Twenty-three hours of labor.
Never been the same
down there.
It's a miracle,
the gift of childbirth.
Here it comes!
Penny Husband-Bosworth's son
sells his sperm
on the Internet!
You don't even
need a man, Bridget.
Some people have
marvelous lives
without them!
I mean, look at you.
A nice flat, a lovely job.
Nice flat!
I'm putting
the phone down now, Mum.
Oh, um...
Say happy birthday to Bridget.
Colin!
Happy birthday to Bridget.
Thank you!
I love you, darling.
Now don't forget,
I'm counting on you
to head up my media campaign.
It's the parish
council elections, Mum.
Not the US Primaries.
Annual phone call
from Mum reminding me
to take my ovaries
out of retirement.
The truth was that by now,
I thought I would
have had a little baby to love
with the chisel-jawed
love of my life.
But sometimes, life gives you
shallower compensations.
And at least
I was finally down
to my perfect weight.
Buongiorno, Miss Bridget.
There was life
in the old dog yet.
Hadn't exactly
been put out to grass.
Ding dong.
But this year,
all these things
were brought
into sharper focus
by an event
I hadn't expected to
attend quite so soon.
Hi.
So, how are you feeling?
Are you okay?
Mmm. Yeah.
Just can't believe
he's gone, really.
His death seems to have hit
the Eastern European
teenage modeling community
particularly hard.
They found
the flight recorder,
but still no bodies.
Strangely fitting
that he should have died
going down in the bush.
Shh.
Sorry. Oops.
We are
gathered here to
celebrate the life
of Daniel Vivian Cleaver.
Daniel was a kind
and wonderful son.
Fuck.
What the fuck
is he doing here?
A loving uncle
and brother.
Oh, you know what
he's like, wanting to
do the decent thing.
Is that his Wife?
Mmm.
Did I ever
get over losing Mr. Darcy?
Was he my Mr. Right?
Oh, Christ.
A man
of outstanding charm
and charisma.
Just a bit emotional.
I would like
to invite his loved ones
up to share
some of their
memories of Daniel.
Daniel could be
very sensitive.
Make you feel like you were
the only woman in the world.
I first met Daniel in Moscow.
He once took me
rowing on the Serpentine
and quoted Keats by heart.
He could quote
Keats by heart!
"Where be ye going,
you Devon Maid?
"And what have ye
there in the basket?"
there in the basket?
"Ye tight little fairy
just fresh from the dairy,
"Will you give me
some cream if I ask it?"
He did it to everyone.
Would anybody else
like to say a few words?
Say something for his mum.
Get up, go on.
Um...
Daniel was a man
who touched many
of us here today,
including me.
Oh, dear.
This is when Daniel would say,
"Shut up, Jones."
And he would be right
because all I really
need to say is, um,
dear Daniel,
I will miss you terribly.
We all Will.
- Give you a call?
- Yes, very good.
Bye, Bridget.
Bye. Bye.
Oh!
Bridget.
Mark!
This is Camilla.
Hello.
Bridget. An old friend.
Well, less old,
more childhood!
So, nice memorial,
as memorials go.
Almost makes one look forward
to one's own.
Yes, well...
Goodbye.
Goodbye!
Maybe that's
the reason Mark Darcy
and I never made it.
I always felt like
a verbally incontinent
old maid
even when we were together.
Still, I wasn't going to
dwell on the negatives.
At least no one at work knew
it was my birthday.
Or, indeed,
how old I was going to be.
Surprise!
Happy birthday, Bridget!
Gosh!
Or so I thought.
Who told you?
It's so hot. So many candles!
Happy 43rd birthday to you
Isn't there some sort
of statute of limitations
about the number of
sodding candles on a cake
once you get to a certain age?
Josh, I need you
to see what Reuters
is saying about
the attacks on Ramallah.
We might need a live link.
I may have been
another year older
and still single,
but I could
always take consolation
in my job as
top news producer.
So, how will I be
changing the world today?
Well, our main feature
is the exclusive interview
with the Foreign
Secretary about NGochi.
OMG. How did you do that?
NGochi.
You're good at that!
I know.
I've been practicing. NGochi.
NGochi.
NGochi?
It's harder than you think!
NGochi.
Plus,
have great new ISO-something
work colleagues
who are not obsessed
with children and marriage.
How do we plan on
celebrating tonight?
Well, night out
with the gang.
Please say that
involves group sex.
Gang bangs?
Ooh. We like to do that.
I know a smashing little club
round the back of
Berwick Street.
Chance
would be a fine thing.
I'm beginning to think
I've passed my sexual
sell-by date.
No! There are names for
women like you now, Bridge.
You're a cougar.
You are a MILF.
I'm not a MILF.
I'm not even a mum.
I'm a spinster.
I'm a SPILF.
Three minutes
till we're on air.
It's called Voyeurz,
with a 'Z'.
You tell them
that Cathy sent you.
And if you go on a Thursday,
there's a Chinese buffet,
all you can eat, as it were.
But whose advice was,
nevertheless,
sometimes a tad
too modern for me.
- It's me. Checking talkback.
- Yep.
You didn't freeze your eggs
by any chance, did you?
No. I imagine
they're hard-boiled by now.
You know what, Bridge?
This weekend,
you and me need to go out
and get stuck into
some serious...
Binge drinking, a dangerous
scourge on society.
Is new legislation needed?
Bridget, Miranda.
I've told you,
don't talk between the bongs.
Stick to the questions
on the cue cards.
Miranda, cue.
The Foreign Secretary
will be live in the studio
to talk about the looming
crisis in Muribundi.
You could always try
online dating again.
The other night
I was on Tinder.
Half an hour later,
- I'm having a three-way with...
- Miranda, cue!
Prince Andrew, the Royal
Special Representative for
Trade and Investment...
You did that on purpose.
...has just written his
first children's book.
He had a massive cock.
Live in the studio, I'm joined
by Foreign Secretary,
George Wilkins,
who has just returned
from war-ravaged Muribundi...
Miranda, I'm in your ear.
Just follow my lead.
...where the assassination
of bloody dictator,
Charles NGoohi,
has resulted in civil war.
One take.
Come back to four. Four.
Minister,
was this a military coup?
Well, the signs are that
NGochi's own generals
did take him out in
a rather bloody way.
Hi, Tom. Can't talk.
How was
Daniel's memorial?
It's just sad.
I can't believe
he's gone, actually.
It's just sad.
I can't believe
he's gone actually.
Uh...
I don't think there was
any particular sadness
in his passing.
His persecution of
the Unbutu people
amounted to genocide.
That is well documented.
I know he had his faults.
Well, I know he
had his faults.
He could be
a massive arsehole.
But I miss him. We all do.
Well, he was
certainly a very colorful
character
on the world stage, Miranda.
I grant you that.
But I think
the genocide resulting in
the deaths of over
10,000 of his own people,
men, women and children,
probably did rather put him
on the wrong side of history.
At least he was never boring.
Well, at least
he was never boring.
One, two
and three. Clear.
Do you think
a spirit of democracy
can carry over
into West Africa
now NGochi's dead?
Do you think, Minister,
that the spirit of democracy
can carry over
into West Africa
now that NGochi is dead?
Now that is an interesting
question. Finally.
Running out
of time here.
Miranda, wrap it up!
Briefly, please, Minister.
It is a complicated issue.
Yes or a no?
Miranda,
make it the last answer.
Let's hope so.
I'll take that.
Thank you for joining
us on the sofa today.
Stand by.
Toby on one.
Over to you, Toby.
And now, what if a man
was to experience labor?
Well, thank you,
Miranda, Bridget.
You couldn't just
behave yourselves
when the new
management team were here?
They're the new
management team?
That is Alice Peabody,
new Brand Manager.
Apparently, Hard News
is too old-fashioned,
too serious,
and she is
the smiling assassin
brought in to sack
anybody older than her.
Everybody's older
than her.
I've got tins of
soup in my cupboard
older than her.
Look at them all.
With their apps,
and their ironic beards.
Maybe one of them
could give Bridget some sex.
What?
Does Brid... Do you need sex?
Yes! No!
Which is why I'm taking her
on a girls' weekend
to beat all girls' weekends.
Bridget, isn't it?
Yes. Nice to meet...
Team meeting tomorrow morning.
We can do introductions then.
9:00 a.m.
We should all start
an hour earlier from now on.
You think she saw that?
Uh, quite possibly not.
And you're sure you
don't wanna come out
with me and my crew?
Mmm-hmm.
Thanks, but can't
let the old gang down.
They're stay-at-home mums now.
They'd be disappointed.
Ooh.
Hmm.
Huh.
Thank God for the gays!
Now whatever
fears you're bringing
in the room with you today,
I want you to
take those fears
and I want you to tell them
to fuck the fuck off!
Yeah!
Are you ready for this?
Then ride, you sexy bitches.
Ride!
Look, I'm so sorry, Bridget,
but I'm actually gonna
have to blow you out, too.
Oh!
I didn't wanna have
to tell you this today,
but Eduardo and
I are adopting.
What, a baby?
Yes. A baby.
Or gayby, in our case.
That's fantastic news!
Tom!
Yeah.
I'm going to Bogoté tomorrow
to start the paperwork,
so I've gotta go and pack.
Wonderful! Go!
Happy birthday. Have fun.
Congratulations!
Thanks, darling. Bye.
Fucking excellent.
And that was how
I wound up back here again.
The last barren
husk in London.
And of the two
loves of my life,
one is married,
and the other is dead.
Right.
New birthday resolutions.
I, Bridget Jones,
am done with
affairs of the heart
and dedicating my autumn years
to the pursuit of hedonism.
Will hang only with new,
free-spirited friends
like Miranda.
And when the going gets tough,
the tough go on
a luxury spa weekend!
What the fuck?
Love the shoes.
I didn't tell you
because you wouldn't
have come!
Seriously,
it's been five years.
You gotta shake
yourself out of this
self-imposed
purdah you've been in
ever since you split up
with your precious Mark Darcy.
Rubbish.
I barely think of him.
What you need
is a good shafting.
You need some
good old-fashioned,
lie-back-and-think-of-England
bonking.
And festivals are
sexual free-for-alls.
Like Sodom and Gomorrah,
with tofu.
First man you meet,
you gotta sleep with.
First man?
I'm not taking
no for an answer.
I'm gonna find our
backstage passes.
You get the maps.
Wanna know where you are?
Maps!
I may be old and
inappropriately dressed,
but at least I look
fucking amazing!
Oh.
That's exactly why
I didn't wear my heels.
Ding fucking dong!
May I?
Uh...
Ah.
Um... Uh...
Ooh.
Thank you.
On!
Ah. There you go.
It fits.
MIRANDA; Bridget!
Bridget!
Is that your
wicked stepmother?
Yes.
I'd better go before
she has me sweeping
fireplaces all day.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Ah-ha. Birthday
resolution number two.
Must remember
the way to a man's heart
is not through beauty,
sex or love...
It's Jack.
...but merely
the ability to fall arse
over tit in the mud.
By the way.
Right.
Which one's ours?
Uh, let's try up here.
And anyway,
it's not camping.
It's glamping.
Putting a "GL"
in front of it doesn't
make it any better.
Calling him Gladolf Hitler
wouldn't
suddenly make you forget
all the unpleasantness.
Oh. Fuck me!
NGochi!
NGcohi!
It's 2:30
in the afternoon!
I should be hoovering!
This is incredible!
We've got to get a photo!
Excuse me?
Do you mind
if we ask you to
take a photo of us?
- Yeah. Sure.
- Thank you.
All right. You ready?
Hey, what are you doing?
I was taking a photo.
I thought you guys
wanted a photo.
Yeah, we do. Of us.
Yes. Terribly sorry,
but we thought it
would be really fun
to get a photo of us backstage
among all these
glamorous people.
I think that's
the guy from Bargain Hunt.
It would be great
if you could get
him in the shot.
Quick, quick, quick!
So, you don't want me
in the photo at all?
Oh, God. You can lose
the attitude, babes.
Is it really that difficult?
God. They let any old
riff-raff backstage nowadays.
I don't know. I thought
he was kind of cute.
But he looks familiar.
I think he works at
the Starbucks in Balham!
Here we go!
One, two, three, sing!
Oh, my God!
I know!
It's the guy from Starbucks!
Crowd-surf!
Whoo!
Miranda!
Miranda?
Shit.
Hey, Miranda.
Oh, God!
I have to admit that was fun.
And you're right.
What I need is
a good shafting.
Some good old-fashioned
lie-back-and-think-of-England
bonking.
Well, sign me up.
Oh, my God!
What are you doing
in my yurt?
With all your clothes
and luggage and possessions.
Yeah. It's as if
I've come in,
made it my own.
Wait, it's you.
The creature from
the Black Lagoon.
Oh. Yes. Sorry.
Well, you don't
really expect me to believe
that you accidentally crashed
into my yurt, do you?
Oh!
Since you're here,
maybe I could help you.
Well,
he is the first man I met.
And his yurt is
one heck of a lot
nicer than mine.
Bridget!
Where the fuck are you?
I'm so pissed!
MIRANDA; Bridget!
I'm zorbing with Ed Sheeran!
Oh, God!
I've just slept with
a complete stranger!
I'm nothing but
a feckless prostitute.
No, no.
I'm an elegant older woman
taking men for
my own pleasure.
Or am I just a deluded,
middle-aged fool?
Fuck it!
Miranda.
Good morning.
So, it lasted six hours?
What lasted
six hours, Mum?
Um, a puppet show that
Auntie Bridge went to.
Six-hour puppet show?
Hello.
So, tell me, were
they little puppets or...
Very nice-sized puppets.
And did he put
his puppet in your mouth?
God! I feel like my days
of puppet shows are behind me.
I've had finger puppets.
And has he called?
Well, it doesn't
work like that anymore.
You just hook up
with rugged troubadours
at music festivals
and there are no strings.
Puppets with no strings.
Take the wings off.
They're for little girls.
Come on.
Hello?
Where the fuck are you?
Speeding through
lovely countryside
on our way to
your christening.
No, we're not.
Why is Auntie Bridget lying?
Shh.
Bridge,
I thought you should know
after Tom dropped out,
Giles asked Mark
to be the godfather.
What?
He did what?
Yes, I know.
He really is a useless cock.
Did it without asking me.
Oh, my God!
Mark Darcy again.
Twice in the space of a week,
I turn up at church
as rent-a-spinster.
Where the fuck were you?
Sorry. Sorry.
Sorry.
Good morning,
and welcome.
Well, this isn't
embarrassing at all.
Mark Darcy and I at
the altar with a baby.
That's lovely.
Okay, now. Nice big smiles.
Looking at me.
Thank you. Lovely!
Okay.
Can I just get
the godparents now, please?
So, how are you?
Very well, thank you.
How are you?
Well. Thank you.
Mmm.
Are you here with your wife?
I can't remember her name.
Camilla. No, she, uh...
No, she couldn't make it.
Ah. Mmm.
You with anyone?
No, no. Not today. No.
Come on. It's not a funeral.
Can I get a couple of smiles
out of you two, please?
Maybe give her a little kiss?
You know, on the
forehead there.
Uh... I was talking
about the baby.
Lovely!
All right.
I'll see you later,
I shouldn't wonder.
Yeah.
Unless I make a break
for it with this thing.
Could this day
actually get any more awkward?
Just keep walking,
keep walking,
keep walking, keep walking!
Hello.
How are you?
Very well, thanks.
I'm fine.
So am l.
Well, goodbye.
Goodbye.
A glass of wine.
A whiskey, please.
Big. Big glass.
Double.
Thank you.
I'd ask you to join me,
but I'm pretty sure
you're not a big
Gangnam Style kind of guy.
I was only there very briefly.
Where?
Gangnam.
What are we talking about?
Gangnam. Dancing.
Ah!
Not the suburb of Seoul.
No.
Not familiar with Gangnam,
the suburb.
It literally means
"South of the Han River."
It was inhabited as early
as the Paleolithic Period.
Suddenly seems so
much less catchy!
Now something for
you lovers out there.
We're entering
"the erection section."
Don't say fucking
"erection" at a christening!
Oh.
Would you like
to get some air?
I mean, some more air.
Sure.
I don't suppose
you happen to
have a cigarette?
No.
Gave up
1,891 days ago.
Not that you're counting.
Since when
did you smoke?
I don't.
It's been a tense time.
Maybe I'm nervous.
Why?
You have a train
in your hair.
I'm aware of that.
Courtesy of one of
my many godchildren.
Seems to be stuck.
And this would be...
Cake?
Profiterole.
It's technically
more of a dessert
than a cake, I suppose.
What are you doing?
You're married.
No, I'm not.
I mean, I am.
I'm getting a divorce.
That's why she's not here.
Weren't you together
at the memorial?
No. She was just
being supportive.
She's gone back to The Hague,
where she's now living
and I'm not.
Oh, I'm so sorry, Mark.
Right at this precise moment,
I'm not sorry at all.
How the fuck am I supposed
to get in here?
Again?
Mr. Darcy.
Wow.
Bridget.
Mmm-hmm?
God, I've missed you.
Are we on schedule?
I have a flight to
Khartoum tomorrow.
I'm so sorry, Mark.
Had to leave.
Probably sounds pathetic,
but I got scared.
The fact that we
went round and round
for the best part of 10 years
without ever making it
across the finish line
leads me to think
we did the best thing
by ending it when we did.
Sometimes it feels scary
still being on my own at 43,
but you and I have
been here once before.
We always loved
the fantasy of us,
but the reality,
as we both know,
is quite different.
Ta-da!
We could both come up
with 100 reasons why
we didn't make it.
But in the end...
I always felt that
you were never there
and I was mostly alone.
No, can't go back
and keep making same mistakes.
Must keep moving forward
and make new ones.
And will launch myself
into frenzied keep-fit regime.
Am allowing four weeks
to reduce thigh circumference
in order to squeeze lardy arse
into teenage skinny jeans.
Obviously not meant
for women of a certain age.
All this bloody
cycling is pointless.
I'm putting on weight.
Let's rule out some
of the other options,
shall we?
You're not pregnant, are you?
Of course not.
A lady is always prepared.
And I always carry
these in my handbag.
Oh, God!
You didn't use those?
The vegan condoms?
"Biodegradable and
dolphin-friendly."
If I'm going to be slutty,
it's nice to think
I'm helping the environment.
Christ.
Bridget, I remember
when you bought those!
That was decades ago!
Sell-by dates
don't mean anything.
Do they?
They were a gift.
Don't ask.
Tumbling rapids,
frothing waterfalls,
a babbling brook!
Oh, come the fuck on, Bridget.
How long do you
think it takes?
I think that's
a positive result.
I'll just make sure.
Oh, don't shake it.
You'll hurt the baby!
The baby's not
in the stick, Bridget.
I think this is when
you're meant to jump for joy.
Oh, my God.
You're pregnant.
I'm pregnant?
I'm pregnant.
You're going
to have a baby.
I'm going to have a baby.
Yeah.
If you've got footage of her
punching a horse, I want it.
Bridget,
do you want a baby?
I don't know.
I mean, I'm 43.
It might be the only
chance I'm going to get.
Look, one broken,
out-of-date condom
I might have
believed was an accident.
But two?
You wanted it.
Maybe I did.
Ooh.
Can we get a medic, please?
Oh, my God!
I'm pregnant!
This is it!
More to the point,
whose is it?
This is not how I thought
this moment would be.
Always imagined myself
in OK! magazine
with the man of my dreams.
Oh, Christ.
Too many dilemmas to ponder.
Not least of all,
who was that man
I shagged in a tent?
And so, your age will be 43?
Mmm.
Huh.
So, um, which of the times
with my wonderful man
do you think
we got pregnant on?
Does it matter?
Well, yes.
It's such a special moment.
We'd like to know
which one it is,
so we can treasure it.
Can't you
treasure both of them?
Oh. Yes. We will.
I mean, we do,
but surely one of those dates
is more likely than the other?
Uh, well, actually, day 10,
which was his birthday,
is a little early.
And day 16, which was the...
Anniversary dinner.
Ah, yes. The osso buco,
I recall, is a little late.
Are you sure there wasn't
another treasurable occasion
in between?
Yes, I'm quite sure.
He was away.
So, which of the two
would you go for?
Couldn't say.
They're both equally likely.
It could've been
after the events
because as you know
sperm can live
for several days
after ejaculation.
No.
Couldn't you just
have a guess for me?
What about the first scan?
Would that show
when conception took place?
No. Ring this number
to fix a date.
And do bring along the father
if you can work out
which one he is.
Right.
Right. Um...
Just out of interest...
Mmm?
If someone did have
an element of confusion
about the father...
Well, you can get a DNA sample
at the amniocentesis.
And I do recommend
that you have
the amniocentesis
because there are
always more risks
with a geriatric mother.
"Geriatric"?
Mmm.
That's outrageous.
Indeed.
Unless you can
sign on for your
child support
and pension at the same time.
That's hilarious.
It's called "news"
'cause it should feel new.
Otherwise,
it would be called "olds."
Sorry.
Last night, top stories.
Earthquake in Asia.
Seen it before.
Car crash on the M5,
blah, blah, blah.
We are making olds.
We need to flip the switch,
mix it up.
I want to NutriBullet
the shit out of the news.
She's on the Warpath.
Susan the Floor Manager's
gone.
She's six months pregnant.
We've got to
grab the attention!
Get the eyes on the screen!
I want to see headlines like
"ls your sofa bed
giving you cancer?"
"ls your freezer
giving you Alzheimer's?"
Oh, my God. Are they?
Literally no evidence
whatsoever, but you're
missing the point.
You're intrigued, aren't you?
I want to re-launch Hard News
with a clear new objective.
We have
a presentation in 12 weeks
at the London Media Show,
and I am looking
for someone dynamic,
innovative, focused,
to lead the charge.
Any volunteers?
Whatever happens now,
must hold on to job.
Must prove to fascist boss
that I may be single mother,
but am willing
to roll with
the ironic-bearded hipsters.
Anybody at all?
Do you need the loo, Bridget?
No. I want to volunteer.
♪ Let's do this.
It's me, it's me.
Turn on your TV now.
Look at your TV.
Now! Now! Now!
Turn on Channel 4.
Bridget, I found him!
He's the dating website guru!
See, you have to
trust the science.
Algorithms don't lie.
You only slept with
a fucking billionaire!
So, tell us,
Bridget, um,
what was it that
initially attracted you
to the billionaire,
Jack Quant?
Was it his face or his body?
Yeah. Well,
I'd do him, obviously.
Big dick?
If I were you,
I wouldn't tell
either of them.
All you need's a DNA sample
from one of them.
And then you can eliminate
the other one from
your enquiries.
What would I say to Mark?
"Hello, Mark. I know
I just left you asleep,
"but I don't suppose
you've got any blood,
"sperm, or old fingernails
lying around?"
But how would you even
get in touch with Jack?
Yeah.
He is a bloody mogul.
Can't just ring him up.
Oh!
May have just
worked out how to win
favor with new boss
and eliminate one father
from my enquiries.
I have to say, Bridget.
I'm actually excited
about this next guest.
Relevant, relatable,
extremely fuckable. Good work.
Welcome to CSI Hard News.
One minute left
on the VT now. Out on Simon.
Bring in next five,
stand by. Thank you.
Thank you, my love.
If you could
just fuck off,
that would be great.
Jack, this is Cathy.
She'll get you ready.
- Hi, Cathy.
- Jack.
Nice to meet you.
I was just thinking
like a simple
magenta eye-shadow.
Make your eyes pop,
and little bit
of rouge, maybe?
Kidding.
You're funny.
Yeah, but you do
happen to have
a little stray
gray hair there.
There we are.
Ah! Jesus.
That's it.
Actually, there's a whole
gray patch up there.
Shall I just...
Yeah. Let me see.
Let's just get in there.
Yeah, my hair is
full of gray hair.
That's it.
I've sorted it.
Okay.
Jesus Christ.
All gone.
Yeah, that's lovely. Oh.
These fingernails
on this silver fox
could do with a bit of a trim,
couldn't they?
These hands
haven't experienced
much manual labor, have they?
No. I'm a mathematician.
They're silky soft.
Tell me, Jack.
Do you happen to
like Chinese food?
Jack. Let me take you to set.
Great. Thank you.
I do, sometimes.
Yes. Thank you.
I don't think
she put any makeup on me.
It's fine.
You look radiant.
Okay. Coming out of
VT in five, four...
And remember the gear shift.
And Miranda, cue.
But now, though,
I'm joined by Jack Quant.
Raised by a single
mother in Baltimore,
he created the matchmaking
website, Qwantify,
and he claims to have
found an algorithm for love.
And he's here today
to tell us all about
his number one best-seller
Qwantum Leap.
It is absolutely wonderful
to have you on our sofa today.
Thank you.
It's great to be here.
Now, we'll talk all
about your new book soon.
Obviously.
Yes.
But first,
let's talk about romance.
Qwantify has found
true love for millions.
Mmm.
Coming to two.
Has it worked for you?
Now if I answer that,
can we go back and
talk about the book?
Maybe.
Can you please try
not to shag him on air.
This is dynamite.
Tell her to
flirt with him more.
Some people had
their first crush
on Farrah Fawcett.
My first crush
was an algorithm.
And we've lost them!
If he carries on
talking about algorithms,
I'm cutting to the VT
of cats who look like Hitler.
Back to four.
Love it. Thank you.
He's avoiding the question!
Get him off maths.
Ask him if
he's with someone now.
For someone so
good at matchmaking,
is there a special
someone in your life?
Apart from Lady Mary
on Downton Abbey?
Now, can we go ahead
and talk about the book?
Cue Hitler cats!
Don't be evasive.
Oh, don't be evasive.
Uh, it's apparent
you have everything.
Why have you chosen
to have no family...
Why the decision to
have no family and...
No children?
And no children?
Brilliant.
Zoom in on four.
Go on four.
Love it.
Look, I love kids.
But I've always found
the idea of being a father
myself kind of petrifying.
Which is why I've been
drawn to algorithms.
Cue Hitler cats!
They're rational,
reliable, predictable.
Everything a kid isn't.
So, can you have children?
And can you have children,
though? I mean...
Are the soldiers working?
What?
Well, I believe so.
The barracks are in
pretty regular use.
Really?
Yes.
Because for someone
with a supposed
algorithm for love...
Isn't it odd that
you've never found it?
Well, I think in
order to find something,
you have to be
actively looking for it.
I've just been too busy,
so I haven't.
What about
the Quant family bloodline?
And what about
Are there any
skeletons in the closet?
Sexual deviants?
I'm sorry. I don't know
where we're going
with all of this,
but I have to tell you,
I can attract
the wrong type of women.
That's really great.
Thanks for sharing that
with us.
Fuck.
Fuck, fuck, fuck.
Bridget, what are you doing?
You wouldn't believe
some of the weirdos
that cross my path.
Really?
Get up!
Fuck, fuck.
Can you tell me
what she's doing?
Ask him something
about algorithms.
This has to be
the last question. Has to be.
Lastly, algorithms.
Yes.
What first
attracted you to them?
The logic, and...
Wonderful.
Jack Quant,
thank you for
coming on my sofa.
I hope you've had as
much fun as I have.
Jesus.
That's it from me. Goodbye.
That was great.
You look really familiar,
outside of being on the show.
Are you on Tinder?
What?
Then we won't have met.
No. Okay.
Well, hey!
How about seeing you here.
Hi.
Great to see you.
Great to see you, too.
I was going to come
and find you to say hello,
but you know how live TV
can be so chaotic!
Well, you know
there are easier ways
of getting in touch with me
than inviting
me on national TV
and asking me about my sperm.
No. That's not what... No.
I would have liked to
have heard from you.
I was disappointed
when I came back
that morning and you'd gone.
You were?
We had an amazing night.
And I thought you were great.
At least I did
until I became a clip
of the 50 most embarrassing
chat show moments of all time.
Really sorry about that.
Yes, that, um...
I don't know
how to, uh, explain. Um...
I'm pregnant.
Wow. Okay.
That's so much better than
you being mentally unbalanced.
I'm about 12 weeks.
Oh. Right. Wow.
So, you mean
it's the music festival.
Yes.
I know,
it's quite a surprise!
Yes. Um...
But, um...
I'm fine.
And you should know
that I don't... I'm not...
I'm not looking for
anything from you.
Well, except for
a complete DNA check
and review of
my medical records.
Well, the thing is
that I didn't mean
for you to find out
about this yet.
And I'm feeling, um,
a bit foolish right now.
Mortified, actually.
Yes. I'm mortified.
And, um, I'd like to just
retreat gracefully.
Mr. Quant,
will you sign my book?
Um...
Please.
Oh, God.
I didn't even tell him
he may not be the only daddy.
I love this book.
Hey, Katie Couric!
I need to talk to you!
What if this DNA
turns out to be Jack's?
Do I want
the father to be Jack?
I don't even know Jack.
And what if it's Mark Darcy's?
Christ.
I'll have to confess to him
I've been a whore
with dolphin condoms.
Good.
So, the baby's okay?
Perfect.
See?
Oh, my God. Is that it?
Mmm-hmm.
And it's all right?
Sound as a bell.
Cooking nicely.
Have a listen.
There you are.
I've recorded that for you.
You can watch
that for a moment.
So glad you've decided
on the amniocentesis.
Hello, you.
Is that your ear or your foot?
You have got very big feet.
Oh, and look at you,
waving already.
Hi.
You're the best thing
I've ever seen.
I promise I'll try my best.
So, you just stay safe
and snug in there
while I try and
sort the mess out here.
And hopefully...
What the fuck is that?
Um, it's the amniocentesis
needle.
We just pop it in,
take a little amniotic fluid,
test it for any abnormalities,
and also the DNA sample
that you require.
Now, there is the slightest
risk of miscarriage.
So, you'll have to stay
very still indeed because
we don't want
the needle to
come into contact...
What? No, no.
I'm not taking that chance.
And it's enormous.
It'd go straight
through the other side.
Come on, I'm taking you home.
Your mother will
be over the moon.
Will you promise not to
tell her? Just not yet.
No, no.
Of course. No, no. I promise.
Really sorry, Dad.
Not to know
about the father.
Don't be daft.
I know dozens of people
who could have been anybody's.
So, you're not disappointed?
You don't think
I belong on Jerry Springer?
Not a bit. I'm thrilled.
Actually,
I'm not sure if you're mine,
or that nice
Lieutenant Colonel's
who ran the bowls club.
Hmm.
Only joking.
You've got my feet.
I've always had
very dainty feet.
Just tell the truth,
Bridget.
Can't go too far wrong
telling the truth.
"Mark,
I have some exciting news. "
"Mark, I have the funniest
story to tell you."
"Mark, I'm up the duff."
My Lords, my Ladies.
There is only one fraud
committed here today
and it is this.
To use the laws of one country
to destroy the freedom
of speech of another.
A cynical political
expedient to take away
the right of these
brave young women
to speak the truth
about the country they love.
Now you may not
like their music.
And for that,
I cannot blame you.
They may not have mastered
the fundamentals of melody,
or even the most basic
tenets of musicianship.
But this is
the land of Shakespeare,
Orwell, Lawrence.
Oh. I'd forgotten
just how hot he is
in that wig and gown.
...to any country,
any ruler,
any despot, that here,
in the United Kingdom,
we will always
defend and protect
women such as these
who have selflessly
and courageously
risked their liberty
and quite possibly their lives
to tell the truth.
The court will now adjourn
and judgment will be
given in due course.
Poonani! Poonani!
Power to the Poonani!
Poonani!
Christ. I'm looking
forward to going back
to some good
old-fashioned genocide.
Silence! Silence!
Right.
How to do this?
I wasn't expecting
to see you again
after the events
at the christening.
Crap.
He's dived right in.
No. Right. I understand.
Okay.
Maybe flattery will work.
You were very impressive
in there today.
Thank you.
Although dealing with them
over the last month
has given me
a certain amount of sympathy
for the totalitarian dictator
who wants to silence them.
Okay. Jokes.
Will laugh harder next time.
There's only
a certain number of times
one can listen
to the resolutely un-catchy
Menstruation, Castration,
Liberation.
Mark.
That's hilariously funny.
Please.
So...
So, Mark.
Yes.
The gardens look lovely.
Autumnal.
Yes.
Is that a conker tree?
Bridget.
I...
Am pregnant.
Right.
Congratulations.
How can I help?
I'm three months pregnant.
Oh.
You mean the christening?
Right.
Would you excuse me
for just a moment?
Mmm.
I think that this
is quite possibly
the most wonderful
piece of information
I have ever
received in my entire life.
Oh!
Okay.
Of course,
I've got no expectations
for how things
should work out.
I just thought
you should know.
No, of course.
I mean, how do you feel?
Are you happy?
Yes, lam.
But so much has happened
in the past 10 years.
A lot has changed.
I mean, you've been married,
and I've been
on a number of
long-haul holidays.
But, um...
So here goes on Jack.
And, I mean...
No, I know that.
It's just,
right now, I can't quite
bring myself to
feel gloomy about it.
How can I tell him now?
State of emergency,
cannot sleep.
Looping thoughts
going round and round in head.
It's surely weird
that you can do something
as complicated and important
as growing a baby
or invading Iraq
without any
instruction at all.
Keep thinking all the alcohol
I've drunk over the years
will give the baby
fetal alcohol syndrome.
These are
the things I could do.
Tell Mark about Jack,
but risk hurting him so badly,
I couldn't live with myself.
Not tell Mark about Jack?
But I'd never be able
to go through with it.
Tell both of them
the other one is the father,
and then if the one
who isn't the father
is upset about it...
Oh, Christ. Tell no one
and make a run for it.
Hello?
Hey! It's the father
of your child.
Jack?
Yeah. Who else?
Come up.
Okay-
Oh, fuck, fuck, fuck.
He's probably employed a team
of Google Earth detectives
to find me.
Okay. Just act naturally.
Hi.
Come in.
Okay.
You found it.
Try it on. See if it fits.
Wow.
I didn't expect to see you.
I wasn't expecting to come.
I'm not used to
being rejected.
Twice.
I hope you've got
cake in that bag.
I've been doing
a lot of thinking.
Bridget,
this whole baby situation
threw me initially.
We squashed
an entire relationship
into one night
and skipped straight
to starting-the-family phase.
We never even had
a real second date.
Just so you know, if we did,
I would have taken
you to Ottolenghi.
Oh.
You would have had
the grilled salmon
and pine-nut salsa.
Unbelievable and healthy.
Oh.
And we would
have come back here,
had incredible sex,
spent the next couple days
sending each other
filthy texts.
I would not have
let you do that
on a second date.
Why not?
You let me on the first.
And then we'd go
on a naughty weekend
to the seaside,
and I would prove
my manliness by winning
you a cuddly toy.
Aw.
At the pier.
But I really wanted
the giant Scooby-Doo.
Oh, nobody wins those.
Coconuts are glued on.
What are those for?
To apologize.
We had our first fight.
I was not flirting
with that waitress.
She means nothing to me.
And then,
I would have bought
Swedish furniture
for us to make.
If we can get through this,
we can get through anything.
Anything.
I'd find it
adorable how your neck
gets all blotchy
when you get nervous.
And I know you'd be
the greatest possible
mother to my child.
Oh, no.
Cannot fall in love
with shiny new American.
I'll tell them both tomorrow.
Definitely.
Hi.
So, I just wanted
to connect
to check how
the presentation
is shaping up.
Mmm-hmm. Yeah. Totally
on top of it. NutriBullet-ing
the shit out of it.
I'm relying on you, Bridget.
I need you to get this right.
Do you understand?
100%. You can count on me.
Great.
You all right?
I'm fine.
Big celebration.
I so glad to see
you back together, huh?
Certainly is, Gianni.
Wonderful news, huh?
I was thinking about "Jack."
Huh?
If it's a boy,
after my grandfather.
It's a good strong name.
You can rely on a Jack.
Yes. One for the list.
To Jack.
To Jack!
Oh!
So, this is Dad, I presume.
So glad you could be here.
This is a unique
and wonderful moment.
Dr. Rawlings,
I wonder if you could
maybe do me a little favor?
Mmm.
So, this is Dad, I presume.
Pleased to meet you.
I'm so glad you could be here.
This is a unique
and wonderful moment.
Before we start,
would you like
to know the sex?
Maybe we should be prepared.
You know, I'm not sure.
It's a boy.
Oh.
A boy!
A boy.
- Aw.
My boy.
Okay. Right.
This time,
I have to tell them.
Will start with Jack.
Have invited him
to big scary
work presentation.
And will explain
all afterwards.
Welcome.
In a digital age
where every cell
phone is a camera,
we are all broadcasters.
Hard News is partnering
with the London Media Show
so that you will be able
to use your smartphones
to create your own
news broadcasting channels!
Simply download
the new Hard News app
and broadcast
directly to our studios
where Miranda is waiting
for our first ever
live simulcast.
And hello, everyone,
live at the London Media Show,
and welcome to the new look
of Hard News studio.
We are now live!
And yes,
our viewers are broadcasting.
Right.
Let's now go to the Grampians
where Adam
Wollaston is leading
a team of Venture Rangers
to the top of Ben Nevis.
Hello, Adam Wollaston!
Hard News sucks balls!
Jesus!
Oh, dear. Well, let's
put that news story
firmly behind us.
Technical glitch.
Of course,
it's never been easier
to email or text the show.
Just search "Hard News,"
or simply,
Because“.
Uh...
Holy fuck!
What's he doing here?
Because at Hard News,
we believe...
We believe that we are ready
and on the frontline,
asking the questions
the world wants answers to.
Turn around.
Thank you.
Okay.
Career down the toilet.
Both men in the same room.
What could possibly go wrong?
I hope you don't mind
my just showing up
and surprising you.
No.
Anyway, well done.
It was very...
Yes.
Hey.
...technically adroit.
Mark, I would love
for you to meet...
Uh...
Ari Yaratra Sitharamthanthan.
Ariyaranta is
the Area Manager for DTC
Technological Solutions.
Aren't you, Ari Sinatra?
Hi.
Hello.
Hey.
What the hell was that?
What were you thinking?
I've got four voice mails
from David Cartwright
on my phone
that I dare not listen to.
I'll be right back.
You call that
a presentation?
I don't know if I've got
the right people around me
because you're not...
Alice,
I'm so sorry, but...
Sorry doesn't cut it.
Excuse me.
Look at me when
I'm talking to you.
Excuse me?
I'm so sorry,
but I really...
What?
Bridget, I'd like
you to meet Jack Quant.
He's rather extraordinary.
I was just reading
a profile of him
in The New Yorker.
Right. Yes.
We actually know each other.
Yes. We certainly do.
Good job.
Why didn't you introduce me
to this man before?
He's brilliant. You know, he
represents the punk-rock band
that's being extradited.
That's right.
Yes, yes. I knew that, too.
Hi. We met
fleetingly before as well.
I'm in charge of
data management
for most of Daventry.
On.
Well, um...
I must say it's fantastic
that you're getting on so well
because you have
a lot in common.
Shall we get out of here
and find a place
a bit quieter?
Uh, yes.
Why not? I booked Gianni's.
Great.
That sounds lovely.
Oh. Um...
You might have to sit
this one out, Ari...
I'm sorry.
So, do you
actually believe that
mathematics can...
How did you put it
in your book?
"Help us analyze behavior
previously invisible
to science"?
Well, my dating
algorithm is to help people
find love,
not necessarily replace it.
Oh, no. ls incredible idea.
Have you ever tried it out?
You're single, right?
Well, I'm...
Yes, I suppose so.
And how did you two meet?
Oh.
Yeah.
It's, um...
It's sort of a funny story.
Sort of.
You see, um, a few months ago,
on the fourth of the month,
I met Jack at
a music festival.
Right.
And we got on very well.
And sort of
had, um, relations.
And the next week,
that is to say,
on the 11th of the month
at Jude's baby christening
to be exact,
uh, following the consumption
of quite a lot of alcohol,
Mark and I, well,
we had similar relations?
And this is
the funny part, I suppose.
Owing to these relations,
uh, the resulting life form
currently residing in my tummy
could actually,
in fact, be either of yours.
I know I should have
told you both before.
But I just didn't.
You both seemed so happy.
So, correct me if I'm wrong,
but did you just say
that the baby could
be either of ours?
So, you have no idea
which of us is
actually the father?
I know,
it's all very confusing.
I'm sorry.
So, however we choose,
uh, to do this,
the most important
thing now is this.
Is this.
Okay, Bridget, I'm not gonna
pretend this isn't a shock.
But I want you to know,
whatever the circumstance,
you're right.
The most important
thing is the baby.
Who knows, this could
be a great adventure.
I'm afraid you're going
to have to excuse me.
I have a meeting.
Oh. Uh...
I'm sorry.
Mark. Um...
Gianni, can we have
the bill, please?
And if I thought
that was tricky,
how would
the news go down at Mum's
parish council
election campaign?
Honestly,
we started half an hour ago.
Where have you been?
You said it was an emergency?
Well,
The Gazette wants to take
a family portrait.
What are you wearing?
Oh, my God.
Bridget, are you...
Yep.
Oh!
Yeah.
Why didn't you say anything?
Well,
didn't want to upset you.
Well, why would you?
Oh, no, Bridget.
Who's the father?
It's not Mark, is it?
Oh, do say it is.
Well, there's
at least a 50% chance.
"A 50% chance"?
Mark or this really
nice American called Jack.
No, Bridget. An American?
Did you have a three-way?
Mrs. Jones.
Here, take this and
pretend everything's fine.
Everything is fine.
Mrs. Jones. Can we...
Look, here's a lovely
place for you to stand.
Are you ashamed of me?
No, darling.
It's just the circumstances.
I'm running for
high office, you see.
So long.
It's not the 1950s.
Look around you.
Two lesbians have
just adopted at number 32.
If you don't change
the way you look at things,
you're going to lose
your precious election,
and perhaps your daughter.
Bridget, so lovely
to see you.
Are you...
Yes. I am.
How wonderful.
We thought you'd just
got all fat again.
BRIDGET. I'm now
the Mary Magdalene
of Middle England.
Have alienated
Mum and Mark Darcy.
Am like tropical female insect
that shags men to
impregnate self,
then eats them.
The question is,
will Mark even turn up
and engage in our
polyamorous family?
Hey!
Hello!
First prenatal class.
Exciting, huh?
Yeah!
Wow.
You look great.
Hello.
Hello!
Oh, I'm so glad you came.
Yeah, me, too.
Brought you an iced tea.
Oh, well!
Thank you.
It's awesome
to see you, man.
But there's a heck of a lot
of caffeine in that tea.
I brought you
a super juice.
Oh!
Thank you!
Um... Shall we go in?
Why not?
Sure.
Let me carry that for you.
Oh. Thank you.
Can I carry
your phone for you?
Okay.
Thank you.
And who do we have here then?
I'm Bridget
and this is Jack.
And this is Mark.
Oh!
Lovely.
You're our second
same-sex couple today!
Uh, no,
actually, we're...
Absolutely!
We just need
the gift of a baby
to make us feel complete.
You must be the surrogate?
Exactly. Yes.
Just helping this
wonderful couple
make their dream come true.
See, Mark is very nervous
about all this.
It's all new to you,
isn't it, lamb chop?
Like all visionaries,
we'll encounter bumps
along the road.
How would you
like to give birth
to your placenta?
Quickly!
Are you okay?
Are you sure?
And of course,
massage can have
many benefits
throughout pregnancy.
Can we name some of them?
Yes. It relieves stress
and promotes
feel-good hormones.
And is also to be avoided
in cases of
high-risk pregnancy.
For example,
when there is
a geriatric mother.
Right! Excellent.
Someone's been reading up.
Would you like to have a go?
No, I think I'll let
Jack get on with it.
I think he seems
to have it covered.
That's very sweet of you.
That's why I love you,
my little teacup.
What if we asked
the right question
and applied
the laws of mathematics
so that
the science of courtship
could be quantified?
Uh-oh!
Yippee!
It's a match!
Oh.
May I please
make an application
for leave to
appeal in the case of
Her Majesty's Government
and Saddiq Al Bashir.
As Your Lordship is no doubt
aware, Mr. Al Bashir lost...
So, everything's
all right?
Yes, well,
it's this combination.
Gherkins,
anchovies, banana juice,
and Pringles!
So, essentially...
It's wind.
Huh.
Right. So, going forward,
regular Pringles,
not hot spicy barbecue?
Or possibly
no Pringles at all.
- Try that.
- Ugh.
Ah! Is everything all right?
Is Bridget okay?
Yes. Perfectly fine.
She in there with...
That's Dr. Pringle.
He's testing her blood.
This is interesting.
This is a new
bedside technique
we're testing out of Oslo.
It's Norwegian...
It's all right.
I know about Jack.
Thank you, Doctor.
Oh, thank goodness.
Why didn't you tell me?
She's fine.
He's calmed her down
completely actually.
I'm sorry.
I got your messages.
I was in court.
Oh.
Hi. It's all right.
Can't be helped.
You should get it.
It might be work.
Don't worry. I got it covered.
Yes, I can see that!
Wow. Okay.
You need to chill out.
We have to do this together.
You know, in Peru,
the Um Bat Do
consider paternity
a task shared
between the many tribesmen.
Well, unfortunately,
we Um Bat Don't live in Peru.
I live in Ealing.
Negative energy is
just so bad for the baby.
Stop it, both of you!
This isn't a competition.
She's right.
We should take
this toxic energy
out of the room.
I won't be a minute.
What's up?
Come on, buddy.
Why are you so angry?
You know what?
I'm really not your buddy.
And I don't know
about vibes or negative
energy or prenatal wind
and even less
about algorithms.
So, I will confess that
the laws of attraction
are somewhat beyond me.
In fact, Bridget defies
comprehension generally.
But despite,
or perhaps, owing to
the bewildering
litany of catastrophes
I've witnessed over
the last 40 years,
I feel I've come to
know Bridget rather well,
and I've spent those years
caring for her very deeply.
And that may defy
automated reasoning,
but there's nothing
I can do about it.
Nothing you can do about it?
Maybe you should try
and stay around a little
instead of saving
the world by cell phone.
I make her happy, Mark.
And I suppose your
algorithm tells you
you're destined to
be together, does it?
Actually, it does.
The fact that you've been
trying and failing for
the past 1 O years
tells me you are not.
No.
I don't want to
fight with you.
We should think about
Bridget and the baby.
For better or worse,
fate has brought us together.
It wasn't fate,
it was condoms.
What do you mean?
Those ridiculous
dolphin-friendly things
from the bottom
of Bridget's bag.
I'm sorry, I have no idea
what you're talking about.
When Bridget and I
got it on,
I was not dressed
for the occasion.
No Mark today?
No.
We must thank one person
who was prepared
to fight for us
when no one else would.
And we say to that
person with all our heart...
Free speech!
Bridget. Camera back.
I still can't believe
Mark ducked out like that.
Well,
it's not really his fault.
I suppose we just have to
hope it's Jack's, right?
I mean, let's face it.
Things could be worse.
He is pretty fucking amazing.
He's richer than God,
and he has a very
nice-sized puppet.
He does.
And we match up
very nicely on paper.
How do you know?
You just have to have faith.
You just have to
ask yourself,
"Can I see myself
growing old with this guy
"and not Mark Darcy?"
There it is. Uh-oh!
There we go.
Oh, hey!
Oh.
You know, first few months,
they only see black and white.
This will help
stimulate spatial awareness.
Or early onset
motion sickness.
I got him one of these.
A bouncy chair.
Ah!
Not quite sure where
we're going to put it.
Yeah.
About that,
uh, it's kind of
cramped in here,
don't you think?
It's cozy.
You know,
I've been thinking...
Might be nice if
we moved in together.
You think
we're ready for that?
I'm just tired of
living in hotel rooms
and airport lounges.
We could be a family.
Me, you and him.
What do you say?
What if it's not yours?
What?
What if the baby
turns out to be Mark's?
Well, I mean,
it would certainly
change things.
Is that what you want?
For it to be Mark's?
Oh. Uh...
Are you in love with him?
I have been.
In the past.
And me?
I could be one day.
Bridget, I haven't been
entirely honest with you.
Mark thinks
the baby isn't his,
and I let him
believe it was mine.
That's why he disappeared.
Why would he think that?
Because I let him.
Because I wanted
you for myself.
Oh.
We could be so good
for each other.
97%.
On paper.
But falling in love
doesn't happen on paper.
Sometimes you love a person
because of all the reasons
they're not like you.
And sometimes
you love a person
just because
they feel like home.
I've got to find Mark.
Hello, Pierce.
It's Bridget.
I'm trying to
get hold of Mark.
He just got back
from a trip, Bridget.
He's in a taxi
on his way home.
Hi.
Approximately
eight weeks to go.
Mmm.
You don't really
need them, you know.
All they're good for
is fitting car seats
and blaming things on.
They really just get
in the way after that.
You're absolutely capable
of doing this on your own.
I did.
You know what?
I can do this on my own.
We can do this on our own.
One of the perks
of being pregnant
is no longer feel like
a tragic, lonely spinster
because of miniature
miracle growing inside.
Hello.
Hello!
Mum's throwing
a Christmas
party/political rally.
It's like the G8
summit with Scotch eggs.
Oh.
Be brave. Go in.
Hello, darling!
Hello.
Sorry, I didn't
realize everyone was here.
I'll just pop upstairs.
No, nonsense. Nonsense.
Una's had all
the posters re-printed.
- Oh.
- You've inspired me.
It's still so long.
You were quite right,
as it turns out.
This place is teeming
with single mothers,
single fathers,
bisexuals, surrogates,
and they're all lovely.
And so normal.
Do you know, I've even got
two homosexuals on the team?
No, thank you.
Who knew?
Everybody.
I'm so proud of you,
darling, you know that?
What you're doing is not easy.
But if anyone can
make it work, it's you.
That child is
the luckiest boy on earth
to have you as his mum.
And he's going
to have the love
of a million fathers
with you by his side.
Oh...
Come on.
We've got some
campaigning to do.
Make way, make way.
Single pregnant
mother coming through.
Laura, Josh.
We need to give six minutes
to General Lu Tong, okay?
It's a huge scoop.
Yeah. Alice wants to
pull the interview.
What?
She's got a feature on
"ls the world really
ending on Tuesday?"
Well, it may as well
if we lose Lu Tong.
Lu Tong stays.
Six minutes.
Let's do this.
General Lu Tong. Hi!
Sorry it's so
chaotic in here today.
Thank you for coming on.
We're on live in two minutes.
Miranda will
probably want to start
with what's going
on in Naypyidaw.
Miranda,
get back on General Lu Tong.
Keep pressing.
So, let me ask you
one more time,
General Lu Tong,
will you take responsibility
for the human rights abuses
perpetrated by
your own government?
He's on the rack.
Tight on four.
Get those beads of sweat.
In you go,
four, push in.
I'm sorry.
I can't answer that.
Can't or won't, Lu Tong?
Can't or won't,
General Lu Tong?
On balance
I'd suggest "can't"
considering I've just found
General Lu Tong in the lobby
and his chauffeur is
currently live on-air
answering questions about
Far Eastern geopolitics.
No?
Any comment you want to make
about the use
of sexual torture
by your own military?
Ask him about London traffic.
London traffic,
General Lu Tong?
Anything to say about that?
No comment there.
Unbelievable.
That's it from
General Lu Tong.
We'll see you
after this short break.
Good job!
Unfortunately,
you leave me no choice.
It's actually
illegal to fire somebody
for being pregnant.
I'm not firing her
I'm firing her for
gross incompetency.
Bridget is
the beating heart
of this show.
How could you
want to fire her?
How about for
interviewing a chauffeur
instead of a general?
Using a TV interview
to determine if a guest might
be the father of her child
and being responsible
for the broadcast
of six bare arses?
It's okay.
It's really okay, Richard.
I was going to quit anyway.
Probably.
Believe it or not,
I was a little like you
when I started here.
A little chunkier,
much less make-up.
But I wanted to
make my mark, too.
But I don't want to be
part of your rebranding.
I haven't got
the right haircut anyway,
and I don't drink
cocktails out of jam jars
or post photos of
my lunch on Instagram.
And I suppose
it's become unfashionable
to care about wanting
to make something worthwhile.
But I would
rather be old-fashioned
and unemployed
than part of a show
that celebrates the inane.
Then maybe when my boy
is old enough to understand,
integrity will be
fashionable again.
What have I done?
Oh.
It's all very well
fighting for your principles
when there's no food
in the fridge.
I mean,
how difficult can it
be to find another job
when you've just been fired
and you're nine months
pregnant?
And whatever happens now,
I'm going to get you
one of those bloody Bugaboos.
Birthday?
Oh, God.
Brain's gone to mush.
First shag?
No!
Ooh!
Bugged
I'm really sorry.
I've gone all crap
all of a sudden.
Right.
No, no, no.
Oh, fuck.
Bugger, bugger, bugger.
Okay.
New pre-birth resolutions.
I, Bridget Jones,
am going to be the best mother
in the world.
I'm going to try not
to leave you in a shop
or put you in
the washing machine
like that woman in
the newspaper with her cat.
Look,
I know I made you a promise
I would get things sorted
before you got here.
Well, the truth is, I haven't.
But you and me
can do this together
because knights
in shining armor
don't exist anymore.
Or do they?
Hi.
Bridget.
Good God,
what are you doing there?
You're all wet.
Yes.
I locked myself out.
I left my bag,
lost my keys, phone,
my mind.
What are you doing here?
Well, it seems
I can always find time
to save the world.
But you're my world.
I thought you were
back with Candida.
You know perfectly
well her name is Camilla.
Camilla.
I came round your
house to find you
and she was there.
She came to collect her bags.
Gone back to The Hague.
I've just taken
her to the airport.
Thank you.
Bridget,
you know I find
emotional declarations
difficult.
But the truth is...
Why are my trousers warm?
My waters must have broken!
Oh, Jesus.
So sorry. I'll get a cloth.
But you're not due for another
two or three weeks at least.
Oh. That's a contraction.
I think we should get
to the hospital quickly.
Absolutely.
Let's take your car.
I came in a taxi.
Oh, for fuck's sake.
Well, how was I
supposed to know?
No, not you. The contractions!
No, we'll take your car.
We can't!
The car keys are in my bag
with everything else.
Oh!
Five, six, seven, eight.
You just pant and
breathe and count.
Nine.
That's what you're
supposed to do, isn't it?
Ten...
You should get that.
It might be work.
No! Don't!
Oi!
What the fuck?
That's really sweet.
But we've got to call a cab.
Oh, shit.
Right. What do we do?
I'll think of something.
- Look out!
- Move, move, move!
We goin' ospedale.
We gonna make the baby.
God!
This is really happening!
I'm going to be a mother!
Maybe I'm too
old for all this.
Wait!
Why are you stopping?
A margherita with
onion and pineapple,
number 17. I thank you.
Who has onion and pineapple,
huh? Some people,
they are crazy, no?
Oh.
Okay!
Yeah.
Okay.
Don't you worry, Miss Bridget.
We get you there, huh?
There is no traffic:
this time of night.
It's okay, yeah?
Poonani! Poonani!
Power to the Poonani!
I cannot believe,
it's a bloody
women's rights march!
Oh, jeez, not now!
Christ!
It's those women I defended.
It's those infernal Russians.
Just hold my hand.
We really need
to get there.
We need to get there.
All right!
We're getting out!
Uh, no,
I don't think that's wise.
Ready?
No, Bridget. Bridget!
Call Jack.
I come behind with the bags,
Mr. Mark.
And I call Mr. Jack.
It's all right, Bridget.
We'll find a way.
I don't think I can walk.
All right. I'll carry you.
Good God, Bridget.
You're immense!
I can't help it!
I think my lung's collapsed.
But this is not about me.
My contraction's
starting again!
I'm going to have
the baby in the street.
I'll tell you what.
We'll rest for 10,
and we'll walk for 10.
All right?
Okay.
It's not much further?
No.
No?
I think it's about...
I don't think...
...a mile and a half to go.
Are you okay?
It's probably best if
I don't talk too much.
Yes.
Okay. I'm here. Okay.
I can take it from here.
I'm here. Okay.
I got this!
Thank you!
I got this.
Okay.
Jesus!
I'm here.
This is a two-man job.
Okay.
- Take her. Take her!
- I got her. Got her.
Jesus! Don't drop her!
Just go in.
Okay.
Do you want to go this way?
Yes. Go there!
No, I'll go this way.
Okay. Go. Go.
All right. Squeeze in.
Are we gonna get in?
All right.
Squeeze in.
I'm squeezing.
And, push!
No, no, it's fine.
We're out.
Okay.
Nurse!
Carol, Carol,
wheelchair, wheelchair.
One, two, three...
Yes.
Over here, please. Thank you.
You Okay?
Which of you is the father?
I am.
Right.
Oh!
Breathe out the pain.
Oh, good!
I was wondering how
many fathers we'd get.
Full house! Bingo!
Bridget,
how do you want to do this?
Epidural?
No, you can do this.
A positive mental attitude
is stronger than any drug.
Just think away the pain.
Bollocks to that.
No. I want everything.
Gas, air,
injections, morphine.
Bridget, remember your yoga.
Fuck yoga!
Oh, I couldn't
agree with you more.
It's supposed to relax one,
but I just spend
the entire time
clenching my sphincter
in an effort not to fart.
Now, can we turn you over?
I just need to
check your cervix.
Mmm. Mmm.
You're doing very well.
That's it. Turning around
to me. Gently.
Just a little rummage.
Right. Ready? Rummaging now.
Oh!
Ow! Oh!
Yes. Oh, good, good! You're at
eight centimeters already.
That's excellent!
That means you can't
have any drugs at all.
What?
Yes, you're too far gone.
Well done!
Oh, another contraction.
I'm not sure how
much there is to gain
from you two
being at the coalface,
if I'm honest.
My ex-husband said it was
like watching his
favorite pub burn down.
So, your choice.
Maybe Dad should go
and fetch Mum a cool flannel.
I know, I know.
Okay. It's okay. It's okay.
You can do this.
Okay,
just think away the pain.
Oh!
Motherfucker.
Just think away the pain.
Get out, both of you!
Where are you going?
I've changed my mind.
You can do this.
You can.
We can do it together.
Just think what life's
thrown at you already.
You've turned
disasters into triumphs
with your sheer,
joyful, indefatigable,
infectious lust for life.
You've managed
this entire pregnancy
almost entirely on your own,
despite a lunatic mother,
repressed men,
and cheating boyfriends
who don't deserve you.
Just the last few moments.
Just the last few moments,
my love,
and then you'll see
your beautiful baby.
What if it's not yours?
Then I'll love him anyway.
Just as I love you.
Just the way you were,
the way you are,
the way you always will be.
Ow!
I think you'd better go
and have that seen to.
Thank you.
I'll handle it
from here.
"Think the pain away."
You're pushing
an entire human being
out of your vagina.
I'd like to see them
thinking it away.
And with 367 of the votes,
the winner is,
Pamela Margaret Jones.
Pamela! Darling,
it's Bridget.
Not now, Colin.
It's about the baby!
I hereby declare that
Pamela Margaret Jones is...
I'm so sorry.
You'll have to excuse me.
We are about to
become a grandmother!
Well, that's it
for this special
late-night edition
of Hard News.
Grams going
at 25 seconds to off-air, 25.
Bridget's in labor.
Bridget's in labor!
Except to say,
Bridget Jones is in labor!
Yeah! Brilliant!
Run the credits!
Run it!
Run the credits! Run it!
I hope
I'm bloody godmother.
Cue the fucking weather!
Listen...
I owe you
an apology.
I know I haven't behaved
very well in all this.
No, it's okay.
Hello.
Aw!
Say hello to
our beautiful boy.
Go ahead.
Thank you.
Hi.
That's who you are.
Isn't he perfect?
Yes.
Oh, hello.
I'm so sorry
I'm late, Bridge.
Some lesbians are having
a stupid all-night march.
Actually, they're marching
in aid of free speech.
It's rather important.
Oh, my God.
Look at him.
Bridget.
Bridge.
I'm so sorry we weren't here.
This unbelievably
annoying march...
Actually, the march
is critical to...
Can I be godfather?
Oh, I'm depending on you.
Oh, congratulations.
Yeah, well done.
Well done. Congratulations.
- Thank you very much.
- Well done.
To both of you.
To all of you.
My daughter!
Where is she?
I'm so sorry we didn't
get here on time!
Daddy's parking the car.
There's some march
for women's rights.
I mean, honestly, do we
need any more rights?
Mum, meet your new grandson.
Aw, the darling.
He looks just...
Not that it matters,
but do we know
who the daddy is yet?
Shall we find out?
Come on, you two.
Time for a little test.
So exciting, isn't it?
It's like the final of
The X Factor or something.
Dial 0-1 if you
want it to be Mark
and 0-2 if you
want it to be Jack!
Oh, good luck.
You, too.
Please.
Thank you.
You look beautiful.
Hello, darling! Hello.
Hello.
Hi.
We're really doing this.
No going back now.
We are gathered here
to celebrate the union
of Bridget Rose Jones
and Mark Fitzwilliam Darcy.
And by the powers
vested in me,
I now pronounce you, finally,
husband and wife.
Jack, what on earth
are you doing with my son?
Well, don't leave me
alone with him again.
I have no idea
what I'm doing.
Is he traumatized?
Oh!
Hello, William Jones-Darcy.
Are you ready?
Some champagne for you?
Yes, please.
Dear Diary,
and so, I, Bridget Jones,
am a singleton no more.
Married? Yes.
Smug?
Well, it's about time,
so maybe just a little.