Previously onDynasty...Life is too short
to wait for what you want.
Marry me.
FALLON:
I can't do this anymore.
I love Culhane.
I'm sorry, Liam, but it's over.
ANDERS:
I'd like you
to come and live here.Really?
I'd like that.
That recording of Jeff
running an illegal card game
in his innocent sister's club
is my insurance you'll behave.
Leave Monica out of this.
I'm not the one who put
her club in my sights.
For you, Sam.
This card means new life.
[baby crying]HANK: You'll never
have to see me again.
I'm taking the money,
and I'm hitting the road
like a lonesome wolf.
It's been a pleasure.
[baby crying]
[knocking at door]
ALEXIS:
Hold on, I'm coming!
Randy, uh, did something happen
at the loft?
We were supposed to meet
at 9:00?
To go over the final punch list.
Oh, what time is it now?It's 11:30.
Look, I can come in now if...[baby fusses]
Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't realize you had a...
A guest. Yes,
it's been a very long night.
Uh, just give me 30 minutes,
and I'll freshen up.
[baby crying]
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no, none of that.
You've got to be
very, very quiet.
Yeah, that's it. Shh, shh, shh.
HANK: You've reached Hank.
I mean, you haven't,
because I can't come
to the phone,
but you've reached
my voice mail and...[beeps]
Where are you, Hank?
I don't know who the hell
this Claudia is
or why I have her baby,
but you need to come
and get it right now![baby crying]
Shh, shh. No, no, no, no, no,
no, no. I'm trying, okay?
I need you to work with me.
Shh.
Look, I don't want to get
the authorities involved, Hank.
But if they trace this baby
to you,
they trace you to me,
and we both end up in handcuffs.
I can't take care
of this infant.
Oh, is this how people
without night nurses live?
Oh, God. [sighs]
You still want to get married?
And do that every morning?
I'm in.
Let's get a ring
on that finger.
I want the whole world
to know you're mine.[chuckles]
Maybe we should start
with the whole family?
[sighs]
[chuckles]
FALLON:
What are we waiting for?
Doesn't Dad know
we all have things to do?
Yeah, I have a massage in 30.
The first
of the Christmas decorations
will be here in a few minutes.
It's a little early, isn't it?
Thanksgiving's over.
What's this even about?
Maybe a Welcome Wagon
for your new neighbor?
[door opens]Me.
Oh, finally. Oh.
What's going on here?
Those bags under your eyes
are impressive, Alexis.
Not getting enough rest out
in that tin can of yours?
Kirby, that's enough.
[sighs]Definitely a welcome addition.
I really can't stay.
I have things to do.
Good, you're all here. I
hope you all got champagne.
We have news to celebrate.
Last night I asked
Cristal to marry me.
And she said yes.
What? You're engaged?
Is she pregnant?
SAM:
Oh, my God.
What if that's the
baby the psychic meant
and I just wanted to
believe it was for me?
I'm not pregnant.Thank God for that.
This is not some shotgun
wedding, although...
I wouldn't mind a few little
feet running around here.
Oh...
Then what's the rush?
I mean, the last one's
barely cold.
Seriously, Fallon.BLAKE:
There's no rush.
I promise, your
wedding will be first.
That's not what I meant.
If there's anything the
last year taught me,
it's that life is precious.
And short.
And I'm not gonna waste
any of it.
It's time for a new chapter
around here.
KIRBY:
Guess that means
yours is officially closing.
Too bad.
It's been a real page-turner.
[sighs]ANDERS:
Not even a comment
about the latest
Mrs. Carrington?
You must be in a hurry.Clearly, I'm not the only one.
But I have more
pressing concerns right now.
Blake's whims tend
to work themselves out.
Until he reproduces with them.
[donkey brays]
Already?
Well, how tacky.
Van Kirk Industries, huh?
Oh, I was just catching up
on some news.
You hang onto some shares
in the C.A. sale,
or just keeping tabs on Liam?
Well, just because I sold
the company
doesn't mean I forgot about it.
And it's still a part
of my family's legacy.
Someone has to care,
and it's clearly not my dad.
Well, maybe he has
the right idea.
Seriously? I mean,
he's known this Cristal
even shorter than the last one.
There's something to be said
for seizing the moment.
[sighs]You know what,
and he still said
that we could go first.
Okay, well, I'm not having
my wedding date dictated
by my dad's whims.
Been there, done that.
So what do you want to do?
Not get married?
No, no.
I just want to do it
on my own terms. Ourterms.
But right now I have to go.
I'm having lunch with Monica.
Bye.[phone buzzing]
Bye.
JEFF:
There you are.
My guys want to know if we're on
for the game Tuesday.
Yeah, we're good.
All right.
You are an angel
for helping me.
I just can't decide
on this accent wall,
and you have got
such a great eye.
Mm-hmm. Just as long
as I don't have to paint it.
Olga just worked the knots
out of my shoulder.[baby cooing]
What's that?
Is that a baby?
Sound effects? A little extra.
Oh, my God.
It's real.
You must be joking.Hey, buddy.
Where'd you come from?
You're okay. Shh, shh, shh.
You're good, buddy. Hey.
Oh, look, there's a note.
"I deserve more
"than my mother can give.
Please take good care of me."
Oh, my God.FALLON:
What the hell is that?
What's what?ALEXIS:
Sam found
a baby in the manger.Whose baby?
What baby?
Oh, sweet Mary and Joseph.
♪ Hallelujah.
♪
Who would leave a baby
in the driveway?I'll canvass the staff,
see if anyone's misplaced
their offspring.
Maybe we should call the police.
I just got off the phone
with Child Services.
What? You read the note.
Well, we don't know who
wrote the note, Sam.
What if somebody took him?
Like they did Adam.
Well, they had no
missing children reported,
so they said
they'd send somebody
as soon as they
can, but you know
how underfunded these agencies
are. It could take days.
Days? What are we supposed to do
with it until then? Keep it?
He's better off here
than in some orphanage.
They have foster homes.
No one's gonna take better care
of him than we are.
I think God
put him here for me to find.
You'd think God
would know better.SAM: I'm serious.
I've been praying for a baby,
and he needs a family.
It's like a textbook miracle.
Let's not get carried away.
Well, he's probably
better off here
than in a foster home.
And he does even look
a little bit like you, Blake.
Are you just a little Blake?
Huh?
BLAKE:
Let me see him.
[baby fusses]
Yeah. Hey.
Oh!
And that's my cue to leave.
It'll come out in the wash.
Yeah, not my first rodeo.
Those were good days,
weren't they?
When the kids were babies.
Yeah, before they could talk.
You know, maybe Sam's right.
This is a sign,
this baby, for us, too.
I mean, as the psychic said,
you and I share a destiny.
Nobody wants Steven and Sam
to have a family more than I do,
and if this is their baby,
no one would be happier.
I knew you felt it.
Somewhere in there...
But us becoming grandparents
to that kid or any other
doesn't mean we'd be
doing it together.
Because if there is such a thing
as destiny,
mine is with Cristal.
Move on, Alexis.
♪ And every time
♪ I close my eyes
it's you and me ♪
♪ I feel your energy
♪ In all these lucid dreams
♪ I really wanted you to stay
♪ Ever since you went away.
You don't even need
the sound system,
but I'll have my best mixer
here on Tuesday night.
Can I come, too?
I might be able
to pull a few strings,
get you on the list.
Isis, Alexe, this is
Fallon Carrington. This is...
St. Beauty. I'm a fan.Isis is a friend
from way back.You're lucky
you can still book us.
I first saw them at a showcase.
Then they get signed
by Wondaland,
suddenly they are
too cool for me.
Hey. Monica, you should
do a showcase here.
With your club. I mean, you've
always had an eye for talent,
and there's plenty in Atlanta
waiting to be signed.
Except I don't have
a record label.
Why not?Okay, I'm still
figuring out this business.
Speaking of which,
I'll see you guys Tuesday?
We'll be here.
Good to meet you, Fallon.
You, too.
I can help you. I know
how to start a company--
ask your brother--
and I know how to run one, too.
Don't ask your brother.
Are you really suggesting
that we start a record label?
Together?
We can use this as a launchpad.
We bring the artists
directly to the audience.
Can be independent, female-run.
You know I love you,
but I don't think
working together
is the best idea for us.
Did you already forget
the drama we had
over this place?
Oh, that was different.
You just finished
selling a company.
Why don't you take a minute
to just... do you?
But this is me. I work.
And I need something
to focus on.
Wow, you really don't want
to plan a wedding, do you?
But I'm not trying to be
someone's project, Fallon.
I'm sure you'll find
another one.
Can you wait
ten more minutes to eat?
I need to go check inventory.
What a lovely coat.
Is that a polyblend?
It's cashmere, actually.
But thank you.
Pretty flowers. Weren't those
in the dining room this morning?
Just borrowing a few odds
and ends for my place
until I have time
to go shopping.
Is the loft finished already?
Things move fast
around here.
You don't have to tell me.
And now we have
a baby here, too.
I just can't wait to put down
new roots. Literally.
We've been through a lot
as a family, but...
that's what family is:
people with...
a shared history.
And Blake and I have a long one.
I'm just looking forward
to a long future here.
Make sure you don't
overwater that dracaena.
Roots can rot, you know?
[laughs]
How sweet of you.
You know, if I were you,
I'd get out now,
while that pure little heart
is still in one piece.
This may seem like
a big house,
but... there's
only so much room.
I know this is moving fast...
but I love Blake,
and I think he loves me, too.
Since we're about to
go to look at rings.
[chuckles]: Oh.
I'm surprised that jeweler
hasn't given him
a punch card by now.
Don't say I didn't warn you.
I got it. Don't worry.
[door closes]
ANDERS:
So, seam on the outside,
and fold on the inside.
Thank you.
[groans] Has that dog
ever been on a leash?
We'll have to work on that.As wonderful as it is
that you want to take Bo
under your wing,
and as glad as I am to
have you staying here,
um, has it ever occurred to you
to perhaps get a job?
I mean, outside of the home?
That's very feminist
of you, Daddy.
Don't forget you still
owe a heavy sum to Steven
for that stunt you
pulled in Paraguay
using his credit card.
I'll fill out some applications.
Hey.
Is this thing on right?
Where did you even get that?
The baby shower.
At least some good
came out of it.
We have almost
everything we need.
Just like it was
meant to be.
Until Child Services arrive.
And when they come,
they'll see Little Blake
has everything here.
Obviously,
I'm gonna need some help.
At least until
Steven's back.
I can help.
At least until I get a job.You realize
that a nanny is responsible
for another human being?
Yeah, and she
could barely handle Bo.
But...
you could be, like,
my assistant.
I'd pay you, of course.
I already owe you and Steven,
so why don't we
just call it even?
Sold. First order of business:
finding an actual nanny.
ANDERS:
If you insist,
we might as well do it right.
I'll pull some résumés.
Perfect.
Ooh.
[sniffs] Kirby,
can you run point?
Someone needs
a new diaper.
How about...
this one?
It's beautiful.
See?
I have good taste in
the important things.
[laughs]
Yes.
Alexis mentioned.
She made sure to remind me
that you've done this before.
And that doesn't matter.
I know. I know.
But I don't think she likes me.
What did she say?That she didn't like me.
[chuckles]And how the two of you
have a long history together,
and I should get out
before my heart
gets broken.Hey, hey,
Alexis is delusional.
It was that damn
psychic, I swear.
Apparently, she told Alexis that
we were meant to be together,
and Alexis ate it up.
Adriana has a strong intuition.So do I.
I don't need a psychic to
tell me how I feel about you.
And I sure as hell
don't need Alexis.
And I'm relieved to hear that.
Do you have any more?MAN:
Of course, sir.
What is that?
Well, obviously,
nothing is set in stone;
this is just to give you
an idea of what I'm thinking.
Did you seriously just make
that in the last 20 minutes?Mm-hmm.
I should have known.
Once you have something
in your head...
What I have is the technical
experience and strategic vision
to make this company viable.
You have the real estate.
You have the creative judgment.
We both have the capital.
We could be
equal partners, 50-50.
You gonna put
that in writing?
Sure.
Okay, is something wrong?
Is this about
Culhane, or...?
No. No, no, no.
This is not
about my wedding.
This is about me.
I told you I work.
What I'm thinking is we build
on what you already have.
People come to see St. Beauty,
and they get to see some of
the greatest up-and-coming
talent in Atlanta.
A showcase.
Now that you mention it,
there's a utility room upstairs
that could be a greenroom.
Does that mean you're in?
Let's just start with Tuesday
and see how it goes.
I'll have Jeff get his
poker tables out of there.
Poker?
I let him have a game up there
the other week while you were
busy getting divorced from Liam.
Well, maybe he'll invite me
to the next one.
ALEXIS:
Please be gentle with those.
There are antiques in there that
are worth more than your car.
Yes, Ms. Carrington.Actually, put them
right over there in the corner;
I'll empty it myself.
I'm also gonna need to borrow a
few things from the main house:
the good silver trays,
Lalique decanters...
I think Mr. Anders might notice.
Well, they're
not for me, dear.
I want to have everyone over for
a little family housewarming.
Blake needs to know
that I'm here to stay
before he puts a diamond
on another Cristal.
This is my new chapter, too.
My flowers-- what...
what happened here?
Even the cactus is dead.
It's like a plant Holocaust.
What evil spirits
did you piss off?
I mean, someone
did die in here.
♪
Oh, did Monica make you
a promoter?
Actually, it
was my idea.
Welcome to Broken Glass
Recording Artists,
bringing the next generation
of women into the spotlight.
Oh, you are just full
of secrets.
Didn't know
you were trying
to break into
the music business.
Mm. I wasn't. Sometimes
you just see an opportunity
and you have to take a leap.
And if I know you, you'll be
the female Clive Davis by 30.
And it all starts Tuesday night,
when we bring the most
promising artists
in Atlanta to Club Colby.
MONICA:
So, you're gonna have to have
those tables out of there
by Tuesday morning.
[sighs]
But we're playing that night.
Doesn't St. Beauty
already have a record deal?
Until I make them a better one.
Let me be clear.
Your game's over.
And you and your friends
should be coming
to the showcase
to support your sister.
Are you sure
this is even a good idea?
Going into business
with another Colby?
You were the one
who warned me against it,
and look what happened.
There were some...
extenuating circumstances.
Like the fact
that you slept with her
and that she was
our secret cousin?
FALLON:
I'm just saying,
this time is different.
MONICA:
I'm going into this eyes open.
And the showcase will be
a good test.
And unless you have a problem...Is there a problem?
No.
Nope.
Good.
[knocking at door]
I'll get it.
You carry on.
Cristal.
What are you doing here?
I've been thinking
about what you said earlier,
and you're right;
you and Blake have
so much history.
And with a grandchild,
especially,
you're not going anywhere.
Well, I'm glad
you understand.
So I really want us
to get off on the right foot.[chuckles]
You really think
I'm that gullible?
I'm just trying
to be friendly.
We're not friends,
and you know it.
You don't like me, and I don't
buy your act of kindness...
unless you're
trying to kill me.
Are they laced?
Oh. I hope not, because
I had one on the way over.
You're right,
we're not friends.
The truth is...
you're kind of scary.Hmm.
Oh, my God, is that
the fern from the house?
None of them are looking
too good, are they?
They're all dead.
It's spooky.
It is strange.
And it seems fine
everywhere else.
I mean...I'm sure that there's
a logical explanation.
The place is not haunted.
You're a sensitive person,
Alexis;
I'm sure
you can feel it, too.
I mean, after what happened
to Celia, I can only imagine
the bad energy that must
be swirling around here.
How could anything live?
Andneither of us wants
Celia's spirit unsettled.
I have some sage
in the house.
Let me go get it.
We can clear this
place together.
Mm, I suppose there's
no harm in a little sage.
Here are the top 25 candidates,
all eminently qualified,
carefully vetted,
and handpicked by me.
[scoffs]:
Prudence?
What is this, 1700?
Well, she didn't name herself.
She kind of looks like someone
who wouldname herself Prudence.
Pass.
You haven't even considered
her experience, her skills.
Oh, you're right.
I can't make this decision
off a piece of paper--
I need to see them in action.
Well, why don't I arrange
to have them come in person?
Then you can vet them.
And they can vet you.
[Little Blake fussing]
CULHANE:
You really think
this record label's
a permanent thing?
You know these girls,
when they get their hearts
andtheir wallets
set on something.
[exhales]
We'll just have to tell Ada
something came up.
Youwant to tell her that?
Then I should tell Monica.
I'm not cool
keeping this from her.
What if Ada finds out they know?
I don't want
to drag them into this.
It's a little late
for that.
Fallon's the one
she has dirt on.
And it's Monica's club.What are they gonna do?
I know you want to be the hero,
but shouldn't you get
the secrets out of the way now?
I can handle
my own relationship.
Have you done this before?
Um, can't say that I have.
Energy is... a little
bit like perfume.
Once it's there,
it tends to linger
until you wash it away.
Sage is...
kind of a spiritual shower.
Oh.
Before we
burn anything,
we'll open the window
to make sure the energy
we're trying to get rid of
has someplace to go.
Now...
we light the sage.
Just be careful.
[exhales]:
Mmm...
[coughing]Any energy
not of the highest
or greatest good,
we respectfully ask that
you leave this place.
Amen.
You can use a feather
to fan the smoke.
Like this.
Yeah. Go.
♪
Smells like a
hippie's armpit.
But if it works...
[fire alarm beeping]
Oh, no.
[screaming]
[both screaming]
What have you done?!I didn't mean to.
I'm sorry!
Do you have any towels?
Not the painting! Oh!
You've done enough damage
already! Get out!
I'm sorry.
[door opens]ALEXIS:
Ooh!
Did that little chupacabra of
a fiancée tell you what she did?
If you mean Cristal,
she told me
that while she was trying to
help you, she accidentally...
That was no accident!
She wasn't trying to help.
She was trying to ruin my loft
so I couldn't move in.
And I wouldn't be surprised
if she was the one
that killed all of my plants
in the first place.
Do you hear yourself right now?
I'm sure it was
an honest mistake.
There is nothing
honest about her.
She is not the angel
that you think she is, Blake.
Not everyone is like you,
Alexis... thank God.
I will show you
exactly who she is!
[whistles blowing]
All right, scalawags,
stand tall and listen up.
This isn't just any baby.
This is a Carrington
baby, and as such,
you're about to go through
a rigorous vetting process
designed by the best--
us.
I need to know
what you're capable of
and how far you're willing
to go for my baby.
And me. Let's make it
an even 40/60.
♪ Ah, push it...
Any questions?
Wrong! No questions.
That's a demerit.
Anyone else?
Okay, then.
Time to show us
what you've got.
[whistle blows]
Faster!
The Carrington jet is about
to take off, and we
can't have Little Blake
at 40,000 feet
with a full diaper.
Think of the smell!
Make the shot!
We're boarding![people grunting]
You hit the rim! Demerit!
I need multitaskers!
I need champions!
[grunts][baby doll squeaks]
Disqualified!
[whirring]
Plum and...
a hint of truffle?
What the hell's
all the noise?
Oh, just What to Expect When You're Expecting
meets
American Ninja Warrior.
I need someone
with energy.
Someone with style.
Someone who will impress Bey
when we do play dates
with Rumi and Sir.
This is no way to
hire a professional.
With all due respect, Anders,
your ways are
a little bit old-fashioned.
Well, my old-fashioned ways
served Steven and Fallon
just fine.
Steven and Fallon are two of the
most messed-up people I know.
And I say that with love.
Well, at least
get them some water.
I think
we're killing it.
Totally.
[door closes]Who knew we'd make
such a great team?
Should we get
matching T-shirts?
Or tattoos.
Oh, my God,
that would be hard-core.
We'rehard-core.
Maybe we don't
even need a nanny.
We got this, don't we?
Mm.
I'm gonna put
this girl Kira Watson last,
right before St. Beauty.
Look, I love Kira and her voice,
but I mean, why a Whitney cover?
Why set her up to fail?
I've heard her.
She's got it.
And I've got this.
I'm the creative judgment,
remember?
You put it on the napkin.JEFF:
Hey.
Be careful with that.
Just watch the wall.Oh.
Jeff? Jeff?
You're an objective
third party.
Where do you stand
on Whitney covers?
Is this a trap?
No, no. We're just trying
to settle an argument.
No argument.
It's my jurisdiction,
and she's doing the song.
You just know that he's
gonna agree with me.
I know it can be hard to
admit when you're wrong.
You would know better
than anyone.
[scoffs]
How long have you been
working together?
Huh? 24 hours?
Trouble in paradise already?
You know, it's not too
late to call this thing off.
You can still save face.
You're right.
Not you. You.
I told you you were
in charge of talent.
You get to choose
what they play.
I'm sorry.
Whitney is
risky, though.
Thank you, Jeff.
We're good.
[phone clicking]
Fallon?
So what is this really about?
I just need to keep my head in
something other than my head.
I love Culhane, so much so
that I told Liam I couldn't
talk to him anymore.
I just wish that meant I didn't
think about him, either.
Does Culhane know about this?
Of course not, and
he doesn't need to.
I'm moving forward.
And I hope we can, too.
JENNINGS:
If this is about
the damage, I'll pay for it.
I don't care about
the sprinklers right now.
There is something else
happening in there.
It's bad energy.
[whooshing, creaking,
both gasping]
Ooh.
It must be 100
degrees in here.
And I have the thermostat
turned all the way down.
It doesn't matter.
And then there's that.
It won't stop!
Look, I don't know
what you did last night,
but that dark spirit
that killed my plants is...
[soft rumbling, clanking]...angry.
Maybe the sage didn't have
a chance to work.
Look, I need more
than burnt leaves!
If I have to raze this place
down to the ground,
I will.Maybe that's the only way.
[loud clanking]
[Jennings yelps,
rapid clanking]
Mm.
Is that for us?
I'm starving.
It's for the applicants.
I noticed
that you two didn't seem
to be particularly
exerting yourselves.
It was exhausting to watch.
Those nannies
did everything wrong.
Total carnage.
Well, now that
I know your... criteria,
perhaps I could pull
some more suitable candidates.
Thanks, but I think
we're good.
If Kirby and I can
manage to organize
all of this
by ourselves,
then I think
we can definitely
handle a baby.
Yeah.
It's been 24 hours.
I don't need that negativity
around him, Anders.
Only love.
Well, since you seem to have
this whole thing in hand,
if you'll excuse me,
I'll go and find somebody else
to burden with my negativity.
Jonathan.
Come on, man.
[horn toots]
[distant siren blaring,
train whistle blowing]
Your money for
this week's game.
It's all in there.That's impressive
since this week's game
hasn't happened yet.
We got double booked,
an event at the club.
But we'll have everything
back on track by next week.
We're-we're gonna find
another venue.Are we?
You think this is
just about cash?
I think you'd be upset
if you didn't get yours.
You're right about that.
Who's the problem here?
It's not you.
Is it your friend,
Mr. Colby, or his sister?
Whoever it is, I may have
to send a little message.Whoa!
I told you, this was
just a temporary hiccup.
I gave you one job,
so do it.
Get the game back on track
for next week, or I will,
by whatever means necessary.
♪ Take me to the water
♪ To be baptized.
[applause and cheering]
Thank you.
[whooping]
She's got a voice.
Mm-hmm.
It's a pretty good crowd, too.
St. Beauty's
on in five.
Let me get my drinks now, then.
Where have you been?
I texted you.
Yeah. Fallon asked me
to help out
with some last-minute errands
for tonight,
so I got busy.You make that delivery yet?
Yup. It's done.
We're cool.Really?
Yeah. I told Ada that we'd get
things sorted out for next week.
We'll get them sorted out
for next week.
I'm gonna go get Fallon a drink.
Okay. Bar's nuts.
I'm going straight
to the source.
All right.
Hey, there you are.
Michael, this is Cindy.
She is in A&R at Capitol.
Cindy, this is
my fiancé Michael.
Michael, it's a pleasure.
All mine.
Have you seen Monica?
I think she was looking for you.
Oh. She's my business partner.
Will you excuse
me for a sec?Yes, of course.
Be right back.
What are you doing here?
I told you I
would handle it.
And what do you
want with Fallon?
Nothing, Michael.
I'm here to watch you.
And make sure
the game is still on.
[electrical buzzing,
Little Blake cooing]
This is so amazing.
I'm feeling the love, literally.
I'm feeling bee stings,
but it's worth it.
Oh, God, don't tell me
you're tattooing the baby.
Just the Carrington crest
on his ankle. It's tiny.
Come on, Anders.
Have a little faith.
He's just here
for moral support. Hi.
[Little Blake cries]
I thought you said
you needed me.
We do. Sam's almost done.
You're up next.
What?
You expect me
to get a tattoo?
You're part of the team, Daddy.
Even if
Sam and I got a little
carried away earlier.A little?
Let's not get
hung up on details.
The point is, we're family.
And if this baby's
gonna make it out of here
even a little bit normal,
he need us.[Little Blake coos]
All of us.
[Little Blake cries]
Come on, man.
It's not a good time.
We're having a moment.
Here. Let me try.
All right.
[crying continues]
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
Turn him on his left side?
And maybe rub his back a little.
It helps with digestion.
[crying stops,
Little Blake coos]
I baby-sit a lot.
[Little Blake cooing]
Hey, uh,
what was your name again?
Manuel.
Seriously?
How'd you like
to stick around, Manny?
[screams]
[gasps]
Oh, my God!
Cristal?!
Are you okay?
What is this?
JENNINGS:
It says I'm a liar.
That I disgraced
the spirits, and
I brought a curse
upon this house.
Oh, my God. I mean, who
would have done this?
I mean, this can't be real.
It is real, and
they're right.
I lied. I'm so sorry.
Lied about what?
I killed your plants!
I paid one of the staff
to spray your plants
with bleach, and
the sprinklers-- it was me.
You were right.
I did it on purpose.
What on earth...I felt
you were gunning for me.
I thought
I could beat you to it,
drive you out first.
[speaking Spanish]
Cristal.
Cristal.[exhales]
Smile for the camera.
What?You tried to play
my game in my house,
but you failed.
So now I have
this pathetic episode of...
Ghost Hunters
so that I can prove it to Blake.
Please don't.
We just got engaged.
What if he breaks it off?
I am counting on exactly that.
[sighs]
Mm.
Fruit punch and gelatin.
It's quite sticky.
[scoffs]I will have
the cleaning fees added
to your bill
when you leave.
♪ Oh
♪ And every time
♪ I close my eyes
♪ It's you and me
♪ I feel your energy in all
♪ These lucid dreams
♪ I really wanted you to stay
♪ Ever since you went away
♪ Time goes slowly
♪ You're the only
♪ You'll come
♪ And go
♪ Till tomorrow... Hey.
Culhane said you
were looking for me.
I haven't seen him.
Oh. That's weird.
Well, I was looking for you.
I have someone I
want you to meet.
She works at Capitol--MAN: Fire!
[alarm beeping]Hey!
[screaming]
[bone cracks][Monica shouts]
Monica!
Michael!
MAN:
Move, move, move!
What the hell?
Moni? Monica?
[shouting, screaming]
Fallon!
Monica?!
[groaning, grunting]
[alarm continues beeping][shouting, screaming]
I lied. I'm so sorry.Lied about what?
I killed your plants.
You should know what you're
going to bed with every night.
Told you Cristal was a liar.
[sighs]
She's right.
I'm so sorry, Blake.
ALEXIS:
I wish
I hated to say
I told you so.
BLAKE:
Would you, uh,
give us a moment, please?
I was going to give
you a ring today...
I totally understand
if you want to call off
the engagement,
but if you will
just give me the chance
to explain...
Instead, I'm gonna
give you this.
You're right.
We haven't known each
other very long at all.
But...
that just means we have
a chance to grow together.
[chuckles softly]
What is this?
There's a diamond in there.
Somewhere.
We can find it and
polish it and make a ring.
Together.
And don't worry
about Alexis.
She's the thorn that
just keeps on pricking.
It'll work itself out.
Mm.
I know it will.
[exhales]
Here.Thank you.
You scared the hell
out of me, Mon.
When I couldn't
find you in there,
when I didn't know
what had happened to you...
Hey. Except for a broken ankle
and some broken shoes,
I'm fine.
Though they were
expensive.
[chuckles]
It wasn't your
fault, Jeff.
Actually, it kind of was.
I've been lying to you, Moni.
And I was just trying
to protect you, and...
Lying about what?
[shuddering exhale]
[footsteps approaching]
Hey. You okay?
I can't believe I am.
I can't believe
Monica got out of there
with just a broken ankle.
I mean,
we're lucky nobody was killed.
Yeah, just
the showcase.
Yeah. And the label,
for now.
Monica's spooked.
Not that I can blame her.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
Me too.
But, you know,
when everything was happening,
that was the last thing
on my mind.
All I could think
about was you.
I just wanted to find you.
I wanted to have you with me.
I'm right here.
Michael, I have
to tell you something.
I kissed Liam
at the divorce party.
And he convinced me
to do this last kiss thing,
but it was me.
And it scared me,
that I might
still have feelings for him.
I know.
I heard you on the phone.
Why didn't you say anything?
You didn't.
You're right.
But I don't have feelings
for him, Michael.
I know that now.
And I am all-in on us.
I want us to get married
as soon as we can,
so I never have to be scared
of losing you again.
Fallon.
Yeah.
I don't ever want
to lose you either.
[birds chirping]
JENNINGS:
Sam.
I'm glad I caught you.
I have a favor to ask.
Yes?This might
sound odd,
but could you pop
by Alexis' trailer
and check her size for me?
Her clothes got ruined
the other night,
and I want to
replace them.
A peace offering, if you will.
Well, the best way to her heart
isprobably presents.
[chuckles]
My thoughts exactly.
I'd go myself, but I wanted it
to be a surprise.
Sure.
Gracias.
De nada.
ADA:
I'm impressed
by your ingenuity.
And I don't give out
compliments easily.
Screw you.
You once told me not to bluff
against the dominant hand.
Well, I'm folding.
Done.
You're calling me out
on my hand?
Trust me, you don't
want me to play it.
Everything that happened
last night-- that was you.
You're here,
exactly where you are,
because of a series
of decisions that you made.
You're not going anywhere.
I have a very important client I
was hoping to host at the game.
Hence my disappointment.
But...
it's not too late
for you to redeem yourself.
I'll let go of the club
and your blackmail
if you do
one last thing.
Let me guess, you want me
to deal the cards now.
Cute.
But no.
I need you to pick
something up for me.
I'll be in touch.
[knocking]
Who is it?
Oh, my God.
Don't tell me you're still here.
[chuckles]I thought
you were
just a temporary infestation.
I thought you could use
some help cleaning up.
Well, the floors are still
a bit damp, and I am
having a housewarming
this evening.
Oh.You could probably
hold a blow dryer
without burning the place down.
Just don't hold it too close,
and keep it moving.
Okay.
Mm, some towels might help.
What are you doing?
Don't open that.
Why?
Were you hiding something
in here?
Oh, that's right. You were.
I didn't mean to!
I'm sorry!
Do you have any towels?!
You've done enough
damage already!
Imagine my surprise
when I went,
the other night,
looking for towels
and found the Baby Jesus
instead.
The same one
that's been missing
from the nativity scene
since Little Blake showed up.
Obviously, you are
desperate to keep Blake.
[chuckles]But this is
a whole new level,
accusing me of...
[stammers]
I don't even know what.
Of course you'd think
this was about Blake.
You admitted it.I said what
you wanted to hear.
I knew what you thought.
That I was weak, naive.
That you could bully me out
of here.
You know, if I were you,
I'd get out now,
while that pure little heart
is still in one piece.
This may seem
like a big house, but...
JENNINGS:
"There's only so much room."
Right?
So you didn't kill my plants?
Oh, I did. To give you
a taste of your own medicine.
And I set off
those sprinklers, too.
Because if one of us had to go, it wasn't gonna be me.
[beeping]Oh, no.
Clearly, that wasn't
a permanent solution.
Water dries.
So when I saw the Baby Jesus,
I realized it was better
than anything I could come up
with to drive you out.
And when you came running in
to show me all
the flickering lights
and the banging pipes...
It must be 100 degrees in here.
...I realized you were
trying to call my bluff,
daring me to fold.
Going bigger and bigger
to scare me into a confession.
And it worked.
But if you knew,
why'd you play along?
No, because it couldn't
be too easy.
I needed you to believe
it was genuine...
I will have the cleaning fees
added to your bill
when you leave.
Really?
Google Translate?
Bitch.
...so when I finally gave it up,
you'd run right to Blake.
That was all the time I needed.
I told you Cristal
was a liar.
[sighs]
She's right.
And where is this Baby Jesus?
Did you give him to Blake?
I thought of it.
But I knew if I was
the one to discover it,
you might just say
that I framed you.
I needed someone else
to find it.
So I asked Sam
to do me a little favor.
Hello?
What the hell?
JENNINGS:
What is he going to think
when he finds
the Baby Jesus
in an old car seat
in your trailer, Alexis?You put it there.
When he realizes
that you're the one
who put the baby in that manger.
That you've been lying to him.
To the whole family.
Preying on their emotions,
just so you can get your claws
back into Blake.
Oy, that's positively
Shakespearean.
What's the phrase,
"hoisted on your own petard"?
I can explain.
Maybe you should start with
where the hell
you got that baby.
Captioning sponsored by
CBS
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org