# Is it me, for a moment...
# Love
# Reign o'er me
# Bell boy
# Can you see
the real me, can you?
# I went back to the doctor,
to get another shrink
# I sit and tell him
about my weekend... #
Darlin'! Whey!
# Whoo!
# Can you see the real me,
Doctor?
# Doctor?
# Can you see
the real me, Doctor?
# Whoa, Doctor!
# I went back to my mother
# I said I'm crazy, Ma, help me!
# She said,
I know how it feels, son
# 'Cos it runs in the family
# Can you see the real me,
Mother?
# Mother?
# Can you see the real me,
Mother?
# Whoa, please!
# Can you see,
can you see the real me?
# The real me, the real me
# Can you see the real me,
Preacher?
# Preacher...
Fuck off!
Bollocks! Fuck off!
Why don't you get off and push?
# Can you see?
Can you see? Can you see?
# Whoa!
# Can you see the real me,
Doctor?
# Can you see the real me
# Mother!
'Ere, Ferdy. Ferdy.
Say, 'ello, Jim.
How's it goin', eh?
All right.
'Ere, you got
something nice for me?
Shh!
At your service, friend.
They keep your brains warm?
How many d'you want?
Well, come 'ere.
I want about a dozen.
Fuck off, Jim.
All right, 20. But how much?
They're pretty scarce right now.
I went abroad to get these.
Got on a banana boat
back to Jamaica, did you?
No. Brixton.
And as you know, Jim,
it costs money.
All right, all right. How much?
Quid.
You're a fuckin' liberty-taker.
Oi! Ferdy!
- Hello, lovers!
- Hi, Monkey!
Go on, get in there!
She won't bite.
'Cos if you don't, I might!
- No, I'm not bothered.
- Not much.
I know, I'll ask for you.
- No, you won't.
- Oi, Steph!
Fuck off!
# Now, you know, you know
you're gonna knock 'em dead #
# I love the way you walk
# I'm crazy 'bout your walk
# You're my baby... #
Pack it up. Don't do that.
- Why not?
- Just go to sleep.
I always do. I'm fed up with it.
Here, Yvonne.
You got any scissors?
Under the table.
Oh, what you done?
Dunno what I done.
I can't see, can I?
It's only some nail varnish.
I'll clean it up tomorrow.
You're so bleedin' clumsy.
'Ere, you wanna watch it,
you know.
One day you'll come from under
there with first degree burns.
It happened to my mate's sister.
Oh, piss off.
# Why should I care
# If I have to cut my hair?
# I got to move with the fashion
# Or be outcast
# I know I should fight
# But my old man
is nearly all right
# And I'm still living in hope
# Even though it won't last
# Zoot suit!
# White jacket with side-vents
# Five inches long
# I'm out on the street again
# And I'm leaping along
# Dressed right,
for a beach fight
# But I just can't explain
# Why that uncertain feelin'
# Is still here in my brain #
# Well, be-bop-a-lula
# She's my baby
# Be-bop-a-lula,
I don't mean maybe...
Oi! Will you leave
that out, please?
Do what?
Er, don't sing all that
old rubbish, eh?
That ain't rubbish, pal!
That's Gene Vincent, all right?
That's what I said. Old rubbish.
Why don't you just turn over and
do a few underwater farts, eh?
Why don't you just fuck off?
You fuck off.
# Well, be-bop-a-lula
# She's my baby...
# Da-da da-doo! Do-do do-doo!
- # Yeah, you really got me
- # Be-bop a-lula...
# ..Don't know what I'm doin',
really got me...
- # Yeah! You really got me
- # Be-bop-a-lula!
- # You got me so...
- # Don't mean maybe...
What are you? Couple o' fairies?
All right, all right.
Cut it out!
What d'you think this is? The
bloody Eurovision Song Contest?
Ahh!
Right, I'll sort you out.
Look! If you wanna start,
I'll see you outside...
- Fuck me.
- Kevin Herriot?
Jimmy.
Yeah, yeah.
I thought you was in the army?
No, I got out. You?
I'm all right, yeah.
The army didn't teach
you singing, did it?
Nah. Give me my brush back?
'Ere, pile the liquor on, mate.
Two'n'eight.
Cheers.
Hello, Jim.
What's the matter
with you, then?
That gear you've got on,
it's leather.
That's it.
Goes with the bike, dunnit?
I never realised.
You never realised what?
Well, you was...a rocker.
What am I, black?
You ain't white
in that get-up, are you?
Nah.
Give us a cuppa tea, mate.
Anyway, how long you been back?
Coupla months ago.
Couldn't stick it, eh?
Nah, they messed me about,
didn't they?
They treat you like shit.
Some poncey Sergeant Major's
always ordering you about.
"Don't do this, don't do that."
Drove me fuckin' mad.
Then ship you to Wogland.
Whereabouts?
Aden.
Was all right, as it 'appens.
Shooting matches
with the rebels and all that.
But they stopped that.
- Ship you home.
- You're joking!
Back to the same boring routine.
- Drove me fuckin' mad...
- Gotta go, Kev.
- Where you goin'?
- See you later.
- All right?
- Yeah, fine, John.
What's this fuckin'
rocker doin' here?
Jim?
Here's your towel.
See you later, Kev!
Bollocks.
- How does that feel?
- Awkward.
- What?
- Bring it in 'ere.
- I could bring it...
- All right, Dan?
- All right, Jim.
- Put your hands there.
Stop fuckin' about!
Don't use that
language here, sonny.
Talk like that you can
make your own suit.
There you go.
30 shillings, please.
I'll bring that in.
What about this?
I want it by Saturday.
Saturday. Yeah, Saturday.
- What d'you think?
- Rent-a-tent, innit?
Two pound nine pence, please.
- Don't matter.
All right, darlin'?
Saturdays, I hate 'em.
I thought I'd just
drop by and say hello.
Been up to no good?
Not really.
Just paid me suit off.
- Yeah? What's it like?
- Handsome.
Three buttons, side vents.
16" bottoms.
Dark brown.
Have I got to wait
all day while you finish?
I'm wearin' it down to Brighton.
Gonna be one of the faces there,
are you?
What d'you mean "going to be"?
I am one of the faces.
# I'm the hippiest
number in town
# And I tell you why
# I'm the snappiest dresser
right down to my inch-wide tie
# And I'll get you wise
# I'll explain to you
# A few of the things
that a face is supposed to do #
That Bombers?
Give us a couple.
Chalky! The Ponce,
he's about again.
Not a tight-arse, are you?
I ain't had one for days.
Why? You get banged up
in Margate or something?
Banged up in Shepherd's Bush.
My old man ain't let me out
since Margate.
Even padlocked
the scooter, right?
I went round,
he tried to do me over.
I wouldn't stand for it.
If my old man
took them sort of liberties,
I'd fuckin' do him.
You seen his dad? He's 6'2".
How come you're so small?
- Dunno, it's... thingy...
- Genetic.
His nan's a midget.
There's a party
down Kitchener Road.
- Told you.
- That posh bird?
- Yeah. Right goer.
- One with...?
Wanna go to a party?
Everybody's going.
- Where?
- Kitchener Road.
Yeah?
It only takes 20 minutes
to get there by scooter.
Where you off to, then?
I'll see you later.
Come on, Jim.
Ferdy!
This is the place, lads.
Come on!
All right, John?
Yeah, straight in, no problem.
Come on!
No gate-crashers.
Gate-crashers? Lads, he's
callin' us gatecrashers.
You didn't even
bring any bottles!
Who the fuck are you?
Bleedin' Prince Philip?
I'm the boyfriend
of the hostess.
Listen, it's Sandra's party,
and me and me mates are invited.
Sandra?
'Ere, where'd you
get that shirt?
All right, Jim?
Anything you fancy?
There's nothing there.
You found a bird.
I know her.
'Ere, that's mine, ain't it?
Can I have that one? Ta.
'Scuse me.
'Ere, Dan. Seen what's
goin' on in there?
Go in there. It's a laugh!
You'll love it!
Cheers.
Oh, let's have some!
Come on, Monkey,
don't mess about.
Not unless you
give me something.
What?
You always have to ask,
don't you?
1, 2, 3 for you.
Where'd you get these, eh?
That'd be telling, wouldn't it?
You forgot I work
for the chemist.
Come on, then!
Let's go.
# People try to put us down
# Talkin' 'bout my generation
# Just because we get around
# The things they do
look awful cold
# Talkin' bout my generation
# Hope I die before I get old
# Talkin' 'bout my generation
# My generation
# My generation, baby
- # Why don't you all f...
- Fuck off!
# Talkin' 'bout my generation
# Don't try to dig
what we all say
# Talkin' 'bout my generation
# I'm not tryin' to cause
a big s...ensation
# Talkin' 'bout my generation
# Just talkin'
'bout my g-g-generation
# My generation
# My generation, baby #
And again!
Dave?
Leave it out, Jim.
Give us a break.
Sorry, John, eh?
Get in there.
- Dave!
- What?
What are you doin'?
What d'you think?
Oh, yeah? Where've I seen
that face before?
- You all right?
- Yeah, get in there!
Piss off, will ya?
Sorry, sorry.
Shut the door!
Oi!
Jimmy!
Whoo-hoo!
Jim!
Great!
What is this? What's going on?
Look at my plants!
# Every year is the same
# And I feel it again
# I'm a loser - no chance to win
# Leaves start fallin'
# Come down is callin'
# Loneliness starts sinkin' in
# But I'm one
# I am one
# And I can see that this is me
# And I will be
# You'll all see I'm the one #
Eh?
'Ere.
And the paper.
Thank you.
Take that to Mr Phelps.
That's for Phelpsy, eh?
- 'Ere.
- You're late.
The letters...
Saw the rounds yesterday,
Michael.
For people like you, Phil, eh?
I'd like you to look at them.
Sure, what's the problem?
Well, the overall
campaign's going well.
Seen the posters?
Yes. Gorgeous tart.
The trouble is, the clients
are getting over-greedy.
As usual.
They want to corner
the entire youth market.
Cut right across the groupings.
It's all right
with A's and B's...
..young managers, graduates,
that type of person.
It's C's and D's
I'm worried about.
It's a bit up-market for them.
I'll look at it for you,
Simon. With pleasure.
- 2:30 all right?
- Fine.
You don't think this lung cancer
talk will make a difference?
No, young people...
They're not worried.
Glad I gave it up.
'Pychopathic,
that's what it was.'
- 'I thought something's wrong.'
- 'Shut up and listen to me.'
'Your next assignment
is to get Sir Thomas Weller.'
'You bonkers? He's the
guv.'
Ow!
'What, no lolly?'
Where you been?
Fell asleep on the train.
I wound up in bloody Neasden.
Ridin' about on them motorbikes
all night, I'm not surprised.
It's not normal.
'A nice quiet piece of
scenery and kick him to a pulp.'
Oh, yeah? What's normal, then?
What's that?
Hello, Jim.
Thought I'd just pop by, like.
You don't mind, do you?
No, I don't mind. Come in.
Cheers.
What's the matter, then?
She's misfirin' a bit.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
It's your plug.
Got some tools on the bike,
hold up.
It'll break your
bleedin' leg off, that.
No wonder you wear
those boots.
It's the best bike
ever made.
I've got a ton, five
out of that.
Better than that poxy hairdryer.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Well, that isn't it, is it?
I mean, it isn't the bikes,
is it? It's the people.
And people riding these are
states, third class tickets.
Do what?
Rockers, all that greasy hair
and clobber. It's diabolical.
I don't give a monkey's arsehole
about mods and rockers.
Underneath, we're all the same,
ain't we?
Nah, Kev, that's it.
I don't wanna be the same
as everybody else.
That's why I'm a mod, see?
I mean, you gotta
be somebody, ain't you?
Or why not jump
in the sea and drown?
That's why I joined the army,
to be different.
To get away from all this.
Wherever you go,
there's always some cunt
who wants to push you about.
Run it, please!
Two bob.
I'll see you.
Two fives.
Hey!
Nah, that's bollocks.
Three of a kind don't beat that.
- It does.
- Who says?
I do!
He's right you know, Harry.
Will you run it, please?
I was late.
She was waiting
in the wrong place.
And by the time I found her...
Did you get us some blues, then?
I'll have to see, won't I?
I dunno.
One card.
Down and dirty.
Make a mod out of you yet,
Harry, eh?
I don't think, though,
they make Levis in your size.
Bollocks.
- Is it me?
- Yeah.
All right.
- Threes.
Two bob.
I'm out.
Yeah, so am I. You're a fuckin'
jammy bleeder, Cooper.
You're gettin' chicken, Des.
Look, I only had an ace.
I gotta go
to Broadwick Street now.
Take some stuff up there.
Will you run
that film again, please?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh, yeah, Des. I don't like
to be cruel. Take it all back.
Nah, it's yours. You won it.
That's the ten bob I owe you.
Fuck off! I ain't carrying
all that fuckin' change about!
Take it or leave it, me son.
Take it or leave it.
I'll see you later, Harry.
See you, Des.
Er, Mr Cale sent me to collect
some stuff for Broadwick Street.
Yes, we've been waiting
for you for over an hour.
Yeah?
Come on, that stuff's got
to be over there fast. F.A.S.T.
Watch the cloth, moth.
Tacky little herbert.
- You want to hear it?
- Yeah.
Number two.
Oh, boy!
What you gonna do tonight?
Wait for a call, I suppose.
Listen, I'll see you
later, all right? Bye!
Wotcher, Jimmy.
What you doing here, then?
- Waiting for you.
- Yeah? What for?
- To give you a lift.
- Great.
- Steph?
- What?
You goin' to Brighton
this weekend?
- Yeah, you?
- 'Course I am.
Who you goin' with?
Pete's taking me.
Gonna be good, innit?
Yeah. Good.
You and Pete gettin'
a bit strong, then?
No, 'course not.
He's a laugh, that's all.
Bit flash though, ain't he?
I wouldn't be with him
otherwise, would I?
Nah. S'pose not.
You jealous?
'Course I ain't.
Nah? That's a pity,
I thought you was.
It's a technique!
All right, boys?
So what we gonna do about pills?
If we're goin' to Brighton,
we'll need bloody millions.
I wanna get out me head.
That's not difficult
with your little monkey brain.
Bollocks!
Get some rockers off their
heads, knock 'em off!
I was thinkin' about
getting a gun.
Don't talk bloody daft!
I'm gettin' my suit tomorrow.
Only 'cause
you wanna screw Steph.
- No!
- Hey, Jim!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Go outside!
We're goin', ain't we.
Oh, let's go, then.
The rolls have got scabs on 'em!
Shit.
- Get off it a sec.
- Spider!
What's up, then?
- Dunno.
- Breakdown?
Must be the points.
- See you there.
- Yeah. Ten minutes.
You'd do better to catch a bus!
We will, then!
Shit.
What's up with it?
How am I supposed
to bleedin' know?
# Met him on a Monday
and my heart stood still
# Da do ron ron ron,
da do ron ron
# Somebody told me
that his name was Bill
# Da do ron ron ron,
da do ron ron #
Oh, shit!
What's up? Your mother's
hairdryer blown up, has it?
Rubber band busted?
- Yeah.
- No, let's fix it.
Hold on,
we don't do nothin' for nothin'.
Why don't you piss off?
Bloody leave us alone.
Hold on, Lenny,
they don't want our help.
Are you the boy or the girl?
It's hard to tell with you lot.
This one. Give us a kiss.
Piss off!
You bastards!
This one's the bird!
Bugger off!
- Spider!
- Let's go!
Spider!
So long, suckers!
Fuck off!
Bloody hell.
# Yeah, my heart stood still
# Yes, his name was Bill
# Yeah,
and when he walked me home... #
Lads, I've just seen Spider
outside. He's taken a kicking!
Some rockers have had him!
- You're joking?
- He's outside on the stairs.
Come on!
Spider? You all right, yeah?
What's this about rockers
kickin' you in?
I'm gonna murder
the bleedin' scum!
You lot! Come on!
Stay there, right?
- What we gonna do?
- Fucking kill 'em!
- Right! Come on!
- Are you with me?
Murder!
# Yes, he looked so fine
# Yes, I made him mine
# And when he walked me home
# Da do ron ron ron,
da do ron ron
There they fuckin' are!
Fuckin' hell!
Fuckin' have 'im!
Jim!
You wanted it, didn't you?
Fuck off! Leave 'im alone!
Leave 'im alone!
- Leg it!
- Fuckin' law'll be here!
What sort of time
d'you call this?
I haven't got a watch.
Don't come funny, lad.
It's nearly midnight, isn't it?
I ain't gonna turn
into a pumpkin, am I?
Anyway, you're pissed.
Fuckin'...
What's going on?
I've been sat up,
waiting for you.
I can do without
your clever remarks.
George!
Who d'you think you are?
I don't know. You tell me, eh?
You're barmy, that's what.
Staying out all hours.
Gettin' up to God knows what.
Dressing like a bloody freak.
Stand still when
I'm talking to you.
I wouldn't be surprised
if you're on drugs.
- Yeah.
I know what you
get up to, your gang.
You've got to be part of a gang.
Got to be a mod.
Haven't you got
a mind of your own?
I'll tell you,
you're schizophrenic, you are.
What's that, then, eh?
I'll tell you.
It's somebody like you,
who doesn't know
where his mind is.
Bloody split personality.
Half your mother's family
were the same.
That's where you get it.
Your Uncle Sid was always
trying to kill himself.
And when he did
it was an accident.
He never knew what he was doing.
- What happened to him?
- He got drowned, didn't he?
Fell down a bleedin' well
in the garden.
Go on, get off to bed.
Jimmy? Jimmy!
Come on, you,
you're late as it is.
- Jimmy!
- Don't...
Come on, wake up.
I'm not well, Mum.
- What?
- I can't go in. I'm not well.
Oh!
Something wrong with your head?
Lying there in your clothes!
It's not normal.
Well, I can't stand here.
I've gotta get on.
Make sure you go to the
doctor for a certificate, hear?
Yes.
Hang on, what about them blokes
Pete was on about?
What? Always got bags of it?
Straight out the back door
of the chemical factory?
That's fuckin' rubbish.
Just the sort of bollocks you'd
expect from that flash cunt.
Yeah, but it's worth a try.
- I'll try him now.
- Nothing to do?
All right, George,
half a minute.
I'll pick you up later.
Yeah, all right, Jim.
D'you want a push start?
No, thanks.
Hey, Jim!
I'll be on me own bike tomorrow.
Eh?
The scooter's back
from the garage.
Burn the arse off
your rust bucket.
Any time.
Butch! Jenny! It's all right.
Go on, get back in there.
Hello, young Jim. On holiday?
Nah, just fancied the day off.
You'll be a bloody beatnik
before you know it.
Ban the bomb and do fuck all.
Poncin' about.
Oh, you're all right.
Just you and your Uncle Charlie.
Don't have to bother
with a load of cunts.
- You know what I mean.
- I don't.
No work, no money.
And I like money.
'Ere, Pete, what about Brighton
this weekend, eh?
What about it?
Er, pills.
We thought you might
get hold of some.
Why me?
I'm not a fuckin' pusher.
No, but you know
some blokes who are?
Not me.
Charlie's mates.
And I'm not gonna start blabbing
about mates of Charlie's.
They're fuckin' big.
They don't mess about.
Anyway, don't know why you're
worryin'. Ferdy'll have some.
Well, Ferdy ain't
been seen, has he?
He'll turn up. Friday, he'll pop
up like a jack-in-the-box.
Or a golliwog.
Ain't bloody here, is he?
Cunt. I wonder where he is?
I dunno.
This place gives me the shits.
Bleedin' nig-nogs everywhere.
Shut up.
It's like bleedin'
Calcutta round 'ere.
Calcutta's in India.
Yeah, West India. That's where
they bleedin' come from, innit?
- Yeah.
- What's so funny?
Just who you lookin' for,
Mister?
Is Ferdy in?
He not here. Him gone out.
Looking for Ferdy?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
He's gone out.
Oh. Yeah.
Stitchin' me up an' all,
the bloke. Fuckin'...
Peter Fenton!
Oh. Peter!
Thanks.
Peter Fenton. Who is it?
Fuckin' hell, why ring me here?
Listen, you cunt. Tell us
where to find these blokes,
- or we're stuck for Brighton.
- OK. This time.
Hold this, then.
What for?
Well, I ain't goin' in there
with me parka on.
Jim!
What d'you want, son?
Is, er, Harry North about?
Who are you, then?
I got a message for him.
Hang about a minute, all right?
Come through here.
Come through, come through.
Go on, through here.
That's him in the grey suit.
Go on, you're all right.
What can I do for you, son?
- Me uncle Charlie.
- Who?
Charlie Fenton, he said...
You Charlie's boy?
His nephew, yeah.
His nephew.
What's your name, son?
Jimmy.
It's a pleasure to meet
any one of the Fentons.
D'you wanna drink, son?
No, thanks.
I gotta get goin' soon.
What can I do for you, then?
You can talk here.
We're all pals.
Well, I wanted some pills.
Oh. What d'you want?
Purple Hearts, blues, Dexedrine?
- Some blues.
- Some blues?
I got a tenner.
Not in here, son.
Teddy! Come here.
This is Teddy. Go for a walk
with him, he'll do the business.
Here, give my regards
to your Uncle Charlie, son.
Pill-head.
Come on, Ronnie!
Come on, Ron!
Tosser.
Wotcher.
It's all there.
250, it'll see us through
till Christmas, eh?
One for the road, eh?
Come on, hurry up.
That ain't a blue!
It's paraffin!
We've been done!
That's my three quid wasted!
Yeah. And mine!
Let's do the bastards' motor.
Right.
Come on!
Get out the way!
- Come on!
- Go!
You on?
Wankers!
Shh.
Go on.
Shove it, man.
Nice one.
You're fuckin' makin' a racket.
- Do we have to do this?
- 'Course we do.
We don't wanna leave
prints all over, do we?
My arse. It's the smell.
Shh.
We must be able
to find some pills here, eh?
Shh!
Oh, yes!
Shut up!
- Fucking shut up!
- All right.
Shh. Shh.
Jim, I just thought.
What?
- Footprints.
- Footprints?
You got lines on your feet,
same as your fingers.
Must be thousands
of pills here... Millions.
Ah, nothing's there,
I'm gonna search in here...
I'm puttin' me socks on.
I ain't stupid.
Police!
Lads, look at these! Johnnies!
Fuckin' hundreds of 'em!
Chuck us some packets!
You got something
planned tonight?
'Course I have.
Oh! Yellows.
Chalky, what you doin'?
Give us a hand, eh?
Not takin' no chances, am I?
Come on! Shut up!
Get down to it, eh?
A-ha! Found 'em! They're blues!
I found some blues.
There's not many.
Perhaps someone's
been nickin' 'em.
Fuckin' hell!
Hang on.
Chalky, come on!
I'm just gettin'
somethin' for me mum.
I'm droppin' all the blues!
Just get out!
- Right...
- One and tuppence?
OK, you behave
yourself tonight, OK?
I'll try. I'll try
and behave myself tonight.
Yeah, I'm flyin'!
Terrific, ain't they?
Did we have it off or what?
- Hi.
- We done your chemist's.
- You didn't?
- Yeah.
I was gonna phone.
Why didn't you?
I know where everything is.
Here y'are. Got you a Pepsi.
- And a present.
- What is it?
You nicked 'em, didn't you?
You're handling stolen goods.
I'll give you some more.
Listen, d'you fancy
takin' me home later?
What about Pete, then?
I'll worry about Pete.
But if you tell him, I'll never
ever speak to you again, right?
Don't worry. I won't tell him.
And I'm still going down
to Brighton with him.
Yeah.
I've said I would, haven't I?
Yeah, I s'pose so.
# Girl, you really got me now
# You got me so
I can't sleep at night
# You really got me. Whoo!
# Really got me. Whoo!
# Please...
Ah, cheers.
How much you get?
Mr Fulford mentioned your
unexplained absence yesterday.
Like what?
Like, don't do it again.
Unless you want to hear him
read the riot act?
I take it you don't.
I'd rather be dead, Mr Cale.
All right. Off you go.
You too, Alec.
Have a nice weekend!
The only way you'll keep
that up is with lacquer.
- No, no lacquer.
- Just a little?
No, poofs wear lacquer.
I wear lacquer.
That's what I mean, innit?
- There y'are.
- Cheers.
That's all right.
My bird'll pull that back.
Long as that's all she pulls.
All right.
The usual miracle?
Careful, I've got a rash.
You know how the hair falls?
Goes down the back.
- All right.
- Know what I mean?
- See you, Dan.
- Yeah.
Brighton tomorrow!
Yeah, see you there.
Mum? Mum?
Where've you put
them old newspapers?
You're not gonna make
my carpets wet again?
Nah, I've wrung 'em out
this time.
They're under the sink.
Gordon Bennett!
What have you got on?
Is this some kind of new fashion
thing I haven't heard about?
Sopping wet trousers?
They're Levis.
Never mind what they are,
they're bleedin' wet!
You gotta shrink 'em on you,
so they fit right.
He's definitely gettin' worse.
# I can go anyway
# (Way I choose )
# I can live anyhow
# (Win or lose )
# I can go anywhere... #
What's this rubbish, then?
Ready, Steady, Go!
Ready what?
Ready, steady, go?
Bunch of louts.
Bloody moron.
I suppose they wear
wet jeans and all?
Eh?
I..Is that how you're supposed
to play a guitar now, then?
Eh?
Oh, gawd help us.
Here, have you seen this?
I haven't got time
for that rubbish.
I can sing better
than that little ape.
You call that singing?
Sounds like a drowned dog!
That'll make you deaf, you know.
Gerry & the Pacemakers.
The Animals are next.
This is Big L, 266.
Wonderful Radio London. Whoopee!
Good morning, it's 6.01. Here
are the main points in the news.
After yesterday's conference
session the Colonial Secretary
commented that he hoped for
independence in Aden in a year.
The Bank Holiday started
in earnest last night,
with motorists taking advantage
of the fine weather,
heading towards
the South Coast resorts.
Traffic was reported heavy on
the A127, the Southend road,
and there were jams southbound
on the M1, causing long delays.
Shopkeepers in the Brighton
area, fearing a reoccurrence
of disturbances by groups of
rival youths in other resorts,
were putting up
shutters last night.
A spokesman said, while they
weren't expecting any trouble,
they were going
to be prepared...
Show off!
Fuck off!
He thinks he's Davey Crockett!
Give us a mirror!
Piss off!
Chalky!
Hold the bike.
Hey, Chalky! Chalky!
Chalky, you all right?
Chalky!
Yeah, I'm all right.
Anything broken?
Nah.
Shame, eh? Shame.
Nah, it looked good
from back there.
Don't take the piss,
I nearly broke me fuckin' neck.
You're all right.
We'll get 'em, right?
- Fuckin' grease monkeys.
- Follow us up.
Told you I'd burn you.
- See you, Chalk!
- Hang on!
- See you down there!
- See ya!
# Get out and don't come back
# Don't come back
# Don't come back #
Look at that!
That is Brighton, my sons.
Terrific! All right, lads!
Nice one!
John!
Ace!
Here they are!
Whoo!
Hi! What about this?
Everyone's here.
This is great!
Great? Brilliant!
Hey, look! There's Bonzo!
Bonzo? Bonzo!
Bonzo!
When'd you get down here, then?
About half an hour ago.
We left before it was light.
- What's it like?
- Dark, weren't it?
Look at him!
Don't he look smart.
Wallop!
Look at the scooter!
That is ace!
Whoo! Whoo!
So, erm... What happened
to you last night?
That'd be tellin', now,
wouldn't it?
Chalky!
Thanks for waitin'!
Bleedin' turd.
Where'd the bird go?
How many you want?
He's out of his head.
Jim, you come up, then?
- Yeah, I'm really up.
- Fuckin' great!
- Greenwich Village.
- Where?
Greenwich Village, New York.
Geezer with the hair, man.
- Oi, Dave! Dave!
- Yeah?
The one with the hair!
Let's watch. He's brilliant!
- Jim?
- See you there.
Come on!
Monkey! Come dance!
All right, there, Steph?
Hello.
Great dancer, ain't he, eh?
Must be the ace face, eh?
Good-looking.
You wanna dance with a face?
- All right.
- C'mon, then.
C'mon!
Oh, c'mon, let's dance over
there! C'mon, I wanna watch him!
- No, dance here.
- C'mon!
- Where you going?
- To dance!
Oh, dance with yourself!
Look at him!
What's he doin'?
Out the way, son.
Out the way. Come on.
Oi! Bouncers!
Yah!
You're out. Come on, out.
You could've killed
yourself. Come on.
Get off! Leave 'im!
Jimmy!
- Monkey!
- No!
Get out and stay out!
Bit of a girl, was she?
- Where to?
- I wanna ride!
I'm findin' somewhere to kip.
You seen Jimmy?
He was bein' kicked out.
- Fenton's pulled again.
- Makes you sick.
He's sorted his sleepin'
arrangements out.
- Let's ride, Chalk!
- No, get some kip.
- See ya, Dave.
- Cheerio, Spider.
- Oi, Steph!
- What?
You comin' with us?
No, we're goin' to a bed
and breakfast, ain't we, Shirl?
- Bye.
- See ya.
I wouldn't say no
to bed and breakfast.
I ain't got no dough.
Not you. Them!
Oh. Yeah, not half.
Can you imagine it?
Legs wrapped round your face...
- Fuckin' amazin'.
- Whoo-hoo!
Bit of all right is Steph.
- So where we gonna kip?
- I dunno.
What we gonna do?
Go back to the beach?
Oh, yeah? Can you swim?
I don't wanna sleep anyway.
Do you?
Hey!
What d'you reckon?
It's cheap.
Bit of a shithouse, innit?
I dunno, never slept
in a shithouse, Chalk.
What d'you reckon?
Make your fucking mind up.
..Kin' hell!
Sorry. Is there room?
Come on, then, let's move.
Get a move on.
I've heard there's
a few mods about.
See you down there.
What d'you want?
Bacon sandwich, please.
Spider!
Hello, girls!
- Where's Jim?
- Over there.
Jim! How's the human cannonball
today?
Leave me hair alone, Dave!
Eh?
We're in this beach hut,
it's dark, right?
Wakes up this morning,
there's greasers everywhere!
- Right, Dave?
- Yeah, screwing some bird.
Yeah, what did
she look like then?
Dunno, we only saw her arse.
But that wasn't rough.
Well, apart from the splinters.
One was the geezer
that rode me off the bike.
He's on my fuckin' list.
All right if I sit down, eh?
Yeah.
What you got the 'ump about?
- Hey?
- Why you so humpy?
Nothing.
Just lookin' at the sea,
that's all.
Oh, yeah?
Christ Almighty.
Take your feet off the table.
Piss off!
Just watch it or you're out!
Where'd you get to, then?
Nowhere!
Just kipped on the beach.
You're fuckin' mad,
getting chucked out.
You shoulda stayed around, mush.
You woulda been well in.
What d'you mean?
She was all on her Jack Jones.
Steph?
Yeah.
Fucking Fenton gets off
with this beatnik chick.
And she's all on her own.
Tell you, I'd have been up her
like a fuckin' ferret!
Well, if I hadn't known
you were so...
So what?
I ain't gone on her, you know?
Hello, Jimmy!
Everybody
knows you fancy her.
I reckon she's a right
good bunk-up.
Oh, you animal.
Hi.
- All right, Steph?
- Yeah, great, innit?
- Where's Pete, then?
- Dunno. Don't care.
Don't care?
Dave! Come on. Dave!
We are the mods,
we are the mods!
We are, we are, we are the mods!
Fucking wankers!
That's the geezer that
run me off the road yesterday!
Let's fuckin' have 'em!
Have 'im!
Pete! Stop 'em!
No!
They've gone berserk!
Get somebody here!
What's that... Stop!
Jesus Christ,
they've gone... Oi!
What's goin' on here?!
Over the edge!
Jimmy! Jimmy!
All right! I was there! Mods!
Mods! Mods! Mods!
There was a geezer, man, I tell
you, I went, crack! Crack!
We are the mods,
we are the mods!
We are, we are, we are the mods!
Quick!
Fuckin' hell! Run! Run!
We are the mods,
we are the mods!
We are, we are, we are the mods!
Mods! Mods! Mods!
We got some rockers!
Kill the bastards!
Steph, come on!
Out the way!
- Come on!
- Wait for me!
- Steph!
- Jimmy!
Jesus Christ! The Law!
Right, keep them in!
Control those kids!
We are the mods,
we are the mods!
We are, we are, we are the mods!
Run. Run! Run!!
Up here, up here! Come on.
Oh...
Ho...
Come 'ere.
Come here.
Uh... Oh...
Ooh...
'Ere, c'mon.
Down 'ere.
Come on!
Get onto the footpaths!
Get onto the path!
Get off! I ain't done nothing!
Go on, go on!
Right, give him here. Come on.
Steph, come on!
Oh, no.
Fuck!
All right, all right!
Fuck off! Cunt.
Cheers.
All right!
# I feel I'm bein' followed
# My head is empty
# Yet every word I say
turns out a sentence
# Make love to a stranger
# Just asking for directions
# Turn from being help
# To being question...
Oi, Steph? Are you all right?
# I see a man
without a problem #
It seems strange
to see this procession
of miserable specimens.
So different from the strutting
hooligans of yesterday,
who came here to pollute
the air of this town.
Yes.
These long-haired, mentally
unstable, petty little hoodlums.
These sordid Caesars, who can
only find courage, like rats,
by hunting in packs,
came to Brighton
with the avowed intent
of interfering with the life
and property of its inhabitants.
And so far as the law
gives us power,
this court will not fail to use
the prescribed penalties.
It may, perhaps, discourage you,
and others of your kidney,
who're infected with this
vicious virus,
that you be ordered
to pay a fine of 75.
I'll pay now if you don't mind.
Haven't got a pen,
have you, Your Honour?
That's enough, silence!
Take him away!
James Michael Cooper.
You stay right where you are!
I don't have to ask
where you've been, do I?
I suppose you think this is
clever? Proud of yourself?
- No.
- No?
You was there, weren't you?
Yeah, we were there.
And you had more of this filth
with you, didn't you?
You can look shame-faced,
my lad.
I've a good mind to get the law.
- Where'd you get these?
- Dunno.
- Someone gave 'em to me.
- Oh, did he?
And you had to take 'em?
- No.
- You've gotta look big.
If they was rat poison
you'd have taken them anyway?
Then gone off like savages
ruining everybody's peace!
I look at you and don't know
what I've brought up!
Your sister's not like this!
Ain't she?
What do you fucking know, eh?
Drugs and filthy pictures!
Running riot over everywhere!
You're a little animal,
you wanna be locked up!
Look what I've got!
A bloody mad thing!
All right.
You're a little savage!
Get out of my house, go on!
Get out!
You're no son of mine!
Wait till your
father comes home!
- I'll wait!
- Go on, get out!
Yeah, fuck off!
...fuckin' house anyway, eh?
# Get out
and don't come back no more
# Get out, don't come back
# Get out
# and don't come back
# no more #
Come.
The post room boy.
Be with you in a minute, Cooper.
Absent for a full day
last week, Cooper.
Now, I understand one day's bank
holiday's not enough for you,
so you have to take two.
May I enquire if there's
any reason for this?
Not really.
Not ill or anything, were you?
No.
Mr Cale tells me you spent
the weekend in Brighton.
I imagine you were involved
in the...disturbances there?
Yeah, I was there.
You weren't arrested or
detained or anything, were you?
No.
I must say, I find your attitude
fairly incomprehensible.
I feel I must warn you, Cooper,
that we cannot tolerate
this kind of absenteeism
amongst our junior staff.
You've got a good steady job,
Cooper.
Plenty of young men'd give their
eye teeth to be in your shoes.
Yeah?
Find one, then.
I beg your pardon?
You heard. Find one, then.
I'll tell you
what to do with your job.
You can take that mail,
and that franking machine,
and all that other rubbish
I have to go about with,
and you can stuff 'em
right up your arse!
Hey, Jimmy. You lose a shilling
and find sixpence, eh?
Well, look who it isn't.
Jimmy, I thought
they'd locked you up.
Yeah, I got fined,
didn't I? 50.
Jesus.
Another good customer
bites the dust.
We couldn't wait for you,
had to get back to our jobs.
Yeah, well, I ain't bothered.
I was with Ace and that.
Yeah, we went to court together.
Yeah.
Christ,
he's really weird tonight.
I couldn't give a shit.
Ferdy?
Jim?
You got any blues?
Yeah, how many you want?
Dunno. How many you got?
A ton. French blues.
I'll have the lot.
- What?
- You can't afford it!
Where'd you get all that, then?
Golden hand shake, innit?
Two weeks' money.
Told him to stuff the job
right up his arse.
You sure you want the whole bag?
Yeah. Why not, eh? Why not?
All right.
A fiver.
Fiver.
What you gonna do with that lot?
Start a one-man riot?
Yeah. I might.
Why'd you chuck your job?
'Cos I felt like it.
Well, you're bleedin' nutty.
You was on a cushy number.
Look, don't give it
all that, right?
I just got fed up.
Fancied something outdoors.
So do I.
She's not bad, is she?
I found her by the road
in Brighton.
See you found yourself
a new little boy, then?
Hey, Jimmy?
Hope you find a new job.
Oh, yeah?
I could get you a job
on the rubbish carts?
You're good at going
up and down in alleys.
If I see you round 'ere again
I'll fuckin' kill you!
- Get off me!
- What's the matter?
You're not a face!
- Piss off!
- You piss off!
Forget her, Jimmy!
Shut up and piss off. You're all
wankers and cunts. Wankers!
Jimmy!
Pack that in and clear off!
What d'you want,
you old spunker, eh?
Eh? What d'you
want? What d'you want?
I'll have you,
you little bastard!
Are you mad?
What's the matter with you?
You're worse than he is!
Come on in!
You'll wake the whole street.
It's a bit late for that!
If he comes
here again I'll kill him!
Can't you
come in and talk about it?
Do they all have to know
our business?
Hello, Steph.
What you doin' here?
I wanted to see you.
You've seen me, OK?
Wait a minute, will ya?
What you gonna do? Beat me up?
What d'you want?
Come on, I'm late.
Well... I left home last night.
I kipped out, didn't I?
In some nuthouse?
Look, I ain't mad!
What is wrong with you, then?
Well, I dunno.
It's just...it seems like
everything's going backwards.
Steph?
You sure it's not you
going backwards?
No, it's just... I can't
think straight, that's all.
I mean, nothing seems right,
apart from Brighton.
Brighton was OK, going to court
with the Ace and that.
I was a mod there, you know?
I mean, that's something,
innit, eh?
What are you talkin' about?
Brighton was a laugh,
that's why we went down there.
Oh, yeah. And me and you, then?
Was that just a giggle?
Oh, what do you think?
All right, so I fancied you.
We had it off.
But that don't mean nothin'.
It did to fuckin' me.
I can't help that, can I?
If I'd known you'd go mad,
I wouldn't have.
I told you, I ain't
fuckin' mad, right?
No, not much. Look at you?
One minute you're all right,
next minute you're going stupid.
You can't have a bit without
kicking your mates' head in.
Just leave me alone,
Jimmy! All right?
Steph, please. Steph, please!
Fuck off!
You slag!
Ah, you cunt!
Bastard! Cunt!
What the bloody hell you doin'?
We could've killed you!
Hey?
Look at this.
Ah, fuckin' hell!
Look what you've done!
You cunts!
Why didn't you stop?
You've killed me scooter!
Fuck off! Leave it alone!
Get off it!
- Only a dent...
- Fuck off!
Get off it!
Take it easy, take it easy, now.
Fuckin' leave it alone!
Get off! Get off it!
There it is.
It's on the floor now.
You're lucky you weren't killed.
- Fuckin' lucky, am I?
- 'Course you are.
- Bastard!
- I didn't see you.
Fuck off! Go away.
15 years, never had an accident.
No fuckin' accident!
You got me, didn't you?
Why don't you kill me?
All of ya!
All of you fuckin' Mr Postmen,
fuck off, go on!
Fuck off!
# Why should I care?
Why should I care?
# He-man drag,
in a glittering ballroom
# Greyly outrageous,
in my high heeled shoes
# Tightly undone,
know what they're showing
# Sadly ecstatic
that the heroes are news
# Girls of 15 ( sexually knowing)
# The ushers are sniffing
( eau-de-Cologning!)
# The seats are seductive
( celibate sitting!)
# Pretty girls diggin'...
What you lookin' at?
# Magically bored,
on a quiet street corner
# Free frustration,
in our minds and our toes
# Quiet storm water,
m-m-my generation
# Uppers and downers,
either way blood flows
- # Inside, outside
- # Leave me alone
- # Nowhere is home
- # Inside, outside
- # Where have I been?
# Out of my brain on the 5:15
# Out of my brain on the train!
# Out of my brain on the train,
on the train
# Wow! I'm out of my brain!
# Only love
# Can make it rain
# The way the beach
# Is kissed by the sea
# Only love
# Can make it rain
# Like the sweat of lovers
# Layin' in the fields
# Love!
# Reign o'er me
# Reign o'er me, reign o'er me
# Love
# Reign o'er me
# Reign o'er me, reign o'er me
# On a dry and dusty road
# The nights
we spent apart, alone
# I need to get back home
# To cool, cool, rain
# I can't sleep,
and I lay and I think
# The nights are hot
and black as ink
# Whoo, God, I need a drink
# Of cool, cool rain
# Rain
# Rain on me
# Rain over me, over me, over me
# Whoa, rain
# Rain on me
# Whoa!
# On me...
Fuck it!
# Rain...
# A beach is a place
where a man can feel
# He's the only soul
in the world that's real
# But I see a face coming
through the haze
# I remember him
from those crazy days
# Crazy days
# Ain't you the guy
who used to set the paces
# Ridin' up in front
of a hundred faces
# I don't suppose
you would remember me
# But I used to follow you
back in '63
# I've got a good job
and I'm newly-born
# You should see me
dressed up in my uniform
# I'm workin' in a hotel,
all gilt and flash
# Remember the gaff
where the doors were smashed?
- # Bell boy!
- # I got to get runnin' now
- # Keep my lip buttoned down
- # Bell boy!
- # Carry this baggage out
Bell boy! Bell boy!
# You were under the impression
# That when you
were walking forwards
# That you'd end up
further onwards
# But things
ain't quite that simple
# You got altered information
# You were told
to not take chances
# You missed out
on new dancin'
# Now you're losin'
all your dimples
# My jacket's gonna be cut
slim and check
# Maybe a touch of seersucker
with an open neck
# I ride a GS scooter
with my hair cut neat
# I wear my wartime coat
in the wind and sleet
# Love, reign o'er me
# Reign o'er me
# Love
# Had enough of living
# Had enough of dying
# Had enough of smiling
# Had enough of crying
# Taken all the high roads
# Squandered and I've saved
# I've had enough of childhood
# I've had enough of graves
# Love
# Reign o'er me
- # Reign o'er me
- Me!
# Love
# Had enough of discos
# I've had enough of pills
# I've had enough
of street fights
# I've seen my share of kills
# I'm finished
with the fashions
# And acting like I'm tough
# I'm bored with hate
and passion
# I've had enough
of trying to...
# You stopped dancin' #
# Laugh and say I'm green
# I've seen things
you've never seen
# Talk behind my back
# I'm off the beaten track
# I'll take on anyone
# Ain't scared of a bloody nose
# Drink till I drop down
# With one eye on my clothes
# What is it? I'll take it
# Who is she? I'll rape it
# Got a bet there? I'll meet it
# Gettin' high?
You can't beat it
# What is it? I'll take it
# Who is she? I'll rape it
# Doctor Jimmy and Mr Jim
# When I'm pilled
you don't notice him
# He only comes out
when I drink my gin #