- We're going down.
- Chaplain Burke.
I just transferred
to the chapel here on the Navy Yard.
Her body was on at plane.
- What's her name?
- First Lieutenant Gabriela Flores.
There were only two Marines,
in those three cases.
Flores wasn't one of them.
We will do whatever it takes
to find her and bring her home.
No Marine is ever left behind.
Flores was blindsided in an attack on
a girls' school she was helping rebuild.
It was the people
she was working with?
That's the teacher.
Anyone who worked
at that school could be in on this.
- That's gotta be her.
- Are those children?!
She was trying to save them,
and she got caught.
Don't come back without her.
Go ahead.
Ask.
Ask what?
Tell Him what you're thinking.
In my experience,
He's not a big talker,
but His actions speak volumes.
His actions have been questionable.
Your daughter, Gabriela,
tried to save those kids.
She dedicated her life
to serving her country.
If she's any indication
of His actions, then
I have to disagree.
She should have gone back
to base that night.
- She should have followed orders.
- Yes.
But by following her instincts,
maybe she was following
His orders instead.
Can Gibbs bring her back?
Well, look, I haven't known
Special Agent Gibbs for very long,
but he's a good man
and he's working with the best.
So I have faith they they will do
everything they can to find her.
I know they'll find her, Chaplain.
The question is will she be alive?
What is it?
NCIS Season 9 Episode 09
Engaged 2/2 1.0 LOL
Synchro: Gaillots,
Keller & Kujathemas.
Rereading: Bruno & Magic Turtle.
www.Team-NCIS.com
Welcome to the belly of the beast.
- Smooth ride?
- Till somebody started shooting us.
It's Kabul's welcome wagon.
Next time, bake cookies.
What's the status?
Got some locals
to change their story.
They confirmed Lieutenant Flores
and the two girls were taken.
Did they identify the insurgents?
Changing their story is one thing,
but giving up names gets folks killed.
- People are afraid to talk.
- So why keep Flores alive?
Information.
Radicals don't like Westerners
opening up their kids' eyes.
167 schools were hit last year
throughout the Middle East.
More than half were
in Afghanistan alone.
And as a FET, Flores knows
where new ones are being built.
FETs act as a conduit between
the locals and the Corps.
I'll introduce you
to Staff Sergeant Littleton.
She was there that night.
Schools can be
a big part of what they do.
Good news is the 2 girls that Flores
saved were just found
about 7 clicks due south.
Abandoned roadside. They're being
transported here for treatment.
Are they all right?
Dehydrated, scared,
clearly tortured.
But alive.
We'll need see them.
As long as you're prepared
for what you'll see.
I grew up in this region.
Looks like you turned out okay.
I can hold my own.
Copy that.
Staff Sergeant Littleton.
- C.O. says you wanted to see me?
- Yeah. Sit down.
Understand that
you were with Flores
the night the school was attacked.
I already gave a statement
to the Investigative Unit, sir.
I know, but I just got
here and I'm anxious to hear.
There's nothing really
different to say.
Just trying to get a clear picture.
A bunch of us evacuated
before all hell broke loose.
I thought we were
all together in a seven-ton.
I kept yelling her name,
but she didn't answer.
She couldn't answer.
If I'd have stayed with Gabby,
she might not be in this mess.
Or you might be dead.
Know that woman?
Soraya?
She's one of the fortunate ones.
Fortunate? How?
She wasn't at school that day.
She was seeing
her family outside Kabul.
Have you seen her since?
We think
that she used being a teacher
to know when to strike.
The kids trusted Soraya.
We all did.
- She took advantage of that trust.
- And she succeeded, sir.
At being a coward.
Now it's our turn.
We may believe that every one
should be taught to read and write,
there are still some in the Middle East
who do not see it that way.
Yeah, but on the other hand, back in
the Crusades, the Knights Templar,
they were willing to kill
for what they held sacred.
Tragically, in both instances,
innocent children suffer.
A battle for young hearts and minds.
And Lieutenant Flores found herself
at the very center of that battle.
Look at you two...
hitting Wong's after hours
and talking the night away like
a couple of college coeds.
Commander Burke offers
a perspective I find quite...
provocative.
I bet you do, Ducky.
Anyway, we're tired
and waiting for answers.
That was Homeland Security.
The Jaysh El-Mo'mineen
have links to terror cells in Yemen,
Saudi Arabia and the Philippines.
What's the next step?
We need one of those
cells to turn on our radicals.
The less that they trust each other,
the more we can destabilize them.
What about you, Tony?
Me?
I hope you're not wasting your time
on that bucket list
I keep hearing about.
It's not a waste of time...
Oh, ye of little faith.
Present company excluded, of course.
Yeah, I am working on bucket list.
Perhaps all this talk of terrorism
has me anxious about certain...
insecurities.
You, DiNozzo?
Yes, me.
Shocking, but beneath this incredibly
masculine body armor,
there is a vulnerable do-gooder.
Vulnerable to...?
Telling you would be like Superman
telling Lex Luthor
about his vulnerability
to Kryptonite.
It's not gonna happen.
So what is it, Clark Kent?
What are you so afraid of?
- Good morning, Agent Gibbs.
- Evening, Director.
That you in the background,
Mr. Secretary?
Burning the candle
at both ends, Sir.
Careful,
people are gonna think you care.
Nice scarf.
- Update.
- Boss, we got an I.D.
on our loving Afghan teacher.
This is from a classified military
personnel file on the school.
Full name is Soraya Zoranj.
Grew up in Baghlan, Afghanistan.
Parents were killed by
the Russians when she was a teenager.
Soraya also had two siblings:
an older brother, Osman, who died
in an IED explosion two years ago,
and a younger brother, Asa,
who's in the U.S. on a student visa.
- He's going to law school here in DC.
- Talk to him.
Think he might keep
in contact with the big sis'?
Find out.
On it.
I love the smell
of coeds in the morning.
You need coffee.
So do I.
Working on Afghan time is
messing up our internal clocks.
I used to thrive on all-night
stakeouts and sub-zero surveillance.
Maybe this is a sign something's
missing from my life.
Like what, frostbite?
The kid's roommate told us Asa
spent all night in the law library.
- Might as well start there.
- I hate libraries.
Another one of your fears?
Don't mock me.
What's to hate about libraries?
The smell gets me every time.
Yeah? What does
a library smell like?
Lonely smart people.
Tony, that's our guy.
Soraya's brother.
Hey, kid.
We'd like to talk
to you for a second.
Can we ask you a few questions?
Now I'm gonna spill my latte!
You cannot do this!
I've done nothing wrong!
- Then why'd you run?
- You owe me another coffee.
It's funny we should find
you with your nose in a book.
Why is that funny to you?
All those kids wanted
was a chance to read.
Those girls...
just wanted to learn something.
And yet, here you are,
enjoying all the benefits
of an American education.
You are a country of
extraordinary power.
I see.
Study the power,
find the weakness?
Let me ask you a question.
You think those kids
really threaten your way of life?
You know nothing about our way of life,
our culture.
I know plenty.
I also know a closed-minded,
radical parasite when I see one.
The kind that likes
to prey on innocent children.
Your ignorance is amusing.
You know what I find amusing?
The idea of you in
a tiny little orange jumpsuit,
all alone in a six-by-six
cell crying for mommy.
I will not spend one minute
in your filthy prison.
I wouldn't bet on it.
Unless, of course, you want
to give us the name
of your little gang of school haters.
How many are there?
We are few,
but...
we are very strong.
You cannot defeat us.
Say it again.
You're breaking up.
Soraya's little brother, we got him.
- He tell you where his sister is?
- Not yet.
- But we're squeezing him.
- Squeeze tighter.
I need her.
She's the best hope we have...
Hey, Matteson.
I thought everyone
was going to the E-club.
They are.
Thought I'd get out instead.
You want me to take a look?
But you can start the engine.
Make yourself useful.
- You sure you don't want me to...
- Again.
You know,
I really should know better by now.
Yes, you should.
I'm headed to Pendleton soon.
I heard
maybe you're going there, too.
Okinawa.
Next week.
Japan.
Well, good luck over there.
You know, Gibbs...
if you ever find
yourself in Japan...
or even if you don't...
I'll always be around.
Give me a call.
I'd like that.
The girls, Gibbs.
Did you hear?
Hear what?
I had Tony. I lost him.
The girls Flores saved.
They are here.
Girls are both orphans.
Parents were killed by insurgents.
What are their ages?
10 and 13.
Already been through more
than anyone should in a lifetime.
Hot grease was thrown
in the older one's face.
The other one's covered
in cigarette burns.
Their names are Kinah and Lala.
We need to ask you some questions.
Do you remember Lieutenant Flores?
Gabriela?
Gabby?
Gabby! Yes.
She still there.
- You go bring?
- Gabby, Gabby she's still alive?
They're not...
done yet.
Notify the commandant.
Tell him we're a go.
Flores could still be alive.
That's very good.
You know that you're both safe here.
Can you tell us about Gabby?
They hurt her.
No cry.
Do you remember anything about
where these people took you?
It smelled bad?
Like what?
Car.
And ground, it was black.
Oil.
Ziva, we need a sample.
And then you get them
anything they want.
You never stop smiling, okay?
Abby,
did you get the sample analysis?
McGee, I have decided
that I am never going to complain
about anything ever, ever again.
How can I whine about the cost
of my DVD-by-mail service when
- there's real problems in this world?
- When you put it that way.
Take this evidence, for example.
Normally, I would whine
about not being able to
examine the actual item.
But given that we are 4,000
miles from Afghanistan,
we have to settle for a basic chemical
breakdown from the Marine unit.
And I took their breakdown
and I made lemonade.
Who knew that geochemistry
could be so cool?
You know, I actually took
a college class in fossil fuels.
Of course you did.
Just like the chemical compositions of
plant life are unique to any given area,
crude oil deposits
are like a geographic fingerprint.
This is from outside Kabul,
Afghanistan, on the Afghan pipeline.
There was no oil where
the girls were found, so...
So it's probably where
they were being held captive.
And where Lieutenant Flores
still might be.
Commander?
Chaplain Burke? Hello?
Anybody here?
Cool Hand Luke.
Of course, You knew that.
I could've used You a couple months ago.
Got my head scrambled pretty good.
Of course,
I understand You're a busy guy.
We haven't talked much.
That's my bad.
I'm doing the best I can down here,
you know.
For a DiNozzo.
Hopefully
living up to my end of the bargain.
You do remember
our bargain?
Be nice to hear from You.
So You have a plan?
Anything You want to
share with me?
How about You let me know
I'm on the right track?
I'm not talking to myself?
You are so predictable.
Well, I guess what we have here
is a failure to communicate.
You looking for me?
Chaplain.
Tell Joseph Flores we think we know
where his daughter might be.
I'm getting out of here.
Extraction team in place.
Zero hour.
That's what they call it.
I'd like to take this time
to wish everyone luck.
Luck's for the unprepared,
Mr. Secretary.
I'd rather have it than not,
General.
Game on.
Scopes and helmet cams.
Air support's on standby.
Thermals indicate five people.
The one on the ground's probably Flores.
Okay. Let's do this.
Corpsman!
Go! Go! Go!
Pressure.
You hang in there.
I got him, sir.
Keep breathing, Captain.
Go, go, go!
That's her.
Fine, sir.
Your call.
Give me a reason.
So what's it gonna be?
Feed you to the locals
lifetime at Gitmo,
or you die right here?
Target's secure!
Don't you say a word.
- How am I doing?
- You're doing great. Just hold on.
We're gonna need 3 liters of O-neg.
I gotta get him lidocaine.
Anybody call for medevac?
It's on the way.
Ma'am, I can take it from here,
step back.
Don't go, David.
I'm not leaving you.
- I need you...
- I said I am not leaving!
You look at me, Captain.
Look at me.
That's right.
My mom and dad.
Tell them...
I'm sorry.
Where are they?
What are their names?
Come on. Stay with me.
Maryland.
They own
a small motel on the bay.
You have to tell them...
I love them.
I promise I will.
I promise
I will tell them everything.
We'll get you home.
What is it?
We got her, sir.
Yo daughter Gabriela, she's alive.
Thank you.
God bless you.
She's alive!
Drink.
I have been, sir.
Drink some more.
There are some folks happy
to hear you're alive, Lieutenant.
I know.
Your dad's pretty happy, too.
- I'm anxious to see him.
- Yeah, I bet you are.
Quincy, sir...
he wouldn't be dead if I hadn't...
if I hadn't...
Quincy died doing his job.
He was your commanding officer.
That made you his responsibility.
Why'd you do it?
Running off with the kids,
disobeying orders.
I didn't have a choice.
I knew what would happen
to those girls.
If I had to do it again...
You would.
Yes, sir.
People died because of that teacher.
What do you think
should happen to her?
Sir, that's not my decision.
But you've thought about it, right?
She should be held accountable
for her crimes.
How?
She should watch
those girls change the world
in positive ways
she never imagined.
That a punishment?
That's a gift, sir.
Punishment is knowing
she could have done the same.
You're rare, Flores.
Come on. Let's go home.
- What?
- Nothing.
Definitely something. What?
You intrigue me.
Why?
When something's broken,
I want to fix it.
I hate to break it to you, but you ain't
got enough tools in your woodshed.
You might be surprised.
So how do I intrigue you?
In a naughty Catholic schoolgirl
kind of way
because I'm in need of what your kind
calls "spiritual guidance"?
Well, lucky for me, the latter.
You don't have to worry about me.
I'm rock solid in the spirit department.
That's fascinating.
You know what's even
more fascinating?
No, what's that?
I don't believe you.
When you're ready to face that fear,
Agent DiNozzo
I'm ready to face it with you.
You know...
I was just trying to save them.
And you did.
- Should've been me in that box.
- No, Lieutenant.
And it should not have
been Captain Quincy either.
What's going on?
What's it say?
Helo went down. Lost six Marines.
- Where?
- Okinawa, Japan.
Poor bastards just got there.
I think that Matteson
girl was one of them.
I never actually talked to her,
but she beat three of my course times.
She was good.
Hell of an athlete.
Gibbs, you remember Matteson.
Present arms!
Welcome to my classroom.
Why am I here?
Instead of a direct flight to Gitmo,
I thought we could talk.
Have a family reunion.
I have nothing to say.
When was the last time
you saw each other?
No, let me guess.
Terrorist convention in Toledo?
Mock me all you want, Agent Gibbs,
you will never
understand our motivation.
You gained the trust of these kids,
and then you hurt 'em.
By teaching future generations
not to be influenced
by your histrionic lies?
In this country,
teaching children is a privilege.
you waste money sending
your kids to college to have fun.
- They're taught to think on their own.
- They are rich, spoiled brats.
This is how you answer that?
You're radicals who maim
and kill innocent children,
because they want to learn
how other people think?!
You think we do this for ourselves?!
You come into our villages and towns
with your disgusting Western ideals.
You teach our children
to question their heritage,
to rely on the Internet
instead of the Koran.
Yes, this is our answer.
It is the only answer.
And you will see.
I'll see.
I'll see what?
You are here.
We are here.
Lieutenant Flores is here.
And our older brother is here, too.
Asa, don't!
According to our file, he's dead.
You think our fight is over.
But...
it has just begun.
Look what the Corps sent back.
Rough trip, Ziva?
"Rough" is an understatement, McGee.
Lieutenant Flores is back.
As is Captain Quincy.
And there lies the scratch.
The rub.
- "There lies the rub." It's a classic.
- I need some rest.
No rest for the weary, Ziva.
Party isn't over yet.
- Older brother, talk to me.
- Osman Zoranj, 38 years old.
Born in Helmand Province.
Fought with the Mujahideen for
seven years against the Soviets.
Raised to the rank of commander.
Helped drive the Russian
occupiers out of Kabul.
- War hero.
- Until he joined the Taliban.
And he brought
his brother and sister with him.
- Tell me something new.
- I got something here.
According to the DIA,
Osman was killed
in an apartment complex,
raid in Gardez, Afghanistan,
two years ago.
Raid set off a gas-line explosion.
Osman was among two dozen dead.
Not according to his siblings.
- And you believe them?
- Yeah.
D.C.?
You tell me.
Putting out a BOLO
on the "Oos-Mahn".
We need Asa's cell records.
Already on it.
Also alerting LEOs at the train depots,
bus stations and airports.
Homeland and Metro PD.
This group is up to something.
Find out what.
If Osman's little brother
had been in D.C. the whole time...
He might know where
the big brother is.
- Did you lose something, Gibbs?
- Yeah, knife.
Well, you always have one
in your pocket, right?
This one's different.
There are others watching.
Nope.
Just us.
No record of this conversation.
Don't need one.
Let us get started, okay?
Where's that son of a bitch
brother of yours, Osman?
Want a smoke?
No.
It is against Allah's wishes.
Yeah, it's against
fire regulations, too.
But if you want one, go ahead.
It's okay.
Look at her.
Cigarette burns over
60% of her body.
In unspeakable places.
Look at it!
Go on, look at it,
you son of a bitch!
You cannot do this!
- Stop, Agent Gibbs!
- I got this, Leon!
You're about to break
16 laws right now!
- He deserves it!
- It doesn't matter!
His brother Osman is dead anyway!
FBI took him down
in a raid about 20 minutes ago.
We went to tell his sister Soraya,
but it was too late.
She'd taken her life already.
She hanged herself in her cell.
They're both gone.
My family is dead.
Fight's just begun?
We were going to finish
what my sister had started.
- How?
- A bomb.
Electronically detonated.
My creation.
Where?
They are not dead.
Okay, jobs Osman had.
- What'd he have access to?
- He had several occupations.
- Never as a school teacher.
- Mainly as an auto mechanic.
Buses.
Museums and memorials, boss?
I want to know every school
trip scheduled today.
- That's a lot of kids.
- Do it.
Park Service isn't showing
anything out of the ordinary.
Couple of local junior highs.
Some professional tours.
I have something.
The National Consortium for
Independent Girls' Schools.
300 girls from around
the country at the science museum.
That's it. When is it?
- Now.
- Let's go.
Class trip.
Give me the phone, Osman.
Put the gun down,
or I hit the last number.
Ziva, get the kids off the bus,
nice and easy.
On it.
You don't want to do this.
It must be done.
Then you'll die, too.
Then I will die
a martyr for the cause.
McGee.
Got it, boss.
Signal-jammer, Osman.
That's why your detonator's dead.
You could have killed me.
Coulda, shoulda...
didn't.
You are weak.
No.
Just better.
Cuff him.
Get him out of here.
Thank you.
That was the Commandant.
Tell him he still owes me
dinner from 16 years ago.
He called to thank you personally.
Think he called to
thank you personally.
It's protocol.
You wanted to see me, Director?
I want you to take some time off.
And do what?
I don't know.
Do something fun.
Fun?
Fun.
Rest.
Recreate. Fish.
Build something.
Whatever you do.
I do this, Leon.
Pass on the vacation.
I am having dinner with
Lieutenant Flores.
She's doing great.
Thanks, anyway.
And, Leon...
this is fun.
Do I really have to do this?
Yes. Just relax, breathe.
- It's hot in here.
- No, it's not.
I'm sweating.
Maybe I'm having a heart attack.
My left arm is tingling,
I should go to the infirmary.
You'd rather go see
a doctor than do this?
- My God, DiNozzo, you're shaking.
- Of course I'm shaking.
- I'm having a heart attack.
- You're terrified.
Very Special Agent Anthony
DiNozzo doesn't get scared.
I've jumped out of airplanes,
dead-dropped onto aircraft carriers,
and I've killed people, sweetheart.
Lots of them.
I've gotten the plague,
kissed a transvestite,
and been tortured by the best
the Middle East has to offer.
And, still, you're shaking.
It's time to face my fears.
How bad can it be?
Bring it on, Chaplain.
Congratulations, Agent DiNozzo.
Your greatest fear,
is now about to have a snack
of grapes and cheese crackers.
You want to join them?
www.Team-NCIS.com
www.tvsubtitles.net