Downloaded from
xPau.se
(FANFARE PLAYING)
(MUSIC ENDS)
WOMAN (ON P.A.):
May I have your attention, please?
The curbside is for immediate loading
and unloading only.
No parking, waiting,
or stopping, until...
(CONTINUES SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(FAINT CHATTERING)
(CAR APPROACHES)
(BRAKES SQUEAK)
WOMAN (ON P.A.):
Attention, passengers...
- (CAR DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
- (LUGGAGE CLATTERING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
MAN: They should have more personnel.
I'm going to miss my flight.
I'm standing here for over an hour.
(BREATHING HARD)
Excuse me.
- Excuse me. I'm not in first class.
- Okay.
I'm on the Denver flight
that leaves in 40 minutes.
Could you check me in here?
I only have carry-on.
You're not gonna miss it.
That flight's been canceled.
If you go right over to customer service,
they can help you. I'm sorry.
I told you already.
Tomorrow morning is
the earliest flight I can put you on.
That's not good enough, okay?
I'm a surgeon.
I have an emergency surgery to perform
in Baltimore tomorrow, okay?
Look, he's 10 years old.
He's a 10-year-old boy.
Mark, I can come straight
from the airport if I have to.
Emma can meet me there
with the dress,
and I can just change
in the back of a cab.
Is my mother there?
Oh, Lord.
(LAUGHS)
I'll be there.
Oh, honey.
I'll be there, okay?
(SIGHS) Look, let me go,
so I can figure this out. Okay. Bye.
I'll fly wherever I have to tonight
to get there for tomorrow morning.
- Can you help me?
- MAN: I'm afraid there won't be
any more flights tonight because
of the storm coming through here.
- No, you said that.
- MAN: So, I would suggest...
WOMAN: I need to get
to Denver for the red-eye.
MAN:...that you get a voucher
before the hotels fill up.
- Right. Okay.
- WOMAN: Yes, hold on.
Yep. No, it's just me.
Could I get a pen? Uh-huh.
Yes.
MAN:
Hold on, one second, sweetheart.
WOMAN:
Sir? Sir, I'm sorry.
Sorry, I couldn't help hearing.
I think we may have the same problem.
I'm trying to get to Denver before dark,
so I can catch a red-eye to New York.
There's no rental cars.
I checked for rental cars.
He's told me that the flights
are canceled, so...
No, I know.
I have an idea.
What's your name?
Alex Martin.
Yours?
- Ben.
- Ah.
(HAMMERING)
ALEX:
Hello?
- Hello? Walter.
- That's me.
Alex. We spoke.
Yeah. Hey.
- Yeah.
- So, what's the rush?
Oh. Actually, I'm getting
married tomorrow, so...
Can't miss that, can you?
Congratulations.
- Oh, no, no. No, we're not together.
- No, we're not getting married.
- We just met.
- No.
I got a twin on the tarmac.
Can take two.
$800.
Done.
- (GROWLS)
- BEN: Oh!
- Hey!
- Don't worry about him. He loves people.
Oh, yeah? Hey!
- (BARKING)
- Whoa.
(CHUCKLES)
I won't be long.
You stick with the dog.
He'll let you know when I'm ready.
(GROWLS)
Hey. (CHUCKLES)
ALEX: We should check the time
of the Denver red-eye.
Midnight.
Gets into JFK about quarter to six.
I booked us a couple of tickets.
There weren't that many left.
- Oh, you did?
- Yeah.
ALEX:
Thank you.
Filed your flight plan?
No need to. Still light out.
I can go VFR.
BEN:
What about the storm?
- We'll beat it out.
- You sure?
Flew F-5s into Vietnam.
As long as nobody is shooting at me,
I'll get you there.
So, what took you to ldaho?
Medical conference.
You live in New York?
Baltimore.
But you're from England, right?
London.
- I married an American woman.
- Ah.
WALTER:
That there is the High Uintas Wilderness.
- Gets over 700 inches of snow a year.
- (CAMERA CLICKS)
- Million acres of pure-ass nature.
- (DOG BARKS)
Easy, boy. By the way,
I was stationed near London.
48th Fighter Wing at Mildenhall.
- ALEX: Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Met the love of my life there.
- You did? That's so romantic.
- (SEATBELT CLICKS)
- Where is she now?
- (DOG WHIMPERS)
Who knows? That was...
that was... fi-fi...
50 years ago.
Oh. What, you didn't marry her?
No, she was already married
to someone else.
- Oh!
- Anyway, I'm not the marrying kind.
I didn't wanna miss out on anything.
- (RATTLING)
- Oh!
You might wanna strap in.
What's that?
It's Candy Crush.
Ah.
I need to occupy my amygdala.
That's the reptile brain
that looks after...
Yeah, I know what an amygdala is.
What brought you to Idaho?
Shooting skinheads.
Neo-Nazis for The Guardian.
- A journalist?
- Uh-huh.
That would explain the questions.
(BARKS, GROWLS)
Hey, buddy.
WALTER:
Hey, stay out of the food, boy.
(THUNDER CRASHING)
Walter, you see that?
Storm must have moved.
Salt Lake Center.
(RADIO STATIC)
Salt Lake Center, this is twin zero-niner.
Uh, whiskey-niner.
Affirmative.
Squawking zero one.
- One.
- Walter?
O-one.
- (ENGINE ACCELERATING)
- Walter?
ALEX:
Shit.
- (SEATBELT CLICKS)
- Walter.
- (DOG BARKS)
- Squawking zero. Zero-two-zero.
- I-I don't... I-I don't...
- Walter.
- What's going on?
- What's wrong with your hands?
I think he's having a stroke.
Oh, my God. Is he okay?
I just need you to look at me, Walter.
Just look at me.
(ENGINE ACCELERATING)
Shit! Oh, my God!
Shit!
Jesus Christ.
What do we do?
Walter? Walter?
Just get on the radio.
Get on the radio.
This is twin zero...
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
ALEX:
Oh, my God! Jesus Christ!
- Okay, Walter.
- Shit!
- Okay. Just grab that!
- Oh, my God!
Shit!
- (THUDS)
- (ALEX YELPS)
The dog! The dog!
Shit! Oh, God!
(SCREAMS)
Put your seatbelt on.
- Put your hands behind your head!
- Okay!
- Put your hands...
- (METAL GROANING)
Sit back! Sit back!
(THUDDING)
(CRASHES)
Alex. Alex.
- (BREATHING HARD)
- (WIND BLOWING)
Hey! Alex.
Ah.
(INHALES SHARPLY, HUFFS)
Hey.
Yeah, you're there.
(BREATHING HARD)
Shit.
(BREATHES SHAKILY)
- (WHIMPERS)
- Oh great. You're alive.
(GROWLS)
Ah!
- (GROANS)
- (WATER DRIPPING)
- (BREATHING HARD)
- (DRIPPING)
(WIND BLOWING)
(PHONE CHIMES, CLICKS)
(WIND HOWLING)
(GASPS)
(DOG WHIMPERS)
(GROANS)
(ECHOING) Hey!
Hello!
Anybody!
Anybody.
- (BEN GRUNTS)
- (FIRE CRACKLING)
(WIND WHISTLING)
(WIND BLOWING)
(WHIMPERS)
God bless you.
(FIRE CRACKLING)
(BREATHING SHALLOWLY)
(MOANS)
(MOANING)
(GROANS)
- Hey. Hi.
- Ah!
Hey, Alex.
Hi. Alex?
Hi. Hey. Okay. Alex.
- Mark?
- Can you look at me?
- Left home.
- There you go.
- Oh, thank God.
- Mark. Where's Mark?
- Thank God.
- (BABBLES)
I need my phone!
You want your phone.
Alex?
Alex, your phone's smashed.
My phone has no signal,
and we're pretty high up.
- But we're alive.
- Oh, my leg!
Try and sit up,
and I'll give you some water.
What's your name?
- My name?
- What's your name?
There you go. I'm Ben.
Well done.
What?
- I have some Advil in my backpack.
- Oh. Yeah.
Yeah, you do.
I found them when
I was changing your trousers.
(PILLS RATTLE)
Are you okay?
Couple of bruises, few scratches,
couple of cracked ribs.
I'm okay. I got lucky.
The pilot?
I buried him yesterday.
(PILLS CLATTER)
He... He didn't file a flight plan.
No. No, but there was radio contact.
How long has it been?
36 hours.
There was a thing in the manual
about a beacon.
Yeah, it would've been in the tail.
God knows where that ended up.
Oh, Jesus. Mark has no idea where I am.
He'll be going out of his mind.
Okay. Okay.
Someone is definitely coming to get us.
We've got plenty of water,
as long as we can melt the snow.
We've got four packets of almonds...
couple of candy bars...
a half-eaten sandwich, and some cookies.
That should hold us until we're rescued.
(GRUNTS)
What kind of cookies?
What?
Joke.
(GRUNTING)
(BANGING)
(BREATHING HARD)
(DOG WHIMPERS)
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTING CONTINUES)
Oh, God.
- (SNAPS)
- (JET PASSING OVERHEAD)
Plane.
Plane! I need the flare! Flare!
Quick! (GRUNTS)
- Alex, give me the flare gun.
- In here! Here!
Take it!
- No, wait, wait. It's empty!
- (POPS)
- Ben!
- I need a flare.
- Here!
- (GRUNTS)
- (BARKING)
- Quick! Hurry!
ALEX:
Hey!
Down here! Down here!
- They can't hear you.
- I know!
It's... it's...
(CRIES)
It's just what you do.
Okay.
We're down to the rule of three.
We can go three weeks without food,
three days without water...
- What?
- ...three minutes without air.
Let me help. Let me help.
BEN: You wanna help?
This is how you help.
You stay off the leg.
That would help you,
and it would definitely help me.
Please?
BEN:
Anything that will burn.
Here.
BEN:
You took these?
- Uh-huh.
- They're good.
I'm sorry you missed your wedding.
I can't stop thinking about him
not knowing I'm alive.
You told him
you were chartering a flight, right?
No.
I was gonna call him
when we got to Denver,
and have him be all proud of me
for figuring it out.
I would have got there.
Even if it meant rushing
down the aisle like...
like Dustin Hoffman in The Graduate.
Someone's gonna find us.
You called someone.
You called your wife, right?
No.
Nobody?
I think Dustin Hoffman was
trying to stop the wedding
in The Graduate.
What?
He was banging on the window.
"Elaine!"
Yeah, yeah.
I remember now.
(WIND BLOWING)
Yeah. Yeah?
I have to pee.
- You have to what?
- I have to pee.
Need help with your trousers?
No.
Yeah.
- Scoop your bum.
- (GRUNTS)
Thanks. Thanks.
I got it. I got it.
Thank you.
(TINKLING)
Okay.
Ben.
It looks pretty healthy.
Cool.
What are you doing?
It's been three days.
(DOG WHIMPERS)
We're down to individual almonds.
- We should get moving.
- No.
- It's just best we stay here. Yeah?
- Oh God.
You're not gonna get far with that leg.
No way, Ben.
I'm not staying here. Come on.
I see. There's no...
Alex, stop!
Then you go.
- Huh?
- I can't go!
You wouldn't... you wouldn't...
(SIGHS)
You wouldn't make it without me.
And I'm still telling you to go.
How hard is it for you just to sit still?
- (HUMPHS)
- (DOG WHINES)
(DOOR OPENS)
- (GRUNTS)
- Alex. Okay, okay, okay.
There's a ridge up there.
I'll hike it, climb it, and see
if I can see a road or anything, okay?
- Okay.
Wait, wait, wait. Take this.
(BEEPS)
You can use the telephoto.
You'll be able to see farther.
Hey.
It's okay if you don't come back.
What?
I got you into this, so...
I'll understand.
Alex, if I wanted to leave...
I would have left three days ago.
(TARP RUSTLES)
Oh, yeah.
- Oh!
- (WHIMPERS)
(BRUSHING TEETH)
How do I look?
- (ROCKS CLATTERING)
- (GASPS)
(INHALES, SIGHS)
(WHINES)
Stop.
If I can't have it...
- you can't have it.
- (MOANS)
(GRUNTS) Shit.
Okay.
Let's see.
She's pretty.
Don't look at me like that.
(BREATHING HARD)
(BIRD CAWING)
(WIND BLOWING)
(CLICKS, CHIMES)
BEN: Date. July 7.
Endoscopic-assisted management.
- (BEEPS)
- WOMAN: Hey, Ben. Surprise!
I can't believe you left
your little recorder unattended.
It's very unlike you.
I know you like to keep control of things.
Mmm, maybe that's unfair.
I've already said this...
but I wanted you to have it for good.
I'm happy that we've had
this time together...
no matter how bad things have gotten.
- (BEEPS)
- (SIGHS)
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTS)
(SHOUTS)
(SCREAMING)
(ROCKS CLATTERING)
(GRUNTING)
- (FOOTSTEPS)
- (BARKING)
Ben?
Ben!
- (FOOTSTEPS)
- (BARKING)
Okay, stop.
Stop, stop, stop.
- (FOOTSTEPS)
- (BARKING)
Oh, my God!
Jesus Christ!
What the hell is that?
- What is that?
- (GROWLING)
What is that?
- (BARKING CONTINUES)
Oh, my God.
Shit!
No! Quiet! Quiet!
- (BARKING, SNARLS)
- Stop! Stop!
(GROWLS, HISSES)
Hey! Hey!
Hey, come back.
Come back.
- Come back!
- (COUGAR SCREECHING)
- God, no!
- (DOG WHINING)
(ALEX CRYING)
Oh, God!
(BARKING)
(SNARLING)
Oh, God.
(GROWLING)
(SNARLS)
(CLICKS)
Oh, God.
(GROWLS)
(SCREECHES)
(SHOT ECHOES)
Alex?
Hey!
(DOG WHIMPERS)
- What happened?
- It was a cougar.
Can you help him?
- God. Jesus.
- Oh, wow.
- (YELPS, GROANS)
- Okay. All right. Okay.
Easy, easy, easy.
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
- You okay?
- I'm okay.
- How did he get in here?
- No, I...
Well, he did... he didn't get in.
I-I... yeah, I got the...
- I grabbed the flare.
- Flare?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- This boy almost got it.
- Wait.
- You really shot that cougar with a flare?
- Uh-huh.
(DOG GROANS, WHINING)
Did you check your phone?
There's nothing.
(GRUNTS, SIGHS)
What's your wife's name?
Sarah.
I hope I get to meet her.
She must be so worried about you.
Oh, God.
Do you have kids?
No.
(MEAT SIZZLING)
BEN:
Don't eat too quickly.
Your stomach could cramp up.
- (WHINES)
- You know, that was a close one.
That should last us for about 10 days...
which is great, because we're stuck here.
I was thinking...
If we could get down low enough...
maybe we could get enough
signal on your phone.
No. No, forget the phone.
There's no signal.
I think the search and rescue probably...
Well, they haven't found us yet, so...
I know, but they're less likely
to find us if we leave here.
They'll be focusing their search
on the beacon.
Jesus Christ, Ben.
No, there's a system here, Alex.
Yeah, systems fail all the time.
They haven't found us.
We have to get going.
You know, you wanted to wait.
I waited.
Alex, honestly,
it's too dangerous, okay?
I nearly fell off a cliff. Okay?
I honestly nearly died.
If we stay here, we're safe.
If we leave...
Look, I don't wanna die up here
because you're too scared
to take a risk.
Hey, I'm not gonna fall off a mountain
because you're reckless and selfish.
What?
You know what?
You're absolutely right.
You did get me into this.
(KNIFE CLANKS)
(SCOFFS)
I was trying to be nice.
- Wait a second. No.
- I was trying to help!
- I was trying to help you.
- No. Hold on a second.
You weren't trying to help me.
You know, I could be married by now.
Do you ever think about that?
Is that what we're talking about?
Your ceremony?
My God, poor Mark!
What about my patient?
You think about that?
Yeah? Do you think about my patient?
Don't blame me for your fucking problems,
'cause if it wasn't for me, you'd be dead.
You're the lucky one.
Unlike me.
I'm stuck with you.
I would've had a much better chance
if I didn't have you around, honestly.
Okay. (BREATHING HARD)
Let's go.
He's probably gonna eat you, anyway.
(DOG WHINES)
We'll find something.
Just keep walking.
(GASPS)
(ECHOES)
Alex!
No.
Okay.
- Hey.
- (CLICKS)
Smile.
(CLICKS)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
(LABORED BREATHING)
Don't give up.
BEN (SHOUTS):
Alex!
(DOG BARKING)
You could have said goodbye.
I had to try.
I had to try my way.
I'm just so glad I found you.
Me too.
ALEX:
So...
do we go back?
No, we wouldn't make it back.
We have to get down to the tree line.
- Keep moving.
- Okay.
(GROANS) Okay.
Tell me something.
What?
Tell me about your wedding.
My wedding?
Yeah.
Didn't you hear?
I missed it.
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah.
No... can't talk.
You tell me something.
Tell me, what...
what kind of a doctor are you?
- Oh.
- Um...
I'm a neurosurgeon.
Oh, yeah? Yes.
Yeah. Brains. Why brains?
It's an intense responsibility,
you know, to...
cut into someone's brain.
It's where their perceptions are...
their intelligence...
their emotion.
ALEX:
What about the heart?
Huh?
The heart's nothing but a muscle.
BEN:
That's it, boy.
- (ALEX GRUNTS)
- We made it to the tree line.
Let's find shelter.
- (MUMBLES)
- (DOG BARKING)
I think something's here.
This cave will work.
Come on.
(WIND BLOWING)
Yeah. Yeah.
- Here.
- Ah.
I know.
Oh, jeez. It's freezing.
Quite a bit of swelling there.
- Any better?
- Yeah. That does look better.
- Look at that bandage.
- Yeah.
It's holding up actually.
Hey, you know what would be funny?
If you weren't really a doctor.
Why would that be funny?
Well, you'd just be doing all this
so you could see my fancy underwear.
They're not that fancy.
(CHUCKLES)
All right.
Thank you.
It's okay.
Where's your gloves?
(BLOWS)
God, Jesus.
Shit, you're freezing.
Here, come on.
There.
Better?
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
I owe you an apology.
I did find that beacon.
I saw it.
It was smashed to pieces.
No, you didn't know that
when you came looking for me, did you?
I think we should stay together.
I mean...
stick together.
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah.
It's the best chance we have at survival.
I know, I'm sorry.
Jeez, I'm sorry... for all of it.
I'm only telling you 'cause I don't
wanna be left on this mountain by myself.
(HUMPHS)
Me neither.
You wouldn't eat me, would you, boy?
(GROWLS)
(MUMBLES)
- Alex.
- (GASPS)
(SHIVERS)
You were talking in your sleep.
Yeah, I forgot to say, "I love you."
- Who?
- I didn't say, "I love you," to Mark...
- Oh.
- ...when I talked to him from the airport.
You know, at the end of the call,
you know, always say, "I love you."
He knows.
Of course he does.
Thank you.
(WIND BLOWING)
I'm gonna take a look around.
You want coffee?
(WHIRS)
BEN:
Well, I can't see anything now.
A little lower than that, I think. It's...
You know, it could have been anything...
just sunlight reflecting
off some ice, maybe.
Or man-made.
Huh?
We should check it out, though.
I mean, we only got
three days left of food.
Let me help you with that.
Can I ask you something?
How long have you been married?
Why would you ask me that?
- I'm only asking because...
- Because what?
Well, you wear a wedding ring, but...
but you don't talk about your wife.
Let's try to find out what that was.
(SIGHS)
- Come on, buddy.
- (BARKS)
BEN: Let's try to get there
before it gets dark.
All right?
Yeah.
- That's it. Up, up, up.
- (GRUNTS)
Good, good, good. Okay.
(BREATHING HARD)
(BEN GRUNTS)
Come on, boy. Let's go.
- (DOG WHINING)
- BEN: I reckon we're...
another thousand feet down.
He hates his leash.
I'm gonna let him go.
Almost looks like he knows
where he's going.
I think he was safer on the leash.
Come on.
- Another hour...
- Okay, okay.
...then we'll stop.
(WATER CRASHING)
Oh, shit.
ALEX:
No, no, no!
No! Damn it!
This is impossible!
We have to try and go back up, Alex.
Find another way around this.
Look, I can't go up, can I?
There has to be a way down.
No. We just gotta go back
and find another way.
I think if we follow this path...
Alex, we're not doing that.
We follow that path, and we... and we die.
The last time you thought
you knew something, we ended up...
What do you mean,
the last time I thought?
The last time I thought,
I was trusting my instincts, you know.
- Alex. Calm down.
- I was trusting my gut, my heart.
Just calm down, all right?
Let's just think about this logically.
- There's no actual way...
- Stop!
I'm scared.
Okay? I'm scared.
Admit that you're scared, too.
Ben...
do you actually know
what it means to be reckless?
It means to abandon safety.
- I know exactly what it means, Alex.
- And sometimes...
- But right now...
- Right now,
we don't have a choice, okay?
Nobody knows where we are.
You know, all we have is me and you.
That is it, Ben.
I don't want to die! Okay?
Tell me, Doctor, from your heart.
Do you a... Do you actually think
we're gonna make it?
No.
My instinct tells me
that we're gonna die up here.
But we do have a choice.
And we're still alive.
(WATER CRASHING)
(WATER ROARING)
(GRUNTS)
(ALEX GRUNTS)
(BOTH BREATHING HARD)
BEN:
Here we go. There we go.
We're both tired.
Sorry.
Just get on with it now, yeah?
We just have to get on with it.
Yeah.
Okay.
We must be...
a couple of thousand feet downhill by now.
Your phone.
We should check... We should check it.
My phone.
(BEEPS)
We should just see
how much juice you have left.
There is no reception.
- Haven't got much battery left.
- (BEEPS)
You were listening to something.
At the airport.
Probably shouldn't...
Could you just, for one minute,
please just...
just give us one percent?
(BEEPS)
Just one percent of something.
(CLASSICAL PIANO MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC CONTINUING)
BEN: Are we still headed
towards the flash you saw?
ALEX:
Yeah. It's way down this way.
(BOTH GRUNT)
I'm good. I'm good. I'm good.
Just look how beautiful that is.
I want you to take a picture of me.
What?
If I'm gonna die...
I want this to be my very last picture.
- (BREATHLESS) I can't.
- I want you to take it.
(SCOFFS)
How do I look?
I was halfway through an assignment.
Um...
(SCOFFS)
I got close to... to a group of girls.
Guerrilla fighters.
You know, they... they let me follow them.
There was this one girl, she...
she told me all about this boy she liked,
and, you know...
and I gave her my lipstick.
Then...
there was an explosion...
and she...
was badly injured.
I was there.
I went to help her.
She was still breathing then, but...
she was beyond hope.
I...
I went into my bag...
to get out my... camera.
She looked at me.
I looked at her.
I took her picture.
And then she died.
I can't take your picture.
I'm sorry.
(CASE CLICKING)
We're not gonna die.
Not today.
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
Shit.
(GRUNTS)
ALEX:
Where are we going?
BEN:
We're alive.
That's where we're going.
ALEX:
We've been walking for three days.
(GRUNTS) We haven't found anything.
BEN:
Let's hope this valley leads us there.
ALEX:
Can we stop? For a minute?
BEN:
Yeah.
That's it.
- Jeez.
- You okay?
Okay. Yeah.
Just... Just put your leg up.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
How about an ice-cold drink?
Sure.
Thank you.
How about some ice with that?
You're funny.
I am getting used to the cold, though.
- Yeah.
- Which is weird.
Yeah, well, your body...
your body's acclimatizing.
It's quite ingenious, what God did.
Your body sort of figures it out.
ALEX:
Where's the dog?
BEN: We can't call him
'cause we don't know his name.
You're going to ask me to go
look for the dog, aren't you?
(CHUCKLES)
BEN:
Yeah.
Come on, man.
BEN:
Hey!
(WHINING)
Here, boy.
What are you doing?
(BARKS)
What are you eating?
Been holding out on us?
(ICE CRACKING)
Ben?
- (KNOCKS)
- BEN: Hello?
Nobody here?
(DOG WHINES)
Hey, Ben!
(ICE CRACKING)
Ben!
Ben?
- (ICE CRACKS)
- (YELPS)
Alex! Alex!
(GRUNTS)
Ah! Come on!
Come on!
Shit!
Come on.
Alex!
(WIND BLOWING)
(WATER DRIPPING)
Okay.
- (WOOD CREAKING)
- (WIND BLOWING)
(HOLLOW THUD)
(PIANO PLAYS DISCORDANT NOTES)
I'm scared.
And if you don't wake up soon...
I think I warmed you up too fast.
You're severely dehydrated.
I found a syringe
of medicine for snake bites.
Emptied it out
and jerry-rigged an IV of saline fluid.
Now, it could go wrong, Alex.
Infection or something, but...
I think you'd want me to do this.
I know you would.
You'd tell me trust my instincts
or something.
(WIND BLOWING)
(PIANO PLAYS LOW NOTE)
(WHINES)
- (WEAKLY) Ben.
- Alex.
(MOANS)
Did we get rescued?
(SIGHS) No.
(CHUCKLES)
No, we didn't.
Thank God you're back.
This is that cabin you saw.
Can you help me pee?
I thought you'd never ask.
(CHUCKLES)
You're gonna feel a bit dizzy.
Okay.
You should have some.
I have.
Thank you.
Here.
So...
So, tell me something.
What else happened when I was away?
Well, you didn't miss much.
Snowdrifts are 10-feet deep.
I know, 'cause
I was nearly buried in it twice.
But I did find two cans of soup.
What happens now?
We just have to wait
for a break in the weather.
Then at least we can see
where we're going.
Mmm. (SCOFFS)
It's January.
How long...
How long can we survive
on two cans of soup?
Ben.
We've been lost almost three weeks.
Don't you wanna get home?
(WIND BLOWING)
(INHALES SHARPLY)
I'll find a way.
(WIND BLOWING)
(FRUSTRATED GROAN)
(WHINING)
(BREATHES HARD)
(DOG BARKING)
(BARKING CONTINUES)
Hey!
- (BEEPS)
- (BARKING CONTINUES)
SARAH:
Hey, Ben.
Surprise.
Get it, boy!
Grab that rabbit. Go on!
Go on, boy!
Where'd he go?
- Get him!
- (GROWLS)
No.
You got it. Come on.
Did you get him?
Huh? Dig!
SARAH: I can't believe
you left your little recorder unattended.
I know you like to keep control of things.
- (DOG GROWLS)
- (FRUSTRATED GROAN)
- (WHINES)
- Okay.
Come on.
Ah! Bullshit!
(DOG PANTING)
Okay, you tried.
- But I wanted you to have it for good.
- (DOOR SLAMS OPEN)
- (BEN MUMBLES)
- No matter how bad things have...
(BEEPS)
- I'm... I'm sorry. Umm...
- What are you doing?
What are you doing?
- I... I shouldn't have done that, Ben.
- Jesus, Alex.
- I'm really sorry.
- I turn my back for two minutes,
and you go through
all my stuff. Is that it?
(RECORDER CLATTERS)
ALEX:
No, that's not it. That's not it.
I just...
We might die together.
And I don't even know you.
You wanna get to know me? Play it.
Play it.
(BEEPS)
SARAH: I'm happy that we've had
this time together...
no matter how bad things have gotten.
And I'm sorry that I'm leaving.
I'll always love you.
You just...
This is not something
that you can control.
- Love you, bye.
- (BEEPS)
(WIND BLOWING)
I want you to know...
this was a really unfair way
of me trying to understand who you are.
And I'm sorry.
I haven't heard that message in...
two years.
(DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
(DOOR OPENS)
I'm gonna go cut more wood.
(SIGHS)
I'm not like you, Alex.
I still can't talk about it.
(DEEP SIGH)
- Mmm.
- (SIGHS)
- (GRUNTS)
- (INHALES DEEPLY)
(WIND BLOWING)
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(BREATHING HARD)
(CLICKS)
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
(CLICKING)
(CAMERA CLICKS)
(SIGHS) Morning.
Morning.
Ben...
I've been thinking.
There has to be a road.
We must be close to something.
I'm trying...
to find us a way.
You'll make it faster if I stay here.
I don't wanna leave you here.
I might not even make it.
- (DOG WHINES)
- But you have to.
We can't just stay here.
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
Alex, my wife didn't leave me
the way you think she did.
We were married happily...
for eight years.
She got sick.
A brain tumor.
My wife became my patient.
And I couldn't save her.
She died.
I'm so sorry.
- (WIND BLOWING)
- (SOMBER MUSIC PLAYS)
Alex.
You're coming with me.
I'm gonna get you home.
I'll slow you down.
- I can't leave. Not without you.
- What?
(ALEX GROANS)
(ALEX GRUNTS)
- Oh! (GRUNTS)
- (DOG WHINING)
ALEX:
I can't. I'm sorry.
BEN (WHISPERS):
We're gonna get there.
(BEN PANTING)
(ALEX MOANS)
(WIND BLOWING)
(GRUNTS)
(WHINES)
(BARKING)
(DISTANT BANGING)
(CHUCKLING)
Alex!
Alex.
Come on. Come on.
Please, please. Come on.
Come on. We're here.
We're here. We're here.
Come on, come on.
(GRUNTS)
Alex.
(DISTANT BANGING, WHIRRING)
Alex, do you see that?
- Yeah, I see.
- Alex.
I see it. I see.
(BREATHING HARD)
Oh, God.
(CLACKING)
(BOTH BREATHING HARD)
Ben?
I know.
Won't say anything.
I won't say anything.
(CRYING)
ALEX:
Where's the dog?
- He'll find us. Come on.
- Yeah.
(SIGHS)
(SHOUTS)
Come here, boy!
Walter's dog, come here!
Hey, buddy. Come here.
What are you doing?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
No! Come here.
Now! Now! Here!
See what that is?
We gotta go. Let's go.
There you go.
We need to get out of here.
We're almost home.
- (CLANKS)
- (SCREAMING)
Ben?
Alex!
Ben!
(SCREAMS)
ALEX:
Ben?
- (CHAIN CLINKS)
- (SHOUTS)
(CRYING)
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
- Jesus! Jesus.
- Alex.
Jesus Christ.
What... what are we gonna do?
(CREAKING)
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTS)
No! No! Alex. Alex!
Please! No. No. Just...
Alex.
(SOBBING)
- Ah! Alex!
- (GASPS)
(PANTING, MUMBLES)
Go get... Go get... Go get help.
Okay.
Christ.
(CHAIN CLINKS)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
(WIND BLOWING)
- (BEEPING)
- (BANGING)
- (GRUNTING)
- (HEAVY MACHINERY RUMBLING)
Stop!
(BRAKES SQUEAK)
BEN:
Alex?
(MONITORS BEEPING FAINTLY)
(MONITORS BEEPING)
BEN:
Alex?
(BUTTON CLICKS)
WOMAN:
We need a doctor in 111 immediately.
Dr. Bass?
Yeah.
ALEX:
Oh, Ben.
(SIGHS)
(MUMBLES)
Oh, my God.
ALEX:
Oh, God.
We made it.
You... Can you believe it?
Yeah.
Your hands, let me see.
- Look at your hands.
- I know. I won't be...
I won't be knitting for a while.
(CHUCKLES)
I feel alive.
I feel alive because of you.
Yeah.
(TOILET FLUSHES)
Oh. I want you to meet Mark.
You're Mark.
Yeah. Ben, right?
Yeah.
BEN:
Oh, man.
Yeah. I can't begin to...
Thank you.
Yeah.
ALEX:
- Yeah? Okay, babe?
- Yeah. Yeah.
So, this is Ben.
Yeah, I know. I know.
Wow, it's Mark.
Good. It's good to, uh...
it's good to meet you.
Alex told me how you saved her life.
Yes. No.
No, you saved my life, Alex.
- ALEX: Ben. Ben.
- Umm...
It's true.
Yeah.
BEN:
Umm...
They're chasing me.
I need to go back, okay?
(MUTTERS)
All right.
(WOMAN SPEAKING ON P.A.)
Careful. Here you go.
(WIND BLOWING)
(CRYING)
Come here. Come here.
- (WOOFS)
- Come here.
- (CLINKS)
- Go on.
(WOOFS)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Mrs. Qabbani, how are you?
Are you feeling better?
How is your arm? Let me see.
MAN (ON TV): We're really serious
about this type of criminality.
MAN 2 (ON TV):
Yes, but in the end, that won't matter,
for the public and businesses
when shopping online.
Retailers are highly impacted
by retail crime.
And we estimated cost to be
somewhere around 1.3 billion pounds,
which will impact everyone, including...
(FIRE CRACKLING)
(WHINES)
- ALEX: Don't leave me.
- MARK: I'm not.
- (PEOPLE CHATTERING)
- It's our party, you know?
I know, but, you know.
- Honey...
- I don't wanna be...
(LAUGHS) I just don't
wanna be by myself.
These are our friends
to welcome you.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Everybody okay?
You all have drinks? Need anything?
Could use a little ice,
actually, if you don't mind.
Oh, that's really funny.
(LAUGHS)
Oh, Pam! Hi!
How are you?
- I'm fine, dear.
- Great to see you.
- (BOTH KISS)
- Look at you. You look wonderful.
- Oh, thank you.
- You know,
I don't want to pry, I don't want
to be inappropriate,
but I'm sure that you took some pictures
during your ordeal.
Oh. Umm...
This is an amazing story,
and I expect those photos
are amazing, too.
I really think people
would like to see them.
Well, I... (SIGHS)
You know, Pam, I'm not really...
I'm not really ready for that.
- Will you think about it?
- Yeah, sure. Yeah.
Yeah. I'll think about it.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(RAIN PATTERING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
- (BREATHING HARD)
- (LINE RINGING)
- (PHONE RINGING)
- (PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(CLICKS)
(BEEPS)
Hi, Ben.
It's Alex again.
Just calling to say hi.
Try me back.
(PHONE CLICKS)
Tell you what. We'll skip out early,
you know, once the thing's over.
We can leave before the reception.
Hey.
What?
It's all right.
- Was... did you...
- Yeah, no.
I was just talking about the fund-raisers.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Sorry.
Alex, I...
I get that you haven't wanted
to talk about this...
but... I... I know
what I'm in with you.
I always told myself I'd...
I'd get some call from somewhere.
So, I made a deal with myself.
That I would always love you,
even if you came home missing
a piece of yourself.
- (SIZZLING)
- (SCRAPING)
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(COUGHS, GASPS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(LIGHT CLICKS)
(CHEMICALS SLOSH, DRIP)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(PACKAGE RUSTLES)
(SIGHS)
(CARS HONKING IN DISTANCE)
(PHONE RINGING)
- (CLICKS)
- (RINGING STOPS)
Hello?
(HORNS HONKING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Hi. I'm sorry I'm later than I...
You look brand-new.
- Oh, so... so do you.
- How are you?
Yeah. Good.
Sit down.
WOMAN:
Can I get you something to drink?
Oh, no.
Just water's fine, thanks.
BOTH:
So, how are you?
How's your leg?
How's yours?
(LAUGHS) Yeah.
I can't run, but I get by.
(CHUCKLES)
I kept the dog.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
So what'd you call him?
Umm... dog.
- (LAUGHS) He still...
- (LAUGHS) No.
He still doesn't have a name.
You look... You look...
You look beautiful, Alex.
Thank you.
How is everything?
Umm, good.
I'm working with people more.
Post-trauma patients,
you know, the extreme cases.
I sort of float between a NHS clinic
and a rehabilitation center
in South London, where I live now.
- It's good to be home.
- No more surgery?
No. No, I can't do that anymore.
And you? How are you?
I'm okay, too. Yeah.
I... I came home and...
everything had shifted, but...
I kind of had to wait it out,
but it's okay.
No more conflict zones.
And the last thing
I feel like doing is getting on a plane.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
So I'm teaching now, part-time,
staying closer to home.
BEN:
Yeah.
How was it?
How was the wedding?
Oh. We didn't have one.
What?
What? You didn't...
No.
I couldn't.
Mark is a really wonderful man, but...
but I...
I couldn't.
I'm really sorry, Alex. That's...
(SIGHS)
Why didn't you tell me?
You're not that great
at picking up the phone.
Are you guys hungry?
- No.
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
I didn't pick up my phone
'cause I thought you were married, Alex.
I thought you were married.
You could have called back.
It was hard enough
for me to lose Sarah.
I struggled with the idea
of losing you, too.
And then when you sent
those photographs...
I, uh... I felt alive.
I really did. I...
We made it, you and I.
(BREATHES SHAKILY)
And I had to see you.
I loved you on that mountain.
I tried to pretend that I didn't,
but I did.
I came home and nothing was the same.
And then I tried to reach you, and it...
(SIGHS) it was so...
It was just too painful.
So I had to...
make myself accept
that maybe it wasn't real,
and it would never work,
not in real life.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
There's a moment for these things,
and then it... it passes.
Hey, so...
Could you... Could you give
the dog a name?
He kind of deserves it.
I think you're wrong, Alex.
I think we survived
because we fell in love.
Up there it was just...
it was just me and you.
The world is bigger than that.
And the heart is just a muscle.
Right?
What idiot said that?
(SIGHS)
(SOBBING)
(POP MUSIC PLAYS)
♪ Not tryna be indie ♪
♪ Not tryna be cool ♪
♪ Just tryna be in this ♪
♪ Tell me how you choose ♪
♪ Can you feel
where the wind is? ♪
♪ Can you feel it through? ♪
♪ All of the windows ♪
♪ Inside this room ♪
♪ 'Cause I wanna touch you, baby ♪
♪ And I wanna feel you, too ♪
♪ I wanna see the sunrise
and your sins ♪
♪ Just me and you ♪
♪ Light it up ♪
♪ On the run ♪
♪ Let's make love, tonight ♪
♪ Make it up ♪
♪ Fall in love, try ♪
(DISTORTED)
♪ But you'll never be alone ♪
♪ I'll be with you
from dusk till dawn ♪
♪ I'll be with you from
dusk till dawn ♪
♪ Baby, I'm right here ♪
♪ I'll hold you
when things go wrong ♪
♪ I'll be with you
from dusk till dawn ♪
♪ Baby, I'm right here... ♪
♪ I'll be with you
from dusk till dawn ♪
♪ Baby, I'm right here ♪
♪ We were shut like a jacket ♪
♪ So do your zip ♪
♪ We will roll down the rapids ♪
♪ To find a wave that fits ♪
♪ Can you feel where the wind is? ♪
♪ Can you feel it through? ♪
♪ All of the windows ♪
♪ Inside this room ♪
♪ 'Cause I wanna touch you, baby ♪
♪ I wanna feel you, too ♪
♪ I wanna see the sunrise
and your sins ♪
♪ Just me and you ♪
♪ Light it up, on the run ♪
♪ Let's make love tonight ♪
♪ Make it up ♪
♪ Fall in love, try ♪
(DISTORTED)
♪ But you'll never be alone ♪
♪ I'll be with you
from dusk till dawn ♪
♪ I'll be with you from
dusk till dawn ♪
♪ Baby, I'm right here ♪
♪ I'll hold you when things go wrong ♪
♪ I'll be with you from dusk till dawn ♪
♪ Baby, I'm right here ♪
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)