I found a van for you.
When do you want it?
- When are you getting the blood?
- I can't get that much blood in one day.
- You're getting it in batches?
- Yeah...
- About a thousand litres.
- That's a lot, yeah?
- We do it at my place or here?
- I can get people to my home
and we can work there,
even through the night.
You'll get paid tomorrow.
You know everyone was asking
what are the containers for.
And we said they're
meant for honey.
Let's fill these ones.
- How many are they?
- Enough.
We've got a thousand litres of blood.
What is that?
It's okay. I don't want to know.
Naila! Come, come, come.
I'll leave you guys
to your party.
Let's go.
This is actually
the first part.
The World Bank
says Kenya is growing faster
than any other Sub-Saharan
African nation.
But there is one major impediment
to the country's continued growth.
Kenya has been run dismally
as one of the most corrupt
countries in the world.
We've found some pigs.
We can go pick them up.
We still have time.
Did you guys bring the paint?
MP!
The MP is looking for its salary.
Don't disturb it!
Now you see how you're going
to paint that guy! He's running away.
The rumour is that we'll show up
with caskets and dead people.
We've really confused them!
Parliament is not for profit!
It belongs to the people!
This is a gift for
the Members of Parliament!
Take your gifts MPs!
Stop chasing the Member of Parliament!
Get the hell out of here!
We want peace!
Stop beating him!
Why are you beating us?
Stop the oppression!
We are taxpayers!
Gentlemen.
This conference is of
crucial importance
to the future of Kenya.
Upon the degree of our
success or failure,
will depend the well-being,
the livelihood, and perhaps even
the physical safety
of all the citizens of Kenya
of whatever race or creed.
Kenya's vice president
has denied orchestrating post-election
violence since 2007
that left more than a thousand dead
and 500,000 homeless.
Drama that erupted.
The police lobbed tear gas canisters
at a group aged between
six to fourteen years.
Despite what happened here today,
the organizers of this movement
are vowing to fight on.
They say this is a battle that goes
to the very heart of democracy in Kenya.
No, Nate, Nate, Nate, share.
Please share.
No, no, no, no.
Just give it to him.
You're the big brother.
You're watching TV, you're playing.
Good job.
Our protest has been banned.
Yeah by the government. They say
we're planning to topple the government
and that we're funded by USAID.
We need to go. Freedom Corner
is actually an open place for anyone to go.
So what do we do?
So we go.
There will be violence today.
I don't know how. Help me.
Yeah.
Go get that spoon now.
It's good for us to get arrested so the people
can know this government is intolerant.
I tell people, President Uhuru
is not a tolerant person
and they don't believe me.
Guys, man, let's do this.
- So you'll go with Mummy.
- Where are you going?
I'm going to topple the government.
Get off the bike, sweetie.
Daddy, I want to go with you.
You can't go with me because
I'm going to a very dangerous place.
And welcome to Capital Talk.
The program we hope will have
an impact on the future of Kenya.
My guest today is a
rebel with a cause.
Twice CNN Photographer of
the Year, Boniface Mwangi.
Folks, this young man
is one word: fearless.
I'd always wanted
to cover war.
As a news photographer, I wanted
to cover action, violence.
Kill him!
2007 was a life-changing
year for me.
Immediately after they
announced the elections,
there was burning and violence.
My very first photo
was a man coming home from work.
Some people stopped him and asked him,
"What tribe are you?"
When he said he's Luo,
they cut him with machetes.
They just messed him up.
He showed his ID saying,
"I am a Kenyan."
And the police looked at him, they did
not do anything because of his tribe.
I could go, take pictures
in the slums of Mathare, Kibera,
then come back to the
newsroom in the city center
and guys are having coffee
like everything is normal.
Every day I covered violence.
Every day I filed my pictures.
Every day they decided not to publish
my photos because they were too violent.
And every day I got more pissed
and more pissed.
The violence ended on February 28th
and about seven to eight
months later, I quit my job.
I can't stand politicians.
I can't stand the hypocrisy.
I thought, something was amiss.
Please, let's keep walking
so that others have a chance to look.
You can see his head hanging.
I have never seen such things.
Was it like this?
The head being beaten
until it falls down.
This is so bad.
These people need
to be arrested.
All those who did this.
Look at this.
He was just left hanging.
And people are just
walking by without caring.
Whom do they want to lead?
If they want to make us kill each other.
They want to lead fools.
They eat together while
we are here fighting.
We kill our friends while they
eat together peacefully.
Their kids are in good
schools studying.
While we stay in poverty.
Let's burn these!
Burn them!
The country is ours!
Politicians lied to us.
That's why there was violence.
Open your eyes! It's young
people who were affected.
You are being misled.
Can't you see?
I want to show that
you've been blinded.
I knew... he was going
to be very outspoken about issues
and he wants things to change.
That's the guy I met.
And probably that's the guy
I fell in love with
because he was very ambitious
in the sense that
he saw a different Kenya
in five, ten years to come.
Like things could change
and they needed to change.
You may kiss your wife.
They signed the Peace Treaty
on a week before our wedding.
And he broke down at our wedding.
Now when I think about it,
maybe it had something to do with it.
That he has actually lived
to that moment
to see himself getting
married and he's with a child.
- Look at Daddy!
- Hi Nate!
These are the embarrassing pictures
that children are shown when
they are a little older.
When I look to write
my list of achievements,
they're not the kind that
you can write on paper.
They're very family centered
and that's my
greatest achievement.
That day remember
we had a fight.
Yeah.
When my son was born,
my wife and I,
we had made up our mind that we would
not give our kids our tribal names.
So I gave my son a Zulu name.
"Simphiwe", which means gift.
- This looks nice.
- Yes, it looks very nice.
- Yeah.
- You're looking smart.
For Kenyans, your tribe betrays you.
That means that when
I meet you and ask you
"Hey, what's your name?"
and you say my name is Boniface
or my name is David, Sarah or Rachel.
They'll be like, "No, what's your name?"
They want to get your last name,
so that they know
how to place you tribally.
And so the identity in Kenyan politics
is not nationalism, patriotism,
core values, a bigger
vision for a better Kenya.
The identity of this country is tribe.
Your last name defines you.
So imagine you are the British.
A small country, very cold,
and you come across
a country in Africa.
Very warm, very good looking.
How do I conquer the people?
You divide them among tribes.
In that colony, you take
different tribes for different roles.
The Kikuyu play a big part
in this expansion.
They're a colourful people,
rich in legend and tradition,
but they're also highly intelligent.
Quick to learn
the white man's techniques
and pick up new ideas.
Kikuyus are money lovers.
Kambas are loyal servants.
Luhyas are cooks and watchmen.
All these descriptions were
actually done by the British.
So come independence, we have
the first president of Kenya,
Jomo Kenyatta, who is a Kikuyu.
And what does he do? To conquer the country,
he decides, you know what?
Kikuyus are supreme.
Kikuyus are important.
And what he did,
during the ensuing years,
is kill anyone who was a threat.
And you see that the British planted
the seed of tribalism,
but the first government of this country,
the Kenyatta government,
and subsequent governments, actually
watered the seeds of tribalism
and made it prosper
and become the culture of the country.
It has never happened before,
a serving head of state appearing
before the International
Criminal Court
on charges of crimes
against humanity.
That's what happened today
at The Hague.
President Uhuru Kenyatta of Kenya,
the son of the country's first
president post-independence,
faces charges
concerning his role
in widespread and brutal violence,
which followed the 2007 elections.
We cannot continue being
embarrassed to be called Kikuyu!
Let's see who will be against us.
We will go to their houses and
expose them as traitors!
"This is a traitor!
Shame on you, traitor!"
Kenya's vice president has denied
orchestrating post-election
violence in 2007.
William Ruto and journalist Arap Sang
have pleaded not guilty
to three counts
of crimes against humanity.
The ICC prosecution laws conceded
it is handling
the most challenging case
since its establishment.
As of today, three witnesses
pulled out of the case
against President Uhuru
Kenyatta, citing security fears.
The disappearance of ICC witness
Meshack Yebei is still a mystery.
Veteran journalist John Kituyi
of the Weekly Mirror was last evening killed
by unknown assailants
as he was on his way...
Two human rights activists
from the Oscar Foundation are gunned down.
Among them, the director of the foundation,
Oscar Kingara.
Many of the foot soldiers,
who it's claimed were
hired by the government
to do its dirty work,
have simply disappeared.
No more killings!
So listen, you are the police.
We are not armed and we have a right…
we have a right to protest.
And you have the right to protect me.
What you're going to do sir, you tell these
guys to search us because we're going in.
Can't you hear,
they are going to Parliament.
Are you deaf?
Keep throwing tear gas!
Stop dragging your feet
and get in there.
Beat up these people!
Why are you arresting me?
What have I done?
I haven't done anything!
Has Njeri seen you like this?
Hey Dad.
Daddy, your eye.
When are you going to open this eye?
Come here.
Even the dogs.
I need a good one.
Okay, pray.
Thank you for my Father
who art in heaven.
Thank you for my daddy
when he got hurt by the police...
please tell him to get a better job
not to hurt people and to be better.
- In Jesus' name, we pray amen.
- Amen.
Thank you.
I can't protect him.
I've never been able to protect him.
It's not something I can do.
I have many fears of losing him.
But the thought of him dying,
I mean the children,
the absence of a father,
what would I tell them?
He was fighting for, you know,
human rights and a better country.
And now why did he have to die?
Could he not have done this
in a way differently?
Kenya's top politicians were targeted
by the International Criminal Court
and it ended in another mistrial.
Like the president before him,
on Tuesday, Deputy William Ruto
saw the crimes against humanity
case against him collapse
because of lack of evidence.
Today I got a forward
of an email
from the Chief Justice,
Willy Mutunga.
And there's a hit list of people
who are going to be killed
by people working
for the president.
And my name apparently
is on that list.
- What's that word, introspection?
- Reflect?
Yeah. And give your
children what you have not
given them in the past...
in their lives.
Cause they're just ten.
Your oldest is ten.
My oldest or our oldest?
I have given my oldest
and my youngest and my middle one...
- Enough time?
- My life.
You have given your country
your life.
So maybe now, you give your children
- There you have it.
- Then after that,
you can give the country
what is left
instead of giving your
children what is left.
I give my kids the best.
In order of importance, God…
- Country, family.
- No.
What?
For you, I think
it's been country, then...
- Others.
- Others. God, family...
- How do you arrange them?
- Country first.
You've never been mistaken
about where country falls for you.
- Country comes first.
- Yeah.
Because when you fight for your country,
your kids benefit.
The revolution comes first,
then love follows.
God first family.
For President Uhuru Kenyatta
and his arch-political rival Raila Odinga,
the August election is a high-stakes rematch.
Raila Odinga, son of the country's
first vice-president.
Since then, the Odingas have
always been in opposition.
Red is the colour of Jubilee.
Their candidate is the incumbent.
Uhuru Kenyatta, son of
Kenya's first president.
The big political dynasties live on
more than 50 years after independence.
None of them believes in anything,
and to be honest with you, in this country
if you choose between NASA and Jubilee,
you're not choosing between any two ideals.
You're just saying who
is the better and nicer thief.
So the first step to getting elected
is to have a voter's card.
And if - Njeri, come.
So, today's the journey
that begins...
Could be, you mean,
the journey that begins.
No today, voting today,
coming to apply
for a voter's card in Starehe
shows that
my heart is made up that
I'm going to vie.
But I can always change my mind.
Another thing that we
need to think about...
Are you saying that with certainty?
No, you see, a wise man changes his mind.
A fool, never.
True, but are we
having this conversation?
It's ninety percent there,
and the ten percent...
You told me that I must do a few things,
which I'm working towards that.
So there's my end of the bargain
that I must fulfil.
- Mummy.
- Hey pumpkin.
Why you don't say hello to me?
Hi.
Hi Daddy.
Hi Nate.
Boni's a very closed person.
So I've struggled with that
because like I said,
Boni wakes up and he decides,
and he will think about it for long...
Even months.
He will just not mention it.
You don't come and tell me I'm vying
and you never told me about it.
I'm like, "What? You're running for office?"
No, we need to be on the same page.
For me, that's the one
thing that makes family.
That we have agreed that this
is what we are going to do.
Okay! Let's do this!
Thank you so much for coming today.
Ukweli Party is a new political party
that brings together citizens
who want to live in a Kenya where
everyone is empowered.
We may sound like the lone
voice in the wilderness,
but we're here to stay
and reclaim our country.
If someone has been a thief before,
accused of stealing before,
why are you electing them?
We, as Kenyans, must rise up
and use common sense.
And so we're asking for
a ballot revolution.
Mwangi!
If you go to Parliament,
who will fight for us?
The money will destroy you!
I am going to fight them there!
You will find so much money,
and become blind toward us!
No one has ever helped us.
- Walk everywhere, people will listen.
- That's what I'll do.
Do not be afraid.
We need someone who
will stand up for us.
This is how I'm feeling:
It's a new journey!
- So we'll be meeting every day?
- Every day, Monday to Friday.
Every morning, eight to ten.
In fact, I should be leaving now
to go to the office.
Eight to ten here, two hours.
We're following up on what
everybody said they'd do.
We want to know what you're
doing during the day,
like things you think in your head,
they need to go into this meeting.
Can we get at least five
to do a video next week?
Boni, concentrate.
Concentrate man! Concentrate here!
I'm listening to you.
I'm looking at you, yes.
Think. Think quick!
Boni, I have a job to do. So hurry up!
He's really easily distracted,
Boniface.
He's a great guy, but
he's easily distracted
and he has a lot of things on his mind
so he's not able to plan ahead.
So I try and get his
phone away from him
so that he can concentrate
on the planning and forward thinking.
I think he'll get used to it.
It's hard,
when I take his phone away
he tries to keep himself busy
with the dog or something else.
So it's a challenge,
but we'll get there.
I'm looking for that number.
Yeah okay, I'll tell you when it arrives.
- What next, on my list?
- That's it.
Okay. You, go.
What are you doing?
This is my wife, Njeri.
These are my kids.
Would they like candy?
You guys want candy?
- You guys want candy?
- Yes.
I'm running for MP, will you vote for me?
- Give me some money.
- Give you money?
I don't have money.
So we are supposed to
vote for you for free?
I was raised here.
This is home.
It may be home,
but you still have to pay.
- It's upstairs?
- Upstairs.
- This used to be your house?
- Yes.
My house was very small.
When my mum was alive,
we had a double decker.
So I used to sleep on top
then my mum down here.
Then we'd cook outside.
Jabu, would you live here?
Would you live here?
Never!
I would live there if I were you.
- You'd live there?
- Yeah.
It hurts to be poor, man.
You are taught to become
timid and avoid trouble
as your default setting.
When you see trouble,
when you see problems, you run away.
I was the softest child,
I was the smallest child,
and they thought
I was very weak.
So they would call me "Softie".
I was born poor.
I grew up poor.
Single mother, seven kids.
I want better for my country.
A country where everyone
has a decent shot in life.
Doesn't matter if you're poor,
doesn't matter what tribe
or what gender.
That you matter to this country.
And this country
knows that you exist.
On August 8th
vote for Boniface Mwangi,
a young man from here.
That's my mum. She used to
sell books on the streets.
She died in the year 2000,
when I was 17.
So you are vying for MP?
I knew your mother well.
Punitive taxes
should be eliminated.
They keep taxing you
without providing services.
When elected I'll make
the city police wear uniforms to
identify themselves
because they keep harassing vendors,
like they did to my late mother.
They harassed me too
when I was a vendor here.
- I don't have money.
- Just buy me a soda!
I don't have money.
Just 100 shillings.
Boniface is a good person
but he doesn't give money.
Money!
Money is the biggest problem.
Kenyans don't get
service from their government.
So what happens is every five years when
a politician comes to you to ask for vote,
that's when you ask for everything that
the person was supposed to do for five years.
That's your time to
get as much as possible
from this person, because you
might never see them,
because whatever they say,
they might never do.
So you can't trust this person.
All I'm asking is to work for you.
- You can work.
- But our stomachs need to be full!
And the thing that we're trying to say is,
all those things can be done.
But they can be done after this person
gets into Parliament
because that's where
the money and the resources are.
That is a big mindset change.
And every politician who doesn't want
to do the right thing likes that.
So what do they do?
They come with a car.
They stand in the car.
They wave. They throw T-shirts.
They throw a bit of money
and off they go.
Call me Casanova
I'm coming over, Jaguar
In my Rover
They watching over
Popular musician, Charles Njagua
Kenya alias Jaguar,
will now fly the Jubilee flag
in Starehe constituency
during the August elections.
So we have a guy called
Jaguar, very dodgy.
Has a lot of money,
no one knows from where.
Track record, maybe one song.
You know, musician
who produced one song.
You want him to manage
the city affairs!
Come on people of Starehe,
you can do better than that.
- Are we voting for Jaguar?
- Yes!
You didn't care where I came from!
You didn't ask me
where my wife is!
But just in case you want
to know, I have two wives.
Get off! You'll scuff the car!
Are you Kikuyu?
Are you not Kikuyu?
- What is your party?
- Ukweli party.
- Who are you supporting for president?
- I just care about the MP seat.
- We want to know who you support.
- I respect everyone.
You must be for Raila Odinga.
Listen, I am not with Raila
or Uhuru or anyone else.
I'm here running for the MP seat.
The most important question is:
what is my platform?
It's my policies that matter.
If there's a problem,
you don't call the president!
You will call me, as your MP.
I want to be your voice.
Yes, but we might love many women,
but can only marry one!
Hello.
Give me some money.
I don't have anything to give.
- You must be a weak candidate.
- Please vote for me. I'll work for you.
Look at this broke idiot!
These women love money,
just give them something.
We will vote for Jaguar!
Mbogo!
No, it's Jaguar!
Jaguar!
Mbogo is the right candidate!
- Stupid Luo!
- The Luo tribe will vote for Mbogo!
You know, why am I doing this?
Why am I doing this to myself?
You're dealing with a lot
of silliness and stupidity.
Naila, come and see.
Come and see a goat,
where meat comes from.
Nate, Nate!
All of them are hard.
Get a ripe one.
You are my passion.
Or take this one and make it passionate.
When you look at Boni, how is he doing?
Honestly.
I don't know. Sometimes
I think he's just in motion.
Cause sometimes when he stops,
I think he gets overwhelmed
by what this really means.
And it feels like just jumping
into a river of crocodiles.
I'm on my way.
Okay, thank you sir.
Daddy is watching a book.
Launching a book.
I'm going to the launch, but I'll pass
downstairs to my barber for a cut.
Like this.
You have done your makeup.
- No, you're fine.
- You have done your makeup.
I just need a line.
I launched my book two days ago.
During my book launch,
someone gave a letter to my wife.
And she tells me that
the letter was a threat to me,
that something is going to
happen to me.
And beyond that, the person
purported to have written
that letter claims that he is part
of the team that killed Jacob Juma,
and the same thing that happened
to Jacob Juma is going to happen to me.
So that's the story of today.
I'm about to get to the office.
Let's see how the day goes.
Unexplained deaths are becoming commonplace
as we get into the campaigns.
Jacob Juma was gunned down
late last evening.
One of the things that stands out
is how vocal he has been on matters
to do with corruption.
Executions or police or security
that is killing is nothing new.
It's a well-trodden rich path
that the Kenyan police has been on.
Four suspected police officers
walked into a hospital
and shot a man dead.
Do not come
home, they will kill you.
Activist Boniface Mwangi
says he fears for his life after
receiving death threats that for the first
time target his wife and children as well.
Damn! My dad just found out.
Now you will have to talk to him
because I am driving.
Hello.
Hello Boni.
- How are you?
- I'm fine.
Just got home, and I'm shocked
by reports from my wife.
Boni, we are worried,
very worried, extremely worried.
This is a very dangerous situation
and it really bothers us.
I understand.
I just fear for you.
I'm scared and I told
myself to support for you.
Me and the kids, which means...
I have to look over my back
for I don't know how long.
I keep thinking with every phone call
that something is terribly wrong.
Or just that gut feeling.
Or when I'm going home, I'm afraid.
I can't hide.
I'm in the car with my children.
Have a safe journey.
We will be praying for you.
So I feel like I need to be strong
and make this look like, you know,
it's not the end of the world.
It seems mad, but it's gonna be fine.
So, I just need to be very strong.
I'm not afraid of death.
So that's not a scary thing for me.
I'm just concerned about my family
and your well-being and...
How is your dying
and my well-being not connected?
You need to have an ideal you live
for that is worth dying for.
I am willing to die for my country.
If it means me dying, for Kenya
to be better for my kids...
You think it will be better if you die?
I don't want to die, but if I die
and my death changes a few things...
- What if it doesn't?
- If it doesn't, then it was a waste.
So how does that make you feel?
How does it make you feel?
I'm not feeling very well.
I was campaigning and along
the way I started feeling dizzy.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
So now we're gonna ride,
thanks to you, you've let me down.
He's gonna ride and if we fall down
and he breaks his neck...
Your husband will kill me.
It's your problem and if I die,
my husband I swear he'll come after you
and literally crush your balls and then
cut them and then feed them to the dogs.
Anyway listen, we're gonna leave now.
I love you much and I have to go.
I have to get this guy some medication
and get him fixed up.
I'll speak to you later.
He's insisting to ride a bike
because fucking Martin let me down.
We're talking about the race.
What is it about us
that we are always in campaign mode?
We're talking about 2022,
we haven't finished 2017,
and we don't seem to even be ready.
The biggest problem with the Kenyan psyche
is we are always in panic mode.
Why? Because our election
cycles are winner-takes-it-all.
What needs to change in this country
is we need to develop a politic
and a brand of politicians
who actually stand for something.
Stand for anything.
Your face doesn't have any.
It's white, it's white.
Whee! Whee!
My fingers are freezing.
Oh my gosh.
Hi, how are you, Jabu?
Good.
How's America?
I am going to bed, I had a long day.
Tomorrow's Saturday, what are you doing?
I'm shooting a video
for the songs, the music video.
Boni, Boni
People of Starehe come out and vote
Fight corruption in Starehe
Get clean water in Starehe
With Boniface Mwangi
Let's fight for our rights Starehe
Njeri, you should sing for me a song.
You used to sing songs.
I was about to be eaten by wild animals
Waiting for you my love
I was calling the wild animals
Your name my love
I want to donate to Boniface's campaign
cause he was asking people to donate.
And I just wanted to do something
for the country, but it was not easy.
You couldn't meet anybody who was really
genuinely interested in making a difference.
Vote for Boniface Mwangi for Starehe MP.
When I joined, we had
problems with funds.
There was no money to
run the campaigns.
Immediately, we sat
together and brainstormed.
And you know, if Boniface
has a million followers,
and if all these people follow him
because they want change,
then surely they'd be willing to fund it.
My name is Boniface Mwangi.
I want to say thank you so much
and I want to ask for your continued support.
Give whatever you can.
10 bob, 20 bob, 30 bob.
Support this campaign
and I'm going to become the next member
of Parliament for Starehe.
Boniface has revolutionized
the way that political
party campaigns are funded in Kenya.
So he was able to raise
about 1.6 million shillings
from individual donors,
especially small donors.
Don't ever give up on voting,
just vote for the person
you trust in and one day
we'll change this country.
He's a good guy.
We need to vote for him.
- So he's okay?
- Yes, he is.
- You'll vote for him?
- Yes, I will.
Thanks.
You will vote for me!
In so many ways, Boniface Mwangi
is a radical and a maverick.
So he pioneers some of these
unconventional approaches
to organizing, to political expression,
to activism.
Activist!
He just crossed over the one million
shilling mark. Okay, here's the thing.
Boniface Mwangi is trying to
do politics the right way.
If a voter is willing
to put his money into a candidate,
he's most likely also
to put his vote to the same candidate.
I'm Boniface Mwangi.
- Oh my God. It's you!
- Yeah.
You look more handsome in person!
For real!
It is the first time
we are seeing a candidate run
on principles in a major
constituency in this country.
We must have
equal representation.
I promise that when I'm elected,
I will fight for us to get our fair share.
Come on babies.
It's today. It's today.
Who's graduating,
who's moving on up?
Which one?
This one, sorry this one!
Thank you!
Kindergarten
went by so fast
But now it's time to go
Just 32 days before the country
heads to the polls.
The electoral commission is
expressing confidence
that the technology to be used
during the process will not fail.
The success of this whole ballot
depends on what happens in this building.
The Independent Electoral and
Boundaries Commission, or IEBC,
is the arbiter of the whole process.
There is no room for
manipulation of numbers here.
What are we saying?
What we are saying is
that the results submitted
from the polling stations are final.
Immediately, they are transmitted.
It will be available to Kenyans,
it will be available to the media,
and it will be available to all
the stakeholders in the process.
He's called me,
but he's not talking to me.
He's forgotten he's called me.
He could at least have said hi
and tell me what's going on.
Get off me!
What did you write?
What is it about?
Father's Day.
- It was an assignment?
- Yeah.
What did you write in the card?
Can you read what you wrote in the card?
Okay.
Dear Mum, I love you very, very much.
You are thoughtful and provide
me with the things I need.
I hope this day will be great for you.
And I will try to save up
for a camera for you.
Why did you write "Dear Mum"?
You don't have any message for him at all?
How you doing? I guess.
That he misses out on his children,
it breaks my heart.
I know the kind of man,
husband, and father he wants to be
and that's who I am with.
That guy who wants to be that.
I'm afraid the day I stop believing
that that's the person he wants to be,
I'll be with who he is.
And for any married couple,
when you get to a place
of indifference, that's the end.
I have a letter from my wife.
It's been almost ten years
and I don't think we ever wrote letters
like this before between us.
I don't know where to start,
what to say.
I've been agonizing about
our current situation.
And however I look at it,
it's not easy.
Right now the kids are happy.
No one knows who they are
or what their story is.
They're happy in school,
normal, almost stable.
Jabali told me yesterday
that he's having bad dreams
that someone bad has come
and taken him away.
Have you taken your medicine?
I need to bring it for you.
Let me get it for you now.
I feel like my two worlds
are not in the same place anymore.
And I have to find a way
to balance them.
And this is the hardest part for me
at this point in our lives.
I don't know what is best, but I think
I want to believe that our kids come first.
That we'll do whatever it takes
to ensure their safety and well-being.
Clearly, she doesn't want to come back home
and I understand why.
That's the story, man.
We battled the big fish
for the nomination!
All that's left is a small fish
that can't defeat us.
Put that away.
Let's keep following him.
We'll get more money.
I need 200,000 manifestos
and 50,000 flyers for two million shillings.
Flyers and posters.
Posters and manifesto.
Why was that not in the list of actions?
Everything has to be on that list.
If it's not on that list,
we don't know. We can't chase people.
Every fucking street,
there's photos of ugly Jaguar,
like it's as if there's
no other competitor.
Here on Kipande Street...
Have you seen what I sent you?
Come see.
Come look at this. There is no way
we will win if they're all over the place.
People don't even remember
what you look like.
You're mistaken because
we don't have T-shirts here.
Then he's not an honest candidate.
Fine, no need for all the noise.
Just keep telling yourself that.
It doesn't change the fact
we don't have T-shirts.
Spread the word, there are no
T-shirts in this van.
They were threatening me,
they'll spoil their vote.
I told them, "go!"
They are used to being begged.
Go fuck yourself.
They're fucking dickheads.
They don't even have voter cards!
They're used to intimidating people.
People have become comfortable with us.
It will be a comfortable win.
I pray everything goes well.
Right now what we need to do
is go one-on-one with a man
who has moved from being a photojournalist
to a political activist and
now he wants to try his hand at politics.
Boniface Mwangi.
The news of you now taking
a whole new direction,
because you've changed
who you are now.
This is gonna be the second
time you're making a change.
I can only imagine how scared I'd be,
first of all, as a wife,
to see my husband taking to the streets
being that activist.
Now he's taking that to Parliament.
How do they handle what it is you do?
So my wife, when we started
she was very scared.
But she knew deep down
that she couldn't stop me.
So what ultimately happens,
if you can't beat them you join them.
Okay, so she joins you in the streets?
She comes with me to the streets.
She's been arrested together with me.
That is a strong woman,
I must say.
- Who wears the pants in your home?
- My wife.
I had a feeling
that that was the case.
You're loud outside, but inside
she tells you, "sit down, be humble".
The truth is,
if you ever find a man
who says that he runs the house,
that man is a dictator.
- N-J?
- E-R-I.
Oh, so that's how you pronounce it.
You don't pronounce the N?
I don't struggle being a mother.
Being Boni's wife, that's hard.
Because then I am his wife.
People don't see me for me.
They don't know me.
It's like I don't exist.
It's like I don't have my dreams,
I don't have my ambitions,
I don't have normal struggles,
girl problems.
It's like I don't have all that.
Why are you introducing me
as somebody's,
while I am standing
right here myself?
Hi Njeri.
I want to ask you...
Put words into what you are thinking
so that I hear what is on your mind.
Politics is a very bad thing
actually in this country.
And the way it's going,
it's going to get nastier and dirtier.
And if I don't have someone
that I can talk to and share things
before I do them without making these
long distance calls...
I think I'll be caught up
in the whole nonsense
in a way that I don't want to be.
So, I would prefer that you come back.
I want to be there for you.
Like totally, like in a heartbeat.
But I need you to be there for me.
This is the first time I think
since we've come to the U.S.
that you've done nothing but
talk to me and look at me.
Because normally I am on my phone.
Or in the dark, sleeping
and I'm talking to myself.
Because I want to hear your
voice before I go to bed.
- Okay.
- Bye for now, love you.
I want another baby.
Hey! We missed you Daddy!
Hey son.
All the anxiety, the nervousness,
everything, everything I had...
I'm just excited.
Excited, excited, excited to be home!
Hello?
How are you?
I am calling on behalf of Boniface Mwangi.
So you are not a registered
voter in Starehe?
You can leave word for him.
How has it been
trying to settle back in?
I'm not even sure how I'm doing
on that front about settling.
Everything is everywhere.
Everyone is everywhere.
Oh! Dad has a billboard!
Hey, my sister.
- Talk to Dad.
- Hi Dad.
- Talk to Dad, talk to Dad.
- What, Dad?
- I don't know how to skate.
- I'll teach you!
Okay, but we have penguins so they could...
Okay, Naila, Daddy doesn't
want us to skate now.
He wants us to come where he is.
Don't cry.
Can we be here for Daddy?
Yeah?
Being here for Daddy
means you don't cry, okay?
Being here for Daddy...
Being here for Daddy means
we don't cry.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
- Can you do that?
- Yes.
So this is my long-loving,
suffering wife.
- Hi everyone.
- Hi.
When people ask you,
"What's your name?", what do you say?
Say your name out loud
like it's yours.
I can't hear you!
Say your name!
We are here because you are here.
We are going where we're going because you
believe that there is a better future, right?
We deserve better.
We Kenyans deserve better.
As a generation, as my son is saying...
We believe.
So let's keep this going.
Whatever happens on the 8th,
many of you might not be
voters of Starehe.
But you've given of yourselves,
whatever you have given.
Give it all.
Whatever happens on the 8th,
we have already won.
As far as I am concerned, we have won.
Because the way people are thinking,
the way people are moving,
we have already won.
So let's keep it going,
and let's keep believing. Thank you.
Welcome back. This is our continuing
coverage of the breaking news
on the shock death of Chris Msando,
the data center
and infrastructure manager of the IEBC.
There is no room for
manipulation of numbers here.
What are we saying? What we are saying
is that, at the end of the voting day,
no result can be transmitted for more
than the people who have been identified
in that polling station.
I don't know if I'm making myself clear?
He was actually murdered,
tortured and killed.
In fact, possibly he was
also strangled before he was killed.
We're expecting a press conference
from NASA in a moment.
In the meantime,
we want to take you to Bomet
where President Uhuru Kenyatta
is addressing the crowd.
He might talk about this.
Let's listen in.
My colleague is still here with me.
We're following that.
President Kenyatta and
his deputy William Ruto
did not mention in the entire speech...
We've got reporters there,
they did not talk about this
breaking news out of the IEBC.
Oh my gosh, these guys
will do anything.
I don't know who these guys are,
but they're people who'll
do anything at any cost.
In terms of the thing that
I fear the most, causing panic.
I mean they did, they scored
a hundred and one percent.
Because they did cause panic.
Why would they kill him?
Who killed him and why?
Then that they cut his hands.
So that what?
Biometric fingerprints?
They want to use his
fingerprints for what?
Altering the system, why?
Thank you.
It makes me question a lot of things.
Because for that guy to have been killed,
it's not even how he was found
or how his body was found,
but for him to have been killed...
It's like sending a warning
signal to IEBC officials.
That there's a way things need to go
and if they don't go the way
we want them to go
there are consequences.
What does your gut feeling
tell you about the election?
I don't know.
I think I'm in a bit of a daze.
This campaign...
My head is buried in one place.
I'm focused in there.
And in there, it feels like
we're doing the right thing.
I'm hopeful that things will not go bad.
Hello.
It's very heavy, of course! So is a bullet.
It's heavy so it won't kill you.
I can't walk around with a bulletproof vest.
It's very heavy.
- You're wearing it, maybe not now...
- No, not today.
- Yeah, but you're wearing it.
- When?
- You'll be wearing it!
- But...
Wait, wait, don't say but, just wait.
Stand there and wait.
There's nothing to protect my balls?!
Freedom never comes for free
We vote tribal or real cash, ask Boni
I'm richer than my neighbour
but we're both in a slum
If the rich always win
why should the popular run?
Unless democracy is a word
we say only for fun
My people, my people, my people.
Good morning Naila.
Naila, Naila.
Wakey, wakey.
Where is Jabu?
Jabali, wakey, wakey.
Come, come, come, come.
Hi Mum.
Hi, how are you?
Did you sleep well?
Come.
- Are we going to school?
- No.
No, no, no, not to school.
Where?
Push this behind you.
- Where are we going?
- We are going to vote for Daddy.
I thought you said that we're too young.
We're gonna vote for Dad.
Yes, we're going to vote for Dad.
Good morning.
Shoot your gun in the air!
People will die here!
Are you okay?
Lie down over here.
I'm looking for my shoes.
You won't get them now.
This doesn't even have
a password and it's on.
They are throwing tear gas at us, Boni.
They are throwing tear gas at us!
We've been here since 3 a.m.
We've been in the line,
and we haven't voted.
The lines are not moving.
Talk to them, Boni!
Violence has broken out in Kenya
following yesterday's general election
after the leader of the opposition,
Raila Odinga,
said that
the Electoral Commission's IT system
had been hacked
to manipulate results.
A British firm has been accused
of running an online smear campaign
against NASA leader Raila Odinga.
Top executives of Cambridge Analytica
were caught on camera boasting
about their covert campaigns
that have helped politicians, including
President Kenyatta, win elections.
Stop killing us!
I talked to OCS central.
We have permission to hold
a peaceful demonstration.
We are starting at Freedom Corner.
We provided a route.
- Where is the letter?
- Where is it?
Someone has a copy,
but I have it on my phone.
We love you!
- We can't go to the county commander.
- You said you talked to him!
We gave him our letter!
Madam, wait! Don't beat us!
Look, they even signed.
Tell these guys to leave.
Please do not beat us.
We are peaceful.
So we can walk?
No, go back!
Where are we going back to?
Don't beat us.
There's no need.
There's no need to beat us.
We have not broken any laws.
There's no need.
Madam, there's no need.
We are walking on the sidewalk.
Listen, why do you want to hurt us?
Madam, we will get beaten with you.
Let's walk with her.
Stand next to her, so if they beat us,
they beat us together.
If you throw tear gas,
we'll be together.
We will walk with you.
We will stick with you.
We stick with them when
they throw tear gas.
We shall suffer together!
Are you ready?
Shoot that thing!
I'm not going anywhere!
Where will you take me?
My shirt is on fire.
For Raila Odinga to literally say,
I'm putting down my hard stance.
I'm quitting the opposition
to work with the government.
There must be something at stake for him.
It is something we might never understand
because we really don't know
what were the contents of the agreement
between these two individuals.
Indeed, Raila's influence seems
to have grown as a result of the handshake.
People died for Raila Odinga,
but he has forgotten them.
All these politicians are
a pile of shit.
Have they pronounced the winner?
- Yes Naila.
- Did you win or did you lose?
And? And?
Go on, we're waiting for it.
- Guess.
- You won!
No.
- You lost.
- I lost.
I lost, yes, I lost.
- To who?
- Jaguar.
- So, you didn't win the...
- No.
- But Jaguar's the winner, not you.
- Not me.
- Can I give you a hug?
- Go and give your dad a hug.
Thank you.
Next time, yes next time, Nate.
Wait, there's a next time?
I think I'm secretly
happy that he lost.
Not because I wanted him to.
Honestly, if he had won,
it would have been the greatest.
I'm still hoping that
he can be a family man
and I want him home
for his children.
Nate!
I can't find cooking oil.
- This one?
- Which one?
- This?
- Yes, that is cooking oil.
Thanks.
Siri, how do you make cereal?
Here's what I found.
The recommended ratio of traditional oats
to water or milk is one cup...
Get set, go!
We were fighting for country.
We were fighting for
a better world, a better Kenya.
We were there together.
But now I feel like I
am just fighting for us.
- Nice to see you!
- Good to see you.
- I know it didn't work very well.
- Yeah.
- But maybe there's always a next time, okay?
- True.
- We really wanted change, okay?
- Yes.
There will always be a next time.
- And that's good, okay?
- Okay.
- I'm George.
- Boniface.
Yes, I know! I know you're Boniface.
I think I need to stay here and fight,
but not even from the front line.
I think right now I need
to fight for my family.
Subtitles: Raggio Verde - Rome