JUDGE: Always considering
the best interest, welfare…
…and well-being of the child.
Therefore, you may make visitation
to you daughter…
…every other week
and on Christmas Eve…
…and on Easter Sunday,
wearing your pretty Easter outfits.
Your honor, my ex-husband is addicted
to pills and he's a thief!
Because of his arrest record, I lost
my job as a secretary for the FBI.
He was the finest high-school
tailback I ever saw.
Of course he's had his run-ins
with the law, but he's…
…made his accommodations
with the authorities.
Being an informer
for the Dade County vice squad…
…hardly qualifies him
to raise a seven-year-old!
Neither does being
a mother without a job!
- But I lost it because of him!
DARRELL: Heh, heh, heh.
Little lady…
…my decision is final.
Next case.
The big man's here!
- When does she go on?
- Pretty soon, Jerry.
- Welcome to Eager Beaver, gentlemen.
ERB: Thank you.
Keep it close.
- Keep it very close.
- You got it.
Last stop, okay?
- What do you say, congressman?
- Poontang.
The night is young
and full of promise, my boy.
ERB:
Great.
Now look, this has to be
the last one. Now I told…
Come on!
We got a rehearsal tomorrow.
PAUL: Melissa thinks I'm in temple.
What if she calls?
[THE SPENCER DAVIS GROUP'S «GIMME
SOME LOVIN'» PLAYING ON SPEAKERS]
[MEN CHEERING]
[MEN WHISTLING]
Well, I feel so good
Everybody's getting high
DJ: We've got the legendary
twin temples from Fort Lauderdale.
Miss Urbana Sprawl wrapping up
on the great stage.
[CROWD CHEERING]
And I'm so glad you made it
So glad you made it
Nice spot, isn't it, Erb?
It's very uplifting, sir.
[MAN WHISTLING]
WAITRESS: The usual Evian with lime?
- Please.
DJ:
From Paris, France…
…put it together
for the fabulous Monique, Jr.!
[BILLY OCEAN'S «GET OUTTA MY DREAMS
GET INTO MY CAR» PLAYING ON SPEAKERS]
[CROWD CHEERING]
- Hey
- You
Oh, my God. I love you!
- Who me?
- Yes, you
Oh, man.
That song is killing me!
Those babies gonna wind up in traction,
you don't play some ballads.
STRIPPER:
God, it's freezing!
They could store meat in here.
In fact, they do store meat in here.
No, I've been trying all day!
Are you positive?
No, thank you.
URBANA: Can't reach her?
ERIN: Darrell's phone's out of order.
I just know he's moved with her
again to some new dump.
God, what a nightmare!
He drives around with her in that van.
Drinking, taking pills…
He doesn't even think about
putting a seat belt on her.
He's a dirtbag!
You hang in there, honey.
You'll get Angela back.
That judge will see the light.
It's expensive light,
I'll tell you that.
It's gonna cost me $15,000
for this appeal.
Is there even a chance
I can make that in six weeks?
You'll have to dance day and night
and hope some Arab sheik shows up.
I love you, girls, I do. But I can't
work here when I go back to court.
«Your honor, I found a new job.
I'm working at the Eager Beaver. »
It's honest work.
You have nothing to be ashamed of.
I know that and you know that.
But the judge won't.
Not him.
Ugh…
God, I still get nauseous
before I have to go out there.
You'll get over it.
Really? I can't imagine that.
[MEN CHEERING]
MAN 1: Yeah!
MAN 2: Yeah! Yeah!
I'll be the sun, shining on you
ORLY:
You guys having a good time?
Here's the lucky guy!
You've come to the right place.
Monique!
Look at these hunks!
We're having a party!
Get out of my dreams
Keep an eye on them bachelors.
Get into my car
They look like real trouble.
Yeah!
Get out of my dreams
Get into my car
- I said, hey
- Hey
- You
Get into my car
[CROWD CHEERING]
It's time to strap yourselves in
because you are going for a ride!
In her eighth week here…
…put your hands together
and make her feel good.
For the one, the only Erin Grant!
How about that!
- Larry King's at table six.
ERIN: What's he wearing?
MONIQUE: Tank top and gold chains
ERIN: That's Larry, all right.
Yo.
- How do I look?
SHAD: Better than me.
That ain't easy.
You talk to her?
Darrell's phone's out of order.
I think he moved again.
I'd embrace the opportunity
to maim his white ass up.
That's really thoughtful, but I
don't think it'd help me in court.
Erin, come on. Chop-chop.
I can't have an empty stage.
Man, let the chumps wait!
[ANNIE LENNOX'S «MONEY CAN'T BUY IT»
PLAYING ON SPEAKERS]
[CROWD CHEERING]
Money can't buy it, baby
Sex can't buy it, baby
Drugs can't buy it, baby
You can't buy it, baby
Going to the head.
You'll behave?
I believe in love alone
Yeah, yeah
Take the power to set you free
MAN 1: Yeah!
MAN 2: Whoo! Yeah!
Throw away the key
Give up your needs
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Whoa.
I believe in the power of creation
I believe in the good vibration
[MAN WHISTLING]
An angel appeared.
An angel of pure delight.
What we're coming to
Oh…
Till we watch those dreams come true
All the money in the world
Won't buy you peace of mind
You can have it all
But you still won't be satisfied
Money can't buy it, baby
MAN:
Go, Paul!
Sex can't buy it
Yeah!
MAN:
Go, Paul!
I'm getting married
this weekend to Melissa.
You love Melissa?
- Very much.
- Then go home to her.
ERIN:
Shad!
I got every kind of thing
That the money can buy
ORLY: Listen up! The Flesh Farm
is killing us and you know why?
- They have free buffalo wings.
- Their girls are hookers.
No, because their girls dance fast.
And fast means sweat.
And sweat…
…means drinking!
[ERIN SCREAMS]
Oh, my God!
ERIN:
Shad!
What was that?
I got this.
[CROWD CLAMORING]
MEN:
Whoa!
Coming through.
Move out of the way.
Way to go, Davey!
[LAUGHING]
Everybody, go. Run.
Back up! Back the hell up!
- You all right?
- Fine. How about this guy?
Good thing he was drunk.
You could've gotten hurt.
DJ: On the main stage,
our lost little pussycat.
Put your hands together for the one,
the only Miss Sabrina Hepburn!
Meow!
[CROWD CHEERING]
[LIGHT CRUST DOUGHBOYS' «PUSSY,
PUSSY, PUSSY» PLAYING ON SPEAKERS]
Meow
- Is this your cat?
- Yoo-hoo
- Look at this cat
ERB:
I leave you alone for five minutes!
Will you get in?
Watch your foot, stupid.
Malcolm's gonna shit a brick.
Thank you.
DILBECK:
Did I touch any girls?
ERB: Not this time,
but you were recognized.
Okay? Happy?
- How are you, little angel?
- I'm fine, thank you.
- Kids just tear me up.
- She's a brave one.
You'll be in my prayers.
God bless you, ma'am.
[DARRELL SNICKERS]
DARRELL:
Last stop, little 'un.
Daddy, you're mean!
Evers and Jennings.
This is the new model, the X12.
- You're happy?
- Oh, mucho happy.
- Mucho happy?
- Get in the van.
Mucho, mucho, mucho!
Get in. We're in a loading zone.
We don't wanna break the law.
Daddy, did you tell Mommy
that we moved?
Of course I did, buttercup.
Of course I did.
[WOLF HOWLS]
How about a wine cooler, Erin?
I got mango, passion fruit…
Water would be just fine,
Alberto. Thanks.
Rita, the reason I stopped by
is Darrell's moved again…
…and I need his new phone number.
Yeah? Well, you come
to the wrong place.
Rita, please. I hardly sleep nights
and then I break out into…
Look, Erin, I got no idea
where my brother is, okay?
[CAT SCREECHING]
Shit! They got the cat!
Wolves got no restraint.
- Careful, sweetie.
RITA: Shut up!
[WOLF GROWLING
AND CAT SCREECHING]
She's all caught up with them cubs.
Some of the guys down
at the nuclear plant…
…they were asking me
if you'd do, like…
…private parties.
I don't think so.
Oh, that's a shame.
Because I'll bet that
you are a great dancer.
Alberto, I'll go crazy if
I don't get Darrell's new number.
I promised Angie I would
call her every day and…
I hear he moved, Darrell.
Alberto, where is he?
You have to ask Rita about that.
He calls here about twice a week.
Collect.
Need money, as usual…
…but he don't speak to me.
Got no respect for me
even though I am…
…a professional man.
You're looking real good.
Oh, God, I've got such a headache.
Oh, yeah?
You want some Advil?
That would be so great.
Well, now, you sit right here.
I'm gonna fix up
that mean old headache.
Alberto, never mind. I've gotta run,
but thanks anyhow.
Deerfield Beach?
We had a good day, baby.
[PHONE RINGING]
Phone's ringing.
Think it's Mama?
No, little 'un. I talked to her
and she's too busy to call you.
[LINE RINGING]
Damn him!
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[ANNIE LENNOX'S «COLD»
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
Come to me, run to me
Do and be done with me
Cold, cold, cold
Don't I exist for you?
Nice leg.
Maybe I'll take it home.
I recommend you let go.
Here's 500, baby.
SHAD:
What'd you say?
Cold
Everything I possess
Given with tenderness
Wrapped in a ribbon of glass
Time, it may take us
But God only knows
How I've paid for those things in the past
Dying is easy
It's living that scares me to death
Ooh, yeah
I could be so content
Hearing the sound of your breath
Ooh, yeah
Cold is the color of crystal
The snowlight that falls
From the heavenly skies
Catch me and let me dive under
For I want to swim in the pools
Of your eyes
I want to be with you, baby
Oh, slip me inside your heart
What's with Princess Di tonight?
Her husband disappeared
with the kid again.
Nothing can tear us apart
Come on now, come on now, come on now
Telling you that I loved you
Right from the start
But the more I want you the less I get
Ain't that just the way things are?
I don't suppose you'd
accept this in appreciation.
No need.
Senor Cucaracha
here is gonna make me rich.
Oh, my God!
Is that a roach?
No, it's a fucking shrimp.
Move, you're in my light.
Get some manners, mister!
So this is the new brainstorm, huh?
The Wall Street Journal says
this is the hottest-selling yogurt.
I'll bring this in…
…say my hair fell out
from the shock. Boom.
They pay off bigtime.
Lawyer thinks it's a genius idea.
Your lawyer has an office
over a video store.
Call me a dreamer.
I don't wanna be a bouncer forever.
- Erin! Note from Jerry!
WOMEN: Ooh.
What does it say?
«Dearest Erin: I can help you
get your daughter back.
I ask nothing in return
but a kind smile. »
- Yeah, right!
- He's a weirdo.
You guys!
He is totally harmless.
Come on!
«Also, could you add
Kenny G to your routine?
Anything from his Christmas album. »
That's sweet.
We could do a Christmas show here!
Seriously, it couldn't hurt
to talk to him, right?
ARIEL: Only talking, no touching.
ORLY: Ladies! Attention!
- Major announcement.
ARIEL: Major asshole.
I heard that.
On Monday, I'm installing a ring.
- Oh, no.
- Mud wrestling?
No, no, no. This is something
that's really happening.
It's contemporary. It's now.
And it's creamed-corn wrestling.
- Corn?
- Corn wrestling?
SABRINA:
That's disgusting!
I'm not putting these in corn.
No way!
What? No, it's terrific!
In Israel, we did falafel wrestling.
All the girls broke out
in hives everywhere.
And I mean, everywhere!
Well, falafel, sure.
This is corn!
- What is this, a mutiny?
ERIN: I don't think so.
ERIN: No chance that I'm gonna roll
around naked in creamed corn…
…with drunken yahoos trying
to stick niblets up my hoo-hah.
Not naked. Topless.
Health Department won't go for naked.
Not with food products.
I always liked the Health Department.
So you'll think about it?
- Not for one second.
- Erin!
Please!
You're getting a big following here.
Even with that shit music,
the guys love you.
You go into the corn, you set
a great example to the other girls.
No.
I got it!
How about pasta wrestling?
Now that's classy.
Linguine, rigatoni?
Just nothing with meat or fish.
Orly, if I wanted to wrestle…
…I would've joined
the World Wrestling Federation.
- And speaking of real class?
- What's the problem?
We hate these.
They degrade women and beavers.
I'll take it under advisement.
But just the coasters and the napkins.
Not the sign.
That's a landmark!
URBAN A:
Good night, darling.
For you, Miss Grant.
They're beautiful, Jerry.
Thank you.
You can call me Erin…
I can't.
I worship you too much.
ERIN:
Believe me…
…I'm no one to be worshiped.
I'm just trying to make a living.
I worship your essence.
If you were a nurse or a teacher,
I'd feel the same.
You receive my note?
I did and, you know, I was wondering
what you had in mind.
I believe I can help you
get your daughter back.
I believe I can
get to Judge Fingerhut.
- How?
- Through…
…a certain congressman who
I'm certain will listen to me…
…because I know some things.
Things? Really?
Well, you know what, Jerry?
You're really a terrific guy…
…and so supportive of me
ever since I started here.
Maybe you shouldn't…
Just give me a week.
Good night, my precious.
Melissa thinks I was in synagogue
the night this happened.
What do I tell her?
You left synagogue and a gang
of skinheads jumped you in the parking lot.
In the meantime, we'll develop these,
we'll see what we have.
I see mucho damages. These strip
joints are insured up the ass.
My neck really feels better,
Uncle Al.
Oh, yeah?
How's it feel now?
[SCREAMING]
[CHUCKLES]
Call Little Caesars.
Order me a health pizza.
Get some for yourself.
No, thank you, sir.
I'm dieting.
I'll just grab a yogurt
out of the fridge.
This is a major disaster!
Major. Unbelievable.
Without doubt…
…the most asinine piece
of human behavior.
It's never gonna
happen again, Malcolm.
I've got it under control.
You see…
…I just love naked women.
It's a character flaw.
God's testing me…
Oh, will you shut up!
You idiot.
You can't talk to me like that.
I'm a U.S. congressman.
I can't? You go psycho in a titty bar
six weeks before the election.
What should I call you?
Winston fucking Churchill?
It was all I could do to keep…
…Willie Rojo from strangling you
with his bare hands.
Everybody has a bad night.
If you're under pressure like we are,
under the public eye…
Who recognized me?
His name…
…is Jerry Killian.
And he's waiting outside.
Now?
Now. We gotta move on this
before we get eaten alive.
Move on what?
If this is a shakedown,
get Willie to pay them like always.
- Why drag me into it…
- Because it's not about money.
- It's not?
- No.
He wants you to persuade
Judge Fingerhut…
…to reverse a child custody case
for some stripper.
DILBECK:
Who he's porking?
It's disgraceful to have
a man like me deal with…
He's not porking her.
Well, then, why does he care?
Because he's nuts!
That's why he's dangerous.
If he was porking her, at least
I could deal with him man to man…
…but this is fruitcake love.
I mean, Fingerhut's a democrat.
He won't listen to me.
You can't say that
to this little creep, Davey.
You gotta string him along.
Bullshit him.
Use the old…
…Dilbeck charm.
What if he doesn't go for it?
Then we have a serious problem.
MALCOLM:
Mr. Killian!
Come in and meet
Congressman Dilbeck.
I'll bet that's Jerry Killian.
GARCIA:
Lucy!
Come here.
Come on.
DONNA:
How perfect is this?
You know, I was just thinking…
…is this really on
the same planet as Miami?
[DONNA CHUCKLES]
I can read.
Where's Andy?
He's been fishing since 8.
ANDY:
Dad!
There's a floater!
ANDY:
He's still got his glasses on.
GARCIA:
Yeah.
Go tell Mom to call the police.
- You're the police.
- I'm the Miami police.
We just need the local law here.
Go on.
Man.
Of all the lakes…
…in all the counties…
…in all the world…
…you gotta float up in mine.
You son of a bitch.
ANGELA:
Mama!
Hey, come here!
I've been trying to reach you, baby.
Heard you stole my sister's mail!
That's a federal offense.
Wait for Mommy.
I'm gonna go talk to Daddy.
Why do you keep moving?
How will she make any friends?
Aren't we the child psych…
ERIN: It has nothing to do with child
psychology, you moron!
Where's she going to school?
Opa-locka? Deerfield Beach?
Have you even thought about it?
Yeah, I thought about it plenty.
Hey, you only got two hours!
That's what the judge ruled,
right there, from that bench!
I'll be right behind you just in case
you're thinking about snatching her!
ANGELA:
Mommy, does «snatch» mean «kidnap»?
- How did you get so smart?
- Heh, heh, heh.
Is Free Willy back yet?
Still out.
People are pigs.
Sit on movies like they own them.
Freak.
[DRILL WHIRRING]
It's Shad. Open up.
It wasn't me. It was a temp.
Where's Perry Mason?
Our good friend, Mr. Shad!
Come on in, we have lots to discuss.
No shit.
If I buzz twice, you say my mother's
on the line. She has chest pains.
ERIN: What do you mean
he's a wheelchair salesman?
ANGELA:
There's one nice thing about hospitals.
A lot of kids in chairs are
really sick, and I wave at them…
…and they smile
just like on Jerry Lewis.
- And do you do this every day?
- On Fridays I stay with Aunt Rita.
That's a wholesome environment.
ANGELA:
She has real wolves.
I don't want you
touching those animals.
They're not like dogs.
[CAR HORN HONKING]
Time.
I love you more than
anything in the world.
- You know that in your heart.
- Mm-hm.
- Mommy?
- What, baby?
Do you know those dolls you got me?
Daddy says he can't
find them anywhere.
We'll get you new ones.
- I love you.
- Bye, baby. I love you.
Hey, let's go!
All right, you go on.
I'll bring your stuff.
DARRELL: Hey, baby!
Did you have a good day?
- Mm-hm.
- Good.
She told me about your new profession.
Really admirable.
At least I ain't naked.
«At least I ain't naked»?
You get caught using
that child in a felony…
- …and Family Services will put her…
- No way I'd get caught.
Got me one of them doctor's
jackets and a stethoscope.
Look like one of them dudes on ER.
Darrell, would you think
for once in your life?
Hey!
I don't need no stripper
telling me how to behave.
I'll see you in two weeks.
- You ready?
- Mm-hm.
ALAN:
You know where that was taken?
Your mama's birthday party.
Heh, hen. The Eager Beaver. Last
Wednesday. Can you identify those people?
Yeah, this old fool. Erin.
Erin's the stripper?
What'd you say?
Erin's the stripper.
- Dancer, fat-ass.
- Dancer. She's a dancer!
All right, look.
The young man who was
so savagely beaten…
…is my client, Paul Guber.
No shit. Too bad for him.
I don't think so.
The third person in that photo
is none other than…
…David L. Dilbeck.
So what?
Do you follow politics, Mr. Shad?
Do I look like I follow politics?
David Dilbeck
is the United States congressman…
…from the fifth district.
He's up for reelection in six weeks.
You gonna put the squeeze on him.
Nice.
What that gotta do with me?
I'll give you 10 percent of the squeeze.
Is this conceivably
as big as the yogurt deal?
«As big»? Heh.
Congressman Dilbeck is chairman
of the subcommittee on sugar, okay?
The Rojo family cannot
allow him to lose.
Because their price supports are worth
hundreds of millions of dollars.
And quite frankly, Mr. Shad…
…this is the opportunity
of a lifetime.
Good.
Just keep Erin out of it.
I'll do my best.
She's out. Erin is out.
Erin who?
[SOUL SURVIVOR'S «EXPRESSWAY TO
YOUR HEART» PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
[MAN WHISTLES]
Whoo-hoo!
They're all the time
Getting in front of me
Charming spot.
Look. Steven Spielberg's house.
I wish he'd come in here.
I'm sure he would have big hots for me.
You'd turn his whole life around.
Steven Spielberg's shower. Can you
imagine me and him in that shower?
- Oh, that cute little beard!
- Yours or his?
Hey, Jerry, it's Erin Grant.
What a long beep.
STRIPPER:
Someone's waiting for you.
Maybe you're out of town…
I'm just calling to see about
that legal matter we discussed.
If you get a chance,
just give me a call at the club.
Thanks, bye.
- Michael Jordan's at table eight!
- Great.
Say hello to
the fantastic Monique, Jr.!
[CROWD CHEERING]
[BOOKER T AND THE MG'S «GREEN
ONIONS» PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
ORLY:
Lieutenant Garcia with homicide.
What's he want with Erin?
Got no idea.
All I need is scandal.
What do you know about Prozac?
It makes you happy.
There's side effects.
Like what?
Limp noodle.
Who cares?
I haven't had a hard-on
since I started running this place.
Closest I got was Sea World.
Porpoise got me hot.
What the fuck
you telling me that for?
I'm going next door.
See what Ling's up to.
- Drowned?
- Yeah.
ERIN:
Oh, my God.
He had pictures of you
all over his apartment.
He was a really big fan.
He used to bring me flowers…
He was just a fan?
There was no touching?
This has been a real pleasure.
I dance, so I must turn tricks?
Nice way to open a conversation.
«I understand you're a hooker?»
You don't work in a library here.
I'm trying to figure out
the man's life.
He was a customer.
That's all I know about his life.
Except that it's over.
Okay. I apologize.
Sincerely. Look, I'm real…
I'm nowhere on this.
I could use some…
Please give me a minute?
Please?
- So where did this happen?
- Lake Okeechobee.
It's where I made the serious
mistake of taking my vacation.
Your family? Nice.
It's not the kind of place
you'd expect to encounter a homicide.
- Homicide? You said he drowned.
- No, we did an autopsy.
The water in his lungs,
they come up clean.
- There was tap water in his lungs?
- Exactly.
Somebody killed him, like in a bathtub,
then dumped the body in a lake.
Do you read mysteries?
Up till three months ago,
I worked at the FBI in Miami.
A secretary. Until I got fired
for having a defective husband.
I'm in a pretty bad custody fight.
Jerry was trying to help me.
From the shores of the Dead Sea…
…a decorated nurse
in the Israeli army…
…say shalom to
the fabulous Ariel Sharon!
[CROWD CHEERING]
[LALADIN'S «LOVE CHILD»
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
Ah
[SIGHS]
Could we go outside?
I could really use some air.
[SMOKEY ROBINSON'S «YOU'VE REALLY
GOT A HOLD ON ME» PLAYS ON SPEAKERS]
[CROWD CHEERING]
I don't like you
But I love you
Seems that I'm always thinking of you
Oh, oh, oh, you treat me badly
I love you madly
Oh!
You really got a hold on me
Really got a hold on me
Oh, Mr. Orly!
What a wonderful surprise.
Nice to be in quality club, eh?
Yeah, if you like freak shows.
Ling! Ling!
Get over here!
Move it!
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
But that's Mr. Chris Rojo…
…of the sugar Rojos.
Typical of the kind
of rich big shots we get here.
My love is strong now
You really got a hold on me
Really got a hold on me
Baby
Is this the place
where I met my angel?
I don't know which angel
you're referring to.
[ALL CHEERING]
GARCIA: A congressman?
- A congressman.
You mean a U.S. congressman?
Well, he wasn't specific who it was.
I told him it was bananas…
…and maybe it was better
that he stayed out of it.
On Wednesday, there was an incident,
a guy with a bottle…
Oh, he was a total whack job.
Drunk out of his mind.
Can you remember,
was Mr. Killian here?
No, not offhand, but maybe.
Think about that and let me know.
Here's all my numbers.
Once again, I apologize.
I mean, for any aspersions.
You wanna make it up to me?
- I beg your pardon?
- I need a favor.
You've got friends on the vice squad?
They're not my bosom buddies.
My ex-husband's an informant.
It's why this idiot judge
gave him custody.
- Are you joking?
- I wish.
But I was thinking,
if vice dumped him as an informer…
…when my appeal
came up in six weeks…
…I could then say
my ex-husband is unfit.
- He's such a criminal…
- Wait a minute. He's a criminal?
Your ex? He's a criminal?
He steals wheelchairs.
Thank you very much.
All right, let me see what I can do.
- Good night.
- You know, not having her around…
…it's like my heart is missing.
I'm sure.
Let me see what I can do.
Good night.
How much you pay them?
I think they're up to $30 a day.
Subtract room and board,
booze and smokes.
You know, who knows?
Maybe they pay us! Ha, ha, ha!
- Hell of a business.
- It's the best!
We gotta protect it,
my friend, right?
Son, I've been protecting
your family for 20 years.
You're the greatest, man!
I'm saying, until the election,
no more girls, huh?
Bring your wife down here
for a weekend.
What's her name? Alice?
Mary Pat. Mary Pat.
Chris, I met an angel.
- I mean, she's a dancer.
- Oh.
She's so pure and clean.
Not like the rest of these whores.
- If I could be with her…
- What?
You'd be a good boy?
I'd be perfect. I'd be perfect.
I swear I would.
I would stop going to clubs.
I would stop drinking.
I would just lead
a regular life, you know?
With my wife and a steady mistress.
And I would have a decent life.
So let's do it!
Where'd you see her?
[GRUNTING]
My brain has just turned to shit.
That's why you're in Congress!
[BOTH LAUGHING]
You're probably right.
[ANNIE LENNOX'S «LITTLE BIRD»
PLAYING ON STEREO]
I look up to the little bird
That glides across the sky
He sings the clearest melody
It makes me want to cry
It makes me want to sit right down
And cry, cry, cry
Yeah
I walk along the city streets
So dark with rage and fear
[ERIN HUMMING AND SINGING
ALONG TO SONG]
And I
I wish that I could be that bird
And fly away from here
I wish I had the wings
To fly away from here
But my, my, I feel so low
My, my, where do I go?
My, my, what do I know?
My, my, we reap what we sow
They always said that you knew best
But this little bird's fallen out
Of that nest now
I've got a feeling
That it might have been blessed
So I've just got to put these wings to test
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
[MUSIC TURNS DOWN]
Who is it?
It's Lieutenant Garcia.
Is it a bad time now?
No, just a second.
I was rehearsing.
Morning.
Morning. I was nearby.
I probably should've call…
No, no, it's fine.
Please come on in.
GARCIA:
Thank you.
ERIN: Can I get you some coffee
or English muffin?
No, no, thanks.
You know, I was thinking…
…and if I had to guess,
I would say…
…that Jerry was probably there
because he was there most nights.
So do you know anything new?
Actually, I have some good news…
…and I have some mediocre news.
The good news is Darrell
lost his informant status.
Yes!
GARCIA:
9:00 this morning.
Vice thought his information
was bogus anyway.
This is great! Now in six weeks,
I can go to the judge…
That's the mediocre part.
Judge Fingerhut had a heart attack
early this morning…
…at a porno theater on Ocean.
- Don't tell me that!
- He was DOA…
…at Don Shula Hospital.
Anyway, I called around,
and the earliest…
It'll be six months
before your appeal's heard.
The system is all backed up.
I can't allow her to stay
with him for another six months!
There's nothing you can do
from a legal standpoint.
Absolutely nothing.
I understand.
Is today Friday?
Yeah, it's Friday.
I gotta run now.
[BAND PLAYING UPBEAT MELODY]
[WOMAN SINGING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
- How are you?
- All right.
WOMAN:
You're wonderful, Mr. Dilbeck!
Thank you very much. Thank you.
Phil, how you doing?
Shalom, darling. Shalom to you.
Manischewitz!
Congressman. Alan Mordecai.
- Alan, how you been?
- Fine, sir.
Congressman, I brought
a little souvenir for you.
Obviously, the ramifications of that,
if it were to become public…
- Is this me?
- Yes, I'm afraid so.
If this became public,
it would be devastating…
- …and I'd like to avoid that.
- It's her.
It's my angel.
Heel! Slow down!
Heel, will you? Heel!
Are you going to your house, Mama?
No, we're going to our house.
For the whole day?
Even better.
Really?
Really.
You snatched me, didn't you?
I guess I did.
You sure did.
Come on, pumpkin.
Zippity-doo-dah.
I didn't know she had a child.
Of course you…
She's divorced, but the husband
has custody. Remember?
DILBECK:
She's carrying numerous bags.
That doesn't look like just
a visitation, does it, Erb?
I'll look into it.
Check custody status
of Ms. Erin Grant.
God, give me strength.
What an extraordinary creature.
How perfect in every detail.
Davey, you promised you'd behave
until after the election.
You don't understand.
This is love.
Please.
I won't campaign…
…until I can possess…
…her actual velvet self.
In the meantime, I want you
to bring me something.
Something of hers.
Something…
…personal to tide me over.
How personal?
Intensely personal.
Am I a good help?
Honey, you are the best
laundry assistant I've ever had.
All right, let's hit the road, Jack.
Who's Jack?
It's just an expression.
Come on.
This is some picture.
It's fatal.
I don't accede to blackmail.
Willie, I agree with you
in principle…
…but this gets out,
we're in a bigtime shitstorm.
Pop, pay the guy off.
You got a cancer,
you talk nice to it?
- No. You cut it out.
MALCOLM: Willie.
We can't operate like
we're in the funeral business.
I'd rather buy cops than
pay blackmail. Understood?
I just think we should
consider other options.
Understood?
Yes.
What else?
A connected matter.
Davey wants to nail this stripper,
and I'd like to use the boat.
That way, we can control
the situation.
- She's the girl from the picture?
- That's correct.
- What does she know?
- Well, we gotta find out.
The good news is she got custody
of her child illegally, so she's vulnerable.
Vulnerable isn't good enough.
I say let Davey have his fun.
Then lose her.
Willie, Willie.
First, let's determine
whether she can hurt us or not.
I'm sure she's just
another dumb whore.
For her sake, I hope so.
MONIQUE:
Phooey! I go back three.
- This is complicated.
- It's easy.
All right, is it your turn?
URBANA: Uh-uh. You stay here with us,
sweetie. Mama's orders.
ORLY:
Everybody, listen up.
This is Lorelei.
Formerly of the Flesh Farm.
She and her snake, Monty Python,
have signed an exclusive…
…contract with us.
You've got a snake?
- Monty.
- And she starts tomorrow.
So why don't we make
her feel at home…
…and give her a real
Eager Beaver welcome!
Welcome, darling.
I'm Ariel, Miss Gaza Strip.
I'm Tiffany Glass.
- How big is your snake?
- It's big.
ARIEL:
So what brings you here?
Just what we needed, another blonde!
ORLY:
What the hell is that?
It just came from Ling's.
Monty sleeps with the fishes.
Lorelei has no idea, right?
No, it just got here.
It's fresh.
Go rustle up a new snake.
Where? The A&P? Who the fuck
carries pythons at 10:00 at night?
There's an all-night
snake farm on Route 27.
Ask for Jungle Juan.
And get rid of that.
God, I hate this business.
You know why?
It's lost its humanity.
DJ: Say hello to a gorgeous creature…
- Bring change.
…the unbelievable Erin Grant!
[CROWD CHEERING]
[ANNIE LENNOX'S «LITTLE BIRD»
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
I look up to the little bird
That glides across the sky
He sings the clearest melody
It makes me want to cry
It makes me want to sit right down
And cry, cry, cry
Yeah
I walk along the city streets
MAN:
All right!
Yeah!
And I
I wish that I could be that bird
And fly away from here
I wish I had the wings to fly away from here
Yeah
But my, my, I feel so low
My, my, where do I go?
My, my, what do I know?
My, my, we reap what we sow
They always said that you knew best
But this little bird's fallen
Out of that nest now
I've got a feeling
That it might have been blessed
So I've just got to put these wings to test
SPEAKER:
Because he believes in the family…
…in the values that made us
a God-fearing people.
Because he's long been
a friend of this organization.
Get him out of there.
Preferably with his clothes on.
David…Oh, my God!
Tell me I'm dreaming. Please.
No, no, no!
I cannot believe this!
No, no, no! Davey, no!
Is this lint fresh?
- Hot out of the Maytag.
- Oh.
[SNIFFS]
You just can't imagine!
This is the very essence
of that glorious creature.
I gotta say, even for you,
Davey, this is off the charts!
Why are you shiny?
It's Vaseline.
It's Vas…
Great. It's Vaseline.
You've never covered yourself
with Vaseline?
Not unless I have third-degree burns.
You don't know what you're missing.
I've got it all over.
It's down in my boots. I can feel
it squishing in between my toes.
All right, okay. Davey,
the Young Christians are waiting so…
- When will I see her?
- It's in the works.
- When?
- It's in the works!
Clean yourself up!
I did not go into politics to pimp
for a twisted old fuck like you!
I've had it, Davey.
I quit.
You are such a child.
CROWD [CHANTING]:
Davey! Davey! Davey!
SINGERS [OVER SPEAKERS]:
Onward, Christian soldiers
Marching as to war
With the cross of Jesus
Going on before
Christ, the royal Master
Leads against the foe
Forward into battle
See his banners go
Onward, Christian soldiers
Marching as to war
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
You are too kind.
What a privilege for me to be here
for you good people tonight…
…and to talk about an issue
that is so critical…
…to this campaign and
to all of the American people.
I'm talking about the issue…
…of family values.
LORELEl: Where's Monty?
He isn't here yet.
He's on his way.
Relax.
ERIN:
Do me a favor and watch Angela?
I'm gonna get my car,
it's pouring out.
- Yeah, sure, gorgeous.
- Thanks.
ERIN:
Where have you been all night?
Doing my Christmas shopping early.
Martha Stewart recommends it.
If that's not a snake,
then it's an amazing belt.
I gotta find a new line of work.
This shit is getting out of hand.
Let me put this down
and walk you to your car.
I'm fine.
I'll see you tomorrow.
- Evening, everybody.
- Shit!
- Where's my little 'un?
- Where you can't get her.
Is that ever the wrong answer.
Bring her to me now!
I am not bringing her to you
in this lifetime.
I'll go to that judge and tell him
my whore of a wife abducted…
Guess what, Darrell?
The judge is dead.
So you'll just have to kill me.
- Go on!
- Think I'm afraid to?
Think I don't have the manliness
to take your life?
I think you are all man.
That death row-lethal injection thing?
That's not gonna scare you.
They'd never execute a daddy.
Drop the knife.
You got till three. One.
Suck my dick.
Whip the little fella out. Two.
This here is a domestic squabble.
Ah!
Three.
You broke my arm!
SHAD:
You sure?
[DARRELL GRUNTING]
DARRELL: Bitch!
ERIN: Bully!
DARRELL:
Argh! Argh!
I'm gonna get you!
- Are you okay?
- Just had a tiff with my ex.
I know what that's like.
Did you see? Monty finally got here.
That's great, Lorelei.
Hey, baby. Say hi to Erin.
- Cute.
RECEPTIONIST: Homicide.
Lieutenant Garcia.
DARRELL:
She's a kidnapper!
OFFICER:
Watch your head there.
GARCIA: The fact is he threatened,
and he did not attempt.
What if he kills me?
Can I press charges then?
The law is the law.
I'll screw around here.
If you like, I'll lose your paperwork.
He makes bail, she's his.
I should split and
take her to New England.
Understand this.
If you split without formal custody,
you'll lose her forever.
I've dealt with Family Services.
They are pencil pushers.
- This is by the book.
- I'm dealing with a maniac.
I understand.
I repeat, you can't take off.
You cannot.
You might have a bigger problem.
- I can't have a bigger problem!
- Look at this.
Any of these clowns the one
who might have assaulted Mr. Guber?
This clown.
- You're positive?
- Absolutely.
Who is he? He looks
like that guy on F Troop.
That's Congressman Dilbeck.
This nut is a congressman?
You haven't heard from him?
From any of his staff?
No.
Wait.
This is who
Jerry was talking about.
Are you saying I am in danger
from a congressman?
No.
Let me know if you hear
from him though.
I think that's in both our interests.
How did I get so popular?
ERIN [SINGING]: Hush, little baby
Don't you cry
Mama's gonna buy you a something
ANGELA:
Pumpkin pie.
ERIN:
Oh, you're awake.
- Can Mommy put you down?
- No.
ERIN:
Fair enough.
ANGELA:
Mommy.
ERIN: Brush your teeth.
- I'm too tired.
Okay, don't brush your teeth.
Go on to bed.
«Mr. Dilbeck requests the pleasure
of your company for a private dance.
You'll receive $2,000 cash
for a one-hour set.
Obviously, discretion and confidentiality
are of the utmost importance. »
Mommy, do you like dancing?
Why are you still awake?
I was just thinking.
Do you like dancing?
Not really.
- It's not fun?
- No.
You're just dancing.
Just dancing's fun, honey.
Sure, that part of the job.
What's not fun?
The customers?
Urbana said some of them
are mean and stupid.
Pumpkin, have you ever seen me dance?
Have you?
- I told the girls that…
- I came out tonight.
While I was dancing?
You looked really pretty.
No, I didn't.
Yeah, you did.
You looked great.
Thank you, baby.
ANNOUNCER [ON PA]: Good afternoon,
ladies and gentlemen.
Welcome to the
Miami Seaquarium's Top Deck.
We are going to celebrate the oceans
and all the living things in them…
…as we proudly present to you
a splash of the islands.
WOMAN: Okay, now, I need all
the camp kids to come with me.
Come on. You too.
It's okay. You can go.
Go on. It's all right.
I'll be right here.
Don't worry.
She's spent so little time with kids…
GARCIA: It'll change.
Once she's with you full-time.
I hope so.
GARCIA: Let me get this straight.
He offered you two grand?
To dance for one hour?
- I don't know.
- I can't turn it down, Al.
Now that I have Angie with me,
I've gotta find another job immediately.
Which will pay me nothing
compared to what I'm making now.
But, you know…
…she saw me last night.
Can you imagine?
Was she upset?
She said no, but come on.
One day she's gonna realize…
…and say, «That was my mother. »
How about you? You ready
to feed Flipper? Step here.
Oh, my God.
- It's safe, though, right?
- What?
With Dilbeck. I'm bringing Shad.
I think as long as they think you
don't know anything, you'll be fine.
Keep your ears open.
What will you do with her tonight?
Urbana said that she'd…
Why don't you drop her
off at our house?
- I can't do that.
- Why not?
I told Donna everything.
Your whole situation.
She said if you needed a hand
she'd love to help.
She doesn't think I'm something
out of A Current Affair?
Come on, you're a terrific girl.
You know that.
So you made a mistake. You married
a bum. What are you gonna do?
You gonna beat yourself up
for the rest of your life?
Well, I usually don't,
but it's…
I mean, it's just that…
…you know, she saw me dancing.
Yeah.
It'll all work out.
I want her free and clear,
whatever it takes.
Good job, baby!
CHICO: You're Mrs. Grant?
- No, I'm Barbara Bush.
CHICO: Who is he?
- George Bush.
George Bush is not invited.
- Take a hike.
SHAD: Heh, heh, heh.
Oh, no, no.
See, if he goes, I go.
Raise your hands.
I gotta pat you down.
Stop.
NICO:
Right this way.
[DEAN MARTIN'S «MEMORIES ARE MADE
OF THIS» PLAYING ON STEREO]
Your lips and mine
Two sips of wine
Memories are made of this
[SING ALONG TO SONG]
Then add the wedding bells
One house where lovers dwell
Hello, Erin.
My name is Congressman Dilbeck.
You are…
You're a beauty. Heh, heh.
Stir carefully through the days
See how the flavor stays
Good evening.
I'm Erin Grant.
And you must be…
Convak Dilvak.
[STAMMERING]
Congressman Dildo.
[LAUGHS]
I am Congressman David Dilbeck.
And welcome, welcome.
Welcome.
You are truly, truly welcome.
Thank you.
Have we ever met before?
No, no, no, no, no.
But actually, I have seen…
…many, many beautiful
photographs of you.
Well, I'm honored.
And a congressman.
Very successful congressman
you must be.
This is not my boat.
It belongs to a very
close friend of mine.
Do you like Dino?
Dean's great, yeah.
But you know, I've brought my own.
Do you care for The Artist
Formerly Known as Prince?
Fold in lightly with a dream
I care for you.
Your lips and mine
So, George, you get to watch
any of the auditions?
- Watch, my ass. I do the hiring.
- No, no, no.
I've seen every girl in Florida.
What are the criteria?
Monster jugs?
Firmness is crucial.
I gotta hold them for a while.
Shake them.
You shake their tits?
It ain't no picnic, man.
Got tendinitis in my right wrist.
On a rainy day, it's agony.
You audition anybody famous?
- What?
- You know, before they were famous.
Sure did.
Meryl Streep.
Come on!
Meryl Streep stripped?
One of the best.
Chesty La France.
That was Meryl.
Chesty La France. I heard of her.
[PRINCE'S «IF I WAS YOUR GIRLFRIEND»
PLAYING ON STEREO]
Ooh!
I give you anything you want.
A diamond ring.
A Lexus.
I'll get you a condo on the beach.
Just be my girlfriend.
- Can't do that.
- Why not?
I love you.
You don't know what
I've done for you recently.
Really? And what was that?
DILBECK: I talked to Judge Fingerhut
about your daughter.
You did?
And how did you know about my case?
Little birdie told me.
It must have been a little old
birdie who knew me very well.
«Who» is not important.
Come on now.
Not just a little hint.
I can't do that.
But I know the new judge.
He's a very good friend of mine.
The Honorable Jack Goldberg.
He'll be more amenable.
Darling, if you just come
into Davey's life…
…good things will happen.
You don't know how much
I worship you.
How much?
I sent my aide, Erb,
over to your Laundromat.
He brought back some of your lint.
My lint?
Fresh…
…hot lint.
And what did you do
with that fresh, hot lint?
I'm afraid I made love to it.
Close your eyes.
I've got a little surprise for you.
Keep them closed.
No peeking.
- Ow!
- Don't invade my private life again…
…or I'll kill you. You understand?
Show's over, big boy.
This is abnormal.
You'll come back tomorrow?
Same time?
I don't think so.
I'll give you $5,000.
Five thousand dollars for no sex?
You love me that much.
Just the touch of your hand
sets my pecker on fire.
Maybe you should see a doctor.
Same time tomorrow?
If I come, can we talk more
about my case?
We can talk about anything.
As long as you're naked.
We'll see.
MALCOLM:
Good evening.
You don't know me.
I'm Malcolm Moldovsky.
Dilbeck's right hand.
You must be a very busy man.
Touche.
I wish to give you some advice…
…about your adorable
little daughter, Angela.
- What about her?
- Your custody of her is illegal.
That's just temporary
until the appeal gets heard…
Please, please, Miss Grant.
Really, it's of no concern to us.
As long as you refuse to cooperate
with certain individuals…
…who seek to harm
and slur Congressman Dilbeck…
…for their own selfish
political gain.
I don't know what you're
talking about. Excuse me.
Perhaps you don't.
But what a pity if Angela were
to be placed in a state home.
Pretty grim, most of them.
A lot of strange people working there.
I'd recommend that you cooperate
with us for the child's sake.
Which means you talk
to no one about tonight…
…or any night.
Understood?
Of course.
Good.
Now if you'll excuse me…
…I'd better toss the congressman
into a cold shower.
By the way, I can see why
he's so taken by your charms.
Good night.
Watch your step on the gangplank.
She ain't dumb enough.
- Try anything?
- No.
He ask you back?
No.
Aren't we Miss Talkative tonight?
I'm a little tired.
LORELEl: What's the matter, baby?
Come on.
[LORELEl GRUNTING]
Monty.
[GRUNTING]
MAN: All right!
- Yeah.
[GRUNTING]
This reptile's a freaking lemon.
Who are you?
Help!
- So how did it go?
- Fine.
- No problems?
- No, none.
But no information.
Zero.
Look, I gotta run, you know.
Angela's wiped.
I'll see you later, okay?
MAN:
Come on, come on!
MAN 2:
Come on, you can do it!
Get this off of me.
MONIQUE:
Do something!
I'm doing something.
I'm protecting you.
- Stand back.
- Oh, my God. What a show.
That's not Monty!
SABRINA:
You're fine, hon. You'll be fine.
Who was that snake?
It doesn't look bad.
What happened here?
We got a problem with a dead snake.
Gee, that's funny.
So do I.
GARCIA: Here's that brilliant, charming
attorney of yours, Mr. Mordecai.
Found him 400 yards offshore.
Now show him the rest of his kisser.
Crabs find lawyers
a particular delicacy.
Looks like lasagna.
Cover that shit up.
You wanna tell me why your name
was on his calendar for tomorrow?
I was involved in litigation
with a yogurt company.
From my limited experience,
this isn't something…
…a yogurt company
would ordinarily do.
He represented the kid
who got mauled at your club.
Now that I find fascinating, Shad.
He had a picture. Ugh.
Man, I'm gonna lose it.
No, no. A picture of what?
A legislator?
Yeah, beating a kid's ass.
- Where's the original?
- I got no idea.
Here, freshen up.
All right, thanks.
- Can I interest you in dessert?
- Just the check.
- Come here.
CORONER: Ha, ha, ha.
- Dilbeck didn't invite her back?
- She said no.
That's good. I don't think she should
go there again, even with you.
She seemed all edgy tonight.
Man, she got her moods.
Could be that time of month.
So you're like the gynecologist-bouncer,
bouncer-gynecologist.
- I just watch out for the girl.
- So do I.
That's a grand total
of two people in Florida.
The higher-ups in my department
aren't pushing this investigation.
- Because of this asshole congressman?
- Bingo.
We got two homicides here,
and nobody gives a shit.
And I'm worried about that girl.
She's out there all by herself.
Where's the sheriff?
ERIN:
Hello, city desk?
It is an unusual time
for a news conference…
…but the congressman feels
it will dramatize his message.
NEWSWOMAN:
We'll send a camera crew.
- Confirm?
- There won't be any need to confirm.
- Got everything.
- Thank you.
Good morning, pumpkin.
How'd you sleep?
Good. How about you?
Well, I just…
I slept great, honey.
Want some cereal?
Not right now.
RECEPTIONIST: Good morning.
- Hello, CNN?
- May I help you?
- News desk.
One second, please.
This is Jennifer…
…and I'm calling from
Congressman Dilbeck's office.
Malcolm Moldovsky asked me to call…
…about the news conference
at the refinery.
[TOM SCREAMING]
ERIN:
Mm-hm.
[ANGELA LAUGHING]
DARRELL: Ugh!
RITA: Quit moving!
Whose Mercedes is that?
- Some orthodontist from Tampa.
- God, what would Mom say?
She'd say, «Nice fucking car. » Ow!
You got a mouth like a sewer!
I need some morphine.
I don't got none for humans.
What do you mean?
All's I got is some
from when Lupa had her cubs.
- Wolf morphine?
- I don't know. I think so.
So give me. I'm dying.
Busted arm, two nights in jail.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, Darrell!
How'd you break it?
Playing polo with Donald Trump, okay?
RITA: It says here you take two
every four hours with a bowl of milk.
Sounds good to me.
I said two!
Goddamn it!
You have to throw down a spade,
another seven, unless you have an eight.
Then you can change suits.
So that's why
they call it Crazy Eights.
ANGELA:
When are you coming back?
By two. But I hope
you will be asleep.
We'll take care of her.
Don't worry.
You're going out?
I'll be back by two.
I'll dance the late shift.
- Can you tell me where you…
- No, I can't.
- You be good, pumpkin.
- I will.
She'll be fine.
Don't worry.
ERIN:
See you, baby.
You're going to the boat?
Not without me.
I'll be late.
SHAD:
Listen up.
- You said you weren't going.
- I didn't want anybody to know.
- Like who?
- Garcia.
Then just say, «Don't tell Garcia. »
What's up?
They'll put Angela in a foster home
if I don't keep my mouth shut.
- Says who?
- Dilbeck's guy, that creep Moldovsky.
Promise me you will stay with her
every second. I need to know that.
I can't let you go there alone.
They're gonna pay me $5,000.
I need the money.
I need to get out of here and
live a normal, fully-dressed life…
…with shopping lists
and school buses.
If they wanted to kill me,
they would have.
Let me get this straight.
So you gonna go there, dance
and come back here.
Correct.
Something's up.
I've got it under control.
Promise me you'll stay
with Angela every second.
- I'll see you later.
SHAD: Erin.
DRIVER: Bonsoir.
ERIN: Bonsoir.
[SEAT BELT SENSOR BEEPING]
[HORNS HONKING
AND TIRES SCREECHING]
[SEAT BELT SENSOR
CONTINUES BEEPING]
[HORNS HONKING
AND TIRES SCREECHING]
DRIVER:
Sorry.
You speak English?
Sometime.
What do you think
about the people you work for?
They're filth.
Exploiters of the poor.
I think you and I are gonna
get along just fine.
For $5,000, I expect to get laid.
It's only human.
Davey, listen to me.
DILBECK: That beautiful lady
doesn't understand.
She doesn't understand what it's like
to make love to a congressman.
The ecstasy, the wonderful…
Listen to me, you sick fuck!
She's been meeting with a cop.
Maybe he's from the titty squad.
MALCOLM:
He's homicide.
She used to work
at the FBI as a secretary.
This bitch is poison.
She's out to slaughter us.
Make a fool of me.
Screw yourself bowlegged,
Davey of the Navy.
Then let us handle it.
I'll be on the top deck.
I thought she cared for me.
We're heavy.
Copy.
- Uh-huh.
TIFFANY: No cheating.
- One, two, three…
MONIQUE: Doesn't look good.
- Whee!
SHAD: Can't get a break.
[WOMEN LAUGH]
MONIQUE:
Shad's a loser. Shad's a loser.
Yo! Yo!
LORELEl:
All right, Miss Angela.
Six!
She always gets six.
[EURYTHMICS' «SWEET DREAMS»
PLAYING ON STEREO]
Sweet dreams are made of this
Who am I to disagree?
I travel the world and the seven seas
Everybody's looking for something
Some of them want to use you
Down, Bowser. Be patient.
Don't tease me!
I'm not teasing.
You just sit back…
…relax, have yourself another drink.
Because tonight is the night.
It sure is.
Sweet dreams are made of this
Who am I to disagree?
Ah! Ow!
Who are you?
I want my daughter.
What? Chico!
How'd you get onboard?
My little 'un. I want her.
Your «little «un,»
whoever she is, is not here.
Chico!
Keep your head up
Moving on
[GUN CLICKING]
What's this?
- Damn!
- Yeah, look…
Well, there's a sight
to raise the dead.
Who's that old freak?
Hold on a second.
I know who that is.
Is that the… Hey.
Is that that guy
from Price Is Right?
- Hey!
- Argh!
Oh, damn.
[GRUNTING]
You got my daughter…
…and now you try
and kill me with a ax!
I don't have your daughter!
You're confused.
And it's «an» axe.
I'm stoned…
- …but I ain't confused.
- Hey. Hey!
You stole my little 'un!
Sweet dreams are made of this
Who am I to disagree?
[GLASS SHATTERING]
Before we make love,
I wish to shave you.
I don't need a shave.
Everybody's looking for something
Some of them want to use you
Evening, partygoers.
Some of them want to get used by you
Some of them want to abuse you
Some of them want to be abused
[CROWD CHEERING]
Sweet dreams are made of this
Who am I to disagree?
I travel the world and the seven seas
Where's Erin?
Everybody's looking for something
I don't hear you.
Bullshit.
[CROWD CHEERING]
Hold your head up
Keep your head up
MAN 1:
Tiffany!
Hold your head up
Moving on
Keep your head up
Hold your head up
Moving on
Keep your head up
Hold your head up
Moving on
Keep your head up
MAN 1:
Yeah!
MAN 1: Tiffany!
MAN 2: Here we go, babe! Here we go!
[CROWD CHEERING]
Sweet dreams are made of this
Who am I to disagree?
I travel the world and the seven seas
Everybody's looking for something
Is Mommy okay?
She's fine, honey.
We're gonna pick her up now.
MONIQUE: We'll play card games,
have some fun!
She won't like this.
She told me…
I don't care what she told you!
How could you let her go alone?
- I thought you were in jail.
- I made my bail.
- This son of a bitch your…
- Hang on.
Here's your nickel.
Nice dance.
- Would you please just get out of here?
- Unh! Ow!
Hey. Are you that guy
from Price Is Right?
No. I'm Congressman David Dilbeck.
Congressman?
DILBECK: Yeah.
DARRELL: No shit?
Well, I steal wheelchairs…
…so we got a lot in common.
I'm getting tired. I think
I just killed a lying weasel.
You did what?
Beat him with this here club.
Well then, get out!
And leave us alone!
I'm about to mount this here beauty.
Maybe not.
You're talking about my wife.
It's time for us
to take a little drive.
Malcolm.
Malcolm!
ERIN: Move it, move it!
DILBECK: Yes, ma'am. Yes, ma'am.
DARRELL: Get on…
ERIN: Keep quiet!
DILBECK: Pick a good one. Take it!
ERIN: Hurry it up!
Shit, look at this.
Help me, you assholes.
DILBECK:
Help!
CHICO:
Stop! Stop!
I voted against gun control.
Weapons could end up in the wrong hands.
Will you please shut up?
What?
- It doesn't start.
- Come on, man.
We are in trouble.
Oh, no!
Tsk, tsk, tsk.
[LAUGHING]
That fracture looks bad.
We ought to drop him off
at the doctor.
- We're not dropping anybody anywhere.
- My sister Rita done up my arm.
Oh, really?
I'm a great believer in family.
Do you have a pen and paper?
It didn't feel the way I thought,
killing a man.
- Killing a man?
- It felt terrible.
- I want you to write something.
- What?
I want you to give me
custody of Angela.
- No way.
- You're going to jail for what you did…
…and I will not have that child
placed in a foster home.
So please. A simple note.
«I, Darrell Grant…»
I love that little 'un.
I know you do.
«…give full custody…»
- You do?
ERIN: Yes, I do.
Let's do this for her.
Let's not put her at risk anymore.
«…to my wife, Erin Grant. »
Okay.
Good boy.
You know, you write quite poorly.
Are you a high-school graduate?
Darrell.
Shit!
[TIRES SCREECHING]
Everybody just stay put, all right?
This girl is nuts.
My prostate doctor said…
…that I have to urinate
whenever possible.
Then go relieve yourself over there.
Go. Pierre, just stay with him.
Darrell?
Darrell? Darrell!
Now wake up.
Come on. Here.
You gotta sign this.
Sign your name,
that's all you gotta do…
…before you get arrested.
Now come on.
Sign your name.
There you go.
«Darrell Grant. »
Good boy. Good.
That's right.
I'm back!
No more teasing.
Oh, finally.
What?
Finally you take me like a man.
Like a congressman.
I knew you cared for me.
Malcolm didn't know
what he was talking about.
- Now take me.
- Here?
I've got a special spot
picked out for us.
Get that music box for me,
will you, honey?
- Sorry, boss. It all happened…
- Shut up, you nitwit!
Don't explain. We got a goddamn
stripper about to bring us all down.
How do I look?
Not bad.
- What happened to him?
DILBECK: I hit him with a rock.
Who's the man?
You're the man.
You are the man and oh, so strong.
- Well, here we are.
- Here?
You ever make it
on a pile of sugar before?
No, but I'm willing to try.
Well, you're in for a treat.
You're in for a treat too, darling.
Now you just let me
put some music on…
…while you take off
those pretty little pants.
You'd better put on
some blast goggles.
Because you're in
for an overwhelming sight.
SHAD:
Shit! Radio for help!
GARCIA: What do I tell them?
Congressman Dilbeck abducted a woman.
They'll shut off their radios
and go help him.
So we're it.
A cop and a bouncer.
Plus two strippers and a kid.
We're in great shape.
[DEAN MARTIN'S «RETURN TO ME»
PLAYING ON STEREO]
And two. How come here?
How come not that yacht?
I'm kind of private.
I don't like people watching.
Me neither.
I don't like anything kinky.
I know you don't.
You're a real man.
I knew it when poor Jerry
was killed and Shad's lawyer.
I said, «Davey's the real thing.
An M-A-N man. »
DILBECK:
A man blackmails you…
…you got to deal with it!
You got to be hard and firm.
Whoo! And you can dance.
- Marry me.
- What?
Marry me. Just say it.
- You are married.
- I know.
But I'd leave my wife in a heartbeat.
She wouldn't care.
She doesn't like me anyhow.
Well, this is very sudden,
and I have a lot to think about.
- I'll make you proud of me.
- I know you would.
It's like when Jerry said,
«I'm gonna shake down Dilbeck. »
And I said, «Are you crazy?
Blackmail a real man like that?»
I said to Malcolm,
«Just do what you have to do…
…to Jerry, that fat lawyer.
Just do it!»
- Just do it.
- Just do it! And he did.
- Didn't he?
- He sure did.
MALCOLM:
You idiot!
- Shit.
- Hi, Malcolm! How you doing?
I'd like to introduce you
to my fiancee.
This is Miss Erin Grant.
Sorry, Davey.
You both gotta go.
Willie's orders.
You are sick.
- Murder-suicide, Miss Grant.
- Suicide?
Hell of a story, isn't it?
A congressman and a stripper.
Excuse me.
What did you call me?
A stripper.
Dancer, asshole.
George Bush!
That's not George Bush.
That doesn't look anything like George Bush.
Drop them.
You got till three.
One.
- What are you, nuts?
- Yeah, psycho.
Delusions of invincibility combined
with a strong homicidal urge.
I have a kick-your-ass fetish.
Two.
Boss?
SHAD:
Three!
Nico. Ah! Goddamn it!
Good evening, everyone.
ALL:
Postman, postman
Do your duty
Send this letter
To an American beauty
GARCIA:
You're now under arrest.
For a variety of charges.
[GROANING]
I need some coffee.
Why don't we start with homicide.
You're not arresting anyone.
Black.
No sugar.
[MACHINE BUZZING]
I said, no sugar.
[ALL COUGHING]
You know you have
a serious dandruff problem.
Ladies!
Mama! Mama!
Baby!
- You okay, Mama?
- I'm fine, baby.
See how you could get tendinitis?
WOMAN:
Come on, guys.
Congressman, you called
a news conference?
Holy shit!
[ALL COUGHING]
Thank you.
There comes a time in
every public figure's career…
…when he has to think
about his future.
You are making
a tragic mistake here.
[REPORTERS CLAMORING]
DILBECK [ON RECORDER]:
- Jerry, fat lawyer. Just do it! And he did.
MALCOLM:
You idiot!
Do you have any idea
how nuts this was?
Mama?
We're going, baby.
Thank you for all your help.
Yeah, likewise.
Keep me posted
on what you decide to do.
- Maybe I'll run for Congress.
- There's gonna be a seat open now.
- I'll talk to you soon.
- Yeah. Stay in touch.
You shouldn't have
done this without me.
It won't happen again.
[English - US - SDH]