TOMMY, HIT IT UP !
LET'S HAVE IT !
♪
MAY I CUT IN ?
WHY, CERTAINLY.
BOYS WILL BE BOYS.
WHOO !
NOT ALL GIRLS ARE RAVING
BLOODY LESBIANS, YOU KNOW.
THAT IS A MISFORTUNE
THAT I'M PERFECTLY WELL AWARE OF.
SHE SAYS THAT I THINK MORE
OF YOU THAN I DO OF HER.
WELL, YOU DO,
DON'T YOU ?
WELL, WE WON'T
GO INTO THAT.
OH !
GO RIGHT AHEAD, BOYS.
DON'T MIND ME.
BUT YOU'RE NOT A GIRL,
YOU'RE A GUY, AND WHY WOULD A GUY...
WANT TO MARRY A GUY ?
SECURITY.
I THINK THAT THE RIGHT WOMAN
COULD REFORM YOU.
YOU KNOW, I THINK THE RIGHT
WOMAN COULD REFORM YOU TOO. OH !
THESE AREN'T MY CLOTHES.
WHY ARE YOU WEARING THESE CLOTHES ?
BECAUSE I JUST WENT GAY
ALL OF A SUDDEN !
[ Lily Tomlin ]
IN A HUNDRED YEARS OF MOVIES,
HOMOSEXUALITY HAS ONLY RARELY
BEEN DEPICTED ON THE SCREEN.
WHEN IT DID APPEAR, IT WAS THERE
AS SOMETHING TO LAUGH AT...
OR SOMETHING TO PITY,
OR EVEN SOMETHING TO FEAR.
THESE WERE FLEETING IMAGES,
BUT THEY WERE UNFORGETTABLE.
AND THEY LEFT A LASTING LEGACY.
HOLLYWOOD,
THAT GREAT MAKER OF MYTHS, TAUGHT STRAIGHT PEOPLE...
WHAT TO THINK
ABOUT GAY PEOPLE...
AND GAY PEOPLE WHAT TO THINK
ABOUT THEMSELVES.
NO ONE ESCAPED ITS INFLUENCE.
MOVIES ARE PART
OF MY LIFE.
PART OF
EVERYBODY'S LIFE.
THAT'S WHERE
WE LEARN ABOUT LIFE.
WATCHING CARY GRANT TAUGHT ME
HOW TO BEHAVE WITH A WOMAN,
HOW TO GET DRESSED AT NIGHT,
HOW TO GO TO A RESTAURANT
AND ORDER DINNER.
THEY'RE OUR STORYTELLING.
THEY'RE THE FABRIC OF OUR LIVES.
THEY SHOW US WHAT IS GLORIOUS...
AND TRAGIC AND WONDERFUL
AND FUNNY...
ABOUT THE DAY-TO-DAY EXPERIENCES
THAT WE ALL SHARE.
AND WHEN YOU'RE GAY AND DON'T
SEE THAT REFLECTED IN ANY WAY,
EVER,
IN THE MOVIES,
YOU BEGAN TO FEEL
THAT SOMETHING TRULY IS WRONG.
YOU FEEL INVISIBLE; YOU FEEL
LIKE A GHOST,
AND A GHOST THAT NOBODY
BELIEVES IN.
THERE'S THIS SENSE
OF ISOLATION.
JOIN THE CLUB,
MAN.
[ Laughs ]
THIS IS A WHOLE GROUP,
YOU KNOW,
THAT IS NOT REPRESENTED.
WE ARE PATHETICALLY STARVED
FOR IMAGES OF OURSELVES.
SO MUCH SO THAT A FRIEND
WILL CALL YOU UP AND SAY,
"OH, THERE'S A MOVIE YOU MUST
SEE !"  THIS HAPPENED TO ME.
"THIS MOVIE YOU'VE GOTTA SEE.
THERE'S THIS INCREDIBLE LESBIAN RELATIONSHIP IN IT.
"AND THERE'S THIS GREAT
LOVE SCENE, AND--
ALL RIGHT, THEY'RE VAMPIRES;
BUT YOU GOTTA SEE IT. IT'S GREAT."
THERE ARE LOTS OF NEEDS
FOR ART.
THE GREATEST ONE IS THE MIRROR
OF OUR OWN LIVES...
AND OUR OWN EXISTENCE.
AND THAT HUNGER
THAT I FELT AS A KID,
LOOKING FOR GAY IMAGES,
WAS TO NOT BE ALONE.
MY MOTHER TOOK ME
TO THE SILENT MOVIES...
IN A SPIRIT
OF OSTENTATIOUS CONDESCENSION.
SHE TOLD ME THAT THEY
WERE NOTHING LIKE REAL LIFE...
AND THAT I MUST NOT
BELIEVE THEM.
AND SHE WAS WRONG,
BECAUSE EVERYONE...
WHO COMES FROM ENGLAND
TO AMERICA AND GOES BACK...
SAYS ONE THING FIRST.
"IT'S MORE LIKE THE MOVIES
THAN YOU'D EVER DREAM."
AND IT IS.
[ Tomlin ]
FROM THE VERY BEGINNING, MOVIES COULD RELY ON HOMOSEXUALITY...
AS A SUREFIRE SOURCE OF HUMOR.
YOUR IDEAS ABOUT WHO YOU ARE
DON'T JUST COME FROM INSIDE YOU, THEY COME FROM THE CULTURE.
AND IN THIS CULTURE THEY COME
ESPECIALLY FROM THE MOVIES.
SO WE LEARN WHAT IT MEANS
TO BE A MAN OR A WOMAN, TO HAVE SEXUALITY.
[ Dyer ]
THE MOVIES DID PROVIDE US WITH SOME KIND OF HISTORY...
OF HOW SOCIETY
THOUGHT HOMOSEXUALS WERE.
A VERY GOOD EXAMPLE IS THE
CHAPLIN FILM BEHIND THE SCREEN.
THERE IS AN EXTRAORDINARY MOMENT
WHERE CHAPLIN KISSES SOMEONE WHO LOOKS LIKE A MAN.
HE KNOWS THAT IT'S A WOMAN.
AND SOMEONE ELSE COMES ALONG
AND SEES IT AND IMMEDIATELY STARTS SWISHING AROUND...
IN THE MOST KIND OF OVERT,
EFFEMINATE WAY.
IT'S FASCINATING
THAT THOSE STEREOTYPES WERE SO COMPLETELY IN PLACE...
THAT A, YOU KNOW, MAINSTREAM
POPULAR FILM COULD ASSUME...
THAT THE AUDIENCE WOULD KNOW
WHAT THIS SWISHY MIME WAS ALL ABOUT.
- MR. ERNEST.
- ERNEST.
DEAR ERNEST !
DEAR LADY GRAYSTON.
ERNEST, I'M SO HAPPY YOU WERE ABLE TO COME.
YOU MUST EXCUSE MY COMING
IN MY TOWN CLOTHES,
BUT THERE WASN'T A MOMENT
TO LOSE, SO I CAME JUST AS I AM.
[ Tomlin ]
ENTER THE SISSY,
HOLLYWOOD'S FIRST GAY
STOCK CHARACTER.
THE SISSY MADE EVERYONE
FEEL MORE MANLY OR MORE WOMANLY...
BY OCCUPYING THE SPACE
IN BETWEEN.
HE DIDN'T SEEM TO HAVE
A SEXUALITY,
SO HOLLYWOOD ALLOWED HIM
TO THRIVE.
[ Woman ]
THEY WERE SISSIES, NEVER ADDRESSED AS HOMOSEXUAL.
IT WAS A CONVENTION
THAT WAS ACCEPTED.
THEY WERE PERCEIVED AS
HOMOSEXUALS JUST SUBLIMINALLY.
THIS IS A SUBJECT THAT
WAS NOT DISCUSSED PRIVATELY.
UH, CERTAINLY NOT PUBLICLY.
IT WASN'T DISCUSSED,
BUT YOU KNEW.
THEY WERE ALL VERY PRISSY.
YOU KNOW, THESE LITTLE SKINNY
WHITE MEN WITH LITTLE MOUSTACHES WHO WOULD GO LIKE THIS.
[ Women Chattering ]
GIRLS !  GIRLS !
BE CAREFUL OF MY HATS !
WE GOTTA GET ON THE STAGE !
I DON'T CARE !  I WON'T
ALLOW YOU TO RUIN THEM.
I TOLD YOU THEY WERE TOO HIGH
AND TOO WIDE.
WELL, BIG WOMAN,
I DESIGN THE COSTUMES,
NOT THE DOORS
FOR THE THEATER.
IF YOU HAD,
THEY'D HAVE BEEN LAVENDER. HMPH !
THIS IS RIPPED.
WHO WERE YOU WITH LAST NIGHT ?
STRANGLER LEWIS.
OH !  CATCH AS CATCH CAN, HMM ?
IF WE COULD GET THE RUNS
WITH THIS SHOW THAT THESE DAMES GET IN THEIR STOCKINGS,
I'D BE ABLE TO MAKE
THE SECOND PAYMENT ON MY KIMONO !
HERE, CLARENCE.
PUT THAT IN THE TRUNK.
AND DON'T WEAR IT.
SELFISH.
THEY WERE A CLICHE. I DON'T CARE
WHETHER THEY WERE A GAY CLICHE OR WHAT.
I THOUGHT THEY WERE DISGUSTING,
UNFUNNY, HAD NO BUSINESS
BEING IN IT.
AND I NEVER UNDERSTOOD
WHY PEOPLE LAUGHED.
IT'S THE SAME THING WHEN THEY
HAD THE STEPPIN FETCHITS FOR THE BLACKS.
I LIKE THE SISSY.
UM, IS IT USED
IN NEGATIVE WAYS ?  YEAH.
BUT MY VIEW HAS ALWAYS BEEN...
VISIBILITY AT ANY COST.
UM, I'D RATHER HAVE NEGATIVE
THAN NOTHING.
THAT'S JUST
MY PARTICULAR VIEW, AND ALSO 'CAUSE I AM A SISSY.
♪ AND GO DASHING
UP AND DOWN THE HALL ♪
[ Tomlin ]
IN ONE MOVIE YOU COULD EVEN FIND SISSIES TABLE-HOPPING...
IN HOLLYWOOD'S FIRST PEEK
AT A GAY BAR.
♪ IF A SAILOR IN PAJAMAS
I SHOULD SEE ♪
♪ I KNOW HE'D SCARE
THE LIFE OUT OF ME ♪
♪ AND ON A GREAT BIG
BATTLESHIP ♪
♪ YOU'D LIKE TO BE ♪
♪ WORKING AS CHAMBERMAIDS ♪
[ Patrons Laughing ]
WELL, SISSY CHARACTERS
IN MOVIES...
WERE ALWAYS A JOKE.
THERE'S NO SIN
LIKE BEING A WOMAN.
WHEN A MAN DRESSES AS A WOMAN,
THE AUDIENCE LAUGHS.
WHEN A WOMAN DRESSES AS A MAN,
NOBODY LAUGHS.
THEY JUST THOUGHT
SHE LOOKED WONDERFUL.
[ Male Audience Exclaiming ]
I SAW MARLENE DEITRICH
IN MOROCCO...
WHEN I WAS A TEENAGER;
I JUST WAS FLIPPING THE CHANNELS AND SAW HER...
AND DECIDED
TO SETTLE IN FOR AN OLD MOVIE.
AND THERE'S
THIS SCENE...
WHERE SHE COMES
INTO A NIGHTCLUB, AND SHE'S JUST STUNNING...
IN THIS TUXEDO.
MAY I HAVE THIS ?
OF COURSE !
[ Everyone Laughs ]
AND THE CAMERA LINGERS.  IT
WASN'T LIKE I WAS CATCHING THIS OUT OF THE SIDE OF THE SCREEN.
IT'S RIGHT IN THE CENTER.
SHE HAS A ROMANCE
WITH GARY COOPER IN THIS MOVIE,
BUT THAT WENT RIGHT
OUT THE WINDOW FOR ME.
I WAS JUST LIKE, WHO WAS THAT
WOMAN ?  WHAT HAD HAPPENED ?
I STARTED WRITING
A WHOLE OTHER SCRIPT FOR WHAT WAS REALLY GOING ON.
SO THE THING WORKED
FOR EVERYBODY OF EVERY SEX.
AND WHAT'S AMAZING,
I DON'T THINK THEY'VE DONE ANYTHING...
AS DELICIOUS SEXUALLY
AS THAT SINCE.
THEY DIDN'T PRETEND IT WAS
ANYTHING BUT WHAT IT WAS:
SHE WAS DOING IT TO TURN ON
BOTH THE WOMAN AND THE MAN,
WHICH APPEALED TO EVERYBODY.
AS IT SHOULD.
IT WAS SO FREE.
[ Woman ]
EBBA !  COME IN.
[ Man ]
NOW DON'T DALLY, YOUR MAJESTY.
YOU HAVE A BUSY DAY.
MORNING, EBBA.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING UP
SO EARLY ? I COULDN'T SLEEP.
[ Tomlin ]
THE MOVIE QUEEN CHRISTINA...
WAS BASED ON THE LIFE
OF A REAL SWEDISH MONARCH AND LESBIAN.
HOLLYWOOD CHANGED THE STORY,
BUT TRACES OF THE TRUTH
SEEMED TO LINGER.
THERE ARE RUMORS
THAT YOUR MAJESTY IS PLANNING A FOREIGN MARRIAGE.
THEY ARE BASELESS.
BUT YOUR MAJESTY,
YOU CANNOT DIE AN OLD MAID !
I HAVE NO INTENTION TO,
CHANCELLOR.
I SHALL DIE A BACHELOR !
WE HOPE THAT IT
WILL NOT BE NECESSARY...
TO CLOSE ALL
THE MOTION PICTURE HOUSES...
BECAUSE OF SOME OF THE ONES
THAT ARE NOT DESIRABLE,
BUT THAT WE WILL HAVE CLEANER
AND BETTER MOTION PICTURES,
SO THAT THEY MAY ALL STAY OPEN.
WHAT HAPPENED, OF COURSE,
IN THE '20s AND THE '30s...
WHEN THEY BEGAN TO GET
VERY RAUNCHY,
THE CATHOLIC CHURCH AND
FUNDAMENTALIST PROTESTANTS...
CAME DOWN HARD.
YOU KNOW THERE WAS
A LOT OF PULPIT STUFF, A LOT OF PREACHING...
ABOUT ORGIASTIC ASPECTS
OF WHAT WAS HAPPENING ON THE SCREEN.
[ Man ]
THE BIG CHANGE OCCURRED WHEN THE MOVIE MOGULS GOT TOGETHER.
"LET'S SAVE HOLLYWOOD.
"WE MUST GET AN OUTSIDER,
PREFERABLY SOME POLITICIAN...
WHO IS ABOVE SUSPICION."
SO THEY LOOKED INTO THE CABINET
OF WARREN G. HARDING.
AT THAT TIME THERE WERE A NUMBER
OF UNINDICTED MEMBERS OF HIS CABINET.
AND THEY PICKED THE POSTMASTER
GENERAL, WILL HAYS OF INDIANA,
WHO LOOKED
NOT UNLIKE MICKEY MOUSE.
THE CODE SETS UP HIGH STANDARDS
OF PERFORMANCE...
FOR MOTION PICTURE PRODUCERS.
IT STATES THE CONSIDERATIONS...
WHICH GOOD TASTE AND COMMUNITY
VALUE...
MAKE NECESSARY IN THIS
UNIVERSAL FORM OF ENTERTAINMENT.
[ Tomlin ]
WILL HAYS WOULD HEAD THE MOVIES' FIRST VOLUNTARY EFFORT...
AT SELF-CENSORSHIP.
THE EARLY HAYS CODE WAS A TOKEN
GESTURE, SELDOM TAKEN SERIOUSLY.
BUT BY 1934 THE CATHOLIC CHURCH
HAD DEVISED...
A SCHEME OF ITS OWN.
THE LEGION OF DECENCY NOT ONLY
RATED MOVIES AS TO CONTENT,
BUT THREATENED MASSIVE BOYCOTTS.
HOLLYWOOD PROMISED
TO PLAY BY THE RULES.
THE HAYS CODE JUST...
SET UP A SERIES OF RULES
THAT WERE INVIOLABLE.
[ Tomlin ]
CODE DIRECTOR JOE BREEN...
RAN HOLLYWOOD'S CENSORSHIP
MACHINERY FOR OVER TWO DECADES.
HE WAS AUTHORIZED
TO CHANGE WORDS, PERSONALITIES AND PLOTS.
A NOVEL ABOUT A SEXUALLY
CONFUSED ALCOHOLIC...
BECAME A MOVIE ABOUT AN
ALCOHOLIC WITH WRITER'S BLOCK.
A NOVEL ABOUT GAY BASHING
AND MURDER...
BECAME A MOVIE
ABOUT ANTI-SEMITISM AND MURDER.
OUR AMERICAN PEOPLE
ARE A PRETTY HOMELY...
AND WHOLESOME CROWD.
COCKEYED PHILOSOPHIES OF LIFE,
UGLY SEX SITUATIONS, CHEAP JOKES
AND DIRTY DIALOGUE...
ARE NOT WANTED.
THE DECENT PEOPLE
DON'T LIKE THIS SORT OF STUFF,
AND IT IS OUR JOB TO SEE TO IT
THAT THEY GET NONE OF IT.
HAVE YOU EVER
MODELED BEFORE ? NO, I HAVEN'T.
I'M DOING A STUDY OF A YOUNG
GIRL'S HEAD AND SHOULDERS.
YOU WON'T OBJECT TO REMOVING
YOUR BLOUSE, WILL YOU ?
NO, I GUESS NOT.
YOU CAN GET READY
BEHIND THAT SCREEN.
[ Tomlin ]
THE PRODUCTION CODE...
DIDN'T ERASE HOMOSEXUALS
FROM THE SCREEN; IT JUST MADE THEM HARDER TO FIND.
AND NOW THEY HAD A NEW IDENTITY
AS COLD-BLOODED VILLAINS.
I'M READY NOW.
- YOU'LL WANT THESE
PULLED DOWN, WON'T YOU ? - YES.
WHY ARE YOU LOOKING AT ME
THAT WAY ?  WON'T I DO ?
YES, YOU'LL
DO VERY WELL INDEED.
DO YOU LIKE JEWELS, LILY ?
THIS IS VERY OLD
AND VERY BEAUTIFUL.
I'LL SHOW IT TO YOU.
I DON'T THINK
I'LL POSE TONIGHT.  I--
I THINK I'LL GO,
IF YOU DON'T MIND.
PLEASE DON'T
COME ANY CLOSER !
[ Screaming ]
I DIDN'T EXPECT TO SEE YOU,
MRS. DANVERS.
A WINDOW WASN'T CLOSED,
AND I CAME TO FASTEN IT.
WHY DID YOU SAY THAT ?
I CLOSED IT BEFORE I LEFT THE ROOM.
YOU OPENED IT YOURSELF,
DIDN'T YOU ?
[ Bright ]
REBECCA IS ONE OF THE MOVIES...
IN WHICH THE WORD HOMOSEXUALITY
OR LESBIANISM IS NEVER UTTERED.
BUT THERE'S THIS ONE SCENE...
THAT REALLY STANDS OUT
FOR A GAY AUDIENCE.
AND THAT IS, REBECCA IS DEAD.
SHE WAS THE BEAUTIFUL WOMAN
WHO IS MYSTERIOUSLY NOT ON THE SCENE ANY LONGER.
AND HER FORMER HOUSEKEEPER,
MRS. DANVERS,
IS OBSESSED WITH HER,
EVEN AFTER HER DEATH.
THIS IS WHERE I
KEEP ALL HER CLOTHES.
YOU WOULD LIKE TO SEE THEM,
WOULDN'T YOU ?
FEEL THIS.
IT WAS A CHRISTMAS PRESENT
FROM MR. DeWINTER.
HE WAS ALWAYS GIVING HER
EXPENSIVE GIFTS THE WHOLE YEAR ROUND.
I KEEP HER UNDERWEAR
ON THIS SIDE.
THEY WERE MADE SPECIALLY
FOR HER BY THE NUNS IN THE CONVENT OF ST. CLAIR.
SHE OPENS THE UNDERWEAR DRAWER !
IT'S SO SENSUOUS.
LOOK.  YOU CAN SEE
MY HAND THROUGH IT.
THE GUYS WHO RAN THAT CODE
WEREN'T ROCKET SCIENTISTS. THEY MISSED A LOT OF STUFF.
AND IF A DIRECTOR WAS SUBTLE
ENOUGH AND CLEVER ENOUGH, THEY GOT AROUND IT.
WHAT'LL IT COST
TO BE ON THE SAFE SIDE ?
OKAY.  GO AHEAD.
GARDENIA.
QUICK, DARLING. IN WITH HIM.
WE KNOW PETER LORRE'S GAY
IN THE MALTESE FALCON EVEN BEFORE WE SEE HIM.
WE'RE TOLD THAT THERE'S A MAN
OUTSIDE WEARING PERFUME, GARDENIA.
AND THEN WE ALSO HEAR SOME KIND
OF FUNNY, SLIGHTLY ORIENTAL,
FEMININE MUSIC.
- WILL YOU SIT DOWN,
MR. CAIRO ? - THANK YOU, SIR.
[ Tomlin ]
THE ORIGINAL NOVEL DIDN'T MINCE WORDS ABOUT LORRE'S CHARACTER.
IT READ, THIS GUY IS QUEER.
MAY I OFFER CONDOLENCES
FOR YOUR PARTNER'S UNFORTUNATE DEATH ?
[ Tomlin ]
THE MOVIE COULD ONLY HINT-- BROADLY.
SEE, MR. SPADE,
I'M TRYING TO RECOVER AN ORNAMENT...
THAT, UH, SHALL WE SAY
HAS BEEN MISLAID ?
UH-HUH.
I HOPED YOU COULD ASSIST ME.
THE ORNAMENT IS A STATUETTE,
A BLACK FIGURE OF A BIRD.
[ Tomlin ]
LEAVE IT TO ALFRED HITCHCOCK TO CREATE...
NOT ONE,
BUT TWO GAY VILLAINS.
MURDEROUS LOVERS, BASED
ON REAL-LIFE PSYCHOPATHS...
LEOPOLD AND LOEB.
WE KNEW THAT THEY WERE GAY.
YEAH.  SURE.
I MEAN, NOBODY SAID ANYTHING
ABOUT IT.
THIS WAS 1947.
LET'S NOT FORGET THAT.
THAT WAS ONE OF THE--
THE POINTS OF THE FILM,
IN A WAY.
BRANDON,
HOW DID YOU FEEL ?
WHEN ?
DURING IT.
I... DON'T KNOW, REALLY.
I DON'T REMEMBER FEELING
VERY MUCH OF ANYTHING.
UNTIL HIS BODY WENT LIMP.
AND I KNEW IT WAS OVER.
AND THEN ?
THEN I FELT...
TREMENDOUSLY EXHILARATED.
H-HOW DID YOU FEEL ?
[ Laurents ]
I DON'T THINK THE CENSORS AT THAT TIME...
REALIZED THAT THIS
WAS ABOUT GAY PEOPLE.
THEY DIDN'T HAVE A CLUE
WHAT WAS AND WHAT WASN'T. THAT'S HOW IT GOT BY.
[ Tomlin ]
SOMETIMES THE CENSORS TURNED A BLIND EYE...
TO LESBIANS ON THE SCREEN
AS LONG AS THEY WERE KEPT SAFELY BEHIND BARS.
HI, ANNE.
HELLO, HARPER.
SINCE YOU WENT FANCY
WORKIN' FOR BENTON, I KIND OF MISSED YOU.
THIS IS MARIE ALLEN.
MRS. BENTON SAYS TO PUT HER IN LAUNDRY.
MARIE'S GONNA HAVE A BABY.
A BABY, HUH ?
WHY, YOU'RE
JUST A KID YOURSELF.
SO LONG, MARIE.
GOOD-BYE, ANNE. THANK YOU.
LET'S YOU AND ME
GET ACQUAINTED, HONEY.
YOU MAY BE A NUMBER
TO THE OTHERS, BUT NOT TO ME.
SIT DOWN IN THIS CHAIR.
IT'S KIND OF ROOMY.
[ Bright ]
THERE'S SUPPOSED TO BE A SOCIAL MESSAGE TO ALL THIS.
ISN'T IT TERRIBLE
TO GO TO PRISON, TO LOSE YOUR FEMININITY ?
FOR A WOMAN TO GO HARD ?
WHAT'S YOUR NAME ?
HOW'D YOU HURT YOUR HAND ?
I'M A BIG GIRL, AND THIS ISN'T
MY FIRST YEAR AWAY FROM HOME.
MY NAME IS MARIE ALLEN.
IF I SAID NO TO KITTY,
I'M SURE NOT GONNA SAY YES TO YOU.
[ Woman Laughs ]
SHE'S A CUTE TRICK.
♪ I MAY BE WRONG BUT ♪
[ Bright ]
IN YOUNG MAN WITH A HORN, WE HAVE ONE OF MY FAVORITE...
LESBIAN GLAMOUR SYMBOLS.
JO'S INTERESTING, ISN'T SHE ?
SO SIMPLE AND UNCOMPLICATED.
IT MUST BE WONDERFUL TO KNOW
JUST WHICH DOOR YOU'RE GOING TO WALK THROUGH.
SHE'S SO TERRIBLY NORMAL.
♪ I MAY BE WRONG ♪
SHE'S A GOOD SINGER TOO.
I LIKE LAUREN BACALL
BECAUSE SHE GETS UP IN THE MORNING,
AND SHE HAS NO IDEA
WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN TO HER NEXT.
I'M DYING TO SEE THE REST
OF YOUR SKETCHES.
WE'LL HAVE DINNER OUT
AND THEN GO BACK TO MY PLACE.
HOW NICE OF YOU
TO COME TO THE PARTY, RICHARD.
THIS IS MY HUSBAND,
MISS CARSON.
I TOLD YOU ABOUT HER,
THE GIRL WHO PAINTS SO WELL.
HOW DO YOU DO ?
SEE YOU AT 9:00,
THEN, AMY. FINE.
IT'S BEEN A WONDERFUL PARTY.
THOSE MOVIES WERE A WARNING
TO LADIES TO JUST WATCH IT...
AND GET BACK
TO THE KITCHEN...
WHERE GOD MEANT THEM TO BE.
WHAT A SWELL COMBINATION
WE WERE !
YOU SAID YOU WANTED
EXPERIENCES, AMY.
WELL, HERE'S ONE FOR YOU.
I'M LEAVING YOU.
I'D LIKE TO KILL YOU !
YOU ALMOST DID.
YOU'RE A SICK GIRL, AMY.
YOU'D BETTER SEE A DOCTOR.
[ Allen ]
I LOOK BACK ON THE '50s NOW AND THINK THAT IT WAS HALCYON.
PEOPLE WERE STILL
BEING EDUCATED.
THERE WASN'T A RACE WAR ON.
THE DRUG THING WASN'T--
I-IT SEEMS LIKE
A KIND OF PARADISE NOW.
BUT AT THE TIME THAT
WE WERE LIVING THROUGH IT,
WE THOUGHT THAT WE
WERE IN A DECADE...
OF SUCH TOWERING DULLNESS
AND STUPIDITY.
I WANT TO BE PROUD
OF HIM.
THAT'S WHY I HAD HIM
IN THE FIRST PLACE.
BUT HE MAKES IT
SO DIFFICULT FOR ME.
MY ASSOCIATES ASK ME
WHAT HE WANTS TO BE,
AND I HAVE TO TELL THEM
THAT HE HASN'T MADE UP HIS MIND.
BECAUSE I JUST WON'T TELL
THEM THAT HE WANTS TO BE A--
A FOLKSINGER.
♪ THE GRIEF ♪
♪ OF LOVE ENDURES ♪
[ Tomlin ]
IN '50s AMERICA, MASCULINITY RULED.
SEEMING GAY WAS ALMOST AS BAD
AS BEING GAY,
SO A MAN HAD TO WATCH
HIS EVERY STEP.
LOOK, TOM,
THE WAY YOU WALK--
OH !
I'M JUST TRYING TO HELP YOU !
NOBODY GAVE A DAMN
ABOUT HOW I WALKED 'TIL LAST WEEK !
OKAY, OKAY !
FORGET IT !
AL ?
YEAH ?
[ Dyer ]
TEA AND SYMPATHY IS DEFINITELY ABOUT BEING HOMOSEXUAL.
I'M SORRY.
TELL ME HOW I WALK.
IT'S A FILM THAT'S ABOUT
CURING HOMOSEXUALITY.
AND THE SIGNS OF HOMOSEXUALITY
ARE EFFEMINACY.
WELL, THEN, YOU WALK.
LET ME WATCH YOU.
I-I NEVER NOTICED
HOW YOU WALK. OKAY.
DO IT AGAIN.
IF YOU TELL ANY OF THE GUYS
ABOUT THIS ! DO YOU THINK I WOULD ?
WE KNOW THE SAL MINEO CHARACTER
IS GAY...
PARTLY BECAUSE HE HAS
A PICTURE OF ALAN LADD IN HIS LOCKER,
BUT ALSO FROM HIS ADORATION...
OF THE JAMES DEAN CHARACTER.
HEY, YOU WANT TO COME HOME
WITH ME ?  THERE'S NOBODY HOME AT MY HOUSE.
HECK, I'M NOT TIRED.
ARE YOU ?
SEE, I DON'T HAVE TOO MANY
PEOPLE I CAN TALK TO.
WHO HAS ?
[ Man ]
PEOPLE TALK ABOUT WHETHER THAT WAS A HOMOSEXUAL RELATIONSHIP.
THE INTENTION WASN'T THAT.
BUT ANY FILM IS
AT THE SAME TIME...
AN EXPRESSION OF A WRITER,
AND IT'S AN OFFERING...
TO AN AUDIENCE...
TO CREATE THEIR OWN FILM.
ARE YOU COLD ?
[ Stern ]
REBEL WAS ABOUT TENDERNESS, INTIMACY.
IT WAS AN ATTEMPT TO WIDEN
THE PERMISSION TO LOVE...
WHEN MEN WERE SUPPOSED TO BE
ONE WAY WITH EACH OTHER.
CAN I KEEP IT ?
WELL, WHAT DO YOU THINK ? HERE.
I THINK IF I WERE WRITING
THAT SCRIPT AGAIN TODAY...
THAT I WOULD BE MUCH MORE
SPECIFIC ABOUT PLATO.
I WOULD LET HIM
BE AN OUTCAST...
BECAUSE THE GANG
THOUGHT HE WAS A FAGGOT,
AND LET HIS ISOLATION
COME FROM THAT OPINION.
WHAT ARE YOU GUYS
DOING ?
WE WANT YOUR FRIEND !
YEAH, WE GOT EYES FOR HIM !
[ Dyer ]
THE REAL REBEL SEEMS TO BE THE SAL MINEO CHARACTER.
HE'S GOT SOMETHING
TO BE REBELLIOUS ABOUT--
NAMELY, BEING GAY
IN A HOMOPHOBIC SOCIETY.
AND HE HAS TO BE KILLED.
- [ Guy ]
TURN OUT THE LIGHTS ! - [ Girl ]  JIM !
[ Dyer ]
THAT'S WHAT HAPPENS TO REAL REBELS IN OUR SOCIETY.
[ Gunshot ]
WELL, YOU GOT VERY GOOD...
AT PROJECTING SUBTEXT
WITHOUT SAYING A WORD ABOUT WHAT YOU WERE DOING.
THE BEST EXAMPLE I LIVED THROUGH
IS WRITING BEN-HUR.
BEN-HUR AND MESSALA,
ONE JEWISH, ONE ROMAN,
HAD KNOWN EACH OTHER IN YOUTH.
THEY DISAGREE OVER POLITICS,
AND NOW THEY HATE EACH OTHER FOR THE NEXT THREE HOURS.
WELL, THAT ISN'T MUCH
TO PUT A WHOLE THREE-HOUR MOVIE ON,
EVEN SOMETHING AS GORGEOUSLY
JUNKY AS BEN-HUR.
THE DIRECTOR OF THE MOVIE,
WILLIAM WYLER, SAID WHAT DO YOU DO ?
I SAID, WELL, LOOK.
LET ME TRY SOMETHING.
LET'S SAY THAT THESE TWO GUYS
WHEN THEY WERE 15 OR 16,
THEY HAD BEEN LOVERS,
AND NOW THEY'RE MEETING AGAIN,
AND THE ROMAN
WANTS TO START IT UP.
MESSALA, PLAYED BY STEPHEN BOYD,
WANTS TO START IT UP AGAIN...
WITH BEN-HUR,
PLAYED BY CHARLTON HESTON.
HEAVEN KNOWS WHY.
ANYWAY, HE'S ROMAN.
SO, UH, WILLIE STARED AT ME,
FACE GRAY.
I SAID, I'LL NEVER
USE THE WORD.
THERE'LL BE NOTHING OVERT.
BUT IT'LL BE PERFECTLY CLEAR...
THAT MESSALA IS IN LOVE
WITH BEN-HUR.
WILLIE SAID,
"GORE, THIS IS BEN-HUR.
'A TALE OF THE CHRIST,'
IS THE SUBTITLE," HE SAID RATHER VAGUELY.
AND WILLIE FINALLY SAID,
"WELL, IT'S CERTAINLY BETTER THAN WHAT WE'VE GOT.
WE'LL TRY IT."
[ Both Laughing ]
AFTER ALL THESE YEARS !
STILL CLOSE.
IN EVERY WAY.
[ Vidal ]
HE SAID, "HAVE YOU TALKED TO ANYBODY ABOUT THIS ?"
AND I SAID NO.
I SAID,
"YOU TALK TO BOYD-- MESSALA.
"DON'T SAY ANYTHING
TO HESTON,
BECAUSE CHUCK WILL FALL APART;
I'LL TAKE CARE OF HIM."
SO HESTON THINKS
HE'S DOING FRANCIS X. BUSHMAN IN A SILENT VERSION.
HIS HEAD IS CONSTANTLY
ON HIGH LIKE THIS.
AND STEPHEN BOYD
IS ACTING TO PIECES.
THERE ARE LOOKS THAT HE GIVES
HIM THAT ARE JUST SO CLEAR.
I SAID I'D COME BACK.
I NEVER THOUGHT YOU WOULD.
I'M SO GLAD.
LOOK AT YOU !
LOOK AT YOU.
YOU'VE COME BACK A TRIBUNE.
WHEN I HEARD THAT NEWS,
I DRANK A TOAST TO YOU.
WE'LL DRINK ANOTHER NOW.
♪ ONCE I HAD A SECRET LOVE ♪
♪ THAT LIVED WITHIN THE HEART ♪
♪ OF ME ♪
[ Tomlin ]
HOLLYWOOD HAD LEARNED TO WRITE MOVIES BETWEEN THE LINES.
AND SOME MEMBERS OF THE AUDIENCE
HAD LEARNED TO WATCH THEM THAT WAY.
GOSH A-MIGHTY !
YOU'RE THE PURTIEST THING
I EVER SEEN.
NEVER KNOWED A WOMAN
COULD LOOK LIKE THAT.
SAY.  HOW DO YOU HOLD
THAT DRESS UP THERE ? PLEASE !
IT'S AMAZING HOW
IF YOU'RE A GAY AUDIENCE...
AND YOU'RE
ACCUSTOMED TO CRUMBS,
HOW YOU WILL WATCH
JUST TO SEE SOMEBODY WEAR AN OUTFIT...
THAT YOU THINK MEANS
THEY'RE A HOMOSEXUAL.
THE WHOLE MOVIE CAN BE A DUD,
BUT YOU'RE JUST SITTING THERE...
WAITING FOR JOAN CRAWFORD
TO PUT ON HER BLACK COWBOY SHIRT AGAIN.
I'M GOING TO KILL YOU.
I KNOW.
IF I DON'T
KILL YOU FIRST.
[ Laurents ]
GAY AUDIENCES WERE DESPERATE TO FIND SOMETHING.
I THINK ALL MINORITY AUDIENCES
WATCH MOVIES WITH HOPE.
THEY HOPE THEY WILL SEE
WHAT THEY WANT TO SEE.
THAT'S WHY NOBODY
REALLY SEES THE SAME MOVIE.
LET'S GIVE 'EM A HAND
OVER HERE. SURE.
THAT'S A GOOD-LOOKING GUN
YOU WERE ABOUT TO USE. CAN I SEE IT ?
MAYBE YOU'D LIKE TO SEE MINE.
NICE.  AWFUL NICE.
MONTY CLIFT AND JOHN IRELAND
KNEW WHAT THEY WERE DOING.
I THINK THAT'S WHY THE SCENE
IS, I THINK, FUNNY--
'CAUSE OF THEIR DELIGHT
IN PLAYING THE SEXUALITY OF THE GUN.
YOU KNOW, THERE ARE ONLY
TWO THINGS MORE BEAUTIFUL THAN A GOOD GUN:
A SWISS WATCH
OR A WOMAN FROM ANYWHERE.
YOU EVER HAD A GOOD
SWISS WATCH ?
GO AHEAD, TRY IT.
HEY, THAT'S VERY GOOD.
HEY, HEY.
THAT'S GOOD TOO.
GO ON,
KEEP IT GOING.
MOST EXPRESSIONS
OF HOMOSEXUALITY...
IN MOST MOVIES ARE INDIRECT.
AND WHAT'S INTERESTING
ABOUT THAT IS THAT'S WHAT IT WAS LIKE...
TO EXPRESS HOMOSEXUALITY
IN LIFE--
THAT WE COULD ONLY EXPRESS
OURSELVES INDIRECTLY,
JUST AS PEOPLE ON THE SCREEN
COULD ONLY EXPRESS THEMSELVES INDIRECTLY.
AND THE SENSE
IN WHICH THE CHARACTERS ARE IN THE CLOSET,
THE MOVIE IS IN THE CLOSET,
AND WE WERE IN THE CLOSET.
♪ NOW I SHOUT IT ♪
♪ FROM THE HIGHEST HILLS ♪
♪ EVEN TOLD
THE GOLDEN DAFFODILS ♪
♪ AT LAST MY HEART'S ♪
♪ AN OPEN DOOR ♪
♪ AND MY SECRET LOVE'S ♪
♪ NO SECRET ♪
♪ ANYMORE ♪
[ Men ]
♪ ONE, TWO, THREE, FOUR ♪
[ Man ]
THERE WERE FILMS EVEN IN THE '50s...
THAT GOT AWAY WITH AN AMAZING
AMOUNT OF AT LEAST GAY SUBTEXT.
MY GOD, I THINK YOU CAN'T
KEEP GAY LIFE, GAY BEHAVIOR, OUT OF THE MOVIES.
IT'S LIKE KEEPING IT
OUT OF LIFE IN GENERAL.
SO IT POPS UP,
OFTEN IN SOMEWHAT HIDDEN...
OR SOMEWHAT CODED WAYS.
♪ AND I'LL PIN ♪
[ Rudnick ] IN GENTLEMEN PREFER BLONDES,
THERE'S A GYM
FULL OF BODYBUILDERS...
WHO HAVE ABSOLUTELY NO INTEREST
IN JANE RUSSELL.
♪ DON'T ANYONE KNOW
ABOUT BIRDS AND BEES ♪
♪ AIN'T THERE ANYONE HERE
FOR LOVE ♪
♪ SWEET LOVE ♪
♪ AIN'T THERE ANYONE ♪
♪ HERE FOR LOVE ♪
DOUBLES, ANYONE ?
COURT'S FREE !
TWO OUT OF THREE ?
ANYONE ?
[ Whistles ]
DOESN'T ANYONE
WANNA PLAY ?
IN THE '50s AND '60s,
ESPECIALLY IN SEX COMEDIES,
THERE WERE OFTEN CHARACTERS
WHO COULD BE READ AS GAY,
WHETHER THEY WERE
THE TONY RANDALL ROLES...
OR THE BOSS OF THE
DECORATING ESTABLISHMENT.
AND HERE ?
HMM.  THIS ISN'T BAD EITHER.
WHAT COLOR
IS THAT FLOOR ? LILAC.
LILAC !  LEONARD,
WHO HAS A LILAC FLOOR IN THEIR KITCHEN ?
I HAVE.
OH.
WELL, LEONARD, EVERYONE
ISN'T AS ARTISTIC AS YOU ARE.
WE HAVE TO SELL THIS WAX
TO AVERAGE, ORDINARY, EVERYDAY PEOPLE.
[ Groans ]
THEM !
IN HOLLYWOOD,
FOR YEARS AND YEARS AND YEARS,
THERE WAS WHAT WAS CALLED
THE "D.F. MOVIE."
ALL THE DORIS DAY MOVIES
WERE D.F. MOVIES; IT WAS DELAYED FUCK,
BECAUSE THEY
COULDN'T SLEEP TOGETHER 'TIL THEY WERE MARRIED.
NO SEX BEFORE MARRIAGE.
THAT WAS THE LAW
OF HOLLYWOOD.
[ Thinking ]
WHAT A MARVELOUS-LOOKING MAN.
I WONDER IF HE'S SINGLE.
[ Thinking ]
I DON'T KNOW HOW LONG I CAN GET AWAY WITH THIS ACT,
BUT SHE'S SURE WORTH A TRY.
[ Maupin ]
ROCK HAD A SCREENING ROOM AT HIS HOUSE,
AND HE LIKED TO ASSEMBLE
HIS HOUSEGUESTS AND SHOW HIS OLD MOVIES.
MOST OF THE GUYS I KNEW...
REALLY LIKED TO SEE
THE OLD DORIS DAY FILMS.
AND I THINK ONE OF THE REASONS
WE LAUGHED AT THEM SO HARD...
WAS THAT THERE WAS A REAL
GAY IN-JOKE OCCURRING...
IN ALMOST ALL
OF THOSE LIGHT COMEDIES.
BECAUSE AT SOME POINT
OR ANOTHER,
THE CHARACTER THAT ROCK HUDSON
PLAYED POSED AS GAY...
IN ORDER TO GET A WOMAN
INTO BED.
TELL ME ABOUT YOUR JOB.
IT MUST BE VERY EXCITIN'
WORKIN' WITH ALL THEM COLORS...
AND FABRICS AND ALL.
[ Maupin ]
IT WAS TREMENDOUSLY IRONIC, BECAUSE HERE WAS A GAY MAN...
IMPERSONATING A STRAIGHT MAN...
IMPERSONATING A GAY MAN.
MMM !
AIN'T THESE TASTY !
MMM.
I WONDER IF I COULD GET THE RECIPE.
SURE WOULD LIKE
TO SURPRISE MY MA WHEN I GO BACK HOME.
MMM.
[ Curtis ]
WE'RE ALL HALF MAN, HALF WOMAN.
WE COME FROM THOSE TWO CELLS,
YOU KNOW.
SO WHEN I PUT TOGETHER
JOSEPHINE IN SOME LIKE IT HOT,
I THOUGHT
OF GRACE KELLY, THOUGHT OF MY MOTHER,
AND A LITTLE BIT--
A LITTLE BIT OF EVONNE.
MY NAME
IS JOSEPHINE. I'M DAPHNE.
MMM ?
[ Curtis ] I THOUGHT MY TOP LIP WAS THIN,
SO EVERY TIME
I STOPPED TALKING I WOULD--
MEN !
OH, YOU DON'T HAVE TO WORRY ABOUT THAT.
WE WOULDN'T BE
CAUGHT DEAD WITH MEN !
ROUGH, HAIRY BEASTS
WITH EIGHT HANDS !
THAT KIND OF SEXUALITY
OF OURS WHICH OVERLAPS;
SOME LIKE IT HARD,
SOME LIKE IT SOFT.
THAT KIND OF WAVING IN THERE
IS IN THAT MOVIE.
JUST DELICATELY, YOU KNOW ?
OSGOOD, I'M GONNA LEVEL
WITH YOU.  WE CAN'T GET MARRIED AT ALL !
WHY NOT ?
WELL, IN THE FIRST PLACE, I'M NOT A NATURAL BLONDE.
DOESN'T MATTER.
I SMOKE.  I SMOKE
ALL THE TIME.
I DON'T CARE.
I HAVE A TERRIBLE PAST.  FOR
THREE YEARS I'VE BEEN LIVING WITH A SAXOPHONE PLAYER.
I FORGIVE YOU.
I CAN NEVER
HAVE CHILDREN.
WE CAN ADOPT SOME.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND,
OSGOOD !
AAAH, I'M A MAN !
WELL, NOBODY'S PERFECT.
[ Tomlin ]
WHEN THE SUBJECT TURNED SERIOUS AND ACTUAL SEX WAS SUGGESTED,
OUT CAME THE BLUE PENCIL,
THE SCISSORS AND THE SCENE.
"ANTONINUS.
SICILIAN, AGE 26.
SINGER OF SONGS."
FOR WHOM DID YOU PRACTICE
THIS WONDROUS TALENT ?
HMM ?
FOR THE CHILDREN OF MY MASTER,
WHOM I ALSO TAUGHT
THE CLASSICS.
CLASSICS, INDEED ?
WHAT POSITION HAVE WE,
I WONDER, FOR A BOY OF SUCH VARIED GIFTS ?  HMM ?
YOU SHALL BE MY BODY SERVANT.
INSTRUCT HIM.  COME WITH ME.
THE FIRST TIME
YOU SEE ANTONINUS IS THERE IN THE LINEUP...
WHEN HE SAYS I WANT HIM
FOR MY BODY SERVANT.
THAT'S THE ONLY INDICATION:
BODY SERVANT.  WHAT DOES THAT MEAN ?
HE SAYS BODY SERVANT;
THE NEXT THING YOU KNOW WE'RE IN THE TUB AND I'M WASHING HIM.
IN HERE WITH IT.
[ Curtis ]
THERE'S SOME CHAT BETWEEN US, AND FINALLY HE SAYS,
"ANTONINUS,
DO YOU LIKE SNAILS ?"
I SAID, "YEAH, I DO."
"WHAT ABOUT OYSTERS ?"
I SAID, "I DON'T THINK SO."
DO YOU CONSIDER THE EATING
OF OYSTERS TO BE MORAL AND THE EATING OF SNAILS...
TO BE IMMORAL ?
NO, MASTER.
OF COURSE NOT.
IT IS ALL A MATTER
OF TASTE, ISN'T IT ?
YES, MASTER.
AND TASTE IS NOT
THE SAME AS APPETITE...
AND, THEREFORE, NOT
A QUESTION OF MORALS, IS IT ?
UH-OH.  YOU CAN SEE EVEN
IN THAT LONG SHOT I'VE--
I'M KIND OF GETTING AN IDEA
OF WHAT HE'S TRYING TO SAY TO ME.
I SAID, "YES, MASTER."
HE SAYS, "I LIKE BOTH OYSTERS AND SNAILS."
HE REALIZES THAT HE'S GONNA
BE ASKED TO DO SOMETHING...
THAT HE'S NOT PREPARED TO DO.
I LIKED ANTONINUS FOR THAT.
YOU KNOW ?  "TAKE ME
OUT TO DINNER FIRST; GIVE ME A GOOD TIME.
DON'T THROW ME IN THE TUB
AND DROP THE SOAP."
MY TASTE
INCLUDES...
BOTH SNAILS
AND OYSTERS.
[ Curtis ]
THEY CUT THAT SCENE OUT.
I HAVE NEVER SEEN SUCH A TIME
IN MY LIFE WITH CENSORSHIP.
YOU STARTED DRINKIN' WITH YOUR
FRIEND SKIPPER'S DEATH ! THAT'S THE TRUTH, AIN'T IT ?
[ Vidal ]
THEY CUT AND CUT CAT ON A HOT TIN ROOF.
THERE WAS NO WAY THAT BRICK
COULD HAVE HAD ANY KIND OF SEXUAL DESIRE FOR HIS BUDDY.
WHAT ARE YOU SUGGESTIN' ?
NOTHIN' !  BUT--
BUT WHAT ?
COME ON, SAY WHAT'S ON YOUR MIND !  SAY IT !
WHY ARE YOU SO EXCITED ?
GO AHEAD.  SAY IT !
WHAT ARE YOU SHOUTIN' FOR ?
SKIPPER AND I WERE FRIENDS ! CAN YOU UNDERSTAND THAT ?
GOOPER AND MAE SAID--
SKIPPER IS THE ONLY THING I GOT TO BELIEVE IN !
AND YOU ARE DRAGGIN' IT
THROUGH THE GUTTER ! JUST A MINUTE !
YOU ARE MAKIN' IT SHAMEFUL
AND FILTHY !  FILTHY !
[ Vidal ]
IT WAS CLEAR, TO ANYBODY ON THE WAVELENGTH, WHAT YOU WERE DOING.
YOU JUST COULDN'T USE THE WORD.
AND I MET THIS HEAD-ON
IN A MOVIE CALLED SUDDENLY, LAST SUMMER,
FROM A TENNESSEE WILLIAMS
PLAY.
YOU KNOW WHY
I WAS DOING IT.
I TOLD YOU.  I WAS
PROCURING FOR HIM.
SEBASTIAN WAS LONELY,
DOCTOR.
[ Vidal ]
THE LEGION OF DECENCY, HEADED BY THIS...
SORT OF SHARK-LIKE
JESUIT PRIEST--
I MUST HAVE HAD
FIVE MEETINGS WITH HIM.
WELL, YOU CAN'T SAY THIS,
YOU CAN'T SAY THAT.
BY THE TIME WE STARTED
TO CUT IT, IT WAS MAKING NO SENSE AT ALL.
SEBASTIAN ONLY NEEDED YOU
WHILE YOU WERE STILL USEFUL.
USEFUL ?
I MEAN YOUNG, ABLE TO ATTRACT.
SHE'S BABBLING AGAIN.
BABBLING AND LYING.
HE LEFT HER HOME
BECAUSE SHE HAD LOST HER-- BECAUSE YOU STOLE HIM !
LOST HER ATTRACTION !
WHAT WOULD ATTRACTION HAVE TO DO
WITH A SON AND A MOTHER ?
I'LL TELL YOU--
IS THERE NO WAY TO STOP THESE LIES ?
YES.  HAVE MY BRAIN CUT.
IT WAS LIKE WORKING
UNDER THE KREMLIN, LIKE WRITING FOR PRAVDA.
YOU DID LEARN HOW TO WRITE
BETWEEN THE LINES OR PHOTOGRAPH BETWEEN THE LINES.
YOU'D DO IT WITH A LOOK
OR SOMETHING.
THERE'D BE A TAKE ON HEPBURN'S
FACE AS ELIZABETH TAYLOR WOULD BE TELLING HER.
GETTING CLOSER AND CLOSER
TO THE TRUTH WHICH THE LEGION OF DECENCY WOULDN'T LET US SAY.
WE WERE DECOYS.
DECOYS ?
FOR SEBASTIAN.
HE USED US AS BAIT.
AND WHEN SHE WAS NO LONGER ABLE
TO LURE THE BETTER FISH INTO THE NET, HE LET HER GO.
BAIT FOR WHAT ?
WHAT WERE THE BETTER FISH ?
WE PROCURED FOR HIM.
[ Vidal ]
DID SEBASTIAN LIKE BOYS OR NOT ?
WELL, THE FACT THAT HE'S
EATEN UP AT THE END BY--
ADMITTEDLY, TENNESSEE
OCCASIONALLY WENT OVER THE TOP WITH HIS DRAMATIC EFFECTS.
WHEN HE TRIED TO ESCAPE...
FROM THOSE STREETS,
DOWN THOSE
LITTLE SIDE STREETS BETWEEN THE BUILDINGS,
THEY CAME FROM EVERYWHERE !
SO THE ONLY WAY WAS UP.
[ Tomlin ]
SEBASTIAN WAS THE PERFECT HOMOSEXUAL FOR HIS TIMES,
ONE WITHOUT A FACE OR A VOICE.
SINCE HE LIVES AS A MONSTER,
HE MUST DIE AS ONE,
IN A SCENE REMINISCENT
OF AN EARLY HORROR CLASSIC.
[ Woman ]
I DON'T KNOW HOW. HE NEVER RAN.
BUT HE RAN AND HE RAN
AND HE RAN !
HE NEVER REACHED THE END !
NEVER !
THEY OVERTOOK HIM.
HE SCREAMED JUST ONCE.
I-- I-- THEN I--
I-- THEN I--
HELP !
SO SUDDENLY, LAST SUMMER OPENS,
AND THE NEW YORK TIMES...
IS GOING TO DESTROY
THIS DEGENERATE FILM, THE WORK OF DEGENERATES.
SO YOU'VE GOT A REVIEW
FROM BOSLEY CROWTHER THAT IF YOU LIKE INCEST, RAPE,
SODOMY, CANNIBALISM,
DEGENERACY,
THIS IS THE MOVIE FOR YOU,
THIS SICKENING PICTURE.
EVERYBODY IN THE COUNTRY
WENT TO SEE IT.  THAT REVIEW MADE THE MOVIE.
[ Announcer ]
A TAUT, TENSE DRAMA...
OF THE MOST UNTALKED-ABOUT
SUBJECT OF OUR TIME.
[ Tomlin ]
WHILE HOLLYWOOD REMAINED RETICENT,
BRITISH FILMS BEGAN TO TACKLE
HOMOSEXUALITY HEAD-ON...
WITH A MAJOR STAR
LIKE DIRK BOGARDE AS THE SCREEN'S FIRST GAY HERO.
I WANT TO KNOW THE TRUTH.
I WANT TO KNOW
WHY HE HANGED HIMSELF.
HE WAS BEING
BLACKMAILED. THAT'S WHY HE STOLE ?
YES.
SOMEONE FOUND OUT
HE WAS A HOMOSEXUAL AND BLACKMAILED HIM ?
THAT'S IT.
IT TAKES TWO TO MAKE
A REASON FOR BLACKMAIL.
WERE YOU THE OTHER MAN ?
WERE YOU ?
THERE IS A SCENE IN THE FILM
IN WHICH HE IS QUITE EXPLICIT...
ABOUT WANTING TO HAVE SEX
WITH ANOTHER MAN.
AND THAT'S AN EXTRAORDINARY
STATEMENT FOR A STAR OF THAT MAGNITUDE,
IN A POPULAR ENTERTAINMENT
MOVIE, TO MAKE IN 1961.
ALL RIGHT, YOU WANT TO KNOW.
I SHALL TELL YOU.
YOU WON'T BE CONTENT, WILL YOU ?
'TIL YOU'VE RIPPED IT
OUT OF ME !
I STOPPED SEEING HIM
BECAUSE I WANTED HIM.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND ?
BECAUSE I WANTED HIM !
[ Tomlin ]
BACK IN HOLLYWOOD, THE PRODUCTION CODE...
HAD GRADUALLY
BEEN WHITTLED AWAY.
MOVIEMAKERS,
FED UP WITH RESTRICTIONS,
SET OUT TO SMASH THE LAST TABOO.
HOMOSEXUALITY WAS FINALLY
BEING TALKED ABOUT ON THE SCREEN,
BUT ONLY AS SOMETHING
THAT NICE PEOPLE DIDN'T TALK ABOUT.
AND WE SEEN THINGS TOO.
WHAT THINGS ?
BAD THINGS.
I CAN'T TELL YOU.
YOU'RE ANNOYING ME VERY MUCH.
IF YOU HAVE ANYTHING TO SAY, SAY IT.
I CAN'T SAY IT OUT LOUD.
I'VE GOT TO WHISPER IT. WHY ?
I DON'T KNOW.
I'VE JUST GOT TO.
[ Woman ]
AT THE TIME THAT WE MADE THE PICTURE,
THERE WERE NOT REAL DISCUSSIONS
ABOUT HOMOSEXUALITY.
DO YOU KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE SAYING ?
[ Woman ]
IT WAS ABOUT A CHILD'S ACCUSATIONS.
IT COULD HAVE BEEN
ABOUT ANYTHING. STOP THE CAR, JOHN !
STOP THE CAR, JOHN !
SO NONE OF US WERE REALLY AWARE.
WE MIGHT HAVE BEEN THE FORERUNNERS,
BUT WE WEREN'T REALLY,
BECAUSE WE DIDN'T DO THE PICTURE RIGHT.
WE WERE IN THE MIND-SET...
OF, UM--
OF NOT UNDERSTANDING
WHAT WE WERE BASICALLY DOING.
YOU'VE GOT TO KNOW !
I'VE GOT TO TELL YOU.
I CAN'T KEEP IT TO MYSELF
ANY LONGER !
I'M GUILTY !
[ Sobbing ]
YOU'RE GUILTY OF NOTHING !
THESE DAYS THERE WOULD BE
A TREMENDOUS OUTCRY, AS WELL THERE SHOULD BE.
WHY WOULD MARTHA BREAK DOWN
AND SAY, "OH, MY GOD, WHAT'S WRONG WITH ME ?
I'M SO POLLUTED !
I'VE RUINED YOU !"
SHE WOULD FIGHT.
SHE WOULD FIGHT
FOR HER BUDDING PREFERENCE.
AND WHEN YOU LOOK AT IT,
TO HAVE MARTHA PLAY THAT SCENE--
AND NO ONE QUESTIONED
WHAT THAT MEANT...
OR WHAT THE ALTERNATIVES
COULD HAVE BEEN UNDERNEATH THE DIALOGUE--
IT'S, UH-- IT'S MIND BOGGLING.
WE WERE UNAWARE.
DON'T YOU SEE ?
I CAN'T STAND TO HAVE YOU
TOUCH ME.
LOOK AT ME !
OH, IT'S ALL MY FAULT !
I'VE RUINED YOUR LIFE,
AND I'VE RUINED MY OWN !
I SWEAR I DIDN'T KNOW IT !
I DIDN'T MEAN IT !
OH, I FEEL
SO DAMNED SICK AND DIRTY !
I CAN'T STAND IT
ANYMORE !
[ MacLaine ]
THE PROFUNDITY OF THIS SUBJECT...
WAS NOT IN THE LEXICON
OF OUR REHEARSAL PERIOD, EVEN.
AUDREY AND I
NEVER TALKED ABOUT THIS.
ISN'T THAT AMAZING ?
TRULY AMAZING.
THE LOATHING SHE FEELS,
HOW SICK SHE IS WITH HERSELF...
STILL MAKES ME CRY
WHEN I SEE THAT.
WHY AM I CRYING ?
WHY DOES THIS STILL GET TO ME ?
THIS IS JUST
AN OLD, SILLY MOVIE,
AND PEOPLE DON'T FEEL
THIS WAY ANYMORE.
BUT I DON'T THINK THAT'S TRUE.
I THINK PEOPLE DO FEEL THAT WAY TODAY STILL.
AND THERE'S PART OF ME,
DESPITE ALL MY LITTLE SIGNS-- LIKE HAPPY, PROUD,
WELL-ADJUSTED, BISEXUAL,
QUEER, KINKY.
NO MATTER HOW MANY POSTERS
I HOLD UP...
SAYING "I'M A BIG PERVERT
AND I'M SO HAPPY,"
THERE'S THIS PART OF ME
THAT'S LIKE, HOW COULD I BE THIS WAY ?
HE SAID TO TELL YOU
BEFORE YOU GO ON WITH THE LEFFINGWELL MATTER,
YOU OUGHT TO REMEMBER
WHAT HAPPENED IN HAWAII.
AND THEN HE HUNG UP.
WHAT HAPPENED IN HAWAII,
BRIG ?
WHAT WAS THE VOICE LIKE ?
IT WAS CRAWLY.  HE MADE IT
SOUND LIKE HE KNEW SOME KIND OF NASTY SECRET.
I'VE BEEN ON THE FRONT PAGES
THE PAST FEW DAYS.
I'M BOUND TO GET
SOME CRACKPOT CALLS. JUST HANG UP.
[ Maupin ]
I SAW ADVICE AND CONSENT...
IN MY SENIOR YEAR
IN HIGH SCHOOL-- VERY MUCH A VIRGIN.
I DIDN'T ACTUALLY
HAVE SEX WITH ANYBODY UNTIL I WAS 25 YEARS OLD.
SO EVERYTHING WAS THEORETICAL
AT THAT POINT.
AND ALL I SAW
WAS A LIFE THAT MIGHT LIE DOWN THE ROAD FOR ME.
♪ LET ME HEAR A VOICE ♪
♪ A SECRET VOICE ♪
♪ A VOICE THAT WILL SAY ♪
[ Maupin ]
WELL, SENATOR BRIGHAM ANDERSON, WHO'S BEING BLACKMAILED,
GOES TO CHECK OUT
THIS FORMER LOVER AT A BAR.
IT WAS MY FIRST GLIMPSE...
INTO WHAT I IMAGINED
ORGANIZED GAY LIFE TO BE,
AND IT WAS VERY, VERY SCARY...
BECAUSE IT SUGGESTED PEOPLE
WHO HAVE TO REMAIN...
HIDDEN IN THE SHADOWS.
WELL !  COME ON IN !
DON'T JUST STAND THERE.
HEY, DON'T RUN OFF !
♪ ARE TIGHTLY BOUND ♪
RAY ?  RAY, YOU'RE WITH ME !
BRIG ?
WAIT A MOMENT,
BRIG. TAXI !
LET ME EXPLAIN.
BRIG, WAIT A MOMENT ! TAXI !
I NEEDED MONEY, BRIG !
WHEN YOU WOULDN'T SEE ME, I KEPT CALLING.
I WAS DRUNK !
DRIVE, WILL YOU ?
DRIVE ! BRIG !
I FELT THAT SOMETHING DREADFUL
WAS GOING TO HAPPEN TO ME,
SOMETHING THAT I WOULDN'T
BE ABLE TO TURN BACK ONCE I'D HAD--
ACTUALLY HAD SEX
WITH ANOTHER MAN.
AND THAT THE END OF THAT ROAD
WOULD BE SUICIDE.
AND I GOT THAT IMPRESSION
FROM THE MOVIES.
IS THAT BRIG ?
WHAT'S THE MATTER ?
HE'S DEAD.
BRIG ?
IN HIS OFFICE.
HE CUT HIS THROAT.
OLIVER SAW YOU.  YOU WERE
WITH DOVE ALL AFTERNOON.
LYING TO ME, HALEY,
IS--
OH, WELL, PERHAPS MATURITY
WILL CHANGE ALL THAT.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
I'LL MATURE INTO ?
YOU ?
I WANT TO KNOW WHAT'S GOING ON
BETWEEN YOU AND THAT BOY !
ARE YOU IN LOVE
WITH THAT TEXAS DIRT FARMER ? HE'S MORE THAN THAT.
AHH.  IT'S GONE QUITE FAR
ALREADY, HASN'T IT ?
YOU'D LIKE TO MAKE
ALL HIS DREAMS COME TRUE.
PERHAPS EVEN
GET MARRIED. YES.  EVEN GET MARRIED.
ALL RIGHT, HALEY.
I'LL BE SORRY TO LOSE YOU.
IF YOU THINK THE WORLD
IS YOUR OYSTER, TAKE IT.
BUT HOW DO YOU THINK THE BOY
IS GOING TO FEEL WHEN HE FINDS OUT WHAT YOU'VE BEEN ?
HE'LL FORGIVE ME.
GO TO HIM.
A GIRL LIKE YOU
HAS SO MUCH TO OFFER A MAN:
A KNIFE
TO CUT HIS HEART OUT. I'LL CHANGE !
OF COURSE !
BUT HAVEN'T YOU SAID THAT SO MANY TIMES BEFORE ?
BUT TELL HIM.
TELL HIM ABOUT THE DAYS AND NIGHTS OF HALEY GERARD.
ABOUT THE MUD YOU'VE ROLLED IN
FOR YEARS !  WELL, TELL HIM !
GROWING UP IN THAT PERIOD
IN THE '60s,
ALL WE HAD WERE
IMAGES OF UNHAPPY,
SUICIDAL,
DESPERATE GAY PEOPLE.
[ Male Character Thinking ]
THE THOUGHT OF TURNING--
OF TURNING INVOLUNTARILY
INTO ONE OF THEM...
FRIGHTENED ME
AND MADE ME SICK WITH ANGER.
I WENT DOWN THERE.
I HAD HEARD
ABOUT THE WATERFRONT.
PEOPLE GIGGLE
AND MAKE JOKES ABOUT IT.
I HAD HAD ONLY TWO EXPERIENCES
BEFORE:
ONCE IN COLLEGE,
ONCE IN THE ARMY.
I THOUGHT I'D GOTTEN IT OUT
OF MY LIFE, BUT I HADN'T.
I LOOKED AT THEM.
WAS THIS WHAT I WAS LIKE ?
OH, MY GOD.
TWISTED FACES, OUTCASTS.
LIVES LIVED IN SHADOWS, ALWAYS
PREY TO A MILLION DANGERS.
PEOPLE DON'T REALIZE
WHAT WE GO THROUGH.
I WAS RAISED IN A FAMILY
THAT WOULD NOT EVEN ADMIT...
THERE WAS SUCH A THING
AS A HOMOSEXUAL IN THIS WORLD.
AND HERE I WAS,
AND I COULDN'T DO ANYTHING ABOUT IT.
I COULDN'T STOP.
THESE IMAGES
MAGNIFY THE SADNESS,
THE HATRED OF US,
THE PREDICTION THAT
WE WILL NOT FIND LOVE.
HOW COME YOU
NEVER GOT MARRIED ?
YOU'RE NOT BAD LOOKING.
FEATURES ARE GOOD.
NICE LEGS.
CLOTHES.
BUT YOU NEVER HAD A MAN.
THINK THAT'S REALLY
YOUR PROBLEM.
THE FATE OF GAY CHARACTERS
IN AMERICAN LITERATURE, PLAYS, FILMS...
IS REALLY THE SAME AS
THE FATE OF ALL CHARACTERS...
WHO ARE SEXUALLY FREE.
HALEY ?  HALEY !
GET JO OUT OF HERE !
NO !  NO !
[ Man ]
COME ON ! HALEY !  HALEY !
[ Laurents ]
YOU MUST PAY.  YOU MUST SUFFER.
IF YOU'RE A WOMAN
WHO COMMITS ADULTERY, YOU'RE ONLY PUT OUT IN THE STORM.
WHO HAS ANOTHER WOMAN, YOU BETTER GO HANG YOURSELF.
IT'S A QUESTION OF DEGREE,
AND IF YOU'RE GAY...
YOU HAVE TO
DO REAL PENANCE, DIE.
I KNEW YOU WERE GAY
THE MOMENT YOU WALKED INTO THE BAR.
HOW COULD YOU KNOW ?
WE KNOW EACH OTHER.
SOMETHING ABOUT THE WAY
YOU WALKED.
SOMETHING ABOUT THE EYE.
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH YOU ? [ Yelling ]
WHAT IS THE MATTER
WITH YOU ?  YOU--
MY GOD !  POLICE !
LET GO !  I'LL CALL--
DON'T !
OPERATOR.
DON'T DO THAT !
OPERATOR, I--
YOU--
[ Tomlin ]
BY NOW THE PATTERN WAS CLEAR.
CHARACTERS OF QUESTIONABLE
SEXUALITY...
WOULD MEET WITH A NASTY END
IN THE LAST REEL.
FEED YOUR FACES
AND KEEP YOUR TRAPS SHUT IF YOU DON'T WANT--
[ Screams ]
KILL HER !  KILL HER !
[ Gunshot ]
HELP !
[ Moans ]
OH, MARTHA.
I'LL TELL YOU SOMETHING:
YOU WON'T HAVE THE GUTS.
IT'S NOT ALWAYS
LIKE IN PLAYS !
NOT ALL FAGGOTS BUMP THEMSELVES
OFF AT THE END OF THE STORY.
- [ Man ]
♪ ONE, TWO, ONE, TWO ♪ - OH, CHRIST.
♪ SINGLE, SINGLE, DIP ♪
WHOO !
WAIT A MINUTE !
IT'S THE GERIATRICS ROCKETTES !
[ Tomlin ]
FINALLY, IT HAPPENED. HOLLYWOOD MADE A MOVIE...
IN WHICH GAY MEN TOOK A LONG,
HARD LOOK AT THEIR OWN LIVES.
IT'S THE SENSATIONAL
MENSTRUATIONS !
[ Tomlin ]
AND, IN A REFRESHING TWIST, THEY ALL SURVIVED.
[ Sandler ]
I REMEMBER THE GREAT THING ABOUT SEEING BOYS IN THE BAND.
I HADN'T COME OUT YET,
AND WHAT IT DID FOR ME
WAS PRESENT GAY MEN...
AS HAVING THIS INCREDIBLE
SENSE OF CAMARADERIE,
THIS SENSE OF BELONGING
TO A GROUP,
WHICH I'D NEVER
REALLY FELT BEFORE.
[ All Laughing ]
AW, STEP, BABY !
♪ FORGET YOUR TROUBLES
COME ON, GET HAPPY ♪
♪ YOU BETTER CHASE
ALL YOUR CARES AWAY ♪
WHAT'S MORE BORING
THAN A QUEEN DOING A JUDY GARLAND IMITATION ?
A QUEEN DOING
A BETTE DAVIS IMITATION.
I KNEW A LOT OF PEOPLE
LIKE THOSE PEOPLE,
AND I WOULD SAY THAT PROBABLY
ALL NINE OF THEM...
ARE SPLIT-OFF PIECES
OF MYSELF.
WHAT I AM, MICHAEL,
IS A 32-YEAR-OLD,
UGLY, POCKMARKED,
JEW FAIRY.
AND IF IT TAKES ME A WHILE
TO PULL MYSELF TOGETHER...
AND IF I SMOKE A LITTLE GRASS
BEFORE I SHOW MY FACE TO THE WORLD,
IT'S NOBODY'S GODDAMN BUSINESS
BUT MY OWN.
AND HOW ARE YOU THIS EVENING ?
[ Crowley ]
THEY WERE MISERABLE AND BITCHY.
IF I WAS WRONG, IT WAS
DEFINITELY A REFLECTION...
OF WHAT WAS, UH,
WRONG IN MY HEAD.
BUT THAT'S THE WAY
THAT I SAW THINGS THEN.
[ Man ]
YOU'RE A SAD AND PATHETIC MAN.
YOU'RE A HOMOSEXUAL,
AND YOU DON'T WANT TO BE.
BUT THERE'S NOTHING YOU CAN DO
TO CHANGE IT.
NOT ALL YOUR PRAYERS
TO YOUR GOD.
NOT ALL THE ANALYSIS
YOU CAN BUY IN ALL THE YEARS YOU'VE GOT LEFT TO LIVE.
YOU MAY VERY WELL
ONE DAY BE ABLE TO KNOW A HETEROSEXUAL LIFE...
IF YOU WANT IT
DESPERATELY ENOUGH,
IF YOU PURSUE IT
WITH THE FERVOR WITH WHICH YOU ANNIHILATE.
BUT YOU'LL ALWAYS BE
HOMOSEXUAL AS WELL.
ALWAYS, MICHAEL.
ALWAYS.
UNTIL THE DAY YOU DIE.
[ Laughs ]
FRIENDS.
OHH.
THANKS
FOR THE NIFTY PARTY.
I THINK THAT
THE SELF-DEPRECATING HUMOR...
WAS, UH, BORN OUT OF, UH...
LOW SELF-ESTEEM,
IF YOU WILL.
FROM A SENSE OF WHAT THE TIMES
TOLD YOU ABOUT YOURSELF.
HOMOSEXUALITY WAS STILL
CLASSIFIED AS A MENTAL ILLNESS.
[ Screams ]
YOU WENT IN A GAY BAR, YOU KNEW
YOU WERE LIABLE TO BE ARRESTED,
OR THE PLACE BE RAIDED.
I'VE BEEN IN THOSE SITUATIONS.
THERE WERE STILL
NOT JUST ATTITUDES, THERE WERE LAWS AGAINST...
ONE'S BEING.
THE CORE OF ONE'S BEING.
IF WE COULD JUST
NOT HATE OURSELVES SO MUCH.
THAT'S IT, YOU KNOW.
[ Sobbing ]
IF WE COULD JUST LEARN NOT TO HATE OURSELVES...
QUITE SO VERY MUCH.
THE FIRST FILM THAT REALLY
CELEBRATED HOMOSEXUALITY,
AS FAR AS I WAS CONCERNED,
WAS CABARET.
♪ [ Victrola ]
[ Crowley ]
FOR ME, IT EMBODIED THE VERY LIFE...
I WAS BEGINNING TO LIVE
IN SAN FRANCISCO,
IN WHICH THERE WAS NO REAL ONUS
PLACED ON HOMOSEXUALITY.
DOESN'T MY BODY
DRIVE YOU WILD WITH DESIRE ?
WELL, DOESN'T IT ?
IT'S A VERY NICE BODY.
OH, DO YOU REALLY
THINK SO, DARLING ?
IT DOES HAVE
A CERTAIN KIND OF STYLE.
I MEAN, LOOK.
IT'S VERY FLAT HERE. NOT MUCH HIPS.
AND, UH... HERE.
IT'S A LITTLE EARLY IN THE DAY
FOR THIS SORT OF THING, ISN'T IT ?
[ Victrola Stops ]
MAYBE YOU JUST DON'T SLEEP WITH GIRLS.
OH.  YOU DON'T.
WELL, LISTEN.
WE'RE PRACTICALLY LIVING TOGETHER !
SO IF YOU ONLY LIKE BOYS--
I MEAN, I WOULDN'T DREAM OF PESTERING YOU.
WELL, DO YOU SLEEP WITH GIRLS
OR DON'T YOU ? SALLY !
YOU DON'T ASK
QUESTIONS LIKE THAT.
I DO.
THE BOY WAS-- WAS HOMOSEXUAL,
AND IT JUST SEEMED RATIONAL;
IT SEEMED REASONABLE.
THAT'S WHAT THE STORY
WAS.  NOBODY--
THERE WAS NO
FUSS WITH ANYBODY.
NONE AT ALL.
OH, SCREW MAXIMILLIAN !
I DO.
[ Chuckles ]
SO DO I.
[ Crowley ]
SO THINGS CHANGE...
MORE QUICKLY
THAN YOU MIGHT IMAGINE.
WHO ARE YOU ?
I'M BERNSTEIN.
YOU'RE JEWISH ?
NO, DARLING. I'M GAY.
[ Guests Laughing ]
I DON'T CARE HOW YOU FEEL,
YOU'RE A GREAT DANCER !
YOU'RE NOT BAD YOURSELF,
MOM !
I THINK IT WAS EASIER...
FOR THE POWERS THAT BE
TO SHOW A BLACK AS A HOMOSEXUAL...
RATHER THAN A WHITE
CHARACTER AS A HOMOSEXUAL.
WHY ?  YOU KNOW,
I DON'T UNDERSTAND THAT.
BUT I DO UNDERSTAND IT.
JUST LIKE IT'S MORE EASY TO US
TO HAVE THE SITCOMS...
AND SITUATION COMEDIES
ON TELEVISION...
AND NOT THE SERIOUS DRAMAS
ABOUT OUR LIVES.
BUT A LOT OF THINGS
CAN BE SAID THROUGH COMEDY.
WOULD YOU PLEASE GET OUTTA MY
FACE, YOU SORRY-LOOKIN' FAGGOT ?
OH, OH, OH.
WHO YOU CALLING SORRY-LOOKIN' ?
[ Laughing ]
CAN'T YOU-ALL SEE
THAT SHE AIN'T FUNNY ?
SHE'S JUST ANOTHER
POOR EXAMPLE...
OF HOW THE SYSTEM
HAS OF DESTROYING OUR MEN.
HONEY, I AM MORE MAN
THAN YOU'LL EVER BE,
AND MORE WOMAN THAN
YOU'LL EVER GET. SHIT.
[ Tomlin ]
BUT THERE WAS A DOWN SIDE TO THE NEW GAY VISIBILITY.
THE THREAT OF RETALIATION
COULD BE WAITING JUST DOWN THE ROAD.
THIS IS THE FIRST IMAGE
I REMEMBER HAMMING...
ABOUT ANYBODY BEING GAY
IN A MOTION PICTURE.
IT WAS THE HITCHHIKERS
THAT WERE PICKED UP IN VANISHING POINT.
PARDON ME, BUT COULD YOU PLEASE
TELL US IN WHICH DIRECTION YOU'RE HEADED ?
I'M GOIN' TO FRISCO.
OH, WELL, THAT'S PERFECT.
THANK YOU.
ONE OF THE GUYS WAS CARRYING
A PURSE; THEY WORE VERY, VERY TIGHT CLOTHES.
HE HAD SORT OF A LASCIVIOUS
LOOK ON HIS FACE.
WHY ARE YOU LAUGHING ?
I'M NOT LAUGHING.
YES, YOU ARE.
IT'S BECAUSE YOU THINK
WE'RE QUEERS, ISN'T IT ?
HEY.
THIS IS A STICKUP.
STICKUP ?
[ Laughs ]
WHY ARE YOU LAUGHING,
MARY ?
WE ALL HOWLED,
BECAUSE ALL YOU SAW...
WAS THE CAR SPEEDING
AT 60 MILES AN HOUR, SCREECHING TO A STOP,
AND THEN THE TWO GUYS
WERE THROWN OUT.
WE THOUGHT THAT WAS GREAT !
"DID YOU SEE HIM ?
THOSE TWO GAY GUYS,
THOSE HOMOS, WERE THROWN OUT OF BARRY NEWMAN'S CAR !"
WE THOUGHT THAT WAS AMAZING.
THERE IT WAS ALMOST--
THE IMAGE OF WHAT
A HOMOSEXUAL WAS. BITCH.
TO BE A GAY MAN MEANT
THAT NOT ONLY DID YOU WEAR PINCHED CLOTHES...
AND YOU HAD THIS LOOK
ON YOUR FACE, BUT YOU CARRIED A PURSE AS WELL !
I'VE HAD THE EXPERIENCE
OF BEING IN A THEATER...
AND REALLY ENJOYING A MOVIE.
AND THEN SUDDENLY,
OUT OF NOWHERE,
COMES SOME KIND OF
PSEUDOHOMOSEXUAL CHARACTER...
WHO IS SORT OF THE VILLAIN,
THE KILLER, OR IS KILLED,
AND THE AUDIENCE
WOULD BURST INTO APPLAUSE.
I WAS WITH A LOT OF FRIENDS,
AND WE WERE WATCHING A MOVIE CALLED FREEBIE AND THE BEAN.
ALL OF A SUDDEN, THERE'S
THIS KILLER TRANSVESTITE...
WHO DOES SORT OF
A MURDEROUS BALLET. [ Grunts ]
THEN, OF COURSE, TRIUMPHANTLY,
OUR HERO PULLS OUT A GUN...
AND BLOWS FIVE MILLION HOLES
THROUGH THE MURDEROUS TRANSVESTITE,
AND THE AUDIENCE
BURSTS INTO APPLAUSE.
[ Gunshots ]
I THINK THERE WERE
TWO THINGS HAPPENING:
PEOPLE WERE APPLAUDING
THE DEATH OF THE VILLAIN,
BUT THEY WERE ALSO APPLAUDING
THE DEATH OF A HOMOSEXUAL.
YOU KNOW YOU'RE WATCHING
A HETEROSEXUAL MOVIE;
YOU KNOW THAT'S THE DEAL
WHEN YOU PAY TO SEE A HOLLYWOOD MOVIE.
BUT SOMEHOW YOU'RE
STILL NOT QUITE READY FOR BEING INSULTED.
DO YOU KNOW,
AT THIS MOMENT...
I HAVE SUNK AS LOW
AS I CAN GO.
I WAS WRONG.
WAIT.  ARE YOU GONNA TELL ME
YOU'RE A FAG ?
IF YOU'RE GONNA,
I DON'T THINK I CAN HANDLE IT.
I'M NOT A FAG.
I'M A... WEREWOLF.
I NEVER HEAR
THE WORD NIGGER USED...
UNLESS IT'S EITHER
BY TWO BLACK PEOPLE...
AS A FORM OF AFFECTION...
OR BY A TOTALLY BIGOTED...
SOUTHERN SHERIFF--
YOU KNOW,
THE BLUBBERING STEREOTYPE--
TO POINT OUT HIS IGNORANCE.
HE WOULD USE THAT TERM.
YOU SEE ?
FAGGOT IS NOT USED IN THAT WAY;
FAGGOT IS USED BY...
UH, JUST ANYONE
TALKING TO ANYONE ELSE.
HEY, RAM.  DOESN'T
THIS CAFETERIA HAVE A NO FAGS ALLOWED RULE ?
HEY, KILLER.
WHY YOU ON YOUR KNEES ?
YOU QUEER OR SOMETHING ?
I KNOW WHAT YOU BEEN AFTER,
YOU GODDAMN FAGGOT.
YOU MUST BE CREAMIN' ALL OVER
YOUR LITTLE FAGGOT SELF.
YOU WON'T HAVE TO HANG OUT
WITH THAT FAGGOT CAESAR ANYMORE.
UNHAPPY, FAGGOT ?
YOU'RE A FAGGOT,
A DIRTY QUEER.
YOU QUEER ?
HELL, NO, SIR !
- WHAT'S THE MATTER ?
YOU GOIN' FAGGOT ? - YOU TURNING FAG ON ME ?
- YOU'RE A TOUGH FAGGOT,
AIN'T YOU ? - WHAT DO YOU FAGGOTS WANT ?
YOU HEAR ME,
YOU FUCKIN' FAGGOTS ?
- FUCK YOU, FAGGOT.
- FUCK YOU, QUEER.
- WHO IS THIS FAGGOT ?
- YOU BALD-HEADED, FLATFOOT FAGGOT.
YOU BECOME EITHER INURED TO IT
OR CONDITIONED TO ACCEPT IT.
AND IT BECOMES THE ATTITUDE.
IT BECOMES
THE PREVAILING ATTITUDE;
IT BECOMES THE WAY PEOPLE
PERCEIVE GAY PEOPLE.
♪
[ Tomlin ]
WHEN HOLLYWOOD FINALLY ACKNOWLEDGED...
THE BURGEONING GAY SCENE,
IT CAME UP WITH A GRISLY THRILLER...
SET IN THE WORLD
OF LEATHER BARS.
♪
HOW BIG ARE YOU ?
PARTY SIZE.
WHAT ARE YOU INTO ?
I GO ANYWHERE.
I DON'T DO ANYTHING.
THAT'S COOL.
HIPS OR LIPS ?
[ Unzipping ]
[ Nyswaner ] I DID HAVE AN EXPERIENCE...
WITH THE MOVIE CRUISING.
NOT ABOUT SEEING THE MOVIE,
BUT BEING THE VICTIM OF SOMEONE WHO HAD.
MY LOVER AND I WERE
GAY BASHED BY YOUNG MEN WHO WORKED IN A MOVIE THEATER.
THEY THREATENED US;
THEY CHASED US UP OUT OF THE THEATER,
INTO THE STREET, AND AS I
WAS ESCAPING FROM ONE OF THEM,
HE SAID TO ME,
"IF YOU SAW THE MOVIE CRUISING, YOU KNOW WHAT YOU DESERVE."
[ Singsong Voice ]
WHO'S HERE ?  I'M HERE.
YOU'RE HERE.
AND I'M AFRAID.
[ Tomlin ]
HOMOSEXUALS IN MOVIES HAD CHANGED...
FROM VICTIMS TO VICTIMIZERS.
SHOW IT.
LIFT UP THE SWEATER.
PLEASE.  PLEASE.  PLEASE.
PLEASE.  PLEASE.
[ Gasps ]
YOU MADE ME DO THAT.
[ Gasping, Sobbing ]
[ Crowd ]
STOP THE MOVIE CRUISIN' ! STOP THE MOVIE CRUISIN' !
STOP THE MOVIE CRUISIN' !
[ Crowd ]
GAYS FIGHT BACK ! GAYS FIGHT BACK !
GAYS FIGHT BACK !
[ Tomlin ]
ONE MOVIE WAS SO BOLD AS TO DEPICT HOMOSEXUALITY...
AS AN ACT OF LOVE,
NOT VIOLENCE, SO HOLLYWOOD HAD TO WARN THE PUBLIC.
[ Sandler ]
UH, THIS WAS 1982.
THERE HADN'T BEEN ANY
GAY CHARACTERS IN LEADING ROLES, AND IT WAS A BIG JUMP.
OKAY.  THE TRUTH IS
I HAVE GOTTEN INTO A LOT OF DIFFERENT SCENES.
I'M A WRITER.
I HAVE TO OPEN MYSELF UP TO NEW THINGS.
EXPAND MY HORIZONS.
[ Exhales ]
BART.
ZACK.
WHY DON'T YOU JUST SAY IT ?
- I'M GAY.
- THANK YOU.
[ Chuckles ]
YOU'RE WELCOME.
IT WAS VERY HARD TO CAST.
UM, THE MEN WERE HARD TO CAST,
BECAUSE EVERY ONE
OF THEIR ADVISORS,
BOTH HARRY HAMLIN
AND MICHAEL ONTKEAN,
TOLD THEM NOT TO POSSIBLY,
POSSIBLY PLAY SOMEONE WHO WAS GAY,
THAT IT WOULD DESTROY
THEIR CAREER.
THERE WAS THE GENERAL
PERCEPTION, AT LEAST IN THE EARLY '80s--
I DON'T KNOW WHAT IT'S LIKE
NOW-- BUT THAT HOLLYWOOD WAS PRETTY MUCH OF A COWBOY TOWN,
AND A STRAIGHT COWBOY TOWN.
I'M SURE THAT INSIDE OF ME...
THERE IS THE SAME HOMOPHOBIA
THAT WE ALL SHARE.
IF I SEE A GUY WHO'S PLAYING
A GAY ROLE, I'LL QUESTION IT.
I'LL SAY, WOW, IS HE GAY ?
AND WHY I DO THAT,
I DON'T KNOW.
THEN I'LL STOP AND SAY,
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.  YOU'VE BEEN THERE; YOU'VE DONE THAT.
THE OTHER QUESTION IS,
WHY DO WE CARE ?
I MEAN, WHO CARES ?
I'LL DO THAT.
THE STUDIO, THE OWNERSHIP
OF THE STUDIO, CHANGED HANDS,
AND A NEW PERSON CAME IN WHO
WAS NOT FROM THE FILM WORLD...
NOR THE INTELLECTUAL WORLD NOR
THE WORLD OF LETTERS AND ARTS.
AND... I HAD...
THE UNPLEASANT TASK...
OF RUNNING
IN A SCREENING ROOM,
FOR THIS MAN AND HIS
LOVELY WIFE AND DAUGHTERS,
THE ROUGH CUT OF THE FILM.
AND NONE OF MY COLLEAGUES
WOULD BE THERE.  THEY WERE ALL AFRAID.
SO I WAS THERE BY MYSELF,
SITTING IN THE BACK.
HE WAS SITTING UP FRONT
IN A SMALL SCREENING ROOM.
HE WAS SQUIRMING
ALL DURING THE MOVIE.
HE JUST COULDN'T SIT STILL.
AND AT THE PART IN THE MOVIE
WHERE THE TWO MEN EMBRACE AND KISS,
HE JUMPED UP AND SAID,
"YOU MADE A GODDAMN FAGGOT MOVIE !"
AND STALKED OUT.
[ Sandler ]
THE DAY IT OPENED, I HAPPENED TO BE IN MIAMI.
I SAT DOWN,
THE MOVIE STARTED,
AND AS THE MOVIE PROGRESSED,
YOU SENSED THE AUDIENCE GROWING
MORE AND MORE UNCOMFORTABLE...
WITH WHAT WAS GOING ON
ON THE SCREEN.
IT KEPT ESCALATING,
AND WHEN THEY HAD THE FIRST KISS,
YOU THOUGHT THERE WAS
AN EXPLOSION IN THE THEATER.
PEOPLE PANICKED.
I MEAN, IT WAS PANDEMONIUM.
PEOPLE STARTED, LIKE,
STORMING UP THE AISLES, AND AT THAT POINT I JUST LEFT.
MAINSTREAM PEOPLE
DISLIKE HOMOSEXUALITY...
BECAUSE THEY
CAN'T HELP CONCENTRATING...
ON WHAT HOMOSEXUAL MEN
DO TO ONE ANOTHER.
AND WHEN YOU
CONTEMPLATE WHAT PEOPLE DO,
YOU THINK OF YOURSELF
DOING IT.
AND THEY DON'T LIKE THAT.
THAT'S THE FAMOUS JOKE:
I DON'T LIKE PEAS,
AND I'M GLAD I DON'T,
BECAUSE IF I LIKED THEM I WOULD EAT THEM, AND I HATE THEM.
[ Tomlin ]
THERE WAS A TIME WHEN MEN WERE FREE...
TO EXPRESS TENDERNESS
ON THE SCREEN.
BUT AS THE WORLD GREW
MORE AWARE OF HOMOSEXUALITY,
MALE-TO-MALE AFFECTION...
WOULD BE SEEN
AS AN INCRIMINATING ACT.
A KISS WOULD BECOME
AN ASSAULT...
[ Screaming ]
NO !
OR AN UGLY ACCUSATION.
I'LL SHOW YOU WHAT YOU'RE GONNA BE !
WHAT YOU ARE.
WHAT YOU ARE !
I'LL KILL YOU FOR THAT !
[ Grunts ]
AMERICANS, PERHAPS, ARE MORE
SCARED OF THEIR SEXUALITY.
THEY'RE PREPARED TO SHOW
VIOLENCE OF ALL KINDS,
BUT WHEN IT COMES TO SEXUALITY,
I THINK AMERICA IS VERY SELF-RIGHTEOUS...
AND TRIES TO BURY IT...
AS IF IT DIDN'T EXIST,
WHICH IS SILLY.
AND YOU'RE ALL RIGHT ?
MM-HMM.
[ Schlesinger ]
WE HAD QUITE AN ARGUMENT ABOUT THE KISS.
THE SCREENWRITER
FELT THE WHOLE THING SHOULD BE IN LONG SHOT AND SILHOUETTE.
I SAID NO WAY.
IT SHOULD JUST HAPPEN.
AND THAT'S WHAT WE DID.
[ Bright ]
THERE'S A WORLD OF DIFFERENCE BETWEEN HOW AN AUDIENCE...
LOOKS AT TWO MEN
GETTING IT ON...
AND TWO WOMEN GETTING IT ON.
THERE'S A COMFORT
WITH FEMALE NUDITY...
AND FEMALE GIRLISHNESS...
AND KIND OF "GIRLIE BONDING,"
THAT IT CAN BE SEXY,
AND IT CAN BE COMPLETELY
PALATABLE, EVEN EROTIC.
WOMEN DON'T FIND IT THREATENING,
AND MEN EITHER FIND IT
COMPLETELY UNTHREATENING...
OR TITILLATING.
[ Goldberg ]
I THINK STRAIGHT MEN ARE MORE UNCOMFORTABLE...
WITH TWO MEN MAKING LOVE.
BECAUSE SOMEHOW THAT
MEANS YOU'RE WEAK, YOU KNOW.
AND PEOPLE EQUATE WEAKNESS...
WITH MALE SENSUALITY
TOWARDS OTHER MEN,
NOT REALIZING THAT
THAT'S A RIDICULOUS THEORY.
BUT THAT'S WHY PEOPLE SAY,
"I'M A MAN !"
LIKE, BEING A MAN
IS BASED ON WHO YOU HAPPEN TO BE BONING THAT DAY.
IN THE COLOR PURPLE,
CELIE HAS FALLEN IN LOVE WITH SHUG.
[ Giggles ]
THEY'RE TWO WOMEN
WHO LOVE EACH OTHER.
THIS INTIMACY IS NOT ABOUT SEX.
I THINK IT'S MUCH DEEPER.
LET'S KEEP GOIN'.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN ?
[ Woman ]
OH, I THINK IT'S MUCH EASIER FOR AUDIENCES...
TO ACCEPT TWO WOMEN BEING
AFFECTIONATE... GO !
THAN IT IS TWO MEN;
THAT'S A BIG, BIG TABOO.
YOU SURE ?
YEAH.
HIT IT.
[ Woman ]
BUT WHEN I PUT THE KISS IN AT THE END OF THELMA AND LOUISE,
THAT GAVE PEOPLE PAUSE.
I TOLD GEENA.
I DIDN'T TELL ANYBODY ELSE.
MY FEELING WAS THAT
THEY WERE BEYOND SEXUALITY, THAT IT WAS LOVE.
IF YOU'RE ABOUT TO GO
OFF THE CLIFF, I DON'T THINK YOU'RE MAKIN' A PASS.
IT WAS A DECLARATION
OF--
THAT THEY WERE FINISHING
EACH OTHER'S SENTENCES.
THEY WERE THERE
FOR EACH OTHER...
IN THE TRADITION
OF BUTCH CASSIDY AND THE SUNDANCE KID.
EXCEPT THEY DIDN'T GO DOWN
IN A RAIN OF BULLETS.
[ Shouting ]
WOULDN'T THAT HAVE BEEN GREAT IF
BUTCH--  WELL, THEY WOULD HAVE HAD MORE REASON TO SHOOT THEM,
IF BUTCH AND SUNDANCE
HAD KISSED AT THE END.
BUT THEY DID
WHAT GUYS DO IN MOVIES: THEY GOT THEIR GUNS OUT,
'CAUSE THEY COULDN'T
GET THEIR DICKS OUT.
AND THEY WENT DOWN
WITH THEIR GUNS, SO THAT'S WHAT BOYS DO.
♪ [ Piano ]
ARE YOU MAKIN' A PASS AT ME,
MRS. BLAYLOCK ?
MIRIAM.
MIRIAM ?
NOT THAT I'M AWARE OF,
SARAH.
[ Sarandon ]
ORIGINALLY IN THE SCRIPT IT WAS, UM,
KIND OF A PLAYBOY VERSION
OF THEM GETTING TOGETHER.
IN OTHER WORDS,
IT HAD A LOT TO DO WITH LINGERIE AND POSING...
AND THERE WAS NO REAL SCENE.
AND SO I SAID THAT
I REALLY THOUGHT THAT WHAT WAS SEXY...
WOULD BE THE FIRST MOMENT
THAT PEOPLE TOUCH. ♪ [ Operatic Female Duet ]
SO I CAME UP WITH THE
LITTLE SCENE WHERE SHE SPILLS SOMETHING ON HERSELF.
AND SHE GIVES HER SOMETHING
AND THEY TOUCH THAT WAY AND THEN THEY KISS.
AND THEN YOU GO INTO
THE KIND OF "CURTAINS BLOWING OVER THEIR BODIES" STUFF.
THE OTHER THING WAS THAT THEY
FELT I SHOULD BE REALLY DRUNK.
SO THAT WAS THEIR WAY OF TAKING
AWAY HER CHOICE, IN A SENSE.
AND I INSISTED THAT
THAT NOT BE THAT WAY,
THAT CERTAINLY YOU
WOULDN'T HAVE TO GET DRUNK TO BED CATHERINE DENEUVE,
I DON'T CARE WHAT YOUR
SEXUAL HISTORY TO THAT POINT HAD BEEN,
AND THAT IT WAS
MUCH MORE INTERESTING IF SHE WENT VOLUNTARILY.
♪ [ Operatic Duet Continues ]
I DON'T THINK,
FOR BETTER OR WORSE,
THAT WOMEN ARE TAKEN VERY SERIOUSLY IN THIS AREA.
I THINK THE FEELING IS THAT
IF TWO WOMEN ARE TOGETHER, THEN IT'S PROBABLY EXPERIMENTAL...
OR SOME KIND OF PHASE--
IF THE RIGHT GUY CAME ALONG, THAT WOULD CHANGE.
AND SO IT'S ACTUALLY
SOMETHING THAT STRAIGHT MEN CAN WATCH...
AND NOT BE THREATENED BY, AND
STRAIGHT MEN ARE THE ONES...
THAT ARE PROPELLING
THE INDUSTRY FORWARD.
SO I DON'T THINK
IT'S TAKEN THAT SERIOUSLY.
I SUPPOSE WHEN YOU GO
TO THE MOVIES AND YOU SEE MEN BEING AFFECTIONATE,
IT'S JUST-- BESIDES THE SEX--
JUST THE AFFECTION ITSELF...
IS JUST TOO MUCH.
GUYS ARE SUPPOSED TO BE
STRONG AND UNFEELING.
I GET SO ANGRY ABOUT
WHAT HOLLYWOOD WILL DO...
WITH AN ORIGINAL STORY
OR SCRIPT TO GET RID OF THE LESBIAN ELEMENT...
THAT I FEEL LIKE STANDING UP
IN THE THEATER AND JUST SHOUTING:
"THESE CHARACTERS ARE DYKES, AND
THIS MOVIE ISN'T SAYING SO."
WHAT'S YOUR MOTHER GONNA SAY
WHEN SHE SEES US BOTH DRUNK ?
[ Laughs ]
YOU GOTTA STOP WORRYIN' ABOUT WHAT PEOPLE THINK.
I KNOW.
I MEAN, YOU'VE ALWAYS DONE THE RIGHT THING.
YOU TOOK CARE OF YOUR
DADDY, THE PREACHER, WHEN HE TOOK SICK.
YOU TAKE CARE
OF ALL THE KIDS OVER AT THE CHURCH SCHOOL.
YOU'RE GONNA TAKE CARE
OF YOUR MAMA.
I KNOW.  AND I'M GONNA MARRY
THE MAN I'M SUPPOSED TO.
YOU'RE GETTIN' MARRIED ?
AS SOON AS
THE SUMMER'S OVER.
[ Bright ]
THE PASSION THAT THESE TWO WOMEN FEEL FOR EACH OTHER...
WAS NOT PRESENTED
IN AN OPEN WAY IN THE MOVIE. BOY, AM I GONNA MISS YOU.
IT'S LIKE SOMEBODY'S
JUST POWDERED ME WITH FLEAS THE ENTIRE TIME.
I'M BEING IRRITATED
THAT THEY'RE NOT TELLING THE TRUTH.
EVERYBODY IN THE BUSINESS,
WE ALL GET PAID MORE THAN WE SHOULD;
WE ALL GET PAID MORE
THAN OUR FATHERS EVER MADE.
AND THERE'S ALWAYS THE FEAR
THAT THEY'RE GONNA TAKE IT AWAY FROM US,
SO WE BETTER BE--
AND THAT'S WHY MOST PEOPLE IN THOSE ROLES ARE CONSERVATIVE.
MOST PEOPLE
WHO RUN BIG BUSINESSES IN AMERICA ARE CONSERVATIVE.
MOST NEWSPAPER CHAINS
ARE RUN BY PEOPLE WHO ARE CONSERVATIVE.
THE PUBLIC IS ALWAYS
AHEAD OF US ABOUT WHAT THEY'RE READY FOR.
I THINK.
AND IF YOU DO IT WELL,
IF YOU PIERCE THE HEART TRUTH...
OF WHAT THE PUBLIC
IS FEELING AND THINKING, YOU HAVE A HIT.
[ Hanks ]
THERE IS THIS CONSTANT DESIRE ON THE PART OF THE STUDIOS...
TO MAKE CHARACTERS LIKEABLE.
MY SCREEN PERSONA
IS PRETTY MUCH NONTHREATENING.
I HAVE NEVER BEEN ONE TO STRIKE
FEAR INTO ANYBODY'S HEARTS...
WHEN I ENTER THE ROOM
OR FIRST APPEAR ON SCREEN.
AND BECAUSE OF IT, THEN,
THIS IDEA OF A GAY MAN
WITH AIDS IS NOT SCARY.
IT'S SOMETHING ELSE,
BUT IT DOESN'T HAVE TO BE SCARY.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO BE THREATENED
BY THIS MAN'S PRESENCE,
AND PART OF IT'S
BECAUSE LITTLE TOMMY HANKS IS PLAYING THE ROLE.
OH, UH, WHAT ABOUT
MY BLOOD WORK ?
WE'RE WAITING.  MEANWHILE,
I WANT TO PREP YOU FOR A COLONOSCOPY.
WE WANT TO TAKE
A LOOK INSIDE.
SOUNDS DELIGHTFUL.
WAIT A MINUTE. WAIT A MINUTE.
- WHY DO YOU
NEED TO DO THIS ? - WHO ARE YOU ?
WHO ARE YOU ?
DOCTOR, UH--
THIS IS MY PARTNER.
YEAH.
HE KEEPS RECORDS
OF ALL MY HOSPITAL VISITS. IT'S NOTHING PERSONAL.
OH.  UH, I'M DR. KLENSTEIN.
LISTEN, YOU'RE RIGHT,
A COLONOSCOPY IS NOT A PLEASANT PROCEDURE,
BUT IF THE K.S. IS CAUSING
THE DIARRHEA, WE'VE GOTTA KNOW ABOUT THAT RIGHT AWAY.
HEY, BUT IT COULD BE PARASITES,
AN INFECTION--
REACTION TO THE A.Z.T.
[ Klenstein ] ALL THESE ARE POSSIBILITIES.
NO, LISTEN TO ME.
HE'S NOT GOING THROUGH SOME PAINFUL PROCEDURE...
UNTIL WE CANCEL OUT
EVERYTHING ELSE !
I'M TRYING TO HELP
YOUR PARTNER, OKAY ? OKAY.
YOU'RE NOT
HIS IMMEDIATE FAMILY. I'M NOT ?
I COULD HAVE YOU REMOVED.
REALLY.
LOOK, HE'S UPSET.
HE'S SORRY.
DON'T APOLOGIZE FOR ME,
OKAY ?
OKAY, HE'S NOT SORRY.
THE IDEA THAT
THERE HAD TO BE AN AUDIENCE THAT WANTED TO SEE...
STORIES ABOUT BEING GAY
IN AMERICA,
WHO WANTED TO SEE STORIES
ABOUT A GUY WHO HAS AIDS,
IS THIS ALMOST BACKWARDS
UNDERSTANDING OF HOW IT WORKS...
WHEN YOU'RE STANDING
IN FRONT OF THE BOX OFFICE...
IN YOUR LOCAL "DODECAPLEX,"
AND YOU HAVE A CHOICE
BETWEEN WHAT MOVIE SHOULD WE GO TO.
WE CAN GO TO THE MOVIE ABOUT
SUPERSPIES FROM OUTER SPACE, A COW WHO TALKS,
THE LAWYER WHO HAS AIDS
OR THE BIG PUPPET SHOW.
WELL, LET'S--
I GUESS THE LAWYER WITH AIDS.
THAT'S THE ONE THAT'S
GONNA BE THE MOST DIFFERENT.
PHILADELPHIA WAS TERRIFIC,
BUT I DON'T THINK IT PROVES ANYTHING...
IN THE SENSE THAT IT'S A STORY
ABOUT A GAY HERO WHO DIES,
WHO IS A TRAGIC FIGURE.
IT REMAINS TO BE SEEN
WHETHER HOLLYWOOD AND THE PUBLIC...
WILL EMBRACE A GAY HERO
WHO LIVES.
WE FELT THAT WE WOULD FAIL
IF OUR MOVIE PLAYED TO PEOPLE...
WHO ALREADY THINK THAT
DISCRIMINATION AGAINST PEOPLE WITH AIDS IS WRONG,
OR PEOPLE
WHO ALREADY BELIEVE...
THAT PEOPLE
SHOULDN'T DISCRIMINATE AGAINST HOMOSEXUALS.
IF OUR MOVIE ONLY PLAYED
TO THE PEOPLE WHO THOUGHT JUST LIKE WE DO,
WE WOULD HAVE DONE NOTHING
VERY SIGNIFICANT.
[ Hanks ]
WE ALL END UP MAKING OUR CHOICE...
OF WHO WE'RE GONNA
BE IN LOVE WITH; THAT'S WHAT WE'RE ALL SEARCHING FOR.
AND ANDY FOUND MIGUEL,
AND MIGUEL FOUND ANDY.
♪ CAN'T GO WRONG ♪
[ Hanks ]
THAT'S A LOVE THAT IS BORNE OUT OF EVERYTHING...
THAT GOES INTO TWO PEOPLE
DECIDING TO BE WITH EACH OTHER.
IT'S FORGED THROUGH TIME.
IT'S A CONSTANT; IT'S THE SPEED OF LIGHT.
I THINK THAT'S
WHAT THE MOVIE IS SAYING, THAT IT IS ALL THE SAME.
LOVE IS SPELLED, YOU KNOW,
WITH THE SAME FOUR LETTERS.
♪ CAN'T GO WRONG ♪
ALL THE READING I WAS GIVEN
IN SCHOOL WAS HETEROSEXUAL.
EVERY MOVIE I SAW
WAS HETEROSEXUAL.
AND I HAD TO DO
THIS TRANSLATION.
I HAD TO TRANSLATE IT
TO MY LIFE, RATHER THAN SEEING MY LIFE.
HAPPY TWO-WEEK
ANNIVERSARY.
OH, ED,
YOU REMEMBERED.
WHICH IS WHY WHEN PEOPLE SAY
TO ME YOUR WORK IS NOT GAY WORK,
IT'S UNIVERSAL,
AND I SAY "UP YOURS; IT'S GAY.
"AND THAT YOU CAN TAKE IT
AND TRANSLATE IT...
"FOR YOUR OWN LIFE,
IS VERY NICE.
BUT AT LAST I DON'T HAVE TO DO
THE TRANSLATING.  YOU DO."
[ Keys Plunk ]
[ Tomlin ]
THE LONG SILENCE IS FINALLY ENDING.
NEW VOICES HAVE EMERGED,
OPEN AND UNAPOLOGETIC.
THEY TELL STORIES
THAT HAVE NEVER BEEN TOLD...
ABOUT PEOPLE WHO HAVE ALWAYS
BEEN THERE.
WE'RE VICTIMS
OF THE SEXUAL REVOLUTION.
THE GENERATION BEFORE US
HAD ALL THE FUN,
AND WE GET TO PICK UP
THE FUCKIN' TAB.
OH, MOVIES ARE IMPORTANT
AND THEY'RE DANGEROUS,
BECAUSE, YOU KNOW,
WE'RE THE KEEPER OF THE DREAMS.
YOU GO INTO A LITTLE, DARK ROOM
AND BECOME INCREDIBLY VULNERABLE.
ON ONE HAND YOUR PERSPECTIVES
CAN BE CHALLENGED...
AND YOU CAN FEEL SOMETHING
YOU COULDN'T FEEL NORMALLY.
IT CAN ENCOURAGE YOU TO BE THE
PROTAGONIST IN YOUR OWN LIFE.
AND ON THE OTHER HAND,
IT CAN COMPLETELY MISSHAPE YOU.
[ Oxenberg ]
THERE'S BEEN AN INCREDIBLE ERA OF CENSORSHIP.
OF, I WOULDN'T SAY POSITIVE
IMAGES OF GAYS AND LESBIANS,
I WOULD SAY REAL IMAGES
OF GAYS AND LESBIANS.
'CAUSE THINK OF ALL THE HEROIC
STORIES THAT ARE REAL.
HERE GAY AND LESBIAN PEOPLE...
HAVE LIVED, BRAVING
THE OSTRACISM OF SOCIETY,
LOVING EACH OTHER, SURVIVING.
THERE ARE SO MANY HEROIC STORIES
THAT ARE JUST REAL.
YOUR PARENTS KNOW
YOU'RE GAY ? SURE.
TOLD 'EM
WHEN I WAS 16.
SIXTEEN ?
YEP.  I HAD A BOYFRIEND IN HIGH SCHOOL.
THEY FREAKED.
THE USUAL BULLSHIT.
"HOW COULD YOU CHOOSE
THIS KIND OF LIFESTYLE, PETER ?"
I SAID, HEY, GUYS,
IT CHOSE ME.
I WANT YOU TO PUT ON
YOUR CLOTHES AND LEAVE.
[ Woman ]
NO, YOU DON'T. YES, I DO.
- NO, YOU DON'T.
- I WOULDN'T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
YOU CAN START BY PUTTING
THE DO NOT DISTURB SIGN ON THE DOOR.
[ Maupin ]
HOLLYWOOD STILL RUNS SCARED...
FROM PEOPLE WHO FEEL THAT THE
VERY MENTION OF HOMOSEXUALITY,
THE VERY DISPLAY OF IT
IN SOME FORM ON THE SCREEN,
LEGITIMIZES THE SUBJECT.
WELL, OF COURSE IT DOES.
IT SHOWS THAT HOMOSEXUALS ARE HUMAN BEINGS.
[ Yelps ]
[ Maupin ] THE MOVIES COULD BE...
MAKING US LAUGH A LOT MORE
AND CRY A LOT MORE...
IF THEY WOULD ACTUALLY
ACKNOWLEDGE THE TRUE DIVERSITY OF HUMANITY.
IT'S NOT FAIR;
YOU BEEN IN LOVE A BUNCH.
JUST ONCE, REALLY.
NOW HE'S GONE, RIGHT ?
HE'S RIGHT HERE.
- I LOVE YOU.
- I LOVE YOU TOO.
CLOSED-CAPTIONED BY
CAPTIONS, INC.  LOS ANGELES
♪ ONCE I HAD ♪
♪ A SECRET LOVE ♪
♪ WHO LIVED WITHIN THE HEART ♪
♪ OF ME ♪
♪ ALL TOO SOON ♪
♪ MY SECRET LOVE ♪
♪ BECAME IMPATIENT ♪
♪ TO BE FREE ♪
♪ SO I TOLD ♪
♪ A FRIENDLY STAR ♪
♪ THE WAY THAT DREAMERS ♪
♪ OFTEN DO ♪
♪ JUST HOW WONDERFUL ♪
♪ YOU ARE ♪
♪ AND WHY I'M SO ♪
♪ IN LOVE WITH YOU ♪
♪ NOW I SHOUT IT ♪
♪ FROM THE HIGHEST HILL ♪
♪ EVEN TOLD
THE GOLDEN DAFFODIL ♪
♪ AT LAST MY HEART'S ♪
♪ AN OPEN DOOR ♪
♪ AND MY SECRET LOVE'S ♪
♪ NO SECRET ♪
♪ ANYMORE ♪