Henry?
Henry.
Darling, what is it?
What are you doing?
He's coming for us.
I couldn't move.
I started shaking. I was getting dizzy.
I was sure everyone in the room wanted to kill me.
I've never been so scared.
Pointless in the end though, fear, isn't it?
That's your best advice, doc?
All right.
What do you think controls you?
Your body or your mind?
Your money controls me, sugar.
Ah, there you go.
-Fine. -Okay, okay.
I think my body and mind control each other.
Well, let's find out.
Is this real?
Yes.
-Yes? -Yes.
The mind
is incredibly creative.
It can make us see situations
that appear completely real,
but are in fact
nothing more than illusions,
perceptions of truth.
How did you do that?
Sometimes we all need a little help
to see the difference between reality and illusion.
And that's about taking control,
about not letting fear control you.
Because fear in the end only exists in your mind.
All right. Sorry to say good night.
I'm looking for Dr. Price.
-Good night. -I'm Arthur Gates,
Chief Legal Officer of the Winchester Repeating Arms Company.
Really?
See you next week, sugar.
You're a hard man to reach, Dr. Price.
Good night, Nancy.
-Good night. -Good night.
I'm on sabbatical.
Good night.
What do you want? A prescription?
I've come to offer you employment.
-Whiskey? -No, thank you.
Are you familiar with Sarah Winchester, Dr. Price?
Mrs. Winchester's husband William
was the majority shareholder
of the Winchester Repeating Arms Company.
Twenty-five years ago, William passed,
leaving Mrs. Winchester a rather large inheritance,
and 51% of the company.
Mrs. Winchester also lost her only child, Annie.
It's said in her grief,
she turned to a medium... Spiritualist of some sort.
The medium may have taken advantage of her mental state.
That's not uncommon after a tragedy.
I can assure you,
Sarah Winchester is anything but common.
Aye, after her spiritual encounter,
she moved across the country to San Jose,
-where she purchased what... -Where's my...
Was then an eight-room house.
Maybe it's in the garden room.
She spent the last 20 years expanding it.
What stands now is
a gargantuan seven storied structure,
with no apparent rhyme or reason,
no master plan,
each maze of halls more confusing than the next.
A house under never-ending construction,
built on the orders of a grieving widow
whose mind is as chaotic as the house itself.
Over the years, she's become more and more reclusive.
Last month, the Board of Directors
enacted its right to assess
Mrs. Winchester's state of mind,
to determine if she's fit to control the company.
You want to take it away from her?
We're worried about her sanity, Dr. Price.
We need a professional.
Any kind of diagnosis
from such a long distance would be impossible.
Well, Mrs. Winchester's agreed
to let you stay at the residence.
An offer that is exceedingly rare.
An unwilling patient, the long distance.
This is not something ordinarily I...
Name the amount.
Doesn't really work like that.
How much do you owe?
Mortgage?
Hospital expenses?
Medicine?
Three hundred.
We'll pay six.
For the appropriate assessment.
Mrs. Winchester requests the bay window frame
be installed by sundown.
Move with haste.
Let me get that, sir.
Thank you.
Busy day of construction here, sir.
-Yes. -Days and nights
are always busy here.
Really? Nights, too?
Right round the clock, sir.
This way.
Most of the rooms don't stay up very long,
like Mrs. Winchester's garden room there.
That might not last the season.
Really?
Check the measurements here have been done.
Please wait in the library, sir.
I'll call for Mrs. Marriott.
-Jesus! -My apologies, sir.
The door was making a terrible racket.
No, no, no, no, no.
That's quite all right.
Gave me a fright.
Dr. Price?
-Yes. -Welcome.
Marion Marriott, Mrs. Winchester's niece.
Oh. Well, it's a pleasure to meet you.
I must say, I have never quite seen a house like this.
My aunt advised me of the nature of your visit.
As you are aware, it is unfortunate timing,
so I would ask you to behave in a manner
befitting the circumstance.
Unfortunate, how?
A tragedy occurred.
Oh.
Well, I'm sorry to hear that.
Are you carrying firearms?
Should I be?
Aunt Sarah forbids them.
Well.
I'm completely unarmed.
Good. You, like I, like everyone,
are guests in Aunt Sarah's home.
You will abide by her rules.
Understood.
You are to stay in this section of the house, the east wing.
Aunt Sarah's private domains are off limits.
Understood.
So...
Are you close to your aunt?
Is this already part of your evaluation, Dr. Price?
No, ma'am, it is not.
Yes.
Aunt Sarah is an exceptional woman.
She does not deserve to be treated
with anything less than complete respect.
Yes, ma'am. Quite right.
May I?
This is the grand ballroom,
built almost entirely without nails.
The walls and parquet floor are made of six separate hard woods.
The silver chandelier was imported from Germany.
Follow me, Doctor.
There are almost one hundred rooms in the house.
It's easy to get lost.
How unusual.
Aunt Sarah suffers from arthritis.
This makes climbing stairs manageable for her.
The house can be overwhelming. Do keep up.
What is this?
It's a communication device.
Really?
You speak into the holes, and a series of pipes
travel the sound to the desired room.
-Ingenious. -Yes.
You'll find many of my aunt's inventions are state of the art.
I trust you'll find everything you need with the room.
Aunt Sarah will be joining us for dinner.
Perhaps you would like to freshen up beforehand.
I very much look forward to meeting your aunt.
Aunt Sarah would not approve of you
drinking before dinner hour.
Her sense of smell is still as acute as mine.
Respect her wishes.
You were right about me, Ruby.
I am
a fraud.
You're a phony, hmm?
That feels good.
Well, you don't know what you're doing.
You don't know what you're doing.
Oh, yeah. You prove nothing.
For Christ's sake.
Jesus Christ!
Ah!
Who are you? What do you want?
Dinner will be served in 10 minutes.
-You're alone, yes? -Yes, sir.
-Nobody else with you? -No, sir.
No? You didn't see anyone just come out of here?
Are you all right, sir?
I'm fine. I just thought someone else was...
Well, I thought I saw someone else in my room.
Interesting.
Look, I'm fine, yes.
Dinner in 10 minutes, yes?
-Sir. -Good, thank you.
Take it nice and easy.
There.
Henry.
Stop it.
Henry, stop that!
Henry. Henry! Just...
Henry, you must be very excited
to spend some time in your great aunt's house.
We're here because Father died.
Well, I am very sorry for your loss, young man.
-I'm not. -Henry!
It's my fault. I didn't mean to pry.
Of course, you did. That's why you're here.
Yes. Suppose so.
I recently lost someone myself.
So if you feel like discussing anything,
I might be able to provide some assistance
to yourself or young Henry here.
I imagine you must be very good at your job
if Aunt Sarah chose you to be her assessor.
I had no idea she chose me herself.
I'm just hoping I can help.
If you want to help, Doctor,
you can give my aunt a clean bill of health
and be on your way.
Well, I have a duty to my profession
and an obligation to my employers.
Aunt Sarah is your employer.
It is still half her company.
-Madam. -Good evening, Madam.
Good evening, Madam.
Dr. Price.
Mrs. Winchester, it's a pleasure to finally meet you.
The pleasure is due to the lawyers
of the Winchester Repeating Arms Company.
Yes.
I suppose you're right.
I hope everything has been to your satisfaction so far?
I cannot fault the hospitality.
It's quite a special house, is it not?
Now that, ma'am, is a fact beyond dispute.
Thank you.
I understand the Winchester is still considered
the superior rifle on the market, ma'am.
Superior?
Superior at what?
Accuracy, range, stopping power.
Killing.
Indiscriminate killing.
Very superior.
You feel responsible for the misuse of your product?
If a weapon works as intended,
one can hardly call it a misuse.
Well, it can be used for good or bad,
depending on the person wielding it.
Yes.
Then again, perhaps roller skates are a less dangerous endeavor.
The company is expanding,
looking for other opportunities.
I understand that was at your behest, Mrs. Winchester?
It was.
To the displeasure of the board.
It appears that strapping wheels to one's feet
can also be a perilous endeavor.
Hear, hear.
Tell me the story about the farmer
-who owned the old mule. -No.
I always liked that story.
A delusional disorder.
-Yes. -That's what you called it.
Yes.
I don't want to talk anymore.
I need you to believe me.
I want to be with you, Ruby. Together forever.
Hello?
Christ!
You've poisoned your mind, Eric.
You've poisoned your mind.
I need some air.
Deja vu.
Hey!
Move, hey! Move! Move!
I see you.
Oh, Henry! Darling!
What's happening to you, sweetheart?
Thank you.
Darling, what's happening to you?
Mrs. Winchester,
I really must have your full attention.
Oh, you have it, Dr. Price.
Yes, but perhaps you would be more comfortable if...
Last night was quite a traumatic event.
I'm grateful for your actions.
I fear you may have me at a...
An emotional disadvantage today.
Yes, I understand.
I don't mean to pry, but has Master Henry
been prone to sleepwalking in the past?
No.
But you may know, he did witness
the death of his father.
Yes.
Well, this is the first
in a series of sessions I wish to conduct.
And I can assure you that today will be quite benign.
No, no, no. Let's just get straight to it, Doctor.
You are here to assess my erratic behavior,
are you not?
Well, erratic behavior is not the phrase
that I would've chosen, but...
-Now, I'll speak with you truthfully. -Please.
But you will do me the same courtesy.
Of course.
Do you suffer from soldier's syndrome?
I'm sorry?
Are you an abuser of medication?
Mrs. Winchester, I think it's best if I ask the questions.
Your wife, did she believe you are a good therapist?
We're not here to discuss my wife.
Your wife Ruby?
No, we are not.
And I would appreciate your honesty.
Are you an abuser of medication?
No, I'm not.
-So... -I will share a fact with you,
which you may find questionable.
But I assure you, it is a fact.
Please.
I am cursed.
Cursed, how?
Have you read my papers?
-Of course, I have. -And what did they say?
Well, among many things,
they say that this is the house that spirits built.
See, profiting from such a thing as violence and death,
that is a wickedness that follows you like a shadow.
Yes, we might also call those shadows "guilt."
But tell me, how do these shadows follow you?
I may be getting old, Dr. Price,
but I assure you, I have not lost my senses.
I know the difference between illusion and reality.
I see.
Your mind rules your body.
The mind can be incredibly creative.
But it can also, at times, fail us.
My mind has never failed me.
What we see, taste, and touch
are interpreted and processed to give us our truth.
And that truth can in turn be an illusion,
created, distorted, by grief.
Do you believe in ghosts, Dr. Price?
No, ma'am. Why would I?
Offering my staff that bill would be greatly appreciated.
Even the nickel inside the bill
would be a respectable start.
Really! Silly illusions?
Do you take me for a fool?
No, ma'am. I do not.
No more diversions from reality.
No more parlor tricks.
And your medication will have to be confiscated.
Mrs. Winchester, I'm sorry, but I must insist, I'm not a child...
-This is my home, Dr. Price. -And I will not be...
You will obey my rules.
If you want me to open up this house for you,
you need clarity.
Do you have another question for me?
Yes, ma'am.
Is it really necessary to confine me to quarters?
That is Madam's wish, sir.
Hmm.
And the condition of Master Henry?
He too is confined to quarters.
And Mrs. Marriott has not left his side.
Damn it!
"Sir, the members of the board eagerly await your evaluation.
"I trust you will make an accurate assessment.
"Regards, Arthur C. Gates, Chief Legal Officer."
Sarah Winchester's psychological assessment
and mental status examination.
Dr. Eric A. Price, April 16, 1906.
Appearance, normal.
Hygiene, physical characteristics, all normal.
Patient struggles with the loss of her husband and child.
Her behavior is at times slightly aggressive.
Perception, visual hallucinations
that patient often refers to as shadows or ghosts.
I feel them, their presence.
Go on.
I feel their presence, their energy.
Their unfinished business has brought them here.
Do you perhaps in any way blame them
for the death of your husband and child?
I will mourn William and dear Annie always.
I love all my family very much, Dr. Price.
They are the true riches of my life,
and I will do whatever it takes to protect them.
Can you tell me why the...
Why those bells chime at midnight?
It's midnight, sir.
Well, yes.
But is there any significance to it?
It's midnight, sir.
Thank you.
I swear, the laudanum is still in my system.
Let's just hope it's withdrawals.
It always was withdrawals. It had to be. Had to be.
I have a question for you, Dr. Price.
Again, Mrs. Winchester, it's best if I ask...
What is it like to die?
Talking about your...
Deceased for three minutes, were you not?
You know, I keep records
of all the lives a Winchester has taken.
Hundreds have been reported. Probably thousands haven't.
The guilty, the innocent...
The rifle doesn't discriminate.
And many of the souls make their way to this house.
That's impressive.
As you can clearly see, I am still here.
So perhaps you could do me
the kindness of taking me off that shelf.
You were shot.
I was.
This.
And it did kill me.
You kept it and refurbished it.
-I did. -Why?
Well, because it's a reminder of my past.
Because it's my connection to death
and to all that I've lost.
Instruments of death
have a powerful connection to the afterlife.
We hold on to mementos to help us heal.
But sometimes, they do more harm than good.
Precisely.
So tell me, what do you think it is you're holding on to?
Have you ever been to a spiritualist?
But I understand you have.
You know, it is believed
that once we've departed this world,
we can see others
who have left their physical selves behind.
Is that right?
Have you ever experienced such a thing?
I can't say that I have, no.
Is it painful to die?
Mrs. Winchester,
we really must continue with this evaluation.
Please, Doctor. Please.
Yes.
And then nothing.
Just a calmness.
And when I came back, it was painful again.
If that makes sense.
Yes.
Yes, because you too have experienced great pain.
Grief can be far more crippling
than arthritis, Doctor.
Mrs. Winchester, do you blame the shadows
for the loss of your husband and child?
Were you out of your room last night?
Yes, I was.
Thank you.
Thank you for telling me the truth.
So, why all the noise? Why all this construction?
They want me to build, Doctor.
The spirits killed by the rifle,
they guide me.
Guide you in drawing building plans?
Yes.
For what? Why?
For the rooms, of course.
You see, once their rooms are completed,
their presence grows stronger.
Hence, the house that spirits built?
Yes.
The shadows that follow me,
they have unfinished business.
You saw what I did last night, didn't you?
I did.
At the chime of midnight, they clamor.
The bells summon them.
They communicate through plans, drawings.
They want me to reconstruct the rooms that they died in,
then they can enter our world.
And the trouble is, I don't always know
who it is I'm speaking with.
It could be some innocent bystander
or a victim of a crime,
or someone else.
Who else, Mrs. Winchester?
Last night, a spirit more powerful
than any I've encountered endangered my family.
Who are you?
Doctor, who do you see in this room at this moment?
Just you.
Only me?
It will take time.
You still need to clear your head.
Oh, sir!
I would like to check in
on Mrs. Marriott and Master Henry, if I may.
I will inquire, sir.
Perhaps, may I ask you a question?
A question, sir?
Yes. I mean, tell me, have you ever seen any...
Any ghosts?
No, sir.
But you have heard the rumors, the stories?
I have heard tall tales.
Some taller than others.
Have you ever witnessed anything out of the ordinary?
So display cabinets along the walls,
and then a line of them down the middle of the room.
Yes, ma'am.
And what type of Winchester would you like delivered?
Every type, every model.
Okay, let's go back.
Tell me please what happens once these rooms are finished?
Well, the spirit's presence grows
more powerful and more...
More focused.
Their voices get stronger.
And we converse.
Converse how? About what?
I show them my deep remorse.
I want to help them let go of their grief and their anger.
And how do they react?
Favorably. Yes, mostly.
Once they are at peace, then they can move on.
We can tear down their room, and then we start again.
And are there those that don't react so favorably?
Yes.
Yes, we lock them away.
How does one lock a spirit away?
Thirteen nails seals them in.
Once they find peace, we can release them,
and they can leave this house.
So 13 is
a devilish number to protect you from devils?
No, no, no. That is a divine number,
to protect the cycle of life and death.
And does this divine number always work?
I mean, what if a spirit simply doesn't want to be locked away?
The unmendable souls
prey upon the innocent and the pure.
And by the innocent and pure, you mean Master Henry?
We can stand between them.
I and you.
With your assistance,
I can help this spirit find peace.
You don't believe any of this. I understand.
Ma'am, I do not.
I do not believe in anything I cannot see or study.
Mrs. Winchester, you have built this house,
this place, this reality.
Therefore, you can control it, can you not?
Yes, perhaps.
We all have the ability
to create and control our own reality.
But for some, for you, Mrs. Winchester, for you,
that will mean letting go of the past.
Make your assessment, Doctor.
Say what you feel is the truth about Sarah Winchester.
And if that means you lose control of your company?
There are worse things in this world to lose than that, Doctor.
I see you've finished the new room.
Of course.
Must be very profitable for you,
all this working round the clock.
We all appreciate
Mrs. Winchester's ongoing employment
and her creativity.
I must say, that creativity
certainly leads to some rather odd designs.
Do you think it possible a woman of advancing years
may be susceptible to flights of fancy?
No, sir. I do not.
Could I see inside the garden room, please?
I had one similar, and I would be much obliged if...
No, sir. That room is sealed.
Therefore, it's off limits.
Good day, Doctor.
Well, Eric, that's going really well.
How is he?
Fine. Resting.
Has he ever been prone to behavior like that in the past?
No.
Never?
She told you, didn't she, about the Winchester curse?
Yes.
Do you believe her, or do you think she's crazy?
I think crazy is a dangerous word.
People have certain medical conditions
and with the right diagnosis and treatment,
they can be helped.
I do not believe in curses, Doctor.
Good. Nor do I.
I think perhaps your son's behavior
has been triggered by the sudden death of his father.
Yes.
Could you tell me how your husband died?
He had demons,
but not the kind that my aunt believes haunt her.
Go on.
Aunt Sarah's husband died suddenly of tuberculosis.
And then she lost poor Annie.
She believes our family curse is spreading.
My husband loved the drink
more than his wife and child.
I believe that was his curse.
Now he is gone, and I'm alone,
better off in so many ways without him.
But it terrifies me.
Don't let that fear control you.
Fear only exists in your mind.
When we fear the most,
we must take control.
You can be a fighter. You can be a protector.
I do not feel like a protector.
Aunt Sarah is the fighter.
-Yes. -She would die to save us.
Perhaps.
Have you ever loved someone so much you would die to save them?
I have.
I also knew someone who was haunted by demons, voices.
And did the time ever come when you had to protect them?
It did.
What did you do?
I died.
Henry!
Ahh!
Henry.
Henry!
Henry! It's me!
No.
Ah!
Henry! Henry!
-Henry! Henry! -Stop it! Stop!
Stop, Henry, stop!
-Who are you? -Die!
Mother?
Oh, Henry.
Henry. Henry.
I'm so sorry, Aunt Sarah.
I've let you down, and I've let Henry down.
No, no.
This spirit has a power we've not seen before.
Oh, my God.
It can take over a mind.
John, send everyone home.
Only we in this room must remain.
Yes, ma'am.
This child must be taken to a hospital immediately.
No, no. We must watch over him.
To a hospital immediately.
No. No one else will understand.
-He must stay here. -This is insanity.
We will watch over him.
Dr. Price may be right.
No. No. We will protect him.
We will protect him at all costs.
John, come with me.
Aunt Sarah!
Ma'am, I insist that you receive medical treatment.
Seal that door. Thirteen nails.
Now.
Now!
Yes, ma'am.
You leave my family alone.
You speak with me.
Let's just think this through.
Please, Mrs. Marriott, be rational.
Henry clearly has a trauma and needs help.
Your aunt is caught in a superstition.
We need...
Thirteen hooks.
You must listen to me.
Is the rifle room finished?
Yes, ma'am.
My God. This presence is so strong.
Oh, I feel its hatred...
Oh, enough with the games!
We're taking this boy to a hospital.
-We should listen to him. -Yes!
The boy tried to kill you.
No. The shadows will follow us.
Wherever we go.
No, Henry will not suffer the same fate
-as my darling Annie... -Henry's condition
cannot be cured by witchcraft.
The boy needs a doctor.
Conditions can be cured, Doctor.
Curses cannot.
Mrs. Marriott, will you please listen to me?
-Marion... -I'm...
I'm going with Dr. Price.
-No. Henry must stay. -I'll make the arrangements.
-Gentlemen, you'll excuse me. -No! No!
Marion, please! Henry must stay.
He must stay with us.
Aunt Sarah, I must think of Henry.
I should go with him.
I will prove it to you.
Yes, I... I will.
This way.
Operator.
Winchester Repeating Arms Company.
This is Arthur Gates.
Mr. Gates, it's Dr. Eric Price here.
I trust the assessment is going well, Doctor.
I understand you received our letter.
It's fine, Mr. Gates.
But I require immediate transportation to the nearest hospital.
Is everything all right?
Everything is fine. Just please, a driver, as soon as possible.
-Of course, right away. -Thank you.
And the assessment, Doctor?
You'll get what you wanted.
Christ!
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to be rude.
Sir, we're all deeply concerned for Master Henry's well-being.
If the anything I can do to assist you, I...
Well...
Actually, you can.
I need to get my bags, please.
-Of course. -Thank you.
Happy to help.
Mrs. Winchester is truly a remarkable woman.
She knows what she's doing.
She has created a vessel
for the deceased to communicate with her.
She's certainly created some architectural oddities.
This house, I've seen things.
I know this room.
Things?
The dead.
Criminals.
Lost souls who met a violent end.
You've seen them, haven't you?
Dr. Price, many staff have reported hearing noises.
They come from inside rooms that have been nailed shut.
Strange occurrences in those rooms...
That is why the doors have been sealed,
to keep the unruly in.
But the staff have only heard noises.
To see them, well,
I believe you and I are unique.
Really?
Yes, perhaps it's all just a symptom
of Mrs. Winchester's persuasive influence.
Sir, locking Mrs. Marriott and her child away
is only delaying the inevitable.
And what is the inevitable?
They're all Winchester.
They will all die.
Mr. Hansen. Is she in there?
-Yes, Doctor. -Good. You need to hear this.
Mrs. Winchester, there is a man in your employ
who has clearly lost his mind. He just...
That's him.
You saw him? You spoke with him?
Well, yes, I spoke with him just now.
The man threatened you.
Read it. Read the paper.
"Corporal Benjamin Joseph Block was killed during a siege
"at the Winchester Repeating Arms general office."
That's impossible.
This newspaper is 20 years old.
Cruelty, grief, and loss
can make people do unimaginable things.
Ben lost two brothers on the battlefield.
The youngest was only 14 years old.
Their Confederate muskets were no match
for the Winchester rifles of the Union Army.
They were cut down.
Ben swore revenge.
To him, the people who created the weapon
that killed his brothers were as guilty
as those who pulled the trigger.
He killed 15 innocent people that day.
He locked himself in the display room.
We used to call it the show-off room.
We know you're in there.
We have the building surrounded.
# Beautiful dreamer
# Wake unto me
# Starlight and dewdrops are waiting for thee
"Officer John Mandel told the press,
"'I'm extremely proud of my team,
"'and that scum like Block
"'can't escape my men and their Winchesters.'"
Weapons ready!
This way. When the bell chimes at midnight,
he'll be at his most powerful.
Do you know who the most terrifying monster is, Doctor?
No.
The one you invite into your own home.
This is it.
This is the room.
This is an exact replica of the room he was killed in.
Yes.
And now that it is complete, he is in this world.
Do you see anyone, Doctor?
It's impossible.
Doctor, you must believe.
It's illogical.
Corporal Block,
please,
please feel my deep remorse
for the death of your brothers,
of James and young Harry
by the Winchester rifle.
I know all three of you feel pain and torment.
But violence cannot bring justice.
Only more suffering,
and I will not allow my family to suffer anymore.
Leave this house with your brothers.
I hope together you can find peace.
# Beautiful dreamer
# Wake unto me
# Starlight and dewdrops
# Are waiting for thee
# Sounds of the rude world
# Heard in the day
# Led by the moonlight have all passed away
It's Ben.
Stop them! Ah!
No!
Ah!
Mrs. Winchester?
I'll find another way to get to you!
Henry, sweetheart, where are you?
Henry? Henry?
Henry?
# Beautiful dreamer
Henry! Henry!
# Wake unto me
Eric, this is just in your mind.
Fear is just in your mind.
It is only in your mind.
Henry?
Henry, where are you?
Henry, sweetheart?
Where are you?
Be free, my brothers.
I always loved our garden room, sweetheart.
-Ruby. -But you let it die.
Oh, no.
Tell me the story about the farmer
who owned the old mule.
-No. -I always liked that story.
They built our garden room.
The farmer's old mule fell into his well.
Go on, Eric.
The farmer heard...
What?
He heard the mule crying.
And it broke his heart.
He chose to bury the animal in the well
-and put it out of its... -Its hardship.
He started shoveling.
The mule realized that every time dirt fell on his back,
he could shake it off and step up.
Shovel after shovel.
He could shake it off
-and he could step up... -Shake it off.
It wasn't long before the old mule,
battered and exhausted,
stepped over the wall of that well.
What should have buried him...
-Saved him. -And he overcame...
This is not real.
This is not happening. You are not real.
I've tried to be a good wife.
The voices are not real, Ruby.
They were never real.
They were just inside your head.
All these years, all I wanted was for you to believe me. But...
-I should have put you in care. -You never did.
I should have put you in care.
Just something that can be diagnosed and treated,
like any other crazy person.
Yes. Yes. I did. I made a mistake. I'm sorry.
A delusional disorder.
-Yes. -That's what you called it.
Yes. Put the gun down, Ruby, please.
We can talk about this.
I don't want to talk anymore.
I need you to believe me.
I don't know what I believe anymore.
Someone like you never will.
Please, Ruby, don't.
Please, I'm lost without you, Ruby.
I'm lost without you.
Don't do it. No!
You can go on.
You need to let go of your guilt,
so that I can let go of mine
and see the truth.
I'm so sorry.
Mrs. Winchester, are you all right?
This spirit is destroying the balance of this house.
It has to be stopped.
Master Henry and Marion, we need to find them.
Seal that door.
Ben must not leave.
# Beautiful dreamer
Henry?
# Starlight and dewdrops
# Sounds of the rude world heard in the day
# Led by the moonlight have all passed away
Thirteen.
Sit.
Sarah, I can see them.
I can see all of them.
You're the only one who can.
You believe?
I do. I do.
Dead for three minutes,
killed by the Winchester rifle.
You are connected to this house.
Yes.
Henry.
I'm not afraid.
I won't let fear control me.
Henry!
Oh, please, please come back to me!
Marion and Henry are in grave danger.
The only way to save them is to stop Ben here and now.
Ben, leave my family alone.
You speak to me.
Talk to me.
Now.
Sarah.
Corporal Block is in this room.
The Winchesters are a vile plague!
This whore bitch has to die!
Sarah, fight him!
My brothers were killed by the rifle,
murdered by this instrument of death...
-Fight him! -That killed your wife.
Sarah, control him!
Be present, Sarah. Be present.
I want you to suffer.
Marion is mine.
Henry is mine!
No, no, no! Fight him!
And eye for an eye! Get off me!
These vermin profit from death.
-Sarah, fight him. -No more!
No!
Seal the floor, Doctor.
Thirteen nails. Hurry!
His rage is endless.
But he can be stopped.
-How? -By something...
Something in this room.
He's afraid of something.
I felt it.
His gun.
That's 12.
This is the gun
he used to kill.
-Do you see him? -No.
There. Done.
Now he's locked in.
And so are we.
Ben, show yourself.
Show yourself!
Your anger will never defeat us.
You took everything from me!
They're going right through him.
-You saw him? -Yes.
Who's there?
You're there.
You are there amongst the dead.
It's not the gun.
He's afraid of something else.
You kept it and refurbished it.
All because it's a reminder of my past.
Instruments of death
have a powerful connection to the afterlife.
What should have killed him, saved him.
Ben, we can help you be free of your torment.
I'm a mother...
A fighter.
Show yourself.
A protector.
And I am not afraid.
See the truth.
Yes.
He's at peace.
He has joined his brothers.
You've done it. They're gone.
Everybody else, go back to your rooms.
All of you.
Henry.
Henry!
Henry! Oh, Henry!
Dear Mr. Gates,
below you will find my psychological assessment
and mental status examination
of Mrs. Sarah Lockwood Winchester.
It was conducted at her home between the dates of April 12
to April 19, 1906,
and prepared at the request
of the Winchester Repeating Arms Company.
In my professional opinion,
after having observed Mrs. Winchester
for the past week,
it is my conclusion that she is of sound mind and body,
and is fit to continue in her role
with the Winchester Repeating Arms Company
for as long as she desires such a burden.
Yours truly, Dr. Eric A. Price.
It's time for us both to leave this house.
I'll always miss you.
Thank you, Dr. Price, for your help.
Young man.
Thank you.
Time for me to say goodbye.
Ruby loves you.
That did not stop after her death.
You know that, don't you?
I do.
You know, in spite of everything,
you really do have a beautiful home.
What are you going to do next?
Rebuild, of course.
Of course.