♪ MTV ♪
♪ tense music
♪
[grunting]
♪ pulsing, dramatic music
♪
[people laughing]
Did I see Jake's
on Instagram now?
Did you see that?
I don't know how he's gonna
manage both of his followers.
- I'm one of them.
- Hey, I followed you.
And you?
Yeah, three, I got three.
[Travis]
That-That's what you're gonna
do now, you're gonna
be an influencer?
Go to a truck stop and say,
"I'll post from here
if you'll give me
some free nachos"?
- Extra cheese.
- Free nachos!
Hey, do you remember...
do you remember Stacy's?
Remember that old saloon?
There's a-- there's a saloon
- Do I remember Stacy's?
- in Gateway.
And back in its day,
it was pretty wild.
In the men's bathroom,
there's a hole
in the drywall above the urinal.
And the staff
put a sign there that says,
"Customer looked down
and saw the size
of his penis and put his head
through the wall
out of fucking despair."
That's how-- that's how rank
this place is.
So, we're--
we're outside,
and there's this old boy,
and he's very drunk.
And he sees us,
and he throws his keys
as hard as he can,
hits Rip in the chest.
He says,
"Where's my fucking truck?!"
Like he's a valet.
Like he know-- like he knows
where the fucking truck is.
- You remember this?
- Shit, yeah. How could I forget?
[laughs]
[Travis] And Rip
looks at him and says,
"Son, you would think
there were ten of me."
And he-he was drunk,
but he wasn't stupid,
so he grabs his keys
and off he goes.
We hop in our truck and leave.
Ryan looks at him and just
goes, "Rip, where did
you hear that? That's the
funniest thing I ever heard."
And Rip says, "Yeah,
it wasn't funny
first time I heard it."
Trust me, it wasn't.
[Beth]
I can't ever get you
to a bar. But you've been to
every bar in the fucking state
- with this son of a bitch.
- Hold on-- hold on a second.
I've taken you to two bars,
and I'm O for two
getting your ass home.
Don't start with me, now.
Jimmy, let's go.
- We got to get on the road.
- [Jimmy] You're riding back
- with us?
- Fuck no, I'm not riding back
with you.
I'm driving to the airport
and I'm gonna get out and you're
gonna drive to fucking Texas.
Let's go.
- Yes, sir. [sighs]
Might be heading
your way soon, amigo.
Yeah, you found an outfit?
Yeah, it's called
my Capri Camper. [laughs]
- Mm-hmm.
- He's gonna babysit me
- on the rodeo circuit.
- [Walker] Tough job.
Somebody's got to do it.
You need anything, you holler,
- all right?
- Thanks, bud.
Travis, thank you.
My pleasure. Boy, those legs
do go all the way
to the ground, don't they?
Get the fuck out of here,
will you?
[Travis laughs]
[indistinct chatter]
Travis?
Well, if you're looking for,
like, loper or turnback help,
I, uh...
[sighs]
I could use the work.
Yeah? Why's that?
What's wrong with here?
Too many memories.
Well, I can ride.
You know I can.
Yeah. Yeah, no,
I've seen you ride.
Let me tell you what,
why don't you ask Jimmy
what working for me is like,
so you know what you're
getting into, all right?
What's working
for that asshole like?
It's a hell that
has to be experienced
to be fully comprehended.
Well, is he fair?
I mean, he's not gonna
chew your ass for no reason,
but he... he's really good
at finding reasons.
That's fair.
I love him. Jimmy's so happy
to see me every weekend,
it's like a new puppy
every Saturday.
Jimmy, let's go! Fuck!
- [pants]
- [laughs]
- That's disgusting.
- I like it.
[Travis]
Any time.
- There's no rush whatsoever.
- [Jimmy] Yep, yep.
We're just-- we're
on your timeline.
Disconnect your phone.
I don't want to listen
to yacht rock for an hour.
I'll be there in a week.
All right.
Now go buy an audiobook
and learn how to speak
fucking English,
'cause I don't talk hillbilly,
and I ain't trying
to fucking learn. Go.
See you in a week.
- Yes, sir.
- Seat belts, Emily.
Not you, Jimmy.
No one gives a shit if you live.
Tried to warn you, Teeter.
♪ wistful music
♪
[Jake]
Five hundred, let's do it.
I've never even seen $500.
- [Jake] Come on.
- [Ryan] Give me a break.
- What you want to do with that?
- Come on. Come on.
- You like it?
- Come on.
- Ooh, bad luck for me.
- Ooh, look there,
- buddy.
- All right, Teeter.
Looks like I'm headed to Texas.
Yeah?
What about you?
I'm gonna stop wasting time.
Well, that ain't a direction.
Yeah, it is.
♪
Hey, baby, take a shower.
You smell like a hyena.
How do you know
what a hyena smells like?
I don't, but I assume.
And I assume
they smell like you.
[typing]
What are you doing?
- I want to show you something.
- Mm.
So, I'm not the expert,
but...
around 600 pairs,
irrigated hay meadows,
little house, big barn.
How many acres?
Seven thousand deeded,
another 20 in a BLM lease.
You could use that
for yearlings, right?
Mm-hmm. Where is it?
- 40 miles west of Dillon.
- Mm-hmm.
Over two hours from an airport.
Not a fucking ski resort
in sight.
Hm.
You think you could
make a living here?
Uh, I mean, you're not gonna
get rich, but you can
pay the bills.
Well, you let me worry
about the rich part.
It's far from town, honey.
I hate town.
And far from a bar.
You'll build me a bar.
Mm-hmm. That I can do.
- Well, what do you think?
- [chuckles]
I mean, look, it's, uh,
it's good country,
all old ranches.
And ain't nobody from the city
gonna want to put up
with them winters.
So you could make something
like this work?
Yeah, I could make something
like this work.
Well, that's a relief.
I bought it this morning.
Whoa, whoa, you did what?
Who's gonna
run this place, Beth?
I'll explain that tomorrow.
[sighs]
Fuck it.
[phone rings]
Hello?
♪ somber music
♪
[door closes]
[breathing heavily]
Morning, baby.
What happened?
Funeral home called.
He's ready.
Okay.
Can I help you with the service?
No service.
Just Kayce and...
you and the cowboys.
Gonna need a preacher
or the first thing
my father will do
in his grave is roll over in it.
Well, when do you want to do it?
How fast can you dig a hole?
I mean, we still have
the excavator, but, I mean,
give me a couple hours.
You just tell me where.
Beside my mother.
You know which one that is?
Yeah, I know which one.
[heavy sigh]
[door opens]
[door closes]
[sniffles]
Lynelle?
We're doing it today.
[country music playing softly
on speakers]
[faucet squeaks off]
Remind me not to go a month
without seeing you again.
- [chuckles]
- Goddamn.
I have horses to ride today.
Hey, little ears.
- Where?
- Mine.
- Oh, my God.
- [Lloyd] You know what they say
about guys with little ears,
don't you, Ryan?
Oh, really?
Is that what they say, Lloyd?
Well, you must
have to tuck your pecker
in your boot.
Judging by the size of those
mud flaps stuck on your head,
I'm surprised the wind
doesn't blow you off your horse
- like a fucking kite.
- [scoffs]
Get out of here.
♪
I got to take this one with me.
Y'all want to come take a seat?
Does everyone know
where they're going?
Ethan and I hired on
down to the N Bar.
Well, that's a good outfit.
Teeter, how about you?
Uh, Travis hired me.
[chuckles]
Shit. God help you.
Ryan?
Think I'm just gonna
wander for a bit.
Wandering don't pay so good.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
Yeah.
Thank you, sir.
- [Rip] Jake.
- Thank you, sir.
- Teeter.
- Thank you.
- Walker.
[Rip]
Yeah.
I just got a favor to ask.
What do you need?
Get ready and meet me outside.
♪ gentle music ♪
♪
How far over
do you think we should put him?
Well, let's put him
as close as we can.
And let's pile
all the dirt on this side.
Last night went smooth?
They'll never be able
to find them.
And if they do, they'll never
be able to get them.
You think that'll stop them?
I think it'll anger them.
Then they'll make
a lot of noise.
Then people will start
paying attention.
Then we start making noise.
♪ pensive music
♪
[door closes]
[vehicle door closes]
[Thomas]
Monica.
I must say,
your husband has me curious.
You and me both.
Not even the wife knows?
[laughs softly]
Not even the wife.
[door opens]
Should I stay inside?
Affects you, too, buddy.
Affects all of us.
- Kayce.
- Morning.
Y'all want to sit on the porch?
We'll sit wherever you tell us.
We call this East Camp.
Doesn't connect with the ranch,
except through the BLM lease.
When the wolves push in,
we'd lose 40 calves a spring.
You couldn't hunt them
back then, so...
East Camp's not big enough
to run a whole outfit over here,
and it's too big
for one man to cover,
so my grandfather shut it down.
But it's big enough for us.
I can make a living here.
Get out from under
the weight of this thing.
My family can't afford
the inheritance tax
on the ranch.
I wouldn't think so.
You can't afford to buy it.
I wish I could, Kayce.
Only corporations have the money
to buy your land.
And then it is land no more.
Subdivisions,
shopping centers and condos,
airports and ski resorts.
Everything they flee they will
recreate on your land.
I know.
My vision told me of two paths.
On one, my family.
On the other, the ranch.
I could only save one.
I used to think that meant
that one couldn't be saved.
Then I realized it only
meant that I couldn't save it.
But you can.
When my ancestors came here,
land sold for $1.25 an acre,
back when it was your land.
Even though you didn't sell it,
that's what it sold for
when they took it.
And that's the price
I offer you.
Under two conditions:
East Camp I keep for my family.
And you can never develop
the Yellowstone
and you can never sell it.
♪ hopeful music
♪
We can't sell our land, Kayce.
We have laws that forbid it.
Is your sister okay with this?
She's okay with it.
I made a promise
to your father once...
...that I would one day
have this land.
And I would return it
to the state that man found it.
I would remove any evidence
that he had been here.
I'm sure he took it as a threat.
And at the time,
that's how I meant it.
But your people
are buried in that land
and so are mine.
It is sacred.
And that's how we will treat it.
That's all I ask.
[knife clicks]
[speaking Indigenous language]
This knife
wears my blood.
[grunts softly]
This knife wears mine.
We are brothers now.
To each other
and to the land.
I will deed this East Camp
back to you.
So your family
forever has a home.
[singing in Indigenous language]
♪
[sniffles]
[Kayce]
We're free now.
[phone vibrates]
Yeah?
[speaking Indigenous language]
[birdsong in distance]
You gonna need another shower.
- We all are.
- [Rip] Y'all can go
get cleaned up.
[grunts]
[bird calling out]
Look at that.
I ain't the biggest
believer in signs.
- But I'll take that one.
- Mm.
Yeah, me too.
Beth bought a ranch
outside of Dillon.
A big hole.
- Yeah.
- You won't forget the winter.
Mm. No.
Mosquitoes the size
of sparrows in the summer.
[chuckles]
True enough.
Ought to keep them fucking
Californians away, though.
Yeah.
So, have you figured out
what you're gonna do?
I think we got a room
for an old, busted-up cowboy.
I want to pull that loose string
- out of West Yellowstone.
- Mm.
See if I can talk some sense
into these city folks.
[chuckles]
Good luck.
If I can't cowboy here...
...just rather not do it at all.
Well, brother,
if you change your mind,
our door is always open.
Thank you.
Yep.
Anything else to do around here?
Soon as we fill this hole,
we're done.
♪ somber music ♪
♪
[Jamie] As both the state
of Montana and my family
reel from the loss
of our governor
and my father,
our suffering is compounded
with new evidence
that indicates foul play
in the death of John Dutton.
Furthermore, an attorney
for the development group
tasked with ushering Paradise
Valley into the 21st century
was found murdered
in broad daylight.
While no physical evidence
connecting these events exists,
empirical evidence
screams a connection.
[shower running]
- [faucet knob squeaks]
- [water stops running]
[spurs jingling]
My father's death
is more than just a murder.
It's the outright defiance
of the rule of law.
My father's murder
was not just
the murder of a man.
It was the murder
of Montanans' right
to choose their representatives
and for those representatives
to freely execute
the will of the people.
John Dutton's murder
is an attack on your liberty,
a murder of your freedom.
As the highest-ranking law
enforcement agent in the state,
it is my sworn duty
to seek justice on your behalf,
to wrest from the unjust
your liberty
and to return to you
your freedom.
[soft melody playing]
♪
[music box continues playing]
[Rip] I can get everybody
to come up here.
We can walk down together.
In these fucking shoes?
Are you kidding me?
I'll drive down.
Walking down is tradition, Beth.
Your family's been doing it
for 120 years.
And how do we gain
from that tradition?
I do not need ceremony
to highlight the magnitude
of this moment.
I am well aware.
[Rip] Hey, so we're just
gonna come to you.
Yeah.
Everyone's ready when you are.
[glass clinks]
She seems pretty mad.
Some people
deal with death differently.
She has a right to be mad
on this one.
Let's go.
[engine revving]
Guess when she said she'll
drive, she meant just her.
I guess so.
Come on.
♪ gentle guitar melody
♪
[engine revving in distance]
[engine shuts off]
♪
[car door closes]
I was there when you called.
I hope you don't mind.
You're his protector now.
Why would I mind?
[sniffles]
Appears he said yes?
He said yes.
To everything.
Where is he?
Barn.
♪ mournful music
♪
He'd have liked that.
[sniffling]
[inhales sharply]
[sighs]
You made me promise...
...not to sell an inch.
And I hope that you understand
that this is me keeping it.
There may not be cows on it,
but there won't
be condos either.
We won.
[sniffles]
Breaks my heart...
that I had to lose you to do it.
Gonna let you rest now, Daddy.
You go be with Mama.
♪ quiet music
♪
I'm ready.
♪ gentle violin music
♪
[breathing heavily]
[Carter]
Beth.
You okay?
No.
[breathing heavily]
[sighs] Do you just want
to watch from here?
[shudders]
I don't want to watch at all.
♪
[priest]
Almighty God,
Father of all mercy...
[continues indistinctly]
♪
Mrs. Dutton.
[sniffles]
Lay this upon him
and say goodbye.
[sniffles]
[shudders]
I think I'll say something else.
[shuddering]
♪ low, somber music
♪
[sniffles]
[whispers]
I will avenge you.
♪
You have something you want
to say to him, you say it.
You don't have
to say it out loud.
You can say it in your heart.
I don't know what to say.
That's fine, too, buddy.
What did you say?
I said I forgive him.
Thank you.
[sighs]
Well, John, I, um...
I wore the tightest skirt
I could find in your honor.
You go easy on the angels
up there.
You will be missed...
and thought of often.
[speaking Indigenous language]
You and me.
I will protect this for you
and for all our relations.
♪
[sighs deeply]
How does this work?
Uh, well,
I-I believe the poles rotate
and you lower the straps
with that crank.
Uh...
We have people who will do that.
No, no, no. I'll do it.
[clicking]
[priest]
Well, that's...
it's just symbolic,
uh, it's just in case
the family wants to lay
the first bit of earth down.
Well, it ain't symbolic today.
Today this shovel works.
[clicking continues]
Would you like me to stay?
No, I think
we're about prayed out.
If he ain't already in heaven,
then he ain't going
or there ain't one.
Hey, y-you missed the service.
I don't do funerals.
- [mutters]
- What's up, Gator?
- How we doing?
- Smells good.
[Lynelle]
Thank you. Thanks so much.
What will happen to them?
I don't have any idea, babe.
[Ethan]
What's up, Gator?
What are you making?
Rib eyes, beans,
sourdough biscuits,
blueberry cobbler.
One of his favorites.
- Why not?
- There you go, ma'am.
- [Lynelle] Thank you.
- Let's hop in the truck, buddy.
[Ryan]
No, thanks, man...
- Kayce?
- Think we're gonna
head home, man.
Ain't you already home?
Nah, this ain't my home.
I'll see y'all around.
[Teeter]
Goodbye, sir.
♪ dark, suspenseful music
♪
[panting]
[exhales sharply]
[shovel thuds]
I don't even know what to say.
Thank you.
I want you to know
I'll take care of your daughter.
You have my word.
I'll try and love her
the same way that she loved you.
All right.
[grunts]
♪ slow, somber music
♪
I'll see you around.
[exhales sharply]
[engine revs]
[line ringing]
Where's she going?
[Lloyd]
Hell, I don't know.
Maybe she just needed
to take a drive.
That was a lot to swallow.
[Jamie] Now, with respect
to those attempting
to invent a false narrative
that involves me and Ms. Atwood
in a sexual relationship,
I would like to point out
that knowingly spreading
disinformation
and slandering a public official
with an intent
of tarnishing an investigation
is obstruction of justice,
and my office
will be treating it as such.
What we have lost...
is a governor with a vision
and a dedication to the people
of the great state of Montana.
And whether you shared
his vision is irrelevant.
Many didn't, myself included,
but we respected it.
And we respected the rule of law
and the will of the people
to execute that vision
if it was the will of the people
that it be executed.
What we will not lose,
what I refuse to surrender
to those who attack us
are the blind scales of justice
that measure the mettle
of our constitution
against the traitors
intent on destroying
the freedoms Montanans cherish.
Thank you very much
for your time.
♪
No way. Mm-mm.
[Ryan] That better have
a full tank of fuel.
- [groans]
- Git, git, git, git, git.
[tailgate closes]
- Ethan.
- See you around, my friend.
- It's been a ride, hasn't it?
- Sure has.
[Ryan]
I beat you out of this place.
- You did.
- [laughs] Who would've thought?
- Who would've thought?
- Take care of yourself.
- No more holes in you.
- Yes, sir.
- Love you, big dog.
- Laramie.
How come barrel racers
get cremated when they die?
Why?
'Cause the ground
is never good enough.
- [laughter]
- Oh. All right, all right.
Be safe, young man.
[Laramie]
He's been waiting for that one.
- [softly] You suck at cards.
- [laughs]
[Lloyd speaks indistinctly]
[Ryan sighs]
See you down the dusty trail.
That's where I'll be.
- [truck door closes]
- [engine starts]
♪ fast, tense music
♪
[engine starts]
[Rip] Get in.
I know where she's going.
[Lloyd]
Go.
[phone ringing]
Hey, baby.
[Rip over phone]
I know where you're going.
Well, you're almost
an hour behind.
Better put the pedal
to the metal, honey.
No, I need you
to pull the car over.
- I can't do that.
- Beth,
pull over.
Pull over the fucking car!
You're worried about me,
so I'm gonna let
the yelling slide.
- Don't do it again.
- Beth, please.
There's got to be another way,
all right?
- We can come up with a plan.
- I have a plan.
You're a big part of it,
so speed up, would you?
[sighs]
How about if I call Kayce,
- see what he has to say?
- You keep Kayce out of this.
Rip, I gave him my word.
The last thing I will ever say
to my father
was making this promise.
I'm gonna keep it.
[device beeps]
Fuck.
[newswoman over radio]
In a fiery speech,
Attorney General Dutton
addressed the circumstances
around his father's death,
as well as the death
of Sarah Atwood,
which appears to be connected.
[newsman]
Which the attorney general
seemed to acknowledge.
[newswoman] I think he agrees
and is energized
to seek answers and hold
the guilty parties accountable.
[newsman]
It was an excellent speech
and exactly what Montanans
needed to hear.
At a time when we find ourselves
without a leader,
a leader needs to rise,
and one did.
[newswoman]
Sure did.
[sighs]
Yes.
Mm-hmm.
[exhales]
♪
[clears throat]
[pours drink]
[shouts]
[Jamie grunting]
What did I say?
[groaning, gasping]
You know, it's hard for you
to understand the notion
of keeping a promise.
But when I make one...
...I fucking keep it.
[both grunting]
[gasping]
[coughing]
[mutters]
[coughs]
[groaning]
[panting]
- [shouts]
- [grunts]
How do you think
this is gonna work?
[Beth grunts]
Huh? This part of your plan?
[both grunt]
[Beth gasping]
You make it too easy.
[groaning]
Now I call the police,
and you go to prison
for attempted murder.
Then I'll bring charges
against you
for the murder of our father
and for Sarah.
And you will fucking take
every bit of it without a peep.
Or I will pull back the curtain
on everything our father did
and everything his father did
and his father before that.
You don't even have
to worry about
the inheritance tax
on the ranch anymore
because the class action
lawsuit's gonna take
every inch of that place.
And then you can sit back
and watch me turn it
into the most desirable
recreation destination
in America
from your 8x8 cell
in Deer Lodge.
We sold the ranch.
What?
Sold it.
The fuck you did.
Nobody can afford
that ranch, Beth!
Sold it for $1.25 an acre.
[chuckles]
1.1 million
for the largest ranch
in Montana.
[panting]
Why, why would you...?
Who?
The reservation.
What?
[laughing]
Your face.
All your dreams...
Jamie, all
of your fucking ambitions
- just fucking gone.
- [snaps fingers]
Just like that.
You did what?
- You did what?
- [groaning]
You did what?!
What the fuck?!
[screams]
[both grunting]
[knife clatters]
[Beth groaning softly]
[choking]
You know what
you're about to become?
Another one
of this family's secrets.
[groaning]
Wait.
[panting]
- [Beth grunts]
- [Jamie groaning weakly]
Look at me. Look at me.
That's it.
That's right.
I'm gonna be the last thing
you ever fucking see.
[breathing shakily]
[groans weakly]
Hey, whoa, whoa. Hey, hey, hey.
Hey.
Sit, here, come here.
[Beth panting]
How bad are you hurt?
Bad.
I don't know how we're gonna
hide this one.
I'm gonna get you somewhere.
I just don't know
where yet, okay?
I don't need to hide anything.
It's part of the plan.
I don't see a plan here, Beth.
You will, baby. You will.
You're gonna get rid of him.
You know where, right?
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna call 911.
[panting]
You saved me again.
Love you.
[sighs heavily]
[groaning softly]
♪ slow, dramatic music ♪
♪
What's this here?
That's the carveout
for the 5,000-acre parcel.
We don't control
the forest leases.
You'll have to work that out
with the Department of Forestry.
[Mo]
Best of luck with that.
They can have it.
We don't need it.
Where's the part that says
they can't build on it?
14A, next page.
The Yellowstone will be declared
a wilderness area.
Nothing can be built.
So no motorized vehicles,
no bicycles.
Can only be traversed on a horse
or your own two feet.
Congratulations.
You just made
the worst land deal
since my people sold Manhattan.
But look at Manhattan
and what it's become.
Then look at your ranch.
It'll never change.
Thank you for the sacrifice
and for saving it.
[Mo speaks Indigenous language]
Think I need a minute.
[panting]
[door opens]
[door closes]
[cries]
Kayce.
♪ mournful music
♪
I'm free.
[cries]
You've always been free.
This is closure.
This is forgiveness.
It's freedom, too.
Free from this.
There's a wolf.
He's digging
for his supper, I think.
They don't dig for supper.
That's foxes and coyotes.
What's he digging for, then?
A den. Building a home.
Guess he likes it here, too.
[Monica chuckles softly]
Great.
There goes my chicken coop.
[chuckles softly]
You won't have any problems
with that wolf.
That one ain't real.
Then how can we see it?
Guess it's our vision, too, now.
I'm gonna put this O2 monitor
on your finger.
- Okay?
- [Beth] Mm-hmm.
[indistinct radio chatter]
- There you go.
- [grunting]
Jesus.
One hell of a beating.
She make a statement?
She came here after
their father's funeral,
which he chose not to attend.
Confronted him about it.
Accused him of involvement
in their father's death.
He started beating her.
Tried to fight him off.
Used pepper spray at one point.
Found the can over there.
He got her on her back
and punched her
until she was unconscious.
Woke up, he was gone.
Says she doesn't remember
the house being
as torn up as it is,
but she's pretty woozy.
Thanks.
[Beth grunting softly]
Pretty bad beating?
I've had worse.
I'm sorry to hear that.
You, uh, accused your brother
of having involvement
in your father's death.
I sure did.
You said he lied
during his speech. How so?
He was sleeping
with that attorney.
I saw her here.
In this house, right there.
Naked as the day she was born.
If I were you,
I would be looking
for LLCs in her name.
[gasps weakly]
And then...
I would be looking
for large wire transfers
to numbered offshore accounts.
That is how you will find
the people who killed my father.
Sarah Atwood is the bitch
that paid for it.
My brother is the piece of shit
that awarded it.
And I am evidence
of what he is willing to do
to prevent someone
from looking into it.
[EMT]
I need to get her on the road.
The right lung presents
punctured
and her extracranial hematoma
is grade three.
Is she concussed?
[EMT]
What do you think?
Pretty lucid for a concussion.
[EMT]
All right. Let's get her going.
A lot of practice, buddy.
[Dillard] I'm gonna need
to speak to you more about this.
I'm at your beck and call.
And if you have
any physical evidence
corroborating your claims,
I'd love to see it.
You think he did it, too?
When I spoke
to the attorney general,
he was not forthcoming.
He struck me as a man
with something to hide.
You just summed up
his entire life.
[EMT 2]
On my count. One, two, three.
I'll be in touch.
♪ ominous music
♪
[siren chirping]
[Rip]
Let's go.
[exhales sharply]
[body thudding]
[Lloyd] What do you want
to do with the car?
[Rip] Not here.
I want you to stay close to me.
- [Lloyd] Yeah.
- I don't need anybody
- running these plates.
- You got it.
♪
[engine starts]
In yet another bizarre turn
in the death
of Governor John Dutton,
Lewis and Clark County has filed
aggravated assault
and domestic violence charges
against Attorney General
Jamie Dutton,
whose vehicle was found
by authorities in Central Idaho.
Idaho State Police
state that the vehicle
was intentionally set on fire
in what appears to be
an attempt to destroy evidence.
Lewis and Clark officials
have not
ruled out additional charges,
and the state assembly
is meeting later today
to begin impeachment proceedings
against the attorney general.
- Here's your smoothie.
- Oh, thank you.
What are those?
For the pain.
Not what I asked.
It's oxycodone.
Yeah, I'm not taking that shit.
You say that.
Broken ribs
are extremely painful.
I know.
I'm the one who's got 'em.
I'll talk to the doctor
about something milder.
Whatever lifts your skirt, lady.
Hey, buddy?
Can you pass me that purse?
- Yeah.
- Please.
Thank you.
[sighs]
♪ gentle, hopeful music
[moans softly]
Mmm.
♪
Goddamn.
Well, I can't wait to ride
one of them badasses.
You can't wait to what?
The fuck did you just say?
I said I can't wait to ride
one of them badasses, sir.
I thought I told you to get
a book on speaking English.
I listened to it
the whole way out here.
Yeah? Well, it didn't work.
You think I'd ever let you
get on a horse like this?
Go to the cutting pen,
get on a turnback horse,
turn back for Spud.
There's a horse tied there
named Man Killer,
tied to the fence with a chain.
Have fun with that.
- Yes, sir.
- Goddamn.
Good to see you, Teeter.
Hey, you, too,
till I fucking die
on the back of a horse
named Man Killer.
He's a sweet horse.
Fuck are you smiling about?
- It's a good day, sir.
- Yeah? For who?
Not that horse you're on.
Jesus Christ, you've been
jackhammering his back
all fucking morning.
I swear to God, Jimmy,
the more you do it,
the worse you get at it.
I've never seen anything like it
in my fucking life.
Yes, sir.
I just don't think
this is the job for you.
Maybe you should
look into training
fucking dogs or something.
Yes, sir.
[tongue clicks]
[indistinct chatter]
Just one.
All I got left is standing room.
Standing room's fine.
["Hang Tight Honey" playing]
♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh
♪ I got a bus
'fore I got a house ♪
♪ 'Cause that's what dreams
make you do ♪
♪ Hittin' them
neon honky-tonks ♪
♪ To play a two-step or two ♪
♪ 200 days to a hundred towns
♪ Bringin' boots
to a sawdust floor ♪
♪ While this six-string
calls my name, baby ♪
♪ I'll be missin' yours,
come on ♪
♪ Hang tight, honey,
I'm a white line ♪
♪ Runnin' down a dream
on a long-lost highway ♪
♪ Me and this band
playin' one-night stands ♪
♪ For some fans gettin'
straight-up sideways ♪
♪ Baby, I miss
your blue-collar kiss ♪
♪ Just one more day
to get through ♪
♪ Hang tight, honey,
got a pocketful of money ♪
♪ And I'm headed
straight home to you ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh
♪ Yeah, you can't hold me
and I can't hold you ♪
♪ From two time zones away ♪
♪ When you're clockin' out,
yeah, I'm clockin' in ♪
♪ Gettin' ready
to hit the stage ♪
♪ Just know
they're singin' along ♪
♪ To all those songs
I wrote about you ♪
♪ And I'll be savin'
all my lovin' for you ♪
♪ Come Sunday afternoon ♪
Whoo!
♪ Hang tight, honey,
I'm a white line runnin' ♪
♪ Down a dream
on a long-lost highway ♪
♪ Me and this band
playin' one-night stands ♪
♪ For some fans gettin'
straight-up sideways ♪
♪ Baby, I miss
your blue-collar kiss ♪
♪ Just one more day
to get through ♪
♪ Hang tight, honey,
got a pocketful of money ♪
♪ I'm headed straight home to ♪
♪ You
Whoo!
♪ Hang tight, honey
♪ Every good run
comes to an end ♪
♪ Hang tight, honey
♪ Till I'm in your arms again
♪ Hang tight, honey,
I'm a white line runnin' down ♪
♪ A dream
on a long-lost highway ♪
♪ Me and this band
playin' one-night stands ♪
♪ For some fans gettin'
straight-up sideways ♪
♪ Baby, I miss
your blue-collar kiss ♪
♪ Just one more day
to get through ♪
♪ Hang tight, honey,
got a pocketful of money ♪
♪ I'm headed
straight home to you ♪
♪ Hang tight, honey,
got a pocketful of money ♪
♪ I'm headed straight
♪ Home
♪ Ooh, ooh
♪ I'm headed straight
home to you ♪
- Whoo!
- ♪ Ooh, ooh
♪ I'm headed straight home to ♪
♪ You
- [song ends]
- [cheering]
[mouths]
[indistinct chatter]
Where do y'all learn that?
Drape yourself like a scarecrow,
and it somehow looks cool.
Yeah, it's called
14 hours a day in the saddle.
Hmm.
How's Texas treating you?
Yeah, I survived.
Looks like it's treating you
pretty good.
Can't complain.
It's good to see you.
I made a mistake.
Picked the wrong thing.
Thought you were playing
your Super Bowl.
I did, and we lost.
How so?
Well, it... it just got me
thinking about stuff, you know?
[laughs]
Damn, you cowboys.
You'll write poems
about a horse,
but you can't tell
a woman how you feel.
- You want to know how I feel?
- Yeah, I do.
You are my Super Bowl,
and that's how I feel.
Man, that sounded a lot cooler
coming up with it in my truck.
Explain to me what that means.
It means that when I'm laying
under the stars
in the West Texas night,
all I can think about is you.
♪ slow, dramatic music
♪
When do you go back
to the ranch?
I don't go back to the ranch.
I go where you go.
- You quit your job?
- Mm-hmm.
I am gonna need
another one, though.
How much does moving
all this heavy shit around pay?
- It's better than cowboying.
- Is it?
Yeah, but I got another job
in mind for you.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Come on.
Let me introduce you
to life on a bus.
I'll take it.
♪ slow, atmospheric music
♪
[floorboard creaks]
Do you want anything
from the office?
Something personal?
I spent my whole life trying
to get away from this place.
Seems silly to cling
to its things now.
It'll all be in storage.
Well, someday
Tate might want them.
Or at least to know his story.
It's a story worth remembering.
♪ sweeping, heartfelt music
♪
[engine shuts off]
We figured that
you would want this.
I think I might, um...
I'm gonna start my own brand.
Why don't y'all use it?
All right. Well, we'll keep
it at our place.
And if you change your mind,
just let me know.
I won't.
How many, uh, pairs are you
thinking of running?
I think I can do 300.
That's a lot of work
for a man and a boy.
- Yeah.
- [chuckles]
Well, if you need any help,
you just let me know.
Give me a holler, yeah?
I will. I'll need it.
All right, brother.
[engine starts]
See you around, Kayce.
[auctioneer]
All right, next in the ring
we got a set of 30 head
of black straight heifers,
averaging 605,
coming off the Hirschy Ranch
in the Big Hole Valley.
Turned down on grass
and vaccinated,
ready to go your way.
Let's sell 'em.
What are we looking for?
Well, you want to look
at their back.
You want that to be straight.
Good hip.
This looks like
a pretty good bunch right here.
Let's make a run at 'em.
[auctioneer] Somebody give 175.
Somebody? 175.
75. 75. Somebody? 175, anybody?
175. 175. Now two.
Anybody get two? There's two.
Two and a quarter.
Get 225. Now half, half, half.
250. 250. 75.
275. Three dollars. Anybody
give three, three, three?
Somebody give three dollars.
Sold out, 275.
Buyer number 269.
269 buys.
[singing in Indigenous language]
♪
You did it.
I didn't do anything.
Creator did it.
♪
[singing in Indigenous language]
[grunts]
[Mo]
Hey! Stop!
They protected this land.
They died for this land.
And this land
is where they'll stay.
Go back.
♪ melancholy music
♪
[grunts]
[Elsa]
141 years ago,
my father was told
of this valley,
and here's where we stayed.
Seven generations.
My father was told
they would come for this land,
and he promised to return it.
Nowhere was that promise written.
It faded with my father's death
but somehow lived in the spirit
of this place.
Men cannot truly own wild land.
To own land, you must
blanket it in concrete,
cover it with buildings,
stack it with houses so thick,
people can smell
each other's supper.
You must rape it to sell it.
Raw land. Wild land.
Free land can never be owned.
But some men pay dearly for the
privilege of its stewardship.
They will suffer and sacrifice
to live off it
and live with it
and hopefully teach
the next generation
to do the same.
And if they falter,
find another willing
to keep the promise.
♪ grand, sweeping music
♪
[cattle lowing]
Now, when they come out, they're
not gonna know where they're at,
so we're just gonna
ease 'em to water.
- There's three of us.
- [Monica laughs]
[Kayce]
Takes one man to move one cow,
two to move two.
Three men can move 300.
Is that true?
We're about to find out.
[mooing]
This is how I always thought
it would be, in my dreams.
Yeah, mine, too, baby.
Come on, bud.
- Thanks, boys.
- Yes, sir.
♪
[shushing]
[mooing]
What's wrong with those ones?
Well, they're sick.
I'll doctor 'em here
and then I'll turn 'em back out.
I tell you,
the grass here is good.
About as good as I've ever seen.
Cowboys are the only
people on Earth
that get excited about grass.
[laughs]
In this business
it's the only thing worth
getting excited about, honey.
You seem happy.
I am. I am happy.
- I'm getting happy.
- Good.
There's a bar in town.
Went there for lunch,
just two old guys
playing dominoes.
Said they make a mean steak
for dinner.
I asked the bartender
about tourists,
and he just laughed at me.
I said, "Well, do tourists
pass through here?"
And he said,
"Yeah, they pass through,
but we don't let 'em stop."
[chuckles]
Sounds like my kind of place.
There's a...
there's a hitching post
out front,
in case we want to ride.
Well, I'll saddle you a horse.
♪ "My Heroes Have Always Been
Cowboys" by Willie Nelson ♪
♪
♪ I grew up dreamin' ♪
♪ Of bein' a cowboy
♪ And lovin' the cowboy ways
♪ Pursuin' the life
of my high-ridin' heroes ♪
♪ I burned up
my childhood days ♪
♪ I learned all the rules
of a modern-day drifter ♪
♪ Don't you hold on
to nothin' too long ♪
♪ dramatic orchestral music
♪