Where is it?
Go to hell.
You did this to yourself.
Sara,if you're listening, I only hope,by now,you've found your safe haven.
I took advantage of you, put you in a place that's every doctor's nightmare.
Sara tancredi. You know her well?
I'd know her a lot better if you can get my ass moved.
I'll talk to the warden.
"Another chance" and "safe haven." Those are the names of some of the chapters in the book they use an aa.
Make no mistake about it.
We will be a family if it kills us.
That's your map?
What happened to your arm?
My dad drinks,too.
My tummy hurts.
She needs that medicine. She can't go two days without it.
Kacee's going into the system now. Aiding an escaped con.
Tell her lawyer I'll turn myself in.
Kacee said you need to run.
If you get busted or turn yourself in, dede won't have either of you.
Michael,I want for this to be over.
That makes two of us.It's just a question of looking at whatever it is your father gave you.
It's just a key.
If I may,sir,the president...
she could be useful.
Madam president?
I want you to come home,paul.
We can fix this,but not with those brothers running around the country.
Caroline...
bring them in,paul,and everything can go back to the way it was.
Evansville,Indiana
agent kellerman.
Paul,where are you?
Out in the cold. Remember?
I'm speaking in chicago tonight.
lincolN.
Sara.
It's funny how you only call me when you need me.
- Maybe "funny" is not the right word. - All of this can go away,paul.
- Can it? - Yes.
I'm the president of the united states.
Please just come back to chicago and turn burrows and scofield in.
I promise you that I will make everything go back to the way it was.
I have to go.
Just come back,paul.
I need you.
You actually think we have a shot?
It depends on what your father gave you.
This fell out of his pocket when I found him. I don't recognize the insignia,do you?
No.
But,uh...
sara,we've got someone working with us now.
good morning,sunshine.
How did you sleep?
I'll tell you what.
I'll go unlock the kids and make us all breakfast.
No. I'll get the kids.
- No... - tu-tut-tut. I insist.
No.
I'll get the kids.
Some hand cream will make them rope burns feel better.
It won't work.
'Course it will. Says right here on the bottle: "Soothes skin irritations and..."
no. This.
It won't work.I've got a job. The kids have school.
We're all going to get back to our normal routines once this little adjustment period is over.
- There's someone coming over today. - Who?
This woman,patty,from the welcome wagon committee.
- Call her and canceL. - I don't have her number.
And,if she shows up,and I don't answer the door,
she's going to know something's wrong.
Teddy...
teddy bear...
you need to go.
If she recognizes you...
I don't want you to get in trouble.
That's nonsense.
It's no trouble.
No trouble at all.
XXXXXXXXXXXX
Hi,sara.
What's done is done. We all want the same thing.
You didn't tell us you left her to die.
I was scaring her.XXXXXX
No. No,you left me in there to drown.
I wonder how long you can hold your breath. Maybe we should find out.
You need me,and you know it.
You need me. You need me,and you know it.
Why?Why do we need him?We have the key. We'll find out what it's for.
I can tell you what that key's for right now.
It's to a private cigar club.
Where?
Chicago.
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=- proudly presents
sync:YTET-gagegao xjeff00 mina -=www.ydy.com/bbs=-
Prison Break Season 02 Episode 16
We have to hurry.
We have to hurry,larry. I did a bad thing.
God! I did a very bad thing.
All gas stations: On 80,30,77.
I want scofield's and burrows' pictures on each and every gas pump.
If they have no fuel,they can't get anywhere.
- Sir? - What?
We might need to divert our attention away from scofield and burrows for a while.
Why would I do that?
Because one of the other escapees just killed a civilian.
A man fitting his description was spotted running from the scene of a brutal homicide.
Happened in algoma,wisconsin, less than four hours from the prison.
Call the field office in madison, and have them get some agents out there right away.
- Okay.I'll notify headquarters. - I didn't say headquarters.
I said,are you not following direct orders?
Oh,I am following direct orders,sir.
Just not from you anymore.
Everything goes through headquarters from now on.
may I?
yeah.
You heard about patoshik.
Just now.
Good.
He goes.
Come on,the man is mentally ill. He doesn't know anything,he's not a threat...
patoshik was one of scofield's cellmates for awhile.
Scofield included him in the escape. Who knows what he knows?
- Scofield and burrows are still out there. - Don't worry about scofield and burrows right now.
So,again...
patoshik goes.
Take care of it.
- Hi,are you in charge of seating? - Yeah,can I help you?
Agent paul kellerman,secret service.
I'm transporting a fugitive to chicago. I need you to clear a car for me.
- A fugitive? - Yes,that's right.
Well,it's just that we're already near capacity...
you want him to rub elbows with your other passengers?
- No,sir. - Okay.
- What's he wanted for? - Killing people.
Good lord. Make it happen.
All right,come on,follow me.
It's gonna be all right.
If you say so.
We use him to get what we need,then we dump him.
Okay.
I'm sorry you got involved in this.
The fact that you're helping us...
means a lot.
Thank you.
The other riders aren't in any danger,are they?
I mean,should I make an announcement or anything?
You want pandemonium?
- No,sir. - Okay,then no announcements,right?
Just keep everybody out of this car then everything is jake.
I've done this a million times. Never had a problem.
Okay,will do.
Let's go.
We'll be in chicago in about five hours.
Want to get some rest.
You okay?
Yeah.
Joliet.Illinois Fox River State Penitentiary
Brad. You don't look too good.
I helped you with sara tancredi, and you were supposed to get me into ad seg.
I tried.
But your new warden... Mm...
straight as an arrow.
But I might be able to do you one better than ad seg.
You found scofield and burrows through the russian girl,right?
Yeah,nika. Why?
And you tracked down bagwell by following susan hollander.
Yeah.
And I blow my nose with my right hand and I wipe my ass with my left.
What of it?
I've got very powerful people behind me that want me to finish my job.
They can push through the quickest habeas corpus proceedings the courts have ever seen.
Paperwork's sitting on the right person's desk as we speak,
setting forth all the constitutional violations in your prosecution.
It's just waiting to be rubber-stamped.
And what do I have to do?
You just find those cons.
Only,this time...
you're gonna do it for me-- unofficially, under the radar,no paper trail...
I need a junkyard dog who's willing to do the ugly things it takes to bring a con to justice.
Are you my dog,brad?
Damn hell,yeah,I am.
This is delicious. What'd you call it again?
That,my dear patty-cake,is what my auntie back in 'bama used to call "hobo chicken.
" One part chicken,two parts spice,three part actual hobo.
I know,uh,uh...
fowl isn't part of a traditional brunch,per se,
but I have found a lean meat can act as an aperitif to,uh...
awaken the pallet for more subtle flavors and textures,such as...
mama mia!
Pumpkin cinnamon breads with fresh strawberries and cream.
Oh,boy!
Now,how did you two meet?
Church.
after my,uh...
accident,uh,I was volunteering with some other amputees.
My parish back home did an exchange program with churches all over this fine country and...
well... the good lord just saw fit to plop my country rump right down in the pew beside my susie Q.
And you just stole her heart.
I'm a regular one-armed bandit.
A one-armed bandit...
mrs.Wallace,teddy just bought me a brand-new bike.
It's out in the garage. Wanna go see?
Sure.
- We have got company. - Oh,that's okay.
No,it's not; it's rude. Zack knows better. Isn't that right?
You do know better,zack.
you gotta have discipline.
Without a strong father figure, a young man might just end up in prison.
since you are such a fan of lame store-bought blueberry pie,
I am gonna bake you a real pie...
hi,my name's lance and I'm an addict.
Hi,sara. Hi,my name is not lance,I'm not an addict.
hey,michael...
do you know if there's any way  I can get any water?
Yeah,I think there's a bathroom downstairs.
I'll check.
Thanks.
It was never personal,sara war never is.
Yeah.
sara!
*********
*****
******
****
*******
you get one of those!
You get one of those.
One.
Get down,right now.
What?
These three guys said they saw what looked to be a fight going on in there.
They didn't,all right?
Just get the train to chicago.
Do I need to notify the police?
You need to do what I just told you to do.
You take the tickets,I'll watch the fugitive.
You guys can just continue to do bong hits,
or whatever you do back there,okay?
Now would you guys mind your own business?
Everybody clear?
Great.
Don't interrupt again,please.
********
If she tries that again...
you'll do what?
Just stay on the other side of the car.
It wasn't personal,paul.
*****
What're these?
Oh,I'm,uh...
gonna do some renovations.
Uh,I was just tappin' the sheetrock,lookin' for the stud.
Looks like you already found one.
Potty mouth!
Me and the girls get together every  friday for book club.
You ought to host it this week and  everybody can meet you.
I'll see you then!
Can't wait.
this ain't ever gonna work here.
Go pack your things;
we're movin'.
**********
if you don't stop me,I'm gonna eat this whole thing by myself.
All right,sweetie,
listen.
I'll make a deal with you.
Remember that merry-go-round that we saw today?
You're not gonna get a chance to ride it,
if you don't eat something.
Go ahead.
I don't feel good.
Oh,sweetie.
Okay,come on.
Let's go,all right?
I got you.
Okay,just hold on.
Okay,sweet pea?
Check,please?
All right!
Nobody move!
Hey,sara?
********
how is she?
Well,she wants to be alone.
So we get what her dad locked away with that key.
What do we do then?
I mean...
you saw what they did with the tape we made.
They're gonna bury everything we put out there.
That's why we're keeping him close to us.
He's got a lot of connections in washington.
So we get to the cigar club,
open her dad's box...
what if the only thing inside's  a bunch of stogies?
I think it's worth making the trip to find out.
Yes?
Caroline.
Paul.
Where are you?
I need to know exactly what you meant when you said you were gonna make this right.
I need specifics.
Where are you?
What's that noise?
I'm on a train. I'll be in chicago later today.
But I need to know specifics.
Where are burrows and scofield?
Are they with you?
Don't worry about them;
worry about me.
Paul,
there are still positions in my administration that need to be filled--
including chief of staff.
I want that to be you.
When I get to chicago,we'll meet.
We'll talk.
all of it.
Man,I just brought enough to get a sandwich.
I was sitting right there,okay?
If you're lying...
look,my daughter is sick,
and I don't want to spend any more minutes in here than necessary.
Trust me,that is all that I have.
What do you got,sweetheart?
What do you got?
You don't want to listen?!
Hey,hey,calm down,man.
Shut up!
-****** -All right.
Listen to me,you've got to calm down.
All right,I can help you get  everything that you want.
But you don't want to hurt anybody else,right?
Come on.
Look,listen.
Why don't you go ahead and lock the door,
and turn the closed sign back,
so everybody thinks that this  place is closed,all right?
And then,we can get everybody away from the winw.
Is that cool with you?
Everybody's away from the window,okay?
Let's move everybody onto this side of the room.
Get on this side of the room,everybody.
Let's move to this side of the  room from the window.
-Move! -Everybody,
let's get on this side of the room,okay?
This side of the room.
Why don't you take my daughter,okay?
Take her on this side of the room,so that everybody...
everything is gonna be okay.
Everything is gonna be fine.
Because you're not gonna put your hand on another person,right?
RighT.
We're all good.
Y'all good?
We're good,right?
Hey,sara?
Come on in.
I've been sitting here evaluating.
I,uh...
I jumped bail.
I'm on the run,
and I just tried to take a man's life.
I'm not using.
Which is actually quite an accomplishment.
But three weeks ago,I was a doctor.
You can get that back...
all of it.
You need to believe that.
You believe that?
You think you can get it all back?
I choose to have faith.
Because without that,I'm nothing.
It's the only thing that's keeping me going.
I got two things keeping me going.
First,is that I want the people who killed my dad.
And actually,the second...
ironically,I probably wouldn't even say if I hadn't lost him,but,um...
you should know that...
the first thing they tell you  when you take the job,
is,um,never to fall in love with an inmate.
what's going on?
Roadblock.
*****
It's locked.
You can't be in here.
run the roadblock.
Man,I can't do that.
Run it!
bradley bellick,fbi.
Brad bellick,federal bureau of investigations.
Brad bellick,fbi.
Special agent brad bellick,fbi.
Hi,there,I'm brad bellick with the fbi.
I'm an agent with the fbi,brad bellick.
Brad bellick.
I'm with the bureau.
Brad bellick.I'm with the bureau.
I already talked to the cops,told them all I had to say.
Yeah,well,I'm no local hayseed cop.
I'm federal.
And you're not going to get away with lying to me.
I didn't lie to nobody.
Really?
"He was just some homeless guy,hangs around hancock square,"
hitting up college kids for change.
"He's down there all the time.
If he's not there,I don't know where to find him."
That's your statement,right?
Pretty much.
Right.See,the problem is charles "haywire" patoshik is a paranoid,
who suffers from fear of crowds,
who's terrified of strangers.
If he's anywhere,he's in the middle of nowhere,
keeping to himself,being a weirdo.
And?
And if you want to get tough...
how about I arrest you right now for hindering a federal investigation?
Who they going to believe?
An agent with 15 years on the force and three presidential citations
or a piece of white trash with a juvie record?
I didn't ask him to do it,
but in case you haven't noticed,
I ain't exactly broken up over my stepdad's death.
Why can't you just leave this patoshik guy alone?
Where is he?
Or do you want to get locked up...
right now?
yeah.
I got a lead on patoshik.
Where?
I'm on my way.
Keep him there.
AlonE.
Any information on scofield and burrows,
I want to be notified immediately.
If that works out for you.
They're gonna have cops waiting for us at the next station.
We need to jump then.
And do what?
Hide under a barrel?
Linc's right.
Okay,you just put those in there.
I'm so sorry about all this.
It's okay,sweet pea.
Here's everything right here,man.
It's good.
All right,everyone in the storage room.Now.
What?
Get back there until the cops show up.
No,no,no,no,I can't go back there.
Come on.
No.
Look,you kept a cool head this whole time.
Don't get yourself killed now.
You know what?Listen to me.
I'm a wanted man.Okay?
If the police show up here,they'll take me back to prison,
and you know what?That's fine.
But my little girl right here?
She's sick.
And she's going to be left alone.
And I can't let that happen,so can you please let us go?
Go!
Come on.This way.
Let's go.
all right,everyone in the back.
Move.
Not yoU.
- No! - You're coming with me.
Go on.
Move.
Okay,I want you to stay right here,okay?
Go on!
Hey.
I think you should let her go,man.
take off.Last chance.
You've got the money.
Burglary and assault.
Man,hey,that's change,man,that's little time.
But this right here...
you will be in prison for the rest of your life.
Believe me on that.
Unless you want your daughter to see you die,move.
I'm trying to help you,man!
come here!
sweetie,stay right there.
oh,no.
who did this?
I did.
Thank you.
Bellick: Haywire!
Don't move!
Run!Larry!Run!
Hurry!Hurry!
Dino,it's eric.
We've got four jumpers.
Three males and a female.
Call it in and get us to the next station.
Do you hear me?
Get us to the next station.
The men who pushed through the roadblock are jumping off
the train near mile marker 54,just south of the tedford bridge.
freeze!
Don't shoot!Don't shoot!
Turn around!
I'm an employee of the train company.
Dino,it's eric.
We've got four jumpers.
Three males and a female.
Call it in and get us to the next station.
Let's go.
Come on.
They told us to jump and run and not to look back or they'd shoot us.
We need to find a car.
yeah.I got haywire trapped.
Don't do anything.
Just hold him until I get there.
No problem.
I got this wingnut treed.
caroline.
Paul,where are you?
Did you send the police?
No,of course not.
How did they know I was on that train?
Paul,I have no idea.
I'll let the president know.
I contact the president directly.
Are burrows and scofield with you?
I was expecting to brief the president.
You report to me now.
Paul?
Where did we spend my 35th birthday?
What?
The restaurant.
Where was it?You remember.
Don't be ridiculous.I have to go.
Do not hang up.
I have to go.
Just get burrows and scofield...
hey.
Whoever this is...tell bill kim that he just screwed up...big-time.
Paul?Paul?
What's all this?
Some whacko climbs up to a grain elevator,people want to watch.
(oh,god,you we supposed to keep a handle on things.
Do you know what that means?
I got you haywire.
What else do you want?
FbI.He's my chargee.
How you doing,charles?
I don't want to go back to prison.
I don't blame you.
I want to go to holland.
That's not what i expected to hear.
But you can't go there,son.
I just...
I just want to go...here.
See?
Yeah.I'll tell you what.
You don't have to go to prison.
But you can't go to holland,either.
Oh,no,no,no,no,no,no.
It's okay,it's okay,it's okay.
Hey,you're in a tough spot.
You feel trapped,you got no options,and...
caught in a situation where you have no control.
I know how you feel.
I do.
It takes its toll on you,and all you want to do is run.
But run where?
I just want to go.
There's a way out.
A way out?
- Yeah. - Of this maze?
Yeah.
Chicago,Illinois
There are private humidors in the back.
Each member's name is on their box.
Any security?
A receptionist.
That's it.
I'm not a wanted fugitive.
Give me the key.I'll do it.
Want to take a walk?
Yeah.
I know you killed your parents because they hurt you.
And I know you killed that guy yesterday because he was hurting sasha,
but what you did...was wrong.
You know that.
I just want to go.
You caN.
I want to go now.
it's okay.
Sara.
Um...about before.
Me,too.
Yeah.
www.ydy.com proudly presents
sync:gagegao xjeff0 Mina www.ydy.com