Mr Selden, what luck.
-Good luck?
-Yes...
I'm on my way to Gus Trenor's
at Bellmont...
and I've missed the three-fifteen
to Rhinebeck...
and there isn't another train
till half past five.
How nice that you come
to my rescue.
What form should my rescue take?
Oh, almost any.
Shall we go to Sherry's fortea?
I'm dying for a cup of tea, but
isn't there a quieter place?
I live near here.
-At the Benedick still?
-Yes.
On the top floor.
Is it cool up there?
Come up and see.
I'll take the risk.
Oh, how delicious to have a place
like this all to oneself.
Even women have been known to enjoy
the privileges ofa flat.
Governesses, yes, but not
poor marriageable girls.
I even knew a girl
who once lived in a flat.
Oh, if I could only do over
my aunt's drawing room...
I should be a better woman.
Is it so bad?
That shows how seldom
you come there.
Why don't you come oftener?
When I do come, it's not to look
at Mrs Peniston's furniture.
Nonsense.
You don't come at all.
Yet we get on so well when we meet.
Cream or lemon?
Lemon.
I can't make you out.
Of course there are men who
dislike me...
and others who are afraid of me.
They think I want to marry them.
But I don't think you dislike me.
And you can't possibly think I want
to marry you.
No, I absolve you from that.
Well then?
Well, perhaps that's the reason.
The reason forwhat?
The fact you don'twant to marry
me.
Perhaps I don't see that as a
strong inducement to go see you.
Dear Mr Selden...
it's stupid of you to be
disingenuous...
and it's not like you to be stupid.
I've been about too long.
People are getting tired of me.
They're saying I ought to marry.
Isn't marriage yourvocation?
What you're all brought up for?
I suppose so.
So why not take the plunge and
have it over?
You collect, do you?
First editions and things?
And do you collect Americana?
No, that's ratherout of my line.
And Americana are horribly dull,
I suppose?
I should fancy so.
Except to the historian.
And yet they do fetch such fabulous
prices, don't they?
Oh, only the very rich can afford
to buy them.
And you knowthat I'm not rich.
But life is very expensive.
Do you mind not being rich?
And having towork...
do you mind that?
Oh, the work itself is not so bad.
I'm rather fond of the law.
But do you mind enough to have
to marry to get out of it?
God forbid.
You see, there's the difference.
A girl must, and a man if he
chooses.
Perhaps you'll meet your fate
tonight at the Trenor's.
I thought you might go there.
Those big parties bore me.
As they do me.
Then why go?
You forget...
it's part of the business.
Good luck at Bellmont.
Miss Bart?
Well, of all people.
Oh, Mr Rosedale.
Howare you?
Been up town doing some shopping?
Yes.
I came up to see my dressmaker.
I didn't know there were
any dressmakers at the Benedick.
That's the name of this building?
Yes.
I own it.
The name means
"confirmed bachelor".
I'm on my way to the Trenor's.
Let me take you to the station.
No.
Thank you.
You are very kind...
but I don't want to trouble you.
MrGryce, it's you.
The seat next to me is empty.
Do take it.
I suppose you're off to Bellmont.
Yes. For a week.
A whole week?
How delicious.
How are you getting on with your
Americana?
I've got a few new things.
Your uncle had a very fine
collection, I believe.
Yes, he collected for
a number of years, but...
I must have this seat, Lily...
Mr Gryce.
How do you do?
I came this morning from
Mount Kisco in the motor car.
Had to kick my heels at
Garrison's for an hour...
without even a cigarette.
I don't suppose you have
one left, have you, Lily?
What an absurd question, Bertha.
You don't smoke?
Sincewhen did you give it up?
You don't smoke either, Mr Gryce?
How stupid of me.
It was simply inhuman of Pragg
to go off now.
When I was in Tuxedo...
I asked a lot of people down and
I mislaid the list...
And I can't remember who's coming.
This week will be a failure too.
Judy, as if anybody's ever bored
at Bellmont.
Everything's gone wrong.
And now Bertha Dorset is
furious with me.
Furious with you? Why?
Because I told her Lawrence
Selden was coming, but...
hewouldn't after all and she's
unreasonable enough...
to believe it was my fault.
I thought thatwas all over.
Oh, so it is. On his side.
I shall call him on the telephone
and tell him he simply must come.
Oh, don't.
Good gracious, Lily.
Do you dislike him so much?
Not at all. I like him.
Oh, don't say there's
any real harm in Bertha...
but she delights in making people
miserable, especially her husband.
Poor George.
But she is dangerous.
And you are not nasty.
For always getting what she
wants...
commend me to a nastywoman.
l thought you were fond of Bertha.
Oh, I am.
It's much saferto be fond of
dangerous people.
Did you know his father made a
fortune...
out of inventing a device which
excludes fresh air from hotels?
Who?
Why to be sure, Lily.
Percy Gryce.
But he's horribly shy and
easily shocked...
Why don't you say it, Judy?
I have the reputation for being
on the hunt for a husband.
Lily, I asked him here
on purpose foryou.
Percy Gryce and I are becoming
very good friends.
You're sure you wouldn't like
me to telephone Lawrence Selden?
Quite sure.
I do enjoy the quiet.
Don't you, Lily?
I wish men would always stay away.
It's much nicerwithout them.
Oh, you don't count, George.
One never talks to one's husband.
But wives never like their husbands
talking to other women.
Only if the women in question are
slightly too eligible or divorced.
Wives may do as they wish.
Husbands are expected to be like
money, influential but silent.
If divorcees were more acceptable,
I might be tempted.
Gus! Oh dear.
You see, I came after all.
Thank you for keeping me from
playing bridge tonight, Mr Gryce.
Not at all, Miss Bart.
I have no head for the game or
the rules of betting.
I have been dragged into it
in the past...
and I have lost an appalling
amount of money.
Mr Gryce, I have shocked you.
Whilst I do not approve, Miss
Bart, I do approve of you.
I hope that means you forgive me.
For I am penitent.
Will you go to church tomorrow?
Yes.
May I accompany you, Miss Bart?
Of course, MrGryce.
Good night.
Good night, Miss Bart.
Dear me, am I late?
Late forwhat?
Late forwhom?
Perhaps you had an earlier
engagement?
Yes, I had.
Perhaps I am in theway then?
Mr Selden is at your disposal.
l never interferewith
Mr Selden's engagements.
But I have no engagement
with Mr Selden.
I was to go to church...
and I'm afraid that the carriages
have left without me.
Have they left, do you know?
Yes. I heard them drive away
some time ago.
Then I shall have towalk.
It's too late to get there.
Well, I'll have the credit for
trying at any rate.
You must be quite breathless.
How fast you walk.
Thought I'd never catch up.
But I've been sitting here
for nearly an hour!
Waiting for me, I hope.
Waiting to see ifyou'd come.
Weren't you sure I would?
If I waited long enough.
But I only had a limited time
to give to the experience.
Why ''limited''?
By my other engagement.
Now I see why you were
getting up on yourAmericana.
That's why I was waiting for you.
To thank you for giving me so many
points.
You can hardly dojustice to the
subject in so short a time.
Won't you devote the afternoon to
it?
We'll take a walk and you can
thank me at your leisure.
Let us sit here.
I have broken two engagements for
you today...
both of them with Percy Gryce.
How many have you broken for me?
None.
My only engagement at Bellmont
was with you.
You really came to Bellmont
to see me?
Of course I did.
Why?
l like to seewhat
you're doing.
You're such awonderful spectacle.
Well, now you're here, you can
see the effect first-hand.
I don't think that my coming...
has deflected your course of action
at all.
Give me one. I haven't smoked in
days.
Why such unnatural abstinence?
It is not considered becoming in a
'jeune fille a marier'.
And at the present moment...
I am a 'jeune fille a marier'.
You must suppose me a
dull kind of person...
If you think I never yield
to an impulse.
But I don't suppose that.
Your genius lies in converting
impulses into intentions.
My genius?
My genius would appear to be my
ability...
to do the wrong thing
at the right time.
Or vice-versa.
Is there any final test of genius
but success?
I certainly haven't succeeded.
But you will marry
someone very rich.
What a miserable future you foresee
for me.
Haven't you seen it for yourself?
Of course.
But it seems so much darker when
you show it to me.
Why do you do this to me?
Why do you make the things that l
have chosen seem hateful to me...
if you have nothing
to give me instead?
No. I have nothing to give you.
If I had, it'd be yours,
you know that.
But you belittle me, being so sure
they're the only things I care for.
Isn't it natural for me to belittle
everything I can't offer you?
Do you want to marry me?
No, I don't.
But perhaps I should
ifyou did.
It would be a great risk.
I've never concealed how great.
You are a coward.
No.
It's you who are the coward.
Are you serious?
Why not?
i took no risk in being so.
Why is it that when we meet...
we always play this
elaborate game?
It's getting late.
Let us go down.
l thought Mr Gryce meant
to stay all week.
He did, that's the worst of it.
It shows he's running away
from you.
Bertha's done her work and
poisoned him.
What was it Bertha really
told Percy?
Don't ask me. Horrors.
All I can say is, Lily, that l
can't make you out.
He's not completely lost.
There are ways.
Whatever you do, do nothing.
Lily, you'll never do anything
if you're not serious.
Out of spirits?
I'm a little dull.
Is your last box of Doucet
dresses a failure...
ordid my wife rook you for
everything at bridge?
I have to give up Doucet
dresses and bridge.
I can't afford either any more.
And Judy thinks me a bore.
Fact is, she's angry with me.
Angrywith you? Nonsense.
Mywife's devoted to you.
She's my very best friend, and
that's why I mind vexing her.
I want to make my peace with her.
She has her heart set on my
marrying money.
Agreat deal of money.
You don't mean Percy Gryce?
Good Lord.
How could Judy think you'd
do such a thing?
Sometimes I think a man...
understands a woman's motives
betterthan herown sex does.
Good Lord. I could've
told Judy that.
Oh, by the way, Miss Lily...
I wish you'd try to persuade
Judy to be civil to Rosedale.
I did a neat stroke of business
through him lastweek.
If she'd only ask him to come
and dine now and then...
I'd get almost anything out of him.
He's going to be richer than
all of us one ofthese days.
Would you do me a favour?
A very great favour?
Why, of course.
I don't mean to bore you with all
this...
but I'm entirely dependent on my
aunt...
and though she's very kind,
she gives me no regular allowance.
I have a tiny income of my own
but it's been badly invested.
Seems to bring in less each year.
And recently I've lost money at
cards.
I've paid off my debts,
ofcourse, but...
I dare not tell my aunt.
I can no longergo on living my
present life.
And Percy Gryce?
I can't make that sort of marriage.
You gave him the sack, and that's
why he left by train this morning?
I can make you a handsome sum
without endangering your capital.
I am so ignorant about money
matters...
and I'd be so grateful to
have a good advisor.
Leave it to me.
I'll find a solution.
Really, Lily...
you're as careless and frivolous
as your poor parents were.
Why do you go to Bellmont...
if you don't rememberwhat happened
orwhom you saw there.
But therewas no one new.
Just the usual throng.
Was Mr Selden there?
Yes. He came later.
And Mr Rosedale,
was he there?
No, of course not.
Why do you ask?
Passing interest, merely.
Mr Selden tells me that socially
Mr Rosedale...
is very ubiquitous now.
I have always thought that
men like Rosedale...
and their methods of gaining
fortunes...
were at best, questionable,
at worst, criminal.
To grow richer...
at a time when most people's
investments are shrinking...
strikes me as very bad taste.
But society still uses such men,
ifonly obliquely.
If obliquity were a vice
we should all be tainted.
Only someonewithout family could
make such a vulgar remark.
Aunt Julia, you are my family.
Just as I thought.
Extraordinary that I can't teach
the parlour-maid...
to draw the blinds down evenly.
Will you see to it, Grace?
Jennings, we'll take tea
in the upstairs sitting room.
Lily, you read me the obituaries.
Aunt Julia, Grace does it
so much better than me.
She can make the most insignificant
death seem interesting.
I'll see to the blinds.
Verywell, you mayjoin us later.
It's a Mrs Haffen, Miss.
Shewon't say what she wants.
You want to see me?
Something you might like to see.
You have something belonging to me?
Not exactly.
I don't understand.
If it's not mine,
then why are you here?
When I worked at the Benedick...
I was in charge of cleaning the
gentlemen's rooms.
Most gentlemen are careful about
the letters they get.
Burn them in winter, tear them
into bits in summer.
But Mr Selden wasn't
so particular.
I know nothing ofthese letters.
I have no idea why you've
brought them here.
To sell them.
I saw you coming out of
Mr Selden's rooms.
So I guessed they were worth
more to you than me.
You promised me we'd meet...
when George was away from town.
Although you've forbidden me
to come to you, I will.
I cannot bear George near me.
If he touches me I want to scream.
His very presence is unbearable.
My darling Lawrence, you are
my consolation, my only joy.
In you I find more freedom and
support than I've ever known.
Your devoted Bertha.
What do you want for them?
One hundred and fifty.
One hundred.
I've got to live too.
I've offered you all that I'm
prepared to pay for the letters.
One hundred.
If you would forgive your enemy...
first inflict a hurt on them.
Oh, Bertha.
How could you have been so
indiscreet.
l now pronounce you man and wife.
Never seen you look more lovely.
Oh, Gus.
Lily, I've got a cheque for you.
Another dividend?
You have both Rosedale and me
to thank for it.
I've made you five thousand
on his tip...
And re-invested four
on your behalf.
With promise ofanother big rise.
Well...
I can't thank you properly now.
I don't want to be thanked. I want
you to be nice to Rosedale and me.
I'd like to see you now and then.
Come on overto Bellmont.
I'll send the motor.
You say the most absurd things.
Besides, it's impossible.
My aunt is back in town...
and I must stay with her.
You must come...
to see Mrs Peniston and l
next time you are in town.
Then you can tell me how to better
invest my small fortune.
This is luck.
I was wondering if I'd be able
to have aword with you.
I haven't recovered my self-
respect...
since you showed me how poor
my ambitions were.
On the contrary...
I thought I had been
the means of proving...
they were more important to you
than anything else.
Lily.
We thought you'd given us the slip.
Been hunting all overfor you.
I wanted to invite you to my box...
at the opera
on opening night.
Gus has promised to come
to town on purpose.
He's a tremendous admirerof yours.
I fancy he'd go a lot farther for
the pleasure of seeing you.
The Trenors are my best friends.
l think we'd all go a long way
to see one other.
How's your luck been
lately on Wall street?
I hear Gus pulled off a nice
little pile foryou last month.
I had a little money to invest...
and Mr Trenor has been helping me
in such matters.
I had a lucky turn.
Is that what you call it?
You've had a great many yourself.
Is that the latest creation of the
dressmaker at the Benedick?
If so, it's a great success.
Isn't it, MrSelden?
That's nice of you.
It'd be nicer still ifyou'd
get me a glass of lemonade.
Pleasure.
They met six weeks ago at Bertha
Dorset's...
and have been devoted ever since.
The engagement's to be
announced next week.
They say it'll be the nicest
marriage possible.
One dull fortune
marrying another.
Evie Van Osburgh and Percy Gryce?
Well, well.
Ladies and gentlemen...
Miss Lily Bart, as 'summer'
byWatteau.
She's never looked so radiant.
l like her best in that simple
dress.
Makes her look like the real Lily.
The Lily I know.
The Lilywe know.
She's herselfwith a few people
only.
She has it in her to become
whatever she's believed to be.
We must think the best of her.
I'll tell her that.
She always says you dislike her.
Well, Grace. How's life at
Richfield?
Quiet.
Aunt Peniston sees very little
company.
I'm sure your being there
gave her much pleasure.
I am as reliable
as roast mutton.
But Aunt Julia is not alone...
in preferring Lily's
erratic brilliance.
You should marry, Grace.
We should all marry,
MrSelden.
You never speak to me.
I'm never near you enough.
You think hard things of me.
l think of you...
at any rate.
Why do we never see each other?
I have my law practice and...
you're always surrounded
by admirers.
There's no admirers at my aunt's.
Well...
then, perhaps I might take
tea with you.
At Mrs Peniston's
next week?
Yes.
Come at four on Friday.
Then we can talk.
I've so much to say to you.
I need your help.
You promised me once you'd help me.
The only way I can help you...
is by loving you.
Love me.
But don't tell me so.
I'd hate to miss the train.
Selden, going too?
-Aren't you staying for supper?
-No.
When people crowd their rooms so
you can't get nearanyone...
you wish to speak to I'd sooner go.
My wife was right to stay away.
She says life is too short to spend
it breaking new people in.
Thank you.
Lily and Gus Trenor, you say?
Aunt, of course I don't mean...
Then what do you mean, Grace?
Do people say he's in love with
her?
People always say
unpleasant things.
It's a pity, though, that Lily
makes herself so conspicuous.
Conspicuous?
Does he mean to divorce
then marry her?
No, it's...
it's a flirtation.
Nothing more.
A flirtation?
With a married man?
Such things were never heard of in
my day.
Look here, Lily...
Judy and I've been in town for
weeks. When am I going to see you?
You can find me any afternoon
at my aunt's.
Come see me there and
we can have a quiet talk.
You put me offwith that at the
Van Osburgh wedding.
Truth is, now you've got what you
wanted you'd rather not see me.
Don't be foolish, Gus.
If you want to see me
you can come to my aunt's.
What else is being said?
That Gus Trenor pays her bills.
Rubbish.
Lily has herown income.
And I provide for her handsomely.
There are hergambling debts.
What do you mean?
She plays bridge.
Who told you my niece plays
cards for money?
Mrs Gryce told me that it
was Lily's gambling debts...
that frightened Percy.
In fact people are inclined to
excuse her on that account.
Excuse herforwhat?
Foraccepting the attentions of
men like Gus Trenor.
Thank you fortelling me, Grace.
But I must say, this unwelcome
information...
has ruined the Mozart for me.
Lily, let's leave before the first
act starts.
Judy's as cross as two sticks when
she's away from Bellmont.
Come to the house now.
Is Judy unwell?
A visit from you might be just
what's needed.
Very well, Gus.
I shall come with you.
Doesn't it look as if we're waiting
for the body to be brought down?
Where's Judy?
She's not up to seeing anybody.
You mean to say she's not well
enough to see me?
Devil of a headache.
Quite knocked out by it.
In that case, will you have the
goodness to call me a cab?
Why must you go?
It's late and we are alone.
I must insist.
Always the same old story.
Can't give me five minutes but
you're charming to others.
I only went to that stupid
opera to be with you.
I insist that you call me a cab.
Suppose I won't?
What then?
If you force me I shall
go upstairs to Judy.
Sit down.
I've got aword to say to you.
If you have anything to say to me
you must say it at another time.
I shall go upstairs to Judy unless
you call me a cab at once.
Go upstairs, Judy isn't there.
You mean to say that Judy
is not in this house?
She isn't even in town.
I don't believe you.
My wife's still at Bellmont.
If she were not coming to town
she would have telephoned.
She did.
I received no message.
I didn't send any.
How dare you compromise me in this
way?
Don't take that high tone with me.
I've been patient long enough.
After all...
if you pay for the dinner you're
allowed to sit at the table.
I don't know what you mean.
I didn't begin this business.
Kept out ofthe way.
But I can see fast enough when
I'm being made a fool of.
Nowyou've got what you wanted,
Gus isn't needed any more.
Well that isn't playing fair, Lily.
It's dodging the rules of the game.
And now you've got to pay.
You mean I owe you money?
You told me it was all right.
It was all right. It is all right.
You're welcome to it. All of it.
I just want to be thanked a little.
I have thanked you!
Or do you wish for payment in kind?
No!
If I owe you money, I'll pay you!
You owe me nine thousand dollars.
Nine thousand?
I will pay you.
I suppose you'll go to Selden or
Rosedale for it.
Unless you've settled those
scores already...
and I'm the only one left out
in the cold.
What more do you have to say to me?
Go home.
Come here Lily.
I wish to speak to you.
Ant Julia, it's very late
and I am very tired.
I must insist, Lily.
You're a bad colour, Lily.
This incessant rushing about is
beginning to tell on you.
I don't think it's that.
I've had otherworries.
The fact is...
I owe some money.
I...
I've been foolish.
There are bills that are pressing.
I paid your dressmaker's bill
last October.
But if you owe Madame Celeste
anotherthousand dollars...
She may send me youraccount.
It's a good deal more than that.
A good deal more?
Towhom?
Do I knowthese people?
Some by name,
others by reputation.
Then they're of no consequence.
These debts I speak of
are different.
The fact is...
I've been playing cards.
It's true then?
You play cards for money?
Do you play on Sundays?
You're hard on me, Aunt Julia.
l never really cared for cards...
and one hates to be thought
priggish and one...
drifts into doing what others do.
I've had a dreadful lesson.
If you help me out, I promise...
You needn't make any promises.
It's unnecessary.
When I offered you a home...
I didn't undertake to pay
your gambling debts.
Aunt Julia, you mean
that you won't help me?
I shall certainly not do anything
to give the impression...
that I countenance your behaviour.
Aunt Julia, I will be disgraced!
I consider that you are
disgraced, Lily.
And now I must ask you to leave me.
This scene has been
extremely painful to me...
and I have my own health
to consider.
And tell Jennings I wish to see no-
one until tomorrow afternoon.
And then only Grace Stepney.
Grace?
Yes, Aunt Julia.
Lily, it's after midnight.
What will Aunt Julia think?
I don't care.
I couldn't go to my room.
I hate it so.
Lily, what's happened?
Can't you tell me?
l thought I could
manage my own life...
But I've been so foolish, Grace.
To the point of being compromised.
Bywhom?
Mr Selden?
No, not Mr Selden.
I've been careless and imprudent
about money.
I'm frightened to think what I owe.
Grace, you know Lawrence.
If I asked him to help me...
told him why...
would he loathe me if I told
him everything?
No.
You must not do that.
He is like other men.
They have minds like moral
fly-paper.
They can forgive a woman almost
anything except losing her name.
If you wish to keep your
reputation intact, Lily...
tell him nothing.
But he must've spoken about me.
What does he really think of me?
We've never discussed you, Lily.
I have no ideawhat
Mr Selden thinks.
But I must trust in his good faith.
I'll write him and ask him to come.
Goodnight, Grace.
Goodnight, Lily.
Lawrence!
Jennings. Is my aunt downstairs?
No, Miss Bart.
Mrs Peniston left for Richfield
early this morning...
with Miss Stepney.
Thank you.
Would you see that the boy delivers
this to Mr Selden at the Benedick?
Yes, Miss.
Would you serve tea at four...
in the downstairs sitting room and
show Mr Selden in when he arrives?
Yes, Miss Bart.
Thank you.
Mr Rosedale.
Pretty well done.
Yes, very well done.
Why put up this kind of bluff?
Why aren't you straight with me?
l know there have been times
when you've been worried.
A girl like you shouldn't have
worries.
You're quite right, Mr Rosedale.
I have had worries.
I've been careless about money.
I'm offering you the chance to turn
your back on that once and for all.
I know you're not in love with me.
You're not even fond of me.
Yet.
I'm very much flattered by your
offer...
but I should be selfish and
ungrateful...
if I made my reason for accepting
your generosity financial.
Miss Bart...
I generally get what
I want in life.
I have a certain social position
and the means to maintain it.
Now all I want is the woman...
the right woman, to share both
with me.
You're fond of luxury and amusement
and to not have to settle for it.
I can provide the style...
and the means of settling.
You're mistaken on one point...
Mr Rosedale.
Whatever I enjoy...
I'm prepared to pay for.
I have spoken too plainly.
I didn't mean to give offence.
Give me time to consider your
kindness.
Goodbye, Miss Bart.
You will consider my proposal?
Of course.
Yes?
Are you alone, Lily?
Yes, quite alone, Bertha.
Everyone has gone away.
My aunt to Richfield,
everyone else to Europe.
Except Lawrence Selden, who's gone
to London.
How unsophisticated of him.
Will you join us then on a cruise
to the Mediterranean?
Well, I'm not sure I'm able to.
You'll be doing me a great service.
You're always good with George...
listening to the stories he's been
telling since the Civil War.
You're the only one with enough
fortitude to take an interest.
Nonsense.
George can be charming.
Good. You'll come then?
Yes. It'll be delightful.
Goodbye.
MrSelden.
Mrs Fisher.
Dojoin us.
What brings you to Monte Carlo?
I finished my business with a
client in London...
and decided to come down and renew
my objective interest in life.
So you're not so far removed from
being manipulated...
by the strings of society
as one might think.
Mrs Fisher, none of us are.
We're starving to death because we
can't decide where to lunch.
One gets the best things at ''The
Terrasse''...
but all the Americans go there now.
I do believe the Dorsets are back.
It's their yacht...
"The Sabrina"
Oh, yes.
I often have this strange and
vivid dream...
of an unknown woman
whom I love and who loves me...
and who, each time,
is neither exactly the same...
nor exactly different but
who loves me and understand me.
For she understands me and
my heart is transparent...
to her alone, alasl
Which ceases to be a problem...
to her alone, and the sweat
of my pale brow.
She alone knows
how to cool it with tears.
Is she brunette,
blonde or red-head?
He's reading Verlaine to her now.
In French.
What's the use of mincing matters?
We all know what Bertha brought
Lily abroad for.
The Silverton affair is
at the acute stage.
George needs to be distracted.
And I'm sure Lily distracts him.
A clever woman would know when
to play her cards right.
But she's never been clever in
that way.
I hope there hasn't been
a row.
Where the devil are they?
Bertha!
How did you find London,
Mr Selden?
More agreeable than NewYork?
In someways, yes.
Nevertheless, I came to see you.
To see me?
Or to see an older friend?
I beg you to leave the yacht.
To leave?
Why? What has happened?
Nothing. But if something should,
why be in the way of it?
How do you think I'd leave Bertha?
You have yourself to think of now.
Nothing will happen.
Of course not. I'm sure.
Have you seen Bertha?
No.
Is she not up yet?
Not up yet!
Has she gone to bed?
You know what time she came
aboard this morning?
At seven!
Seven?
Was there an accident?
There was no accident.
I waited for them all night.
Why didn't you call me
to share your vigil?
You wouldn't have liked the
denouement.
The denouement?
Isn't that too big a word for
such a small incident?
Don't!
I only want to help you.
You do so by being sweet
and patientwith me.
You can't want to see me
ridiculous.
If it hadn't been for you I'd
have ended it long ago.
I'll go to see Selden.
No!
No.
Why not?
One lawyer is as good as another.
Very well.
Go and see Mr Selden then.
You'll have time before dinner.
I ought to say good morning.
l tried to see you but
you weren't up.
No. I got to bed late.
Afterwe separated during the
fete, we thoughtwe should wait...
butwe missed you.
You missed us?
But I thought you didn't get back
to the yacht until this morning.
Who told you that?
George.
Is that his version?
Poor George.
He's had one of his attacks again.
It's very bad for him to be
worried.
Anything upsetting always brings
on an attack.
''Anything upsetting''?
Yes.
Such as having you so
conspicuously on his hands...
during the small hours.
You know, my dear, you're
rather a responsibility...
in such a scandalous place after
midnight.
Well really...
considering you burdened him with
that responsibility.
A married man should not have the
burden of being seen alone...
with a single woman.
Yes, we were alone.
Is that so dreadful?
After all, we lost you as much
as you mislaid us.
So now it is my fault...
for not having the superhuman
cleverness to find you...
in that dreadful crowd?
Or the imagination to believe...
that you wouldn't wait for us on
the quay until we met you?
No, simply by us
all keeping together!
''Keeping together''?
Lily, you are not a child
to be led by the hand.
Nor to be lectured, Bertha.
Lecture you?
Heaven forbid.
I was merely trying to give you
a friendly hint.
It's usually the other way round.
I'm expected to take hints...
not to give them.
Hints?
From me to you?
Negative ones merely.
What not to be or to do
or to see.
But if you'll let me say so...
I didn't knowone of my negative
duties...
was not to warn you when you took
your imprudence too far.
Did you see George today?
Yes.
Well...
What happened?
What will happen?
Nothing, as yet.
And nothing in the future.
You're sure?
I'm not sure, but I'm
a good deal surer.
No, thank you.
Assume everything
is as usual.
Before I go I want to
leave you the Brys.
Charming ofyou to remember me.
What you really mean is...
that you've snubbed the Brys
and you know they know it.
Carry!
If you'd have even managed to
have them invited...
onto "The Sabrina" once.
Especially when royalty was
coming.
Stay over and I'll get the
Duchess to dine with them.
I shan't stay over.
The Gormers have paid for
my salon-lit and I leave tonight.
But get her to dine with them all
the same.
I've danced all my life, you're my
husband.
They'd be much obliged.
Do you sing?
Really?
Lily, if you're offto the yacht.
Miss Bart is not returning to the
yacht.
Bertha...
Miss Bart...
there's been a misunderstanding.
Some mistake.
Miss Bart...
remains here.
And I think, George, we'd better
not detain our guests any longer.
I have some business to attend
to...
and it's easier for me to remain
ashore forthe night.
Mr Selden, you promised to see me
to my cab.
Do you know of a quiet hotel?
To go to alone? lmpossible.
Well, it's too wet to sleep
outside.
There must be someone you can go
to.
At this hour?
God, ifyou'd only listened to me.
Not now.
You must go immediately to the
Stepneys.
I can't. You mustn't ask me to.
You don't know Gwen.
Come, you must appear to have gone
there directly.
What if she refuses?
Shewon't. Trust me.
I, Julia Grace Peniston...
being of sound
mind and body...
declare this to be my last
will and testament...
hereby revoking and declaring
utterly void...
all wills and clauses of wills
here to fore made by me.
It is my will and desire that,
after my death...
all my just debts shall be
paid by my executive...
here in after named.
Second, it is my will and
desire...
Lily will get everything, of
course.
Aunt Julia was always
a just woman.
Well, it's only about four hundred
thousand.
Eight. And to my niece,
Miss Lily Bart...
l bequeath the sum of ten thousand
dollars.
Nine. And the residue
of my estate...
l bequeath to my dear niece...
Grace Julia Stepney.
Given under my hand and seal...
22nd May 1906.
My dear Grace.
I am so glad.
What sweet shall we have today?
Lily!
My dear Carry,...
you wouldn't let the head waiter
see I've nothing to live on...
but my Aunt Julia's legacy?
Think of Bertha Dorset's
satisfaction...
if she came and found us lunching
on cold mutton and tea.
I was horrid to you in Monte
Carlo, Lily.
I'm ashamed of myself...
and I've wanted to tell you so
ever since, and that's the truth.
Well, what is truth?
Where a woman is concerned it's a
story that's easiest to believe.
If I'd have got the money,
no-one would dare ignore me.
And if they did, it wouldn't
matter. I'd be independent.
Lily.
It's so unjust.
Grace Stepney must feel she has no
right to that inheritance.
Anyone who knew how to please Aunt
Julia has a right to her money.
But she was devoted to you.
Be honest, Carry.
She disapproved of my going with
the Dorsets...
and she heard of my break
with them.
After all, Bertha did
turn me off the yacht.
I must know where I stand,
Carry.
And know what's being said of me.
I don't listen.
One hears such things without
listening.
Good afternoon, Mrs Fisher.
Carry, how delightful to see you.
How delightful, Judy.
Oh, Lily.
What a pleasure to see you.
Gus!
Miss Bart.
I must see the head waiter, Judy.
Where Judy leads, the world will
follow.
Not your real friends.
Meanwhile, what do you say to
putting a few things in a trunk...
and spending the summer with
me and the Gormers?
To take me out of my ''friends'''
way you mean?
Till they realise how much they
miss you.
Besides, the Gormers have taken
a tremendous fancy to you.
I know they're not yourset, kind
of a social Coney Island.
But anyone's welcome who can make
noise and doesn't put on airs.
Yes.
I shall come.
Well, what shall it be?
Coup Jacques
orPechesa la Melba?
The more I think of my getting
you here, the better I like it.
More noise, more colour,
more slapdash sociability.
But greater good nature too.
Less rivalry.
Yes, it's true.
Soon everybody will be leaving...
for Newport and Bar Harbour
and Long Island.
And me to a hotel in
broiling NewYork.
Lily...
you must marry.
As soon as you can.
Do you mean to recommend me
to 'a good man's love'?
Neitherof my candidates answers
to that description.
Neither?
There are actually two?
Perhaps one-and-a-half.
All things being equal, I think
I'd prefer half a husband.
Who is he?
George Dorset.
Don't fly out at me till
you hear my reasons.
Since they got back from Europe
things have been going very badly.
Bertha's behaviour has strained
even George's credulity.
They're over at their place now
but the end will come soon.
The end will nevercome.
Bertha will always get him back
exactly when shewants him.
Oh, Lily.
He wouldn't stay with her ten
minutes if he knew.
"Knew"?
If he had positive proof, I mean.
Please, let's drop the subject.
It's too odious to me.
And the second candidate?
We mustn't forget him.
Sim Rosedale.
l think I'd like to go fora walk.
Miss Bart.
I've been hoping to meet you.
I'd have written if I'd dared.
I wanted to apologise.
Don't let us speak of it.
I was very sorry for you.
You must let me explain.
I was deceived.
I am more sorry for you then.
But you must see that
I am not exactly...
the person with whom this subject
can be discussed.
Why not?
It's you of all people I owe
an explanation to.
No explanation is necessary.
The situation was perfectly
clear to me.
Miss Bart, don't turn away.
You must understand...
that afterwhat happened, we
cannot be friends again.
Wasn't I punished enough?
Is there to be no respite?
I'd have thought you had complete
respite...
in the reconciliation that was
effected at my expense.
Don't put it that way.
All I ask you to understand is
that...
after the use that Bertha made of
me...
after all that her behaviour has
since implied...
it is impossible that you and l
should meet.
Please help me.
I am sorry.
There is nothing I can do.
You must have other friends...
otheradvisors.
l never had a friend like you.
Besides, you're the only one who
knows.
You were there in Monte Carlo.
You are mistaken.
I saw nothing.
l know nothing.
Just saywhat you know and the
way will be clearfor us both.
l know nothing.
You are sacrificing both of us.
Absolutely nothing.
Who's gonna catch you?
Come along.
You ought to be in bed.
Yes, mother.
Goodnight, Miss Bart.
Goodnight, Edith.
Go on.
Where are the others?
I'm your only fellow guest.
Carry was trying to be subtle.
You look tired,
I've been sleeping badly.
In fact, I came especially
to see you.
On a delicate matter.
I hope you can believe that.
Thank you, I believe what you say.
lIyou wish.
But, Miss Lily...
I suppose that is what you wish.
And though I was unable to consent
when last you spoke to me...
I am ready, now that I know you
much better...
to put my happiness in your hands.
My dear Miss Lily...
you made me feel that my suit was
so hopeless that...
I had no intention of renewing it.
I can only blame myself...
if I gave you the impression
that my decision was final.
Before we say goodbye...
I want at least to thank you for
once having thought of me.
Why do you talk of saying goodbye?
Can't we still be good friends
all the same?
What is your idea of being
"good friends"?
Seeing me without asking me
to marry you?
That's about the size of it.
I like your frankness...
I'm afraid that our friendship...
can hardly continue
on those terms.
Miss Lily, what I mean...
What you mean to say is that
I'm not as desirable a match...
as once you thought me.
Yes, that is what I do mean.
I don't believe the stories about
you...
but my not believing them
won't alter the situation.
If they are not true, doesn't that
alter the situation?
You know as well as I do, last
year you wouldn't look at me.
Now you appear willing to do so.
What's changed in the interval?
Your situation.
You thought you could do better.
You think you can?
Yes, I do.
I've done verywell.
I've placed Wall Street under
obligations...
that only 5th Avenue can repay.
But the quickest way to queer
oneself with the right people...
is to be seen with the wrong ones.
I want to avoid mistakes.
I understand.
Goodbye, Mr Rosedale.
Why don't you use her letters?
Don't ask me how I know you
bought them.
I know.
I don't suppose you bought them
just to collect autographs.
You see, I know where you stand.
You have Bertha completely
in your power.
You wish to be rehabilitated
socially...
and you have the means of your
redemption.
In a deal like this, nobody comes
out with perfectly clean hands.
If you're going to fight Bertha,
don't inflict an open injury.
Reduce it to a private
transaction.
'Give and take' you mean?
Yes.
As in business.
Or politics.
You see how simple it is?
There's no point frightening
Bertha into line.
You have to keep her there.
That's my part of the business.
That's what I'm offering you.
To reconcile with Bertha and then
you'll marry me?
What do you say, Miss Lily?
You are mistaken in both the facts
and what you infer from them.
Well, I'll be damned!
I suppose it's because the
letters are to him?
I thought we understood each
other.
We do now.
Come in.
It's such a blessing to have a
quiet few weeks here.
Thank you for inviting me here.
I do love it in Tuxedo.
Yes.
It's a pleasant house.
One of my few treasured
possessions.
How are the Brys?
Louisa Bry is a stern taskmaster.
Talk about love making
peoplejealous.
It's nothing to social ambition.
I had a visit from Mattie Gormer
the other day.
She was with Bertha Dorset
of all people.
No doubt the rabbit always thinks
it's fascinating the anaconda.
Now they're fast friends...
I think Mattie will sacrifice
anything for her.
Including me?
My dear...
the world is vile.
Lily.
Mrs Hatch, I'm not dressed!
It doesn't matter.
This is the 20th Century,
not the Dark Ages.
As soon as you've eaten,
come to my rooms.
I'm leaving in twenty minutes,
so please be quick.
I cannot find my prescription.
Do you have it?
I'm always losing them.
You usually leave them on your
bureau, Mrs Hatch.
Of course I do.
Get it filled for me today.
Without my chloral I never sleep.
I have to see my beauty doctor
or I cannot face society.
The manicure will have to wait
till tomorrow.
Not up to it today, put heroff.
Don't look sour, Lily,
she won't mind.
She never minds.
After lunch I shall go to
Sherry's for tea...
then this evening I'm playing
bridge with my lawyer.
I'll try to go for a fitting
tomorrow morning...
but only if it doesn't interfere
with the art exhibition at four.
Then supperat...
No, theatre first, then supper.
If you don't tell me in advance
of these changes, How can I...
keep your diary accurately?
Engagements are made to be broken.
Especially with tradespeople.
They expect it.
Yes, Mrs Hatch.
By the way, Lily...
on Friday I'm dining with Melville
Stancy and the Gormers.
Yes, Mrs Hatch.
Don't forget my prescription.
It's on the bureau.
Mrs Fisher was anxious to know
how you were getting on.
Why didn't she look me up
herself then?
Afraid of being importunate.
You see, no such scruples
restrained me.
Then you've come to be
of some use to me?
Yes.
So what am I to do with you?
Talk things overwith me.
What makes you think that I have
anything to talk about?
My initiative doesn't go beyond
putting myself at your disposal.
I shouldn't have come if I'd
thought I'd be of no use to you.
Do you know where you are?
Of course I know where I am!
You must let me take you away from
here.
If you've come to say disagreeable
things about Mrs Hatch...
It is precisely your relationship
with her that concerns me.
My relationshipwith Mrs Hatch...
is one that I've no reason to be
ashamed of!
She's helped me earn a living...
when my old friends were quite
content to see me starve!
Nonsense!
Starvation is not the only
alternative.
Your aunt's legacy could make you
moderately independent.
Well, what you don't know...
is that I owe every penny
of that legacy!
Good God!
Every penny...
and more besides.
I have no money except my small
income...
and I need to earn money to keep
myself alive!
I should be happier to see you out
of this particular 'employment'.
But I should not.
ljust want to point out to you...
the false position you have placed
yourself in.
I suppose by that you mean my
being on the outside of society?
But I have long been excluded
from it...
and I remember you once telling me
that it was only those on...
the inside who took the difference
seriously!
Mrs Hatch's desire to be inside...
may put you in a false position.
You cannot want this!
You have already told me that the
sole object of my upbringing...
was to teach me to getwhat
I want.
Why not assume that that's
precisely what I am doing now?
You're not a successful example...
of that kind of upbringing.
Give me a little more time.
I may still do credit to my
training!
That was undignified.
Where does dignity end and
rectitude begin?
Good day, Miss Bart.
Good day, Mr Selden.
She got five dollars and her
picture in the paper.
The hat?
No, she got that yesterday.
No, the one with the green
paradise.
Madame asked me to alter that
Virot hat.
She's tall, slight,
but her hair's all frizzed out.
A lot like Mary Leach.
Only thinner.
Miss Bart.
Look at these spangles.
Every one sewed on crooked.
I'm sorry.
I'm afraid I'm not well.
If you can't do better, I'll
give the hat to Miss Kilroy.
Go back to binding edges.
Miss Bart.
Miss Bart, I must draw your
attention...
to the fact that yourwork
is poor...
and your attendance irregular.
Miss Haines is right.
I am clumsy and slow to learn.
I have been indisposed lately.
But I'll try to improve.
It's too late for that.
I took you on as an untrained
apprentice...
as a favourto Mrs Fisher...
but against my betterjudgement.
I'm afraid that I will have to
dispense with your services.
I trust you'll find a position
more suited to your skills.
Thank you.
How are you, Grace?
Her memory is everywhere.
The whole house.
And you, Lily...
how are you?
You look dreadfully tired.
I don't sleep at night.
Since when?
I don't...
I can't remember.
There are otherworries.
Dreadful things.
What things?
Poverty.
I can't think ofanything worse.
I can't go on this way.
Do you have any idea when the
legacies will be paid?
No, Lily.
No-one has received them yet.
Not even me.
The truth is, I need the money.
Would you be willing to lend me
the amount of my legacy?
You must be patient.
Remember how beautifully patient
Aunt Julia always was.
But you'll get everything, Grace.
It would be easy foryou to borrow
ten times the amount...
that I'm asking for.
Borrow?
I am at the end of my tether.
You imagine fora moment that I'd
raise money...
on my expectations from
Aunt Julia?
If you must know the truth...
it was your being in debt...
that brought on her last illness.
You won't help me then?
If there's anything I can do...
to make you realise the folly of
your course and ...
how much she disapproved of it...
I shall feel it is the truest way
of making up to you for her loss.
Thank you, Grace.
It was good of you to see me.
Goodbye.
Can I help?
Mrs Hatch?
Yes.
You mustn't increase the dose,
Mrs Hatch.
Of course not.
Miss Lily?
What's the matter?
I'm a little tired.
It's nothing.
Stay with me a moment, please.
We can't stay here.
Let's go to The Longworth
for some tea.
Take your tea strong.
I haven't seen you in ages...
I wondered what had become of you.
I have joined the working classes.
I was trying to learn to become a
milliner.
You can't be serious.
Perfectly serious.
I understood that you were with
Mrs Hatch.
She dismissed me two months ago.
After she had got into society...
it seems my reputation had become
a social liability.
Since then I have been obliged to
work for my living.
That wasn't for you anyhow.
I must go.
No, no, rest a little longer.
What did you mean about learning
to become a milliner?
Just what I said.
I am an apprentice at Madame
Regina's.
I was an apprentice at Madame
I understood you received a legacy
from your aunt.
Ten thousand dollars.
But it isn't paid until spring and
anyway, I owe it already.
Thewhole ten thousand?
Every penny.
I think Gus Trenorspoke to you
once...
about having made me some money in
stocks.
He made me nine thousand dollars.
I knew nothing about business.
I thought he had invested my
own money.
In fact what he had made
he had given me.
It was meant in kindness...
but it wasn't the sort of
obligation I could remain under.
I was incredibly stupid.
I spent the money before
I realised.
And so my aunt's legacy must
go to pay it back.
That is why...
That is why I must now work.
That'll clean you out altogether.
Altogether.
Yes.
Miss Lily, ifyou want my
backing...
Thank you.
Yourtea has been a great backing.
I feel equal to anything now.
Surely this isn't the place?
Yes.
I room and board here.
I have lived too long
on my friends.
You can't go on living here.
I have gone over my expenses
very carefully...
and I think I can manage it.
That's notwhat I mean.
It is what I mean.
I shall be out ofwork now.
What a way for you to talk.
You in a place like this.
My situation is nothing
exceptional.
But you are.
It's an outrage.
Look, it's none of my business...
but you must accept help from
somebody.
You spoke to me ofyourdebt
to Gus Trenor...
I'll lend you the money
to pay him.
Let me finish.
It'll be purely a business
arrangement.
What can you have against that?
Only this...
that is exactly what Gus Trenor
proposed.
Once the debt is paid I shall have
no security.
I have been compromised once...
I cannot be so again.
I am very grateful foryour
kindness...
but it is impossible.
You must see that.
We must think of your future.
If you only knew what little
difference that makes now.
At least let me tell Selden
where you're living.
It will do no good.
Please.
Very well.
You may tell him if you wish.
If only you'd let me help you...
you could wipe your feet on
them.
Why don't you use the letters?
It would be so simple.
It is so simple.
Today I'll tell you about the
plight of...
the poor people of Russia under
the Tsar.
Would you please inform
Mrs Dorset...
that Miss Lily Bart wishes to
speak with her.
Mrs Dorset is not at home, Miss
Bart.
Then I'd like to speak with
Mr Dorset.
I'm sorry, Mrand Mrs Dorset left
for the country two days ago.
Shall I take a message?
No.
No message.
I can recommend the armchair.
I came to say I am sorry
for the way we parted.
Forwhat I said to you
that day at Mrs Hatch's.
I was sorry too.
You look tired.
Do sit down.
You're drenched.
Let me make you some tea.
No.
I must go in a moment.
I must go.
I may not see you again
for a long time...
I have never forgotten the things
you said to me at Bellmont...
they have helped keep me...
from becoming the person many
people thought me to be.
I'm glad.
But nothing I said really
made the difference.
The difference is in yourself.
No, don't say that.
That is all that I have
lived on.
Don't take that from me.
We resist the great temptations...
but it is the little ones that
eventually pull us down.
I remember your saying that such a
life could never satisfy me...
and I was ashamed to admit
that it could.
That's what I wanted
to thank you for.
I have tried.
I have tried hard.
But life is difficult...
and I'm a useless person.
And now I'm on the rubbish heap.
Lily...
can I help you?
You told me once that you could
help me only by loving me.
You did love me for a moment...
and it helped me.
But that moment is gone.
And I let it go.
And one must go on living.
Lily, you mustn't speak like this.
Things...
may change, but...
you'll never go out of my life.
Let us be friends.
Then I shall feel safe...
whatever happens.
What do you mean?
What's going to happen?
Nothing.
Nothing's going to happen.
But I'd like some tea now.
Goodbye, Lawrence.
The WaldorfSavingBank
West53rdstreet. New York.
Ten thousand dollars.
Ten...
thousand dollars.
CharlesAugustus Trenor
Oh, Lily!
Lily?
Miss Bart?
It's a great mercy.
May I...
may I see her...
alone?
Will it take long?
It won't.
Lily.
Oh, Lily.
I love you.