Mm.
Ugh...
You call this a smoothie?
Viscosity's way off.
It's just juice.
Okay, alright.
Good note, good note.
I'll keep that in mind.
So, look...
Denise, you got my attention.
I didn't know what
to believe before,
but I'm listening now, okay?
And I'm sure you've signed
some kind of
non-disclosure agreement.
- So let's talk about smoothies.
- Oh!
Let's say Smoothie City
was releasing
a new lactose-free smoothie,
and you knew
that it was just filled
to the tits with dairy.
Where would I look to
find evidence of said dairy?
They'd have no reason
to do that.
Dairy alternatives
are big business.
I'm talking about
Horamo, Denise.
Horamo, the migraine medication.
I need to know what's going on
there, and why you left.
Oh, I didn't leave.
I was fired.
What?
- Mm.
- You were...
Kate,
I'm trying to figure out
what to get Julian
for his birthday, and...
Wait, you didn't
say anyone was here!
I should go.
No, please, please, please.
Just give me a minute, okay?
Thirty seconds, tops.
Thirty seconds!
Thirty seconds.
Hey, buddy, what's up?
Uh, okay, so this whole
open relationship thing
isn't really working for me.
But Julian's
birthday's coming up,
and I thought that would be a
good chance to get him something
that says "Happy Birthday"
as well as
"Please only be with me."
Okay, okay, a gift.
Uh, you know what?
Don't get him anything.
Why don't you, um,
uh, play your sax?
Are you sure?
I am positive, I am positive.
You go write something from the
heart, and it's gonna go great.
Oh!
Okay, he's gone.
No more distractions.
You said you were fired?
Why?
Ram knows
that I know
that he has friends
on regulatory boards,
and that's why Horamo's
being released so quickly.
Okay, well, it's actually
being delayed, okay?
Ram is putting it
back through R&D.
He's not delaying anything!
In fact, he's moving up
the release date on Horamo.
It's going to market early?
You didn't hear it from me.
Thank you both for coming in,
taking time out of
your busy schedules.
You're welcome.
Fucking Ram.
Where are you?
Hi, yes!
Uh, happy to be here, of course.
Well, I have good news!
You've both been selected
to organize the school fun fair!
I thought you said "good news."
I can't...?
Well, everyone
says that at first,
but you have been selected
for a very good reason.
Well, what reason?
Well, all parents
are expected to contribute
in some way, and so far
you two have contributed...
in no way.
Yeah.
And we pay a lot of money
to contribute in no way.
Woo?
Yoo-hoo!
Hm?
Hi.
Sorry.
Uh, work... stuff.
Yes, well,
you also have kid stuff,
considering how
bad things have gotten
between your two children.
- Zoe and Charlie?
- What's going on?
Oh my, they hate each other!
The tension between them
can be quite distracting.
So it wouldn't hurt if you two
could set a good example
and try to work together
harmoniously.
I'm sorry, but this is
bullshit, okay?
I'm in the thick of it at work.
I don't have time
to plan a fun fair.
And I know what you're
gonna say, but...
I'll do it.
What, you will?
Why?
Because I'm a good person?
Uh-huh...
What's the catch?
No catch.
I don't treat people like shit,
and I'm not a psycho.
And besides,
you can't, and I can.
I mean, I guess you do have
a little more time
on your hands right now.
If you're referring
to my employment status,
I'll have you know
I have an interview today.
It's with a great company
and I'm a great fit,
because I'm a great person!
Yeah, you mentioned that.
Alright, well, thank you.
And good luck!
Thanks.
Oh, look at them.
They're fine.
I mean, what is
she talking about?
Well, even if they weren't,
it's definitely not Zoe.
She's an angel baby.
So, maybe check on Charlie.
Will do.
Bye.
Hey, Alice.
It's me calling, again.
I'm just calling to check in
on you, see how you're doing.
Uh, call me back, please.
Fuck!
I hear that.
Hey.
What are you doing here?
You got time?
You know what, I've given
therapy to friends before,
and it... it doesn't
really work out.
Think of this
as therapy-adjacent.
A conversation between
like-minded ragey friends.
One just happens to
be a professional.
Okay, I am also busy.
I have appointments.
Clear your schedule.
You can't bribe me, Sloane.
I don't feel like
myself at work.
myself at home.
My vagina's broken.
Different doctor for that.
Look, the point is,
I'm tasking as hard as I can.
At work, at home.
I'm tasking so hard, I'm losing
my goddamn mind, and I-I...
I need help.
Well, I...
I don't know what
"tasking" means, but, uh...
I do know about
not feeling like yourself.
The thing is, you lose yourself
the second you give birth.
Funny how nobody mentions
that little gem
prior to getting pregnant.
I mean,
don't get me wrong,
being a mother is so fulfilling
and so beautiful.
But kids will take and take
and take until they wear you out
and block your number
like you're a call centre
from a different...
Okay, I'm sorry, this doesn't
sound like my thing at all.
No, but it's your future.
And I thought you of all people
would want to know the truth.
I'm telling you,
you gotta be ready.
Because when that day comes...
And it is coming...
When your kid wants
nothing to do with you,
you gotta know
who you are without them.
Who were you before?
Who's...
old Sloane?
Pre-baby Sloane.
Get to know her again.
She's increasingly foggy.
I'm taking the day off.
You coming?
Right
this way, ladies.
Wow, the backroom!
You don't get out much, do ya?
What?
Who doesn't like a backroom?
You ready to walk a mile
in Old Sloane's shoes?
Yep, I didn't play hooky
for nothing!
Well, buckle up, bitch!
Okay.
You are moving up
the release date of Horamo?
Kate!
Kind of thing you might want
to discuss with your PR firm,
- don't ya think?
- Okay, Kate...
No, I came to you
with legitimate concerns
about Horamo, and you lied
about looking into it!
Okay, can I speak?
I'm feeling a little
attacked here.
Yeah, 'cause you're
under attack.
Who told you about the release?
I have a...
I have a source.
Was it Denise?
'Cause Denise can't be trusted.
Really, 'cause at
the moment it is you
who are not looking trustworthy.
Really?
Can I show you something?
No.
Yes.
There's your
trustworthy scientist,
caught selling
our formula for Seedless
to a foreign competitor.
No way.
She is not a criminal.
Maybe she's just, you know,
workin' late with
some colleagues.
Certainly aren't
colleagues of mine.
You know, I don't
even know that that's Denise.
No, that's her.
That is definitely her.
Look at her scratching.
She loves to scratch.
Clearly there were
some surveillance cameras
Denise did not know about.
Look, you're gonna
see she gets paid...
right there.
Shit, well, that
explains the psoriasis.
On top of that,
her work had become erratic.
She was unreliable.
So I guess you don't have
the regulatory boards
in your back pocket?
What, why would you think that?
Well, I mean, Horamo
was approved pretty quickly.
Because Horamo is ready.
Here's what R&D told me when
I took your concerns to them.
Okay.
So, pain and memory
are housed in the same part
of the brain, and Horamo
floods those pain receptors
with serotonin,
thereby reversing the effects
of a migraine,
when you have a migraine.
Now, if you take Horamo
when you don't have a migraine,
it's gonna go looking for pain,
and when it doesn't find any,
it's gonna attack
memory instead.
That's why you and your friends
experienced temporary
memory loss and elation.
We were elated...
yeah.
And this will all be noted
in the drug's documentation.
When you used to get migraines,
you said,
because of salt, right?
Oh, yeah.
Bowl of cured olives,
for instance, pssht!
It's like a mallet to my brain.
Okay, okay, so wouldn't you have
done anything at that time
to make it stop?
Well...
Okay, you don't believe me...
Believe these.
Testimonials, from the Horamo
trials, of migraine sufferers.
When people are in pain,
they just want to make it stop.
And Horamo does that
in 45 minutes, tops.
Kate, this is a miracle drug.
Think of all
the people we could help.
Mmm!
Mmm, my God,
this is so delicious.
I don't remember the last time
I took lunch for myself.
I don't remember
the last time I ate lunch
without being milked
like a prized cow.
I usually spend mine
arranging Jayme's playdates
and shoving week-old Rotisserie
chicken down my throat.
I should probably
pump after this.
Shit, I forgot to register
Jayme for gymnastics.
Fuck!
No!
No, we are not doing this.
You're right!
Rediscovering our old selves.
You wanna have some fun?
Yes!
Everything okay?
No, actually.
My deepest apologies,
Ms. Mitchell.
What seems to be the problem?
Neither of these meals
are any good.
So, why don't you take 'em back
to the kitchen and try again?
Right away.
So sorry, Ms. Mitchell.
Oh, uh...
What was wrong with them?
- Nothing.
- Really?
That guy was... he looked like
he was about to cry!
That's the whole point!
Old Sloane loved this shit!
Oh...
Yeah, I mean...
that... cool.
Yeah, it's not quite hitting
the same way that it used to.
No.
Okay, okay, apart from
terrorizing wait staff,
what made Old Sloane feel alive?
What's the craziest shit
you used to do?
You really wanna know?
Ladies!
Who's hungry?
Wait, Kate told me about this.
These aren't... are these...
Meatboys?
You're goddamn right they are.
Okay.
I'm also skilled at creating
and implementing systems.
I have experience
working with teams,
as well as leading projects.
And, as I always say, every
development team is only as good
as the donuts you bring in
for them on Monday!
Wait until the team
hears that one!
They're gonna love it.
Jenny, this has been great.
I think your positive energy
would be a valuable addition
to the team.
I get that a lot.
Well, thank you
again for coming in.
We'll be in touch!
Did I get it?
Get what?
The job.
Oh, um, well, we still have a
few more interviews to do, so...
Yeah, well, I saw
the competition out there...
I mean, yikes!
What do you mean?
You know, ugly, stupid, boring.
They look like they're gonna go
home to their lightsaber toys.
Oh, well...
They come highly recommended.
Are you gonna make me beg?
I was a manager.
I've done interviews.
You just have a gut feeling
about these things.
So, do I have the job or not?
Well, 30 seconds ago, you did.
But now... you don't.
This interview's over.
I'm gonna have to
ask you to leave.
Fine!
I'm over-qualified
for this shit job anyway.
Also, your bangs are stupid!
Ooh!
You are so tense!
Yeah, I wonder why.
Take five.
Take five?
We're not doing anything wrong.
They're getting paid,
everyone's having fun!
Yeah, you're right.
No, totally.
Yeah, we're having fun.
Isn't that the whole
point of today?
Yes!
Right.
You're right.
And besides, you ever
do shots off a six-pack?
What?
You, here.
Care to share your abs with us?
Woo!
O-okay...
Ooh!
Sorry.
It's cold.
To Old Sloane!
Alright!
Ah!
Are you having fun yet?
Aah!
Honestly...
not really.
I think I just want
to be with my kid.
Yeah, me too.
Let's get out of here.
Yeah.
No more zombies!
Look!
Oh, shit.
Is that...
Juniper?
Yup.
She and Forrest couldn't
decide who'd be the face
of their next prototype.
Guess she won the coin toss.
It was somehow less horrifying
when it was a zombie.
I dunno...
I think she's kinda cute!
Is there... is there
anything else, Rose, or...?
No.
Yes.
I was hoping to take
some vacation days.
You already maxed out
your vacation days for the year.
What are you talking about?
You took two weeks off
because your cat was depressed.
- Those were sick days!
- You were in Mexico!
And I got sick there.
People don't tell you
not to drink the water!
Literally the first thing
people say about Mexico is
"Do not drink the water."
Well, a bunch of my girlies
are going to Vegas
for Christina Miller's
bachelorette, #It'sMillerTime.
And I haven't technically
taken a vacation since...
You can go, okay?
But it will be unpaid, because
again, you've maxed out!
Well, what's even
the point of being partner?
This blows!
Sorry, Rose.
I don't know what to tell ya.
Well, don't apologize to me!
Why don't I call
Christina Miller right now
and you can explain to her
why her maid of honour
can't be there for her
last weekend as a free woman!
- Got a minute, boss?
- No.
It's just that my friend
Christina Miller's
- getting married...
- Do not start.
You still poring over
those Horamo testimonials?
How are you still on the fence?
I just... I want to be sure,
you know?
This is our reputation
on the line.
Not sure if you noticed,
but it says "Kate Foster PR"
on the door.
Imagine it said "Mo Daniels PR."
Oh, I do.
Every day.
Okay, well,
then you get it, right?
If they go down, we go down.
I dunno, I thought
reading these people's stories
would help, but...
I don't know what to believe.
Yeah, the way I see it,
when you're looking for
problems, you'll find problems.
Why don't you start
looking for a solution?
Very helpful.
Poetic, even.
You've got hundreds of
first-hand accounts here.
What else do you need
to convince yourself
that this pill needs
to be on the shelves?
What?
It's my cheat day.
Man, you're gonna be bloated
after all that salt.
Oh, no.
Oh...
There she is!
Okay...
Where are the pills?
Here we...
Yeah!
Oh...
You look like you could
use some baby love.
There you go, little man.
Go to your mama.
Mmm...
Well, it's gettin' late.
I'm gonna head out.
Oh yeah,
I made you a bouillabaisse.
It's a little cold right now.
I wasn't sure what time
you'd be home at,
but 90 seconds in
the microwave should do it.
No one has ever
taken care of me like this.
Well, that makes me sad
because you deserve it.
Move in with us.
Are you sure?
You deserve
to be taken care of too.
Oh, you reek of champagne.
Hi, Alice.
Uh, I guess you've
blocked my number.
Anyway, um,
I just called to say...
I hope you have a good sleep.
Goodnight.
What happened to you?
You're back?
I just... missed my bed.
So, thanks
for coming over, um...
Yeah.
I know it's
kind of like a weird time.
Thanks for inviting me.
Augh...
Yeah, um,
and actually,
the reason I asked you
to come over was, uh,
because I have something special
planned for your birthday.
Oh, fuck.
And I thought
I could give it to you now,
uh, since we're alone.
I told you not to do anything.
Yeah, yeah.
Sit.
I call this piece, "Monogamy."
Oh God, no...
Julian...
I want to spend
every second with you.
I want to watch you
wake up every morning.
I want to share everything.
Like, I'd use your toothbrush
and carry your garbage
in my pocket.
What?
Because it feels
like we're one person.
Your garbage is my garbage.
Your skin is my skin.
Let's be buried together
in the same casket
and be this close forever!
Okay, NJ, just stop!
Please!
I'm just speaking
from the heart!
Well, it's weird!
Look...
I'm... I'm just gonna say it.
I love you.
And I know you want to be
in an open relationship,
but I think I can be enough
if you just let me try.
No, just stop, okay?
I-I thought
you were cool with this!
You can't just trick me into
monogamy with your saxophone.
This...
isn't working.
Oh... fuck...
It worked.
It actually worked.
It's all gone!
It's all fuckin' gone!
Hello?!
What the hell?
I can't do this.
No, no, wait, Julian, please!
Hold on!
Julian, please, don't go!
Just wait for...
Unbelievable.
What is wrong with you?
Huh?
I did exactly what
you said to, and guess what?
It backfired!
Oh, hey, I'm... Look, I'm sorry.
I'm... I'm so sorry, I just...
Thanks a lot!