Eat up!
One day you'll never
see me again.
That's right, Charlie.
The farm life
may be it for you,
but it sure ain't
for me.
I'm special.
Mama's gonna feel real stupid
when she finds out, won't she?
One day, the whole world's
gonna know my name.
You agree,
don't you, Mary?
Oh. Why, thank you.
I do love
a good audience.
Y'all see me
for who I really am.
A star.
What are you doing in here,
Mr. Goose?
Theda!
Go on, girl.
Take it.
You aren't to
indulge in any more
such foolishness.
It's just dancing, Mama.
It's selfish
is what it is.
With all the farmhands gone,
I can't do everything
around here myself.
I help.
Anything for me
in the post today?
No.
It says the Allies
have taken control of France.
You can read it
after supper.
But, Mama,
this could mean
the end of the war!
Do as I ask, Pearl.
I don't want to hear
about any more
dead Germans tonight.
Supper's ready, Daddy.
Bless us, O' Lord,
and these thy gifts
which we are about
to receive
from thy bounty
through Christ
our Lord. Amen.
Amen.
"My precious Pearl.
"It feels as if
it has been
an eternity without you.
"All we do is walk,
it seems.
"I never know
if we'll get to where
they say we're going.
"They have us chew
on bouillon cubes
"so we don't notice
the pains in our feet.
"I find it most frightening
at night in the trenches.
"The mortar shells
are deafening.
"Many soldiers
have gone mad
with the fear.
"Carnage from the gas
"has shown me things
I won't soon forget,
"and thinking of you
has been my only reprieve.
"I will always be proud
to serve my country,
"but one thing
this war has made clear
"is that I cannot wait
to return home
"and begin our life together.
"I never want to be away
from you again.
"Till death do us part.
"Your loving husband,
Howard."
I'll go to town tomorrow.
Pick up more medicine.
Which means
I get to stop
by the pictures.
Just don't tell Mama.
They show
all the best dancers
at the pictures.
I could be on the line
with those girls one day.
I know I could.
Pearl.
I didn't want to waste
the hot water.
The money for his medicine
is on the kitchen table.
Remember
to cover your face.
And don't linger close
to anyone.
Papers are warning
of a lethal resurgence.
God forbid sickness
returns to our home.
The time is now...
Two-bits, please.
♪ Poor Johnny's heart
♪ Went pitty, pitty pat
♪ Somewhere in sunny France
♪ He met a girl by chance
♪ With ze naughty,
naughty glance
♪ She looked just like
a kitty, kitty cat
♪ She loved to dance and play
♪ Tho' he learned no French
when he left the trench
♪ He knew well enough to say
♪ Oui, oui, Marie
♪ Will you do zis for me?
♪ Oui, oui, Marie... ♪
Did you enjoy the picture?
Cigarette?
Oh, go on.
I don't have the bug.
You like the movies?
I like dancing.
Oh, a future Tiller Girl.
I can see it now.
I wish.
Why not?
You're pretty enough.
On account of a husband,
I gather?
He's overseas,
but my father's infirmed,
so I have to help at home.
I'm sorry to hear that.
You want to come
watch the second show?
Free admission.
I'm the projectionist.
I need to get going.
Mama's expecting me,
but I appreciate the, um...
Stay there for just
one minute, would you?
Okay.
From what you just saw.
Aren't you showing it again?
Ah... Sure,
but it's only one frame.
Nobody will notice once
I splice it back together.
You know,
caring for your family
during these times
is admirable.
You ought to
take pride in that,
but don't forget to live
your life, too.
I wouldn't mind seeing you
up on that screen
one day, missus...
Pearl.
Well, if you come back,
knock on this door.
I'm always here, and,
well, I can run the pictures
as much as I like.
Thank you.
I will.
May I have this dance?
I'm married!
Shh...
What took you so long?
It's a far ride, Mama.
What is on your head?
Found it along the road.
Do not bring it inside.
It may be covered
in germs.
Wash your hair.
If you're lucky,
it's only full of lice.
When you finish,
your father needs changing.
Don't let him
sit in his mess.
I saw
a new picture today.
You'd have liked it.
The girls were all flawless.
There's no room
for even the tiniest
lack of precision
in a troupe like that.
It takes absolute perfection.
What a charmed life
it must be
to star in the movies.
Are you still in there?
Bless us, O' Lord,
and these thy gifts
which we are about to
receive from thy bounty
through Christ
our Lord. Amen.
Amen.
Where is
the rest of the money
I lent you?
-There was none.
-I can count, Pearl.
There are eight cents missing.
I may have gotten some
hard candy for the trip home.
That is enough, then.
You ate the candy,
that was your supper.
The food I worked hard
to prepare alone is not.
But, Mama,
I rode all that way.
I'm starving.
You may have
what's left of it
in the morning.
-Where are you going?
-To bed!
I did not excuse you
from the table.
I know that.
And I am careful.
Good.
Please, Lord,
make me the biggest star
the world has ever known
so that I may get far,
far away from this place.
Amen.
Afternoon, Pearl!
Hi, Mitsy!
I like your dress.
Oh, thank you.
It feels wonderful
to finally be able to
don something pretty again.
It's the first time
we've left home in weeks.
Mother is so afraid
of getting ill.
Mama, too.
Well,
we were a bit worried
about the both of you
being out here all alone,
so we brought some food.
That's very kind.
How have you
been getting on?
Any new letters
from Howard?
- Uh-uh.
- Oh, well...
Mother has been
riddled with worry.
They say no news
is good news, though.
If only his pride
hadn't gotten him
involved in this dreadful war.
You know we had a doctor
willing to declare him
ineligible?
Anyone would've taken
that opportunity.
Not Howard.
First, he runs off
to become a farmer.
Now, the army.
The lengths
my brother will go to
just to spite his father.
All this isolation
has been enough
to make one mad, hasn't it?
It really has.
No, we don't accept charity.
Oh, for God's sake, Ruth.
It's just a pig.
Can I share
a secret with you, Pearl?
Mother would throttle me
if she knew I was
planning on attending.
But there's a dance audition
this Saturday at our church
for a Christmas chorus line
to bring merriment to folks
throughout the state
during the holidays.
Word is, they're putting
together a troupe
and will be touring
seven different cities
before the year ends.
Don't that sound exciting?
I would love so much
to be a part of it.
So would I.
We should
go together then.
But you can't tell a soul.
I would never.
Splendid.
It'll be our secret.
Mitsy!
I better skedaddle.
We got three more pigs
to drop off this afternoon.
Saturday at 11:00.
Okay.
Sister-in-laws have to
stick together, right?
Mitsy!
-Time to go!
-See you later, Pearl.
Bye, Mitsy!
Charlie, this could be it.
Pearl?
Pearl!
Well,
I didn't expect to see you
again this soon.
Have a seat.
I can't believe
you get to see
the pictures every day
for free.
Yeah, not a bad gig, huh?
Thank you.
So, to what do I owe
this pleasure?
I've been thinking
a lot about
what you said to me
the other day
about not forgetting
to live my life,
and, well,
there's a dance audition
coming up at the church.
Oh, I like
the sound of that.
So do I...
But I've never really danced
in front of anyone before.
What if I'm not perfect?
You can do anything
if you want it bad enough.
I want it.
Then don't let anything
stand in your way.
What would you like to see?
Palace Follies.
Oh, come on.
You saw that already.
How about something
different tonight?
How about...
How about a film
nobody else has seen?
Okay.
I picked this one up while
I was in the service
in France.
Do you live in here?
I lay my head on that pillow
from time to time,
but I wouldn't say I live
anywhere in particular.
I'm what more civilized people
refer to as bohemian.
I don't know what that is.
It means I can pack up
and leave whenever I want to.
Sounds like a dream.
Just as long as I can
keep from waking up.
What is this?
Just watch.
Never seen anything
like that before
now, have you?
There are all kinds of
underground stag films
like this out there.
Is it legal?
Doing it, yeah.
Filming it, no.
Not here, anyway.
It will be eventually.
People would pay an arm
and a leg to see this.
Pictures like this are going
to revolutionize the industry
and I, for one, plan on
capitalizing early.
It's reality.
There's no denying
we all share a fascination
in seeing people
as they truly are.
I don't like reality.
Where I live,
I mean.
So leave.
It's not that easy.
Well, sure it is.
There's a road
right out front there
that'll take you
all the way
to New York City.
One day my mother and father
will be gone.
I can do what I want then.
What if that's too late?
The fact and truth
of the matter is, Pearl,
you only get
one take at this life.
And if you don't
make the most of it
when you're young,
you don't get
a second chance.
If only they would just die.
Pardon?
Nothing.
It's real nice to be able to
talk to someone for a change.
Been cooped up
on that farm for so long
sometimes I worry
that maybe
I'm not the same
as other people.
Why would you ever
want to be
like everybody else?
I don't know.
Sometimes it just seems
more peaceful, I guess.
Did you mean
what you said?
About wanting to see me
up on that screen?
Sure, I did.
I'd do anything
to be up there.
Well, then,
you ought to go overseas
when this pandemic ends.
That's what I'm doing.
The arts are so much more
alive in Europe.
You can be whoever
you want to be there.
Really?
You could even be
in pictures like this.
I know I'd watch you.
I should go now.
Thank you.
What for?
For seeing me tonight.
What are you
staring at?
Theda!
I'm leaving soon.
I can't stay here
any longer.
Howard was supposed
to take me away.
It'd be easier for me
if I didn't feel like
I was abandoning you.
You understand that?
I love you, Daddy,
but this is
no way to live.
Pearl?
What are you doing?
Talking with Daddy.
We need to get him
back to the house.
Why do you hate me, Mama?
I only want what's best.
When do I get what I want?
One day you'll understand
that getting what you want
isn't what's important.
Making the most
of what you have is.
Life rarely turns out
how you expect.
You need to be
prepared for that
if you ever want
to be happy.
Come back inside.
Where are you?
Stop staring at me.
How'd you find that?
I am not blind to
what goes on around here.
Take your dinner.
Stay in the bunkhouse.
But it's freezing
out there!
You should've thought of that
before putting me at risk.
Isolate yourself
until we know
you're not ill.
That is what's right.
There's a dance audition
in town tomorrow.
I'm going to it.
No, you're not.
-Yes, I am.
-Why?
Find out
if I'm good enough.
Good enough
for what, Pearl?
Something more than this.
Where does all this
ungratefulness stem from?
How is it you find our life
so beneath you?
You've always had
a roof over your head,
food in your belly.
Do you not think that came
at great sacrifice
from your father and I?
Or do you think we are
beneath you, too?
If I'm meant to live out
the rest of my days
with you and Daddy
on this farm,
then so be it.
But I'm only young once.
If I go to this audition
and I don't get picked,
then I'll come home
and I'll never speak
of it again, I swear.
But I have to know
that I tried
or I'm gonna regret it
for the rest of my life.
Please, Mama.
You have no idea
what I'm capable of.
Oh, yes, I do.
I've seen the things
you've done in private,
when you believe
no one is watching.
You think others
won't notice?
You can't keep
your true self
hidden forever, Pearl.
They will notice eventually,
and they will be frightened,
just as I am.
-You're wrong.
-Am I?
Then what a fine woman
you hope to become,
leaving your mother alone
to rot
so you can dance with
a bunch of city whores.
Let alone the illness you may
contract and spread.
You've seen what it does
to your father.
That's what you want
for yourself and others?
And maybe that is what
you wish for me.
-Of course not.
-Stop lying!
I can't stand
the sound of it anymore!
It's almost as abhorrent
as your sinful behavior!
You are not well, Pearl!
It's only a matter of time
before you hurt
someone else.
Malevolence is festering
in you, I see it.
And I will not,
in good conscious,
let you leave
this farm again.
You can't stop me.
Oh, yes, I can.
You don't want to know
what I could do to you.
I shoulder a burden
you will never understand,
spend my days feeding
and wiping the snot
off the face of the man
I married.
You dare sit there
and talk to me
about regret?
I was supposed
to be his wife,
not his mother!
Don't you ever speak
that way to me again!
Do you hear me?
-I'm sorry.
-No! You're not!
Or you would stop
all this!
Here! Take it!
That's what
you really desire,
isn't it?
Perhaps I should
kill him for you?
That way you don't have to
care for him any longer.
Would that suit
your selfish dreams better?
Then we can both
go to the dance audition!
Your husband is gone.
So is mine.
Why should we be saddled
with caring for them
or the work of this farm?
What about us
getting what we want?
I won't suffer for you
any longer.
You want to leave? Go.
But when you fail...
And you will fail...
I want you to remember
what it feels like
because that's how I feel
every time I look at you.
Nearly everything
I ever had has been
taken from me, Pearl.
What more do you want?
I just don't want to end up
like you, is all.
I hate you!
You harlot!
I won't let you flaunt
your arrogance in my face!
-You are not better than me!
-Yes, I am!
I'm going to be a star!
The whole world
is going to know my name!
Where are you going?
It's not even
6:00 a.m. yet.
I have to
practice my routine.
I need to be perfect
for my audition today.
You still think
I'm pretty enough?
Oh, not much has changed
in the last 24 hours.
Yes, it has.
Oh. You forgot this
last time.
I'm glad you came back.
So am I.
Let me at least
drive you home.
Somebody you know?
I'm not really sure.
Well...
It's hard to know
who anyone is nowadays
with all these masks
people are wearing.
Wait here a minute.
Daddy,
I'm so sorry.
I'm going to get you
cleaned up real soon, okay?
I just have
a guest right now.
Shh!
Ah. Ah.
Okay, come in!
This is my father.
Pleased to meet you, sir.
Want to go up
to my bedroom now?
I want off this farm forever.
I don't know.
It doesn't seem so bad.
It is.
What was that?
Nothing.
Tell me more about Europe.
When can we go?
Don't you think
you should go check?
No.
All right.
I'm sorry.
Whatever that is,
we can't just ignore it.
It could be your father,
for Christ's sake.
It's not my father.
Please don't go.
What's the matter with you?
Nothing.
It's our dog.
She made a mess
in the kitchen
while I was away,
so I put her
in the root cellar.
I want to
show you something.
That's Charlie!
She's always hungry.
We can't afford to feed her
like we used to.
And over here,
this is Mary.
Ain't she a dish?
Mmm.
This is Francis.
They're my best audience.
I named each of them after
my favorite picture stars.
I've put on so many shows
for them over the years.
It'll be sad to say goodbye,
but like they say,
"If you're not moving forward
in show business,
"you're moving backwards."
We used to have
many more animals,
but they all died.
What about your dog?
Huh?
-What's its name?
-We don't have a dog.
I thought you said
you, uh, did?
In the cellar?
Oh.
Right. Yeah.
Yeah, well, um...
Oh, boy.
Oh, I better be getting back,
you know?
-What?
-Oh, I've got to go
and screen the matinee,
you know,
but you gotta practice,
remember?
You gotta get those
dance moves perfect.
Now's not the time to be
resting on your laurels,
is it?
Nice seeing you,
Pearl.
Did I do something wrong?
No.
Then why did you
just go cold on me?
I don't know what you mean.
What did you see?
I didn't see anything.
You're lying.
-No, I'm not.
-Yes, you are.
I know because
I feel things
very deeply.
Look, I've got to get back
to work, all right?
-I'll... I'll see you later.
-When?
-What?
-When will I see you?
I don't know, Pearl.
It's just an expression.
You're not going to
take me to Europe,
are you?
Tell me the truth.
What did I do wrong?
- Nothing. Calm down.
- No!
Why are you leaving me
if I didn't do
anything wrong?
I don't understand!
I thought you liked me!
-I do like you. I just...
-Tell me the truth!
Why are you leaving me?
What did you see?
Why did you change?
You're scaring me, Pearl.
Okay?
I wish you the best of luck
with your audition.
Sincerely.
You're not
gonna leave me here!
I'm not staying
on this farm!
Nothing's going to
keep me here!
You hear me?
Nothing!
Not you! Not Howard!
Not Mama! Nobody!
No. No.
I want you to remember
what it feels like.
'Cause that's how I felt
every time you looked at me.
Okay, Daddy.
Let's get you cleaned up.
I wish you wouldn't
look at me like that.
What do you think?
Thank you for everything.
I know you'll look down
on me proudly.
You are loved.
Au revoir, poor Johnny!
Oh, thank goodness
you came.
I was beginning to think
you weren't going to show.
Sorry.
I had some chores to do
around the house.
Well, I've been
in such a flap
all by myself.
I feel worse
than I imagine I would
had I contracted
that awful flu.
What's in
the suitcases?
All my things I need
for going on the road.
Wow.
You're confident.
Rumor has it they may only be
taking one gal per town.
It has to be me.
I don't think you meant
to say that out loud, Pearl.
Well, if it's not me,
then I hope it's you,
right?
It has to be me.
Next.
That's Dorothy Collins.
Can't say I'm too
saddened for her.
Some people just think
they're God's gift,
you know?
But they always get what's
coming to them eventually.
I feel bad saying that,
actually.
She's a nurse.
I don't know how to do
something like that.
Oh, Pearl.
I'm so nervous.
What if they laugh me
right off stage?
I don't think
I could handle that.
How are you not scared?
I guess I'm just
more used
to the feeling.
Next.
Oh, Lord.
Switch places with me.
I don't think I can do this.
I'm too frightened.
-What?
-Come on, Pearl.
Switch before they open
the doors again.
Come on. Move.
Thank you.
You're a good friend.
Am I?
Of course you are.
Sister-in-laws have to
stick together, right?
Next.
Your turn, Pearl.
Time to show them
what you can do.
I'm gonna show them all.
Break a leg.
Ready, miss?
Thank you.
But it's gonna be a no.
Pardon?
Sorry, you're just not
what we had in mind.
Well, that was the best
dancing I've ever done.
Yes, it was very nice.
But we already have
plenty of gals like you
in the troupe.
We're looking for
something different today.
You know?
More all-American,
younger and blonde.
Someone with X factor.
What?
Next!
Come on.
-Come on.
-No.
I'm afraid so.
Come on, miss.
Time to go.
Please.
You don't understand.
I need this.
Next in line, please.
I can make it better.
Come on now, darling.
You don't want to make a scene
and spoil everything.
Please! Just give me
one more chance.
-Come on, now.
-No.
I'm a... I'm a star.
Come on.
Come on, miss.
I'm sorry.
-It's time to go.
-No, I'm a star!
Come on.
Please! I'm a star!
I'm sorry. It's time to go.
Please,
somebody help me!
Please! Help me!
Help me!
No!
Pearl?
How about
I take you home?
Is that our pig?
Should I go
and fetch your mother?
No.
How about I get you
something nice to drink?
Mama was right.
I'm never getting off
this farm.
And where would you
want to go?
-Europe.
-Europe?
What on earth for?
It'll be in ruins
and you'll never get Howard
back there, I'll tell you.
Oh, come on, now.
I know you're disappointed,
but there's no sense
in taking it this hard.
It's just a lousy
old church group.
Those old dolts,
they don't know the first
thing about quality dancing.
You don't understand.
What don't I?
Come on, Pearl.
What's really the matter?
I don't feel
well.
You're not coming down
with something,
are you?
No.
It's nothing like that.
Oh, thank goodness.
If I snuck out of the house
and ended up bringing home
nothing but the germ,
my mother and father
would just kill me.
I'm worried there
may be something
real wrong with me, Mitsy.
How do you mean?
Seems like there's
something missing in me
that the rest
of the world has.
Have you told Howard?
I've never spoken about it
out loud to anyone.
So afraid of
what people might think.
Pearl...
Howard's your husband.
He adores you.
You shouldn't be afraid
to tell him how you feel.
I'm scared of
what I might say.
Well, practice
on me first, then.
Pretend I'm Howard,
and you just say
whatever's on your mind.
-I can't.
-Yes, you can.
Go on. Get it all out.
-Really?
-Yes.
Trust me.
Howard...
Go ahead, Pearl.
I hate you so much
for leaving me here,
sometimes I hope you die.
I'm sorry.
I feel awful admitting that,
but it's the truth.
I was curious
about other men.
I'm sure you don't
want to hear about
a stranger satisfying
your wife,
and I swear it was only once.
It was a mistake.
It wasn't him
that I wanted.
I know that now.
And I wish things
could just go back
to the way
they were before,
but I don't see
how they could,
not after the things
I've done.
What else
have you done, Pearl?
Oh, Howard.
I realize
how this all must sound.
Honestly, there was a time
I was flattered
to have someone
as handsome as you
pine over me.
You're such a good person.
I know that.
I made sure to always be
mindful with your heart.
I never wanted you
to feel jealous.
It's an awful feeling
like a rot,
the way it just twists
and turns at your insides.
I know that aching so well.
I feel it.
Whenever I see others
whose lives come easy
because the truth is,
I'm not really a good person.
Pearl, I think
I should just...
The reason I kept my eyes to
the ground around other men
was never to avoid
hurting you.
It's because I understood
how lucky I was
to have your attention.
I may be
a poor farm girl, Howard,
but I'm not stupid.
I spotted you the moment
you came to live with us.
You worked hard
like the other farmhands,
but you were different.
You're from somewhere.
A nice, comfortable place
that you could return to
whenever you wanted.
I'm so desperate
to have that.
All my life,
I've wanted off this farm
and you were my ticket out.
So...
I made sure to never let you
see who I really was.
It worked like a charm, too.
Then when you finally
brought me back
to your home
to meet your family,
it was just as I hoped.
A life straight
out of the pictures.
At least that's what
it felt like to me.
And you didn't want it.
You just wanted
to stay here on our farm,
and that made me so angry.
How could you?
I'm certain you knew
I hated it, you must've.
How could you be
so selfish and cruel
after all I've done
to make you happy?
I was even pregnant
with your baby.
I never wanted
to be a mother.
I loathed the feeling of it
growing inside me.
It felt like sickness.
Pulling and sucking on me like
some needy animal in a barn.
How could I be responsible
for another life?
Life terrifies me.
It's harsh, and bleak,
and draining.
I was so relieved
when it died.
It was one less weight
keeping me trapped here,
but then the war came
and you left me, too.
Why did you leave me, Howard?
I hate feeling like this.
So pathetic.
Do people like you
ever feel this way?
I figure you don't.
You seem so perfect
all the time.
Lord must've been
generous to you.
He never answers
any of my prayers.
I don't know why.
What did I do?
What is wrong with me?
Please, just tell me
so maybe I can get better.
I don't want to end up
like Mama.
I want to be dancing up
on the screen
like the pretty gals
in the pictures.
I want what they have
so badly,
to be perfect,
to be loved from
as many people as possible
to make up for all my time
spent suffering.
Sometimes I wake
in the middle of the night
and the fear washes over me,
'cause what if this is it?
What if this is
right where I belong?
I'm a failure.
I'm not pretty
or naturally pleasant,
or friendly.
I'm not smart,
or funny, or confident.
I'm exactly what Mama said
I was, weak.
I don't know why.
What did I do?
Why wasn't my family
like yours?
I hate what it feels like
to be me and not you.
I'm so scared that
when you finally come home,
you'll see me
and be frightened
like everyone else is.
I know what I've done,
the bad things,
terrible, awful,
murderous things.
I regret them now,
but I liked how they felt.
I wish I didn't, but I did.
At first, it was only animals
smaller than myself.
Nothing with feelings.
Nothing that could
hurt me back.
It felt good.
Killing's easier
than you think,
till recently with Mama
and the boy
from the picture house.
They were different.
They were more meaningful.
I hurt them
so they too might know
what it feels like to suffer,
but poor Daddy
didn't deserve that.
I wish I hadn't done
what I did.
Mama meant well.
She had a hard life.
She only wanted a home
to feel safe in.
I can see that.
I thought I hated her,
but I just want to
feel safe, too.
Lord...
I made
such a mess of things.
I don't know how much more
I can take.
I need to clean this up.
All of it.
I need to make things right
before you see me again.
Maybe if I can turn this farm
into a home for us
like you wanted,
things will finally
be different.
I can forgive.
I can be
who you want me to be
if you'll just stay with me.
Would you do that, please?
I can't be
all by myself anymore.
It's too hard.
We can love each other.
I'll do that for you
if you really meant all that
"till death do us part."
It'd be enough,
just you and me
here on this farm.
All I really want
is to be loved.
I'm having such a hard time
without it lately.
I should probably
get going now.
Mother will be
wondering where I am
if I'm not home soon.
Are you
frightened of me?
No.
Of course not, Pearl.
Do you think I'm sick?
No.
Thank you.
I'm happy for you.
What?
For getting the part
in the dance troupe.
You deserved it.
-I didn't get the part.
-It's okay.
You don't have to
pretend anymore.
My feelings won't be hurt.
If it wasn't me, I'm glad
it was you, right?
-But, Pearl, I...
-Please...
Don't lie to me.
Well, yes.
Thank you.
It's going to be
real swell,
dancing around the state.
I hope you can come
see the show sometime.
You always get
everything you want.
You're younger
and more blonde.
I have to go now.
You're not gonna
say anything, are you?
No.
I really do love Howard.
I know.
Nobody has to know.
I can fix things.
It can be
our secret, Mitsy.
Help!
Help me!
Somebody, please help!
No!
No, please.
Help! Help!
Help!
Help me, please!
Please, no! No!
I won't tell anyone!
Please, I swear!
No!
Please! I'll do anything
you want.
It's not about
what I want anymore, Mitsy.
Please.
It's about making the best
of what I have.
No! No!
No!
Bless us, O' Lord,
and these thy gifts
which we are about to receive
from thy bounty,
through Christ our Lord.
Amen.
So long, y'all.
Pearl?
Howard?
I'm so happy you're home.