MAI CHI?
SHE IS HERE?
WHAT SPIRIT
CALLS MY NAME?
SPIRIT?
I AM HERE BEFORE YOU
IN LIFE.
DECEITFUL GHOST.
WHY "GHOST?"
IF YOU WERE REAL,
I COULD SEE YOU.
MAI CHI...
IT IS SAID YOU HAVE
THE GIFT OF PROPHESY.
WHO WERE YOU
IN LIFE, POOR GHOST?
I AM KWAI CHANG CAINE.
I SERVE ONLY
THOSE WHO PURSUE
ILLUSIONS.
IT IS SUCH A QUESTION THAT
MAKES ME SEEK YOU OUT...
FOR I, TOO, MAY BE
PURSUING AN ILLUSION.
TELL ME.
TWO YEARS AND LONGER,
SINCE I CAME TO AMERICA,
I HAVE SOUGHT THE MAN
WHO IS MY BROTHER.
I REMAIN IN DOUBT
IF HE IS ALIVE...
OR IF HE WAS EVER ALIVE.
DO YOU HAVE HANDS, GHOST
OF KWAI CHANG CAINE?
THE MAN YOU CALL
BROTHER--
THE MAN NAMED
DANNY CAINE--
IS WAITING FOR YOU
AT THE END OF
THIS JOURNEY.
BUT IT WOULD BE
BETTER FOR HIM
AND FOR YOU
IF YOU WOULD NOT
FIND HIM.
WHY?
OTHERS SEEK HIM
AS YOU DO, AND
WILL FIND HIM...
AND DEATH WILL BE
CLOSE BEHIND.
CAN YOU TELL ME
NOTHING MORE?
HOW CAN I ANSWER,
GHOST,
WHEN I NEITHER SEE
NOR HEAR YOU?
WAIT.
BEWARE, SHAOLIN.
YOU, TOO, ARE NOT
ABOVE ILLUSION.
Master Kan:
YOUR TREAD MUST BE
LIGHT AND SHORT,
AS THOUGH YOUR PATH
WERE UPON RICE PAPER.
IT IS SAID
A SHAOLIN PRIEST CAN
WALK THROUGH WALLS.
LOOKED FOR,
HE CANNOT BE SEEN.
LISTENED FOR,
HE CANNOT BE HEARD.
TOUCHED,
HE CANNOT BE FELT.
THIS RICE PAPER
IS THE TEST.
FRAGILE AS THE WINGS
OF THE DRAGONFLY.
CLINGING AS THE COCOON
OF THE SILKWORM.
WHEN YOU CAN
WALK ITS LENGTH
AND LEAVE NO TRACE,
YOU WILL HAVE LEARNED.
WELL?
I ASKED HIM
FOR DIRECTIONS.
GOT A REAL
GOOD LOOK AT HIM.
YOU WERE RIGHT.
THAT'S HIM.
I THOUGHT SO.
TURNED INTO A FARMER.
WOMAN'S HIS WIFE.
MORE LIKELY, HIS WIDOW...
GIVE OR TAKE A DAY OR TWO.
WHAT'S
THE NEXT MOVE?
KEEP AN EYE ON HIM.
SEE HE STAYS PUT.
WAIT FOR CURLY BILL.
WHY WAIT?
I CAN HANDLE IT.
YOU'RE TOO ANXIOUS,
SLADE.
MAYBE SO,
BUT I'M HERE...
AND I'M READY.
HOW OLD ARE YOU?
I'M OLD ENOUGH.
YOU'RE OUT OF
KNEE PANTS HOW LONG?
8 YEARS?
LISTEN, FORBES,
I COULD TAKE HIM.
MR. FORBES TO YOU,
SONNY.
NO, THIS IS
CURLY BILL'S PLAY.
MAYBE YOU'LL MAKE IT
ONE DAY, IF YOU'RE SMART.
YOU'RE HEAR TO WATCH
AND TO LEARN.
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU?
EXCUSE ME...
I AM LOOKING FOR THE FARM
OF DANIEL CAINE.
RIGHT DOWN THERE.
THANK YOU.
Young Caine: MASTER...
OF MAN'S ROOTS,
WHICH IS THE STRONGER?
IT IS A SHAOLIN BELIEF
THAT THE PATERNAL LINE
CONTROLS.
Caine: WHAT IS A MAN
WITHOUT ROOTS?
WHAT IS A TREE
THE DEEPER INTO THE EARTH
THE ROOTS REACH,
THE STRONGER THE TREE.
Young Caine: A NAME,
A FACE IN MY MIND...
A PLACE...
IT IS ALL I KNOW
OF MY FATHER.
ONE HALF OF MYSELF,
AN EMPTINESS...
A MYSTERY.
Master Kan: SEEK
TO DISCOVER IT, THEN,
FOR IT IS THIS THREAD
WHICH HOLDS YOU
TO THE PAST
AND BINDS YOU
TO THE FUTURE...
TO FIX YOUR PLACE
FOR ALL TIME IN ETERNITY.
YES?
I AM SEEKING
DANIEL CAINE.
ARE YOU A FRIEND OF HIS?
NOT EXACTLY
A FRIEND...
AND NOT A STRANGER,
EITHER.
AND YOU?
I'M DANNY'S WIFE...
ADA.
I SHOULD--
NO, THANK YOU.
I CAN MANAGE.
BUT YOU NEVER TOLD ME
WHO YOU ARE.
A RELATIVE.
OH...
I'LL GET HIM.
MY FATHER IS DEAD.
SO IS MY MOTHER.
BROTHERS? SISTERS?
I HAVE NONE.
YOU HAVE ONE.
BROTHER.
HALF BROTHER,
I GUESS.
YOUR FATHER WAS
MARRIED ONCE BEFORE.
HE'D BE ABOUT 3...
4 YEARS OLDER
THAN YOU.
WHAT CAN I DO
FOR YOU?
YOU ARE THE SON
OF THOMAS HENRY CAINE?
WHO ARE YOU?
I AM KWAI CHANG CAINE...
YOUR BROTHER.
BUT YOU'RE CHINESE.
HALF BROTHER.
OUR FATHER IS THE SAME.
WHEN YOUR MOTHER DIED,
HE WENT TO CHINA...
WHERE HE MET...
MY MOTHER.
I WAS NEVER TOLD.
NOR WAS I...
UNTIL I CAME TO
OUR GRANDFATHER'S HOUSE.
HE GAVE ME THESE.
THE LETTERS YOU WROTE HIM.
HE NEVER
ANSWERED THEM.
I...STOPPED WRITING.
HE ASKED ME TO FIND YOU.
WE HAVE A COMMON BOND
OF BLOOD.
YOU, UH...YOU KNOW
A LOT ABOUT ME
FROM THESE LETTERS.
I DON'T KNOW
ANYTHING ABOUT YOU.
WHAT DO YOU WISH TO KNOW?
THERE'S TIME.
YOU'RE WELCOME
TO STAY, OF COURSE.
I CAN FIX YOU
A PLACE TO SLEEP
BY THE FIRE.
WE DON'T HAVE
MUCH ROOM, BUT--
THANK YOU.
I DO NOT WISH
TO UNSETTLE YOU.
PERHAPS I COULD SLEEP
IN THE BARN?
WHATEVER YOU SAY.
SUPPER WILL BE
READY SOON.
I HAVE EATEN.
I HAVE COME A LONG WAY.
YOU'LL WANNA
GET SOME REST.
WE'LL TALK
IN THE MORNING.
YOU DIDN'T GIVE HIM
A VERY WARM RECEPTION.
I DIDN'T KNOW HOW
TO GREET HIM, ADA.
AFTER ALL, I DON'T HAVE
A FULL-GROWN BROTHER
MATERIALIZING ON
MY DOORSTEP EVERY DAY.
PARTICULARLY CHINESE.
I DIDN'T MEAN THAT.
HEY--DON'T DO THAT.
THOUGHT I TOLD YOU
NOT TO LIFT
ANYTHING HEAVY.
OH, DANNY,
STOP BABYING ME.
I'M NOT BABYING YOU.
I'M BABYING
THE BABY.
IT'S GOOD TO SEE YOU,
CURLY BILL.
WHAT'D YOU FIND OUT?
HE'S DOWN THERE
IN THAT FARMHOUSE.
PUT HIMSELF
OUT TO PASTURE, HUH?
IT'S A GOOD PLACE
TO HIDE OUT.
WELL, MAYBE NOT...
'CAUSE WE FOUND HIM.
I'VE BEEN LOOKING FORWARD
TO MEETING HIM...
FOR A LONG TIME.
NO SIGN OF HIM YET.
JUST THAT CHINESE FLUNKY
DOWN THERE DOING CHORES.
DON'T WORRY.
HE'S THERE.
YOU KNOW, IT'S FUNNY...
HE'S ALWAYS BEEN
KIND OF LIKE A HERO TO ME.
I'M REAL ANXIOUS
TO MEET HIM.
I KNOW.
WHY...DID YOU DO ALL THIS?
THANK YOU.
WOULD IT NOT BE
MORE CONVENIENT
TO HAVE A WELL
NEAR THE HOUSE?
IT WOULD BE
WONDERFUL!
ONLY THING IS, UH...
THERE ISN'T ANY WATER
NEAR THE HOUSE.
OH,
BUT THERE IS.
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
CERTAIN PLANTS DO NOT
GROW BUT OVER WATER.
DANNY?
THERE ARE TOO MANY
OTHER THINGS
I GOTTA DO FIRST.
I WOULD BE HAPPY
TO DIG THE WELL.
WE'VE GOTTEN ALONG
WITHOUT IT, SO FAR.
AS YOU WISH.
LOOK...
WHAT DO I CALL YOU?
KWAI CHANG.
IT IS MY NAME.
WELL, IF YOU'RE
LOOKING FOR WORK,
THERE'S ALWAYS SOMETHING
TO DO AROUND A FARM.
I WOULD BE GRATEFUL.
ALRIGHT.
COME ON.
BREAKFAST
WILL BE READY
IN HALF AN HOUR.
Danny: THIS'LL BE AS GOOD
A PLACE TO START AS ANY.
I HAVEN'T HAD A CHANCE
TO CLEAN IT UP LATELY.
WHAT KINDA WORK DID YOU DO
BEFORE YOU CAME TO THIS COUNTRY?
I WAS A PRIEST.
A PRIEST?
YES.
WHAT KIND OF PRIEST?
SHAOLIN.
THAT IS
A BUDDHIST SECT.
LOOK, UH...
THAT CAN WAIT.
THE WORK?
I CAN GET IT LATER.
OH, NO,
I DON'T MIND.
YOU'RE A STRANGE MAN,
KWAI CHANG.
YES?
YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW ME,
AND YET YOU DON'T MIND
DOING A DIRTY JOB LIKE--
OH, IT IS HONORABLE
WORK, DANIEL,
TO BE A FARMER.
EVEN A PIGSTY?
EVEN A PIGSTY.
DANIEL...
YES?
DO YOU KNOW
THERE ARE MEN
WATCHING THE FARM?
2 OF THEM.
THEY'VE BEEN THERE
THE LAST COUPLE OF DAYS.
NOW THERE ARE 3.
THEY MEAN YOU
NO GOOD.
THEY'RE NOT ON MY LAND.
BESIDES,
IT'S NO CRIME TO LOOK.
DO YOU KNOW
WHAT THEY WANT?
I'M NO MIND READER.
BESIDES, I'VE GOT
OTHER THINGS
TO THINK ABOUT.
Young Caine:
YOU ONCE TOLD ME
MY PRESENT IS ROOTED
IN MY PAST.
AND IT IS THROUGH
THOSE ROOTS
WE DRAW
OUR NOURISHMENT
AND STRENGTH.
DO NOT THE ROOTS, THEN,
ALSO FORM THE FUTURE?
UPROOTED,
CAN A TREE FLOURISH
AND BEAR FRUIT?
WITHOUT THE FRUIT,
WHAT MAY BEAR THE SEEDS
OF FUTURE GENERATION
AND THUS FULFILL
THE ORDAINED CYCLE
OF ETERNITY?
THEN MY FUTURE
IS ROOTED IN MY PAST...
AND HALF MY ROOTS
ARE ACROSS THE SEA
IN AMERICA.
HOW WILL I FIND MY PLACE?
TIME AND YOUR TAO
WILL TELL YOU THAT,
GRASSHOPPER.
ANYTHING HAPPENING
DOWN THERE?
FARM WORK.
Forbes: HE KNOWS
WE'RE HERE.
I THINK IT'S TIME
WE PUSH HIM A LITTLE.
DANNY, WHAT ARE THEY
DOING UP THERE?
TARGET PRACTICE.
NO CONCERN TO US,
LONG AS THEY KEEP OFF
OUR PROPERTY.
DANNY...
WHAT DO THEY WANT?
WHO?
THOSE 3 MEN.
WHO ARE THEY?
I DON'T KNOW.
CAN'T WE MAKE THEM
GO AWAY?
HOW?
WE COULD NOTIFY
THE SHERIFF.
NO, ADA.
AH!
ARE YOU ALRIGHT?
HERE...SIT.
EASY...EASY.
EASY, ADA.
IT'S GONNA BE
ALRIGHT.
JUST LAY BACK.
EASY.
COME ON.
IT'LL BE ALRIGHT.
EASY...EASY...
LISTEN...
IF THEY'RE STILL
THERE TOMORROW,
I'LL GO TALK
TO THEM, OKAY?
DANNY...
WHO ARE THEY?
I DON'T KNOW.
I HONESTLY
DON'T KNOW.
I'LL FIND OUT
TOMORROW.
OH...DANNY!
Forbes: AFTERNOON. MA'AM.
I HOPE YOU DON'T MIND US
DROPPING BY.
YOUR FRIEND HERE
LOSE HIS WAY AGAIN,
DID HE?
NO, NOTHING
LIKE THAT.
MY ASSOCIATES...
MR. SLADE
AND MR. CURLY BILL
GRAHAM.
YEAH.
I'VE BEEN
LOOKING FORWARD
TO MEETING YOU.
MUST BE ABOUT
2 YEARS NOW.
ALL OF THAT.
BEEN THROUGH
SO MANY TOWNS
I CAN'T REMEMBER
THE NAMES,
ASKING ABOUT YOU.
ALWAYS HEARD THE SAME
STORY, MISTER, UH...
CAINE.
DANNY CAINE.
YEAH, WELL...
STORY GOES THAT YOU'RE
A PRETTY FAST GUN.
MAYBE THE FASTEST.
NO. YOU--YOU'VE
MADE A MISTAKE.
WELL, THAT'S WHAT
I'M HERE FOR...
CHECK THAT OUT.
YOU CAN
STOP CHECKING.
ONLY WEAPONS
I USE HERE ARE
A PLOW AND A HOE.
WASN'T ALWAYS
THAT WAY.
Forbes: I APPRECIATE
YOUR MODESTY, FRIEND,
BUT WHEN
OPPORTUNITY KNOCKS,
A WISE MAN'S
GOT TO LISTEN.
ALLOW ME TO BE
IMMODEST FOR A WHILE.
I THINK IT MIGHT SWEETEN
THINGS UP FOR A BIT.
MY TALENT...IS WORDS.
NEWSPRINT.
I CAN BUILD A LEGEND,
THE WAY NED BUNTLINE
DID FOR BUFFALO BILL.
IT CAN BE YOUR LEGEND,
OR, UH...
OR MINE.
ADA, GET BACK
ON THE PORCH.
AND THERE'S
A FORTUNE INVOLVED.
SO WE'VE COME HERE TO
OFFER YOU AN INVITATION...
TO MEET ME OVER IN MEDWICK.
YOU GOT THE WRONG
MAN, FRIEND.
AS I'VE TRIED
TO TELL YOU,
I'M JUST A FARMER.
HE DOESN'T EVEN
OWN A GUN.
I AM READY.
YAAAAAH!
YAAAAH!
YOW!
HAD YOU GOOD CAUSE
TO RISK THIS DANGER?
MY PURPOSE WAS
TO PROVE MY AGILITY...
AND MY COURAGE.
I HAD HOPED
SUCH QUALITIES
WERE ALREADY YOURS.
I SOUGHT TO TEST THEM.
FOR YOURSELF...
OR THEM?
IS IT NOT BETTER TO
SEE YOURSELF TRULY,
THAN CARE ABOUT
HOW OTHERS SEE YOU?
Young Caine:
IF I LOOK TRULY,
WILL I SEE TRULY?
I DON'T WANT THIS.
NOT THE RIGHT FEEL, HUH?
I CAN UNDERSTAND THAT.
BUT YOU'D BEST
DIG OUT YOUR OWN.
HE HAS TOLD YOU
HE IS ONLY A FARMER.
WHO ASKED YOU, CHINAMAN?
PLEASE...LET HIM BE.
UNH! UNH!
OOH! UNH!
NOW HOLD ON, NOW,
CURLY BILL.
WE DON'T WANT
THE SHOWDOWN HERE...
AND CERTAINLY NOT
WITH THE CHORE BOY.
LISTEN...
THERE'S TO BE NO MORE
SHOOTING ON THAT HILL.
YOU CAN PUT AN END TO THAT
EASY ENOUGH, MISTER.
I'LL BE WAITING FOR YOU...
WHENEVER YOU'RE READY.
JUST DON'T MAKE IT
TOO LONG.
COULD'VE GOT YOURSELF
KILLED.
BUT I AM ALIVE.
IT WOULD BE BETTER
IF YOU GOT OUT OF HERE.
YOU WISH ME TO LEAVE?
YES.
IT'S NOT YOUR FIGHT.
DANNY!
HE ONLY WANTED
TO HELP.
I DON'T WANT
HIS HELP.
I'M GONNA DRIVE YOU
INTO TOWN.
THERE IS NO NEED TO.
I TOLD DANNY
WE OWED YOU THAT...
AND MUCH MORE.
HE AGREED.
I WOULD HAVE LIKED
TO SAY GOOD-BYE TO HIM.
HE ASKED ME
TO SAY IT FOR HIM.
THEY ARE GONE.
OH.
WHAT DID THEY WANT?
I DON'T KNOW.
DID NOT DANNY
TELL YOU?
HE DOESN'T KNOW.
I WISH I COULD
HAVE COME TO KNOW
HIM BETTER.
I DON'T KNOW HIM
THAT WELL MYSELF.
I MEAN, WHAT HE DID
BEFORE WE WERE MARRIED.
HOW LONG HAVE
YOU BEEN MARRIED?
2 YEARS.
BUT HE DOESN'T TALK
ABOUT HIS PAST.
HE SAYS THE FUTURE
IS ALL THAT MATTERS.
IT IS CLEAR.
YOU HAVE A GREAT
LOVE BETWEEN YOU.
YOU ARE ONE.
I DON'T WANT ANYTHING
TO CHANGE THAT...
EVER.
WHOA.
I'M SORRY YOU'RE
LEAVING, KWAI CHANG.
I WILL REMEMBER
YOU AND DANNY.
LOOK WHO'S HERE.
Ada: WHAT
ARE YOU DOING?
WHERE'S
YOUR HUSBAND, MA'AM?
HE COME IN WITH YOU?
NO.
AND HE ISN'T COMING.
HE'S NO GUNFIGHTER.
I DON'T BELIEVE
THE LITTLE LADY KNOWS.
THAT MAN YOU'RE
TIED UP WITH...
HE'S JUST THIS SIDE
OF FAMOUS.
Forbes:
THAT'S A FACT, MA'AM.
HE'S RIGHT UP THERE
WITH JESSE JAMES
AND COLE YOUNGER.
Slade: HE DONE IT LEGAL,
OF COURSE--WITH A BADGE--
BUT HE'S A KILLER,
JUST THE SAME.
YOU'RE WRONG.
HE CAN TELL YOU.
HE'S HIS KIN.
LIKE A POLECAT IS
TO A HORSE.
Forbes:
EXACTLY HOW MUCH DO YOU KNOW
ABOUT YOUR HUSBAND, MA'AM?
ENOUGH TO KNOW
HE'S NOT A KILLER.
SHOW HER THE PICTURE.
THIS IS HOW HE LOOKED
3 YEARS AGO,
BEFORE HE STARTED
SPORTING A MUSTACHE.
THEY'RE THE SAME MAN.
THIS WAS TAKEN...
RIGHT AFTER
HE GUNNED DOWN HOBIE DURANT
AND TWO OF HIS GANG.
IT'S JUST A PICTURE.
DOESN'T
PROVE ANYTHING.
Forbes: OH, MA'AM,
THIS LITTLE PICTURE
WAS TAKEN FROM THE FILES
OF THE BENSON GAZETTE,
A NEWSPAPER DOESN'T LIE.
PLEASE...
RELEASE THE HORSE.
WE AIN'T FINISHED
WITH HER YET.
LEAVE HIM ALONE, SLADE.
GO AHEAD, SLADE.
DRAW.
YOU ANGLING FOR A REPUTATION,
I'LL SEE YOU GET IT...
AS A PUNK!
STYLE AND CLASS
OF A PACK RAT!
I GOT AS MUCH CLASS
AS ANYBODY.
IN A STREET BRAWL
WITH A CHINESE FLUNKY?
YOU WANT RESPECT...
YOU EARN IT.
IS IT TRUE, DANNY?
ARE YOU
WHAT THEY SAID?
ADA, IF YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT I AM BY NOW,
YOU NEVER WILL.
WHAT ARE YOU
GOING TO DO?
WHAT I HAVE TO.
NO!
I WANT YOU ALIVE!
ADA, I DON'T
WANNA GO.
THEN DON'T!
ADA, LISTEN...
I CAN'T LET THEM
COME OUT HERE AGAIN.
YOU COULD BE HURT.
DANNY,
I CAN'T LOSE YOU!
I THOUGHT YOU LEFT.
I WILL LEAVE WHEN WE
HAVE TALKED TOGETHER...
DANNY.
ABOUT WHAT?
YOU.
I KNEW YOU WOULD AGREE
TO MEET THIS MAN GRAHAM.
LIKE YOU KNEW THERE
WAS WATER UNDERGROUND?
AS I KNOW...YOU ARE
NOT MY BROTHER.
WHEN GRAHAM FLIPPED ME
THAT GUN,
AND I CAUGHT IT,
THAT'S WHAT TIPPED YOU,
WASN'T IT?
NO. I KNEW BEFORE.
WHEN YOU
RECEIVED ME,
IT WAS NOT...
AS A BROTHER.
IS MY BROTHER...
ALIVE?
I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED TO HIM.
Master Kan: A PICTURE
OF THE WORLD WE LIVE IN.
NOW YOU WILL TEAR
YOUR PAPERS...THUS.
WHEN YOU ARE FINISHED,
YOU WILL REASSEMBLE
THE PIECES IN
THEIR PROPER PLACE.
MASTER KAN...
I HAVE FINISHED, MASTER.
SO SWIFTLY?
IT IS CORRECT...
IN ALL RESPECTS.
HOW DID YOU DO IT,
MY SON?
IT WAS NOT DIFFICULT,
MASTER.
ON THE OTHER SIDE
WAS A PICTURE OF A MAN.
I PUT THE MAN TOGETHER,
AND THE WORLD WAS REMADE
AT THE SAME TIME.
THE MAN...THE WORLD.
THE WHOLENESS OF EACH
SEEMS RELATED.
AND ALL MEN
ADDED TOGETHER...
DO THEY NOT MAKE UP
THE WORLD WE LIVE IN?
Danny: WE MET
DURING THE WAR.
SERVED TOGETHER.
WE TALKED,
AS SOLDIERS DO
BETWEEN THE BATTLES,
WHEN THERE'S NOTHING
TO DO BUT WAIT.
HE TOLD ME ABOUT HIMSELF...
HIS FAMILY.
I LISTENED. REMEMBERED.
WHEN I WAS
MARSHAL OF BENSON,
DANNY CAME TO SEE ME...
ASKED ME TO HOLD
A PACKAGE FOR HIM.
NO QUESTIONS ASKED.
6 MONTHS AT THE MOST,
HE SAID.
2 YEARS PASSED.
HE DIDN'T COME.
AND...YOU DID NOT
SEE HIM AGAIN?
AFTER THAT LAST GUNFIGHT
IN BENSON,
I--I JUST GOT SICK
OF THE KILLING.
I--I KNEW I COULDN'T
STAND THAT ANYMORE.
IT WASN'T A MATTER
OF UPHOLDING THE LAW,
IT WAS WHETHER
I WAS FAST ENOUGH...
OUTDRAW ALL THOSE
YOUNG BUCKS WHO KEPT
COMING TO TEST ME.
THAT BADGE I WORE,
IT'S BECOME A TARGET.
I HAD TO KILL
JUST TO STAY ALIVE.
SEE, DANNY HAD
GIVEN ME HIS PAST
AND A WHOLE NEW FUTURE...
EVEN THE DEED TO HIS FARM.
SO I TOOK IT.
I HAD TO.
AAAAAH!
HAPPY NEW YEAR,
HONORABLE DEMON.
WHY DO YOU NOT
TREMBLE BEFORE ME?
IS THE STUDENT CAINE,
THEN, SO FEARFUL?
HOW DID YOU KNOW?
YOUR CHI IS NOT THAT
OF A DEMON, KWAI CHANG,
ONLY A MASK.
THUS, WHILE YOU
APPEAR TO BE A DEMON,
YOUR INNER ENERGIES BETRAY
WHO YOU REALLY ARE.
I SUPPOSE
THE TROUBLE IS,
I DON'T REALLY WANT
TO BE A DEMON.
AH. YOU HAVE HIT
ON A PROFOUND TRUTH.
CAN YOU NOT TELL ME
WHAT IT IS?
I MUST FIRST DECIDE
WHO AND WHAT
I WANT TO BE.
AND THEN, IN ORDER
TO ACHIEVE THAT IDEAL...
I MUST BECOME ONE
WITH IT.
POSSESS...AND BE
POSSESSED BY IT,
UNTIL YOU ARE
WHAT YOU WILL TO BE...
AND NOT MERELY A MASK,
ATTEMPTING TO DECEIVE
YOURSELF AND OTHERS.
Caine: DANNY
GAVE YOU A MASK
BEHIND WHICH
TO REBUILD A LIFE.
I THINK HE WOULD'VE
UNDERSTOOD THAT, TOO.
IF YOU GO AGAINST
THIS GUNMAN,
WILL YOU NOT
BE REVEALED?
LOSE ALL YOU
HAVE WORKED FOR?
AND WILL NOT
THE TESTING GO ON?
YOU KNOW, I TRIED TO BURY
LIGHTNING LUKE...
I THOUGHT I HAD.
AND SOME YOUNG BUCK
COMES ALONG
TRYING TO DIG HIM UP
AND KILL HIM AGAIN.
YOU HAVE NOT
TOUCHED YOUR GUN
FOR A LONG TIME.
THE LIGHTNING MAY BE
GONE FROM IT.
YOU MAY DIE.
I'VE NEVER BEEN
AFRAID OF DYING...
ONLY LIVING IN HELL,
BEING HUNTED AND HOUNDED.
THE LIFE OF A FARMER
IS GOOD...
HELPING THE EARTH
TO BRING FORTH FRUIT.
I KNOW.
YOU CANNOT GO.
WHY SHOULD IT
MATTER TO YOU?
I AM NOT YOUR BROTHER.
LUKE!
Slade: LIGHTNING LUKE.
I ALWAYS WONDERED WHY
THEY CALL YOU THAT.
YOU GONNA SHOW ME?
WITH A GUN
IN YOUR HAND
ALREADY, SON?
WELL, NOW,
THE WAY I HEARD,
A MAN NEEDS
A LITTLE EDGE AGAINST YOU.
HE DOES NOT WISH
TO FIGHT.
HE'S GOT A CROWN
ON HIS HEAD.
IT'S GONNA FALL
TO THE MAN WHO TAKES HIM,
AND THAT MAN'S
GONNA BE ME.
DANNY! OH...DANNY.
IT ISN'T FINISHED.
THERE'S STILL
CURLY BILL.
BUT YOU CAN'T!
I HAVE TO.
WHAT WILL YOU DO?
MEET HIM.
WOUNDED?
I'LL MAKE IT.
HE WILL NOT MEET YOU.
HE WISHES YOUR CROWN.
HE WILL WAIT
UNTIL YOU ARE READY.
IS THIS NOT THE CODE?
TAKE HIM.
FORBES...
I'M TIRED
OF WAITING.
MR. GRAHAM.
WHERE'S YOUR BROTHER?
THE LUKE HASKELL
YOU SEEK...
IS NO MORE.
I'LL FIND HIM.
NO.
CURLY BILL...
HE'S OVER THERE.
AAH!
TWO GUNS AGAINST
A CHORE BOY WITH
A PLOWSHARE.
WHAT DO THEY SAY WHEN
A MAN IS FINISHED?
HE THREW IN HIS HAND?
WELL, THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT HE DID.
IT'S OVER, DANNY.
IS IT?
LUKE HASKELL
IS DEAD.
NOT BEFORE HE KILLED
ANOTHER MAN.
HE WOULD HAVE KILLED YOU.
YEAH, THERE IS
ALWAYS THAT.
NO...THIS WAS
THE LAST ONE.
IF ANYONE ELSE
COMES LOOKING FOR ME,
THEY'LL--
NO ONE ELSE WILL COME.
YOU KNOW, WHEN--
WHEN I FIRST SAW YOU,
I THOUGHT, "MY BROTHER,
MY EXECUTIONER."
AND NOW?
AND NOW,
KWAI CHANG, I--
I'D LIKE TO THINK
WE ARE BROTHERS.
WE ARE.