Fear does not exist in this dojo.
Does it?
No, Sensei!
Pain does not exist in this dojo.
Does it?
No, Sensei!
Defeat does not exist in this dojo.
Does it?
No, Sensei!
Fear does not exist in this dojo.
Does it?
No, Sensei!
Pain does not exist in this dojo.
Does it?
No, Sensei!
Defeat does not exist in this dojo.
Does it?
No, Sensei!
Prepare!
We do not train to be merciful here.
Mercy is for the weak.
Here, on the street, in competition,
a man confronts you, he's the enemy.
An enemy deserves no mercy.
What is the problem, Mr. Lawrence?
Class, we have visitors.
I hear you jumped
some of my students last night.
Afraid the facts mixed up.
Now you get your boy on the mat
or you and I will have a major problem.
Too much advantage, your dojo.
Name a place.
Tournament.
Come on, Johnny, kill him!
Point! Chop! That's two for LaRusso!
Time out, time out.
Go to your sensei. Turn. Kneel.
Hey, Johnny, you're a cream-puff!
Sweep the leg.
You have a problem with that?
No, Sensei.
No mercy.
Warning for illegal contact to the knees.
Ready?
No mercy! No mercy!
Weigh the fist, Johnny.
Finish him!
Winner!
Now who's the loser?
You're really sick, man.
How does second place feel now?
- He can't breathe.
- Mind your business.
- You're gonna kill him.
- Sensei, please. You're hurting him.
He's sorry, okay? He really is.
Let him go.
Beat it, slope, or you're next.
"Mercy is for the weak.
"We do not train to be merciful here.
"A man face you, he is enemy.
"Enemy deserve no mercy."
Come, Daniel-san.
Time go home.
- You could have killed him, couldn't you?
- Hai.
Why didn't you then?
Because, Daniel-san,
for person with no forgiveness in heart...
... living even worse punishment
than death.
Sensei Kreese, this is Pat Johnson
from the All Valley Tournament.
We're sorry you lost all your students.
I guess the Cobra Kai won't
enter the tournament this year.
We've made repeated requests
for payments of dues...
... but since you've failed to respond...
... we have to drop the Cobra Kai
from our membership rolls.
If you have any questions, give me a call.
Have a nice day.
Mr. Kreese, this is Pacific Bell.
This is the final call regarding your bill,
and if you do not pay immediately...
Mr. Kreese, good morning.
What a surprise. Some coffee?
- Where's the boss?
- He's upstairs.
Thanks.
Come on!
You're telegraphing that wheel kick.
Johnny!
What a surprise, man!
Yes!
What's this? You moving in?
This is "I give up." I came to say good-bye.
- Here are the dojo keys.
- What are you talking about?
I'll pay you that back rent soon.
You think I bought that place for the rent?
I bought it for you.
- Mr. Silver?
- What?
The plutonium deal.
Johnny, every business has a slump
at one time or another.
Ten years ago
nuclear was the preferred waste.
You could dump it anywhere.
Now, everybody's a detective.
I'm lucky if I make one deal a year
without being indicted.
Thank you.
Let's get some air.
It's been nine months since a student
walked through my doors.
You're not listening to me.
Come on, snap out of it.
I can't.
I'm broke and I'm going nowhere.
You're wrong.
You're going to Tahiti.
Now.
All right, I've made up my mind.
This slope, Miyagi, and that punk kid...
...I'll get them for what they did to you.
They made you suffer,
so I'll make them suffer.
When I think they've suffered enough,
then I start with the pain.
- Terry, you don't have to do that.
- Don't have to? I want to.
It's not over. We're Cobra Kai.
Come on, say it. Cobra Kai.
Say it! Cobra Kai.
- Never dies.
- You bet your ass.
- I owe you, man.
- You don't owe me anything.
I don't owe you anything?
What about Vietnam?
How many times did you save my ass?
I don't know. I lost count.
Get the hell out of here.
Have a good trip, Captain.
The White Zone is for the immediate
loading and unloading of passengers only.
Smog.
Smells like home, huh, Mr. Miyagi?
Daniel-san,
why mother not here to meet you?
You tell her right flight number?
I told her the right flight.
I just told her the wrong day.
I told her we were coming in tomorrow.
She loves surprises.
Hope so.
We take taxi apartment house.
Then Miyagi go back to work.
106 Los Angeles. Crank it up!
What are you doing in my cab?
- We just came from the airport.
- I thought that was the cab I ordered.
- Mrs. Milo, what's going on?
- What does it seem? Progress.
I got a message for you from your mother.
I told you that bum would sell the place
and you'd be out of a job someday.
You wouldn't listen to me.
- What's the message?
- What message?
- The one from my mother.
- She said call her at your Uncle Louie's.
No worry nothing, Mrs. LaRusso.
Daniel-san room all finished.
Yeah, I take good care of him.
You just look out Uncle Louie.
I might be here for a few months.
A 70-year-old man gets emphysema,
it's no joke, you know.
Are you sure there's no problem
for him to stay with you?
No problem.
Pleasure.
Mr. Miyagi, thank you.
Welcome. Bye-bye. Here Daniel-san.
Nice mama.
You sure you don't need me there?
No. You stay with Mr. Miyagi
and start college.
I can't believe it, "Mr. College Man."
When's registration?
It's this Tuesday.
And classes start Thursday.
And when is Kumiko arriving?
She's not.
She got this great job
with a dance company in Tokyo.
I guess she just couldn't say no, so...
You're disappointed, huh?
Yep. But that's life, I guess.
I'll survive.
You'll do more than just survive.
I gotta go, okay?
Listen, Uncle Louie says hi,
and I love you.
Okay, say hi to Uncle Louie.
I love you, too.
The little maple's still in there.
I'll get it.
No. I go.
Mr. Miyagi, you okay?
Just remembering.
I'll bet there are a lot of memories
here for you.
So what are you going to do now?
Don't know.
Well, did you ever think about
opening a bonsai store?
Hai, Daniel-san.
In my dream.
My retirement.
What do you call this?
Call "time to go."
You know, I've been thinking about
the bonsai shop idea.
You already have all the stock.
How hard can it be?
Not too hard, Daniel-san...
...if Miyagi have money for lease,
deposit, fix-up.
But since we build house
for Yukie in Okinawa...
...money very short supply.
"Supply"?
Supplies are us.
Thank you, Daniel-san,
but that not money.
It looks like money. Smells like money.
Good money. Smell that.
Smell like college education.
I know, Mr. Miyagi,
but I have a great idea...
Daniel-san.
No idea.
Discussion closed.
But what about your dream?
And, Mr. Miyagi, no offence,
but if you miss the train this time...
...there may not be another one
for a long time.
Then Miyagi take bus.
Revenge? Of course you want revenge.
I'm gonna get it for you.
The day you step off the plane, you're
the biggest dojo operator in the valley.
What are you talking about?
I bought 20 locations today.
Yours, 100 percent.
You are back, my man,
bigger and badder than ever.
You're a sweetheart, that's great!
But what about those two jerks?
Those two jerks are taking up
100 percent of my time from now on.
So just have patience.
I'm just getting things rolling.
When I'm finished with that kid,
he'll be begging me to be his teacher.
You know what he's gonna learn from me?
Pain in every part of his body
and fear in every part of his mind.
And here's the kicker:
he's gonna thank me for it.
What about the old man?
Him I hurt for the kid.
By the time that little twerp
steps into the ring to defend his title...
...I'm gonna have him thinking
he's invincible.
Then he's gonna find out
what pain and fear really mean...
...right in front of a thousand people.
How do you know he'll compete?
He'll compete. Don't worry about it.
You just have fun.
Go give Mimona and her girlfriend
a squeeze for me.
How do you know about her?
I know.
Anything else you want?
Yeah.
Make his knuckles bleed.
I like that, Johnny.
I'm gonna use that.
I'm going to be working full-time
on this from now on.
Very good, sir.
No, it's too nice.
I gotta look poor.
This isn't bad. Fix the collar.
Make me look humble.
- About the Borneo call?
- All right, but that's the last one.
For the next few weeks,
my business is revenge.
Everything is in place, sir.
All right,
let's see what you've got for me.
Cute but wrong.
It's got no character.
A truck.
Yeah, I like it. Make sure it runs.
Yes, sir.
- Where are the magazines I ordered?
- Right here, sir.
- Have a very pleasant evening, sir.
- Thank you, Margaret.
"Karate's bad boy.
"Mike Barnes."
Perfect.
Mr. Miyagi, I'm home.
Daniel-san, just in time.
How was fishing?
We find out pretty soon.
So, how first day at college?
College?
College...
College is...
Well, you know college, Mr. Miyagi.
It's a place that I didn't go to today.
What?
Mr. Miyagi,
may all your dreams come true.
What this?
There's only one way to find out.
All right, I'll tell you.
It's my college diploma.
- What?
- I'm only joking.
Daniel-san, you have sense humour.
"Lease."
For your new bonsai store.
Congratulations.
"One month security, two month rent."
Yes. With just enough left over
for renovations, if we're careful.
Daniel-san, thank you very much,
but cannot accept.
But it's your dream, Mr. Miyagi.
Why not?
Because money in pocket
was not for Miyagi dream.
Was for college education.
I know, just listen to me for a minute.
I know me. I just can't take courses
to take courses.
I'll get bored.
Once it happens, forget about it.
It's bye-bye college.
I've been going to school non-stop
since I'm five. I could use the break.
- I don't know, Daniel-san.
- I do.
- Just come with me a second.
- Where?
- Come with me.
- What about fish?
The fish is not going anyplace.
That fish is dead.
What a moment!
You are now crossing over
to the right side of the tracks.
- What that?
- That's opportunity knocking.
Straight ahead. Right up there.
Your dream come true,
and there's plenty of free parking.
Right here, Mr. Miyagi.
- This place?
- This place. Wait till you see it up close.
So, is this the opportunity
of a lifetime or what?
Now, I know you're worried
about this area...
...but the landlord says
this neighbourhood is up and coming.
We're in on the ground floor over here.
Look, a pottery shop across the street.
We could set a deal,
get some planters made up for the bonsai.
Wait till you see inside, man.
This is going to be great.
Come on in.
Mr. Miyagi, welcome to your dream.
Now don't let this throw you.
Looks can be deceiving.
We have to think potential here.
Think potential, all right?
You see all this stuff? Everything in here?
You own it. Everything.
It's all yours. You could use this stuff.
This is good wood.
We can make shelves out of this stuff.
Back here,
I thought this would be a great spot...
...up here, to do like a bonsai display.
All those pine trees you have?
We could show them in different stages.
You know, the possibilities are endless.
Over here, right,
I thought this would be a great spot...
...for a little work area.
Over here we got like a bonsai hospital.
The little guys get sick. Take care of them.
I work for free. And I thought of a name.
Check it out.
"Mr. Miyagi's Little Trees."
Simple, direct, catchy.
It doesn't look it now,
but this place is a gold mine.
I know you can make it work, Mr. Miyagi.
If anyone can, you can.
What did I do? Did I forget something?
Well, what did I miss?
Your name on lease, next to mine.
- Partner.
- Partner?
Yes! Mr. Miyagi, this is gonna be great.
You're welcome.
What?
Don't bullshit me.
What do you mean
you can't dump it in Borneo?
Who in Borneo
knows what chloride sludge is?
Just do it!
Do it!
Call me when it's dumped.
Where were we, Margaret?
"And, in conclusion,
I reject your final offer.
"If you proceed,
I'll sue your collective asses accordingly."
Best to Lorna and the kids. Sincerely...
Yeah?
Good, bring him in.
What else?
The grand jury.
What do you intend to do about them?
Bribe them, as usual.
Lighten up, Margaret.
- Who's the DA on the case?
- Mr. Cole.
Good.
Let's invite Willie to dinner Tuesday night.
We'll have his favourite.
- Poached salmon.
- Very well.
Mr. Silver?
You must be Mike Barnes. Welcome to LA.
Thank you for bringing me down,
Mr. Silver.
Milos, call the boys.
This place is intense.
- Consider it home.
- Thanks.
Snake, Dennis.
Mike Barnes.
Dennis will take care of your training.
Snake takes care of everything else.
If you're looking to be a bad boy in LA,
Snake's the boy to be bad with.
You know it.
You get a weekly draw and a car.
Any questions?
Remember on the phone you said
if I come here...
...and I beat this LaRusso
in the All Valley Tournament...
...that you'd give me 25 percent ownership
in your new dojos?
Which I think is more than generous.
But I've been giving it some thought.
For me to do my absolute best,
which is what I want to do for you...
...l'm afraid I'm gonna need 50 percent.
Fifty percent?
Well, I don't know
if I can afford more than 35.
I understand. I guess I'd better get going.
It was nice meeting everybody.
- Do you fight as hard as you negotiate?
- Harder.
You got your 50 percent.
- And I get that in writing?
- By noon today.
You just bought yourself a champion.
You remember that.
- Snake, show him to his room.
- Yes, sir.
See you later, Mike.
Milos, my blue pinstripe.
So, what do you think?
He's obnoxious.
Yeah, he's perfect.
Very good. This make special bonsai.
You really see a bonsai in here?
Where?
Inside.
Inside?
Hello, any bonsai in here?
Daniel-san, not inside. Inside you.
Same place your karate come from.
But my karate comes from you.
Only root karate come from Miyagi.
Just like bonsai choose own way grow.
Because the root is strong.
You choose own way.
Do karate same reason.
Yeah, but I do it your way.
One day you do own way.
Remember what you said before about
bonsai being free to grow as they choose?
All bonsai aren't free to choose.
We tell them how to grow
by using clippers and then the wire.
But, Daniel-san,
our bonsai not true bonsai.
True bonsai grow wild. Very rare.
You ever seen any?
Okinawa.
What about here?
I only know of one.
What did it do, immigrate?
With Miyagi.
Only thing Miyagi bring from Okinawa.
Where's the tree now?
There.
Devil's Caldron.
Devil's Caldron?
No can see bonsai from here.
Good place. Very safe. Nobody bother.
Why did you put it
in such a hard place to get to?
True original bonsai
worth many thousand dollar.
Come, time learn special
Miyagi-family kata.
Now you ready.
Like all bonsai found in tree,
all karate found in this kata.
Come, together we do kata.
Hi, Mr. Miyagi.
I brought this tree,
the one you were working on this morning.
I thought you might want
to give it another try.
Thank you.
A change of scenery
might bring what's inside outside.
- Where should I put it?
- Over here.
Very good.
You've done a lot of work here.
This place is bigger than I thought.
- There's your charcoal.
- Thank you.
Perfect.
I hope you don't mind...
...but I opened that letter.
The one that came today
from the All Valley Tournament.
There's a new rule this year.
- Would you like to read about it?
- No.
That's okay because I got it memorised.
It says:
"Under the new rules...
"...the defending champion
only needs to fight in the final match."
Isn't that great?
That limits my fights to just one.
That's better
than what I had to put up with last year.
And let's face it, it's another year.
It's a year later.
I'm a lot more experienced.
So I think we should
seriously reconsider this.
- Right?
- Wrong!
Wrong?
Should consider get
new pot for bonsai.
I don't know what the big deal is.
I mean, what is your problem with this?
If karate used defend honour,
defend a life...
...karate means something.
If karate used defend plastic metal trophy...
...karate no mean nothing.
Understand?
I wish I did.
Go find a nice pot for bonsai across street.
Here's your pen.
Before I forget.
And if you have a minute,
just in case you change your mind...
...here's the application.
Okay?
It's no rush.
I mean, it says at the bottom...
We have a couple of weeks
before we have to send it in.
I'm sorry if I made it seem
like we had to do it today.
We have some time.
Hello?
Hi. Could you turn that off?
Sure.
Thanks.
Hang on, I'm almost finished.
That's okay.
It's okay. Take your time.
That's pretty cool.
Thanks.
So, what can I do for you?
Actually, I was looking to buy some pots.
Yeah, what size?
This would be good. Like this.
They're for bonsai trees.
We're opening a shop across the street.
Great. Welcome to the neighbourhood.
Thanks.
Yeah, I love bonsai.
They're so perfect, you know?
Maybe when we get our trees in
you could come visit the shop.
And meet my partner, too.
I haven't even really met you yet.
I'm sorry.
- Daniel LaRusso.
- Jessica Andrews. Hi.
Hi. Is that you in that...
Yep, that's me.
What happened to the guy
who lost his head?
Elizabeth Anne Rooney happened to him.
The traitor.
The pots?
You know what we could do?
Could you put like a bonsai tree
on the side of the pot?
- It's sort of like our trademark.
- Like embossed?
Right on the side.
I'll draw a picture of it for you.
That would be great.
- Jessica, come on. I'm late, hurry up.
- Listen, I got to deal with this guy.
Thanks, I'll see you soon then.
How soon?
How soon? Well, I don't know.
- Busy tonight?
- No.
No?
Well, then I'll see you tonight.
If that's okay with you?
Okay. About 7:00?
Well, sure. 7:00 is good.
I just live right upstairs,
so go around the side, okay?
- I'll see you around the side, 7:00.
- Bye-bye.
Charles is going to get angry.
Open up the gate.
You found it, huh?
Thanks to you.
Thanks to me? I didn't do anything.
That looks great.
You find something?
Yeah. Yeah, actually I did.
I found a date.
You didn't send me over there
just to look at pots, did you?
Yeah, I knew it.
Did you sign it?
You didn't sign it.
No.
I understand your feelings on this.
But you have to understand mine.
This is the biggest thing
I've ever done in my life.
I'm proud of this title.
Why can't I defend it?
Daniel-san,
you no look answer Miyagi.
Just like a bonsai live inside the tree,
answer live inside of you.
The only thing living inside me right now
is a lot of confusion.
I have the chance
to be the champion again.
- All I have to do is put my signature to it.
- Or match to it.
A match to it?
Then you watch confusion disappear
with the smoke.
"442nd."
What are you doing here?
- Forget something.
- What?
For shop. Bring good luck.
Well, I hope it brings good customers, too.
Daniel-san look good.
Thanks for the shirt. I love it, man.
What doing?
I've been thinking about what you said,
and I decided to take your advice.
I'm going to let my confusion
go up in smoke.
I'm not entering the tournament.
I want my karate and your karate
to mean something.
Good decision, Daniel-san.
This way no more bruises.
Save money on Band-Aid.
Get out of here.
They never laid a hand on me last year.
Just an elbow, a few feet.
I'll never forget that knee to the groin.
That was interesting.
I'll see you later, Mr. Miyagi.
- Hi.
So, you all set to go?
First I gotta tell you this.
After you hear this,
you just might change your mind.
What do you have, poison oak?
A boyfriend.
You see, he was in the headless picture.
You know, we broke up two months ago.
You mean Elizabeth Anne Rooney...
We were both a little dumb about it,
but we've been talking on the phone.
I don't know, we're gonna give it
another try when I go home.
- Where's home?
- Columbus. Ohio.
Yeah, I'm gonna go back
after Thanksgiving.
- I just didn't want to lead you on.
- No.
I did come on kind of strong.
No, don't worry about it. It's refreshing.
We could go Dutch.
That sounds great.
It's just that I've been here
for two months...
...with absolutely nothing to do
and I haven't even met any friends.
Meet your first friend.
All right.
Yeah, this is wild.
Wait till he hears about this one.
Who?
Mr. Miyagi. He's my partner.
You wanna meet him?
Yeah, why not?
You are about to meet the greatest guy.
This guy, he's funny, he's smart.
You got a problem, he's got the answer.
He's like no one you'll ever meet.
On top of that,
he happens to be my best friend.
Why do you call him "mister"?
Mr. Miyagi.
Meet Jessica Andrews from
Columbus, Ohio, and across the street.
This is Mr. Miyagi
from Okinawa and Reseda.
- How do you do?
- Hi.
- Jessica's gonna make those pots for us.
- Very good.
- Welcome to the neighbourhood.
- Thank you very much.
How's it going so far? Good?
I never know retirement
mean such hard work.
- You like to see inside shop?
- Yeah, I'd love to.
Partner show you around.
Don't forget lock up.
No, I won't.
- Good night. Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you, too.
- I'll see you later.
- Bye-bye.
- You see why I call him "mister"?
- Yeah. He's nice.
He's the best. Come on in.
What's this?
That's Mr. Miyagi's.
He brought it for good luck.
What do you think?
It is going to be great.
- Yeah, it is.
- It needs a little work, but...
So where'd you meet him?
I met him when I moved out here.
He started teaching me karate.
Karate?
- You do karate?
- Yeah, I do.
He doesn't really look like
the karate-teacher type.
He doesn't act like it either.
Half the time he teaches me stuff,
I don't know what it is.
What do you mean?
It's like that vase
you were making this morning.
He'll make a whole karate lesson
out of that.
No, I'm not kidding.
Show me how you were making that...
- You go up and then you go down.
- Okay, now you do that.
Okay, go up.
Now, okay, right, see just like that.
Now go down.
Okay, now do that again. Go up.
I'm a mugger.
I'm gonna grab you,
now grab the back of my head.
Then pull down and bring your knee up.
Room for one more down there?
- What are you doing? We're not open.
- The door was.
I meant for business, pal.
I didn't come here for business.
Came here to talk to you.
We heard you weren't entering
the All Valley this year.
Is that true, Daniel?
- Where'd you hear that?
- Is it true?
Yeah, that's true. So what?
- We'd like you to reconsider.
- Is that why you guys came down here?
- I need your title.
- Then enter the tournament and go for it.
Maybe you didn't hear me.
I need your title.
You don't enter
and that effects my financial future.
I won't let that happen. Get it?
I have nothing to prove.
I have no reason to fight.
I do. I got some money to make.
Give me the application.
Forget it. I'm not going to fight...
Sign it!
You sign it, man!
Come on, man! Right now!
Let's go, punk!
Let LaRusso sleep on it.
Come on. Mike!
Yeah, you sleep on it.
And you can dream about me.
You slimeball.
Slimeball? That's cute.
Did your mother teach you that?
Come on, Mike.
You'll have to excuse him.
He's usually a very mellow guy.
See you later.
Do you know those creeps?
No.
And I wanna keep it that way.
Excuse me.
Mr. Miyagi?
My name is Terry Silver.
My master is Kim San Jang
of South Korea.
My teacher sends his respects.
John Kreese of the Cobra Kai dojo
was our school's number one student.
Word reached us in Korea
only two months ago...
...about what happened last year
at the tournament.
My teacher sends his apologies
for John Kreese's dishonourable actions.
Accept apology.
I was sent here
to help John regain balance.
Hope you can be successful.
Unfortunately, I arrived too late.
I buried John last week.
He's dead? What happened?
His doctor said it was cardiac arrest,
but I knew John better than anyone.
Karate was his life.
And after he lost all his students,
it just broke his heart.
John was a hero.
He wasn't always like what you saw.
He saved my life in Vietnam.
War does something to a man.
You had to have been there
to know what I mean.
Have been.
Do know.
442nd?
Man!
More medals of honour
came out of the 442nd...
...than all World War II put together.
I bet you've been there.
Is this your student? The champion?
Yeah.
Our apologies to you, too.
John had vowed
to come and apologise himself.
He planned...
Look, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry to interrupt your training.
Mr. Silver...
...very sorry to hear about death of friend.
Me, too.
Thank you.
God, that's too bad.
Too bad, Daniel-san.
Come, we continue kata.
Hello?
- Eat yet?
- No, I haven't.
I was supposed to dine with my Aunt Pat.
She owns the shop.
She had to do some things, so I got stuck
with all this macaroni and cheese.
Macaroni and cheese?
You know what I like!
I grew up on macaroni and cheese.
I never say no
when it comes to macaroni and cheese.
- Here, have a seat.
- Thanks.
I used to eat this stuff by the ton.
I want you to try this, okay?
And be honest.
Okay.
On a scale of one to ten, I'd give it as...
...eleven.
Let's eat. I'm starved.
I hope you like this.
I'm not sure if this is
exactly what you wanted, but...
Hey, this came out great.
- Look at the tree. You got it just right.
- Good.
- Wait until Mr. Miyagi sees it.
- Do you think he'll like it?
Like it? He's gonna love it. Here.
- I have something for you.
- For me?
What is this?
The Down Stairs? What is that?
It's a dance club. Yeah, it's great.
It's got live music.
It's for the night before you go back home.
I figured it would be
a nice going-away present.
Daniel, that is so sweet.
Come on, guys. This isn't funny anymore.
Come on, turn on the lights.
Danny, I hope you got some good news
for my friend Mike here.
- I hope so too, Daniel.
- I told you.
I can't help you. Forget about it.
Where are you going?
You haven't signed the application yet.
I'm not signing the application.
I won't compete.
Take your friends and get out of here.
Dennis, he didn't sign it yet.
Come on, guys.
This is getting out of hand now.
- I'm not signing the application.
- Sure you are.
I'm not going to be there.
You're wasting your time.
- Take off, all right?
- You take off!
- Come on, Dennis, take him out!
- Put his eye out!
Come on!
Come on, punk!
Let's see what you've got!
Nice kick. Not bad.
Better. Good, but not good enough.
Come on, get up!
Why are you being so stubborn?
Don't do that!
I am running out of patience.
Now sign it and let's get on with it.
Stop it!
It's your ass!
Just get out of here!
- Save it for the tournament!
- Nail him!
Mike, come on, let's get out of here!
Come on, old man!
Mike, let's go!
Let's go! You wimp!
I'll be back, LaRusso.
I'm gonna get you.
You're finished!
You can't watch him forever, Buddha-head.
So, Daniel-san, time take Jessica home.
Yeah. Jessica, you all right?
Yeah. I just want to lie down.
I can't believe you're singing.
Forget it.
Feel lucky, Daniel-san.
Lucky? How could you feel lucky?
Feel lucky. Bonsai tree not in shop.
Safe at home.
That makes us real lucky.
I never felt luckier in my life.
Daniel-san, we can rebuild the shop.
Cannot rebuild stock.
We sell a few trees, fix shoji screen,
start over again.
What if those guys come back again?
What are we going to do then?
If they come back,
what are we going to do?
Just tell me,
what do we do if they come back?
Sing happy song.
Where are the trees?
Where'd you put the trees?
They stole them!
I can't believe it. They stole the trees.
Don't they get it?
I'm not going to sign this thing.
Mr. Miyagi, what are we going to do?
- Where are you going?
- Get fishing pole.
What?
Sometimes I don't get you.
The shop's wrecked. We've just been
robbed, and you're going fishing.
We're flat broke and you're going fishing.
You're just going to fluff it off?
Doesn't this even bother you?
Daniel-san, sometime better be bothered
on full stomach than empty one.
Great, another great thought, huh?
That really does me good.
You go fishing.
I'm going to the police to report it.
Show them the application
so they can arrest these jerks.
This is the '80s,
you gotta do something, Mr. Miyagi.
You can't be so damn passive.
Somebody's gotta do something
about these guys.
I bring the tournament application
to the police station.
As I walk in, they start laughing at me.
Finally the sergeant said,
"Son, we'll look into it."
We'll see. I hope.
I still think you should ask Mr. Miyagi
before going after his tree.
He wouldn't have hidden it
in the middle of nowhere...
...if he wanted people to dig it up.
- I don't have a choice.
If he doesn't sell this tree
we're looking for...
...he loses his business. He's broke.
His social security can barely cover
the expenses on his rowboat.
This tree is like money in the bank.
Great. So now we're robbing a bank.
How much do you think
this thing is worth?
I found out these original bonsai trees
start at $10,000.
- Seriously?
- See, that's why it is so important to me.
This one tree can set Mr. Miyagi up for life.
That's the least I could do for him.
It's a long way down there.
- You know what I think?
- What?
I think when the tide comes in,
the ocean fills up the bottom down there.
Yeah, Mr. Miyagi sure knows
how to pick 'em.
Yeah, no kidding.
How are we supposed to find
Mr. Miyagi's tiny little tree in all this?
He told me he put it halfway down
the steepest cliff...
...where it would catch
the first rays of the sun.
Good luck. We're never gonna find it.
- Wait! That must be it! I found it!
- Are you sure?
God, it's beautiful.
It's like the one on the back of my gi.
Come on, let me see.
You see that ridge, where the sun hits...
It's just like the one on the pot I made.
How are we going to get
all the way down there?
You leave that to me. I'll teach you.
Come on. We gotta go get the ropes.
- You sure you understand everything?
- Yeah, I got it.
I feed this through here
and I hold this back here and I pray to God.
Okay. Now, are you sure
you want to do this?
I wanna do this?
- I gotta do it. I'll be okay.
- You got it. You'll be fine.
Remember, the rope is your friend.
Everything will be great.
Friend? This rope's more than my friend.
I love this rope.
This rope and I are going steady.
Right, rope? Just you and me, rope.
Just lean. Okay, you got it. Don't worry.
Just sit back. Just lean back. You got it.
This is almost fun.
I'm coming, okay? Just keep going.
This isn't so hard.
You're a pretty good teacher.
Thanks.
Daniel! Look out! I got you, okay?
- I'm coming! Daniel, are you okay?
- I'm okay.
Hold on! Don't move, I'm coming.
Stay there.
Okay, I got you. I got you.
Put both hands on the rope.
Put your feet against the rocks
and push out. I got you.
Push out! There you go!
All right, I got you.
Okay, now guide your rope.
Slide your hands to the brake.
To the brake. Right here. All right?
You okay?
Listen, I'm so sorry about the rock.
- You sure you're okay?
- No, I'm fine. Don't worry about it.
God, it's a lot steeper
than it looks from up there, huh?
- You've done this kinda stuff before, right?
- Yeah, but not from this high up.
Great!
Maybe we should go back.
Do you want to?
No, I gotta keep going.
I don't have a choice.
Well, just be careful, okay?
Watch your footing, there you go.
All right. God, you scared me.
I scared you?
- You can get killed doing this.
- Just think positive.
- How are we going to get back up there?
- Don't worry about it.
You're right. I got enough to worry about.
- What?
- Where's the tree?
It's right there, between the two ropes.
Come on.
It's a beautiful tree.
Mr. Miyagi must have looked like
Spider-Man coming down here, huh?
Yeah, no kidding.
Now, remember how I told you to lock off.
Take the rope
and you put it around your butt.
And you tie it around your leg.
Okay, get it?
- There you go. I got it!
- There you go. You got it.
- All right.
- Now you can use both your hands.
All right.
So he really planted this here, huh?
What, this tree? He brought this
all the way back from Okinawa.
What if he tells you to put it back?
What if he does?
He's not going to tell me to put it back.
Believe me, I know this guy.
That bonsai shop
was his dream come true.
- He won't have me put it back.
- I don't think we should be doing this.
I saw his face when he lost his job.
Believe me, I know what I'm doing.
But what about the tree?
Isn't it going to die?
The tree will be fine. The most important
thing is to pack the roots well.
Believe me, he's taught me everything
about these trees.
- Do you want me to take this for you?
- No, I got it.
All I need is a bag to pack the roots in.
- Daniel! Help me up!
- Hang on!
Don't let go! Grab the rope!
Are you okay?
I got it!
Oh, my God! The tree's in the water!
I gotta get it!
It's gonna get washed out!
Move! Hurry up!
Get out of the way!
I gotta get it!
It's gonna get washed out!
The rope! Hurry!
Get the canteen, quick!
We gotta wash the roots off.
The salt water will kill them!
- Is it gonna be okay?
- Mr. Miyagi will know what to do.
- Just move it!
- I got the canteen. It's ready.
We gotta get out of here!
The tide's coming in!
Wash the roots off. Be careful.
All right, let me have it.
- It's soaked.
- You did good. Put it right in there.
Little fella,
I'll have you home in no time.
No big breaks. We're in good shape.
- I just should have tied off better.
- It's not your fault.
Look, it was my idea to...
The ropes.
LaRusso! How you doing?
Heads up, Danny-boy.
Here's something you forgot.
How'd they get here?
- Hey, this isn't a joke anymore.
- I know.
So let the ropes down.
First sign the application.
Screw you, man!
See, I think you got it backwards,
buddy-boy.
I'm not the one who's screwed here.
Now I figure the tide's gonna come
in about 12 minutes.
Hope you brought a life raft.
How do we get out of here without a rope?
- Without a rope, we're dead.
- We're dead. Yeah, well, this guy's dead.
You're dead. You want me to sign it?
Fine, I'll sign it.
We'll get in the ring
and we'll see who's laughing then.
We'll see who's smiling.
You're gonna be dead meat.
I hate this guy.
Here. I signed it.
You want it? You work for it.
You pull us up!
All right! We'll send them down.
Let them go.
I never learn.
I should have just signed
the damn thing in the first place.
I should have signed it
and gotten it over with.
You didn't know this would happen.
With this guy, I should have known.
I should have known with that guy.
I should have just signed the damn thing.
We wouldn't be stuck down here.
The tree would be safe.
I'm just such a jackass.
Come on, get us out of here!
Come on, pull!
All right, I got you.
You're one heavy wimp, Daniel.
Come on, don't stop. Keep pulling!
- What are you doing?
- Pull us up.
Leave him there. Get the application.
No, you get the application
when I get up there.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
All right, here. Just hold us.
- Go get it.
- Here, take it.
Check it out.
It's cool.
That's it.
Don't even think about backing out, man...
...because then I'll really be pissed.
And this, well,
this'll all seem like a happy memory...
...compared to what I'd do to you.
And what we'd all do to her.
Now you're talking.
- Hey!
- Come on! Pull us up!
What, Tarzan?
Pull us up!
- What will you give me?
- I gave you the application.
Yeah, the stakes just went up.
- Give me the tree.
- Daniel, don't!
- No!
- Shut up!
All right.
Just hold us. Don't let go.
Here. Now please be careful with it.
- Please, be careful.
- I will be.
- What are you gonna do with it?
- I'm gonna plant it down there!
- No!
- No, don't, please.
All right, enough. Give me it.
- You want it?
- Just don't throw it over.
Be careful with it, please.
Daniel...
...make a wish.
No!
Mr. Miyagi?
Daniel-san.
The trunk's split. See?
I put the roots in peat moss,
but they got salt water on them...
...and I washed it.
Will you be able to save it?
I didn't mean for this to happen.
I'm sorry.
I just figured maybe we could sell it...
...so we wouldn't have to close.
I didn't want it to be my fault
your dream didn't come true.
Whoever bought it would take good care.
Even better care than yourself.
- Tape. A wide one.
- That's so stupid.
How can someone take care of it
better than where you left it?
- I didn't mean for this to happen.
- Hold.
- I'm sorry. Please forgive me.
- Miyagi forgive you.
You do? I'm such an idiot.
- Is it gonna be okay?
- Depends.
If roots strong, tree survive.
Where do you want these bonsai trees?
Over there on rack, okay. Thank you.
- Trees?
- Peat moss.
Trees? What? What did you do?
Did you buy these?
With what?
Sell truck.
You sold the truck?
Well, why didn't you tell me
that's what you were going to do?
I wake up this morning, you gone.
Damn it!
Why am I so stupid?
No worry, Daniel-san.
Everything work out.
Everything okay now.
Mr. Miyagi,
I signed to fight in the tournament.
Why?
I don't know why.
Because I'm not you, that's why.
I don't always have the right answers.
We were at the bottom.
They pulled the ropes up.
I made a decision on the spot.
It was the wrong one.
What else was I supposed to do?
Understand.
You do?
Listen, Mr. Miyagi,
I gotta be honest with you.
I don't stand a chance against this guy
unless you train me.
Understand.
Well then, you'll train me, right?
Daniel-san, Miyagi always train you.
But for tournament, cannot.
Cannot?
Cannot? What?
What do you mean, cannot?
Mr. Miyagi, why not?
You know what the worst thing was:
When he told me he wouldn't train me
for the tournament.
- Then I knew I was dead.
- What a drag.
Great, let me get some water.
I'm dying of thirst.
- You can't swallow.
- I won't.
You can't keep stopping like this.
You gotta build up your wind.
So bonehead can knock more out of me?
You gotta have more confidence.
- Remember you are the champion.
- Yeah, I'd like to forget it.
Jessica, this is...
Hi, there.
- Sorry, what's your name?
- Terry Silver.
Terry Silver, this is Jessica Andrews.
- You training for the Olympics?
- No, it's a tournament.
The one you won last year?
What's it called?
The All Valley.
Right. Good for you.
A champion should defend his title.
John Kreese told me you had a lot of heart.
Listen, do you know how to front sweep?
- Not really.
- Learn.
Most tournament guys
are suckers for the front sweep.
You can catch them every time.
Ask your Mr. Miyagi. He'll show you.
I'm kind of training for this one myself.
That's too bad.
I got a good book on sweep techniques.
I'll drop it off for you sometime.
Great.
Nice to meet you, Jessica.
Take care of our champion.
All right, I will. 'Bye.
That was a nice offer about the book.
Come on, you ready?
- Let's go. Yes.
- No, I'm pooped.
- All right, here I come.
- Come on. You're gorgeous. Hurry.
- Okay, I'm running.
- You gotta get some muscle.
Oh, man.
Get out of here! I signed it!
- Why'd you call the cops?
- Why'd you steal the trees?
You have no proof.
Who left the application, the tooth fairy?
It's your ass, man!
There's nothing you've got
that I can't counter.
- Your karate's a joke.
- Let him up, punk!
- Who are you, his mother?
- Maybe.
Get up! Get up!
You see this? You see it?
Get your hands off me!
If I see you even on the same street
as this kid...
...I won't be so charitable with your health.
- Understand?
- Yes!
Get the hell out of here.
Who is that guy?
- That's the lunatic who wants my title.
- Come on.
- I was hoping you would kill him.
- That's not what karate's about.
- It's for defence.
- I know, you're right.
- Here's your book.
- I brought that for you.
Right. Thanks.
There's only so much
you can learn from a book.
You're telling me.
Come on, stand up.
Let me show you a couple of moves.
Help you deal with punks like that.
Make a strong stance.
Back leg up a little more.
Okay, now sweep me.
- Well, what do you mean, like that?
- I'm not made of glass. Do it right.
Better.
Now a little higher
and at the end twist your hip.
Keep your hand up.
Are you okay?
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry, man.
- That's good.
That's a strong move.
Everyone needs a teacher, Daniel.
I'm opening the Cobra Kai dojo again.
It's time to set things straight.
Anytime you want to train,
I'll be there for you. No strings attached.
Thanks. I appreciate that, but...
Listen, thanks for helping me out.
It's my pleasure.
All right, I'll see you around.
I'll see you.
Thanks again.
- Hi, Jessica.
- Hi, Daniel.
Hey. Mr. Miyagi.
Listen, I have a favour to ask of you.
- Look, Jessica make. Beautiful. You like?
- I stayed up all night firing them.
I saw one the other night. They're great.
Listen, I have a favour to ask of you.
I just want to ask you,
do you know how to sweep?
Of course.
Would you mind showing me?
I'm not asking you to train me.
I don't want you to train me. One thing.
I'd be so appreciative.
All you have to give me is one thing.
That's it. Please, you gotta do it. Be a pal.
You wait here. I be right back.
Where you going?
Just wait here.
This is great.
Mr. Miyagi will teach me front sweeps.
I found out from this guy, tournament guys
are suckers for front sweeps.
- Really?
- I mean, if I get that down, man, I'm...
Daniel-san, you hold like this.
First, left sweep...
It's no joke, all right?
You don't want to show me,
you don't show me.
Just don't make fun of me, all right?
I'm sorry for asking.
Don't worry. It won't happen again.
- Hey.
- Hi, that was great, man.
- How you doing?
- Good.
- Just trying to work the rust out.
- Listen, I gave your offer some thought.
And?
If it's not too much trouble,
I'd like to take you up on it.
I mean,
you know, just on a short-term basis.
Trouble, are you kidding?
lt'd be an honour.
How does Mr. Miyagi feel about it?
Well, Mr. Miyagi...
...doesn't need to know about it, if...
- But he knows you're competing?
- He knows that.
He just doesn't approve.
Everybody has a right to his opinion.
- Look, I won't say anything.
- Thanks.
So, when do you want to start?
No, I mean, that's up to you.
Whenever it's...
I got a gi hanging in the closet.
I think it'll fit.
What do you say we go right now?
Now?
One more.
Good. Catch your breath.
Come on over here.
You're better than I thought.
You're ready to move on, Mr. LaRusso.
You're ready to move on.
There are three things
that make a champion.
The three "D"s:
Desire, devotion and discipline.
The first two I can't give you.
The last one I can,
but you have to be willing to receive it.
Are you, Mr. LaRusso?
Sure.
The response you're looking for is,
"Yes, sir."
- Right. Yes, sir. I'm sorry.
- That's okay. Stand up straight.
Now, over the years I've developed
a system of intensive short-term training...
...for situations just like this.
It comes in two parts and has three rules.
- I call it "Quick Silver."
- That's good.
You like that, huh?
Rule Number One:
A man can't stand, he can't fight.
Repeat it.
With conviction, Mr. LaRusso.
- A man can't stand, he can't fight.
- Good. All right.
Imagine these two-by-fours are legs.
Sweep them.
What are you...
That's too low.
Any higher it'd be like hitting the knee.
Right?
Did you come here
to teach or to be taught?
We're not sweeping floors here. Harder.
Come on, put your hip into it.
That's where the power is.
That's it. Harder.
Harder.
"Ow" is not an acceptable kiai in this dojo,
Mr. LaRusso.
Isn't this a little bit extreme, sir?
I mean, come on.
Extreme situations
require extreme measures.
Now, you come back tomorrow.
We'll start again.
You did good for your first day.
Thanks.
I really appreciate all your help.
- Thanks again.
- You're welcome.
Who is it?
Why don't you come in?
Just catching up on some sit-ups here.
You know, it's not easy
when you're training yourself.
What happened foot?
What foot?
Look at that!
I don't know.
Maybe I banged it in my sleep.
I don't remember.
- What's that?
- You soak foot.
Be better tomorrow.
- You got a new foot in there for me?
- No. Next best thing. New foot powder.
Smells like old foot powder.
What's in there?
Better you don't know. Give me foot.
- It's hot!
- Hot, hot...
Good.
Maybe tomorrow
you remember what happened foot?
Then you tell Miyagi.
Tomorrow? No.
I have so many things to do tomorrow.
Tomorrow, I'm busy.
Tomorrow is a bad day.
In the morning, I'm supposed to...
In the afternoon, I'm meeting with
a buddy of mine I haven't seen since...
...we got back, you know, from Okinawa.
What am I doing?
Hope confusion end soon.
Miyagi heart empty without you.
The bruise on your foot is gone.
That's good. You're a fast healer.
All right, let's go.
That's a nice move.
Mr. Miyagi teach you that?
- No.
- I didn't think so.
- What was the last thing he taught you?
- We did kata.
- Kata?
- Yeah.
Kata is good for working up a sweat.
It won't win the tournament.
Come on over here. Hold the bag.
Rule Number Two
of the "Quick Silver" method:
A man can't breathe, he can't fight.
Now, imagine this is the enemy.
These are his ribs, behind them his lungs.
- You got it?
- Yeah.
Good. You try it.
Wait a minute. Let's do it over here.
- Where?
- Right here, his ribs.
Lay into him.
Why do I have to do this with this thing?
Because it's part of the training.
Because I'm teaching you
techniques you don't have.
Techniques you need
to win the tournament.
What, do you think you can rely
on that crane crap?
I did pretty well with it last time.
Wake up and smell the coffee.
Last time you weren't fighting this.
You don't get it, do you?
If you want to lose because of a little pain,
I can't be a part of that.
I make wimps into winners,
not the other way around.
Christ, I'm wasting my time.
Yeah?
Damn it! Can you come back later?
Why are you doing this to yourself?
Doing what?
What you doing.
Because...
...extreme situations
require extreme measures, okay?
That not sound like you talking.
It is me talking, all right?
I'm sorry if you don't like it,
but I got problems...
...and if you won't be part of the solution,
don't give me a hard time.
Okay? You got it?
What are you wasting your time
with kata for?
Didn't I tell you
it's useless in a tournament?
- Yes, sir!
- Yes, sir. You're right. I'm sorry.
All right. Come over here.
Let's get back to learning something
that can do some real damage.
Rule Number Three:
A man can't see, he can't fight.
If you hit him square in the nose...
...he'll be blinded by his tears
and choke on his own blood.
Here's how it works.
You wait until your man is attacking
and when he's close enough...
But that would be face contact.
I'd be disqualified.
- He ran into your fist, not your fault, right?
- Right.
He can't continue. That means you win.
- You like that?
- I like that.
Good. Give it a shot.
Let's try it over here on your friend.
Reverse punch.
Visualise.
This isn't a bunch of sticks
and pipes anymore.
This is a living fighting machine
that wants to detach...
...your head from the rest of your body!
It's blood. So what?
Make believe it's his.
This guy wants to break you.
Humiliate you. Stomp you into the ground.
What are you going to do about it?
- Gonna nail him!
- Then do it.
- Yes! You did it!
- I did it, man!
You nailed him!
- You're ready!
- I'm ready!
- What new teacher?
- The guy who's been training me.
You met him. We were jogging
and he pulled up in the car.
I know who you are talking about.
He's teaching me stuff
I thought I'd never be able to do.
- That's what you said about Mr. Miyagi.
- But this guy's different.
- How do you mean "different"?
- I'll show you sometime.
- Come on, let's rock 'n' roll.
- All right, let's do it.
What are you looking at?
What are you doing
looking at other guys like that for?
I don't play that.
- I got some nerve?
- You got some nerve...
What about you?
- No, you get...
- Get out of my way, white boy!
If I don't get something to drink,
I'm gonna die.
Tell me. I could drink a horse.
- Mr. Silver, what are you doing here?
- You told me you'd be here, remember?
- Hold up, sexy lady.
- Who's your friend?
- I've been watching you and you are hot.
- She's with me, man.
- Says who?
- Says me.
I'm taking her home.
What are you doing?
What is wrong with you?
What, are you nuts?
Come on. We gotta get out of here!
Up you go.
- What happened?
- He broke my nose, man.
Where's that guy with my money?
Get out of the way!
Man, that was beautiful.
You didn't even think.
Something got in your way, bang!
Down it went!
I gotta go back in there.
- What are you saying?
- I gotta check that guy out.
Technique and killer instinct.
You got it all now, kid.
- No, I gotta get out of here.
- Where you going?
What's wrong? You did the right thing.
You had no choice.
Who is it?
It's me, it's Daniel.
What do you want?
- Can I talk to you?
- I'm busy.
Just give me a minute. Please.
I want to apologise for tonight.
It shouldn't have happened.
You should tell that to the guy
whose nose you broke.
I am. I will.
I just didn't want you leaving
thinking that was me.
It wasn't you?
Then who was it? Conan the Barbarian?
I've been trying to be someone I'm not
and it's not working.
I feel like I'm losing control of everything.
The only thing I see you losing control of
is your temper.
Well, and your friendship
and Mr. Miyagi's trust.
I've lost everything.
I don't know what to do.
I've wrecked everything with Mr. Miyagi.
I know he's written me off.
And I can't blame him. I don't blame him.
I don't know what the hell I'm going to do.
Nobody's written you off.
Just because I got upset
doesn't mean I'm not your friend anymore.
Mr. Miyagi, he loves you.
He has faith in you. He told me that.
Let's see how much faith he has
when he hears about what I did tonight.
- I think he should hear it from you first.
- It's too late. I blew it. It's blown.
You're gonna blow,
unless you do something about it now.
I know, you're right. It's easy to say.
It's just, I don't know if I could face him.
You'll do fine.
You just gotta do it.
Well, I don't know if I can.
I'm gonna miss you.
Send me a Christmas card, okay?
You got a deal.
- 'Bye.
Thanks.
Anytime.
I just told the other nurse
that I don't know his name.
I'm the guy who broke his nose.
I need to talk to him.
I need to tell him I'm sorry
and that I want to pay for it.
Please, let me speak with him.
No, I can't wait until tomorrow, all right.
I gotta talk to him now, damn it!
All right. I'm sorry, okay?
I don't mean to be rude, I'm...
Hello, miss?
Look at this.
Look at my sweatshirt.
I got some poor guy's blood all over me.
Everything you taught me,
I did the opposite.
I couldn't have been worse.
I did everything wrong.
I just feel like your tree.
You know, the one that I wrecked.
I feel just like that.
I feel like I'm falling apart.
Miyagi show you something.
I feel like the whole world
is coming down on me.
It's all my fault. I did it myself.
Everything can heal. Just take time.
Take patience.
I'm sorry. When I started out
I never meant for it to end the way it did.
Sometime when take trip,
better know where trip end.
Otherwise better just stay home.
It's budding.
Look at that, it's gonna make it.
Make it because have strong root.
Just like you, Daniel-san.
Inside you have strong root.
No need nothing
except what inside you to grow.
Understand?
I do understand.
You're right.
I gotta go. I'll be right back.
I'll just be a little while.
Where going?
You remember that guy, Terry Silver?
He's the one that's been training me.
He meant well,
but I want to tell him it's over.
- It not wait for tomorrow?
- I'll feel better if I get it over with now.
You like Miyagi come help you?
No, I did it myself.
I'll get out of it myself, all right?
I'll be back in a little while.
Hello.
Mr. Silver?
Hello?
Hey.
- Hi.
- Here you are.
- Where'd you go?
- I had to go think about some things.
- And...
- And?
And I've...
Listen, I've decided not to defend my title.
I really appreciate
everything you've done for me.
I mean, you've been great. I just...
You know, when I hit that guy,
that's just not me.
I just wanted to come here
and tell you in person...
...'cause I figured after everything,
I owed you at least that.
You owe me a lot more than that,
Danny-boy.
I'm sorry.
I thought the lessons were free, but...
No. Nothing's for free.
You are going to defend.
You're getting in that ring.
Excuse me, Mr. Silver...
...you can't make me do something
I don't want to do.
Danny.
Since you met me, I've made you do things
you didn't want to do.
What are you talking about?
- What am I talking about?
- Yeah, what?
Let's show him what I'm talking about.
I'm what he's talking about, shithead.
- We have a simple agenda here.
- You're crazy.
Either you fight one fight
or fight for the rest of your life.
- You're sick!
- What's it gonna be?
I'm not gonna be there.
So just forget about it, all right?
Let's show Mr. Kreese
how he's going to get his business back.
- I won't fight.
- You don't have to.
You can just stand there
and let him kick your ass.
- Do the crane, Danny-boy!
- You're doing this to yourself, man.
Yes!
- You wanna see some more?
- I wanna see a lot more.
Bring him back.
You see his face?
See the trail? I think he peed in his pants!
Well, look who's here. The big war hero.
What are you waiting for?
Party time.
We're old friends.
Come on, little man.
Let's see how good you really are.
You think this is the end of it, old man?
I'm going to open Cobra Kai dojos
all over this valley.
Hell, I might even teach for free.
From now on when people say
karate around here...
...all they'll mean is Cobra Kai karate.
John Kreese's karate.
You won't even be a memory.
Yes, he will. You won't.
Now will you train me?
Now Miyagi train you.
Come. Waste time here.
We plant tree here.
- You take tree.
- All set.
- Careful.
- I got it.
Happy to be home, old fella? Yeah, I bet.
Let's get this crummy plastic bag off you.
Put you back where you belong.
There you go.
Nice comfortable spot.
- That feel good?
- Good spot, Daniel-san.
I got just what you need.
A nice cool drink.
Let some of your old roots soak that up.
Daniel-san, this bonsai have strong root.
Same you.
This tree now choose how it grow.
So must you choose how you grow.
Miyagi have great faith in you.
Understand?
Come on, Daniel-san.
See you around, old fella.
Point Barnes!
The score is 2-0.
- Let's do it up, do it right!
- Ready? Begin!
- Did you teach him that?
- No, that one is his.
A warning for a kick to the groin.
Once more, costs you a point.
Fighting positions. Ready? Begin!
Three points for Barnes.
- Danny-boy's gonna get murdered up there.
- Winner!
Face me. Bow.
Shake hands.
You're next, LaRusso. I own your ass.
While we wait for the challenger
to catch his breath...
T-shirts! Get your Cobra Kai T-shirts!
... I'd like to thank a new patron of ours
for the purchase and donation...
... of the permanent home
of the All Valley Championships.
Ladies and gentlemen, the president
of Dyna-tox Industries, Mr. Terry Silver.
Yeah, Mr. Silver!
Thank you, John.
Thank you very much.
I've always lived my life by the rule:
"If you get, you give."
For the last 20 years,
I've gotten from karate.
I've gotten discipline...
... health, self-confidence...
... inner peace.
Everything that makes me
what I am today.
And today, it's time for me to give back.
It's my pleasure to announce
my partnership with the greatest...
... karate man I have ever known,
Sensei John Kreese.
Yeah, Mr. Kreese.
Together, we are about to open
a chain of Cobra Kai dojos...
... where young people can come
and learn the same values I've learned:
Honesty...
... compassion...
... and fair play.
Thank you all for coming.
Enjoy the final match.
Thank you, Mr. Silver.
And thank you again
for your most generous contribution.
Remember the game plan.
First you win a point,
then you lose a point.
Keep the score 0-0.
Pulverise him for the full three minutes.
Then in sudden death,
you get the point, we win.
I want him to experience pain.
- First he suffers.
- Then he suffers some more.
Representing the Cobra Kai,
the challenger, Mike Barnes.
And in this corner,
someone who needs no introduction...
... the defending champion
from the Miyagi dojo...
... Daniel LaRusso.
This match will have
a three-minute time limit.
The first fighter to score three points
will be designated this year's...
... All Valley Under-18 Champion.
- Fighters to your marks!
- Go out there and get him.
Flatten him out, Mike. Fight him!
Remember, folks, the new rule this year
states that if there is no winner...
... at the end of three minutes
the championship match will go...
... into sudden-death overtime.
When it's over,
his mother won't recognise him.
You both know the rules.
Light contact is allowed to the body,
and I do mean light, Mr. Barnes.
No face contact is allowed.
Any violation of the rules
will result in a penalty point.
On your lines.
Come on, Daniel!
Face this way, bow. Face each other, bow.
I said bow.
Fighting positions. Ready? Begin!
Break, break! Let's go.
Out of the ring. No point.
Begin!
Point, Barnes.
Score: 1-0.
Look over at the slope.
Is that perfect?
One point Barnes for the punch.
Fighting positions.
Begin!
Danny-boy, how are the family jewels?
Get off the mat! Now! Get off the mat!
Do that again, Barnes,
and you're disqualified.
That illegal groin kick
will cost Barnes his previous point.
Score is now 0-0.
Kick to the groin. Penalty point.
- Score is 0-0.
- You're dirty, Barnes.
- He'll get you 'cause you're dirty.
- Fighting positions. Ready? Begin!
That's the one, Mike.
Barnes scores the point. Reverse punch.
Go, Daniel!
Come on, Daniel.
Let's go, LaRusso.
Point Barnes.
Score is 1-0. Ready?
Come on, Mike, you got him.
Begin!
Break, break!
On your line!
That's it, Barnes.
One more violation and you're disqualified.
That illegal punch
will cost Barnes one point.
The score is again 0-0.
You all right, LaRusso?
Intentional face contact, penalty point.
- Perfect.
- Score is 0-0.
Fighting positions.
Ready? Begin!
Now the real pain begins, Danny-boy.
On your lines.
That's a warning
for running out of the ring.
Come on, Barnes!
Fighting positions. Ready? Begin!
Break! Break!
On your line.
He'll get up.
He's too dumb not to.
LaRusso, on your line.
Get up, you pansy-ass!
- No point for kick to the back.
- No point scored.
- This is beautiful. It's beautiful.
- Fighting positions. Ready? Begin!
Break!
What's the matter, you can't breathe?
- On your line.
- I love it when he pounds him!
- This is more fun than I thought.
No clean technique on that exchange.
No point scored.
The score remains 0-0.
Ten seconds left in the match.
- Let's go, Danny.
- Fighting positions.
- You gotta turn it around.
- Ready? Begin!
Time!
Break!
There will be a one-minute rest period.
Then the match will continue
with sudden death.
- Daniel-san!
- Mr. Miyagi, it's over.
- No!
- It's over, forget it.
- I'm afraid. Let's go.
- I want to go home.
- Can't! You must not!
Is okay to lose to opponent.
- Must not lose to fear!
- Yeah, well, I'm afraid!
I'm afraid of him, all right?
What do you want me to do?
You stay focused.
Daniel-san,
your best karate is still inside you.
Now time let out!
That's the end of the rest period.
- Fighters on your lines.
- Come on, get up!
Get on that line!
Get on that line, LaRusso!
You're worthless!
Your slope teacher's nothing!
Get up, man!
You're no champion. Get up!
You suck, LaRusso! You suck, man!
And your teacher's karate is shit.
You hear me? He's shit!
You're done, LaRusso.
Your karate is a joke.
And your teacher's worth shit.
He's nothing! And you're nothing!
I own you! I own you, LaRusso!
Where's your little Jap teacher now?
He's a phoney, man.
He's a fake
and he didn't teach you nothing.
Your karate's shit. You hear me?
Get up!
Come on, Mike!
This is what we've been waiting for!
Fighting positions.
Ready?
Begin!
Mike! Take him out!
Hit him!
Get the point! Get the point!
Hit him, Mike! He's hallucinating.
Winner!
The winner and the first to ever win
two years in a row...
... the grand champion, Daniel LaRusso.
Mr. Miyagi, forget about it!
We did it! We did it!
Subtitles by SOFTITLER