'Cause he's an asshole!
Tell him no.
Tell him no, too.
Him,
tell fuck you.
No, I'll be here
a minute.
Got some guy coming up
who thinks he'll muscle me
out of my property.
Another tough guy,
that's all.
They're driving up.
Get their pieces.
Hmm.
We got a surprise
for these gentlemen.
Robert Durant,
you and your girls are going
to stand for a search.
All right, move it.
There you go.
Oh, a bunch of cuties,
huh?
Just hold it
there, cueball.
Bum leg?
No leg.
I was engaged to a girl
with a wooden leg.
What happened?
Had to break it off.
All right, cut the crap.
I got three things
to say to you, Durant.
One,
I ain't selling
my property.
Two, nobody
muscles Eddie Black,
especially
a bunch of dinks.
And three, if y'alls
don't like that,
which I can already
see you don't,
we can cut
your balls off.
Maybe that would be
more satisfactory to you.
Ha ha ha ha!
Die!
Take them down!
Take him down!
Take that one
with the goddamn gun!
Now...
let's consider
my points...
one by one.
One.
I try not to let
my anger
get the better
of me.
Two.
I don't always
succeed.
Three.
I've got seven
more points.
System ready
to receive input.
Just hold together,
you little...
shit.
Fragmentation.
Time?
99 minutes...
again.
Why?
Why, why, why?
Synthetic skin
data analysis...
What is
destabilizing it?
Why won't the liquid
skin last?
The vivification process
was easy.
Tissue rejection?
We licked that.
I know we're close.
We're smart guys,
so what is it?
Why can't we make
these cells stable?
What now?
Now?
Well...
we think it out again.
Patiently.
Objectively.
I don't care how long
it takes, Yakitito,
I know it's out there
waiting for us.
Ah, I can feel it.
God, I can almost
taste it.
Here she is... the
girl of your dreams.
Oh! Oh, Peyton!
Ah, you were sweet.
How's the skin coming?
Still won't last
past 99.
It'll happen. It will
happen, you know.
Ha ha ha!
Look at you.
Rebel without a clue.
Those were the days.
Hey...
What?
Come here.
Oh, I know what's
on your mind.
God, you always wear
things that are
so difficult to...
Ta-da!
Oh, yeah!
Come on,
let's dance.
Herb Gorson, please.
Here you go, babe.
Peyton!
Oops. Sorry.
Yeah?
Herb, hi.
It's Julie Hastings.
Listen,
I found some memos
when I was researching
the Von Hoffenstein deal
that I don't think
I was supposed to find.
They're from Strack
to a guy named...
Claude Bellasarious.
They're records
of payments
to various people
on the Zoning Commission.
Well, I think
they're payoffs.
Yeah, well,
what I want to do
is talk
to Strack first,
give him the benefit
of the doubt.
Yeah, O.K.
All right, I'll talk
to you later, Herb.
Bye, Herb.
Oh, I don't want to go.
Don't go.
I have to go.
I have to go now!
I'm late.
Julie!
I'll call you
later.
Maybe.
Julie!
Julie, wait.
What is it?
I've been thinking.
Mm-hmm.
We should get married.
Marriage?
Uh-huh.
I've just started
getting things going at the firm,
and I really like
having my own place.
We're practically
living together now.
All marriage means
is you answer the phone
in the morning,
and if
it's my grandmother,
you don't pretend
it's the wrong number.
The woman thinks
she has Alzheimer's.
I can't talk
about it now.
Jules, I'm asking you
to marry me.
Peyton, I love you...
I realized...
but I got to
think it over, O.K.?
Mr. Strack, I've been
going over
some documents.
I've come across
something
that puzzles me.
It's a memo
from your office
to a Mr. Claude
Bellasarious.
It details certain
payments that...
Yes, I know the memo.
It seems like
the payments were...
were payoffs
to the Zoning Commission.
Bribes, to call
a spade a spade.
Does that shock you?
No. I guessed as much.
You weren't supposed
to know about it.
That file was not
supposed to circulate.
However, I am asking you
to understand.
Take a look
at that model, Julie.
That's the dream...
acres of riverfront
reclaimed from decay,
thousands of jobs
created.
A building block,
a very large building block
laid for the future.
Not such a bad dream,
as dreams go.
And if the price
of realizing that dream
is the occasional
distasteful chore,
well, I don't run away.
I say so be it.
So...
want to book me?
The fact remains
that I'm in possession
of evidence of the
commission of a crime.
Let me suggest this...
you excuse yourself
for few minutes,
go to the ladies room
leaving your briefcase here.
What happens
to that memorandum
while it's
in my custody
is my responsibility.
I wish it were
that simple,
but I don't have
the memo with me.
I'm trying to protect you.
Does the name
Robert Durant
mean anything to you?
Drugs, racketeering...
and real estate.
Robert Durant is a competitor
for the riverfront.
He's a very
dangerous man, Julie.
I fully believe
he'd do anything
to get his hands
on that document.
DNA content...
acceptable.
Glucose...
right on.
We've
even checked
the collagen
congeners.
They're fine.
This is
unbelievable.
Every day,
it's a different
combination.
Time, Yakitito.
Time.
98 minutes.
Oh...
the circuit again.
I'll fix it.
I knew we pulled
too much juice
on that line.
Yakitito, time.
Huh?
Time?
99.
100 minutes!
What? What?
The cells,
they're holding.
They're stable!
But, Dr. Westlake,
why now?
The dark.
Oh, of course.
I think the
synthetic cells
are
photosensitive.
This is
unbelievable!
What is it
about the dark?
What secret
does it hold?
They're still
stable.
Time, Yakitito,
Time!
101 minutes.
Finally...
we can replace
damaged skin tissue!
No, Yakitito,
not quite, my friend.
We've just got
a piece of the puzzle.
There's still
the big question...
how to keep
the cells stable
past 99 minutes
in the light?
Now we know
it's all about light!
I'll get it.
No foolish heroics,
if you please.
We've come
only for documents.
Tell us where to find
the Bellasarious
memorandum,
and we shall disappear
like a nightmare
before the breaking day.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Unfortunate.
What memorandum?
No, please.
We want
the memorandum.
Should your houseboy's
predicament
not jog your memory...
you may bid him
Godspeed.
He's a lab assistant.
For God's sakes,
let him breathe!
You heard the doctor.
Ventilate him.
No...
No!
Ooh! Ooh!
Bingo.
Goody!
Bring the Asian's fingers.
Gentlemen.
Rick, I'm proud of you.
Clean through the brain...
that's how I like it.
"Marry me?"
Didn't see you
doing much work.
That guy got
blown to pieces.
All they found
was an ear.
Tiny little
piece.
Didn't take long
to bury that.
You'll be all right.
We'll need
some sponges.
O.K., I got 'em.
Great.
We'll get ready.
Let's check
the eyes.
Get a gurney
in here.
Right there.
Straight in.
Next, we have
a 30, 35-year-old male,
no I.D.,
no medical history.
He was found
on the riverbank
just south of the city.
There are homeless
and indigents there.
We get three no-names
every week.
Nobody does anything until
they become train wrecks
like Mr. John Doe here.
He's got burns
covering 40% of his body.
The hands and face
are the most severe.
Ten years ago,
pain from the burns
would have been intolerable.
He would have spent
his life screaming.
Now we use
the Rangeveritz Technique.
Quite simply,
we sever the nerves within
the spino-thalamic tract,
there... which, as you know,
transmits neural impulses
of pain and vibratory sense
to the brain.
No longer receiving
impulses of pain,
you stick him
with a pin...
Ouch.
and he can't
even feel it.
As in many
radical procedures,
there are serious side
effects to this operation.
When the body
ceases to feel,
when so much
sensory input is lost,
the mind grows hungry.
Starved of
its regular diet of input,
it takes the only remaining
stimulation it has...
the emotions...
and amplifies them,
giving rise to alienation
and loneliness.
Uncontrolled rage
is not uncommon.
Now surges of adrenaline
flow unchecked
through the body and brain,
giving him
augmented strength.
Hence, the restraints.
Naturally, we give them
every chance of recovery.
Remain optimistic,
inspire confidence,
talk to him about
rehabilitation potential.
Personally, I give him a 9
on the buzzard scale.
Code blue, burn unit.
Doctor?
I'm in charge here.
Damn it,
let me through!
Ju... lie.
Julie!
It's...
me!
My lab.
All my work.
Oh, my God, no.
No! No!
No! No! No!
Hello, my friend.
Home.
Good. Good.
System re...
System... System ready
for digitization program.
Enter code.
O.K.
Digitalization
in progress.
In progress.
Insufficient data.
Oh, God.
Oh, no, please.
Please, no.
Quadrant A, Quadrant C
unrecognizable.
What am I doing
wrong?
What?
Yes.
Quadrants.
Extrapolate.
Yes.
Quadrant recognition
active.
Digitization
in progress.
Yes, that's it.
Clever, clever.
I must perfect the skin.
Wrong!
My hands.
They took...
They took my hands.
They... They took...
They took my hands!
Thank you for coming.
Julie... with what you've
been going through lately,
I, uh...
I haven't wanted
to bother you.
But I have to know
whether you've come
to a decision
regarding the Bellasarious
memorandum.
The decision's been
made for both of us.
The papers were
destroyed in the fire.
And I'd rather not
talk about it,
if you don't mind.
Julie, I'm sorry
I mentioned that.
Believe me,
I understand
how you feel.
I really do.
Unfortunately,
there's no cure
for grief.
But there is
something
that eases
the symptoms.
It's called dancing.
Would you, uh,
like a martini?
Yes.
I would love one.
Ventilate him.
His name's
Robert G. Durant!
I told you where
they make the pickup!
Oh, God! Don't!
I've told you
everything!
I know, Rick.
I know you did.
But let's pretend
you didn't!
Here you are, doll.
Here's your favorite.
How you doing, honey?
I'm pretty good today.
It wasn't that bad.
Hey, Pauly.
¿Que pasa?
How are you, man?
Where's Rick?
Here's the cash, man.
Got you a gift,
huh?
You be good.
I'll see ya.
See you later, pal.
System ready for
digitization program.
Enter code.
Code... Code recognized.
Data entry required.
System standing by.
It's time.
Yeah.
Yo, Pauly.
Hey, Durant wants to know
where Rick is,
and he is hot.
I mean really hot.
Don't ask me why.
I know
he likes Ricky.
Pauly, do you know
where the hell Rick is?
Mmm-mmm.
You O.K., Pauly?
Yeah.
Here's the cash.
Pauly, we've been very
concerned about you.
Hey, Mr. Durant.
I must've overslept.
I'm sorry. I guess
I missed the pickup, huh?
Where's the money,
Pauly?
What money? I... I didn't
make the pickup.
Rio.
And first class.
How delightful.
And another one
for Rick.
Well. That explains
his disappearance.
Hey, I don't know
nothing about that.
Where is the money, Pauly?
What money?
I swear, Mr. Durant,
I didn't make
the pickup.
I've been here sleeping.
Jesus,
I swear to God.
Why... I don't even know
how I got dressed!
Well, Pauly...
have a nice flight.
Oh, God. What have I become?
What have I become?
Please.
Hold. Please hold.
Oh, just this once.
Oh, what?
What am I?
What am I, hmm?
Some kind of a circus freak?
Is that it?
Is that it? Huh?
Some kind of a freak?
Maybe I should wear
a funny little hat.
Do you like it?
Yeah? Yeah?
See the dancing freak
Pay five bucks
To see the dancing freak
Only five bucks
Just five bucks
I'll give you a show!
I'll give you
a goddamned show!
Yeah!
I'll show you
I'm not a freak!
Yeah!
Oh, God.
Oh, Jesus, God.
Oh, keep a lid on it!
I'm a scientist.
Uh-huh. That's it.
Think objectively.
Analyze. Analyze.
Wait. Wait. That's it.
Control the rage.
Just...
take it easy, Peyton.
take it easy, boy.
I'm a scientist.
Reconstruction program...
Reconstruction program complete.
Julie.
No.
It's all right, Julie.
It's me, sweetheart.
No.
Please, Julie, please.
Don't be afraid.
Listen to me.
Who are you?
It's me.
Peyton.
You... are dead.
No, no, Jules. No.
I was in the hospital.
A coma.
Dead to the world.
Jules... please.
Please.
Please hold me.
Oh, I'm...
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I didn't know
how to tell you.
I needed to see you.
I needed to know if things
could be the same.
Yes. But, Peyton,
I don't understand.
Shh.
I know it's a shock.
There's so much to it.
And I'll tell you
everything.
I just need
a little time.
Then just hold me,
Peyton, and don't let go.
I just... I just need
a little time.
I understand why
the doctors said
you shouldn't see me
after the coma.
That's their opinion.
What's yours?
I've got to have time
to work this out,
Julie...
on my own.
But where does that
leave us, Peyton?
I don't want to be
without you again.
I need you, too, Jules.
That's why I'm here.
It's just that I've...
I feel like a rag doll
all pieced together.
My insides
are on my outside.
If you could only see
how I feel inside.
I was ashamed. Afraid.
I was afraid
that you wouldn't
want me anymore.
Of course
I still want you.
Julie...
Julie,
what if I was hurt?
Like...
Like horribly scarred,
that you couldn't bear
to look at me
or have me touch you.
What then, huh?
Huh?
I don't know.
Honestly,
I don't know, Peyt.
But why do you
ask me that?
Look at you. You're fine.
And you're back.
Yes. I am back,
aren't I?
Just like always.
Yeah, what do you
want, buddy?
The name isn't Buddy.
It's Durant,
Robert G. Durant,
and I wish to speak
to Mr. Guzman.
O.K.
Thank you.
Rudy, some asshole's
on the phone for you.
Hey, Mr. Durant.
Ah, Rudy.
Pay attention.
Don't speak. Listen.
The funds Pauly
misappropriated
are beginning
to nettle me.
He's caused a serious
cash flow problem.
Did you receive
certain monies
from Chinatown today?
No, not today.
Unfortunate.
Then we shall have
to call upon Hung Fat.
Either he provides
the revenues owed to us,
or he becomes
part of my collection.
It would make
a nice addition.
Ha ha.
That's right.
You want me
to pick you up
at your place
tomorrow morning
around 8:30?
That would be...
just fine.
Just fine.
Would you like a bag
for this, buddy?
That would be...
just fine.
Hey, hey,
take it easy, buddy.
My name isn't Buddy.
It's Durant.
Robert G. Durant.
Yes.
I'm Robert G. Durant.
Just fine.
Robert.
It's so good of you
to favor me
with your
venerated presence.
The money.
The money? Yes, Robert.
How I tremble
with shame.
I have no money.
How many times
do I have to tell you?
I was nowhere near
any convenience store!
They had the whole thing
on video.
Keep them
out of my hair!
You have to sign
those papers.
Where are you going?
Hong Kong Restaurant,
and fast!
White powder no longer flows
in its former volume.
All the members of Tong
languish in poverty.
Of all your
unworthy servants,
Hung Fat is
the most destitute.
Even my own
miserable slaves
sometimes ignore
my wishes
and upset those whom
I cherish most deeply.
So, until
that shining day...
may it soon come...
when I shall once again
honor you with offerings...
goodbye, Robert.
Robert, goodbye.
You will provide
the revenues owed to us
by the time
I finish this cigar.
But, Robert...
O.K., Bob, you win.
Damn! Drive!
Can't go no further.
Sorry.
It's a parade.
I'll get there myself.
What about
the fare?
Eat it!
Move!
Move it!
Where is he?
Where's who?
Guzman!
I thought
he was with you.
Shit!
Dios mio! ¿Que pasa?
There's two of those
son of a bitches!
Shoot him!
Which one is Durant?
Not me, him!
Shoot him!
Goddamn it!
Whose little boy are you?
It doesn't matter.
You're dead!
No, no. This one.
Don't just stand there.
Do something!
Son of a bitch sets
me up with the cops,
and you practically
hand him the cash.
Madre mia!
Mr. Durant, I'm sorry.
Step right up and take
a spin on the amazing...
Come on!
One more!
Would you stop looking
at that watch?
To hell with time!
Forget about going
back to the hospital.
We're going to spend
the whole day together.
And the whole night.
I can't. I've got
my therapy group.
Peyton, we need
more time together.
Why are you so
uncomfortable with me?
All right, Jules.
Listen to me.
I got to tell you
something about me,
how I've...
changed.
When I was
in the hospital, I...
See the mutant man!
Half man, half beast!
Witness this cruel
accident of science
with your own eyes.
Everybody gather 'round
and look closely.
As you can see...
Peyt, what?
Peyton, what is it?
When I was
in the hospital...
was there
someone else?
No.
Yes. There was a man
who comforted me,
and I respected him
for his kindness,
but he means
nothing to me.
Is that what it was?
Was that it, Peyt?
God, I love you,
darling!
Oh, it's good
to be back.
Come on,
Julie Hastings,
I'm going to win
for you the biggest,
fuzziest, pinkest
doll on that rack.
Yes.
Then I
got to run.
You always
have to run.
Why is it always
so dramatic?
I have my hospital
sessions.
I'm not 100% cured yet,
but I soon will be.
Where is
this place exactly?
I want to be
involved somehow.
Can I take you there?
No. Please, Julie,
I don't want you
to see me there.
I don't want you to think
of me as an invalid
or some kind of a freak.
Uh, the pink
elephant, please.
It don't count unless
you're behind the line.
I was
behind the line.
Not hardly.
I was standing right
here with my girlfriend.
Now, the pink elephant,
if you please.
No way.
It doesn't matter,
Peyton.
It matters.
I won a pink elephant
for my girlfriend.
Why don't you
just, uh...
get lost, pal?
The elephant.
Quickly.
Didn't you hear me...
weirdo?
Scram.
Take it! Take it!
Take the fucking elephant!
Please, no!
Forgive me.
Peyton, wait!
Half man and a freak.
He's a freak,
ladies and gentlemen,
he's a freak.
A freak.
Peyton.
Peyton?
Synthetic skin
data analysis.
Amino acid content
equals 64%.
Membrane potential equals
122 megavolts.
Destabilization
registering at 99.008.
Why didn't you
tell me, Peyton?
You should have
told me.
come to me, Peyt.
You didn't
have to lie.
Peyton.
I would have tried
to help you.
I can help you now.
You don't have to hide
from me anymore, Peyt.
Julie.
Louis,
we have to talk.
Excellent.
I love to talk.
Brandy?
No.
I'll have one.
It's Napoleon,
and it's
quite good.
I can't see you anymore.
Honey, take it easy.
As you say,
let's... let's talk.
You know about Peyton,
the man I was
involved with?
Of course.
He's alive.
He's back.
I won't be a moment.
Yes?
Franz,
this is a bad time.
The closing price?
I think it's
sufficiently diversified.
It's immaterial to me
what the market's doing.
I want you to buy.
10,000 krugerrands.
Fresh ones.
Yes. The Bellasarious
memorandum.
I'm sorry you had
to find that, Julie.
Our relationship didn't
need this further strain.
You burned
Peyton's lab.
Not me personally.
I have an employee who does
certain things for me,
unofficially,
off the books.
Robert doesn't
like to pay taxes.
And now you'll kill me.
Hardly.
You have nothing on me.
You'd find the extremely
expensive police department
quite unsympathetic.
Julie, consider
the big picture.
Consider what
we're building here.
You and I,
we're building a city.
We can't let anything
get in the way of that.
Despite the way
things might appear,
you can't pretend
certain moments haven't
passed between us.
We still have that.
If you're not
going to kill me...
I have things to do.
I suppose this is
goodbye then.
Send Robert in.
Yes, Mr. Strack.
Robert, I have
good news and bad.
Custom dictates that you
render the bad news first.
We have a little problem
with Miss Hastings.
It appears she has
uncovered our alliance.
No problem at all.
And the good news?
Your wife died.
I'm joking, of course.
No. The good news
is that I know
who's behind our little
troubles of late.
When you retrieved
my memorandum,
you failed to excise
the good doctor.
Westlake?
He's extinct.
I saw to it myself.
He's alive.
I don't like
loose ends, Robert.
Finish it.
Where is he?
I believe we have a guide.
Julie!
Look out!
I think he's out here!
He just went
on the roof!
Julie!
Oh, you've got to be
shitting me.
Hey, Smiley, he went
into the warehouse.
He's in here.
This door!
System ready
for digitization program.
Data entry required.
Smiley, is that you?
Smiley.
Where the hell are you?
Close.
Chinga tu madre!
Smiley, is that you?
Don't shoot, Smiley!
It's Guzman!
Holy shit.
Good shooting.
Come here.
You... have...
been... a...
bad... boy.
Set it down.
Set it down!
I want anything done,
I guess
I'll have to do it myself.
O.K., Durant.
I'll take care of that...
Take it up!
Knock him off!
Get him off!
Oh, shit!
You're dead!
Holograph
recognition active.
Holographic imaging
complete.
You're next, Durant!
I'm coming for you!
Shake him.
What the hell was that?
Go after him!
I got him!
Get away!
Get back!
He's mine!
Oh, shit!
Excuse me.
This is Police Air-12.
Set down the man gently
and land your craft.
Put down your craft!
Dip him.
Look out!
Watch it!
No more Mr. Nice Guy.
Damn!
Hold it steady.
What the hell's he up to?
Kiss your ass goodbye!
No! No!
Burn in hell!
You look like hell,
Robert.
That son of a bitch
Westlake
malfunctioned
my helicopter.
How terrible for you.
He's a cockroach.
You think
you kill him,
and he pops up
someplace else.
I expect
he'll pop up here soon.
See, I know
how he thinks.
I don't think
the world will grieve
over one less attorney.
It's the tragedy
of my life
that I have to kill
the ones I love.
My wife...
late wife...
held certain deeds.
I sent her on a plane
over the Smokies.
Let's just say
I landed on my feet.
I'm glad
you survived, Robert.
I'd hate to see your kids
deprived of a role model.
They do look up to me.
When I was young,
my father made me work
high steel.
Just me and the Indians.
No one else crazy enough
to run around up here
against the wind
at $4.50 an hour.
Call me crazy.
Sometimes I miss it.
Life on the edge.
Five inches wide,
650 feet down.
High steel!
Oh, by the way,
you don't have
any kids, Robert.
You truly are one
ugly son of a bitch.
What do you think,
Julie?
Who's the real
monster here?
I destroy to build
something better.
Whereas you,
you're a man
who destroys for revenge.
Look.
Look about you.
It's all mine.
Because I built it.
I built it all!
What have you got,
besides a little trouble
with your complexion?
I'm joking, of course.
A troubled conscience?
A little blood
on your hands
from what you
consider justice?
Justice.
You and I know
it's just another
word for what I do.
We should be
working together.
I could use
a man like you.
That's why
I brought you here.
You'll make lots of money
working for me.
If you still want her,
I'll throw in Julie.
Sound good?
Oops.
Pey...
Bitch!
Peyton!
Here you go!
Julie.
Peyton?
Come on.
You're going down,
Burn Head!
Oh, no!
Help me!
In your absence,
I've gotten to know Julie
quite intimately.
Her tastes are varied,
but I can tell you this...
she doesn't date freaks.
Peyton!
Julie!
Go ahead.
Do it.
Do it,
Westlake.
But think of this...
you let me die,
and you become
as bad as me. Worse.
You can't.
I know you too well.
Dropping me
is not really
an option for you.
It's not something
you could live with.
I'm learning to live
with a lot of things.
Don't look at me.
I want to look.
You'll perfect the skin.
You'll make it work.
It doesn't matter.
Julie...
don't you think
I told myself that,
night after
sleepless night?
It's just a burn.
Skin-deep.
It doesn't matter.
And if I covered it,
hid behind a mask,
you could love me
for who I was inside.
Without pity.
But a funny thing
happened.
As I worked on the mask,
I found the man inside
was changing.
He became wrong...
a monster.
I can live with it now,
but nobody else can.
I want our life back.
Peyton!
Peyton is gone.
Peyt?
Hey!
I'm everyone...
and no one...
everywhere...
nowhere.
Call me...
Darkman.