Downloaded from
YTS.MX
(dramatic music)
Official YIFY movies site:
YTS.MX
- Victory!
The fort is ours!
(dramatic music)
Our victory is complete, Excellency.
The last resistance has been crushed.
- Make sure no Legionnaire is left alive.
The French will wonder
a long time at this.
(dramatic music)
Take that flag down.
And Yessouf,
assemble my men at the
usual place tonight.
(dramatic music)
You have done well!
(men cheering)
I charge you to keep this secret.
Let no man speak of what has been done
under penalty of death.
(men chattering)
(dramatic music)
- But French Intelligence
doesn't seem to understand
the feelings of a woman.
With my own life torn apart and
now my brother killed,
I feel I've sacrificed enough for France.
- But you must realize that--
- No, General.
I cannot bring myself to
accept another assignment.
I will not leave Paris.
- But this is a very urgent
matter, Mademoiselle.
- You know the people,
you know the country,
their customs, their language.
You can't let us down.
- Intelligence let me down.
They gave up the search
long ago, but I didn't.
And I never will.
- We've tried very hard
to locate Captain Norton.
We understand how you feel, Mademoiselle.
- No.
No man can really understand
a woman who's lost
the only man she ever loved.
I wish I could help you,
General, but I can't.
(dramatic music)
- Mademoiselle will reconsider.
- [Man] Well?
- I'm sorry.
I get paid to work here, you know.
I can't leave with you.
- Suppose I persuade the management
to let you have the evening off?
- Oh, no.
No, I couldn't.
- Why not?
- Because I'm an artiste and
I never miss a performance.
- I don't quite understand you.
Why do you work in a place like this?
- Uh-oh, that's my cue.
I've got to change now.
(piano music)
- Hey.
You'll be here tomorrow night, no?
Aha. (laughs)
(piano music)
Well, um, Jeff!
- Hello, Chavez, how are you? (laughs)
- What are you doing here?
- Hey, that stuff is
gonna kill you in the end.
- In the end, who cares?
- Two of the same.
- Frances, you heard me talk
about my good friend Jeff, no?
- How are you?
- I thought you was at Sidi Bel Razeer.
What are you doing here?
You got a leave?
- No, a transfer.
- Transfer?
- Mm-hmm.
To an outfit down here.
Report in the morning.
- Say, everybody's getting
transferred down here
all of a sudden.
What's going on?
- I don't know.
Ask the General.
(all laugh)
- Ask the General! (laughs)
- Hey, I want you to meet Sandra.
Prettiest girl in North Africa.
- Hello.
- How do you do?
("I'll Follow You")
(singing in French)
♪ I'll follow you ♪
♪ No matter where ♪
- She's some dish, huh?
- No, you soldier.
His Excellency wouldn't like it.
- [Chavez] His Excellency?
- [Sandra] Amir Al Raman.
You know who he is, don't you?
- [Chavez] Oh, sure, he's the
richest man in North Africa.
- She's a lucky girl.
♪ It's meant to be ♪
♪ It's meant for me ♪
♪ To be alone ♪
♪ For without you ♪
♪ My life will have no meaning ♪
♪ And so in spite of all ♪
♪ I'll go on searching ♪
♪ I'll follow you ♪
♪ No matter where you'll be ♪
♪ How many dreams I've
had of us together ♪
♪ How many hopes of all
the things to come ♪
♪ But if I ♪
♪ Never find you darling ♪
♪ I'll go on searching ♪
♪ Just the same ♪
♪ I'll follow you ♪
♪ No matter where ♪
♪ And hope and pray ♪
♪ That someday you will be there ♪
♪ For without hope what's left to me ♪
♪ Is nothing ♪
♪ I'll always love you ♪
♪ And so ♪
♪ I'll follow you ♪
(crowd applauding)
(Bal-musette music)
- Jeff!
Come with me for a minute.
I've got to see you.
- Sorry, I'm busy.
- But we've been looking
for you everywhere.
- Funny you couldn't find me.
That's exactly where I've been.
Everywhere.
- I've got to talk to you alone.
- I don't think it's a good idea to talk
when there's nothing to say.
- Please listen to me.
- I'll do all I can to make that
completely impossible, my dear.
But excuse me now.
Good evening.
(Bal-musette music)
Double scotch.
- As bad as that?
- How come you know Mademoiselle Del Mar?
- I don't.
Fill it up again.
- That won't help.
You know, you drink too much.
- I don't drink too much.
But I talk too much.
I talked to much just now.
- [Chavez] Why don't you
go down and tell her?
- You know something, Chavez,
I think I will.
- What's the matter, my dear?
- Nothing.
- You seemed to really
feel that song in there.
Who were you singing it for?
Me?
If anything's worrying you, tell me.
(Bal-musette music)
- [Officer] Hut, two, three, four!
Hut!
(military drums beating)
(Sergeant speaks foreign language)
- Mueller.
- Mueller?
(military drums beating)
Italiano?
- Si, Richetti.
(military drums beating)
- [Legionnaire] (nearby) Hut!
Hut, hut, hut, hut, hut!
Hut!
- You English?
- Does it matter?
- When I ask question, I want answer.
You see this?
- You asked a personal question, Sergeant.
You ought to know better.
- Also I know when somebody
too big for britches.
What's your name?
- Brown.
- Brown, eh?
Not Smith?
- Brown.
- Good.
Originality is a thing I like.
- Thanks.
- You got a big mouth.
- [Officer] Ten-hut!
- The men just transferred
from the 21st, sir.
- Good.
- [Legionnaire] (nearby) Hut, hut, hut!
Hut, hut, hut!
Hut, hut, hut, hut!
Hut, hut, hut, hut, two, three, four!
Hut!
Hut, hut, hut!
Hut, hut, hut, two, three, four!
Hut, hut!
- All right.
- All right, Sarge.
- Put down your bags.
Ah.
You are now no longer in
stinking outfit like 21st.
You are now in good outfit, my outfit.
And you, you seven been
assigned to this squadron.
My squadron.
I am glad.
I like your looks.
- That means he thinks
you got money, amigos.
- Quiet!
(men laughing)
You're going to be like my children.
I be like father to all my men.
Is right?
- [Legionnaire] Is right.
Just like Father!
- (laughs) Is right, there.
I look after you.
I make your life here very, very happy
if you are good fellows.
Not stingy.
Understand?
Ah.
Open your bags.
I make inspection.
Hey, you.
You!
Where are you going?
- Right here.
I like it by the window.
- Oh, you like, huh?
You like?
Everybody like, but is me
who says who goes where.
- You've got some objections
to my having this bed?
- I got objection you don't ask me.
I'm Sergeant.
- Mm-hmm.
- Open your bag.
Open your bag!
Ah.
Hey!
Pretty good cigar.
Hey, you like same kind cigar I like.
- You like?
- Yeah.
- Please, take one, Sergeant.
- You give me?
- Why, sure.
- Oh, thank you! (laughs)
Yeah.
What you got here?
You're going to be Private long time.
Hey!
Cognac, my favorite brand.
Very good.
- I like it, too.
- Oh, you know something?
When two men like same brand cognac,
is good sign they're going to be friends.
- I'm awfully glad to hear that, Sergeant.
- You should be.
Is very fortunate for you. (laughs)
And this fine bed I
give you by window, huh?
- That's right, mm-hmm.
- Okay.
I borrow, no?
- No.
- What you mean?
You crazy?
In the Legion it's share and share alike.
- This is private property.
- In the Legion there
is no private property
when Sergeant say so.
- That's where you're wrong.
It says so in Code Militaire
article 17, paragraph 9.
- Ha!
A lawyer! (laughs)
Maybe you don't hear this.
To the victor belongs the spoil--
- Sure, sure.
But there hasn't been any
victory yet, Sergeant.
- Oh?
You think maybe you could
be victor over me, eh?
- Not with that stripe.
If you didn't have it on, I might try.
- Oh, you want to try, huh?
Huh?
All right.
- Hold it, Jeff.
Remember, for hitting a non-com,
it's eight years in the clink.
- Never mind the clink!
There's my stripes.
- [Legionnaire] I bet
10 francs on the lawyer!
(men chattering)
I take that back.
(men scuffling)
- Attention!
- Help him up.
- Get away from me!
What?
Oh!
- Sergeant, report this man.
- What?
Oh, for what, sir?
- For attacking a superior.
- Attacking?
I beg Lieutenant's pardon.
Nobody attacked.
- No?
Then what's supposed to have happened?
- Ah.
Oh, I slip on the combat
bottle of cognac there,
I slip, bang! (laughs)
- Right on your face, huh?
- Oh, no, sir, I...
Well, yes, right on my face.
It's stupid.
- Yes, very.
For a man who likes his stripes.
Who is Legionnaire Brown?
- Here, sir.
- [Lieutenant] Come with me.
- Yes, sir.
(men chattering)
- Baroness.
Your cousin.
- Thank you, Lieutenant.
(door thuds shut)
(dramatic music)
- [Jeff] Baroness?
Cousin?
What is this?
- I had to find some way of seeing you.
- Well, now that you've seen me, goodbye.
- I know you don't understand, Jeff.
But you must have patience.
- Patience?
So you can pull one of your tricks again?
I buried myself in this
Legion for two years
on account of you.
Or maybe you don't remember.
- Only too well.
But you've got to believe in me.
There's never been anyone for me but you.
- Oh, no?
I think a woman ought to play square.
One man at a time.
Go back to His Highness.
The least you can do is
give him his money's worth.
(slap lands)
(tense music)
(door slams)
- Pretty good cognac, huh?
- [Man] Mm-hmm.
(Sergeant laughing)
- There we are.
Drink up.
Oh!
Hey!
I saved this for you!
- Looks like you saved me
from getting drunk, too.
- Hey, Brown, you're some fighter.
- You, too.
Next time let's be on the same side, huh?
- (laughs) Is bargain.
- Okay.
- Brown, one of the transfers, he in here?
- Here.
- The Colonel wants to see you.
- The Colonel?
- Tell him I'm busy.
- You're what?
- What are you, crazy or something?
- Is it on the level?
- Why, certainly.
- Oh, my friend Jeff is in.
Very good.
Or terrible bad.
Why, that pig.
He drank it all!
(men laugh)
- I wouldn't say I have the
best memory in the world,
Legionnaire Brown.
But I seldom forget a face.
I've seen yours before.
Paris?
- It's possible, sir.
I believe I've seen you before.
Monte Carlo?
- That's possible.
The man I remember was an
officer in the French Army,
the Signal Corps.
Have you had any experience in that field?
- I know something about it, sir.
- And this fellow spoke
Arabic rather well.
You, uh...
- I can get by, sir.
- Good.
Those can be very useful talents at times.
Thank you.
And Brown.
- Yes, sir?
- If it comes to you where we met,
let me know.
- I will, sir.
If it comes to me.
(dramatic music)
- Amir Al Raman.
I've never had any reason to
question his loyalty to France.
- But you don't know him.
We do.
- He'll stop at nothing
to get what he wants.
He'll set the whole country ablaze.
- Colonel, the massacre at Fort Algiers
was designed for just one thing:
To convince the French
that only he has the power
to keep order among the tribes
and that unless he is given
control of the territory,
there will never be peace.
- What has he to gain?
- Black gold, oil.
- If the French are forced
to recognize his authority,
he will seize the oil lands
which now belong to our tribes.
- Then he will take the oil for himself
and dispose of it as he wishes.
- Gentlemen, thank you for
your loyalty and cooperation.
France will see to it that
your rights are protected.
- I trust so.
- Goodbye, gentlemen.
(dramatic music)
- Well, good evening, Excellency.
- Why, gentlemen, good evening.
Mademoiselle Del Mar,
my good friends Major Colle...
- A pleasure, Mademoiselle.
- Thank you, Major.
- And Lieutenant Picard.
- Mademoiselle.
- You looking for someone?
Why don't you join us?
- Well...
Thank you.
As a matter of fact, we're
looking for Captain DuPont.
- He doesn't seem to be here yet, Major.
- No.
- Please sit down.
We'll have a farewell drink
with Mademoiselle Del Mar.
- Farewell?
- Yes, I haven't told you.
We're leaving for the desert tomorrow.
- The desert?
- Yes.
- How exciting.
- And His Excellency has
been kind enough to insist
that we stay at his palace
in El Hazeer, Mademoiselle.
- Anything I can do for
the French, I'm delighted.
- Oh, the desert.
I envy you.
- You may have my share
of it, Mademoiselle.
- Really?
You couldn't take me in his
place, could you, Major?
- Why,
I should be delighted.
- If you're serious, Yvette,
if you'd like to spend a few days there,
I'm sure you'll enjoy it.
- Oh, Amir, how could I?
- There's nothing
primitive about my place.
We've all the modern conveniences.
And you have the French
Army there to chaperone you.
- (laughing) You don't
get an offer like that
every day, Mademoiselle.
- Well, Yvette?
- I don't get an offer
to sing in a nightclub
every day either.
- Do I have to buy this place
in order to get you away from it?
- Well, I don't think
you'll have to do that.
- You'll come, then?
- Well, since the French
Army is going to be there...
- Wonderful!
To the desert.
- To the desert.
(dramatic music)
- La Dona!
(Sergeant scoffs)
- Well, play, play!
- Wait, wait.
I've got to think.
- You've got to think!
You'll lose anyway.
(Sergeant laughs)
(man speaking foreign language)
- Okay.
You got something there, smart guy?
- Let's see your hand.
- Oh, what for you want to see my hand?
- If you've got the
cards I think you've got,
you didn't get them from the dealer.
- Oh, you think I cheat, maybe, huh?
- Just let me see your hand.
- No!
Do you think I cheat?
We play it all over again.
Give me your cards!
I'll show you if I cheat.
- Ten-hut!
At ease.
Company C and the 22nd Infantry Regiment
is alerted for movement.
Sergeant.
- Yes, sir?
- Have your men ready to move at 04 hours
Wednesday the 12th with full equipment.
- Yes, sir.
- Passes will be issued to those
wishing to leave the post tonight,
but all men will report in by midnight.
That is all.
- Attention!
Dismissed!
(men chattering)
- Where do you think
we're going, Sergeant?
- Well, the General's staff
don't tell me their plans,
but, uh,
I got pretty good guess.
- Where?
- Fort Algiers.
(Chavez speaks in foreign language)
(dramatic music)
(horse whinnying)
(concertina playing)
- Say, that march nearly
killed me. (groans)
- It was not so bad.
- Not for you.
You ride.
- Sure.
I'm Sergeant.
- Hey, Sergeant, you look
pretty good on a horse.
There's only one trouble.
Horse is better looking than you.
- Quiet.
Ah, Jeff, it's your turn
for detail on guard duty.
- Okay, okay.
- Come on.
- I'm coming.
Play something else, will you?
- What?
- I told you before, I
don't like that song.
- It's a free country.
- You heard him.
Play something else.
- I play what I like.
No!
- Then don't play that song!
- All right, I won't!
Give it to me!
(crickets chirping)
- No.
(concertina playing)
(dramatic music)
- Amir.
Come and tell me what all this means.
That man, for instance,
what's he doing?
(man speaking in foreign language)
- He's a storyteller.
He repeats the old legends of the tribe,
reminds the people of their
glories in times gone by.
It's a very honored profession.
(tense music)
- What's going on there?
- Yessouf, put a stop to that.
(tense music)
- That's horrible.
- I'm sorry, my dear.
There's a thief in every marketplace.
But that doesn't excuse such brutality.
Pardon me, I'll attend to this myself.
(tense music)
- Did you recognize him?
- I couldn't be sure from this distance.
- Go and find out.
- Yes, sir.
(dramatic music)
- What is it?
- There's just a possibility
that man was our agent here.
If so, there may be a change in plans.
I'll let you know.
We'd better go inside.
(dramatic music)
- More coffee, my dear?
- Thank you.
- Excellency.
- Yes?
- A messenger for Major Colle.
- Have him come in.
- This just came for you, sir.
- Thank you.
(Colle scoffs)
There's no answer.
I'm afraid we shall have to cut
our visit short, Excellency.
- Oh?
When must you leave?
- We must leave for the fort immediately.
Sorry.
- But you'll be riding all night.
- Those are the orders, Excellency.
I shall have one of my men
accompany you to the city.
- Oh, that won't be necessary.
My home is yours.
- Well, I couldn't think
of staying here alone.
- You'll have all the
protection of my armed guards.
- As a matter of fact,
Mademoiselle, it is a hard ride.
- The Major's right.
- Well--
- I can take you back to
the city in the morning.
- Perhaps it would be best, Mademoiselle.
- I seem to be outvoted.
- Good.
Then you'll stay.
- Please excuse us, Mademoiselle.
- Of course.
Goodbye, Lieutenant.
- Mademoiselle.
- Major.
(dramatic music)
It's been a pleasure, Excellency.
- Thanks.
(dramatic music)
- Well, my dear,
you are now in the hands of a barbarian.
Are you planning to
run away in the morning
or to stay?
- I was wondering about that myself.
- Have you reached any decision?
- Not yet.
Well, it's quite late and I'm tired.
Goodnight.
- Goodnight.
(dramatic music)
(concertina music)
(men chattering)
(playing concertina)
- What's the matter?
You don't watch what you're doing.
- You're right, I guess I don't.
- Here.
- So long as you watch what he's doing.
- Does something eat you maybe?
- No.
- Well, something's
eating me, I can tell you.
You don't think those two
officers come down here
for their health.
I've been in the Army a long time.
They're cooking up something inside.
Don't worry.
- (chuckles) We not worried.
Are we?
- Go on, Luigi, play.
It's your turn.
- The death of our agent
at El Kazeel leaves us
in a difficult position.
- Perhaps I can find
someone to replace him.
- What, on short notice?
The qualifications alone--
- Are that he would have
to know the language.
- I'm afraid that's not
quite enough, Colonel.
- No, no, no.
- He'd have to know codes, signals.
- How about a former officer
of the Signal Corps, gentlemen,
who knows Arabic?
(men chattering nearby)
- We play for big money this time, eh?
- Okay.
But I warn you, no miracles.
- Miracles?
Who wants miracles?
- I don't.
- (laughs) I play very scientific game.
- Sure.
- Your bet, Luigi.
- [Lieutenant] Private Kalmani?
- Sergeant Kalmani, sir.
- Private Kalmani.
30 day demotion seems to be,
uh, in the cards, Private.
- Ehh.
(gentle music)
- You play an excellent game.
- You're very good yourself.
- Oh, I hardly play at all.
- I wasn't talking about the chess.
I meant the game you're playing with me.
- Oh?
What game?
- You didn't come out
here to see the desert.
What did you come out for?
You like me, don't you?
- I'm not sure yet.
How can I check you?
- Why try?
- That's the way to win the game.
- There's a better way.
You know,
I like you.
Very much.
- And you'd like to add me to your harem.
- I don't have a harem.
You see, I'm a modern sort of barbarian.
- So I've heard.
A one-woman man.
One after the other.
- None of them are working in nightclubs.
Oh, that reminds me.
I have something for you.
(gentle music)
Here, take them.
- Amir.
I don't know what to say.
- There's a history behind
those pearls, Yvette.
They deserve you.
Go on, put them on.
Yes?
- May I speak with you, sir?
- Yes, what is it?
- Alone, Your Excellency.
- Excuse me.
(gentle music)
I'm very sorry, my dear,
but something's come up.
I won't be able to go
riding with you tomorrow.
- Oh, that's too bad.
I was looking forward to it.
Well, if you're going to
be busy, I can't insist.
- Yes, you see, Yessouf
has just reminded me,
I must prepare for my guests,
the leading sheiks of this area.
- May I help?
- I may call on you, at that,
to charm some of my friends.
- Well, if they're as handsome
as you, it'll be a pleasure.
- Why, thank you.
- Not at all.
(dramatic music)
- So is everything clear now?
- I think so, sir.
- Good.
(watch chiming musically)
You know if you run into trouble,
there's nothing we can do to help you.
The minute you leave this place,
we never even heard of you.
- Certainly, sir.
But there ought to be two of us on this,
just in case something happened to one.
- Colonel?
- Take anyone you want.
I trust your judgment, Brown.
- Thank you, sir.
- Now, remember,
"My grandfather had one just like it."
- Yes, sir.
(dramatic music)
(knocking on door)
- Yvette?
- Mademoiselle Del Mar is
not in her room, Excellency.
- Where is she?
- She went to the village.
If I may make a suggestion, Excellency.
- Yes?
- Mademoiselle Del Mar
moves about quite freely.
After all, she's not an Arab and
since we caught that French spy--
- Mademoiselle Del Mar is my guest.
- As you wish, sir.
(dramatic music)
(watch chiming musically)
- Do you wish to sell this?
- Yes.
(watch chiming musically)
- How much you asking for it?
- 10,000 francs.
- Heaven protect you, my
son, as it does all mad men.
- That's an interesting watch.
Do you want to sell it?
- What?
- The watch, is it for sale?
- Why, no.
I mean, yes.
- Let me look at it.
(watch chiming musically)
My grandfather had one just like it.
How much do you want for it?
- 10,000 francs.
- It's too expensive.
- 7,000.
- Madame, he's a cutthroat.
I can show you much better
things at half the price.
- 5,000.
- No, it's still too much money.
- Tell me, this kind of thing,
did you ever do it before?
- Of course.
- Well, why didn't you tell me?
- I tried to, you wouldn't listen to me.
- Try again sometime.
5,000, madame, it's my last word.
- 2,000, my good man, that's my last word.
- But madame, the music
alone is priceless.
And isn't the memory of your grandfather
worth a few thousand?
- 3,000 for the box and the watch.
Now, take it or leave it.
- Very well, madame, but you'll ruin me.
I have five children to feed.
- Plans for the palace
and your instructions
are in these bills, understand?
- Yes.
(dramatic music)
(object clatters)
(tense music)
(gentle music)
(horses galloping nearby)
- They come nearer this time.
- Yeah, they're on that side road now.
- I go look, you stay here.
- No, I go look.
You stay here.
Private.
(dramatic music)
- What is it?
- Another sheik and his
men headed for the palace.
- I wonder what's going on.
- We'll soon find out.
- Ah.
(dramatic music)
Ah!
- And so instead of
striking at another fort,
our full forces will
take over the oilfields.
- Destroy them?
- No, work them.
Then let the French drive us out.
We'll have the sympathy
of the entire world.
- But this is revolt!
- Possibly.
Are there any objections?
- Yes.
I've followed you until now, Amir,
because your birth makes
you the rightful leader
of our tribes,
but revolt?
Why, this is madness!
I'll follow you no longer.
- Perhaps not, Al Haroon,
but there are countless
thousands that will
and I cannot help but believe, Haroon,
that your words are those
of a paid French agent.
- Liar.
I wonder whose money you've
been spending so freely.
Not your own, I'm sure.
Possibly that of some nation
that would like to see fire and bloodshed
sweep over our land for
its own selfish aims.
- I am free to accept help
from whomever I choose.
- So you are.
But you'll have no more from me.
Heaven go with you, gentlemen.
(men all replying)
- One moment, Haroon.
We must not part in anger.
To your friendship and loyalty.
- Are your secrets safe with Al Haroon?
- I'm sure he will never betray me.
(Haroon cries out)
And we will crush anyone
who stands in our way.
I do this to keep the
profits in our hands.
Make your men ready.
We will strike within 24 hours.
- [Sheik] We must be careful
in organizing our men.
The French will suspect us.
- They suspect us now.
But as long as we're
right, what does it matter?
(tense music)
- Quiet!
- And may good fortune
ride with us tomorrow.
Oh, no, no, this way, my friends.
(tense music)
- Oilfields.
At Sidi El Bar.
Target for attack.
Within 24 hours.
- Let's go.
(tense music)
- I thought you gave me
the key to this room.
- Sorry.
I keep a master key.
- If you'd knocked, I'd have let you in.
- Would you?
At this late hour?
- Well, as a matter of
fact, I was about to retire.
I've been admiring them.
They're beautiful.
- So are you.
More beautiful tonight than ever before.
(dramatic music)
- [Yvette] But I am tired.
Couldn't we talk tomorrow?
(tense music)
- Talk fast.
- The mic went dead and...
- What did you hear before
it was disconnected?
(tense music)
- Wait!
She's signaling again.
(tense music)
- Send Yessouf here.
- They've caught her.
- Let's get going.
We've got to get to fort.
- You go ahead.
- Jeff, you crazy!
Come back here!
(thrilling music)
- Now that you know everything,
how much does French Intelligence know?
- Nothing.
Nothing at all.
- [Amir] You lie.
(Yvette cries out)
(thrilling music)
Yessouf!
- Excellency!
(pounding at door)
Excellency, Excellency!
(thrilling music)
You! Come here!
Excellency!
(thrilling music)
- [Jeff] Yvette!
- Excellency!
(thrilling music)
- After them!
(gun fires)
(thrilling music)
(guns firing)
They'll try to get to the fort.
Send riders to overtake them.
Have them brought back here to me.
- Yes, Excellency.
- And Yessouf,
have all the tribes alerted.
My plans have changed.
We'll attack the oilfields at midday.
- Yes, Excellency.
(thrilling music)
- Come on!
(guns firing)
(thrilling music)
Quick, this way!
Well, that's that.
We'll have to head for the oilfields.
Not now.
Now we got a long ride ahead of us.
We'd better let the horses rest a while.
- I could use some rest myself.
(gentle music)
- Hello, stranger.
- We could be strangers, at that.
Two years.
Two long years.
- Mm.
It seems like 50.
- Jeff, I've got to tell you something.
- Mm-hmm?
- Please, listen.
- Beautiful eyes.
Lovely hair.
- You don't seem to care.
- About the past?
Why should I?
Now I know you're a secret agent.
So?
- I suppose you didn't
know then that you'd be
dishonorably discharged for
hitting a superior officer.
You almost killed that Colonel.
- I wish I had.
- He was a traitor, you know?
And I was assigned to get the proof.
And then when he was finally convicted and
I could talk, you were gone.
Disappeared, as if the
earth had swallowed you up.
- You know, you're wonderful
when you get excited.
- Oh, Jeff, you haven't
heard a word I've said.
(romantic music)
(thrilling music)
(gun fires)
(horse whinnies)
(dramatic music)
- I hope Kalmani got through to the fort.
Let's hurry.
(dramatic music)
- [Man] Corporal of the guard!
(bugle blowing)
- Colonel Lasalle speaking.
Proceed with all haste to
the Sidi El Bar oilfields.
Expect attack within a few hours.
(bugle blowing)
(dramatic music)
24th Mountain Battalion,
proceed with all haste to
the oilfields at Sidi El Bar.
(dramatic music)
(phone ringing)
- No, I guess you're right.
The lines must be cut.
- [Man] Hey, we can rig this
paddleboard for a detonator.
- Have you any dynamite?
- Yeah, we have some.
- Maybe we can make use of this.
Where is it?
- Outside.
- Let's get it.
(dramatic music)
- There it is.
- [Guard] They're coming now!
They're assembling!
(dramatic music)
- All right, bring it out.
- [Guard] Hurry, down there!
- Got some nitroglycerine here, too.
(dramatic music)
- Any old cans around?
- We got plenty of empty beer bottles.
- They'll make good grenades.
- Let's go!
(dramatic music)
- Take that lead wire
back to the paddleboard.
Show the girl how it works!
Plant the dynamite deeper,
we'll get more blasts.
Come on, men, hurry!
(dramatic music)
Bring more wire here!
Let's go, men!
(dramatic music)
- Here they come!
- That's enough.
(dramatic music)
(horses galloping)
- Charge!
(men shouting)
(horses galloping)
- Remember, men, hold your fire!
If any of them get through,
throw the grenades.
Ready, Yvette?
- Yes, ready!
(horses galloping)
(bombs blasting)
(thrilling music)
(guns firing)
(bombs blasting)
(dramatic music)
(guns firing)
(thrilling music)
(men cheering)
(triumphant music)
- And so, for services to France
above and beyond the call of duty
and by order of the
President of the Republic,
we bestow upon you the rank of
Knight of the Legion of Honor.
(dramatic music)
May I add my personal thanks.
- I think we should thank you, General.
- Congratulations, Captain.
- Thank you, sir.
- Goodbye, General.
- Oh, not goodbye, Mademoiselle.
We may again have need of your services.
Au revoir.
- Goodbye.
(gentle music)
Goodbye.
(romantic music)
(dramatic music)