(WHISTLES)
I'll get it, darling.
Some morning I'm
going to catch up
with that kid.
If cows only knew
how I hated them.
What would they do?
BOY: Hey, Ralphy!
Goodbye, Mother.
I'll be home late.
Scout meeting.
Goodbye...
Dream witch.
Goodbye... Pest.
Hey, Ralphy.
My name is Ralph.
R-A-L-P-H.
There's no "y" on the end of it.
I looked at my
birth certificate.
Bye, now.
Mmm.
Ralph.
Ralphy!
Ralphy, your bicycle!
I'll be late for the first bell.
Ralph... Spelled
R-A-L-P-H,
considers himself
too old to kiss
a man.
Another
milepost, Dan.
Mmm-hmm.
They're sailing by
pretty fast these days.
Next thing you know,
Cindy will be announcing
she wants to get married.
I do...
But he hasn't asked me...
Ha-ha!
Yet. Ha-ha!
Dan.
She's still a child.
Even though
she doesn't look
like a child?
Hmm?
Cindy.
Try not to mention
Chuck to your father
on the way to work.
All right, Mother.
Darling, try
not to mention
Chuck Wright
to Cindy in the car.
You know how
touchy she is since
she's been in love.
In love?
Ellie, that girl
knows no more
about love than...
Than Ralphy does.
(CHUCKLES)
Have a nice
day, dear.
(TURNS RADIO ON)
ANNOUNCER: The early
morning escape
was cleverly
masterminded
by Glenn Griffin.
He, his younger brother Hal,
and another convict named Kobish
brutally overpowered
a guard and fled without
arousing suspicion.
Griffin made
headlines here
four years ago
when during a
violent gun battle,
he deliberately
shot a policeman,
then surrendered.
While making the arrest,
an enraged
Deputy Sheriff
named Jesse Bard
slashed his gun
across Griffin's face,
breaking his jaw.
Griffin swore to
someday get even
with Bard, who is...
Hi, Dutch. Any of
your relatives in there?
Nah!
Hi, Jesse.
Hi.
About time.
Overslept.
What's the beauty
contest out there?
Oh, it's routine questioning.
Federal prison
break at
Terre Haute.
None of our concern.
Lifer named Kobish.
Couple of
brothers by the
name of Griffin.
Griffin?
When?
Just before dawn.
Why didn't you call me?
Call you? Why?
Dutch, get me
Lieutenant Fredericks,
State Police.
DUTCH: Yes, sir.
Oh, relax. Just
an FBI case.
Who's this third one,
this Kobish?
"Kobish, Samuel.
Age 44.
Male. White.
"6'3",
260 pounds."
Three-time loser
with a record
makes my hair stand on end.
MAN: Lieutenant Fredericks
on the line.
Fredericks,
this is Bard.
What do you got?
Nothing. I wondered
when you'd start yipping.
They melted into
the earth as soon
as they hit fresh air.
Have you
checked Griffin's
girl, Helen Miller?
Sure did. She
left town three weeks
ago. Not a trace.
Look, Bard, we got
roadblocks up and
down the whole state.
City police
are ripping entire
buildings apart.
You don't know Griffin.
He won't be
any place you'd
think of looking.
No roadblock,
nothing's going
to stop that bird
from coming
right back to
Indianapolis.
Lad, take the chip
off your shoulder.
You want Griffin?
Go out and get
him yourself.
Griffin?
Is he the
one who...
Yeah.
He's the one.
(DIALING TELEPHONE)
Hey. Look at that.
How about it, Glenn?
Yeah.
(MUSIC PLAYS ON RADIO)
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
(DOORBELL RINGING)
(RINGING CONTINUES)
All right, I'm coming.
Sorry to bother you,
ma'am, but it looks
like I lost my way.
Could you kindly
direct me to
the Bowden Dairy?
Well, there
are no dairies
close by.
(GASPS)
Take it easy, lady.
Easy, I said. Easy.
You scream,
and the kid
will come home
and find you in a pool of blood.
That's better.
Kobish, upstairs.
Where's the phone?
That the only one?
Extension upstairs.
All clear back here.
Hey, there's
a big car in
the garage.
The garage lock's broken.
Key to the car, lady.
The keys? I...
Lady, when I speak,
you snap and snap fast.
The keys to the car.
Top of the refrigerator,
I think.
Get them, Hal.
Check the car.
Yeah.
Take the car.
Take anything!
You stick with me, lady.
Nobody home but her.
Smart gal.
(CAR STARTS)
How many
bedrooms?
Three...
And two bathrooms.
(LAUGHS)
What a layout.
(SIGHS)
Ain't had
me a drink
in eight years.
Where's the liquor?
Here, make yourself
sick on a good
cigar instead.
Get in there
and keep an eye
peeled out that side.
It's a kind of liberry.
Improve your mind.
(CHUCKLING)
Crude, ain't he?
Why, let's see
the rest of the house.
Back stairs.
(DOOR OPENS)
Big car's ready
in the driveway
facing out,
but it's low on gas.
Stick on that door.
Oh, Hal...
What?
Now, lady,
you and me got
some business.
Come here.
They had to
pull something, Bard.
How come we're just getting it?
This is Mr. Carson, FBI.
How are you? It says
here they beat up
a farmer before dawn.
How come we're just getting it?
They left him
in his barn out cold,
ripped out his telephone,
and about 15 minutes
ago, he staggered into
a general store
and reported
his car stolen.
How are you?
Battered gray
sedan. 1941.
Did you put this on the air?
And give every crackpot
and amateur detective
a crack at it?
We'd be flooded
with phony leads.
Then we'll follow
them all down.
Every one of them.
What do you say, Carson?
Well, the way I understand it,
you know this Griffin
fellow better than
anyone else around here.
How about your taking
over this section?
I'll string along.
Okay.
Let's find that car.
Put the description on the air
and have them
repeat it every
half hour.
MAN ON RADIO:
Contact the police immediately
if you have
any information
concerning this car.
This is radio
station WTLI,
Indianapolis.
We now return
to our regularly
scheduled...
(RATTLING)
Huh.
(OBJECTS CRASH)
You paid
this insurance
on the 19th?
Yes.
This all the
cash you got
in the house? Huh?
My husband
always says
too much cash...
(CHUCKLES)
The old man's right.
Ain't never safe
to leave too much
dough laying around.
(GROANS)
(WHIRRING)
(CHUCKLING)
(SHOUTING PLAYFULLY)
Knock it off.
My guts are growling.
Here, chew on this.
(CHUCKLING)
Now, uh... Maybe it
slipped your mind.
You supposed to go
someplace tonight?
No. No, I told you.
How many times...
As many times
as I say!
Are you sure there
ain't some little
thing you're forgetting,
like a gun in the house, maybe?
You got it hid from junior.
You want me to let
Kobish root around
upstairs and find it?
Put a gun in Kobish's paw,
and his fingers get itchy.
He's only got
half a brain,
if that.
I don't want
nobody to get
hurt around here.
Maybe you got different ideas.
Okay. We'll let
him dig it out.
Wait.
I'm waiting.
Top shelf of my closet.
In my room.
Behind the hatbox.
Hal!
Yeah, Glenn?
Kobish, watch the back door.
Yeah?
Lady's got a present for you
top of her closet,
back of the boxes.
Now, do you think
you can talk on the phone
without busting into tears?
The phone.
Whom do you want me to call?
(CHUCKLING)
I always go
for a dame
with guts.
That's "whom"
you're going
to call.
A little lady with real guts.
Long distance.
No fancy
double-talk and
nobody gets hurt.
Mr. James is
calling Mrs. James.
Atlantic 6-3389.
No, no, no, no.
We don't write
nothing down.
Atlantic 6-3389.
Pittsburgh.
Pittsburgh, PA.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Operator,
I want to place
a person-to-person call
to Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.
ELLIE: Mrs. James.
Mr. James
is calling.
Atlantic 6...
GRIFFIN: 3389.
ELLIE: 3389.
That you, doll?
Don't talk now.
Listen.
Get here as fast as you can.
WOMAN: Indianapolis?
Yeah. Any trouble,
call on the phone.
The number's, uh,
Broad Ripple 8493.
Address is 6459 North Preston.
Got it?
Yeah.
Okay, doll.
I'll look for you
around midnight.
Only careful, see.
I'll see.
Got a customer, Dutch.
You got a warrant?
You got a warrant, Dutch?
Fresh out of warrants.
Where is she,
Sal?
Who?
She left you
only three weeks ago.
Where'd she go?
I don't know who you're
talking about. I want to
see Sheriff Masters.
Deputy Bard's in
charge here all week.
The gentleman wants to tell
you where Helen Miller
went after she left him.
Only no rough stuff, Dutch.
Masters doesn't
like rough stuff.
Where's Sheriff Masters?
In Michigan.
Fishing.
One coming.
After you.
(SIGHS)
Dad, can't you go
a little faster?
I may not drive a hot rod
like your lawyer friend,
but I'll get you there.
Now, Dad...
Your mother didn't say
we couldn't talk about
Chuck on the way home.
How is he?
I don't know.
We had a fight.
Aw, I'm crushed.
Nothing trivial, I hope.
Nothing serious.
So sorry.
Uh-oh. Your mother
left the car out again.
Open the garage door,
will you, dear?
Close the door
in back of you, folks.
Dan.
That's being real
sensible, mister.
Ellie.
I'm all right, Dan.
Where's Ralphy?
He's not home yet.
Stop pointing that gun at her.
Glenn, they left
the garage door open.
Shut it!
The house is
crawling with them.
What are you
doing here, Griffin?
They're looking
all over five
states for you.
They ain't looking here, pop.
What do you want?
Take it easy, pop.
Why here?
Why my house?
Your break.
I like the location.
And I like a house
with a bike outside.
I love people with kids.
They don't take no chances.
You get it now, Hilliard?
You can get brave
just about any time
you feel like it,
any one of you.
Might even get away with it.
But I ain't saying
what's going to
happen to the others.
How long?
You ain't dumb, are you, pop?
DAN: How long?
About midnight.
Maybe sooner.
See, pop, we can
play this together.
Then nobody loses.
Why midnight?
I got a friend bringing
me some dough.
Soon as she gets here,
we hightail it out.
What if the police come?
What if they find you here?
What then?
It wouldn't be pretty.
If that happens,
you folks get it first.
There's a kid
turning in. Walking.
If you let me
explain to him...
You pull anything, Hilliard,
I'll let you watch me
kick the kid's face in.
(DOOR OPENS)
DAN: It's all right, Ralph.
What's going on?
Who are they?
It's all right, Ralph.
You listen to
your old man, kid.
He knows where it's buttered.
How come you're so late?
I don't have to
tell you nothing.
Oh, Ralphy, I've
been so worried.
Scout meeting.
Remember?
Missis, it don't pay
to forget around
here tonight.
Griffin, what if I could get
you the same amount of
money you're waiting for now,
before midnight?
You may be
a big shot
in your office,
but I've seen your bank book.
800 lousy bucks.
Let's face facts, pop.
You're a punk.
I could raise more.
Don't get your mind
in an uproar, pop.
Listen to him,
anyway, Glenn. The
guy's using his brain.
Use yours. Helen's
on her way here now.
Yeah, but that ain't it.
He's got other business
in this town.
What do me and
the kid care who
busted your jaw?
I'll bust yours
if you don't shut up.
Why should we
stick out our necks...
Shut up...
Just so's you can get
some copper knocked off?
Go spill your
stinkin' guts
somewheres else.
Who got you here?
Who done it?
Now, get out in the back.
Using his brain,
is he, Hal?
Look at him.
Clickety clickety click.
I can see it perking.
Don't ever try to
come in between,
you smart-eyed slob.
We're sticking.
Sweetie, take the
kid upstairs and see
he don't get out.
I don't want him
hollering out any
windows, either.
She's a honey, ain't she, Hal?
Four years, pop.
It don't cost
nothing to look.
By the way,
you got a gun
in the house?
Just stay looking
at me and answer
the question.
No. No gun.
That's right, you ain't.
Show him, Hal.
You know, for a minute
there, I thought you was
gonna lie to me.
I always like
doing business with
a man I can trust.
Now, get out in the kitchen
and cook that chicken
I seen in the icebox.
Do it yourself.
My wife's not
your servant.
I always wanted me a servant.
I don't mind, Dan.
Well, I do!
Stay here, Ellie.
Listen, Hilliard,
you ain't calling
the tune.
I got my guts full
of you shiny-shoed,
down-your-nose
wise guys
with white handkerchiefs
in their pockets.
Next time, I'll wipe
them on you.
Now get out there and cook!
CINDY: Ralphy!
Ralphy!
Where's
my other DC-7?
I don't know, kid.
What did you do with it?
I'll get you
another one, Ralphy.
You're gonna
let 'em get away this?
I'll take that, kid.
No. It's mine.
Give me it, I said!
Kobish, grow up.
Ralphy!
Sit tight, pop.
Hand it over.
You brat!
Dad! Dad!
It ain't gonna
be like this, see?
Not like this!
You think
I'm gonna let...
Not like this!
Dan, what's happened?
Get back to
the kitchen and take
the kid with you.
Oh, Dan.
Get back!
Go ahead, Ellie.
I'm all right.
Hal, put that away.
(SIREN WAILING)
(SIGHS) All the wrong places.
This is Bard.
Put Carson on.
What a waste of time.
CARSON: Bard?
Carson, nothing here.
Anything new there?
Plenty. We've spotted
Griffin's girl.
Where?
She's heading west from
Pittsburgh on U.S. 40.
Going to be here
around 11:30 or 12:00.
Now, listen, don't let
anyone tail her, but
I want her clocked...
Every town she
goes through,
every village.
Got it.
About 20 miles
out of the city,
we'll put a real tag on her,
and she'll breeze
right in and lead us
straight to Griffin.
Good.
(MUSIC PLAYS ON RADIO)
(CLANGING)
(BELCHES)
Pretty good chow.
What time is the next news?
They're not so tough.
You hit the big guy.
You could've licked
him, couldn't you?
I lost my temper, that's all.
I can't do that again.
I can climb out my window,
cross the roof there, and drop.
It's not much higher
than the garage.
I've jumped off
the garage roof before.
How many times have I
told you to stay off...
The roof of the garage?
But you could.
You could let yourself drop.
I bet you could, Dad.
Now, listen, Ralph.
You want me to call
you Ralph, don't you?
You want to be
considered a grown boy.
Then you've got
to act like one
and think like one.
We could get word
to the Wallings
or to the police,
but then what, Ralph?
The police would
know what to do.
Ralph, those guns down there...
They're loaded.
It's not like
in the comic books,
son, or television.
Those are real bullets.
You're afraid, aren't you?
Yes, son.
I'm afraid.
And I'm not ashamed of it.
Sometimes it's
better to be afraid.
Well, I'm not,
and neither is Cindy.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Hal, upstairs.
Come here, sweetie.
You get the pleasure.
(RINGING CONTINUES)
If it's for Mr. James,
I'll take it.
Anybody else,
let them talk,
except the brat.
Make it sound right,
just like any other
night... Normal.
(RINGING CONTINUES)
Hello.
No, I...
Sore? No, no.
No, please.
Not tonight.
No, wait, please...
I flunked.
Who was it?
Sherlock Holmes.
The boyfriend.
His name's Chuck,
and he's coming over.
You're not as wise
as I thought, sweetie.
Well, she couldn't help it.
He didn't give her a chance.
Hey, Hal, how would
you like to take the
little spitfire dancing?
You ought to see him dance.
He's got all
the babes groggy.
Come on, come on.
You want to dance,
take a dance.
What's the matter?
Aw, cut the clowning.
Ok, spitfire, now, when
Sherlock Holmes stops
out front, you duck out.
Hilliard, I got a job for you.
Ellie, go upstairs
with Ralphy and
lock the door.
Don't open it
until I tell you to.
The gas is low
in that fancy car
of yours. Get some.
Fill her up, and check
the battery and oil.
Hey, Griffin, are you crazy?
The kid and the missus stay.
As soon as he gets
out of that door, what
you think he's gonna do?
I tell you, Kobish, nothing.
Pop here's a smart cookie.
Clickety clickety
click. I can hear them
wheels going around.
He's saying to hisself,
"That Griffin means business.
"He ain't afraid
to pull the trigger."
He's thinking,
"Is it worthwhile
calling the cops
"when I only got
a few hours to go?"
But if they track you down here,
it wouldn't be our doing.
Maybe, maybe not.
I'd never know.
But you couldn't
blame us!
I can do anything I want.
This is all you got
to remember, pop.
You, too, sis.
Any red lights
show up out front,
them coppers start
setting up machine guns,
throwing tear gas
through the windows,
you know who's
gonna get it first?
Not you. Them.
That's all you got to
keep on your mind.
Hey, mister, get me some liquor.
No! No liquor.
This time he's right, Kobish.
You letting
this joker give
the orders?
Nobody gives me orders.
Make it bourbon,
Hilliard. Bonded.
Bring back some
late-edition papers.
Would you like a scrapbook, too?
Wait upstairs until Chuck comes.
Pop, when you get back,
park the car heading out.
Nice family you got here.
(DOOR CLOSES)
But you'll see,
he'll do something.
(HORN HONKING)
(ALL LAUGHING AND TALKING)
YOUTHS:
* Row, row, row your boat
* Gently down the stream
* Merrily, merrily,
merrily, merrily
* Life is but a dream...
Good evening, sir.
Fill her up.
Yes, sir.
(WHISTLING)
Hi, Cindy.
Hello, Chuck.
CHUCK: Mmm.
Well, this is more like it.
On the phone, I thought, um...
Chuck, let's go. Please.
I'm glad you came, Cindy.
I was afraid you wouldn't.
Why?
Oh, you know.
After last night...
I'm sorry, Cindy.
About time.
You wouldn't mind taking your
hands out of your pockets,
would you, pop?
How about that?
Kind of generous,
aren't you, pop?
Clickety clickety click.
You're off your rocker.
Not that we ain't thankful.
Only you don't really want us
to drink ourselves
to sleep or
something, do you?
Kobish, go out
and check that car.
This guy's getting
ideas every minute.
Maybe there's coppers
hiding in the backseat.
You check it.
Hal!
Yeah, Glenn?
Look at that car.
I'll cover you.
All right, pop.
In there.
Over there.
(BANGS COUNTER)
Eight years.
Then you can't get it open.
All right, pop.
You're working your
headpiece overtime,
but you're not a bad guy.
Your woman's waiting.
Here's a guy ain't
yellow, Kobish.
I taught him, didn't I, Hal?
Yeah, you taught me everything.
That's right.
Everything.
Except how to live
in a house like this.
Darling, it's such
a short time now.
Less than three hours.
All they'll have is the car.
Even that's insured.
As soon as they've gone,
you'll pick up the phone?
Yeah. Sure.
Dan, what are you thinking?
Nothing, dear.
What, Dan?
You're right, Ellie.
It'll soon be over.
No, there's something else.
They'll leave.
You'll pick up...
They can't let you
do that, can they?
Ellie...
How can he stop it?
He can't, dear.
He must have a plan.
I know.
I know what
you're thinking.
Don't imagine things, Ellie.
They'll have to take someone.
RALPHY: Dad...
Don't let them take me.
Ralphy...
I just explained to your mother.
Please, don't let them
take me along.
They're not going to
take you or anyone.
I won't let them.
How are you gonna stop them?
I'll stop them.
I'll find a way.
Get under
the covers, darling.
Go back to sleep.
I just had a silly idea,
that's all.
Those men hadn't even
thought of that.
Good night, Chuck.
You had me so balled up, Cindy.
But I know now.
What? What do
you know?
It's your father, isn't it?
I know how he feels about me.
Well, I'm going to
have it out with him.
No! No, Chuck. No.
The lights are still on.
He must be up.
I said no.
It's...
It's not that at all.
Well, what is it, then?
(CAR DRIVING OFF)
KOBISH: Well, sweetie...
What you been doing?
(GASPS)
Get upstairs, miss.
Nah, nah, nah.
She ain't been
searched yet.
Where's Griffin?
Stay up there,
Mr. Hilliard.
Searched the old man, didn't we?
Come upstairs, Cindy.
Where's Griffin?
Lift your arms, baby.
Hold it, Kobish.
Hold it, I said!
What you think...
Where did you get that?
You go upstairs now, miss.
Where did you get that gun?
Hal, you fool.
Go sleep it off, Kobish.
Both of you...
You both got guns, huh?
Only me.
I should've known.
Okay, you brothers, you wait.
You just wait.
Get to bed!
Just a minute, sis.
You don't get
off that easy.
Close those curtains.
Give me that coat.
Now lift your arms
like the man said.
Griffin!
Shut up!
Come on, come on, get them up!
(DOORKNOB RATTLING)
Watch 'em, Hal.
I got to stop that fool.
Hold it right there.
Don't think I won't.
Kobish.
Huh?
(GROANS)
Oh...
ELLIE: Cindy!
Don't move,
neither one of you!
Glenn!
Hal, this girl is ill.
If there's any
decency in you...
Glenn!
Miss, miss.
There's no cause to be scared.
Hold it!
(HAL SCREAMS)
Ow!
Open the door!
Lock the back door.
Turn off all the lights!
Ellie, go up to Ralphy.
Stay away
from the windows.
They're all outside.
Operator?
(CLICKING)
(ELLIE SCREAMS)
Dan, don't!
RALPHY: Dad! No!
WOMAN: Operator.
Operator.
Is that...
Yes.
Your call, please.
Dad, they've got Ralphy!
This is the operator.
Your call, please.
Go upstairs.
Get in our room,
both of you.
Lock the door.
Ellie.
What?
If you hear a shot,
make the call.
Ralphy.
Ralphy, where are you?
Here, Dad...
(MUFFLED SHOUTING)
Try something
now, Hilliard,
the brat gets his.
Let the boy come in, Griffin.
Gun first.
Hold it.
Set the safety.
(DROPS GUN)
Now the lights.
Back inside.
I tried, anyway.
Get up to your mother, son.
Jumped off the roof.
Brave kid
you got there, Hilliard.
Brave family.
Going on midnight,
and you couldn't wait.
You couldn't wait!
You ain't learned yet
who's running this show,
have you, Hilliard?
Hands off, Griffin.
HAL: Glenn.
Get Kobish in here.
Bard?
Yeah?
Hold on to your
hat. Helen Miller's
not coming.
She ran a red light
in the outskirts
of Columbus.
What?
Patrol car
gave chase.
You mean they arrested
Helen Miller for
a traffic violation?
No. She gave them the
slip and ditched her car
in downtown Columbus.
But they had orders.
It's been on every
teletype between here
and Pittsburgh for hours...
Do not arrest!
Oh, those greedy,
duty-happy crumbs,
trying to pick
her off on a
lousy 15-buck fine.
Come on.
Take it easy,
Bard, will ya?
Don't tell me to take it easy!
Well, if she's not coming,
she's got to call him.
Dutch, get me
a court order quick.
I want every long-distance
phone call from Columbus,
Ohio, to Indianapolis
between 8:00 and
now and straight
through the night...
As fast as they get
them, any number
to any number.
DUTCH: Got you, chief.
Names, addresses,
numbers, the works!
(CAR APPROACHES
AND PASSES BY)
Ralphy?
Shh. Don't move, Dan.
What time...
After 1:00.
Midnight! He
said he'd be...
Shh. Dan, listen.
Huh?
Close your
eyes and listen
to me, darling.
You must never
do anything like
that again.
Ever.
You might have
been killed, darling.
What are they saying?
Why haven't they gone?
Dan, listen.
Nobody knows
anything about what's
happening here.
We're all alone
in this, Dan. I want
you to promise me.
Ellie...
How long has it
been since I
said I love you?
(CRYING)
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Oh!
Hal, upstairs.
Lady, get that.
Hello?
OPERATOR: I have a collect
call for Mr. James
from Mrs. James.
Put her on.
Will you accept
the charges?
Yeah. Put her...
Put her on.
Get them inside.
Get inside and shut the door.
(DOOR CLOSES)
HELEN: Hello.
Yeah?
Is this you?
Yeah. What's up?
I ran into some
trouble in Columbus.
I can't come on.
I'm heading for
Louisville instead.
You know where.
Yeah. Now, listen...
That stuff you're carrying,
put it in a plain envelope
and take down the address
I'm going to give you.
Okay?
Yeah.
As soon as I get it,
we'll make tracks, doll.
Watch out, see?
I'll see you.
Close them curtains.
What if they trace that call?
Ever hear of
a town called
Circleville, Ohio?
Here it is.
24 miles south
of Columbus.
Think them dumb cops
are going to start
tracing phone calls
from a jerk town
like Circleville?
What if we get trapped in here?
We'd be better
off anywhere else.
It can't be nowhere else!
With all that dough
in this town,
I'll have that
copper put on
ice for good.
Cindy...
DAN: Go to sleep, dear.
You, too.
(CHILDREN SHOUTING
AND LAUGHING)
GIRL: I'll get you!
You don't drink your
milk, junior, you
ain't gonna grow up
to be a big,
strong man
like daddy.
(LAUGHING)
How much longer, Griffin?
Well, now, pop,
is that any way to
talk to your guest?
How much longer?
Till I get a certain
envelope in the mail.
Meanwhile, everything
goes on just like
before, see? Normal.
You and the spitfire go to work.
Junior here gets a break.
He misses a day at school.
It won't hurt you, kid.
Missed a few myself.
And look at you.
Yeah, you're looking.
Pass you on the
street, you'd look
right through both of us.
Well, you're seeing us now, sis.
(PERSON WHISTLES)
Hal!
(LAUGHING)
ELLIE:
The morning paper.
Get your kicks young, kid.
Hal, the paper.
You're going to be late
for the office, Hilliard.
Why do you want
to go on torturing
my husband?
You take pleasure
in torturing people,
don't you?
Hmm, I'm getting
attacked from all
sides this morning.
Lady, I take
pleasure in looking
out for my own skin.
No, no. It's some sort of
game with you, you...
Cruel, inhuman... Filthy!
Ellie! Ellie!
(GROANING)
Why don't you
pick on somebody
your own size?
(CHUCKLES) The whole
family's getting tough.
All right, pop, get moving.
I'm not leaving
this house today!
Okay, pop.
You stay and we stay.
'Cause we ain't going
to beat it out of here
till we get that dough.
And that dough is in
a letter addressed
to you at your office.
We don't want no federal men
tracing anything up to our
front door, now, do we, pop?
He'll go. He'll go.
I'm all right now, Dan.
I'll stay upstairs
with Ralphy. Cindy,
get your coat.
Hey, Ralphy!
Shake a leg!
Ralphy's staying
home today, Buck.
He hurt his leg.
He did?
The lucky stiff.
Tell him he's
going to miss
the big game.
A+, pop.
You heard me, Ralph,
and that's what
you're gonna do.
Stay home
and with your
mother, all day.
GRIFFIN: Don't be so hard
on the kid. He saved
my neck last night.
It's all right, Dan.
We'll be all right.
(GRIFFIN LAUGHING)
What's so funny?
I don't see nothing so
funny you should break
your neck laughing.
I'll laugh when I feel like
it, and you ain't got nothing
to say about it, that right?
That right, Hal?
Yeah. Yeah,
that's right.
Get the dough
and come back,
both of you.
No mistakes, see?
That nick on
your head, you got
a story ready?
It wouldn't take
much of a slip today,
just a little one,
and you're gonna wish
you never come back
through this door.
Griffin, I never understood
before how a mind like
yours works, but I do now.
You're going to be late
for that time clock.
I know exactly how you feel
because I've got
the same thing in me.
I want to kill you.
Pop, you're a
regular comedian.
If anything goes wrong here,
any harm comes to any one of us,
I'll do it.
I'll kill you, so help me God!
You understand that?
Yeah, I got you.
We understand each
other all the way.
Lady, you didn't know
what a tough old bird
you married, did you?
No.
No, I didn't.
Dad...
Are we making
a mistake not
going to the police?
Maybe. I don't know.
I've tried to think
of everything...
But you heard him, Cindy.
I won't gamble
with your mother's
life or Ralphy's.
(CRYING) Oh, Dad.
Oh, Cindy, baby.
Now, listen to me.
Nobody can know
anything about this.
Not Chuck, nobody.
Another thing...
You're not going back tonight.
Go to your
girlfriend's
or a hotel,
but don't come home.
(SOFT MUSIC
PLAYING ON RADIO)
(VEHICLE APPROACHES)
Hal.
(MUSIC STOPS)
Get the old lady down here.
Who is it?
Mr. Patterson.
He hauls away
the trash.
Let him pick it up and beat it.
This is the end of the month.
He'll come to
the door to collect.
Okay. Pay him.
Hal, get back upstairs
with the brat.
What...
I said pay him.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Wait.
Yes?
Just a second.
Here, let me see that.
Use your head.
Hal's upstairs with the brat.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
Yes!
Good morning,
Mrs. Hilliard.
Mr. Patterson.
Oh, thank you, ma'am.
Is there any...
Say,
aren't you feeling
yourself today,
Mrs. Hilliard?
Well, I...
Just a headache,
Mr. Patterson.
Oh.
Thank you.
Well, I'll just take
these here papers
with me.
Goodbye, Mrs. Hilliard.
What's up?
Want me to grab him, Griffin?
Huh?
He's going away.
Shut up, both of you.
Give me
the gun, Griffin.
I'll stop him.
Griffin, ain't
you going to
do nothing?
He's getting back in the truck.
You want him
to get away?
Give me it.
(DOOR CLOSES)
She paid him
with a check.
Get it back.
If you get
into any trouble,
don't come back here.
(TRUCK STARTS)
Oh, I can't take it.
GRIFFIN: Get back upstairs.
Keep going, George.
(HORN HONKS)
(TIRES SCREECH)
Keep your eyes
on the road, George.
MAN: Why don't
you watch where
you're going, you stupid...
Drive out of town.
I'd like to see some country.
Good morning,
Mr. Hilliard.
Good morning.
Good morning,
Mrs. Sadler.
Good morning.
Good morning, Miss Wells.
Good morning,
Mr. Hilliard.
Um...
I'll open it today.
Not interrupting anything, am I?
Clint, I'm busy
as the devil this morning.
Do you mind?
Okay, Mr. Executive.
What happened
to your head?
Well, I...
Suppose you tell
me some time when
you're not so busy.
(CHUCKLES)
Miss Wells,
when's the next mail?
This afternoon,
Mr. Hilliard.
There's one more delivery.
Bring it in as soon
as it arrives.
Yes, sir.
Unopened.
(DOOR CLOSES)
VENDOR: Extra! Read all about
the daring prison break!
Extra! Extra!
(VENDOR CONTINUES SHOUTING)
Boy,
I want you to take
this to the city
police station
around the corner.
The police station?
Are you a guest
of the hotel?
Yes.
And no questions.
Oh, ho, yes, sir.
No questions at all, sir.
VENDOR: Extra! Extra!
Extra! Paper!
Read all about
the daring prison break!
Extra! Extra!
(DOG BARKING)
Aw, missed.
Turn here.
You ain't going to be
needing it, George.
Mister,
I ain't going to open
my mouth. Honest.
I ain't going to say
a word to nobody.
I know you ain't, George.
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
I have to talk to you,
Mr. Hilliard.
Some other time, Chuck.
I'm sorry,
Mr. Hilliard.
I just had lunch
with Cindy.
Hmm?
Yeah?
Mr. Hilliard,
what's happening?
It's nothing, Chuck.
Nothing?
She's miserable.
She looks like
she's crying all the time.
If I'm the cause...
Oh, it doesn't
concern you.
If it concerns Cindy,
it concerns me.
You stay out of it!
Don't you care
Mr. Hilliard?
What kind of
a father are you?
(INTERCOM BUZZES)
Yes?
WOMAN: A Mr. James
is calling, Mr. Hilliard.
Put him on.
Yeah?
Hilliard, you recognize
my voice?
What do you want?
What's happened?
KOBISH: Come and get me.
Where are you?
Out Fall Creek Road.
The golf course.
You won't see me,
but I'll be waiting
for you.
It'll be a long wait,
Mr. James.
You'll wish you didn't.
If I get nabbed,
I'll spill my guts.
Wait a minute.
This is a private
conversation.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Yeah?
Hilliard, you there?
Yeah.
I'm gonna call
the coppers right now,
give them the address.
Let them shoot up
the joint.
Stay out of sight.
It'll take me about
an hour to get there.
That's the last delivery today.
(SIRENS PASSING OUTSIDE)
Mr. Hilliard,
is there anything
I can do?
Yes.
You can mind your own business.
Mr. Hilliard.
I'm sorry, Chuck.
Not now.
It's a .38.
That guard
at Terre Haute,
his gun was a .38.
Bard, you got an obsession.
You can't tie in
every crime in
the state with Griffin.
Then you tell me
why anybody would
want to pump three slugs
in the back of an
old man like that?
He wasn't even robbed.
Nothing much.
Here's his address.
Tom, go to his house
and find out
what neighborhood
he worked today.
I'm bushed.
Get a list of all
his customers.
One of them probably
the last person
that saw him alive.
(HUMMING)
Singing bother you, mister?
Kobish, you better
tell me what you were
doing out there.
Maybe I was
playing a game of golf.
(LAUGHS)
Give you
a little hint,
Hilliard,
just like on them
quiz shows, hmm?
Three bullets left.
(CHILDREN LAUGHING
AND SHOUTING)
Mr. Hilliard,
tell Ralphy we beat
the socks off of them!
Buck, now beat it.
Go on! Get away here!
All of you!
Hey, fellas.
What did
I say wrong?
What did I say?
Well, Cindy...
When she was Ralphy's age...
(DOOR CLOSES)
Ellie.
Dan
Dan, you remember
Miss Swift,
Ralphy's teacher?
Why, sure I do.
How are you,
Miss Swift?
I want you to meet...
Hey, Johnny, come here.
Er... I just met
Johnny in a bar.
We had a couple.
He's an old friend of mine.
I promised him another.
Will you excuse me?
Oh, there you are, Johnny.
(WHISPERING)
She's seen me.
I'll get her out of here.
DAN: Make yourself at home!
You know...
I'm sure Ralphy will be
all right Tomorrow.
DAN: Pour yourself
a real one.
I'll be right back.
Thank you, Ralph.
Uh, hiya.
I, uh...
I better be going.
Dan, Miss Swift just dropped by
to see how Ralphy was feeling.
Oh, she did, did she?
Miss Swift,
I think that's
a darn nice
PTA practice.
I'll be sure you
get full credit
for it, Ralph.
For what?
Why, his, uh,
his week's composition.
Oh, excuse me.
Do you mind?
Miss Swift...
Do you encourage
such drivel as this?
Mr. Hilliard, you're in
no condition to discuss
anything today.
In that case,
I'll wait and read it
in the morning.
How about
a little drink
Miss Swift?
Come on, we'll make it a party.
No, thank you.
I'm very sorry.
Nice work, pop.
Hey, we got
to stop her.
She's seen me.
She didn't recognize you.
He's right, Kobish.
Hilliard took
her mind off of you.
Had her in
a real sweat. Pop...
Gotta hand it to you.
You'd have made a great con man.
What about the old
guy in the truck?
He ain't picking up
no more trash.
Tailed?
Nah.
Mr. Patterson...
He saw their car in the garage.
GRIFFIN:
Hey, listen to this.
"Dear Miss Swift,
bring help right away.
"There are men
in the house with guns.
"They are criminals."
Kid's a good speller, pop.
(SOBS)
Crying department's
upstairs, lady.
(CRYING)
Griffin, it came.
Afternoon mail.
Yeah?
How could it?
It wasn't mailed
till this morning.
You...
Take it easy.
Only it ain't
enough, pop.
Thanks anyway.
Hey, Glenn.
That's enough for us.
Let's blow.
Tomorrow.
Why are you crowding it?
Why go on taking
these chances?
I kind of like taking chances.
You don't take chances,
you might as well be dead.
Yeah. That's what
you're going to be,
all of us if this goes on, dead.
Oh, I'll take
the .38 now, Kobish.
I kind of like
the feel of it, Griffin.
Clickety clickety click, pop.
Don't work it overtime.
Griffin...
When you leave here,
if that time ever comes...
Watch your manners.
You know I'm going
to pick up the phone
and call the police.
Oh, now, pop,
you wouldn't do
a thing like that.
What'll you do about it?
Rip it out.
There's one next door.
What's on your mind?
I know what
you're planning, Griffin.
You're not taking anyone along.
Say, that's not a bad idea.
I never thought
of that.
You thought of it.
All the way.
I tell you what, pop.
You give us a fair shake,
we'll give you a fair shake.
Then, if the dough gets here,
we'll take you with us.
Just you.
Nothing happens,
we ain't followed,
you get out
and walk home.
That's a deal, Griffin.
Sure, pop.
A deal's a deal.
In the meantime,
don't get ulcers.
I know what's
eating you, kid.
I'll tell you what.
We'll take the girl
along just for you.
Is that what
you call a fair shake?
Guys like Hilliard
ever give you
a fair shake?
I'll take the automatic now.
Get Kobish's...
I'm hanging on to this one.
WAITRESS:
Two burgers, no onions.
COOK: Two burgers,
no onions.
All the main roads are covered.
It'll be dark in half an hour.
Tom, I want this
whole area combed,
every one of
the trash man's
customers.
Knock on every door
and report it...
Say, there ain't going
to be no shooting
here, is there?
No, no, no.
Just get us some
coffee, will you?
Report anything
unusual, anything.
And especially
the garages, you hear?
That's police talk, lad.
This just came
into the city
police station.
The bellhop's given
six different descriptions
of the man who tipped him.
A 5-spot to deliver it.
All we know
for sure is the man
was wearing clothes.
"To the police...
Innocent people
will be in the house
"or automobile with
the three fugitives you want.
"If you shoot,
you'll be responsible
"for the lives
of people who have
done no harm.
"To attempt to trace this letter
"will only endanger
those same people."
No signature.
Well, now we know.
Nah, it's a blind.
That letter's
no blind.
The idiot.
Doesn't he know
you can't play ball
with savages like that?
Let's get moving,
Winston.
Fredericks,
what are you going to do?
Follow your instructions.
Knock on a few doors.
That letter pretty well proves
they're here someplace.
I'm countermanding those orders.
Bard, you can't
put off a showdown.
Nobody wants a showdown
any more than I do,
but we can't get
the poor slob's
family massacred.
Listen, you frisky
young punk,
and listen good.
Pity is a luxury
your badge
doesn't afford.
Did you hear that?
Is it any wonder
the guy doesn't
sign his name,
why he doesn't trust
the police to help him?
What do you propose, Jess?
I propose keeping
those prowl cars
off the streets now.
Bury 'em.
Then Tom and me
will cruise around and
see what we can spot.
Oh, fine.
In the meantime,
they slip out.
There's plenty of
side streets, alleys...
Block them all.
It's too big an area for that!
If they slip through,
your name is mud.
And yours, too.
Get some equipment
moved in here.
OFFICER: Yes, sir.
Take my car, Jess.
It's not marked.
Better get some riot guns,
tear gas brought up.
The works.
Wait a minute, Cindy.
Please, Chuck.
Stay away from here, will you?
I don't want to see
you anymore,
do you hear?
DAN: Cindy!
Didn't I tell you...
I couldn't help it, Dad.
Clickety clickety click, pop.
You've only got one trouble.
You don't know
when you're licked.
Hal,
the spitfire had
to come back to you.
You didn't blab
to the boyfriend,
did you?
Chuck knows nothing.
Then what's
he doing still
sitting out there?
Get back on that window.
If you pulled a fast one...
Chuck doesn't know anything.
Kobish.
Hey, Glenn.
Here he comes again.
Kobish!
(CAR DRIVES AWAY)
Glenn, this can't go on.
First the old man in the truck,
then the schoolteacher,
now this guy out here.
Somebody's going to get wise.
I'm not sticking any longer.
Kobish, watch them.
All right, beat it.
I'm getting out, Glenn, now.
Don't lose
your head, kid.
We're accessories now, Glenn.
I'm not going to the chair
'cause that ape in there
got trigger-happy.
The dough will be
here in the morning.
What good's the dough gonna
do you in the death house?
Listen, kid.
It's that gal.
She's got you all messed up.
Ain't I always learned ya?
You want something, take it.
Your brother
knows it's not
that simple, Griffin.
I'll make it that simple!
You stay out of this!
Hal gets what he wants.
I doubt it, Glenn.
I doubt if I ever will.
Listen, you yellow little punk!
They'll have
you back in stir
in less than an hour!
I can take care
of myself.
Since when?
Since right now!
I don't advise
your leaving here
now, Hal.
They won't catch me,
Mr. Hilliard.
Come along, Glenn.
You ain't gonna take no car.
I'll take the girl's coupe.
They'll have
that license plate
traced in 10 minutes.
Yeah.
Okay,
Mr. Hilliard.
I can pick up a car anywhere.
You're gonna listen to me.
You're not
stopping me,
neither one of you!
Who's stopping you?
You got more guts
than I thought, kid.
Here.
Take this.
I got more coming.
Thanks, Glenn.
Take care of yourself, see?
No chances.
You get in any trouble,
you know where I'll be.
Yeah.
Be careful, Hal.
Okay, Glenn.
I mean it, see?
What are you gaping at!
(CHUCKLING)
You better get hold
of yourself, Griffin.
I got hold.
You got yours coming, sweetie!
All of you!
Why did you let him go?
Good riddance.
He was getting on my nerves.
You satisfied?
Now listen, Griffin.
Shut up,
Mr. Hilliard!
"Mister," he called you.
You can't turn this on us.
Stay shut! I got my guts
good and full of you,
Mr. Hilliard,
guys like you,
smart-eyed,
respectable suckers.
We seen them, Kobish,
sitting on parole boards.
"Throw him back in his cell!
"He ain't fit to live
with decent folk."
Decent!
(MUSIC PLAYS ON RADIO)
ANNOUNCER:
We interrupt this program
to bring you a bulletin
from the WTLI newsroom.
We have an unconfirmed report
that the combined
police agencies
of the state, city,
and Federal Bureau
of Investigation
are now concentrating
a search for the three
escaped convicts
in an area just north of the
city limits of Indianapolis.
Glenn.
I got to phone.
What are you
going to do?
Shut up.
Stop the car.
Listen, fella,
I got a wife
and kids...
I said stop the car!
All right, get out.
Oh...
Get out!
(HORN HONKS)
Two cups of java
and some change,
please.
Oh, excuse me.
Hey, Nick!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(GUNFIRE)
(HONKS HORN)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Glenn! Glenn!
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
GRIFFIN: Take it, Hilliard.
Hello.
Yes.
This is Carl at the store.
You know that special
delivery letter
you told me about?
It just came.
There's nobody here
to bring it out to you.
Tell him you'll pick it up.
I'll be down right away, Carl.
Thanks.
GRIFFIN: Okay, snap it up.
Go to Ralphy.
The money's here.
I told the night
watchman to call me.
I'll be back right away.
Ellie, when they leave,
I'll have
to go along.
No!
Only for a short time,
and only me,
just to make sure they
get out of town safely.
I won't let you go!
Listen to me.
Wait four hours.
Four hours?
No longer.
If you don't
hear from me,
call the police.
Oh, Dan...
GRIFFIN: Snap it up up there!
Ellie, it's the only way.
That man hates you.
He'll kill you.
GRIFFIN: Hilliard,
that dough's waiting!
Darling we're not saved
if anything happens to you.
I won't let you go.
That's the way
it is, that's all.
You do as I say.
GRIFFIN: Hilliard, come on!
(CRYING)
Go in to your mother,
both of you.
Dad, come here.
Go ahead.
What is it?
When they take you,
I'm going, too.
You'll do nothing of the sort.
You'll do what I tell you.
I've had about all
I'm gonna take from you,
young man.
GRIFFIN: Come on. Hurry it up.
Grab a taxi,
but don't bring it
back here.
Just remember our deal.
On your way, pop.
I'll be back in 45 minutes.
Come on, step on it.
Get going.
All right, go ahead.
Two soups, take 'em away.
What is this?
What's your business?
Attorney,
Holmby and Edwards.
What's this all about?
Look, I'm in hurry,
so don't take me
around any curves.
What are you doing
cruising around
up here tonight?
Is that against the law?
Don't get fresh.
You can't hold me.
You got no warrant, no charges.
I don't bully, Officer.
You fronting for those rats?
What rats?
Maybe you don't read the papers.
We know they're up here, see?
Holed up in one of those houses.
What's up?
Nothing.
You know something.
No.
Suspect something.
Don't lie to me.
Your face looks like
I just kicked you.
It's just kind
of a shock,
that's all.
Why?
My girl lives around here.
Where?
Name, address.
I don't know what
I'd do if I were
in your shoes,
but I'm in mine,
and I'm gonna
get that name.
Now spit it out
or I'll slap you
in the pokey so fast...
You can't hold me.
Oh, yes, I can, if
you don't cooperate.
Withholding evidence,
aiding and abetting,
accessory to murder.
Carson speaking.
Yeah. They killed a man
this afternoon.
That's the kind of scum
you're letting your girl
spend the evening with.
Now talk, fast.
You'll have to make me.
I can do
that, too.
Hold it, will you?
Yeah. Spell it.
H-I-L-L-I-A-R-D.
"D" as in David.
Hilliard. Got it.
What happened?
The state police
killed Hal Griffin.
He was carrying a gun
registered in the name
of Daniel C. Hilliard.
Daniel C. Hilliard.
We got it!
One son, age 9.
Daughter, 19.
Cynthia.
I don't know her.
Then you got nothing
to worry about.
Alert everybody.
They're at
6459 North Preston.
We're moving in
as close as possible.
Okay, Chief.
Tom, throw a cordon
around this house.
Let no one in
or out of the block
and keep
everything out of sight
of the windows.
Listen, if I get inside
the house with a gun...
You listen. Don't
get any wild ideas.
We can't let anything
go haywire now.
Wait!
What can I do?
You can hightail it
out of here and maybe
say a prayer,
but nothing else, you hear?
Nothing!
COOK: Poach two and
an order of bacon.
(LAUGHS)
What's going on?
Where's the phone?
Around the corner.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Hey, up there!
Kobish, upstairs.
You take it, sis.
Hello?
Oh, I'm fine, Chuck.
Cindy, I've been thinking...
(ENGINE REVS)
Can you hear me?
I'm in a garage.
I said I've been thinking
about everything.
I've got to talk to your father.
I know he doesn't like me,
but let's get
the whole thing
straightened out now.
No! No, not tonight,
Chuck.
Uh...
Mother and Dad have company.
They're playing cards.
Oh. I don't care, Cindy.
I'm coming over.
You're not playing
cards, are you?
No, I...
Then you come out
when I honk the horn.
If you don't, I'll come in.
What's he up to?
What does he know?
You ain't going nowhere.
You heard him.
He'll come in here.
We don't want nobody
else in here now.
Shut up a minute.
Who calls it, Griffin?
We've still got two of them,
all we need to
get away, ain't it?
It's all right,
Cindy. You go.
What do you mean by that?
He means your old lady
is gonna be with us
in the car when we blow.
That means any cops
stashed outside,
any guns go off,
you'll find her in a ditch.
The brat, too.
(KNOCKING)
There you are,
Mr. Hilliard.
Thanks, Carl, thanks.
(HORN HONKING)
Is that him?
How come he
got here so quick?
(HONKING CONTINUES)
Go on.
No.
I'm staying here.
You're doing
nothing of the sort.
You're going out
that door now.
No!
Cindy, did you hear me?
(CRYING)
No, Mother!
He's getting out of the car.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
Cindy, please.
No, Mother.
I'm not leaving you.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
Hello, Cindy.
Mrs. Hilliard.
I told you, I can't go out.
Yes, she can, Chuck.
Oh, stop kidding me, Cindy.
Good night,
Mrs. Hilliard.
You're out, Cindy.
Thank God you're safe.
What do you mean?
(SOBBING)
Chuck, what...
They're all around
the block, Cindy.
(SOBBING)
Excuse me, sir.
Where are you going?
Home.
I'm going home.
What's it to you?
We're police officers.
What's your name?
Walling.
Claude Walling.
Address?
What's happened?
For God's sake, tell me
what's happening here.
Are you Daniel Hilliard?
I've got to get home.
Come along with us,
Mr. Hilliard,
and let's be quiet about it.
They're still in there, sir.
This way, please.
Mr. Hilliard...
Come on upstairs.
Dan.
We didn't know.
Claude...
Dad!
Your mother?
Ralphy?
No.
Mr. Hilliard?
Is Ralph okay?
Yeah, yeah.
Okay, Harris.
Stand by.
What I'm asking, Bard,
is how come you let
so much time get away
and did nothing?
Gentlemen, this is
Mr. Hilliard.
He was walking back
to his house.
How did
I slip up?
You didn't.
Young Griffin
is dead.
He had your gun.
My name is Masters,
sheriff of this county.
I just came on,
Mr. Hilliard.
I'm taking over.
Did you write this letter?
If you read that,
you know
the whole thing,
and that you can't use these.
Mister, you're
not telling us how
to do our job?
If you'd come to us
in the first place,
you wouldn't be in this fix.
I'd have been in it sooner.
Nobody's blaming you,
Mr. Hilliard.
Nobody in his right mind.
Are they both still
in the house?
Yeah.
How many guns?
One, with three bullets.
Well, that helps.
Also my wife and son.
Now, no one wants
to see innocent people
hurt, Mr. Hilliard.
Then get away from here.
Take your men, your guns,
your lights, and get away!
There's been
a murder committed
in my county.
The papers are
starting to scream.
I don't care.
What do I care?
My family's
in that house
over there!
You've got to consider
what those men can do
if they bluff their way
out of that trap.
You don't want them
to kill a lot of others.
I don't want them
or you to kill
my wife or boy.
That's first.
With me, that's first!
What do you suggest,
Mr. Hilliard?
I've got several thousand
dollars in my pocket.
Until they get that,
they're not coming out.
FREDERICKS: Then we move in.
What am I supposed to do,
sit up here and watch it happen?
It's plain suicide
to go back there, now.
Sheriff, there comes
a time when that fact
just doesn't enter in!
BARD: Masters, give him
a chance. Let him take
the dough in.
What's the difference
does it make whether you
get Griffin now
or when he comes out?
Just so you get him.
You'll win your election.
You're out of it.
You don't go back.
The minute you're
ready, we move in.
Gentlemen, since this
is a federal case,
it's my decision.
You want a gun,
Mr. Hilliard?
No, thanks.
They search you?
Yeah.
Carson, if this thing
blows up in your face,
I want a public statement
exonerating my office.
You'll get it.
I'll take the gun.
(BULLETS CLATTERING)
An empty gun?
You crazy?
Maybe.
But Griffin doesn't think so.
That's a pretty
long shot, isn't it?
I don't have
any short ones
in sight. Do you?
They're waiting for me.
Hilliard,
I'll give you 10 minutes
from the time you go
through that door.
And remember,
we're playing it your way.
Good luck, sir.
That gentleman's had it.
A man plays with dynamite,
he's gonna get it.
See that
he gets through.
Okay.
You got the dough?
ELLIE: Dan?
Stay with Ralphy,
and lock the door.
No! Before I let you go
with them, I'll scream!
I mean it!
You open your mouth,
missus, the old man
gets a slug in the stomach.
Now fork over the dough!
I'll give it to you in the car.
You'll give it right now.
Get your hands up.
Get them up!
I'll take that.
You'll take what?
(CHUCKLES)
You had it all doped out,
didn't you, Kobish?
Why, you
double-crossing rat!
Use your fat head.
Without me, you're cooked.
Here. Put this
in your pocket.
Forget your big ideas.
Okay. Let's roll.
Clickety clickety click.
You got to keep
trying, don't you, pop?
Right to the end.
Oh!
Ellie, go back in that room!
I'm ready, Griffin.
Yeah, but this gun
wasn't part of our deal.
Much as I appreciate it.
Dan, I meant
what I said.
Get in that room!
Lady, bring down
the kid. We're going
on a picnic.
Lock the door!
Knock it off, pop.
Now, didn't you
just hear me invite
the family to a picnic?
What are we
waiting for? I can
kick down that door.
I said I was
ready, Griffin.
I heard you,
but you're so full of ideas
that I'd feel better
in a car with lots
of people around me.
Cover this wise guy.
Did you hear that?
What?
Hey, folks,
you don't want to
miss the fun.
Sounded like...
GRIFFIN: Come on!
We're gonna be late
and all the ice cream's
going to be ate up.
What's going on
out there?
I don't know.
I thought I heard something.
GRIFFIN: You want me
to kick the door down?
Okay, lady,
you just ain't smart.
You bring the coppers
back here?
No. No.
You're lying
in your teeth.
(GRIFFIN KICKING DOOR)
You crazy?
I don't see nothing.
Might be hiding.
Could be the police.
GRIFFIN: Now, just do
as I say, lady, and junior
grows up to vote.
You out there!
Coppers!
We still got the Hilliards!
(SCREAMING)
(SCREAMS)
Oh, Dan!
(SCREAMING)
Dan!
Don't kill me!
(GUNFIRE)
Ralphy!
Dad!
Dad! Dad!
Oh, he's got Ralph!
Go out the back door.
Get over to the Wallings.
Do as I say!
Ralphy's going to be all right.
Dad, hurry!
Go ahead!
Dad!
You're gonna get me
out of this, Hilliard.
Let go of the boy, Griffin.
Fat chance with
those cops out there.
If you want my help, Griffin,
you'll take your hands off him.
Okay.
You move, kid,
I'll blow
your head off.
Ralph...
I want you to do exactly
what I tell you now.
This man is not
going to hurt you, son.
Just make a move, kid.
You'll find out.
Will you do exactly
as I say, Ralph?
Hilliard, you don't
know me if you think
I'm bluffing.
Run!
Feel that?
(CLICKING)
Out the back door.
The boy's coming out!
MAN ON LOUDSPEAKER:
Yes, we see him.
Mr. Hilliard,
are you all right?
Yes!
Stay where you are!
You ain't got it
in you, pop.
I got it in me.
You put it there.
What are you waiting for?
It's not going to be
that easy for you.
I want to tell you
about your brother.
He's dead.
Full of police bullets.
And you did it!
How does it feel?
How do you like it?
Go ahead.
Get it over with.
(COCKS GUN)
Can't do it, can you, pop?
Get out.
Get out of my house.
MAN ON LOUDSPEAKER:
We're waiting for Griffin,
Mr. Hilliard.
Look, pop...
Get out!
Let me have this.
Griffin, this is Bard speaking.
Come on out.
Griffin, we're waiting for you.
Come ahead, Griffin.
Mr. Hilliard, keep away
from the front of the house.
Griffin, raise your
hands above your head
and walk into the light.
BARD: Raise your hands
above your head!
(GUNFIRE)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(SIRENS WAILING)
Dad...
Yes, Ralph?
BARD: Congratulations,
Mr. Hilliard. Fine work.