(WOLF HOWLING)
JONATHAN: What was that?
NINA: Just a child
of the night, John.
Come.
Sit here beside me
on the verandah.
(DOOR CREAKING)
(FOOTSTEPS)
JONATHAN: It's chilly
out here.
NINA: Oh, no, it isn't
It's beautiful.
I love the night so.
I've never seen you look
so beautiful before, Nina.
So pale...
So...
Luminescent.
Yes?
Your lips
are so red.
Are they?
Would you like
to kiss them?
(KISSING)
(KISSING CONTINUES)
Why are you looking at
me so strangely, Nina?
It's not you, Jonathan.
Your neck!
Has anyone ever told you
it looks beautiful.
JONATHAN: No.
Come.
Lay your head
on my breast.
Stop, you creature
of the night!
(HISSING)
Who are you who interrupts
my nightly feeding?
I am Peter Vincent,
vampire killer!
No!
(KISSING)
NINA: No! Keep away!
Keep away from me!
(WHIMPERING)
No.
(THUD)
(NINA SCREAMING)
(MAN SCREAMING)
(MOANING)
(KISSING)
TV ANNOUNCER: And now
your host, Peter Vincent.
WOMAN: Fright Night!
This is Peter Vincent,
bringing you
Fright Night theater.
Charley, Peter Vincent's on.
Forget Peter Vincent.
But you love him.
(IMITATING VAMPIRE)
But I love you more.
(LAUGHING)
Tonight's journey
into horror
is Blood Castle.
I think if would
Charley, stop it.
PETER: I know it will.
It is one of my favorites
for a very good reason.
I star in it.
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
WOMAN: Fright Night!
Charley,
I said stop it!
Jesus, Amy,
give me a break!
We've been going together almost a year, and
all I ever hear is, "Charley, stop it."
I'm sorry, Amy.
Me, too.
I'm just scared,
that's all.
(MOANING)
Let's get into bed.
You mean it?
Charley...
I'm ready.
Amy, you're not gonna
believe this.
There are two guys out in the yard and
I think they're carrying a coffin.
(HOWLING) MAN: We have
pledged ourselves to evil.
Sure.
And they're on
the moors, right?
Amy, I'm serious.
So am I.
Do you wanna make love or not?
Amy, quick come here.
You've got to see this!
(DOOR SLAMS)
Amy!
Okay, maybe it
wasn't a coffin,
but I did see two guys carrying
something into that house.
I don't understand you.
First you want to make love, and then you don't.
Amy? Charley?
What's wrong?
Uh, nothing, mom.
Come in here, you two.
Are you kids having
a lover's spat?
No, mom,
nothing like that.
Well, there's nothing
wrong with it.
It says right here that the
divorce rate is 76% higher
among couples who don't
argue before marriage.
Mom, we're in high school.
Well, never hurts
to plan ahead.
Oh, Amy, will you
remind your mother
we are playing poker
at her house this weekend.
Yes, Mrs. Brewster.
Well, good night, Charley.
Yeah, good night.
Good night, Mrs. Brewster.
Goodnight, Amy. Thanks for helping
Charley with his homework.
Any time.
See you tomorrow, Charley?
Charley,
that wasn't very nice.
Not walking Amy
to the front door.
Mom, there are
people next door.
Oh, I guess the new
owner is moving in.
What new owner?
Didn't I tell you? Bob Hopkins said
he'd finally got rid of the place.
Who'd he sell it to?
I don't know, some fellow who
fixes up houses for a living.
Supposed to be
very attractive, though.
I just hope whoever he is, he knows
what he's getting into with this house.
And now for the local news.
A man was found
murdered tonight
behind the rail road yards.
Details are pending, awaiting
notification of next of kin.
Thank you, Mr. Smith.
Have a good weekend.
That bastard!
Why didn't he tell us he was
going to spring a pop quiz?
Well, that's the point
to a pop quiz, Brewster,
to surprise you.
Thanks, Teach.
Hey, Amy. Amy!
Did she finally find out
what you're really like?
Buzz off, Evil.
Call me anything you want.
You're the one failing
Trig, not me.
(ROCK AND ROLL MUSIC
PLAYING ON RADIO)
(MUSIC STOPS)
(HUMMING)
Oh.
Is this 99 Oak?
No. No,
that's next door.
Oh. Thanks.
Hey, mom? Yeah? I'm in here.
Have you seen the new
guy next door yet?
No, but I did hear
he's got a live-in carpenter.
My luck.
He's probably gay.
No. I don't think so.
Why? What do you know
that I don't?
Oh, nothing. I've got to study.
I'll see you later.
Study? You?
(GIRL SCREAMING)
(ROCK MYSELF TO SLEEP
PLAYING)
♪ Rock myself to sleep
♪ Every night
I rock myself to sleep
♪ Just thinking about her ♪
Hi.
Hi!
Look, I'm really sorry
about the other night.
Oh, it was my fault.
Not yours.
It was?
Look, Amy, I love you.
I never want to fight
with you again, okay?
I'm glad we're getting
this straightened out.
I've been miserable
the last two days.
MAN ON TV: ...the second
murder in two days.
The second victim, whose body
was found early this morning,
was a known prostitute.
...not talking to
you on the phone.
Charley, are you
listening to me?
MAN ON TV: The badly
mutilated corpse
was found under the north creek
bridge by the old mill.
As yet, the police
have no leads.
You know what I heard
on the police band last night?
What?
That wasn't
the only murder.
The second in two days.
And get this...
Both of them had
their heads chopped off.
(CHUCKLES)
Can you believe it?
You're sick.
Hey!
Charley?
(LAUGHING)
Oh, you're so cool,
Brewster!
I can't stand it!
Hey, kid!
(GASPS)
What are you doing?
Nothing.
Oh, yeah?
Well, just make sure
it stays that way, kid.
(GIRL SCREAMING ON TV)
Oh!
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
Mom, you got to get up!
Mom, I can't believe
what's happening next door.
What, what, what?
He has fangs!
The guy who bought the house has fangs.
Oh, fangs. That's lovely Charley!
I have to get up at 7:00.
(DOOR OPENING)
Charley?
(FOOTSTEPS)
(WIND RUSHING)
You forgot something.
(BITING APPLE)
Charley.
(GASPS)
What are you...
This microwave never melts
marshmallows right.
Drink that.
Mom, I don't need hot cocoa.
I didn't have a nightmare.
They did kill
a girl over there.
How late did you
stay up studying?
Mom, I'm not sick!
The guy did have fangs, and
a bat did fly over my head.
And a second later he
stepped out of the shadows.
Don't you see
what that means?
Wait let me guess. What?
He's a vampire.
A What?
A Vampire! Damn it, haven't you
listened to anything I have said?
Charley, is this some sort
of a trick to get me back?
Forget it.
I'm going to the police.
Charley, you can't go to the
police with a story like that.
They'll lock you up.
All right, then I won't
tell them he's a vampire.
But I'll tell them
about the two women.
Charley! Charley!
You sure about this now?
Yes?
Mr. Dandrige?
I'm his roommate,
Billy Cole.
Lieutenant Lennox, homicide.
Mind if we come in?
No, come on in.
LENNOX: Quite a place
you have here.
BILLY: Yeah,
we're restoring it.
Where is
Mr. Dandrige?
He's away on business.
ls there anything I can help with?
A murder occurred
last night.
Charley lives next door, thinks
he saw the victim in this house.
Jerry and I were
the only people here.
That's a lie. He carried her
body out in a plastic bag.
What do you say
to that, Mr. Cole?
The kid's crazy,
officer.
I took some bags
of trash out last night.
Amy.
BILLY: Let me show you.
The bag I saw had a body in it.
Not trash.
You actually
see the body, Charley?
No, but---
I'll show you the bags
I put in the garbage.
Okay, let's see them.
Look I can prove
he's lying!
Look in the basement.
What's down there,
Charley?
Yes, Charley.
What's down there?
Obviously,
the boy's made a mistake.
A coffin.
I saw them carry it in.
What?
You'll find
Jerry Dandrige in it,
sleeping the sleep
of the undead!
Ooh!
(LAUGHS)
What are you saying?
He's a vampire.
I saw him in that room last night.
He had fangs, and he bit her neck.
For heaven's sake!
Come on.
We can't leave
like this!
LENNOX: I've got
a coffin for you.
Lieutenant, please,
please listen to me.
Jerry Dandrige
is a vampire.
Sure, and I'm Dirty Harry.
Now let me tell you something, kid.
If I ever catch your ass
at the station again,
I'm throwing it
in jail forever!
Lieutenant, please.
Just listen to me.
I know its crazy,
but... Lieutenant!
(FOOTSTEPS)
Oh, my God!
CHARLEY: Evil!
Evil! Evil!
To what do I owe
this dubious pleasure?
The vampire knows I know about
him, or he will tonight.
(CHUCKLING) What are
you talking about?
A vampire lives
next door to me.
He'll kill me unless
I protect myself.
(LAUGHS) What?
Evil, I can't explain.
Tell me how
to protect myself.
Very funny.
I'm not kidding.
Tell me what to do.
Don't call me Evil!
Why should I help you?
I've got eight bucks.
Help me and it's yours.
Far be it for me to turn
down a fool's money.
Now...
Where and when do you expect
the vampire to attack?
In my bedroom tonight.
Start With this.
But...
You must have total faith
in it for it to work.
Put links of garlic
around your neck
and hang some
from your window.
If he comes for you,
that will be the way.
Then there's holy water,
but a priest has to say
a blessing over it first.
That's it?
I'm afraid so.
Your best protection now,
Charles,
is that a vampire cannot enter
your house without being invited
by the rightful owner first.
Are you sure?
Positive!
Thank you.
JUDY: Charley,
could you come down here?
There's someone
I'd like you to meet.
(WHISTLING) Yeah, mom.
(HUMMING)
Charley, this is our
neighbor, Jerry Dandrige.
Hello, Charley.
Well, Charley, don't be rude.
Shake hands.
What's he doing here?
I invited him for drinks.
What?
I invited him over.
Why?
What's wrong?
Afraid I'd never come
without being invited?
You're right.
Now that I've been
made welcome,
I'll probably
drop by quite a bit.
In fact, anytime
I feel like it.
With your mother's
kind permission, of course.
Oh, anytime.
It's so nice that
someone interesting
has finally moved
into the neighborhood.
Charley, are you all right?
Yeah, mom, I'm fine.
I've got to
get back to my Trig.
Nice to meet you,
Charley.
See you.
Soon.
(WIND HOWLING)
(THUD)
(THUDDING)
(DOOR CREAKS)
(CREAKING)
(CREAKING CONTINUES)
(SIGHS)
(RATTLING)
(SNAPPING)
(WHISTLING
STRANGERS IN THE NIGHT)
(SIGHS)
(GASPING)
We shouldn't
wake your mother.
Then I'd have to
kill her, too.
Right?
(SCREAMING)
Do you realize how much
trouble you've caused me?
(CHOKING)
Spying on me,
almost disturbing
my sleep this afternoon,
telling policemen about me!
You deserve to die, boy.
Of course, I could give you
something I don't have.
A choice.
Forget about me, Charley.
Forget about me,
and I'll forget about you.
What do you say, Charley?
Fool.
(SCREAMING)
(COUGHING)
(GROWLING)
JUDY: Charley?
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Charley!
Huh!
Charley.
I can't open this door.
Charley!
(GROWLS)
(KNOCKING)
Charley, can you hear me?
Charley, is that you?
Charley, my door is stuck.
Charley.
Charley!
Charley, what's going on?
Nothing.
I just had a nightmare.
(SIGHS)
(GASPS)
I had one last night!
I was at this white sale.
I suddenly realized
I was naked...
(CRASHING)
What's that?
Raccoons.
Go back to sleep.
What about
your nightmare?
Do you want a valium?
No, I'm fine now.
Honest.
I start night shift
tomorrow.
Three o'clock in the morning.
It's bad for my complexion.
Night, Mom.
(BAT SCREECHES ON TV)
(SCREAMING)
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
I know you're there, Charley.
I see you.
(WIND HOWLS)
What's the matter,
Charley? Scared?
You started this, Charley,
and I'm going to finish it.
I just destroyed
your car, Charley,
but that's nothing compared to
what I'm going to do to you...
Tomorrow night.
MAN ON TV: And once again,
your host, Peter Vincent.
PETER: Good evening,
horror fans.
Did you know
there are a lot of people
who do not believe
in vampires?
Well, I do.
Because I know they exist.
I have fought them
in all their guises.
Man, wolves, bats.
And I have always won!
That is why they call me
the great vampire killer.
Watch me do it.
Go, Peter.
Mr. Vincent.
Could I talk to you?
It's very,
very important.
What do you
want me to sign?
Pardon me?
You do want
my autograph, don't you?
No.
I was curious about what you
said last night on TV, you know,
about believing
in vampires.
What about it?
Were you serious?
Oh, absolutely.
Unfortunately, none of your
generation seems to be.
What?
I have just been fired
because nobody wants to see
vampire killers any more.
All they want are demented
madmen hacking up young virgins.
If you will excuse me...
I believe in vampires.
That's nice.
If only there had been
more of you,
my ratings might
have been higher.
I have one living
next door to me.
Would you help me kill him?
Pardon me?
Remember the murder
of that girl?
Yes.
The guy next door
to me did it.
He's a vampire.
If this is a joke,
I'm not amused.
I am not joking.
I am deadly serious
Oh, well.
If you will excuse me...
Mr. Vincent, you have
to believe me.
I'm telling the truth.
You just said you believe in vampires.
I lied.
Please!
Leave me alone.
You have to listen to me.
The vampire tried
to kill me last night
and trashed my car
when he didn't succeed.
He's going to be back
after me tonight.
And if I don't get help
he's gonna kill me.
(ENGINE STARTING) Mr.
Vincent, please! Listen to me.
No! Wait!
Mr. Vincent, wait!
What are you
doing here?
What about you?
I thought you just dumped him.
None of your business.
You do like him!
AMY: Anybody home?
Hi!
Wow!
What's all this for?
Self-defense.
Not that I'll need it.
He'll be dead
before nightfall.
Who will be?
Dandrige.
I am waiting for the guy
he lives with to leave
and then I am going to go
next door to find his coffin
and then pound this
through his heart.
That's murder, Charley.
You can't murder
a vampire, Amy.
They're dead, remember?
Listen. Listen.
I just taped this.
Amy!
What are we going to do?
This is just
like Fright Night.
MAN ON RADIO:
Now for the 2:00 news.
Another body of a woman was discovered early
this morning in the back of a Sheridan...
See that?
I don't have any choice.
Somebody has to stop him.
Charley, it's going
to be dangerous
going into that house
all alone, isn't it?
I mean, you're gonna need all
the help you can get, right?
Somebody like Peter Vincent,
for instance?
ED: Yeah!
I tried him already.
Well, why don't you let us try
again before you do anything.
There's not enough time, Amy!
What if you go into that
house alone and he gets you?
Who's gonna stop him then?
Yeah, then he'll be able to suck
his way through the entire town.
But it wouldn't be
much of a loss.
Charley, it's going
to be dark soon.
You don't want to go into
that house then, do you?
No. You're right there.
All right,
we'll try him again.
Great!
Now, you promise you're
not gonna do anything
till you
hear from us, okay?
Okay. Come on.
Amy.
You don't believe me,
do you?
I love you, Charley.
ED: Hey, Amy, come on!
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Yes?
Mr. Vincent, could we
talk to you for a moment?
Oh, well, I'm afraid
now is not the best time.
Please.
It's very important.
(STUTTERING) If you would just
wait there for one moment,
I'll... Um...
Come in!
Now, what can
I do for you?
(STAMMERING)
An autograph, perhaps,
or perhaps an interview
for your school newspaper?
I'm afraid this is
much more important.
Really?
What could be more important
than my autograph?
Saving a boy's life.
Oh, yes.
I can see where that
could be more important.
Perhaps you would
care to explain.
You remember a fruitcake kid
named Charley Brewster?
He said he came
to see you.
No.
He's the one that believes a vampire
is living next door to him.
Oh, yes. You know,
he is insane.
Oh, my dear, I do hope
he's not a friend of yours.
Yeah, she's got
the hots for the creep.
Amy!
We need your help
to stop him, Mr. Vincent.
See, he really does believe his
next door neighbor is a vampire
and he's planning
to kill him.
Yeah. With a stake
through the heart.
Are you two serious?
Your friend needs a psychiatrist,
not a vampire killer.
Please, Mr. Vincent.
I'm afraid not.
You see,
Hollywood beckons.
I have just been offered a
starring role in a major film.
I have even had to quit Fright Night.
And so you see...
AMY: I'll give you money.
How much?
I have a $500
savings bond.
I'll take it.
Now, how are we
going to cure
your little friend
of his delusion?
I got it all
figured out.
We all go next door
to the neighbor,
and you perform some kind
of vampire test on him
to pronounce him human.
You know, like in
Orgy of the Damned,
where you looked
in the mirror,
the guy didn't have
a reflection,
and then you knew
he was a vampire.
Yes.
That was one of
my favorite roles.
Do you know...
I still have the prop.
(CLOCKS CHIMING)
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Yes.
It's for you.
(YAWNS)
Yes?
Yes, this is
Jerry Dandrige.
I see.
Well, yes.
Yes, of course.
I'm always willing
to help young people,
but I'm afraid that crosses
are out of the question.
You see, I've been
reborn recently.
He's a reborn Christian.
He thinks crosses
would be sacrilegious.
Ask him how he feels
about holy water?
How about holy water?
No.
Tell him it's just ordinary tap water.
All he has to do is sip it.
Yes.
Well, yes. Yes, okay.
That sounds fine,
but don't bring him over
until 6:00 tomorrow.
I'll be out until then.
Well, it seems we don't have
to go out tonight after all.
His friends are bringing
him over tomorrow night
to prove to him that
I'm not a vampire.
(CHUCKLING)
It's 6:10. He said he would
be here at 6:00, right?
Relax, he said he'd be here.
He'll be here.
Here he comes!
Oh, thank you.
Charley Brewster,
I presume.
Peter Vincent,
vampire killer.
Mr. Vincent, I cannot tell you
how much I appreciate this.
Good evening. Good evening.
Now, down to business.
Where is the lair of this
suspected creature of the night?
There.
Oh, yes, I see
what you mean.
There is
a distinct possibility.
Shall we go?
Hey, wait, wait a minute, wait a minute,
where's your stakes and hammers?
Oh, I left that
in my bag.
You're not going in
there without them!
But, I have to prove that he's a
vampire before I kill him, Charley.
Look, I know
he's a vampire!
I am the one
who has to know, Charley.
How're you gonna do that?
This is holy water.
If a drop touches him,
he will blister.
In this case, I've asked him to
drink it while we all watch.
He readily agreed.
Yeah, but, Mr. Vincent, if I am right
and you prove he is a vampire,
he's gonna kill us all
right then and there.
No, he won't, Charley, after
all I am here to protect you.
I am Peter Vincent...
I know, Mr. Vincent, but...
Hey, Peter Vincent.
Billy Cole.
This is a pleasure.
Oh.
Won't you all come in?
Hello.
And Charley.
Hey, Jer!
They're here.
Perhaps,
he didn't hear you.
Oh, he heard me,
all right.
(BITING APPLE)
Ah.
Mr. Vincent, I've seen
all of your films,
and I've found them
very amusing.
Oh, thank you.
And, uh,
who are these two...
Attractive young people?
Ed Thompson.
Ed.
PETER: Amy Peterson.
Charmed.
Isn't that what vampires are
supposed to do, Charley?
(LAUGHING)
That's some vampire,
Brewster.
(SIGHS) Oh, God!
He's neat.
Ah.
Please excuse the mess.
I haven't finished unpacking.
Where do you keep your coffin?
Or do you have more than one?
Charley!
It's all right,
Mr. Vincent.
I'm used to it by now.
As you may or may not know,
Charley even brought the
police over a few days ago.
Charley, you didn't.
Damn right I did. Only, they didn't
believe me any more than any of you,
but you'll believe me
in a second.
Mr. Vincent,
give him the holy water.
Charley, there's no reason
to be rude about this.
It's perfectly all right,
Mr. Vincent.
Where is it?
And are you sure that
this is, uh, holy water?
Positive.
I saw Father Scanlon bless it down
at St. Mary's myself.
Get ready to run.
I'll protect you with this.
Well...
Bottoms up.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Ah.
There.
Satisfied?
Totally.
Well, now, Charley,
you saw that.
Are you convinced now
that Mr. Dandrige is not a vampire?
It can't be.
But, Charley, you saw it.
You know, as well as I do that no
vampire can drink blessed water.
Then it wasn't blessed.
Are you calling me
a liar, young man?
If he's not a vampire,
have him touch this.
Oh, Charley!
You've made a fool
of yourself once.
There's no reason
to compound the error.
Yes, Charley. You've already caused
your friends quite enough pain.
You wouldn't want to cause
them any more, would you?
No.
No, of course not.
And you're finally convinced
I'm not a vampire, either.
DANDRIGE: Right?
Yes.
Well, I'm glad
that's settled.
I can't tell you
how much
I appreciate this, Mr. Vincent.
You've been a great help.
PETER: Not at all.
Glad to be of service.
DANDRIGE: It was nice
meeting both of you.
Please feel free
to drop by anytime.
You'll always be welcome.
I'd like that,
Mr. Dandrige.
Please call me Jerry.
CHARLEY: Come on,
let's get out of here.
AMY: Just a minute.
DANDRIGE: That goes for you too, Ed.
I expect we have a lot of the
same interests, you know,
in horror movies
and the occult.
(MIRROR LANDING ON FLOOR)
Something wrong,
Mr. Vincent?
(STAMMERS) No... I...
I felt a little...
Oh, it, it...
It's just my clumsiness.
Are you sure?
Oh, yeah, I'm positive.
We've been taking up
too much of your time.
Thank you so much.
Come along now,
everybody.
Thank you.
Bye-bye.
What's wrong with you?
Nothing.
Then why are you shaking?
I'm not shaking.
You saw something
in there, didn't you?
You saw something that convinced
you he was a vampire.
Of course not.
Please, Mr. Vincent,
you have to tell me.
Our lives depend on it.
All right!
He didn't cast a reflection
in my mirror.
(CAR ENGINE STARTS)
Satisfied now?
Mr. Vincent, you have
to call the police!
Mr. Vincent! Shit!
Where you going,
pencil dick?
(CHUCKLING) Home!
No way! We walk
Amy home first.
DANDRIGE: Looks just
like her, doesn't she?
One good thing.
They'll never
believe him now.
(GLASS CRUNCHING)
DANDRIGE: No?
Let's cut
through here.
No way! Come on, we want people and lights.
The more, the better.
Ah, listen, Brewster,
vampires don't exist.
Haven't you gotten that
through your thick head, yet?
What if you're wrong, Evil?
What if Dandrige is a vampire
and he thinks
you know it?
Would you walk down
that alley then?
Oh, fuck you,
Brewster.
All right, come on, please
just stick with us, all right?
Forget it! You may be
chicken shit, but I'm not.
What do we do?
Let him go. No vampire's
gonna want him anyway.
Probably give him
blood poisoning.
(ED SCREAMING)
(WHIMPERING)
Are you all right?
Jesus, I warned him!
He got me, Charley!
He bit me!
You know what you're gonna
have to do now, don't you?
Kill me.
Kill me, Charley.
Before I turn into a vampire
and give you a hickey!
(LAUGHING)
You asshole!
You really believed me,
you poor dope!
You'll get yours someday.
Oh, yeah, when?
When I'm bit by a vampire?
There are no such things
as vampires, fruitcake!
Jeez!
(FOOTSTEPS)
(WIND RUSHING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Charley, Amy, is that you?
If that's you, it's not working.
I'm not scared.
Shit!
(PANTING)
(YELLS)
Hello, Edward.
You don't have to
be afraid of me.
I know what it's like
being different.
They won't
pick on you any more
or beat you up.
I'll see to that.
All you have to do
is take my hand.
Here, Edward,
take my hand.
(ED SCREAMING)
What was that?
It was just Evil
messing around again.
Cut it out, Evil!
It's not funny!
Amy, what if Evil
was really in trouble?
Charley, you're not going to let
him sucker you in again, are you?
(EXPLOSION)
Tell me this
is a power outage.
Well, what else
would it be?
(WIND RUSHING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(CLUB MUSIC PLAYING)
Hey! Hey, you
can't come in here!
(ARMIES OF THE NIGHT PLAYING)
♪ The armies of the night
Are coming, they're coming
♪ Life will be a scream
For you and me ♪
Who're you calling?
The police.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Who is it?
EDI It's me, Evil Ed.
PETER: What do you want?
Hurry, there's a vampire
out here. Let me in!
(PANTING) What're we gonna do?
What're you gonna do?
Not me!
(SCREECHES)
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
Now, I used to admire you,
you know that?
Of course,
that was before
(WHIMPERING) I found out
what a fake you were.
Peter Vincent!
The great
vampire killer!
(SCREAMING)
(WHIMPERS)
(GULPS)
What have you done to me?
Back!
(GROANING)
The Master will
kill you for this,
but not fast!
Slowly! Oh, so slowly!
Back!
(GROANS)
I say back!
He doesn't believe me!
I'm scared, Charley.
I'm really scared.
I am not going to
let him get you, Amy.
I promise.
You got
Peter Vincent's number?
He doesn't care about us!
I paid him to be there today.
It doesn't matter, Amy.
We don't have any choice.
Give me his number.
(GOOD MAN IN A BAD TIME
PLAYING)
♪ Inside close quarters
♪ Night's calling
Under blood red skies
♪ This madness starts burning
♪ The victim
Of a strange desire
♪ Mistaken, we follow
♪ Restless emotions
Take you down
♪ Unwilling, still hunger
♪ For lustful pleasures
I have found
(GASPS)
♪ He's a good man
In a bad time
Look, you've
got to help us.
Dandrige has me and Amy
trapped in this club.
No, Charley, I'm sorry.
I just can't do that.
Mr. Vincent,
you've got to come.
Come on, you're the only one
who knows what's going on!
♪ Soft voices seduce you
♪ A butterfly
In a spider's web
♪ Infectious behavior
♪ You're damned
To do it all again
♪ He's a good man
In a bad time
In a bad time ♪
(GIVE IT UP PLAYING)
♪ Wonder why
♪ I try to fight the chemistry
♪ I get high
♪ Every time
Your body looks at me
♪ I don't need a book
To show me how
♪ I don't need
An English teacher
♪ To help me to say
I want you now
♪ I'll give it up
Yes sweet honey you win
♪ Ooh I wanna
Give in to temptation
♪ A fire's burning
Underneath my skin
♪ That tells me
Stop the hesitation
♪ Well I try to do
The things you want me to
♪ Yes you're right
♪ You want me
And I want you too
♪ No ones gonna tell me
Wrong from right
♪ Oooooh oooooh
♪ Lovin' you
Is all that matters
♪ Baby I can't wait
Another night
♪ I'll give it up
Yes sweet honey you win
♪ Ooh, I wanna
Give in to temptation
♪ A fire is burning
Underneath my skin
Let her go.
♪ That tells me
Stop the hesitation ♪
Filthy son of a bitch!
You shouldn't lose
your temper, Charley.
It isn't polite.
You can't kill me here.
I don't want
to kill you, Charley.
(GROANS)
I want you to bring Peter Vincent
to my house, just the two of you.
That is, if you ever
want to see Amy again.
Let her go!
I got him.
She's mine.
Man, you go
someplace else.
Out of my way.
Move it.
(GROWLING)
Leon!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(YOU CAN'T HIDE FROM
THE BEAST INSIDE PLAYING)
♪ You can't run
♪ You can't hide
♪ There ain't nothin'
You can do
♪ Can you run
♪ From the beast
Inside of you ♪
Amy!
Charley!
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
Peter!
Peter, open the door!
PETER: Who is it?
It's me, Charley Brewster.
Let me in.
Are you one of them?
What're you talking about?
Here.
Grab this.
Come on!
Peter, we don't
have much time.
Dandrige chased me
and Amy all over town.
He trapped us in this
place called The Club...
What're you doing?
I'm leaving.
You can't!
Just watch me.
But Dandrige has Amy!
He says he's gonna kill her
unless we come to his house.
Oh, my God!
The police!
I'll call the police.
They won't believe you.
I've tried.
Peter, it's just us.
We're going to
have to save Amy.
I can't.
I...
was paid...
to be there today.
I know.
You still
want my help?
Yes.
You're Peter Vincent.
The great vampire killer.
That is a character
in a movie.
That isn't even
my real name.
I'm terrified.
I'm sorry, Charley,
but I am.
I can't do it alone, Peter.
If you don't help,
Amy is going to die.
Me, too, probably.
Please, Peter.
I'm sorry, Charley.
(ROMANTIC INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC PLAYING)
(MOANS)
She's someone I knew
a long time ago.
Where am I?
Where's Charley?
(SOFTLY) Where?
(ROMANTIC MUSIC CONTINUES)
(MOANING)
I...
(GASPS)
(MOANING)
Peter Vincent,
ready to battle the undead.
Peter,
this is serious.
I am serious.
Hold this.
Clamp.
There.
Let's see, now.
Flashlight, stakes, hammer.
Ah, yes, a cross.
How are you going to
stop Billy Cole?
With this. It's from
Orgy Of the Damned.
Bullets won't stop him
if he's not human.
Doesn't he walk
in daylight?
Yeah.
Then he is human.
Come on.
Peter,
I want to thank you.
Not now.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Nothing at all.
(CREAKING)
Are you crazy?
Not the front door.
Let's go around back. Sneak in.
(CREAKING)
Too late.
I am Peter Vincent,
the great vampire killer.
(DOOR SLAMS)
Oh.
(SIGHS)
This way.
(WIND RUSHING)
Did you hear something?
No.
Let's come back at dawn.
He'll be asleep then.
We'll have a better
chance of getting Amy.
Amy will be dead
by then. Come on.
(SCRATCHING)
(IMITATING PETER)
Welcome to Fright Night.
For real.
Where's Amy?
Up here.
All you have to do
is get by me.
Back,
spawn of Satan.
(LAUGHING SARCASTICALLY)
Oh, really?
You have to have faith
for this to work on me,
Mr. Vincent.
Stop.
Back.
(MOANING)
We're gonna make it.
(GRUNTS)
(THUD)
(WHIMPERING)
(CHUCKLES)
Mrs. Brewster.
Operator, get me the...
Thank God.
The phone wires
have been cut.
I know.
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
I did it.
Where is Charley's mother?
Oh. Well, apparently
she's working nights.
But she left a note.
Oh.
Mmm. Mmm.
His dinner's in the oven.
(GRUNTING)
(GASPING)
(GROWLING)
Ah.
(WHIMPERING)
(SCREAMING)
(WOLF MOANING)
(GROWLING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(MOANING)
(WHIMPERING)
I...
(GRUNTS)
You wanted her,
there she is.
Here. You're going to need it
just before dawn.
What have you
done to her?
(WHISTLING)
Amy?
No!
(SIGHS)
(WIND GUSHING)
(SNIFFLING)
Charley.
Peter?
Charley, I'm going
to break the door down.
Make as much noise
as you can.
Help. Help.
Let me out.
Help.
Open the door!
I think she just
opened her eyes.
Help.
Help, somebody.
Grab her.
Let's get out of here.
We can't. Look.
Oh, my God.
Something wrong?
Yes.
We have a visitor.
Is it too late
to save her?
No.
Not if we kill Dandrige
before dawn.
Are you sure?
Everything has been
like it was in movies.
We just have
to keep hoping.
(HEAVY BREATHING)
Let's go.
(GROANING)
Well.
What do we have here?
Vampire killers?
Stop, or I'll shoot.
I mean it.
Don't make me shoot.
Stop.
(GROANING)
We have him.
Do you?
What did he mean
by that?
Nothing.
He was just bluffing.
(FLOORBOARDS CREAKING)
Oh.
(THUDDING)
(FLOORBOARDS CREAKING)
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS)
Amy.
(MOANING)
Amy?
(GROWLING)
CHARLEY: Peter.
She's worse.
We're running out
of time.
(HEAVY BREATHING)
DANDRIGE: Amy awake.
I command you to...
(GROANING)
awake.
Show me how much
you love me, Amy.
Kill them.
(GASPS)
Both.
(GRUNTS)
He's on the roof.
I'm going up there.
(AMY SCREAMING)
(GROWLS)
(GASPS)
(SCREAMING)
Charley.
CHARLEY: He's not up here.
Look out.
(SCREAMS)
He's going downstairs.
Charley.
(BANGING ON DOOR)
So.
Stay back.
(SNARLING)
Back.
(GRUNTING)
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
You have to have faith
for that to work,
Mr. Vincent.
Remember?
(CONTINUES LAUGHING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
(CLOCKS CHIMING)
(WHIMPERING)
(GRUNTS)
You're out of time,
Mr. Dandrige.
Look over your shoulder.
(GRUNTS)
No!
(SCREAMING)
Charley. Back.
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
(GROWLING)
(SCREAMS)
(SCREECHING)
Are you all right?
Yeah.
He's in the basement.
His coffin.
It's got to be down here somewhere.
(DOOR CREAKING)
What was that?
You keep searching.
I'll check it out.
Amy? It's me.
I know.
(SNARLING)
Oh.
Charley.
I found it.
Don't be frightened,
Charley.
Hurry, Peter.
Get it open.
He's locked it
from the inside.
What's wrong?
Don't you
want me any more?
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMS)
It's not my fault,
Charley.
You promised
you wouldn't let him get me.
You promised.
Amy.
(CROSS DROPS)
(GROWLS)
(SCREAMS)
(SNARLING)
(GRUNTS)
CHARLEY: Peter.
(GROWLING)
(SNARLS)
(SCREAMING)
(GROWLS)
(GROANING)
(SCREAMS)
Charley, watch out.
(SHRIEKING)
(GROANING)
(SCREAMING)
(LAUGHING TRIUMPHANTLY)
Amy!
MAN ON TV: Look, we've
been going in a circle.
MAN 2: We're back
where we started.
TV ANNOUNCER: Ladies and gentlemen,
Fright Night theater.
PETER:
This is Peter Vincent.
Back once more
as host of Fright Night.
I thought I'd let the vampires
rest for a little while.
Right, Charley?
Tonight, the threat comes
not from beyond the grave,
but from beyond the stars
as alien beings stalk
an unwary summer camp
in Mars Wants Flesh.
I do not star in it.
(MAN SCREAMING)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
Charley?
ls something wrong?
No.
(ED LAUGHING)
ED: Oh, you're
so cool, Brewster.
(FRIGHT NIGHT PLAYING)
♪ Fright, fright
Fright, fright
♪ Night, night
Night, night
♪ Fright, fright
Fright, fright
♪ Night night
♪ Ooh
♪ People say I'm crazy
♪ And I make no sense
♪ But they don't understand
The man's got influence
♪ He's a gigolo or liar
♪ A man of many faces
♪ So don't be fooled
♪ By what you think you see
♪ He's gonna make his move
♪ On you and me
♪ Fright Night
♪ Fright night
♪ Who's it gonna be tonight
♪ Lock your doors
And windows tight
♪ Soon we'll all believe
I'm right
♪ We're all in
For a most frightening night
♪ Night, night
Night, night
♪ Ooh
♪ Intuition tells me
That it's time to blow
♪ But my sense of danger
Tells me no
♪ I've got to find a weakness
♪ To put an end to this
♪ Can't you see
He's tearing us apart
♪ I've got to drive a stake
Right through his heart
♪ Fright Night
♪ Fright night
♪ Who's it gonna be tonight
♪ Lock your doors
And windows tight
♪ Soon we'll all believe
I'm right
♪ We're all in
For a most frightening night
♪ Night, night
Night, night
♪ Ooh
♪ Fright night
♪ Bop a di di
Bop choo bop a di dz
♪ Fright night
♪ Bop a di di
Bop choo bop a di dz
♪ Fright night
♪ Aaahh
♪ I look into the mirror
And it's as black as night
♪ I see it fall to pieces
As my heart ignites
♪ Just waiting for the moment
♪ For that commanding thing
♪ Don't make a move
♪ We've got to keep this in
♪ We're waiting here
♪ And we're dressed up to kill
♪ Fright night
♪ Who's it gonna be tonight?
♪ Lock your doors
And windows tight
♪ Soon we'll all believe
I'm right
♪ We're all in
For a most frightening night
♪ Fright night
♪ Who's it gonna be tonight?
♪ Lock your doors
And windows tight
♪ Soon we'll all believe
I'm right ♪