本字幕由高清电台整理发布，更多高清电影请访问
https://gaoqing.fm
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
?辊ㄓ方?CMCT刮钉    ?戳?掸??Lee
陆????my-lullaby    ????
セ?辊獶??紇跌陆亩  ??紇跌?暗溃?矪瞶
〗
ヘ夹よ?020
Target bearing 020.
钡Μ020
Contact 020.
-禯瞒?窾  -禯瞒?窾絏
- Range 20,000.  - Range 20,000 yards.
-??255  -??255タ絋
- Course 255.  - Course 255 true.
-硉?13  -硉?13?ń
- Speed 13.  - Speed 13 knots.
蝉疾碍
Cowboys.
"綤??  馋ゑ焊"
"Enchanter, Mobile."
ǐ??环  ?眶??
Well, we're a long way from home. Wake 'em up!
?瓁
It's the Navy!
ер篨??ㄓ
Quick, put out the flag!
綤??腹
Enchanter!
硂琌?瓣?─牡矫钉
This is the United States Coast Guard.
氨?ㄓ  非称钡?秸琩
Heave to and prepare to be boarded.
綤??  ?琌?看?瓣差  и?璶祅差秸琩
Enchanter, you are a US-flag ship, and we are going to board you.
瞷?氨?ㄓ
Heave to now.
???差??差繷
Muster your crew on the bow.
???  ?玡??
You two, go forward.
孽紈焊  蛤иㄓ
Randall, come with me.
-??êㄠ  -各?
- Stay where you are.  - Kneel down.
差?  差?
Captain. Captain?
蔼?钉?  叫弧
Go ahead, Senior Chief.
ぃМ  程????尼魁诀ㄓ
It's a bad one. I think you'd better send over the video camera.
狽?  秈ㄓ
Jack, come on in.
-????ゅンΤ?蔼  -?阀硂?蔼
- How high is the pile on your desk?  - About this high.
-瞷?琌硂?蔼  -ぐ?薄猵
- Now it's this high.  - What have you got?
钮筁玭?扒ゑ?êンㄆ盾  и璶冈薄
You heard about that business in the South Caribbean? I need the details.
-??璶  -荷е
- By when?  - As soon as you can.
-??  -狽?  ?み翴
- OK.  - Jack? Be discreet.
-ぐ?種?  -?穦?笵
- What do you mean?  - You'll find out.
????...
Mysterious...
и稲??
I love a mystery.
-苦  ?揩  P  -琵?硄筁
- Ryan, John P.  - Let him through.
-硂ń  -谅谅
- Here you go.  - Thank you.
-?粄眔隔盾  -粄眔  谅谅
- You know where you're going?  - Yes. Thank you.
-??ń氨ó  -ê娩
- Where do I park?  - Right over there.
┕玡???璶硄笵
Main passageway, going forward.
??康  ヒ狾?Τ﹀格...
Master stateroom, blood on the deck...
т?19猅紆催
19 cartridges were recovered,
临Τ祇??紆?ㄢや猌竟
as well as the two weapons that fired them.
Μ栋??﹀睪妓セ蛤差?  甃┘眔
Blood samples taken were consistent with the crew, Hardin
??ヾ?  ㄠ?㎝?ㄠ常??
and his wife and his son and daughter.
?虫㎝狤繷??﹀格
I got blood on the sheets and pillow
?察㎝オ察琜?常Τ
on both starboard and portside racks.
êㄠ?Τ﹀格
There's blood there, too.
?ㄓ??琌?┬ń何谋?砆炳
They were killed in their staterooms apparently as they slept.
砆┰?ヒ狾?砆┻??
Dragged topside and thrown overboard.
êㄢ?稱発ǐ??  程?щ?砆Ι┿
The two men in custody surrendered after a brief attempt to escape.
и?癸êㄢ?砆???  ?笵?ぶ
What do we know about them? The men in custody?
せΩ?猧??砪瑀砆?  羆参?ネ
Half a dozen arrests for drug trafficking in Bogota, Mr President.
瑀珇
Drugs.
胔好籔???瑀竇Τ闽  ぃ琌沉紈狶...
Suspected ties to the Cali cartel, not Medellin...
-??  ?⊿ㄆ盾  -...?沮?ユ场
- You alright, James?  - ...according to DEA.
-?ぐ?  -⊿ぐ?钵妓  ?ネ
- Why?  - Nothing exotic, sir.
?洪琌???卑㎝垦炳  硂ぃ琌材?Ω
Straight piracy and murder. It's not the first time.
材?Ω?ㄆ?琌и?狟ね
It's the first time it was a friend of mine.
琌?
Yes, sir.
-ぐ?ㄆ  ?⊿ㄆ盾  -⊿ㄆ
- What was that? You alright?  - Yeah.
и??せ??⊿Τ何筁  иΤ笵瞶盾
I haven't slept in 36 hours. Did I make any sense?
?弧ぐ?  弧?絵?  暗眔?
What did you say? Just kidding. Good job.
-?赣秨甭?ユ揭祘  -?龟弧?セ琌и?戮砫
- You should give diplomacy lessons.  - To call it as I see it is myjob.
-硈??琌??  -单и
- And he's yours.  - Wait for me.
闽?
Shut the door.
и??瓣?チ┯空筁  璶癸?瑀珇拜肈
I promised the American people I'd do something about the drug problem.
?Τ
You are.
и?や???ゑㄈ?  癸кêㄇ瑀竇...
You support the Colombians' efforts against the cartels...
玱?礚??  硂ㄇ瑀砪??и礚?
And accomplish nothing. Do these drug dealers think we're powerless?
????ぃ耞暗硂贺ㄆ  玱眖⊿Τは莱
That they can keep doing this kind of thing, and there's no response ever?
?琌?矗某??︽笆
Are you suggesting a course of action, sir?
и矗某???︽笆?礚琌矪
The course of action I'd suggest is a course of action I can't suggest.
и...  ぃ?笵薄猵穦??祇甶
I'm... not sure where that leaves us.
硂ㄇ瑀竇琌癸?瓣瓣產??
These drug cartels represent a clear and present danger
篶Θ笹??符??繧
to the national security of the United States.
??笵?暗?ぐ?ㄆ
Do you know what you've done?
и炳???搁
I killed a thief,
и炳???敖и?狥﹁?...
a thief who was stealing...
...搁
...from me!
临Τ??ヾ?  ㄠ?  Ч?ぃ臮?狦
And his wife, and his son, and his daughter,
琵???????  ?иňぃ秤ň?
apparently with no thought of the consequences.
ㄓ蠢?克厨こ
Should I let his children avenge their father's death when I least expect it?
?琌?瓣羆参?
He was a good friend
?ね㎝現獀幅ね
and a political ally of the President of the United States.
иぃ稰???
That doesn't surprise me.
-ê赣蛤?Τ闽  -????暗ぐ?
- It should concern you.  - What can they do?
ㄓти  ╇?и
Come after me? Arrest me?
??и甡┤
You're scaring me.
??氨?ㄓ  蛤?酵?ン?璶ㄆ薄
Will you stop long enough for me to tell you something important?
谅谅
Thank you.
?竨叫и???臮拜  и碞倒?種ǎ
Listen. You pay me to counsel you, and I am counselling you.
иノ癟?ㄓ玂???㏑
I'm keeping you alive with information.
?狦?ぃ瞶穦и?腢?
If you disregard my counsel
?硂妓暗ネ種??
and keep running your business the way you have been,
ぃ竒?福?  Τㄢンㄆ穦祇ネ
with your balls and not your head, two things will happen.
иぃ?  τ?碞砆炳
I'll quit, and you'll get killed.
?а?  ?禗и??畉?ㄆ
You forgot to tell me about your scouting trip.
-и⊿Τа癘  -?钡牟筁????  街
- No, I didn't.  - You made another contact. Who?
鸽吹??盽拜癬и?钡繷?
Castro always asked me about my sources.
-и羆琌倒????氮?  -鸽吹?倒??筍骋ぃのи
- I always gave him the same answer.  - Castro didn't pay you what I pay.
硂?Ωぃノ??だゅ
This one will cost you nothing.
??
A woman.
??ノ????
You're using a woman.
ウぃ穦疊癬ㄓ?
It won't float.
-?揩  ?璶ぐ?  ??  -疢绘
- John, what do you want? Toast?  - Waffles!
-⊿?丁暗疢绘?  -街ǎ筁и?芲巴
- No time for waffles.  - Anybody seen my keys?
?玡????  ?┪???砋ń
Either on the front hall table or in your pocket.
-и?芲巴??ń  -痁磚
- Where aremykeys?  - Pancakes!
-???  -谅谅
- Toast, please.  - Thank you.
?ǎ  ??
Bye, Dad.
-?ǎ  -ウぃ穦疊?
- Bye, pal.  - It won't float!
ウぃ穦疊?  硂琌看肩弗  ウ赣??┏?
It's not supposed to float, it's a submarine. It goes under water.
狽?
Jack.
??
Hello?
碭?
When?
и??眞?稰玙
I thought I had the flu.
?狦??⊿?禗и  и临??琌稰玙
I'd still think so if they weren't telling me otherwise.
???妓弧
What are they telling you?
?狦и⊿钮岿  莱琌糉甡??纽砾
Pancreatic cancer of an aggressive nature, if I heard them right.
ぐ?種?
Well, what does it mean?
и?獺иΤ???陈沸
I guess it means I'm in big trouble.
-????琁も砃  ┪?...  -??
- I mean, can they operate, or...?  - Maybe.
琌??弧?"??"и瞦琌单?弧"ぃ"
That's what they said, "maybe", which sounds suspiciously like "no" to me.
ê琌??ㄤい??
There's one of them now.
и临⊿Τ?
I'm not dead yet.
и?洛皘ń  ?琌弧и?獶?快そ?
I am in a hospital, which means that I'm not in my office,
?琌弧иぃ?笵薄猵
which means I don't know what's going on.
-и惠璶??êń  -?ń
- I need you there.  - Where?
-?и?快そ?ń暗и???  -单??...
- In my office, doing my job.  - Wait a minute...
??笵и癚菇磝搐ぃ??薄猵
I hate not knowing what's going on, you know that.
иぃ来暗????
I wouldn't know how to do your job, sir.
???Τ把籔  ??筁フ甤
You've been around. You've been to the White House.
-?Ω  и癚菇ウ  -?⊿Τ
- Once. I hated it.  - No, you didn't.
稱粄醚地脖箉?現獀盾  ???...
Want to know about politics in Washington? Four words.
"讽み璉?"
"Watch your back, Jack."
猧ゑ  ?赣琌材???笵  ┪?琌材?  ??
Bobby, you should be the first to know, or the third or fourth.
苦盢穦暗竝瞶薄厨Ы捌Ы?
Ryan is to be Acting Deputy Director, Intelligence.
ê讽礛琌既?┦?〆ヴ  ????眃確
It will be a provisional appointment, of course, until James recovers.
???虏厨??  и?癸??ゑㄈ?穿?璸购
Get him up to speed on our aid programme to Colombia.
?璶弧狝菏服〆?穦  ?挤蹿??きκ窾じ
He must talk the Oversight Committee out of another $75 million.
临?窾??忌ㄤ祏
And not make a complete fool out of himself.
甃┘眔砆炳??ン??妓
What about the Hardin murders?
и?蛤秈  羆参璶??秸琩
I'm on it. The President's calling for a full-court press.
??璶拟も???
So, you guys are going to be working together hand in hand.
??
That's great.
皑古腞  ?笆??狥﹁??
Margaret, why don't we leave all his things?
??  ??
OK, yeah.
苦狽?  иぃ??獺
Ryan. I can't believe it!
???琌?ぃ????
He's not a team player, is thatwhat you're saying?
?琌?フ猫
He's a Boy Scout.
??赣??フ猫  ?獺┚み  稧间㎝盉?
A goddamn Boy Scout. Believes in loyalty, cleanliness and knot-tying.
?恨???
So leave him out of it.
?讽薄厨Ы捌Ы?  ê穦?雌も
He's the Deputy Director of Intelligence. That will be tricky.
?璶?笵ぐ?
What does he need to know?
?ぐ??ぃゲ?笵  ?ぃ穦?笵ぐ?
Nothing. He needs to know nothing. He's going to know nothing.
и璶??羆参甭舦
I want a copy of the President's authorisation
癸瑀竇??穝︽笆?捌セ
of this new action against the cartels.
-?璶ぐ?  -?钮?
- You want what?  - You heard me.
?ぃ?薄?
He doesn't know about it.
и倒?虏虫?秆睦  硂?琌??︽笆
Let me explain it to you very simply. This is your deal, not mine.
埃獶иΤ??甭舦  ?玥硂ンㄆぃ穦秈︽
Unless I have written authorisation, this thing is over before it begins.
иぃ稱??拜肈?  パиㄓ璽?砫
I'm not going to be the only one left without a chair when the music stops.
"が磃"??羙???腹
"Reciprocity." That's a clever name for it.
厨確琌??だ?繧?笆诀
Revenge is a very, very, very dangerous motivation.
硂?︽笆???莱?眔ㄓ  и?璶?琌┪?
Are you able to handle this operation or not? I'm looking for a yes or no.
?璶????現獀?年舥?
You're looking for a political mess.
-琌┪?  -??璶ê妓
- Yes or no?  - Is that what they want?
–??ヴ現┎常稱莉眔硈ヴ
They want what every first-term administration wants. A second term.
и?獺瓣穦临⊿Τу非硂ㄆ
I don't imagine the boys on the Hill have approved this.
??Τ⊿Τ
Have they?
ê琌?弧"ぃ"
Is that a "no"?
赣?
Shit.
и?︽笆ぇ玡  め?ń璶Μ?窥
I want the money in my account before I move an inch.
⊿拜肈
You got it.
-и璶Τ硄獺矫琍羛╰  -??
- I need a Comsat link.  - You got it.
-?や?钉  -???Τ?や场钉
- An insertion team.  - You can have a brigade.
?璶12?剪醚?∕Α?驹??
Just 12 men who understand discretionary warfare.
疭?︽笆  ﹁痁?粂
Special Ops. Spanish speaking.
-?ネ  ??盾  -??
- How are you today, sir?  - Very well.
-叫拜??砐?ヘ?  -そ?
- The purpose of your visit?  - Business.
-?暗ê?︽㎡  -и芥╈┰诀
- What business are you in?  - I sell tractors.
и?硑㎝?扳ウ?
Well, I build them, then I sell them.
-?穦硆痙??  -碭ぱ
- And how long will you be staying?  - A few days.
и?笵?玙繧  ?临Τぐ?よ猭
I know it's a risk, but what's the alternative?
ノせ?┰紈?筗ち埃跌呼饯  ぃ穦贾芠
Zapping a retina with 6,000 rads of cobalt? Not a pretty picture.
ゑ耎床??福紽??ㄇ
Prettier than a tumour spreading in the cranial sack.
-??ぐ???  -иタ?逗㎡
- What is her name?  - I'm trying to have lunch.
钮帝...  ▄緅盾
Listen... Hungry?
-?緅  -и???と繺
- Starved.  - We could forget about lunch.
-и??Ω?刚筁  癘眔盾  -и?癘眔  ?㎡
- We did that last time, remember?  - Do I remember? Do you?
-ぃ?癘眔  -?砛и赣矗???
- Vaguely.  - Maybe I should refresh your memory.
-?砛琌?  -??Τ籓?
- Maybe you should.  - Your table is ready now.
-и?ぃ璶?  и??璸祘ó  -宾腞
- We don't need it. I'll get a cab.  - Moira?
-??盾  狽??妓  -???
- Hi! How are you? How's Jack?  - He's great, just great.
-临?羛ü秸琩Ы??盾  -Ы?快そ?
- You still with the FBI?  - The Director's office.
-ê琌街  -и?穝狟ね
- Who was that?  - My new friend.
纒?腜
Ser Roberto Landa.
-??妓?钩狽?盾  -琌盾  и?眔ぃ睲贰
- Doesn't he look like Jack?  - Does he? I can't quite see.
-?畉琌┰?膟  -┰?狽?  硂?и眔???
- Only Latin.  - A Latin Jack? This I have to see.
и璶ǐ?  ?ǎ
I have to go. Bye.
и??笵硂ぃ琌???卑  ?祍穦敖差?
Well, we know it's not piracy. Pirates steal boats.
??ō?Τ?祇?草Ν?猧???诀布
They had plane tickets to Bogota the morning afterthe killings.
-笷?  -薄猵?妓
- Hey, Dan.  - How's it going?
и?タ發琩帝??笆诀  馋笷?  羛ü秸琩Ы
We're sneaking up on a motive. Dan Murray, Bureau.
-?ユ场  ?贾?  -弧筁ぐ?
- Ralph Williams, DEA.  - Said anything yet?
-"и?琌睲フ?"-单浪诡﹛倒??矗?ユ??
- Yeah. "We're innocent."  - Till the DA offers them a deal.
?竒矗??  炊硄?临琌疭??
He already has. Regular or extra crispy?
??琌??蔓┪?ê眎筿慈
Either referring to fried chicken or the electric chair.
??谋眔?Τず薄
Are you picturing a hit?
祇ネ????穛???膟坝??妓
On a respectable American businessman and his family?
?安砞?琌??穛?絵?
You're assuming he's respectable.
и?Τ獽兵  獺ン  獺ノ?挡?虫
We have memos, letters, credit card statements,
筿杠虫  ?稱ノㄓ瘆秆??盞絏?狥﹁常Τ
phone bills, everything you could need to break his code.
-硂琌ぐ?  -蔼い侣?厨
- What's this?  - Old high school yearbook.
-并み  ì瞴钉...  -?谋眔㎡
- Sweethearts, football team...  - You think?
-ぃ?笵  -??  ?и?Τぐ?
- I don't know.  - OK, let's see what we've got.
-⊿Τイ猳  -ノ??
- No cream?  - There wasn't any.
眖ネら帝も  ??矗蹿诀盞絏?﹚琌???ネら戳
Let's startwith birthdays. Bet your ATM code is your birthday.
-钡??  -?锣Ω?
- Close.  - In reverse?
??ネら琌...
Alright, his birthday is...
êび甧??  琌盾  刚???锣Ω?
That would be too easy, wouldn't it? Let's try it in reverse.
岿  ?びび?
No. His wife's?
岿  ?ㄠ??
No. His son's?
-硂??暗...  -碭?る
- This could take...  - Months.
ㄠ??ネら?锣  硂琌倒??
Son's in reverse. This is for you.
岿  びび?ネら?锣
No. Wife's in reverse.
岿  ?ㄠ?ネら?锣
No. Daughter's in reverse.
?眔?э??矗蹿诀盞絏
You've got to change your ATM code.
ぃ琌  ぃ琌ヾ??ネら  ぃ琌?ㄠ?ネら  ぐ?常ぃ琌
No. Wife, daughter. Nothing.
??
Got it.
秈??
I got it!
びび??ネる?  ?ㄠ?ら?  ㄠ????
Wife's birth month, daughter's day, son's year.
?ぃ琌?锣Ω?  ╆簆
But not in reverse. Sorry.
???倒и
Print me out that one.
???
Good boy.
??玡甃┘眔Μ???掸?刽
Three years ago, Hardin received an infusion of foreign capital
?ノㄓщ戈??瓣?????潦?いみ
which he invested in 20 major shopping centres in the US.
?竒蕾癐癶戳丁  ?莉眔瘆?魁???
In the middle of the recession, he posted record profits,
?ぶ癸??倪?祙Ыㄓ弧琌硂妓
at least to the IRS, who he feared more than his own partners.
?沮?倒????狥羘?
To them, according to the stockholder statements he was giving them,
êㄇ潦?いみ?ネ種?ぃ瞶稱
the shopping centres weren't doing nearly as well.
??篔??场だ??せ货き?窾じ
But he wasjust skimming most of the profits, $650 million,
临рウ?秈縞此躇  ぺ?皑
and putting it in accounts in Luxembourg, Panama
㎝秨耙竤畄?め?
and the Cayman Islands.
????τ炳?
They killed him for it.
街
Who?
-??╃郎  -街琌??╃郎
- His partners.  - Who were his partners?
??陪?蠢??ゑㄈ?瑀竇瑍窥
It seems clear that he was laundering money for the Colombian drug cartels.
ぱ摆  и粄醚?ê?????  и?琌?厩
Jesus! I knew the man for 40 years. We went to school together.
临碭???暗ネ種
We almost went into business together.
ê赣穦ぃ岿
That would have been good.
肚碈穦癸硂ㄆン絘發瞨ゴ
The press is going to have a field day with this.
-硂┬丁??⊿Τ??笵  -??羆Τよ猭
- No one outside this room knows.  - They will. They always do.
穦处臩?  ?弧眔ぃ岿  ??и?
It will come up, you're right about that. When it does,
穦癸?㎝甃?闽╰?淮磞睭糶
we'll downplay your relationship with Hardin somehow.
-ぐ?  -ぐ?
- What?  - What?
-и?рウ絯㎝  -?ぃ?種
- We'll defuse it.  - Do you disagree?
ぃ
No.
ㄤ龟琌?種  и穦ノ??贺よ猭
Well, actually, yes. I would go in the other direction.
?狦癘?拜?㎝甃琌?狟ね  и穦弧"?狟ね"
If a reporter asked if you and Hardin were friends, I'd say "good friends".
?狦??拜??琌??狟ね  и穦弧"沧ō?ね"
If they asked if you were good friends, I'd say"lifelong friends".
???礚眖?も  ⊿Τ穝籇?厨旧
Give them no place to go, nothing to report. No story.
и種?琌  琂礛?紆?竒ま脄?...
I mean, it's no sense in defusing a bomb after it's already...
...??斗?╊埃獺恨
...it's already gone off.
-綼  -赣?
- Damn!  - Shit!
???盾
Do you see him?
???钉??オ簿ㄢμ
Alright. Move your team two metres to the left.
??  氨
That's it. Stop.
ǐ?ê?睱︹?帮  ?阑も????竚
Touch that light-coloured grass. Sniper at your feet.
瓁??  硂ń⊿ぐ?
Nothing here, Sergeant Major.
-赣?  -???︹
- Damn!  - He is good.
?钡?  ??簿笆眔硂?е
Thatwas close. How's he moving so fast?
и?ǎ?  筁ㄓ  ??筁ㄓ  瞷?禲
I see him. Come in. Straight in. Now. Run!
??筁ㄓ
Keep coming.
氨  ??オ?  ??オ?
Stop. To your left. To your left.
氨ゎ  ?阑も????竚
And stop. Sniper at your feet.
琌ぐ?
What is it?
??硂ń?筁と繺
He had lunch here.
沉讽骋??簙躇?
McDonald's quarter-pounder.
??イ筎
With cheese.
赣?
Damn.
-赣?  -???
- Damn!  - That's four.
硂Ω?蜉?  ?ㄓ?
Alright, you won this one. Come on out!
??  ??ǐ眔硂?钡?и
Soldier, how did you get that close to me?
?﹛  ?阑も暗?碍??睼矹  ㄓ钡?旧畍
Sniper approached instructor by being a sneaky bastard, Sergeant Major!
讲蝴吹  ??笵???  メ︰В?籃蹿
Do you know the fine for littering in California, Chavez?
?笵  ?﹛
Yes, sir!
и??阑も癡絤いǎ筁?  ???︹
I saw you on the sniper course. You looked good.
-い?  硂ń?癡еЧ拨盾  -琌  ?﹛
- Just about finished here, Sergeant?  - Yes, sir.
?戴辨盿ヾㄠ??安
Looking forward to taking some leave with your wife and kids?
-?﹛  и⊿Τヾㄠ  -?Τぐ?
- Don't have any wife or kids, sir.  - What do you have?
??ぶゴ筿杠倒??  ?⊿Τ?ぶㄓ┕?獺ン
You don't call anybody often, you don't write or receive many letters.
?﹛  и??拜?琌街
Who are you, sir, if I may ask?
???ネ㎝иタ郸购?兜︽笆  и?舱琌ㄤい?场だ
Mr Clark and I are putting together a mission. My team is a part of it.
?程?穦?せ?る  ?狦ぇ?临?帝
You'd be gone up to six months, after which, if you're not dead,
?Τ舦匡拒疭贺场钉ず?ヴ叭
you'd have your choice of assignments in Special Ops.
...?埃??е盢Θ???ンぁ籇?拜肈
...defusing an issue that was snowballing into another scandal.
??ら厨  厨旧?㎝甃琌?狟ね
"The New York Times" reports that you and Hardin were good friends.
ぃ琌?狟ね  и?琌沧ō?ね
No, not good friends. We were lifelong friends.
琌и弧?  琌и弧?
I said that. I said that.
и??ê妓弧
I told him to say that.
-ぐ?  -и⊿Τ弧ぐ?
- What?  - I didn't say anything.
-???稱帝?ンㄆ  -⊿Τ
- But you were thinking something.  - No.
и?琌稱帝  ?蛤???贡?陈沸
I was just distracted by the trouble you were having with your ensemble.
?ぃ琌–ぱ常璶杆??綼?
Well, it's not every day you have to look trustworthy.
-街?街弧ぐ?  -êぃ?璶
- Who told who to say what?  - It's not important.
-琌羆参盾  -琌?
- The President?  - Yeah.
洱弧?ゑ羆参寥??窥
Mom says she makes more money than the President.
???琌癸?  ?ǎ
She's probably right. Bye.
苦痴?  稰谅??戈?
Thank you, Dr Ryan, for the information you've shared with us.
-谅谅  把某?  -и??﹚璶腊???ゑㄈ?
- Thank you, Senator.  - We have to help the Colombians
??ゎêㄇ瑀竇??笆
in their struggle to curtail the drug cartels' activities.
?иぃ?フ  ???粄?肂??挤蹿
However, I'm confused. How do you see additional funds
Τ?硂兜⊿Τ???璸购
advancing this programme from the failure that it is?
-??フи?種?盾  -иぃ??フ
- You see what I'm getting at?  - No, I'm afraid I don't.
?弧硂兜璸购癸и?Ч?Τ?
You said this effort would be totally benign on our part.
и???????ㄑ莱㎝?某
Our assistance is limited to supply and advice only.
и?竒弄筁
I've read that.
и?弄筁????き?玡糶?摸?厨?
I've also read a similar finding written 35 years ago
Τ闽?狥玭ㄈ  ?矪翧????翺狶
regarding a little-thought-of sliver ofjungle in Southeast Asia.
癸ぃ癬  ?рは瑀挤蹿ビ叫蛤禫玭?ゑ耕
You're comparing our request for anti-drug funds to Vietnam?
и?硂?〆?穦–Ω砆璶―?
I'm comparing it to every time a committee such as this is asked
常穦癸戈?ぃì?ビ叫???耞
to render judgement based on less than all the facts.
?┤иぃ?笵?妓?莱
I'm afraid I don't know what to say to that.
????и?玂靡  и???眔┮Τㄆ龟
You can assure us that we have all the facts.
и粄?иΤ
I thought I had.
ê??????и?玂靡  硂掸肂??挤蹿
You can further assure us then that this increase in funds
ぃ穦砆ノ??盞?瓁ㄆ︽笆
will not be used for any covert military action.
иぃ?フ??穦硂妓稱
I don't know how you're getting to this.
?戳?竒喷
Long experience, sir.
⊿Τ瓁钉
No troops then?
и眏秸ê翴  ??иぃ稱?岿
I enunciate that clearly because I don't want there to be any mistake.
⊿Τ瓁钉
No troops.
???弧  и???杠?┯空
You could say I have your word on that?
???ê妓
You could indeed, because you do.
钮帝  埃??礟  рウ?肚?ㄓ
Listen up! Dog tags. Take 'em off, pass 'em forward.
浪琩?砋ń  ??粄?ōだ?狥﹁
Check your pockets for anything that can be used for identification.
?嘲??
We're feet dry.
?辅跋?辨  非称
LZ in sight. Get ready.
??產?笲  ?ъ???
Good luck, boys. Go get 'em.
??  瞷??辅
OK, let's take her down now.
е  е  е
Go, go, go!
糑  猧ゑ
Hey, Bob.
-??盾  -??
- How you doing?  - Good, sir.
ǎ??痷?
Good to see you.
-狽?  Ν  -苦  秈ㄓ?
- Morning, Jack.  - Ryan! Come on in.
-粄醚?產盾  -常粄醚
- Do you know everyone?  - Yes, yes.
-〡柏  并并伴  -陈沸?  堵〡柏
- Coffee? Bagel?  - Coffee. Black.
-產??盾  -??
- How's the family?  - Good, sir.
-и???粄醚???苦痴?  -??戴辨粄醚?
- When do I meet the other Dr Ryan?  - She's dying to meet you, sir.
??  Г?
Good, good. Sit down.
谅谅
Thank you.
ê?...
So...
-êㄇ窥ご?êń  -?ネ
- The cash is still there?  - Sir?
-?甃┘眔?瞒─め?  -せ货き?窾じ
- In Hardin's offshore accounts.  - $650 million.
-㎝箂窥  -㎝箂窥
- And change.  - And change.
-и?临Τê?め?腹絏  -琌?
- And we have the account numbers.  - Yes, sir.
и?临单ぐ?  ??ウ?
Well, what are we waiting for? Let's get it.
-??  -и?р硂狥﹁锣筁ㄓ
- Let's get it?  - Let's turn this thing around.
せ货き?窾じ㎝箂窥
$650 million and change.
ê琌現獀戈????
It's worth ten times that in political capital.
ぐ?
What?
甃㎝êㄇ瑀竇?闽硈  ?琌??瞦代
Well, this connection between Hardin and the cartels is a theory.
-瞦代  -и?瞦代
- Theory?  - Atheory of mine.
-硂琌?瞦代  -и?笵êㄇ窥琌?êń
- It's a theory?  - Well, I know the money is there.
?иぃ?笵ㄤ龟甃蠢街??
But who exactly Hardin was working for, I don't know.
и???そê掸窥ぇ玡  璶?琩靡ê?翴
I think we would have to establish that before we could seize the money.
ê?碞?êń琩靡ウ
So go down there. Establish it.
-??ń  -??ゑㄈ
- Go where?  - Colombia.
街  и
Who, me?
иメ??ㄢ?琍戳  ?玱今秈???炒ɡń
I leave you alone for two weeks, and you walk into a big bear trap.
и?稱ぐ?
What was I thinking?
?稱?羆参痙??钩  ?ぃ赣ê妓暗
You were thinking about impressing the President. You shouldn't do that.
-??る  -?る
- November.  - January.
琌???
Of last year.
êńΤ???  ??玡???êń...  ??
There's a guy down there, at least he used to be... Clark.
и?粄醚???  琌???
We go way back. Good man.
?狦?笿?陈沸  ?т?
If you hit a brick wall, look him up.
??盢
Admiral Greer?
-て励  -赣?
- Chemotherapy.  - Oh, shit.
?ㄓ?
Here we go again.
筽?蚌篈??妓
How's Ritter behaving?
筽?砮??  ⊿Τ瞶穦и
Ritter's Ritter. He's leaving me alone.
痷?  钩??芅?╪帝?
Are you sure? Watch him like a hawk.
-??盾  -??
- How are you feeling today?  - OK.
и?穦蠢?т?┬丁  倒??ㄇを脆  琵?仅?
We'll get you in a room, give you warm blankets, get you lying down.
礛?и?盿???┬丁  ヰ???
Then we'll get you back to your room and comfortable.
跑秖  硂琌??  非称硄杠  Ч拨
Variable, this is Knife, stand by to copy, over.
??  硂琌跑秖  ??癟腹琌き?き  Ч拨
Knife, this is Variable, your signal is five by five, over.
礚毁锚
Clear.
蔓?羚ń?  Ч拨
The chicken is in the pot. Over.
-礜?ウ  -Μ?
- Cook it.  - Roger that.
克稲?  и璶筐??
Honey? I'm late.
-?ǎ  -?隔抖?
- Bye.  - Have a good trip.
иぃ穦弧?ㄓ
I'm not gonna say it.
?弧
Don't.
?み
Be careful.
セ??丁蛤地脖箉??  Ν?11翴16だ
Local time is, well, actually, it's the same as Washington, 11:16am.
?放琌地ん69?...
Temperature is 69 degrees Fahrenheit...
苦痴?
Dr. Ryan!
?ユ场疭贺贝?繬?  ??盾
DEA Special Agent Jean Fowler. How you doing?
-?Ωㄓ猧??  -琌?
- First time in Bogota?  - Yeah.
и????硂ń  琵?產??秨簀
Let's not stand here and let someone take a shot at you.
е  ?﹛  и?ǐ?
Come on, sir, let's go.
-硂ㄢ?㎡  -??琌??
- And these two are?  - They're brothers.
?ê妓  陈沸?倒苦痴??翴??
Don't do that. Give Dr Ryan a bit more air back here, please.
ň紆
Bulletproof.
и?⊿Τ酚?  肅?瓜?薄厨??
We don't have a picture. Escobedo's intelligence officer.
и??ぃ?笵??  ??笵???
We don't have a name either, but we know he exists.
ê?留??
The invisible man?
篊篊?  ノ??も
Gently, gently, with your hands.
筽吹  р蛮も???癬
Luis, put your hands together.
ぃ  蛮も
No, your hands together!
筽吹  痙種旧畍
Luis, watch the canter.
癸?  ??
Yes, very good.
ぐ?ㄆ
Yes?
и??穕ア??琜?诀
We lost another plane.
?笵?
OK.
-琌街??  -?狦璶и瞦...
- Who is doing this?  - If I had to guess...
и⊿Τ??瞦  и??瞦
No, I did not ask you to guess. I can guess.
Τ?猲臩倒絩瑀?牡?
Someone has been talking to the drug police.
ぃ??  ?狦Τ??牡よ?盞  и穦材???笵
Impossible. If anyone spoke to the police, I'd be the first to know.
?瓜
Ernesto?
琌?и癸??ê??瓣??  Τ?稱篟反и
Is one of the others trying to ruin me after what I did to the American?
и瞦êぃ琌?稱钩?ê妓
I guess that wasn't quite the deterrent you thought it would be.
тê???ㄓ
Find out who it is.
??  ?粄??妓
What do you make of this, Colonel?
??诀穦
An opportunity.
粒猧  ??诀穦
An opportunity, Sipo.
-と?  -Τ?獺盾
- Good afternoon.  - Messages, please?
-苦痴?  -??  ╆簆и筐?
- Dr Ryan?  - Clark? Sorry I'm late.
иΤ?だ牧
I've got ten minutes.
и?﹚甃蛤瑀竇Τ闽  ê琌砪瑀?窥
I'm positive Hardin was tied into the cartels. It's drug money.
-??靡龟ぃ?  -ヘ玡?ゎ
- But you can't prove it.  - So far.
-?ざ種и拜???拜肈  -ぃざ種
- Mind if I ask you a question?  - No.
????禗и硂ㄇ  и?竒癶????
Why are you telling me all this? I've been out of the game for a long time.
и?笵?剪醚硂??カ  ???約
I was told that you were wired, and that you knew the town and people.
-?琌??も  -街?禗??
- That you were a player.  - Who told you that?
?タゅ
Jim Greer.
??盾
How's he doing?
ぃ??
He's not good.
?眞?砾膒
He has cancer.
ソ戳
Terminal.
-?琌???  -程??
- He's a good man.  - The best.
苦痴?  ?耻〡柏盾
You a coffee drinker, Dr Ryan?
-и尺舧耻〡柏  -刚??硈?礟
- Yeah, I like coffee.  - Try the Lindo brand.
-硈?  -и?獺?穦尺舧ウ
- Lindo?  - I think you'll like it.
羆参?ネ  иΤ???
Mr President, I've got some good news.
???粄醚甃?硂ń?╃郎  肅?瓜
Hardin's partner here was someone you may know of. Ernesto Escobedo.
-Τ瞶パ  -硂琌????兜瞦代
- Escobedo? It figures.  - Is this another of your theories?
ぃ  硂琌ㄆ龟  肅?瓜钩硂ń?瑀柄?妓
No, sir. We can call this one fact. Escobedo, like every drug lord here,
?秈︽?猭ネ種  甃蛤硂ㄇネ種Τㄓ┕
also had legitimate businesses. Hardin was doing business with these.
ㄤい琌秈?〡柏  ê⊿ぐ??ぃ?
Importing, among other things, coffee, which means nothing,
???蔼基潦?硂ㄇ〡柏  –絊せ??κじ
but he was paying too much for this coffee. $6,200 a pound.
-ê琌?禥?〡柏  -и?種
- That's expensive coffee.  - I'd have to agree.
硂琌???  и?獺硂????
This is good news. I think this does it.
и?Τㄇぃ?????
Sir, I also have some other news which is not so good.
ぱ摆
Oh, God.
?ユ场谋眔硂ń?現┎  稱?眔?そ??窥
The DEA feels that the government here would want the seized funds.
-┪琌?ぶ??场だ  -硂琌и??窥
- Or at least a large portion.  - This is our money.
-и?т??  -и???沽刚?禗??
- We found it.  - We can try telling them that.
沽刚  ???弧┪ぃ弧??  иぃ恨
Try? Tell them. Or don't tell them, I don't care.
-?и玙デ...  -?禗??硂琌и??窥
- Sir, with all due respect...  - This is our money, tell them that.
иぃ来眔?妓弧┪琌眖?弧癬  иぃ琌?酵?盡產
I wouldn't know what to say or where to start. I'm not a negotiator.
??粄醚現┎ń??
You know someone in their government?
???浪诡羆?琌и??厩
I went to school with their Attorney General.
谅瓣?穦筁ㄓ  ?ㄓ酵?  硂琌и??窥
Jacobs will come down. He'll negotiate. This is our money.
谅...
Thank...
谅谅
Thank you.
и癚菇硂???
I hate this job.
泊氟  ?
Eyes up!
ボ璖舱  ?
Demo team, up!
脄?
Fire in the hole!
и?ㄓ?  еǐ  е  е  е
Let's go, let's go! Move out! Go, go, go!
瓀?  瓀?
Down! Down!
街??硂ㄆ?﹚?
Whoever did this is dead.
街癸и??硂ㄆ  ?﹚?
Whoever did this to me is dead!
??钮?盾  ??琌?钮?и弧
Do you hear me? Are you listening to me?
谅?ネ  ?瞒?玡  ??帽硂?
Mr Jacobs, could you sign these before you leave?
宾腞  ??ぱぃ?叫痜安
Moira, why don't you call in sick tomorrow?
临Τ?ぱ  иぃ穦癸?弧
And the next day. I won't tell anybody.
?瘤礛ぃ?硂ń  临Τ????璶暗
Even when you're not here there's plenty to do.
-??︽祘?  -?蛤и?阶硂?
- Your itinerary.  - You're arguing with me about this?
?び对е?  ?ǎ
You work too hard. Adiy.
-纒んそ?  -纒?腜
- Landay Landa.  - Roberto Landa, please.
-и琌独宾腞  -叫单?穦
- This is Moira Wolfson.  - One moment, please.
????紅  叫单??
I think he's on the factory floor. Hold on.
-街  -Τ??独宾腞т?
- Yes?  - A Moira Wolfson is calling.
и?禗????紅  叫量
I told her you were on the factory floor. Go ahead.
-宾腞  -??
- Moira!  - Hi.
蛤帝?碭ぱ?Τ?盾
You free the next couple of days?
-硂碭ぱ  -иΤ?
- Next couple of days?  - I am.
и????瓣?
My boss is leaving the country.
-и筐ㄇт??盾  -??  и?產  ?ǎ
- Can I call you later?  - Alright, call me at home. Bye.
と?  は瑀︽笆Τ???
Good afternoon. Good news in the fight against drugs.
?兜パ猭叭场秈︽?秸琩
An investigation by the Department of Justice
?竒絋粄?碭?眖縞此躇
has identified several bank accounts from Luxembourg
?秨耙竤畄?め?  砆ノ?瑍堵窥
to the Cayman Islands, used for laundering drug money
琌玡┮ゼΤ?祘?  瞣疉き??瓣現┎
on an unprecedented scale. With five foreign governments
и??竒??︽笆  ?そ硂ㄇ蹿兜
we have taken steps to seize those funds
-计ヘ禬筁せ货き?窾じ  -綼
- which amount to over $650 million.  - Shit.
ョ穦?そ??瓣挂ず??丁?玻竒犁щ戈そ?
Also to seize 20 real estate joint-venture investments in the US
硂ㄇ常琌瑍窥?笆い??璶?瞶?
which were the primary agencies in the laundering operations.
?弧琌せ货き?窾じ
You did say $650 million?
ぃ岿  せ货き?窾じ㎝箂窥
That's right. $650 million. And change.
???敖и?窥
They're stealing my money!
-и?眔??ぶ  -瞷?临?螟弧
- What's our take?  - It's hard to say at the moment.
讽礛?  ??敖и?窥  и寥?  ?ㄓ敖
No, it isn't. You're stealing my money. I made it, you're stealing it!
и???т羛ü秸琩Ы?谅瓣?  酵硂ンㄆ
Mr President, can we speak with FBI Director Jacobs about this?
-谅瓣?⊿Τ?丁  -Τ?璶?硂ンㄆ?
- Jacobs is not available.  - Someone will die for this.
?克ō矪瞶秸琩  τ??Γ
He's personally involved in the investigation and is pretty busy.
璶磷筁硂兵隔  ??穦眖诀初ㄓ
This avenue has to be avoided. They'll be coming from the airport.
眖︺?緗诀初????瓣?笵
Up Avenida Aeropuerto El Dorado all the way to Gran America.
и??蒾滇?も  瘤礛и?稱?硂ㄆ
Santa Fe's our spot. As much as I'd love to be here for this,
?и眔?地脖箉快ㄇㄆ  壕窰?ㄆ叭
I have to take care of business in Washington, tying up loose ends.
?本絬  ?本絬
Hello? Don't hang up, don't hang up.
-街  -??诀竟ご秨帝  宾腞
- Hello?  - The machine is still on, Moira.
-︺ゅ  ǎ??痷?  -?瓆  ǎ??痷?
- Emil, good to see you.  - Andy, good to see you.
-馋贝?  禣?吹?ㄏ  -??  ┋穦
- Agent Murray, Ambassador Ferris.  - Hi, good to see you.
-硂琌程穝戈?  -??  и?ǐ?
- This will bring you up to date.  - Alright, let's go.
-???妓  -钩茎﹁?垫
- How's the food?  - It's like Mexican food.
-?癚菇茎﹁?垫  -и癚菇茎﹁?垫
- You hate Mexican food.  - I hate Mexican food.
-??  -??
- Hi.  - Hello.
и????琌眖??馒вい粄醚?瓣
All my secretary knows about America is what she reads in People magazine.
-硂??よ?妓  -秈ㄓ???
- How's the place?  - Come inside and find out.
??┤
It's awful.
琌盾
Isn't it?
и稱?ぃ赣耻êㄇ?
So I take it you shouldn't drink the water?
??┬丁ńΤ?  ?и临琌耻瞺杆?
They put water in your room, but I'd stick to the bottled stuff.
ê??ノぐ?ㄓ??
So what do you brush your teeth with?
ノ瞺杆???  ?玥?穦?ōぃ滴狝
You use the bottled water, or you'll be in the can all yourtime here.
êΩ簀?蛤現┎Τ闽
The hold-up was a government connection?
琌?  Τ闽╰
Yeah, that's the connection.
癶?  癶?
Back up! Back up!
-еǐ  -ヱ?  ヱ?
- Step on it!  - Stay down. Stay down.
赣?  癶?
Damn it! Back up!
-еǐ  еǐ  -?瓆  ?み
- Let's go! Let's go!  - Take it easy, Andy.
璶膥尿ǐ  狽?  еǐ
Got to keep moving. Go, Jack!
ㄓ?
Incoming!
笷?
Dan!
笷?  笷?
Dan! Dan!
и?ぃ?痙?硂ń
We can't stay here!
ê进ó  ウ笆盾
The car! Is it running?
笆?
It's running!
废铭穦被臔и?  硂琌и?斑?诀穦  иㄓн?
The smoke will give us cover. It's our only chance. I got him.
≧??诀?ê娩  非称??  ǐ
Make for the driver's side. Ready? Go!
-秈?  -еǐ  еǐ
- Get in!  - Go! Go!
睲间┬丁
Housekeeping.
びび  癸ぃ癬
Oh, excuse me, ma'am.
-Τ筿杠т苦洛ネ盾  -单?穦
- Do you have a call for Dr Ryan?  - Just a moment.
...さぱ?猧??刁?
...in Bogota today.
????  ???端
Ten members of the escort party were also killed and eight wounded.
Τき???琌玂???...
Five of the dead were security personnel...
-古滇  -??禗и??硂ㄆンい
- Cathy?  - Don't tell me you're in this.
ō炒ㄤい  笷???
Right in the middle of it. Honey, Dan was killed.
馋笷?
Dan Murray.
и禯瞒?へ  ぐ??暗ぃ?
He was ten feet away. There was nothing I could do.
-и?產?  -谅ぱ谅?
- I'm coming home.  - Thank God.
и稲?
I love you.
-?ぃ琌?盞?êń盾  -琌?
- Wasn't his going there a secret?  - It was.
-êиぃ?フ祇ネぐ?ㄆ  -⊿Τ??笵
- Then I don't get it. What happened?  - Nobody knows.
-硂ㄇ??猜  -??????礚┮ぃ?
- How stupid are these people?  - They believe they can do anything.
??笵盾  ??岿?
You know what? They're wrong.
-琌?  -??岿?
- Yes, sir.  - They're wrong.
???钡珼驹?瓣現┎
They've directly challenged the sovereign power of the United States.
ぃ眔?祇癟?
No more sending messages.
礚阶?妓  ?稱??钡Μ?癟?
He wants them to get the message whether the phone rings or not.
-ê琌?弧?  -钮ㄓ?钩??杠
- Those are his words?  - Do they sound like his words?
?稱?絢?獽ぃ?睲捶
He can't be clear when clarity is what he wants to avoid.
??種?琌璶眏祑?翴
What he means is the gloves come off.
и癸?弧  硂ンㄆ蛤и礚闽
I'm telling you, I had nothing to do with it.
?篅琌и暗?  ???赣  ?ぃ琌и暗?
I didn't. I wish I had done it, they deserved it. But it wasn't me.
ê?琌街
Who did then?
?⊿Τ氮?
You know, you have no answers.
鸽吹?ê?琌硂妓?盾  ⊿Τ氮?
Is this the way it was with Castro? No answers?
-?ぃ稱?笵氮?  -и稱
- You don't want to hear an answer.  - Yes, I do.
琌ㄤい??璶рウ暗Θ琌???
Itwas done to look like you did it. By one of the others.
タ??胔好  羆琌??程绩???狟ね
As you suspected. It's always a friend who hates you most.
р筿杠倒и
Give me the phone.
-縞︺?  -琌???盾
- Rojas.  - Did you do this thing?
琌?и??  ?ゴ筿杠ㄓ拜琌?и??
Did I do this thing? Are you calling to ask me if I did this thing?
?⊿Τи?㎝絉坝  ??甡?產
You don't consult with us. You put us in danger.
?璶и?獺ぃ琌?
And now you want me to believe it wasn't you?
︺?  ぃ琌и
It wasn't, Enrique.
?瓣?穦?и?厨確
The Americans will retaliate against all of us.
и祇粆蛤硂ンㄆ礚闽
I swear I had nothing to do with it.
???и穦钮?硂ㄇ晾杠
Why do you expect me to listen to you when you lie?
-?瓜  ?ǎ  -ぃ  ぃ  ぃ
- Goodbye, Ernesto.  - No, no, no!
?本絬  и?璶秨?穦某
Don't hang up. We must have a meeting.
-碭?  -荷е
- When?  - As soon as possible.
?边  иぃ琌??  琌叫―?
Tomorrow night. I am not telling you, I am asking you!
?边и???ǎ?
May we meet tomorrow night?
-?ぱ?と  -谅谅
- Tomorrow afternoon.  - Thank you.
-??佩稺  -?莱赣佩稺
- He's scared.  - He should be.
иぃ?笵  ?癸?弧?ぐ?  ?ê琌癸?
I don't know what you said to him, but it was right.
?谋眔?┣盾
Strange, don't you think?
谅瓣?㎝??????ぱ砆炳
Jacobs and his secretary getting killed on the same day.
ぃ琌????  琌??玂???
He wasn't his secretary. He was a member of the security detail.
街
Who?
-и癘ぃ癬????  -и琌?宾腞
- I don't remember his name.  - I'm talking about Moira.
ぐ?
What?
宾腞  癘眔盾  谅瓣????
Moira, remember? Jacobs's secretary.
и粄醚宾腞  ??弧ぐ?
I know Moira, honey. What are you talking about?
-?弧?琌?┰?苦狽?  -?琌
- She said he was a Latin Jack Ryan.  - He was.
-?ê妓嘿㊣?  -拜肈琌  ?琌?┰??
- That's what she called him.  - The point is, he's Latin.
硂р?㎝谅瓣?ぇ?
Which connects her death and Jacobs's
瞣硈???闽╰??
beyond the fact that they worked together.
?ǎ筁胔好琌ㄢ﹙垦炳???も
You saw somebody you think is responsible for both killings?
-琌?  -琌?
- Yes.  - Yes.
?ǎ筁
She did.
и?环矪ǎ筁??璉紇
I saw him from a distance. From behind.
-い单ō?ぇ摸  -и?????
- Medium height, medium build, etc?  - Mind if I look at these?
ê丁????ê?弧
Is that what the people from the cabin said?
琌?
Yeah.
?Τ?琩筁  硂ㄇゴ?〆ず风┰?筿杠
Did you check out these calls to Venezuela?
???
Disconnected.
-ê??⊿Τ絬?  -иΤ??
- So you have no leads?  - I have a lot.
??安?祅癘  ??敖ㄓ?ㄓ筿獺ノ?腹絏
Afictitious name on a register. A stolen phoned-in credit card number.
ㄢ?ヘ阑靡?  ㄤい????  ???⊿Τ
Two eyewitnesses, one of whom saw a guy but really didn't see him.
癸ぃ癬  ????冀?Ω
Excuse me, could you play that again?
琌?  ?﹛
Yes, sir.
??诀竟ご秨帝  宾腞
The machine is still on, Moira.
?Τ?も羘??魁?
You have a recording of the killer's voice.
???
Maybe.
狽?  и稱и?Τ絬??  筿杠魁?诀魁??
Jack. I think we've got something. This is from the answering machine.
琌琎ぱ魁?ㄓ?  и冀倒?钮
And this was recorded yesterday. I'll play it for you.
??诀竟ご秨帝  宾腞
The machine is still on, Moira.
τ?...
And...
??佩稺  иぃ?笵  ?癸?弧?ぐ?  ?ê琌癸?
He's scared. I don't know what you said to him, but it was right.
т??皌???ㄓ
Run a match on that.
?琌?ぺ?
He's Cuban.
35?45烦
35 to 45.
??瓣?毙▅  ?瓣狥场
Educated in the United States. Eastern United States.
-琌???羘?  -??﹚
- It's the same voice.  - You're sure?
-琌?  -Τ??﹚
- Yeah.  - How sure?
?Θ
90 percent.
-и璶????  -??琌计?窾?...
- I need a name.  - Could be hundreds of thousands...
и?笵  и璶????  临璶е
I know. I need a name, and I need it quick.
300腹?ヒ狾
300 is topside.
ヘ夹?絋﹚
Target is set.
-划疭  -︺?
- Hector!  - Enrique!
ǎ??痷?
Good to see you!
-и??ぃ??  -??盾
- It was not easy for us.  - How are you?
縞︺?  拦ㄈ吹...
Rojas, Diaz...
硂?┏琌ぐ?
What the hell is this?
硂琌ぐ?
и?穝?ㄣ  尺舧盾
My new toy. Like it?
???盾
You see this?
ê琌??穝ヘ夹  埃獶ウ临ぃ镑?
That's your new target, unless it's not big enough.
跑秖  硂琌礡?  钮?盾  Ч拨
Variable, this is Easy Rhino. Do you copy? Over.
?睲贰  礡?
Loud and clear, Easy Rhino.
-Τㄆ璶暗盾  -ぃ岿
- Do we have a gig?  - That's a Rog.
ヘ夹?竒獹帝
Target is lit.
秨﹍?
Start the music.
?阑
Into attack.
诀穦ㄓ?  ヘ夹玛﹚??獹帝  ?ㄓ?
Pickle's hot. Target is acquired and lit. Coming down.
禣孽瓆  ??...  ?荐緓
Fernandez, Vega... Looks like a full house.
赣?  ???ぃ??硂兵隔
Damn it! Why doesn't he fix this road?
赣?  ???常ㄓ?
Shit! Thought we had everybody.
玂?ヘ夹
Keep the target painted.
?﹛
Sir?
ぱ摆
Mother of God!
碻吏岿粇??┦箂
Circular error probability zero.
疾阑蔼?脄?  ????
Impact with high-order detonation. Have a nice day.
硂??浩?  ?ぃ?笵...
The man's completely out of control. He has no...
?﹎尝  ?尝滇?
His name is Cortez, Felix Cortez.
??玡临琌?ぺ薄厨Ы???
A colonel in Cuba's intelligence service
纯竒ア萝?琿?丁
until a few years ago. Disappeared.
程?蠢猧?兢??┢?笆舱麓沉Λ筽吹??
Turned up working for the Macheteros, a terrorist group in Puerto Rico.
??ア萝
Disappeared again.
琎ぱи?敖钮?  ?蛤????瑀竇??酵杠
Yesterday, we taped him talking to a Cali cartel subject.
и穦р┮眔?戈?筿肚??  ?狦??瞷碞ъ?  ?盾
I'll fax what I have on him. If he shows, pick him up, OK?
-??笵иぃ?ê妓暗  -и琌?牡よ
- You know I can't do that.  - I mean the police, the Colombians.
??ゑㄈ牡よぃ穦ъ瑀竇??
The Colombian police do not pick up members of the cartel.
埃獶??稱?  ??ㄓ筁硂ń
Unless they've got a death wish. You've been down here.
单??
Wait a minute.
ぱ摆  狽?  硂ńΤㄆ祇ネ
Oh, Jesus! Jack, something's happened here.
?ぶ???砆炳  ?珹?ㄇ包扩
At least 30 people were killed, including women and children.
?紆??琜妮?縞︺??═óい脄?
The bomb exploded in a car belongingto a Rojas associate.
-狽?  -琌  ??Μ?
- Jack?  - Yeah, are you watching this?
-硂ㄆ?祇ネ  -??
- Did this just happen?  - Just now.
р┮Τ戈?肚倒и  ?狦и?祇瞷?碞蛤萝?
Send me all the stuff, and we'll put a tail on him if we spot him.
?狦?临?帝  и璶ǐ?
If he's still alive. I've got to go.
-...?╰??脄?ㄆン  -牡よ羘嘿  忌?ㄆン...
- ...a series of explosions.  - Cops claim the violence...
-?弧琌?脓  -?だΘ?
- A surgical strike, you said.  - It was perfect.
-??笿甡????瓣穝籇い  -?弧璶眏祑?翴
- They brought out a kid. On NBC.  - Take the gloves off, you said.
-и?笵и弧筁ぐ?  -э跑?種Τ翴筐?
- I know what I said.  - A bit late to change your mind.
иぃ琌璶э跑?種
I'm not changing my mind.
и⊿Τ箇璸硂贺?盿?穕甡
I hadn't counted on this kind of collateral damage.
-??⊿Τ  -ê穦砆??琌и弧?
- Neither had he.  - It will be interpreted as I said.
癸ミ簍跑Θ═ó脄?
Rivalry that ended in the blast of a car bomb.
边?
Goodnight.
-腞捣  Ν  厨?ЧΘ?  -程穝??
- Morning, Rose. Finish the report?  - Hot off the press.
谅谅
Thanks.
??い?Τ?ノ??
Could any of the bombing victims' names be aliases?
┮Τōだ常絋粄?  ??辨琌街
No. All IDs have been confirmed. Who were you hoping for?
?狦?ぃ?硂ń  尝滇?  ?ぃ?硂ń
If he's not here, he's not here. Cortez. He's not here.
-??︽笆舱Τ硂?捌セ  -筽?蚌璶―?
- Why was Operations copied on this?  - Ritter requested it.
筽?蚌  ?さぱ?簘獹
Ritter? You look very nice today.
谅谅
Thank you.
═ó?紆
Car bomb.
═ó?紆ま祇?穦?妓
What happens when a car bomb goes off?
-脄?  -ウ穦??㎝??脄
- It explodes.  - It blows up and out?
?紆㎡
And a missile?
-硂?耕瞏??  -ê琌ㄥ??
- This deeper crater?  - That's characteristic.
???ê矫琍酚?
Bring up the satellite photo.
HMX㎝?祐膀ヒ璮
HMX and TNT.
讽??70ゑ30?だ秖睼?  碞眔??贺?暗OCTOL??借
When you mix it 70-30, you get a compound called Octol.
ì??═óい脄?  硑Θ??ê妓???
Put enough explosives in a car, you get a crater that big.
-ウ?铆﹚  ??禥  -ウ?临穦痙??ず
- It's very stable. Very expensive.  - Would it still be in the crater?
-?瞨?  -?矪常穦Τ窰?
- Very violent.  - There would be pieces all around.
-OCTOL??ń?硑  -???よ  稼瑆  ?瓣
- Where is Octol made?  - Lots of places. Europe. The US.
?⊿Τ?ノウ  ⊿Τ?璽踞眔癬  埃?瓁よ
But nobody uses it. Nobody can afford it except the military.
?紆??暗眔?  ?êぃ琌???紆
An aerial bomb would do that. But that's not an aerial bomb.
-ぃ琌  -ぃ琌
- It's not?  - No.
?矪常Τ?贺胖蝴襖?摧错
There is also a cellulose residue on everything.
莱赣Τ?紆窰?  硂ń㎝硂ń
There should be shrapnel. Here and here.
-?琌⊿Τ  -⊿Τ?紆窰?
- But there isn't.  - No bomb fragments.
"?襖胖蝴?臞甮旧??紆"
"Cellulose encased laser-guided bomb."
ゅン
Paper.
?瓣?ㄓ?
The Americans are here.
"и?Τ???硄翴  碞琌⊿Τρ狾?穞い??"
"We have something in common. We cannot implement policy
"?產常磅︽ぃ?現郸"
without tacit authorisation from our employer."
"и?常?笵  Τ?瓁???ゑㄈ"
"We also both know that there are American troops in Colombia
"ゴ帝?初獶猭驹?"
fighting an illegal war."
"и琍戳?穦?ぺ?皑カず??翭皊┍"
"I will be at Hotel Paloma de Oro in Panama City on Wednesday."
"и矗某и?穦?"
"I suggest we meet."
-せ  硂琌?繷  -硂琌せ
- Six, this is Point. Over.  - Six here.
êㄇ狥﹁?硂ń  Τ??
The stuffs here, a lot of it.
и临??100?150??瘪??
I'm also looking at 100 to 150 men, armed,
?单帝ぐ???  Ч拨
waiting around for something. Over.
琌???ゑㄈ瓁钉  Ч拨
Colombian Army? Over.
ぃ琌  ??钩琌侗赌?
Negative. They look like mercenaries.
-Ч拨  -??  ?ㄓ
- Over.  - Alright. Get back here.
?斌︽笆  ?確  ?斌︽笆  ǐ
Abort mission. I say again, abort mission. Out.
?κき???瘪??
150 armed men?
叫羭癬蛮も
Raise your arms, please.
稰谅?硂?е?莱и??獺
Thank you for responding to my note. And so promptly.
и蛤谅瓣??ネ??礚闽
I had nothing to do with the death of Mr Jacobs.
ê琌?浩╣?︽?  ?玱琌и?侗???ㄥ?も猭
It was an act of madness. But typical of the men I work for.
-?璶ぐ?  -蛤??妓  膓瑄?
- What do you want?  - Same as you. Mineral water.
???種?璶?瓣?璶瑀珇  ??碞眔?ㄑ莱
You agree that as long as Americans want drugs, someone will supply them?
иぃ稱?硂ń?粇?丁
I don't want to be here any longer than I have to.
?矗の?初腊?ぇ驹  ê琌ぐ?種?
You mentioned a gang war. What does that mean?
-碞琌и??ヘ夹?璓  -痷?
- That we want the same thing.  - Same thing? Really?
?瞷???暗????ひ
Only, so far, you've done all the work.
矪竚?êㄇ?辰
You took care of the little fish.
и穦矪竚簗呼?ê?兵
I will take care of the one that got away.
肅?瓜?ǐ  и碞??腊?
Once Escobedo is gone, I will be in a position to help you.
-?稱腊и  -腊??瓣產  ???チ
- You want to help me?  - Your country. Your people.
?舱瑀珇ネ種
By restructuring the drug trade.
俱獀ウ  ?狦и盢
By regulating it. What would you say
笲┕?瓣????搭?  ?弧?妓
if I promised to halve the cocaine shipments to the US?
и弧?ノ眔び???玻珇
I'd say you'd been using too much of your product.
и???竒盽倒?  ╇??璶????肂
I can also promise you regular quotas on major arrests
??牡よ??ミ?
that your police can take credit for.
稱??  栏粿┦?苯亢  ?碩搭秖
Imagine. Dramatic seizures. Drastic reductions.
ぃ?Τ⊿瞶┦?忌?  ?穦眔?秤?
No more senseless violence. You'll have your victory.
?ぐ?ㄓユ传
In return for what?
и?璶?瑀竇逞??墩?  ?ミи???
I also need a victory, to establish my position
―?秤?  и?腊眔??
with what is left of the cartel, so I can help you.
и璶ゴ毖êㄇ竩種脄瘆???
I need to defeat those soldiers blowing up everything they see.
р????竚?瓜倒и  ち耞???硄癟
Give me maps of their locations. Cut off their communications.
?ユ场穦癳ㄓ菏钮魁?盿  и临⊿ΤΜ?
DEA's sending the audio surveillance tape. They haven't got it yet.
?仅?痜?  临?稱帝ぐ?
You know what you think about when you're lying here?
??笵е璶??  临稱帝...
You know you're gonna die, and you think...
...ぃ璶候  ?????
...that's alright. You lived a long time.
?Τ??稲??產畑
You had a family that loved you.
Τ?????籔?ぃ????
You had a job that you thought made a difference.
?????篴
That you thought was honourable.
礛????硂?
And then you see this.
?狦и?瞏?秸琩...
I'm afraid if I dig any deeper...
...?┤⊿Τ?尺舧и?祇瞷
...no one's gonna like what I find.
??筁?粆...
You took an oath...
...?狦?临癘眔...
...if you recall...
...?讽?ㄓ蠢и???
...when you first came to work for me.
иぃ琌?癸?瓣瓣產??臮拜
And I don't mean to the National Security Advisor of the US.
и琌?????
I mean to his boss.
и?ぃ琌?羆参
And I don't mean the President.
?┯空?┚...
You gave your word to...
...????
...his boss.
?┯空?┚...
You gave your word...
...?瓣??チ
...to the people of the United States.
??┯空碞琌????
Your word is who you are.
?临Τㄇぐ?
What else have you got there?
и倒?盿?ㄇ穝馒в
I brought you some new magazines.
狥?╖?薄猵?ㄓ?竒铆﹚?ㄓ
The situation in East Timor seems to have stabilised during the day.
??
Good.
-碞琌硂妓  -临Τ??ンㄆ
- Is that it?  - Except for the other thing.
и?ЧΘ???ヴ叭  Τ龟借?Θ狦
We've accomplished a lot. We're seeing results.
瑀珇块?秖?竒??  カ初基?タ??ど
Drug shipments are down. Price on the street is rising.
現┎?︽笆琌タ絋?
The perception is the administration is doing something right.
胊??琌ぐ?
What's the bad news?
谅瓣?砆炳?  皑?祇ネ═ó脄?ㄆン  ?и踞み
I'm worried about the car bomb coming so soon after Jacobs's assassination.
êタ琌肚碈闽猔?狥﹁
Just the kind of thing reporters live for.
-??稲рㄆン?硈  -?粄???穦
- They'd love to make a connection.  - And you think they will?
и粄?琌??懒竚俱ンㄆ
I think it's time the whole thing went away.
-?狦?粄?ê妓  -琌?
- If that's what you think.  - I think so.
ê?碞懒竚?  ウ眖⊿祇ネ筁
Then it should go away. It never happened.
Τ???
Well, it's possible.
?狦??禗и  ?稱卖秈街?╰参穦耕甧?
It would be easier if you told me whose system you want to break into.
-苦痴?  Ν  -Ν
- Morning, Dr Ryan.  - Morning.
?竒ぃ?琌瞦?ネら戳
Well, we're way beyond birthdays now.
и璶糶??疭?祘Α
I'm gonna have to write a special program here.
??
Right.
??  并み  秨??
OK, sweetheart, let's get to work.
??  ??
Fine, good.
琌?  ㄓ?
Yes. Here we go.
ぱ?
Jesus!
が磃  ê琌ぐ?
Reciprocity. What's that?
-ぐ?  -иа?  ?禗?
- Yeah?  - I forgot to tell you,
??眔盞絏?
after you get the code,
璶单?闽诀????祅?
wait until he's off his system before you log on.
-?玥?穦?笵  -ぱ摆  ┘眔  び筐?
- He will know it when you do.  - Jesus, Petey, it's too late.
и?ぱ
Oh, my God!
腐??
Cutter.
ぐ?ㄆ
Yeah?
-猧ゑ  и琌苦狽?  -狽?  ?Ν
- Bob, Jack Ryan here.  - Good morning, Jack.
?砛и?秨﹍眔?畉玪
Listen, maybe we got off to a bad start.
?狦и?璶??  赣が??秆??
We're going to work together. We should get to know each other.
?ゴ呼瞴盾  呼瞴  ?ゴ呼瞴盾
Do you play tennis? Tennis? Do you play tennis?
-иΤゴ呼瞴  -ㄓ?Ω籈穦??
- Yeah, I play tennis.  - How about we get together?
?琍戳  ?痁玡?盾
Next week? Hour before we startwork?
-狽?  -琌?
- Jack?  - Yeah.
筿福祍叛琌?腨??竜︽
Computer theft is a serious crime.
笻は舅猭?竜︽?琌?妓
So are crimes against the Constitution.
睼矹
Son of a bitch!
ㄓ?  ㄓ?
Come on, come on.
??
Clark.
琌?
Yeah.
狟ね  ?璶Г╟?
You'll go to jail, pal.
ê琌ぐ?  ????ъ?ぐ?
What is that? What do you think you have there?
?デ?猭
You broke the law.
?痷琌?フ猫
You are such a Boy Scout.
???泊い?Τ堵籔フ
Look at you. You see everything in black and white.
ぃ琌堵籔フ  琌癸籔岿
No, not black and white, Ritter. Right and wrong!
-??盾  ?ㄓ?  -??и睝ぃ?薄
- You see? There you go again.  - Why was I kept out of it?
?ō炒ㄤい  ??筁瓣穦
You're neck deep in it. You went before Congress.
莉眔挤蹿  ?临祇安粆
You got the money for it. You lied under oath...
-и⊿Τ?瓣穦弧晾  -????弧ぃ穦Τ瓁钉
- I never lied to Congress!  - You told them no troops.
-êńΤ瓁钉  -??笵и琌?ぃ?薄
- There are troops!  - You know I didn't know that.
и癘ぃ癬?  硂?杠?璶厩
No. I have no recollection of that. That's the term you have to learn.
-街??硂ㄆ  -???﹚穦拜
- Who authorised this?  - Sure, they'll ask you that.
-街??硂ㄆ  -и癘ぃ癬?  把某?
- Who authorised this?  - I have no recollection, Senator.
и⊿Τ把籔?產赣??現獀р栏
I did not sign up for somebody's bullshit political agenda.
街??硂ㄆ  腐
Who authorised this? Cutter?
⊿Τу非  腐硈竕綾盿?ぃ?
Cutter couldn't tie his shoes without permission.
-?狦и璶?籓  ??眔蛤帝  -?岿?
- If I go down, you're going with me.  - Wrong again.
иΤ?眎  帽???"?禣?夯"靡
I have an autographed "Get Out of Jail Free" card.
"羆参甭舦い薄Ы捌Ы?筽?蚌"
"The President authorises the Deputy Director CIA, Robert Ritter,
"?揣が磃︽笆  ?珹?场┮惠や穿"
to conduct Operation Reciprocity including all support necessary."
"?兜︽笆癸?瓣瓣產???だ?璶"
"This operation is deemed important to the national security of the US."
单单  单单
Etc, etc, etc.
?⊿Τ???  狽?
You don't have one of these, do you, Jack?
η︹  ??琌η︹?  狽?
Grey! The world is grey, Jack.
??Τ快猭毙и叉ō
Got any idea how I'm gonna get out of this mess?
Ч?⊿Τ
Absolutely none.
琌?  и琌
Yeah. This is he.
碭?
When?
タゅ
James?
谅谅
Thank you.
?タゅ?盢拨ネ癪膍瓣產の產畑
Admiral James Greer devoted his life to his country and his family,
礚╬?膍???醇紌㎝稲
giving selflessly of both his wisdom and his love.
??瓣產狝叭?禬筁き??
He served his country for more than 50 years.
??烦????瓁  ?瓁?拨穨
Enlisting in the Navy at 17. Graduating from the Academy.
﹛顶ど??琍?盢
Achieving three stars for his flag.
?竒菌瓣產?Ω??睹ㄆン
He lived through tumultuous events in his country's life.
?把籔ㄤい  ???厩拜  ㈱港  タ?㎝玦?
He participated in them. He made them clearer to the rest of us,
?и???絋瞶秆
with his knowledge, his honesty, his integrity and his courage.
и?ぃ???  ?и?笵???êń
I can't see them, but I know they're there.
瞒???竚狥﹁きそń
Five kilometres due east from your position.
膥尿?玡  и?穦ъ???
Keep pushing forward. We'll trap them.
?眖ぃ淮??獺
Never, though, was he deluded into thinking that one man
????毕獀??
could solve the ills of the world.
????钉い?瓁?  ??驹玭びキ瑅
Always the soldier, on the battlefields of the South Pacific,
龙瓣  禫玭㎝地脖箉
Korea, Vietnam and Washington, he fought as part of a unit
??矫瓣產?...
to preserve the ideals...
-??  硂琌跑秖  Ч拨  -...瞶├
- Knife, this is Variable, over.  - ...of his nation.
??  硂琌跑秖  Ч拨
Knife! This is Variable, over.
и?ри?ね??逻砰  獺綼ぉ????臔
To the refuge of the earth, we entrust our friend's body.
р??艶活獺綼ぉ???玂?
To the protection of our God in Heaven, we entrust his soul.
р??弘?㎝ネ??玥
To ourselves, we entrust his spirit
獺綼ぉи?
and the principles he lived by.
タゅ  и?穦胔├?
We're gonna miss you, James.
跑秖  硂琌??  Ч拨
Variable, this is Knife, over.
跑秖  и钡Μぃ?  и?笿?瞨疨脓阑
Variable, I am not receiving. We are under heavy attack.
-惠璶?いや穿  Ч拨  -е  е  е
- Need air support, over.  - Go, go, go!
跑秖  硂琌??  Ч拨  锣
Variable, this is Knife, over! Switch!
跑秖  硂琌??  ??┏??ń
Variable, this is Knife! Where the hell are you?
?????もㄓ
Present arms.
и???瓣璓?и??玸饱
On behalf of a grateful nation, our condolences.
-?琌??ぃ癬?稲瓣?  -谅谅
- He was a very great patriot.  - Thank you.
阑いヘ夹
All aim.
-??  -繬?т苦狽?痴?
- Hello?  - Jean Fowler for Dr Jack Ryan.
и琌
This is he.
狽?  ?璶钮?钮硂?
Jack? You've got to hear this.
さΝ钡Μ??
Picked it up this morning.
跑秖  硂琌??  и?笿?脓阑  惠璶?いや穿
Variable, this is Knife. We are under attack, need air support.
跑秖  硂琌??  ??┏??ń
Variable, this is Knife, where the hell are you?
?稱и?妓矪瞶硂ㄆ
Jack, what do you want me to do with this?
??兵捌羘盿  ??兵
Make a copy, Jean. Make ten copies.
荷е倒и癳筁ㄓ  谅谅
Get them to me as quick as you can. Thanks.
ぱ摆  ??璶рêㄇ?痙?êń
Jesus. They're going to leave those guys down there.
?タ???915痁诀  穦?边?7翴50だ╄笷猧??
He's on American 915. He'll be in Bogota 7:50 pm.
-ぐ?ㄆ  -и琌筽
- Yeah?  - It's Ritter.
-??洱????ń  -и?Τ?螟
- Where the fuck have you been?  - We have a problem.
и?Τ?╝螟  и羛蹈ぃ?и?も?
We've got a disaster! I can't get through to my men.
и?璶闽奔矫琍硄癟
We had to shut down the satellite link.
-??  -?璶ぐ?
- Clark?  - You had to what?
硂琌苦  ?祇瞷?ち  临?纞璶硄?瓣穦
It's Ryan. He found out everything. He threatened to walk up the Hill
?狦и?ぃ氨ゎ︽笆
if we didn't shut down the operation.
??  氨ゎ?  倒и?翴?丁琵и?も?叉繧
OK. It's shut down. Just give me some air and my men are out of there.
???⊿痙み钮и弧  ⊿Τ?丁?  и?砆ち耞
Clark, maybe you're not hearing me. There is no air. We are shut down.
иタ?诀?  и璶炳??
I'm on a plane. I'm gonna kill him.
筽
Ritter?
???诀  ?璶ㄓт?
Don't get on a plane. He's coming to you.
?瓣??7翴50だ  ⊿Τ玂?
American Airlines at 19:50 hours with no security.
-?琌街  -瓣產??臮拜腐??
- Who is this?  - National Security Advisor Cutter.
苦?ǐи?碞?確硄癟
Once Ryan's gone, we're back on line.
??フ盾
You understand?
?フ
Yes, sir.
??
Clark.
-ぱ摆  -?ó
- Jesus!  - Get in the van.
?硂妓  иㄓт??
Don't be an asshole, I came to find you.
?т?и?  ?ó
You found me. Get in.
??
Alright.
Г?よ?絃?
Behind the wheel.
??
Clark.
秨ó
Drive.
-筽  -苦??
- Ritter.  - Ryan's dead.
??穦
How?
и炳??  ?币笆矫琍?
I killed him. Turn the op back on.
??и?奔苦  и???確??  琌盾
You said get rid of Ryan and we're back in business, right?
?ㄓ硂ń?ぐ?
What the hell are you doing here?
иㄓ腊?毕??も?
I came to help you get those guys out.
????妓腊и
What can you do to help me?
?惠璶ぐ?
What do you need?
?琜?ど诀
A helicopter.
ぃ  谅谅
No, thank you.
-硂琌"舧贾??"盾  -ッ环常琌"舧贾??"
- Is this happy hour?  - It's always happy hour.
-??诀畍局Τ硂??よ  -???硂ń
- Your pilot owns this joint?  - He lives here.
??硂ń
Here he is.
-Ν?  -Ν?
- Morning.  - Morning.
?Ν  и稱?ê琜?ど诀
Morning. I'm here to rent the Huey.
╆簆  и?ぃ???  ????扳
Sorry, we don't rent it any more. But it is for sale.
?ぶ窥
How much is it?
ㄢκ窾じ
Two million dollars.
и?诀畍㎝и璶??︽代刚
My pilot and I would have to do a test flight.
??  ??惠痙?璹?
Of course. You just have to leave a deposit.
璶?ぶ
How much is that?
ㄢκ窾じ
Two million dollars.
?Μそ?や布盾
Would you take a company cheque?
Μ
Yes.
-и?ㄓ?  -?琌?睼矹  琌盾
- Here we go.  - Big son of a bitch, ain't she?
-??筁?丁?硂贺摸?盾  -?翴
- Do you have any time in this type?  - Nine o'clock.
-??и??ど诀  -ぃ  琌и??ど诀  ǐ?
- Get out of my chopper.  - No. My chopper. Let's go.
??程??Ω硄癟?硂??竚
Their last communication put them here.
程钡??篗癶琌硂ń  ?硂?甽é
The closest extraction point is here, in this gorge.
и?笵?
I got it.
-??ê?琌?砰盾  -琌?
- Is that a body down there?  - Yeah.
-и?ㄤい??  -иㄤい??
- One of ours?  - One of mine.
т???辅?翴  и??тㄤ??
Find a place to set her down. We'll look for the others.
⊿?よ発ǐ  ⊿?よ跟旅
Nowhere to run to. No place to hide.
?矪常Τǐ?猠ê娩?﹀隔
Blood trails everywhere. They all lead to the river.
硂ㄇ琌и?眖?い???聄ガ
These are the falls we saw from the air.
?砰赣????阀き?μ
The bodies should be about 50 metres down.
?瞒斌и?  Ч?⊿倒и?や穿
You left us! You left us with no support at all!
赣??  ?琵и?单?
Fuck, you left us out to dry!
-?硂睼矹  -?猀  ?猀
- You son of a bitch!  - Easy! Easy!
-ぃ琌??岿  -琌街?岿
- It's not his fault.  - Whose fault is it?
琌и?岿
It's my fault.
程??Ω脓阑?  и蛤?繷硄筁杠
I was on point when the last attack came.
禯瞒禬筁??
Over a mile away.
и?ㄓ??竒Ч?
By the time I got back, it was over.
??盿ǐ?而默钉?
They were taking the Captain and Oso.
ㄤ??㎡
The others?
и甀旅???
I buried them.
礛????
Road to the town.
???硂ń┿ǐ??  ?矪常琌﹀
They loaded the prisoners here. Blood everywhere.
-ぱ惧眔??瞷???ń  -肅?瓜?笵
- God knows where they are now.  - Escobedo knows.
?稱??妓  篤???
What are you going to do? Knock on his door?
?Ν  и稱ǎ肅?瓜  и⊿Τ箇?
Morning. I'd like to see Ernesto Escobedo. I have no appointment.
谅谅
Gracias.
??
OK.
羭癬もㄓ
Hands up.
Hands up!
窥?
Wallet.
琌?魁?诀
It's a tape recorder.
?秈??
He's in.
?尘  硂琌跑秖  Ч拨
Bird, this is Variable, over.
苦痴?  叫秈
Dr Ryan. Come in.
Г?  Τぐ????骋
Sit down. What can I do for you?
иぃ?笵赣т街  иΤ??螟肈
I didn't know who else to turn to. I have a problem.
иΤ??狟ね  琌??〡柏禦產㎝???も
An associate of mine, a coffee buyer and his assistant,
ㄓ?硂ńそ?
were on a business trip in this area.
??琎ぱア萝?  и?踞み
They unexpectedly disappeared yesterday. I'm very concerned.
〡柏禦產
Coffee buyer?
и?稱碝???
It's very important to me to find them.
Μ禦〡柏琌禫ㄓ禫?繧?ネ種
Coffee buying is becoming a dangerous business.
琌?  ê琌?甃┘眔暗?
Yes. Well, it was for Peter Hardin.
-街  -?琌硈?〡柏?臮?
- Who?  - He was a client of Lindo Coffee.
-硈?〡柏Τ??臮?  -??﹚Τ钮筁硂??
- Lindo Coffee has many clients.  - You must have heard of this one.
?ろ??そ???掸窥
He owed your company a great deal of money.
и璶蛤穦璸酵??
Well, I'll have to talk to accounting about that.
せ货き?窾じ
$650 million.
㎝箂窥
And change.
?琌?矗某腊иΜ年眀
Are you offering to help me with the collection of an unpaid debt?
-ぃ琌  -??矗某ぐ?
- No.  - What are you offering?
?兜ユ?  尝滇??芥??
Atrade. Felix Cortez has sold you out.
?穦炳?㎝??產?
His next move is to murder you, your family,
礛?钡恨栋刮
and take over the cartel.
и?魁?诀??ń
Where's my tape recorder?
冀?ê琿盿?
Play the tape.
еǐ
Let's move.
и稱?ǎи?穝狟ね  苦痴?
I'd like you to meet my new friend, Dr Ryan.
"洛ネ"?ぐ?  Τ?痜?
Doctor? Why? Is somebody sick?
?稱璶ぐ?
What does he want?
??狟ね?キ???
The safe return of his associates.
ノぐ?ㄓユ传
And what does he offer us in return?
?
You.
硂??癸?弧?常琌晾杠  ?綼弧晾蝴ネ
Whatever this man has told you is a lie. He lies for a living.
?暗薄厨??  ??暗薄厨??
He's in the intelligence business. You're in the intelligence business!
?矪竚?êㄇ?辰
You've taken care of the little fish.
и穦矪竚簗呼?ê?兵
I will take care of the one that got away.
肅?瓜?ǐ  и碞??腊?
Once Escobedo is gone, I will be in a position to help you.
拜肈琌...
So, the question is...
...и赣??矪竚?
...what am I supposed to do with you?
и赣ノ硂や次炳??
Well? I guess I'm supposed to kill you with this bat!
癬ㄓ
Get up.
栏粿┦?苯亢  ?碩搭秖  ぃ?Τ忌?...
Dramatic seizures. Drastic reductions, no more violence...
?穦眔?秤?
You'll have your victory.
?ぐ?ㄓユ传
In return for what?
-????ń  -?硂ń
- Where are they?  - They're here.
ê?瓣?炳??肅?瓜  и?еǐ
Kill the plant. The American killed Ernesto! Let's go!
?尘т跑秖  Ч拨
Bird to Variable, over.
?尘  硂琌跑秖
Bird, this is Variable.
??┏??ń
Where the hell are you?
и??辅?玭?きそń矪絃臂
I'm cruising about five clicks south of the village.
-痙?êń  и?羛蹈?  -Μ?
- Stay there. I'll get back to you.  - Roger that.
-⊿Τ?  -êㄇ?デ
- No one.  - The prisoners!
ㄓ?  ??  и?еǐ
Come on, guys. Let's go, son.
и?璶?產?
We're going home, boys.
?硈?〡柏紅钡и?
Pick us up at the Lindo Coffee factory.
ぃ虫и???肚碈处祇?  ?????
Not only can I expose you to the press, so can the soldiers.
??稱蛤猭畑㎝癘?玙繧
Do you want to take your chances with the courts and the reporters?
挡??羆???現獀ネ睵
Do you want to end the career of your commander in chief?
и?ǐ
Let's go!
е?ㄓ  и?璶ǐ?
Get your asses in here! Come on, we got to go!
ㄓ?
Come on!
篊帝  и?璶单苦
Hold it! We wait for Ryan!
ぐ?  и?璶ǐ?
Yeah? We're out of here!
??  ????
Set it down! He's down there!
ㄓ?
Come on!
иъ??
I've got you!
讲蝴吹  被臔и
Chavez, cover me!
??も  р??も倒и
Your hand. Give me your hand!
羆参瞷?ǎ?
The President will see you now, sir.
狽?  ??ㄓ痷?
Jack! I'm glad you're here.
Г?  璶耻翴ぐ?
Sit down. Can I get you anything?
ぃノ?
No.
-ㄓ?  Г?  -и圭篅?帝
- Come on, sit down.  - I would prefer to stand, sir.
硂ńΤ?ㄇㄆ薄  иタ秨﹍痙種?
Some things have gone on here that I'm just becoming aware of.
и钩??妓??睝ぃ?薄
I was kept in the dark, as you were, for a very long time.
-陈沸?ㄆ薄  -琌?
- Troubling things.  - Yeah.
瞷?и?璶矪瞶ウ?  ?街璶璽砫
Now we have to sort them out, figure out who is responsible for what
㎝?妓矪竚ウ  и?临璶?み︽ㄆ
and what to do about it. We have to do this very delicately,
?玥????穦粇穦
otherwise people might get the wrong idea.
и?璶弧晾
We have to lie.
-иΤê妓弧盾  -?⊿Τ
- Did I say that?  - No, you didn't.
-??ネ?  -и?ネ?
- You're upset.  - I'm upset.
硂琌??教秆?  ?ざ種и倒??翴┚?
It's understandable. Do you mind if I give you a bit of advice?
??笵硂ンㄆ  ??羙?
You know this because you're smart.
讽?ネ?????璶?∕﹚
Never make important decisions while you're upset.
?Τ  タ??ウ  ?瓣??㎝キチ常??
You did. American soldiers and civilians are dead because of it.
-и⊿Τ?㏑?...  -??蛤и瑼ê甅
- I never ordered any...  - No. Don't play that game with me!
??杆?ぃ?薄  τ???籜槽
You won't dishonour their memories by pretending you didn't know!
-?澈幢癡旧...  -?澈幢
- How dare you lecture...  - How dare you, sir?
?澈幢?硂ㄠㄓ  钩?浩???и╣?
How dare you come here and bark at me like a junkyard dog!
и琌?瓣羆参
I am the President of the United States!
硂ンㄆ?иぃ??
It gives me no pleasure to do it, sir.
??竝瞶薄厨Ы捌Ы?
As Acting Deputy Director of Intelligence it is my duty
?把某皘菏服〆?穦厨?硂ㄆ  琌и?戮砫
to report this matter to the Senate Oversight Committee.
?ぃ?ê妓暗
You're not going to do that.
-иぃ?  -ぃ  ぃ
- I'm not?  - No, no.
?も?瞷?Τ?膚絏
You've got yourself a chip in the big game now.
???рウ痙?ㄓ
You're going to tuck that away,
讽???Τ陈沸?
save that for a time when your own ass is on the line.
碞рウ??ㄓ
And then you're going to pull it out.
и?????传Θ瞷?  琌盾
And I'm going to cash it in for you. Right?
и⊿Τㄤ?ㄆ璶??弧?
I don't think I have anything more to say to you, sir.
瓣產ぃ??Τ??﹙ぁ籇  ???玂
The country can't afford another scandal, Jack. To protect itself,
ウぃ?琵??﹙皋璸  紇臫?蔼糷
it won't allow another deception that goes all the way to the top.
?璶?砫  腐㎝筽?穦璽??ㄇ砫ヴ
You'll take the blame. Cutter and Ritter will take some, too,
??琌?淮稬
but it won't amount to much, a slap on the wrist.
礛??量厩伴?寥?羱?窾じ
Then $20,000 an hour on the lecture circuit.
ㄤ??砫ヴ盢辅??ō?
The rest of the blame will fall on Greer.
ぃ岿  ?穦盿帝??籓
Yeah, you'll take him down with you.
?穦篟反???臕
You'll destroy his reputation.
??穦?ê??˙  钩?ρ?猧Λ皑??˙籖
But that's as far as it will go. The old Potomac two-step, Jack.
癸ぃ癬羆参?ネ  иぃ铬籖?
I'm sorry, Mr President, I don't dance.
苦  ?Τ?丁盾
Ryan, have you got a minute?
⊿Τ
No.
и?璶酵??
We need to talk!
苦
Ryan!
〆?穦穦某タΑ秨﹍  ?畊瞷?肚?苦痴?
The Committee will come to order. The Chair will now call Dr Ryan.
苦痴?  稰谅?さぱ?畊穦某
Dr Ryan, thank you for appearing before the Committee today.
谅谅?  ?畊
Thank you, Mr Chairman.
叫癬ミ  羭癬???も
Please stand and raise your right hand.
?琌?腨德?祇粆  ??盢???ㄑ迭
Do you solemnly swear that the testimony you're about to give
琌ㄆ龟  ?场?ㄆ龟
is the truth, the whole truth
?Τㄆ龟  ―?玂??
and nothing but the truth, so help you God?
琌?
I do.
苦痴?  ?????粆  叫Г
Dr Ryan, you may consider yourself under oath. Please be seated.