×ÖÄ»
Sound familiar to you, Sheriff? No?
There were no grandparents
×ÖÄ»
or kin suitable to take the children in,
so they were sent into foster care.
×ÖÄ»
Then, when they became of age,
they started to become everyone's problem
×ÖÄ»
The oldest is Brick. He is Johnny Boy in the flesh.
Can't seem to stay out of trouble.
×ÖÄ»
And boy, does he love his guns.
Then it looks as though they tried to go legit for a minute.
×ÖÄ»
So they put their middle brother,
Lincoln, in Southern Circuit Wrestling.
×ÖÄ»
He ended up killing seven men in the ring. And guess what?
Absolutely nothing was done about it.
×ÖÄ»
Nope. Promoters wouldn't charge him,
saying it was accidental and part of his neck-breaking gimmick.
×ÖÄ»
And to make this giant fucker even freakier, he cannot talk.
Or at least he couldn't last time anybody checked.
×ÖÄ»
Wrestled under the name the Dixie Reaper.
And then there's McQueen. Practically illiterate.
×ÖÄ»
He's the baby of the brood. He was well on his way
to becoming a real-life G.I. Joe.
×ÖÄ»
But he's got a bit of an issue with authority.
Whoo!
×ÖÄ»
That's a mighty fine detective job you've done, son.
- Thank you, sir. - But... it ain't as easy as all that.
×ÖÄ»
- So you do know the Oodie Brothers? - Like I said, I know all.
I can't just bring them boys
×ÖÄ»
in 'cause some suit from Philadelphia wants me to.
Well, you can if some suit
×ÖÄ»
from Chicago tells you to.
The longer you stay down here, the more you're going to realise,
×ÖÄ»
we don't like being told what to do, son. Now...
...if you'll excuse me, I got other work to attend to.
×ÖÄ»
No, Sheriff. Listen, I'm just asking for,
you know, a little cooperation.
×ÖÄ»
Once this thing gets wrapped up, I'll get out of your hair.
Why don't you let me worry about my county?
×ÖÄ»
We'll be in Dallas by midnight.
I'll drive us until I can't drive no more.
×ÖÄ»
Can you believe she went ahead and paid us five grand up front?
I know, right?
×ÖÄ»
I mean, you'd think she'd have some trust issues, right?
- But hey, each to their own. - Each to their own, man.
×ÖÄ»
Each to their own.
Now, I know we've got an address to Austin,
×ÖÄ»
but shouldn't she have given
us like a picture of the kid or something?
×ÖÄ»
How many kids you reckon they got up there?
I mean, they ain't running a day-care centre.
×ÖÄ»
- OK. - Yeah.
What if we get there and Rob's a baby?
×ÖÄ»
Well, if he's a baby, they got baby junk up there.
- Oh, that's smart. - It's not like they're riding around
×ÖÄ»
with a baby in a shoebox or nothing. I mean, come on.
Besides that, them bullet
×ÖÄ»
scars didn't look too fresh on Celeste's belly.
- You're right. You're right. - Yeah.
×ÖÄ»
- What if there's more than one kid?
- Why are you asking me so many
×ÖÄ»
goddamn questions, man? We just went over this! What?
What do you want to know?! What do you want to know?!
×ÖÄ»
- How will we know which is Rob? - I'm gonna say which one's Rob!
How about that? I'm gonna say,
×ÖÄ»
"You know what, I don't want Kevin!
I don't want Michael! No, I don't want Stephen!"
×ÖÄ»
If there's a bunch of
fucking kids around I'm gonna say, "I want Rob!
×ÖÄ»
How about that? Fucking hell, man!
It's a damn simple smash and grab!
×ÖÄ»
We smash whoever's in front of us and we take Rob!
Damn! Plain and simple! What? Sorry, Lincoln.
×ÖÄ»
- I don't know why you have to yell...
- Your faggoty brother won't shut up!
×ÖÄ»
I'm inquisitive, and you know that!
Where'd you learn that word? Inquisitive?
×ÖÄ»
- Where the fuck did you pick that up? - It's in my lexicon, man!
- Jackass. Yeah? - I've got it up here.
×ÖÄ»
There's a lot you don't know about me.
Are you ready for a potty break?
×ÖÄ»
How many books you read, motherfucker?
- Where are we? - We're in Crockett.
×ÖÄ»
Davy Crockett. What time is it?
Four.
×ÖÄ»
Hey.
Hm... I guess there's a little candy in every pinata.
×ÖÄ»
Shh.
Got some free shit!
×ÖÄ»
Take it easy, Van Damme! Hey.
Hadji at the front desk said we're only a few hours from Austin.
×ÖÄ»
- Nice! - Whoo! Ow!
- Who that? - Fuck. Who do you think?
×ÖÄ»
Don't answer that shit, man!
Don't answer it. Don't you...
×ÖÄ»
- Hey. - Hey?
Don't hey me. The hell are you?
×ÖÄ»
Texas.
Texas?
×ÖÄ»
Well, what in the Sam
Hill could you possibly have to do in Texas?
×ÖÄ»
Hey, man. Check this out.
Permian Stadium from Friday Night Lights. It's on the way!
×ÖÄ»
I took a job out here.
Oh, you took a job! Well, excuse me.
×ÖÄ»
What was I thinking? I forgot
you guys are freelance artists. So, Mr Brick,
×ÖÄ»
- what job did you take? - Look, it's not a big deal, man.
All right? It's just a little gig out here. We can handle it.
×ÖÄ»
Oh, you're going to handle it like you handled me yesterday?
It's bad enough you can't check a damn address,
×ÖÄ»
but you also got to lay them pork chops out in my backyard?
- Put it on our tab. - What was that?
×ÖÄ»
- Nothing! - You watch your mouth, son.
This ain't a joke. This little misstep is gonna be a pain for me,
×ÖÄ»
but you may have just stuck your dick in a hornet's nest.
What are you talking about? What do you mean?
×ÖÄ»
I've got some jackleg ATF agent up my ass,
looking to make a name for locking up you idiots.
×ÖÄ»
The last thing I need is for
you dumb shits to draw more unneeded attention.
×ÖÄ»
I mean it, Brick. I better
not hear shit about your little Texas job.
×ÖÄ»
Keep your ass off the grid.
Don't call my house. Write this number down.
×ÖÄ»
And for the love of God, get rid of that damn cell phone.
- Yes, sir. - Damn well better.
×ÖÄ»
You mess around and fuck up my pension, that's your ass.
I don't even know you.
×ÖÄ»
Hey!
Check it out, man! Permian Stadium!
×ÖÄ»
It's on the way, man! You want to win, put bubba in!
It's not on the way, jackass.
×ÖÄ»
It is, man! It's Odessa, Texas!
Huh?
×ÖÄ»
Man! Don't take it out on me because you got your ass chewed.
We got work to do, boys.
×ÖÄ»
I'll get my badge.
No. I figured we'd do the old Roosevelt slammer.
×ÖÄ»
Fuck, yeah! Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Dibs, bitch! Whoo!
×ÖÄ»
Goddamn it, Montane! I didn't
want you to blow the place to hell and back.
×ÖÄ»
I don't give a shit!
Would you fucking listen to me every now and then?
×ÖÄ»
Please? Goddamn it. Come here, baby. Come here!
I don't know if your mama told you, but you are hotter than shit.
×ÖÄ»
Goddamn.
Fuck. That's the shit right there, boys!
×ÖÄ»
From now on, no more nickel and diming!
You get it? Only the finest!
×ÖÄ»
- Hey, how come she's not naked? - Don't know, boss.
Find out.
×ÖÄ»
Hey. I'll call you when I need you.
All right. Bye.
×ÖÄ»
Doesn't anybody know how to use finesse any more?
You all right?
×ÖÄ»
- The helmet ain't work for shit. - I told you. Aah!
All right, you go east, I go west!
×ÖÄ»
Plain and simple. Smash and grab.
Oh, shit.
×ÖÄ»
My bad, lady. You OK?
In my defence, you do work for an asshole.
×ÖÄ»
You Rob?
Brick!
×ÖÄ»
Goddang. Brick!
Goddamn it.
×ÖÄ»
Fuck.
Oh, shit.
×ÖÄ»
Boss! Boss, are you all right?
What the fuck does it look like, Marty?
×ÖÄ»
It looks like a fucking bomb went off.
Denny?
×ÖÄ»
- What the hell happened? - The kid.
- Say what? - Three guys come in.
×ÖÄ»
Yes, I know three guys came in! They came all the fucking way in!
- I see that! - They took the kid.
×ÖÄ»
Fuck! Goddamn it!
They shot my motherfucking maid!
×ÖÄ»
OK, Marty, I know it's over a year ago,
but I need you to fucking think, OK? You did kill Celeste, right?
×ÖÄ»
You wouldn't lie to me about that shit, would you?
I put three bullets in her gut. She looked dead to me.
×ÖÄ»
But you didn't check to see if she was dead, did you?
Guess not.
×ÖÄ»
That was our golden ticket, you stinking fuck!
How am I going to pay for this? You got the dough?
×ÖÄ»
Hm?
You got a fucking piggy bank in your fat ass?
×ÖÄ»
Sorry, boss.
OK. As long as you're sorry,
×ÖÄ»
I guess that's all that matters, isn't it?
I'll take care of it, boss.
×ÖÄ»
I'll make sure it's right. I'll take care of it.
Good, good. Thanks, thanks.
×ÖÄ»
Yeah. Hand me my goddamn pills, will you?
You still want to go look at that car?
×ÖÄ»
That Carlos man make you cripple?
Hi, buddy.
×ÖÄ»
I don't think he can talk.
- Well, ain't this some shit, man. - What?
×ÖÄ»
That he's all, you know...
- Don't do that shit! - What?
×ÖÄ»
'Cause you're being mean! He can't help it.
You OK?
×ÖÄ»
You hurt?
You OK? He can understand us.
×ÖÄ»
How the hell did you get "I'm OK" From that?
Hey, look, buddy. We ain't going to hurt you,
×ÖÄ»
all right? Celeste sent us.
You know Celeste?
×ÖÄ»
Huh?
Yeah! There he goes! See? He understands us just fine.
×ÖÄ»
Once again, how the hell do you know what he's saying?
You the tard whisperer?
×ÖÄ»
You say that again, I'm gonna kill you.
- I'm not making fun. I'm just saying.
×ÖÄ»
- Say it again. You are making fun.
- I'm not making fun. I'm just saying.
×ÖÄ»
- You are making fun of him.
It's just a little weird
×ÖÄ»
that she didn't mention the poor little fella's
- all buggered up, you know? - It don't matter.
×ÖÄ»
She sent us to get Rob. We got Rob. All right?
You good, buddy?
×ÖÄ»
- I wasn't being mean. - You were being mean!
You were making fun of him.
×ÖÄ»
Bless his heart. He ain't got no control over that.
It's a damn good thing he wasn't in the living room.
×ÖÄ»
I'm just saying.
Hm-mm. Yeah, we can do that.
×ÖÄ»
Oh, we can get that done.
All right, Carlos. I'm just finishing up a little something here.
×ÖÄ»
Then we'll get on the road.
Don't you worry about a thing, sweetie.
×ÖÄ»
Excuse me, councilman.
What? He wanted a bath.
×ÖÄ»
Another one already? I didn't even get off.
- It's for Carlos. - Well, that makes it a bit better.
×ÖÄ»
Doesn't get much better than this, Bill.
It'd be better than this if
×ÖÄ»
the fish was biting as well as these chiggers.
You gotta be shitting me.
×ÖÄ»
This is where the real police matters are handled, huh?
Oh, you mean on private property? Yeah, sometimes it is.
×ÖÄ»
Anthony Reese, ATF.
- Bill Hawkins. Nice to meet you.
×ÖÄ»
- Bill's a representative for the state.
Ah, nice to meet you, sir.
×ÖÄ»
Bill, have you heard about an investigation going on in our area?
No, I haven't.