This movie is based on true
happened facts but remains fiction.
None of this can be used
be before the court.
ATHENS
Coffee?
- Yes please. But not too much.
Since what time have you been awake?
- Since 08:00.
Do you want something too?
- Yes please.
You work hard. You must be tired.
I'll be right back.
Is this the right floor?
Everything is secured.
Send the French in.
He's not here.
Put them on the couch.
Where is he?
- I do not understand you.
Abdelhamid Abaaoud.
I do not understand you.
- Not?
Look closely at the photo.
- Ahmed?
Where is he? Do you know him?
I don't know anything about him.
- Where is he?
Maybe he's on the roof?
Do you have anything down there?
We have nothing to report.
He's not here.
- Not then?
This was it.
SDAT 3, Athens. 09:48
Attempt to arrest Abaaoud ended.
Failed.
PARIS
10 MONTHS EARLY
Yes?
To all units.
Gunfire in the 10th arrondissement.
I repeat: gunshots
in the 10th arrondissement.
We return. Yes Marc?
- Two bombs in the Stade de France?
Héloïse speaks with the prefecture.
Call everyone to the office.
And gunshots in it
10th arrondissement? Where exactly?
Rue Bichat and Rue de la Fontaine au Roi.
So 10th and 11th.
At least two men shoot
from cars to the crowd.
Stay tuned. Are there any injuries?
- You're not high, are you?
Large caliber. Reinforcements requested.
It's a war scene.
Automatic weapons.
- Send reinforcements.
Anti-terrorist unit, I'm listening.
All briefing monitors in room F.
One commando is in the Stade
de France and the other in Paris.
In the 11th, shots were fired at the 'Carillon'.
Rue de la Fontaine au Roi en
Rue de Charonne.
Séverine, to the Stade de France.
Sébastien to the 10th arrondissement.
Terrorists invaded the Bataclan.
In the middle of a concert.
France must remain strong against
this wave of terror.
Marco, are you after the terraces
got into the Bataclan?
How many attackers are there in total?
Is anyone injured?
Marco, I'll call you back. Yes?
Fred, prepare the RAID and the BRI
prepares to storm the Bataclan.
We already know about
the number of victims?
Not exactly yet. About 30 in Paris.
But we know nothing about the Bataclan.
We must mobilize everyone.
- Everyone's on their way.
I have all available powers
advanced and mobilized.
We need these terrorists
stop as soon as possible.
We need safety in all
to re-insure affected places.
I also decided to
to close the borders.
Mission canceled in Les Halles.
False alarm.
No, false alarm. How's the situation?
On the rue de la Fontaine au Roi
they search the cellars.
Compatriots, my thoughts go out
to all victims.
But also to the families of
those who were injured.
There are dozens of deaths.
It's terrible.
I need a schedule.
- How is the situation?
It's two or three commands.
One in the Stade de France and
one in the 10th.
They're in the Bataclan.
One remained on Boulevard Voltaire.
Rue Bichat to Nation and then Bataclan?
We check the timing.
- Who coordinates the emergency calls?
One unit but the network is overloaded.
The hotline 197 has been activated.
The information flow is not allowed
end in chaos.
The Bataclan is stormed.
Storm at this very moment
law enforcement a building in Paris.
The army is deployed to
prevent new attacks.
I'm in the ministry.
I'll call you back. Good evening.
Keep having faith in it
that our security services...
do everything for our nation
to guard against terror.
Is there a balance?
From firefighters and hospitals
we expect higher numbers.
The terrorists in the Bataclan are not
who attacked the terraces.
Does that mean they're on the run?
Since we don't know how much
terrorists are on the run and...
others are still taking action
like Coulibaly did in January...
I suggest putting the city in lockdown
place until everything is safe again.
We mustn't panic.
This is not panic.
- A state of emergency is declared.
The first information is
just arrived.
A preliminary assessment of the
fire department in the 11th arrondissement.
There would certainly be 60 to 80
victims are in the Bataclan.
The number of victims is increasing. I know
not sure if it has anything to do with Athens.
Yes, I don't know.
I'll contact you but I'm coming
not go home while they are on the run.
Give the kids a kiss from me.
I have another phone.
At least, as you know
100 killed in Paris.
It's a massacre.
Doctors take care of the victims and
the fire brigade evacuates.
Our local colleagues secure the city.
We are prepared.
If it's too stressful emotionally,
can you get outside.
Who is one of the victims
thinks you know...
better go home or go
help on site.
There's no room for this
personal emotions, okay?
Marco's team is investigating under my direction
in coordination with Stéphanie's team...
that evaluates the process.
Sarah leads the security where
the research team asks for.
Julien and Mélanie lead the cyber team that
infiltrates and controls the networks.
Track all sympathizers
messages to IS on, okay?
The Margaux team takes care of it
for the victims.
Identification and hospital admissions.
In Paris, two or three
terrorists on the run.
It's 01:17. They disappeared
around 22:00 from the radar.
So they have an edge
of more than three hours.
We're investigating possible whereabouts
and shut down Paris and the suburbs.
All informants, undercover agents
and agents must work together.
Anyone who in the past 24
hours is caught, is arrested.
Everyone has to concentrate
on his job.
Like any other day. Okay?
Thank you.
We have the attackers' car
of the terraces in the picture.
A black seat.
That is him.
Here he drives up the Rue de Charonne and
he turns onto the Boulevard Voltaire.
One of them gets out.
So there are only two of them.
- Yes.
OK, and then?
- The car continues to move.
Here he is at Place de la Nation.
Guard. What?
OK, are you sure?
- This is where we lose them.
Next time we'll see them here
on the Rue d'Avron.
After the Rue d'Avron we are on their trail
completely lost.
Check all suburbs to the east.
Vincennes, Saint-Mande,
Montreuil and Bagnolet.
Boss, the forensic team has an ID
found in the car in front of the Bataclan.
Salah Abdeslam.
- A Frenchman?
No, a Belgian. Van Molenbeek.
A friend of Abaaoud.
The rest of the news is even worse.
He fled to Belgium with two others.
Salah Abdeslam, 26, born
in Brussels is on the run.
He rented the cars
the attacks were used.
The first was left behind
for the Bataclan.
The second, a black Seat, was used
to attack the bars with kalashnikovs.
The occupants are still on the run.
Salah Abdeslam became two this morning
men seen at the border with Belgium.
There is no evidence that Abdeslam
was in Syria.
According to the Belgian authorities
is he a childhood friend of Abaaoud.
He could have run the operation from
Belgium or Paris.
But under the supervision of Abaaoud.
Is Abaaoud really in Syria?
- That's almost certain.
From Athens he traveled via Bulgaria
to Raqqa.
We've had no trace since then.
The president speaks at 8:00 PM.
What does SDAT do?
All are working and
follow several directions.
So far there are 214
searches carried out.
There were 37 arrests.
Good. And the domestic
intelligence service?
We are interested in Omar
Alaoui. A drug dealer and...
classified as dangerous.
Radicalized in prison.
That is him.
Three new SIM cards in two weeks.
It has been since early October
three times in Belgium.
He has since escaped our surveillance.
I sent you Alaoui's file.
- I received it.
The DGSI sends its SIM number.
- Good.
Have him keep an eye on it.
- Right away.
Here, from the DGSI.
- What do you have on Omar Alaoui?
He could be involved
are with the terrorists.
We are looking for a black Seat.
An important watch request.
- Will be taken care of.
Djibril and Foued, you love
Watching Omar Alaoui.
Rue du Faubourg 35, Saint Denis.
Come on, grandma.
Come on, my little one.
There it is.
09:30. Alaoui gets out of a black Smart.
License plate Bravo, Mike, 547, India, Echo.
That is it. Well done, my friend.
I need the CCTV footage.
- Look at this.
Still no trace of the Seat?
- No.
Is he still in custody?
Okay, thank you.
It's so bad dude. Our brothers
go straight to paradise.
I had celebrated that here on the street.
Mashallah, but not on the phone.
Are you home tonight?
Yes, what can I do for you?
It's about the package I got you
gave three days ago.
But we are not discussing this
on the phone. It's too inconvenient.
Can I come over?
- Whenever you want, brother.
When?
- Like last time.
Then I'll see you later.
I overheard Benkhadra.
Tonight he meets a certain Mokrani.
Do we know Mokrani?
- Doesn't tell me anything.
Me neither.
Here's the SDAT. We need something
check on the Benkhadra case.
I'm looking for a certain Mokrani.
Benkhadra is known but
we have nothing on Mokrani.
Benkhadra is a criminal.
- Mokrani interests me more.
Why?
- Nobody knows him.
That is interesting.
According to the cyber team, he's staying
aloof in Salafist circles.
Great, I'll let him in
keep an eye out. Thank you, Ines.
Thank you.
BRUSSELS
Police.
No movement.
Let go, asshole. Damn.
Stand still.
No movement. To the ground.
On the floor, damn it. Lie.
Abdeslam calls you and you go him
drop off 600 kilometers further at night.
And you think that's all normal?
I did not say that.
Salah is like a brother to me.
If he calls, I will always help him.
But you don't know where he is?
- No, for the tenth time.
I just had him at the train station
have to turn off.
That's enough. Didn't he tell you anything?
- Eventually, yes.
That he was involved in the attacks.
That this was just the beginning and
that it will continue to boom in Paris.
And that he has a bomb belt.
We thought he was lying.
- Did he say anything specific?
No, that's all he said.
What did he say?
- That he would blow everything up.
Okay, you know what we're going to do?
You remain in custody.
I have done nothing.
- In case of terror, even six days.
Danger of second attack.
I cooperated anyway.
- We're accusing you.
I have done nothing.
Wait, he stops. Wait a second.
He gets out.
Djibril, don't go right there.
He goes in.
He is inside. Djibril, go after him.
Can I help you?
- A package for Mr. Alaoui.
End of the corridor on the ground floor.
- Thank you.
Shift change in 30 minutes.
Start the transfer
to the new teams.
Any news about Mokrani?
- Surveillance starts tomorrow morning.
That is too late.
Benkhadra meets him today.
You already have so many pending cases.
We'll do it as soon as possible.
Yes, hello?
Okay, are you with the district attorney?
In the car were three Kalashnikovs,
six magazines, shells and magazines.
The fingerprints and DNA tests
are in progress.
The numbers are not archived.
The forensic team is checking them out.
Did anyone see you get out?
- No, we'll keep interrogating him.
Is that the Croix de Chavaux station?
- Yes.
Check the security cameras.
- It's up to us now.
Keep me informed.
- Yes.
Fred, Alaoui was tracked to Vitry.
I've asked the RAID to assist
at the arrest.
Police. Omar Aloui.
Omar Aloui. To the ground.
No movement.
Stand still.
- Police. No movement.
Stop, stand still.
Hands up. To the ground.
13 kilos of cocaine?
- Yes, that's why Alaoui went into hiding.
Has he nothing to do with the commandos?
- No.
Isn't the DGSI allowed to know that?
- What can I say?
Is there new about the Seat
in Montreuil and Abdeslam?
Nothing so far.
Yes?
We have strategically placed moles
in bars, mosques and prisons.
How are you?
- Boss?
The Railway Police has the
video of the subway station.
You see two suspects.
We'll have him in 30 minutes.
That's too long. Mark.
Tell the railway police we
need it within 15 minutes.
We've already said it here.
We are at war.
You also talk about war?
- We knew the danger.
Now it happened. Only one
few months after 'Charlie Hebdo'.
The government measures are not
enough to protect us.
It has been rumored for months
a number of attacks were thwarted.
If we are to believe the press,
they were poorly organized.
The security authorities have
not protect us from that.
Damn.
23:04. Benkhadra arrives at the
alleged residence of Tarek Mokrani.
You saw two armed men.
Is that correct?
- Yes.
One also said something, but
I don't remember what.
I know it's hard
but try to remember.
He turned to the other and said something.
You were dressed normally.
- He laughed.
He turned and laughed.
- Young.
I looked one of them in the eye.
It was as if he saw nothing.
He didn't look at anything.
The people they wanted to kill,
meant nothing to them.
Do you remember details of the clothes?
He was wearing a navy blue hoodie.
- Well done.
The same color as your jacket.
How old were they?
Was he one of the attackers?
No.
The only one I've seen
wanted to shoot me.
His gun jammed.
So he tried again.
It still didn't work.
I don't know why I'm still alive.
It's fine this way.
I was hiding behind a table and
only saw feet.
One of them wore orange sneakers.
Orange?
- Yes, a bright orange.
And then... just silence.
Yes, that's interesting.
I know honey but you would
also say something nice.
I would like that.
SDAT16 passes the presumptive
home of Tarek Mokrani.
It's 12:45. We draw up a protocol.
Exactly, Enghien-les-Bains, three days.
Just you and me.
The windows are fitted with curtains.
No suspicious movement inside.
Foued, something is moving. Get out of there.
- Exactly, three days.
We also see the movement.
One person, North African male,
beard and about 25 years old.
I confirm that.
- I can't hear you anymore.
Turn the camera back on. You are so Beautiful.
Ask for the Belgian number plate
after at EUCARIS.
Yes, I'm taking Diego home
and get to work.
Delattre.
Hey, wait. Delattre.
A group of loyal soldiers
of the caliphate...
has the capital of Europe where the flag
depends on the monstrous perversion...
called crusades, attacked.
Namely Paris.
May Allah grant power and victory.
Eight brothers have selected
locations in the French capital...
capital attacked with
bomb belts and assault rifles.
The Stade de France. The Bataclan, true
hundreds of renegades held a feast.
And other destinations in it
10th, 11th and 18th arrondissements.
At least the attacks came
200 crusaders killed.
France and supporters must know
that they remain the main target of IS.
This attack was just the beginning
of the storm and a warning.
ISIS is responsible for this
claimed before the attacks.
Do you know why I let you know that?
So you could hear the voice of your friends
hear again.
The prosecution will have enough evidence
that the weapons come from you.
You're going to stay here for years.
Not a few months.
I've been here for two months and
I do not understand...
I just want you to understand
who am I talking about.
I have no weapons on
those jerks delivered.
The serial numbers on the guns
of the terrorists agree...
with the weapons that were yours.
Your weapons were found in the
car of the gunman in Montreuil.
If you want this to remain unofficial,
do you have to give me more.
Otherwise, I'll write down everything you say.
So say it.
I'm sorry I have nothing to say.
I also have principles.
You have principles.
That includes arms deliveries
to Islamists?
Is that why you have that beautiful cross on your arm?
130 dead, do you realize that?
Mothers, fathers, young people.
Kids woke up yesterday
to hear...
that they would never see their parents again.
Do you have children?
Do you have children or not?
- Mind your own business.
Where are they?
With your ex? With your mother?
I can hand her over tomorrow
to the assistance.
I'll tell her where you are
was involved.
I didn't know who I was selling to.
- What?
A year ago...
- I do not hear you.
I was commissioned a year ago
to take weapons to a container.
They just said where the key was.
- Okay.
Let's pretend you like us
volunteered.
That will be the prosecutor
like to hear. Your contact?
I was told that
his name was Abu Omar.
Abu Omar. Is that him?
- No, I don't know him.
OK, what else?
What do I have to gain?
My patience but not for much longer.
Spread the word.
Two or three weeks later
I another assignment.
In the greater Paris area.
I don't know if it's related.
Everything is connected. What was his name?
- He didn't say that.
I met him at the fair.
- And?
I knew him from Fresnes Prison.
His name is Khalid Ben Ahmet.
I sold him the guns
because he's an unimportant fagot.
Those 130 deaths were not my weapons
only 50 years of worthless politics.
Is that all?
- No.
On Friday, the army consumed napalm
all suburbs must throw.
But you don't have the balls.
- That must be it.
Look closely at my crotch.
It stays where it is.
How come this
Ben Ahmet could go into hiding?
That's our fault. We loved him
in sight but lost him.
I know this is difficult.
- And not even a little bit.
We don't have enough agents
for the hundreds of threats.
But still enough for someone who
has an arsenal of weapons, right?
Let's not let the authorities
questioning.
Finding the fugitives
is now more important.
Why don't we know yet?
It's been three days.
Three days, damn it.
- My people have been awake since Friday.
We do too. What's your point?
Maybe you don't understand which one
responsibility we have.
Excuse me?
- We have to keep the citizens safe.
The minister expects results.
Find that Ben Ahmet.
Check all of Ben Ahmet's recordings
of the past six months.
Khalid, this is Mouss.
Where are you? I can never reach you.
Where is the detention file?
He was on the tape.
Call me back. I have a contact person
for instruments and guitars.
Hello, Khalid?
Radicalized in Turkey in 2013.
- We're looking for Khalid Ben Ahmet.
I need the report in ten minutes.
- The DGSI lost him.
And on the internet?
- Nothing.
Nothing but the confession of IS.
Brethren, who has a car for me?
Guard. Three weeks ago
he bought a Mercedes.
Brilliant. I am coming.
- Okay.
State the model and
the license plate of the car.
Send out a witness call
with his description.
And the car?
- The emergency services have the license plate.
The helpline?
- We're drowning in information.
Yesterday alone we had
more than 500 calls.
Police.
Tarek Mokrani, you are
arrested at 1:45 p.m.
For participating in a criminal
organization with a terrorist motive.
Do you want a doctor or a lawyer?
- I want to speak to your boss.
Well, as you know...
- Can we talk now?
I want to see Martin Bérieux.
Hello? I work for you.
Three years of undercover operations
ruined in one day.
I'm sorry.
- Oh yeah?
Explain that to your people
so they don't mess it up too.
Not in this tone.
- Make sure your service is back in order.
Take it easy.
If I go to 20 people for you
send a coke dealer, I'll pull your...
secret service, no doubt.
What do you want to say?
- Do you want to hear more?
What do your undercover agents have
already discovered?
I knew nothing about the DGSI.
That's not the problem.
But the problem is that DGSI didn't clear
that we had found Mokrani.
There was no collaboration with
the surveillance and investigation team.
And of course no log.
I want to know where you
got the address from.
From an internal source.
- The truth, please.
I followed him.
- Who followed you?
Benkhadra.
I knew he was going to meet Mokrani
and followed him.
It was urgent. I knew
not that he worked for DGSI.
Please wait. You think
the problem lies with the DGSI?
No, it's about efficiency
of this device.
You ignored all rules and procedures.
Imagine arresting Abdeslam.
His lawyer would have heard
that there was no legal basis whatsoever.
Do you know what would have happened then?
Then he would walk free again.
Is it clear now?
- I felt it my duty.
Yes, but this is not Roubaix CID.
No more unauthorized research.
Is that understood?
What you considered your duty,
was the worst case scenario.
Same as we those men
would help escape.
I'm sorry.
- Justifiably.
This was the first and last time.
You can go. I want in two hours
an update on the calls.
Shit, damn it.
Everything fine?
How many testimonials
do we need to process?
It was already 1250 calls
since this morning.
Okay.
Good day, anti-terrorist unit.
- Good day.
How can I help you?
With more information about Khalid Ben Ahmet.
We know that Ben Ahmet this mosque
has visited.
Several sources point out
his involvement in the attacks.
Can you tell me something about him?
I wish I knew more.
Khalid was a good boy.
It closed down a few months ago
to brothers who had lost their way.
If I knew where he is
i would tell you.
But he hasn't been seen for weeks.
Help him, please.
Yes?
I wanted to call you back.
We have Abaaoud for sure.
The Ministry sent Mirages.
The French army conducted yesterday
airstrikes on Raqqa.
The IS stronghold in Syria.
Ten fighter-bombers dropped
20 bombs fall on...
weapons depots, training camps
and command posts.
It was the largest operation
for France since the…
September 27 attacks began.
The target was Abdelhamid Abaaoud. He would
behind Friday's attacks.
The jihadist made a name for himself in January then
his arrest in Athens failed.
If his death is confirmed,
Would that be a hard blow to ISIS?
The influence of Abaaoud at
the French jihadists was growing.
There was a possibility...
I did athletics.
The high jump came first...
followed by the long jump.
I'll call you back, honey.
Yes?
- The Ben Ahmet file.
Thank you.
It was Friday at 10:00 PM
flashed in Montargis.
He was not in Paris during
the attacks.
But he was looking on the 14th
to a shelter.
And since yesterday 23:00 his mobile has been switched off.
Good thank you.
I may have something.
A woman from Saint-Denis says
to see the terrorists.
Under the A86 at Aubervilliers.
Dressed like bums.
She talks about Abaaoud and Abdeslam.
And she's talking about neon orange sneakers.
So?
That's what a witness at the hospital said.
That did not leak to the press.
She says she is a cousin of Abaaoud
catches. One Hasna Aït Boulahcen.
Is that the explanation?
- Yes.
That's unlikely, right?
It's weird for the sake of it
those neon orange sneakers.
Let's Hasna Aït Boulahcen and the
check the witness's environment.
Hello?
- Am I talking to Samia Khelouf?
Yes.
- Inès Moreaux of the anti-terror unit.
You contacted us today.
Why are you only calling back now?
- There were more calls.
I know where the terrorists
hide.
Can you repeat that?
Madam?
I know where the two terrorists are.
Marco, can I talk to you for a minute?
Samia, 30 years old, resident
of Saint-Denis, unknown to us.
She harbors a cousin of Abaaoud
which is not in the files.
Samia says that the terrorists are located
hide under the A86 at Aubervilliers.
One is wearing jeans
and looks like a Roma.
The other has a beard and wears
a bomber jacket and orange sneakers.
The problem is that they are Abaaoud
and Abdeslam identified.
Abdeslam is in Belgium and Abaaoud
died in the air raids.
I know that.
- Doesn't she just want some attention?
Only three witnesses knew
of the orange sneakers.
She needs to be heard.
- Good, okay.
Let them arrange a meeting.
This is BAC26. We follow a wanted black
Mercedes from a distance.
Number plate Bravo,
Charlie, 254, India, Uniform.
One person in the vehicle.
We are waiting for instructions.
After the shock is in France
held a minute's silence.
Commemoration in the cities
civilians the 130 victims...
Come here. Stand still.
Staying here.
- Police.
aside.
- Stand still.
Stop. Police.
Get lost. Get out of the car.
To get off.
- Let go of me.
Hands up.
- It is well.
Give me your hands.
Khalid ben Ahmet?
Is the name correct?
Or shall we call you Abu and something else?
Jackie Delattre, does that mean anything to you?
Does that mean nothing to you?
That is him.
They were in prison together.
They bought guns from him.
Where were you on the evening of November 13?
It struck like lightning.
Are you afraid?
I can see that you are scared.
Our brothers will you
kill all.
What do you know about the
attackers from the terraces?
All I can say
is that the hand that hits you...
not just a hand.
It is the hand of Allah
and his prophet Muhammad.
Allah bless him and give him peace.
And it's not over yet.
She will keep hitting.
The brothers who are still free will you,
kill your women and children.
Fred.
- Let him go.
It is well. Everything fine.
Stop that right now.
What's wrong with you?
Get yourself together.
Go home when you feel yourself
cannot control.
Get yourself together and think.
I need you.
And let that asshole talk.
Samia Khelouf?
Ines Moreaux. We spoke
on the phone yesterday.
Come with me.
Can I look in your bag?
Turn around. Arms aside.
Can you turn back?
I'm sorry, those are the rules.
We go straight ahead.
This way.
Your name is Samia Khelouf, born
on August 16, 1983 in Epinay-sur-Seine.
You are a French citizen and resident
at 45 Rue Paul Éluard in Saint-Denis.
Hasna Aït Boulahcen is already staying
with you for two months.
We listen.
Okay, it was around 9:30 or 10:00 PM.
We drove to the A86 interchange
at Aubervilliers.
Hasna called.
I don't know with whom
it was someone in Belgium.
How do you know it was someone in Belgium?
I saw the number.
She wanted to quit for her 14-year-old
nephew to bring.
He doesn't have an apartment
and lives on the street.
We were at the entrance to the camp.
He saw us right away.
He was wearing a black hoodie
and orange sneakers.
I couldn't resist asking
whether he had committed those attacks.
He looked me straight in the eye and said yes.
He attacked the terraces.
He said they have a police station or one
nursery in La Défense wanted to attack.
He told Hasna that she needed him
help to find an apartment.
Then we went back to the car.
She immediately started calling people to
to find him a place to sleep.
And then we drove home.
That's all.
What was in his car?
- Just his fingerprints.
No traces of explosives?
- Nothing.
We have the photos from his cell phone.
- Let me have a look.
Go back. Over there.
Further. That there.
Enlarge the building.
Even bigger.
We found out about you.
It's about a journey
five years ago.
Just fuck yourself, okay?
- Yes.
Fuck you.
Is that you in the picture?
Look ahead.
You see? The place was hard to
find but we suspect Isfahan.
I have the right to a private life.
Yes, that's very important.
Do we need your IS friends
tell me you were with the Iranians?
I was there with a friend.
I have the right to do that.
A Shiite? That is not good.
Gosh, bitch.
- Listen, asshole.
Tell me who did it and me
don't put it on facebook...
that you are dating a Shia woman.
For the wire with it. Forward.
Good, it's coming off.
I don't know those guys.
You bought weapons.
For my cell. I was not
in Paris on the 13th.
When I heard about the attacks,
I wanted to hide the weapons.
Where?
- In a forest in the countryside.
Where exactly?
- I don't remember exactly.
You talk shit.
It's true.
- Tell me the truth.
In the life of the Prophet Muhammad,
it's the truth.
Allah is my witness.
Through the life of the Prophet.
We're going to succeed.
it was him.
- Are you sure?
Yes, he lost weight and his face
came in but it's him.
Abaaoud?
- Yes, 100 percent sure.
I saw him under the A86.
Let's go back again.
Tell us why you went there.
What does it matter?
- What?
Abaaoud's cousin is staying
with you and three days...
after the attacks
you take her to her cousin?
Don't you find that strange?
- She said her cousin was 14.
Hasna is virtually homeless.
I didn't know she was lying and that
I would meet this psychopath.
I saw his eyes in the rearview mirror
when he said he shot people.
In the rearview mirror?
They were outside.
No, we were in it first
camp and then in my car.
In your car?
- What was he doing there?
Don't know. Maybe he was cold.
- Cold?
Do you think I'm lying?
Let's take it easy.
It's still unclear.
They met him outside and then went
three or four of them to the car.
Yes.
- Three or four?
Why four?
- The second terrorist.
He stayed with the junkies.
But you said it was Salah Abdeslam.
He has not left the camp.
- Eventually Yes.
Outside I caught a glimpse of him.
From the car?
- Outside.
Are you sure?
- I was in the car... No.
Wait, I was in the car
- In the car?
I was in the car and they were outside.
Then I saw her when Hasna...
Exactly, Hasna got out with her cousin.
They went to the camp and
the three of them talked.
But I didn't see her well.
They stood in the dark.
I didn't have time to look closely.
- Shame.
Do you think I like this?
I don't know what you want.
Take it easy one more time, okay?
The man you identified as
Abdelhamid Abaaoud asked Hasna...
to find shelter, right?
Yes, she agreed and he said he
would later give her the money.
And did she find an apartment?
- I think so.
How does she find one so quickly
if she has no shelter of her own?
She called people.
- Which people?
She asked people in her family.
Which of her family?
Stop me like a criminal
to treat.
I have nothing to do with it.
- That is not certain yet.
Is this a joke?
- It is important that you are accurate.
We try to understand why one
IS leader as Abaaoud sleeps under the bridge.
And why he to no one else
then asks his cousin and friend for help.
Don't know.
- You don't know much.
I'm talking to Fred.
Take a discreet look around with your team
under the A86.
Inès, just check discreetly.
No more than that, okay?
16:01 At the point mentioned by the witness
building in the Rue des Bergeries.
Nothing to report.
Boss.
I hope it tastes well.
- Thank you.
Look at the license plate.
20:16 Enter a Belgian car
near Rue des Bergeries.
License plate: 9, Oscar,
Uniform, Yankee, 462.
We're going back to Levallois.
It's the ideal hideaway.
Isolated and dark.
A mix of homeless people, migrants and junkies.
A Belgian car came towards us.
The license plate has not yielded anything yet.
Marc, what do you think?
It's unlikely.
Samia had correct info but I can
cannot rule out the possibility that it is a trap.
It could be a false trail that
leads us away from the shooters.
We're exhausted, Fred.
We're at the end.
If she wants to deceive us,
we drive straight into a wall.
Ines, your verdict?
I believe her.
- Why?
I know many women like
Samia in the suburbs.
They often avoid problems.
But she risked a lot.
I think she's telling the truth.
Abaaoud is presumed dead.
His cousin has been living with her for weeks.
She says she spoke to him.
She mentions orange sneakers.
Abaaoud would plan further attacks.
What do we know about the witness?
- Nothing.
Nothing about her connection to
the Abaaoud family or the cousin.
Her file is thin.
- What do you think about it?
Don't ignore her statement.
But it's dangerous.
- We have no choice.
Let's intervene, Fred.
- Okay.
I'll inform the investigation team.
I'm contacting the people in Morocco
who keep an eye on Abaaoud's uncle.
Okay.
She's on her way.
Djibril, she's coming to you.
Foued, she's coming.
I'm watching her.
Hello.
- My colleagues are listening.
Is that your computer?
- No, this is mine.
Do you never use it?
- No.
Can I see your room?
- Yes of course.
Here it is. Don't mind the mess.
Don't touch anything. You do not want
that she knows we were here.
Why don't you arrest them under
the highway? We're wasting time.
That will happen.
- Good thank you.
Go downstairs. I'll do the rest.
It concerns a transfer from Belgium.
Yes, Heloise? I'm flying to Morocco.
Abaaoud's uncle was arrested.
He only talks to a representative
of the anti-terror unit.
I'll keep you informed. Bye.
Sophia, help me. It's crowded here.
- Go...
It is up to you. You take over.
Excuse me. Where is she?
Djib, do you see them?
- No.
It is well. I have her back.
No, she's not. Damn.
Cadre, Rudy, we lost her.
Maybe she will show up at your place.
Ines, come down.
Hasna is gone.
Understood. She is gone.
- What?
You lost Hasna?
Let's clean up quickly.
Do you need help?
- No, it works.
I'll put this away.
- Yes please.
Ines, do you hear me? Ines?
Everyone, we've been spotted. Quit the mission.
Damn.
Shit.
Ines, Hasna is here.
Come down now.
Ines, do you hear me?
Ines.
- That's not possible yet.
What are you going to do? What is he doing?
Framework goes to the building.
- No, let him come back.
He's not wearing his headphones.
Sorry, sister. One moment, please.
My friend Aziz Markoum lives
somewhere around here. Do you know him?
No.
- Hold on, please.
I have to pick up something for UNI.
Where was that?
- Inès, Kader stops Hasna.
Come down. Come on.
- I will.
We have to clean up.
- Go away you.
What do not you understand? Get lost.
- Give me a minute.
Fuck off. Keep hands to yourself.
- I know that. Excuse me.
Is that good?
- Yes, go now.
Come on, damn it.
Do not touch me.
- Sorry.
I don't have time for this.
- Calm down.
I don't know that man.
Okay Sarah, she's coming out.
Frame too.
- Guys...
Please, Commissioner.
- Thank you.
Good day, I am a commissioner
in the anti-terror unit of France.
Inès, the uncle confirms that Abaaoud
was in Belgium two weeks ago.
You called. We checked.
So it's under the A86.
We have Hasna's address
shelter needed.
Get in touch with Samia.
I am counting on you.
- Okay.
People gathered all over the world
to commemorate the victims.
Trafalgar Square in London sparkles
in the national colors of France.
If we intervene under the highway,
can they escape.
We don't know how many there are or if
they have reinforcements and weapons.
We'd have someone in camp
should get, but they should...
can be quickly exposed
and innocent people would die.
We cannot intervene and
we need the address.
I don't have the address.
Why don't you arrest Hasna?
If we arrest her,
we lose our advantage.
I know it's hard.
But you have to help us
and find out the address.
That's your job. I have here
not my business.
I know that.
- So?
We need you.
There is no other way.
Damn.
- You are very brave.
I know you can do this.
Finish it.
And Hasna? What are you doing with her?
We're not after her.
After that we will help you with everything
What you need.
We'll be there for you.
You going to help me?
- I promise.
Your name is nowhere to be found.
Give us the address and we will intervene.
After that it's a thing of the past for you.
Don't worry.
I swear to you, okay?
I swear. Believe me.
We are almost there.
- Damn.
I will try.
Nothing is certain, but I try
to find out the address.
Okay.
What is?
Nothing.
Is it because of me?
Samia?
We have reason to believe
that another attack is imminent.
Hasna Aït Boulahcen got a transfer
through Western Union.
A terrorist has received money
from Belgium.
According to the witness, he has
case one bomb belt with him.
He wants a police station or
attacking a nursery in La Défense.
I'll inform the president.
I drive her around 9pm or 10pm
to the apartment.
I have the money and I'll take a taxi.
Can't you go there alone?
He is my cousin.
- And then?
Why do you have to go there?
Why are you involved?
I do not understand that.
Give me the address and I'll pick you up.
You are annoying. Stop.
- At midnight.
What is that? Do you want to betray me?
- What are you talking about?
You live with me. Do not forget that.
I share everything with you.
You meet the most dangerous guys
from France.
I want to help you and I trust you
and you doubt me?
Then go away if you doubt me.
Now don't cry.
I'm dying.
- No, you're not going to die.
You will have a nice life.
What do not you understand?
I will never have a nice life.
Don't you get that?
Stop that.
- It's useless.
Please stop. Believe me.
Stop. Relax.
I will save my cousin.
He will do whatever it takes.
He becomes a shahid.
And I'm going to paradise.
Hasna, stop that. Stop.
Believe me. Only me.
Forgive me, my sister.
Forgive me please.
Hasna, stop that, please.
Stop.
You must not destroy your life.
If I want you to pick me up,
i will send you a message.
I'm sending you a message.
Mouss found the hideout.
Rue du Corbillon 8 in Saint Denis.
To everyone. Drive to 8 Rue du Corbillon
in Saint-Denis to explore.
SDAT95 continues to track Hasna.
Got it, let's go.
Everything is prepared.
This is the terrain. Snipers here.
Surveillance teams here, here and here.
And here mobile task forces.
- Okay.
A vehicle is approaching.
A BMW.
- He's going around the roundabout.
I don't know what he's doing.
Maybe there's a deal going on there.
They talk. I do not know
what's going on.
Can you identify someone?
- Negative.
He starts. He drives off.
Yes, he's leaving again.
SDAT52, a taxi is approaching.
License plate: Alpha, Delta, 219,
Delta, Oscar.
Cab.
We found her cell phone.
She's in the taxi.
He goes around the roundabout.
Looks like he has to wait.
He stopped.
I do not see anything. There are too many people.
I see two men in fur coats.
Bomb belt possible.
Shots possible.
- Access not authorized.
He's going to drive.
The taxi leaves.
Keep us informed.
Launch the drone.
To all units. The vehicle is located
located 700 meters from the destination.
We'll let her go in
in the apartment.
Heloise?
- Yes?
They're here.
The suspected terrorists are in it
apartment with Hasna Aït Boulahcen.
The task force is ready.
Good.
The president authorized the raid.
Laser 1 for Laser 2 and 3.
We need the element of surprise.
We don't know what's in the apartment
and whether the terrorists have explosives.
We are almost there.
To everyone. Shut off the street.
Locking ended.
Laser 2, go ahead.
Laser 3, in.
Police.
- The door didn't open.
Bring it on. Just come in.
In the name of Allah. Die with us.
The surprise effect is gone
We keep them at bay.
Explosion risk is too high.
We keep them at bay with continuous fire.
Stop! Let me out
come, please.
I beg you.
Let me come out.
- Hands up.
I have done nothing.
- Palms open, fingers spread.
Let me come out, please.
I beg you.
- Where's your friend?
He's not my friend.
- Where is he?
Let me out.
- Show yourself.
Don't mention it.
Laser 5 for Laser 1. We're in
the apartment. Location secured.
There's nothing here. Everything is destroyed.
No visual contact with suspects.
Everything is in ruins.
Send Explosive Ordnance Disposal.
End of the storming.
I repeat and confirm:
Okay.
It is over.
I'm sorry.
- Get me out of here.
Get me out of here now.
I want to get out of here. Do you understand?
You lied to me.
Am I the criminal here?
No.
- I help you and you lock me up?
Don't you want to say anything?
- I'll talk to you, I promise.
Stop your promises.
You don't even follow them.
Damn.
Where is Hasna? Where is she?
Where is Hasna?
Is she safe?
She is dead.
I'm sorry.
- No...
Before she could get out
he blew himself up.
Her cousin killed her.
Are you sorry? Damn.
I'm sorry Samia.
I'm sorry.
What will become of me now?
What will become of me?
I can't tell you now.
Don't know.
I don't know, but we'll...
I do not know anything. I did not think
that you would be arrested.
Don't know.
It's true they're not here
should be.
I gave her my word.
- I know that.
But that's the law.
We will arrange this. Your case is unique.
Star witnesses get a new identity
but there is nothing for ordinary people.
That's disgusting.
I understand how you feel.
Nobody likes to break their word.
- Yes.
It's disgusting.
- This is just unreal.
I promised her help.
You promised.
I gave her no choice.
I told her I'll be there later
would be for her.
We used her.
She helped us.
You can't just blame the law.
Tell yourself you're doing well
have done.
Ines, you should be proud of yourself.
No.
We have one in five days
unbelievable storm.
We paid a horrible
high price.
We will be the victims of
never forget this Friday.
November 13 has a favour
and one after.
Anyone who has the past few days
experienced, will be better prepared.
The battle we are fighting is
inexorable and unfair.
As for our fellow citizens,
the investigation is closed.
It's only just beginning for us.
In the attacks of November 13, 2015
131 were killed and 494 injured.
The investigation took five years.
Thousands of interrogations were conducted.
The studies were in
4 continents and 25 countries.
Salah Abdeslam was born on March 18, 2016
arrested in Belgium.
In France, 37 people were arrested.
In Belgium 27 and in Austria 5.
Samia Khelhouf's case caused concern
for amendment of the law.
From now on, the law will protect citizens
who helped fight terrorism.
It's good to know the character
by Samia Khelouf is fictional.
Her character does not represent
the entire Islamic community.
After a process that lasted 9 months
20 suspects were convicted...
to punishments ranging between
2 years and life.
Salah Abdeslam was sentenced to life without
the possibility of ever being released.
Subs: Dominika Berger
Translation: u335555