♪ ♪
(bell tolling)
♪ As the sun goes down ♪
♪ And the shadows grow long ♪
♪ Trying to find a gal
I can call my own ♪
♪ Gettin' back on the road,
not a moment too soon... ♪
Aunt Marta's gonna be
at the house 7:00 sharp,
so you best be ready.
You can't be late for school
and she can't be late for work.
No, you cannot walk home
with that boy.
We've had this conversation.
He's bad news.
No.
I have enough things
in my life to worry about
without having to worry about...
(screaming)
♪ Boom, boom, boom, boom ♪
♪ Bang, bang, bang, bang ♪
♪ How, how, how, how ♪
♪ Hey, hey ♪
♪ You gotta come on. ♪
SEBASTIAN:
Okay, easy now.
(wind chime tinkling)
Anytime you, uh,
you want to take a break,
CJ, you know, just...
just let me know, okay?
No, I'm good.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm an NCIS agent now.
This is, you know...
(straining):
this is a piece of cake.
Let's set it down.
Yeah, that's a great idea.
Just out of curiosity...
Huh?
how'd you make it
through basic training again?
That's...
Got through from
studying and effort,
both of which you could
use a little more of.
I'm just trying to help, Mom.
Only 'cause you want
Danny's room now that he's gone.
Back to studying,
Math test tomorrow.
Go.
See you, newbie.
I can't believe how fast
he's growing up, you know?
all my boys are growing up.
Danny joining the Navy,
you at NCIS...
Oh, thanks, Doc, you know
I feel the same about you.
You're like the mother
that I never had.
You have a mother, Sebastian.
I've met her.
Exactly.
So, what, this gonna be
the Wade cave now?
Hmm? 60-inch plasma maybe?
Poker table,
a couple lava lamps?
I was thinking art studio,
actually.
I used to paint all the time
before I got married.
Wait, wait, hold on.
I never knew
you were married.
Yes, I was.
A long time ago, different life.
Have a look for yourself.
Is this him?
WADE:
Reginald.
Easy on the eye, isn't he?
Yeah, look how beautiful
you were.
That's... um, not that
you're not beautiful now.
Obviously, you're... you're
very beautiful, it's just...
you know, when you...
It's all right, Sebastian.
Reginald was a good man
when we first met.
We had some good years
together...
until we didn't.
What happened?
Let's just say he changed...
not for the better.
(cell phone beeps)
WADE:
Duty calls.
Looks like I've got a body.
Yeah, NCIS.
It's probably the same body.
You want to share a ride?
Only if you don't ask
any more questions.
(siren wailing,
helicopter blades whirring)
LASALLE: These guys'll
take care of you.
You'll be all right.
She the first on scene?
Streetcar driver, just
showing up for work.
Not the best way
to start a day.
About as grisly as it gets.
Any witnesses?
Not according to NOPD,
but hopefully we got something
from these security cameras.
Well, I doubt it.
Killer placed the body
directly behind
these streetcars,
blocking all the cameras.
I doubt the killer was
trying to avoid cameras.
It's too specific
of a location.
Profiler in me seems
to think that whoever it was
was trying
to make a statement.
(cell phone beeps)
Take it you don't want to ask
her out again, am I right?
Blind date, high risk.
I told you,
they're not worth dinner.
Just drinks, and you definitely
don't give your number
until you're sure
you like her.
Is that you profiling,
Gregorio?
That's me dating, amateur.
Mm, I've dated plenty.
I'm not an amateur.
Maybe a couple of hookups,
but not potential
relationships.
It's a whole different deal,
and this whole airbrushed-photo
thing on dating apps...
I mean, the only way to trigger
the yay or nay hormones
is to have good,
old-fashioned eye contact.
I never knew you
as a romantic, Gregorio.
Profiling's not just
for finding criminals.
Comes in handy, trust me.
(camera shutter clicking)
All I know so far is the
victim's Chief Karen Decker,
based out of Belle Chasse.
Still waiting on Loretta,
so we can't take
the body down yet.
Not a lot of blood
on the ground,
considering all the stab wounds,
which means she was killed
somewhere else,
and then moved here.
The question is, why here?
Big risk...
taking the time and effort
to string her up,
not to mention the mutilation.
Talking ritualistic?
Crucifix pose indicates
she was meant to be a sacrifice.
Eyes dug out so she couldn't
see her killer's soul.
PRIDE:
Okay, so, we figure out
what she was sacrificed for,
we might be able to ID
the lunatic who did this to her.
WADE:
My God.
Loretta.
Loretta, you all right?
Please, get her down.
Let's go find a ladder.
Look, Gregorio,
I'll check with Decker's C.O.,
all right?
You take Christopher
and get with Patton,
find out as much about her
as you can as fast as you can.
Copy that.
Tough to look at,
isn't it?
I saw something like this
once before.
I'd hoped never to see it again.
Man, hard to believe anybody
would want to do her harm,
especially that kind of harm.
20-year vet,
unblemished record,
Navy counselor who
helps other sailors.
Yeah, a couple of
months from retiring,
according to her record.
About to start a new life.
Only to have it stolen away
by some monster. Why?
C.O. says Chief Decker got an
urgent call yesterday at noon,
rushed out, never came back.
Check her phone log?
Putting it up
on the screen.
PATTON:
Looks like the only incoming
call she got yesterday.
GREGORIO:
But from the same caller
who called several days before.
Can you trace that joker?
Can't, burner cell.
Powered down, too.
Or, more likely, destroyed.
Well, any chance you can find
out where the call originated?
Read my mind, bossman.
There, pinged
from a cell tower
across from the old
Peters Junior High School.
Now, Peters has been
abandoned since Katrina,
and who would want
to be hanging there?
GREGORIO: Obviously,
somebody who doesn't
want to be found. Shall we?
Keep me posted.
I'm gonna go to the morgue.
See what Loretta knows.
(camera shutters clicking)
Bad news.
Damn it, Sebastian!
Don't sneak upon me like that.
Whoa, whoa,
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Are-Are you okay?
Yeah.
Uh, it's just...
Uh...
You got something?
Um, u-unfortunately, no.
There's nothing from the crime
scene that turned up any clues.
No prints, trace evidence,
DNA, nothing.
Whoever did this obviously
knows what they're doing.
You want me
to keep trying?
NCIS probably doesn't
need me back for awhile.
Glass tray.
What is it?
I mean, clearly,
it's a strand of hair, but...?
WADE: I found it
in the victim's hair.
It's not hers.
Could be the killer's.
And, if I'm right,
I've crossed paths
with him before.
Yo, I'm not bragging, but I got
a pretty good track record
when it comes to matchmaking,
just not for myself, mind you,
that's a whole
different story.
Well, why is that?
You know, it's
just complicated.
(hinges creaking,
door clatters)
Looks like we just
missed somebody.
"Jack Gordon.
Clozapine"
LASALLE:
Clozapine?
Is that for psychosis?
Schizophrenia?
Mm-hmm.
Looks like we've found
where Chief Decker was murdered.
Which means we've found
our monster.
PRIDE:
Good job, Christopher.
Secure the scene,
get a BOLO out.
I'll send Sebastian
to collect evidence.
(phone beeps off)
Loretta, we might have...
Loretta.
Might have a suspect.
Ex-con, just got paroled.
Jack Gordon.
Yeah. How'd you know?
I worked the case
on his first victim
20 years ago.
And, if he did this...
...I could very well be next.
(jazz music playing nearby)
She all right?
Don't know.
Tough lady.
I've never seen her
rattled like this before.
(Pride sighs)
Tell me things.
Jack Gordon,
aka "The Jackknife,"
paroled eight days ago
from Angola after serving
just over 20 years
for murder.
Loretta said he was a streetcar
driver back in the day?
Drove streetcar number 963,
the same streetcar
Chief Decker's body
was strung up behind.
Hard to believe
it's a coincidence.
Yeah, plus the blood
we found at the school
is a dead match to
Decker, which means...
Decker was killed at the school,
then moved to the streetcar.
GREGORIO:
Guy's out of prison
barely a week,
immediately targets Decker,
and kills her the same way
he killed a woman
20 years ago.
LASALLE:
Petty Officer Janet Ortega.
She and Decker were bunkmates
on the U.S.S. Enterprise in '97.
And Ortega and Jack Gordon
were high school
sweethearts back then.
GREGORIO (scoffs):
Some sweetheart.
Never proved motive,
but it's got
crime of passion
written all over it.
Yeah, well, I remember
the Ortega case.
NOPD handled it
when I was a sheriff.
Gordon got his nickname because
the murder weapon was a knife.
Jack Gordon, Jackknife, cute.
But why kill Chief Decker as
soon as he gets out of prison?
And make it so obvious
that he did it?
Well, we need to dig
into the old case,
but if I remember right,
Chief Decker testified
against Gordon at the trial,
claimed he was unstable.
Well, based on the empty bottle
of clozapine we found
at the school,
he's even more unstable now.
Plus, his DNA
matched a strand of hair
Doc found on the victim.
LASALLE:
Well, it's pretty
clear, isn't it?
Gordon gets out of prison,
takes out his revenge on Decker
for testifying against him
20 years ago.
Problem is,
according to Loretta,
she testified against Gordon
20 years ago, too.
I was the M.E.
on Janet Ortega's case.
The slaying was...
brutal, sick.
Gordon claimed he was
innocent, of course,
but the evidence
was overwhelming.
Ortega's body showed signs
of previous assaults.
The knife they found at the
crime scene belonged to Gordon,
and he was so hopped up
on amphetamines,
when they went to arrest him,
he couldn't even remember
where he was
the night of the murder.
GREGORIO:
Amphetamine psychosis
certainly could explain
that level of violence.
WADE:
Nothing explains
what he did
to that poor woman.
I just never understood
why the prosecutor cut a deal.
She should've put
that man away for life.
And now look what happened.
You've got to
find him, Dwayne,
before he hurts anybody else.
We're gonna do everything
we possibly can, Loretta.
Still, if Gordon
did kill Chief Decker,
why did he call her so many
times in the days before?
Taunting her, maybe?
Yeah, but, why would
she accept them?
Why not just hang up and
alert the NOPD instead?
He hasn't tried
calling you, has he?
He wouldn't dare.
GREGORIO:
Nevertheless,
if, in fact, he's
targeting people
who testified against him,
we've got to protect you
until we find him.
I can take care of myself.
PRIDE:
Not this time, you can't.
Until we know
exactly what's going on,
safest place for you is with us.
Which means, CJ...
I spoke with Danny, and CJ's
on base with his brother.
All right, well, good.
In the meantime,
we need to find out
who else testified
against Gordon, warn them.
You should look into the defense
attorney, Devon Mitchell.
I remember Gordon blamed him
for not getting him acquitted.
Let's find Mitchell.
Patton and I will get
up to speed on the old case
as quickly as possible.
Try to get leads
on how to find Gordon.
Go.
LASALLE:
You got it.
We'll find him, Loretta.
Yeah.
I promise.
(streetcar bell clanging)
(bell continues clanging)
(door closing)
Can I help you?
LASALLE: Special Agents
Lasalle and Gregorio.
We need to speak to
Mr. Mitchell, please.
Oh, don't worry, he hasn't
done anything wrong.
But we do need
to speak to him.
Of course. I'll let him know.
Thank you kindly.
Mr. Mitchell...
That's exactly the eye contact
I'm talking about.
Clear connection,
no doubt about it.
I'm not doing this
with you, Gregorio.
The chemistry is
immediately palpable,
you can't fake that;
even I can feel it.
If you don't go
for her, I will.
What?
MITCHELL:
Are you sure?
I mean, I didn't even know
that Jack was out.
He hasn't tried
to contact you, or call you?
No, nothing.
You really think
that he killed Karen Decker,
just because she testified
against him?
That's what
we're trying
to find out, Mr. Mitchell,
but if he did,
you could be in danger, too.
Yeah, we heard Gordon was
particularly upset with you
for not getting him acquitted.
I did everything that I could.
I even took the
case pro bono.
I mean, I knew Jack.
He was the streetcar driver
who took me to work here
every day.
I didn't want him
to get stuck with a PD,
so I offered to defend him.
So you haven't talked
to him since the trial?
I called him in prison
to check up on him,
but all he ever wanted me
to do was get the case reopened.
Because he still believed
he was innocent?
He never stopped believing it.
Didn't change
the facts of the case,
but Jack never really cared
about facts.
(sighs)
Look, if anything,
Jack owes me.
I got the D.A. to agree
to a reduced sentence
based on Jack's mental state.
I mean, I saved his life.
Why would he be after me?
We're not sure he is,
Mr. Mitchell,
but we're gonna get you
protection just in case.
Is there anything you
remember that might help us
find Gordon?
Family or friends?
Well, we're especially concerned
about anybody else
Gordon might be after.
We're putting together
a list, that...
Uh, Todd Borger.
Friend of Jack's,
drove the night shift.
You need to protect him.
The D.A. tripped Borger up
on the stand,
got him to admit that Jack
was violent, jealous.
Between that
and the coroner's testimony,
the jury was ready to convict.
Murder one.
WADE:
There's no doubt,
Jack Gordon
murdered Petty Officer Ortega.
That is my professional
opinion,
and it is my personal opinion.
MITCHELL: Objection, Your Honor.
Dr. Wade is qualified
only for expert testimony.
JUDGE: Sustained.
Please, just answer...
Court footage
of the Ortega case?
Yeah. Circa court 1997.
Just saying, Dr. Wade
looking mighty fine.
And pissed, too.
Yeah. Wasn't an ordinary case.
Horrendous murder.
Lot of emotions.
Yeah, well, the good
Dr. Wade's barely hiding hers.
...oftentimes
is a precursor for murder.
MITCHELL: Objection.
(gavel bangs)
DISTRICT ATTORNEY:
And you think the defendant's
mental illness could've made him
capable of extreme violence?
MITCHELL: Objection,
she's not a psychologist.
JUDGE: I will allow it.
I didn't kill her! I'm innocent!
Forensics don't lie!
I didn't do it!
I didn't do it, and you know
JUDGE:
Mr. Gordon, Mr. Gordon!
I didn't kill her!
The hell you didn't!
GORDON: I didn't do it!
(gavel banging)
You know that's not true!
I didn't do it!
WADE: The hell you didn't!
(gavel banging)
My behavior was inexcusable.
The past has a way of catching
up to you, doesn't it?
(saxophone playing jazz)
♪ ♪
WADE:
I don't know.
There's just something
about this case
that I just personalized.
I was supposed
to state the facts,
(chuckles)
as I knew them.
The science.
Not give my opinion
on innocent or guilt.
Yet Gordon was guilty.
He pled out, he confessed.
But why?
Was he really guilty,
or did I sway the jury with
something other than facts?
Loretta, you've testified in
dozens of cases over the years.
Why are you beating yourself up
over this one?
You know why, Dwayne.
You saw the courtroom footage.
I wasn't myself.
And I've known it
for a long time, too.
I just never wanted to face it.
(saxophone continues playing)
(streetcar bell clanging)
MAN:
Jack and I grew up together.
We went to high school,
joined the transit authority.
Back then, streetcars only used
one driver both ways.
I take it you knew
Janet Ortega, too?
Well, sure. She rode
Jack's streetcar to work
on the early shift,
mine back home at night.
Saw her pretty
much every day.
She and Jack were good together.
Until he killed her.
Still can't believe he did it.
Meaning, what?
You think he was innocent?
At the time, yeah. I mean,
I know how much he loved her.
Jack struggled
with paranoia and delusions
his whole life.
I thought he had it
under control.
Is that what the D.A.
got you to say in court?
Yeah. It helped send him away.
Yeah, well, he's out now,
and if he killed Karen Decker
out of revenge,
then you're not safe, either.
Is there any chance
you might help us figure out
where Gordon might be?
I mean, the sooner we
get him off the streets,
the sooner the people who
testified against him are safe.
I think I saw Jack
earlier today,
across the street
from the station.
So, why didn't
you call the police?
I wasn't sure it was him.
Besides, I didn't know
he'd just killed somebody else.
(wind chime tinkling)
Uh, good news.
Mm-hmm.
Christopher says everyone
who testified against Gordon,
(thunder rumbling)
under police protection.
Apparently, so am I. Here.
(chuckles)
Oh, by the way. I don't snore.
At least, not that I know of,
anymore.
(both chuckle)
I don't know if I do anymore.
You think either of us will
ever get married again?
Oh, I'm not in
any hurry, myself. You?
If the right person
came along, maybe.
Last one kind of soured me
on the idea.
Yeah. Long time ago, though.
Divorce happened just before
Gordon's case, didn't it?
That's the reason I moved here.
New beginnings and all.
(water running)
Yeah. A lot to go through.
Gordon's case
must've made it even harder.
Where are we going
with all this, Dwayne?
Not going anywhere, just...
I know that your husband didn't
treat you right, either, so...
No, it isn't that he didn't
treat me right.
You know it. He froze me out.
He wasn't like this at first,
just started
to resent my success.
Then it got even worse
when they passed him over
for others less qualified.
Then he got mean.
It took a long time to find
the courage to leave him,
but I finally did.
I was lucky.
Luckier than Janet Ortega.
You were both victims.
And they were both abusers.
But I was still
so upset and so angry
with how Reginald treated me,
that when I testify, I projected
all that onto Gordon.
And...
ever since,
I've worried that I biased
the jury against him.
It doesn't change the fact
that the evidence against Gordon
was overwhelming.
Wasn't just your testimony.
But my testimony
made an impact.
I saw it in each
and every one of
the juror's faces.
I wasn't trying to make
Gordon pay.
I was trying to make
my husband pay.
And it's haunted me
ever since.
(thunder rumbling)
Loretta.
Don't move,
and stay calm.
Okay?
Gordon.
Mm-hmm.
Outside.
Just wait a minute
and call 911.
I'm gonna go
get this blanket,
pillows.
Put them out on the sofa,
I'll be right back.
(thunder crashing)
Oh!
(Pride and Gordon grunting)
Get off me!
Calm down, Gordon.
Stop fighting.
Relax.
(grunting)
Stop fighting.
You're under arrest, Gordon,
for the murder of Karen Decker.
I didn't do it. (groans)
(thunder crashing)
I didn't do it!
The blood at the school
wasn't me!
You just don't understand!
Help me understand,
Gordon,
what were you doing
outside Dr. Wade's house.
I need my meds.
Get me my meds!
PRIDE: I'm getting them.
The agitation you're feeling
right now is
clozapine withdrawal.
You're not
going anywhere.
Try and breathe.
Swallow.
Who's there?
Who's on the other
side of there?!
There's somebody
looking at me!
I know there is!
Who's on the other side?
Dr. Wade, is that you?
I wasn't gonna hurt you,
I swear.
I just wanted your help!
PRIDE:
Talk to me.
Gordon, look at me.
(sobs)
What do you mean when you say
you want her help?
For what, medication?
No, no.
I just want... I wanted her!
(Gordon sobbing)
I need someone
to believe me!
I didn't kill Janet!
(crying):
I swear to God.
I didn't kill Janet!
If Gordon didn't
kill Janet Ortega,
he didn't kill
Chief Decker either.
All right, slow down,
okay?
Just 'cause he claims he's
innocent, doesn't mean he is.
He's a desperate man.
Yes, but he has been claiming
his innocence for over 20 years.
Guilty or not,
we have to be sure.
Gonna give him his clozapine,
then talk again
after he settles down.
We're gonna take this
one step at a time,
just like we always do.
Maybe there's
something I missed.
Or maybe it was
really because
I just wanted
him to be guilty.
Loretta...
(sighs)
I need to check,
you need to check.
Because if Jack Gordon
is innocent,
then the killer is
still out there.
You want one of us to stay with
her, make sure she's safe?
She'll be okay.
Killer's either locked up
in our interrogation room,
or out there thinking
he's won the game.
Killing again would just
prove Gordon innocent.
You're not convinced Gordon's
our killer, are you?
I'm convinced
there's a possibility
he's telling the truth,
so we're gonna keep
investigating.
Well, all due respect
to the doc,
but somebody would be going
through a lot of trouble
to set Gordon up twice
across a span of 20 years.
I admit it's a stretch,
but like Loretta says,
we need to be sure.
All right,
what's the plan?
Loretta's gonna review
the forensic evidence
on Janet Ortega, in case
she missed anything.
Gonna ask the D.A.
to exhume the body.
That means I need you
to go to Morgan City,
pick it up and
get it to the morgue.
You got it.
You and Patton need
to comb through both
Ortega's murder and Decker's.
See if you can find
a connection to anybody else
other than Gordon.
Pills, King.
If somebody had 20 years
to frame Gordon
for another murder,
chances are they didn't
make a mistake.
But if they did,
we need to find it.
We need to be right
about this.
Both for Gordon and Loretta.
Okay.
Knock, knock.
It's okay, Sebastian,
come in.
Okay, cool, I didn't want
to scare you again.
Kind of freaked me
out last time.
Not your fault,
obviously.
It's just childhood issues.
You know, jumpy mother.
I'm thinking I should
get into therapy...
That for me?
It is.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
Anyway, uh,
the D.A. released Ortega's old
case evidence from Property.
What are we looking for?
Frankly, I'm not sure,
but I want to be sure
I didn't miss something.
I perused the case file.
I don't think you did.
I mean, every "I" is dotted,
every "T" is crossed on your
forensic findings.
At least, you know, to my eye.
Can never be too certain.
There's too much at stake.
Meanwhile...
...you mind to take
a closer look at this?
What is this, the hair
sample you found
on Chief Decker's body?
I already identified it
as Gordon's.
Mm-hmm, but we need to know
if it fell from his person,
or if it was placed
on the victim by someone else.
You think Gordon was set up?
Do a calcium carbonate test.
Let's find out.
You can uncuff me now.
I ain't gonna hurt you.
Well... at least
till the meds wear off.
Thank you.
(sighs):
Jack Gordon...
pled guilty to killing
Janet Ortega 20 years ago.
A week after your release,
a key witness
against you was murdered
in the exact same way.
Why should I believe
you're innocent?
Because I am innocent.
I never stopped trying
to prove it, never will.
Why'd you call Chief Decker
the moment you were paroled?
Because I needed her help to
prove I didn't kill Janet.
I convinced her
I wasn't guilty.
So, somebody set you up
20 years ago?
Somebody set you up yesterday--
is that what you're saying?
I know how
this looks, okay?
I'm a diagnosed
schizophrenic.
But you have to understand,
I loved Janet.
When she joined the Navy to get
away, it nearly destroyed me.
The murder weapon,
the jackknife--
Jack's knife--
belonged to you.
I gave Janet that knife
for protection.
From me.
I got crazy at times.
And I abused her when I wasn't
in my right mind, I know.
But that's why I wanted
Janet to be able
to protect herself in case.
She had to leave me.
I could never kill her,
Agent Pride.
Same way I could never
kill Karen Decker.
Karen was the only one
willing to help me.
Wh-Why would I?
So let's say I believe you.
Who set you up?
You must have some idea.
All I know is someone
else liked Janet,
and they was pursuing her.
It had to be
whoever killed her
killed Karen Decker, too.
And maybe they thought
we was close
to figuring out who they was.
Close? How?
What do you mean?
The Innocence Project--
they gave me
my case files
while I was in prison.
Okay, I poured over the files,
I didn't find anything...
till I found
this one photo of Janet.
Last time I saw her,
an hour before she was killed,
she was wearing a necklace...
with a purple gemstone...
but it wasn't from me.
So?
So it wasn't
on the body when she was found.
And I looked
at every crime scene photo,
and it wasn't there.
Killer took it.
'Cause he knew
that it might
connect back to him.
You could check
the photos yourself,
and you'll see I'm right.
You'll see I didn't do this.
(hissing, keyboard clacking,
door opens)
WADE:
You find something?
I think maybe, yeah.
Gordon's hair had trace amounts
of calcium carbonate on it.
Transferred from the latex
gloves the killer used
to plant a hair
on Chief Decker's body.
Yeah.
Which means if Gordon
didn't kill Chief Decker...
he probably didn't kill
Janet Ortega, either.
Which also means
an innocent man spent 20 years
of his life in prison,
and I helped send him there.
PRIDE:
Nothing else?
No other connections
to the other murders other
than how they were killed?
Nothing we can
find so far
other than the obvious
connection to Gordon.
It's too obvious
for my taste.
Too clean, too.
Yeah.
If Gordon didn't do it...
whoever did knew how
to cover their tracks.
GREGORIO:
Like someone in the Navy
or law enforcement--
but we checked
both victims' records,
nothing jumps out.
Nothing to confirm
Gordon's claim of Janet Ortega's
mystery suitor?
Nothing other than the
purple gemstone necklace.
However,
the victim was wearing it
right before she got killed,
like Gordon said.
This is from a
surveillance camera
at the Decatur streetcar
station that same night,
20 years ago.
Except,
she wasn't wearing it
after she was killed,
also like Gordon said.
Well, it makes sense,
right?
Killer doesn't want
anybody tracing it back to him.
You know what? I'm starting
to think maybe Gordon's right,
somebody's setting him up.
Especially since
the more grisly
and violent the murders appear,
the more a jury's
predisposed to believe
that abuse and mental illness
could be the cause.
Problem is, other
than Gordon's claim,
we don't have much,
if anything, to go on.
But we find out who
gave Janet Ortega that necklace,
and we will.
LASALLE: Took 'em longer
than they thought to dig it out,
that ground
was still pretty damp.
Fortunately for us,
burying the deceased
in cemeteries
near peatland marshes
prevents putrefaction,
decomposition.
SEBASTIAN: You really think
she can tell us something
after all this time?
WADE: Time may
heal all wounds,
dear, but not when you're dead.
Still, it's
hard to believe
you, of all people,
missed something.
Yes, well,
if Jack Gordon is innocent,
then I must have.
I'm headed back to headquarters,
to help them find that necklace.
Keep me posted.
SEBASTIAN:
So these are
Ortega's original
autopsy photos?
Yes, uh,
this is the one
of particular interest
of the back of her neck.
SEBASTIAN: Oh, yeah,
some kind of abrasion.
At the time, I noted it
as consistent with other wounds
likely inflicted
when she was dragged
to the car,
but after hearing
about the necklace...
It could be the wound
was caused when someone
ripped it off her neck.
If so,
it could be what I missed...
in my rush to judgment.
Sebastian may have something.
Go ahead.
SEBASTIAN:
Right, well,
we reexamined a cut on the back
of Janet Ortega's neck
and we found microscopic slivers
of platinum
imbedded in what was left
of the tissue.
If the killer ripped
the necklace off her neck...
Slivers might've gotten lodged
beneath the skin.
That narrows
our search.
Big time,
since platinum is pretty pricey.
Hey, how's Doc Wade
holding up?
Oh, you know.
She's still beating herself up
pretty bad over all this.
PRIDE:
Can't change the past.
But we can do
everything we can
to make things right
moving forward.
We'll get back to
you, Sebastian.
Hey, I think I may have a lead.
I've been runnin' the necklace
from the Ortega photo
through imaging software,
but I just narrowed it down
to platinum pieces only
and bam!
Canal Street Boutique
designed and sold
the very same platinum,
diamond and amethyst necklace
in 1997.
If we can track down
purchase receipts,
we might be able to find
a suspect
who intersected
with Ortega's life 20 years ago.
PATTON:
Can't be many.
4,500 large.
That's some serious change.
LASALLE:
Check this out:
the store is located
at the end of
the Decatur streetcar line.
That's the same
street line
Janet Ortega took to work
every day,
with Jack Gordon
driving in the morning.
LASALLE: And his buddy,
Todd Borger, driving at night.
Could be a coincidence.
but on the other hand...
If we connect Borger
to her necklace,
we can connect him
to her murder.
Still, $4,500,
pretty steep
for a young streetcar driver
making, what, eight,
ten bucks an hour back then?
Not too steep
for a young lawyer.
Jewelry store is right next to
the office of Gordon's attorney.
Right, Devon Mitchell.
We were there yesterday.
Which means what?
Mitchell's the one who
gave Ortega the necklace?
Hold on, why would Mitchell
kill Janet Ortega,
frame Gordon,
and then turn around
and defend him?
Pretty good way to make sure
Gordon loses the case.
And if Mitchell
killed Chief Decker, too,
make sure
it didn't get reopened.
We need to find Mitchell.
(blow landing)
Sebastian!
MITCHELL:
Should've just
let things be.
All right, now what?
Now? Now, you're gonna
delete every piece of evidence
from your server.
Why? You're just
gonna kill me anyway.
Well, your lab tech back
there didn't see me hit him,
but I can always carve
out his eyes, too.
Go.
Jack went to Chief
Decker for help,
and she came to you, didn't she?
Just delete the files.
Just out of curiosity, how'd
you know I had any evidence?
D.A. called me,
told me you were
exhuming Janet's body.
Hurry up.
I forgot how chummy
you two were.
Surprised you didn't talk her
into the death sentence
for Jack.
Yeah, well, the jury
wouldn't buy premeditation
because of his condition.
Otherwise, I would have.
So, what,
just because
Janet wouldn't leave Jack
for you,
you kill an innocent woman,
ruin a man's life,
then kill again?
Couldn't have done it
without you, Doc.
Your testimony against Jack
really sealed the deal for me.
Don't you dare blame
what happened to Jack on me.
This is all on you.
Yeah,
well, unfortunately for you,
you and I are the only ones
who know that.
Aren't we?
(door opens)
PRIDE:
Loretta?
(gunshots)
(shouting)
(screaming)
(gunshots)
You all right?
Huh? You good?
(whimpering)
(Wade crying)
You did good.
(sniffles)
SEBASTIAN:
Please tell me
that getting my ass
kicked all the time
is just part of the
whole newbie thing.
'Cause if it's not, I
am seriously considering
going back to the lab.
That or just buying a
bunch of life insurance.
You did great, baby,
and you're doing great.
Just hang in there.
(chuckles)
That's easy for her to say.
Gregorio's been knocking heads
and taking names for years.
SEBASTIAN:
Yeah, she grew up in New York,
you know? I'm from Peoria.
(chuckles)
Here, knock 'em back, Peoria.
How's Wade? Anyone talk to her
yet this morning?
Pride has.
He says she's doing much better.
Yeah, 'cause she's kicking ass.
Oh, stop.
PATTON:
Not better than Lasalle.
I heard Lothario's got himself
another hot date.
Oh, he's not
a lothario anymore.
Your boy's all grown-up.
Besides, it's just breakfast.
And, pray tell, how come
you know all of this?
Well, you know,
been giving him a few tips.
Unsolicited, maybe,
but he's listening.
Ah. Handy having a profiler
on the team.
Not being cocky here, but
I think I pretty much identified
his perfect type.
Not quite sure how
to break it to him though.
Why's that?
Tough,
loyal, whip-smart, sassy,
can hang with the boys,
and gives as good as she gets.
Percy?
Like I said, not quite sure
how to break it to him.
Where you going?
I'm going to get me
some pills, too.
Just the thought of them
together makes my head hurt.
(streetcar bell clanging)
(bell continues clanging)
Never got tired of driving
a streetcar through the city.
It's a great job.
Loved every minute of it.
(clacking)
(whirring)
Might be able
to pull some strings,
see if I can get you
your-your job back.
You're a free man now, Jack.
Besides, the city and the state,
they owe you more than that.
Still,
it's a little scary being out
all of a sudden,
cleared.
I spent so many years
trying to prove my innocence,
I didn't think much about
what I'd do if I succeeded.
Well, the-the halfway house
can help you adjust.
So can I.
So can Dr. Wade.
Is that why you wanted
to meet, ride with me?
One of the reasons.
Look...
...you were right to...
go to her for help.
There's no reason
to stop now, Jack.
She feels bad
about what happened,
more than she deserves.
Bad? Hell, didn't she just help
exonerate me?
Anyway, I never held anything
against her.
I mean,
she didn't do anything wrong.
I... I hurt Janet.
Got used against me.
All she did was say it.
Actually,
she probably ended up
saving my life,
getting the jury to take pity
on me 'cause of my condition.
Then maybe you'll be open
to the other reason
I wanted to talk to you.
The good doctor's
donated her time
to the Innocence Project
for a lot of years.
Could use what you learned to
help others wrongly imprisoned.
Might give you some direction.
Maybe... help the two of you
heal a little bit.
Interested?
(bell clanging)
Storage?
No. Trash.
I'm not gonna let the past
weigh me down any longer.
It's time to move on.
Unless you want me to bore you
with more talk of my ex-husband.
I'm out of here.
Mm, that's what I thought.
(wind chime tinkling)
Thank you.
(chuckles)
Would you like to come in
for some tea, Mr. Gordon?
Sure.
Captioning sponsored by
CBS
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org
Uh-oh.