Downloaded from
YTS.MX
(upbeat music)
* Sweet sugar honey bunny *
Official YIFY movies site:
YTS.MX
* You can't buy my love
with your money *
* Work on the bird,
y'all the devil's work *
* I ain't got time for
that, ain't you heard *
* And he my man *
* He my man *
* Don't you understand *
* Oh, he my man *
* He my man *
* Don't you understand *
* Oh, the rooftop in
the chicken shack *
* And I don't ever
want him back *
* He's a hustler *
(upbeat music continues)
(upbeat music)
(motorcycle rumbling)
- Need some help?
- Yeah, please.
My boss is on his way,
but I have no idea
what I'm looking at here.
- Yeah, that's all right.
I dabble.
- You fix cars?
I wouldn't have guessed that.
- Yeah.
Don't let this suit fool you.
I only wear it 'cause I have to.
All right, let's have a look.
- [Driver] It started smoking
right before I pulled over.
- [Luke] How long
you been out here?
- [Driver] Too long.
- Look, I think you might
have a bad radiator hose.
It happens with
these old trucks.
Now look, this is a
temporary fix, okay?
So you, your boss, whoever,
you guys gotta go in and get
this thing properly checked out
when you get a chance,
all right?
- Hey, how much should I
tell my boss this cost?
- Don't worry about it.
Feel free to come
by anytime, okay?
We'll get you all sorted.
- Appreciate it, man.
- Happy to help.
(motorcycle rumbling)
- Too pretty.
Ooh, too many issues.
Oh, now you have potential.
- Wait. Do not ruin this
moment of me thinking
that you're finally
on a dating app.
- But this one
could complete me.
Well, come on.
It's a 1954 Chevy Bel Air
with a 3.5 liter V8 engine.
Oh, I think I'm in love.
- Speaking of love,
the guy who got his
car serviced yesterday,
he not-so-subtly
left you his number.
- Which car?
- Oh, just the fact
that you have to
identify him by his car
says more than you know.
- Oh, come.
- Late model Bronco.
- Oh!
- He was cute.
- Not my type.
The car or the guy.
- Jess, you've got to
put yourself out there
and open yourself up to romance.
- I have my job
and I have my cars.
I have my class, which,
ooh, is starting really soon
and I haven't finished prepping.
So see ya.
(upbeat music)
(motorcycle rumbling)
- Good morning.
Hey, Mike.
Thank you.
I know.
Morning.
- [Receptionist] Luke?
- Okay.
- [Receptionist] Your shirt.
- Great.
Okay.
Do you mind?
Thank you.
Okay.
Sorry I'm late.
Yeah, hi, Pete. Good morning.
Morning.
I'm sorry, Dad.
Something came up.
- What's with the shirt?
- Fashion. Young guy thing.
- This was a strategy meeting.
It's kind of essential
that the VP of corporate
strategy be here.
- I planned on being here, Dad.
- You were back under a hood.
- There was a kid.
He was stranded on
the side of the road.
I couldn't just leave him there.
- You're a great kid, Luke,
but you need to stay focused.
You belong here, beside me.
Now, come on.
We need to get
back to my office,
review the sales
figures for the quarter.
- What's that?
Are we looking to
acquire Barro's?
- It's a great location.
That would be a
smart acquisition.
- Are you sure you
wanna do that, Dad,
well, considering the history?
- This is the company's future.
And yours.
Now, come on.
(somber music)
(Jess sighs)
- I heard that.
Keep those nerves in check.
- Is it that obvious?
- You're gonna do great.
What's on the docket today?
- We're gonna start
nice and easy.
I want women to feel comfortable
and confident around their cars.
Like how to change a spark plug.
- Well, I already told Eden
to set side part of her summer
break to take your class.
- Really?
- Yes, of course.
And I can't think
of a better person
to learn from than you.
- Yeah, if only I could
stand up in front of the rest
of the class without
breaking into a cold sweat.
- Yeah, about that.
I was posting on
social media about it.
- What did you do?
- It's good for business.
- Hi there.
Hello.
I'm...
Welcome to Barro's Auto Repair.
I'm Jess Barro.
I'm also the head
auto technician here.
So today we're going
to be talking about
the oh-so-useful,
but often misunderstood
spark plug.
Let's begin.
Eden, these are fantastic.
- You think so?
- Yeah.
No wonder your mom says
you're the star of the class.
- Star? Not yet.
I really wanna get picked
to be the photographer
for the school's
paper next year.
My teacher said this
project's my chance to shine.
- Well, you, my friend,
are radiant.
Make sure your teacher's
wearing shades.
- Thanks. If only had an
idea of what to shoot.
(horn honks)
- Well, inspiration
is everywhere.
Come on.
Dad, I love it.
Oh, it's beautiful.
- It is?
- With every restoration,
I'm not looking at what is,
I'm looking at what it could be.
So maybe this one says
showroom floor, 1957.
Or hot pink with shag
upholstery and fuzzy dice.
You know, some of
the best ideas come
when you just throw convention
out the window and go for it.
- My daughter's never been one
for sticking to convention.
- Yeah, well, I guess
I was raised right.
(phone buzzing)
- Excuse me. I
have to take this.
- Well, since I am trying
to raise you right,
we better get going.
You're gonna be late for class.
- Okay.
See you later, Jess.
- All right, see you
later, superstar.
Can't wait to see
what you come up with.
- Can we find some
middle ground here?
I'll get back to you.
I've gotta go out
for a little bit.
- Is everything okay?
- Yeah.
I just have to
run a few errands.
- Okay.
I'll hold the fort.
(traffic whooshing)
- I don't know how
to say no to the man.
- Do you know how many people
would jump at the opportunity
to work-
- Suffocate behind a desk?
No. I spend more
time changing typos
than transmissions, man.
- Hey, no one spots an I
before an E like my man Luke.
- Thanks, Pete. I
appreciate that.
You know, my granddad used
to give away oil
changes for free?
I loved that.
I loved working with him
and my dad back then.
It just seemed
like it was small,
but we're doing something
of that mattered, you know?
- Look, in marketing,
the first step
to changing minds is
to find common ground.
Figure out how to talk to your
dad in a way he understands.
Then maybe you can
help him understand
your version of the future.
- Whatever that is.
Anyway, I appreciate it, buddy.
I gotta go.
I got a date tonight.
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
You seen my keys?
- Oh, I'm gonna give
Eden a quick call.
I'll meet you at the bar.
- All right, I'll grab a drink.
- Okay.
- Oh, somebody dropped their...
- Keys.
That would be me.
- Luke.
- It's nice to see you, Jess.
- Fancy.
- Company car.
How are you?
- We don't need to
do the small talk.
- No small talk.
Genuinely asking.
- What are you doing
this side of town?
- I was having a drink
with a friend.
On my way to a date.
You look good.
- You look like you sell bonds.
- I'm gonna choose to
take that as a compliment.
- Well, I guess
I'll see you around.
- Yeah, definitely.
- Yeah.
Is there something else?
- My keys.
- Right.
Enjoy your date.
- I'll try my best.
It's good seeing you, Jess.
- Mm-hm.
- Who was that?
- That is Luke.
- The Luke?
Wow. He's...
- I'm gonna get us a table.
- I'm just saying.
Are you ever gonna tell me
what happened between
the two of you?
- No, I already told
you it doesn't matter.
- Clearly it does.
Something about Luke's dad
cutting Ray out of Tune Up Wiz?
- Yeah.
So it was back when Luke
and I were in college
and Luke's grandfather
wanted his dad and my dad
to be partners, take
over the company.
- Okay.
- [Jess] But Luke's dad refused.
- Oh.
But you broke off with
Luke because of that?
How does that make any sense?
- So Luke knew his father's plan
to cut my dad
outta the business,
and he said absolutely nothing.
My dad was completely
blindsided.
By the time he found out,
there was nothing he could do.
So he started over.
From scratch.
- Yikes.
(upbeat music)
- Hello?
Anybody here?
Hello?
- Oh, hi there.
Sorry.
Wait, are you...
You're Wayne LaRoche
from "Road Renegades."
My dad and I used to watch
that show all the time.
- And you are Jessica Barro.
- How do you know my name?
- Well, you did a
restoration for my friend.
A '66 Pontiac GTO in...
- Marina Turquoise.
- That's the one.
Blew me away.
- Thank you.
- Which is why I think
you're perfect for this.
- Perfect for what?
- Hey guys, come on in.
Come on.
Don't worry. They don't bite.
Oh, and none of this
footage is gonna be used
without your permission.
- My permission?
- We're doing
a competition show
for car restorers called
"American High Gear."
Look, Jess, when
I saw your work,
I had to meet the
genius behind it.
- Ah, well, if you could see
behind the grease on my
face, I'd be blushing.
- So I've been
scouting contestants.
And to be frank, it's all men.
I think having
a woman in the show
would inspire a lotta people.
- Well, I wouldn't be so sure.
Sorry, can we just cut the
cameras for a second, please?
- Of course. Yeah.
So we're gonna be shooting
at the Classic
Car Fest in Alden.
Do you know it?
- Yeah. I used to go there
all the time, actually.
- Well, it's gonna be fantastic.
Beautiful cars, packed audience.
And did I mention
top prize is $50,000?
- Look, I really appreciate it,
but not exactly a TV type.
- With all due respect,
that's why you're perfect.
I mean, you're authentic,
you're brilliant at what you do,
and I can't think
of anyone better.
- I appreciate it, but
I'm really busy here.
Good luck with it though.
Sounds fun.
- Sure.
Look, if you change
your mind, call me.
Our contestants are staying
at the Pinefield B&B.
- I used to stay there
all the time as a kid.
- No kidding!
See, it was meant to be.
Jess, I really do
think it'd inspire
a lot of people
seeing you up there.
Just think about it, okay?
- Okay.
- You're great.
Okay, guys, let's go.
(gentle music)
Good job, buddy.
(Jess laughs)
- And he's going on and
on about my restorations.
You remember the '66 GTO?
- In Marina Turquoise?
What a beauty.
- What a beauty.
Ah, I don't know, though.
I'd rather not.
Large crowds, I mean,
all those people.
It's not exactly my forte.
- You do whatever
you feel is right.
(gentle music)
- You okay?
Been acting really weird.
- Yeah, it's fine.
- Dad, you can talk to me.
You know that, right?
- That call I got was
from our landlord.
- Okay.
- He's raising our rent.
You know how competitive shop
space is downtown right now.
- Yeah.
- Apparently he's getting offers
from tenants willing
to prepay for the year.
He wants us to do the same.
- That's insane.
- We don't have that
kind of reserve.
- Okay.
What about a loan?
- It's tough.
Hey, I don't want you
to worry about it.
I'll figure it out.
- No, no, it's just
that TV producer today,
he said the winner of the
competition gets $50,000.
Go a long way towards our rent.
- I think it sounds like
a great opportunity.
Not for the garage, but for you.
You are the best
mechanic I know.
And I'm not just saying that
because I'm your father.
- I don't know, Dad.
Being a woman in this
business is hard enough.
I can't handle the pressure
of trying to prove myself.
- You don't have to
prove anything to anyone.
Your work speaks for itself.
I'm just saying.
(gentle music continues)
(bright music)
(kids laughing)
* Baby, baby, I've been
meaning to tell you *
* And it's taken
me far too long *
* You make every
day a happy day *
* I'm so lucky that
you came along *
* So if I have *
(engine sputtering)
- Hey, there.
Need a hand?
- Not unless you got
a new car battery.
- Oh, I think it's
the alternator.
- I know my way around a car.
It's the battery.
- Hey, would you try
something for me?
- Sure.
- You got a radio
installed in there?
- [Driver] Yeah.
- Okay.
Hop on in, turn her on.
Set the radio to AM and
then find a low frequency,
something with no music.
- [Driver] Okay.
- All right, now step
on the accelerator
and tell me if you hear
a high-pitched noise.
(car ringing)
- You know, I think it
might be the alternator.
- That is a handy trick.
I see we both trained
under my granddad.
- Luke.
What are you doing here?
- I convinced my dad to
get a Tune Up Wiz booth.
You know, strategy.
Bar charts, pie charts,
various kinds of charts.
- Wow. You got that
corporate lingo down.
- You think so?
- Yeah. No.
- Oh, okay.
What are you doing here?
- Uh, I'm just here to
check out classic cars.
- Yeah, it's the festival.
It's been a minute.
Can't help but
remember all the times
we used to run around here.
Hey, do you remember that
time we hopped the fence?
- You know, I'd rather not.
- Sorry. Of course.
Enjoy the festival, Jess.
- Yeah.
Yeah, you too.
Don't get motor oil on
your fancy sports coat.
- What, this old thing?
It was on sale.
- I can tell.
(melancholy music)
(people chattering)
- [Wayne] Jess!
You made it.
- Happy to be here.
Looks like you've
got your hands full.
- Oh, you have no idea.
One of our contestants
dropped out just this morning.
- Seriously?
- I wouldn't joke about that.
Thankfully we found
a replacement here
at the festival.
- Well, I guess if you're
looking for car people,
this is the place to find them.
- That's for sure.
Oh, here comes
our replacement now.
- Jess?
- Wait, you're
in the competition?
- So, is everything okay?
- Can I talk to you for a sec?
Me first.
I'm so sorry.
It's just, I didn't realize
he was gonna be on the show too.
- So what's the issue?
- Well, you know,
it's a really long story.
Tragic one, really.
- Wait, wait, wait.
Is this...
Are you two...?
- Oh, we're not dating.
- But you were.
Oh, this is television gold.
- No, no, no, no. It's not gold.
It's not even bronze.
- You never said you were
a contestant on the show.
- Well, you said you
were manning a booth.
- I was manning a booth
until this lovely
gentleman approached me
desperate for
another contestant.
But if it's a problem,
I can bow out.
Unless you're not afraid
of a little competition.
- Oh, please.
I'm just afraid you can't
handle losing to me.
(Kevin slurping)
- Oh, don't mind us.
- We're your fellow contestants.
- Is this show about car
restoration or couples therapy?
- I guess it's on.
- Oh, it's on.
(upbeat music)
- [Announcer] Ladies
and gentlemen!
Take your seats!
"American High Gear" will
begin in five minutes.
(contestants chattering)
- Don't be nervous.
There's no shame
in losing to me.
- Look, the only thing I'll
be losing is your number.
(audience laughing)
(upbeat music)
- Welcome to
"American High Gear."
(audience cheering)
The show that separates the
hot rods from the clunkers.
I'm your host, Wayne LaRoche.
Over the next week,
we'll put our contestants'
restoration skills to the test.
The three finalists
will then compete
for a winner-take-all
championship round,
which will determine America's
top classic car restorer.
(audience cheering)
Let's meet our
contestants, shall we?
First up, we got Kevin from
White Plains, New York.
Next we've got Ike from
Tupelo, Mississippi.
Then we have Clark from
Minnetonka, Minnesota.
Last, but definitely not least,
got Luke and Jess
who both actually hail
from right here
in Detroit, Michigan.
- Happy to be-
- I'm so sorry.
- I insist.
- You always insist.
- Ooh, looks like these
two have some history.
(audience cheering)
All right, folks,
before you are some of the
most iconic cars to restore.
From a 1970 Chevy Chevelle
to a 1966 Ford Thunderbird.
- That Thunderbird's
gonna be tough.
Not enough time to
fix a car that bad.
- Maybe for some.
- Now, for our opening round,
the contestants will
have two minutes
to sand down a
randomly-selected car hood
from one of these vehicles.
Now, the winner
will get to choose
which vehicle to restore
and then assign another
vehicle of their choice
to the next ranked competitor.
These will then be the
contestants' vehicles
for the rest of the show.
Contestants, take
your positions.
Go.
You got it.
- Just pretend it's
your computer mouse.
- Appreciate your concern.
(audience cheering)
- Oh, and to up the ante,
we've souped up the motors
in your orbital sanders.
So hold on tight, because
we're moving fast.
Three, two, one, go!
(upbeat music)
- They're not even here.
(sanders buzzing)
- Woo, it's got some torque.
- I've changed over 100 diapers,
this is nothing.
(sanders buzzing)
(upbeat music continues)
- Man, I'm on fire.
- Oh no.
- I got it.
- It's all right.
No, no, no, no, it's fine.
Do your thing.
It's all the way
on the other side.
- I got it.
- [Luke] You sure?
- [Jess] Yep. Here.
- Okay. Okay.
- Here.
- Turn it off.
- Cable.
- Watch the cord.
- Okay.
- My cord's around your cord.
Jess, Jess, just let it go.
- Luke! Luke!
Luke, just stop.
(hood clatters)
(crowd gasping)
- [Wayne] 10 seconds remaining.
10 seconds.
- Here, I got the horse.
- Three, two, one...
That's time!
(audience cheering)
Well, folks, it looks like
our Michigan mechanics ran
into some troubles.
But hey, it's okay.
It's still anybody's round.
Judges, please tally
up your scores.
We'll be right back after
a short commercial break.
And the results are in.
In first, our new dad, Ike.
Congratulations, Ike.
All right, contestants,
it's time to decide
which car you'll be foisting
on your competition.
- Luke assigned me
the '66 Thunderbird.
That's the most beat-up car
of the group to restore.
- Oh, that's not very
gentlemanly of him, is it?
- No, it's rude.
- Or, no, you
should be flattered.
- What?
- Because he knows
you're the only one
on that stage that
can handle it.
- Well, I can and I will.
You know, that's not even
the worst part, though.
The worst part is the only
reason he's ahead of me
on the leaderboard is
because my nerves got to me.
I see the crowd,
I completely freeze.
- Yeah, everybody gets nervous.
Just try not to topple over
a massive car hood next time.
- Oh, you're mean.
(Tori laughs)
You know, that's
not even really it.
I feel like when my mom died,
I lost like a really
big part of myself.
That part of me that felt
like I could do anything
and I could be anyone.
(melancholy music)
I just feel really
lonely sometimes.
- Hey, but you know that
we are all here for you.
We love you and support you.
- Thanks.
- I'm gonna be in
that crowd tomorrow.
So you're good.
You okay?
- Yeah, it's just,
it's tragic, really.
I'm gonna have to
show 'em who's boss.
- That's my girl.
(glasses clinking)
(insects chirring)
- I think the universe
is punishing me
for stepping outside
of my comfort zone.
- Just worry about
your own work.
Don't let it get to you.
Boy, I wish I could
be there to watch,
but, ah, I gotta keep
things running here.
- It's fine.
It'll be good to
see a friendly face.
- You're gonna have
lots of friendly faces
once they get to
know you, honey.
I love you.
- I love you too, Dad.
Come on!
Where there is the
power on this thing?
We can just pull it.
- If you're taking
that up to your room,
could I get one last cup?
- What are you doing up?
- Was on my way to the gym
when I came across
this attempted robbery.
May I?
- Be my guest.
(machine beeps)
Clever.
Thank you.
- I'm sorry about today.
That was a disaster.
- It's not entirely your fault.
I was on edge.
- It's kinda fun, though,
doing this together again.
Takes me back.
Remember that time in college
when we stripped the
'54 Caddy to the studs?
- We almost broke my dad's
hoist in the process.
I remember.
He does too.
He forgives you, by the way.
- He's a good man.
- Well, I'm gonna head up
and finish studying on
the '66 Thunderbird.
Cheap move, by the way.
- It's only 'cause I knew
you could handle it.
- Oh, you're going
down, Luke Childs.
Get your beauty rest.
(bright music)
(birds chirping)
- I got some great photos at
the festival this morning.
- What? That's amazing.
- Good.
- Maybe you'll find something
that will inspire your project.
- Well, I mean my teacher
told us to make a statement,
to express who we are.
- You should snap some shots
of the dirty laundry
on your bedroom floor.
- Mom, stop it. Stop.
- I mean, it's accurate
representation.
- It's okay.
All great artists suffer,
but they find their
way eventually.
- Yeah.
- Or they're driven crazy
by their ex-boyfriends
and go completely insane.
- Whose ex-boyfriend?
- What's that?
Uh...
- Mine.
- Teri's!
- Ah.
I'll see you at the competition.
- Mm-hm.
- [Luke] Okay.
- Okay.
- [Teri] That wasn't
awkward at all.
- What was that?
Wonder why they kept you
both in the competition.
Great tension.
- What tension?
- Romantic tension.
Oh, they must be eating it up.
- Yeah. There's no
romantic tension.
I just wish she'd forgive
me, stop blaming me.
- Well, maybe she's
not blaming you.
She just doesn't think
you took her side.
- I didn't take anybody's side.
- Maybe that's the problem.
- Welcome to day two of
"American High Gear."
(audience cheering)
Now, to be a top
restoration mechanic,
you can't just know
your way around cars.
No, you need to be encyclopedic
about tools, parts, and systems.
- Hey, here's to not toppling
car hoods today, huh?
- Huh? Okay.
- All right.
- Oh, too slow.
(audience laughing)
- Uh-oh.
It looks like our
Michigan mechanics are
at it again, folks.
Play nice, you two.
Now contestants, remember,
every second section is
an elimination round,
which means we'll
be saying goodbye
to whoever loses in trivia.
Here we go.
Buzzers at the ready?
- Yep.
- Question number one.
How many volts should a
healthy battery register
on a multimeter?
Jess?
- 12.6.
- Correct.
(audience cheering)
Looks like somebody's
batteries are charged.
Second question.
What kind of power is produced
in the engine cylinder
as a result of fuel combustion?
Luke.
- It's indicated power, Wayne.
- Correct! Wow.
Michigan contestants are
off to a blazing start.
Look out, folks.
- You're lucky
I taught you that.
- Yeah. Okay.
- Rear traction control.
- Electronic control unit.
- The scrub radius.
- Wayne, that's a
catalytic converter.
- Four of them.
- 14.7 parts air
to one part fuel.
- Three degrees before
top dead center.
- Oh, that's four
degrees, Clark.
Four degrees. Sorry, big guy.
- Spring-loaded Muncie shifter.
- Flywheel.
- [Wayne] Jess, you buzzed in.
(upbeat music)
- Oh.
- We're waiting.
- You know this.
- Camshaft. It's camshaft.
- Oh, camshaft is correct,
but I'm sorry, you're just
a little bit too late.
Now, adding up today's points
with the previous days.
- It's all right.
You're all right.
- Luke and Jess have
climbed up from yesterday.
Kevin is now in fourth,
which sadly means
we'll be saying goodbye
to our friend Clark.
I know, I know.
(audience clapping)
We'll miss you, pal.
But hey folks, still
anybody's game.
Until next time for
"American High Gear,"
Wayne LaRoche.
- And Clark.
- And we're out.
(bell rings)
Good job.
Great job.
- You okay?
- We'll find out.
- You know, I gotta say,
as the only female contestant,
Jess is more than
holding up her own
but you see those
nerves showing?
I mean, that's death on TV.
Anyway, with these
elimination rounds,
she continues like this
she's not gonna last,
which would be a real shame.
(crowd chattering)
- Well, that was rough.
- It's okay.
Om...
(gentle music)
- How exactly is this helping?
- We are centering ourselves
and we are connecting
you to the voice inside.
- Oh, I can hear that voice.
It's saying stop
sitting cross-legged.
You're getting sciatica.
- Focus, Jess.
We're almost zen.
Om...
(football thudding)
- I mean, does he have to
play football right there?
- New plan. Get on your feet.
- No.
- Come on. Up.
And arms up and oh!
Release the tension.
Let it all out!
- Well, this was a good idea.
- What's going on over there?
- They're centering themselves.
I do that most mornings
before my first
round of video games.
- That does not surprise me.
- Whatever works.
It seems like Jess
could use a reset.
- Yeah, Jess is all right.
She's the strongest
person I know.
- I don't doubt it.
But what exactly is
going on between you two?
I'm sensing some hurt feelings.
- Yeah, we got
some healing to do.
- Well, she better heal quick.
I don't intend on losing in
any of these elimination rounds
and she's next on
the chopping block.
- All right, Kevin.
Slow down.
- This is ridiculous...
- Ly effective.
- I'm gonna take
your word for it.
- Okay. Sit down again.
We have got to figure out
what is holding you back.
What happens to you when
you get up on that stage?
- I don't know, okay?
I lose my nerve.
- Jess, I have seen you
at work in the zone.
You can accomplish anything.
- I just feel so much pressure.
- Yes, there has
been a lot going on,
but it's all gonna work out.
- Not if I don't win.
- Stop it.
Has your father gotten this far?
Survived this long with giving
up when things get tough?
If you win, great.
If you don't, we
will figure it out.
And that vulnerability
that you see as a weakness,
honey, that is your strength.
That sensitivity is what
makes you an artist.
You're stronger than you know.
Om!
- No, I'm not doing it.
- When it comes to
restoring a classic car,
it can take a rigorous
search through vintage parts
to find the exact
piece you need.
- Missed you at breakfast.
- I hope you didn't fill up,
because you're about
to eat my dust.
(audience laughing)
- There she is.
- Today, our contestants are
gonna replace their headlights,
install a new battery,
and rewire whatever they
need to turn them on.
- Yikes. It's not gonna be
easy with that Thunderbird.
The housing on the lights
is gonna have to fit
the grill just right.
- I know.
- Good.
- So, first team to fire
up their lights wins.
- Teams?
- That's right.
Just to make things a
little bit more challenging
we've broken our competitors
up into teams of two.
So Kevin, Ike, you're
on the Skylark.
Jess, Luke, you're
on the Thunderbird.
- Well, looks like we're
in this thing together.
I got your back.
- Prove it.
- Contestants,
on your marks, get set,
go.
(upbeat music)
(audience cheering)
- If you wanna hold my hand,
you can just ask.
- Your hands are so soft.
What? No tools at the office?
(audience laughing)
- It figures.
- Boom!
This'll work.
- See anything?
- What do you got?
- I got two pin.
- Great. We're missing a three.
Keep looking.
Bingo. Got it.
- Okay.
(audience cheering)
- Keep it going, guys.
It's still anyone's
game. Let's go.
- This is the Jess I remember.
- Then let's win this thing.
- Fire 'em up.
(audience cheering)
(audience groans)
- Uh-oh.
Misfire on the Thunderbird.
Looks like they're not done
troubleshooting just yet.
- No! We blew a fuse.
Hey, I saw one
in the parts pile.
Go see if you can find.
- It's just gonna keep blowing
unless we figure out
what's wrong with the wiring.
- Didn't you gimme
the Thunderbird
'cause you knew
I could handle it?
Luke, trust me.
I know what I'm doing.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Come on, Kevin.
- Signal switch.
- Keep it going,
gang. Keep it going.
- And the signal relay.
Directional relay.
Nope.
The trunk relay.
(upbeat music continues)
- [Luke] Got it.
- [Jess] Got it?
- [Luke] Yeah.
- It's gonna be a close one.
- All right, fuse is in.
Give it a go.
- Hit it.
(upbeat music continues)
(audience cheering)
(Jess laughs)
- We did it!
- Leaderboard time.
Remember, judges have
awarded points according
to how teams place,
but they've also
tripled the points
to those who've
gone the extra mile
with their craftsmanship.
- Craftswomanship.
- And let's take a look.
And that's it for today.
For "American High
Gear," I'm Wayne LaRoche.
We'll see you next time.
(upbeat music)
- Dad, I wanna talk to
you about something.
I think you should
reconsider acquiring Barro's.
There's a lot of other
shops that we could get.
- Barro's is in
a prime location.
If we don't nab it,
one of our competitors will.
- But why not help them?
When grandad was alive, all the
shop owners knew each other.
We were competitors,
but we were friends.
Jess is also on the show.
- I think you're
letting your feelings
for Jess cloud your judgment.
Right, do me a favor,
leave this with me.
Acquisitions are
all about timing
and I don't want Ray
learning of this offer
until it's properly presented.
- What are you asking me?
You're asking me not to
mention this to Jess?
- Well, there's a lot
of factors that go
into our decision
to acquire a shop.
- And I'm asking you to make
our history one of them.
Dad, for me.
- All right, I hear you.
I'll put my finger on
the pause button for now.
Now come on, you get out
there and you make us proud.
- Yeah, sure.
Okay.
(people chattering)
It's a great job today.
You really pivoted out there.
Next generation of
auto techs right here.
These two, it's your influence.
- I mean that's why I
used to love coming here
with our families.
Surrounded by auto enthusiasts.
A sense of connection.
- Speaking of connection,
did you hear about
the social activity
that Wayne's got slated for us?
It's a way for the
contestants to bond.
- Do I wanna know?
(upbeat music)
I can't believe this place
is still around.
I haven't been roller
skating in forever.
- That's our song.
Do you hear it?
- Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
- That is not the attitude
of a 7th-grade champion.
If I recall correctly,
we dominated a very, very real
roller skating competition.
- Okay, well, that's because
there was one other couple
and they dropped out
when both of them fell.
- I don't know about all that.
But what I do know
is that you and I.
Three, four, here we go.
Boom, one, two.
Let's go.
Here we go.
One, two.
* Let's have a little fun *
* When the music
starts playing *
* We're gonna have
a little fun, yeah *
* Can you hear what I'm saying *
* The weekend's almost here *
* And I'm just waiting
for the moment that *
- Ready to lose, old man?
- I'm gonna fold
you like a onesie.
- What a strange and
fantastic comeback.
Here we go. Pizza
and ranch dressing.
Just like the old days.
- Thank you.
Hm. Can't believe you
remembered our old routine.
- I still practice
every night before bed.
You don't?
- Really.
- Yeah.
- Wow.
Well, I mean, that's smart
because you never know
when a big business deal's
gonna come down to a
winner-take-all skate off.
It's good life choices.
- Don't get me started
on life choices.
- Come on, you're
getting through.
You're doing fine.
- As if you think that.
- You're working for your dad.
I'm working for my dad.
We're both doing
the best we can.
- Except you're
doing what you love,
and I'm stuck in
an office playing
with spreadsheets
and having meetings.
- Yeah, it's like a
spreadsheet video game.
It's fun.
- The greatest.
- Okay, fine, it's not
exactly apples to potatoes.
- No, it's not apples
to potatoes at all.
I got sucked into
this thing, you know?
Couldn't say no.
- Well, I mean, you can say no.
But...
How's your mom?
- Mom is good.
She moved to Arizona
after the divorce.
- Oh.
- Still talks about you a lot.
- Oh yeah?
- I wish it would
stop, honestly.
But, you know, in
this competition,
you remind me a lot of your mom.
- We're talking about
the same mom, right?
- Same mom, yes.
- My mom. Okay.
Yeah. Yeah.
My mom who could just walk
in front of a group of
people and not break a sweat.
My mom lit up every
room she walked into.
I can just barely get my
words out when it's my turn.
- I know it might
feel like that,
but I don't see it that way.
Your mother was fierce.
She was strong.
She was the kinda person
who would stand up
to any fear in front of her.
And that's what you're doing.
I'm just saying, your mom
was an impressive woman.
So are you.
- Thank you.
Even if you're lying,
it sounds nice.
(birds chirping)
- I'm really proud of you, Jess.
- Dad, it's only
the first round.
I'm barely out of last place.
- Not just yesterday.
Everything.
Being in the competition,
putting yourself out there.
I haven't seen this side
of you in a long time.
- You know, it's funny
because I have spent years
avoiding this kind of situation,
but now that I'm in it, I
just, I wanna go for it.
- That's good.
It really is.
Do you think working with Luke
has had something
to do with that?
- Dad, I'm fighting for the
future of the garage, okay?
I don't have time for feelings.
If there were any.
Speaking of the garage,
did you hear any news?
- I talked to the landlord,
but he's holding firm.
- You know, if I win this thing,
it's gonna solve
all our problems.
- Nothing solves all problems,
but don't worry about that.
I've applied for a loan.
For now, enjoy the moment.
That's all I care about.
- No, I'm not gonna
let you down, Dad.
- You never could.
- [Luke] So there I
am, parts everywhere,
trying to put it
all back together
when the customer shows up.
- [Audience] Uh-oh.
- Yeah. Uh-oh was right, Wayne.
So he's standing in the doorway
and I look like I just
committed automotive murder.
And a single tear
rolls down his cheek
and he goes, "Just came
in for an oil change."
- Ouch. That is quite the
first day on the job, Luke.
- That's quite the last day too.
- True.
- Folks, if you're
just joining us,
we're doing a quick Q&A
with our contestants
to get to know them just
a little bit better.
Now, Jess, I understand that
you grew up around cars.
What is it exactly
that you love about
restoring old classics?
- Ah, well, I've loved classic
cars from a very young age.
Their charm, their design.
I love the way that they
demand that you get in there
and you get your hands dirty.
If I really, really
think about it,
I love what these
cars represent.
Cars are at the center of so
many of my favorite memories.
Family outings and road trips.
Going to restaurants,
drive-ins.
Car is what makes
those memories happen.
Memories fade and
cars deteriorate, but,
I mean, if I can be
just a small part
in restoring those memories
and keeping them alive,
then that means
everything to me.
(gentle music)
You got anyone special
coming to cheer you on?
- My buddy Pete's coming later.
- What? That's it?
Nobody else?
- I don't have a
special cheering section
if that's what you're asking.
Last date I went on
was a disaster.
I knew within the first two
minutes it wasn't a match,
which made the next five, six
hours just super romantic.
How about you? You
seeing anybody?
- No. After my last
string of dates,
which I would rate
from bad to horrible,
pretty much given up.
- Well, at least I can't
say you're a quitter.
- Okay. All right, fine.
I haven't given up, but when
I know I'll know, you know?
Oh, speaking of knowing,
you know the first car
I restored completely
on my own was a Dart.
I painted it purple.
- I remember.
You were an artist
with a spray gum.
Probably still are.
How often are you
restoring these days?
- Ah, it's a side
thing, but I love it.
- Doesn't have to be
a side thing, you know?
Could expand it.
- Yeah, well, that's the dream.
Eventually, but right now
I've gotta help my dad
with basic services.
It's our bread and butter.
Besides, I don't think
I have it in me
to be the front person of
my own restoration biz.
- Jess, you're a natural.
They'd be lining up
around the block for you.
- Yeah, well, that can't
happen soon enough.
- What do you mean?
Jess, you know you
can talk to me.
I am happy to listen.
- We're having some financial
problems at the garage.
- I'm sorry to hear that.
- Yeah.
That's why I joined
the competition.
If I don't win,
I dunno what we'll do.
- Jess, there's something
you should probably know-
- You know, it's funny because,
for the first time,
I actually feel like
things will work out.
I mean, I joined the
competition to save the garage,
but it sort of feels
like something more.
- That's great.
- At least that's what
I keep telling myself
because I really can't
handle any more pressure.
- Right.
(upbeat rock music)
- Our competitors are
racing head-to-head
to diagnose and to repair.
But it looks like Jess is
speeding to the top of the pack.
- Hey, Hercules, feel free
to give us a hand over here.
- If I do that,
and then you're coming
to me every time
you need to open
a jar of pickles.
- And that's a costly
fumble for Mike.
Hold on to those tools, folks.
It all comes down to this.
Now, since the scores
are so neck to neck,
the first three contestants
to fire up their engines
will be moving on
to the last round.
Whoever comes in
last, walks home.
- Socket.
Hey, Luke, you
took my 3/4 socket.
- Yeah, but I also gave it back.
- It's not here.
- [Luke] There we go.
- Ooh, this is close.
Jess is getting close.
(car sputtering)
- Yes!
- Look out!
- Whoa!
- Thanks.
- Yeah. You okay?
- Mm-hm.
- Good.
- I am sorry, Ike,
but that fumble cost
you precious time
putting you in last place,
which means it's
Luke, Kevin, and Jess
moving on to the final round.
(audience clapping)
- Nina, Daddy's coming home.
- Lots to be proud of,
Nina, lots to be proud.
Until next time for
the final round.
For "American High Gear,"
I'm Wayne LaRoche.
And we're out!
- We'll miss you, Ike.
- That's on making
it to the finals.
You two are like a dream team.
- We you make a
pretty good team.
- We're not a team.
- Not a team. No, not a team.
Just meant in the
competition, right?
- Right.
- It's kinda like
a sport, you know?
There's no "I" in team.
There is a me if you
switch letters around.
I'm gonna stop.
This is Pete.
He's the director of
marketing at Tune Up Wiz
and my friend.
- Hey.
- Nice to meet you.
I love a good comeback story.
- Thanks.
- But, hey, I better head back
to the office before your dad
notices I've been at lunch
for 2 1/2 hours.
- Right. Yeah. Let me
walk you to your car.
I'm gonna be right back.
- Let's go.
- Okay.
- Nice to meet you.
- Bye.
- Hey!
Yeah.
(people chattering)
- Yeah, yeah. I can't
keep doing this.
- What you talking about?
You're killing it out there.
I think you could
win this thing.
- And put Jess's dad
completely outta business?
- What?
- They need the prize money
to keep Barros's doors open.
- Are you serious?
- Yeah.
- You should tell her what's
happening with your dad.
It'd be worse if she
finds out on her own.
- I know. I know.
I want to.
I tried, but she doesn't
need the added pressure.
I don't know how I keep finding
myself in this situation.
- The universe
provides, my friend.
- I don't know what
that means, Pete.
Did you read that
on a fortune cookie?
- No.
Okay, look, one time, yes.
But I'm serious.
We attract the things
we need to overcome,
- Right. Yeah.
Thank you for that, Yoda.
I'm gonna attract
her hating me more.
Do you understand
what I'm saying?
- She won't if you're honest.
She's a good person
and so are you.
Don't forget that.
I'll see you around.
- Thanks, buddy.
(people chattering)
- Eden's photo
exhibition is tonight.
She keeps checking in with me
to make sure that you're coming.
- Of course. I wouldn't miss it.
- Good, good.
- Early afternoon and
we're already done.
I can get used to this.
- Well, hi.
- [Luke] Hi.
- I'm Terry.
- I'm Luke.
- I work for Ray and this one.
- Yes, I've heard a lot
about you from Jess.
- Lies, all of it.
No, I'm just kidding.
- Right. Of course.
- No.
Didn't you used to go to
high school with Jess?
- Yes I did.
And I have the frosted
tipped hair to prove it.
- Well it just so happens
that my daughter goes
to the same high school.
- Is that right?
- Yeah. And tonight she's having
a photojournalism exhibit.
Yeah. You wouldn't wanna come?
I mean, Jess is gonna be there.
You could join her.
You could go back to your
old stomping grounds.
- I would love that. Thank you.
- Yeah. Great.
- [Luke] Yeah.
- It's a date.
- Great. I'm gonna
go frost my tips.
- Okay.
He's cute.
- Yeah. Teri, I know
what you're doing.
Luke and I had our time.
We're just friends now.
- You know what, Jess?
It's really easy
to shut people out.
The real challenge is opening
yourself back up again.
Taking a chance.
I will see you both tonight.
(people chattering)
- Wow. It's so different.
Almost erases the trauma
of failing algebra.
- Wow. These kids
are so talented.
- Yeah.
- Takes some guts to put
your heart on display.
- No guts, no glory, right?
- Jess!
- Eden.
Oh, this is Luke.
- Nice to meet you.
- Oh, I know who you are.
- Okay.
- Well, I'm glad you're here.
- Are you kidding?
I wouldn't miss it.
You're gonna be a famous
photojournalist one day
and I wanna be able to say
I was at your first exhibit.
- Well, I'm one step closer.
My teacher loved the exhibit.
I got the job on
the school's paper!
- Oh, congratulations.
I knew you could do it.
- And it's thanks to you.
- What do you mean?
- Well, come on. I'll show you.
I kept searching for an idea
that expressed who I was.
You know, a belief or cause,
but then I realized it was
staring me right in the face.
I wanted to inspire
people to be themselves,
strong and proud because
that's who you are to me.
What do you think?
- I love it.
Thank you.
(gentle music)
- Okay, well, I'll
see you guys later.
- Wanna get some air?
- Sure.
(rain pattering)
- Remember it was pouring
rain during homecoming?
- Yeah. It didn't
stop us from dancing
in this field right here.
Or that kid from sliding
and slipping all the way
down the bleachers.
- Down the bleachers.
- What's that kid's name again?
- Derek.
- Come on.
- Dinkleman.
- My granddad sold
him his first car.
- Oh yeah?
- Yeah.
- I did not know that.
- Yeah, he used to always
say that most important part
of a car was the person
behind the wheel.
- He had an amazing spirit.
- Yeah, he really did.
That's exactly how I'd run
the company if were up to me.
- Yeah, well, it's
not up to you.
Not now anyway.
- Yeah.
- You know, when we broke up,
it was really hard for me.
- Me too.
(gentle music)
* Think about the things *
* Think about the
things you said *
* I have never been *
* Never been the kind, babe *
* But if it's all
the same to you *
* I'm gonna lock you in,
throw the key away *
- What are you doing?
- It stopped raining.
Gimme your umbrella.
* No I'm not ready *
* I can never let you
go, just let you go *
* Just let you go like that *
* I'm not ready, ready *
* Just look around *
(gentle music)
- Well, it's been quite a ride,
but it all comes down to this.
The final round.
(audience clapping)
Now the scores have
all been cleared,
so each contestant has an
equal chance of winning.
The final challenge
will be to complete your
vehicle's restoration
with a custom paint
job within two days.
- [Audience] Wow!
- The judges will
not only assess
for quality, but creativity.
- Let's do this!
- Contestants, have at it.
- You two have been
fun to chill with,
but now it's go time.
You're going down.
(upbeat music continues)
- Whatever happens, one
of us has to beat Kevin.
- Absolutely.
- My money's on you.
(gentle music)
- Well, I've got a
lotta work to do,
so I'm gonna get going,
but I'll see you later.
- Promise?
- When I got your text
inviting me for drinks,
I assumed you'd meant to
send it to a different Ray.
- Yeah, well, it's
been a while, huh?
So I hear that Jess
made it to the finals.
Yeah. You must be very proud.
- You were never
one for small talk,
so what's this really about?
- I wanna buy your garage.
- I appreciate that, but
the garage isn't for sale.
- Oh, come on Ray.
I sense that Jess wouldn't be
involved in this competition
if you didn't need the money.
It's a generous offer.
There's enough there you to
be able to retire comfortably
and for Jess to
make a fresh start.
- The answer's no.
- Come on, Ray.
Don't make this about the past.
You could lose your
entire business.
This is a way out.
- I have no intention
of losing it.
I have my best employee on it.
I bet everything I have
every time on Jess.
You know, you might consider
betting more on your son.
Nice seeing you, Steven.
(upbeat music)
(fire crackling)
- Is this reserved?
Can anyone sit here and
stare pensively at the fire?
- Please, join me.
- Didn't wanna join
the party, huh?
Kevin's in there.
He is teaching everybody
a great dance movie
called the lawnmower.
- Okay. I gotta see that.
Huh, looks like he's
moved on to flossing.
That's exactly what
I hoped it would be.
- He's good, right?
- I was just thinking
about the time when went
camping at Lakeport.
- I'd never seen as many stars.
It was really good to get
away after my mom's passing.
You were always there for me.
- Until I wasn't.
I wanted to tell you
what my father was doing
with your dad and the business,
and maybe I didn't fully
comprehend what was happening,
but more likely I
didn't have the courage
to stand up to him,
to stand up for you.
And my goodness do I regret it.
It takes a lotta courage
to do what you're doing.
Getting up on that
stage every day,
knowing how scared you are.
Maybe if you could
be that brave,
I can too.
- I don't know if
I'm that brave.
As much as it pains
me to say this,
I don't think I could do
this crazy thing without you.
- I never thought that I'd
get you back in my life.
You know, I never
wanted to lose you.
(gentle music)
* I see you, baby, acting cool *
* Ain't no doubt
gonna make you mine *
* I wanna kiss you
and hold you tight *
* Whoa, there's a fire burning *
* I know you can feel it *
* I can see it in your eyes *
* All right *
(upbeat music continues)
* And it feels so good *
* Say you love what you do *
- And where there's
Motown, there's a Jess.
- Can't paint without it.
It was my mom's favorite.
- Oh, I know.
- Paint's done.
- There's no way.
- Yeah, I'm waiting
for it to dry.
- Okay. I gotta see this.
- Oh, no, no, no.
- I gotta see it.
- No, no, no, no.
Patience, my friend.
There are dividers for a reason.
- You free later?
Some things I wanna
talk to you about.
- Yeah.
That sounds more serious
than the color of paint
you're gonna choose.
- Maybe slightly.
- Okay.
Well, listen, my dad
and Eden and Teri
are gonna come for lunch,
but how about dinner?
- Yeah, it's a date.
- Okay. Good.
There are just a couple
more things I have to grab.
But hey, no peeking.
- No peeking? No promises.
Okay.
- [Steven] Hey, Luke.
- Dad, what are you doing here?
- You said you wanted to talk.
So what's on your mind, son?
- You know I want the
best for you, right?
And I appreciate everything
that you've built,
but I think something
needs to change here.
- What are you getting at?
- That if Barro's is in trouble
and you don't want
our competitors
to have their location,
then I think, given our history,
the least we can do is help
them get back on their feet.
- That's just not how
our business works, son.
Look, I need someone on my side
that I can trust in leadership.
And that person is you.
- I appreciate that.
But I wanna be building
community like Ray and Jess.
- Look, I know you wanted me
to hold off, but I went ahead
and I presented
Ray with an offer.
- What?
- He turned me down.
He seems to have lost
sight of what's imminent.
I tried to reason with him.
But he won't let go of the past.
- Okay, so what now?
- Well, I spoke to his landlord.
I made a conditional deposit
on a multi-year
lease for the garage.
It will take effect if
he defaults on his rent.
I'm protecting your future.
- [Luke] I appreciate that.
- [Steven] I'm just leaving
the rest of it to fate.
- Hey, Teri, can you
hang on a second?
- If he can't come
up with the money,
he's gonna be out anyway.
He'll be forced to
sell the business.
I mean, at least this way,
we ensure that he
lands on both feet.
This is what makes
the most sense.
- Yeah. Hey, I'm here.
Did you know Tune Up Wiz was
trying to buy the garage?
- How do you know about that?
- So it is true?
- Luke's father made an offer,
but your dad refused it.
Unfortunately, the bank has
rejected his loan application.
So he's looking for things
that he can sell
to raise the money.
- Well, if we can't, Steven's
gonna take over our lease
and kick us out anyway.
You know, hey, can
I call you back?
(people chattering)
(melancholy music)
(phone ringing)
- Pick up, Jess.
- [Jess] Hey, this is Jess
from Barro's Auto.
(Luke sighs)
(paint gun clicking)
Who's done this?
What is your issue?
(compressor clacking)
(compressor whirring)
(paint gun hissing)
No.
Okay.
(people chattering)
- Luke.
(somber music)
What?
(Jess gasping)
- It was an accident.
- What happened?
- The compressor,
it wasn't working.
I was distracted.
Jess, I am so sorry.
- Did you enter the competition
to keep me from winning
so your father could
buy the garage?
- What?
- I overheard your dad's plan.
- No, that's not why I entered.
I just found out.
I knew he wanted to acquire
the garage, but I didn't...
- I know what he's
planning, Luke.
So you knew he wanted
to buy the garage
and you stay in the competition
so I don't win the prize money.
And you want me to believe
this was an accident?
- I never wanna hurt you,
Jess. Please believe that.
- That's just it.
I don't think that I can.
(somber music continues)
- Hey.
I'm not really too sure
why you wanted me here.
- Dad, please take a seat.
I think it's time that you
and I had a very real talk.
- Go ahead.
- I want you to call
off the plan for Ray's
and I want you to help them.
- You already know
I can't do that.
- He was your partner.
The Barros are
practically family.
Do you really think that
granddad would've wanted this?
- Your grandfather wanted
this company to grow.
That's all I'm trying to do.
- He would never have wanted
you to treat a friend this way.
- Because of that friendship.
Ray's gonna be better
off and so is Jess.
- This should not be
your decision to make.
And I know you have it in
you to be better than this,
but if you can't see that
this is the right thing to do,
then I can't be a part of it.
Any of it.
This is my resignation.
- Whoa, whoa.
Hey, Luke. Luke, wait.
Hey, you think of your future.
- That's exactly
what I'm doing, Dad.
I may have lost the most
important person to me,
but I'm gonna do
everything that I can
to make sure she doesn't
lose the most important
thing to her.
- Let's just take a
moment and think, okay.
The competition isn't over yet.
- It is for me.
I can't prep and paint
a car before the finale.
I let everybody down.
- You did great, Jess.
I'm sure you would've won.
- Can I have a word
alone with Jess?
- Absolutely.
Come on, you.
Let's take a walk.
(waterfall whooshing)
- I'm guessing this isn't
just about the garage.
- When Luke joined
the competition,
I felt all these memories
just come flooding back to me.
The way he let me down,
the way he changed your life.
- I'm fine, Jess.
- Yeah, but it upset me.
Then something amazing happened.
I started seeing
the old Luke again,
the one I fell in love with.
And it was such a
relief, you know,
because I started
feeling this part
of me coming back again.
But it wasn't real.
And I never should've
let him back in.
- Sure.
And that way you can
just move through life
without ever hitting
a bump in the road?
Your mom and I weren't perfect.
We hit lots of bumps
along the road,
but through it all,
she always brought
out the best in me.
This competition was never
just about cars for me, Jess.
- Well, cars don't cause pain.
- They also don't love.
Maybe it was an accident.
I just, I don't see
sabotage in Luke's heart.
(waterfall whooshing)
Come here.
It's okay.
- [Jess] Mr. Childs?
- Hey, Jessica.
- Somebody was saying
you wanted to see me.
- I'd really like to talk
if you'd just have a seat.
- Sure.
- Look, I really need
to explain myself.
My dad and I were
very different people,
and in many ways he was
actually a lot like your dad.
And I wanted to have
a different kind
of relationship with Luke.
You know, in my effort to
bring us closer together,
I seem to have driven
him further away.
I made Luke choose
between you and my family.
And that was a big mistake.
Luke would never do anything
to hurt you or your dad.
He's a good man.
In many ways, he's a
better man than me.
I'm deeply sorry for what I did.
(gentle music)
- Thank you.
I really needed to hear that.
(phone ringing)
- Come on.
- Hey, I wanna talk.
- Sure.
I'm just trying to reach Wayne.
I'm dropping out
of the competition.
- No, Luke, you don't have-
- The paint was an accident,
but my hesitation to tell
you about my dad wasn't.
I don't blame you
for not believing me.
- Look, Luke, I
talked to your father
and-
- I resigned.
- That was a big step.
- Yeah, it was the
right thing to do.
At the end of the day,
I wanna like the person
I see in the mirror.
- Good.
'Cause I like that guy too.
- Still?
- Yes. Still.
Because he reminds me
to believe in myself,
and he always has.
And that guy, he
reminds me who I can be
when I'm not hiding.
Plus he's really
fun to be around
and I would miss him if he
wasn't in the competition.
- We're still talking
about me, right?
Are you sure you
want me to stay in?
- Yes. I don't
want some pity win.
That's not who I am.
And Luke, I know you
didn't do it on purpose.
- Okay.
- Luke, I couldn't
do this without you.
Please, please stay.
- I've ruined your car.
What are you gonna do?
- Figure it out.
(upbeat music)
- All right, folks,
the moment we've all
been waiting for!
The final restoration reveal.
Who's ready?
(audience clapping)
All right, first up.
Mr. Big Gulp himself, Kevin.
(fingers snapping)
(audience clapping)
That is an impressive
showroom shine, Kev.
- Great job, Kevin.
It's beautifully done.
- Precision. It's who I am.
(audience clapping)
- Next up, Michigan's
favorite son, Luke.
(audience clapping)
(audience member whooping)
Very impressive.
Motor City will be proud.
Well done, Luke.
- Thank you, sir. Appreciate it.
- Now Jess, before
we reveal your car,
I heard you ran into
a little snag when one
of the contestants accidentally
sprayed paint on it.
Is that true?
- Well, it's just a couple of
bumps along the road, Wayne,
but it wouldn't be a
journey without them.
- All right, let's reveal it.
(audience clapping)
(upbeat music)
Wow.
The judges have
locked in their votes.
Folks, your first winner ever
for "American High Gear" is
Jess Barro!
(audience cheering)
(uplifting music)
And that's it for your first
season of "American High Gear."
I'm Wayne LaRoche.
We'll see you next time.
- Oh, too slow.
(uplifting music continues)
- My girl, you rocked it.
So proud of you.
Look at this thing!
(gentle music)
- I'm so proud of you. Jess.
- Barro's Auto lives on.
You have no idea how
happy that makes me.
- Okay. I gotta see this.
- And your support.
- Well, it's the
least I could do.
(glasses clinking)
- All right, you guys. Come on.
Get in front of Luke's car.
Come on.
- Okay.
- Hey Ray, congratulations.
You were right to
have faith in Jess.
- Your son's pretty
exceptional too.
I see a lotta your dad in him.
- When my father said
that he wanted us both
to run Tune Up Wiz,
I was pretty hurt.
I thought he didn't have faith
in me to run the company,
but it's okay.
I now realize that,
well, he wanted the values
that you both shared
to carry on as well.
I think it's time that
Tune Up Wiz invested more
into this community.
I think it would be
great for longevity.
It would honor our history.
- Why don't you
and I grab a coffee
in the next few days and...
- Yeah.
- Talk about it.
- That sounds really good.
Thanks, pal.
- Yes!
- Fantastic job, Jess.
You really came into your own.
So much so that the
network wants to see more,
possibly even your own show.
- Are you kidding?
Have you met me?
- You're authentic,
you're sincere,
you elevate this craft
into an art form.
Any ideas of what a
show might look like?
- Actually, I think I may.
- Three.
- Welcome to "Community Garage,"
the show that breathes
new life into old rides
for the benefit of
organizations in needs.
Thanks to our
sponsor, Tune Up Wiz,
today we'll be restoring
this beautiful 1954 Bel Air
to be sold at auction
with proceeds going to a rebuild
of our local community center.
I will be giving it a
stylish new exterior
while my crack mechanic, Luke
here, rebuilds the engine
so it runs as good as new.
- As good as new?
Better than new
if I can swing it.
- So we'll see you
after the break.
We are just getting started.
- Great job, guys.
- Thank you, Wayne.
Appreciate it, pal.
First episode.
Buckle up.
- Yeah, it's gonna
be a wild ride.
(upbeat music)