Previously on prison break:
I'm breaking out,and you're going to make sure my brother goes with me.
I'm sorry,henry.
This message is for maricruz.
I'll be there in the airport in ixtapa waiting for you.
Sucre,down the road,if you're in trouble,post a note on the message board.
What's it called?
Europeangoldfinch.Net
That's a bird,right?
Go pack your things.
We're moving.
We will be a family if it kills us.
Pull this off and you're halfway home.
You remember what home is like,don't you?
Stay away from my family!
She needs that medicine--
she can't go two days without it.
I don't feel good.
Oh,sweetie...
michael,I want for this to be over.
That makes two of us.
It's just a question of looking at whatever it is your father gave you.
It's just a key.
It's in a lockbox at the corona de oro cigar club.
I'm not a wanted fugitive.
Give me the key.I'll do it.
You want to take a walk?
Miss tancredi?
I need to have a word with you.
- Miss tancredi?
- Of course.
Miss tancredi?
Ma'am?
it's time to go.
They're going out the back.
come on,come on.
MINNEAPOLIS,NINNESOTA
NINNEAPOLIS/ST.PAUL INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT
pediatrics,please.
hello.
Cameron.
Hi,dad.
- How are you doing,big guy?
- Good.I'm eating my lunch.
How is it?
Pretty disgusting.
maybe your mom can bring you some dinner from home.
- Did you see the doctor today?
- Yeah.
He said I can go home this week as long as I stay out of the street.
You're a smart young man.
You know how to cross the street.
Are you mad at me?
Listen to me.
No one is mad at you.
And this wasn't yo fault.
I'm the one who should have been looking out for you.
You weren't even there.
But I should have been.
aw,man.
Hey,buddy,listen.
I got to go,but I'll call you back later,okay?
- okay.Bye.
- Cameron...
I love you.
cam?
yeah.
What have we got on franklin?
Nothing new since this morning.
Another witness from the minnesota diner robbery gave a positive I.D.
Good.
'Cause I just landed in minneapolis 15 minutes ago.
- Anything else?
- Yeah.The girl.Dede.
Apparently,she's been ill,some chronic condition.
Fax franklin's mug shot to every hospital in southeastern minnesota.
Already done.
With any luck,she'll get sick enough to need one,then he'll show his face.
You don't have kids,do you,lang?
Nope.
Call me when you have something else.
I'll take that.
- We didn't get it.
- What?
And we need to get back in there soon.
Once the company finds out sara was in there,
it won't be long before they start wondering why.
Find a spot close to the club and sit tight.
We're going to take the car.
- We'll be back in a couple of hours.
- Where you going?
Turns out that maybe there's one member of the club who can help us.
Who?
Pope?
just a minute.
HenrY.
What are you doing here?
Aside from jumping bail and evading the authorities?
There's something that you need to hear,but,first,I need to know if you'll listen.
I can assure you,sara,we've got nothing to discuss.
Sir,please.I need five minutes.
After that,if you want us to,we'll leave.
Who's "us"?
-= huodidao.com =-
Prison Break
Season 02 Episode 17
- I don't want any trouble.
- Good.
Because that's not why we're here.
What the hell are you thinking about,waltzing in here?
You're a wanted criminal!
In case you've forgotten,I dedicated my career--
my entire life--
to keeping people like you behind bars.
You're talking about guilty people.
My brother is innocent.
And we may have the evidence to prove it.
Well,I don't care; I want you out of here.
It's in a lockbox at the corona del oro club,and you're a member.
Out!
Henry,please listen.
Sara,I'm tempted to say you should have known better.
But after what you did...
my father was looking into the burrows case when he was murdered.
This key is the only thing I could recover from his body.
CONECUH COUNTY,ALABAMA
Where are we going?
They're hungry.
We've been driving all day.
Chick-o-stick.
They need real food.
Soon enough,pumpkin.
Alackaday.
Miscreants.
Defilers.
Defacers.
Despoilers.
what is this?
My home.
TECPATAN,MEXICO
35 MILES OUTSIDE OF IXTAPA
aw,no,no,no!
No.
Where you headed?
Airport
You're in luck.
How far is it?
Twenty minutes.
Catching a flight?
My girl's on the four o'clock flight.
Shouldn't be a problem.
Good.
??????
Cadena here.
How close are you?
Twenty miles.
Roger that.
What was that?
I'm airport security.
American fugitive's flying in,something like that.
MINNEAPOLIS,MINNESOTA
okay.
All right,sweetie,why don't you sit over here,okay?
All right.
I'm going to go over there and I'm going to talk to the lady.
All right?
You need anything?
You sure?
Okay.
Yes?
My daughter,dede,she's really sick.
She's had this kidney thing since she,she was real young.
It's mostly...
where is she?
She's sitting right there.
- Have you been here before?
- No.I'm from out of town.
Can I see your insurance card?
Um...
no,no.
I don't have any insurance.
After I left the army,they discontinued my insurance.
Are you a resident of hennepin county?
Like I said,we're from out of town.
You have a driver's license?
Look,I don't have a driver's license,an insurance card,
or anything like that,but I do know the law.
You have to see my little girl.
- Let me go get my supervisor.
- Good.
I don't give a rat's ass about you or your brother.
I trusted you,I took you under my wing,I treated you like my own son.
I believed you!
Day after day,you lied to me.
What kind of a man does that?
- A desperate one.
- Yeah.
Well...
you two made a big mistake coming here today.
You give me no choice.
I'm going to notify the authorities right now.
I'm sorry...
but I can't let you do that.
I don't want to hurt you,henry.
Said by the man with the gun.
If it's the only way I can convince you,so be it.
Well,you're not going to convince me by doing that.
I'm not the man you think I am.
Yeah,well,I have a pretty good idea who you are,michael.
If that's true,then you already know I never wanted to be in fox river.
I ner wanted to meet you,henry.
- I certainly didn't want to ruin your life.
- Yeah.
Well,you've done a pretty damn good job.
You're not saying anything to him I haven't said myself,henry.
I've looked into this.
What he's saying to you is absolutely true.
I just want my brother's life back.
I want people to know the truth.
I'd give anything for that.
I'd lay down my life.
Well,that's easy for you to say,standing on that side of the gun.
What if I'm standing on this side?
There are places that can better serve your needs.
Look,I know my rights,okay?
This isn't a primary care facility.
We provide necessary care in life-threatening situations.
Look,I know what this i are you going to wait until she's dead before you give her some help?
- Is that what you're telling me?!
- I'm not going to argue with you,sir.
This is a hospital,not a homeless shelter.
A what?
What did you just say to me?
I can't believe you people.
Come on.
The line is a little bit too long,okay?
We'll go somewhere else.
Where are we going?
We got to find another doctor,sweetie.
Oh,my god.
Let's go.
Move!
Come on,baby.
Franklin!
Move out of the way!
Fbi!
Stop!
Okay.
Okay,okay.
All right.
Just one second,baby.
Baby,you got to get down,okay?
- No!
- No,no,sweetie,you got to get dowN.
- You got to let him go,honey.
- Get down.Get down.
Honey,you got to let him go.
- Come on
- No.
Man,she's not letting go.
Don't let her pay for your mistakes.
you hear me?
I could shoot you right now and not even think twice.
But you won'T.
You spent too much time around prisons to throw your life away like that.
What the hell are you trying to pull?
It's simple--
that's the key to an innocent man's freedom.
Come on, henry.
We both know there's something going on here.
Too many people have died.
Look me in the eye, tell me you don't believe there's a cover-up going on right now.
I've got no moral obligations here, michael.
As far as I know, lincoln is as guilty as hell.
Then take a ten-minute drive with me, and we'll find out.
That's all I ask.
Henry, you've looked into this before.
You've thought about it.
I have.
And I've come to one conclusion--
this has nothing to do with me.
But I am a man of the law, and right now,
I've got a convicted felon standing inside my house.
Well, maybe there's something I can offer you to make you change your mind.
what do you intend to do with us?
You grease monkey.
You don't deserve minimum wage.
The hell i don't, working graveyard.
There ain't no man deserve more pennies on a dollar per hour
than they got iq points in their head.
I ain't stupid.
Seems equal stupid as the rest of you.
Seems to run in the genes.
Teddy.
Ten symonyms.
Pick a word.
Destroy.
Ten synonyms for "destroy.
" Annul.
Mutilate.
Liquidate. Abrogate. Quell.
Ravage. Expunge. Demolish.
Extirpate. Extinguish.
Whoo, you see that?
Stupid, my pail, my boy's gonna be president.
how come you ain't studying?
'Cause I'm tired.
'Cause I feel like a circus freak.
Well...
now... it's in your own best interest.
Don't you understand that? Hmm?
Now, you're going to be president someday.
You mark my words.
Susan: Theodore.
Theodore, do you hear me?
What are you going to do with us?
We're gonna put down some roots.
You wanted me dead, paul.
Just following orders.
Sent me to the chair for something I didn't do, all for your president.
You were willing to do that.
Just... following... orders.
Steadman said you loved her.
Steadman was a deranged man that lived in a locked box.
You don't love someone that loves power more than life.
Bitter, huh?
Am I?
No offense, but you're not capable of understanding the relationship.
Okay, any way you look at it, there is no light at the end of this tunnel.
One way or another, you and I, we die.
Your brother, too.
Which is a shame given all he's done for you.
I have a sister I haven't talked to in 15 years.
Think she's better off for it?
We'll make it.
What is that, faith?
Yeah, that's faith.
All I see is a black hole.
And sooner or later, they are going to suck each one of us into it.
But when they come for me, I'm going to take as many of them with me as I can.
She must have really broken your heart, paul.
president reynolds attended a chicago fundraiser last night
as part of her two-day stop in the windy city.
Reynolds' popularity continues to soar in the midwest with
appearances scheduled in indianapolis, detroit and flint,
michigan later in the week.
At a democratic fundraiser...
Mr. Kim... sarah tancredi surfaced in chicago.
She was spotted at the corona de oro club about an hour ago.
Corona de oro club?
It's a cigar club.
Her father was a member.
He kept a private humidor there.
Get me a jet to chicago.
hey,i got to,yh ,split.
terminal's this way
yeah,****bathroom.
there's ***terminal.
really,man,thanks.
thanks for the ride
Got ****sidearm?
May****guy.
He's here
tell me you're not still thinking he's going to show.
He's let you down so many times.
You know that.
Yeah, well, maybe it's the baby in me
that's telling me that this time it's going to be different.
I don't mean to burst your bubble, but he's not going to show.
Bubble's not burst.
I got three words for you.
Yeah?
We gotta run.
Good seeing you, theresa!
I'm so glad you came.
You're crazy.
How did they know?
You're certain...
about what's in the box?
No,but it's all we've got.
Thank you,henry.
You sure about this?
No.
Either way,you still owe me dinner.
Is that so?
Yeah.
First week in fox river,you promised me,if you ever got out of there,you'd take me to dinner.
Well,maybe,after we wrap this up,we can stop off and get you a burrito on the way back to pope's house.
Scofield,I don't know what you're used to,but anything short of a filet mignon is not going to cut it with me.
It's a date.
Hey.
- How did you pull that off?
- I'll tell you later.
- Is he in yet?
- Yep.
This shouldn't take more than a couple of minutes.
Any longer than that,we'll know we've got trouble.
This way.
Thank you.
Mr. Pope.
Hey,warren how's it going?
Did you hear what happened this morning?
Sara tancredi came in.
Yeah.
So I heard.
Next time,don't let her get away.
Thanks.
Excuse me,do you mind if I borrow your computer for a moment?
- No problem.
- Thanks.
pitch in,chitlins!
We can't do this.
We can't live herE.
No,of course not like this.
We gonna clean.
We are cleaning!
We gonna rebuild!
You can't do this to them.
Look at them.
Y'all mind coming along here for a minute.
Come on.
I think we're past me waving that gun around,don't you think?
Thank you.
- What are you doing?
- Nothing is gonna happen to them.
Susan.
Susie Q.
Do you think I'd bring you here to so sacred a place to me as this if I meant you ill?
Look at me!
I am not the animal you think you see before you.
I am the laws of karma all come down wrong.
- Don't you understand?
- I don'T.
What I'm trying to say is that...
I am the sin of my father.
- Why are you telling me this?
- Because I love you.
Because I want you to understand me.
I am the last in the line of bagwells.
The tail end of a corrupted breed.
The earth,thank god,shall see no more of our generations.
I cannot procreate,susan.
And yet,there's something in that that gives me great hope.
No more bagwells shall roam this planet.
Not with that vile blood in their veins.
All I want to do is end the bloodline,extirpate it,
and start another,
afresh.
- A new family.
- Oh,teddy.
Those children are my salvation,my chance to make this world a better place.
my chance to make this world a better place.
I will be good,susan.
I will love them.
I will love you.
I will take communion,be baptized under a truer light.
All I ask is that you love me back,just a little.
Or learn to do so in time.
Can you do that,susan?
I can'T.
I'm sorry.
Teddy.
teddy.
- Mommy.
- Please,please.
teddy,it's okay,it's okay.
teddY.
Teddy,please.Teddy
teddy,I'm sorry.
I can do it.
I can love you.
Where are we?
: At the doctor's office,sweetie.
Hello.
Hello,I have an emergency in here.
Hello?
Hello.
Hey,you the doctor?
- Need to wait your turn.
- No,it is my turn.
This is an emergency right here.
I need you to look at my daughter,okay?
She's not feeling too good.
Please.
Sweetie,hold on,so I can...
all right,look,this is all the money I got,okay?
That's $400.
Please look at my daughter.
What's the matter with her?
She has a kidney disease--
pkd.
Normally,we have it under control,but I don't like what I'm seeing right now.
Her stomach hurts,okay?
And she's always hot.
How's her appetite?
It's gone.
She's always tired,ain't that right,baby?
All right.
Hop up here.
Thank you.
Okay.
He just wants to take a good look at you,okay?
- May need to run a few tests.
- Just do what you have to do,man.
I'm gonna be right here,okay,baby?
Okay.
- Yeah.
- What's going on now?
Still in there.
This is taking too long.
Wait,wait,wait.
Here he comes.
- What's happening?
- We got company.
Hello,henry.
I didn't know you were a cigar man.
Who are you?
Uh,a friend.
A colleague,in fact.
We're both in law enforcement.
I'm not anymore.
That's right.
You're,uh,retired.
- Know the guy?
- Yeah.
Looks like the lifestyle's treating you well.
Yeah?
Socializing over cubans and cognac?
But that's not what you were doing,is it?
Henry.
- You don't mind if ask you to empty your pockets?
- As a matter of fact,I do.
I'm not going to play any games with you.
We both know why you came here today.
I suggest you get out of my way,young man.
I can't do that.
Unless you'd like to cause serious trouble for yourself and your family,
Iadvise you to hand over whatever it is you found.
Now.
Michael?
get in!
let's go!
Linc!
sara!
whoa,whoa,it's okayit's okay. Easy,easy,it's okay,it's okay.
ma'am,are you all right?
I don't understand.
We got a call.
Someone said there's a hostage situation here.
No one knew we were here.
are you okay?
Okay.
Hey,so what's going on?
I'm afraid your daughter shows signs of renal failure.
She ever had hemodialysis?
No,hemo... no.
No,this has never really gone that far.
What,are you planning on doing it right here?
Were not set up for it. And neither is she.
But there is a county dialysis clinic a few blocks away.
But we're gonna have to place a catheter in her neck so she can be examined.
Hold on,sweetie,this is gonna be a little cold.
It's okay,baby.
Whoa,whoa,wait,wait,wait. Wait,what,what is that?
It's a trocar. It's used for placing the catheter.
I got her.
Do we really have to go this far?
Look.
I'm doing the best I can here,but you got to understand something.
Your daughter is sick.
Now,this may look like a desperate measure because it is.
This is gonna hurt a little bit.
Stop! Stop.
Come on,baby.
Come with me. I can't do this.
What's going on?
I made a deal with pope.
You made a deal with pope? What kind of deal?
If he came with us and if we got what we needed,
I said I'd turn myself in.
What?
We don't even know what this thing is!
It could be nothing,michael.
You know about this?
Not until it came out of his mouth.
It's the only thing I could think of.
You two can still finish this.
You'll just have to do it without me.
- I'm not gonna let you do this,michael.
- Just...
there's no coming back from this.
Hold on.
What's the holdup?
Your brother's right. I wouldn't count on the courts to show you any leniency in this.
That doesn't matter. I said I'd hold up my end of the deal.
You already did.
I listened to this.
You have something here.
There's gonna be a lot of people who wish you didn't,but you do.
- Listen,henry...
- I'd go now if I were you.
And don't consider this forgiveness.
In fact,I'm about ten seconds away from changing my mind.
Thank you.
okay...
here,listen...
let's tuck you in,all right?
come on. Let's go.
let's just... let's just sit for a bit longer,okay?
We're gonna go in a little bit,okay?
you know daddy loves you with all his heart,right?
I love you so much.
I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry,baby.
Yeah.
Got a call for you.
I'll call back. I just heard from some clinic up north.
They had contact with franklin a half an hour ago.
I think you want to take this.
Put it through.
yeah? Mahone.
Is this the man in charge?
Oh,yeah.
My name...
is benjamin miles franklin.
And I want to turn myself in.
But I got one condition.
My wife,she goes free.
My little daughter,she needs her mother.
I don't think I need to make a deal with you,Mr. Franklin.
And what if I got something you need?
your wife was released an hour ago.
She'll be here soon.
You promise me that she will be okay.
Just hold up your end of the deal.
I will.
I'll get you scofield.
Come on.
here we go.
You think it's a conversation?
One they don't want us hear.
You ready?
Let's do it.