We're serious about getting married.
Whatever. I sent you a note
to say I couldn't come.
I gave it to Eileen Pickford
to give to you.
Eileen?
My mother? Yeah.
No, don't tell me you didn't get it?
I'm very... fond of you.
I just don't think
I can do this any more.
I'm arresting you on suspicion of
assault.
You're not arresting him!
There's summat about you
bending over in a field
that makes me almost
unable to contain myself.
Ow!
Tell me about when my dad died.
It wasn't an accident.
She killed him.
We decided against
an engagement ring,
so instead, we bought
a car between us.
Judith, this is William, my eldest.
Hello.
He's had that bitch in our house.
Don't come back.
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.
You can't just leave him. Can't I?
Why not? He left me.
I mean, you can't just abandon him
in the middle of nowhere.
You think I should let him humiliate
me over and over again...
Bend! ..and pretend that
everything's fine and dandy,
when in actual fact
I'm having a nervous bloody
breakdown?
Mum!
Oh.
Are you all right?
Caroline?
Idiot. You're an idiot.
Why am I an idiot? Telling her.
He probably wasn't even
doing anything.
He hates her. He hates Judith.
He was probably
just trying to get rid of her.
Mum.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have said anything.
They weren't doing anything.
They were just drunk.
He let her into the house.
It doesn't matter whether
they were doing anything or not.
What matters is that he's shallow
and weak-willed...
and I can't trust him.
Much as I'd like to.
For your sake.
My sake.
Everyone's sake.
Are you all right, Mum?
Are you?
Come on.
I couldn't find a parking space.
What have they said?
Um... they're not pressing charges.
It is just a caution.
Oh.
Here, I know it looks extravagant,
the car.
And, yeah, your mother might have
liked one, but I don't know, I...
She were never bothered about cars.
Odd.
That thing you said about
my mother not giving you that note.
Do you wish she had? Given it to you?
Well, you can't think like that,
can you?
No, but do you?
No! Course not!
But you aren't cross with her,
for not doing?
No.
She was a fantastic woman, my mother.
Yeah, she were. You're right.
I've certainly got no complaints.
Done and dusted.
And next time, give the weedy
little twat a wide berth.
You all right?
What were it about?
Gillian? You know as much as me,
Robbie.
What did he say, the inspector?
Stuff.
I'll see you back there. Right.
And what was Paul Jaktri saying?
Shit.
What kind of shit? Can I go in
t'Lexus with my grandad?
What kind of shit? Grandad,
can I go with you?
You OK?
I'm sorry I spoilt your party.
Ah...
Ah.
I'm going to my room.
I thought I'd better hang about.
You left the door unlocked.
I'll ring Celia, see if she's all
right.
Right. Mm.
How... how were things
at the, um... police station?
I'd hate you and Caroline
to get the wrong idea about us.
For my dad's sake.
This isn't how he behaves, Raffy.
He's a good lad.
I'm sure he is.
God knows why he couldn't rise above
it. He... he would do normally.
Kids. Well, boys, anyway.
I...I helped myself. Good.
I hope that's... Absolutely fine.
Sorry about... What?
Oh, dirty linen in public.
Me and Caroline.
Hey, listen. Don't apologise to me.
Not for anything.
I don't judge people.
Never have done. Life's too short.
Let's be frank.
We're none of us perfect.
The ironic thing is...
What? Oh.
I had this...
fling thing,
affair-fest,
embarrassing mistake thing
with this Judith,
four... three months ago.
Tell me when I get boring.
Oh, the point is she...
I was in the house by myself.
Our house, mine and Caroline's.
And she turns up. Judith.
And I can't get rid of her.
William comes home from school early,
because he's in the middle
of his A levels.
He assumes we're up to stuff.
Which we're not. Absolutely not.
All over.
Thing of the past. Big, bad mistake.
Desperately grateful to be back
with glorious, snotty, mad Caroline,
albeit in the spare bedroom.
But now she's gone all berserk
and says I'm out on my ear again.
Shit.
I've...
just got to pop upstairs
and see if Raffy's OK.
Sure.
Raff?
I want to know what Paul was saying
that made you so cross.
He's an idiot. Well, I can't say
I'd argue with you over that.
And you're an idiot as well.
How's the car? Smashing.
You couldn't drive me
to the nearest railway?
Well, where are you heading?
Well, Harrogate.
Well, I'll drive you there.
I'm off over to see Celia.
She's barely seen that car.
But it'll have to be tomorrow
morning.
I'm not setting off now!
It's dark. Fine. Great. Is that...?
So... so could I stay?
Can he stay?
Alan's very kindly offered
me a lift back to Harrogate
tomorrow morning. Course.
Only I'd be grateful if you...
you didn't drink any more.
I don't want you throwing up in
t'car before Celia's even sat in it.
Celia all right?
Well, I think she'd have liked
a turn in t'car.
Perhaps I should phone for that taxi.
Don't be daft. You stay put.
Oh, I'll go and put t'kettle on.
You want to stick up for yourself
more, you do.
Me? Yeah.
You know, if you weren't doing owt,
if you genuinely weren't
doing owt with this Judith...
why accept being chucked out?
And presumably half the house
is yours.
Morning, everyone!
Daddy's back! Daddy's home!
♪ Allons enfants de la Patrie
♪ Le jour de gloire est arrive! ♪
Breakfast! I'm cooking!
Who wants pancakes?
Morning! It's ten to eight.
Yes, I... Sorry I'm late.
Oh!
'The Sunday morning
service comes from the church
of St James the Great...'
Oh, piss off.
Pa-pa-pa pom!
Do you believe in God?
I used to... to believe.
Mid-to-late 1970s.
What happened in the mid-to-late
1970s?
I'm not sure.
But, er... that's when we just
seemed to stop going. Why?
I think I'd like to get married
in a church rather than
a registry office...
on reflection.
Who's that making that din?
Well, we can do.
I...I don't think
it's obligatory these days,
to believe in God, just cos
you want to get wed in church.
What the hell on earth do you think
you're doing?! Morning, darling.
Don't you shitting well
"darling" me! Potty mouth.
What are you doing?
Breakfast. Want some?
Is that John? Has she let him in?
I live here!
How has he got back?
No, you don't live here,
because I chucked you out
for being an arsehole!
Yes, well...
half this house is mine!
I wasn't doing anything wrong!
She turned up!
William exaggerated! Get over it!
Don't you touch that!
And next time your mother slaps me,
you tell her I will slap her right
back! Harder!
You are not making a mess
in my kitchen!
That's right!
I'm making a mess in my kitchen!
You forfeited any right
to anything when you went off
shagging that whore!
Shout a little bit louder, Caroline!
It's not funny! No.
Morally, I can't argue with you.
Legally, however, a tad more
compromise!
I do not want you here!
Well, I don't mind you being here.
It isn't like there isn't room,
is it?
So, if you can't be civil to me,
just bugger off into another room,
all right?
Because if you're going to be
difficult and unco-operative,
I might just chuck
all your things out, OK?
What's happening?
Nothing.
Your father's behaving like a pig!
Oh, damn. She's shut the window.
You see, I'm not behaving like a pig.
I'm willing to be entirely
reasonable.
You're doing breakfast, Popsicle?
Yes, I am. Cool.
It's not funny!
Hey!
How do you fancy driving over
to Buckstones Ridge?
Oh...
I'm just off to work.
Raff.
Ah.
What have you been saying to our
Raff?
Oh, steady on, Gillian.
And going to the police?
What kind of bloke gets
beaten up by a 16-year-old
and goes whining to the police?
How about, "Thank you, Paul,
for not pressing charges"?
What did you say to him?
"Thank you, Paul, for letting
him get off with a caution."
Nowt. I were just, like... You know.
What?
I were just saying
what a fine woman you was.
You idiot. Any time, love.
Well, he didn't believe you,
anyway. Ha-ha.
Nah, he did.
Not to start with, cheeky git.
Not till I described the way
your wallpaper's peeling off
above t'window where it's damp.
And your five million pair of shoes.
And that photo he has by his bed of
him, his Uncle Robbie and his dad.
Yeah, yeah,
I think that's when he realised
I really had been in your upstairs.
He went mad. Lickle bastard.
That's...
Hello? Gillian?
Yeah? It's John Elliot.
Caroline's husband.
Oh.
John.
Hello.
I'm just ringing to say thank you
for putting me up last night.
Oh, that's...
I stuck up for myself, and, er...
well, she didn't like it.
Not surprisingly.
But I did it.
He's talking to someone.
'Who?'
I've got no idea. He's smirking.
It's probably her, Judith.
Well, I've no idea, Caroline.
I'm sorry I upset you.
I'm sorry I didn't listen to you.
You were right. He's an absolute...
jerk. I've spent
the best years of my life
married to an unreliable,
shallow-minded...
self-centred...
jerk.
Yes.
What am I going to do?
Divorce him,
and not just talk about it this time.
Sell the house, split everything.
Start again.
I can't sell this house! 'Why?'
Because I... I've put so much into
it. I've worked so hard for it.
It's perfect.
I don't want to sell...
Anyway, I can't,
because my mother...
Actually, my mother's
probably going to move out,
because she's getting married.
Your mother? Yes.
Your mother is getting married?
Who to?
Oh, it's just...
How sweet.
Would you like me to come round?
'Would you like to go for a walk?
Would you like to do something?'
Me going on about stuff
a bit too much, probably...
That's such a beautiful
part of the world that you live in.
John? John, John.
I'm... I'm sorry.
I've got to go, cos I'm at work.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Yeah, no... no problem.
Ta-ta, then. Me waxing lyrical.
Yeah. Aw. Bye!
Probably see you again some
time anyway. Yeah, yep.
Bye. Bye-bye. Bye.
Sweet exotic creature.
'So, 2 o'clock, then?'
Jesus Christ.
He's lit a cigarette.
'Is that very...'
How bad is that?
We don't smoke.
Oh. Ah.
And he's drinking whisky
at quarter-past 11 in the morning.
And he's listening to the...
bloody Archers!
I've got to go.
Right, well, I'll see you at...
You silly bitch!
What kind of example
do you think you set these boys, hm?
Smoking! And drinking
and fornicating!
And wallowing there like some...
self-indulgent tosser!
How dare you do that?
I do not want you here!
Well, bad luck. I live here,
and if I want to smoke and bring
women here, then I'll bring them!
But I don't want to bring women here!
Because I want our marriage to work!
You mad cow! This marriage is over!
It is dead! It is redundant!
It... it never was!
And I do not want to waste
another second of my life
pretending it's something
worth saving!
♪ The static from your arms
♪ It is a catalyst
♪ You're a chemical that burns
♪ There is nothing like this. ♪
If anybody had told me
a few weeks ago
that I'd be sitting
up at Buckstones Ridge,
holding hands with a man
who isn't my husband,
and who's just driven me
here in his Lexus,
I'd have thought they were
pulling my leg.
Not that I'd have ever sat anywhere
holding hands with a man
who was my husband.
Kenneth wasn't
the hand-holding sort.
I mean, even before the trouble,
I don't think he'd a romantic bone
in his body.
And then after, when I'd found out
what a randy sod he'd been, well...
that put the tin lid on any sort
of... Anything resembling romantic.
I mean, I stopped going
anywhere with him socially.
I mean, he didn't know who knew
and who didn't.
And I work on the
principle it's always wise
to assume the worst.
I mean, it's not nice, is it?
Folk nudging each other, going,
"Ooh, that's her
"whose husband's at it with
all and sundry behind her back.
"I wonder if she knows, poor bitch.
"I wonder what she's not doing
that's making him look elsewhere."
So, you stop in. You don't go out.
And your world gets smaller.
I should have divorced him.
But it's easy to say,
with a child to bring up
and no money of your own.
And you see, I'd not worked.
I had no career.
I'd given up my job
when Caroline was born.
Women did in them days.
Could have killed him one time.
I mean, literally, I could have!
He was decorating the kitchen.
Painting the ceiling
up a little stepladder.
He was hopeless
at anything to do with DIY.
Anyway, he slipped
and banged his head.
He must have been out for... oh,
well, no more than a second or two.
But of course, I panicked.
Till he came to.
It was only afterwards
I realised I'd been slow.
And I decided if it ever
happened again I'd slip
a cushion over his face
and suffocate him.
Have I shocked you?
No.
Oh, God.
I'm sorry I go on about him.
No, no, no, no. I'm just sorry you...
you had it to go through.
I'm only telling you this
so you know what sort of a woman
you're marrying.
Do you fancy a pint in a pub?
I was thinking... Oh, aye?
Why don't you stop tonight
in Harrogate?
Oh, I don't mean anything untoward.
I've got a spare room.
Only it's going to be a long haul
for you otherwise,
taking me back to Harrogate
then setting off to Halifax.
And you were up
at the crack of dawn this morning.
I'd have to buy a toothbrush.
Raff?
Raffy?
Answer it.
'I can't take your call. Leave a
message and I'll ring you back.'
Raff, it's me.
Where are you?
Just ring me or... or text me.
I...I need to know where you are.
I'm sorry if I've upset you.
I know I've upset you.
But I need to know that you're all
right.
Oh, shit.
Gillian? Is Raff with you?
He is, yeah.
Is he all right?
Yeah, he's absolutely fine.
What's he said? Nothing.
Well, can I talk to him?
He's a bit busy at the minute.
He's on the Xbox.
Yeah? Well, get him off the f...
And to be frank I don't
think he'd want to talk with you.
I don't know what's happened,
other than him fighting
with that dickhead,
but I assume something has.
I assume that he's finally seen the
light and worked out what a mad
bitch you are,
so you know, if he wants to move
in here, that's fine by me.
I'm not keeping him here by force.
Don't you dare fill his head
with rubbish about me.
Will that be everything, then?
You just tell him to ring me!
Hello? John?
Yeah? It's Gillian.
Alan's daughter.
Gillian.
Sorry I had to ring off this morning.
Only the boss were breathing
down my neck and...
No, no, that's...
I thought nothing of it.
Good, good.
Good. So, how's things progressing?
Oh, she's having a little
coven in the garden
with some insipid little
witch that she works with.
Nice.
Lawrence says she's a lesbian.
God knows why Caroline's
invited her here.
You know what you said last night
about you having this
affair with this...
Judith?
Yeah? Well...
I did something similar and...
You did? Yeah, a...
stupid, stupid thing.
And Raff's found out,
and that's what that fight was about,
and he's gone to live with Robbie.
That's his uncle, the policeman.
And he's a right bastard and...
Bollocks!
It was exactly the same
when me and Richard got divorced.
Neither of us could afford
to buy the other one out
so we had to sell up,
split everything.
Right down the middle.
Beautiful house we had.
It was heartbreaking.
But you find a way forward.
I'm going to have to get
proper legal advice.
Yes, obviously.
I don't know what I'm talking about.
Don't you? I was being sarcastic.
I just said I've been through
exactly the same thing,
but, yes, you should get
proper legal advice.
Why are you being so snippy? Why?
What?
My dad's got Alzheimer's.
Did you know that?
God, I'm so sorry.
There's a million and one things
you don't know about me, Caroline...
cos you never ask, and I try not
to inflict things on people
unless I think
they're actually interested,
but I've never really had
the impression that you were,
but you just take it for granted
that I'll be interested in you.
Don't you? You offered
to come round.
Mm, but you rang me up.
After you'd dumped me. Shh.
You rang me up expecting me
to be sympathetic, which I am.
Not that it'll do me any good.
And then you're like a man.
You just make this decision
that I haven't got a clue
what I'm talking about
even though I've been through it.
I think you're overreacting.
You're reading things...
And then having a go at me last week
for talking to someone when
I was upset about what had
happened.
Someone who was sympathetic
and interested.
Michael bloody Dobson?
He tried to blackmail me.
He didn't. You'd better go.
Am I being dismissed?
I shouldn't have rang you up.
I'm sorry I did.
Don't say that.
I just want you to understand...
the effect you have on me.
If you ring me, I'll run round here,
even though I know you're not
really interested in me.
I'm not... not interested in you.
I'm...
I don't know what I am. I...
You're right, I've never asked
you anything about you,
and it's not because I don't...
It's because I'm selfish
and hopeless...
and you've been a really good
friend, and I don't know how to be
a good friend.
To anyone.
My parents never got on.
I grew up in a house on my own
with these people
who never spoke to each
other unless they had to,
and I thought that was normal.
And now she's met this bloke,
this Alan, and he's a sweet man,
and he thinks the world of her,
and she thinks the world of him,
and she's so different!
And I can't help wondering
if she'd been in love with my dad
and he'd been in love with her...
how different things
would have been.
I don't know what
normal relationships are like.
I see them,
but I don't know how to do them.
So I'm sorry.
I'm sorry if I've hurt you
or taken you for granted.
I will endeavour not to do that...
in the future.
Because I do value
your friendship and...
I'm sorry if I've never said
or made that clear or done what...
normal people do
to express these things.
So, I'm sorry.
Thank you.
I think you've got to give yourself
a break, Gillian, I really do.
He's 16 years old. Give him a week.
Give him a week
with Robbie's microwave cooking.
Give Robbie a week with a bloody
teenager in the house. You're right.
You know where he is. You know
he's safe. OK, he's had a shock.
He's found out his mother has sex.
Get over it.
I know, I know.
It's just life, you know?
And he has to realise
that you have...
you know, just like
everyone else does,
urges, feelings,
and when he's an adult,
he'll get it.
He will not look back on you
and make judgments.
He just needs a little bit of time.
Step back from it, Gillian.
I know it's not easy.
He's your boy, but,
if you can... Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, you're right, you're right.
Oh, kids.
Gosh.
So, how's things in the garden?
Oh, much the same.
Oh, God!
Paul. Jesus.
What's happened? Paul? What?
Who did this?
Who did it? Was it Raff?
Robbie?
OK. Come on.
Let's get you inside.
I think we should get you up
to the Princess Royal.
I'll be all right.
What happened?
Darren and Gavin.
Hayley's brothers found out
I'd been at it with you
so them and a couple of big
bastards laid into me.
So, I... I guess the
engagement's off, eh?!
You dirty sod.
They said they was going
to pour petrol over me
and set me on fire.
I believed them.
Let Granny in.
Thanks.
Morning! Hi.
Just to let you know...
Oh, you're very smart.
Me and Alan are popping
over to Halifax
to look at possible venues
for the wedding.
So I won't be here this evening.
I'll be stopping over at
Gillian's with Alan.
Right.
I'm sorry to pop over so early
but you'll be going to work so...
Brush your teeth.
Where are my shoes?
Wherever you left them.
He's very nervous.
He's got his first English paper.
He stopped over last night, Alan.
Yes, I assumed. I, um... saw the car.
He was going to sleep
in the spare bedroom but...
I don't know,
one thing led to another,
and I've got a double bed
and we are getting married so...
we shared the same bed.
OK.
I don't know what people'll think.
Well, good for you.
I just thought, "What the hell?"
What people?
I don't care. Anyone.
Right.
As I say, it's not as though
we're not getting married,
cos we are, so...
So?
You don't mind? Me? No.
No, of course not.
So... It's great.
I'm talking about sex.
Yes, I realise that.
It was marvellous.
I'd forgotten.
I can be quite a romantic,
when push comes to shove,
not that your dad ever appreciated
that. Oh, can you not just...?
What? Well, it's...
Oh. Have I embarrassed you?
I don't need to know.
It's fine, it's fine.
Whatever you do, it's fine, it's
good. You're adults. It's...
I thought you might be happy for me.
I am. I am!
I love you, you know.
I know you do.
I can't get through
to our Gillian.
She's not answering
her mobile or anything.
Can I get you some more tea?
No, no. No, no, I'm fine.
Another egg? No, thanks.
Sorry, what did you say?
Something about Gillian?
Right, where to?
I can't go home.
My dad's chucked me out and my mam
says she never wants to clap eyes
on me again.
I'm not giving you Raffy's room.
Hello?
John? It's Judith.
What do you want?
Er... I, um...
You shouldn't ring this number.
What if Caroline had answered it?
Isn't she at work?
What do you want?
You couldn't lend me some money,
could you?
It's just that the landlord's
getting... unpleasant with me
about the rent arrears and...
You get benefits for that.
Yeah, yeah.
The thing is...
I've spent it. Oh, Jesus.
And you don't want me turning up
on your doorstep, do you?
I must have spent hours in
here when I was a kid.
Yeah, so did I.
I always tried to, er... wangle it
so that we'd sit somewhere
where I could gaze at you.
You didn't? You daft article.
You were the only thing
that made it bearable.
I hated it, church.
I used to get so bored and miserable.
Yeah, well.
Mind you, it's better than all this
happy-clappy stuff they have now.
Mm? Do you want a mint?
Is it? Why? At least with
the happy-clappy stuff,
people actually look like
they want to be there.
Well, it's not proper, is it?
They have pop songs at funerals now.
Yeah? So what?
Pop songs at funerals?
Religion when we were kids
was all about control.
It was about the ruling classes
being hand in glove with the Church
to keep the ordinary hard-working
people terrified of having a mind of
their own.
Was it hell?! No, it was.
You think about it.
I won't get into a debate.
Why shouldn't you have
a pop song at a funeral
if it's something that you've liked,
something that's meant something to
you?
Pop songs are for... for discos
and pubs and social clubs.
In church you sing hymns.
Pop songs at funerals
are about ordinary folk celebrating
whatever, in their own way,
not accepting what's inflicted on
them by people in high places,
who just want to keep everybody
frightened and miserable.
Well...
some people need people
in high places to tell them
what's what now and again.
You're going to tell me next
you voted for Margaret Thatcher.
Well, you can't have liked
Michael Foot?
In his anorak at the Cenotaph?
A very intelligent man, Michael Foot.
Oh, he can't have been that
intelligent
or he wouldn't have gone around
looking like a scarecrow.
I didn't dislike Tony Blair... Oh!
Until he muckied his ticket
in Iraq.
Now, Gordon Brown,
there's a much-maligned man.
Gordon Brown? Mm.
Trying to get everybody to like him,
with his phoney grin?
And he's Scottish.
Now, there's an unassailable
political argument!
Well, it hardly needs pointing
out he buggered up the economy.
No, he didn't.
He did not. He had vision.
Oh, God. I can see this is a subject
we're going to have to avoid.
No, don't worry, I'll teach you.
You damn well won't.
Yeah, we'll buy you
a copy of the Guardian.
You can keep your Guardian.
I thought I spotted a Daily Mail
lurking in your recycling bin.
What's wrong with the Daily Mail?
What's wrong with it?
What's right with it?
Do you know, I'd never have
had you down for red-hot Labour.
I thought you had more about you.
Do you know,
the good thing about David Cameron
is that even he knows he's an arse!
No, every time he opens his mouth,
you can see him thinking,
"I was born an arse,
I'll die an arse, but at
least I know I'm an arse."
You've suddenly got very coarse,
Mr Buttershaw.
So, what will you be walking
down the aisle to, then? Mm?
Jerusalem? Rule Britannia?
The Arrival Of The Queen Of Sheba.
What?
No, no, that's...
What?!
It's very appropriate!
Mm, I'd turn up for that.
I can see how I'm going to have
to re-educate you, Alan Buttershaw.
Does that mean I get to choose
the music we walk out to?
Hell, no.
It's become screamingly obvious
I can't trust you any further
than I could chuck you.
Hey.
I forgot we're in church.
We've been swearing like troopers.
Well, we'd better find t'vicar, then.
If this is what you want.
Well, not if you think
I'm oppressing the masses.
Oh, it'll be worth oppressing
the masses for half an hour or so
to see you arriving
like the Queen of Sheba.
I hope it isn't a woman.
Who?
The vicar.
If you're insisting on a Saturday
slot, you're looking at four...
five months away.
I think sooner rather than later.
Mm.
Are either of you divorced?
No. No, no.
Widowed.
And you're both regular churchgoers,
obviously?
Well, we have been in the past.
Hm.
So, you're not regular churchgoers
now?
Not... No.
When did you last go to church?
Er... Christmas?
19...oh, er...
77?
What about you,
Mrs Dawson? About the same.
Mm.
So, why do you want God's blessing,
if you don't go to church?
I'm just interested.
We thought he might like the trade.
Miserable bitch!
I mean, no wonder folk don't go.
Oh, we could live over t'brush.
Ah, but then you wouldn't be
Mrs Buttershaw.
No, and I fancy having a do.
I want to buy a hat.
Oh, we could find another vicar.
I bet they're not all like that.
No, she's put me off. That's it,
now, with me and the Church. End of.
Good night, Vienna.
I've left the building.
Well, where would you like
to get wed?
Cos, I mean, you can get
wed anywhere now, you know.
Oh, somewhere classy.
Oh, yeah.
South Ouram Hall.
Oh, I used to love South Ouram Hall.
Is it still there?
Yeah, yeah, far as I know.
They've not mucked it up?
No, I think
it's just as creepy as it ever were.
What's he doing here? It's my house.
Slapper.
Yeah, whatever.
What do you mean? Is this what...?
You and him?
Right. I'm off upstairs
to get the rest of my stuff.
I'll be outside.
You really do need
your head examined.
Ah! Ah!
Oh! Oh!
Hello? Shop?
What, nobody about?
No, doesn't look like it.
Hello?
My cousin Alice
saw a ghost here once.
Where? Er... upstairs.
What was it like?
A woman.
Don't go.
I can't chuck him out.
He's got nowhere else to go.
I'll... I'll go.
You can't! You... You can't.
Don't.
I...I think it were this room.
Er... she came through that door.
She walked across here...
and disappeared through that wall.
Ooh.
Shall we go?
Power cut. Let's go.
Oh!
Hello? Is anybody there?
Hello?
Hello? Telephone.
I've got no reception.
Neither have I.
What the...
Oh... No...
Do you think anyone's
realised that we're missing?
I just worry about my dad having
his pills on him for his heart.
There's somebody up there.
How do you know he hasn't
taken her to some hotel
for a wild night
of nudge-nudge, wink-wink?
Where the hell are they?
Why's the car there and
them not in it? You still have to
stay sober long enough
to actually get it down
in black and white. Piss off!
Do you think they're dead?
What were you doing with that
dipstick? Did you torch my
Land Rover?
I'm not living with you while you're
having it off with someone else.
Well, you know where the door is.
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.