| Winterfell |
SUBTITLE MADE BY : ABU SAyED ABDULLAH
| driftmark |
here you are
The sea serpent will die, right?
... (Luke) -
I can't be the lord of the waves
My grandfather was the greatest sailor the world had ever seen
As for me, I get seasick
Before the ships leave the port until
I will spoil everything
"I don't want to rule" Driftmark
Sir Vimond should have inherited it.
We can't choose our destiny, Luke.
Our destiny has the upper hand
My grandfather allowed you to choose whether you wanted to be his heir
This is what you said yourself
And... would you like to know the whole truth?
I was terrified
I was 14 years old as you are now
And I wasn't ready to be the Queen of the Seven Kingdoms
But... it was my duty
And over time I realized that I should be worthy of my inheritance too
I don't look like you
From what side, my dear son?
... I'm not
so perfect
I am far from ideal
My father took care of me and helped me prepare to fulfill my duties
And your mother will do the same for you
Good morning, Your Highness
Good morning, Sir Laurent.
Princess Rennes just arrived by dragon
I have requested an urgent meeting with you and Your Highness, Prince Damon.
Princess Renee Targaryen
Thank you, Sir Laurent.
Princess Rennes, shall we expect news of Lord Corliss' recovery?
Viserys is dead
And I'm sad to lose him with you too, Rinera.
...my cousin
Your father had a good heart
That's not all
Egon has been crowned as his successor
They crowned him?
How did Viserys die?
I can't say for sure
Since when ? -
It's been a day or two -
I was locked up in my room while the Queen made preparations
Viserys was definitely killed
And Aliscent told you to kneel to Aegon?
Already done
And she refused
Yet you're still alive
The High Priest himself crowned Aegon in the Dome of Dragons
I witnessed it with my own eyes before I ran off on Melis' back.
They crowned him in public?
To prove to the public that it is their rightful property
That bitch queen killed my brother and stole his throne
And you could have burned them all because of that
I'm as sure of a war as I'm sure of their betrayal
But it's not my war to wage it myself
I was in a hurry to warn you only out of loyalty to my husband and my clan
The Green Hightowers are coming to get you, Rinera.
And from your children
You should leave Dragonstone immediately
The baby will be born now
Your pregnancy isn't complete yet, this shouldn't happen now
! But it's happening right now
Calm down, Your Highness Princess, come
You've done this five times before
Keep your spirits, and this time will not be different
!! Away! Away! get away
I want patrols around the island in search of
What small ships might anchor here?
If they attack us now, the attack will be hidden
And not directly
We don't have enough men to surround the island
But we can create the illusion that we are stronger than they are
You can also make use of the Dragon Guard
They are good fighters
And don't waste time
Everything will be done, Your Highness
What was it you just did? -
I am sorry -
Perhaps you would like to be a little indulgent with him, Your Highness
So that he can learn what you are trying to teach him
Your mother would like to meet you
both of you
Mom ?
the curse
your Majesty
Your grandfather, King Viserys, passed away
(Viserys)?
The Green Party denied the Caliphate and seized the Iron Throne
Aegon is crowned king
And what are we going to do about it? -
nothing yet -
And where is Damon?
I don't know.. he lost his mind
Hurry up to plan war
I'll take care of Damon myself
... (Jess)
( geysers )
Whatever right I have to claim the throne, you are now his heir
I forbid you to take any action without my orders
I got a message this morning
It states that the serpent of the sailor has recovered and left Evenfull
And where is it headed? -
It is not clear yet, Your Highness.
We must send letters to our closest allies
Lords Darkling, Massey and Barmond.
! (Damon)
Would you like to speak to the wise, Your Highness?
I'll fly to Riverless myself and get Lord Tully's support.
You won't
My mother was ordered to refrain from any procedure while she was in childbirth
It's good that you're here, little prince
We need you to secure the airspace on the back of Fermax.
Did you hear what I just said?
Handle the letters, Lord Bartmus.
I'll take care of it
Summon Sir Stefon.
The Royal Guard is wanted on the Dragon Bridge
Come with me, I will show you the true meaning of loyalty
You swore a covenant as a royal guard
As did anyone who wears the white cloak, Your Highness
To whom ?
I swore the first time to King Jerrys, Your Highness
And then to His Majesty the King (Viserys) when he succeeded him
Do you recognize the entitlement of the caliphate dynasty?
yes -
Yes, Your Highness.
Do you remember who chose King Viserys as his successor before his death?
Princess Rinera
I am grateful for your service to the property for such a long time
And that is why I will give you an option
Renew your vows to Rinera by acknowledging that she is the Queen
And Prince Jesiris is heir to the Iron Throne
...and only
If you support the usurper of the throne, confess now
And you will have a quick and honorable death
... but if you choose betrayal
If you swear allegiance now, you will betray us later
... be sure that you two will die
screaming in pain
Princess, let us help you
!! get out
Please, Your Highness
get out of here -
You shouldn't do this alone, Your Highness.
Let us help you
I do not intend to harm my brothers
I swear to use my power to protect the Queen
And redeem it with my blood
.. I will not marry any woman
...and I won't have anything
And I will have no offspring
I will keep her secrets and obey her orders
I will stand by her side and defend her name and honor
my queen
Queen Rinera Targaryen, the first bearer of her name
Queen of the Andalus and Ruinar peoples and the first ancestors
Lady of the Seven Kingdoms and protector of the kingdom
Your Majesty
Here's the wine, my queen
Thank you, Rina.
come
What is our current position?
We have 30 knights, 100 crossbows and 300 armed men
Easy to defend "Dragonstone" but in terms of invasion
The army is still missing a lot
I sent letters to my loyalists from the city guard
I'll have some support there, but I can't tell how many they will be
We already have keltigar and staunton back up.
Massey, Darklin and Barmond.
My mother was a lady of the Arin clan
The peoples of the valley will not betray the will of their king
The rulers of Riveran have always been close friends of your father, Your Majesty
After Prince Damon agreed, I already sent a letter to Lord Grover
Lord Grover is vacillating and easy to persuade
We must be sure of the strength of our position
And support us if we go to war
I will deal with him myself
What about "Storms' End" and "Winterfell"?
We've never seen a Stark betray a covenant
And with the support of the Stark clan, the entire North will support us
Lord (Burse Baratheon) must be reminded of his father's reign
And what's the news about Driftmark?
Lord Corliss is sailing towards the Dragon Stone
To declare allegiance to his queen
The Villaria fleet is under my husband's command
It is he who decides where to sail
We will pray for your support and your husband's support for us
As we used to pray every night for the healing of the sea serpent
There is no harbor by the narrow sea
He might want to antagonize the Villaria fleet
What about our enemies?
We certainly have no friends in the Lannister clan
And (Thailand) served the King's aide for a long time
And he will not betray him
And Otto Hightower needs the Lannister fleet
Without the Lannister clan, we are unlikely to have
On any western allies, Golden Tooth
both
Riverland is essential, Your Majesty
Forgive my frankness, Your Majesty
But the discussion about humans is useless
Your court has powers the world has never seen
Since the Old Testament of Philaria
dragons
The Green Party has dragons too
They have three mature dragons by my calculations
And we have Syracuses, Keraxes and Melis.
Your sons have Vermax, Arax and Tyrax.
Bella has a moondancer.
Damon, none of our dragons participated in a war before
There are also dragons without patrons
Sismoke is still at driftmark
Fermathur and Silverwing on Dragon Mountain
They are still without horses
And there are also three wild dragons, they all live here
And who will lead it?
There are 13 dragons in addition to the original four
I also have some eggs in the incubator on Dragon Mountain
We need a gathering point, a base big enough to fit us
Here at Harrenhal, we will isolate the West like this
We surround Kingslanding with dragons
This is how we can eliminate all members of the Green Party before the end of the damned month
Your Majesty, a ship has been spotted off the harbor
"Big Ship Flying the Flag" Three Green Dragon Heads
Inform the control teams, and watch the air range
I'm here on behalf of the Queen Dowager Alicent.
King's mother (Aegon), the second bearer of his name
Lord and protector of the Seven Kingdoms
I received orders to deliver her message to Princess Rinira only
Where is your highness princess?
HRH Princess Rinera
I am Queen Rinera now
And you are all traitors to the kingdom
King (Aegon Targaryen) is the second bearer of his name
In his wisdom and desire for peace, he offered negotiating terms
Confess Aegon as king
And I swear to obey the Sovereignty of the Iron Throne
And in return, His Majesty will acknowledge your ownership of the Dragon Stone
And your firstborn son (Jeseris) will inherit it at your death
The right to succession to Luceres will be recognized by Driftmark
And all the lands and possessions of the Villaria clan
And your sons who are descendants of Prince (Damon) will also receive a high position in the royal court
Little Egon will be carrying his shields
And Viserys will bear his cup
And finally, the king in good faith
He will pardon any knight or lord who conspires against his ascension to the throne
I'd rather feed my sons to dragons before I make them pregnant
Shields and cups
For the sake of your king, the usurper, the drunken asshole
Aegon Targaryen ascends the Iron Throne
He wears the crown of the victor and carries his sword
And bears the name of the victor
He was crowned by a religious priest in front of thousands of commoners
And all conditions of eligibility belong to him
There are also the Stark, Baratheon and Tully clans
Those who have also received and are currently considering adequate terms from the King
The Stark, Tully and Parthion clans swore allegiance to me
When King Viserys chose me as his heir
Old Testaments won't put you on the Iron Throne, Princess
The dynasty of the caliphate changed the day your father's first son was born
What I regret is that you and he were the last to comprehend this
You are not the king's assistant, as Egon is not the king
You damn traitor
High Priest
What the fuck is this?
Queen Aliscent has not forgotten the love that once brought you together
No need for bloodshed
May the kingdom go on living in peace
Queen Aliscent is eagerly waiting for your answer
She can get her answer right away
Inside her father's mouth with some of his dismembered organs
We will not end this farce
Sir Eric, bring me Lord Hightower.
To have the honor of killing him myself
both
Tomorrow, King's Landing will receive my answer
It's not easy for humans to be dragon slayers
But dragons can kill humans,
I have done this before
But the obvious fact is that we have
More dragons than Aegon
The Wisers talk a lot about the history of the Valerians.
I know this very well
When dragons fly to war, everything burns
I didn't want to rule a kingdom full of ashes and bones
Would you consider accepting the terms of Clan Hightower, Your Majesty?
As Queen, what are my true duties to the kingdom, Lord (Bartimus)?
To make sure that peace and unity are spread
Or sit on the Iron Throne at all costs?
This is what your father said
My father passed away
I chose to be his heir
To protect the kingdom, not to enter it with all-out war
Our enemy has declared war
What are you going to do about it?
clear the room
Does the prospect of war excite you?
You can't submit to the Hightower clan.
They stole your rights
If you could seize the Iron Throne
Without putting the head of Otto Hightower.
on shaft
- Would you do that?
- Aren't you angry?
Should I teach war because I am angry?
No, but your duty as a queen is to quell rebellions
You know my oath is beyond our personal ambitions
A song of ice and fire
What?
The coming war against darkness in the north
victor's dream
Viserys told me this when he made me heiress
My brother was a slave to prophecies and ominous signs
He would do anything to make his weak judgment purposeful
It is not dreams that make us kings
But the dragons did
He never told you
Right?
I flog men for sleeping during probation time
You are not a man
You left me when I needed you most
Both of our children were kidnapped from us
I need you
Bella and Bina needed you
And you left us for more adventures at sea
Like I always did
I had nowhere else to turn to
I lost everything
We lost, Corliss.
we
I heard we have a new king
The stranger casts his long shadow over this family
Your brother died too
Hurry up to bury you and claim your place
He stood before the king and announced that Lenore's children
They are illegitimate children
Damon killed him because of it
It has always been an ambitious ambition
A weak point in the valerian family.
You were right, Raines.
I longed for so much,
And it was in vain
Our ambition to win the Iron Throne
come to an end
We will not support anyone anymore
We'll go to Hightide and have our grandchildren suffice
Jace, Luke, and Geoff.
Crown Princes
These boys will not be safe
As long as Aegon was the king
Rinera was complicit in the death of our son
That girl destroys everything she touches
That girl is the one who brings the kingdom's diaspora together right now
All the men standing around the table
They pleaded with her to send men to war
Rinera was the only one who...
Show self-control
The purpose of war is to fill the graves, dear Lord Staunton.
The trick is to bury more of them and less of us
It is easy for a commander to say this to protect his fortress
- That doesn't make it untrue
- Lord (Tide)
Lord (Corlis Valerian)
And his wife, Princess Reigns Targaryen.
Gentlemen
Lord (Corlis)
It's comforting to see you standing and healthy again
I'm so sorry about your father princess he was a good man
Where is Damon?
There are other matters of interest to the Prince at the moment
Are these your avowed allies?
yes
They are less than winning a battle for the throne
We were also hoping for the support of the Irene, Baratheon, and Stark clans.
Hope is the ally of fools
Both clans of Irene and Baratheon.
They share blood with my family
But they all swore allegiance to me
Like the Hightower clan did, as I remember
As you did, Lord Corliss.
Your father's kingdom was all about justice and honor
Our families share blood and purpose
This Hightower clan's treachery cannot be accepted
You have the full support of our fleet and our family
Your Majesty
It is an honor for me, Lord Corliss.
Princess (Rennes)
But as I said to the banner campaign
I promised my father to keep the kingdom strong and united
If war breaks out
It won't be the first blow on my hand
Do you not intend to attack?
Caution does not mean inaction
I would like to know who my allies are before I send them to war
As a result of my imminent death in the Step Stones.
is that we rule it now
This time I made sure to leave a garrison in the field
In a matter of days there will be a complete blockade of the shipping lanes
That is if they haven't already
The Trinity was defeated, and the sea became ours again
If we close the entrance
We can cut off all trade and sea travel to the king's lands
I'll take Melis and secure the entrance myself
When we close the narrow entrance to the sea
We can besiege the king's lands and besiege the red castle
We force the Green Party to surrender
If we had enough soldiers to besiege the king's lands
First we have to make sure that we support
The Winterfell, Hutch, and Storm Edge clans.
I will prepare the crows, my lady
We have to send these messages
Dragons can fly faster than crows
It is more persuasive
Send us
The prince is right, my lady
Good
Prince Jesiris will fly north
First to the Bekaa for my mother's cousin, Lady Jane Irene.
And then to Winterville.
Discuss it with Lord Kerrigan Stark to get support from the North
Prince Luceres will fly south to Storm's End
And he makes a pact with Lord Boros Baratheon.
We have to remind these lords of the promises they swore
And what will it cost them if they violate it?
They say we are a Targaryen clan.
Closer to God than humans
And maybe the Iron Throne puts us a little closer
But, if we were to serve the Seven Kingdoms
We must respond to their gods
If you accept this task,
You will go as messengers, not as warriors
You should not take part in any fight
I swear it now before the seven gods
I swear by this
Thank you
Kerrigan Stark is closer to your age than me
I hope you guys find common interests
present my lady
Storms and End near here
The blood of the Baratheon clan runs through your veins
From your grandmother's side, Raines.
And Lord Burroughs is a very proud man
It is an honor for him to host the prince of the kingdom and his dragon
I expect you to get a warm reception
Present mom, I mean madam
go then
I am Prince (Luciris Valerian)
I bring a letter from the Queen to Lord Boros.
Prince (Luciris Valerian)
Son of Princess Rinera Targaryen
Lord (Poros)
I bring you a message from my mother
the Queen
But I received a letter from the King earlier today
So what will it be, king or queen?
Looks like the Dragon Family doesn't know who's ruling it right now
What is your mother's message?
Where is the damn world?
Remind me of my dad's oath?
At least King Aegon made an offer
My soldiers and flag bearers in exchange for a marriage agreement
If you do what your mother asks
Which of my daughters will you marry?
boy?
Sir, I am not available for marriage
I'm already engaged
So I came with empty hands
Go home, baby
And tell your mother that the lord of clan Storm
not a dog
She can call him when she needs to to unleash him against her enemies
I will pass your answer to the Queen, sir
Slown down
Oh Lord (Strong)
Did you really think you could fly to the kingdom
Trying to steal my brother's throne without paying a price?
I won't fight you
I came as a messenger, not as a warrior
The fight will be a simple challenge
no
I want you to gouge out your eye
price for my eyes
One will do
I will not blind you
I intend to give it as a gift to my mother
no
So you are a coward and a traitor
- not here!
- Give me your eye, or I'll rip it out, you bastard!
Not in my castle
The boy came as a messenger
I will not allow blood to be spilled in my place
Escort Prince Luceres to his dragon
right Now
to focus!
Watch out, Arax.
be quiet!
listen!
obey
Fly oh (Arax)
Run away you bastard
Hurry up, turn around
you have a religion
Oh boy!
No, Arax!
No, Arax, obey my commands
No, no, no, no, Vigar.
No, Vigar, obey my orders, fly up, Vigar.
No, Vigar, no, no
SUBTITLE MADE BY : ABU SAyED ABDULLAH