Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
It has been said that magic vanish
- From our world a long time ago
And through the power of wishes
To those of who lost the wondrous vision of childhood eyes
Submitted here is the story of a little boy,
and a magical Christmas wish,
that changed his life... forever.
It began in 1985,
in a town just outside Boston.
It was Christmas eve,
and all the children were in high spirits.
That special time of year,
when Boston children gather together
- and beat up the Jewish kids.
- Hey green bob! Get him!
But there was one child who
wasn't in such good spirits,
little John Bennett.
That one boy in every neighbourhood,
who just has a tough time making friends.
Hey guys, can I play?
- Get out of here Benet!
- Get lost Benet!
- Get out of here Benet.
- Yeah Benet, get lost.
John longed with all his heart, for that
one true friend that he could call his own
and he knew that if he ever found
that friend, he would ever let him go
well, as it does every year,
Christmas morning finally came
all of the children were opening
their gifts with holiday glee
and for little John Benet, Christmas day
brought a very special new arrival.
Wow. I guess Santa played attention
to how good you were this year huh...
aww, merry Christmas John
"I love you"
He talks.
I'm going to name you Teddy.
John became instantly attached to teddy,
there was something about that bear
that made him feel as if he finally had a friend.
with whom he could share his deepest secrets
"I love you"
I love you too teddy
you know, I wish you could really talk to me
because then we could be best
friends forever and ever
now if there’s one thing
you can be sure of,
it’s that nothing is more powerful
than a young boys wish
except an apache helicopter...
an apache helicopter
has machine guns and missiles
it is an unbelievably impressive
complement of weaponry.
An absolute death machine
Well, as it turned out, John had picked
a perfect night to make a wish.
Teddy...
Teddy?
Hug me.
You're my best friend John.
Did you... did you just talk...
don’t look so surprised, you’re the one
who wished for it aren’t you?
Yeah...
I did wish for it.
Well, here I am...
you mean... we get to
be best friends for real?
for... real.
forever and ever?
sounds good to me
John was just about the happiest boy in the world.
And he couldn't wait to tell everyone the good news
mom... dad... guess what,
my teddy bears alive
really... oh isn’t that exciting...
No mom, he's really alive.
Look.
merry Christmas everybody
Jesus H Fuck...
- lets all be best friends.
Oh my god.
get away from that thing,
get over here right now.
but dad...
Get over here!
- Listen to your father, come here.
- Helen, get my gun.
Dad, no!
Is it a hugging gun?
Helen, get my gun and call the police
I’m sorry Mr. Benet, I didn’t
mean to scare anybody
I just wanted john and I to be friends
yeah dad, I made a wish last night that
teddy was alive, and my wish came true
Oh god.
It's a miracle.
It's a Christmas miracle.
You're just like the baby Jesus.
well it wasn’t long before the news of
Johns little miracle was sweeping the nation
out of a Boston suburb comes, what is
without doubt the most incredible story
a young boys stuffed animal, has
magically come to life for unknown reasons
LOOK WHAT JESUS DID!
before long, teddy had become a
huge celebrity in his own right
Hello, Teddy.
you surprise me, for some reason I
thought you were going to be taller
I thought you were
going to be funnier.
but for all the fame, teddy never
forgot his very best friend, John
the thunder can’t get us, right?
nope. were thunder buddy’s.
and the thunder knows it
were totally safe
- Teddy.
- Yeah, John?
do you promise that
we'll always be together?
I promise.
thunder buddy’s for life
thunder buddy’s for life.
and that was a promise that
neither one of them forgot
so... where are John and teddy today?
well, let me put it this way
no matter how big a splash you make
in this world, weather you’re a
Corey Feldman, Frankie Muniz,
Justin Bibber...
or a talking teddy bear...
eventually nobody gives a shit.
TED
Look, all I’m saying is that Boston
women are, on the whole,
a paler uglier sort than women
from the elsewhere’s of life.
That's bullshit... what about Lori?
she's hot.
No Lori's from Pennsylvania
that’s not a Boston girl
there not that bad...
see, the fact that you have to say there
not that bad, means that they are that bad
you ever hear a Boston girl have an orgasm?
oh yah, oh yah, harder harder
oh god... that was so good. now I’m going
to stuff my fucking face with pepper flan
Jesus this is weak,
not even getting me high
I’m going to have a talk
with my weed guy
working for me...
I think it sucks, I’m going to have
a talk with him
I don’t know you want to go to
a drug dealer with complaints
I’ve known this guy a long time,
I’ve known him since 9-11
you remember?, I was like,
aww shit 9-11, I got to get high
is it 9.30?
- yeah...
shit, I got to get to work
I don’t know if I can drive
It's ok. I'll drive you.
I feel fine.
- Fuck.
- Aww, shit.
Aww, Johnny I'm sorry man,
that car just came out of nowhere.
Aww, god is it bad?
- John, may I speak with you please?
- Shit.
it’s alright, go go go.
I’ll pull out of here
hi Thomas, how are yah
Asshole!
That’s my bad,
I was sending a tweet.
John, its almost 10 o'clock
I know sir, I’m sorry
it wasn’t my fault
what do you mean?
well I.. I guess I wasn’t prepared
for a follow up question
John, all you got to
do is not fuck up
and you get my job when
I go to corporate next month
you’re the new branch manager
all you got to do, is not fuck up...
I realise now
- good, glad to hear it.
cos in a month... my life,
could be your life.
a cushy 38 thousand dollar a year
branch manager,
who’s personal
friends with Tom Scarritt.
Not a bad life is it?
no.
let me show you something I don’t
like showing people,
'cos I don’t want
them treating me differently.
boom! that’s me and scarritt
wow...
god damn right wow
I’m going to dock you for dinging the car
and for showing up late today alright
try and be a little more
responsible tomorrow
I will sir, I promise.
"not going to let you down goose"
what?
Top Gun...
so...
Tom Scarritt...
I know that
get out of here ok
thank you sir
and hers your keys, rental agreement,
complimentary map of Boston
thank you for choosing liberty,
drive safely
thanks
- thanks so much.
heard you got busted...
Jesus Guy, you look like shit man
what happened?
I don’t know,
I got fucking wasted last night
and my phone says I texted someone at
3.15, asking them to beat me up
and then at 4.30 I texted the
same person saying thanks.
- And you don’t remember it?
- No, same as last time.
It just seems kind of gay doesn’t it?
I don’t know, maybe yeah.
Do you think your part of some gay
beat up underworld?
Like one of those gay beat
up clubs or something?
I don’t know, I dig chicks man,
I don’t remember any of it
I was so fucked up.
I might be gay I don’t know.
do you mind covering
for me for a bit?
I might go lay down in the John
hey buddy’s, where’s it hanging?
- hey Alex
what's up?
you get in the club last night?
ahh, I didn’t get in because
the bouncer was douche face
but I make friends in the line
well that’s good I guess.
Hey guys, anybody know a nice restaurant?
Like something where they give out
free bubblegum in the bathrooms.
For what?
Lori and I have been dating 4 years tomorrow.
I want to take her some place really nice.
aw, congratulations John.
You guys have been going out for 4 years?
My last relationship lasted 6 months.
Then she farted in her sleep.
I'm like, I'm out of here man.
And I was gone before she woke up.
wow you’re not very tolerant huh...
Lori ever fart in front of you?
Yeah.
- Really?
- A million times.
You Italian?
No.
Why?
never mind, take her to binate
John look, don’t you think after 4 years maybe
she’s hoping for something more than dinner?
like what?
I don’t know. but if it were me,
I’d be expecting a proposal
oh come on, no one’s expecting
anybody to propose...
I mean marriage isn’t... I mean...
isn’t love enough? I submit love is enough
you can put the ring in her ass...
and let her fart it out?
so bad, but so good...
Hey by the way, don’t let me forget you and I got to
nail down a plan for the ruins game tomorrow night.
Oh no I can’t,
I'm taking Lori to dinner.
For what?
Well, we’ve been dating
4 years tomorrow.
Ohh... fuck me, nice.
Let me ask you something,
you don't think she’s going to be
expecting something big, do you?
What... like anal?
- No...
like a circular gold
thing on the finger.
Oh fuck that. it’s been 4 years Johnny
you and me have been together for 27 years.
Where’s my ring?
Huh...
where’s my ring asshole...
where’s my ring motherfucker?
Put it on my
- fuzzy finger you fuck.
- Alright knock it off
I'm just saying...
do you think she might be expecting
me to make that kind of a move?
no no no, I don’t think
and not only that,
it’s the wrong time
it’s a terrible idea, you got the economy,
you got the credit bubble, the supreme court
look at Haiti
I guess I didn’t think about that.
Well, you know, it's a factor.
- Who are you? -Flash Gordon,
quarterback, New York Jets.
This is the American
fantasy right here.
- A professional NFL player is called
upon to save the world. -Yeah.
Tom Brady could do that...
Tom Brady could do that.
- Hey.
- Hey sweetie.
Hey, Lori.
Hi.
- What you got there?
- turkey burgers
oh turkey burgers, are we having
homosexuals over for dinner?
- tonight is it?
- Ha, not just you homos.
You kind a just re-worded my joke,
but haaaa.
how was work?
- oh it was fine
haws your dickhead boss?
Rex, is fine.
he only hit on me once today so,
it’s a good thing
hey Johnny how about a beer huh?
oh couple of chowbukowskis...
couple of brewstoievskis...
maybe a mibrewstowsky?
perhaps a teddybrewski...
that’s a good one
I think I too want a
Martina navratilovaski
oh... no no no
that doesn’t work
Bullshit...
that totally worked...
no, no
yeah it does,
- it doesn’t work
the name has to have a ski at the end of it, and you
just put brewski at the end of Martina Navratilova
I just thought we
were saying funny names
No, no. It has to have ski at the end of it,
otherwise where's the challenge?
If there’s no ski at the end of the root word,
then we'd just be idiots saying nonsense.
- Hey.
- They found the missing hikers.
- They did?
- Yeah. -What happened?
they said
they got separated, and one of them had
there foot stuck under a rock for like 5 days
you know, if your leg got trapped under
a rock, id chew it off to get you free
you would?
- I sure would
is that cannibalism?
No, I think it’s only cannibalism
if you swallow.
Oh yeah, don't worry about that,
'cos I don’t swallow.
Really? 'cos that's not what I heard.
well it’s not true ok,
I’m a classy broad
yeah
I can see that
umm, listen, speaking of classy
chow belles a really expensive restaurant
so we can go anywhere else tomorrow.
I really don’t care as long as were together
are you kidding me?
no, 4 years we've been going out...
I’m taking you to the best place in town
I love you
I love you too.
- and your nasty
you want to get nasty?
nasty girl
I don’t understand... 35 years old and
your still scared of a little thunder
I am not
thunder buddy’s for life right Johnny
- fucking right.
alright
come on lets sing
the thunder song
when you hear the sound of thunder
don’t you get too scared.
just grab your thunder buddy,
and say these magic words
fuck you thunder...
you can suck my dick,
you can’t get me thunder,
cos your just gods fart
hey Lori... can you set the alarm for 11 A.M?
I got allot of stuff to do tomorrow
hi Lori
morning
ok
you ok there sweetheart?
you look a little flustered
I’m fine, I just didn’t have time for breakfast
and the garage was full
ohh and that’s right, my boyfriend
can’t sleep through a thunder storm
without his teddy bear
I don’t understand why you
keep putting up with him...
yeah, the guys 35 and he’s working
for a rental car service...
you guys, it’s not about that.
I don’t care about that
I’d love him if he was a janitor
he has a huge heart
and we laugh allot
it’s just a bonus that he’s like
the hottest guy in Boston
I don’t know, I just wish hed
get his life together
our life... and he can’t. and I swear
to god it is because of that bear
you should give him an ultimatum,
it’s you or the bear
no, I can’t do that.
that would devastate him
besides, what...
what if he chose ted?
well hello there, sorry if I’m interrupting any
girl talk about Channing Tatum's index finger
but Lori, I need to
see you in my office
the thing is Rex, I have allot
of work I need to get through
oh this is work I swear
ugh great.
good luck,
- thank you
he’s such an asshole
- out of control...
he’s such a sleaze. 100 bucks says
he’s showing her the diving photo
check this out
it’s me on the
high school diving team
we dove the shit out
of the pool that year
you promised me
this was about work
Lori... why don’t you like me?
I’m rich,im good looking,
my dad owns the company...
I have a boyfriend.
I have told you this.
yeah, the guy with the bear
but I’m talking about a
mature relationship Lori
if we were together, our
babies would be spectacular
I mean, my top of the
pyramid Caucasian genes
and your splash of... dark... beautiful...
Smokey... Baltic...
Czech?
- goodbye Rex
ok, that was perfect
would you like me to
wrap your leftovers?
No, I'm good, thank you.
Actually, could you wrap just this up for me
please? I want to scare the shit out of somebody.
Sure.
what are you, like 5 years old?
- yeah
but I read at a 6
year old level, so...
sir... and madam
here is your desert,
and champagne
Ohh, crystal.
It's a special night,
we've been dating for 4 years.
And hey, all those rich black people
can’t be wrong, right?
doesn’t feel like 4 years does it?
no it doesn’t
you know, you had no business being out on that
dance floor. But I’m really happy that you were
this song is so great
oh yeah, Chris Brown
can do no wrong
wow you can really move
you like that huh?
check this shit out
oh my god
are you ok?
oh god, I am so sorry
I’m fine,im fine
Jesus I’m so sorry, I didn’t see
you it was an accident
did you hurt your head?
- yeah
my head hurts allot
oh man, here,
let me get you some ice
sorry... sorry,
does it hurt?
no
it... its fine
ok, hers a test to see how much
you actually care about me
you remember the night after the club,
we went and had late night eggs and waffles
till about 5 A.M, we watched a movie
on the little TV in the diner
name that movie...
"octopussy"
baby... gold star
and by the way, my dancing
was not that bad
it was pretty bad...
- I have cool moves
yeah, and so do people
with Parkinson’s
that’s not how I remember it
ok how do you remember it?
alright... whatever you say
hey, hers to 4 more years huh
cheers,
- you make me happy
I know we said no gifts, but...
- we said no such thing...
but I got you something anyway,
in clear violation of the no gift rule
we had no such rule...
Lori, I wanted to give this
to you for a long time
John...
those are the ones you like right?
from the kiosk at the mall
yeah...
you know Lori, some day there’s
going to be a ring in there
but I want to wait till I get
you something really special
I just do have the money right now
look, I’m only saying
this because I love you
you’re not going to have any sort of
career if you wasting time with ted
Oh, geez. Here we go.
baby, please ask ted to move out
so we can move on with our lives
Lori, look he’s been my
best friend since I was 8
I was not a popular child,
you have to understand
I had no friends before he came along
he’s the only reason I ever
gained any fucking confidence
but your no longer 8,
your 35 years old
and unless your too blind to notice,
he’s not your only friend anymore
Can we talk about this another time and
just enjoy our anniversary dinner?
oh shit, hang on a second
my phone fell under
the seat somewhere
can you call it?
yeah
is that a new ringtone?
oh, yeah
what is it, cos it sounds negative
no, no, it’s from the notebook
this is going to take some doing I think
- ill just meet you upstairs then...
yeah, I’ll be right there
ugh,
Lori... your home early
what the hell is this?
the lady’s and I were just
watching Jack and Jill
Adam Sandler plays a guy and his sister
its... it’s just awful
its unwatchable, but they're
hookers so its fine
this place is a wreck,
who are these girls?
oh where are my manners, Lori
this is Angelic,
heavenly,sharinne and
sovereign blank
I love you girls. You know somewhere out there, are four
terrible fathers I wish I could thank for this great night
what is that?
what is what?
there’s a... a shit on my floor
in the corner, there is a shit
oh, yeah, we were playing truth or dare...
ad shrine’s pretty ballsy
there’s a shit on my floor!
well, or... or is the
floor on the shit...
who lives here? I’m coming to get
whoever lives here
you owe me lobster money
ha-ha, that’s my buddy Johnny,
not the lobster, the guy running it
I found my phone,
what’s going on?
is that a shit?
god there are some fucked
up fish out there
oh look at that one.
wispy white guy fish
I married the wrong woman, and
now I lead a life of regret
oh look at this guy, I went
to new York once, in 1981
and I just did not feel safe
ted, you got to move out
you... what
it’s got to happen
what did I do?
my relationship is at a very
delicate stage, you know
Lori and I just need a
little space right now
plus, a hooker took a shit
in out apartment
oh god
- what?
oh this is so gross
don’t tell me, I don’t want
to hear about it. you get it?
oh my god
no I didn’t get it!
I got some on my thumb
no!
- yes I did
you can never cook with
that hand again
oh my god this is the most disgusting
thing ever. -get away from me
look, that was tough
night for all of us
ted, you mean everything to me,
and so does Lori
I mean I’m just trying to find a way
to keep both of you in my life
she’s making you do it isn’t she?
yes, but that doesn’t mean we can’t hang out.
well hang out all the time
yeah but
what bout thunder buddy’s
for life Johnny
I know. I just don’t know what to do here
I know it sucks
but otherwise I’m going to lose her
and I do love her ted
I know you do Johnny
I’ll help you get on your
feet out there, I promise
I know, and we'll hang out all
the time right?
all the time
all right fuck it, bring it in
come here, bring it in your bastard
"I love you"
- fuck... hit... sorry
that’s the... the thing
I’m not gay
- I know
and you’re not gay so were fine
we got to get you a job
I look stupid.
No you don’t you look dapper
I don’t. I look like snuggles accountant
come on, it’s not that bad
John, I look like something you give
a kid when you tell them grandma died
look, I know it sucks ok but you got to make some money so
you can pay for an apartment
I don’t want to work at a grocery store
yeah but you have no skills
I told you, I can
totally be a lawyer
you get the job,
were celebrating after ok
ahaa, and if I don’t get the job...
are we still going to smoke that pot?
probably yes
ahaa yeah, good talk coach
alright buddy
go get em
and don’t worry, I’ll do my very best
to get this job that I so crave
so you think you got what it takes?
I tell you what I got...
you wife’s pussy on my breath
nobodies ever talked to
me like that before
that’s because everyone’s mouth
is usually full of your wife's box
your hired
Shit.
Well, I am a former celebrity
in a minimum wage job.
This is how the cast of different strokes feels all day, every
day. Awful, they must feel awful... the live ones must feel awful.
Come on, it's not that bad, okay?
I got a shitty job and I assure you
I am quite content
Excuse me.
I’m sorry to bother you but,
my son and I couldn’t help
but admire your teddy bear
oh thank you
- thanks
I’m Donny this is Robert
I have to say, I’ve been following you
ever since I was a young boy
and eh, I remember seeing
you on the Carson show
you were just wonderful
oh yeah, that was a weird interview
Ed thought I was Alf. and he kept
muttering anti Semitic comments.
thought Alf was Jewish for some reason
have you ever considered selling the bear?
- what? - excuse me
I want it
hey... I’m not an IT
pal I’m a HE, alright
I’m sorry little guy, but my bear isn’t for sale,
see I’ve had him since I was about your age
he’s very very special to me
- stand up straight when
your talking to me
why the fuck would he say that?
sorry, you know you really shouldn’t
swear in front of children
uh look, were very interested in the bear. if you want to
make some sort of arrangement, hers my address and phone number
you can call me anytime ok?
will do
look, here it goes, in the really important
pocket for really important stuff
ok?
- ok
see you later
ok come on Robert
- take it easy
what the fuck...
can you imagine what that
little shit would do to me?
I can totally see him taking you down to the basement and slowly delimbing while
Singing some creepy Victorian nursery rhyme
"oh my little sixpence my pretty little sixpence"
- stop it
" I love my sixpence"
- knock it off
stop it, fuck. why you got to take it to
that place.. you took it to a... that was real
now it’s a real thing
- aww come on, take it easy
let’s just find a better
place to get stoned
well I guess this is it huh?
yeah, I guess so
first night on your own
yeah, first night in my
beautiful new apartment
well it’ll be great
when its furnished
yeah. and the guy said it aunt hardly
had no murders in it, so that’s good
Okay, so...
- if you need anything.
- Yeah.
I know. don’t worry Johnny, I’ll be fine
I know you will.
Alright.
Hey, there.
Hey.
Listen, umm.
I just want to say thank you.
I know what you did wasn't easy.
And I just want you to know
that I love you for it.
And... I think it’s a new
beginning for our relationship.
Anything for you.
this is all part of the new
grown up John Bennett, so
you better get used to him
really...
well... now I don’t have to be at
work for another 20 minutes
well that’s perfect,
cos I’m only going to need 1
you know what my favourite
thing about you is?
even after 4 years,
you can still surprise me
and to step up and change such a huge part of
your life just to make your girlfriend happier
I don’t know, I guess most
guys wouldn’t do that
well most guys don’t have
you to motivate them
I know I’m not a talking
teddy bear, but...
at least you don’t have to make
a magical wish to get me
how do you know?
ohh... is that a Flash Gordon ray gun,
or are you just happy to see me?
there you go. Thank you very much, please
come again we have allot more groceries
hey uhh, hey Ellen
- yeah?
who’s that over there?
oh that’s the new check out girl
I don’t know her name. seems cute
yeah. very cute
you know what I’d like to do to her?
something I call a dirty fuzzy
ok... alright... so that’s
where well draw the line
hey... how you holding up?
oh I’m alright, I’m just getting
used to things that’s all
It's going to be alright.
I actually went through something
like this with my last boyfriend
really?
- yeah
we were together for 8 months
and I really loved him
and then he got deported back to Iran,
so I know what you’re going through
oh yeah. so I guess we both
lost our furry little guy
we sure did
hey ted. hey Johnny what are you doing?
want to come over and catch a buzz?
well I could probably
stop by after work
fuck that, I traded off yesterday
so I got the other shift
come on, I’m bored as crap over here.
just swing by for a bit...
I can’t just ditch work man
I’m trying to get my shit together and be
an adult here you know, for Lori's sake
Johnny, 5 minutes and
I’ll kick you out, I promise
just come over.
I got the cheers DVD box set
and the guy down at the store told me everybody
talks shit about each other in the interviews
you’ll kick me out in 5?
I will kick you out in 5
John, I’ll have to kick you out. I have so much
teddy bear paperwork to get through it is sick
what do I tell Thomas?
just tell him you don’t feel well
I got to cut out for a bit, Lori tried to break
up a dog fight and guess she got hurt pretty bad
oh my god
yeah that’s the way she is. she sees
trouble and she tries to help out
and I guess one of these dogs clamped its jaws on her
forearm, and wouldn’t let go until a fireman showed up
and had to stick a finger in its ass
oh Jesus
- yeah she’s pretty shook up
up the dogs ass right...
yeah the dogs not the fireman’s ass
I thought the fireman stuck
his finger up his own ass
I don’t think a fire fighter
would do that, I mean...
well go go, take care of it, let me
know how she is. thank you. -Go
woody Harrison... smallest dick
I’ve ever seen on a man
see, that’s why I watch these things. it’s like a
cool behind the scenes thing that you wouldn’t know
oh hey, listen, try this.
I told my weed guy to step it up,
and he gave me that
what is it?
it’s called mind rape,
it’s actually pretty mellow
it doesn’t sound very mellow
well he only had 3 other batches
uh, gorilla panic... uh,
they’re coming there coming
and something called
this is permanent
come on, spark it up
there you go, you got it
ahahaha, nice
good huh? good job
- yeah
take pride in that
- you know, this place looks great
aww thanks man, it’s all IKEA,
did the whole place for $47
nice...
- yeah
how are the neighbours?
ah, you know, there’s an Asian family living next door,
but they don’t have a gong or nothing so it’s not too bad
that’s lucky
- yeah it is
haws work?
- sucks
you?
- you know, not bad actually
I met a girl, she’s a cashier
no way, that’s awesome
- yeah
we should fucking double date, you me
and Lori and... what’s her name?
white trash name, guess...
Mandy?
- no...
Marilyn?
Brittany?
- no...
tiffany?
Candice?
- no...
don’t fuck me on this,
I know this shit
do you see me fucking with you?
alright speed round. im going to rattle off some names, and when I hit it, fucking buzz it ok?
- I will tell you
you got me?
alright
brandy, heather, shanine,briana,
amber,sabrina,melody,dekota
ciara,bamby,crystal,samantha,autumn
ruby,taylor,tara,tammy,lauren,
shelly,shantelle,courtney,misty,jenny,
krista,mindy,nowel,shelby,trina,
casandra,nicky,kelsey,shauna,joleen
ilene,claudine,savanha,casey,dolly kendra,kyley,chloe,demelu
- fucking Becky?
- No.
Was it any one of those names
with a Lynn after it?
Yes.
Ohh, I got you motherfuker.
I got you.
- Okay, brandy-Lynn, heather-Lynn.
- Tammy-Lynn.
Fuck!
What the hell.
hey man, you think you can open more than
1 register? there’s like a 1,000 people here
there’s supposed to be 3 open
for gods sakes
stick your finger in
the loop of my tag
you had sexual intercourse on top of
the produce that we sell to the public
- I fucked her with a
parsnip last week...
and I sold the parsnip to a
family with 4 small children
that took guts
we need guts.
I’m promoting you
- you got allot of
problems don’t you?
alright karim
you suck karim
hello...
hey ted
oh, hey there fella
how are you?
are you out here all alone?
uhh, no, no I’m not
you know, you’re never alone when
your with Christ, so...
no I’m not alone
yeah
yeah me too
you know Robert and I could
give you a very good home
you know, I’m pretty happy where I am
I just got a shitty new apartment
I could offer you $6,000
in railroad bonds
well you know, since I just returned
from active duty in the civil war
that actually sounds very appealing
oh wait, sorry that was 150 years ago
and I don’t give a shit...
ok
teddy come on, were going to be late
for dinner with your friends
ok, I’ll be there in a second baby
as you can see,
my dance card is quite full
I’m going to have to decline
can I just get a hug?
oh, no...
- yeah
and it kills me to have to tell you no.
because I’m a people pleaser
but, thank you for creeping up my night
and Jesus be with you... -ok
in Christ
who was that guy?
oh, that was Sinead O’Connor,
she don’t look so good no more
how great is this huh?
the 4 of us out to dinner
how long have we been saying
we were going to do...
Lori, how you doing?
I haven’t talked to you in forever
I’m good
the companies having their 20th
anniversary party next week, so...
that’s something
Lori's a senior vp at a
pretty huge P.R firm
it’s not that big of a deal
companies turning 20... so you can
bang it, but you can’t get it drunk
right...
yeah she gets it
she enjoys my humour
yeah, I mean Rex is having a house party,
I’m surprised John didn’t tell you
considering you two have seen each other
every single day since you moved out
well you know, it’s funny cos
whenever Johnny and I hang out
the first item on our agenda is...
what’s going on with Lori?
so you know it’s funny that didn’t come up.
it must a have slipped through the cracks
we do, we talk about you all the time
you remember the other day? I was saying
how great Lori's hair always looks
oh my god it always looks so fucking great
I just want to brush it, you know
right Johnny... I say that
so, tammy-lynn. why don’t you tell
us a little bit about yourself
like where you from? I’m always
fascinated to meet teds girlfriends
what do you mean girlfriends? was
there like allot of them or something?
no... that’s not what she meant at all
right Lori?, Lori you didn’t mean that
no, no, what I meant to say was that teds very handsome, so
I’m always interested in meeting the lady that can snatch him up
did you just call me a whore?
- what?
you just worry about your own snatch
how about that honey...
wow, hey... what the hell happened?
we were having a friendly meal
- this was a nice evening
don’t talk shit to me
I just asked you a question
you know, you’re a fricking snob you think your
all cool cos you work at some fancy shit place
whatever. -ok take it easy.
nice Lori, real nice
me... it’s not my fault she
can’t speak English
oh fuck you. just cos your in the business world and shit,
you think everyone should suck your asshole or something?
ok,alright. Tammy, come on honey, lets get out of here. well
go back to my place for a couple of vodka and strawberry quicks
you know what bitch, I gave birth
once, I can kick your fucking ass
and you better not show your face
around Quincy, you hear me? ever
I didn’t know you had a baby,
is it alive?
what a cunt...
I hate that word
- what?
that word, it’s like an electric saw
slashing everything in its path
why would you say that?
you dint exactly stand up for me...
I’m trying to walk a line here. i want
to be fair to you and to him, you know
well I think your being a
little more fair to him
oh, come on...
you know your boss called this
morning asking how my arm was
huh... -yeah because of the dog fight
that I tried to break up
if I had to guess, id say you made up
some bullshit excuse to get out of work
to go to teds.
now...
am I right?
...I made you out to be a hero
you know what John, we asked ted to move
out, to give ourselves a chance without it
you’re not giving anything a chance if your
blowing off work to get high with your teddy bear
your right. I’ve been getting
stoned too much I know that
I’ve been bumming around with ted
too much, I know that too
you give me one more chance,
I promise I can fix it
John, I need a man.
not a little boy with a teddy bear
I know, done, man
right here in front of you, look at
these pecks... these are man pecks
look at the hair on my upper lip...
that’s man hair
I just farted,
that was a man fart
fine...
fine John, but this is,
I swear to god your last chance
trust me, I love you
alright, I love you
I love you so much.
you won’t be sorry I swear
did you really just fart?
yeah... but I pushed it
that way with my hand
I wonder who it’s going to hit first
"so if I told them once, I told them a
million times, these numbers do not add up"
who did this to us?
God damn it, I'm here on business.
Alright, here we go.
I’m really glad that you came
- me too
yeah?
is it ok if I kick your boss's ass? I mean that
wont effect your workplace chemistry will it?
please play nice
for you I will
thank you
- anything
there she is... I was worried
you weren't coming
hey there squirt, how you doing?
where’s your bunny rabbit?
- He's a bear.
- Got it.
oh my god, this
house is fucking huge...
I know, try not to get lost.
come on in
wow, here are the ladies.
look at you guys
you guys look amazing
little heavy on the eye makeup,
but pretty good
you guys know Lori and Jim right?
... John
hi
listen, why don’t John and I
go get a drink at the bar
uh... sure
- great, well be right back
come on buddy
that’s an old sweater huh
this is Wade Boggs
autographed bat
I just barely outbid Phil Donohue
for that at auction
wow cool
yeah... cool
these boxing gloves worn by
Joe Lewis in his first fight
this is art, get it?
these were John Lennon's glasses
there worth like a million dollars
that’s me and Tom Scarritt
ohh... check this out
that’s Lance Armstrong's nut
I had it freeze dried and bronzed
every now and then, when my life’s getting me down and
things are tough. I just come up here, and I look at it
and it reminds me that...
things aren’t so bad
sometimes you feel like a nut
sometimes you don’t
so, talk to me Johnny quest,
how are things with you and Lori
you know, things are great actually
oh that’s great
that... is... great
Lori would hate me for saying this, but
she told me how you are at the office
and as one gentleman to another, I just want to say,
I really fucking hope you get Lou Gehrig’s disease
wow... I think we need to clear
the air here a little
I mean yeah, I’m kind of a fun time
boss and what not
but look man, I do that with
everybody at the office
I’m a cook
I have no designs on your girlfriend
we work together and that’s it
I think you're a great guy.
and she’s a very lucky girl
well that’s good to hear
yeah
excuse me
hey ted
Johnny, were are you you got to get
over here man. why what’s going on?
ok, so
I’m having a little impromptu thing
with some people at my apartment
and John... Sam Jones is here
what!
Sam Jones... Flash fucking Gordon
... is here
holy shit, what
you remember I said my buddy’s cousin
is friends with Sam Jones?
well my buddy’s cousin is in town,
and who do you think is with him...
Sam Jones... Sam Jones is here and John
... his hair is parted down the middle
just like in the movie...
Yes! Get over here right now.
fuck I cant,im with Lori
and I’m already on probation
I just... I cant
John, Flash Gordon was the most important influence of our
informative years. he taught us right from wrong, good from evil
and the word acting apparently
has an extremely broad definition
Flash Gordon is the symbol of our
friendship John. come share this with me
I’m coming
Rex, I got to go. I’ll be back
in like 30 minutes tops ok
Lori cannot find out. she absolutely
cannot know I was gone
if you can cover for me, I’m cool
with all that other shit
I got your back on this
she won’t know I’ve been there
alright, this is one man to another
I don’t really know you, but I’m trusting
you as a man.
this is serious
Dude, one man to another,
I got you on this.
Thank you, I'll be back.
I'm going to have sex
with your girlfriend.
oh Johnny thank Christ, you made it
dude, I got 10 minutes.
where's Flash Gordon?
ok get ready
hey Sam, this is the guy
I was telling you about
how you doing?
good to meet you
I thank you for saving
everyone of us
your welcome
ahh, he acknowledged it
let’s do some shits
- with you?
oh my god... oh my god yes
- yes totally
let’s go
thanks
- There you go my friend.
- Thank you.
"Death to Ming"
you know, you guys seem pretty cool
you like to party?
uhh... cocaine right?
come on dudes, don’t tell me
you never done it before
well uh, not recently no. -I thought
that was just for people in Florida
you better follow me,
come on
Johnny I’m frightened
we are going to party like the 80's
show us how Flash
it’s easy, we just got to nail allot
of girls named Stephanie
Oh, my god Johnny I got so much energy.
We better start doing stupid shit.
look Johnny, if we’re ever going to get serious about
opening a restaurant, we got to start planning it now
Italian...
- Italian yes
what’s the specials on Tuesdays?
eggplant pram
chopped salad, half price
- and it’s a non restrictive place
wait, what do you mean?
- anybody can come
- Of course.
- Jews are welcome.
yeah, why wouldn’t they be?
- exactly, that’s what I’m saying
why would you even bring that up?
- you don’t bring that up, you let them in
so why mention it?
- no one will
why are we talking about it?
- your talking about it, I’m just saying let them in
yeah exactly, right, good, ok
No Mexicans though.
this is how everyone sang in the 90's
trust me, I can do this
- shut up
let him try man
- alright, ok
son of a bitch
...well you never should have
trusted me, I’m on drugs
hey Johnny. I just had a great idea
let’s go get drunk at cars on the overpass
oh come on, I do not sound that
much like peter griffin
You can do any 90's song
with just vowels.
You breaker my wall,
this my home long time.
We're sorry.
It was an accident, okay?
I try to make duck dinner,
now plaster everywhere.
Chill out, okay? Look, can we just
talk about this? What's your name? I'm John.
My name a Wan Ming
Ming?
You blame each other for war,
this bullshit, this all bullshit.
"Death to Ming"
let him go
you crazy, you crazy man
Come on James Franco.
You pay for wall.
Move sucker!
Hey.
Hey, guy.
what’s going on?
this is Gerard, he’s the
guy who beat me up
- And ahh... we're in love.
- Huh?
turns out I’m gay,
or whatever I don’t know
I had no idea
hey Gerard, let’s go grab
another one of these
how we doing ace?
you coming down?
yeah, I don’t feel so good
oh give it a couple of hours,
you’ll be golden pony boy
you want a annex?
oh shit, oh my god
- what?
I got to go
Lori, I...
Lori
Lori, wait please
I’m sorry, I messed up. - I need you
out of the apartment tonight
can I just...
- give me the car keys
can I please just explain...
- no
I was... -I have giving up a huge
chunk of my life for you
I was going to stop in for like 5 minutes,
then Flash Gordon...
just give me the car keys
Lori
Lori please, I love you, come on
hey Johnny, there you are
I had to get some air
that guy from your office is on the couch,
making out with that Van Wilder looking guy
you know what, fuck you,
I don’t even want to talk to you
what...
- do you know what just happened?
do you have any clue?
my fucking life just ended
oh come on, shell go home, shell watch Bridget Jones
some asshole, shell have a good cry. She’ll be fine.
you’ll talk to her tomorrow
come on upstairs
are you even listening to me?
do you even give any thread of a shit?
of course I do... Johnny,
thunder buddy’s for life, remember
Jesus, Lori was right’s should a stopped
hanging out with you a long time ago
I’m never going to have a life with you around.
I’m 35 years old and I’m going nowhere
All I do is smoke pot and watch
movies with a teddy fucking bear.
because of that, I just
lost the love of my life
Johnny... I... I’m sorry
I got to be on my own ted.
I can’t see you anymore
John, wait, listen
"I love you"
so, word through the grapevine
is that your newly solo
Rex, I have allot of work
I need to get to
I have tickets to Norah Jones at the hat shell
tonight, and I would love it if you'd go with me
your asking me out?
a week after I broke up with somebody...
look, I’m going to cut the shit here
please
this is the first time you've been
single in all the years you've worked here
just... go out with me one time?
and if your miserable, and you hate it. then I
promise, I will never hint at the subject again
please
Rex, I don’t think it’s smart
I’m an asshole, I know that. it worked for me
in high school. and it’s been a reflex ever since
Lori, the worst that can happen is you
go on a fun casual date, with a guy
who just wants to prove that he
can be something more than a jerk.
Plus you are a huge catch, and its
about time someone treated you that way
fuck it, fine
sure beats crying myself to
sleep every night
and if that means getting you
off my back, well that’s just a bonus
I'll pick you up at 8.
Hey Johnny, it's me.
go away
Johnny open the door please,
I want to talk
Jesus Christ, what the fuck man
sorry, look Johnny,
I know your pissed alright
but just listen to me for 5 seconds
I saw Lori leaving the
apartment with Rex
what?
I’m serious John. I went over to talk to her,
maybe take some of the heat off you
and there he was, picking her up
they were going to the hat shell
your fucking unbelievable
you know that
I mean how stupid do
you think I am?
if you think that by making shit up like that your going
to make me choose some kind of loyalty to you over her
your out your fucking mind.
John it’s the truth I’m telling you
you know what, get out of here
you know what, your acting like a cock
you know that?
what?
I’m acting like a cock?
yes, you are. so shut your meat hole
for a second and listen to me
huh?... meat hole,
that’s not right is it... no
pudding hole... is that what they say, no can’t be that either
right. cos how can you have any pudding, if you don’t eat your meat
pink Floyd thing... the point is, your blaming
me, for something that you did to yourself
Lori was right about you. you cannot take any
responsibility for anything that goes on in your life
oh and you can?
I don’t have to,
I’m a fucking teddy bear
you know something... I didn’t tie
you up and drag you to that party
alright, I wanted you to come because
your supposedly my best friend
you can’t stand there and tell me you haven’t
always seen Lori as a threat to our friendship
I mean it works out so much better for you when we’re
getting fucked up on the couch at 9A.M doesn’t it?
listen to yourself, what am I, emperor
Ming here controlling your mind
that’s your choice John. and you know by blaming
me, you just make yourself look like a pussy
you know, sometimes I think back to that
Christmas morning, when I was 8 years old
I wish I’d just gotten
a teddy ruxpin
say that 1 more time...
teddy... rux... fucking... pin
shit, ou
fuck man
fucking stop
why you crying?
my dick is squished by the TV
I’m so sorry Johnny
so am I man
I love you
I love you too
listen
you got to let me help you make
things right with you and Lori
there’s no putting things right,
she fucking hates me
look, john, we can get her back
you remember when you were 10?
and you hit that squirrel with your bb gun
and then when we seen it fall from the
tree we both started crying, you remember?
and we ran up to it, and
we tried to give it CPR
and it came back to life.
John, we could do that again
ted, we blew out its rib cage and crushed
its lungs trying to give it CPR
It died.
Come on, were going to the hat shell.
Thanks. We're going to take a short break,
but we’ll be back in a few.
Hey, play chopsticks you jazzy slut.
Teddy!
How are you?
how you doing you fuzzy
little asshole?
Oh you know, I'm not a hot half Muslim chick who’s
sold 37 million records, but I’m hanging in there.
half Indian, but thanks
yeah whatever, thanks for 9-11. hey listen,
I want you to meet a good pal of mine alright
John Bennett... Norah Jones
hi
- hey there... sweaty
you ready to bring down the house?
yes ma'am. thank you for the
opportunity miss... ma'am... Jones
Thank you.
Jesus, you look fantastic
well, your probably not used
to seeing me fully clothed
I know right. me and Norah met in 2002
at a party at Belinda Carlisle’s house
and we had awkward fuzzy
sex in the cloak room
actually you went so bad
for a guy with no penis
yeah. you know, I’ve written so
many angry letters to Hasbro about that
thank you
so I’m going to give my chops a rest,
and bring a friend up to the stage
he’s going to sing a song to a special
lady in the audience who he loves very much
please give a big hand,
to John Bennett
oh... my god
holy shit
I got to fuck her again
umm high, my names John Bennett
and this is for Lori Collins,
cos I love you
and this song always reminds me of the most
important night of my life. the night we met
umm, this is the theme song
from the movie octopussy
still better than Katy Perry
you suck, get off the stage
aww come on, give him a chance
your an asshole
oh Jesus
someone call an ambulance
that was insane
did you see the way the guys body hit
the ground?. it was like a rag doll
I’d rather just not talk about it
you want to go get a drink after this?
I feel like I could use one
after seeing a guy almost die
uh nope, I think I’d rather
just have you take me home
one drink
come on
no, not really feeling up to it
alright, I get it
and you know, I don’t blame you
I mean thing about it, it was actually
unfair of him to embarrass you like that
just to be clear,
I’m not embarrassed
so John and I have our problems,
but at least he tried
you know what, I don’t feel
like talking to you about this
where you going?
taking a cab, I’m going home
finally
down here, not looking up your
towel, swear to god
not looking up your towel,
not looking at your funny business
ted, what are you doing here?
I need to talk to you
listen if your here to fight
Johns battles for him it’s not...
just let me talk first alright,
and then you can say whatever you want
look, John loves you very much
more than anything in the world
and he’s falling to fucking
pieces without you
he knows he screwed up huge. but you
got to believe me,
it wasn’t all his fault alright. I told
him to bail on you that night at Rex's
and he said no, he was going
to stay there with you
and I twisted his arm Lori
so if you just give
him one more chance
I promise I will leave,
and I’ll never come back
alright... he’ll be all yours
ted, that’s a really nice offer.
but I don’t want you to do that
this is between John and me,
and I don’t think it can be fixed
yeah because of me
look look Lori,
you want him to be a man
but as long as he’s got his teddy bear,
he’s always going to be a boy
he’s waiting down at Charles right now,
so if you go down there and just talk to him
I’ll be gone when you get back
forever
and you’ll see. hell never be
scared of thunder again
Michelob ultra Tuscan
orange grapefruit
my god, Americas imploding
high ted
fuck!
Lori... what...
hey
what are you doing here?
you can thank ted
should I... should I sit?
yeah... if you want
- ok
so works good?
everything’s good there?
yeah, works good
well I guess we can’t make
small talk all day huh?
if it’s ok with you, I just want
to say what I want to say
look I could sit here and tell you I’m sorry, and
it was a huge misunderstanding, I’m ready to change
but I don’t think you want to
hear any of that crap
I’m not going to try and get you
to take me back. I mean, why would you
I’ve been a really shitty boyfriend for
the last 4 years, I don’t deserve you
look, I know I didn’t take our
relationship seriously, but Lori
I do love you more than life itself
and I want is...
I just want to end on good terms
I owe that to you.
Alright, I want you to be happy,
you deserve that.
and I just hope, you know,
that we can still be friends
thank you for being so honest
that was pretty much it
Thanks for coming by.
Yeah.
As you can see, you’ve been a part
of our family for quite some time.
Welcome home.
yeah it's kind a funny, I got allot
of pictures of you guys at my house
is he all mine daddy?
yes he is my little winner,
yes he is
ted you've arrived at a lucky time,
it’s almost Robert's play hour
I’m guessing you guys don’t have a ps3
I’m guessing your more of a wooden
horse with a wig kind a family
yeah
eh yeah, no
yeah see there’s a cart
ted, you belong to Robert now.
you do as he says
you think your just going to get away with a
kidnapping?. it’s a nice fucking example your setting
LANGUAGE!... sorry sorry
you know ted,
when I was a little boy
I saw you on television, and I thought you were the
most amazing most wonderful thing I’d ever seen, ever.
and I asked my dad if I could have
a magical teddy bear too
and he said no
can you just email me
the rest of this story...
and I was so heartbroken
and I promised myself that if I ever had a
son,i would never, ever, ever, say no to him
ever
maybe no to a snickers bar every
once and a while wouldn't hurt
me and ted are going to
be best friends daddy
yes you are my little chipmunk
happy playtime
Jesus fucking Christ
I said that word one time
daddy punished me for it
that’s a great story,
I felt like I was there
daddy gave me an ouch
now... I have to give you an ouch
alright kid you win, what you
want to do? you want to play a game?
its playtime right, well play a game
yeah, I’ll play a game
- good
uh, alright let’s see, how about
we play a little game of hide and seek?
I love hide and seek,
ill hide
now hang on there, your daddy likes you
to show good manners, right Tubby McFatfuck
ok, you hide first
great, fantastic. now, you count to 100
and then you try to find me, ok?
do I need to wash my hands
before I play this game?
no... that’s a weird fucking question,
no just start counting
1... 2... 3...
4... 5... 6...
7...
ok,no peeking now,
or you’ll get kid cancer
8... 9...
10... 11...
12... 13...
- Hey.
- Walking home alone, huh?
Yeah.
do you need a lift?
oh I’m ok, I mean if I get raped, then
it would be my fault for what I’m wearing
listen, John
there’s something that I
need to say to you too
hey, -hey
- John, I hope that...
listen I don’t want
you to think that...
sorry
I want us to keep talking...
because I think that maybe...
look, whoever this is,
it’s not a good time
John, it’s me, can you hear me?
ted?... listen I got to call you back
no no, John don’t hang up
I’m in trouble
what do you mean?
what kind of trouble?
they got me, that freaky guy from
the park and that kid
who I think is his son, but may
also be his lover, I don’t know
wow wow wow, slow down.
where are you?
uh.. I’m not sure. its uh...
hello...
hello John...
your not a very
polite guest are you?
shit!
- ted, hello...
ted
what’s the matter?
is he ok?
I don’t know
- well where is he?
I don’t know, he just
said he was in trouble
Can you call him back?
No it's blocked.
Wait a second.
Go, take Columbus to Hilton,
get on the express way.
Hello, 911.
I need the police right away.
This guy took my teddy bear.
Hello?
Let me out of here,
you crazy bastards.
oh... oh... I hear the fat kid running, I
hear the fat kid running. ... that is hilarious
come on, let me out of here
I am a citizen of the United
Stated of America, and I have rights
Robert, seatbelt
should be right here somewhere
Johnny
wow, wow, wow, stop stop stop
that’s them, turn around
stay with them
hang on
back off Susan Boyle
oh my god, he’s going to jump
get closer
alright, easy...
- come on ted
shit
- yes
hey Johnny,
total T.J Hooker right?
yes!, fucking A right!
Go, go, go.
daddy
let’s see how well you
know these streets
where is he?
Jesus
there he is, pullover
no... you can’t have my teddy bear...
holy shit
Sorry, somebody had to go
Joan Crawford on that kid.
Come on.
Ted?
Oh my god.
Ahh, shit.
- Jesus, stay here.
- No, no, no, John.
- Wait, John.
- Stay here.
You're mine, Ted.
Screw you pal,
I belong to John Bennett.
But I can give you love
and rocking horses,
and dancing
I think we're very
far apart on this.
Ted?
- Johnny.
Oh, my god.
Ted.
John.
Lori, get the stuffing.
Get it all.
Johnny...
your going to be ok buddy, can you
understand? your going to be fine
Jesus, I look like the
robot from Aliens
look at me buddy. I promise,
your going to be ok
I don’t think so.
I'm a... I'm... I'm in trouble
I need... I need to
tell you something.
What is it?
don’t... don’t ever
lose her again
she’s the most important...
most important
part of your life
even... even more than me
she’s your thunder buddy now
She's...
I got it
baby, I don’t know if
this is going to work
please, just try
come on buddy
I’m so sorry
you did everything you could
Ted.
- I'm alive Johnny,
- Oh my god.
I’m alive
your magic always worked
your back, I cant...
yeah, I mean when you sawed me up, you put
some of the stuffing in the wrong places John
I'm a little fucked up, but will you
take care of me forever and ever?
nah... I’m just kidding with you, I thought it
would be funny if you thought I was fucking retarded.
- You asshole.
- Come here you bastard.
Welcome back ted.
It was you.
You did it.
Son of a bitch.
You wished for my life back.
No... no no.
I wished for my life back.
I love you.
I love you too.
and I want you to know that
after last night, I don’t want to
lose anyone that matters to me ever again
I'm not going to wait any
longer for my life to start.
...Lori
will you marry me?
All I ever wanted
was you John Bennett.
And so, John and Lori and ted,
lived happily ever after
having discovered at last, that all
they really needed was each other
John and Lori were married in Cambridge,
by a very special justice of the peace
by the power vested in me
by the New York Jets
and by the united peoples
of the planet Mongo
I now pronounce you,
man and wife
you may kiss the bride Johnny
thanks so much for coming
my daughter better be alive
you sick son of a bitch
I am so fake happy for her.
Ahh, you know Sam, there’s only
one way to end a perfect day.
What's that?
Flash jump.
Right.
1... 2...
3.
Yeah.
And that's the story of how one magical wish, forever
changed the lives of three very special friends.
Ted and Tammy-Lynn continued there
torrid love affair for quite some time.
One afternoon, ted was caught behind the deli counter,
eating potato salad off of Tammy-Lynn's bare bottom.
He was instantly promoted
to store manager.
Sam Jones moved back to Hollywood,
with the goal of restarting his film career.
He currently resides in Burbank where he shares
a studio apartment with his roommate Brandon rout.
Remember Brandon rout, from
that god awful superman movie?
Jesus Christ. Thanks for getting our
hopes up and taking a giant shit on us.
Rex was forced to give
up his pursuit of Lori.
Not long after, he fell into a deep
depression and died of Lou Gehrig’s disease.
Donny was arrested by Boston police and
charged with kidnapping a plush toy.
The charge was dropped when everyone
realised how completely stupid that sounded.
Robert got a trainer, lost a
substantial amount of weight,
and went on to become Taylor lautner.
Download Movie Subtitles Searcher from www.podnapisi.net