These streets, they're different.
They're old.
The ties are deep and hidden.
It's where the east claws at the west,
where the south seeks the north.
There's honor here
that must be respected,
rules that cannot be broken.
And if a mistake is made,
Room service.
Hey! What's it rolling?
Apologies. Someone
caught in a bomb threat.
This is how to sit down here!
[gunshot]
[sirens]
Take off your knees!
On your knees!
Come here!
You do your fucking thing, don't move!
Lay down!
Lay fucking down!
Lay down right now!
Don't move!
Unmuse!
Hands, hands, show me your hands!
You, come out, come out!
You, come out on the ground!
Get down!
It's clear!
Delta-twit, Delta-twit.
We're leaving our vehicle to check-in.
Over.
Copy.
On the right.
Team up, Pachner.
I got feet.
Dogs on the scent.
Clap, clap, clap!
Run, run!
Package in hand,
package in hand, exiting.
Use those hands.
You're starting, starting, starting, go!
That man!
Pachin.
We're passing. Run in the
air, go make order, go make order.
If he catches us...
Badger, badger.
Are we good?
We're clean, we're clean.
Still good.
[water running]
It felt good. at the Antwerp
International Airport cargo terminal.
The incident unfolded as the
flight arrived from Johannesburg and suspects,
in police tactical gear raced across the
tarmac to stage an
assault on the cargo hangar.
Preliminary reports
suggest that the thieves
made away with millions
of dollars worth of diamonds
and occasions point to
the Panther Mafia, as potential
orchestrators behind
this meticulously planned robbery.
My man crush.
The Petit Nick.
Did you hear about the
diamond rip at the airport?
Belgium.
About the Antwerp thing?
Yeah.
Oh, so that's what this is about?
Mm-hmm.
Zero grams of sugar.
[crunching]
Lawman, afternoon. Lieutenant, you're
busy. I'm busy. So
let's jump to it, shall we?
Sir, I have reason to
believe my suspect is still operating.
Then you know this how?
I just do.
And what's your ask?
Simple.
Issue a bolo, or at least a purple
notice, so I can continue my investigation.
I can't operate
outside of Kona's without it.
Isn't this case closed by now?
Look, we've investigated the incident ad
nauseam, and the
issue here, Nick, is this.
Whether there was an
actual breach or not is debatable.
And we'd be pursuing
it robustly if there were
abnormalities with any of
the accounts, but there weren't.
Neither us, nor any of our clients,
which translates to every single goddamn bank
in the entire American Southwest and
Guam and Hawaii are missing a dollar. Not one.
Nothing was stolen, Nick.
I speak English.
The potential optics of
this are obviously a non-star for us.
In no world can it be
known or leaked that the Federal
fucking Reserve Bank of the
United States was robbed. Not happening.
Go enjoy Lake Havasu,
son. I know you understand.
Backseat.
I trust you know how to use it.
Clock.
No safety.
So what's my cover?
Your French, of Cote d'Ivoire de Saint.
You're a diamond dealer working out of
London, and we're EDM club promoters here to
promote the
festival for the next two weeks.
So that's our clock.
Hope you got me a good view.
We'll meet defense this afternoon.
She's a sight
holder, and she arranged office
space for you. And
we've sanitized the whole flat.
So you're good to go.
Welcome to Nice. Jean-Jacques.
Here we go.
(suspenseful music)
Jean-Jacques Alors.
What the fuck are you doing?
Follow him.
Follow that fucking car.
(suspenseful music)
What are we doing?
Just relax.
You're gonna be fine.
(suspenseful music)
Get out.
A stripper that doesn't smoke.
Am I the first?
Go fuck yourself.
Still dealing bad food at the club.
(suspenseful music)
Okay, your dude told
you everything, always do.
You knew about the Fed.
You always fuck your suspects?
Is that police procedure?
You know, I could
close these container doors
and it'll be shipped to China.
And when it gets
there, they'll open the doors
and there you'll be dead.
A dead stripper in China.
Sounds kinky.
No, it doesn't.
Make this simple.
Since Merryman's dead,
you're gonna tell me two things.
Where were he and Donnie
going that they didn't get to?
And what did they do with the money?
(suspenseful music)
Who's the lucky guy?
He was all prison weird.
He didn't fuck me.
You did.
And I can post this.
Anytime.
God, that looks so much younger there.
I knew where Donnie went.
I knew where he put the
money, but I want my man's cut.
7 million are the LASD and your daughters
will be super proud
of your amateur porn career.
You understand, motherfucker?
(suspenseful music)
Where is the money?
The Panama-Diamant Bank.
Hey.
Jean-Jacques, this
is my lovely friend, Hava.
Bonjour.
C'est bien compris vous et français?
Oui papa l'herme, français?
Je hommes pas pour français.
Je suis en pou, rusty.
Well, you have to speak
English in this business anyway, so.
You grow up in Abidjan or?
Sigella.
Oh, so you're Baulay, ethnically?
Ethnically, c'est n'faux.
I'm impressed.
You know a lot about the country.
I mean, I have a lot
of friends in his business
from West Africa, tough negotiators.
Who isn't?
So, Jean-Jacques.
You have something
you want me to look at?
I do.
And you came across this--
My family.
We do business in Botswana.
Hmm.
Come on.
Great.
I'll leave you guys to it.
Let's get you set up at the Bors.
Salut, legga.
Bonjour, monjour, monjour.
Cartier d'entités, se vous plaît?
M'am.
(people chattering)
Love ist.
(speaking in foreign language)
(dramatic music)
Bonjour, monjour.
Bonjour.
Le Nouveau, walking through the Bors.
Doctor.
Keep an eye on him, yeah?
We.
(dramatic music)
(speaking in foreign language)
Okay.
(dramatic music)
Hey, salat, monjour.
Bonjour,
(speaking in foreign language)
I'm Salatie, vous vous vous plaît?
(dramatic music)
(humming)
Et voilà.
May I see you on the bench, Oi?
You may.
(dramatic music)
D'accord.
(speaking in foreign language)
Et voilà, Monsieur D'Alou.
Your office.
Lane line from here,
tile three for security,
seven for the concierge,
and eight to dial out.
You're safe.
You dial in your own personnel code here,
but you couldn't
leave it open, to be honest.
You in the most secure
building in continental Europe.
I certainly hope so.
I have some
inventory coming in this week.
Is it possible to
lease one of the vault boxes?
I'm sorry, not possible.
Currently, all the
vault boxes are fully booked,
and they are
reserved for site orders anyway.
Ah, hopefully something opens up.
Bonjourné.
(door creaking)
(sighing)
So?
We're in, but we have a problem.
There's no access to the vault.
Only site holders of L.E. have access,
and there's no security boxes available.
You gotta be fucking kidding me.
Just let me handle it.
(dramatic music)
(dog barking)
(door creaking)
(speaking in foreign language) (sighing)
(speaking in foreign language)
You have an account across the street?
Of course.
What is the offer?
Well, the stones obviously don't come
with Kimberly's certificates.
4.2.
I cannot go lower than five.
It is also the only
offer you will get, Jean-Jacques.
Hello, nous a bon finis.
4.2, here's your cash.
I understand we have a massage.
(paper rustling)
(door creaking)
(grunting)
Afternoon, sunshine.
I'm good, I'm good.
Are you actually living in your car now?
I love my car.
Okay, so one week before the Fed heist,
the account Hofbro Imports LLC is opened
at the Diamand Bank in Panama City.
33 days after the Fed,
$22,127,000 a deposit.
Then it goes dark for a couple years,
except for a few cash
withdrawals in London and Belgium.
Check the PDF I sent you over signal.
Two days after the
diamond rip in Antwerp,
that is a deposit of 4.2.
Since then it's a flurry of activity,
including 1.8 in cash withdrawals.
Dated yesterday.
Fence the stones then payouts.
Correct.
Now, there's only five locations
of the Diamand Bank worldwide.
Marseille, Dubai, Tel
Aviv, Panama City, and Nice, France.
Look at the map I sent you.
What is directly
across from the Nice branch?
Fucking A.
The World Diamond Center.
Okay, who's our POC on the Antwerp job?
Check your J-ring.
Task Force Pantera,
BRB Commander Hugo Cayman.
He'll be expecting your call.
I know you're not
gonna kick this up to Europol.
How are you gonna operate?
Good point, hold on.
Global jurisdiction, US Marshal.
I was deputized on
the Chris Dorner Manhattan.
We didn't know if that
fucker was a Temecula or Paraguay.
Okay, did you re-up?
No, good point.
So you gotta back me up, okay?
If they call me out, validate me.
I can do that.
Thank you.
Now get the fuck out of my car.
All right.
(tires squealing)
(dramatic music)
(door slamming)
(speaking in foreign language)
Como se hacer, quiero.
Someone can speak freely.
Okay.
I am Cleopatra.
Now I've been working
with each one of you individually,
but never as a group.
There's a reason why you're all here.
This will be our
biggest job on the continent yet.
This isn't a smash and grab.
We're here to rob
the World Diamond Center.
We estimate the
score to be 850 million euros.
Use these sims and only
these for all communication.
Vogue, logistics,
Marco, vehicles and transport,
dragga, safes, and tree.
Slavco, comes, sell Overwatch.
Coi, over.
Jean-Jacques.
He'll be doing the
recce and the planning.
(speaking in foreign language)
Okay, okay, guys,
calm the fuck down, okay?
This guy is one of the
best thieves on the planet, okay?
What the fuck is your problem?
(speaking in foreign language)
Yes, fucking normal.
Hey, shut the fuck up.
Okay, we have until
the last Sunday of the month
to execute the job.
So as we advance in
our reiki to the target here,
the World Diamond Center.
The ring of
intelligence we need will be difficult.
Jean-Jacques is our asset on the inside.
He finds our parts to the vault.
And if you have a problem with that,
you can get the fuck out now.
I'm good.
Pause.
What do you need?
I'll need brands,
makes a model of all security systems,
and of course, the vault.
Need to ID all their personnel.
Get to know who we are dealing with,
and somehow, tap in their comms.
Confirm routes, find the exits.
I'll work up the routes.
I'll need to see them
before selecting vehicles.
So are we good?
Yeah.
Oh, bravo.
(speaking in foreign language)
(people chattering)
Here we go.
France.
Italy.
That bends, that is the border.
This is the Alpine run.
No CCTV or plate
readers up on these roads?
Zero.
All on the coast.
This is the route.
I need all wheel
drive, strip out the automation.
No anti-locks.
(speaking in foreign language)
I'm sorry, what was that?
Sorry, yes sir.
(footsteps crunching)
Excuse me.
Sorry, is the captain here?
Captain Kane?
We've no problem.
Okay, we were set for one, 1 p.m.
It's 1.30.
He's aware that I'm here or--
(speaking in foreign language)
Nice to finally meet.
I thought we said one, but--
No.
Anyway, I brought you some swag.
Thought you and the guys might like it.
Oh, merci, mon porte.
Look at that super.
I have LAPD, but not LASD.
It's cool.
Do you want something to eat, drink?
Coffee, maybe a
little one of those croissants.
No, Nick.
It's croissant, not croissant.
Well, clearly I
don't speak French, right?
What American does.
This is Lieutenant
Taborin, Lieutenant Taborin.
Hey, nice to meet you.
(speaking in foreign language)
(sighs)
So here they are.
How are we?
It's very tough to
crack ethnically insular.
They work with the
Italians and Albanians once in a while,
but tactically they are brilliant.
The players are only
aware of who's in the cell
for a particular job.
So if they get
caught, there's no one to rat on.
What?
We don't have to ID them.
We don't get much help from Balkan Ali.
They are all
security services and military.
They know how to stay off the grid.
They often use women
who wear motels or athletes,
who spend a lot of
time in Western Europe.
So they have connections.
Now they're way around.
This guy, Slobodan.
He's a criminal receiver.
He has this with the Andragetta
and all the top jewelers in Italy.
He gives the green light
for every job on the continent.
We've been trying to
bag him for almost a decade.
Take a seat, plique.
So tell us about your suspect.
We have reason to believe, thank you,
that he's operating
out of Europe, possibly France.
We started looking
into it after the Antwerp rip.
A lot of the signatures of that job
were similar to some of
the ones we investigated in LA.
But you know, the police, Aaron O'Tik,
believes that most of them are Balkan.
I thought you said
that they were all Balkan,
except for one.
The one who recruited them.
Okay.
And was he black?
Where?
Okay, so they
weren't all Balkan, is the point.
No.
You guys able to pull
up the surveillance footage
I requested?
Of course.
Well, can I see it?
(clears throat)
How's your croissant?
Great.
I'll make your life a little bit easier
while you're over here.
You know, some of the
letters in French, they are silent.
Like the T in croissant, for example.
You know, in
America, you say salmon, right?
But the L is silent, no?
Am I on candid camera or something?
You know, I
actually say salmon, always half.
Salmon.
So ego.
It's a funny guy, huh?
Okay, this is from the day you requested.
Let me know when to post.
That's it, Diamon bank.
Wait, wait, wait, stop, right there.
Can you zoom in?
Try and find him when he comes out.
Okay, just stop.
Wait, inch forward.
Freeze, freeze there.
Go in.
Hello, this in?
No, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
No?
No.
(dramatic music)
If you need
anything else, I have my number.
Maybe we can go out and have some salmon.
Thank you, but French food kind of sucks.
Oh.
Actually, Nick, it's the best.
But you're American, you have no taste.
It's on.
Yeah, it's nice.
Nice.
Watch your hand,
though, don't chop it off
to get that watch.
Don't chop it off.
(men chattering)
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
No, no, no.
Thank you.
Nice to see you.
(dramatic music)
(men chattering)
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Plus, two.
I don't think you
even write in this town.
Oh, yeah?
My God, this is it.
(dramatic music)
Honey trap is set, check your Pegasus.
We got it.
(birds chirping)
(door creaking)
Mademoiselle.
Grab a seat.
Come on, man, sit down.
Make me nervous.
I won't bite, promise.
(footsteps thudding)
So what you packin' to her?
You don't have any jurisdiction here.
(water splashing)
(sighs)
I didn't rob the Fed.
Who said anything about the Fed?
You know what I was trippin' on just now?
You and I are part
of this weird symbiosis.
Is that you only exist for a line.
Because of me.
We weren't there tryin' to stop you
from smugglin' shit and stealin' shit,
then your shit
wouldn't be worth the fuckin' thing.
It's only worth the trouble,
because we're there tryin' to stop you.
So actually, you need to thank me.
That your shit is worth anything at all.
You're welcome.
Okay.
Cracks me up.
When people pull guns on people,
why don't you just shoot them?
(gun firing) You're not a killer.
I am.
You got over on me for all that.
No one gets over on me.
I'm broke.
And I'm sick of bein' the hunter.
It's fuckin' exhausting.
Let's take a look at your view.
(footsteps)
Word around the LA
streets is that they fired your ass.
So how you gonna get in?
Take it.
(footsteps)
I'm gonna ask you again.
How are you gonna get in there?
Workin' on it.
No, you can't trust me.
And yeah, I can haul
your ass in anytime I want.
Depends on my mood right now, Fraulein.
It's pretty good.
You're gonna rob that place,
and I'm gonna do it with you.
I wanna meet these Panthers.
Set it up.
(crickets chirping)
Fuck.
(somber music)
(speaking in foreign language)
This is our city.
No one can hide from us here.
(speaking in foreign language)
Jesus, that's strong.
Is that her?
Yeah, that's her.
I'm gonna call gettin'
a memo she was a supermodel.
What will he?
(crickets chirping)
And Liski, yeah?
You've worked security?
Among other things.
How'd you guys meet?
Prison.
Gay crews, actually.
(crickets chirping)
(laughing)
Marlboro Man.
(somber music)
(speaking in foreign language)
Yeah, but I mean, that's
why I let them do the work for us.
I play the cops
like I play everyone else.
(speaking in foreign language)
Right now is our key to the vault.
No other option.
(speaking in foreign language)
Invite him tonight.
We'll put him in a deep
hole and see if he cross out.
Lobo.
Lobo, bro.
(speaking in foreign language)
Sorry.
Once you become a
slave to greed, you're fucked.
Then I guess we are both fucked.
(laughing) So, how can I help you?
I was wondering if I can rent space
in one of your
vault boxes for a few weeks.
I have some inventory coming in,
and I do not like the
idea of keeping it in the office.
How much space, exactly?
Around 3,000 cal.
Split the monthly cost and we can do it.
Perfect.
What?
(people chattering)
(speaking in foreign language)
Shoom.
Do le moi?
(people chattering)
(speaking in foreign language)
That's the guy who had the GPS beacon.
Sorry.
(speaking in foreign language)
Don't worry.
Good.
Your job.
(people chattering)
Let's give up.
(dramatic music)
Yo.
Hey.
Good, look good.
(laughing) Holy shit.
Right?
That could be crazy, you know.
So these your new girlfriends?
Take it easy, man.
We're in no rush.
Nick.
Cool name, pleasure.
Dragon.
Nick.
I know you.
Take your time, bro.
Marco.
Nico.
(speaking in foreign language) Thank you.
(dramatic music)
Hey, what's the name of that game?
You know, with the
little metal balls that you throw?
Bocce.
You know, at the cafe today.
I saw you guys there.
Air Police Academy, Tokyo World, Nico.
Fuck the police.
(speaking in foreign language)
What is that?
Shleva.
Say again?
Shleva vica.
When you run out of gas,
you can put this in your car.
Oh, some nasty shit.
What is it?
Try it.
Cops don't do drugs.
So do yourself a
favor, stop being a pussy,
and hit that shit.
(dramatic music)
Holy shit.
(laughing)
Seriously, what are we smoking?
Ashish.
With a little pixie dust.
What?
Eat.
You never try to eat?
Yeah, of course.
(laughing)
(speaking in foreign language)
(dramatic music)
I wish I could fucking dance.
(laughing)
Hey, fucking Europe rules.
Hey, man, sorry about
bombing the shit out of you guys
in the 90s.
That was fucked up.
They came my mother.
No, seriously?
We went to join the
West, but the West didn't want us.
So we rob it.
I fucking love you guys.
Fuck NATO.
Fuck them.
Yeah, fuck NATO.
Oh, I got one coming up.
Hey.
(dramatic music)
He's fucked up.
(laughing)
(dramatic music)
Hey, no good.
Go to Nico, go, go.
No, no.
Hey, this is
Marco's ex, man, and his trip.
Just slow it down
a little bit, all right?
I told him.
Yeah.
(laughing) (cheering)
Hey, what the fuck?
Hey, hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
Fuck this shit.
All right.
Hey, hey.
Keep your fucking hands off of me.
Fucking drama queen, let's go.
See you.
(grunting)
(crowd cheering)
(grunting) (grunting)
Fuck off, go, go, go, go, go.
Oh, fuck.
(yelling)
What the fuck?
Okay, okay, okay.
Okay.
(yelling)
You want to get smashed?
No, I don't want to get smashed.
(laughing)
Hey, hey, hey, hey, push.
Ah, we're really gonna do this right now?
Yeah, man, you got it, you got it.
Oh, fuck.
Shit, yeah.
Yeah, big American tough guy.
You think you are
socialist pussies over here, huh?
What the fuck are you playing at?
Hey, oh, wait,
wait, wait, wait, I got one.
I'm not gonna make you proud right now.
(speaking foreign language)
You got it.
You don't like it?
Quick, quick, fuck.
It's shit, shit.
Come on, I knew that was good.
Donny.
Fucking hurt my back.
(laughing)
Hey, hey.
Hey, hey, hey, we
got a fucking free ride?
This is a bad idea.
Scooter time.
This is bad.
It's just pressed down on the right.
Oh, shit.
This sounds fucking fun for once, man.
Yeah, woo-hoo!
Oh, shit.
Woo-hoo!
50 fucking miles an hour?
(engine revving) Roll on!
(laughing) You just slow ass out my way.
I thought white people watched NASCAR.
You're my bitch!
Woo-hoo!
Wait.
Fuck.
What the fuck is wrong with you?
(grunting)
(sniffing)
Oh.
(panting)
Oh, my God.
That bitch.
Got a horse.
Those are frogs.
(laughing)
That's a cock.
Don't say it like that.
Please call it rooster.
Rooster's life.
Just fucking remember.
I'm fucking starving.
I need water.
You like shawarma?
I don't know.
(engine revving) (engine revving)
Hey.
How'd you find me?
I looked.
So how'd you do it?
Do what?
(laughing)
That isn't missing anything.
There you have it.
How the fuck does the fed up?
No idea it's been ripped off.
How's that happen?
You tell me.
You stole the old money
before it was shredded, huh?
Unfit currency.
(laughing) Technically.
I read that somewhere.
I fucking knew it.
Hey, stop.
Look, you gotta be fucking loaded, right?
Come on.
I don't know rich
people, but isn't it enough?
Why don't you stop?
I don't get it.
I can't.
You know where I'm from?
Hawthorne.
Mm-hmm.
I know everything.
And they're doty and rosecranes.
With the Popeye and the Cornoo
next to the Hawaiian barbecue place.
I killed that Hawaiian barbecue spot.
Right, with a side of fried rice?
Yeah, pineapple chicken.
Fuck yeah.
(clears throat) My Pops.
My Pops was blasted right in front of me
when I was six years old.
Some pi-rues at a larger part.
My mom, she had to support us.
She was a server at Marie Callender's
at the Delama Mall.
She ain't make shit.
One year for Christmas,
all she could afford was a
a nerve hoop that me
and my sister had to share.
That next year, I
was always good in school
and they moved me to
this magnet school in Torrance.
The only thing is I had
to walk to that motherfucker.
Three miles.
Every day.
It was in a nice area,
so the closer I got to school
around that last mile,
I started to see the shift.
Nice, big houses, super clean yards.
So I started to play
this little game in my mind.
I started to see patterns.
See if I can memorize all the houses,
how many people lived in it,
if they would go to work, for how long?
When papers would start
to stack up on the front step.
Who had dogs, who
didn't, what type they were.
Had that neighborhood clocked in no time.
So, Christmas is coming back around,
and I feel my mama's anxiety.
Another fucking year,
where she can't get her shit.
On my way to school, I decided to look
and see what was in one of them houses.
It'll never be enough.
It's because it's not about the money.
It's about the challenge.
Can I get in and get out
without anyone even knowing I was there?
And I just started leveling up.
Where you gonna meet for Christmas?
A coupon to the Hofbrau.
I fucking love that place.
Seeing this weird couple's therapy,
my old man owned a liquor store
right over there off the
shit from anybody ever.
And there was no way he
was gonna open that register.
I had just 38 that
he kept under the counter.
Right there.
And he looked down at it.
These dudes must have gotten spooked
that he was gonna blast their ass
because one asshole shot him.
Like there.
Carpet of blood just below the hip.
He survived.
But from that day
on, he had this fucking limp.
He had it to the day he died.
Never the same.
He put a brave face on, but...
I used to watch him
work, to work every day.
He just put one
foot in front of the other.
That fucking limp.
Broke my heart.
All I could think about was
getting the motherfuckers that did it.
They never did. Never got them.
When I grew up, first chance I got,
I got a gun, I got a
badge, I started to hunt.
Fuck.
This time no one gets hurt.
Absolutely.
(dog barking)
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Okay, okay.
Let's go. Okay.
I didn't even call an Uber.
Fuck it. Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Get in the fucking car.
(engine rumbling)
(speaking Spanish) (somber music)
(speaking Spanish)
A few weeks ago there was a flight
from Africa to Antwerp.
It had something on it.
Something that belongs to us.
To the octopus.
And you stole it.
Get it back.
(engine rumbling)
Hey!
Get the fuck back here!
Are you kidding me?
You stole diamonds
from the fucking mafia?
Like I fucking knew.
Fuck!
Where you going?
Nick! Nick!
Take your shoes off.
Your sink.
Shoes, shoes.
Now what?
What the fuck do you think?
Swim. Swim?
Where, Nick? Oh, to Libya.
What the fuck do you
think, dumb, dumb, to shore?
I can't swim that fucking farm.
I'm negatively buoyant.
Don't you know David Goggin?
Fuck me.
Don't be such a pussy.
Fuck you.
You think it sucks around here?
Actually, yeah, I think it's infested.
You kind of look like shark food.
Stop talking to me.
I hate you.
I fucking hate you, too.
(Wet splashing)
(Grunting)
Fuck it.
I'm out.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. What's your "me"?
Capo di Tutti Capio, where the
fucking skull is where I draw the line.
They go after
families. They don't give a fuck.
You can't do me like that.
All right, I'm dead if you don't.
Well, you're the one that
stole the fucking diamond. I didn't.
What's...
You going bail on me,
you might as well arrest me.
Fuck it.
(Panting)
Don't fucking follow me.
You followed me here.
Deep out there, bitch.
(Door opens)
(Sniffles)
(Sighs)
(Phone rings)
How's the hangover, Mademoiselle?
You watching?
Yep.
Most guards don't do shit.
Smoke, dick around on phones, watch porn.
Those boys are different.
Very.
Been clocking those dudes
for weeks. Those dogs can hunt.
Yeah. This is gonna be interesting.
You feeling it?
Yeah, I'm feeling it.
And the cop goes, gangster.
Get your ass over here,
man. Your espresso's getting cold.
The WDC has no fire doors, no
emergency exit, or increase point.
There's only one door.
One way in, one way out.
Any moments within the district
will result in you coming at a picture.
So there's only one
place they're not looking.
Help.
Bravo.
Dragon.
You're gonna have to put this on.
He's on sale or something?
Where are my two boyfriends?
They're out.
Welcome.
Mako and Vuk, when on?
Your partner now.
This is the entire theater.
We've reckoned every
security measure in the district.
As you can see, there are no dead zones.
So we'll have to create one.
There are 127 cameras fed into
central security right here in this kiosk.
They only run 10 CCTV monitors.
So those 127 feeds cycle through.
At 10 second intervals.
At any given time,
117 of those views are dark.
We will perform a time descent that will
move us undetected
through those dark zones.
As a result of the CCTV monitoring cycle.
What about the recorded
footage once the cameras are offline?
There's a WDC
privacy law that prevents it.
So no footage is being
recorded. It's just being viewed in real time.
But we have a blind spot and a problem.
So the only individuals that are
granted access to the vault is the concierge,
the site holders and their
private security who must be law enforcement.
We tried to flip some
internal assets with access but...
So you're our way in.
Okay.
When does this happen?
Right now.
Like right the fuck now.
You sure you got the
right email? Maybe check.
Yeah. Don't understand.
Oh, here we are. It went to my junk.
Sorry for that.
It happens.
Everything is okay.
Yeah, wonderful.
Okay, man. Just on our way.
Just... just out of here.
Yeah?
Bonjour.
This is Nick, my head of
security. Nick, c'est la façon.
Bonjour.
Ah, non français, eh?
By the way, the derby.
Miesz Manik, are you going?
Olivier de concierge.
Me, some friends,
we're going to support this bar.
Saturday?
Yes.
How am I joining you?
Yeah, come. Come, my friends.
Merci.
So Nick will go with
you to deposit the inventory.
Does tomorrow still work?
Yeah, but first thing in the
morning, I took lock because I'm slammed tomorrow.
Bonjour.
Bonjour. Thank you.
See you. music)
Why, bro? Why?
I don't know what's going on.
Thanks to all the musicians.
Love you, all the money.
Hey!
For real gangster.
You want your life?
Yeah, for real.
This is why y'all
so amped up all the time.
Oh, my god.
Hey.
Now, this is music.
OK.
Wow.
Romantico.
Oh, my god.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
You gotta make love more often, bro.
See, Dragong, he smooth with it.
Them glasses don't fool me.
I see you.
Yeah.
Oh.
You pent up.
Your suit.
It's an ISR.
Records in every direction.
Oh.
All right.
You sure this thing's going to work?
I've worn these in 500 jewelry stores.
They work.
Well, you're a woman.
They tend then to get
frisked, especially beautiful ones.
Well, neither do
cops, especially good ones.
Fucking hate suits.
Nothing good ever happens in a suit.
That was fun the other night.
You know, at the club.
Yeah.
Good DJ.
Cool fight.
I just got divorced.
Oh, that's so sad.
For the record, no attraction to you.
OK.
You got any kids?
No.
Actually, yeah.
You know, I prefer
honesty rather than bullshit.
Then yeah, I do.
I got two.
Dang it.
I thought you were going to wife me up.
I changed my answer.
Don't fuck this up.
Don't fuck me over.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Come.
Bonjour.
My detail.
We have an appointment at the boss
with Miss Falcone in the concierge.
All right.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
You see?
You're good to go.
Come there.
Come.
OK.
Press this cargo.
Thank you so much, Chama.
I have to go.
Come.
Bonjour.
Good morning.
Morning.
Please.
The concierge operates the vault 24-7,
lives on the seventh floor escorts.
Every appointment locks up every night.
Moving on this with him.
Anywhere near there would be very risky.
Yeah, but we'll just
tell him what his movements.
So no more being shared for you.
I tend to hurt people's feelings.
They all fit right in.
Please.
There is a thermal motion.
Yeah.
Can you turn off?
I'm sorry.
There is the vault.
Arm on.
You can put a brief
concern with that side, please.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
How are you?
Did you get involved in most something?
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
Perfect.
The remaining issue is that the security
camera from Hollywood to the foyer
is too high up for us to cover.
And that's the only
camera that doesn't cycle.
What if we cover ourselves?
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
What are we looking at?
I saw the stone.
The top left side.
Second row fit from the top.
I saw the fucking stone.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
Good.
[MUSIC PLAYING] [MUSIC PLAYING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
You're enjoying your time off, huh?
You know, beautiful family.
What?
[SPEAKING FRENCH] Hey there.
I have to go.
Hey.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
I need to quit this shit, man.
I try pretty much every fucking day.
[LAUGHS] So how often you got to see him?
We try for a couple
of time a week, you know?
Well, that's fucking involved.
[LAUGHS] You the same?
I wish.
Christmas and birthdays only.
You know, we go out
into the world, you know?
We try to sort out these problems.
But all we do is we bring them home.
Yeah, it must really
fucking suck being married to a cop.
Well-- be careful
of your new friends, huh?
I'll see you around, Lieutenant.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Low tech beats high tech.
Watch now.
Voila.
Fuck.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Now you stole that garlic over here.
OK.
Now you know, turn around.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
I guess he's making some sales.
[PHONE RINGING]
Are you guys clean?
Come on.
Jalala.
I'm fucking good.
Yo, is that thermal?
Huh?
Is that thermal?
Yeah.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
We're in there again.
[LAUGHTER]
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
Consierge just left.
See you at the van at the egress point.
Copy.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
[APPLAUSE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Anyone, this is carbon actual.
Comes check.
Carbon actual copy.
Comms clear.
Routine one moving on theater.
Copy that.
Routine one in theater.
[MUSIC PLAYING] [MUSIC PLAYING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[CHEERING]
Come on, come on, come on.
Come on.
[CHEERING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Routine one, you are red at
AMSTL 20 seconds to green light.
Copy, carbon actual.
Standing by for green.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
10 seconds to green light.
Five, four.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
You're green, green to Bex.
Green.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Copy, you're red at Bex.
Red at Bex.
12 seconds to green light.
Stand by.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Five, four, three.
Jesus, that's deep.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Fucking hell.
80 seconds to red.
Copy that, carbon actual.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
60 seconds to red.
Come on, eat it more.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
40 seconds to red.
20 seconds to red.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
10 seconds to red.
Five, four, three, two, one.
Corona's red.
Red at Corona.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Houdini One location.
Houdini One and mine shaft at diamond.
Houdini One, quantum at
diamond, quantum at diamond.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Holy shit.
The diamond mantle.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
It's not here.
It's not fucking here.
What do you mean it's not fucking here?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Fuck, it's not here either.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
No, I didn't hear him.
Why?
Sorry.
Bye, guys.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Fuck.
Uddini-1 housekeeper is home.
Return to mine shaft.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Housekeeper is home.
Get the fuck out now.
Fuck.
We gotta go.
OK.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
See it?
No.
See it.
My engine.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Here.
We gotta go, guys.
No, no, no, no.
It's here.
Come on, come on, come on.
One more sec.
Donny, keep going.
Come on, come on.
Wait.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Donny, just fucking leave it.
We gotta go.
Now.
Wait.
What the heck?
Fuck it, God.
Who did he want to come in?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Put any one over on my chest.
Copy.
[GRUNTING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Who did he want to call in Corona?
You're green at Corona.
140 seconds, green at Corona.
Box out of gear.
60 seconds at Corona.
Advex, Advex.
Hold at Vex.
Corona red in 45.
Corona red in 30.
Fuck.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[INAUDIBLE]
Clear.
Hold at Vex.
Corona red in 20.
Vex red.
Three seconds to switch rooms.
Hold for command.
Vex green.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
Carbonation, we are clear.
Okay.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Shit.
Nick! Nick!
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
What the--
Come on.
Check it out.
GB.
Houdini one dogs on the scent.
Vanish.
Fuck.
[GRUNTING]
Come on.
Come on, Nick.
[GRUNTING]
Yeah.
Turn the backpack.
Fuck.
Okay.
Go. Go. Go.
The pole.
Move, move, move.
Carbonation is Vex green.
Copy.
Confirm Houdini one, Vex green.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
So I want you to clear
the ice cream stairs, all right?
Okay. Super.
And don't forget to lock
down the fucking elevator, yeah?
Okay. I'll shoot. [MUSIC PLAYING]
[DOOR OPENS]
Who's clear?
Carbonation.
Location of Houdini one.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
What the fuck is this?
Hands off weapon.
Just relax.
Don't be stupid.
Hey.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
Don't be fucking stupid.
What the fuck?
What the fuck? What the fuck?
Oh, man.
What the fuck?
Relax. Relax.
I am so mad.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
You okay?
It's going to hurt a few days, though.
Sorry about that.
[MUSIC PLAYING] Street,
vanish north side. Now, now, now.
We got him. We got
him. North side. North side.
Copy that.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
It's him. It's him.
Let's go. Let's go. We got to go.
[GRUNTS]
[TIRES SQUEALING]
Ah, fuck.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
Shit. A.M.P.R.
[ call to push units ]
( roar)
[Breathing heavily]
Parker.
If any of us get burned,
Soba-dan will put your cut away,
and it'll be waiting
for you when you get out.
Good luck.
Parker, soon.
Good luck, brother.
[Door closes]
[Door opens]
Flash, flash.
Watch our six. Those
aren't the least headlights.
They're not friendly either.
Fuck.
Mac.
Drive.
Ship.
Call outbreaks.
Copy.
Shit. There's two of them.
[Gunshots]
Fuck. Take the wheel, wheel.
Hey, move, move.
I'm good, I'm good.
[Gunshots]
Catch it.
Give me a better shot.
Hold on.
I can hear you.
[Gunshots]
[Grunts]
Fuck.
I'm fucking right up here.
Hold on.
[Gunshots]
Mac, change.
You all right?
Yeah, I'm okay.
[Gunshots] Me and your muck.
So, just grab an open.
Hey there.
Shit. Still honest. Can you lose him?
Fuckin' trying. These dudes are drivers.
Oh, shit.
[Growling]
[Growling] [Growling] [Speaking Spanish]
[Gunshots]
[Grunts]
Shit. Fuck.
Find a site. I got a clean shot.
Got some break.
[Gunshots]
[Growling]
Come on. Mac, change.
Black on ammo.
[Growling]
[Gunshots]
Son, son, son.
Fuck this.
[Gunshots]
Fuck you.
[Speaking Spanish]
[Gunshots]
Okay, I'm out.
Fuck!
[Gunshots] Fuck.
[Grunting]
Fuck.
[Gunshots]
[Grunting]
[Panting]
[Gunshots]
What the fuck was that?
It was fire.
[Gasping]
[Gunshots]
[Panting]
[Gunshots] [Gunshots]
[Gunshots]
[Suspenseful music]
(speaking in foreign language)
Hey.
Hey you.
It's okay.
Yeah, man.
(speaking in foreign language)
Jean-Jacques.
Nice to meet you.
(speaking in foreign language)
Take a seat please.
(groans)
(laughing)
(speaking in foreign language)
Thank you.
You say it down.
Okay guys, stand up please.
To high self-century.
And to the Panthers.
We believe.
Oh.
You good?
I'm good.
(laughing)
I think Jean-Jacques won.
This is for you.
(speaking in foreign language)
Look at that.
(laughing)
Hey, thank you.
Your style.
Smartest, smartest.
(laughing)
(dramatic music)
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
(yelling)
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
Come on, come on.
(yelling)
Sit down, sit down.
Let's go.
(yelling)
Move, move.
Move.
Let's go.
(yelling)
(speaking in foreign language)
You okay?
Yeah.
You want to do something else?
You do.
You're a jurisdiction.
(sighing)
(dramatic music)
Anything you say can
and will be used against you
in a court of law.
You have the right to an attorney.
If you cannot--
(speaking in foreign language)
(somber music)
These rights in mind,
do you wish to speak to me?
Well played.
I guess.
You want something else?
I have a croissant.
Oh ho ho, parfait.
You know you did the
right thing coming in, huh?
It's strange, huh?
Living on the other side feels good, no?
Yeah.
Too good.
Respect.
Time to go home, huh?
To what?
(somber music)
(speaking in foreign language)
That was fun.
So we're even?
Yeah, we're even.
Feel good about yourself?
Actually, no, I thought
I would feel a little better,
to be honest.
You're a piece of shit.
I need to save your life, Phil.
So that was real?
Yeah, yeah.
So you've just been
fucking with me, this whole time?
No, no, not the whole time.
But at the end of the day,
a tiger just can't change his stripes.
Just can't.
(somber music)
I'll see you for all I'm.
By the way, sit back left.
(somber music)
(sighs)
(speaking in foreign language)
(somber music)
(buzzer)
(wind howling)
(somber music)
(speaking in foreign language)
Back left!
(wind howling)
Get ready to move.
(wind howling) (wind howling)
(wind howling)
Did we just get this over with already?
(speaking in foreign language)
No.
He says relax, enjoy your beer.
(speaking in foreign language)
He says that if he wanted you gone,
that would have happened a long time ago.
(speaking in foreign language)
He wants to meet you.
Because he wants to meet
the man who got his goods back.
(speaking in foreign language)
Because he wants to
know how the hell you did it.
You are an hairy fucking hoodie.
(laughing)
And now you work for me.
So what's next?
(gentle music)
I was the king of my homeland
Facing 10% dust
I'll fight until the end
(gentle music)
The features of my dreams
Raise up and dance with me
Now and forever
I will care
(gentle music)