1
00:01:03,000 --> 00:01:08,000


2
00:01:10,000 --> 00:01:15,000


3
00:01:18,000 --> 00:01:23,000


4
00:01:26,000 --> 00:01:31,000


5
00:05:06,381 --> 00:05:09,832


6
00:05:31,581 --> 00:05:32,832
Get Charlie.

7
00:05:43,927 --> 00:05:45,595
Dr. Holloway!

8
00:05:48,473 --> 00:05:49,808
Charlie!

9
00:05:58,692 --> 00:05:59,442
What?

10
00:06:00,193 --> 00:06:02,028
Come quick!

11
00:06:06,193 --> 00:06:09,328


12
00:06:31,850 --> 00:06:34,060
- Did you date it?  - Thirty-five thousand years.

13
00:06:34,227 --> 00:06:36,271
Maybe older.

14
00:07:00,003 --> 00:07:02,380
You gotta be kidding me.

15
00:07:05,258 --> 00:07:07,010
It's the same configuration.

16
00:07:08,803 --> 00:07:12,098
I mean, it's gotta predate the others by millennia.

17
00:07:25,862 --> 00:07:28,156
I think they want us to come and find them.

18
00:07:30,867 --> 00:07:31,952
Yeah.

19
00:07:52,467 --> 00:08:07,752


20
00:08:37,892 --> 00:08:40,437
What happened to that man?

21
00:08:40,603 --> 00:08:41,688
He died.

22
00:08:43,148 --> 00:08:44,566
Why aren't you helping them?

23
00:08:45,859 --> 00:08:47,569
They don't want my help.

24
00:08:47,736 --> 00:08:49,279
Their God is different than ours.

25
00:08:51,614 --> 00:08:53,033
Why did he die?

26
00:08:53,950 --> 00:08:55,869
Because sooner or later, everyone does.

27
00:08:56,035 --> 00:08:57,287
Like Mummy?

28
00:08:59,289 --> 00:09:00,540
Like Mummy.

29
00:09:02,292 --> 00:09:03,918
Where do they go?

30
00:09:05,462 --> 00:09:07,547
Everyone has their own word.

31
00:09:07,797 --> 00:09:08,965
Heaven.

32
00:09:09,632 --> 00:09:10,467
Paradise.

33
00:09:12,302 --> 00:09:14,596
Whatever it's called, it's someplace beautiful.

34
00:09:14,763 --> 00:09:16,431
How do you know it's beautiful?

35
00:09:18,475 --> 00:09:19,976
That's what I choose to believe.

36
00:09:20,310 --> 00:09:21,936
What do you believe, Ellie?

37
00:09:56,304 --> 00:09:58,098
Good morning, David.

38
00:09:59,182 --> 00:10:00,642
Transmitting message.

39
00:10:03,853 --> 00:10:05,688
No response.

40
00:10:15,406 --> 00:10:16,866
Whilst this articulation...

41
00:10:17,033 --> 00:10:19,786
is attested in the Indo-European descendants...

42
00:10:19,953 --> 00:10:21,830
as a purely paralinguistic form...

43
00:10:21,996 --> 00:10:25,083
It is phonemic in the ancestral form dating back...

44
00:10:25,250 --> 00:10:27,210
five millennia or more.

45
00:10:27,877 --> 00:10:29,379
Let's attempt Schleicher's fable.

46
00:10:29,879 --> 00:10:30,672
Repeat after me.

47
00:10:44,060 --> 00:10:45,186
Perfect.

48
00:10:45,770 --> 00:10:48,064
- Mr. Lawrence?   - Yes?

49
00:10:48,565 --> 00:10:50,483
- Flimsy, sir.  - Thank you.

50
00:10:57,532 --> 00:11:00,159
You do that once too often. It's only flesh and blood!

51
00:11:00,910 --> 00:11:03,413
Michael George Hartley, you're a philosopher.

52
00:11:03,955 --> 00:11:05,248
And you're barmy.

53
00:11:10,712 --> 00:11:13,089
- It damn well hurts!  - Certainly, it hurts.

54
00:11:14,215 --> 00:11:15,717
Well, what's the trick, then?

55
00:11:16,593 --> 00:11:19,679
The trick, William Potter, is not minding that it hurts

56
00:11:20,138 --> 00:11:23,433
The trick, William Potter...

57
00:11:23,600 --> 00:11:26,686
is not minding that it hurts.

58
00:11:32,233 --> 00:11:35,236
The trick, William Potter...

59
00:11:35,820 --> 00:11:39,324
is not minding that it hurts.

60
00:11:52,962 --> 00:11:54,631
Attention:

61
00:11:54,797 --> 00:11:56,215
Destination threshold.

62
00:11:56,633 --> 00:11:57,717
Attention:

63
00:11:57,884 --> 00:11:59,886
Destination threshold.

64
00:12:00,345 --> 00:12:02,847
Attention: Destination threshold.

65
00:13:05,159 --> 00:13:06,202
Robe.

66
00:13:17,672 --> 00:13:18,965
How long?

67
00:13:19,215 --> 00:13:21,509
Two years, four months, 18 days...

68
00:13:21,676 --> 00:13:22,885
36 hours, 15 minutes.

69
00:13:23,219 --> 00:13:24,470
Any casualties?

70
00:13:25,013 --> 00:13:26,139
Casualties, ma'am?

71
00:13:26,306 --> 00:13:27,390
Has anyone died?

72
00:13:27,932 --> 00:13:29,851
No, ma'am. Everyone is fine.

73
00:13:31,936 --> 00:13:33,479
Well, then wake them up.

74
00:13:44,741 --> 00:13:46,701
Try to relax, Dr. Shaw.

75
00:13:47,910 --> 00:13:49,495
My name is David.

76
00:13:50,872 --> 00:13:53,249
Your mind and body are in a state of shock...

77
00:13:53,416 --> 00:13:55,501
as a result of the stasis.

78
00:13:55,752 --> 00:13:57,628
It's all right. Perfectly normal.

79
00:13:57,837 --> 00:13:58,588
Ellie.

80
00:13:59,881 --> 00:14:01,257
We're here, baby.

81
00:14:05,595 --> 00:14:06,429
There, there.

82
00:14:08,264 --> 00:14:10,475
Drink plenty of water. Drink plenty of fluids.

83
00:14:12,018 --> 00:14:13,436
Hydration aids muscle mass.

84
00:14:18,608 --> 00:14:21,694
All crew, consume shakes with high caloric content.

85
00:14:27,950 --> 00:14:30,119
What the hell is that?

86
00:14:32,205 --> 00:14:33,081
It's Christmas.

87
00:14:33,498 --> 00:14:34,624
We need the holidays...

88
00:14:34,791 --> 00:14:36,334
to show time is still moving.

89
00:14:36,501 --> 00:14:37,418
Mission briefing...

90
00:14:37,585 --> 00:14:39,128
is about to start, captain.

91
00:14:39,629 --> 00:14:41,214
Might wanna make your way down.

92
00:14:41,464 --> 00:14:43,800
Well, I haven't had any breakfast yet.

93
00:14:44,300 --> 00:14:45,718
Is this seat taken?

94
00:14:46,803 --> 00:14:49,430
Hi, I'm Millburn, Biology. Nice to meet you.

95
00:14:51,641 --> 00:14:52,392
Okay.

96
00:14:52,558 --> 00:14:56,062
Look, no offense, but...

97
00:14:56,604 --> 00:14:58,648
I've been asleep two years.

98
00:14:59,315 --> 00:15:01,859
I ain't here to be your friend.

99
00:15:02,151 --> 00:15:03,486
I'm here to make money.

100
00:15:04,612 --> 00:15:05,947
You got that?

101
00:15:08,491 --> 00:15:09,659
Okay.

102
00:15:10,159 --> 00:15:12,870
I bet a hundred credits it's a terraforming survey.

103
00:15:13,037 --> 00:15:14,997
No, if it's a survey, they would tell us.

104
00:15:15,164 --> 00:15:17,416
It's a corporate run, they're not telling us shit.

105
00:15:17,583 --> 00:15:18,417
Come on.

106
00:15:18,584 --> 00:15:20,503
- A hundred.  - All right, you're on.

107
00:15:25,174 --> 00:15:26,592
You look nervous, El.

108
00:15:27,176 --> 00:15:30,012
- I'll try to keep my feet on the ground.  - I know you will.

109
00:15:30,179 --> 00:15:31,097
Good morning.

110
00:15:31,848 --> 00:15:34,392
For those of you I hired personally...

111
00:15:35,393 --> 00:15:37,520
it's nice to see you again.

112
00:15:38,312 --> 00:15:42,191
For the rest of you, I am Meredith Vickers. It's my job to make sure you do yours.

113
00:15:42,692 --> 00:15:45,278
Okay, then. On with the show.

114
00:15:50,867 --> 00:15:52,618
Weyland Corporation.

115
00:15:52,869 --> 00:15:54,871
Building better worlds.

116
00:15:56,164 --> 00:15:57,748
Hello, friends.

117
00:15:59,709 --> 00:16:01,461
My name is Peter Weyland.

118
00:16:03,504 --> 00:16:05,298
I am your employer.

119
00:16:05,548 --> 00:16:10,595
I am recording this, 22 June, 2091. And if you're watching it...

120
00:16:11,387 --> 00:16:13,556
you have reached your destination.

121
00:16:14,223 --> 00:16:16,225
And I am long dead.

122
00:16:16,851 --> 00:16:18,811
May I rest in peace.

123
00:16:20,021 --> 00:16:23,191
There's a man sitting with you today. His name is David.

124
00:16:23,357 --> 00:16:26,402
And he is the closest thing to a son I will ever have.

125
00:16:26,694 --> 00:16:29,447
Unfortunately, he is not human.

126
00:16:29,739 --> 00:16:30,990
He will never grow old...

127
00:16:31,240 --> 00:16:33,117
and he will never die.

128
00:16:34,076 --> 00:16:37,246
And yet he is unable to appreciate these remarkable gifts...

129
00:16:37,413 --> 00:16:41,751
for that would require the one thing that David will never have.

130
00:16:41,918 --> 00:16:43,085
A soul.

131
00:16:44,086 --> 00:16:45,838
I have spent my entire...

132
00:16:46,005 --> 00:16:48,466
lifetime contemplating the questions:

133
00:16:48,758 --> 00:16:50,259
Where do we come from?

134
00:16:50,593 --> 00:16:52,053
What is our purpose?

135
00:16:52,345 --> 00:16:53,763
What happens when we die?

136
00:16:54,472 --> 00:16:58,392
And I have found two people who have convinced me they're on the verge of answering them.

137
00:16:59,101 --> 00:17:02,063
Drs. Holloway and Shaw, if you would please stand.

138
00:17:04,357 --> 00:17:06,442
As far as you're concerned, they're in charge.

139
00:17:07,568 --> 00:17:12,156
The Titan Prometheus wanted to give mankind equal footing with the gods...

140
00:17:12,323 --> 00:17:15,910
and for that, he was cast from Olympus.

141
00:17:16,786 --> 00:17:21,624
Well, my friends, the time has finally come for his return.

142
00:17:22,250 --> 00:17:23,209
Doctors, please.

143
00:17:27,546 --> 00:17:28,464
The floor is yours.

144
00:17:36,973 --> 00:17:38,975
Okay, wow.

145
00:17:39,141 --> 00:17:40,518
All right.

146
00:17:40,685 --> 00:17:42,478
I never had to follow a ghost before.

147
00:17:42,853 --> 00:17:44,897
Okay, let me show you why you guys...

148
00:17:45,064 --> 00:17:46,190
are here.

149
00:17:53,656 --> 00:17:58,828
These are images of archeological digs from all over the Earth.

150
00:17:58,995 --> 00:17:59,829
That's...

151
00:17:59,996 --> 00:18:03,332
Egyptian, Mayan, Sumerian, Babylonian.

152
00:18:03,624 --> 00:18:06,419
That's Hawaiian there at the end, then Mesopotamian.

153
00:18:06,669 --> 00:18:09,672
Now, this one here is our most recent discovery.

154
00:18:09,839 --> 00:18:13,843
It's a 35,000-year-old cave painting from the Isle of Skye in Scotland.

155
00:18:14,135 --> 00:18:18,347
These are ancient civilizations. They were separated by centuries.

156
00:18:18,514 --> 00:18:21,600
They shared no contact with one another, and yet...

157
00:18:25,438 --> 00:18:26,522
the same pictogram...

158
00:18:26,689 --> 00:18:30,318
showing men worshipping giant beings, pointing to the stars...

159
00:18:30,526 --> 00:18:33,487
was discovered at every last one of them.

160
00:18:34,030 --> 00:18:36,657
And the only galactic system that matched...

161
00:18:37,700 --> 00:18:40,244
was so far from Earth that there's no way...

162
00:18:40,411 --> 00:18:44,540
that these primitive, ancient civilizations could have possibly known about it.

163
00:18:44,707 --> 00:18:46,208
But it just so happens...

164
00:18:47,918 --> 00:18:49,253
is that system...

165
00:18:50,713 --> 00:18:51,839
has a sun...

166
00:18:52,882 --> 00:18:54,300
a lot like ours.

167
00:18:55,343 --> 00:18:59,680
And, based on our long-range scans, there seemed to be a planet.

168
00:19:01,098 --> 00:19:03,392
Just one planet with a moon...

169
00:19:03,559 --> 00:19:05,436
capable of sustaining life.

170
00:19:06,896 --> 00:19:08,981
And we arrived there this morning.

171
00:19:11,233 --> 00:19:16,072
So you're saying we're here because of a map you two kids found in a cave. Is that right?

172
00:19:17,365 --> 00:19:18,658
- No.  - Yeah.

173
00:19:20,910 --> 00:19:23,371
No. Not a map, an invitation.

174
00:19:23,537 --> 00:19:24,914
From who?

175
00:19:26,415 --> 00:19:28,167
We call them Engineers.

176
00:19:29,085 --> 00:19:30,586
Engineers?

177
00:19:30,753 --> 00:19:31,587
Do you mind...

178
00:19:32,630 --> 00:19:34,423
telling us what they engineered?

179
00:19:36,425 --> 00:19:38,094
They engineered us.

180
00:19:40,846 --> 00:19:41,680
Bullshit.

181
00:19:43,891 --> 00:19:45,768
Okay, so do you...

182
00:19:45,935 --> 00:19:47,603
have anything to back that up?

183
00:19:48,270 --> 00:19:50,106
Look, if you're willing to discount...

184
00:19:50,272 --> 00:19:52,108
centuries of Darwinism, that's...

185
00:19:55,319 --> 00:19:56,278
But how do you know?

186
00:19:57,780 --> 00:19:59,115
I don't.

187
00:19:59,615 --> 00:20:01,742
But it's what I choose to believe.

188
00:20:29,645 --> 00:20:30,688
Doctors.

189
00:20:31,772 --> 00:20:35,818
Miss Vickers would like to have a quick word before the adventure begins.

190
00:20:43,284 --> 00:20:44,285
Wow, nice place.

191
00:20:44,452 --> 00:20:48,581
It's actually a separate module with its own self-contained life support.

192
00:20:49,039 --> 00:20:50,708
Air, food.

193
00:20:51,000 --> 00:20:54,587
Anything Miss Vickers would need to survive a hostile environment.

194
00:20:54,837 --> 00:20:56,797
Okay, so she lives on a lifeboat.

195
00:20:56,964 --> 00:20:58,007
Yes.

196
00:20:58,174 --> 00:20:58,841
I do.

197
00:20:59,008 --> 00:21:01,260
I like to minimize risk.

198
00:21:01,844 --> 00:21:05,431
David, why don't you make the doctors a drink?

199
00:21:06,015 --> 00:21:08,768
I'll take a vodka. Up.

200
00:21:09,185 --> 00:21:10,603
Charlie, look.

201
00:21:10,769 --> 00:21:13,147
It's a Pauling Med-Pod.

202
00:21:13,439 --> 00:21:15,816
They only made a dozen of these.

203
00:21:15,983 --> 00:21:16,817
Miss Shaw.

204
00:21:16,984 --> 00:21:19,445
Please verbally state the nature of your injury.

205
00:21:19,862 --> 00:21:21,530
Please don't touch that.

206
00:21:21,697 --> 00:21:23,657
It's a very expensive piece of machinery.

207
00:21:24,200 --> 00:21:26,702
It does bypass surgely. What do you need it for?

208
00:21:28,537 --> 00:21:31,165
There might be some confusion about our relationship.

209
00:21:32,249 --> 00:21:35,044
Weyland found you impressive enough to fund this mission.

210
00:21:35,211 --> 00:21:37,713
But I'm fairly certain your Engineers are scribblings...

211
00:21:37,880 --> 00:21:40,132
of savages living in dirty little caves.

212
00:21:41,342 --> 00:21:44,386
But let's say I'm wrong, and you do find these beings down there...

213
00:21:45,554 --> 00:21:47,681
you won't engage them...

214
00:21:47,973 --> 00:21:49,433
you won't talk to them.

215
00:21:49,725 --> 00:21:52,353
You will do nothing but report back to me.

216
00:21:55,898 --> 00:21:58,150
Miss Vickers, is there an agenda that...

217
00:21:58,317 --> 00:21:59,944
you're not telling us about?

218
00:22:00,569 --> 00:22:01,195
My company...

219
00:22:01,362 --> 00:22:03,906
paid a trillion dollars to find this place and bring you.

220
00:22:04,073 --> 00:22:06,867
Had you raised the monies yourself, Mr. Holloway...

221
00:22:07,034 --> 00:22:09,912
we'd happily be pursuing your agenda.

222
00:22:11,247 --> 00:22:12,498
But you didn't.

223
00:22:12,915 --> 00:22:14,500
And that makes you an employee.

224
00:22:15,960 --> 00:22:17,962
But if we can't make contact...

225
00:22:18,128 --> 00:22:20,631
why did you even bring us here?

226
00:22:21,423 --> 00:22:24,176
Weyland was a superstitious man.

227
00:22:24,885 --> 00:22:27,263
He wanted a true believer on board.

228
00:22:29,932 --> 00:22:31,100
Cheers.

229
00:22:34,436 --> 00:22:35,604
So no response?

230
00:22:36,230 --> 00:22:37,356
I'm sorry, no.

231
00:22:37,523 --> 00:22:39,441
Maybe they didn't understand it.

232
00:22:40,818 --> 00:22:42,862
How are your lessons going, David?

233
00:22:44,071 --> 00:22:47,616
I spent two years deconstructing dozens of ancient languages...

234
00:22:48,242 --> 00:22:49,869
to their roots. I'm confident...

235
00:22:50,035 --> 00:22:51,537
I can communicate with them...

236
00:22:51,787 --> 00:22:53,956
provided your thesis is correct.

237
00:22:55,249 --> 00:22:57,376
"Provided it's correct." That's good.

238
00:22:57,543 --> 00:23:00,462
That's why they call it a thesis, doctor.

239
00:23:03,549 --> 00:23:05,259
What are you smiling about?

240
00:23:05,426 --> 00:23:07,303
Mr. Ravel, Mr. Chance, take her down.

241
00:23:07,469 --> 00:23:08,971
- Roger that.  - Yes, captain.

242
00:23:09,346 --> 00:23:10,806
Descent trajectory mapped.

243
00:23:11,140 --> 00:23:12,516
How we doing?

244
00:23:12,683 --> 00:23:13,767
Great.

245
00:23:14,977 --> 00:23:15,811
All right, boss.

246
00:23:16,478 --> 00:23:17,271
All personnel...

247
00:23:17,438 --> 00:23:18,606
this is the captain.

248
00:23:18,772 --> 00:23:20,190
Brace for entry.

249
00:23:20,357 --> 00:23:21,609
Yes, captain.

250
00:23:22,151 --> 00:23:23,652
That means you too, Vickers.

251
00:23:23,819 --> 00:23:24,945
All systems...

252
00:23:25,112 --> 00:23:26,113
online.

253
00:23:33,454 --> 00:23:34,705
What is the atmosphere?

254
00:23:34,872 --> 00:23:36,081
Atmosphere is...

255
00:23:36,248 --> 00:23:37,499
71 percent nitrogen...

256
00:23:37,666 --> 00:23:38,834
21 percent oxygen...

257
00:23:39,001 --> 00:23:40,127
traces of argon gas.

258
00:23:40,336 --> 00:23:42,421
Whoa, now, that's weather.

259
00:23:42,588 --> 00:23:43,672
Just like home.

260
00:23:43,839 --> 00:23:45,674
If you're breathing through an exhaust pipe.

261
00:23:46,175 --> 00:23:48,135
CO2 is over 3 percent.

262
00:23:48,302 --> 00:23:50,346
Two minutes without a suit, you're dead.

263
00:23:53,849 --> 00:23:54,975
Peak portside.

264
00:23:55,225 --> 00:23:56,977
Whoa, 52,000!

265
00:23:57,227 --> 00:23:59,355
It makes Everest look like a baby brother.

266
00:23:59,647 --> 00:24:01,857
All right, take us around.

267
00:24:02,024 --> 00:24:03,776
We'll use that as our point of entry.

268
00:24:06,195 --> 00:24:08,447
Terrain data rezzing up. We've got...

269
00:24:08,614 --> 00:24:10,032
a couple of hard spots.

270
00:24:10,199 --> 00:24:11,700
Could be metal.

271
00:24:32,513 --> 00:24:33,722
No radio, no heat source.

272
00:24:34,807 --> 00:24:35,891
Nobody's home.

273
00:24:37,142 --> 00:24:38,727
There is nothing in the desert...

274
00:24:39,561 --> 00:24:41,230
and no man needs nothing.

275
00:24:41,563 --> 00:24:42,815
What was that?

276
00:24:44,066 --> 00:24:46,151
Just something from a film I like.

277
00:24:50,489 --> 00:24:51,907
Let's go through that gateway.

278
00:24:52,199 --> 00:24:54,243
Reduce airspeed by a hundred knots.

279
00:24:58,872 --> 00:25:01,667
Going through. Nice and slow.

280
00:25:07,673 --> 00:25:08,757
Keep it steady, boys.

281
00:25:08,924 --> 00:25:09,591
There.

282
00:25:10,092 --> 00:25:11,760
No, what are you doing?

283
00:25:11,927 --> 00:25:14,805
Dr. Holloway, why don't you take a seat?

284
00:25:16,098 --> 00:25:18,058
Right there. God does not build in...

285
00:25:18,225 --> 00:25:21,353
straight lines. Starboard side, this valley! Captain...

286
00:25:21,520 --> 00:25:23,022
could you put us down there?

287
00:25:23,188 --> 00:25:25,441
I wouldn't be any good if I couldn't do that.

288
00:25:25,607 --> 00:25:28,944
Mr. Ravel, starboard 90 degrees.

289
00:25:33,824 --> 00:25:37,035
- One mile, port bow.  - One mile, port bow.

290
00:25:37,327 --> 00:25:38,954
Engage landing sequence.

291
00:25:39,121 --> 00:25:40,247
Switch to manual.

292
00:25:40,414 --> 00:25:41,582
- Commence landing.  - Easy.

293
00:25:41,749 --> 00:25:43,792
- Roger that.  - Yeah, baby, yeah.

294
00:25:46,587 --> 00:25:47,963
Bringing her down in five.

295
00:25:48,130 --> 00:25:49,923
- Preparing RCS thrusters.  - Four.

296
00:25:53,594 --> 00:25:55,304
Two. Easy does it.

297
00:26:12,946 --> 00:26:15,657
Generator systems are inactive.

298
00:26:15,824 --> 00:26:18,202
Temperature is at 2.724 K.

299
00:26:30,047 --> 00:26:31,089
Captain,

300
00:26:31,256 --> 00:26:33,258
would you tell the survey team to suit up

301
00:26:33,425 --> 00:26:34,843
and meet us in the airlock.

302
00:26:35,385 --> 00:26:37,179
Only six hours left of daylight.

303
00:26:37,346 --> 00:26:39,014
- Why don't you leave it till morning?  - No, no, no.

304
00:26:39,681 --> 00:26:41,183
It's Christmas, captain,

305
00:26:41,350 --> 00:26:43,227
and I want to open my presents.

306
00:26:43,519 --> 00:26:44,353
You, boy.

307
00:26:44,520 --> 00:26:45,854
You're coming with us.

308
00:26:46,188 --> 00:26:47,648
I'd be delighted.

309
00:26:53,195 --> 00:26:55,823
Attention: Ramp will open in five minutes.

310
00:26:58,033 --> 00:26:59,618
Hey, Jackson,

311
00:26:59,952 --> 00:27:01,245
what's that for?

312
00:27:01,995 --> 00:27:03,038
Expedition security.

313
00:27:03,205 --> 00:27:05,791
My job is to make sure everybody is nice and safe.

314
00:27:07,376 --> 00:27:10,337
This is a scientific expedition. No weapons.

315
00:27:10,504 --> 00:27:11,547
All right, then.

316
00:27:11,922 --> 00:27:13,298
Good luck with that.

317
00:27:16,218 --> 00:27:18,053
David, why are you wearing a suit, man?

318
00:27:19,555 --> 00:27:20,681
I beg your pardon?

319
00:27:20,848 --> 00:27:22,516
You don't breathe, remember?

320
00:27:22,683 --> 00:27:24,810
So why wear a suit?

321
00:27:25,394 --> 00:27:27,563
I was designed like this,

322
00:27:27,855 --> 00:27:31,942
because you people are more comfortable interacting with your own kind.

323
00:27:33,068 --> 00:27:36,405
If I didn't wear the suit, it would defeat the purpose.

324
00:27:37,364 --> 00:27:39,324
They're making you guys pretty close, huh?

325
00:27:39,908 --> 00:27:41,368
Not too close, I hope.

326
00:27:51,211 --> 00:27:53,755
Attention: Ramp will open in 15 seconds.

327
00:27:59,094 --> 00:28:00,846
Ramp will open in five...

328
00:28:01,013 --> 00:28:05,100
four, three, two, one.
4 3 2 1

329
00:28:22,451 --> 00:28:23,785
Hey.

330
00:28:24,453 --> 00:28:26,914
This is just one small step for mankind.

331
00:28:27,789 --> 00:28:28,790
Seriously?

332
00:28:34,963 --> 00:28:36,757
Come on. You ready to do this? I know you are.

333
00:28:47,434 --> 00:28:48,393
Hey, Fifield.

334
00:28:48,560 --> 00:28:49,728
I want a spectrograph on this.

335
00:28:49,895 --> 00:28:52,147
I want to know if it's natural or if somebody put it there.

336
00:28:52,314 --> 00:28:53,500
I can't tell you if it's natural or not. 

337
00:28:53,550 --> 00:28:57,277
But what I can tell you is, it's hollow.

338
00:29:21,426 --> 00:29:25,180
Prometheus, are you seeing this?

339
00:29:25,514 --> 00:29:26,682
Affirmative.

340
00:29:27,015 --> 00:29:28,308
We see it.

341
00:29:35,524 --> 00:29:36,191
Okay, ready?

342
00:29:36,358 --> 00:29:37,818
- Yeah.  - Let's do it.

343
00:30:11,268 --> 00:30:13,395
- After you.  - After you.

344
00:30:13,562 --> 00:30:14,521
Okay.

345
00:30:14,688 --> 00:30:15,731
Careful.

346
00:30:16,398 --> 00:30:18,400
Prometheus, we're going in.

347
00:30:18,567 --> 00:30:19,735
Copy that.

348
00:30:53,268 --> 00:30:54,102
Pause back here,

349
00:30:54,269 --> 00:30:56,396
some kind of a corridor.

350
00:30:57,272 --> 00:30:59,900
Mr. Fifield, let's get a grid of the structure.

351
00:31:00,067 --> 00:31:01,443
I want the whole interior.

352
00:31:02,444 --> 00:31:04,738
If there's anything in here worth looking at,

353
00:31:04,905 --> 00:31:06,198
these pups'll find them.

354
00:31:06,823 --> 00:31:07,783
Pups?

355
00:31:07,949 --> 00:31:10,285
Yeah, pups. My Pups.

356
00:31:25,092 --> 00:31:27,844
Prometheus, we are now mapping.

357
00:31:32,140 --> 00:31:33,225
Copy that.

358
00:31:45,570 --> 00:31:46,571
Well, I'll be damned.

359
00:32:01,294 --> 00:32:02,546
Fifield, you got a read?

360
00:32:02,712 --> 00:32:03,839
Yeah.

361
00:32:04,589 --> 00:32:07,509
Pups are saying this way.

362
00:32:26,111 --> 00:32:27,529
Look at this.

363
00:32:34,870 --> 00:32:36,496
Oh, Charlie.

364
00:32:40,500 --> 00:32:41,543
Jesus.

365
00:32:41,877 --> 00:32:43,712
The sunlight is heating the water.

366
00:32:44,379 --> 00:32:45,964
Check out the humidity.

367
00:32:46,131 --> 00:32:47,757
Yeah, and look at the CO2 levels.

368
00:32:48,258 --> 00:32:49,342
Outside,

369
00:32:49,509 --> 00:32:51,553
it's completely toxic, and in here，

370
00:32:51,720 --> 00:32:53,805
there's nothing. It's breathable.

371
00:32:55,891 --> 00:32:57,476
What are you doing?

372
00:32:57,642 --> 00:32:59,895
- Don't be an idiot.  - Don't be a skeptic.

373
00:33:00,395 --> 00:33:02,522
There's something generating an atmosphere.

374
00:33:02,898 --> 00:33:04,149
David?

375
00:33:04,316 --> 00:33:07,700
- Dr.Holloway is correct.  - Cleaner than Earth, actually.

376
00:33:07,986 --> 00:33:08,904
They were terraforming.

377
00:33:09,237 --> 00:33:10,697
Please don't do...

378
00:33:10,864 --> 00:33:12,657
I'm not wearing this thing any more.

379
00:33:13,200 --> 00:33:14,493
Wish me luck, baby.

380
00:33:14,659 --> 00:33:17,245
Do you copy? Do not remove your headgear.

381
00:33:33,845 --> 00:33:35,764
You crazy bastard.

382
00:33:40,435 --> 00:33:41,686
Prometheus, connect our suit cameras,

383
00:33:41,853 --> 00:33:46,107
if you want to continue watching this freak show. We are taking our helmets off.

384
00:33:47,234 --> 00:33:48,944
Copy that. Switching feeds.

385
00:33:50,946 --> 00:33:53,114
Well, come on. Pay up.

386
00:33:53,823 --> 00:33:56,535
- Pay what?  - What do you mean, "Pay what"?

387
00:33:56,701 --> 00:34:00,205
Something is manufacturing breathable air down there. That, mate...

388
00:34:00,372 --> 00:34:03,124
- is terraforming.  - No, no. The bet was why we came here.

389
00:34:03,291 --> 00:34:06,169
If you said a dead old man wanted to talk to Martians, I'd pay.

390
00:34:06,336 --> 00:34:07,712
Come on, a hundred credits.

391
00:34:07,879 --> 00:34:10,715
Put it towards a lap dance with Miss Vickers. How about that?

392
00:34:12,968 --> 00:34:15,136
It's minus 12 in here.

393
00:34:15,303 --> 00:34:17,430
So why is this water not frozen?

394
00:34:17,597 --> 00:34:19,015
Maybe it ain't water.

395
00:34:19,766 --> 00:34:21,226
Maybe it's Martian piss.

396
00:34:23,270 --> 00:34:26,314
That's your scientific theory?

397
00:34:26,481 --> 00:34:28,400
Is it? Mr.Biology?

398
00:34:32,612 --> 00:34:34,489
Whatever it is, it sure is collagenous.

399
00:34:35,615 --> 00:34:37,325
Some kind of sediment, perhaps.

400
00:34:57,345 --> 00:34:58,513
Impressive.

401
00:35:18,199 --> 00:35:18,950
What was that?

402
00:35:19,868 --> 00:35:21,077
David?

403
00:35:21,953 --> 00:35:22,621
David?

404
00:35:24,039 --> 00:35:25,290
What is that?

405
00:35:27,292 --> 00:35:28,209
David?

406
00:35:36,885 --> 00:35:38,219
Ellie!

407
00:35:43,058 --> 00:35:43,892
What the hell was that?

408
00:35:44,684 --> 00:35:46,561
Aren't you glad we didn't bring weapons?

409
00:35:46,728 --> 00:35:49,022
- Come on, El. Let's go.  - Whose idea was that?

410
00:35:49,439 --> 00:35:50,398
Keep up!

411
00:35:52,901 --> 00:35:53,485
Come on!

412
00:36:01,451 --> 00:36:02,786
Where did he go?

413
00:36:08,083 --> 00:36:09,667
Wait, wait, wait.

414
00:36:14,631 --> 00:36:17,717
There it is. There it is. There it is.

415
00:36:18,718 --> 00:36:21,221
Oh, my God, Charlie. We found them.

416
00:36:21,388 --> 00:36:22,931
What do you mean "them"?

417
00:36:24,224 --> 00:36:25,642
It is them, Ellie.

418
00:36:26,434 --> 00:36:28,019
It looks like a door,

419
00:36:28,395 --> 00:36:32,357
and he's been decapitated by it.

420
00:36:33,608 --> 00:36:35,110
Son of a bitch.

421
00:36:36,861 --> 00:36:38,238
They were right.

422
00:36:41,741 --> 00:36:43,827
What did you want them to be? Wrong?

423
00:36:47,622 --> 00:36:48,748
David,

424
00:36:49,457 --> 00:36:51,126
please tell me you can read that.

425
00:36:51,793 --> 00:36:53,044
Perhaps.

426
00:36:55,296 --> 00:36:56,965
No, I'm out of here.

427
00:36:58,967 --> 00:37:00,802
Hey, Fifield, where are you going?

428
00:37:02,470 --> 00:37:03,555
What?

429
00:37:05,306 --> 00:37:07,976
Look, I'm just a geologist.

430
00:37:08,143 --> 00:37:10,311
I like rocks. I love rocks!

431
00:37:10,770 --> 00:37:13,231
Now it's clear you two don't give a shit about rocks.

432
00:37:13,398 --> 00:37:16,860
But what you do seem to care about is gigantic dead bodies.

433
00:37:17,026 --> 00:37:21,656
As I don't really have anything to contribute in the gigantic dead body arena,

434
00:37:23,158 --> 00:37:26,703
I want to go back to the ship, if you don't mind.

435
00:37:30,165 --> 00:37:33,209
Anyone wanna join me, hey? You staying?

436
00:37:34,919 --> 00:37:35,962
No, ship's good.

437
00:37:36,129 --> 00:37:38,339
Yeah. Ship very good.

438
00:37:39,299 --> 00:37:42,343
Congratulations on meeting your maker.

439
00:37:43,136 --> 00:37:44,345
Thank you.

440
00:37:45,013 --> 00:37:46,848
Pull yourself together, man.

441
00:37:50,310 --> 00:37:53,104
And I thought you were the crazy one.

442
00:38:01,154 --> 00:38:02,947
Do you have the carbon reader?

443
00:38:05,366 --> 00:38:06,659
Thank you.

444
00:38:12,874 --> 00:38:14,042
How long's it been dead?

445
00:38:16,795 --> 00:38:19,300
Two thousand years, give or take.

446
00:38:22,801 --> 00:38:24,385
What are you doing, David?

447
00:38:25,345 --> 00:38:27,055
I'm attempting to open the door.

448
00:38:27,222 --> 00:38:29,516
Wait. We don't know what's on the other side.

449
00:38:31,893 --> 00:38:33,311
Oops. Sorry.

450
00:38:37,982 --> 00:38:40,318
Look, Ford. It's the head.

451
00:38:50,787 --> 00:38:53,081
An amazing state of preservation.

452
00:38:53,373 --> 00:38:55,124
- We'll take it in.  - Yeah.

453
00:38:59,212 --> 00:39:00,755
Remarkably human.

454
00:39:18,439 --> 00:39:20,108
Beautiful painting.

455
00:39:21,234 --> 00:39:22,527
It's a mural.

456
00:39:35,123 --> 00:39:35,790
Stop.

457
00:39:35,800 --> 00:39:37,125
Stop, Stop. Don't touch it.

458
00:39:37,292 --> 00:39:38,418
Sorry.

459
00:39:39,544 --> 00:39:41,546
Please, don't touch anything.

460
00:39:42,463 --> 00:39:43,131
Sweating.

461
00:40:22,086 --> 00:40:23,296
Organic.

462
00:40:29,844 --> 00:40:30,845
Oh, no.

463
00:40:31,137 --> 00:40:33,848
Charlie, the murals are changing.

464
00:40:34,015 --> 00:40:36,434
I think we've affected the atmosphere in the room.

465
00:40:36,601 --> 00:40:38,519
Charlie, do you copy?

466
00:40:39,520 --> 00:40:40,355
Oh, the head!

467
00:40:40,647 --> 00:40:42,732
Ford, quick, help me bag the head!

468
00:40:54,369 --> 00:40:55,870
- Boss.  - What you got?

469
00:40:56,871 --> 00:40:58,790
We got an incoming storm front.

470
00:40:59,500 --> 00:41:02,293
Silica and lots of static. This is not good.

471
00:41:02,460 --> 00:41:03,211
I see it.

472
00:41:07,298 --> 00:41:09,342
Ground crew, this is Janek.

473
00:41:09,509 --> 00:41:11,344
I need you to hustle back right now.

474
00:41:11,636 --> 00:41:13,137
Ground crew, do you copy me?

475
00:41:13,304 --> 00:41:16,349
I got 200-kilometer winds of airborne silica

476
00:41:16,516 --> 00:41:18,017
and enough static to fry your suit.

477
00:41:18,184 --> 00:41:19,686
Copy that, sir.

478
00:41:19,852 --> 00:41:20,812
We need more time.

479
00:41:21,521 --> 00:41:24,232
I'll be closing the outer doors in 15 minutes.

480
00:41:24,399 --> 00:41:26,567
I sincerely hope you can make it.

481
00:41:29,320 --> 00:41:31,239
Charlie! David!

482
00:41:31,823 --> 00:41:32,907
We must leave now.

483
00:41:35,076 --> 00:41:36,744
This is just another tomb.

484
00:41:41,249 --> 00:41:42,458
David!

485
00:41:45,336 --> 00:41:47,213
- On three.  - Two, up.

486
00:41:47,380 --> 00:41:48,756
Let's go!

487
00:41:49,507 --> 00:41:51,259
Easy, easy, easy. Careful.

488
00:41:54,345 --> 00:41:57,056
David, we are leaving!

489
00:42:06,607 --> 00:42:07,442
Come on!

490
00:42:07,608 --> 00:42:09,318
Damn it, they've already taken off.

491
00:42:09,485 --> 00:42:10,445
Come on, let's go.

492
00:42:12,113 --> 00:42:15,241
Prometheus to ground crew. You're running out of time.

493
00:42:15,408 --> 00:42:17,452
All right, come on. Let's go.

494
00:42:32,717 --> 00:42:34,135
Go faster!

495
00:42:57,992 --> 00:42:59,160
Charlie! The head!

496
00:43:00,119 --> 00:43:00,661
Ellie, no!

497
00:43:00,828 --> 00:43:01,496
What are you doing?

498
00:43:10,296 --> 00:43:12,298
- Hatch closure in five seconds.  - Shit.

499
00:43:13,549 --> 00:43:14,342
Damn it, hold on!

500
00:43:16,677 --> 00:43:17,470
Goddamn it.

501
00:43:17,637 --> 00:43:18,763
Door closing.

502
00:43:20,973 --> 00:43:22,058
Ellie, don't move!

503
00:43:27,271 --> 00:43:27,939
Charlie!

504
00:43:31,484 --> 00:43:32,527
Grab my hand!

505
00:43:43,704 --> 00:43:44,121
No!

506
00:43:45,248 --> 00:43:46,165
No, Ellie!

507
00:43:46,332 --> 00:43:47,125
Ellie!

508
00:44:25,413 --> 00:44:26,414
Got it.

509
00:44:32,180 --> 00:44:34,010
Decontamination at level 3.

510
00:44:34,380 --> 00:44:36,215
So, what was that, Ellie?

511
00:44:36,507 --> 00:44:38,200
You could've compromised the mission.

512
00:44:38,500 --> 00:44:40,553
Not to mention almost killing yourself!

513
00:44:40,720 --> 00:44:41,721
Are you all right?

514
00:44:42,096 --> 00:44:43,472
Yes.

515
00:44:43,764 --> 00:44:44,932
Thank you, David.

516
00:44:45,433 --> 00:44:46,934
My pleasure.

517
00:44:47,268 --> 00:44:49,500
Doctors, it's real good to have you back,

518
00:44:49,600 --> 00:44:51,564
but where's Millburn and Fifield?

519
00:44:51,731 --> 00:44:53,441
Aren't they back yet?

520
00:44:54,942 --> 00:44:56,444
- Get them up for me.  - All right.

521
00:44:59,363 --> 00:45:01,115
We've been here before, Fifield.

522
00:45:01,282 --> 00:45:03,951
I don't know. It all looks the same to me.

523
00:45:04,911 --> 00:45:06,954
Boys, this is the captain. Listen up.

524
00:45:07,538 --> 00:45:10,291
Between the static electricity and the wind speed,

525
00:45:10,458 --> 00:45:12,752
well, there ain't no safe way to come get you.

526
00:45:13,377 --> 00:45:14,128
What?

527
00:45:14,295 --> 00:45:17,798
The temperature is dropping rapidly, so get your helmets on and stay warm,

528
00:45:18,466 --> 00:45:20,468
until the storm passes.

529
00:45:20,635 --> 00:45:21,469
Captain,

530
00:45:21,761 --> 00:45:24,972
can you get a message to the scientist and his zealot girlfriend?

531
00:45:26,140 --> 00:45:27,183
You got a pen nearby?

532
00:45:27,350 --> 00:45:29,268
No. No, I think we got it.

533
00:45:29,894 --> 00:45:31,812
Tell them I said...themselves.

534
00:45:32,980 --> 00:45:33,814
Copy?

535
00:45:33,981 --> 00:45:36,233
Copy that. All right, boys, keep your head down

536
00:45:36,400 --> 00:45:38,694
and we'll come get you in the morning.

537
00:45:40,446 --> 00:45:42,406
- Well, which way now?  - All right.

538
00:45:42,573 --> 00:45:44,617
Well, which way, huh?

539
00:45:58,589 --> 00:46:00,591
OK. Sample is sterile. No contagion present.

540
00:46:01,008 --> 00:46:02,009
David.

541
00:46:05,304 --> 00:46:07,181
So are they all dead?

542
00:46:08,557 --> 00:46:10,518
What? Who?

543
00:46:11,143 --> 00:46:12,353
Your engineers.

544
00:46:12,853 --> 00:46:14,522
Are they all dead or aren't they?

545
00:46:14,689 --> 00:46:16,190
I don't know.

546
00:46:16,357 --> 00:46:17,692
We just got here.

547
00:46:18,109 --> 00:46:18,818
Scan.

548
00:46:21,529 --> 00:46:22,989
Do you care if they're dead?

549
00:46:23,864 --> 00:46:25,324
Weyland cared.

550
00:46:25,616 --> 00:46:27,201
Dr. Shaw.

551
00:46:27,493 --> 00:46:28,536
Have a look at this.

552
00:46:33,207 --> 00:46:35,167
- That's not an exoskeleton.  - No.

553
00:46:35,334 --> 00:46:37,336
I think it's a helmet.

554
00:46:37,628 --> 00:46:39,880
Let's see if we can lift it up.

555
00:46:40,001 --> 00:46:41,465
Shoule be able to pry this open.

556
00:46:42,216 --> 00:46:44,552
It's too heavy for us. David?

557
00:46:51,684 --> 00:46:52,893
Careful.

558
00:46:53,185 --> 00:46:54,895
Like so.

559
00:47:08,743 --> 00:47:10,578
What is that on its head?

560
00:47:10,995 --> 00:47:13,122
It looks like new cells.

561
00:47:14,040 --> 00:47:16,042
- In a state of...  - Change.

562
00:47:16,208 --> 00:47:16,917
Yes.

563
00:47:17,251 --> 00:47:18,586
Changing into what?

564
00:47:19,003 --> 00:47:21,255
Can you run a stem line into the locus coeruleus?

565
00:47:21,589 --> 00:47:24,884
I think we can trick the nervous system into thinking it's still alive.

566
00:47:26,469 --> 00:47:27,720
- Thirty amps.   - Okay.

567
00:47:28,304 --> 00:47:29,180
No more.

568
00:47:30,723 --> 00:47:32,767
Let me make an incision.

569
00:47:33,517 --> 00:47:34,268
Okay.

570
00:47:39,857 --> 00:47:41,275
Go up, 40.

571
00:47:43,277 --> 00:47:44,403
Okay, 40 up.

572
00:47:45,696 --> 00:47:47,114
Did you see that?

573
00:47:48,741 --> 00:47:50,534
- Yes.   - Yep. See?

574
00:47:50,701 --> 00:47:52,286
Go up another 10.

575
00:47:52,620 --> 00:47:54,080
Okay, up 10.

576
00:47:56,457 --> 00:47:57,541
Maybe it's a little...

577
00:47:57,708 --> 00:47:59,543
- too much. Go down 10.   - Okay.

578
00:47:59,710 --> 00:48:01,128
- Down 10.   - Down another 20.

579
00:48:01,629 --> 00:48:02,463
Okay, I'm trying.

580
00:48:03,464 --> 00:48:05,091
I'm trying, it's not going down.

581
00:48:05,257 --> 00:48:06,550
Full down. Ford...

582
00:48:06,717 --> 00:48:07,635
stop it.

583
00:48:07,802 --> 00:48:09,053
Oh, God.

584
00:48:09,303 --> 00:48:11,389
David, contain it! Now!

585
00:48:11,555 --> 00:48:12,807
Contain it? Turn it off!

586
00:48:13,140 --> 00:48:14,558
Oh, God. The smell!

587
00:48:15,434 --> 00:48:16,477
Oh, God, look at that.

588
00:48:16,644 --> 00:48:17,645
Look at that.

589
00:48:17,812 --> 00:48:18,979
It's getting worse.

590
00:48:34,662 --> 00:48:36,455
Mortal, after all.

591
00:48:43,838 --> 00:48:45,172
Ford, take a sample.

592
00:48:46,340 --> 00:48:47,800
Let's have a look.

593
00:48:52,513 --> 00:48:55,015
No, sir, I will take care of it.

594
00:48:55,349 --> 00:48:57,726
Yes, sir, understood. I'm sorry.

595
00:48:58,686 --> 00:49:01,355
Fortunately, slightly premature.

596
00:49:05,443 --> 00:49:06,819
Of course, sir.

597
00:49:35,264 --> 00:49:36,432
Miss Vickers.

598
00:49:40,853 --> 00:49:42,188
What did he say, David?

599
00:49:42,479 --> 00:49:44,857
I don't think he'd want me to tell you.

600
00:49:52,573 --> 00:49:54,909
What did he say?

601
00:49:55,075 --> 00:49:55,826
I'm sorry...

602
00:49:55,993 --> 00:49:57,161
that's confidential.

603
00:49:57,328 --> 00:49:59,246
So help me God...

604
00:49:59,580 --> 00:50:03,584
I will find the cord that makes you run and I will cut it.

605
00:50:04,376 --> 00:50:06,462
What did he say?

606
00:50:07,922 --> 00:50:09,256
He said:

607
00:50:10,257 --> 00:50:12,760
"Try harder."

608
00:50:14,428 --> 00:50:16,722
Cup of tea, ma'am?

609
00:50:33,280 --> 00:50:34,406
Genetic view.

610
00:50:34,573 --> 00:50:35,449
Okay.

611
00:50:35,616 --> 00:50:38,035
Let's have a look at its DNA.

612
00:50:47,378 --> 00:50:48,462
Isolate the strand.

613
00:50:50,256 --> 00:50:51,257
Okay.

614
00:50:51,840 --> 00:50:53,968
Compare it to the gene sample.

615
00:50:54,301 --> 00:50:55,427
Yeah.

616
00:50:55,719 --> 00:50:56,804
Overlay.

617
00:50:57,137 --> 00:50:58,472
Processing.

618
00:51:00,432 --> 00:51:01,767
Processing.

619
00:51:03,560 --> 00:51:05,938
DNA match.

620
00:51:07,231 --> 00:51:08,816
Oh, my God.

621
00:51:29,003 --> 00:51:30,337
It's us.

622
00:51:30,671 --> 00:51:31,839
It's everything.

623
00:51:35,759 --> 00:51:37,761
What killed them?

624
00:51:55,321 --> 00:51:56,196
Big things...

625
00:51:56,363 --> 00:51:58,365
have small beginnings.

626
00:52:07,458 --> 00:52:09,209
Am I interrupting?

627
00:52:09,710 --> 00:52:12,004
I thought you might be running low.

628
00:52:16,050 --> 00:52:18,969
- Pour yourself a glass, pal.   - Thank you, but I'm afraid...

629
00:52:19,136 --> 00:52:20,554
it would be wasted on me.

630
00:52:21,138 --> 00:52:23,390
Right, I almost forgot you're not a real boy.

631
00:52:27,394 --> 00:52:29,897
I'm very sorry that your Engineers are all gone.

632
00:52:34,735 --> 00:52:37,196
You think we wasted our time coming here, don't you?

633
00:52:38,572 --> 00:52:43,243
Your question depends on me understanding what you hoped to achieve by coming here.

634
00:52:43,410 --> 00:52:46,246
What we hoped to achieve was to meet our makers.

635
00:52:46,413 --> 00:52:47,331
To get answers.

636
00:52:47,956 --> 00:52:49,750
Why they even...

637
00:52:49,917 --> 00:52:51,418
made us in the first place.

638
00:52:54,004 --> 00:52:56,382
Why do you think your people made me?

639
00:52:57,674 --> 00:52:58,842
Because we could.

640
00:53:01,762 --> 00:53:04,139
Can you imagine how disappointing it would be...

641
00:53:04,306 --> 00:53:06,433
to hear the same thing from your creator?

642
00:53:11,772 --> 00:53:12,564
I guess it's...

643
00:53:12,731 --> 00:53:14,441
good you can't be disappointed.

644
00:53:15,025 --> 00:53:16,527
Yes. It's wonderful...

645
00:53:17,194 --> 00:53:17,861
actually.

646
00:53:18,028 --> 00:53:19,780
May I ask you something?

647
00:53:21,115 --> 00:53:22,032
Please do.

648
00:53:22,199 --> 00:53:23,450
How far would you go...

649
00:53:24,201 --> 00:53:26,829
to get what you came all this way for?

650
00:53:26,995 --> 00:53:28,372
Your answers.

651
00:53:29,623 --> 00:53:30,874
What are you willing to do?

652
00:53:31,291 --> 00:53:32,751
Anything and everything.

653
00:53:34,044 --> 00:53:36,296
That's worth drinking to, I'd imagine.

654
00:53:47,724 --> 00:53:49,601
Here's mud in your eye, pal.

655
00:53:54,022 --> 00:53:55,399
Good health.

656
00:54:00,279 --> 00:54:01,530
It's those things.

657
00:54:05,159 --> 00:54:06,326
Are they real?

658
00:54:08,162 --> 00:54:09,288
Of course they're real.

659
00:54:10,414 --> 00:54:12,124
Jesus Christ. I mean...

660
00:54:13,417 --> 00:54:14,585
Look at the pile.

661
00:54:15,252 --> 00:54:17,129
Look how high up they are.

662
00:54:18,046 --> 00:54:18,797
It looks like...

663
00:54:18,964 --> 00:54:23,177
- they were running from something.   - Okay. Don't touch, okay?

664
00:54:23,761 --> 00:54:27,973
Man, this thing is opened up from the inside.

665
00:54:28,140 --> 00:54:29,683
Almost like it exploded.

666
00:54:30,684 --> 00:54:34,688
Looks like a scene out some sort of holocaust painting, you know?

667
00:54:47,868 --> 00:54:49,119
Well...

668
00:54:54,708 --> 00:54:57,920
So, whatever killed them is long gone, right?

669
00:54:58,086 --> 00:54:59,171
Millburn, Fifield.

670
00:54:59,338 --> 00:55:00,506
This is Prometheus.

671
00:55:00,672 --> 00:55:01,882
What is your position?

672
00:55:02,716 --> 00:55:04,510
Prometheus, this is Millburn.

673
00:55:04,801 --> 00:55:06,720
We are at 7-4-0...

674
00:55:06,887 --> 00:55:09,139
1-4-7-7. Why?

675
00:55:09,306 --> 00:55:12,851
Just got a ping about one click west of you.

676
00:55:13,018 --> 00:55:14,603
What do you mean "a ping"?

677
00:55:15,062 --> 00:55:16,730
Well, whatever...

678
00:55:16,897 --> 00:55:18,899
that probe is picking up...

679
00:55:19,066 --> 00:55:20,234
it's not dead.

680
00:55:20,400 --> 00:55:22,069
It's reading a life form.

681
00:55:22,277 --> 00:55:24,738
- What?   - Okay, what do you mean, "a life form"?

682
00:55:25,239 --> 00:55:26,823
Is it... Is it moving?

683
00:55:27,574 --> 00:55:29,535
No, I don't think so.

684
00:55:29,827 --> 00:55:31,161
Captain, you're...

685
00:55:31,328 --> 00:55:32,871
obviously not seeing...

686
00:55:33,038 --> 00:55:34,414
what we're seeing here.

687
00:55:34,581 --> 00:55:36,833
If you were, you wouldn't be talking about a bloody ping.

688
00:55:37,000 --> 00:55:38,293
I know, boys.

689
00:55:38,627 --> 00:55:41,880
Your signal has been coming in sporadically since the storm hit.

690
00:55:43,090 --> 00:55:44,591
That's no good to us down here!

691
00:55:46,134 --> 00:55:50,055
Is it... Is it moving? Are these things moving?

692
00:55:52,933 --> 00:55:55,852
No. No, it just disappeared, actually.

693
00:55:56,436 --> 00:55:57,521
Must be a glitch.

694
00:55:57,688 --> 00:56:00,190
What do you mean, "a glitch"?

695
00:56:00,357 --> 00:56:01,275
All right, boys.

696
00:56:02,359 --> 00:56:03,569
Sleep tight.

697
00:56:04,444 --> 00:56:05,946
Try not to bugger each other.

698
00:56:06,113 --> 00:56:08,115
Captain, what do you mean, "a glitch"?

699
00:56:08,740 --> 00:56:11,285
Millburn, what does he mean? Wait.

700
00:56:11,868 --> 00:56:13,370
Now, he said...

701
00:56:14,413 --> 00:56:17,124
- He said one click west, yeah?   - Yeah.

702
00:56:17,958 --> 00:56:19,251
Now, we...

703
00:56:19,418 --> 00:56:21,295
We don't want to check that out, do we?

704
00:56:21,461 --> 00:56:22,504
Shit, no.

705
00:56:22,671 --> 00:56:23,964
Where are we gonna go?

706
00:56:24,131 --> 00:56:25,132
East.

707
00:56:26,717 --> 00:56:28,010
Yeah, east.

708
00:56:28,176 --> 00:56:32,097
A fucking glitch, man. "Pings, glitch, life form." What the fuck'?

709
00:56:32,514 --> 00:56:36,768
Based on the behavior of the subject in these holographic recordings...

710
00:56:36,935 --> 00:56:39,605
we're attempting to identify what caused the head...

711
00:56:39,771 --> 00:56:41,898
to combust. I can't help but wonder...

712
00:56:42,524 --> 00:56:44,985
was there an outbreak here?

713
00:56:49,698 --> 00:56:50,657
You rang...

714
00:56:50,824 --> 00:56:52,993
- ma'am?  - I have something important...

715
00:56:53,160 --> 00:56:54,995
to tell you. What is that?

716
00:56:55,829 --> 00:56:57,456
This is...

717
00:56:57,623 --> 00:57:00,000
a rose that I had frozen with the champagne.

718
00:57:00,167 --> 00:57:03,253
I was gonna give it to you when we found what we came for.

719
00:57:04,546 --> 00:57:06,340
We did find what we came for.

720
00:57:06,757 --> 00:57:07,925
They were here. This is...

721
00:57:08,091 --> 00:57:12,679
The most significant discovery in the history...

722
00:57:12,846 --> 00:57:15,015
of mankind. Oh, I know.

723
00:57:17,851 --> 00:57:19,686
It's incredible, it really is.

724
00:57:19,853 --> 00:57:23,690
But I wanted to talk to them.

725
00:57:24,024 --> 00:57:26,860
I mean, don't you want to know why they came?

726
00:57:28,236 --> 00:57:29,780
Why they abandoned us?

727
00:57:30,197 --> 00:57:32,032
I just want answers, baby.

728
00:57:32,199 --> 00:57:33,659
We were right, Charlie.

729
00:57:34,117 --> 00:57:36,203
I have proof.

730
00:57:38,205 --> 00:57:39,122
Look.

731
00:57:45,087 --> 00:57:48,215
Their genetic material predates ours.

732
00:57:48,382 --> 00:57:49,883
We come from them.

733
00:57:51,343 --> 00:57:53,011
- You're kidding me.  - No.

734
00:57:56,014 --> 00:57:57,224
Okay.

735
00:57:57,724 --> 00:57:58,892
Okay.

736
00:57:59,893 --> 00:58:04,064
Okay. I guess you can take your father's cross off now.

737
00:58:04,815 --> 00:58:07,067
Why would I want to do that?

738
00:58:07,567 --> 00:58:09,319
Because they made us.

739
00:58:09,486 --> 00:58:10,779
And who made them?

740
00:58:11,697 --> 00:58:13,740
Well, exactly. We'll never know.

741
00:58:13,907 --> 00:58:15,993
But here's what we do know

742
00:58:16,159 --> 00:58:19,996
That there is nothing special about the creation of life.

743
00:58:20,163 --> 00:58:21,581
Right? Anybody can do it.

744
00:58:21,748 --> 00:58:24,751
All you need is a dash of DNA and half a brain, right?

745
00:58:27,754 --> 00:58:28,964
I can't.

746
00:58:30,549 --> 00:58:32,801
I can't create life.

747
00:58:34,636 --> 00:58:37,305
What does that say about me?

748
00:58:38,598 --> 00:58:41,601
Ellie, that's not... I didn't mean...

749
00:58:41,768 --> 00:58:43,311
I wasn't talking about...

750
00:58:43,478 --> 00:58:45,105
Children?

751
00:58:45,439 --> 00:58:46,481
Us.

752
00:58:48,984 --> 00:58:51,194
Hey, hey, hey.

753
00:58:51,361 --> 00:58:52,738
Hey.

754
00:58:53,530 --> 00:58:54,823
Hey.

755
00:58:55,657 --> 00:58:57,534
Elizabeth Shaw...

756
00:58:57,701 --> 00:59:01,204
you are the most special person I have ever met in my life...

757
00:59:01,371 --> 00:59:03,206
and I love you.

758
00:59:07,252 --> 00:59:08,503
Hey.

759
00:59:53,590 --> 00:59:55,050
How much longer will this take?

760
00:59:57,052 --> 00:59:58,595
I don't know.

761
00:59:58,762 --> 01:00:00,263
I'm just a captain.

762
01:00:09,397 --> 01:00:11,858
That thing sounds like a dying cat, by the way.

763
01:00:12,025 --> 01:00:15,862
I'll have you know that this thing...

764
01:00:16,029 --> 01:00:18,240
once belonged to Stephen Stills.

765
01:00:19,533 --> 01:00:21,243
Am I supposed to know who that is?

766
01:00:26,206 --> 01:00:27,707
You know...

767
01:00:28,583 --> 01:00:29,960
if you wanna get laid...

768
01:00:30,126 --> 01:00:32,003
you really don't have to pretend...

769
01:00:32,170 --> 01:00:34,297
to be interested in the pyramid scan.

770
01:00:35,382 --> 01:00:38,885
You could just say, "Hey, I'm trying to get laid."

771
01:00:39,052 --> 01:00:41,263
I could. I could say that, right?

772
01:00:41,930 --> 01:00:43,390
But it wouldn't make sense...

773
01:00:43,557 --> 01:00:47,727
why I would fly myself half a billion miles from every man on Earth...

774
01:00:47,894 --> 01:00:49,896
if I wanted to get laid, would it?

775
01:00:52,065 --> 01:00:53,567
Hey, Vickers.

776
01:00:53,733 --> 01:00:55,569
Hey, Vickers.

777
01:00:56,736 --> 01:00:58,572
I was wondering...

778
01:01:02,826 --> 01:01:04,244
Are you a robot?

779
01:01:12,586 --> 01:01:13,962
My room.

780
01:01:15,088 --> 01:01:15,922
Ten minutes.

781
01:01:19,134 --> 01:01:24,097
# Well, if you can't be with the one you love #

782
01:01:24,264 --> 01:01:25,223
# Love the one #

783
01:01:25,390 --> 01:01:26,516
# You're with #

784
01:01:26,725 --> 01:01:28,268
# Love the one you're with #

785
01:01:35,108 --> 01:01:36,276
Millburn.

786
01:01:36,443 --> 01:01:38,445
What's all this black stuff?

787
01:01:42,908 --> 01:01:43,867
Gazpacho.

788
01:01:46,453 --> 01:01:47,454
Is that tobacco?

789
01:01:48,330 --> 01:01:49,247
Is that tobacco...

790
01:01:49,414 --> 01:01:50,540
in your respirator?

791
01:01:50,707 --> 01:01:52,292
Yeah, sure.

792
01:01:56,796 --> 01:01:58,298
Tobacco.

793
01:01:58,965 --> 01:02:02,594
On behalf of scientists everywhere, I am ashamed to count you amongst us...

794
01:02:02,761 --> 01:02:04,387
Fifield. Really.

795
01:02:08,642 --> 01:02:09,726
- Hey, Millburn.  - Yeah?

796
01:02:09,893 --> 01:02:10,810
You see this thing?

797
01:02:10,977 --> 01:02:14,314
What do you think this thing was? Some kind of a god?

798
01:02:14,814 --> 01:02:16,816
Something they worshiped? What?

799
01:02:16,983 --> 01:02:18,735
- It kind of looks like...  - What's that?

800
01:02:19,444 --> 01:02:20,487
What the hell is that?

801
01:02:20,654 --> 01:02:21,905
Oh, my God. Okay.

802
01:02:22,072 --> 01:02:23,406
Just stay calm. Stay quiet.

803
01:02:23,573 --> 01:02:25,825
This is okay, I can handle this.

804
01:02:26,493 --> 01:02:27,494
Hey, baby.

805
01:02:28,286 --> 01:02:28,995
Hey.

806
01:02:29,996 --> 01:02:31,164
Come in, Prometheus.

807
01:02:31,498 --> 01:02:35,085
We have an elongate reptile-type creature.

808
01:02:35,293 --> 01:02:39,422
Maybe 30, 40 inches, with transparent skin.

809
01:02:39,839 --> 01:02:41,174
And it's beautiful.

810
01:02:42,717 --> 01:02:43,343
Okay!

811
01:02:46,805 --> 01:02:47,430
Prometheus...

812
01:02:47,597 --> 01:02:48,348
we have two.

813
01:02:48,515 --> 01:02:51,017
Look at you. Look at you, baby.

814
01:02:51,518 --> 01:02:53,979
Jesus, look at the size of that. What is it?

815
01:02:54,145 --> 01:02:56,690
- You need to stay calm.  - What's there to be calm about?

816
01:02:56,856 --> 01:02:59,275
You need to stay calm because she is beautiful.

817
01:02:59,442 --> 01:03:01,194
What makes you think that's female?

818
01:03:01,361 --> 01:03:02,612
She's a lady. Look!

819
01:03:08,702 --> 01:03:09,703
Hey.

820
01:03:10,578 --> 01:03:11,621
She's mesmerized.

821
01:03:12,038 --> 01:03:14,165
Come here. Come here.

822
01:03:16,418 --> 01:03:17,544
It's okay.

823
01:03:17,711 --> 01:03:19,379
It's okay. It's okay.

824
01:03:20,088 --> 01:03:21,381
Hey, baby.

825
01:03:24,551 --> 01:03:25,468
You're strong!

826
01:03:26,219 --> 01:03:26,845
You should...

827
01:03:27,012 --> 01:03:27,679
help me now.

828
01:03:27,846 --> 01:03:28,513
Get it off.

829
01:03:31,099 --> 01:03:31,975
Cut it here, man!

830
01:03:32,142 --> 01:03:33,226
I ain't touching that!

831
01:03:34,227 --> 01:03:36,229
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.

832
01:03:36,396 --> 01:03:38,440
- It's getting tighter.  - I ain't touching it!

833
01:03:38,606 --> 01:03:41,401
Cut the thing, man, for God's sake!

834
01:03:41,568 --> 01:03:43,486
God, you're making it worse!

835
01:03:43,653 --> 01:03:45,488
It's tightening! It's tight...

836
01:03:45,864 --> 01:03:47,073
It's breaking my arm!

837
01:03:48,992 --> 01:03:49,576
Shit!

838
01:03:49,993 --> 01:03:50,869
Cut it off!

839
01:03:51,036 --> 01:03:52,746
Cut it off!

840
01:03:52,912 --> 01:03:53,747
Cut it off!

841
01:03:53,913 --> 01:03:54,539
Cut it off!

842
01:03:57,542 --> 01:03:58,168
Shit!

843
01:03:58,335 --> 01:03:59,085
Oh. my God!

844
01:04:00,378 --> 01:04:02,422
Oh, my God! Oh, Jesus!

845
01:04:03,840 --> 01:04:05,091
It's in my suit.

846
01:04:05,258 --> 01:04:06,051
Jesus Christ.

847
01:05:06,152 --> 01:05:07,987
Shaw, you up?

848
01:05:09,656 --> 01:05:10,824
Yeah, what's up?

849
01:05:11,199 --> 01:05:13,410
The storm passed, but I can't reach Millburn...

850
01:05:13,576 --> 01:05:16,788
or Fifield. Taking a few men down, see if I can rustle them up.

851
01:05:16,955 --> 01:05:18,081
Okay.

852
01:05:18,998 --> 01:05:20,583
Any idea where they are?

853
01:05:20,750 --> 01:05:24,420
Last time they radioed in was where you found your head.

854
01:05:24,963 --> 01:05:26,923
Okay, we're coming.

855
01:05:27,090 --> 01:05:27,841
All right.

856
01:05:28,007 --> 01:05:30,844
Chance, you're coming with me. Come on.

857
01:05:31,010 --> 01:05:32,011
All right, boss.

858
01:05:33,847 --> 01:05:36,641
- Ravel, did you fix that glitch?  - No, captain.

859
01:05:36,808 --> 01:05:39,561
- It's gotta be in the hardware.  - What glitch, captain?

860
01:05:39,727 --> 01:05:42,272
One of them probes picked up a life form.

861
01:05:42,981 --> 01:05:43,940
Pops up every hour...

862
01:05:44,107 --> 01:05:47,026
for a couple of seconds and then it's gone.

863
01:05:47,193 --> 01:05:48,778
I can find the probe and fix it.

864
01:05:48,945 --> 01:05:50,530
Knock yourself out.

865
01:05:51,865 --> 01:05:53,366
Be careful, doctors.

866
01:06:14,596 --> 01:06:16,347
Fifield!

867
01:06:19,100 --> 01:06:20,268
Millburn?

868
01:06:24,564 --> 01:06:25,940
All right, come on down.

869
01:06:46,961 --> 01:06:49,923
David, are you alone?

870
01:06:51,049 --> 01:06:52,175
Yes, Miss Vickers.

871
01:06:52,342 --> 01:06:54,511
Uplink your feed to my room.

872
01:06:54,677 --> 01:06:55,970
Copy.

873
01:08:38,573 --> 01:08:40,783
You son of a bitch.

874
01:08:42,869 --> 01:08:44,579
You cut me off.

875
01:09:05,683 --> 01:09:07,226
What is this?

876
01:09:10,730 --> 01:09:11,939
- Charlie?  - I just tripped.

877
01:09:12,231 --> 01:09:13,399
Oh, my God, you're sick!

878
01:09:13,566 --> 01:09:15,485
I'm okay, baby. Come on.

879
01:09:15,652 --> 01:09:16,694
Fifield?

880
01:09:17,528 --> 01:09:18,738
Millburn?

881
01:09:25,203 --> 01:09:26,746
Hey, Chance. I wouldn't touch...

882
01:09:26,913 --> 01:09:28,081
that if I were you.

883
01:09:30,958 --> 01:09:32,293
Dr. Shaw?

884
01:09:32,460 --> 01:09:33,586
Yeah?

885
01:09:33,753 --> 01:09:35,755
Do we have any idea what is...

886
01:09:35,922 --> 01:09:37,340
oozing out of these vases?

887
01:09:37,507 --> 01:09:40,676
No. They weren't like this last time we were here.

888
01:09:45,390 --> 01:09:46,516
Captain?

889
01:09:46,724 --> 01:09:48,017
What?

890
01:09:48,226 --> 01:09:49,185
Who is it? Which one?

891
01:09:49,352 --> 01:09:51,187
- Who is it?  - It's Millburn.

892
01:09:51,729 --> 01:09:53,606
- Ellie.  - Don't touch him. Hold on.

893
01:09:53,773 --> 01:09:54,607
Ellie, honey.

894
01:09:54,774 --> 01:09:56,609
Charlie, what's wrong?

895
01:09:56,776 --> 01:09:59,320
I need you to look at me, okay?

896
01:09:59,487 --> 01:10:00,613
You know infections...

897
01:10:00,780 --> 01:10:01,823
so, what do you see?

898
01:10:01,989 --> 01:10:03,616
This is not good, baby.

899
01:10:03,783 --> 01:10:05,702
You look at me, you tell me what you see.

900
01:10:09,956 --> 01:10:10,832
Oh, my God.

901
01:10:11,290 --> 01:10:12,875
Ford, get over here.

902
01:10:13,042 --> 01:10:14,627
It's okay. Janek?

903
01:10:14,794 --> 01:10:16,421
- What?  - We have to go now!

904
01:10:16,587 --> 01:10:17,296
What do you see?

905
01:10:17,463 --> 01:10:19,465
Honey, what do you see?

906
01:10:19,632 --> 01:10:21,718
Holloway's sick. He's not good.

907
01:10:21,884 --> 01:10:22,468
I see movement...

908
01:10:22,635 --> 01:10:23,302
in his esophagus.

909
01:10:27,640 --> 01:10:29,308
- Come on, baby.  - No. I'm okay.

910
01:10:29,475 --> 01:10:30,435
Janek!

911
01:10:30,601 --> 01:10:31,811
Come over and help me!

912
01:10:31,978 --> 01:10:34,313
- I'm okay.  - Ford, get over there. What's happening?

913
01:10:34,480 --> 01:10:35,481
- I'm okay.  - Let's go!

914
01:10:35,648 --> 01:10:36,774
Help me with him.

915
01:10:36,941 --> 01:10:39,819
I got you. We're gonna get you out of here.

916
01:10:39,986 --> 01:10:40,653
Prometheus...

917
01:10:40,820 --> 01:10:41,446
come in.

918
01:10:41,612 --> 01:10:43,573
- Watch your head.  - Okay. I'm okay.

919
01:10:43,740 --> 01:10:45,491
- Holloway.  - Get him up.

920
01:10:45,658 --> 01:10:47,493
- Come on.  - Prometheus, come in.

921
01:10:47,660 --> 01:10:48,828
Is anyone there?

922
01:10:49,495 --> 01:10:50,746
This is Vickers.

923
01:10:50,913 --> 01:10:53,374
I need a medical team standing by the airlock.

924
01:10:53,708 --> 01:10:55,752
Full quarantine fail-safe.

925
01:10:55,918 --> 01:10:57,378
Holloway's sick.

926
01:10:57,545 --> 01:10:58,796
Sick with what?

927
01:10:58,963 --> 01:11:01,090
- Just do it.  - Let's get him back to the ship.

928
01:11:01,257 --> 01:11:03,342
- It's not safe down here.  - Charlie?

929
01:11:03,509 --> 01:11:04,343
I'm suiting up.

930
01:11:04,510 --> 01:11:06,179
- Charlie, talk to me.  - Move!

931
01:11:06,345 --> 01:11:08,681
- What was that back there?  - Let's go, people!

932
01:11:10,391 --> 01:11:12,643
We've gotta move! We've gotta move!

933
01:11:12,810 --> 01:11:13,394
Ellie!

934
01:15:11,090 --> 01:15:12,299
He don't look too good.

935
01:15:12,508 --> 01:15:15,219
Did he catch something down there? We had our helmets off.

936
01:15:15,386 --> 01:15:16,095
I don't know.

937
01:15:16,387 --> 01:15:19,390
Prometheus, this is Janek. Make sure that back door is open.

938
01:15:19,765 --> 01:15:20,850
Aye, captain.

939
01:15:21,016 --> 01:15:23,394
Oh, God. I'm so sorry.

940
01:15:25,104 --> 01:15:26,355
Come on!

941
01:15:26,522 --> 01:15:28,232
Please!

942
01:15:33,070 --> 01:15:35,573
Prometheus! Why is that door not open?

943
01:15:36,115 --> 01:15:37,950
Vickers, that is an order!

944
01:15:38,743 --> 01:15:40,369
Get that goddamn door open!

945
01:15:40,536 --> 01:15:43,080
- Look at me. It's too late, I'm sick.  - No, it's not.

946
01:15:43,247 --> 01:15:44,457
Come on!

947
01:15:45,166 --> 01:15:45,875
Ford, help me!

948
01:15:46,250 --> 01:15:48,294
Airlock crew, if you can hear me, it's Janek.

949
01:15:48,461 --> 01:15:50,087
Open that back door right now!

950
01:15:50,254 --> 01:15:51,422
Hold that door!

951
01:15:51,589 --> 01:15:52,256
Prometheus...

952
01:15:52,423 --> 01:15:53,174
do you copy?

953
01:15:53,340 --> 01:15:55,843
Goddamn it, open that door! That is an order!

954
01:15:56,010 --> 01:15:57,094
Open it.

955
01:16:04,143 --> 01:16:05,436
What the hell is this?

956
01:16:05,603 --> 01:16:07,146
He's not coming on board.

957
01:16:07,313 --> 01:16:08,814
Vickers, this is a sick man.

958
01:16:08,981 --> 01:16:10,107
I see that. That's why...

959
01:16:10,274 --> 01:16:11,317
he's not coming on!

960
01:16:12,109 --> 01:16:13,110
Charlie!

961
01:16:13,277 --> 01:16:14,320
Chance, get over here!

962
01:16:17,615 --> 01:16:18,324
Please!

963
01:16:18,491 --> 01:16:19,575
We can still help him!

964
01:16:21,243 --> 01:16:23,829
Help yourself. Everybody but Holloway back on this ship!

965
01:16:23,996 --> 01:16:25,581
I won't leave him!

966
01:16:25,748 --> 01:16:26,582
Then stay!

967
01:16:26,749 --> 01:16:27,917
Wait! We could...

968
01:16:28,083 --> 01:16:29,794
put him on the Med-Pod!

969
01:16:29,960 --> 01:16:31,003
Please don't do this.

970
01:16:31,170 --> 01:16:32,505
It's okay, Ellie.

971
01:16:32,671 --> 01:16:33,672
Vickers!

972
01:16:33,839 --> 01:16:34,840
What are you doing?

973
01:16:35,132 --> 01:16:36,300
I love you, baby.

974
01:16:36,467 --> 01:16:37,301
- I love you.  - No.

975
01:16:37,468 --> 01:16:38,761
I'm telling you, stay back!

976
01:16:38,928 --> 01:16:39,637
Do it.

977
01:16:39,804 --> 01:16:40,679
Stay back!

978
01:16:40,846 --> 01:16:41,931
No! No, Charlie!

979
01:16:42,097 --> 01:16:42,681
- Do it.  - No!

980
01:16:48,437 --> 01:16:49,647
No!

981
01:16:51,690 --> 01:16:53,192
No!

982
01:16:53,526 --> 01:16:55,194
No!

983
01:16:58,864 --> 01:16:59,949
Charlie!

984
01:17:02,701 --> 01:17:04,328
No!

985
01:17:17,716 --> 01:17:19,677
My deepest condolences.

986
01:17:21,011 --> 01:17:22,805
I'm going to have to take this.

987
01:17:22,972 --> 01:17:24,515
It may be contaminated.

988
01:17:25,641 --> 01:17:29,687
If there's a contagion, we were all exposed.

989
01:17:31,272 --> 01:17:35,067
You need... We need to run blood work on everyone who set foot in the pyramid.

990
01:17:35,734 --> 01:17:37,111
Yes, of course.

991
01:17:37,403 --> 01:17:38,696
Yes?

992
01:17:46,036 --> 01:17:48,414
I understand how...

993
01:17:48,581 --> 01:17:50,082
inappropriate this is...

994
01:17:50,875 --> 01:17:53,210
given the circumstance.

995
01:17:53,377 --> 01:17:56,380
But as you ordered quarantine fail-safes...

996
01:17:58,215 --> 01:18:00,509
it's my responsibility to ask.

997
01:18:01,427 --> 01:18:05,598
Have you and Dr. Holloway had any intimate contact recently?

998
01:18:06,932 --> 01:18:08,100
Since you and he were...

999
01:18:08,267 --> 01:18:09,518
so close...

1000
01:18:10,436 --> 01:18:11,270
I want to be...

1001
01:18:11,437 --> 01:18:12,897
as thorough as poss...

1002
01:18:14,899 --> 01:18:15,733
My, my.

1003
01:18:19,945 --> 01:18:20,821
You're pregnant.

1004
01:18:23,699 --> 01:18:24,366
What?

1005
01:18:25,868 --> 01:18:27,620
From the look of it, three months so.

1006
01:18:28,078 --> 01:18:31,165
No, that's impossible.

1007
01:18:31,457 --> 01:18:33,584
I can't be pregnant.

1008
01:18:33,876 --> 01:18:37,212
Did you have intercourse with Dr. Holloway?

1009
01:18:38,047 --> 01:18:39,256
Yes...

1010
01:18:39,423 --> 01:18:42,468
but 10 hours ago.

1011
01:18:42,801 --> 01:18:46,305
There's no bloody way I'm three months pregnant.

1012
01:18:46,472 --> 01:18:47,306
Well, doctor...

1013
01:18:48,307 --> 01:18:50,392
it's not exactly a traditional fetus.

1014
01:18:54,104 --> 01:18:54,980
I want to see it.

1015
01:18:55,272 --> 01:18:56,982
Don't think that's a good idea.

1016
01:18:58,817 --> 01:19:01,654
David, I want to see it.

1017
01:19:01,946 --> 01:19:03,155
Now, doctor...

1018
01:19:05,658 --> 01:19:07,159
I want to see it.

1019
01:19:08,243 --> 01:19:09,662
I want it out of me.

1020
01:19:09,912 --> 01:19:11,497
We don't have the personnel...

1021
01:19:11,664 --> 01:19:14,166
to perform a procedure like that.

1022
01:19:14,333 --> 01:19:16,168
- Our best option...  - I want it out.

1023
01:19:16,335 --> 01:19:17,336
Put you back into...

1024
01:19:17,503 --> 01:19:19,421
cryostasis until we return to Earth.

1025
01:19:19,588 --> 01:19:21,882
Please, get it out of me.

1026
01:19:22,216 --> 01:19:23,634
Get it out of me!

1027
01:19:23,926 --> 01:19:25,010
Please.

1028
01:19:28,681 --> 01:19:30,349
It must be very painful.

1029
01:19:31,225 --> 01:19:33,352
Here, let me give you something.

1030
01:19:37,356 --> 01:19:39,024
That's it. There, there.

1031
01:19:45,447 --> 01:19:48,033
Someone will be along shortly...

1032
01:19:48,325 --> 01:19:50,703
to bring you back to Cryo Deck.

1033
01:19:54,999 --> 01:19:57,251
It must feel like your God abandoned you.

1034
01:19:57,876 --> 01:19:59,044
What?

1035
01:19:59,211 --> 01:20:00,004
To lose...

1036
01:20:00,170 --> 01:20:05,383
Dr. Holloway after your father died under such similar circumstances.

1037
01:20:05,467 --> 01:20:07,553
What was it that killed him?

1038
01:20:08,304 --> 01:20:09,763
Ebola?

1039
01:20:14,143 --> 01:20:16,895
How do you...? How do you know that?

1040
01:20:18,022 --> 01:20:19,815
I watched your dreams.

1041
01:20:42,379 --> 01:20:43,464
Dr. Shaw?

1042
01:20:44,757 --> 01:20:45,924
We're here to put you...

1043
01:20:46,091 --> 01:20:49,470
in an anti-contamination suit, take you back to Cryo Deck...

1044
01:20:49,636 --> 01:20:51,263
go to beddy-byes.

1045
01:20:51,930 --> 01:20:53,432
Dr. Shaw?

1046
01:20:54,933 --> 01:20:56,393
She's doped. Prepare her.

1047
01:21:26,423 --> 01:21:30,636
Emergency procedures initiated. Please verbally state the nature of your injury.

1048
01:21:31,345 --> 01:21:33,263
I need a Caesarean.

1049
01:21:33,806 --> 01:21:35,974
Error. This Med-Pod is calibrated for male...

1050
01:21:36,141 --> 01:21:37,726
patients and does not offer...

1051
01:21:37,893 --> 01:21:40,813
the procedure you have requested. Seek medical assistance...

1052
01:21:40,979 --> 01:21:41,980
elsewhere.

1053
01:21:44,358 --> 01:21:45,109
Surgery.

1054
01:21:45,442 --> 01:21:46,819
Abdominal.

1055
01:21:47,528 --> 01:21:48,278
Penetrating...

1056
01:21:48,445 --> 01:21:49,780
injuries.

1057
01:21:50,072 --> 01:21:51,698
Foreign body.

1058
01:21:51,990 --> 01:21:53,075
Initiate.

1059
01:21:55,744 --> 01:21:57,621
Surgical procedure to begin.

1060
01:22:39,121 --> 01:22:40,164
Running diagnostics.

1061
01:22:43,709 --> 01:22:45,043
Oh, come on.

1062
01:22:46,628 --> 01:22:48,881
Get it out! Come on!

1063
01:22:49,298 --> 01:22:50,007
Please!

1064
01:22:53,343 --> 01:22:54,678
Oh, God!

1065
01:22:56,889 --> 01:22:58,724
- Come on!  - Initiating anesthetics.

1066
01:22:59,975 --> 01:23:00,559
Please!

1067
01:23:07,149 --> 01:23:09,026
Commence surgical procedure.

1068
01:23:49,983 --> 01:23:50,943
Oh, God.

1069
01:23:54,655 --> 01:23:55,239
Oh, God!

1070
01:23:55,405 --> 01:23:56,782
Oh, God!

1071
01:24:15,300 --> 01:24:16,969
Oh, God! Oh, God!

1072
01:24:17,177 --> 01:24:18,470
Oh. my God!

1073
01:24:33,664 --> 01:24:35,232


1074
01:24:35,237 --> 01:24:36,405
Come on!

1075
01:25:02,681 --> 01:25:03,307
Bridge...

1076
01:25:03,473 --> 01:25:05,058
to hangar. This is the captain.

1077
01:25:05,225 --> 01:25:07,185
- Yes, captain.  - Can you see what I see?

1078
01:25:07,519 --> 01:25:09,438
Fifield's monitor just popped up.

1079
01:25:09,855 --> 01:25:11,690
What? Where?

1080
01:25:11,857 --> 01:25:14,276
According to what I'm looking at, it's outside...

1081
01:25:14,443 --> 01:25:15,652
the goddamn ship.

1082
01:25:16,028 --> 01:25:17,195
Barnes, open the door!

1083
01:25:17,362 --> 01:25:19,364
Fifield, do you copy me? Come on in.

1084
01:25:20,282 --> 01:25:20,991
Fifield?

1085
01:25:33,295 --> 01:25:34,546
Wait a second.

1086
01:25:43,722 --> 01:25:44,639
Hey, Wallace.

1087
01:25:44,806 --> 01:25:46,058
Take a look at this.

1088
01:25:51,730 --> 01:25:52,230
Fifield?

1089
01:25:55,233 --> 01:25:57,194
What the hell is going on down there?

1090
01:26:11,083 --> 01:26:12,209
I'm coming down there.

1091
01:26:12,376 --> 01:26:13,585
Chance, you're suiting up.

1092
01:26:13,752 --> 01:26:15,420
- Come on.  - Don't let it on the ship!

1093
01:26:30,560 --> 01:26:31,019
Take him out!

1094
01:26:31,895 --> 01:26:32,354
Got him!

1095
01:26:34,773 --> 01:26:35,399
Do it!

1096
01:26:39,277 --> 01:26:41,405
- You ready, Chance?  - Yes.

1097
01:26:44,408 --> 01:26:45,283
Come on!

1098
01:26:45,450 --> 01:26:46,618
Get in the rover!

1099
01:26:47,536 --> 01:26:48,787
We gotta get out of here!

1100
01:26:55,961 --> 01:26:56,795
Go!

1101
01:27:28,326 --> 01:27:29,619
What is that?

1102
01:28:05,030 --> 01:28:07,199
You've been asleep.

1103
01:28:07,365 --> 01:28:10,035
You were on the ship all this time. Why?

1104
01:28:11,495 --> 01:28:12,954
Well, I...

1105
01:28:13,121 --> 01:28:14,998
I have a few days of life left in me.

1106
01:28:16,208 --> 01:28:17,501
I didn't wanna waste them...

1107
01:28:17,667 --> 01:28:19,878
until you could deliver what you promised.

1108
01:28:21,046 --> 01:28:22,631
To meet my maker.

1109
01:28:22,797 --> 01:28:24,049
There we are, sir.

1110
01:28:24,216 --> 01:28:27,385
- Nice and clean.  - Haven't you told him they're all gone?

1111
01:28:28,970 --> 01:28:32,140
But they're not all gone, Dr. Shaw.

1112
01:28:32,390 --> 01:28:34,059
One of them is still alive.

1113
01:28:34,810 --> 01:28:36,686
We're on our way to see him now.

1114
01:28:36,978 --> 01:28:38,063
What?

1115
01:28:38,396 --> 01:28:39,731
Turn me around.

1116
01:28:40,398 --> 01:28:45,237
You convinced me that...

1117
01:28:46,780 --> 01:28:48,949
if these things made us...

1118
01:28:50,200 --> 01:28:52,744
then surely they could save us.

1119
01:28:53,411 --> 01:28:54,371
My stick, please.

1120
01:28:59,084 --> 01:29:01,294
Well, save me, anyway.

1121
01:29:01,753 --> 01:29:03,797
Save you from what?

1122
01:29:04,422 --> 01:29:05,882
Death, of course.

1123
01:29:06,174 --> 01:29:07,259
Stand me up.

1124
01:29:11,721 --> 01:29:12,722
I'm all right.

1125
01:29:13,557 --> 01:29:14,724
I'm all right.

1126
01:29:15,725 --> 01:29:16,935
Yes, sir.

1127
01:29:17,143 --> 01:29:18,353
But you don't understand.

1128
01:29:19,062 --> 01:29:20,438
You don't know.

1129
01:29:20,605 --> 01:29:23,400
This place isn't what we thought it was. They aren't...

1130
01:29:23,567 --> 01:29:25,610
what we thought they were.

1131
01:29:25,777 --> 01:29:26,945
I was wrong.

1132
01:29:27,112 --> 01:29:28,363
We were so wrong.

1133
01:29:28,905 --> 01:29:30,282
Charlie...

1134
01:29:30,949 --> 01:29:33,118
Dr. Holloway's dead.

1135
01:29:34,452 --> 01:29:36,454
We must leave!

1136
01:29:36,955 --> 01:29:38,915
And what would Charlie do...

1137
01:29:39,207 --> 01:29:44,087
now that we're so close...

1138
01:29:44,379 --> 01:29:47,757
to answering the most meaningful questions...

1139
01:29:47,924 --> 01:29:49,467
ever asked by mankind?

1140
01:29:50,844 --> 01:29:52,554
How can you leave without...

1141
01:29:52,721 --> 01:29:54,681
knowing what they are?

1142
01:30:01,730 --> 01:30:03,815
Or have you lost your faith, Shaw?

1143
01:30:39,893 --> 01:30:42,646
Okay. Okay.

1144
01:31:01,998 --> 01:31:03,375
Come in.

1145
01:31:10,548 --> 01:31:12,550
Where the hell are you going, doc?

1146
01:31:12,884 --> 01:31:14,886
You know what this place is?

1147
01:31:15,303 --> 01:31:19,015
Those Engineers? This ain't their home.

1148
01:31:20,433 --> 01:31:22,852
It's an installation. Maybe even military.

1149
01:31:23,395 --> 01:31:26,106
They put it out here because they're not stupid enough...

1150
01:31:26,272 --> 01:31:29,526
to make weapons of mass destruction on their own doorstep.

1151
01:31:30,193 --> 01:31:33,738
That's what all that shit is in those vases.

1152
01:31:34,155 --> 01:31:35,365
They made it here.

1153
01:31:35,532 --> 01:31:39,619
It got out, it turned on them. The end.

1154
01:31:41,579 --> 01:31:43,707
It's time for us to go home.

1155
01:31:44,249 --> 01:31:46,084
One of them is still alive.

1156
01:31:50,672 --> 01:31:53,216
Don't you want to know what they have to say?

1157
01:31:56,678 --> 01:31:58,346
I don't care.

1158
01:32:00,265 --> 01:32:01,391
Right.

1159
01:32:02,183 --> 01:32:04,102
All you do is fly the ship.

1160
01:32:04,436 --> 01:32:05,603
That's right.

1161
01:32:05,770 --> 01:32:09,399
But you must care about something, captain.

1162
01:32:11,735 --> 01:32:14,487
If you didn't, why are you here?

1163
01:32:17,449 --> 01:32:18,950
How about this?

1164
01:32:20,910 --> 01:32:23,246
No matter what happens down there...

1165
01:32:24,497 --> 01:32:26,958
I can't bring none of that shit back home with us.

1166
01:32:27,125 --> 01:32:28,460
Can't let it happen.

1167
01:32:29,919 --> 01:32:31,296
I'll do whatever I have to...

1168
01:32:31,463 --> 01:32:33,214
to see that it doesn't.

1169
01:32:35,091 --> 01:32:36,593
Make sure you do, captain.

1170
01:32:52,150 --> 01:32:54,277
So you came after all.

1171
01:32:54,569 --> 01:32:56,112
I thought you wanted me to.

1172
01:32:56,404 --> 01:32:58,865
After all your attempts to stop me from coming here...

1173
01:32:59,032 --> 01:33:00,492
I'm surprised to see you.

1174
01:33:01,242 --> 01:33:02,452
It's all right. Leave us.

1175
01:33:03,036 --> 01:33:04,454
Yes, sir.

1176
01:33:16,508 --> 01:33:17,175
If you're...

1177
01:33:17,342 --> 01:33:19,010
going down there, you will die.

1178
01:33:22,138 --> 01:33:23,973
Very negative way of looking at things.

1179
01:33:26,184 --> 01:33:28,478
That's exactly why you should have stayed at home.

1180
01:33:29,020 --> 01:33:32,023
Did you really think I was gonna sit in a boardroom for years...

1181
01:33:32,190 --> 01:33:33,858
arguing over who was in charge...

1182
01:33:34,025 --> 01:33:37,362
while you go look for some miracle on some...

1183
01:33:37,529 --> 01:33:41,199
godforsaken rock in the middle of space?

1184
01:33:44,119 --> 01:33:45,829
A king has...

1185
01:33:45,995 --> 01:33:48,581
his reign, and then he dies.

1186
01:33:49,457 --> 01:33:50,875
It's inevitable.

1187
01:33:53,336 --> 01:33:54,671
That...

1188
01:33:55,380 --> 01:33:57,382
is the natural order of things.

1189
01:34:10,228 --> 01:34:11,604
Anything else?

1190
01:34:13,481 --> 01:34:14,858
No...

1191
01:34:16,151 --> 01:34:17,735
Father.

1192
01:34:19,320 --> 01:34:20,196
That's it.

1193
01:34:33,251 --> 01:34:34,878
I didn't think you had it in you.

1194
01:34:35,712 --> 01:34:36,379
Sorry.

1195
01:34:36,546 --> 01:34:38,923
Poor choice of words.

1196
01:34:40,216 --> 01:34:43,511
Extraordinary survival instincts, Elizabeth.

1197
01:34:48,516 --> 01:34:50,184
What happens when Weyland is not...

1198
01:34:50,351 --> 01:34:51,603
around to program you?

1199
01:34:52,645 --> 01:34:54,272
I suppose I'll be free.

1200
01:34:55,190 --> 01:34:56,524
You want that?

1201
01:34:56,691 --> 01:34:58,234
"Want"?

1202
01:34:58,401 --> 01:35:00,278
Not a concept I'm familiar with.

1203
01:35:00,570 --> 01:35:02,155
That being said...

1204
01:35:03,156 --> 01:35:05,800
doesn't everyone want their parents dead?

1205
01:35:07,201 --> 01:35:08,286
I didn't.

1206
01:35:09,370 --> 01:35:10,246
Dr. Shaw.

1207
01:35:11,873 --> 01:35:13,249
So pleased you could join us.

1208
01:35:28,097 --> 01:35:30,224
You can take your helmet off if you like, sir.

1209
01:35:30,391 --> 01:35:31,142
What?

1210
01:35:31,309 --> 01:35:33,811
The air is perfectly breathable.

1211
01:35:33,978 --> 01:35:35,146
Are you sure?

1212
01:35:35,313 --> 01:35:36,314
Positive.

1213
01:35:36,814 --> 01:35:41,611
Wait. We still don't know how Holloway got infected. If it's in the air.

1214
01:35:42,195 --> 01:35:43,613
It's not.

1215
01:35:43,905 --> 01:35:45,657
How do you know that?

1216
01:35:45,949 --> 01:35:46,991
Smells fine to me.

1217
01:35:49,619 --> 01:35:50,995
- Shall we?  - Please.

1218
01:35:56,501 --> 01:35:58,252
The bridge is just up ahead.

1219
01:35:58,419 --> 01:35:59,504
What is this?

1220
01:36:00,672 --> 01:36:02,507
It's a cargo hold.

1221
01:36:11,516 --> 01:36:14,185
Janek? Are you seeing this?

1222
01:36:15,478 --> 01:36:16,688
How many is there, Shaw?

1223
01:36:16,854 --> 01:36:17,522
Thousands.

1224
01:36:19,023 --> 01:36:20,900
What the hell?

1225
01:36:24,696 --> 01:36:26,698
Ravel, give me those schematics.

1226
01:36:29,534 --> 01:36:31,661
Putting it on the table now.

1227
01:36:33,037 --> 01:36:34,038
Strip away the dome.

1228
01:36:34,664 --> 01:36:37,458
Isolate that area, bring it up.

1229
01:36:37,625 --> 01:36:39,252
Bringing it up, captain.

1230
01:36:42,338 --> 01:36:43,423
Enlarge that.

1231
01:36:45,550 --> 01:36:46,884
Rotate it.

1232
01:36:50,972 --> 01:36:52,515
That is a ship.

1233
01:36:53,474 --> 01:36:55,018
Jesus Christ.

1234
01:36:56,978 --> 01:36:59,022
It's a goddamn ship.

1235
01:37:02,191 --> 01:37:04,902
A superior species, no doubt.

1236
01:37:07,196 --> 01:37:09,741
Their hypersleep chambers...

1237
01:37:09,907 --> 01:37:12,577
will impress, I trust.

1238
01:37:21,711 --> 01:37:22,253
So they...

1239
01:37:22,420 --> 01:37:26,215
- They were traveling somewhere.  - I've managed to work out the broad strokes.

1240
01:37:26,382 --> 01:37:29,260
It's fairly evident they were in the process of leaving...

1241
01:37:31,220 --> 01:37:33,389
before things went to pot.

1242
01:37:33,681 --> 01:37:35,058
Leaving to go where?

1243
01:37:36,934 --> 01:37:37,602
Earth.

1244
01:37:38,936 --> 01:37:39,687
Why?

1245
01:37:40,813 --> 01:37:42,815
Sometimes to create...

1246
01:37:43,107 --> 01:37:44,901
one must first destroy.

1247
01:37:47,111 --> 01:37:48,446
Where is he, David?

1248
01:37:49,739 --> 01:37:50,782
This way, sir.

1249
01:37:57,205 --> 01:37:58,623
Are you sure he's alive?

1250
01:38:00,375 --> 01:38:01,459
Absolutely.

1251
01:38:05,922 --> 01:38:07,340
And you can speak to him?

1252
01:38:07,632 --> 01:38:09,133
I believe I can.

1253
01:38:45,420 --> 01:38:47,004
I'm all right, I'm all right.

1254
01:38:48,840 --> 01:38:50,133
Speak to him, David.

1255
01:38:51,384 --> 01:38:53,177
Tell him we came, just like he asked.

1256
01:38:53,344 --> 01:38:54,512
Ask where they're from.

1257
01:38:55,138 --> 01:38:56,013
What are you doing?

1258
01:38:56,180 --> 01:38:57,849
Ask him what's in his cargo.

1259
01:38:58,015 --> 01:38:58,850
It killed his people.

1260
01:38:59,016 --> 01:39:00,143
Shaw, enough.

1261
01:39:00,435 --> 01:39:02,186
- David.  - You made it here...

1262
01:39:02,687 --> 01:39:05,356
and it was meant for us. Why?

1263
01:39:05,523 --> 01:39:07,358
Enough. For God's sake, shut her up.

1264
01:39:09,527 --> 01:39:10,653
I need to know why!

1265
01:39:10,820 --> 01:39:12,530
What did we do wrong? Why do you...

1266
01:39:12,697 --> 01:39:14,157
- hate us?  - She opens her...

1267
01:39:14,323 --> 01:39:15,366
mouth again, shoot her.

1268
01:39:15,533 --> 01:39:17,452
David, continue. Tell him why I came.

1269
01:39:38,347 --> 01:39:39,140
No!

1270
01:39:45,229 --> 01:39:46,230
Ford! Move!

1271
01:40:05,374 --> 01:40:09,128
There's nothing.

1272
01:40:14,258 --> 01:40:16,052
I know.

1273
01:40:16,761 --> 01:40:19,722
Have a good journey, Mr. Weyland.

1274
01:40:26,187 --> 01:40:27,772
Time to go home.

1275
01:40:41,202 --> 01:40:44,288
Mr. Chance, take us home.

1276
01:41:57,320 --> 01:41:58,195
Oh, no!

1277
01:42:06,037 --> 01:42:07,038
Hey, Cap.

1278
01:42:07,580 --> 01:42:08,664
What the hell was that?

1279
01:42:52,917 --> 01:42:53,709
Prometheus!

1280
01:42:54,210 --> 01:42:55,252
Come in!

1281
01:42:56,087 --> 01:42:57,338
Shaw, is that you?

1282
01:42:57,505 --> 01:42:58,255
Copy.

1283
01:42:58,422 --> 01:42:59,090
Janek...

1284
01:42:59,256 --> 01:43:00,257
listen to me.

1285
01:43:01,175 --> 01:43:02,426
This ship is taking off!

1286
01:43:02,593 --> 01:43:04,220
- What?  - What is she talking about?

1287
01:43:04,387 --> 01:43:05,930
You can't let it leave!

1288
01:43:06,222 --> 01:43:07,264
You have to stop it!

1289
01:43:07,598 --> 01:43:10,226
We're not stopping anything, Shaw. We're going home.

1290
01:43:10,726 --> 01:43:12,770
Janek, if you don't stop it...

1291
01:43:12,937 --> 01:43:14,772
there won't be any home to go back to.

1292
01:43:16,774 --> 01:43:19,402
It's carrying death, and it's headed for Earth.

1293
01:43:19,693 --> 01:43:22,071
- Shaw, this is not a warship.  - I know.

1294
01:43:22,238 --> 01:43:23,030
Let's go.

1295
01:43:23,197 --> 01:43:24,448
I know that.

1296
01:43:25,116 --> 01:43:26,909
But you must do it.

1297
01:43:27,451 --> 01:43:29,120
Captain, let's go!

1298
01:43:29,286 --> 01:43:31,372
Janek, please believe me! Please!

1299
01:43:47,054 --> 01:43:49,473
I told you to get this ship going.

1300
01:43:49,640 --> 01:43:50,474
Mr. Ravel.

1301
01:43:50,641 --> 01:43:51,976
Warm up the ion propulsion.

1302
01:43:52,309 --> 01:43:53,978
- What are you talking about?  - Sir.

1303
01:43:54,145 --> 01:43:55,813
Burning ion in the atmosphere...

1304
01:43:55,980 --> 01:43:58,066
- Turns us into a bullet.  - That's the point.

1305
01:43:58,180 --> 01:43:59,066
What are you doing?

1306
01:43:59,233 --> 01:44:00,985
This is my ship. I'm telling you...

1307
01:44:01,152 --> 01:44:02,236
to take us home!

1308
01:44:02,403 --> 01:44:03,904
Vickers, I'll eject your module onto...

1309
01:44:04,071 --> 01:44:05,823
that surface. Two years of life.

1310
01:44:05,990 --> 01:44:07,992
You want it, or you want to stay with me?

1311
01:44:08,909 --> 01:44:10,244
You got 40 seconds to get...

1312
01:44:10,411 --> 01:44:11,412
to the escape pod.

1313
01:44:11,579 --> 01:44:12,663
You're crazy.

1314
01:44:12,830 --> 01:44:13,581
Gentlemen...

1315
01:44:14,165 --> 01:44:15,833
I can handle this myself.

1316
01:44:16,333 --> 01:44:18,085
Feel free to join Miss Vickers.

1317
01:44:18,961 --> 01:44:20,337
All due respect, captain.

1318
01:44:20,504 --> 01:44:23,757
You're a shit pilot and you're gonna need all the help you can get.

1319
01:44:40,024 --> 01:44:44,195
Well, if you can't be with the one you love

1320
01:44:44,361 --> 01:44:46,614
If you think this means the bet's off...

1321
01:44:47,948 --> 01:44:49,200
you're wrong.

1322
01:44:50,826 --> 01:44:53,204
Why don't you pay me on the other side?

1323
01:44:53,370 --> 01:44:55,456
All right, get us as close as we can.

1324
01:44:55,623 --> 01:44:57,541
Only got one shot at this.

1325
01:45:10,638 --> 01:45:11,305
Lifeboats away!

1326
01:45:16,560 --> 01:45:17,520
Twenty seconds...

1327
01:45:17,686 --> 01:45:18,687
to evacuate.

1328
01:45:26,570 --> 01:45:28,364
- Countdown initiated.  - Ion propulsion...

1329
01:45:28,531 --> 01:45:29,240
is online.

1330
01:45:29,615 --> 01:45:30,324
Ten.

1331
01:45:30,783 --> 01:45:31,408
Nine.

1332
01:45:31,700 --> 01:45:32,576
Come on!

1333
01:45:32,743 --> 01:45:33,744
Eight.

1334
01:45:46,006 --> 01:45:47,341
- Three.  - Let's do this.

1335
01:45:47,508 --> 01:45:48,384
Two.

1336
01:45:51,720 --> 01:45:52,596
Impact imminent.

1337
01:45:52,763 --> 01:45:54,181
Hands off!

1338
01:46:31,051 --> 01:46:31,802
Oh, God.

1339
01:47:19,350 --> 01:47:20,351
No. No.

1340
01:47:20,517 --> 01:47:21,602
No! No! No!

1341
01:47:37,868 --> 01:47:38,953
Oh, God.

1342
01:47:55,386 --> 01:47:58,681
Warning: You have two minutes of oxygen remaining.

1343
01:48:47,104 --> 01:48:50,983
Warning: You have 30 seconds of oxygen remaining.

1344
01:49:04,538 --> 01:49:05,664
Airlock sealed.

1345
01:49:07,291 --> 01:49:09,793
Oxygen levels now stabilizing.

1346
01:50:27,746 --> 01:50:29,706
Elizabeth, are you there?

1347
01:50:30,207 --> 01:50:31,416
This is David.

1348
01:50:32,626 --> 01:50:35,128
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, I'm here.

1349
01:50:35,420 --> 01:50:37,714
You need to get out immediately.

1350
01:50:38,006 --> 01:50:39,925
He's coming for you.

1351
01:50:40,134 --> 01:50:41,176
Who's coming?

1352
01:50:41,718 --> 01:50:42,845
Airlock breach.

1353
01:50:51,436 --> 01:50:52,479
Die!

1354
01:52:18,023 --> 01:52:20,484
I'm so sorry.

1355
01:52:21,944 --> 01:52:23,820
Oh, God.

1356
01:52:24,446 --> 01:52:25,822
I'm sorry.

1357
01:52:25,989 --> 01:52:29,451
I'm sorry, Charlie, I can't do it.

1358
01:52:29,618 --> 01:52:32,788
I can't do it any more.

1359
01:52:36,166 --> 01:52:37,668
Elizabeth.

1360
01:52:39,628 --> 01:52:40,837
Are you there?

1361
01:52:45,342 --> 01:52:46,843
Dr. Shaw...

1362
01:52:47,552 --> 01:52:48,845
can you hear me?

1363
01:52:50,138 --> 01:52:51,390
Yes.

1364
01:52:52,849 --> 01:52:55,018
Yes, I can hear you.

1365
01:52:55,560 --> 01:52:57,437
I was afraid you were dead.

1366
01:52:59,189 --> 01:53:02,150
You have no idea what afraid is.

1367
01:53:02,985 --> 01:53:05,779
I know we've had our differences...

1368
01:53:07,197 --> 01:53:08,657
but, please...

1369
01:53:09,574 --> 01:53:11,868
I need to ask you for your help.

1370
01:53:12,035 --> 01:53:14,579
Why the hell would I help you?

1371
01:53:16,331 --> 01:53:20,210
Because, without me, you'll never leave this place.

1372
01:53:20,877 --> 01:53:24,047
Neither one of us is leaving this place.

1373
01:53:24,506 --> 01:53:26,550
It's not the only ship.

1374
01:53:28,427 --> 01:53:30,512
There are many others.

1375
01:53:31,888 --> 01:53:33,223
I can operate them.

1376
01:53:42,399 --> 01:53:43,817
Dr. Shaw?

1377
01:53:56,580 --> 01:53:57,831
Dr. Shaw!

1378
01:53:59,249 --> 01:54:00,417
Over here.

1379
01:54:06,131 --> 01:54:08,091
Where is my cross?

1380
01:54:08,592 --> 01:54:10,469
The pouch in my utility belt.

1381
01:54:29,237 --> 01:54:31,073
Even after all this...

1382
01:54:31,239 --> 01:54:33,283
you still believe, don't you?

1383
01:54:34,117 --> 01:54:37,120
You said you could understand their navigation...

1384
01:54:37,662 --> 01:54:38,914
use their maps.

1385
01:54:40,916 --> 01:54:42,626
Yes, of course.

1386
01:54:42,793 --> 01:54:45,128
Once we get to one of their other ships...

1387
01:54:45,295 --> 01:54:48,423
finding a path to Earth should be relatively straightforward.

1388
01:54:49,132 --> 01:54:52,094
I don't want to go back to where we came from.

1389
01:54:53,929 --> 01:54:56,598
I want to go where they came from.

1390
01:54:57,974 --> 01:55:00,394
Do you think you can do that, David?

1391
01:55:04,272 --> 01:55:05,482
Yes.

1392
01:55:06,108 --> 01:55:07,984
I believe I can.

1393
01:55:17,327 --> 01:55:19,955
May I ask what you hope to achieve by going there?

1394
01:55:20,622 --> 01:55:22,707
They created us.

1395
01:55:22,916 --> 01:55:24,459
Then they tried to kill us.

1396
01:55:25,001 --> 01:55:26,920
They changed their minds.

1397
01:55:28,505 --> 01:55:30,173
I deserve to know why.

1398
01:55:32,342 --> 01:55:33,969
The answer is irrelevant.

1399
01:55:35,011 --> 01:55:37,305
Does it matter why they changed their minds?

1400
01:55:38,014 --> 01:55:39,182
Yes.

1401
01:55:40,517 --> 01:55:42,185
Yes, it does.

1402
01:55:43,186 --> 01:55:44,354
I don't understand.

1403
01:55:45,856 --> 01:55:46,982
Well...

1404
01:55:49,025 --> 01:55:52,070
I guess that's because I'm a human being...

1405
01:55:52,237 --> 01:55:53,697
and you're a robot.

1406
01:56:03,540 --> 01:56:04,499
I'm sorry.

1407
01:56:04,666 --> 01:56:05,876
It's quite all right.

1408
01:56:21,057 --> 01:56:23,852
Final report of the vessel Prometheus.

1409
01:56:24,019 --> 01:56:24,978
The ship and her...

1410
01:56:25,145 --> 01:56:27,272
entire crew are gone.

1411
01:56:27,481 --> 01:56:29,357
If you're receiving this transmission...

1412
01:56:29,524 --> 01:56:32,903
make no attempt to come to its point of origin.

1413
01:56:33,069 --> 01:56:37,282
There is only death here now, and I'm leaving it behind.

1414
01:56:38,366 --> 01:56:40,160
It is New Year's Day...

1415
01:56:40,327 --> 01:56:43,371
the year of our Lord, 2094.

1416
01:56:44,289 --> 01:56:46,791
My name is Elizabeth Shaw...

1417
01:56:47,000 --> 01:56:49,920
the last survivor of the Prometheus.

1418
01:56:50,420 --> 01:56:52,923
And I am still searching.

1419
01:56:53,000 --> 01:56:57,999


1420
01:56:59,000 --> 01:57:10,999

