Your share.
And a passport. And I paid for it meself.
Only seemed fair.
Looks like they put you through it.
I knew something they wanted to know,
didn't I, Charlie?
Fucking hell, Dale.
You want me to say thank you?
Then fuck yes. Thank you.
You wanna hit me?
Go on. Punch me in the kisser.
I fucked myself.
But now, if I'm free,
then I'm free to go where I wanted
before I was stupid enough
to mess around with you.
A fucking Kiwi?
It was the best I could do
on short notice.
Okay.
Know where you're gonna go?
Yeah.
Gonna go find yourself, Dale?
No. I'm gonna lose myself.
Oi.
You. You need hospital?
No. No hospital.
I'm fine.
This is the most capable night manager
in this, the... the best,
cheapest hotel in all of Colaba.
Yaar, Prabhu,
do you realize what time it is?
I don't want any more fucking goras
this late.
But they're very tired
and would appreciate
being checked into the room.
Take them, please.
- I'll do it because it's you.
- Then do it.
- Okay. Fill it in.
- Thank you very much.
This man says he is a hotel guest?
Who?
This man says he is a hotel guest.
Is this true?
Yes, he is a guest.
What is his name?
- Just a second. It's in the register.
- Let me see.
- I'll show you, sir.
- Give it to me.
Show me his C-Form.
C-Form, it would be over here.
The bastard has been fighting
and does not want the hospital.
- Oh, yeah?
- Come on. Why does it take so long?
What happened?
This pandu is a full motherfucker.
If you don't bribe him,
he'll take you to jail. What happened?
I got mugged.
They took everything,
even my fucking boots.
Everything?
I just need to lie down.
Show me his room. Now.
- Lin. No passport, no money…
- What are you doing?
…Is very, very big problem in Bombay.
We have to go now. Lin, let's go.
- Hurry up!
- Yes, sir.
This is the room.
Okay.
Yes, sir.
Okay. Here is water.
Now I see why you're carrying
this impressive medicine box.
You should also be carrying
more than one pair of shoes, na?
Best medicine.
Tomorrow, first thing,
I will take you New Zealand consulate.
They will give you new passport, money.
I can't go to the authorities.
It's not an option for me.
Okay.
Please. Come. Eat, na.
You are my guest,
and Lakshmi, my neighbor, she is making…
…first-class roti.
Thank you.
Good, huh?
- Wow. It is very spicy.
- Mmm.
Dhanayavaad, for everything.
Mmm. I don't know about you,
but I need a drink.
What is that?
It's been three weeks. I still don't know
which waggle means what.
Okay.
Right now it is meaning, "Certainly,
by all means, I'll drink with you."
But it can also mean "no." Or "hello."
Or, "I understand."
Or even, "I am a man of peace,
so please do not be hurting me."
And you could learn this, huh?
Then this won't happen,
this won't happen, that won't happen.
After you.
Mmm.
Oi, take it easy.
So good.
Very, very smooth, yaar.
Okay.
Hey, man.
Keep it.
Is there a problem?
No. Just…
If I was knowing this was my whiskey
and not yours,
I would not have been so generous
with myself in drinking it, na.
Really?
- What are you doing?
- Wh... Hey!
Are you crazy?
This shirt was cleaned today only, yaar.
Take it.
It's for you.
Really?
Dale!
You fucking dog.
Back to where you belong.
Someone once told me that
a dream is where a wish and fear meet.
When the wish and the fear are the same,
we call the dream a nightmare.
You sure it was Rujul?
Fat and shiny, a lot of gold.
Stubby fingers, little mushroom cock.
And I heard his name,
when Walid was cheering him on.
And you're sure Rujul promised Walid
the Sagar Wada slum land?
Yeah.
We were their entertainment,
a way for them to seal their deal.
The other girl, Sunny, understood it all,
who they were, what they were doing.
Rujul and Walid didn't give a shit
if we heard.
Then Sunny disappeared,
and Zhou wouldn't let me leave.
Had to bribe that maid to come tell you.
She's dead, isn't she? Sunny.
I'd be the same if I didn't know you.
They all stared at me
with such intensity,
that I thought they must hate me.
Now I know
they were simply staring at my fear.
It's what people know about themselves
that makes them afraid.
Excuse me. Where's the toilet?
Huh?
How much shouting and yelling
you were doing last night?
Bad dreams, na?
That is why I let you sleep this morning.
Great.
Listen, I really need to go to the...
Hey! Lin, this is Lakshmi.
She made the roti
we were eating last night.
Oh, hi. Hey. Thank you. Was delicious.
Where are we?
This is the Sagar Wada jhopadpatti.
My home.
We are the not-people,
and these hutments are the not-houses
where we are not living.
Whose are they?
Her husband. He's gone.
I can't take her dead husband's shoes.
Not dead, Linbaba.
Gone to Dubai only, for the work there.
Thank you. Thank you.
- I really do need to shit.
- Let us go.
Hurry.
It's good?
You mind?
If you think it helps.
Can't make it worse.
You said you want to quit.
You know what'll happen
if you tell Khaderbhai about Rujul, right?
I'm out now.
We could stay quiet.
If Rujul's betraying us, then
I've worked the last year for nothing.
You would've let me rot in the Palace
if I hadn't known something
that threatened your precious land deal.
You used me.
How are you any different
than Maurizio and Modena?
Or maybe you're the one doing the using.
You don't give a shit about Rujul.
The drugs, me, those guys,
just a way to pass the buck and take
no responsibility for yourself whatsoever.
How are you doing, Arun? Johnny?
Prabhu.
- I'll help them.
- You won't. I'll go.
Go clean the table.
Do you want something?
Chai and roti for us both, please.
How you going?
Come. Sit.
Sit, na. Nandita is making
world best chai in all Bombay. Trust me.
Okay.
Arre, thank you, Kaaki. Thank you.
Thank you.
Who's the gora?
- He is my new business partner.
- Business partner?
Mmm. We are going to be working together
in the tourist business.
Parvati?
I'm coming!
- What did you say to her?
- That you are my good friend.
That is Parvati,
and I am determined to marry her, Linbaba.
That's your girlfriend?
I did not say she was my girlfriend.
This is the first time
we've ever spoken words to each other.
You've never spoken to her before?
It is a momentous day.
Well, glad I could be here to see it.
Listen, mate.
I need to figure out my situation.
Mmm. You can't go to your authorities.
- Shut the fuck...
- But you are needing money, yes?
I have been thinking to help you
get it very fast.
What about the train tickets?
To your village.
You still have them, right?
Can we sell them?
Very difficult to sell tickets for a train
that has already left the station. No.
I think it is best idea
to become business partners. Hmm?
To be Bombay guides together.
- I'm not staying, Prabhu.
- Just think, Linbaba.
- So much money will be coming.
- I just need to get to Karla.
- Listen to me, please. We could both be...
- I can't, Prabhu.
Hey. Hey.
Thank you for last night. All right?
You were a lifesaver. You really were.
But I'm not staying here and hustling,
all right?
It's just not gonna happen. All right?
All right.
I'll be back for my stuff later.
Karla, it's Lin.
Karla, you there? I need to talk to you.
- What happened?
- Madame Zhou figured it out.
They almost killed me.
They took my money,
my passport, everything.
- I warned you it was dangerous.
- You did, yeah. Now I'm fucked.
Then go to your embassy.
I can't.
How is that my problem?
Seriously?
Karla, I don't understand
why you're being like this.
I'm asking for help.
Karla, you need to fucking help me.
I don't need to do anything.
I have somewhere to be.
Is she for real?
You look like a man who needs a drink.
I know you didn't give me
all the dope last night.
Now it's up to me, not her.
Karla can spot them a mile away.
Who?
People she can use.
She didn't force me to do anything.
Didn't need to. It's her gift.
What's so special about Karla anyway?
I'm as beautiful as she is, aren't I?
I feel even better than I look.
Don't.
Lisa, you don't have to do that.
Maybe I wanna feel good.
Don't you? We can feel good together.
- Lisa.
- Hmm?
You're shit-faced.
Why do men like bitches?
It's true.
They fall over women
who treat them like shit.
Can't get enough of it.
This fucking sucks.
You never tried to quit before?
I like being high.
I like there being some distance.
I'm not good with life stuff.
Never have been.
Maybe Karla left that
'cause she knew you'd find it.
Fuck, you're right.
I take this, she can throw me out.
You're not as dumb as you look, Lin.
I'm gonna puke.
How long is it this bad?
Few days.
And then it gets better?
It does.
You don't miss it?
Every day.
Khaderbhai.
Salaam alaikum.
Alaikumu assalam.
It's good to see you. Please.
Thank you.
Is everything all right?
You said it was urgent.
I went to the Palace last night.
Your hate for Zhou is a wound that will
never heal if you keep picking at it.
Zhou was holding my friend Lisa prisoner.
Because of what Lisa knew.
We're being betrayed.
Our business together has been
the usual Bombay dhanda.
Bribes and understandings,
what everyone expects.
But I have other business. You know this.
Out of respect and affection for you,
I've never asked you to cross the line
between my two worlds, Karla.
- Are you certain?
- I wouldn't be here if I wasn't.
I mean, you must be certain
that you are ready
for what telling me
about this betrayal means.
If I don't tell you what I know,
then you'll suffer.
Instead, you would suffer for me.
You've done so much for me.
There is no debt between us.
Love has no accounting or ledger
or quid pro quo.
We invest it because our heart insists
without any demand of return.
And this is the lesson, above all others,
you still need to learn, Karla.
Rujul Aadekar has been meeting
with Walid Shah.
He will accept Walid's bid for Sagar Wada,
not ours.
You better not be wrong about this.
Thank you.
I don't know why people can't be nicer.
Was it a girl?
Turned you on to heroin the first time?
Who was she?
Oh, it doesn't matter.
It's always love
that sends us down the rabbit hole.
Are you scared?
Trust you.
Once we have the money to go to India,
we can do this every day.
We're gonna have
such an amazing time, baby.
Do me a favor? Get rid of that shit.
Sure.
- Lisa. Hey.
- Hmm?
Who's Rujul Aadekar?
Forget you ever heard that.
Tell me.
No. Leave that alone.
You're helping me. I'm helping you.
The Palace is allowed to exist
because it has never taken sides.
Zhou will be reminded of the grace
under which she operates.
Tell me about this man who helped you.
His name is Lin Ford.
I knew he was about to leave town,
so I used him to get Lisa out.
You must have trusted him.
That is no small thing for you.
I was in a hurry. He fit the bill.
Does he know about Rujul?
He heard the name. Nothing more.
Has no idea what any of it means.
But a smart and resourceful man
might decide to ask.
Okay, okay. I'll see you soon.
Thank you, thank you.
Pleasure. Pleasure.
And we do it like this, yeah?
Hey.
What happened to your face?
I got mugged.
- Wow.
- I need new papers.
Why are you asking me?
'Cause you are the biggest crook I know
in Bombay.
- No offense.
- Uh, none taken.
And I can assume,
for reasons I need not know,
that your consulate is not an option?
Bien sûr. Or you wouldn't need a crook.
I need to buy a passport.
You said you know the guy.
Abdel Khader Khan controls
the book business in Bombay.
Well, can you set me up with him?
If they sold my passport to him,
maybe he'd sell it back to me.
Have you read The Godfather, Lin?
- I've seen the film.
- That is Khader Khan.
This is not a man
with whom you just get set up.
What would you offer him?
You said you have no money.
A good passport, one worth having,
will cost a thousand dollars.
A thousand dollars.
Ah, come on.
There must be something I can do.
No one knows this place like you do.
I thought we were friends.
I do not have friends.
Times like this are exactly why.
Well, I gotta do something.
You know,
I slept in a fucking slum last night.
As did half of Bombay.
Do you know a guy called Rujul Aadekar?
Or Ah-dee-kuhr.
Yeah, he's a local politician.
Well, he's involved with some shady shit
at the Palace, Madame Zhou's place...
Just... Keep your...
Maybe that information
would be worth something to someone.
- Could you just ask around?
- Keep your voice down.
Fuck that. I want my freedom back, Didier.
I don't care if I screw over Zhou, Karla…
Will you calm down? Shh.
…the Godfather, Rujul,
whoever the fuck, until I get it. Whatev...
- Fuck.
- Gentlemen.
Dirty Harry, Lin.
I've seen it now on VCR.
It's not a Western,
but very good all the same.
"Did I fire six shots, or only five?"
- It's very cool.
- Uh, bonne chance, Lin. Okay?
Wish you good luck.
For a Few Dollars More
is my favorite, yaar.
And then maybe Josey Wales.
Actually, no, the... the whole
Dollars trilogy would be my one-two-three.
And then maybe Josey Wales is my fourth,
because... just the way he puts it all...
You and me need to have a word.
This guy is crazy. Look at him.
Let me get rid of him. Apologies.
I'm going nowhere, mate.
I just got the shit kicked out of me.
After I went and helped Karla
get Lisa out of the Palace.
What? What happened to Lisa?
Oh, you didn't know?
Zhou was holding her prisoner.
She's a fucking mess.
Sorry. You need to leave.
Thank you.
No, no, no, no.
Where are you going?
It's a joke. Where are you going?
You know, I think you should
stop interfering with my business.
Lin, is Lisa all right? Where is she now?
What, you think I'd tell you arseholes?
Zhou's people took my money
and my passport.
- The way I see it, all of that is on you.
- Hey, hey, hey, hey.
If you went to play hero
for a junkie whore,
that is Lisa's problem.
And if you did it to please Karla…
Tsk, tsk, tsk. That is her problem.
But you and I, we have no relationship.
I owe you nothing.
Oh, I think you're wrong about that.
- Don't fucking walk away from me.
- Arre, chaps.
- It's okay. No, it's okay.
- This is not the place. Please, sit down.
Both of you, sit.
- After you. Oh!
- Have a seat.
Who the fuck do you think you are, hmm?
Aw, you turn up here,
you think you matter?
You know, only a fool plays a game
without knowing the rules first,
or the other players.
Let's go, Modena.
I wanted to smash
his pretty smiling face in.
Because I knew I could
and because it would feel great.
But mainly 'cause I knew he was right.
Prabhu.
Look, after this morning,
I wouldn't blame you
if you tell me to piss off,
but I need to make a phone call,
and I've got no money.
Yeah?
All right. Thank you.
Can I make an international call?
Of course, Linbaba.
For three rupees you can call
anywhere in the world.
But one thing. I thought you had
no one to be calling for help.
There's one person who owes me.
ISD.
- Thank you.
- Dial.
It's okay?
- Yeah?
- Hey. It's me.
Charlie, you there? It's Dale.
You shouldn't be calling me.
There's no contact, we said.
I know. I know, mate.
Look, I need you to send me
some money to Bombay.
Dale, you got what you were owed.
You can't just call and expect
to keep sucking on the tit, mate.
I'm in serious trouble, Charlie.
Well, it's a bit of a habit with you, eh?
Always got your dick in a vice.
This one's nothing to do with me.
Yes, it is, because my whole life
is fucked because of you.
Come on, Charlie.
Just help me out, please.
- You owe me.
- Not anymore, I don't.
Yes, you do. You fucking owe me.
You'd be rotting in a fucking prison cell
if it wasn't for me.
Charlie.
Fuck! F...
Lin.
Lin!
- Lin, wait!
- What? What? Why?
Why you trying to help me?
I barely know you.
You know nothing about me.
Because you're my mate.
Ah, yeah, mates. Mates.
Mates just fuck you over. Trust me.
- Lin.
- What?
Listen. Here, we have nothing.
This place is not working
without everyone helping each other.
Like I want to help you, Lin.
Okay?
I've been a total prick to you all day.
Yes.
I can tell you're having
a not-so-good time.
Hmm?
Also not fully understanding
your situation.
But now, I think you are understanding.
- What? That I'm totally fucked?
- Yes.
And so now you're understanding
we can start getting you…
"unfuck."
- "Unfucked."
- Yes, "unfuck."
With us both working together,
we will make good money fatafat, Linbaba.
All right.
Then I guess we better get started.
Chalo. Chalo, boss.
What kind of man is this Lin,
do you think?
I don't know. But Karla asked him for help
and he gave it.
I got a call from Reynaldo's.
He was there, making a scene.
He knows more than he should
and talks more than I like.
- Ah.
- Ah. Assalamu alaikum.
Alaikumu assalam.
Thank you for coming, Minister.
Of course. You call, I come.
You have been, uh,
doing your homework, I see.
Ah, knowledge is power, Rujul.
Hmm, only if you combine
with money and influence.
Or, in my case,
a very fine government position.
These people in Sagar Wada all know
they are fucked.
But, uh,
there's no power in that for them.
When was the last time you went
to one of the jhopadpattis?
To see the people there.
When I first came to Bombay,
I spent time in one of them.
It's long gone now,
but what I saw then, and still see now,
is they do not believe themselves fucked.
They do not have the brains
nor the education to foster ambition.
- Ambitious men are never content.
- Men like us?
Yes, my friend. Men like us.
You're not in the slum any longer.
No, but I never forgot
the lessons I learned there.
Loyalty is everything.
I wonder what Walid learned
at Zhou's palace.
I know you plan to betray me
and sell Sagar Wada to Walid Shah.
Have I wronged you in any way?
Uh, Khaderbhai...
I financed your entire political career.
We have been friends.
So tell me…
how have I wronged you?
You have fallen behind.
Your insistence in staying
out of the brown sugar and sex trade
means you cannot compete
with Walid's price for Sagar Wada.
So, I did not wrong you?
I am supposed to make less money
because of your absurd code of morality?
Well, you could have come to me.
I would've listened.
And done nothing.
You have become weak, Khader.
Lisa.
Lisa, it's Sebastian.
What are you doing here?
I, uh… I wanted to see if you're okay,
if you needed something.
How did you know I was here?
Uh, Lin.
He came after Maurizio at Reynaldo's.
He's... He's dangerous, that one, I think.
Lin's the one who got me out.
Guy barely knows my name,
and he risked his life for me.
Does Maurizio know you're here?
- No.
- Did he send you?
No. Li...
Lisa, I... I shouldn't have let Maurizio
make you go to such a place.
I should've told him.
I'm... I'm sorry, Lisa.
I can see how you look at me now.
And I deserve it.
It's not your fault you're weak.
I… love you.
Yeah. But you can't look after me.
I, um…
I thought you might need some.
Did you?
Or did Maurizio tell you to shoot me up
so I fall right back into line?
No. Lisa, Maurizio doesn't know
I'm here, I promise. I…
I just want you to be happy. That's all.
Him and me?
You're gonna have to choose, Modena.
You. You, Lisa.
I'd always choose you. Always.
Do you want this? I... I can…
No. I wanna quit.
You say you love me,
then help me with that.
Lisa. Just tell me how.
This is Prabhu.
From personal experience, I can tell you,
anything you want,
he can get you at the best prices.
This is Dieter, Sarah, and Francois.
Right?
- Yeah.
- Keen to buy some top-quality charas.
Mmm. Very pleased to meet you.
- How much charas you are wanting?
- We want a pound.
This is a lot of smoking.
Can you do it?
Arre, of course, this is no problem.
You can go drink your beers,
enjoy the good music.
- I'll bring it, okay?
- Sounds good.
- All right. I'll be in in a minute.
- Thank you.
I told you, Linbaba. Good business.
Big money for this.
Wait.
What? You wanna see the sights?
Buy some charas?
There's a thousand dollars in here
for your trouble,
and a name and an address in Ahmedabad.
They'll be expecting you.
They'll make you a new passport
at my expense.
That's what you need, isn't it?
What changed since this morning?
Oh, you really need me to keep quiet, eh?
Whatever you're looking for, Lin,
it's not here. Not anymore.
I thought maybe you were it.
Now you know different.
Your half of charas deal.
No, you keep it. I got what I need.
Look, I understand
if you think I'm a prick,
but I would like a proper goodbye.
I will not be seeing you again, na?
No.
You have a good heart, Linbaba.
- Did you tell Khader?
- Yes.
Then we just got a man killed.
It doesn't bother you?
I made my choice.
I found the heroin you left behind.
You wanted to see what choice I'd make?
And?
Lin talked me out of it.
I made him throw it away.
I wanna change.
He could've been good for you.
I gave him a way out of Bombay tonight.
It's the best thing I could give him.
Take a life, save a life?
Does that make it all okay?
We danced together all the time, once.
Do you remember?
I remember.
I was in love with you.
Wanted to be everything you seemed to be.
But, then, you know that.
Fuck me.
I'm leaving. All right?
You tell that mad cow Zhou I'm on my way.
I'm leaving Bombay.
There's no need for any of this.
Fuck you!
Fuck.
I was trying to learn my lesson for once.
Be smart and do what I needed to survive.
To be free.