Previously on Californication...
The Miss's caught me eating one of her chocolate bars
out of the cleaning lady's vagina.
Hello, darling.
You fucking fuckface!
I would like you to meet
the poet and philosopher...
- Holy shit, that's Marilyn Manson
- Marilyn Manson.
We are talking about doing
a duet together.
Maybe tour of the States.
That would be really something, right?
I'm just here for the narcotics.
- We're getting married !!
- The Runkles!
I'll fucking marry you Fuckers
on stage at the Greek!
Fuck Yeah, why not?
- You guys are coming on Tour, Right ?
- What ?
We gotta keep writing this musical.
If we are not together, I don't expect you
to have taken some vow of celibacy.
Karen, you want me not to see
anybody else, just say the word.
I decided to go abroad, for an
indeterminate amount of time.
I want to make a
literary pilgrimage.
Watching her go, I don't know...
It kinda feels like
the end of something.
Makes you wonder if she was the only thing that was still keeping us together.
How can you even debate this shit?
Go. Hit the road, don't look back, you fucking idiot.
Right, what if...
What if...
You've lived your entire adult life
according to "what if".
What if the one you think is "the one" is not really "the one"?
What if you shut your fucking piehole
and pour me another drink?
You came to see me.
Yeah, but I can't help where my dreams take me.
Yeah, but what do you dream about when you get there?
That says a lot.
What the fuck is wrong with that ass?
Nothing.
She's pretty amazing.
In some way, she's perfect for me.
The eternal dilemma, isn't it?
"Home, sweet home" vs. "the wild cold world outside your door" .
You know which way you chosen,
you died to regret it.
Says who?
It's not even me talking.
You know that.
I just ask the questions.
Why are you so afraid to give up and let go?
It's ok, Hank.
We tried and we failed.
It's not the end of the world.
But, if I gave up on us, what would I have left?
The rest of your life.
Hank.
You OK?
Just a wet dream
Why on earth are you packing so early?
Well, first of all, it's noon
And second, I'm still leaving after the show tonight
Which brings us to the real question
Should I be packing for two?
Cause I'm pretty sure
I could fit in a multitude of
black T-shirts and jeans and...
Or I could be possibly persuaded to come back to bed
And postpone packing
Be more persuasive
Are you pushing my head now?
- Oh my god!
- Just a little bit.
6th season | Episode 12
-= I'll Lay My Monsters Down =-
Subtitle: Billy | IgoPH
Kiko | Namin
portuguese review: Billy
English version: www.addic7ed.com
[InSUBs]
Quality is irreplaceable!
And... I'm hard!
Thanks, Hanky.
Let me check..
You're a liar.
And I love you for it.
That's hardly appropriate.
Sorry, naughty smurf.
She's not married yet.
Are you sure you wanna go through with this?
- Why are you trying to talk her out of it?
-Yeah, why you be trying to talk me out of it?
Charlie and Marcy Runkle are the
Fred and Ethel Mertz of our time
They belongs together.
That's right.
And if you'll excuse me,
Ethel has to make yellow while
Lucy and Ricky discuss their issues and what not.
So I've... I've a chance to go with Atticus on the road.
- Yeah?
- And I thought maybe...
You would wanna talk about it,
talk, I don't know.
I shouldn't even factor into your decision
But you do,
you always do.
Well...Hank, what do
you want me to do?
I mean... to say:
"Oh, please, stay!"
Let's live happily ever after
I can't do that.
Do you want my permission?
I mean, you're a big boy.
You're gonna make your own
decision about it, anyways.
Besides, I... I thought you're in a
relationship with someone.
Well, maybe that's what's
good for you then,
like a non-relationship relationship.
Cause you have a hard time functioning
within the confines of a traditional one.
Well, it was never anything
traditional about us
Have you heard from our
literary pilgrim?
No, only what she puts up on Instagram.
What's Instagram?
Ok, you guys working shit out?
You back together?
I guess not.
Ok, here's the deal:
Me and CW Runks are gonna do this thing.
And do you know why?
- No, why?
- Because we're gonna be fucking happy.
- And you know why?
- Why?
Because it's better than being
fucking miserable all the time.
This whole time we've been out here
it's been like a midlife crisis roller coaster ride.
And it's fucking over!
Now. So let's all just live happily ever after.
Ok? Good?
It's settled?
Good!
What's going on?
Atticus's had to sell the plane to fund the tour
And the record company ain't giving him
the kind of support they used to.
And no thanks to that nutjob missus of his,
he's having some serious
cash flow problems.
We're back to touring by bus.
- Where is that fucking ginger?
- He's in the bedroom.
He wants to talk with someone
who understands
what it's like to live with heartbreak
I told him, you know,
I've got lots of experience,
but no, he doesn't care, he wants you.
Hey Atticus!
What's up rock star?
I can't play the gig tonight, Hank.
Why is that?
I went home this morning,
and got down on bended knee,
and asked Natalie to take me back.
And she told me to fuck off.
She's really done with me,
which is understandable
given my behavior.
But I've never done an opening night
without a good luck kiss from her.
Back in the early day, she used to give me
this really comprehensive blow job, like balls and all, you know?
Although, I was usually too wired to come.
That's a cute story, buddy.
But I'm afraid the big rock show must go on
But I haven't been on a bus
in well over 10 years.
It's so embarrassingly bargain basement.
Are you kidding? That bus
out there, that's beautiful. That bus.
- Really, you like it?
- Yes, I love it. It's bad ass.
- It's cool?
- It's so cool.
It's like a land airplane
It's gas friendly, eco-friendly
You'll probably get an award for that shit.
- How do you do it, Hank?
- Do what?
The woman that you love is out there
and you know you can't have her.
How do you even get up in the morning?
Booze is always helpful
So is the art.
Everything that I write
is either for her, or about her, so
I'm with her, even when I'm not,
in my writing.
That's very moving, Hank.
- Don't cry!
- Why?
It's unbecoming.
You said something moving,
why shouldn't I cry?
What about your aussie blockiness?
Or your British stiff upper lip.
Whatever the fuck you are.
I think you should come on tour with me, Hank.
I feel like if we finish our
master piece,
our rock opera about love,
maybe we'll both end up with the girl
I'll think about it.
In the meantime.
Are you ready to rock out,
or do you cock out?
I'll admit this is pretty cool.
It's like Disneyland every day
Yeah. Without the morbidly obese
running around in scooters
Even the concept of time is different, you know,
it's rock and roll fucking summer camp forever.
- It's got to end at some point, doesn't it?
- Says who?
All roads lead back home eventually
Sounds like a Country song
Hey. You're Faith, right?
Yeah, that's me.
I'm Vince, from Mysstery.
Two s's. We're opening the show tonight
Well... Hey, Vince from Mistery
with to s's
- Good luck up there.
- Cool, thanks.
I'm wondering if maybe you
want to come hang on our bus
It's the one that says
"Cat Club"
We call it that because
chicks who want to come on
we ask them to pee on this
litter box we keep by the front door
This way we know for sure that
they're willing to party
I'm free,
I got a full bladder.
I don't think you'd have
to do that, though
because you're pretty famous
Thanks for the preferential
treatment and all, no thanks
What? We're not big enough
for the legendary Faith?
No, no, it's not like that at all
But if you're gonna be a dick about it,
I can just come clean
You're just not really that talented
I've heard your album
and it's really shitty mall metal
So, if I were you, I would
just quit now
and maybe Hot Topic will hire
you back this summer
Wow, you're kind of a bitch!
Hey, watch your manners, son.
That's no way to talk to a lady.
Fuck off, dad.
You know what this calls for?
Titty twister!
Good evening, Los Angeles!
You wanted the best?
Well I got stuck in the traffic
coming on the fucking hill.
From London, England,
by way of Mars
The Bacardi Concert series presents:
Atticus Fucking-Fetch!
Good luck out there.
Not that you need it.
You're a fucking rock star
A long way from church, eh?
Are you kidding me?
Do you, bald fucking wanker,
take this sexy little tree stump
to be your immortal beloved?
I most certainly do.
Do!
Right.
And do you,
delicious little spinner
with whom I have shared
a sexual encounter
which will sustain me
well into my golden years,
take this...
sweaty hairless pinhead
to be the very last
sexual parter of you entire life?
Jesus!...
Well, when you put it like that...
Let's do(ce) it.
I do(ce) it.
Good. (*)
Let's get on with it.
By the power vested on me
by the Sun Kill Moon ministry
of Northern California
I now pronounce you wife
and (*) man
Now, while we're here,
does anyone else feel like getting wedded
on this glorious, glorious LA evening?
Anyone?
Karen
Karen, be with me.
Spend the rest of your life
with this fool,
and this fool will spend the rest of
his life making sure you don't regret it
What do you say, babe?
- [audience] Say Yes!
- Will you be my wife?
Come on!
Say yes!
No?
Nobody?
Really?
No? Then get the fuck off my stage.
Be gone, all of you!
I wrote this next song
for my wife, Natalie
in hope that she'll forgive me
although if she did, I'll probably
just bugger it up all over again
But tonight I'm gonna play it
for my good friend and collaborator
Hank Moody. Who knows a thing
or two about heart break himself
- Wait, you look familiar.
- Hank Moody
- Come on
- Manson
Thank you for coming to
my fucking mother show
Hi, Brian.
Actually, I'm surprised that you came
I just want to make it clear,
I was just fucking with you.
I would not give drugs to your daughter.
Because I need them for later.
But wait. How is the kid?
- She's great.
- Good, good.
Would you get her to send me the
picture of me tea-bagging Atticus?
- Will do
- Because I want to put that on my Facebook
Will do
And if you guys aren't together
I would pee in your butt
What?!
It's Becca.
- Hey sweetie
- Hi, dad
- How's the road treating you?
- It's so beautiful out here, dad.
I'm having the time of my life
- And tomorrow we leave for Europe
- Glad to hear it
- Are you happy, Dad?
- That's a loaded question
I was just thinking about
what I want for all the people in my life
And I realized that I just
wanted you to be happy
I want to see you smile
and know you mean it
- are you high right now?
- significantly
We just smoked some killer weed.
Of course you did
Be careful
And have fun, just not too much
Don't worry, dad
All roads lead back home
That sounds like a Country song
- I love you, dad
- I love you too, sweetie
Would you do me a favor and
send Manson
that photo of him tea-bagging Atticus
Ok, will do
Ok, sweetie, I love you
I'm coming with you
That makes me so very happy
Good for you, man.
You made the right decision
Besides, even if you actually had the balls
to do it, and she actually said yes
- what would you have done?
- I would've married her right then and there.
And then, what? You would have fucked
like rabbits for a couple days,
you would have had some sweet little
pillow talk, and then one day she would
ask you to go to Home Depot with her.
Party is over
You know, you talk a good game,
but I was with you when you died
and you were about to do it. You were gonna take
one last shot at the love of your life, buddy.
Sure, I would have given it a try.
Maybe I could even got her back in the sack again.
But eventually, you get out of bed.
You're still you. All the problems
you've ever had, they're still there.
So you're just supposed to give up?
It's not about giving up. It's about letting go.
Finally accepting who you are.
Guess who
God, I can't wait for her to die
and come down
Karen?
Karen!
You have to go, don't you?
Yeah, I do.
I'm sorry, I do.
Don't be.
You just don't know what you're
gonna be missing.
I do.
That's what makes it is so hard.
- I could love you, you know.
- Faith...
I'm... I'm not saying that I do.
I'm saying that I could.
Which is rare for me,
and deserves to be acknowledged
You understand me, better than
any guy I've ever met
You get me.
And that has been the nicest feeling
I'm just saying.
And I'm just saying that you're
pretty fucking amazing.
And I hope you find what you're looking for out here.
I hope you find what you're looking for out back there
I'll even say a prayer for you.
Just not a very big one
- I hate saying goodbye to you
- Then don't
You know what?
The great thing about
never really being together:
never really have to break up
Hank, get the fuck out of here
Before I wrap my legs around you
and convince you to stay.
And you know I can do it.
What is this? Wow what?
- What's going on?
- Hank's got to go
He's got to see a horse about a girl
Is this about following your bliss?
That what we were talking
about in bed yesterday?
- Is it about love?
- It is
Then you must go.
I can't turn the bus around,
but I can send an emissary.
Sorry, crying again.
Don't be sorry. It's unbecoming.
All right, you. Go. My work here is done.
I really see to you happily ever after
I know he means a great deal to you,
as he does to me.
And I just want you to know that
I'm here for you, if you need me
Emotionally,
spiritually,
and obviously sexually.
Thank you, Atticus
I'm serious, darling.
Sometimes and orgasm can
relieve heartache
I've done a lot of research
in the area
Can I at least get a good luck kiss?
I do have a gig tonight, you know.
I'm a bit nervous
I know you're not one for
emoting, Krull,
but thank you
I had a girl once
love of my life she was
Fucked it up, of course.
I thought there'd be time.
Turns out, it's just roads
Long and paved potholes
I read that once in a book.
Go and get her, pal
www.insubs.com