Previously on Prison Break...
There's one big difference
between you and I, Michael.
You can't kill.
I will get you.
This is, uh...
in case you run into trouble
down the road.
Lincoln, he really wants
to see you and your brother.
He hasn't seen Michael
since he was ten years old.
Why are we going?
Michael never met
your grandfather.
Dad.
I got Burrows.
Take care of them.
I think there's a part of me
that enjoys this.
It feels to me like
chasing a high.
And I should know better
by now.
Sara?
Hi, Sara.
Hey, what is this?
It's for my... blood pressure.
Geary, come on, we
can make a deal, man.
No deals.
You just crapped out
your last bargaining chip, pal.
Ain't that the most beautiful
thing you ever seen?
This is the Tribune Police.
Make yourself known.
Hey, you're in luck.
Had a case in back.
Excellent.
Fishing reel oil.
And you want
the whole case?
Whole case.
And the, uh, GPS?
And the GPS.
Must do quite a bit
of fishing.
Yeah, a lot of fishing...
not a whole lot of catching.
$96.23.
Um...
I'm just going to take
the reel oil.
Thank you.
Hey! You have to pay for that.
Just take it;
please don't hurt me.
Please.
You have to pay for that.
Vault. Open it.
One for the team.
He wasn't gunning for me,
he was gunning for my daughter.
Give Anna her papa's love.
I'm going cut your throat out.
I loved you, Michael.
You just used me.
Cops found your girlfriend
fish-belly white,
gargling her own puke.
And what do you care?
As long as she left
the door open.
I feel very fortunate
to have met you.
I'm sorry, Henry.
It's about corporate interests
taking over the government--
buying elections,
fighting wars...
people dying so they
can turn a profit.
We're trying to stop it.
What are you, a
bunch of spies?
Just a handful of
senators, congressmen,
people like me
that once worked
for the company.
People willing to expose
the President
for what she is--
a shill working
for these corporations.
We bring her down,
we bring them down.
What's it got to do with me?
Because the way we're
going to bring her down
is also what we're going
to use to set you free.
About a week ago,
we finally got a break.
An NSA analyst
sympathetic to our cause
finally worked his way up
and got clearance
into the Echelon program.
E-mails, cell phone calls
all across this country,
if it's transmitted,
it goes through Echelon.
It's catalogued, interpreted,
and then stored
for Homeland Security.
Nothing is missed by them.
Nothing.
Including,
by accident,
for a few months after 9-11...
the White House.
The analyst got his hands
on a phone conversation
the President had
with Terrence Steadman...
two weeks after you
supposedly killed him.
Now, the analyst tried
to get this information
out of the building...
...but it turns out,
someone else was snooping, too.
Someone else
wanted answers
about the President.
Aldo and Lincoln want
to be left alone.
Sure, I understand.
24 hours later,
Tancredi is dead,
the analyst is missing,
and the White House
Echelon tapes
have been deleted
from the mainframe.
The tape is still out there.
And judging by how hard they're
going after Sara Tancredi,
I'm pretty sure
they think she has it.
And I think they're right.
She's the key
to this whole thing,
Lincoln.
www.1000fr.com Present
Capture:FRM@FadeOut
Sync:FRM@Navel
I would imagine
that you're feeling
slightly betrayed right now.
I understand.
As you can see,
hi, my name is not Lance,
and I'm not an addict.
Okay.
There is one thing
about me that should mean
a great deal to
you right now.
That is I am reasonable.
If you tell me what
you know, you get to go.
Okay, and then maybe
when this is all behind us,
we get to grab a piece of pie
for old times' sake.
Okay.
I don't know where Michael is.
This is not about Michael;
this is about your father.
He left Washington
with something
that didn't belong to him.
We need it back.
And you killed him for it.
I didn't, no, for
what that's worth.
But I hope that his death
properly illustrates
the magnitude
of the situation
that we're in right now.
So, where is it?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Where is it?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Where is it?
I don't know what you're
talking about.
Sara, there's a next step
involved in this,
and you don't want
to experience that.
I swear to God I don't know
what you're talking about.
My father didn't
give me anything.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Bless me, Father,
for I have sinned.
How long has it been
since your last confession?
This is my first time.
In a long time.
Are you aware
of the nature of your sins?
The nature?
I'm not really sure.
Deep down inside
your heart, you know.
Righteousness, maybe.
Believing the ends
justify the means.
What are
those ends?
Saving someone's life.
And the means?
I've broken just about
every law you can name.
But it's not
just what I've done.
It's what others have done...
...because I let them.
Because I was doing
what I thought was right.
I should have known
better this time.
This time?
When I was a kid...
I watched a man
bleed out and die.
And I was glad...
because he deserved it.
Life is
only for God to give
and take, my son.
Suddenly,
there is this dark space
inside of me.
And I knew
it was wrong.
But here I am.
Thereisa way
to stop this.
Surrender
your will to God.
If I surrender now,
I lose everything that I love.
But do you lose your soul
in the process?
Well, we all have
our crosses to bear.
You okay?
This is never gonna stop.
They're gonna keep
coming after us.
Lincoln, don't.
Is it done?
You are.
Lincoln Burrows.
Your man's dead.
Just like anyone else you
send to take out my son.
We want you.
This isn't about LJ.
There's a very simple way
for all of this to end.
I'll tell you how
it's going to end--
me staring in your dead eye
with my hand around your throat.
You don't even know who I am.
How much further?
Right here is good.
Thanks for the ride.
Agent Mahone.
Bill Kim.
I'm here
to pick you up.
I called Kellerman.
He's busy right now.
Does anyone else
know you're here?
No.
Good.
Can you open
the gate?
And I need a new vehicle.
There's something you
should know about me.
I don't like being
out in the field.
I only do so when
there's been a screwup.
I'm out in the field, Alex.
Then why don't you
open the gate?
You can hurry back to D.C.
before your
shoes get dirty.
We have a lead
as to where Burrows
will be meeting up
with his brother.
It's a place he referred to
as "Bolshoi Booze."
Does that mean anything to you?
Yeah, it's one of a hundred
tattoos on Scofield's body.
What does it mean?
I don't know yet.
You'll need
to figure it out
within the next
couple of hours.
If Scofield and Burrows
cross the border,
they'll be out
of your jurisdiction,
and you'll be of no
further value to us.
Open the gate.
So you can do what?
I want to hear it.
Straight from
the mouth of the guy
who's supposed
to be our closer.
I'll get Scofield
and Burrows...
and all of the rest of them.
And then me and you
and Kellerman,
we're going to part ways.
I just hope you're
properly motivated.
'Cause as long as you do your
job, we'll forget about Shales.
And then you can go back
to Colorado and visit your son.
Cameron.
He's five, right?
Don't you ever mention
his name again.
There he is.
That's what I wanted to hear.
Get cracking, Alex.
A lot of people
are relying on you.
Jane will take care of
it; you can trust her.
I know this is hard,
but it will work out--
you have my word.
Thank you.
Be careful.
Listen, uh...
I know.
Jane's gonna look after you.
I don't even know her.
She's all right.
She's been working
for Dad for a while.
I'll, uh...
I'll see you soon, I promise.
Isn't that the same thing
your dad told you?
Yeah, but I mean it.
Hey.
Hey, it's me.
Just call me
when you get this, okay?
It's important.
the numbers...
Is that my payment?
Medical nitroglycerine?
As promised.
Whoo.
You have no idea how hard it is
to get this kind of grade.
Even with my contacts.
It's time for your
end of the deal.
Where's that plane gonna be?
They call me a couple of hours
before with the drop-off point.
It keeps the DEA off our backs.
Since it's going
to be a while,
you might want to
stay out of the sun.
Hey, hey, hey.
Hey.
Is there a problem?
They're my
cousins.
Now, after your
father accessed
this information, he made
three calls
from his cell
phone, all to you.
What did he tell you?
Just that he was
coming back to Chicago.
Good.
You're being honest. Good.
Now, there's a half an hour
between when your father landed
and when he got home
that is unaccounted for.
I know you stopped by
his office.
Did you see him there?
No.
The last time I saw my father,
he was dead in his study.
Did your father have anyone
give you anything?
Do you think that I'm just
withholding information
because I like
hanging out with you?
If I knew something,
I would tell
you; I don't.
I don't know anything
about any of this.
Really?
Then why did you give
your father the file
on Lincoln Burrows?
Why did you open the door
for Scofield,
and help him escape?
Why did Scofield
send you those
coded notes?
Why did you come to
New Mexico to meet him?
Don't try to float a babe-
in-the-woods routine by me.
It's really going
to piss me off, so...
Come on.
Shh. Shh-shh.
You're okay.
Shh.
Look, Sara.
We're going to have
to come to an understanding.
Yeah, you were right;
they are coordinates.
Plug them into your GPS.
They'll take you to a spot
in the New Mexico desert.
It's in the middle
of nowhere, basically.
Thanks.
Yeah, no problem.
Sir, who are you meeting?
What the hell is he doing?
He's keeping us out of the loop,
that's what he's doing.
Constantly running
from the law with
a bad heart...
Mexico, where I'm from
has got a lot of great things,
but... health care
ain't one of them.
You all right?
You look
a little nervous.
I don't do this every day.
I just want to get
the information on that plane
and, uh...
move on.
Is that it?
That's it.
I know who you are.
You don't have
to worry-- we can't
go within 100 feet
of a federal marshal
to collect the reward,
'cause we got U.S. and Mexican
warrants on our heads.
But this plane to Panama...
Sit down.
This is all
for your brother?
Yes.
I got four brothers,
two in prison.
Accept a call? Yes.
But break them out?
Loco.
My brother gave me
a baseball mitt
for my 14th birthday.
I owed him.
You're a better man than I am.
Time will tell.
Shouldn't they have
called by now...
about the plane?
Yeah.
You know, I...
I have a question.
I thought
that these came
in glass vials,
not plastic.
I thought so, too, but the guy
I bought it from said
he packed it in plastic
for transportation over long
distances to prevent a fire
or an explosion.
Really?
I never heard of that.
What's going on?
We're going to do
a little quality control test.
It's the best available.
We got time.
For the last time,
some black male, early 20s,
jumped me from behind.
I didn't get a good look
at his face.
The assailant
attacked you
from behind?
That's what I just said.
Yet he managed to make contact
square on your forehead.
That's right.
With what? A boomerang?
Come on, why don't you
tell me what happened?
Look, I'm a retired correctional
officer out of Illinois.
How about showing some
professional courtesy, honey?
This is Roy Geary.
Leave a message.
You thieving son of a bitch.
You better get down
on your knees
and pray to God
that I don't find you,
because, if I do,
mark my words,
I'm going to gut you
bow to stern.
President Reynolds was
in Tallahassee, Florida,
early this morning, attending
a $5,000-a-plate
breakfast fund-raiser
for Senator Martin Kleinhenz,
who's running for reelection.
Later this afternoon, her
press conference was derailed
when a reporter asked her
to comment
on Lincoln Burrows'
escape from custody.
She declined.
It's become clear
in her first month in office
that she cannot separate herself
from this manhunt.
And as long as it continues...
...pundits say that questions
about Burrows will contin...
Ladies.
Let's get this party started.
The last 30 years,
I've hated you.
You walked out on me.
You haven't even
seen Michael.
I've seen him before.
Not in the papers, Dad.
Been trying to work out what
kind of man abandons his family.
Now I'm doing
the same damn thing.
You'll see him again.
I'll make sure of it.
How much further?
About three hours.
It's gonna be a few minutes.
My brother should
be here soon.
Maybe I should go outside
and make sure he can see me.
That's a good idea.
I think I'm gonna
send Ernesto to do it.
Ernesto, por favor.
Hello.
Si.
Bueno, te veo.
Was that the call?
Yes, it was.
About the plane?
¿Como se llamas?
Agua con azucar.
Sugar water.
You just made a big mistake,
blanquito.
I'm sorry, I'm
sorry, okay?
I'm not a chemist.
The guy I bought it from
swore it was medical nitro.
We both got screwed.
Yeah, but only one of us
is gonna pay for it.
Look, I just want to get
out of here,
and you want your payment.
My brother's gonna
be here soon.
We'll work something out.
Just name your price.
I already named my price.
You didn't go through.
When's your brother
getting here?
You were planning on turning us
in the whole time, weren't you?
When's he supposed
to meet you here?!
Sueltalo.
Drop it, or I'm gonna
shoot him.
Let him go, or I'll shoot you.
Suelta la pistola.
Ey, no estoy judiendo.
Sueltala, cabron!
Where is it?
My father didn't
give me anything.
Who you risking
your life for?
Lincoln Burrows.
Street thug.
And why is that your concern?
I mean, is there somewhere
in the Hippocratic Oath
where it says,
"I pledge to risk my life
for those who don't care
about mine"?
'Cause they don't
care about yours.
Burrows
and Michael Scofield
just used you.
Are you that surprised that
there are people in the world
who will stand up
to people like you?
Are you that far gone?
That's cute.
Sad.
But cute.
A Cleveland what?
Don't worry,
I'll talk you through it.
And we got
a glass coffee table
right here.
Hell no.
I'll do it
for a thousand.
$500.
$1,000.
$750.
All right.
What the hell?
Leave.
You know,
it's amazing what you
can pick up
at an Army-Navy store.
All that torture stuff,
that was Bellick's idea.
And if you ask me, he took
the whole thing way too far.
Listen,
why don't I just give
you half the money,
and we call it a day?
All right, 60-40.
Come on, T,
we can deal.
Where's the plane
going to land?
Kiss my ass, cobarde.
What are we going to do?
I don't know yet.
We're not going to get across
the border on the ground.
Without that plane,
we're screwed.
He's losing too much blood.
He'll never make it like this.
He should have thought
of that before he tried
to kill us.
We got to take him
to a hospital,
or else he'll die.
Please.
The plane,
and we'll let you go.
Dicelo.
Dicelo todo.
Dicelo ahora!
Finley Road...
off of Highway 8,
there's an airstrip.
There, okay?
Now let us go.
Let's go.
No, no, no!
Michael, let's go.
Por favor... please.
Don't do this,
please don't do this.
Let's go, Michael.
If we were bleeding
he would have not lifted
a finger,
you know that--
he was gonna kill us both.
Let's go.
No, that's not true.
Michael, we're going to
get to that plane...
Don't do this.
Let's go now, please.
Please don't do this, okay?!
Callate!
Don't do this.
Don't do, all right?
Don't listen to him!
Please.
Sara, I care about you.
This is not what I wanted, Sara.
Kellerman.
What's going on with Sara?
Has she told you anything?
Don't go anywhere.
Not yet.
I trust you've been...
persuasive.
Yes, absolutely.
Then kill her.
Well, she knows something.
You disobey me, you are done.
Do you understand me?
Put her in the ground, Paul?
Michael.
Let's go.
Hold still.
Michael, we're doing it wrong--
let's get out of here.
Now, he's gonna
call the cops,
or go get his buddies...
He's not going
to make it.
You have to...
Callate!
We'll call them
when we get safe.
Let's go-- Michael, let's go!
Thank you.
You got to get him to a hospital
right away.
Okay.
Wait. Wait.
Hey, man...
Forget Finley Road.
The plane is going to stop
at the seven mile marker
on Route 4 at sunset.
It's going to stop
for five minutes.
Then it's going to go
to Oaxaca, Mexico.
If you miss it,
you're out of luck.
He bled out on the way over.
Any ID?
Yeah, Roy Geary,
just an out-of-stater.
You know him?
He's a friend of mine.
Mr. Bellick?
Yeah.
You mind answering
a few more questions?
Yeah.
It's Pam.
What's going on?
I just wanted to say hey.
Well... are you all right?
You said it was important.
I know things got kind of ugly
toward the...
you know, the end.
Um... I got ugly.
But I want you to know that,
that there were circumstances
that, uh...
It was better that you
and Cameron
that you were not with me.
Why are you telling me this now?
If I had to do it
all over again...
I'd do it different.
We'd still be a family.
I'd give anything for that.
I just wanted you to know.
Alex...
what's going on?
Nothing.
I just wanted to call to say
that I was, uh....
...that I'm sorry
about everything.
Where are you right now?
I can come get you.
Wouldn't that be nice, huh?
No, I'm serious.
Where are you?
One more thing.
If you hear anything
in the media...
What?
What are you talking about?
Well... I'm glad I told you
about this place.
I'm glad I figured
out how to work a GPS.
Could you make it a little more
difficult next time?
I owe you one.
We're even.
But we got to leave.
Linc.
Hey, buddy.
How are you doing?
Where's LJ?
Safe.
The money?
I'll tell you later;
we got to go.
I brought someone.
Dad?
We've met before.
This is happening
right now, okay?
Don't make me do this.
Even if I knew,
I wouldn't tell you.
You wouldn't? Really?
Are you that stupid?
Are you that stupid?!
Because now
you're going to die!
You're going to die,
and all you had to do
is tell me
what your father gave you.
I know my options.
I can not tell you and die,
or I can tell you
and still die.
No. Wrong.
Sara.
Come on, smarten up!
For once in your life.
Please.
Go to hell.
Huh? Drowning is horrific--
don't get me wrong--
but once you give in and let
the water come into your lungs,
there's a certain
euphoria... I hear.
I guess as a junkie,
I thought maybe
you'd appreciate that.
You did this to yourself.
Welcome to www.1000fr.com