(low, eerie warbling)
(rustling, crunching)
(high-pitched screeching)
(eerie warbling continues)
(screeching, warbling stop)
(thunder rumbling)
(wind whistling)
(bird cawing in distance)
(motor chugging
and squeaking rhythmically)
(chugging and squeaking
continue)
♪ ♪
(clucking)
(birds chirping)
(distant thunder rumbling)
- (distant banging)
- GRADY: Ten-hut! -(gasps)
♪ ♪
(dog groans quietly)
(laughs softly)
(footfalls approaching)
Grab your hunting pack.
We're leaving at 0700.
♪ ♪
(wind howling)
(insects chittering)
♪ ♪
This view never gets old,
does it?
No matter how many times
you see it.
♪ ♪
Ah, don't go anywhere
near those.
These are death cap mushrooms.
The name ain't kidding.
Eat one of those, you'll be
wearing a toe tag real quick
unless someone's got
a brand-new liver
lying around for you.
- (birds chirping)
- (distantly): Blake. Blake.
(normal volume):
Blake.
Did you hear what I just said?
Yes, sir.
What did I say?
Don't eat the mushrooms.
What are they called?
Uh...
See, this is what I'm talking
about-- you're not hearing me.
You're off in your own
goddamn world somewhere.
This place is beautiful.
It's also dangerous.
You can survive if you know
exactly what to do.
Yes, sir.
People get taken from you--
(snaps fingers)-- like that.
It's not hard to die.
It's the easiest thing
in the world.
We are all...
inches away from it.
And I'm not always gonna
be around to watch over you,
but I'm gonna make damn sure
that you know
- how to survive as...
- (twig cracking)
(sighs)
(whispering):
Blake.
(birds chirping, cawing)
(low chittering in distance)
(chittering continues)
(low growling in distance)
(Blake breathing heavily)
(chittering continues)
(shuddered breathing)
You know you need
to stay near me.
Right fucking next to me, boy!
If you don't do what I say,
you get hurt.
Do you want to get hurt?! Huh?
Do you want to get hurt?!
No, sir, I don't. I just...
I wanted to get a better shot
at the deer.
(rustling, chittering)
(chittering continues)
(twigs cracking, rustling)
(low snarling)
Get up in that deer blind.
Now.
(thunder rumbling)
♪ ♪
(bellowing roar)
(heavy footfalls approaching)
(rustling)
♪ ♪
(low grunting nearby)
Cover your ears.
(wood creaking)
(ladder thuds)
(low growling)
(low snarling)
(wood creaking)
(raspy breathing)
(shuddered breathing)
(low snarling)
(loud banging)
(scratching)
(banging)
(low snarling)
(distant thunder rumbling)
(high-pitched trilling
in distance)
(low snarling)
- (heavy thud)
- (snarling)
- (running footfalls)
- (roaring)
(impact grunting)
(thudding)
(thunder rumbling)
(rustling)
(birds chirping)
(shuddered breathing)
- (roaring)
- (gunshot echoing)
(Grady whimpering)
(distant howling)
(howl echoing)
(howling fades)
What was it, Dad?
A bear.
They're all over
this side of the valley.
Pick yourself up, and let's go
while there's still
some light left.
(insects trilling)
(motor chugging
and squeaking rhythmically)
(radio static crackling)
GRADY:
Kiel 714, this is Lovell 819.
(static crackling)
Do you read me?
(clicks switch, static stops)
Where in the hell are you, Dan?
(static crackling)
DAN (over radio):
What is it, Grady?
GRADY:
Dan.
I saw it.
DAN:
Saw what?
GRADY:
You know what I'm talking about.
DAN:
That hiker?
The face of the wolf?
(Grady sighs heavily)
GRADY:
Dan, it's real.
I had it in my scope.
I almost shot it.
(static crackling)
DAN:
Grady, what is the point
in going up that mountain
after dark
looking for something
that doesn't want to be found?
GRADY:
I wasn't looking for it.
I was hunting deer
down by the river.
And it came after my boy.
I'm gonna get it, Dan.
And you got to come with me.
Don't you want
to keep your boy safe?
(static crackling)
(clattering)
(footfalls running up stairs)
♪ ♪
- (siren chirping)
- (jackhammer rattling)
Can we get some ice cream?
Please? Please, please, please,
please, please, please...
I got you a hot chocolate
at the museum.
That's not a dessert.
That's a drink.
Oh, I think it's dessert, missy.
Well, did you know you're
the best dad in the whole world?
(laughs) Yeah,
I'm sure the timing of that
has nothing to do
with the ice cream.
It doesn't.
I just wanted to tell you.
I'm serious.
Eh, this feels
very transactional.
I don't know what that means.
Hey, get down.
Ginger.
Get down right now.
Okay, that's it, no ice cream
in three, two, one.
No, the dog don't jump off
the motherfucking leash!
- Hey, hey, hey.
- (man grunts)
I told you to get down.
Why didn't you listen to me,
damn it?
Why didn't you listen to me?
(Ginger's breath trembling)
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry I lost my temper.
That's not me.
I don't want to be like that.
I just need you to listen
when I tell you something.
'Cause what's my job?
To keep your daughter safe.
Yeah. That's right.
And what's your job?
(sighs)
To read minds.
Can you guess what I'm thinking
right now?
"I love my little girl."
That's amazing.
That's exactly
what I was thinking.
How do you do that every time?
You're so good at your job.
(kissing)
Okay.
I'm sorry. You scared me, okay?
- You owe me a dollar.
- Why?
Because you sweared.
No, I didn't.
You're hearing things.
I'm not, Daddy. You sweared.
(slow jazz music playing
in distance)
(jazz music continues)
Okay, now let me put
some on you.
Oh, my God. Okay, do it quickly.
- Beautiful.
- Mm-hmm. Good?
- Yeah.
- How's this?
(laughing):
You look creepy.
You mean like this?
(laughing)
- You mean like this, Ginger?
- Dad.
- (barking, growling)
- (laughing)
No, uh, yeah. No, I get that.
BLAKE:
Okay, go sit at the table.
No, but I-I have,
I have a second source.
(man speaking indistinctly
over phone)
(whispers):
One minute.
Well, are you gonna ship it
or you gonna let the Times
scoop us again?
- (whispers): Hi.
- Hi, Mommy.
(man speaking indistinctly
over phone)
CHARLOTTE:
Well, so we have a deal then?
What-- This is bullshit.
You've never asked
for this before.
Uh, in the time it takes
to do all of this,
we could've gotten ahead
of everybody.
But I just don't think
we need to do it.
I promise from now on.
Can you just get it online?
- Take that in the other room.
- Shh.
(over phone):
I shouldn't be doing this.
Are you doing it or not?
Charlotte, can you take that
in the other room?
Listen, I-I know what I'm doing.
You know I know because
you taught me how to do it.
(over phone):
Goodbye, Charlotte.
Okay. Bye.
(sighs)
Can you, um...
Can you not do that, please?
What did I do?
I was having an important
conversation with my editor.
Yeah, 'cause you're the only one
that has important stuff
going on, right?
I'm not busy at all.
If I ever have kids, I'm never
gonna fight in front of them.
BLAKE:
We're not fighting, honey.
We're having
a spirited exchange.
BLAKE:
Okay.
So, um...
I just found out my dad has
been finally declared deceased.
Officially,
by the state of Oregon.
Um, I'm sorry.
It's okay.
How do you feel?
I mean, we knew this letter
was coming one day.
But the finality of it...
Yeah, I don't know,
it's still shocking.
Yeah.
Are you sad, Daddy?
(exhales)
I am, yeah.
I'm sad about a lot of things.
I wish I'd known him better.
But he always made me
afraid of him,
so as soon as I was old enough,
I left.
We hadn't spoken in a long time
because I chose not to.
Um, and now that
I can't speak to him...
...I suddenly want to.
(distant siren wailing)
CHARLOTTE:
The whole day.
No way. The whole thing
felt ridiculous, you know?
(chuckling)
Oh.
(Charlotte chuckles)
I'll catch up
with you guys later.
Yeah.
Hey.
This is a surprise.
I brought you some lunch.
Thank you.
We haven't done this in a while.
Yeah.
Are you happy, Charlotte?
Are-are you?
Why-why are you asking me that?
Because I don't think
we're doing well right now.
I came here because
when I got that letter...
...it dawned on me
that you and Ginger are the
only family that I have left.
We have such a short amount
of time with people.
I just want us
to enjoy each other
and try to be happy as a family
while we are here.
I want to be happy, too, but...
(sighs)
I was thinking you should
come up to Oregon with me.
I have to go up there
and pack up all my dad's stuff
in a truck.
Why don't we all go together?
We'd spend the whole summer
up there.
I think it'd be good for us.
It really is stunning.
There's this valley
not far from the farm.
It's between these mountains.
And no matter
how many times you see it,
the view makes you feel like
everything's gonna be okay.
I want you and Ginger to see it.
It sounds nice,
but I can't just leave work.
No, yeah,
but you can work remotely.
Just take some time off.
Ginger would love that.
You could spend some time
with her.
You can work on your book.
Yeah, I don't...
I don't even know
if I'm good at that anymore.
You're a great writer. Come on.
I meant at spending time
with my daughter.
(breathes deeply)
She...
She relates to you
so much more than me.
(sniffles)
♪ ♪
BLAKE:
You are an incredible mother.
You are.
(wind blowing)
Come with me.
(wind whistling)
♪ ♪
Okay, okay, I've got one.
Mm, do you live in water?
Nope.
Okay.
Do you live in the forest?
Sometimes.
CHARLOTTE:
Mm, can you fly?
Nope.
Do you walk on four legs?
- Yes.
- BLAKE: Yeah?
Oh, are you a deer?
Uh... no.
(funny accent):
Uh, are you a bear?
No.
(funny accent):
Are you a dog?
- (Charlotte and Ginger laugh)
- GINGER: No.
BLAKE:
No. I just don't know what...
Don't know the answer.
- No, I'm a fawn.
- A fawn?
- Yeah.
- I said deer.
- A fawn is not a deer.
- CHARLOTTE: It's-it's...
- It's not. -What?
It's literally a baby deer.
GINGER:
It's not.
And fawns live in the forest.
Hello.
They do sometimes, but sometimes
they're in people's
backyards, so...
- CHARLOTTE: Oh. Oh.
- BLAKE: What? That's...
Oh, you are a cheater.
You know what?
- That's it. You know what's
coming? -Don't, Daddy. Stop.
- Daddy, stop. No, Mommy.
- CHARLOTTE: Uh-oh. Uh-oh.
- Tell Daddy he's being immature.
- Uh-oh.
Hey, hey, I can be
just as immature as he can.
Mommy, stop it. Stop, Mommy.
CHARLOTTE: What makes you think
I'm so mature?
- Huh? Huh?
- GINGER: Stop it, Mommy. Stop.
Please, Mommy, stop it.
- Mommy, stop it.
- CHARLOTTE: Please?
- (turns off engine)
- GINGER: Please, Mommy, stop.
(Charlotte and Ginger laughing)
Wait, is this it? Shit.
- Dad.
- Sorry, honey. Shivers.
Let me check the map here.
I have no service.
Me, either.
(breathes deeply)
This does look familiar, though.
(bird chirping)
CHARLOTTE:
Can I see?
There's someone
in that tree house.
Where?
GINGER:
Over there.
She's right-- there's someone
inside that thing.
BLAKE:
Oh.
Uh, let's go, Blake.
BLAKE:
No, it's okay.
No, he has a gun.
Charlotte,
everyone around here has a gun.
Blake, can-can you just
please drive?
- MAN: Evening.
- BLAKE: Hey.
Where you guys headed?
Uh, I'm looking
for my dad's farm.
I just, I haven't been up here
in a while. I forgot...
Who's your dad?
Uh... Grady.
Lovell.
You've been gone
a long time, Blake.
Wait, do I... do I know you?
(man chuckles)
I'm Derek. I'm Dan Kiel's son.
Right.
Oh, Derek. Shit.
- GINGER: Dad.
- Oh, sorry.
BLAKE:
Yeah, no, I remember you.
How are you?
It's good to see you.
Not many of us left
living up here anymore.
(Blake and Derek laugh)
Not really a part of the world.
Yeah. I-I'd agree with that.
You might not remember this,
but, uh, for the most part,
we don't like to be out
after dark on the mountain.
There's no power grid,
no lights.
BLAKE: Oh. I-I thought
that was just my dad.
Uh, you know, I'm actually
a little lost.
You know, I-I was sure
that this was his driveway.
It's not.
Really?
It's mine.
Oh.
Yeah, okay.
Well, sorry.
The usual road to Grady's
is cut off.
I'll take you there,
get you settled in quicker.
(Derek sniffles)
Okay.
(footfalls)
Blake, no. No, absolutely not.
- It's fine. Let him show us.
- No, he...
Why can't he just
tell us where it is?
- He's standing there now.
- What, so...
- Just open the door, Char.
- What are you talk...
- He's opening it.
- Well, stop...
(laughs nervously):
Hi. Hi.
(laughs nervously)
Hi. Uh, no, no, no.
It's okay.
I-I'll just go to the back.
Thank you, ma'am.
- Watch your feet.
- (door closes)
- Just go straight on a ways.
Hey there, cutie.
BLAKE: Uh, Derek, that's Ginger
and my wife Charlotte.
Hi.
(engine starting)
(insects chirring)
How long you planning
on staying?
- CHARLOTTE: Not too long.
- BLAKE: A little while.
It's definitely
an acquired taste.
There are things you have to
come to terms with up here.
Animals.
Diseases.
Well, we're,
we're pretty tough people.
Is that so?
To me, you don't seem so tough.
That's a good thing.
Means you got a good life.
You're healthy, safe.
Your dad's place
is just up ahead.
What do you do
for a living, Blake?
I'm a writer.
I'm between jobs
right now, though.
So... I'm a dad
to that monster in the back.
(laughs softly)
I'm a journalist.
I bet you look at them every day
and wonder how you got so lucky
to have such a smart
and beautiful family.
I do.
- (tires screeching)
- Shit.
(Charlotte screaming)
(tree crashing)
(metallic creaking)
(muffled groaning)
(Charlotte panting, whimpering)
Oh.
- Oh.
- (Ginger whimpering)
Ginger? Are you okay?
GINGER:
I'm okay.
Char, are you okay?
- Hey, are you hurt anywhere?
- (loud crashing)
Are you okay? Ginger?
Charlotte, are you hurt?
- CHARLOTTE: No.
- BLAKE: Huh?
- Derek, are you okay?
- (Derek wailing)
BLAKE:
Hey, hey, no, no, no, no!
(Charlotte and Ginger screaming)
Oh, shit!
Okay. We got to get
out of this thing.
Ginger. Ginger.
- GINGER: No, no, no.
- Ginger, look at me.
GINGER:
No, please. Please, no.
BLAKE: You got to climb
through the window.
Look at me, Ginger.
Climb through the window.
You can do it, honey.
GINGER: No, Daddy,
I'm scared I'm gonna fall.
- You'll be okay. You'll be okay.
- I'm gonna fall.
GINGER:
I'm gonna fall. I'm gonna fall.
BLAKE: It's okay.
Just get onto the top.
- (Charlotte whimpering)
- Just stay right there.
Just sit right there, honey.
(Charlotte whimpering, grunting)
Just stay there, honey.
Mommy's coming.
Charlotte, go.
(grunting)
BLAKE:
You okay?
Stay right there. I'm coming.
- I...
- (low chittering)
- (low snarling)
- (whimpering)
(panting)
(banging)
(banging continues)
(grunting)
- (banging)
- (low chittering)
(strained grunting)
(banging continues)
- (Derek groaning)
- (panting)
(groaning)
(chittering)
- (gasps)
- (Derek yells)
- (sharp slicing)
- (Derek screaming)
(snarling, chittering)
(gasping)
(grunting)
(metallic creaking)
(strained grunting)
(panting)
Okay.
(grunts)
We got to get down. Wait here.
Come on.
Ginger, honey, you have to go.
Come on. I'm gonna catch you.
(panting)
Okay. All right,
Charlotte, come on.
(whimpering)
(grunts)
Are you okay?
- No, yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
- Yeah?
Ginger, are you hurt at all?
- GINGER: No.
- BLAKE: Okay, come on.
We got to go.
We have to find the house.
Watch your step. Come on, honey.
- We got to move quick.
- (Ginger groans)
Where it's safer. Come on.
Careful, honey.
Careful, careful, careful.
- Daddy, I'm tired.
- What?
- I can't go.
- Okay.
(Blake and Ginger grunting)
Charlotte.
Okay, honey.
(Blake grunting)
CHARLOTTE:
Quick.
(all breathing heavily)
Come on, I recognize this.
We're close.
I'm gonna put you down here,
honey, okay?
- Okay.
- Give me your hand.
Come on.
- Come on.
- CHARLOTTE: Careful.
Be careful.
(panting)
Come on. Come on.
BLAKE:
This is it.
- (loud rustling)
- (gasping)
- Run.
- (snarling)
- (panting)
- Run, honey.
Go, honey.
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
- (snarling)
- (running footfalls)
- (whimpering, shrieking)
- Daddy, hurry up.
- Daddy, hurry up!
- (breathy huffing)
Come on. Get inside.
(whimpering, panting)
(loud banging)
(vicious snarling)
(banging continues)
(Blake straining)
(low snarling)
- (panting)
- (raspy breathing)
Wait. Wait.
(Blake panting)
(breath trembling)
(stifled sobbing)
- Stay right here.
- Daddy, where are you going?
- I'll be right back.
- Daddy. Daddy.
- Stay with Mommy.
- Daddy.
(Ginger crying)
(breathing heavily)
(lock clicking)
(rattling)
(breathing heavily)
♪ ♪
Okay.
(rattling)
(door opens)
(breathing heavily)
(lever creaking)
Shit.
(motor sputtering)
(motor chugging
and squeaking rhythmically)
(chugging and squeaking
continue)
(electrical crackling)
(both gasp)
(power whirring on)
Daddy.
BLAKE:
Hi.
Mm. It's okay.
We're safe.
I want to go home.
I know.
We will.
We just can't go outside
right now. Lay down.
We just have to wait
until the morning.
Okay?
(insects chirring)
(Blake breathing heavily)
(gasps)
No, don't go anywhere.
(shushing)
Okay, okay. I'm here.
I'm not going anywhere.
I'm gonna be right here.
Right here.
Is that man dead?
The man who came out
the tree house?
I don't know.
Most likely, he did die.
I'm so sorry that
this happened to you.
It's my job to protect you.
And I didn't.
I've put you through
something very scary.
And I'd never be able
to forgive myself
if this stayed with you.
You know? If it scarred you.
You know, sometimes
when you're a daddy,
you're so scared
of your kids getting scars,
you become the thing
that scars 'em.
(laughs softly)
Hey, what am I thinking
right now?
"I love my little girl."
That's incredible.
You must be able to read minds,
because that's exactly
what I was thinking.
Word for word.
Okay.
I love you.
I'll be right here.
Remember, that's my job.
I'm not gonna let anything
happen to you.
I think we should, um...
I think we should
cover the front door,
'cause if that thing...
if it keeps trying to get in,
the whole door can come off
the hinges.
What was it?
What?
What the fuck
was that thing, Blake?
I don't know.
I know it sounded
like an animal...
but I looked right at it
when we almost hit it,
and I swear to God
it was standing up on two feet,
like a person.
(Blake breathing heavily)
Blake.
Is that gonna hold?
Maybe.
I think we should try
to call somebody for help.
How?
♪ ♪
(static crackling)
(switch clicks, low screeching)
Hello? Test.
(static crackling)
Hello. This is Lovell 819.
Can anyone hear me?
Hello?
Hell...
(sniffing)
(clicks off radio)
Jesus, what is that smell?
Hmm? What? What'd you say?
(sniffing)
(door clatters open)
(switch clicks, light buzzing)
(switch clicking)
Hello?
(light buzzing)
(sniffs)
Well, I found something to eat.
My dad's jerky.
- (crunching)
- (groans)
My jaw. I must've hit it
on the steering wheel.
Oh, fuck.
(Blake moans)
(Charlotte breathing rapidly)
Here. Here.
CHARLOTTE:
Oh, my God.
Okay. Come on. Sit down.
- Just sit. It's okay.
- (moans)
- Just lift your arm.
- (grunts)
God.
I think I cut it
on the window in the truck.
CHARLOTTE:
I-I don't... I don't know.
This doesn't look
like you got cut by glass.
Okay. Okay. Um...
Lift your arm up.
All right, j-just try
a little bit. Just try.
(Charlotte sniffles)
- (Blake grunts)
- (sniffles)
(sighs)
Thank you.
Keep trying the CB radio for me.
Okay?
(pained grunt)
♪ ♪
(insects chirping)
Jesus, Ginger.
I'm sorry I woke you, honey.
Just go back to bed, okay?
You need to get your rest.
Ginger.
Will you listen to me, please?
Go back to bed.
It's almost midnight.
Hey.
Did you reach anyone on the CB?
I-I don't...
(sets down tool)
I'll be done in a minute.
(mumbling):
How odd.
(hammering in other room)
(wood clattering)
(Blake grunting)
(breathing heavily)
(flesh squishes)
(hammer clatters to floor)
Ow.
(breathing heavily)
(water rushing)
(Blake gulping)
(panting)
(faucet squeaks, water stops)
(distant thumping)
(insects chirping)
(low moaning)
(thumping continues)
(thumping, moaning)
(thumping)
(thumping grows louder)
(low growling)
(clattering)
(thumping)
(breathing heavily)
(door creaking)
(insects chirping)
- (low moaning)
- (thumping)
(thumping)
(thumping continues)
♪ ♪
(hyperventilating)
(distant howling)
(insects chirping)
(approaching footfalls)
(whispering indistinctly)
Shh.
(footfalls continue)
(low snarling outside)
(sniffing)
(low snarling continues)
(low snarling)
(footfalls continue)
(footfalls stop)
(sniffing)
(gasps)
- Charlotte. (screaming)
- Blake. Blake.
- (screaming)
- (snarling)
- (whimpers) Blake.
- (grunting)
- (screeching)
- (Charlotte yelling)
Mommy.
- (shrieking)
- Mommy.
- Get back! Get back!
- Mommy. Mommy.
- Get back!
- (pained grunting)
(pained grunting)
(muffled):
Blake. Blake.
(stifled, pained yelling)
(Charlotte's speech distorted)
(pained yelling)
- (gasping)
- (distorted speech continues)
(distorted speech echoes)
(gasps, breathing rapidly)
(clock ticking)
(grunts)
(insects chirping)
- (clock continues ticking)
- (floorboards creaking)
(breathy):
Char?
(Charlotte speaking indistinctly
in distance)
(breathing heavily)
(Charlotte continues
speaking indistinctly)
(Charlotte's speech distorted)
(distorted speech continues)
(distorted):
Can you read me?
(speech continues indistinctly,
distorted)
(distorted):
Can anybody hear?
Hello?
(distorted speech continues)
(clearer):
Can anybody hear me?
This is Charlotte Lovell.
If someone can hear me,
please respond.
(clearly):
My-my husband is, uh, sick.
Um, if-if anyone can, uh,
can hear me, uh,
pl-please call someone to help.
We were attacked
by some kind of animal,
and I-I think my, um, husband
was infected by it.
He's...
(crying):
He's not himself,
and, um, he can't,
he can't talk, um...
Yeah, uh, he doesn't,
he doesn't seem to know
he's sick, but, um...
i-if someone can hear
what I'm saying, please help.
Uh, hello?
(static crackling)
Hello?
Goddamn it!
(sniffles, sighs)
- (Blake wheezes softly)
- (gasps)
♪ ♪
(shuddered breathing)
(breathy grunting)
(wheezing softly)
♪ ♪
(speaking indistinctly)
(breathing shakily)
(quietly):
I'm so worried about you.
I don't know what to do.
(liquid trickling)
(whispering):
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Come on.
Let's get you upstairs.
Come on.
(insects chirping)
♪ ♪
(rustling in other room)
(breathing shakily)
Here. Can you, um...
Can you write it down?
Just tell me what's wrong.
(grunts)
♪ ♪
CHARLOTTE:
No.
You're sick-- that's all--
but we're gonna fix you.
Blake...
You're gonna get better,
because Ginger needs you.
I need you.
I can't do this without you.
What I-I really
want to say is...
...is that...
is that I love you, Blake.
I don't want to do anything
in my life without you.
You're my best friend.
I love you so much.
(speaking indistinctly,
distorted)
(continues distorted)
Ch-Charlotte...
What is happening?
I can't understand you.
(distorted):
What... what are you saying?
(continues indistinctly)
(sniffles)
GINGER:
What's wrong with him?
Hi.
It's okay.
Come here.
Daddy's not feeling well,
but in the morning,
we're gonna take him to the
doctor as soon as we can, okay?
Are you sick, Dada?
(breathy whispering)
What is this?
Why are you bleeding?
GINGER:
Why is Daddy's arm like that?
- Ginger, um...
- Help him, Mommy.
Baby, go to the next room, okay?
CHARLOTTE (gasps):
Oh, my God.
(inhales)
- (grunting)
- (Charlotte gasping)
(low growling)
- (snarling)
- (gasping)
(breathing rapidly)
- (munching)
- (gasping)
(munching)
(low growling)
(munching continues)
(gasping)
♪ ♪
(whispering):
Blake.
(breathing heavily)
♪ ♪
Mommy?
(screen creaking)
(insects chirping)
(shuddered breathing)
(whispering):
Okay, come on. Come on.
Out. Just come out. It's okay.
It's okay, it's okay.
This way, honey.
Okay, come on. Come on.
(door creaking)
(insects chirping)
(grunting)
- Mommy, what if he...
- (shushing)
(distant howling)
- (door clicks shut)
- (breathing rapidly)
(muffled grunting)
(Ginger breathing rapidly)
(creaking)
(breathing gruffly)
(whimpers)
(keys jingling)
(breathing heavily)
(engine whirring)
(whirring stops)
Come on. Come on.
- (engine whirring)
- Come on.
(engine chugging, revving)
Oh, my God.
(engine idling)
(grunts)
(breathing rapidly)
(breathlessly):
Okay, okay.
Okay.
(snarling)
(screaming)
(growling)
(screaming continues)
(engine revving)
- (screaming)
- (knife slicing)
♪ ♪
- (snarling)
- (Ginger screaming)
GINGER:
Mommy, he's coming.
CHARLOTTE:
Up here.
Quick. Climb up here.
(snarling)
(roaring)
(panting, whimpering)
(growling continues)
(Ginger panting)
- CHARLOTTE: Stay still.
- (footfalls)
(low growling)
(growling continues)
(whimpering)
(creaking)
- (hyperventilating)
- (metallic pinging)
(snarling)
- (snarling)
- (screaming)
(breathy snarling)
- (snarling)
- (gasping)
Mommy, please.
Mommy, please, I'm gonna fall.
(plastic creaking)
(snarling)
(panting)
- (snarling)
- (screaming)
(screaming)
(snarling)
(screaming, shouting)
(hyperventilating)
(breathy grunting)
(grunting)
(Blake huffing)
(snarling)
(running footfalls)
- (grunting)
- Come on.
♪ ♪
(panting)
(growling in distance)
(growling continues)
(vicious snarling)
(yelping)
(growling continues)
(door slams shut)
- You left him.
- What?
You left Daddy outside.
He's gonna get hurt.
- He's gonna die! You just left
him outside to die! -No. No.
No, he was trying
to protect you.
(rustling outside)
(low growling, huffing)
(whispering):
Stay here.
Is it Daddy?
(breathing shakily)
- GINGER: He's sick.
- (Blake breathing heavily)
He needs us.
Open the door, Mommy.
(door creaking)
(creaking)
(Blake breathing heavily)
- (breathy grunting)
- (heavy footfalls)
(breathy grunting continues)
- (Ginger gasps)
- (clattering in other room)
(footfalls stop)
(Blake breathing low, raspy)
♪ ♪
(raspy breathing continues)
Daddy?
(breathy grunting)
♪ ♪
(raspy breathing continues)
(snarls)
(low groaning)
Daddy?
Daddy...
what am I thinking right now?
What am I thinking?
(breathy grunting)
(distorted):
I was thinking that I love you.
(continues distorted)
(distorted):
Daddy?
Dad? Dad, can you hear me?
(breathy grunting)
(clearer):
Daddy? Daddy, are you okay?
(clearly):
I love you so much.
(gulping)
(grunting)
(cracking)
- (screaming) -Come on. Come on.
Get up. Get up. Get up.
Come on. Come on.
(Ginger hyperventilating)
(breathy growl)
- Daddy.
- (snarls)
(growls)
(Ginger screams)
(low growling)
(crying)
♪ ♪
(raspy breathing)
(breathing shakily)
(growling)
(Blake yowling)
(grunting)
(growling)
(roaring)
(bellowing)
(screaming)
Get in. Get in.
- Get in.
- Mommy!
(snarling)
(gasping)
(growling)
(yowls)
(breathing heavily)
(snarls)
GINGER:
Mommy!
(grunting)
(low snarling)
(Blake roaring)
(screeching)
(wet crunching)
(growling)
(breathing heavily)
(low gasping)
(spitting)
(breathy growl)
♪ ♪
(breathing heavily)
(Charlotte gasping)
GINGER (muffled):
Mommy!
(Ginger panting)
(door opens)
(door closes)
(Ginger crying)
♪ ♪
(low snarling)
(breathy grunting)
(bones crunching)
(groaning)
(howling)
(raspy breathing)
(bones crunching)
(sharp cracking)
(low growling)
(breathy grunting)
(chittering)
(high-pitched chirping)
(distorted animal sounds)
(Blake howling)
(howling fades)
(insects chirping)
Mommy?
Why did Daddy have to get sick?
Um...
Daddy's father...
A while ago, he went out...
into the forest,
and he never came back.
Everybody thought
he was dead, but...
I think he just got sick.
Sick like Daddy?
Yeah.
I think he may have...
given his sickness to Daddy.
I want him back the way he was.
I know. Me, too, honey.
I-I want him back, too.
I'm always going
to be here for you.
(Ginger crying)
(gasps)
No. Mommy.
Mommy.
♪ ♪
(muffled, breathy grunting)
(low growling)
(growling)
- (thumping)
- (both gasping)
(thumping)
(thumping, clattering)
(crashing, glass shattering)
(footfalls)
(breathing shakily)
- (wood creaking)
- (gasps)
♪ ♪
(whispering):
It's okay.
(breathing shakily)
- (growling)
- (screaming)
(Charlotte and Ginger screaming)
Get back! Get back! Get back!
- (snarling)
- (screaming continues)
Please, Daddy,
you're scaring me.
- (low growling)
- CHARLOTTE: No.
(yowls)
CHARLOTTE:
No. No.
Mommy.
- (breathing heavily)
- (Blake growling)
(snarling)
In here. Come.
(panting, grunting)
(breathing heavily)
(wind howling)
(wood creaking)
(rattling)
(scurrying outside)
(door clattering)
(thumping)
(low snarling)
(crashing)
(crashing stops)
(wood creaking)
♪ ♪
(airy whooshing)
(whooshing fades)
- (trap clanks shut)
- (Blake yowling)
- (snarling)
- (screaming)
(screaming)
(roaring)
(both breathing heavily)
(snarling)
(howling)
(grunting)
(growling gruffly)
(howling)
Come on. Come on.
(munching)
(panting)
(low growling)
(strained grunting)
(grunting)
(panting)
(growling)
(panting gruffly)
♪ ♪
(growling)
(growling gruffly)
(roaring)
(roar echoing)
(roaring fades)
(insects chirping)
(Ginger gasping)
♪ ♪
(snarling in distance)
(Charlotte gasping)
Hurry, Mommy. He's coming.
Here. Just hold this.
Take it.
(clattering)
(snarling)
(breathing rapidly)
Come on. Come on.
(growling in distance)
(breathing rapidly)
All right. All right.
Come on. Come on.
(roaring in distance)
♪ ♪
(snarling)
(panting)
♪ ♪
- (clattering)
- (gasps)
(thumping, wood creaking)
(snarling)
(breathing gruffly)
(thumping)
(Ginger gasping)
(low snarling)
(growling)
(breathing heavily)
(breathy grunting)
♪ ♪
Mommy.
He wants this to be over.
(low growling)
- (snarling)
- (gunshot echoing)
(body thuds)
(Ginger crying)
(both crying)
(grunting gruffly)
(footfalls approaching)
♪ ♪
(Ginger crying)
(breathy grunting)
(birds chirping)
(low, raspy breathing)
(breathing stops)
(sniffles)
(whispering):
Oh, Blake.
(both crying)
I'm here. I'm here.
(crying continues)
♪ ♪
- (distant howling)
- (insects chirring)
("In Red and Blue" by Adalita
and Raul Sánchez playing)
♪ Like a shot through the dark ♪
♪ Like an arrow to my heart ♪
♪ Somewhere in your eyes ♪
♪ There's a little smoke
and flame ♪
♪ I saw you change ♪
♪ And I had
to rearrange it, baby ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Remember us in cars,
dirty bars and dirty hearts ♪
♪ The time it takes to burn ♪
♪ I couldn't even start
to think we'd be apart ♪
♪ Or a life lived in reverse ♪
♪ 'Cause somewhere
back in time ♪
♪ When you and love were mine ♪
- ♪ 'Cause I saw you change ♪
- ♪ Change ♪
♪ And I had
to rearrange it, baby ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ I saw you change ♪
♪ You felt no pain ♪
♪ When you and love were mine ♪
♪ ♪
- ♪ I saw you change ♪
- ♪ Change ♪
♪ Change ♪
♪ And I had
to rearrange it, baby ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ I saw you change ♪
- ♪ You felt no pain ♪
- ♪ Pain ♪
♪ When you and love were mine ♪
♪ And I'll see you again
in red and blue ♪
♪ And I'll say it again,
and I'll say it true ♪
♪ And I'll see you again ♪
♪ In red and blue. ♪
(song ends)
♪ ♪
(music fades)