Billy?
Get number three up now.
And don't come in to eat
before you do.
And check the other two!
Make sure they're wired up good!
I don't want 'em blowing over
again at the first big wind.
Lot of good they're doing.
Billy, you been messing
with the post-puncher?
No!
I told you what would happen...
if you screw around
with this thing.
I said I didn't!
"l don't want 'em
blowin' down again."
Big wind, my ass.
You're the only big wind
out here.
Jacky!
You been messing with the damn
post-puncher again, huh?
No.
Billy, you little asshole!
Why don't you rat yourself out
for a change?
-What did I do?
-You little butt sniff!
I ought to come out there
and kick your ass!
You wish!
Yeah, go on, Mac. Go bite him
in the ass for me, Mackie boy.
God, would you shut up?
Jacky!
-What?
-I don't know.
What?
Help!
Billy!
Help! Help!
Where are you? Billy!
Daddy!
Billy!
Let go! Help me, dad!
-Billy!
-Help! Help! Help!
-Help! Dad! Help me!
Billy!
Stop it! Let go!
-Billy!
-Daddy!
Billy!
Help!
Bannon Bantams! Bannon Bantams!
-Go!
-Louder!
Go Bantams! Yeah! Whoo! Yeah!
Tough as nails, hard as rocks!
We are Bannon's fighting cocks!
Fighting Bantams,
tough as nails!
Bow down now or kiss our tails!
Out for blood,
we're lean and mean!
Bannon County's death machine!
Bannon Bantams! Bannon Bantams!
Go Bantams!
Bannon Bantams, power and might!
Bannon Bantams,
fight, fight, fight!
Incoming!
Bannon Bantams, we're the word!
You don't mess
with a mighty bird!
Down the court
we'll clean your clock!
Better not mess
with the fighting cock!
Bannon Bantams, Bannon Bantams!
Go Bantams!
Bannon Bantams, wings of steel!
Bannon Bantams,
kill, kill, kill!
Who was that? Don't even ask!
Big bad Bantams kick your ass!
Bannon Bantams, Bannon Bantams!
Go Bantams!
Go!
We are the champs!
Tough as nails, hard as rocks!
We are Bannon's fighting cocks!
How long can they keep this up?
Forever. They have a fight song
with the word "cock" in it.
Why aren't you sitting
with your honey?
Bannon County's death machine!
Someone should tell him he just
won the state championship.
I have a feeling
he didn't get to play enough.
Well, shouldn't you be
sitting with him?
After a game, he says
he needs to be with the guys.
You'd kill
his post-game bus high.
Basically. If they lose,
it's a totally different thing.
Can't pry him off me.
Shit.
OK, everybody sit down.
Sit tight.
Son of a bitch!
What in the hell
would you call that?
I don't know,
but whatever it is...
it's sharp as a son of a bitch.
What in the hell
are we looking at?
Sharp enough to flatten a tire,
whatever it is.
You know how thick
that rubber is?
Have to be shot into it
like a bullet.
Jesus Christ! The damn thing
has got teeth in it!
They can't just whip the jack
out and pump this mother up?
The driver can't change a flat
on a bus.
-They need a mechanic.
-So?
So, do you see
any mechanics around here?
You sucked so bad today,
Deaundre...
they're probably saying
you gotta change the flat.
...where she'll
give us the latest update...
-lzzy!
-on a continuing story...
we call
"The Horror in Poho County."
Hey, Poho update!
Well, Peter,
the fire which gutted...
an old church south
of Pertwilla four days ago...
continues to offer up
a gruesome bounty.
County sheriffs
excavating the charred ruins...
say the body count is now up
well past three hundred.
County coroners
say the bodies were found...
stitched to each other...
covering the basement's
walls and ceiling.
One on-the-scene witness
called it...
"a human tapestry
of torture and sadism"...
and "a sight
he will never forget."
Sheila,
the details keep getting...
stranger and stranger
every day this week, it seems.
Any new information?
Some of the corpses
they have found...
had false teeth
made out of wood.
That means some of the bodies
they're finding down there...
are over two hundred years old.
But, Peter, it's
the condition of the cadavers...
that's
the strangest fact of all.
The county coroner's office
reported yesterday...
that they have yet to find
any one complete body.
-Believe that, man?
-No, they're making it up.
...missing an external limb
or an internal organ.
What connection this has--
This is 226, out on east 9.
We are down and disabled.
Home base, do you read me?
You get a good look
at the points on this thing?
It's either ivory
or some kind of bone.
Throw that damn thing away
before you need a tetanus shot.
This is Betty Gorman out on 226.
We are down and disabled
out on east 9.
Pop!
Pop, it dropped something!
Pop?
It was out in the corn, papa.
Here, look at it.
We are out on east 9. We are
down and disabled. Come back.
-What about Kimball, man?
-Say again.
This is 226. Anyone read me?
We are down and disabled
out on east 9. Come back.
We gotta be in some kind of
sun spot or something.
There's no signal getting out.
It's going to be dark
in about an hour.
Well, we still got five tires
on the ground which means...
we can probably limp home
if we keep the going slow.
Say again, this is 226.
Anyone read me?
All of you at the same time?
Lady cheerleaders!
That's not smoke I smell,
is it?
Minxie...
there's not a girl
in the world these days...
stupid enough
to kill themselves...
by sucking on cancer sticks,
am I right?
Back on the bus, ladies.
You saw me, right?
Run that fast break? Huh?
You see that?
-Yeah, I saw it.
-Anybody gonna read about it?
Why do you give ol' Dante
back there so much ink, huh?
I'm serious.
People are starting to think
that you're sweet on him.
Really? I heard that was you.
Hey, it's OK if you are, man.
I mean,
live and let love, right?
Why don't you piss
on somebody else's shoes, Jake?
Shouldn't you be
folding towels somewhere...
or sniffing jockstraps?
You think you can manage
the team, super genius?
Was I even talking to you,
jockstrap boy?
Hey, eat shit, Jake! God!
So this is all because, what,
I don't write enough about you?
You know what the story is
on your scars there, right?
No, tell me.
Got into a fight
when you snuck into a bar.
So?
A gay bar, bro.
You do know what they call you,
don't you, lzzy?
That's my name.
"Or isn't he?"
Hey, let's not make this...
a social event out there,
everybody.
Back on the bus, gentlemen.
We're moving!
Big K,
does that come in a man size?
That means you, too, Kimball!
Let's go!
Smooth move, Big K! Nice, man!
Tippi Hedren, man!
Kimball!
Stop clowning around...
and get your ass
back on the bus!
Off the top, gentlemen.
Assholes and elbows. Let's go.
Damn!
You know,
you could talk about it.
It might help a little bit.
What did I play today,
twelve minutes?
Well, it was
a great twelve minutes.
Hanna's got it in for me--
him and his little
token white boy Barnes.
I don't know...
maybe I got the wrong skin color
to get equal play on this team.
I know you don't mean that.
Maybe they just wanted
to make sure...
everyone got a chance to play
in the championship.
Everyone's not the reason why
we made it to the championship.
Half the losers on this bus
had nothing to do with...
us making it to state--I did.
What the fuck
are you looking at?
Oh, Jesus Christ!
Aw, don'ttell me.
-We blew the other one.
-How?
Back down, everybody. Sit tight.
Shit. We better
break out the flares...
and get these kids off the bus.
Hey, hey, hey!
You want to sit in here
and hope somebody doesn't...
come along, plowing into us
doing ninety, huh?
All right, Duane...
you clear the bus,
I'll set the flares.
What is that, a flare gun?
You plan on being lost at sea
in this thing?
You making fun of my lockbox?
'Cause everything
in this thing...
has saved my sweet ass
at least once.
Oh, I don't believe it.
All right, bring your coats
and stay in a group.
This is Betty Borman,
out on 226.
We're broke down on east 9...
middle of Kissel County.
Anyone read me?
Want me to help you push it
off the road before I go?
I don't think we can move it.
It's on a bare rim in the back.
If you'd let the highway patrol
know, we'd appreciate it.
Sure.
Come on, guys.
Come on, let's go. Off the road.
Everyone on the shoulder.
Everyone stays in a group.
Over by the side of the fence.
Scott, come on!
Everyone stays back
and off the road! Now!
Stuck in the side
of the tire again.
Oh, God. Don't tell me...
that's a belly button
in the middle of that thing.
Minxie, stay off the road.
Everybody, off the road!
Get everyone back on the bus.
-You just said they shouldn't--
-I know what I just said...
but there's something going on
out here, and I don't like it.
I think if we just st--
Coach?
What the f...
Where the hell's the coach?
Charlie?
Charlie!
Get everyone back inside
and close the doors.
OK, champions,
getting back on the Betty Boop.
Bucky, get on the two-way,
see if you can raise anyone.
-I'm talking to you, Scotty!
-What happened to the coach?
Get everyone back onboard
and close those doors.
Do it, Scotty.
All right, you heard him.
Assholes and elbows.
Everybody back on the bus.
Charlie?
Hurry up!
On the bus! Now, now, now!
I repeat, bus number 226...
Charlie!
We have an emergency situation
out here.
Does anybody read me?
This is bus number 226.
We are broke down on east 9.
Jake...
What happened?
-What did you see?
Come on!
Did you see something or not?
She flew away.
What the fuck
is that supposed to mean?
-What I just said!
-People don't fly away!
Sit down, Scott!
What the hell's going on
out there?
I said sit the fuck down
and shut up, god damn it! Now!
You, too, Jake. Everybody.
Go sit down, Scott.
-You got a problem with me?
-No. You got one with me?
-Do I what?
-You heard me.
We don't have time for bullshit,
Scotty. Go sit down!
Oh, God!
What the hell?
Scotty!
What the fuck?
Get the fucking doors!
What was it?
Scotty, what the fuck was it?
-Scotty, come on!
-Scotty, we just want to know.
I don't know what it was,
all right?
It had wings--
big fucking wings.
Central, this is unit 17.
We did a drive-by
in the general area.
Also found no evidence
of forced entry. Over.
0-3-2,
we're 10-7 at Opper's Diner...
for a little coffee and pie.
Copy that, central?
This is central.
Copy that, 0-3-6.
All units,
anybody else getting...
some weird stuff
out Kissel County way?
I just got two calls,
ten miles apart...
both reporting abductions.
All units,
be informed this should be...
strictly 10-36 information.
Someone burning a marijuana
field out there tonight?
'Cause these two stories
are way, way out.
Roger that, 3-6. Come back.
Jacky! Kissel County!
If you ask me,
this is Poho related.
Repeat--Poho related.
You all know
what I'm talking about.
This is Andy Buck.
Can anybody hear me?
Nobody's phone works.
Nobody's fucking phone works.
We are stuck
in a broken-down school bus...
out on east 9,
and we are in serious trouble.
Do you read me?
Fuck! Come on!
Is anybody even out there?
This is Andy Buck!
We're stuck in a broken-down
school bus out on east 9!
Javelins?
We've got spears on this bus?
Sticks.
You want to wait around...
so you can poke at that thing
with sticks?
That thing
shows up here again...
I'd rather have a sharp stick
in my hand than nothing at all.
Hey, guys! Betty's flare gun.
Abunch offlaresforit,too!
Who says we wait around?
I'm serious.
Scotty, you're not talking
about getting off this bus.
You see that?
That means
that there's a farm...
down at the end of this road
somewhere...
and that's as far as
anybody'd have to get to.
With that thing out there?
Scotty,
with that thing out there?
Scotty!
That thing hasn't been
back here in almost an hour.
That doesn't mean it's not
still up there somewhere.
And that doesn't mean
that it is.
Hey, this isn't about
who can run the fastest, OK?
-Or being a pussy.
-What is your problem?
-You tell me, lzzy or isn't he?
-Check yourselves, both of you!
Do I make you nervous?
Thinking you're going
to come onto me...
and every other swinging dick
on this bus makes me nervous.
Yeah, it makes you
fucking stupid, too!
Scotty, stop it!
Stop it!
Scotty, come on.
You get that hand off of me...
or we're gonna have one more
missing person out here.
There's nothing about
any of us on this bus...
that's more important
than sticking together.
It's the only way
we're going to get through this.
You want to play
cock of the walk now, huh?
Now's not the time
for this shit, Scotty.
-Big K, sit.
-I'm serious.
You want to play
cock of the walk, bro?
Why do I think you want
to call me something else?
You want to call me
something else, Scotty?
'Cause I don't think you get...
I can see you thinking it
whether you say it or not.
Just stop it right now.
Both of you, stop it!
You guys all worked together
today to win a ball game.
Now that something
really serious happens...
you can't even be civil
to each other?
You tell him, not me.
Whatever your trip is,
we ain't got time for this shit.
We should all be
looking for ways...
we can defend ourselves
until help gets here.
We have got to move
this piece of shit!
On what, the rim?
Can you drive this thing or not?
We wouldn't get two feet, man!
What do you want me to do?
What the hell does it want?
What the fuck?
Is it looking at me?
Whatever it is,
it's a smell freak, man.
Get that light off him.
Hey, don't shoot
that thing in here, man!
He's right. It'll fill this
place up like a smokebomb.
Holy shit!
Did that just come off the door?
Bucky, get on those front doors
and get ready to open them.
What, you think
we're gonna run outside?
If he fucking comes inside.
Oh, shit!
Oh, my God!
Minxie?
Is she OK?
Minxie. Minxie.
Minxie?
He eats everything.
-He knows no mercy.
-No one is safe.
Every 23rd spring,
for 23 days, it gets to eat.
Eat what?
Eat us.
Minx?
Are you OK?
Look at me.
I thought you were gone, girl.
You passed out. Look at me.
Are you OK?
Your eyes went all the way
in the back of your head.
I think he's gone, man.
I'm willing to bet money on it.
You willing to bet
stepping off this bus?
Because that's the real bet.
How long's it been?
It's gone. It came,
it did its thing, it went away.
It went away,
but what the hell was it doing?
What do you think it was doing?
It was picking people out.
What?
It can smell something
in people, in their fear--
something that helps it
pick people out.
Pick people out for what?
I don't understand how
you would know that, sweetie.
A dead boy told me.
I think
he was trying to warn me.
He was trying to warn
all of us...
that this thing has been around
for thousands of years...
and that nothing
has been able to kill it.
This is a dream you had?
Well, the boy was dead,
so, yes...
I am assuming
that it was a dream, Scotty.
You were waving pom-poms
at people this morning.
Now all of a sudden
you're a psychic hotline?
I don't know!
You want to explain it to me?
Because I can't.
The boy was trying to warn us...
that by morning it has
to go back into the earth.
Oh, come on.
Into the ground
for twenty-three more years.
And then what?
Lives happily ever after? Huh?
Why don't you clean out
your bong, all right?
Scotty, just listen to her.
It is coming back.
This is a dream she had, Rhonda.
Are you going to believe it?
And it doesn't matter
if we're hiding on this bus...
or if we're hiding
under our beds.
It'll find us--
the ones that it picked out.
Minx, take it easy, OK?
The boy told me that...
it can smell in our fear
who it wants...
and what from them...
it wants to eat.
Hello. Is anyone out there?
Hello. We have
a serious problem out here.
We need help right away.
Can anybody hear me?
Is anybody out there, please?
We have a--
This is Andy Buck.
We have a serious situation
out here.
Is anybody out there?
Does anybody hear me?
Dad!
Hello? Hello? Can you hear me?
-226, are you still there?
-I'm so fucking still here.
OK, OK. Just say again
what you just told me.
We're not playing games here,
right?
Just say it, man.
We are trapped in a broken-down
school bus out on east 9...
and something
is going to kill us...
if we don't get help
out here right away.
Where on 9 east?
In Kissel County.
Are you the cops?
What's trying to kill you?
What are you talking about?
Just tell me,
are you the fucking cops?
Look, now listen to me.
I'm already on the 9...
but it's a big highway
and so is Kissel County.
Are there any landmarks
near you?
Are you close to anything?
Yeah, I'm close to peeing
in my fucking pants, man.
Can you just please tell me
that you're on the way?
I can't really judge
the strength of your signal...
but it doesn't sound close.
What does that mean, man?
It means it's going to take me
a while to get to you.
Look, we kind of have
a time-critical situation here.
Roger that.
And please tell me that
you're coming with backup...
because
if you're not the cops...
you got to promise me
that you'll call them...
and you'll tell them
that we're stuck out here.
I'll call them.
I'll call them right now...
but what you've got to do
is hang on.
Can you do that? Hang on.
Keep headed east.
Dad?
Just get us out there.
Do it.
Yes!
It's fucking happening, man!
It's fucking happening!
We're being fucking rescued!
Help me! Get this thing off me!
Help! Help! Get this thing off!
Look out!
Half its fuckin' head's gone.
Fuck.
-You gotta be...
-Fucking kiddin' me.
Get that door open.
Now's our chance.
It's dead, right?
Don't know. Don't care.
It won't open!
Stop pushin' on 'em!
They open in!
Something got screwed up!
The door opens.
Maybe it only opens
from the outside.
It's an emergency exit, idiot.
Then you fuckin' open it, man!
Get that door open.
How can both fuckin' exits
not fuckin' work?
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
He jammed it.
We thought
it was trying to come in...
but this frickin' thing
was making sure...
we couldn't get out.
Break the fuckin' doors!
Holy shit, man.
Hey, we can
pry this thing open.
Give me a pole or a bar or
something metal--something big.
Yeah, yeah. That'll work.
Come on, D.
You need to get to this side.
Come on, everybody. Come on.
This thing's like
a fuckin' shower curtain, man.
It's crazy.
Oh, man,
show like you got a pair.
Man, fuck you.
Come on.
Everybody, let's go.
Shower curtain?
This thing's like
a fucking piece of toilet paper.
What's it doing, Minx?
What's it doing up there?
It just tore its head off.
It's time to go.
What are you talking about,
man? Help is coming.
The 9 is big. Remember?
What if he's an hour away?
What's if he's going
in the wrong direction?
There are fucking cops
on the way, man.
And you want the rest of us...
to sit underneath
that big hole in the roof...
and hope that thing
doesn't come crashing in here?
What do you mean,
the rest of us?
I mean...
it's time to stop being polite.
There are two classes
of people on this bus now.
It had its pick
of twenty of us back there...
and it picked who?
Dante was one.
Another one was you, Jake.
Oh, god damn it, Scott.
Don't--
And we all saw him
go for you, Bucky.
What the hell
is that supposed to mean, huh?
Two classes of people?
What, the "will be eaten"
and the "won't be eaten"?
Fuck you, Scotty.
Minxie says this thing...
gets anybody it picks out,
no matter what.
Don't put me in this.
She also said
that after tonight...
it goes away,
and for a long time, Scott.
You tell us, Minxie.
Are we safe if we can hide out
till morning...
or is this thing
gonna come after these guys...
with everything it's got
'cause it only has till morning?
Huh?
We're screwed, right?
Yeah.
Scotty, you're not talkin'...
about throwing people
off this bus?
It's funny
you should say that, D...
'cause the only other one...
we know it picked out
for sure was you.
Whoa! Hold on a second!
We all saw the way
it sniffed you out back there.
You were the only one
it gave tongue action, man...
-and we all saw it.
-Scotty!
I don't understand
what you're trying to do.
I'm trying to stay alive.
You're trying to split us up!
We have just dropped a notch
on the fucking food chain, man.
This is about
living or dying now, OK?
And if this bus
is the only thing...
keeping that fucker
away for us...
how safe are we, you guys...
with everybody it's hungry for
sittin' inside it?
I want to see hands.
I want to see hands...
'cause as shitty a deal
as it is...
I gotta say I'd like you, Bucky,
and Jake off this bus, man.
You listen to me,
you piece of shit!
He looked at you, too, bro.
I saw him, and you did, too.
He looked right at you
and smiled.
And when you made Jake
take the lights off it...
he could've looked at you twice
and licked his fucking lips...
but we don't know that.
So you keep
your little blacklist.
'Cause when he takes you out--
and I hope he does--
I'm gonna be the one
gettin' as far away...
from your sorry ass as I can.
"Time to go" is right.
-I'm gonna go find that farm.
-Then I'm going with you.
You know I'm coming.
You want to keep this bus?
Then you sit in it.
Right under that big hole.
See how long you last.
Look, I'm sorry, D.
You are so right about that.
Come on, guys.
Come on, help is on the way.
Why are we splitting up?
He said he was coming.
We're gonna leave,
and he's gonna pull up.
That bus is a deathtrap, Bucky.
Use your head.
You're really gonna
let them go alone?
What, do you want
to go with them?
We don't know who it picked out.
Jesus Christ,
it looked at everyone.
Scotty, let go of me.
-Let go of you?
-Let go of me!
Fuck.
Rho...
tell me you're really
walking away from me.
You used me. You used all of us!
All you care about is yourself.
Rho...
You want to know, Scotty,
what I found out today?
When people get really scared...
it's just like
when they get drunk.
The real person
comes to the surface.
We could've protected
D and Jake and all of us...
if we'd stuck together!
You know, like in a team.
Hey. Hey!
Jonny!
-Open the door!
Open the door!
You little cocksucker!
I will fucking fry you!
You open these goddamn doors!
You open them right now!
Jonny, open the fucking doors,
man! Open the fucking doors
Open the--
This is my bus, too, man!
Run!
Run! He's right behind you, D!
Run! Run!
Get back! Get off! Break off!
Oh, God!
-Shit!
-Hold on, hold on!
Hold still!
Stop moving! Stop!
Come on, Scotty!
You're hurting him!
Get me--
-Hold still! Pull it out!
-Hold on!
Stop it! Keep back! Stop moving!
It's in there like it's welded!
Pull that out!
You're hurting him!
Stop it, Scotty!
-Hold still!
-Stop it, Scotty!
Izzy, hold him! Hold him!
Scotty, hold still!
Get it!
Please fuckin' hurry!
Oh, God!
Oh, shit! Please hurry!
Oh, God! Please hurry!
Oh, D, I'm sorry, man!
I'm so sorry!
Please fuckin' help!
Scotty! Scotty!
Damn it! Scotty! Scotty!
What is it, boy? What is it?
Papa!
Go. Go!
Where did you come from?
From that bus?
How far up ahead?
Huh?
Come on, answer me.
It doesn't matter.
There's no one on the bus,
and you can't kill it.
Jacky, get the dog inside.
Look, you can't stop it!
You get in the cabin
with Jack Jr.
You stay down till this is over.
This'll never be over!
It doesn't matter what you do.
It'll be back...
twenty-three years from now...
and twenty-three years
from then.
Get us to that bus.
Jonny?
What was that?
Bucky!
What are you doin' here?
You let her in, huh, Jonny?
Have you seen anybody else?
What are you doing?
That thing is after you, Bucky.
Hey, there's no farm
out there, man.
I must--I must've run ten miles
all over this fuckin' valley.
Bucky...
come on, just please go away.
Don't make me
go back out there again, man.
It's fuckin' freaky
out there, man. Please.
Get around the bus!
Jacky!
Get us around this bus now!
Now! Get around the bus!
Jacky, get out!
Get out of there now!
Jacky!
You all right?
Jacky, answer me!
Are you OK?
I think so.
Jacky, get us away
from the bus!
Come on, let's go!
Get us away from the bus!
Come on, Jacky, go on!
Get us away!
Move it!
Dad?
-Dad?
-Yeah!
Dad!
All you kids, get down!
Jacky!
You gotta get us
away from the bus now!
Come on!
Dad!
Dad, get out of there.
The spool's jammed
in the cradle!
Dad, just get out!
The cradle's welded
to the truck's frame.
Get out, dad!
He'll rip my gun
right out of the truck!
Dad, just get the fuck
out of there!
Dad, dad...
are you OK?
Dad!
Dad?
You're not going
to believe this...
but I think
I found a way out of here.
What?
Minxie said it doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter
what Minxie said.
Right?
The others might've gotten away.
We don't know that.
Kimball, too.
Hey, nobody gets to decide
we die.
No dream, nobody--
nobody gets to decide that!
That is bullshit!
I hope so.
Come on, I want to go show you
a big ugly bug.
That's the truck
that passed us this morning--
you remember,
with the big bug on top of it?
You think we can just
drive away in it?
No, but I think I know
how to hot-wire a truck.
That's how I got
in my bar fight.
I was trying to steal
somebody's truck.
A gay bar?
Jesus Christ.
Wherever he was going,
I don't think he made it.
Oh, my God.
The keys are in it.
Come on, man,
the keys are in it.
It's not birds.
-Come on.
-Fuck!
Shit!
D!
Go! Go, go!
Go, go, go! Go, go!
Go, man, go!
I'm a sitting duck
back here, lzzy! Step on it!
I've got it floored!
Go! Come on, go!
-Go faster! Make it go faster!
-I can't!
Go, go!
Go, man! Go, go!
Izzy, go!
Go! Izzy!
Move this piece of shit!
Come on! Come on! Move it!
Izzy! Go, go!
Izzy, do something!
Izzy!
Get down!
Come on! Come on!
Izzy!
Izzy, fucking do something!
-Get out!
-What?
Come on! Come on! Come on!
-Get out!
-Are you fucking crazy?
Izzy! Izzy!
-Come on! Izzy!
-Stay down!
Stay down!
It isn't dead.
Its time ran out.
It looks dead to me.
You Taggart?
That's right.
Can we see it?
Can you read?
This something real?
Because I heard
it was a bunch of bullshit.
It's still five bucks.
Where'd it come from?
My dad killed it.
Yeah, but where'd it come from?
It's five bucks from you, too.
How'd he kill it?
Ask him.
Come on, man.
We ought to go get
our money back.
What the hell is it?
What do you think it is?
We don't touch it.
What's the story on this thing?
Whatever you've heard, probably.
You expect us to think
that that thing's real?
Don't really care.
How'd you kill it?
Stabbed it
right through the heart...
with a big homemade harpoon.
When?
About twenty-three years ago.
You waiting for something?
About three more days...
give or take a day or two.