MARVEL PRESENTS
THOR : LOVE AND THUNDER 2022
TRANSLATED BY WHITE GOLD
These subtitles are incomplete due to low sound quality, difficult to understand, and only entertained by those who want a fast translation.
If anyone is able to re -translate, welcome.
Oh my god
Almighty, help us
I don’t want help for myself
I want it for my daughter
I'm tired
Oh look what we have here
Look at that
How did he eat my fruit wildly?
forgive me
Oh, one of my followers
I am a grave
From your last student
We lost everything, sir
dry land
All life is lost
But I believe you
We don’t need your words any more than now
The promise of eternal reward
That’s why you celebrate
He thinks there is an eternal award
no no sorry
There is no permanent reward for you, dog
What we celebrate is that we only kill one
We have just released the Necrosword handle
Because with that cursed sword, he can hurt other gods
He threatened to end my kingdom
but sir
Your kingdom is over
There is nothing more to adore you
There are more followers to replace you
always there
We suffer
And we starved to death
My daughter died
for you
And I have to suffer for your god as your only goal
There is nothing for you after death
except death
You are not god
I deny your trust
... now your life is worthless
He finally met his goal
sacrifice yourself for me
Kill all the gods
Do this forever (another meaning is to do this for Eternity) (Eternity is one of the most immortal and powerful comic creatures)
Get your revenge
Open Bifrost for Eternity (rainbow bridge that takes people everywhere)
Unlock Bayfrost for Immortality
The sword chooses you
You are now cursed
It feels like
I don’t feel that I have been cursed
It's like a promise
...Well, this is my oath
All the gods will die
Let's get together
Listen to the legend walk in space
Held God of Lightning
Named Thor, son of Odin
Raised in the manner of a fighter
Thor has been taught to help them win the war
It grows and grows and grows
It's as sensitive as a smile
And she loves everyone with the passion she has
And once again he falls in love with a werewolf
On the female wolf
But Thor’s true love is worldly women
For Jane Farder's side
But Jane Foster is not like that
but unfortunately
In the battle of love, Thor loses
In fact, he lost a lot that day
her mother
her father
And that man And that man and whoever he is
and Heimdall
and his brother
And again his brother
and more
Poor Thor got to see his planet explode
And then he said what did I do?
And apparently he lost everyone and everything he loved
And then he put his heart behind a big fleshy body
can no longer be resolved
And only because he has let go of love
That doesn't mean he stopped fighting
Team up with Guardians of the Galaxy
And start a series of classic Thor adventures
His body became
He gave himself a hard time
He made wealth out of suffering
And he never leaves a leg training day (They always make this joke with Chris Hemsworth because of his small legs)
of his body
He took himself to the statue of the Gods
And behind the statue of his god
He was just a sad person who wanted to get out
Because in all the structures he has had for years
He could not express the pain he was suffering unless he hid it inside them
So, he gave up looking for love
And he accepted that it was only good for one thing
Waiting for someone in a quiet and quiet place: Stay and tell him
Thor, we need your help to win this war
let's go
All right, come on Stormbreaker
How are you?
People are dying
See you down there
Don't move anymore
Let me see
You can solve it now
I'm Grot
Oh, you juice everywhere
Hi all
See who's coming
How are you all
The situation is serious
we are dying
You said that the planet was supposed to be a relaxing trip
I said it would be a relaxing trip
. . .
What do you want more relaxed than this?
A real vacation
God of thunder and lightning
Shah Yerkan |
You finally joined our battle
Well, as they say, being late is better than not at all
thank you
As you know, we used to live in peace
But you know, god was killed
to be killed?
And now our holy temple is left unattended
They control it
And that is our holiest temple
This is rude
This disrespect will not last long
Shah Yerkan |
Tell them what happened here today
Tell them the story of Thor
...
Maybe the situation is the opposite for us
But let me tell you that - let's go -
The story ends here and now
People who don’t want to leave the temple? Do you want to do this?
All good work
We can get the honor of this work together because we are such a team
We use our minds and hearts to defeat the enemy
Wow, the classic adventure has been a revolution
Foster's theory of time travel and space
your book
Well?
i wrote it
Are you Dr. Jane Foster?
yes
hai hai -
What about Paul Rosen Einstein?
difficult. very difficult - yes -
Have you watched the movie Event Horizon?
Not
What is interstellar? - Not -
He might explain everything to you
Um, very good. Paul Rosen Einstein's theory says that
If there are points A and B in space
which has a similar existence
This way
You tore your book
Yes, but now you understand the wormhole problem
Make sure you watch the movie
Well -
All right, I made you spicy Cheetos
So ... how is it?
It went smoothly
Do you have anyone besides me?
Well, when people find out, their temperament becomes weird
... they just
different
...
This fourth degree cancer genius
I mean, how many degrees?
Four toasts - all we know -
Oh, you have to be somewhere else now that is more important than chemotherapy?
Not
You try to go back to the lab
I have a series of ideas
Not that good. Your time is up
So you don’t understand what the world is trying to tell you
I will translate it for you
just relax
I'll fight my way, okay?
Well, for the record, I say my method is not the same as being alone in the lab.
Maybe it’s time to make your space viking card
No cards
why is there? No cards.
He was tall, blonde and well built
handsome
Jane are you sure? - View -
I will solve it like this
I myself
The result remains the same
I'm sorry Jane
If there is anything I can do, call me
Viking Legend Push theory
millionaire
to them
Resilience and enthusiasm
And it gives good health
Health
Welcome to New Asgard, please drive slowly
It smells like a king
Because you deserve it
Eternity Exhibition
Look here
she is beautiful
We came here to take you home
Ya, ke planet Asgard
Asgard is not a planet, my children
Asgard is a human, you
And now is the time
that I went to the spirit world
I will take my place in the great hall of Valhalla
A place for the comfort of the gods
Oh, one more thing
You have a sister
And now that
I will be the star of the gods
And I say goodbye
what happen
I'm lost
nahhhh
Ayah
But wait bro
An unknown gate was built behind us
Change the look
I'm Hela
Goddess of death
Now I will return to Asgard
And the throne I really deserve
And nothing stopped me
Join me - we will not join you witch -
millionaire
impossible
I damaged your laptop
It's your turn to die
Heimdall - Heimdall -
You can almost power
Feel this unique and beautiful stone
All right, let's go back to the village
Where we can drink real Asgardian beer
shake
Thank you
We are afraid we will always be at war without the protection of our god
But now there will be peace and quiet
Receive this gift in return for your service
According to custom, our people donate these animals to the protectors of the planet
giant goat
Oh look at them. This is amazing
Oh look at him, he's moving
Thank you very much Shah Yerkan
listen look
... about the temple - I don't want to talk about the temple -
I know what you mean about the temple
... it made me angry and - just being a bunch of people jerked off -
Okay, I won't talk anymore
Don't forget the goat
what you receive and what you need to bring with you
They are beautiful - yes, they are very beautiful -
They also shouted a lot - no problem happened to them -
Find the control of the Kufti so that we can download the request for help
Where do you put that control?
The child may eat it
Don't play around because they have no control
...
I will get rid of them now
I want to get rid of it too - Thor doesn't work, they don't charge -
Go away!
How are you, Cor? - Yes, I'm great -
...
Oh, hey man - Kraglin -
are you here all the time? - Yes, you told me to stay on the ship -
This is the Calendar. We got married
I'm Groot
What do we say about jumping into a relationship?
I don't have to do this
Yes, you can’t get married on every planet we land on
I'm Groot
!Finally
All right, let's go, the message asking for help has arrived
Please help us, the slaughter of the gods has found us
The slaughter of the gods?
Who killed all these gods?
...
Who can do such a thing?
hey what is this come back
Where are you Thor? - Saif -
We need you here
My friend, you are in danger, we must leave immediately
Start the ship, friends
Maybe we should split up
Many people need help See all these requests for help
Do you have a problem with Thor?
I admire your commitment to each other, it’s a wonderful thing
Something that never happened to me
Dude, can I say something?
say
I was wrong before
Then I found meaning, I found love
But the feeling of being this nonsense is better than the feeling of being empty
I hope you find something one day
It makes you feel stupid
I had love before
Not going according to plan
...
I know this is going to happen, you should go
I will look for Saif
You reach the other. The galaxy needs a guardian
Fine, let's go
...
Take this ship with you as a farewell gift
Will you give me my own ship?
yes for you
...
I will light the ship - thank you -
God bless old friends
Human handshake
Asgardian shook hands
...with a snake
You can't believe it
And we’ll end with a classic Asgardian kick
let's go
Take care of my people
They are having a hard time
! move one
Remember what I said
If you feel lost
Just look into the eyes of your loved ones
They tell you who you really are
Goodbye
...
to go
Only you and I stay
Storm breaker
Be careful with your crazy ax
So what should we do now?
Let's go to Saif
Who or what is it?
Faligar
Guardians of the Phaligarians
We are the best gods you can see
Oh no
shift. I'm Thor
Odin's Son
One of your hands is cut off
I will help you - no -
Leave me here to die as a hero
Battle on the battlefield
That I can take my place in Valhalla
Oh, I don't like telling you this, but
If you want to go to Valhalla as a warrior, you have to die in battle
You survived - no bad luck -
Maybe your hands are in Valhalla
What happened to you
I'm looking for a crazy person
I'm following him here
It’s a trap - who’s that crazy guy? -
The massacre of the gods is coming
It aims to destroy the generation of gods
Asgard next
...
It's not my fault. I have never seen this table before. Now wherever you go
survivors back
Who is this new person?
that person you will like
millionaire
Millionaire ... come here, that's my hammer
Millionaire, come here, son
millionaire
!return
Excuse me, hello, hammer in your hand
And that's how I look
two
...
Jane?
Let me tell you the story of Thor and Jane
Thor is the god of thunder and Jane is also a knowledgeable woman
And even if they are from different worlds
They match up somehow
And Jane taught Thor the ways and habits of people
The longer it lasts, the deeper and deeper their love gets
I want you to promise me that you will always protect him
I love you too, man
And deep love becomes magical
But the more he lived with Jane, the more he feared losing her
But even though Jane wasn’t ready to admit it, she was also scared
Because of that, they built a wall between them
Thor is busy saving humanity
Heimdall
Jane began to do the same
She's really busy
And finally, the distance between them grew and grew
It became so much so that it could not be stopped
...
There are two plates
Jane wrote a note
And Thor read the note
Or so they think
are you okay
Yes, it's just hot here
how about
Can we talk later?
Yes of course
I'm glad to see you
What
Hey, is this a necrosorde?
Very great. I read a story about it
And you know it will hurt
Oh well, stop it
Hey, don't touch my stuff
You better run, coward
Children! They brought children
Mom, help me
! Ibu! Ibu -! Ibu -
The shadow giant is bothering me
That coward must have run away, I found him
...
How long? three? four years?
I have not forgotten eight years, seven months and six days
The last time I saw you, I didn't actually see you because you were gone.
Oh no, you go. You go and write me a beautiful handwritten letter
Actually you weren't there and I had to say no - I -
And if you’re not there to see me go, then maybe you should go first
This is logical
If we both go, then we both go (Again, Ostad Khayabani)
And now you leave me again
Drill, give me the names of all the missing children
My lord, the girl has been stolen and I do not know what to do - they will find her -
Children, they bleed, take them to the hospital. now
drill
People need entertainment
Especially now, in a crisis
in particular
...
So he's an ex-girlfriend?
Former old female friend
Jodie Foster (American Actress) - Jane Foster -
who went
Does that mean he ran away?
Ya ya
I find it hard to see your ex -lover back together with your ex -husband
move one. Come to your father
Hey, you're coming too
I just called you to come
With what? Half of our army is dead
...
He found them
Asgardians
In times like these, we must be united and united
Seeing what is happening here, we are scared
We woke up, we were scared and we were worried
If we want to find a child, we have to look inside ourselves first
I'm sorry Mick, it's hard for me to speak in a normal voice
what are you doing?
It records everything
We don't have time for this
When the children return
write this microphone
Everyone out
I did not find them
What do we know about this person?
It walks through the shadows
And he made monsters with shadows
Must be a scary monster
It has the ability to kill gods
Slowly destroy and kill the person holding it
which means - it infects him -
Yes, he infected her. It is possible
So, basically, we are together
We are in front of shadow zombies, enchanted kidnappers
Great. when do we want to go
Can Thor see me?
He is gone, son of Heimdall
Are you okay, Stride?
My name is not Strid anymore
Now they know me as Axel
...
Your father has given you a great name, and I insist on respecting his choice
superior
Stride - I said Excel -
Step - Excel -
ok dad where are you axel
I'm not sure
Your father told me how it was and I wanted to teach you. You have to focus
And raise your hand
Now concentrate, close your eyes
Thor
Hello how are you
How are we? See where we are
In a cage made with a spear
ya benar
are you going to do something
Yes, yes, I will do it, but not now
I'm a ghost, look
Do you see
So what's wrong with us?
Not stated
Very, very bad situation
You know the good news
You Asgardian, if you die you go to Valhalla
My God, get lost
... stop
All right, guys, calm down, okay?
See, I have a great plan, okay?
I put together a very good group
Uncle Korg is in there
Its king is Valkyrie
Amm with my ex-girlfriend Jane
who has other stories that won’t bore you
Excellent group, but terrible
And before you know it, we’ll be following you
yes
We will take you from here
I'm afraid
We are all scared
Help!
Thor - Please! Please! help -
Thor help us
Hey everyone be careful ok? be careful on the way
See you later, okay? Excel, get me out of here
In the land of the shadows
How did you know?
No translucent color there, I'm not mistaken
Well, if we need color
Let's make a rainbow
Should we make a rainbow? Is that a term?
...
And you see, he moves through the shadows and is in the realm of shadows
That’s right, we can’t go there, it might be a trap, it might be a danger to children.
We need help. We need to start an army
Do you think the same thing I did? - Yes, I think the same -
What do you think - What do you think? -
...
The strongest god house in the world
We can put together the best team
We can agree with the team (Egyptian sun god and creator of everything)
Let's take everyone
Let's bring Tomachuenga(God of War in Maori mythology in New Zealand)
Maybe Quincy Quesaro
And Zeus is the oldest god there
Did you say Zeus?
Yes, Zeus - the same famous Zeus? Zeus Zeus? -
I'm not sure if he has a second name
I need to be there too
Yes
Storm breaker
just relax
No, no, we're not going anywhere with Bayfrost Dagun Stormbreaker
see what happens
We can't go with your little portal in the sky. We can't fit in it
what you say? they are great
Stormbreaker is good too
Stormbreaker only wants one thing
Anything that can control space travel
He has the power to get us there, he just needs something to focus his power on
It was not so unexpected
Well, if we have a ship that can use the Stormbreaker as its power source
Oh, like a motorcycle
Like an engine - we need a ship -
I have a ship
...
Leave the important ones alone
He is very important
...
oh hey - hey -
I'm hanging out with old friends
yes
...
I'm trying to understand Kim
I think I went astray and then I went astray
I see you dressed like me
... well, this is how you are
It's too much for me
So how do you become friends? how it happened
I swear the millionaire made Saddam
Hmm call you
Well, then I came here to investigate
The pieces start to glow and emit a sound
And then ... I became Thor - a madman -
Well, you know what, it suits you
... So
I was just trying
See you again
what
We're just talking
Mom, don't leave me
Do not be scared
Even though I have no love
You will not be alone
In memory of Eileen Foster
And whatever happens
Never stop fighting
two
are you okay - Good -
Do you think I should come?
You are a bully. Of course you have to come
Now, what do you want Josh to do?
You are a Viking now
This means you have to die in battle
You must die in pain and suffering, otherwise you will not die in Valhalla
This is my plan
What about your royal problems?
I love being king
I love my people
But that's all meetings and so on
I miss fighting
I miss my sister
That's why you have to come
All right, we need to go
Did you take your stuff?
What did you take your stuff?
Yes
hand bomb?
Not a speaker
let's go
Is it possible to keep the sink problem between us?
I support you
My Asgardians
We will be back with the kids
With all the children
Maybe it's better to celebrate
Of course, not without children
You don't do that again
...
All right, we better go
no, how about you?
Yes, every weekend
...
I was thinking of giving it to this person when we arrived
What if I have a bad term?
For example, take this hammer
...
No, it's very good for me
The story ends here and now
...
Give me this person first
You never forget the first one
yes
So you have a boyfriend?
Oh, no, I'm too busy, I don't have time
My head is hot and so on
Too bad, let me check here
very great
Who is so stupid? - Han? -
Our building is ugly
what happen
Do I feel anything?
feel? to Jane? No, we don't think about it anymore
We had the feeling last time
It's been a long time. I think you have feelings
Calm down friends, we're a team
I don't know exactly which team we're on, do I?
tim Jane
Think of Thor who is always looking for a way
When Hela breaks her iron hammer
He went and made an ax for himself with a dying star
And with the same arrow he cut off the head of Thanos (First of all)
What an interesting story
...
Is this? oh
what? You liked the beheading just a moment ago
...
I know a little girl like you
And he is brave and wise
Let me ask you a question
About god
They're supposed to protect you, aren't they?
So where are you now?
Thor is on his way
!Ya ya-
yes. I look forward to his arrival
That's why you're here
We were not invited here, so we had to hide
And we have to wear disguise so they don’t recognize us
I am a philosopher now
are they chinese
Real disguise
Clothes for their emotional gods
And each color shows emotion
Where are the emotional gods?
Do not ask
Oh shit
...
Oh look at that
Hey guys, look up, that's god Kronan
!Zeus! Zeus
!Zeus! Zeus! Zeus
!Zeus! Zeus! Zeus! Zeus
!Zeus! Zeus
Yes
I am Zeus
oh they
The same people, myths, legends
I don’t know if you noticed or not, me and this person are very similar
He is the god of thunder
Peachy. You should tell him the same thing when you go to ask the soldier
I will not go up there
...
Oh!
!Zeus
!calm! calm
! Silence
This sacred assembly
from god
But we have a very, very basic problem
to talk about them
... like that
Isn't that nonsense?
... I must have some important business
... now we want this week's winner - sorry -
The most humane victim
Let's introduce the names of God
Okay, maybe not so great
Oh no, not good
No, I don’t think it could be any better than this
These gods may not be able to help
But I think the thunder will start our work
Jane you to the right, Thor you to the left
We will go and take the yellow thunder out of it
All right, let's go
No, no, no, let me see
No news turned yellow, Zeus beat us
I will talk to him when the time comes
Well, the time is now - the time is not now -
who is speaking
this
Korg shut up - do you have anything to tell us? -
I am sorry
...
Who are you two?
Halo
I can't hear your voice
Why don’t you come and speak from the pulpit?
platforms under the sun?
Yes, you can see this area, which is very similar to the lecture platform
I understand
oh how are you
Oh, sorry
good luck das
the mighty zeus
god of the world
I came here to ask for your help
to make an army
There is a psychic who is called a god killer and wants to kill us all
It has access to anywhere, all planets, nature
We are powerless against it and no one can stop it
And I know where he is
With your help, we can eat it
Before he killed anyone else
what you said
Kill some low -ranking gods
proceed? That's all
Pretty boy, sit down and don't talk anymore
Sorry, didn't you hear anything I said?
He also committed genocide
After I say something, then you should shut up
Because you are so far away to be invited to the event
Zeus, we have to do something
You can't come to the party
You should listen to us
Diam!
Well, I am ready to follow your plan. Let's just say - at my signal, we go -
What's the signal? - I said let's go -
Let’s see who you are and get rid of your disguise
and the sudden wind
Damn you blew too much
Shouldn't we help him now?
Finally we will help him. growing grapes
what about the others? Take off your disguise too
Oh no, I'll take it off myself
Let's take it
I took off my disguise, okay?
Asgardians, I think we last saw you when Odin died
And you are Thor, god of thunder
But you can’t make thunder sound on your own
Zeus, this situation is more than we can handle
He brought the children of Asgard
Who do you think we are? God's police
Every god takes care of his people
No more and no less
Asgardian things are their own
See how my hero Zeus is scared
Let me tell you a few things, first of all, yes, I’m scared
Gore has a necrosword, which means it can kill us
which is not good and the second
I know you want to do the right thing, I understand
But the only thing you do is create fear and that’s not good at all
We are safe here and so are you
So calm down
Drink some wine, put some wine on your body
And third, don't talk about Zeus
Now put on your clothes
And now I will return your clothes
If you don’t want to help us, at least let us use your weapons
I need thunder
So I think when you want to take someone’s secret weapon
At least you should ask for it properly
Can I borrow thunder?
group
Not
Don’t worry, the slaughter of the gods will not achieve immortality
Eternity?
What does it mean not to attain Immortality?
Oh shit
Immortality is a very powerful being at the center of the universe
He will grant his wish to whoever attains it first
In your opinion, what can a person named Wrong God expect?
If it reaches Eternity, it can destroy us all in the blink of an eye
Zeus, we have to do something now - he can't do anything -
He has no keys
Is this the goal of the gods? To remain like a coward in a golden castle
Maybe we really got lost
do you know? We will take care of it ourselves
Unfortunately, I can't let this happen
This is a secret place
Same thing for god, now you know where we are
Slaughter God can use you and find us
And this is not good at all
And now you have to stay here
Guardian
So can we go with my plan now?
Yes, Zarti jumped in the middle
Hey, you didn't bring me
Take Thor
coorg
Valk, lower your head
Korg
Taurus
No, not Korg
I'm getting crushed
Zeus
I don’t want this to happen to my son
This is the sound of thunder
...
Thor, I'm here
where are you?
I am here. I'm not dead - Coorg. you live -
Apparently, the living part was just the crown of his mouth
Look korg should call that goat - I'm trying -
...
! I'm done doing it
Then the goat came and came through the window to save you and me
And all the classic Thor adventures
I can't believe you killed Zeus
Yes, someone once said that you can’t meet your hero
What matters is that we are on our way to come to you
How are you here, are you okay?
That's good, we're just scared
Look, I know how scared it is
I think I wasn’t that brave when I was your age
Really?
In fact, I think you are the bravest Asgardian I have ever seen, all of you
Stay brave and take care of each other, you are a team now
Children's team at home
Can you do this - Yes. I think we can do this -
I know you can
good
Thor - John? -
Good to meet my hero - oh thank you friend -
how are the children
As I thought, they were scared because they were young, but I told them things would be fine
So you lied to them
Do you still have a plan?
yes - no, no plans -
We have a plan - No, we don't have a plan -
We can't make a team of gods
Coorg is dead
No, not dead - I'm not dead -
Well, all that's left is you
You were also ridiculed in detail
No, I have an empty joint, which I have no problem with
Jane? - I have no problem -
Coorg? - I laughed by the way -
are we dead serious? - No one is going to die, right? -
Everything is good, our work is very good
We killed Zeus on his ship
Well, now it may be a disaster for the whole world and beyond
And all their gods will follow us in the next few days
But look, you stole this beautiful weapon, didn't you?
This is the army we want
... it’s smooth and polished and strong and beautiful
Good for you, I like good for you, Valkyrie
But, I have my own weapons, but I don’t use them very often
Oh, that's right, old friend
You put a very interesting story in there
Listen, don't we have a problem now?
You know, weird old gun I have
But don't worry
The past is the past, now you and I are together
You know, come and drink your first beer
What do you think
It's delicious
Sorry for being busy lately
two
oh hey
It has a beautiful view, doesn't it? - Yes beauty -
That's so cool what you do
With Mjolnir, you know
... hanya, ya
Space dolphins
You have to look at them, space dolphins
Wow beautiful
Both beautiful creatures and rare creatures are very loyal
...
Oh, how beautiful and attractive she is
I don't know ... I don't know if I want more or not
...
Yes, something like that
Beautiful, very beautiful
Jane - Thor -
I want to feel bad for you - what? -
Umm ... I ... I want to feel stupid about something
And I think that's you
I don't want to hear it anymore - it's not what it looks like -
... a friend of mine who told me about having a sense of nonsense
He said for fear of losing love, one never experiences love and ends up with emptiness
And I think he's right
And this is what I feel today and I push people
And I kept them away for fear of losing them
But I don't want to do this anymore
You close your heart and
Yes, yes, I close my heart and meditate, what are you contemplating?
No, it's very boring
It really makes me even angrier
I'm tired of surrendering to destiny
And understand who the world wants from me
I want to live in the present as if there is no tomorrow
I want to be with you, Jane
What do you say, Jane - I have cancer -
I'm sorry, what - I'm dying -
Hey what happened
No, no, no, Jin, Jin, Jin, look, I don't mean that -
I was joking that I didn’t have cancer
I'm sorry Jane
Don't feel sorry for me
when you will understand
About six months ago
I just felt tired and then
I found out that I have stage 4 cancer
I put myself together
And then I heard that Mjolnir called Saddam
...
That's why you came to New Asgard - yes, because of the iron hammer -
Jane, none of us know how much time we have
I don't know what will happen tomorrow
And millionaires ... millionaires choose you
And he chose you because you deserve it, nothing else
The first time I saw you, I didn't qualify, I couldn't lift the hammer
But you tell me that there is no greater purpose than helping people in need
You deserve me
Whatever you want to do, we can do together
good
And what do you want to do?
I want to return the children to their families
And complete the mission
how do you feel now
I am really afraid
how do you feel - bull sheet -
how crazy - so stupid -
good
I don't know what they're talking about
They don't talk
Oooh
Do you think they both believe the story I told you about making babies?
Unfortunately, they don’t seem to be doing this
it gets bad. I thought Thor would be a good father
Hey, we're here
Discoloration
They are not here
where
What else is going on here?
Bifrost is the key
This is a trap
Can you tell me why you threw Stormbreaker out the window?
With that, he can attain immortality
You really should stop doing this
Call your ax
When you go to the dentist, I will call you
Call the ax -... tell me where the kids are and then I'll kill -
Call your ax
Wow, you are god
You know nothing about being God
You go to the gods to get help from them and they do nothing
Like me
It's not like you at all
What did you say
I said he's not like you at all
I truly create peace and quiet
You killed an innocent god - innocent? -
are you a valkyrie - Yes -
!very interesting
God, they did the same to you
Your sister's association went to the slaughterhouse
Do you pray to the gods for them?
When did the woman you love die on the battlefield?
Did you ask for their help?
...
yes
You are dying
I am sorry
We are same
The sword gives me strength
an iron hammer also gives you strength
But he did nothing to change your destiny
The gods are using you
But they don't help you
There is no permanent reward for us
He will die soon
And you know who can help him, I'll let you guess
I know what your pain is, that love hurts
I once had a daughter
I believe in a higher power that hopes to save him
... and it
Man
And now I understand that my daughter is lucky
He doesn't have to grow up in the world
full of pain
Full of running and evil gods
choose love
Call your ax
are you okay - Yes -
I want to kill this person - I want to, but we have to bring him alive
Just until we found the kids
Oh, thank you Mr. Goat
Wah!
We have to get him out of here
Hey I love you
You're all here, let's go and shake
Bring home our storm breaker
See how many other treatments we can try
But something destroyed his body’s ability to fight cancer
Forgive me Thor
wow you are here
What's going on out there?
Can you believe that a child broke the refrigerator?
how val - Oh, it hurts so much -
But things are stable - very good -
... you know, I just have to do one test and then - oh no no -
It must remain in you so that all the magical ingredients and elixirs enter your body
I'm going out to look for the kids
I will kill the bad guys and then I will come back
did you go without me?
What happened until you said we were going to do everything together?
He uses children to distract you. you need me
It's clear that I need you, I want you alive
It's great that you're by my side on the battlefield and fighting by my side
And the hammer killed you
Every time you use it, it eliminates your death and prevents your body from fighting cancer
So what happens when you say life is like no tomorrow?
That’s for a time I didn’t know that you might not have a tomorrow
Jane, if there is a chance to survive, you must take it
It works for someone who does not have cancer
I know, like a space scientist from New Mexico
He wants to live his dream
But look at me
I want to keep fighting
I am the mighty Thor
And you want me not to do that, so what's the point of doing this again?
I mean I love you
I always love you
And this is an opportunity for us
And if you take the sledgehammer, the chance will be lost
But every day I regret why I didn’t tell you to stay so we could sort it out together
You better come back to me
I will be back as soon as possible
...
Remember that the door to Eternity is in the middle
This is the world, I know - this is the world -
Yes, yes, how many times have you said that? I won't get lost
So how do you do with that scar?
I think I lost my kidneys
Yes, it is completely broken
I wish I could follow you, but
I will probably die on the way to bring the kids back
So you have to go alone
All you have to do is destroy the sword
It is a source of strength, without which it cannot survive
two
not dead
Yes I know
Eternity
!Finally
(This is a Celestial statue)
Hi friend
I knew you were coming
Go, go friend
are they all ok
So collect, collect
I'm glad to see you in person
Well, listen, here's the plan
You sneaked into Stormbreaker
Be careful not to come across the shadow monster
Does anyone here have any fighting experience?
You won't be able to study like now
We are not as strong as you
We're kids - hey, remember, you're Asgardian -
...
Okay, okay, but at least today.
We are Asgardians
Take your weapon
which weapon
Go pick up whatever you find
Come back quickly
Fast!
move fast
They're getting closer, hurry up
Today
The day our names will be recorded in history
This is a day that will be determined for generations to come
This is the day when we walk in space
Prepare your weapons!
...
God's power
Excel Umum
Bring the army to the side of the ax
For Asgard
Not
Jane
Let's destroy the sword, I will die alone
The gate is almost open, you have to stop Starbreaker
no problem. i have it
Storm breakers solve it
Take me back
I'll take you from there
move one
Run away!
Ax ... I ... let go ... go
You lost Mrs. Thoreh
First
my name
Thor is strong
Second
If you can't say Thor is strong
said Dr. Jane Foster, I agree
Third
Eat my hammer!
Storm breaker
I know you can do it
superior
take them home
Jane
I'm good
I only need a minute to catch my breath
Gore, hold your hand
What kind of father will I be?
If I hold hands?
I understand your pain but this is not the way
You are not looking for death or revenge
What am I looking for?
You are looking for love
Love
Why do I need to find love?
Because that's what we all want
oh
Ayah
You turned your back on me
You win, Gore
Why spend my last moments with you when I can be with him?
I choose love
You can also choose, you can cut
do your wish
Finish me
He won't have anyone
He lives alone
He is not alone
my darling
...
Since I took the hammer
I got an extra joon
and magic
This is so bad for you
That's not too bad for God
I think I understand my terminology
incomplete
This is the best term you can say - thank you -
Always open your heart
I love you
I love you too
Protect him
protect my love
Let me tell you about the outer space vikings
known as
strong taurus
Held Dr. Jane Foster
His sacrifice saved the world
He helps the children of gods
He paved the way for them to return home
to their small fishing villages which became tourist destinations
How are you?
Are you sure? - Yes, I'm fine -
Children are saved to be children again
Of course, after their king forced them to go to a martial arts class
Look at that little viking
war cries
Even the son of Heimdall
Axel putra Heimdall
Even though he had his father's scary eyes
He was a good fighter
Asgard's future is guaranteed
This is the future, I create my own future
Now my body is growing back
You ask, what happened to Thor?
He embarked on a new adventure
Because he has found something new to live
Something to love
A pathetic little man from God
He turns into Lord Baba
Breakfast is served
It's from this. Hey, eat your breakfast
Sorry, what is it?
It's called Pan Flaps. For context
I guess I don't like the pen cover
We like - I don't -
why are you there
Well, I've never eaten this in my life. - Well, eat more. We need to go, it's over -
Put on your boots
I'm wearing it
You don't wear it
Why do I wear - No, you don't wear -
Go to hell, devil
Oh God
It's new, thanks for leaving
do you know? Wear whatever you like
Don't come to me later, please, I won't show you any mercy
OK, I won't wear this but - thanks -
Remember what my mother always told me
...
I have - I have -
So where is the millionaire now? Where did you put it?
He was lying in his bed - on the bed? -
Oh wow
It will not be deleted
what did you do - he used to look boring -
Yes I think so
I like it
That's very creative
very good
Aliens there being attacked?
very cool - yes cool -
That's why we have to take care of them - I understand -
We take care of them
I love you my love
I love you Uncle Thor
They are always there for us
walking in space
And his daughter who was born of Eternity
And it has the power of god
Two soldiers
In a good fight, they fight for those who cannot fight
They traveled to many places and gave them many names
But for those who know it
They are known as love and lightning
Presentation by Farsin Geekpedia, a fundamental note of the world of comics and cinema
Thor teaser video and trailer analysis on Youtube: Persian Geek Pedia
News and other extracts on Tel: @persiangeekpedia
...
They beg for mercy on you
But they never know if you’re really listening or not
now
You know they look at the sky
They don't ask for thunder anymore
If they don't ask for rain
They just want to see one of those superheroes
When do we become a joke?
now
No news on this yet
They are afraid of us again
Do you understand what I mean by Hercules?
Do you understand what I'm saying, my son?
yes dad