Our paymasters want us at the top table,
we may have to stand
on some heads to get there.
Shit.
[Adam] My investors chuck in,
what, a few hundred million?
And in return they get a whole country.
Copper, oil, lithium.
I mean, that's the golden goose, right?
You told me you didn't know Teddy.
Extradition to the UK
and a life in prison.
Will you get me on the inside?
[Roxana] If he finds out,
he will kill me.
My father died when I was six.
I watched them dump him at the gates.
[Roper] Teddy's a cowboy.
He's not fit for civilised company.
Danny is my only son and heir.
[in Spanish]
Did you steal the shipment list?
[in English]
Calling the head of the Supreme Court.
Consuelo has the authority
to open the shipment.
[indistinct shouting]
Hey!
[Teddy] Everything's gone wrong.
- The Hong Kong investor.
- [Jonathan] Okay?
I want his picture.
[Mayra] Alex Goodwin,
also known as Andrew Birch.
His name is Jonathan Pine.
He's in Colombia,
and he's onto our arrangement.
What do you want me to do?
He'll have support teams
here and in London.
Identify them and deal with them.
And Pine? Where is he now?
[helicopter whirring]
Leave him to me.
[intriguing music]
[opening theme]
[birds chirping]
[man, in Spanish, on the radio]
Let's continue with today's news.
Sebastián, what have you got?
[Sebastián] Thanks, Julio. Exactly.
The assassin of Alejandro Gualteros
is an ex-guerrilla member
who spent several years in armed combat.
Octavio Pérez is on the run
and considered highly dangerous.
Thanks, Sebastián. Sorry to interrupt…
[Jonathan, in English] How much further?
A couple hours.
[in Spanish] This was a brutal and cynical
attack against Alejandro Gualteros.
Alejandro tirelessly campaigned
for justice in this country.
We are at a heightened level of risk.
[phone buzzing]
I am therefore raising security levels.
[Basil, in English]
Did you receive the red flag?
- Yeah.
- [Basil] Are you moving?
[Sally] Yeah, I'm just about to.
Why haven't you gone already?
Get to the airport now.
- Use the exit parcel provided.
- Okay.
[tense music]
[line ringing]
Yes. It's me.
I'm afraid I'm going to have
to cancel our appointment.
I have guests.
I'll leave you my findings.
Postmarked, of course.
On A4 lined paper.
[tense music]
Mr Karapetian.
Yes. How can I help?
- [assistant] Can I help you?
- [Angela] No, thanks.
[Teddy] He had money
that needed cleaning.
He stole it from a Swiss family bank.
It is what we needed.
[in Spanish] Did I not tell you…?
We needed the fucking money, didn't we?
Or do you have any better ideas, asshole?
[in English] Speak English!
Let me tell you something
about the man you've been dealing with.
He's not a Swiss banker.
He's not a Hong Kong investor.
He doesn't play the piccolo
in a colliery band.
He is a British intelligence agent
with an indecent habit of getting
information people barely knew they had.
Many had been susceptible to this gift.
And I'd lay money that Roxana Bolaños
could be added to that list.
What about you, Teddy?
Were you susceptible?
What do you mean?
Answer the question.
Were you susceptible?
I told Matthew Ellis nothing.
And he has achieved nothing.
The prosecutor is dead.
We will release the cargo
and deliver it to the Cabreras.
So everything is as we planned.
No, the plan was no mistakes.
[door closing]
Where are you, Jonathan?
[intriguing music]
[muffled voices in Spanish]
[Jonathan, in English]
Are you sure it's safe here?
[Roxana] Mm-hmm. Nobody's been here
since my father was killed.
[door opening]
[phone buzzing]
[Martín] You should listen
to this, Mr Robinson.
[Roper] Let me explain something
about the man you've been dealing with.
He's not a Swiss banker.
He's not a Hong Kong investor.
He doesn't play the piccolo
in a colliery band.
He is a British intelligence agent
with an indecent habit of getting…
[in Spanish] Your name is Octavio, right?
People call me Tavo.
Do you have family you can call?
You're going to be safe here.
Until I sort this out.
Okay?
Don't leave me with her.
She's one of them.
It's all right. She's on our side.
Wait here.
[in English] What are you doing?
You want to tell me what's going on?
The man you know as Gilberto Hanson…
He's an English arms dealer.
And he and I have…
history.
And now he knows I'm here.
So, I have to get to him
before he gets to me.
- What about your team? Where are they?
- There is no team.
You told me you had support.
Well, there's no one.
I'm alone.
What about the guarantees I asked for?
I can't give you any of those.
You played me.
I did what was necessary
to get on the inside.
I trusted you with my life.
Do you have any idea
what Teddy will do to me if he finds me?
Which is why I need you to stay here.
Keep your phone off.
Make sure Tavo stays out of sight.
They'll be looking for him.
He's wanted for murder.
- Roxana, I'm serious.
- It's Tavo that we're worried about?
Listen, you chose to work
with these people.
You knew what you were
getting involved with.
Now, I will get you out of this.
- But do not ask me to be grateful.
- You planned this from the minute
- you approached me.
- No.
You lied to me.
You deliberately compromised me.
And now I have nowhere to go.
- I lied to you?
- Mm-hmm.
Let me tell you about
a man called Waleed.
He was my friend. He had three children.
He loved cricket. And he bled out
in my arms because you lied to me.
You helped me for one reason
and one reason only,
which is to save your own skin.
I think…
you… like my skin, don't you?
Stay here.
I'll come back.
Do what you want.
I will never ask anything
of you ever again.
What am I doing here?
[scoffs]
I want to talk to you
about Alex Goodwin's whereabouts.
Alex is dead.
Yeah, you said.
You were returning his body from Spain.
- What was left of it.
- That's right.
Not much of it, was there?
Taken just yesterday in Medellín.
You've been secretly
filming this house, Basil.
And you met Adam Holywell and
tricked him into giving you his phone.
In the church after Rex's funeral
you promised me…
that you were loyal.
[scoffs]
Where's Jonathan Pine?
Hmm?
I have no idea what you're talking about.
Bullshit.
Don't fucking lie to me!
I'm gonna ask you again.
Where is Jonathan Pine?
[tense music]
Charlie.
Let's see if we can jog
his memory, shall we?
[door opening and closing]
[chuckles]
Frisky.
- Thank you for answering the call.
- Oh, no. Anything for you, chief.
[Roper] Battle Boy will show you the way.
If you're lucky,
you might get a bottle of beer.
[Frisky] How you doing?
Who are they?
[Roper] Friends from home.
They're gonna help us find your boy.
Let me do it.
No, no, no.
You focus on the shipment.
The new prosecutor's gonna
release the cargo this morning.
Fly to Cartagena.
Get the cargo out of that port.
That's transportation.
I have boys who can do that.
Teddy, listen to me.
A man hell-bent on revenge
guarantees only his own demise.
You and I have to focus
on the task at hand.
José Cabrera, the anniversary.
Kings of America, remember?
[phone ringing]
Answer it.
[in Spanish] Who's this?
[Jonathan, in English] Put him on.
[intriguing music]
[Roper] Well, you are trouble.
The hilltop restaurant.
I booked a table
under the name of Andrew Birch.
1 p.m.
Come alone.
[line disconnects]
[helicopter whirring]
[tense music]
[man] Mr Hanson,
your friend is already here.
- Sorry I couldn't clear the restaurant.
- No, no. Don't you worry, Santiago.
Andrew's an old colleague from London.
- Top man.
- Okay, sir. Thank you.
Andrew.
Gilberto.
Been too long.
Can I get you anything, sir?
Uh… Two of your delicious juices.
And don't bother with menus.
We'll both have the steak.
- And I want to see blood. Sangre!
- Yes, sir.
Okay, sir. [laughs]
[birds chirping]
I should probably warn you
that this place is owned by a pal.
So if you try anything,
you will come badly unstuck.
That's why I chose it.
I wanted you to feel safe.
I, on the other hand,
could have had a bullet
put in your skull on the drive up here.
But you didn't.
There's always the drive down.
[in Spanish] Thank you.
[Jonathan] Thank you.
[in English] You look older.
[chuckles] Yeah.
Well, I'm certainly wiser.
How's Jed?
Glowing, is she?
I haven't seen her since Cairo.
Well, that's probably best
for her health.
And Angela Burr?
You've spoken to her about all this?
Angela Burr is a coward.
That's a bit harsh.
She made an informed choice.
She lied to me.
So who knows you're here?
- Nobody.
- Oh, bollocks.
[Jonathan] Mm-mmm.
You always have support.
Everyone wants to help Jonathan Pine.
Not this time. I'm alone.
It's just you and me.
Well, if that's true, you're either
very confident or rather desperate.
I have the shipment list.
I know who the arms are being sold to.
I also know
that you're using Aurora,
Teddy's kind hearted charity,
as a front for the recruitment
of young soldiers.
Children to start and fight a rebel war.
And I have Roxana Bolaños ready
to turn state witness to save her skin.
I'm not desperate.
Well, then, what do you want from me?
I want you to hand yourself in.
Bring your collaborators down with you.
Mayra Cavendish,
the British founders, all of them.
And why would I do that?
Because I'm going to
break this operation.
And when I do,
you will have failed to repay
your Syrian debt of 300 million dollars.
And given the kind of people they are,
I don't think you want that.
I'll tell you why I think you're here.
Go ahead.
You've got nothing on me.
Nothing.
I've never even met this Roxana Bolaños.
You can't connect me with Barquero
or the Cabrera operation.
All I am is a name
and not even the right one.
What about Mayra Cavendish?
- The British government?
- Oh.
What do you really have on them?
A piece of paper. No names mentioned.
Page seven in the Guardian,
if you're lucky.
As for me, you'll never get close.
[in Spanish] Thanks.
[in English]
I'm in fortress Colombia now, Jonathan.
And as of yesterday,
the walls just got a little bit thicker.
If you're so confident,
why'd you bother to come?
I hate mess.
I want this cleared out.
I also have
inexplicable affection for you.
Now, look here.
I'm going to make you an offer.
It's a little different to yours,
but in my opinion, it's more achievable.
Alejandro Gualteros is dead.
The impoundment order
will be lifted within the hour.
In a few days, the shipment
will reach its final destination.
And in a few weeks,
the first guns will fire.
Chaos and carnage will ensue.
More guns will be needed.
More money, more young flesh.
You can't prevent it.
So stop trying.
Instead, you leave this restaurant
after our delightful lunch together.
You drive to your safe house,
you pick up the Bolaños girl,
you bring her and the document
you have in your possession to me.
And then you disappear.
In exchange, I wire
Matthew Ellis 50 million dollars.
For real.
Singapore, Zurich, wherever you want.
No one knows you're here.
Start your life again.
[intriguing music]
Why would I do that?
To be a free man.
Jonathan.
You can't tell me that you've
forgotten the beach in Majorca.
I told you then what it takes to see
the chaos and grab your chance.
- I saw the fire in your eyes.
- I was playing a role.
Well, you're always
doing that, aren't you?
Andrew Birch books the table.
Thomas Quince eats the steak.
Matthew Ellis downs the wine.
No, no, no, I…
I struck a chord in you that day.
You crave danger. You need the kick.
Sex with another man's girl.
The smell of death in your nostrils
like napalm in a Turkish valley.
And above all, you need me.
If you came here to win my soul,
you can forget it.
I came here to offer you the world.
It's at your feet.
Just bend down and pick it up.
You can't offer me the world.
You're just a con-man.
Even when you're stretched out stone-cold
dead on a slab of Syrian concrete,
you're lying.
Why should I believe a word you say?
Because you dream of me every night.
Just as I dream of you.
Yesterday, a good man
was murdered in a Medellín wasteland
with a bullet in his skull.
And I failed to stop it.
I won't fail again.
Conscience and shame.
The shackles of slaves.
Conscience is what makes us human.
- Your father teach you that?
- Yes.
Is that what led him to a pointless
death on a street in Belfast?
Blown to bits by his selfless
commitment to service?
That's it. That's it. There.
That's the hot blood of truth.
Go on, Jonathan. Do it!
Stick it right through my heart.
But before you do that, know this.
Your father's values are dying.
Mine are in the ascendant.
My father loved me.
What about yours?
Eight o'clock tomorrow morning.
I'm going to call you on this phone.
You'll agree to hand yourself in.
If you don't,
I will destroy you.
Thanks for the steak.
You are at a fork
in the road, my pilgrim.
Choose carefully.
[intriguing music]
[phone buzzing]
Martín.
Two men. In a black Ford. To your left.
- Did you get it all?
- I think so.
Head to our meeting point.
[Martín] Take the scenic route.
I need some time.
Okay.
[intriguing music]
He's alone. Easy to say goodbye.
[Roper] No.
Follow him.
Find out where he's keeping the girl.
[grunts]
[muffled voices in Spanish]
[sighs]
[in Spanish] Fill up the red car.
Slowly and carefully.
[in English] Your friend Jane called me.
She's still in Medellín.
She's trying to contact
Chief Justice Consuelo Arbenz.
She should have left.
She should be in Europe by now.
It seems you inspire
loyalty, Mr Robinson.
Go back to La Estancia.
Keep listening.
I'll see you in Medellín. Okay?
Okay.
[in Spanish] Men's bathroom.
They're outside, waiting.
At the back.
[in English]
Where the fuck are you going?
No. No. Fuck this.
[tense music]
[in Spanish] Excuse me.
Do you have a light?
I don't speak Spanish.
- [in English] You're tourist here?
- Yeah. Fuck off!
[whistles] Round the back.
He's gone out the window.
[rap music playing on radio]
[phone ringing]
Consuelo Arbenz.
My name is Jane.
I'm a friend of Alejandro Gualteros.
Uh huh.
He was killed because he was
trying to meet with you, Chief Justice.
I know who killed him, and I know why.
[chuckles]
[in Spanish] Thank you, Minister,
for your concern.
Yes, I've been offered
military protection by General Sánchez.
They're with me now.
[in English] Yeah, I can see.
It's because there's a coup being
planned in your country, Consuelo.
And you're going to help me stop it.
[Viktor, in Spanish] Open it.
[seagulls squawking]
[doors opening]
[Teddy, in English] It's all here.
It'll do.
[whistles]
[phone ringing]
[in Spanish] Who's this?
Who the fuck is this?
[Jonathan, in English] You look anxious.
Meet me where we took
the boat trip. 20 minutes.
Come alone and I'll tell you the truth
about Richard Onslow Roper.
[busy signal beeping]
[intriguing music]
[Roper] Fellow called Eduardo dos Santos.
[Sandy] Where did you find him?
[Roper] I just picked
him up along the way.
Wild past,
but loyal.
Like one of these.
[Sandy] Does he know the game?
[Roper] He knows as much as he needs to.
[Sandy] And when all this is over,
what do we do?
You're gonna bring him back with you?
[Roper laughs] Teddy in the Athenaeum.
I dread to think.
No, Teddy's a cowboy.
You should see him on a horse.
A thing of beauty.
He's not fit for civilised company.
[Sandy] Then we can get rid of him.
It's easily done, I imagine.
[Roper] Let's jump that fence
when we come to it, shall we?
- Whoa! Let me explain.
- What the fuck is this?
I recorded this conversation
yesterday afternoon.
Roper is talking to his confidant,
Lord Alexander Langbourne.
You're fucking lying.
Langbourne gave Roper a British passport
and a brochure for a house
in the heart of England.
Extremely beautiful.
But it's not for you.
Did Roper tell you who I am?
I'm a British intelligence agent.
I infiltrated an armed operation he was
running in Cairo in Egypt nine years ago.
I betrayed him to his captors.
I took his money.
That's the money you've been paying back.
From the moment he arrived in Colombia,
he's had one aim,
to settle his debts and get home.
- And he's used you to do it.
- You're lying.
- I'm not lying.
- Shut the fuck up!
- Stop playing with me.
- What did he tell you?
That Barquero was just
the beginning of something bigger?
That you'd rule this continent together?
Is that what he told you?
I know Roper is your father.
- I went to your mother's grave.
- Don't talk about my mother, asshole.
I saw the flower you pay
to be placed on it every month.
I spoke to your sister Clara.
I've been to the monastery
where you were brought up.
Every year you waited
for him in the black car.
You lived for that visit.
Just as you've lived for him ever since.
What the fuck do you want from me?
Play the last file.
[Roper] There's something I want
you to do when you get back.
[Sandy] Sure. Anything in my power.
[Roper] It's Danny.
I want him back with me
at the Oxfordshire house.
I've lost ten years of my boy's life.
- He's away at boarding school.
- Then take him out!
Danny is my family.
He's my only son and heir.
He's mine.
Danny Onslow Roper.
Did Roper tell you about him?
His other son.
Did he? Did he?
- Did Roper tell you about Danny?
- [in Spanish] Just shut up!
[in English] Teddy. Teddy, listen.
- Who the fuck are you?
- Listen. The son he prizes
is sitting in an English
schoolroom right now.
He's used you, Teddy.
Your love and your devotion.
He used you like a dog because
- it's not worth it to keep you alive.
- [in Spanish] Shut up, shut up!
[in English] It's the truth.
This is who he is.
You don't deserve this, Teddy.
No!
[dramatic music]
It's okay, it's okay, it's okay.
It's okay.
[music ends]
When did you last see your sister?
She's been waiting for you.
She's here.
[birds chirping]
[phone buzzing]
[emotional music]
[in Spanish] Eduardo?
Is it really you?
My little brother…
Clara?
I thought I'd never see you again.
[sobs] Where were you?
I'm sorry.
Forgive me.
[emotional music]
You don't know what I've done.
- Forgive me.
- My love.
Forgive me.
[in English] What does he have,
Juan, besides the girl?
What am I not seeing?
[scoffs] Nothing. He's bluffing.
- Revisit every place he's been.
- Come on, Richard.
- We've done it.
- Well, do it again.
Every hotel, shop, restaurant.
[Juan] Okay.
[line ringing]
[Juan speaking Spanish]
[dogs running]
Come on. Come here.
Come here. Good girl. Good girl.
Yes, I know, I know.
[intriguing music]
[glass clinks]
[dog whines]
Good walk today, Juan Miguel?
Yes, sir.
[Roper] Usual route?
[Juan Miguel] Yes, sir. By the woods.
Maximum range to the listener?
It's a supermarket product.
No more than 200 metres.
Find him.
[bell ringing]
[tense music]
Right here, Mr Hanson.
[panting]
[grunts]
[in Spanish] Stop!
[tense music]
Stop! Stop!
[gunshots]
[Teddy, in English]
It's an electromagnetic weapon.
British-made.
José Cabrera's men will drive
the weapon into the middle of Medellín
during the celebrations
of the anniversary of the peace.
When it detonates,
it will plunge the city into darkness.
Chaos.
Homes and hospitals without power.
People will die.
Looting will break out
and the government will be blamed.
And then we will send our army
to restore security in the country.
How will you get
the weapon to José Cabrera?
[Teddy] There is a military base
a few hours from here.
I drive the truck there now.
Tomorrow the weapon will
be dropped by parachute
in Cabrera's camp in the jungle.
[Jonathan sighs]
I need to find a way
to divert that plane.
[Teddy] Only Cabrera can do that.
Okay, well, I need the plane's details.
Anything you can get.
Eduardo.
Be careful.
You too.
- All good?
- [Viktor] Yeah, yeah.
[in Spanish] Let's go.
- [in English] Good.
- [person whistles]
Let's go. [speaks Spanish]
[Juan] Richard!
[tense music]
- [gunshots]
- [dogs whimper]
[birds chirping]
Leave me alone.
Do you not understand
plain fucking English?
I said alone!
[phone ringing]
Is that Teddy?
Answer it.
What the fuck do you want, Roxana?
[dramatic music]
- You okay?
- Yeah.
It was a close call,
but I needed the exercise.
You shouldn't be here.
You should have left.
Yeah, well, I told you,
I'm just not the leaving type.
Where's Teddy?
Teddy's with the cargo.
[Sally] Do you really think
he's gonna come through?
[Jonathan sighs] I don't know.
[speaks Spanish]
- Teddy, how are you?
- All good.
Okay! Gentlemen, let's go!
Unload everything that's in the truck!
And get it on the plane!
[Basil, in English]
It's true. I was on to you.
You've been keeping things from me.
Spinning me half truths.
Treating me like a bloody fool.
So I followed you.
I found this house.
I tricked Adam Holywell.
It wasn't rocket science.
The man's a moron.
I know there's a game on. Colombia.
Arms smuggling, securing mineral
deposits, sponsoring regime change.
What do you know
about Jonathan Pine's plan?
Nothing.
I didn't even know
that prick was still alive.
Whoever lied about his body,
it wasn't me.
I've given my life to this service.
[sighs]
Thank you for your hard work, Basil.
And your sacrifice.
But as I said, sometimes
we have to stand on some heads.
- Game over.
- Mayra, please.
Mayra.
[sighs]
[gun charging]
[gunshot]
[car alarm sounding]
My sister's away for the month,
so we can stay here as long as we need.
Everything go all right?
It's all good.
They're loading the plane now.
It'll be ready to fly tomorrow.
Your phone was switched off at the port.
I know, I'm sorry.
I was doing some paperwork.
Didn't want to be disturbed.
You hungry?
Fats has left you something.
Best thing about Colombia that woman.
[Frisky] Check under every rug and table.
Uh, the lampshade. Check each plant pot,
behind every picture frame.
Juan, down the lavvy.
[Roper] Any joy, Frisky?
Clear so far, boss.
What happened?
Your English friend has been
listening in on the house.
[Frisky] Hey, fellas. Come on.
How could he do that?
I don't know.
I suppose one possibility
is that he followed you here.
Which means he's inside the operation.
What should we do?
You leave that to me.
Don't take it personally.
But when the weather gets rough,
I tighten the ship.
Right, I think I might take a walk.
Just stretch the legs.
Can I walk with you?
No, you get your beauty sleep.
Big day for you tomorrow.
[man] You two guys go across.
Come on, let's go.
[soldiers speaking Spanish]
Get out of here.
Out!
[man, in English] Guys,
I want every inch of this place scoured.
Hey, guys, check this…
[speaks indistinctly]
[intriguing music]
[phone buzzing]
[Sally] Is that him?
[Jonathan] Yeah.
You really did win his heart, didn't you?
Look.
The plane will take off
tomorrow afternoon.
It'll fly to Cabrera's
camp in the jungle.
We have to make sure it never gets there.
[in Spanish] Get out.
Get out!
Come on, move!
[in English] Roxana Bolaños.
My name is Richard Roper.
So I've heard.
My friends call me Dickie.
But you're not one of them.
You could be, if you do me a favour.
But if you try to deceive me,
I will send you back
to your mother in Miami.
And I will send you
there in 31 shoeboxes.
One box a day for a month.
I'm pretty sure we can keep
you alive for at least a week.
[in Spanish] Clear?
Very clear.
[in English] So what do you want?
I want Jonathan Pine.
[Roxana] Well, now I know his name.
Sub extracted from file & improved by
Se7enOfNin9 for addic7ed.com
[intriguing music]