HANHO EMPLOYEE OF THE YEAR
What is it now?
Dad won’t give me
the gallery in Cheongdam-dong.
So annoying.
So what?
I told you not to wear that tie clip!
Good morning, boss.
What?
About the Jungwoon district mall,
we got rid of most of the tenants,
but the carpenter’s shop is holding out.
Mr. Choe...
You’ve been doing this for how long?
It's been 21 years since I started out
in liquor distribution.
You haven't forgotten what we're about
now that we're wearing a tie, have you?
-Mr. Bang.
-Yes, boss.
Take the boys and wrap up
the Jungwoon case.
Right away.
Is something wrong, sir?
Of course not.
I’m going to go for a smoke.
Told you there are plenty here
to use as weapons.
Pros need professional gear.
Mr. Kim Jong-gi?
Hand up.
This is illegal.
I can exercise my right to retention.
You can discuss your rights
with the boss later.
All I need is a signature from you
and we can all go out to lunch.
I’ll count to three.
One...
Two...
Three.
Look who it is!
If it isn't brother Jang!
Aren’t you more used to gukbap?
I need to grease my intestines too,
every now and then.
Why are you here eating by yourself?
Where’s your wife?
That's none of your business, Mr. Yang.
Hand over the rights
to Chungdo Precision to me.
I worked on that place
for six whole months.
Not because Osung Logistics
didn’t work out for you?
What is it?
Do you want to get down and dirty
in the age of IT?
You went to a good school,
why not be more civil?
So what?
What?
You smart prick.
But you know what?
The word "IT" sounds so tacky
coming out of your mouth.
You son of a bitch.
Do you still see me
as your ass-kissing lackey?
You couldn’t even wax my shoe properly.
Do you think you can handle me?
Of course not.
Who can handle that mug of yours?
No one can.
Let’s go have some gukbap!
Yes, it’s me.
Will Chungdo Precision be okay with it?
With private funding,
we will have the controlling stake.
I heard Dong-cheol's men
were working on the Chungdo case.
We were there first.
He won't be able
to say a thing when we make the move.
Don’t forget.
Gangsters always live
with a knife to their necks.
It took us 18 years to get this far.
Congratulations, sir.
"Congratulations"?
It's too early for that.
Where are you going, sir?
To receive grace.
HOPE DINER
My, my.
Aren’t you a bit overdressed
to be having mackerel ramen?
A young woman ran this shop
ten years ago, has it changed owners?
She’s dead.
Eat up, kiddo. Okay?
Check, please.
Why haven't you eaten?
Doesn't it taste
just like you remember it?
Just let me pay.
You don’t like eating alone, is that it?
How do you not have anyone
-to eat with at your age?
-What? I’ll be right there.
It's so sad.
How much is it?
Ma’am, I’m really sorry
but I've lost my wallet.
That’s okay.
This gentleman will pay for it.
What?
-Take care.
-I’m in a rush.
-Thank you!
-Don’t worry, see you.
-Get going!
-Hey!
-Hey, you!
-Take care, kiddo.
Sir, are you ready to pay?
That will be 10,000 won per dish,
totaling 50,000 won.
How can you charge 10,000 won
for a bowl of ramen?
And how is it 50,000 won?
That fat son of a...
I'll make it up to you later
with a little gift.
A successful man such as yourself
can afford to be generous.
HOPE DINER
I’m never coming back to this shithole.
It’s me.
Did you look into Dong-cheol's gang?
Jeez, where am I?
Right, something fell on me
and I fainted...
Kid.
What? What kid?
Are you awake?
What’s she saying?
Why is she calling me a kid?
-What the...?
-Don’t force yourself to speak.
I'll go get the doctor.
-You’re up?
-What? You know me?
Are you okay, kid?
Who are they calling a "kid"?
What the hell?
Why am I lying here?
You there.
You shouldn’t be walking around like that.
Please return to your room.
Your father’s on his way,
-so please wait.
-My father's dead.
-Dong-hyun!
-There he is.
-Who's the baldy?
Son, I thought you would never wake up!
-"Son"?
-I was so worried.
Are you okay?
Please, Dong-hyun.
What are they...?
This is a mirror...
I don’t believe this.
Amnesia?
Yes.
It looks like he's suffering
from retrograde amnesia.
Does that affect his speech pattern?
His tone of speech has changed completely.
Brain injuries sometimes cause patients
to mistake their identity.
Their behavior and speech patterns
could change in such cases.
It’s Dad, don't you recognize me?
Let go! How many times do I have
to tell you that I'm not your son?
What’s with my voice?
What was his personality like before?
Well, he liked to eat.
But he never got into fights.
-Gentle?
-Yes.
A high school student?
That’s okay.
-This gentleman will pay for it.
-What?
Could he be the kid from...
And...
I'll make it up to you later
with a little gift.
That old fart?
What the...?
I'm telling you, that diner
went out of business a long time ago.
I ate ramen here yesterday.
How many times do I have to tell you?
Was it that good?
Is that why you're asking?
Around 5 p.m. yesterday, a 17-year-old
high school student jumped off a building
and fell on a man in his forties, causing
the man to go into a vegetative state.
It seems that Mr. Jang is in a coma
after being crushed by a falling kid.
Jang Pan-su?
Incredible!
That damn woman...
Where the hell has she gone now?
Damn it.
This is my favorite necklace.
Its ring is broken.
Jeez...
Who are you?
Yes, I am...
I’m Pan-su.
Your husband Jang Pan-su.
-You're not going to believe it,
-Stay back!
-but I’ll explain everything.
-Please take a seat.
-Police!
Will you listen to me?
-What are you doing?
-Get away from me!
I’m really Pan-su.
I’ll prove it, so put that down.
If you’re Pan-su,
then I’m your mom, you fatso!
How did you know the door passcode?
Did you escape from a looney bin?
I’ll explain everything, so put that down.
No way! Stay back!
Han Suh-yeon!
Listen to me!
Hold still!
Let me go! This is my home!
Don’t move!
ARRESTED FOR BREAKING AND ENTERING
Why did you break into that house?
Were you going to steal some food?
Listen, Copper. What did you just--
Wait! Dong-hyun!
My son may be big-boned,
but he’s not the type
to steal other people’s food.
He's not himself lately
because he injured his head recently.
He must’ve mistaken the place
for our home, right?
We're releasing him with just a warning,
since he's a minor.
We won't let him off easy next time.
Of course! My apologies.
I’ll teach him properly.
Dong-hyun, come on. Sorry, officer.
Come out, you bastard.
This doesn’t work.
I got it.
Huh? I'm sorry.
Hey, prick! What are you doing to my boss?
It’s not what you think.
Then what?
Did Mr. Yang send you?
You son of a... Wait a minute.
You fat... It’s you!
You fat ass!
You crushed my boss with your fat ass!
So savage!
Bring my boss back! Wake him up!
I understand how you feel.
Let go.
Don't order me around, you brat!
What’s going on?
This is an ICU!
We'll talk later.
Hey! Fat ass!
If I catch you again,
I’ll smoke and grill you!
APARTMENT A
Come in.
Thank you for your hospitality.
I’ll leave as soon as I find
a place of my own.
This is your home, Dong-hyun.
Why do you keep saying
that you're going to leave?
Do you have a job?
What?
I used to.
I'm working part-time
at a grocery store for now.
Wait.
You should take better care of yourself.
Go ahead and eat, son.
I have to eat all of this by myself?
It's only half of what you eat usually,
but I can cook more if you want.
You must be mistaken.
I don’t eat instant or junk food.
Give it a try.
These are your favorites.
Here, for the sake of my effort.
What’s wrong?
See? You love it.
I love that you eat so well, my dear son.
It's greasy.
Get some sleep
and we’ll go to school tomorrow.
School?
I have to go and find out
what actually happened.
I'm not going to let
something like this slide.
How dare they do this to my son.
Mr. Vice-principal.
Hello.
Good to meet you, I’m Jang...
I mean, Kim Dong-hyun.
Dong-hyun injured his head.
I see.
-Please sit down.
-Yes, sir.
Dong-hyun, over here.
I’ve been told that Dong-hyun
can’t remember what happened that day.
Did something happen at school?
He’s not someone
who would attempt suicide.
Maybe he had a reason--
Are you implying that
other students did something to him?
Well, who knows?
Mr. Kim.
I’ve told the police already...
nothing like that happened.
Hey, I’ll look into it.
Why don't you go home, old man?
What?
Vice-principal, right?
I'll be returning to class
starting from today.
Quiet!
Dong-hyun’s not fully himself
due to the accident,
so please help him out until he recovers.
Yes, ma’am.
Go take a seat.
Do you know how hard I had it
while you were away?
All right. Open your books.
Jae-ik, share your book with Dong-hyun.
Page 111.
What does "adjust" mean here?
To alter or adapt, right?
Then the correct answer is D.
Imagine how I feel.
Where’s mine?
-So cute.
-What a cutie.
It’s Hyun-jung.
Why aren't you eating?
-Too bland?
-It’s not good enough for her.
That looks delicious.
Now it's properly seasoned. Try it.
-Go on, try it.
-Eat.
She's got such a poker face.
There's no reaction at all.
Stop it. Please.
-"Stop it."
-"Please."
-Sorry. My bad.
-Look at her.
Hey, you kids.
Let me eat in peace.
So, eat, fatso!
-Why is he asking for our permission?
-Unbelievable.
He must be really hungry.
Is this for real?
This loser must have lost his mind
because of his injury.
"Loser"?
Should I help you remember?
Hey!
What are you doing over there?
Those bastards.
See me after school.
Wow, he really came.
-Go easy on him, Tae-wook.
-Don’t kill him.
Who are you?
"Who are you"?
Are you sure you don’t remember anything?
Why are you talking like an old man?
Hey.
Nothing’s changed, so listen carefully.
Come see me every break time.
Bring me a burger and strawberry milk.
Could it be that I was,
as you kids like to call it,
a "delivery boy" or something like that?
Has something happened between us?
Do you need a beating?
Maybe that will help you remember!
-You bastard!
-Sorry.
I don’t like getting hit.
You crazy bastard!
Not again! Damn it!
Wait!
I have a question.
Did this Dong-hyun kid...
do anything to personally offend you?
Listen to this guy.
There’s no such a thing, you fat ass!
So...
That means...
-he was an easy target?
-Yeah.
You're not just easy.
You are way too fucking easy!
Do you understand now?
Did you start getting boxing lessons?
You've become so healthy suddenly.
Hey, Dong-hyun!
Are you okay?
-Are you okay?
-I’m fine.
-You bastard!
-Hey! Stop!
Let me go!
You rat.
You saw everything yesterday, right?
I didn’t see anything.
Do you want to die, you prick?
I’ll kill you if you’re lying.
Hey.
He’s got quite a package.
Let’s strip him down
and film him for insurance.
That’s a good idea.
No, please!
This isn’t what friends do to each other!
What did this idiot say?
Strip him.
Hold still now.
-Here we go.
-Wait a minute!
-Don’t move.
-Please don’t!
Dong-hyun.
Give it back, you fat ass!
What?
Give it back while I'm telling you nicely.
Is there something I shouldn’t see?
Give it to me!
Are you all right?
I’ll return it tomorrow.
What do we do?
You promise? Tomorrow!
This is Kim Dong-hyun,
how about a comment?
I just have to return the shoe, right?
Yes.
We won’t bother Hyun-jung again.
I promise.
But you have to walk all the way
down that rail to get her shoe.
Then it’s mission clear.
-What the...?
-What's she doing here?
Dong-hyun! Stop!
He’s going to get your shoe back.
It’s too dangerous!
-"It’s too dangerous!"
-It's not dangerous.
And I was right below?
Did I tell you to delete the video or not?
That loser won’t do anything.
Hey, kiddos!
You fat ass, give me my phone!
It was an interesting video.
So what?
Are you going to tell the cops?
It seems you've got some crazy ideas
since you hurt your head.
I’m not a big fan of cops either.
Nor am I a fan of poking my nose
in other people’s affairs.
Other people’s affairs?
I made a copy, as insurance.
Stay out of my sight from now on.
Got it?
They're finally here!
Damn, I almost died waiting!
Mrs. Jang! Good evening.
Mr. Yang?
Mr. Choe. How have you been?
You forgot to zip up.
Just kidding.
What are you trying to pull?
Hey, bring me the goods.
My boys took a lot of photos of you two,
so I was going to send them
to Chairman Han.
This is nasty.
You didn't have to go that far.
You know how much the chairman
hates affairs and stuff like that.
He’s got a strange moral compass.
What should I do with this?
What is it that you want?
Who ordered you to guard him?
You fat ass!
Didn’t I tell you I would grill you?
Do you want to be marinated?
-You little...
-Bang Man-cheol.
Age 43.
Went to Samil High School
and Dongbang Community College.
Began working for the Hanho Group
on October 21, 2001.
Promoted to supervisor
in February 2004. Currently single.
How did you know?
Because I’m Jang Pan-su.
What a load of bull,
my boss is over there.
That scar on your eye.
Stabbed with a broken bottle
on my behalf at 11 p.m., March 21, 2005.
Received 20 stitches at Jinsung Hospital,
costing me 385,200 won.
How did you...?
It seems that I've received
the wrong kind of grace.
MALL SPACE FOR SALE AND RENT
You sure eat a lot.
My appetite won’t die down.
-What is it?
-Those eyes...
You really are my boss.
My apologies.
When else would I ever get the chance
to touch your face?
Why are you guarding me every day
when no one's ordered you to?
There’s a rumor that Mr. Yang
is planning to move in on us.
They say that he's after your life.
Don’t worry.
I’ll return to my body.
No matter what.
But you shouldn’t.
What?
You obtained a fresh new body.
Having to serve in the military again
is a drawback,
but it’s better than being stuck
in a vegetative state.
Put that down.
Meet us at Burger Prince
after seventh period, okay?
The one at the intersection.
We have some proposals.
Sorry, but I have
a student council meeting today.
We have plenty of time. We can wait.
Just be there before midnight.
I can’t keep you waiting like that.
-Of course, you can.
-We’re good at waiting.
Could you step aside?
She can’t get through.
-Go ahead.
-She stinks the entire hallway
whenever she walks by.
-What?
-Stop it.
It’s nothing.
I’m going to quit school
so find me a place to stay.
Right away, boss?
I figured out what happened,
so I don't have any reason to be here.
And the boy’s father is a bit too much.
You should stay there a little longer.
You should enjoy youth
and the school meals, too.
What the hell?
Hey, kiddo!
Take this.
Do you blame me or something?
I told you not to get involved.
You didn't need to butt in.
I’m sorry
but I don’t remember it too well.
Hyun-jung!
Where did you go
after skipping class yesterday?
You didn’t even come by to eat.
I don't want to be caught eating at a bar.
You can come eat before
the customers come in.
HYUN-JUNG'S TENT BAR
Mi-sun?
Wait, are you Dong-hyun?
Hey, I haven't seen you in a while.
Why don't you come over more often?
You've become more handsome.
He injured his head recently
and lost his memory.
You should get going.
Come over for a meal.
Mi-sun, what are you doing here?
Have you...
lost your manners?
How dare you call an adult
by their first name?
He injured his head, he’s not himself!
That has nothing to do with manners!
You little brat!
How dare you call me by my first name?
Run! Scram!
Mi-sun...
is Hyun-jung’s mom?
SPECIAL: MACKEREL RAMEN
You are just asking
for a beating, aren't you?
You have a foul mouth
for a future newscaster, don't you?
Hey, there’s...
-something in your hair.
-Ouch!
What are you doing?
Dong-hyun grabbed Hyun-jung’s hair.
I’m sorry.
Is there a feud between the class losers?
PATERNITY TEST RESULTS
99.999% POSITIVE
It’s too dangerous!
She’s my daughter?
Hyun-jung?
According to science, it's 99.9% positive.
She is definitely your daughter.
It may not be the right time,
but would it be okay
if I congratulated you?
Looks like our caramel macchiato
and mango-banana frappuccino are ready.
Damn it.
Is something wrong?
-Shit!
-What is it?
Where is it?
Hey, Oh Hyun-jung!
Hey!
Did you steal my lip stain?
It wasn’t me.
I left it in my locker earlier.
You were the only one left
in the classroom during gym class.
No use looking for it now, Yun-ji.
Anything she touches rots.
-I stole it!
-What?
I’ve always wanted one, so I took it.
You stole it?
He really did go crazy.
Then show me.
I tried it on and tossed it away.
It wasn’t really my color.
This idiot...
is a pervert.
What’s going on? Back to your seats.
Turn to page 206.
"Invasion of Japan and
the Deployment of National Defenses."
Japan had won the First Sino-Japanese War.
Four targets.
Break each of their limbs.
Show no mercy.
But boss...
I don’t think this is right.
Minors aren’t my field of expertise.
So, you refuse to do it?
I think you should consult
with her directly.
My daughter is being picked on?
Because of me?
Not just because of you.
There's her grades and other things, too.
It's complicated.
I should call her teacher--
From the looks of things,
teachers seemed to be ignoring it
to avoid any problems.
Then...
what am I supposed to do?
I came here to ask if you had any ideas.
Gosh.
It’s all my fault.
I shouldn’t have raised her
as a single mother.
Jang Pan-su, that bastard!
That bastard.
I hope he rots in hell.
He probably has no idea
what his daughter is going through.
He's a piece of trash.
Well, then.
I'll just try to deal with it myself.
You?
I'll try to engage in an open conversation
with the kids at school.
Perhaps that will help.
Are you telling me that
Pan-su embezzled three billion won?
See for yourself, Dad.
TRANSACTION RECORD
TOTAL: 3,035,000,000 WON
Hey.
What can I do...
to become close with my daughter?
I’m still single.
Right.
I think physical affection
could be the best solution.
It would be good to do something
that would make the mind and body strong.
Is that so?
By the way, boss.
You should work on your appearance a bit.
Before you return to your body,
you could die from diabetes
and high blood pressure.
Doors closing.
It was you?
You told my mom to send me here?
What do you mean?
I just came here to lose weight.
I can’t do this with you here.
I’m going to leave.
Says who?
I am your trainer, Master Bang Man-cheol.
Could I...
just get a refund?
Shut your mouth, girl!
There are no refunds,
no absence and no mercy at this gym!
You won’t get away with this.
I sure will.
Keep your eyes wide open.
That's not it!
Look.
Your waist! Use your waist!
Shut up and go away.
Do it right!
Come in. Good!
Keep going!
Are you okay?
KIM DONG-HYUN
Is that really Dong-hyun?
-It's really him.
-He's so handsome.
Why do you have to eat ramen at my place?
I’m starving to death, okay?
Wait here for a bit.
Sure.
MY CHILD CAN BE HAPPY WITHOUT A DAD
WOULD WE BE HAPPY
IF HE WERE HERE...?
We’re having steak tonight.
I'll be home soon, my son!
Jong-gi!
Did you make some money?
Don’t hit his face.
-What’s that?
-Please, give me a little more time.
But we don't have any time to spare.
Hey, muscle heads!
Muscle heads?
Aren't you a brave little kid?
Who are you?
And you?
Hey, kid.
This man's got a loan
he needs to pay back.
Why don't you go on home?
What is this, the eighties?
This is so old-fashioned.
Dong-hyun. Go home, okay?
He's your son?
Hey. Come here.
-You come here.
-"You come here"?
Dong-hyun, listen to me!
Go home!
How did you raise him? He has no manners.
You're the one with no manners.
I’ve had it with this prick.
Damn kid!
Why, you little...
Dong-hyun! No! Please!
Dong-hyun, no! Please don't!
Get the kid.
Get off me!
Kick that little shit!
That’s enough! Stop!
What a tenacious little prick.
I’m going to give you exactly one week.
Call me when you have my 80 million won.
Got it?
EVERGREEN FINANCE
You can get off me now.
They’re gone.
Mister, can you hear me?
Hey.
Hey. Mr. Kim.
Wake up!
Who are you?
-Do you have a boyfriend?
-What?
Close your eyes.
What’s with the commotion?
Which one of you is Choe Dong-gu?
Hand up.
That’d be me, who the hell are you?
Hand.
You have a client named Kim Jong-gi.
Yes.
Let’s lighten his debt a bit.
It’s not a small amount,
we can’t just erase it.
Have you never used a White-Out in school?
If he owes you eighty million
including interest after two years,
he must have borrowed
about five million to begin with, right?
Yes, you are indeed correct.
But still, that's...
I take it you've heard of Mr. Jang Pan-su
of Hanho Partners?
Of course, I have.
But what about him?
Kim Jong-gi is his father.
I see!
What?
It’s okay.
Just accept it as it is.
But that doesn’t...
What’s this? This is amazing!
Incredible!
How are you feeling?
Your father passed out
while being beaten up.
Couldn't you have at least
taken me to the hospital?
I got a call from the loan sharks.
They told me to forget the interest
and just pay back the principal.
Looks like my defensive strategy worked.
So what?
Hey, son!
Don’t lose too much weight.
You’re handsome just as you are.
This is hot!
Hot!
So hot!
The teacher's coming.
-Damn it.
-Sorry.
Screw that. My lunch is all rotten now.
My gosh.
Now it reeks of Hyun-jung.
Want a new plate?
Forget it.
What if it’s not rotten?
What?
Do you want to bet 100,000 won?
Here, you try it first.
What did you just say, you loser?
Are you nuts?
Stop trying to act tough, you loser.
Do you really want to mess up
your school life that bad?
It doesn’t matter.
It’s messy enough already.
But I’d like to change that.
Damn it!
Dig in.
I’m treating you for helping Hyun-jung
at school.
This is...
It’s mackerel ramen. I hope you like it.
I used to have this a lot with someone.
It’s great. You should put this
on the menu.
No way.
It reminds me of him.
"Him"?
Hyun-jung’s dad.
Did things end badly with him?
I still have regrets
when I think about him.
What regrets?
I regret not having  killed him.
I’m sorry.
Actually, you remind me
of him quite a bit.
He used to wipe everything down.
I’ll pack you a few dishes
so you can have them with your dad.
Yes. Thank you.
Ma’am!
-A bottle of soju, please.
-Sure thing.
Where have you been?
I had a guest.
I was saying...
Here you go.
Hey!
You still have a firm ass!
What was that?
Ma’am, is this your son?
Your mom is pretty, so I touched her.
Do you have a death wish?
How dare you bark at a paying customer!
Don’t you want to make money?
Don’t yell at the boy!
You bitch!
Let him go!
Dong-hyun.
Go inside. I’ll take care of this.
You go home, all right?
You two are so sweet, aren't you?
Mi-sun, are you okay?
Get in the kitchen. Now.
-You...
-Listen to me.
You little prick.
Why don't you just head home quietly
if you've had enough to drink?
You worthless good-for-nothing.
Look at this punk.
You prick!
You grabbed my woman’s hair?
Who are you?
Are you sleeping with her?
Stop it, please!
You’ll kill him!
Who are you?
Who on earth are you?
Why do you keep calling me Mi-sun?
You expect me to believe that?
You switched bodies
because of an accident?
Yes, I have to admit
that the way you talk and act
remind me of someone.
But that doesn’t mean you’re Jang Pan-su.
You have a small peach-shaped
mole next to your belly button.
What?
Do you want me to go into
even more intimate details?
Wait.
At which restaurant did we first meet?
Arpeggio in Yeonnam-dong.
You ordered a caffe latte
and I ordered a Bud.
Where did we break up?
The cafe in Sinsa Hotel.
You came to see me for the last time,
and you ordered a lemon tea.
Are you...
really Jang Pan-su?
Yes.
Why didn’t you tell me you were pregnant?
-I'm sorry but she’s not your child.
-I already did a paternity test.
That’s exactly what Pan-su would do.
It's my turn to ask now.
Why did you show up here out of the blue?
Our relationship ended years ago.
Did you think you could move me
by kicking out a few drunks?
No matter what, you're still...
a gangster.
And let's get this straight.
I did not raise your child.
I raised my own kid.
You don’t deserve to be a father.
Leave.
-Mi-sun, listen--
-Get out!
Should I call the police?
You never answered my calls.
You even moved.
You said you couldn’t live
with a criminal.
Of course!
What kind of woman
wants her man to be a criminal?
That’s why.
I told you that we weren't meant to be.
I’m getting married next month,
to my boss's daughter.
What?
Leave memories in the past.
No need to get pathetic and worked up.
Pan-su.
I’m leaving.
Did you say something
to offend my mom again?
She told me to stay away from you.
I've made some mistakes.
I've let your mother down.
You called her
by her first name again, didn't you?
You’re Oh Hyun-jung, right?
Well, yes.
Do you want to come to my birthday party
at my family villa this weekend?
I wanted to throw a big party with friends
before we became seniors.
I can come?
Of course!
I’ll take that as a yes
and call you later.
Let’s go.
Is that someone you like?
No way.
He must be, you're blushing.
No way!
I’m off.
PLEASE, SEE ME
I'M BEGGING YOU
-You came.
-Well, happy birthday.
Thank you.
Shall we?
Hey, hi.
-Bring us some when they're done.
-Sure. Wait inside.
When is he going to get here?
What took you so long?
You promised me
I would get weekends off.
Hey.
Whine again and I’ll call Cheol-ho.
Leave that here and piss off.
Hyun-jung must be so excited right now.
She will be happy that she's been invited.
She’s so clueless, that stupid bitch.
She deserves it.
You came.
What would you like?
Anything.
She'll have a caffe latte
and I'll have a bottle of Bud.
May I see your ID?
I’ll take the Bud
and he'll have a glass of orange juice.
Sure.
Why did you want to see me?
Well...
I understand that no matter what I say,
it's difficult for you to forgive me.
But...
I want you to know
that I sincerely regret
what I did...
and that I'm sorry
for what happened between us.
If it wasn’t for this...
If this unbelievable thing
hadn't happened,
would you still have apologized?
Would you have even looked for me?
You were fine without me until now.
I thought I was...
just someone in your past
that you wanted to forget about.
Mi-sun.
How is this going to change anything?
You’re a married man!
He looks so young though.
I just...
Don’t make me feel even more miserable.
Mi-sun, I was--
You bastard!
Mi-sun, please. Listen to me.
Just once. Please?
I’m sorry, I really am.
How dare you kiss me?
Do I look that easy to you?
I'm so mad right now.
Come. Let’s go to the police.
Wait. There's no need for that.
KIM JAE-IK
What is it?
I just heard something fishy.
Hyun-jung may be in trouble.
Where?
We’ll have to go to the station later.
I've got an urgent matter.
Hey!
Man-cheol?
Get me a car as soon as possible.
Dong-hyun, I don't think
we should be driving as minors.
Shut up and give me the directions.
Is this the right way?
Damn it. This is the way...
but Cheol-ho will kill me.
You'll be better off with him than me.
-Are you okay?
-Don’t!
Drink up!
Quiet down.
Here.
Drink.
Bottoms up.
No, thanks, I don’t drink.
You can’t back out now.
Everyone’s watching, save me some face.
What's that got to do with me drinking?
We put on this party for you,
so don’t disappoint us.
Just go with the flow, okay?
What do you mean?
God damn it.
Listen.
Why would anyone invite a loser like you?
Cheol-ho recommended someone
who wouldn’t cause any problems.
You piece of trash.
-Who do you think you are?
-You bitch.
Don’t you know who his father is?
Forget it.
Can I help you?
This is a members only--
Did you see that?
Listen to me.
What the hell?
-Dong-hyun!
-Who's this?
Who are you?
And you?
We were just having some fun, weren't we?
Let’s go. You shouldn't be here.
Where do you think you're going?
The party's just getting started,
she can’t leave now.
Boys.
Dong-hyun!
Just stand back and watch.
Bunch of little brats.
Did you lose your brain as well
after bumping your head?
Guys.
Get him.
He’s a damn maniac!
How was it?
My punch is a little better, huh?
How cute.
You.
Try me.
Cheol-ho! Get it together!
I’m fine, I just slipped.
Oh, no!
He’s so cool.
Son of a bitch!
Take better care of yourself.
Let me go, you bastard!
Do you want to die?
What? Are you going to hit me?
Try me, asshole.
You crazy bitch.
Help me!
I can’t swim! Help!
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Well done. Let’s get out of here.
THE PYEONAHN HOSPITAL
What’s this?
By the chairman’s order,
no one is allowed inside.
Everyone thinks that
you got into an accident
while trying to embezzle
three billion won.
Your wife is siding with Mr. Yang.
What should I do?
Hyun-jung told me everything.
How are you feeling?
I'm fine.
How is Hyun-jung?
If you’re so worried about her,
please leave...
Forever.
Mi-sun.
What exactly can you do
for her in that body?
What if she figures it out?
All right.
I’ll do that.
What do you want?
Did you come to see Hyun-jung?
Why? Are you here to get her back?
No, it’s not like that.
I just wanted to apologize to you both.
Are you going out with her by any chance?
Are you nuts?
We’re not like that.
In that case...
what about me?
Are you asking me to date
a high school chick?
You’re in high school too.
My answer is no.
Go home and study.
Here.
Bye.
What's got into her?
DONG-HYUN, I LIKE YOU
FROM YOON-JI
What are you doing here?
What were you talking to Yoon-ji about?
It was nothing.
Did she ask you out?
-It’s nothing like that.
-Are you going to go out with her?
I don’t want to go to jail in my forties.
Who's in their forties?
Forget it. I won’t ever date her.
-Then go out with me.
-Hey!
Didn’t you like me all along?
Why were you so nice to me--
I’m asking you out.
I want your answer before the weekend.
You asked who out now?
Dong-hyun.
I thought you liked him.
Are you insane?
No! Never! Not in a million years!
He’s a weirdo, don’t even think about it!
I told you he saved me at the party.
He risked his life to rescue me.
Hyun-jung.
Baby, please.
Listen to me, this is all wrong.
Tell me why I can’t.
He takes care of me like a real father.
That’s exactly why!
I grew up without a dad.
I can’t even get to have a boyfriend
who’s like a dad?
Will you just listen to me?
What exactly did you do
to make her ask you out?
It’s a misunderstanding,
I only wanted to be nice to her.
Does it feel good to ruin
our lives completely?
Mi-sun.
Leave at once, and don’t ever come back.
If you ever show up around Hyun-jung,
I'll kill you, then I'll kill myself.
What do I have to do
to have you forgive me?
If there was a way, I would have already.
Even if I did forgive you,
you're a married man. Did you forget?
Married?
What do you mean?
Hyun-jung.
What did you mean?
About forgiving and marriage.
Why are you two talking about such things?
Hyun-jung.
I’m sorry.
I love Mi-sun, I mean...
I love your mom.
What?
That’s not it, Hyun-jung.
Listen to me.
Is this why you were mad
when I said I asked him out?
Hyun-jung.
It's disgusting.
Hyun-jung!
Jang Pan-su.
Why did you say that?
What’s done is done,
and this is much better
than dating my own daughter.
What?
You crazy bastard!
How could you even say that, you bastard?
Are you out of your god damn mind?
Can I help you?
What the hell?
Jang Pan-su.
It’s a good day to die, isn't it?
Look at him, he's grown a beard.
You should’ve led a good life.
Because you lived a fucked-up life,
you've fucked yourself up in the end.
Pan-su.
Don’t blame me for this.
Seeing how we only live once...
I’ll give you a comfortable farewell.
Mister, your zipper’s down.
What?
What? Pan-su!
There.
Dong-hyun?
You've come at the right time.
I made you a special...
Dad.
I became a strange man. What do I do, Dad?
Don’t call me Dad! Who are you?
I’m your son, Dong-hyun! Kim Dong-hyun!
You must have the wrong house.
This isn’t your home.
Wait, you are...
Mr. Jang?
I’m Dong-hyun!
I have no memories
since I fell off that roof!
What do I do, Dad?
-Stay back! Please!
-Dad!
Don’t come near me!
Dad!
-What is it?
-Dad!
Get out of here!
What in the world? How did you wake up?
You look like someone.
Wait. Are you me?
But I lost so much weight.
Damn it. Yes, I'm you.
Well...
is my body all right?
Dad! Thief!
He stole my body!
Call the police!
Jeez.
Why did you...
He was injured because of you.
Why did you hit him?
I’m sorry. My son injured his head.
-Why did you hit me?
-Be quiet and just sit down.
I’ll explain everything.
That’s impossible.
So, what you’re saying is
that this man is you
and that you are this man.
Right.
Does that mean I have to live out
the rest of my life as an old man?
Daddy.
Yes, sir! Go on.
I don’t know what will happen next.
I'm a victim, too.
You gained 30 years of your life
but I just lost 30 years of my life.
This is so unfair.
Unfair?
Listen, kiddo.
Who do you think
lost all your weight for you?
-Am I wrong?
-That’s true.
Whose side are you on, Dad?
My apologies, sir.
Stop talking funny. It’s me, Dong-hyun!
I’ll get used to it eventually.
Wait a minute.
You expect me to believe all this?
You two are playing a trick on me,
aren't you?
Sit back down. I'm not finished.
You little...
-Dad, sit.
-Yes, sir.
When I had measles at six,
we were both hospitalized
because you crashed your bicycle.
I got a glass shard stuck in my throat
when I was in third grade
and you pulled it out and saved my life.
I remember, sir.
I’m your son, Dong-hyun.
You named me yourself.
-Are you
-Dad.
-really my son, sir?
How in the world did this happen?
Dad.
You smoke, right? I have so much mucus!
You have a wart on your ass.
It hurts whenever I sit.
Anyhow...
I need you to help me.
What now?
You like Hyun-jung, right?
If you help me out...
I'll help you date her.
When I woke up, he was already gone.
How could you screw up like that?
You said you’d take care of it!
Hey!
Do I look like your husband to you?
Watch your mouth.
If he goes to see Dad...
I have my men searching for him,
so go get the money like I told you to!
I shouldn’t have listened
to that greedy pig.
How dare she?
Got it.
They've found a cab driver
who has just driven Mr. Jang.
Mi-sun.
What’s happened?
When he woke up,
we returned to our own bodies.
I’m Dong-hyun now...
and this man is the real Pan-su.
Your bodies swapped back?
This man, I mean... The kid is right.
I’m really sorry.
I want to apologize with all my heart.
I’ve never, once in my life...
forgotten about you.
What are you...
I've been looking all over the place.
Who are you?
Jang Pan-su.
You've bitten off more than you can chew.
Tie them up together
and toss them in the ocean.
Yes, boss.
Excuse me. One moment, please.
What is it?
Do you have any last words?
Don’t kill us.
I just woke up, I can’t die like this.
Who are you people anyway?
He must have a screw loose
from being hospitalized for too long.
-You two get in the kitchen.
-Yes.
What’s this?
What are you going to do by yourself?
Hold on!
Make sure she doesn’t get out.
-Yes, sir.
-Wait.
Ma’am, stay here. They are really scary.
I'm scared, too. This way.
What a load of shit.
Boys.
Bring them out.
Who is this punk?
You still talk too much, Mr. Yang.
Mr. Yang?
How dare you talk like that to an adult.
You should watch your mouth, you prick.
-So what?
-"So what?"
I've heard that somewhere.
Who the hell are you?
I'm obviously a high school student.
Got a problem?
High school?
Which grade and class?
Enough with the census. Come at me.
There isn't much time
before the bar opens for business.
He's driving me nuts.
What are you standing around for?
Take care of this brat.
Hey, Mr. Jo!
Where’s Mr. Jo?
Is he sleeping?
Hey, Mr. Gwak.
Not bad.
Take off your tie, asshole.
-Boys.
-Yes, sir!
Ma’am, don’t! Please, stay put.
Let’s wrap this up.
Didn't I tell you to take off your tie?
What?
Hey.
You.
Hey!
Watch this, Pan-su!
I shouldn’t be killing minors, damn it.
Stop!
Don’t hurt him!
Shit.
He’s the father of my child.
He's your child?
He's the father of my child!
If you touch him...
we all die together.
Shit.
I’m going to count to five.
If you don’t leave by then,
we die together.
You better start running
if you want to live.
Hey, lady!
If you light that, you die too.
Do I look like I’m afraid to die?
This asshole destroyed my life.
Even now, I’m just hanging on by a thread.
Why? You don't believe me?
Did you think I was fine without you?
Why do you think I had Hyun-jung?
God damn it.
I wanted to at least have a child
who resembled you!
I gave you a chance,
but you still left me.
What is she saying?
Did you think a word of apology
would change all that after all this time?
She’s completely crazy.
Did she just say that
she had this kid’s child?
If you want to live...
get out of my bar.
One!
Wait!
Stop it, you son of a bitch!
You’re no different!
Two!
Three!
We better leave, boss!
But Jang Pan-su is still in there!
Four!
No!
Mi-sun.
Are you okay?
Ma’am, I smell gas in here.
I feel dizzy.
Stay back.
I have something to say to him.
-Mi-sun.
-I know!
But...
the man I used to love
is that Jang Pan-su over there.
So please...
I’ve waited so long.
Jang Pan-su.
Watching Hyun-jung grow to resemble you
more and more each day...
I missed you so much...
every time I saw her face.
You can’t even imagine how much.
One year turned into ten...
And finally, after 17 years
we see each other again.
I've aged a lot, haven't I?
Thank you.
Yes.
This is the face.
Did you want to see me, Dad?
Do you know what I detest the most?
What?
Someone who holds a knife
against their own family.
Dear Chairman Han, my dear father-in-law.
If you’re reading this,
I have already fallen victim
to their conspiracy
and have been labeled a traitor.
In that letter,
he says that you've plotted
this conspiracy
together with Mr. Yang.
This is nonsense, Dad.
How could someone in a coma
write this letter?
His handwriting has already been verified.
This doesn't make any sense.
Mr. Yang approached me after the accident,
so he couldn't...
In other words,
are you admitting that you've
conspired with Mr. Yang?
Come in.
Boss. Is it okay to send him in alone?
Who would believe me if I went in?
The chairman wants Jang Pan-su.
Don’t say anything else
and stick to my plan.
I called for him.
Have a seat.
Jang Pan-su,
what exactly are you planning?
Shut your mouth!
What should we do now?
Ask the chairman what he wants.
"Ask the chairman what he wants"!
What did you say?
Well, I wanted to ask...
what he, I mean,
what you would like to do.
I pronounce you the heir to Hanho Group!
Dad!
I’ll vest your entire fortune,
including the money you stole,
to the company!
How could you? I’m your daughter!
You won’t get any inheritance from me,
so don’t ever come back!
What about what he did to me?
He had an affair behind my back
and he even has a 17-year-old daughter.
You didn't think I would look into it?
You went straight to her bar
after leaving the hospital.
Is this true?
Tell him that it’s a misunderstanding.
Well, I...
Sir, I can’t hear you.
Hey, Dong-hyun.
Can you hear me?
Sir, I need your help.
-I can’t hear you.
-Explain yourself!
Well, that is...
-the truth.
-What?
But the child wasn’t born
while I was living with this lady.
An ex-girlfriend gave birth without him,
I mean, me, knowing.
Do you even listen to yourself?
Fact is that you have a daughter,
you son of a bitch.
Don’t swear, lady.
Hyun-jung is a lovely girl.
Dad, look. He’s completely mad.
How could he say that?
Stay out of this!
Continue.
It came to me after the accident.
Should I step in?
What’s more important
than being with the family you love?
Does that mean that you're going to
give up your right as an heir?
I don’t know how rich you are, but yes.
What did he just say?
It won't be easy giving up.
Can you promise not to regret it?
I've lived with too many regrets
until now.
I’m telling you this now
so that I won’t have any more regrets.
You’re all crazy.
Goodbye, ma'am.
As the father of a foolish child...
I have no right to stop you.
Do as you wish.
Thank you. Then I'll...
Goodbye.
Kim Dong-hyun!
Thank you.
You’re a better man than I am.
You too, sir.
You fight really well.
Crazy bastards.
Wake up, sir!
Boss.
You have to keep the mask on.
Man-cheol. Look after Hyun-jung for me.
Yes.
Wake up, sir. Hyun-jung’s here!
Dong-hyun!
Excuse me.
Mom, is he...
my dad?
I saw him in a photo you hid away.
Am I right?
Hyun-jung.
I am your dad.
What?
My daughter, Hyun-jung.
This can't be.
Did you...
get married already?
What?
No, I’m really your dad.
Please.
Forgive me.
I wasn’t there when you were born.
When you said your first word,
or when you took your first step,
I wasn't there for you.
What are you on about?
My dearest Hyun-jung.
Don’t ever forget...
that I love you.
Pan-su.
-Dong-hyun!
-Sir!
Dong-hyun!
Help! Over here!
-Dong-hyun!
-Boss!
I mean, boss!
Did you like my gift?
It’s you!
You've had a difficult time taking care
of your wife and daughter, didn't you?
Get some sleep.
SIX MONTHS LATER
-It’s Dong-hyun!
-Holy cow!
-He’s here!
-Wow!
Kim Dong-hyun!
Thanks to you,
the bullies transferred to another school.
Hey, Dad!
Should we have
some strawberry milk together?
Hyun-jung.
-How do you know Mrs. Jang?
-How do you feel now?
I will fully cooperate
with the investigation
but it's all Jang Pan-su’s fault!
And that punk ass kid!
He got a high schooler to fight!
And you call yourself a man?
Put more strength into it!
Kids will rush in soon.
-Don't pick on me, what about him?
-Jong-gi is way better than you are.
I’m getting pretty good, aren't I?
Come on,
I'm the one who gave you this building.
Do you think I'm the kind of person
who would live off the rent?
Do you even know the value of labor?
I'm sorry, boss, I mean, landlord.
I’ll do my best.
-I’m back!
-Come on in.
-Good afternoon!
-Dong-hyun is here, too.
Go get changed and start cleaning.
Let me do it, ma’am.
See? He wants to do it.
You can do it together then.
You have to promise that
you’ll pay me at least the minimum wage.
Or I’ll report you
to the Department of Labor.
-What?
-Hey, Hyun-jung.
Report her for me as well
and I’ll raise your allowance.
Like father like daughter!
Goodbye.
-Keep kneading!
-Yes, ma’am!
Get changed right away!
-Boss.
-Okay.
Where do you want this?
Go put it down anywhere.
I was talking to the landlord.
Put it in the kitchen, please.
But ma’am, do I have to keep wearing this
in this weather?
There are a lot of high school girls
in the area. Do it as a favor for me.
It's cold, isn't it?
We'll be opening very soon.
-Knead! Knead!
-We're Kneading!
Hurry and get changed!
Where are my clothes?
They're in there somewhere!
-Almost done.
-That's it.
-Come on, guys.
-Hurry.
-How's the food here?
-It looks delicious.
HYUN-JUNG'S DINER
Subtitle translation by Tae-hui Cho