It's the ultimate culinary showdown.
Come on!
20 up-for-it celebrities...
Hello!
..with their eye on one prize...
This is what we call it, yes!
..the Celebrity MasterChef title.
Each week, five new celebs
face off against each other...
You need to dance.
Oh, it's burnt... Cor!
..in a quest for culinary stardom.
It's been emotional.
Nobody won MasterChef
by playing it safe.
They have shone in their careers.
Can they shine in the kitchen?
One of them is going to take
the title.
Let the fireworks begin.
It's week two of the
Celebrity MasterChef competition.
Taking on the challenge of the
MasterChef kitchen...
..reality TV star Chloe Burrows.
If I get past the first day...
..game on.
Olympic athlete
and Gladiator Nitro,
Harry Aikines-Aryeetey.
I'm in it to win it.
Come on, I'm here.
Hype me up, charge me up
and let's go.
Let's go do this together.
Award-winning actor and former
EastEnders favourite,
Danielle Harold.
My friends and family think
I'm crazy for doing MasterChef.
"Are you seriously going on that?
"You're going to look like
such an idiot."
Probably will, but it's all fun.
Stand-up comedian, Eshaan Akbar.
I'm a cook at best.
And I'm a comedian at worst.
So let's see what happens.
And Rochenda Sandall,
stage and screen sensation
and Line Of Duty breakout star.
Breathe, don't be nervous
and move forward.
And just try your best.
WE know what we want -
we want great food.
But we have no idea what
these celebrities are like.
No idea at all.
Hello!
I think we're going to have
a great deal of fun,
and we are going to find
some talent.
Hello. Woo!
Chefs, are you ready?
Gladiators, are you ready?
En garde!
A very, very warm welcome to
Celebrity MasterChef.
This is your opportunity to show
the whole nation
your culinary talent.
We call this first round
Under The Cloche.
In front of us here, there are
five lovely, shiny domes.
Each one of you is going to come up
and choose a cloche.
Underneath that cloche
there is an ingredient,
and with that ingredient, we would
like you to make for us a dish
where that ingredient is the
centrepiece.
Chloe, come on. OK.
Come and choose your cloche.
My friends laughed their head off
when I said I was doing MasterChef.
I'm just very nervous about
this first bit.
But after that, see you
at the final, maybe.
I'm going to go for the middle one.
OK.
What's that, then?
What do you think that is?
Is it fish?
A steak?
Some sort of meat?
Yeah. Very good.
What is it?
OK, it goes quack.
A duck?!
Good...
Thank you...that.
Thanks, Chloe. Thank you.
OK...
Rochenda, come on, come and choose.
I am quite passionate about food.
I love cooking it.
I love eating it even more.
But I think I'm kind of a rustic,
traditional cook, for sure.
Make stuff that's yummy for people
to eat, I hope.
Fingers crossed.
I'm being drawn...
to number two.
Oh, great.
I don't know the name of this,
but I know it's in the
cauliflower family.
Perfect.
Alien cauliflower, I like to
call it.
It's a romanesco. Romanesco!
That's it, that's it.
Gorgeous. OK.
You look comfortable.
You come with me, romanesco.
Well, you know, you'll have to be
the judges of that.
I don't like how confident you are.
Yeah, what's that about?
Making me unhappy.
THEY LAUGH
Eshaan, there's a cloche up here
with your name on it, I'm sure.
Maybe I'm making the rod for
my own back.
I'm feeling quite calm.
Please don't be something sweet.
I don't want anything sweet.
And that might be a problem.
I don't know. You might hear me
screaming in the kitchen, going,
"What have I done here?"
Erm, I'll go for the end.
Kidneys?
Close. Livers.
Hey!
Livers?
From which animal?
They...they look quite beefy.
So I'm going to say chicken.
Well done. Is it chicken?
Oh! OK, livers...
Well done. Thank you.
Very well done.
You've filled me full of confidence,
my friend.
Yeah...!
Am I?!
Danielle, if you wouldn't mind?
I love MasterChef.
I love watching it at home.
But I never thought that I'd be sat
here in the MasterChef kitchen.
It's crazy.
I wouldn't mind the other half
of that chicken.
My worst thing that could happen to
me today probably would be a fish.
To fillet a fish, like, to be
the first thing that you do...
I'm going to go this one,
I think.
Whoa!
You are kidding.
Do you know what fish that is?
A flat one?
It's a plaice.
I've eaten plaice.
I've not seen one like this.
Have you cooked fish?
Yes, I can cook fish.
Brilliant!
Well done. Thanks.
The makings of a cook in there.
Oh, go on, mate.
Yes, mate!
Why do you look sad, then?
You've got this.
Oh, no...!
Careful, Harry, because this one
might be heavy.
Oh, no.
Am I being called in?
Go on, mate. OK.
I'm going to put the other cooks
in their place, yes.
As a gladiator, when Nitro appears,
everyone will know.
Straight to it.
There you go.
Pears.
Nice pear, Harry.
Wahey! Hey, hey, hey.
Woo! Yes!
Harry, you're through to
the next round.
THEY LAUGH
I've never eaten a pear before.
No way. You've never eaten a pear?
First time for everything.
But I'll do what I can.
Great. You smell nice, Harry.
Thank you so much.
It's a little something...
I've been working on it.
Thanks, Harry. Thank you.
They didn't flirt with ME that much.
Oh, mate. I mean...
I was working the pear.
THEY LAUGH
Hey!
You'll have one hour.
And you are also able to use
whatever you like
from this wonderful larder
behind us.
Off you go.
Let's go, mojos.
What am I looking for?
I don't even know.
Vanilla extract anywhere?
Oh! "Extract. Check me out."
I've got a bit of a plan going on,
so we'll see if it works out.
Wish me luck.
Feeling OK, so far,
but I'm avoiding that fish.
The rest of it, I'm all right.
But him?
Looks miserable already.
How hard can a potato be?
VOICEOVER: 28-year-old Love Island
star Chloe Burrows
has over three million followers
online.
She now hosts her own podcast,
interviewing celebrities
and sharing their gossip.
Ew, I literally hate touching meat.
Hate it, hate it, hate it...
What if I feed them something raw?
What if they go home, feel like
it's OK, and then wake up tomorrow
and they're violently unwell
because of my cooking?
There's a lot at stake here.
Is this tougher than Love Island?
Are you joking?! This is solid!
What are you making for us?
I'm going to make you a duck
steak dinner.
We're going to have some chilli
and garlic, Tenderstem broccoli
and some roast potatoes.
So, how much cooking do you do?
Probably once a month, if that.
So, why are you here? Tell me.
Because I want to learn to cook.
I don't want to keep getting
takeaways.
I like cooking when I have a recipe.
Like, I like it.
But I don't have a recipe right now.
So what's a great outcome for you
now? What are you hoping for?
That that's not raw.
And you guys love it.
JOHN: My God, Chloe's cooking
a duck.
Check me out. Wahey!
In the perfect world, that duck
should have lovely, crispy skin.
The flesh should be nice and pink,
and when you cut into it,
there should be no blood
running from it.
How do you know if it's burning?
We're going to have two things
she knows how to do -
crispy roast potatoes with garlic
and rosemary.
Lovely, as long as they're
well seasoned
and nice and crispy on the outside.
And sprouting broccoli with butter
and chilli. Fantastic.
That dish needs a sauce.
It needs something with it.
Can you crack this for me, please?
Not strong enough.
He's not strong...
He's not that strong, is he? Oh.
39-year-old East Londoner
Eshaan Akbar is a rising star
of the UK comedy scene.
He loves to cook the food of his
Pakistani-Bangladeshi heritage,
inspired by his late mum.
I'm not trying to overthink it.
Just follow my instincts
and see if it all works.
I reckon when it comes to making
these dishes on the fly,
I'll stay quite consistent with
the flavour profile.
I'm just saying words I've heard
on MasterChef before, by the way.
Like, "flavour profile" -
I've never said that.
Eshaan. Hello.
Have you decided what you're going
to make for us?
Yes, I'm going to try and make
peri-peri chicken livers
and onion, served with
a cumin flatbread.
Have you cooked chicken livers
before? No, I haven't.
My mum was the cook in the house,
and she sadly passed away
ten years ago.
So, about six weeks after
she passed away,
me, my dad and my brother looked in
the kitchen and went,
"Can anyone cook?" So, for the last
ten years, out of necessity,
we've had to learn to cook.
Are you anywhere near as good
as Mum was?
Absolutely not. No chance.
But, you know, I try,
and so far, I've not poisoned
anyone.
Everyone seems to enjoy the food
I make. So let's see.
Eshaan's going to take those chicken
livers, he's going to pan-fry them
with lots and lots of onions.
And he's making what he's calling
a peri-peri sauce.
What he's actually doing
is just making a sauce of anything
which is hot and red.
It's not peri-peri.
It's just called Ishaan's hot sauce.
He's got peppers, two scotch
bonnets, some yoghurt, some onions
and garlic, all in a blender,
and he's turned it to a paste.
ESHAAN COUGHS
But those chicken livers need
to have a little bit of colour
on the outside, and they should be
nice and pink in the middle.
If they're not pink in the middle
and they go grey,
they can go really dry and sandy.
If you're in the middle of a
stand-up routine now, where are you?
The crowd are wanting their money
back at this point.
25 minutes have gone!
Really excited to be here...!
I can't believe I've got the apron
and everything.
VOICEOVER: 39-year-old Grimsby-born
actor Rochenda Sandall
is best known for playing villain
Lisa McQueen in Line of Duty.
She's also appeared in Black Mirror,
Star Wars and Doctor Who.
She regularly cooks at home
for her partner
and fellow actor, Mark Stanley.
I was dreaming about food last
night.
I had a dream that all these
ingredients
were just falling on top of me.
Yeah! So that's where I'm at.
Rochenda, you seemed really happy
when you got this.
Oh, my God, I was so happy
because...
What I'm trying to do is, I'm trying
to do a journey,
myself and my personal life,
into kind of vegetarianism.
Well, how much cooking do you do?
I do quite a bit of cooking
because I've got a lovely friend
down the road who runs an allotment,
so we get loads of, like, amazing
produce from her,
and it'd be a shame to waste it,
so, yeah.
You look happy and confident, and
that fills me full of confidence.
OK! Good luck, chef.
I hope you like it.
Thank you, chef.
Rochenda seems to be going about
this task the right way,
taking that romanesco and turning it
into a steak,
just cutting it into big, thick
pieces, brushing it with paprika,
which should go nice and smoky.
She's serving the whole lot
with champ potatoes,
which are mashed potatoes with
spring onions in them.
Could be delicious,
as long as there's no lumps
in that mashed potato and
it's really well seasoned.
And then she's making a
chimichurri sauce.
It's almost like a salsa verde.
And she's taking lots of different
herbs, a bit of vinegar,
some chilli, mixing the whole thing
together as a dressing.
Well, that's great.
I think it sounds like a great dish,
and Rochenda is really confident.
Can we have a fist pump?
It's what kids do.
Ah! Boom.
You have 30 minutes.
Just 30 minutes left.
Have you ever seen a Gladiator
sweat? That's the question.
VOICEOVER: 35-year-old Harry
Aikines-Aryeetey won gold
sprinting at European and
Commonwealth championships.
He now appears as the
formidable Nitro
in sports game show Gladiators.
Faking under pressure.
But we like pressure.
Pressure makes diamonds.
Food growing up for me
is a whole family wholesome day
where, you know, the kitchen
is a vibrant, loving space.
And my mum would obviously give us
a lot of love with her cooking.
Soul food.
It feels really odd calling you
Harry. Yes.
Cos to me, you're Nitro.
Argh!
Give it one of those, eh?
So, listen - an athlete,
a Gladiator -
how competitive are you?
I'm too competitive.
As much as I try to dumb it down,
I want to win everything.
I want to do everything well.
But you've got to appreciate
the competition.
Size them up and give them the
respect, and go from there.
How much would I have to pay you
for you to let me win an arm wrestle
on camera? Erm...
We can go whenever you want.
Tell me later.
JOHN: He's taken the pears, peeled
them, cut them into quarters.
He's cooked them with some butter
and brown sugar.
Then he's turning the whole thing
into a pie.
He's made his own shortcrust pastry,
and he's going to make ice cream.
Now, if he can get all that done in
the amount of time, I'll be amazed.
Guys, you have just 20 minutes left.
31-year-old Danielle Harold
won a British Soap Award
playing Lola Pearce-Brown
in EastEnders.
She cooks with her grandad,
who taught her from a young age.
Oh... What's that?
What is that?
Oh, that's disgusting.
My mum is the worst cook in history!
She will literally burn, like,
frozen smiley faces from
the freezer.
But my grandad is a great cook.
So that's where I think I found my
love for cooking, from my grandad,
not my mum. Sorry, Mum.
How did you feel when you got
the fish?
All day I've been saying to these
guys, I don't want a fish
cos I can't fillet it,
and then here I am.
I'm impressed at your courage.
Really? But you've left it
and left it. Yeah.
You're finally tackling it, right?
Yeah, I'm here now!
OK.
Once you get those fillets out -
and you're not doing a bad job -
what's the dish going to be, please?
So I'm going to cook 'em in butter
with some garlic,
some chilli and some ginger,
and some asparagus and mash.
And the secret to perfect
mashed potato is what?
Creamy and no lumps.
No lumps. Hey!
My mum wouldn't say that,
she loves a lump in her mash.
But no lumps.
Sorry, Mum.
Did you ever do any cooking
in EastEnders? No, never.
I did work in the fish and chip
shop for a bit, with Ian Beale,
but he didn't teach me how to do
any of this, so...
It's all plastic fish in there.
Is it? Yeah.
Sorry, I gave it away...
Don't tell anyone...!
The world's smallest fish
fillets ever...!
I hate fish.
That fish is quite difficult
to cook.
In the pan, flesh side down,
cooked for about a minute,
goes brown around the outside,
turn it over,
and let the heat continue to cook it
all the way through.
Otherwise, it's going to be dry
and it's going to be like
cotton wool.
She's going to serve that with
mashed potatoes, some asparagus
and some chilli butter
with some ginger.
Fantastic.
You shouldn't look at this bit,
really.
Wait for it to be plated, you know?
DANIELLE LAUGHS
See that Gladiator power? Bosh.
Bosh.
Harry's competitive, and he is
absolutely going for it.
With only 20 minutes to go,
his pastry wasn't in the oven yet.
And pastry usually takes between
25 and 30 minutes to cook.
Always against the clock.
I hope he's not being overambitious.
Maybe if I can dance around my
pastry, it might cook it quicker.
Heat it up, heat up!
More drama here than there is in
Albert Square. This is...
This is it! Come to me...!
Whatever you're doing,
you have five minutes.
That's all you have, five minutes.
Oh...!
This suddenly doesn't look as
appetising
as I was hoping it was going to be!
What does it look like?
What have I done?
Oh...
SHE YELPS
Loads of them stuck to the bloody
pan!
You've got two minutes!
Two more minutes?
Two minutes! Come on!
Can we get that ice cream out into
those little cups now, please?
Yeah. Right now.
MUMBLING: Cook, cook, cook, cook...
I don't know if it's cooked or not!
How can we make this look nicer?
You've got about 20 seconds, all
right?
Harry, get that into a bowl
and over on your bench, please.
Get it in. Get it in, get it in,
get it in. Just get that in.
He can't get the scoop.
Oh, no.
Come on, Harry, you got this.
That's it. Take it over. That'll do.
Take it over. I was going to
powder them. You are done.
Woo!
THEY CHEER
Time's up. Time's up.
We done it! Smashed it.
Yours looks sick.
It's always a race
against the clock -
in the track, in the arena...
..and here, clearly.
Christ.
Danielle, please.
Yes.
VOICEOVER: First up is former
EastEnders star Danielle,
who served her ingredient of plaice
pan-fried in butter,
ginger and chilli,
with mashed potato and roasted
asparagus.
Congratulations, because the main
part of your dish was the fish,
and the fish flesh is perfect.
And I'm really impressed that
you got those fillets off.
Thanks.
I don't know what you did to that
asparagus.
You've just stuck it on a tray,
put it in the oven
and forgot all
about it. I just forgot...!
Cos it's burnt. Look what happens.
Watch. That one, I don't...
That one's got a bit of a flop.
Love that you've taken inspiration
from your mum
and put those lumps inside
your mashed potato.
Your mum will be really proud
of that.
But everything tastes good,
it's seasoned well.
You've got the warmth in there
with the little bit of ginger
and a good amount of chilli.
This is a really good start.
Oh, thank you.
I feel like I've impressed them
a little bit
with the filleting of the fish.
Well done, girl. Ah...!
I was so tense...
Can only be up from here, right?
I hope.
Comedian Eshaan has cooked his
ingredient of chicken livers
in peri-peri sauce with onions,
served with cumin flatbreads
and lime.
Oh, that's a little bit under.
Is it? Oh.
It's a terrible shame,
because there are wonderful flavours
on this plate.
Marvellous flatbreads with smoky
bits of cumin.
Absolutely fantastic.
If you would have got the timing
on these livers,
I would have said a knockout dish.
OK.
Because you're a couple of minutes
away. OK.
Thank you.
There is a lovely, rich, smoky
flavour of paprika,
chilli heat running through it.
And then a sharpness of yoghurt,
which is all being cooked down.
Almost the flavour of a tandoor.
But I've got to say,
this is a great start, for me.
I feel like John and Gregg
were impressed by my palate.
Gregg saying this was just
a few minutes away
from being a knockout dish, I'm just
going to keep that with me forever.
Actor Rochenda's ingredient
was Romanesco cauliflower.
She's cooked it as a steak
in paprika butter,
topped with chimichurri sauce,
served with spring onion mash,
mushrooms and sunflower seeds.
Honestly, I think it's
a little messy,
and I think it tastes fantastic.
Thank you.
You've kept the shape of
the romanesco.
It's a cauliflower flavour,
it's quite mild,
and it almost feels creamy.
Your mashed potato is really creamy,
there's a little bite of spring
onion in it as well.
This is good flavours,
this is good cookery.
JOHN: The sauce is herby with, like,
lots more chilli in there as well,
and tomatoes. Then you get nuttiness
coming from the sunflower seeds
around the outside, which I like.
Yeah.
You don't have to chuck everything
at a plate.
Sometimes you can just go
a little bit less.
But I'm really pleased with what
you've done and your ambition.
Well, I mean, it feels absolutely
amazing to hear that they think
that you're a good cook and
you've got good instincts,
cos that's the basis
of any good cook.
So it's definitely the beginning
of a long journey, hopefully.
Fingers crossed.
Hello.
Reality star Chloe has pan-fried
her ingredient of duck breast
and served it with crispy rosemary
potatoes and Tenderstem broccoli
in chilli and garlic.
TENTATIVELY: Is it raw?
No. It's great. Yes!
That's good, then.
I'm pleased with myself.
Duck breast is cooked well,
the flesh is pink
and it's juicy in there.
You have never, ever cooked
a duck before.
You couldn't even recognise it.
That's good.
Did you hear that?
The whole thing probably needs
a sauce. Yeah.
Even if you just spoon some jam
into a little bit of stock.
Oh, OK.
It's easier than you think.
The potatoes are nice and crispy,
lots of garlic in there,
which is going slightly bitter.
And the broccoli is cooked really,
really well,
and a tiny amount of chilli on
the outside.
Maybe try a sauce.
And even if it doesn't work,
just give it a go. OK.
We want to call you
Give-It-A-Go-Chlo.
I like it.
Yo, Chlo, give it a go.
Yeah, bro.
Can we stop now?
THEY LAUGH
That was a big, fat win
for little Chlo.
Slay.
Take that.
Chlo, give it a go with my bro,
John.
I rapped with John! What the...?
Ha-ha!
OK...
Judge me.
Finally, it's athlete Harry.
He was given pear
and has made a pear pie,
shortcrust pastry filled with pears
cooked in butter,
brown sugar, vanilla and honey,
served with vanilla ice cream.
You've got a bitterness that's
coming from that brown sugar,
a little bit of butter, vanilla.
Honey richness that comes
from the pear as well.
That's really good.
But your pastry's not cooked enough.
Look, the ambition is brilliant.
But, you know, we're not quite
there. Yeah.
The ice cream tastes like sweetness,
like condensed milk.
Texture-wise, your ice cream,
it isn't creamy and it's not firm.
You couldn't make a ball out
of that, it's too runny.
And your pastry just isn't cooked
long enough.
There aren't many people that know
how to make pastry
and know how to make ice cream.
Even if it hasn't worked properly,
you're on your way.
In track and field, in the arena as
a Gladiator, often,
I find that
you need the worst things to happen
because once the worst thing has
happened, you realise, "I'm OK."
And I live to fight another day.
So I can take pride in that,
and I think it's going to help me
in the next round.
Let me tell you, as starts go,
that was not bad at all.
And we're going to ask you to step
outside,
because next time we see you, we're
going to learn a little bit more.
We will see you soon. Thank you.
Thank you.
Harry's going first, because the
door's a bit stiff.
Tell you what, there's a couple of
really good cooks in here.
A couple of really, really
good cooks.
Oh, wow.
Guys, that went really well!
I know!
We smashed it.
Yeah! Yeah, we did.
We can cook, baby!
I loved Rochenda's dish.
I mean, it looked like a piece
of modern art,
but, actually, it tasted fantastic.
None of our food was inedible.
Well...
So I feel like we're chefs now.
I admired Danielle's courage.
I think she did a really good job
with that fish.
The asparagus was a bit of
a tragedy.
You talking about my asparagus?
You going to bring it up?
Eshaan's got a really good palate.
I loved the cumin in the bread.
I'm going to destroy all of you.
THEY LAUGH
But the big chicken livers not
cooked all the way through,
bit of a shame.
Hey, hey, my turn.
Come on.
You're all going down!
Chloe didn't recognise the duck
at all.
She did a pretty good job.
I think what she needs to do now is
just go for it and not be timid.
Survive and advance, that's what
you do in track and field.
You survive and advance to
the next round.
Oh, that's great. Yeah.
I think Harry did a good job
with the pears.
I thought they tasted really good.
He just got his timings wrong.
But like Chloe said,
everyone's going down now.
You're going down!
CHLOE: There's no friends in
this game any more, guys.
I like these five.
They've got the spirit of the
competition, John.
They're not scared to have a go.
Next time they cook, they can't
afford a mistake, though,
cos one of them will be going home.
Hello. Hi.
Oh, we're back. Hello.
You've now had a taste of
the kitchen.
And this is your opportunity
to really shine.
What we want from you is two
courses, a main course and dessert
that you would serve to your friends
and family at a dinner party.
Something to truly impress,
something to show off a little bit.
At the end of this, we will only
take four of you
through to the next round.
That does mean that one of you
will be going home.
Ladies and gentlemen,
one hour and 15 minutes.
Let's cook.
And we're off.
Oh.
I feel really stupid...!
What's a litre and
what's millilitres?
I'm still good. I'm still here.
I've got another chance to fight.
I'm coming out to do better
and be better.
I'll tell you what, it's a brave
cook who invites you and me round
for a dinner party,
but that's what they're doing.
And it's their chance to show off.
I hope so.
And the fact is, we get five
puddings. That'll keep you happy.
You haven't tried these
brownies yet.
Like, honestly, I'm going to win.
I think I'm confident I can do it
in the time.
Hopefully. Fingers crossed.
Wish me luck.
I just want to showcase Bengali food
a bit.
So I feel like I've got the weight
of the whole nation on me...!
So don't come at me if you're upset
with my process.
I'm celebrating me going into
the MasterChef kitchen,
being a great cook, being handsome,
wearing a nice red shirt.
So much to celebrate.
Just vibes.
What are you cooking, please,
Eshaan?
So I'm making what is usually
served at Bengali weddings.
It's a pilau rice that's cooked
in milk and loads of spices,
and a pan-fried chicken in,
basically,
a caramelised onion sauce.
And I'm going to serve for
dessert
basically a South Asian bread and
butter pudding.
Have you always known these dishes?
Or have you dreamed them up
for MasterChef?
I've always eaten these dishes.
Every week, people were
in our house.
You know, my mum would entertain,
food.
Mum's tiny kitchen was like the hub
of the family, the community.
He's got a chicken leg and thigh
which is marinated really, really
well,
with lots of spices on the
outside.
Pan-frying it first, then he's going
to roast that in the oven.
Served with a white pilau rice.
Oh!
Hello!
Look, his flavours in that first
round were great.
We know he's got a great palate.
He's just got to get the cooking
right.
His Bengali bread and butter pudding
sounds fantastic.
Rich with saffron, sugar, cream,
milk, fried bread, lots of ghee.
I mean, that makes it
really opulent.
So these are classic Bengali
dishes?
Classic Bengali celebratory dishes.
Do you know anything about singing
and dancing?
I used to be a Bollywood dance
choreographer.
No way.
Come on, show us some.
Come on. Come on!
Mate, I tell you...
My knees are cracked.
That's just brilliant.
Mate, that's fabulous!
That's wonderful.
That's fabulous!
I'm more excited than I am nervous.
It's just such a mad honour
and privilege to be here.
Watch this.
It's going to be banging, bruv.
A lot to do.
A lot to do, mate.
Do you do dinner parties?
I do do the odd dinner party.
I mean, mine normally descends
into chaos
because my friends like
a lot of wine.
We don't get to the dessert a lot
of the time.
But we always do a main course.
What are your two courses?
My two courses is a risotto alla
milanese with fillet steak,
and a salsa verde.
With madeleines with a trio of
dipping sauces.
Wow.
I used to work in a theatre
called the Bridge Theatre,
and this is the interval snack.
Rochenda wants to show us
everything she can do,
and she is really going for it.
Risotto milanese.
Risotto flavoured with saffron
and bone marrow.
It should be rich and opulent,
saffron making it lovely and smoky,
and the bone marrow making it
sticky and sweet.
CORK POPS
Whoa!
Oh...
We've got it with a fillet steak,
with a salsa verde.
How do those things fit together?
Here we go.
She's making madeleines.
I mean, they are a classic, classic.
Little sponge cake that you have
with your coffee.
A little bit of crust on
the outside,
slightly sweetened,
very, very fluffy in the middle.
Madeleines with butterscotch,
madeleines with chocolate.
madeleines with Chantilly.
I might pass out.
I try to cook at least five
to ten times a week.
I cook for my Mark.
We've been together for 16 years
this year,
so he's tried everything from
when I was a bad cook
to, hopefully, a good cook now.
So he's a lucky man.
20 minutes have gone.
20 minutes gone.
Cor.
What now?
The pressure's on to, like, get it
right, so I'm a bit nervous.
Are you a dinner party person?
Not a dinner party person.
I'm a bit chaotic in the kitchen.
So my kitchen at home is where
all my friends will come and sit,
and when you're trying to cook
and you get the, "How long?"
Especially from the guys,
My mates, they come around,
"How long? How long?" Yeah, I'm
like, "Get out of my kitchen, guys."
Believe in yourself, Danielle.
Believe in yourself. Thank you.
You took your fish apart.
Yeah. You did really well.
Let's hope.
You should be fine.
Fingers crossed, guys, eh?
Danielle's really nervous.
But I think her menu sounds
really great.
Pan-fried lamb cutlets.
To cook those well and make sure
they're nice and pink and crispy,
that's a bit of an art.
Then we've got dauphinoise potatoes.
Let go...!
She's made those.
Cooked them on the stove first,
She's put them in the oven.
With that we've got honey
roast carrots,
a parsnip puree.
It's got to be silky smooth.
Dessert?
Apple crumble and custard.
I would normally do the roast
dinner, and my best friend, Shana,
does the apple crumble.
I don't get involved in dessert.
So I thought I'd keep the
tradition,
but kind of first time trying
a crumble, so...
How much would you give us now
for a tin of custard?
A lot.
That's what I put in my email
before. I said tin of custard
when they emailed about
what's your ingredients. I went...
Oh, dear...! A tin?
That's when I realised this
really is cooking.
BOWL CLATTERS
Oops.
I'm confident I can pull it off.
Unless anyone's got some really
fancy menus today.
But I've got a puree,
I've got a parsnip puree, so...
Very MasterChef, isn't it?
Still in the race.
Let's make it happen.
Food for me is enjoyment,
it's happiness.
It's social, it's family,
it makes me feel warm.
It makes me who I am, and I'm happy
as a person when I have food.
Harry, what are your dishes,
please, sir?
A jerked coconut curry with
chicken and rice.
And for dessert,
we have fluffy pancakes
with a strawberry compote
and ice cream again.
Do you do dinner parties at home?
If people hang around long enough,
they get fed.
Right.
So, tell me, why these two dishes,
then?
So I would say this dish here,
more so for my track
and for my Gladiatorial life.
But the pancakes are for
my daughter.
She absolutely loves my pancakes,
so this is for her.
Trying to get my creative juices
flowing.
Harry's making a true fusion dish
here.
He's taking jerk chicken, which is
usually cooked over a barbecue,
and he's putting that into a sort of
Thai-flavoured coconut curry sauce.
That's an interesting combination.
Quick taste.
Ooh, lovely.
Test pancake number one.
He needs proper big, fluffy
pancakes.
I'd like to see a small stack
of those.
I want the colour.
Give me the colour.
Served with a strawberry compote.
Not too sweet, because you've
already got sweet ice cream as well.
I'm going to make it better.
Harry's been ambitious in
that first round.
And he really wants to go and do
as much as he possibly can.
I hope he's not overambitious.
He needs to get his timings right.
Oh, no hiding here, eh?
We have 13 minutes to go, please.
As a host, I am the hostess
with the mostest.
As a cook...
..no comment.
Wish me luck.
Two courses. What are you going
to make for us?
We're going to do, like,
a teriyaki salmon with rice,
broccoli again - because you loved
it so much earlier -
and pickled cucumber.
Where did you come by this recipe?
I just found it online.
Thought it would be good,
tried it, blew me away.
But I use an air fryer,
but we're going to use a hob today.
And then I've got the
best gooey brownie
you've ever had in your life.
That salmon can't dry out.
That should fall away in nice,
slippery, thick slices.
Not dry.
Oh, it's burnt.
Oh, it's so burnt...!
I'm just going to take the
skin off...!
TIMER BEEPS
Oh, it's me.
The rice has been turned off.
Oh, my God, it's all gone wrong.
Oh, dear.
For dessert, Chloe's doing a
chocolate brownie.
So we want that slightly sticky
in the middle, but not wet.
Oh...!
Can I serve it to them in this pot?
Well, this needs at least
another 20 minutes...!
Oh...
That is a raw brownie.
You have just seven minutes.
Seven!
Oh...!
God...
Are you kidding me?
It's gone so fast.
Oh, my God, I forgot to put garlic
and ginger paste in it...!
Sugar! That's why.
Forgot to put my lemon zest in.
That'll be the nerves, you know?
That looks like good ice cream
to me.
Just two minutes, everybody.
Two minutes.
Finishing touches, please.
Two minutes left.
Oh, God...!
Ooh. Yeah, great.
I think them carrots are so done.
It's spicier than I would like it,
but...
..maybe that's what they'd like.
Oh, my God, this is so bad.
There you go.
Voila.
That's it, time's up. All done.
Well done.
Yay!
Look at my brownie...!
Literally not cooked...!
Do you want a bit of my watery
custard to go with your...?
No.
ESHAAN: Chicken is cooked,
I'm confident the chicken is cooked.
We'll see.
That looks good to me.
Well done.
I could actually cry.
Rochenda, please.
VOICEOVER: First up is
actor Rochenda,
whose dinner party starts
with risotto
flavoured with saffron
and bone marrow,
topped with fillet steak
and a salsa verde.
Your risotto is beautiful.
The rice has just got a little
bit of give,
and it is rich with bone marrow,
and it's beautifully seasoned
and beautifully flavoured
with the saffron.
Your salsa verde is sharp,
it's great with the steak.
Really good.
The fillet steak, cooked
absolutely beautifully,
and you've got the flavour around
the outside.
You know how to make a risotto,
you can cook a great steak.
you can make a great salsa verde.
That's fantastic.
OK. Thank you very much.
That's so kind, thank you.
For dessert, Rochenda has cooked
madeleines, mini butter cakes,
with a trio of dipping sauces -
whipped cream, butterscotch,
and chocolate.
For a novice, not a pastry chef, I
think you've done a pretty good job.
This little baby here -
this madeleine that now looks like
a spaceship
with its little
hump on the top of it -
is the way a madeleine should look.
Your chocolate sauce is great,
it's a really lovely dipping
chocolate sauce, nice and light,
almost like a sort of thick
hot chocolate.
Love the sweetened cream.
Love the chocolate dipping sauce.
Madeleines, risotto,
fillet steak, salsa verde.
This is knowledgeable, brave
cookery.
And I can't help but admire your
knowledge and your courage.
Nobody won MasterChef by
playing it safe.
You go for it.
Yes, boss.
It was absolutely amazing to hear
the positive feedback.
I'm feeling, overall, absolutely
exhausted!
I'm ready for a nice cup of tea
and a sit by the fire
and watching some TV.
Inspired by Bengali weddings,
comedian Eshaan has made
roast chicken cooked in onions,
ginger, cashew and chilli,
served with rice infused with
cardamom and clove,
and a cucumber, carrot and
red onion salad.
We're a little bit pink in here.
Such a shame, because your flavours
are magnificent.
There is a creamy, buttery sauce
that's got layers of spicing -
some warm, some bitter.
The onions have a sweetness,
and the ones that are deliberately
caught have a bitterness.
It's delicious.
The sauce is fantastic.
My chicken is cooked
and I can eat it,
and it's really good.
It's difficult because we've got two
dishes we both love the flavour of.
I can eat mine, and Gregg can't.
Sorry about the chicken.
I'm sorry for you.
For his second course, Eshaan is
serving
a Bengali bread and butter pudding -
white bread fried in ghee,
served in milk infused with
saffron and rose water,
topped with crushed almonds
and pistachios.
The bread, I think, is great.
Because you fried it
in all that ghee,
it's given it a crusty outside.
And then all of that saffron,
which is summer.
And then of course, the rosewater
that actually smells
and tastes like an old-fashioned
Turkish delight. It's yummy.
I've never had anything
like it before.
Little crispy bits of almonds,
adding a little bit of a crunch.
And this fried bread tastes almost
like a cross between a biscuit
and a breakfast cereal.
It's really tasty.
I'm feeling all right. I'm trying to
focus on the positives,
which was that they loved the
flavours.
I can't believe I gave
Gregg Wallace
undercooked chicken
twice in one day.
That's going to haunt me forever.
Danielle, if you're ready, please.
Go on! Go on, girl.
Come on! Go on, go on!
VOICEOVER:
Actor Danielle's main course
is pan-fried lamb cutlets
with dauphinoise potatoes,
honey roasted carrots
and a parsnip puree.
JOHN: Nice.
Your lamb is cooked beautifully.
Got a lovely crispness
on the outside,
nice and pink through the centre.
That's great.
Your dauphinoise is fantastic.
Lovely and creamy, crispy
across the top, nicely seasoned.
The parsnip puree is smooth,
there's no real lumps in there,
it's quite sweet.
Your carrots are an abomination.
I mean, look at that.
That's one way of getting colour
on your carrots,
that's to burn them.
The carrots aren't great,
but your dauphinoise, your puree
and your lamb meat there
is very, very good.
Thank you.
VOICEOVER: For dessert,
Danielle has made an apple crumble
served with vanilla custard.
You've got sharp flavoured apple
in there
with a nice little bit of spice,
a good amount of sugar
and then across the top of that,
the biscuity, crumbly base is nice
and solid,
almost the texture of a shortbread.
Your custard isn't thick enough,
but it works with this dish.
That combination of
the sweet, creamy milk
and the sharp apple
is really, really working.
And it's working almost by accident.
I could eat all of that
really happily.
Thank you, guys! Thank you so much.
Thank you. Thank you.
I'm really happy!
If they say it as well, I'm going
to take that home now and be like,
"Guys, this is a MasterChef dish,
by the way,
"that was loved by two top chefs,
I'm just saying."
So, yeah, happy with that.
Very happy with that.
Harry, we are waiting for you,
my friend.
VOICEOVER: Gladiator Harry's main
is jerk chicken legs
served with basmati rice,
broccoli and
a Thai coconut curry sauce.
St Lucia meets Bangkok.
Something like that, yeah.
You've got some good cooking here.
Your chicken legs,
they're cooked all the way through.
They're falling off the bone.
You've got all that lovely
jerk seasoning.
Nice and sweet,
but still quite savoury.
That's really, really good.
Your rice is nicely cooked.
I'm not a huge fan of this sauce.
The jerk kind of gets lost
in there.
It is thick and creamy.
I actually think it's detracting
from your lovely jerk flavours.
VOICEOVER: For dessert, Harry has
made his daughter's favourite -
American-style pancakes
topped with strawberry compote,
served with vanilla ice cream
and maple syrup.
You've got light, very fluffy
pancakes, natural sweetness
through the strawberries,
then your ice cream, cold,
sweet, and then more sweetness
with maple syrup.
Mate, I love it.
What can I say? I love it.
The flavour of strawberries goes
from a fresh strawberry
to almost a childhood flavour of
strawberry topping
you get on top of your ice cream.
I think it's really well made.
I think it looks great.
I think it's very, very smart.
Good pancakes.
I like it a lot, Harry.
I feel like I've just got to...
HARRY LAUGHS
Thank you.
That's really nice of you to say.
I'm on cloud nine, purely because of
the fact that I didn't fail
in the way that I thought
I could fail.
Ooh!
You did so well, mate, well done!
They've instilled a bit of
confidence in me
and I'm thankful for that.
It feels like a walk of shame,
this one.
VOICEOVER:
Last up is reality star Chloe.
She's serving teriyaki salmon
with brown rice,
pickled cucumber
and steamed Tenderstem broccoli.
There is absolutely nothing wrong
with that salmon.
That salmon is perfectly cooked.
You burnt the skin,
but you took it off.
The dish needs a sauce.
It needs that teriyaki sauce,
because rice is completely bland.
Your rice is free-flowing
and it's nutty, but it's brown rice,
which means it's a little bit dry.
Broccoli is cooked very, very well.
Your cucumber pickles, lovely.
I'd just like some more sauce
with this.
VOICEOVER:
Chloe's dinner party dessert
is a dark chocolate brownie
topped with white chocolate drops.
It's supposed to be a little bit
gooey in the middle
and sponge-like around the outside,
maybe a crust at the top.
And what we've got is all gooey.
That's not the dessert you wanted
to give us, is it? No, it's not.
You only had 30 minutes
to cook your brownie.
They take about 45 minutes
to cook properly.
The result is, you've got a lovely,
crispy outside, rich cocoa flavour,
but the inside is more like
chocolate jam.
Many people would really enjoy it.
It's not what you set out
to do, though.
You're disappointed by it.
Yeah. I'm disappointed by it.
It's timing for you. It is, yeah.
That didn't go well for me,
and the brownie, I have practised.
Raw! Raw, raw, raw, raw.
It was literally like a mousse.
Not even a mousse,
it was like a yoghurt.
So I just gave them that!
ALL GIGGLE AND SQUEAL
I mean, the sad thing is,
the vibes are going to get
broken up, aren't they?
One of us is going to go home.
I think there was great energy
in here.
We've got ourselves
some cooks in the making.
Two jobs done. An invention test,
our own little dinner party.
And now it's up to the judges.
Yes.
I've got one here who I think
is an absolutely standout cook.
And that is Rochenda.
John, that risotto
was beautifully made,
rich with bone marrow
and heady with saffron.
Fillet steak well cooked.
Who comes on here and does
madeleines? I mean, you know, John,
madeleines is the work
of a professional pastry chef.
Harry has got something, John.
He cooked the rice well,
he cooked the chicken really well.
Not sure about the sauce,
but I'll tell you what
I absolutely loved,
and that was his pancakes.
John, big fluffy pancakes,
ice cream,
strawberry compote, maple syrup.
I'm with you.
I think his food tastes good.
The odd mistake here and there,
but in the early rounds of
MasterChef, I think great potential.
I think somebody who's got real
courage has been Danielle.
Good lamb cutlets,
parsnip puree on the side.
Great dauphinoise potatoes.
The carrots, she took her eye off.
But her dessert, that apple crumble
and the custard,
although there was a couple of
mistakes with it, it tasted great.
I'll tell you what,
that girl has got something.
Now we've got a conversation
about Eshaan and Chloe.
Eshaan has proved himself
to have a really good palate,
great flavours.
That sauce with the onions,
John, it was buttery,
it was absolutely stunning
with those bits of burnt onions.
But I've got a piece of chicken
that was undercooked.
Mine were great, yours weren't.
For dessert, we had a Bengali-style
bread and butter pudding.
Fried bread in ghee, loads of
rosewater, loads of saffron.
I thought that dessert
was delicious.
I think it's a shame, really,
with Chloe,
because I think she showed a good
touch with the duck and the salmon.
But both times, John,
we didn't get a complete plate.
With Chloe, you're a sauce away from
actually making really good food.
But it's a confidence
and a knowledge thing,
and that concerns me a little bit.
That chocolate brownie
just did not work.
What we had there was
a brownie mix. That wasn't cooked.
I wouldn't be surprised
if I had to leave today.
I'll be disappointed,
but realistically...
..it would make sense.
It means so much to stay
in the competition, I think,
because food is so important to me
and my relationship with my mum
and her legacy.
I feel like I'm like trying to
represent the family as well.
So there's a bit of that.
As starts to competitions go,
that's a pretty good one.
So well done, all of you.
We did say at the start of this
that one of you is leaving us.
The celebrity leaving us is...
It's Chloe. Hmm!
That's OK.
Thank you, guys.
It would have been wrong
if any of you lot was going.
Thank you very much.
Thanks, Chloe. Thanks very much.
See you later. Thank you so much.
Take care. Good luck, everyone!
I'm sad.
It was a really good group.
I really enjoyed today.
Like, I had such a good time.
But if any of the others went,
it wouldn't have been right.
So it is what it is.
Thank you, MasterChef,
for having me.
CHEERING
Thank you, guys. Well done, mate!
Cheers, thanks!
I'm happy that
the flavouring of my food
is the thing that got me through,
but I've got to cook my chicken
through,
and that's the thing that
I'm going to be dreaming about
for the rest of my days, I think.
I can't believe I'm still here.
I'm going to go home and celebrate
with a takeaway.
I'm definitely not cooking dinner
tonight, that's for sure!
I'm massively enjoying myself.
I'm taking on the feedback
and hopefully, they give me
the opportunity to go all the way.
Relief, happiness.
Onwards and upwards!
Always climb that hill of ambition.
Yes, come on!
ALL LAUGH
VOICEOVER: Next time, the remaining
four celebrities are back.
And the heat is on...
I'm on my blocks, I'm ready to go.
Let's all have a lay down, shall we?
..as they cook for a place
in the quarterfinal.
Another pan, do I need another pan?
Let's go, let's go. Yes, chef.
Not good. Panicking a little bit.