- Previously on Dynasty...
- Marry me again.
Hell yes.
All the Carrington money
and influence in the world
cannot change the fact
that I am innocent.
For some insane reason,
you hired divers to find Fallon's ring.
I didn't know there were
two bodies in the lake.
Figure out some way to make sure
that my DNA is not all
over Mack's dead body.
To a fruitful partnership.
I really am glad you're here, though.
What's going on? I'm getting kicked out?
Obviously, I had nothing
to do with Liam's accident.
You know, not everything's my fault.
I don't forget things. And you will pay.
You are under arrest for the
murder of Nathan Macintosh.
- Ashley?
- Laura called me.
- That's Liam's mom.
- Yes,
I know who Laura is.
Liam.
I'm sorry. Who are you?
What?
Your sentencing hearing is in 48 hours.
Judge Anson is tough.
Well, shouldn't he be lenient?
I mean, I told the police the truth
about what happened
the night Trixie died.
I mean, yes,
I lied about it ten years ago.
And again the other day.
But if it's the same lie,
does it technically count twice?
We're kind of having a meeting.
I'll chew softly.
The judge's decision
could go either way.
What, you mean, like,
the death penalty or
life without parole?
Not helpful.
And could you please close your robe
and put the judge back in chambers?
As you were saying?
Best-case scenario,
you get a slap on the wrist
and some probation, but if the judge
wants to make an example
of a spoiled rich kid
who's always gotten
away with everything,
you could be looking
at five years or more.
No offense.
I'm not sure there's a
way that's not offensive.
I'll see you in a few days.
Ooh.
Why aren't you more freaked out?
I mean, if there's even a
chance you're going to jail,
you should be... getting
a hard-core mani-pedi and facial.
Or you could flee the country,
but in that case,
I would wax everything.
I am accepting the consequences
of my actions, remember?
And I am not painting or waxing
anything in the next 48 hours.
I need to use that time to
smack the amnesia out of Liam
and to make him remember that
he loves me and not Trashley.
And that way, if I do go to jail,
I'll have my fiancé waiting
for me when I get out.
- It'll be a love story for the ages.
- Right.
- See you later.
- Bye.
Did Fallon just say
that Liam has amnesia?
Good morning to you... Adam.
You know, you shouldn't walk into rooms
asking questions like that.
- It makes you seem weird... er.
- Huh.
What's going on?
Breaking ground.
You are aware that
construction has begun?
Yes, but I want to document
the beginning of the new hotel,
so we're faking it.
It's called creative license.
And that explains the camera.
Exactly. Also...
renovation progress kills on
social media, so, incoming.
Oh, my God, did we just find treasure?
It could be Al Capone's vault.
Unfamiliar with the reference.
There's a painting here.
"Bernard McCarty, 1923."
Someone you grew up with?
Hilarious.
Let's pile it all up,
and I'll have the dumpster wheeled in.
Sam, hang on.
This-this could be a significant find.
This Bernard McCarty could
be an important figure.
I'm going to call the
Atlanta Historic Alliance.
They're going to want
to investigate this.
Well, that investigation
cannot delay construction.
I've already sent out all the
invites for our grand reopening,
and I can't push it back.
I booked Hootie & the Blowfish.
And if I have to settle
for a cover band,
then it basically
becomes a quinceañera,
and then we might as well just
burn the whole thing down.
It won't be an issue.
Trust me, you're doing the right thing.
How are they treating you?
What do you need?
Tell me.
I'll get it for you immediately.
I've been in here, like, an hour.
All right? Relax, both of you.
This will be over soon.
Right now we need to focus on business.
The board of Blue Belt Vineyards
received a substantial offer last week,
and I know they're
considering accepting it
because of my temporary incapacitation.
They can't sell it without you.
They can if I'm not
there to vote against it.
Blue Belt Vineyards was
the first company I ever acquired.
It has a tremendous amount
of sentimental value to me.
I farmed her land,
I nurtured her grapes.
Really?
No! I paid people to do that.
But every time I acquired
another company,
I toasted myself from her oaky barrels.
That company is in my blood.
Also, it's my last major holding.
So I need both of you
to represent me to that board
and put a cork in that sale.
I have been on the phone screaming
at the district attorney.
Your bail hearing won't be for two days.
He has to stay here
- for two more days?
- Not ideal.
You should also know
that your DNA was found
inside Mack's body bag.
Adam, I thought you took care of that!
Bag? What bag? Th-There wasn't a bag.
Uh, it-it wasn't in that room.
Should I really be hearing this?
I'll do everything I can,
but this is a murder case.
The stakes are higher.
This is unbelievable.
Oh, you think I'm happy about this?
Both of you need to keep a low profile
if you want to help Blake.
The less press, the better.
Yeah.
But I heard someone in your family
has lined up an interview already.
What? Who?
Dominique.
Ah, Cristal.
I was literally about to call you.
I've been so worried about Blake.
I didn't come to talk about Blake.
I came to talk about you.
Oh.
My favorite topic.
I heard you scheduled
an interview with TMZ
to talk about the case.
Really more to talk about Jeff.
I want you to cancel it.
Do you?
The less publicity about this,
the better.
Blake needs to look like
a Boy Scout right now.
Cristal, you know I would never
say anything to hurt my family.
Here's what I know, Dominique.
You are not the family spokesperson.
In fact,
you're barely family at all.
Says the girlfriend.
You will cancel the interview?
Otherwise, those secret payoffs
that Blake's been giving
you may stop arriving.
I suppose the police are doing
everything they can for Jeff.
I knew we'd come to an agreement.
It's Dominique Deveraux.
I need to cancel my interview.
I'm going to get you
something even juicier
on my half-brother.
Kirby?
Oh. Hi, Dad.
Um, I'm just here to use the gym.
I'm working on my fitness and all that.
Well, as you probably guessed,
the-the gym's closed for renovations.
Oh.
And since when have you
been a fitness junkie?
Okay, fine. I hate fitness.
I just need a place to shower,
because I've been sleeping at Femperial
since I got kicked out of the manor,
which is totally chill,
but a-a janitor walked in on
me giving myself a sponge bath.
Not one word you just said
sounds... "chill."
Oh, it's-it's fine.
It's all great fodder for the memoir
I'm gonna write one day
and publish myself.
I was under the impression
that you had somewhere to stay.
What happened?
Um, yeah,
I did plan on going to Culhane's.
Um, that didn't really work out.
Of course it didn't.
It was a spectacularly bad idea.
Excuse me?
You know how fond I am of Michael,
but he's in jail, Kirby.
Does your life really need
that sort of complication?
Might I remind you that I'm
dating that complication?
It's my prerogative to move in with him.
You're going to come and live with me.
My new place has an
excellent spare room.
I'm not a child.
I don't need to live with my father.
In fact, I think Culhane's
will work out just fine.
And you have to remember this day.
I mean, our tennis match
was a little intense,
but then we had the most intimate
pillow fort conversation.
It was actually one of
the best days we ever had.
- And this one... you and I were...
- Fallon.
All right, I believe
we had a relationship. I do.
I mean, how else do you explain that?
Who even took that?
Not important. Wait.
So you're saying you remember
we had a relationship?
Because we did, and it was...
it was magical, and it was true love.
It-it is true love.
I also know that when we broke up,
you went a little crazy when you heard
me and Ashley were dating again.
Ashley told you that? Is she here?
Because I'd just...
I'd like to have a word with her,
or maybe a heated argument.
Ashley didn't tell me anything.
She went back to New York
to grab some of her stuff to bring back.
Well, maybe she should
bring back the truth,
because I never went crazy,
and you and Ashley never dated again.
I mean, you don't remember it
that way, do you?
Where would you even
get an idea like that?
Fallon.
What a treat.
Lovely to see you again.
I assume that you're here
to prod Liam into remembering you, huh?
So, is it working?
Well, he remembers
that I'm not a psycho,
despite your best efforts
to paint me as one.
Did you show him a picture of the time
that you followed him to Sun
Valley and bludgeoned Ashley
in an effort to steal him back?
Or the time that you bought
the entire publishing company
and tried to quash the
release of his beautiful book?
No, I'm guessing
you did not bring pictures
of those less touching memories.
I thought I'd just keep
it to the greatest hits.
Liam, I'm going.
I will be back when
Mother Superior is gone.
Well, I'm not wild about the decor,
but I appreciate the single cell.
Give my thanks to the warden.
Huh.
Culhane.
Of all the prison cells in all the towns
in all the world,
you walk into mine.
That is where you're wrong, Blake.
You just walked into mine.
I guess there are no singles in jail.
Except solitary confinement,
which seems less fun.
How fitting is this?
A lifetime of cheating,
treachery and backstabbing
finally lands you where you belong.
Suddenly, solitary confinement
doesn't seem so bad.
There's a whole lot of
angry people in here.
Most of them feel like
they've been screwed over
by a system that favors the one percent.
You,
you're the one percent
of the one percent.
Which means they hate the
Carringtons most of all.
Might be too early to vote
for Most Likely to Be Shivved,
but I'm willing to bet
you will run away with it.
You know,
you can badmouth me all you want,
but as soon as I get bail,
I'll be out of this prison suit
and into my Tom Ford
pinstripe suit... like that.
But don't you worry.
I'll be happy to send you
a selfie of my fabulous life
on the outside.
You just found all this here,
behind the wall?
Yes.
Yes. We haven't touched a thing.
How much do you think we can get for it?
Oh, no. From here on out,
this is all under the purview of
the Atlanta Historical Alliance.
This hotel is a Real McCarty.
Yeah, I'm not following.
Well, it appears this building
was designed by Bernard McCarty.
Who, as you must know,
helped put the city
of Atlanta on the map.
A prolific architect who
later became a city planner.
And honestly,
there's even something
ruggedly dashing about him.
Assuming this all checks out,
your building will be designated
a historical landmark, with a plaque
and all the commemorative
fixings we have available.
Uh, I don't mean
to pooh-pooh your fixings,
but I paid an enormous amount
of money for this place.
You can't just turn it into a museum.
Oh, oh, they're not gonna
turn it into a museum, Sam.
They just want to mark the spot
as an important place in history.
Well, in order to authorize
landmark status,
we need to bring in conservationists
and authenticators, which means
you cannot touch anything until then.
You're saying a lot of words,
and all I'm hearing is "delay,
delay, delay,"
so let's move this thing along,
okay, honey?
And now this is how I spin it into gold:
What if we set up a huge media day
and a public dedication?
Everyone should know what we found here.
And then we can get back to work.
Agreed.
I need to call my boss.
You see? Good things come to those
who respect the past.
Sorry I'm late.
Traffic was horrible,
and for some reason,
my driver kept getting lost,
but if we leave right now,
we can get to the board meeting on time.
Oh, you must not have got my texts.
Uh, they moved the meeting up.
I actually just got back.
What?
Well, I figured you weren't interested
or had a hair appointment or something.
Which looks fabulous, by the way.
Did you get it colored?
This is crazy.
I was supposed to be there for Blake.
I know. That's what I told the board.
But, you know,
it all worked out in the end.
They named me acting CEO of the winery,
which isn't being sold to anyone.
So, Father will be pleased about that.
You rescheduled
the board meeting, right?
Don't be so paranoid.
I'm not in charge of
scheduling board meetings.
And look, let's be honest.
There's really not much
you could have done there,
you know,
considering you're not a Carrington.
Hey, Doctor.
I'm sorry, I don't remember,
are you, uh...
Are you from, uh, psych or neurology?
Yes.
Do you remember me from before?
Uh, no, I don't.
My memory's, uh...
Well, you tell me.
Because this gap in my life is...
insanely frustrating.
Right. Sure.
So... I know we've already
been through this,
but one more time.
What do you remember about
the day of the accident?
Every detail.
Uh, easy. Nothing.
That's great. I mean, that's great
that you don't remember the pain.
So, what's the last thing
you do remember?
How far back?
Shouldn't you already know this?
Yes, but this is how we
continually test your memory.
Well, uh, from what Dave told me,
the last thing I remember is from...
around two years ago.
That's right.
Well done.
Is this normal amnesia protocol?
It's more post-protocol banter.
Good morning, Doctor.
Oh, it's you.
Lovely to see you again.
Mrs. Van Kirk.
You know my doctor?
Yes, I do.
Very well.
Actually,
could I see you outside for a sec?
Uh, I'm an adult.
I'd rather you talk
about me in front of me.
Don't be silly.
I don't keep secrets from my boy.
I promise I'll fill
you in on everything.
Well, maybe not everything.
I heard something about you,
Blake Carrington.
Well... that doesn't mean it's true.
Yeah, well,
I heard is that you're the man
responsible for the porterhouse
steaks we had for dinner.
Best steak I ever had in my life.
Well, no problem, gentlemen.
Just made a phone call to a friend.
Seemed like the right thing to do.
We're all in here together.
No reason to live like animals.
Very kind of you, sir.
You have a nice evening.
Rick?
Hi.
You're even better looking
than your profile pic.
Thank you.
I could say the same about you.
Which is unheard of on
a dating app these days.
So I guess this is where
you offer to buy me a drink.
I'll have an old-fashioned.
My tab.
Let me ask you a question, Rick.
Hmm?
You ever find yourself in the mood
you don't want to be alone?
You're looking for someone
special to keep you company?
I'm in one of those moods right now.
Look at us. Two special souls.
I wonder what else we have in common.
Did someone order the
pan-seared Chilean sea bass?
Fallon? Whoa, what?
I mean, I didn't.
Well, that's the charm of my service.
I deliver it before you
even know you want it.
You really shouldn't have done all this.
Full confession,
I've basically taken a micro-course
in retrograde amnesia
over the past few days,
and stimulating sense memory is
supposed to be the best cure.
Does this mean I don't get to eat it?
No, no, no, not yet. Just smell.
Chilean sea bass is the
first meal you cooked for me.
You know? That's right.
Yeah. Breathe it in.
Mm.
- That smells amazing.
- Yeah.
It was very sweet.
You came over to the manor
and cooked it for me.
It was very romantic.
Sorry, I'm not really
remembering anything.
Other than being hungry.
So can I eat this now?
No, no, no, no, no. Uh, not yet.
- First, phase two.
- Whoa.
Is this like some sort
of Dracula fetish?
No, it's-it's rose water.
It's your favorite.
Come on, just sniff. Sniff my neck.
- Seriously?
- Yes. It's science.
Hey, okay.
No, I'm still picking up sea bass.
Now?
Yeah.
It's actually quite nice.
So it's working?
Something's working.
Oh, what on earth?
It smells like a fish brothel in here.
Okay, you just insulted
everyone in here,
including the bass.
Take your bass and leave.
Ooh, I could do that, or I could stay.
I'm torn, Laura,
but I think I'm gonna stay.
I see.
I need security in here immediately!
Security!
Okay, don't pay attention to that, okay?
We were engaged, okay? I mean...
remember, I proposed to you?
In a rowboat on Lake Carrington.
I even used your father's ring.
Oh, you mean this ring...
that I have worn around
my neck every day
since Liam's father died?
You just have to make things up,
don't you?
Liam, Liam, please, okay?
We were, we were married,
and then divorced.
And then engaged, with that ring, okay.
I know it sounds ridiculous,
but how could I make
something like that up?
I am not that creative.
Please, you have to trust me.
I-I don't know what to say.
Finally. Would you please escort
- this madwoman out?
- No, no, no.
You don't have to do that,
because today,
everybody makes their own choices.
This is family-only visiting hours,
and she is definitely not family.
No, don't come near me. No, get away.
Get away from me. Away, away.
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
- Ah! Oh!
Inhale, Liam, okay?
Let the rose water bring you back.
Do something, do something.
I want her out!
- Come on, ma'am.
- Out!
Get out!
Okay, okay.
Here, just eat the fish, okay?
Eat the bass.
It'll bring you back, okay?
- The fish will work.
- Let's go. Come on.
- Good night, dear.
- Laura!
Kiss my bass.
Kirby?
Funny seeing you here.
Funny?
I think maybe something
got lost in translation.
Hey, are you good?
No. I'm angry.
Because of Kirby?
You got nothing to worry about.
Not Kirby.
I'm angry about this.
You and I have sacrificed so much.
And for what?
For your son to come in behind
my back and take charge?
- Adam?
- After everything we discussed,
he shut me out of the board
meeting for the winery.
He's the new CEO.
Really?
Are you kidding me right now?
You're happy about this?
No, no. I'm not happy
that he excluded you.
But I am proud that he's finally showing
a little Carrington blood.
I was beginning to think
he was a little too soft.
- You don't get it.
- No.
I don't care.
Because at the end of the day,
I'm in charge.
I need to get out of here,
so when is that gonna happen?
I talked to a few people
about the bail hearing.
And it looks good,
but you may end up
owing a lot of favors.
Just hold on for one more night.
Can you?
Hey.
Don't worry. I'm fine.
The people in here like me.
What can I say?
I'm always the most popular
man wherever I end up, huh?
It's a curse, really.
Look, I'm sorry for shutting you down
when you tried to help bail me out.
Hello?
Are you even listening to me or
would you rather go visit Blake?
I'm sorry.
I just, um, I hate what they did to you.
And, uh, I haven't really
been sleeping well, so...
Yeah, me, neither.
Never thought I'd miss
my pillow this much.
Well... if, uh,
if you wanted,
I could go and check on it,
make sure it's okay.
They kicked me out of the manor.
So, you don't have a place to live?
Mm-hmm. That's, um, partly why I'm here.
Kirby, you can crash at my place.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I'm not using it.
Oh, my God, thank you.
I'll take care of everything.
I mean, I'll water your plants.
Do you even have plants?
'Cause if you don't,
I'll get plants,
and then I'll water them.
I swear, the universe is playing
some sick,
karmic joke on me as punishment.
I mean, the Trixie stuff was bad,
and then I had to deal with Ashley,
but saddling me
with Laura Van Kirk?
I mean, really? It's just too much.
And I know that Adam gave her
that ring back, and I know
I can't get her to admit it
and I know I won't be able to prove it.
Have you thought about
maybe just giving up,
and trying things fresh in,
like, three to five years?
Aren't you being sentenced soon?
I-I'm just trying to remind you
of the time factor.
Yes, I am well aware of the time factor.
It's just that...
I keep looking into Liam's eyes
and searching for some glimmer of us,
and there is nothing.
And I-I don't know what to do.
Well, maybe you have
to think outside the box.
This is not your everyday
"amnesia boy meets rich girl
for the second time" story,
this is Fallon and Liam
we're talking about.
Your relationship has always been epic.
Epic is a strong word.
Fine, let's call it crazy, then.
I mean, you-you married the guy
when he was a total stranger
to avoid marrying your cousin.
To be fair, I did not know that
Jeff was my cousin at the time.
Look, all I'm saying is,
if you want to make Liam remember you,
you're gonna have to
be as unconventional
as your relationship was.
Sorry, "is."
You are totally right.
I'm a Carrington.
Of course I'm gonna do something epic.
- Hey.
- Hey...
- Is there a problem?
- Oh, there's a big problem.
You think one steak is gonna
make you part of a crew?
You think that gets you set in here?
All right, let me make some calls.
You got any allergies to shellfish?
Culhane was right about you,
and everybody in here knows it.
Is your life so pathetic
that you have to work this hard
to manipulate everyone
in here to hating me?
I didn't have to try very hard at all.
Just had to tell them
who you really are.
That you see me,
them and every other human being
as pawns you can buy or sell.
See, now, that's spoken like a true pawn
who wishes he had the power of a king.
Mm, I don't want to be a king
if it makes me anything like you.
I'd rather be a man.
You'll never be a man, Culhane.
Because no matter how many
times I ruin your life,
you just keep crawling back for more.
Now, you would've thought
that my poisoning your father
would've done the trick, but no.
Nah, I guess not, huh?
Get...
Hey.
Touch me again and I'll destroy you.
What are you gonna do?
Bring Anders in here to beat me up?
We both know you don't have the
guts to do anything yourself.
You just keep pushing me, Culhane.
You'll find out.
Please.
You talk tough like a man,
but we both know
you're just a little boy
who inherited everything he ever got.
A little boy afraid to
get his hands dirty.
Oh, no, they're plenty dirty.
I'd tell you to ask Mack,
but see, these hands,
they took care of that problem.
So unless you want to end up
at the bottom of the lake,
your better shut your mouth.
I want it to look authentic,
but make sure my shoulders
are rippling under the jacket.
People in the future should
know I worked out, a lot.
Before you say anything judgmental,
or even think anything judgmental...
Thoughts are already forming.
If I'm going to capitalize
on the history of this place,
I got to, well, party like McCarty.
I admire your enthusiasm.
Uhp, just wait.
For media day, I'm planning
to unveil this portrait of me
right next to that portrait of Bernard
in our newly named McCarty's Lounge.
Is there anything else I ought
to know as your number two?
Uh, yes. I'm also having
the McCarty insignia
printed everywhere.
Napkins, umbrellas, toast.
Your ingenuity is admirable.
But? There's always a but with you.
Well, there is this curious RSVP
we received to your media day
from a member of the McCarty family.
Uh... bah-bah, blah, blah, blah...
"...surprised to get your invite.
"I am shocked you are
celebrating my horr...
"my horrible great-grandfather,
and wouldn't be caught
dead there. Pass."
So... she sounds nice.
Nothing about this feels right.
I know. Just give me one hour
to prove to you that I'm
not an insane person.
Well, you're kidnapping
me from a hospital, so...
The hour doesn't start
until we cross the street.
Even when we get bail,
this case isn't going away.
They may ask you to
testify against Blake.
All rise.
Okay, let's move this along.
Mr. Carrington.
On the charge of murder,
how do you plead?
Oh, uh, not guilty, Your Honor.
Very well.
Due to additional evidence that has come
to the court's attention,
your request for bail is denied.
I'm remanding you back into custody.
Evidentiary hearing dates
will be set next week.
We're adjourned.
- What the hell?
- That's impossible.
You can't let them take him back there!
Mitchell, do something.
It's okay.
So glad I could be here for this.
Did I forget to mention that
Joey is an undercover agent?
You see,
I made a little deal with the Feds.
"Get Blake to admit his guilt,
we'll let you walk."
You talked, so I'm walking.
You just made a huge mistake.
Yeah. We'll see about that.
Okay. You were standing right there,
carrying a motorcycle helmet.
I rode a motorcycle?
Yeah. I kind of remember that.
And? That's it?
I mean, you totally
started to flirt with me.
One thing led to another,
and then before you know it,
we were in there in that courthouse,
about to sign on the dotted line.
Oh, and one more thing.
I am wearing the exact same dress,
which is a huge fashion risk,
since it's two seasons old.
I like it.
Well, of course you do.
Because we belong together, Liam.
And we have ever since we met,
at this spot.
I wish you knew how much this
was killing me right now,
because I really,
really, really miss you.
Were you wearing a different color hat?
Yes. Yes, I was.
It was white.
Do you remember that?
Unbelievable.
Kidnapping? Truly?
Is there any line that you won't cross?
Do you have a tracker on me?
Don't be ridiculous.
I have a tracker on him.
What on earth compelled you
to take Liam out of that safe
and-and clean hospital room
into this filthy street?
Honestly, Fallon,
from this stunt to that hat,
you're a poor decision maker.
Liam never shared with you the details
of the night we met?
That's funny,
I thought you two were close.
Well, I guess he didn't think
it was a significant event.
- We're leaving.
- No, no, no, no.
Not so fast.
- You!
- I got it.
- No, no.
- Yes, I got it.
- No!
- No. Oh!
- No.
- Stop it.
- Give it to me. Leave him alone!
- No. You stop it.
- You let go!
- Stop it! Stop it!
- Leave him alone.
- Stop!
- Oh...
Both of you!
Liam, will you please tell your mother
that you remember something
about the night we met.
Maybe I did. I don't know.
I believe what you're saying, I do.
But sitting here watching
you fight with my mother
isn't gonna bring my
memory back any faster.
Don't beat yourself up
too badly, Fallon.
Just enough!
I can tell it's important to you
that I remember our relationship.
I'm afraid my memory
might never come back.
And the pressure you're putting on me
is kind of freaking me out.
So can you please just stop?
So, the media day I have planned
is to celebrate my connection
to your great-grandfather's legacy.
And I was hoping that
you could set aside
your personal differences with him
and be a part of the festivities.
Did he kick you out of
the will or something?
This is not about money.
I can't believe you, of all people,
are honoring him. I mean...
I follow you on Instagram, and I assumed
you'd be all about gay rights.
What are you talking about?
I am all about gay rights.
Every day is Pride for me.
My great-grandfather
Bernard was an advocate
for gay conversion therapy.
He refused to serve or hire gay people
at any of his hotels.
An "abomination," he called us.
Uh... I'm so sorry.
I... I obviously had no
idea about any of this.
Yeah, well,
it's not on his Wikipedia page.
So you're telling me that
the whole city is invited
to my hotel to commemorate
a famous homophobe?
Pretty much.
Well, that's not great.
I have made many
bad choices in my life, Your Honor.
I really can't say which
consequences are fair or just,
but I am ready to atone.
Ms. Carrington,
you are a woman of exceptional means
and what many people
believe is extreme influence
in certain parts of this county.
But rather than lock those assets up,
I'm gonna make an example
of you and put them to use.
I'm sentencing you to 100
hours of community service.
I strongly suggest
you use your means and influence
for the good of this community
and not for yourself.
You're dismissed.
Thank you, Your Honor.
Wow. That's unbelievable.
You got off easy, to say the least.
Easy?
I am off to the hospital
to visit my fiancé,
who almost died, has no memory of me,
and now thinks he's in
love with another woman.
Nothing is easy for me right now.
Carrington, come with me.
Blake Carrington, will you marry me?
I do.
Okay, now, wrap it up so I
can return you to your cell
and get to the women's jail.
Back-to-back ceremonies.
And lose the boutonniere.
I mean, unless you want
someone to stab you with it
in your sleep.
And the ring.
I got to get out of here.
Have Mitchell appeal that
joke of a bail hearing
and figure something out.
I will.
I will do whatever it
takes to get you out.
You killed Mack for me.
I'll never forget that.
I understand this sounds extreme,
but in light of learning
that Bernard McCarty was
a major homophobe, our only option is
to cancel media day.
Some things are better left in the past.
Well, I-I am sympathetic to your plight,
but the president
of the Historical Alliance
has made this her grand
event of the year,
and you do not want to
mess with the president.
I don't think you understand
how deeply I oppose
honoring this man.
And if the president has a heart,
I'm sure I can persuade her to cancel.
She doesn't, and you won't.
Sorry.
Cristal.
I came right away.
Why? I didn't ask you to.
There's a leaked photo of Blake.
- It's everywhere.
- What? Where is it?
I just so happen to have it.
Oh, this is bad.
Yes, dear, I know.
It's a PR nightmare. Can you imagine
all of the potential jurors seeing this?
It's going to take
forever to find a jury
who's not biased.
The great news is
I will happily take the reins
and handle the media, as a Carrington.
That is so thoughtful of you, Dominique,
but since Blake and I just got married,
that makes me a Carrington, too.
And a much more powerful one than you.
So, thank you for your offer,
but I've got it from here.
Oh, my God, hi!
Welcome home.
I'm not sure whose home.
Oh, oh, everything can be rearranged.
I promise. It's just I needed,
um, more room for my stuff,
so I had to rearrange some things.
And redecorate.
Yeah, I-I got you a cactus,
'cause I-I didn't know how long
you'd be staying in jail for.
Oh, and-and this.
That chessboard,
- isn't it from Blake's study?
- Mm-hmm.
I stole it.
Like an-an eye-for-an-eye thing.
For you.
I'm not sure that taking his chessboard
is the same as him getting me arrested,
but I appreciate the effort.
Should we play?
Don't really know how.
Me neither.
Kirby, listen...
Don't say it.
I'm really sorry.
Making yourself right at home.
Well, in my father's absence,
which I do hope will be brief,
I feel quite confident and comfortable
steering the ship.
That's so interesting,
because I feel quite confident
that my husband wants his brand-new wife
to steer the ship.
Well, I guess
congratulations are in order.
Still, he hasn't told me, his son,
what his wishes are,
so until then,
I guess we should keep things
the way they are?
For now.
Oh, and, um,
if it makes you feel uncomfortable,
you don't have to call me "Mommy."
Ah, Fallon, I've been expecting you.
I have a gift.
Ah, let me guess. A restraining order?
Did you peek?
Seriously?
Your outbursts against
me have become violent.
And I don't feel safe.
And apparently, the court agrees.
Does the court know you are insane?
And you are legally prohibited
from coming within 50 feet of me,
or Liam, whenever I'm with him,
which will be constantly.
No, no, no, no, no. You can't do this.
This gentleman has a
digital measuring device
that determines exactly 50 feet.
So, whenever he activates it,
if you're within that range,
it will beep.
Like that.
Wait, it beeps just for me,
or if anyone is within 50 feet?
Well, it's-it's not foolproof.
The point is, when he sees you,
he'll activate it.
And if it beeps, then I have no choice
but to report that to Judge Anson.
And that will surely lead
to your community service
being revoked, and then jail time.
So, back it up, dear.
More.
Okay.
Keep going.
Further.
All right, turn it off.
It's giving me a headache.
Get used to the distance, dear.
You may have won the battle, Laura,
but I will win the war.
No, dear, you're losing everything.
It may take Liam a while to
remember that he loves me,
but it will only take
him a second to recall
how fiercely he hates you.
Which pales in comparison to how much
I hate you right now.
Beep you, bitch.
- synced and corrected by sot26 -
www.addic7ed.com