I'm Harry Tasker,
husband, dad, computer salesman,
and for 17 years the most
important person in my life
didn't know
I was also something else.
Omega Sector's top spy.
I'm Helen Tasker,
wife, mom and professor.
After an unfortunate incident
where I found out
our whole life was a lie,
now I'm also a spy.
Honey, all those things
are true.
They're just, you know...
What?
True lies.
Babe, hurry.
I'm trying.
I think they're
searching the offices.
What do you want me
to do if they come in?
Shoot them.
Ah. Bingo.
Okay.
Guys, I got guards incoming.
I don't think
I can do this.
Ah.
You can do this, honey.
This is what you trained for.
I didn't kill anyone
in training, Harry.
On these missions,
you're always the one
that does all the real shooting.
No shooting necessary.
Come on.
How much time
do we have left?
30 seconds.
I'm not talking
about the bomb. Oh.
Uh, 19 minutes.
Oh, hope there's no traffic.
Yeah, okay.
Nice work, guys.
It was Helen's
first time
guarding the door.
She did great.
Yeah, only because I didn't
have to shoot anybody.
I almost wet my tactical pants.
What's our ETA?
Seven minutes.
We're cutting it pretty close.
Hit the gas.
You got it.
Whoa!
It's insanity.
And the travel budget
for the geology department
is a knife fight
for every dollar.
But anthropology can
travel anywhere they want.
I'm telling you, it's a war.
You know, I heard
that there was a huge explosion
at the Venezuelan Consulate tonight.
Oh, really?
Mm-hmm.
I ran out to get
some more cilantro,
almost didn't
make it back
because I-395
was gridlocked.
But I knew
a shortcut,
so I cut across three lanes
to the exit.
Sounds like you guys get
all the excitement.
We do.
I can't believe
worrying about shooting someone
wasn't the worst part of my day.
That was awful.
There's something
about Doug's voice
that just makes me want
to punch him in the throat.
Harry.
But in a nice way.
I don't understand
why it's so hard
to find couple friends.
You know? It was already
hard enough before,
and now that we're both spies,
it's, like, do we have
anything in common with anyone?
Well, I thought
we really hit it off
with that couple
from counterintel.
The people who wouldn't
stop talking about
"high-end encryption
for secure
data systems"?
Honey, more like
counter-interesting.
Maybe it's too hard.
It's not like anyone's gonna
understand what it's like
to be us. Other
spies aren't married.
Well, you still have
your yoga friends,
and I still have
my bowling pals.
I know, but
I want people that
we can be ourselves
around, you know?
Like, you could do
spy stuff with him,
and then I could talk to her
about clothes and guns.
And then, at the
end of the day,
we could all laugh
about spy snafus.
Like, when you
throw a grenade,
but you forgot to pull
the pin.
That's a nice dream, honey.
I know.
Who am I kidding?
I guess it's just
more boring dinners
with Alice and Doug.
Hey, you know what
wouldn't be boring?
What?
Punching Doug in the throat.
No?
No punching, either.
Just one time?
No.
That would be so much fun.
All right, guys.
Intel combed through the data
we stole last night,
and it's bad.
Eyes up on screen.
Omega Sector
has determined that rogue
Cuban General
Hernan Alvaro Ochoa
has gained control
of a long-range mobile missile.
Ochoa is known
to hold anti-Western views.
Analysis suggests that
he plans to attack Miami,
initiating a new Cold War
and allowing
hard-line communists
to seize control in Cuba.
When's he planning on launching?
Soon as his code guy
deciphers the launch codes.
Ooh, so we're off to Havana?
Not exactly.
American spies in Cuba
can make things worse.
Plus, Ochoa's got
eyes everywhere.
We can't get near him,
which is where
these guys come in.
Valentina and
Emilio Pérez,
bigwigs in Cuba's
defense department.
They'll be in Panama
for meetings.
Harry, Helen, you're gonna pose
as American diplomats,
cozy up to them,
and recruit them
to take Ochoa out.
Gib, it's gonna take
a lot of cozying up to
to convince people
to kill a general.
Yeah, well,
that's the gig.
The good news is,
the Pérez family has lobbied
to strengthen
U.S.-Cuban relations.
I doubt they'll want
all that hard work
to go up
in a mushroom cloud.
Uh-huh, and
the bad news?
Bad news is we know zilch
about how to make the approach.
Which means we're gonna
have to go to Panama,
do some recon,
and execute the world's
fastest
recruitment op.
We leave tomorrow.
So, I have some exciting news.
Aunt Fannie
has invited
you guys to her
annual lake trip.
Wait, actually?
With Cousin Tori?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah. You guys leave tomorrow.
Awesome.
You know,
I've always wanted
to waterski with Tori.
She posts the dopest tricks
on her Instagram.
What about you, Dana?
You don't seem so excited.
Yeah, yeah, it's exciting.
Oh, come on, this is
gonna be great. I mean,
you guys and Tori
have been
super tight
since you were babies.
I remember
when you three
used to take
baths together.
Yes. Aw.
It was so cute.
I should get
those pictures out.
Mm-hmm.
No.
Uh, please don't.
I'm just kidding. I'm saving
those for your prom dates.
Good one, Mom.
Hilarious.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Okay, come on,
go and pack.
You're gonna have fun.
You got to get going.
And don't forget,
they're kind of churchy,
so you're gonna want
to pack your one-piece.
I don't have
a one-piece, Mom.
Didn't I buy her
a one-piece?
I think so.
Okay, team, here's the plan.
Harry, Helen, you're checking
into the Pérez's hotel
as American diplomats.
I got you a room
right above them.
You'll rope down,
break in, and look for intel
you can use to befriend them.
Hobbies, foods, whatever.
The Pérezes have reservations
at the hotel restaurant.
Luther, Maria,
you'll keep an eye on them,
make sure they don't walk in
on our snooping.
So, hit the restaurant
and scout out
surveillance locations.
Have fun out there.
Geez.
Is this the only way
we enter a room anymore?
Climbing on ropes
on buildings?
Did everyone completely forget
about doors?
Well, we have to avoid
security cameras, so, yeah.
Feels weird spying on someone
to pretend to be their friends.
Helen, look at it
this way.
If we had spied on those parents
from Dana's soccer team,
we would've found out
about their pyramid scheme
before we invited them
to game night.
Mm-hmm.
Ready?
Okay.
You guys in place?
Status report?
LUTHER
Identifying targets now.
Yup, that's them.
Four exits.
I have two. Luther has two.
If the Pérezes move, we'll know.
Someone's heading their way.
She's the Pérez's aide.
Flor Alvarez.
Awfully friendly.
Do all Cubans
smooch their staff?
It's a Latino thing.
That's just how
we greet each other.
You're Colombian.
You don't greet me like that.
Maybe if you learn Spanish
and move to Bogotá.
I speak Spanish.
Some Spanish.
I mean, how many words
do you have to know
to get a cheek kiss?
Sir? I believe
you're at my table.
Clearly, it's not
your table, as I was
already sitting there.
I had
it reserved.
You know, it didn't
say "reserved" on it.
Gib, we have a problem.
Some creep wants Luther
to move from
his surveillance position.
Luther, get rid of this clown.
Hey, pal, there's lots
of other tables
in the restaurant.
I'm not your pal.
Ooh.
Crap. I think
this is escalating.
Hah, there we go. The laptop.
Harry.
She's reading the Spanish
version of The Orchid Temple.
Perfect. It's a great way
for you guys
to connect.
Remember, it's the book
about the blacksmith
who's dying of a broken heart?
Yeah, I think
The Orchid Temple is, uh,
way more your area
of expertise on this op.
Your loss, honey.
It's a beautiful book.
Harry,
I will tell you this,
this woman has
amazing taste in clothing.
Oh.
Oh, and looks like
they just went shopping.
All right, this is gonna
take a minute.
Harry, lots of shopping.
Looks like they bought
some new Vans.
One green, one blue.
They must have children.
That's so sweet. I bet
they have teenagers like us.
Harry,
look at this rum.
Amiguitos.
It means "little buddies."
Harry, they sound fun.
Helen, they are
foreign intelligence targets.
Yeah, fun targets.
Sorry.
What did he say?
What did you say?
It doesn't matter.
We have a job to do.
Gib, target's on the move.
What? Where?
They're leaving
out the east exit.
Probably heading
back to the room.
Harry, Helen, uh,
we lost the Pérezes.
I need you guys to peace out
of there right now.
All right, we got to go.
Come on, go, go, go, go, go.
A little nightcap.
Does this lipstick say,
"Take out a general for me"?
Honey, you could take
out the whole regime.
Hmm.
GIB
All right, the Pérezes
just arrived
for their lunch reservation.
You two ready
to make the approach?
HARRY
We're almost ready.
Hey, what's your 20?
Any suspicious activity
in your area?
Luther and Maria
did a sweep.
Everything looks clear,
but we're set up
in the alley just in case.
All right, we're on our way.
I hope Valentina
likes this dress.
I can already tell
she's a vibrant lady.
So, I wore green,
and it's
a little vintage, but
when I looked through
all of her stuff,
I noticed she had
kind of a retro style.
Well, everything's
pretty much retro in Cuba.
I know all of her favorite
foods, I know all
of her favorite hobbies.
I feel like
she's my best friend already.
But remember, this is a mission.
We're not here to get
couple's massages with these
people. We're recruiting them
to take out a rogue general
that wants to blow up Miami.
Yes. All the more reason
to wear the right dress.
It's Dana.
Tell her I said hi.
Hi, honey. What's up?
Mom, I need you to come get me,
like, right now.
Wait, slow down.
What's going on?
It was a mistake coming here.
Okay? I don't know how
to waterski at all.
So?
He's here.
I mean, I thought that he
might be, and he definitely is.
Wait, who's he?
Yousif.
All right?
It's Tori's old neighbor.
He's visiting
from college.
From college?
Mom, I'm not gonna date him,
okay? I just, I don't want
to look stupid.
I don't know how to waterski,
and Tori, she's this pro.
Okay, well, if you're
so worried about it,
why don't you ask Tori
if she can teach you?
I can't. That's the thing.
She's gonna convince me to try,
I'm gonna wipe out,
all of her friends
are gonna post about it,
and I'm literally
gonna have to go into hiding.
Dana, it's okay to ask for help.
It's more than okay.
It's very brave.
Mom, it's not that simple.
It is that simple.
It's also hard.
Whatever. I have to go.
Okay, well, all right.
Well, tell your brother
that he needs to wear
his sunscreen, and
we love you. Goodb...
Every time.
GIB
Okay, the Pérezes
are at the bar.
Status report?
Gib, we're in.
Making our approach now.
Copy.
Dos Amiguitos, por favor.
"Amigwee-toes."
I can't believe
you can't pronounce
the name of
your favorite rum.
Did I do it again?
He did.
Are you an Amiguitos man?
Amiguitos?
It's a very good rum, yes.
Make it four.
Oh, that's very generous of you,
but my wife and I,
we have plans.
Oh, come on, just one drink.
I'm Nick Smith, by the way.
This is my wife, Amy.
Hi.
Emilio Pérez.
My wife, Valentina.
Valentina.
We really need to go.
It's too late.
He already poured them.
Come on,
just one drink.
It's not every day
you get to meet people
with really good taste in rum.
One.
Oh.
Is this dress
Clandestina?
Yes. You know it?
Yes, I adore
Cuban designs.
It's just, you can never
get them in the States.
Bueno. You can't get them
in Cuba, either.
So, what brings you
to Panama?
Uh, business.
Cuban Defense
Department. Mm-hmm.
Mm.
Mm, wow,
that's amazing.
And you?
We work for
the U.S. State Department.
And just between us,
I really wish
our countries
got along better.
We couldn't
agree more.
Salud.
Cheers.
Ah.
Mm.
I have an
idea. This is nice.
We should get
a table together.
Yeah.
Oh, we were supposed to meet
some people at the
embassy reception, but...
But those events are the most
boring things on the planet.
Come on, I insist.
Put this on our tab, too,
por favor.
GIB
You guys are doing great.
Keep the momentum up.
He's 16, and sh-she's 13. 14.
That's the same age
as our kids.
Two teens, two years apart.
Why didn't someone
warn us?
I know.
And then when the blacksmith
dies in his son's arms
in the last chapter...
It broke my heart.
This is why I'm telling everyone
all the time,
"Read The Orchid Temple."
What's it called?
HELEN and VALENTINA:
The Orchid Temple.
You ready? Ready?
Yeah.
So, normally, I wouldn't be
so forward so fast,
but since we all
get along so well,
I was thinking,
maybe my wife and I,
we could talk to you
about, um, a little...
proposition.
Maybe something a... a little
outside of your comfort zone.
But, hey, what happens in Panama
stays in Panama.
GIB
Hey, I'm picking up
some weird signals.
Me, too. Do you hear this?
I think they're swingers.
No. Radio signals.
Something's up.
Whoa.
Do you think Harry
and Helen are gonna swing
with the Pérezes
to save the mission?
Do we listen?
What exactly were you proposing?
In Cuba,
we have a problem.
A rogue general called Ochoa
who leads
an extremist
faction and who plans
to bomb the U.S.
He thinks it will help
his little group of maniacs.
Mm-hmm. So, we were hoping you
could speak to your government
about, you know...
...stopping him.
Wait a minute,
you want us to "stop him"?
See,
in Cuba, he's too powerful,
too connected.
We cannot get to him.
But for your government,
maybe not that hard.
I mean, you said
you would love for our countries
to have better relations.
Wait, wait, wait.
Are they pitching us
on taking out Ochoa?
We're supposed to be
pitching them.
Okay.
I just picked up a swarm
of encrypted radio signals.
Eyes open, people.
We were planning
on approaching a pair of
diplomats at the embassy event.
But then we met
two new friends
working for the
State Department
who like Amiguitos, too.
Yeah.
The funny thing about that...
Guys!
Get out of there now.
I got bogeys incoming.
Luther, get us
out of here now.
Gib, we've got a problem.
What's wrong?
Stay calm.
We'll handle this.
They're here for us!
Harry!
They're Ochoa's men.
I thought you were bureaucrats.
They fight like this
at the State Department?
Gib, talk to me.
We're surrounded, all right?
Get out of there
now. Get out of there.
Go. Gotta go.
Harry...
Okay.
All right, all right.
Okay, okay, okay, okay,
okay, okay, okay, okay.
American citizen.
Take it easy, take it easy.
We're American citizens.
They're capturing that
jackass from yesterday.
What's happening?
What about the team?
We can't save them
if we're dead.
The valet left that running.
Get in the car.
So...
I have a wobbly shoe.
And you two are spies?
Sí.
As are you, I assume.
Que arroz con mango.
What did he say
about mangoes?
It means we're in
a sticky situation.
I can't believe this.
Did you even read
The Orchid Temple?
What about you?
You're a spy, too.
Mm-hmm.
Was anything
about our lunch even real?
All right, look.
We can't trust each other,
we got that.
But we both want
to take out Ochoa.
You guys just beat us
to the punch on the ask.
And now we're all blown.
Yeah, and
somebody tipped him off.
You guys have a mole.
It was not someone
on our team.
Well, it wasn't ours.
We got a radio warning.
You didn't.
Plus, those commandos
rushed in pretty fast after
you mentioned Ochoa's name.
Who'd you have listening?
Wait.
Flor, sh-she was on our radios.
No, no, no, no, you can't think
for a second that it was Flor.
Because I trust her
with my life.
Mi amor,
think about it.
Why else would Ochoa be
in Panama?
She must've told him
we were going to be here
working against him.
As soon as we made our move,
he sent his commandos.
He wants to stop us
before we can stop him.
Oh, but Flor is
like family.
I mean,
she's basically
the third person
in our marriage. I...
I can't
believe this.
Harry, I think their Gib
captured our Gib.
You know...
you're gonna regret
capturing U.S. citizens.
I'm sure of it.
You mean U.S. spies!
Geez, you kick hard.
You run communications
for your team, right?
You're gonna radio the two
operatives who escaped my men.
And if they give me
what I want...
then you will live.
And what is it that you want?
Los Pérez...
because their execution
will be an example
to those
who oppose our movement.
Okay, and, uh...
...what about
the rest of my team?
They're alive.
For now, but that can change.
Oh, you have no idea
who you're up against,
you silly son of--
Hey.
Listen to me!
I think you are the one
who does not understand
the situation, huh?
If you want to see
your team again,
I would suggest
that you cooperate.
Very angry.
Yeah.
So...
you and the Pérezes
are Cuban spies?
Why would I tell you anything?
Spies?
That's why you wanted my table,
counter-intelligence.
I should've just
shot you instead.
Then we wouldn't
be here.
Typical communist.
Just shoot anyone
who doesn't agree with you.
No, not everyone.
Only imperialists who want
to tell us how to live.
Oh, why,
'cause we're right?
Dude, you're driving around
in, like, 50-year-old cars.
Thanks to your
blockade. ¡Oye!
And call me
when your country
has free dental care,
you arrogant son--
¡Basta!
Do you guys want to die in here?
Now shut up.
We need a plan.
It's Gib.
You got to bring
the Pérezes to Ochoa.
He's serious, Harry.
I-I-I don't know what to do.
He said he's gonna kill us all.
Let me speak to Ochoa.
Listen, you want your people,
I want mine.
Alive and unhurt.
Meet me in one hour.
I will send the coordinates.
Now, as for "unhurt..."
...there's nothing
that won't heal.
Oh, my God, if we don't
give him the Pérezes,
he's gonna kill
Gib, Maria and Luther.
If we do, he's gonna
kill the Pérezes.
And blow up Miami, to boot.
Well, there has
to be another option.
There is something
we can try,
but it puts all of our lives
in their hands.
How much do you trust
the Pérezes?
They're fun.
But I don't know about
trusting them with our lives.
Can't you and I just do it?
We can, but our chances go
from low to tiny.
I need
exact percentages.
You don't want
You haven't had a lot
of experience shooting people.
And we need all
the firepower we can get.
Yeah.
But how do we know?
We don't.
You just have to take a leap.
Yeah, but what if we leap,
and they don't catch us?
Then everybody dies.
Oh, wow, what kind of
spy sells out his team
the second something
goes wrong?
Gib didn't sell us out.
Oh, no?
Sounds like he rolled over
and gave us all up.
Gib was giving us intel.
He coughed nine times.
That means nine commandos
on site.
He repeated a word
three times
at the start of a sentence--
three entry points.
Gib wasn't giving up.
He was giving us
what we need to attack Ochoa.
We just can't do it on our own.
You know what you are asking
of us, right?
Yes. Yes, I do.
Forgive me, but how do
we know that you won't
betray us
to save your team?
You don't.
The same way
we don't know
whether or not you'll betray us.
But if we don't
work together,
everybody dies.
And Miami is obliterated.
Which means war.
Well, it looks like we all have
something to lose.
Okay.
I swear on our kids,
you can trust us
to have your back.
And I swear on ours.
And to be clear,
you actually
have children?
Because we do,
and they're amazing.
And we want
to go home to them.
Believe me.
We want the same. Yeah.
Oh, you have a whole handshake.
So, look, I got an idea,
but it's too risky to go back
to our place
and get the equipment.
We need guns.
That's not a problem.
There are guns everywhere.
Huh.
You guys think if you wiggle
enough, you can break
the ropes
with your can-do attitude?
You have a better
idea, nena?
Actually, mijito,
I do.
My hair clip has
a sharp edge.
It's my "just in case I get
tied up with a jerk" knife.
You mean him, right?
Oh.
The jury's out.
Tilt your head back.
Let me see if I can get it
with my teeth.
Can you,
can you do it?
It's just too far.
Right.
It's the wrong side.
Raul will have to get it.
You can't trust
that guy with a knife.
I've seen oil spills
that are less slippery than him.
I'm tied up next
to your mangey neck
because I am also
trying to stop Ochoa.
I want what's best
for my country.
¡Oye!
We're a country
of immigrants.
So if he's a pig,
then so am I.
Oh, that's actually--
Shut up, Luther.
Sorry.
You shut up.
We're gonna
have to work together
if we want to get out of here.
Got it?
Yes.
Don't get any ideas.
See those bars
on the window?
That's a stash house.
You're gonna find
plenty of weapons in there.
Let's go shopping.
Okay.
So they're gonna get
a bunch of guns. Mm.
Then we bring
them to Ochoa.
And then...
...we shoot people?
Yes.
That's sort of how it works.
Of course. Yeah, no.
Yeah, it's totally fine.
Oh!
What is it?
It's my daughter.
Aw.
I gave her some advice.
And she's letting me know
that it worked.
Wow. And she admitted it?
Such miracles
do not happen in Cuba.
What did you tell her?
I-I told her to be brave.
And to ask for help
when she needs it.
Hmm.
And, speaking of being brave
and asking for help...
uh, I am actually new
at this whole spy thing.
I am, I am a
professional spy.
And I've been on missions
and I, um...
and the gun
that I use is my own gun.
It was assigned to me,
and I've shot it, um...
...but I've never
actually shot anybody.
That...
never gets easy.
My advice?
Focus on what
you're doing it for.
Like saving your friends.
Or Miami.
Or not dying in a ditch
in Panama.
Yes, no, ditches are,
ditches aren't my favorite.
No, no, no, no, no, no!
Lo siento.
Everything okay?
We heard shooting.
Muy bien.
And they say Americans
and Cubans can't work together.
Mi amor.
Now what?
Spit it into my hand.
Did you have to use
so much spit?
Can you reach my ropes?
No, I can't reach 'em.
That means that you're gonna
have to cut me free first, huh?
All right, sit still.
I am sitting still.
Ow!
You made me drop it.
You cut my hand on purpose.
Guys, if we don't get that clip,
we are all going to die in here.
So let's tip over.
Okay, let's go on three. One,
two, three.
See?
That wasn't so bad.
Tell that
to my dislocated shoulder.
Americans, so delicate.
Not so delicate
that I can't throw my head back
and crack you
in that thick Cuban skull.
When this is over,
I will hunt you down
wherever you are.
And I will kill you.
Okay, guys, I love the bonding
that's happening right now,
but can you just get the clip?
You ready?
Let's do this, my friends.
Show me you are unarmed.
Bueno,
yeah, yeah, yeah, I got it.
Your friends are inside.
You can see them
when you hand over the traitors.
Bring my people out first.
No.
Why don't you
join them instead?
That way you can say
your final goodbyes.
Now!
Keep firing!
Keep shooting.
Get down!
Don't think, just shoot.
I'll take the gun, thank you.
I knew it!
I knew we shouldn't have
trusted him!
You shouldn't even be here.
This is a Cuban fight.
Tell that to everyone in Miami.
You Americans,
you think everything is
about you.
He's making a run for it.
Go! We'll handle this.
Raul, slide me the gun.
Oh, because Americans
do everything better?
That'd be a pretty sick burn
if it wasn't true.
Come on, I have
the better angle to shoot.
Cooperate now
or I will kill you both myself.
Here.
My turn. Dámelo.
We did it.
Yeah.
Should we split up?
No, look.
Blood. This way.
Gib!
You shoot, I shoot.
Take the shot, Harry.
Take the shot, man.
He's got the missile!
He's gonna launch as soon
as he gets the codes.
My friend?
If you're not gonna do it,
I will have to.
Listen.
No one needs to die today.
Revolutions end
in victory or death.
And I am prepared
to die for Cuba.
Take
the shot, man.
It's either me or Miami.
I didn't think.
I just shot him.
I know, I know.
It's okay. It's over.
It's over.
You know you should have
shot me, right?
But thanks
for not shooting me.
Anytime.
Okay.
Just heard from Omega.
Ochoa's allies
have been arrested.
The missile is
under control.
And Miami is safe.
Which is really good,
because I have
about a third of the Dolphins
in my fantasy football lineup.
Mm.
Are you guys gonna be okay?
With Ochoa gone, yes.
So this is goodbye?
I'm afraid so.
Unless...
you defect to Cuba.
Cigars along the Malecón?
Or you defect to America and
we have beers on the Potomac.
Mm.
Hey, guys.
Exfil's almost here.
All right, we should go.
It was an honor working
with you, hermano.
Honor was mine.
I'm gonna miss you guys.
Yeah, me, too.
I hope I never see you again,
you... arrogant American pig.
Right back at you,
you little Cuban weasel.
Oh, get a room, will you, guys?
Let's go.
I mean, I wasn't,
like, nailing tricks,
but my slalom was solid
and I stuck a backward landing.
And the boy you were
trying to impress?
Mom, I wasn't trying
to impress him.
But he said
that my waterskiing
was badass. Mm.
Maybe the "ass" part was true.
Hey.
Okay, lobster.
Okay, well,
I'm just glad that you asked
for help when you needed it.
It could save your life one day.
Or someone else's.
We were just waterskiing, Mom.
We're good.
Yeah.
Your mom knows
what she's talking about.
Speaking of helping people,
why don't you help
your brother upstairs to put
more aloe on his sunburn?
All right, come on.
You're fine.
It's gonna look really ugly
when you start to peel.
Dana!
You okay?
Is it bad
that I miss the Pérezes?
No, they were super fun.
I know, but I've been thinking--
If we can make friends
with enemy agents,
then maybe
other couples
aren't so hard.
If we just do the work.
Mm-hmm, like
sneaking into their bedrooms
for intel on their hobbies?
Yeah, or going through
the neighbor's trash.
Yeah, what about that couple
in the Tudor?
No, Harry, I'm not
that desperate.
I'm just saying, I'm
haven't given up yet.
There's got to be
that one other couple
out there for us.
Now who sounds like a swinger?
Well, yeah.
Maybe if you get
me drunk enough.
Let me get the rum.
Ah!
Amiguitos!
Captioning sponsored by CBS
and TOYOTA.
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org