Previously on Dynasty...
That is no way to talk to your new boss.
He offered me the COO position.
With Jeff's backing,
I will be chief executive officer
of Carrington Windbriar.
Your new competition.
Matthew coming by today,
was that some sort of test?
Someone spotted you two last night.
There was a
malfunction with the thumper truck.
What if the issue is murder?
You trying to honor the dead
or yourself, Blake?
Wife, mistress...
Widow? Or will you leave
Claudia that scrap?
You have the right to remain silent.
He's accusing you of murder.
I had nothing to do
with Matthew's death.
I can't go and tell
him that my entire past
is one big lie.
Who would do this to you?
Hey!
- You're cool. I got the money.
- What'd you do?
Who do you think set up
tonight's little robbery?
It's missing.
If what's on that phone gets out,
it will ruin the Carrington name.
Come on, let's go!
Did you break a nail back there?
Let's go, Steven!
Hyah! Hyah!
You're off your game, Steven.
Murder charge will do that to you.
Well, this is supposed to cheer you up.
The only thing my brother
should ever be accused of
is his poor taste in men.
Maybe you should screw
one of Dad's lawyers.
Pretty sure they're screwing us
with their astronomical fees.
Well, if they can get you off...
Innuendo unintended.
Without an airtight alibi
to prove that I didn't kill Matthew,
the FBI are saying we
need to provide them
with a credible alternative suspect.
I'm not just gonna let them
throw someone else under the bus.
Well, why not? Daddy would.
As juvenile as it sounds,
I wish Mom were here.
Why?
The only thing she's good for
is the occasional birthday
card that her secretary writes.
She spelled your name wrong last time.
Lots of people think it's "ph."
I just wish I could ask her advice.
Hey, the best thing Mom ever taught us
is what we learned when she left:
you can only rely on yourself.
And me.
Timing's a bit obvious, don't you think?
Getting out of Dodge the day
after the house was robbed.
Don't forget to pack the silver.
Thanks for the bags, Anders.
Where are you going?
Away.
Done with the Carringtons so soon?
I'm just about done with you, Sam.
I'm not exactly over the fact
that you staged a robbery in my home.
It'll be fine. My mom's got her money,
and you can get a less tacky ring,
something that doesn't
belong in a gumball machine.
Right now,
Blake is meeting with Stansfield.
If the cops find out
that it was your friends,
that you were involved,
that I'm lying to my husband...
Add it to the list.
This is different.
You pick and choose your
lies like you do your men.
Okay, enough.
All I've done is jump from
one crisis to the next.
Matthew, a murder investigation,
now my nephew's felony.
It's no way to start a marriage.
So you're running away?
I'm going on my honeymoon.
Wow. Why pack anything at all?
Yeah, put that away.
I don't need to see how
Blake's sausage is made.
Fine. Go.
And this whole thing will
blow over before you get back.
For your sake, I hope so.
And Anders is sniffing around,
so you need to lay low.
I always do.
If the diamond was registered,
we have some hope of tracing it.
Forget about the ring.
That's what insurance is for.
I need that phone back.
If anybody finds out that I had it,
or what's on it,
the FBI's gonna be all over me.
At the moment,
they're busy investigating your son.
Who thinks that I gave it back to you.
You told him.
Well, he knew something was going on.
And if he finds out I lied...
I'm not the only one with
something to lose here.
If anybody else finds out
that I had that phone, they're gonna ask
where I got it from.
If they find out that you
stole it from evidence...
The entire robbery division is on this,
working around the clock.
I don't care what you have to do.
You find the people that took that phone
before they realize what they have.
Not just for my sake or yours.
My family's, too.
Can I help you?
Just looking for the bathroom.
It's easy to get lost in this place.
Not easy enough.
Sorry I'm late.
I thought I'd squeeze in
a little morning ride.
Mm. Anyone I know?
A handsome warm-blood
palomino named Butterscotch.
He was a gift for my
16th birthday from Daddy.
Speaking of, what happened to
the dirt you were looking for?
Nothing from the driver?
Don't worry about the lawsuit.
Your dad's gonna drop it?
No. We are.
We don't need the Carrington name.
This company represents
a new start for me.
We need a new name.
My name.
So what? Like Fallon Co.?
This isn't amateur hour.
Morell Green Energy Corporation?
My middle name.
A reminder that I can
only count on myself.
What about the guy backing you?
As you said, you're backing me.
I'm the one who needs to
prove my value in this market,
and I know how.
The city utility contract
is up for renewal this year.
It's worth a billion at least.
You want to poach the city of Atlanta?
Hasn't C.A. had that contract for,
like, 60 years?
Well, imagine the headline:
"The home of Carrington Atlantic
powered by Morell Corp."
That's ambitious.
You don't hit a home
run without a big swing.
This would put us on the map.
It would show people that clean energy
could scale up in a big way.
And screw over your dad.
It's a win-win.
His new COO can pick up the pieces.
So how exactly are we
gonna pull this off?
Oh, not "we," me.
Chris Pfeiffer runs
point on these things
over at the city council,
and he and I go back
to my C.A. days. He loves me.
Enough to cross Blake Carrington?
Oh, please.
He would leave his wife for me.
And his side piece.
Not that I'm offering. I'm just saying.
It won't take much to get
him eating out of my hand.
Hey, sweetheart.
Anders said you wanted to see me.
What's going on?
With everything that happened,
we missed Bora Bora.
So, plan B.
I've taken care of the arrangements,
packed you a suitcase.
I'm even handling the transportation.
Where are we going?
It's a surprise.
But I can give you a
preview of the itinerary.
Oh.
Just so much going on here.
Steven's charges and now the robbery.
It's just not the best time to go away.
And after this weekend,
we go back to work.
If we don't go away now,
we will be celebrating
our first anniversary
before we take our honeymoon.
I don't know.
You're not Steven's lawyer.
You've told Stansfield
everything you can
about the robbery,
and we'll only be a phone call away.
You make a very firm point.
Mm-hmm.
So when you robbed the place,
did you find some kind of cell phone?
You know, I was wondering
when you'd come for it.
- So you have it.
- Yeah.
It was in one of the
drawers in the bedroom.
I was just grabbing things.
Figured we'd look through
it when it was time to sell.
Wait. You didn't sell it, did you?
Not yet.
Relax, man. I'm gonna cut you in.
No, man, I don't need a cut.
I need the phone.
They're looking for it and for you,
and I think they'll stop
if they have it back.
I'll give you cash.
Can't be worth more
than a couple hundred.
You mean a couple hundred grand, right?
I saw the video, man.
And since it is your aunt,
I'll even give you a little bit extra.
What video?
The one with your aunt and the dead guy.
Let's just say I didn't realize
they knew each other that well.
Or that she was so hot.
A sex tape?
You can't sell that.
Are you kidding me?
That's Kardashian-level
filmmaking right there.
We're gonna have a bidding war for it.
Unless the Carringtons want
to pay fair market value.
I just got you a huge payday.
Now you're getting greedy.
I mean, that's easy to say
when you're living
in their mansion, isn't it?
Give me the phone.
Get my money by 5:00.
There you are.
Been trying Cristal,
but she's not picking up.
Whoa, slow down. What happened?
Remember when I told you I
have some sketchy friends?
Stupid kid stuff, I think you said.
Yeah. Well, it was one
of those stupid kids
who bling-ringed your
house the other night.
- What? Did you know?
- No.
I mean, I told him about the gala,
but I thought he was just
coming for the free food.
Huh. And the free jewelry.
Sounds like a great friend.
I'll call Stansfield.
No, no. Listen.
It wasn't just jewelry.
There was a phone in your dad's room...
Matthew's phone,
with a video of him and my aunt.
He told me he gave that phone back.
We need to come up with
$200,000 in the next few hours,
or my aunt's sex tape
will be all over the Internet.
Cristal didn't do anything,
and she's the one
who's gonna get hurt here.
You have reached the cell phone
of Blake Carrington. Press one...
I don't even know where my dad is.
Well... what would he do?
The hunting cabin.
Can't believe you chose this place.
Of all the Carrington properties,
this seemed the most low-key.
I'm surprised you didn't
figure it out sooner.
Oh, I've always come in by helicopter.
Well, just so you know,
we won't be killing any
animals on this trip.
But I thought it would be
nice to get out of the city.
Just you and me and these trees.
Yeah, not one of them a cell tower.
If you're good,
I might let you get on the Wi-Fi.
There is no Wi-Fi.
My grandfather built this
place to get away from it all.
We never put in Internet.
Even better! More time for us.
Mm.
No wonder people choose
the private sector.
Fallon?
Thank God. There's no receptionist.
Kori Rucks.
I work with Councilman Pfeiffer.
You wouldn't happen to have a
real cup of coffee, would you?
Oh. That's a little too real.
I'm sorry, I don't work for Chris.
I'm on the council... district ten.
I'm told that you're here
- to discuss the utility contracts.
- Yes.
I know that Councilman Pfeiffer
is in charge of all that, so...
Actually, I'm taking over.
So, if you're here to talk energy,
let's talk.
Anders.
Join me for a time trial.
That would require sweat.
Come on, man.
You know Blake is out
of town for the weekend.
You could lose a button or two.
Live a little.
As you know, Mr. Carrington's very upset
- about this robbery.
- Yeah.
I could imagine. That was
a pretty nasty bump on his head.
Finding out who's responsible
is a high priority for him,
as it is for me.
So, if you saw anything,
anything that you thought
might be a bit amiss...
Well, like I told the cops,
I wasn't really watching.
I imagine you had your
head in other matters.
Like Ms. Carrington.
I take it she didn't see much, either.
You'll have to ask Ms. Carrington.
Very well.
But if you should think of
something or hear anything,
let me know.
I don't have to remind you
that this incident doesn't reflect well
on those of us who are employed here.
What does that mean?
It's just that we all have a
stake in putting this to bed,
especially those of us
with families that depend
on our salaries.
Anything specific I should
be listening out for?
Just the personal effects.
Mrs. Carrington's ring,
some watches, and a phone
of particular value to Mr. Carrington.
All right.
I'll keep my ear to the ground.
And your mouth off Fallon.
Morell Corp represents the
next generation of energy,
and Atlanta has a chance
to become a national model
for a green city.
We plan to take clean power
and spread it up and down the coast,
take it national and then beyond.
So Atlanta's just the first step.
Exactly.
Hmm.
I wish you the best of
luck with your new company,
but Atlanta is not a means to an end.
This is my home, my city,
and now my responsibility,
not some pawn in the
Carrington family feud.
Well, I understand the connotations
with the Carrington name,
but Morell Corp.
is an entirely different company.
Well, whatever you call it,
you're still you,
and you haven't changed
since high school.
You went to Penley.
Oh, my God.
Of course. Kori.
You look so different.
Did you change your hair?
Come on, Fallon.
You can't expect me
to buy this "new year,
new me" bit, can you?
Maybe you can.
You seem to have the whole
world bowing at your feet.
I'm sure you'll be fine without Atlanta.
See you at the ten-year reunion.
I didn't know who else to call.
You did the right thing.
This guy is a friend of Sam's.
I don't know if you can
call that a friend, but...
he used Sam to get into the house.
And he has the phone
with this video on it?
He's trying to extort my father,
but Dad is M.I.A.,
and we don't have that much time.
How much does this guy want?
$200,000. That's easy.
But what if I get the
phone back and he's already
- copied the video?
- Right.
Why settle for one payday
if you can have two?
And, uh, the nephew?
No, Sam didn't have
anything to do with this.
He's tied up with some bad people.
The best shot at stopping this
is putting cuffs on both of them.
Arresting Blake Carrington's new nephew
would only invite questions.
Questions you don't want,
since you stole the phone first.
From evidence.
Look, I just want all this to be over.
So I'll go in and buy the phone,
you come in and get this guy.
Silver spoon's first sting.
Your dad would be proud.
Let's just call this what it is.
This is you cleaning
up your own corruption.
You tampered with a murder investigation
when you should have been
actually figuring out who did it
so that I don't go to prison
for a crime I didn't commit.
What exactly do you want me to do?
Do your job.
Find out who really killed Matthew.
Make it right.
How could you not remember Kori?
Well, I do now.
Didn't she have some weird
Hello Kitty obsession?
You still don't.
Maybe I should have been
your wingman, after all.
I'm glad you find this funny,
but I am not losing this contract, Jeff,
especially not over a few hurt feelings.
You really think it's
just about high school?
Obviously.
Why don't you let me try?
Maybe I can smooth things over.
Remind Kori that you're
not the whole company.
Kori Rucks?
Seriously?
You, too?
Fallon had a meeting with her today.
Didn't know who she was.
I might have also asked her
to get me a cup of coffee.
- What?
I know. I thought she was an assistant.
- I'm fixing it.
- No, actually, I am.
I'm gonna call her.
Good luck with that.
You know Kori does not roll over easily.
Present tense?
- You're still friends?
- Yeah.
We went to MJQ last weekend.
I invited you.
Do you listen to anything I say?
Don't take it personally.
Actually, Monica,
what if you invited her out tonight,
and I just happened to be there?
She might be a bit more receptive.
Well, with all due respect,
I'm the one who knows energy.
Yeah, let me butter her up, okay?
Set the stage, then you come in.
And do all the heavy lifting.
Not that your part isn't heavy, too.
I got to say,
I do not mind not having an office yet.
We swimming or what?
Looks like the Carringtons came through.
$200,000. It's all here.
Where's the phone?
How do I know that's it?
Show me the contacts or something.
Okay, turn it off.
You swear this is the only copy?
Even I have a code, okay?
Deal's a deal.
Don't spend it all in one place.
Back at you.
I'm sure Carrington's
errand boy pays pretty well.
You're the one with 200 grand now.
I'm Robin Hood.
Everything okay?
Got it.
And the video?
- He swears it's the only copy.
- Do you believe him?
Look, screwed up as it sounds,
he's not a bad dude.
Why are you freaking out?
I got it. We're good.
Yeah, you can go in.
Yeah, I'll get you the phone
after you get my 200 grand back.
Who was that?
Stansfield.
What?
- You didn't say anything about cops.
- Don't worry.
I told him you didn't
have anything to do with that.
Hey, if anything,
you were the one that solved it.
Let's get out of here.
Go, go, go!
So, I know I said no dead animals,
but since this one's already here,
I thought I'd slip into something
a little more comfortable.
Blake?
Damn it!
What are you doing?
I missed a call from the office.
My damn phone won't even ring out here.
Can't even call them back.
I can't even get voice mail.
So, I'm standing here naked,
wrapped in an animal
that probably died before I was born,
and you're calling the office?
Well, if you'd have told me
we were gonna be off the grid,
I would have planned things differently.
I thought the surprise
would be romantic.
These are the first few days we've
had just to be husband and wife,
and they might be the last
ones we have for a while.
Just want to enjoy them.
Don't you?
- Of course, I do.
- Good.
If I remember correctly,
there's a waterfall
a couple of miles from here.
It's not a hot tub,
but you can't beat it for stargazing.
So, if you're up for an adventure...
- Always. I'll go change.
- Hang on.
One minute.
Well, can we try for two?
Why didn't you tell me
you had gone to Stansfield?
What kind of a friend
robs your aunt's house,
then tries to blackmail
her with a sex tape?
I'm not saying that
what he did was okay.
No, it was technically illegal.
Have you ever broken a law?
I've never extorted anyone.
Because you haven't had to.
You don't know what it is like
to worry about making rent
or what you're gonna do
if your car breaks down.
Are you seriously suggesting
we should've just let him
get away with it?
Taken him at his word
that he's gonna stick to the deal?
- He's a-a criminal.
- Why didn't you tell me your plan?
Look, I didn't want
to make you lie in there.
I was trying to protect you.
And who does that sound like?
I thought you were the different one,
but now I see the family resemblance.
Mr. Carrington.
- You got two seconds for me?
- I'm already late.
Wait, what does this dress say to you?
Bold? Demure?
Loud enough to command a room
yet still whisper
"top of the class at Wharton"?
Is that...?
Matthew's phone.
- What, you took it?
- No.
Sam's friend did when
he robbed our house.
It's a long story.
But Dad told me he'd given
this back to Stansfield.
- Hmm. So, how'd you get it back?
- Sam.
And 200 grand.
But you remember the photo of
Cristal and Matthew in the car?
Yeah.
Well, there's a video on here of
them doing way more than sitting.
Have you seen it?
I can't unsee it.
I don't even want to
know why Dad had it.
Oh. Well, at least it's grainy.
Though she almost looks hot upside down.
Well, I got the phone back,
and I led Stansfield to the robber.
Wait. You helped Stansfield?
I helped everyone...
Dad, Cristal, Sammy Jo.
- Well, what do you get?
- What do you mean?
Well, you're on the hook for
a murder you didn't commit.
You should negotiate.
You give Stansfield the phone,
and he gives you the alternate suspect
the lawyers think you need.
I mean, as long as you're
complicit in police corruption,
- you might as well work it.
- I can't do that.
So if you simply hand over
the phone to Stansfield,
- where does that leave you?
- Back to square one.
No closer to figuring
out who killed Matthew,
and the FBI still thinks I did it.
Yeah, especially if you're the
last one holding onto this.
It is a spectacularly bad time
for Dad to be out of town.
What did I just tell you this morning?
We don't need anybody but us.
Use what you've got, Steven.
The sooner this is all over,
the sooner you can get
back to saving the world,
and I can get back to taking it over.
- Be good in there.
- I'll try.
Hey, why don't you come with?
I need somebody to keep me company
before I meet up with Jeff.
Ah, I didn't really dress for the club.
You're with me.
No one'll be looking at you.
- Do you see Jeff?
- VIP's over there.
I don't want Kori to see me yet.
Not until Jeff fluffs her,
gets her feeling a
little bit more generous.
- Let's get a drink at the bar.
- Okay.
Ugh!
How do people live like this...
waiting in line?
Uh, your Carrington's showing.
Southside?
No. Club soda. I'm working.
Fallon Carrington. Hi.
Robby. What a surprise.
Yeah. Kori Rucks texted me
and told me to come out.
You remember Kori, right?
I didn't know you'd be here tonight.
It's been a while, hasn't it?
Like, seven and a half months, yeah.
- Oh, wow. We're keeping track.
- You know, I've been
texting you,
and I know you've been getting them.
- About St. Barths?
- I thought that already happened.
It did, but I can always go back.
- What's your schedule like?
- Um...
Robby, this is my boyfriend, Michael.
Robby and I went to school together.
It's like a reunion up in here.
Did you go to, uh, Penley, too?
Decatur.
Public.
Wow.
Uh, good for you, man.
And, uh, good to see you, Fallon.
You, too.
Boyfriend?
Let's dance.
I am blowing up.
"Cristal Carrington Sex Tape"?
Is that real?
Oh, it's real.
How do you know?
Educated guess. Excuse me.
I have to make some calls.
Glad this is behind us.
Now, it's best that doesn't make it back
to police headquarters.
Shouldn't make it back
to my father, either.
This is between us.
What are you doing?
You have your money back,
your friend is safe...
But I'm not.
I want to make sure there's
no misunderstanding here.
By giving you this,
I'm giving you a second chance.
It's an opportunity
to make things right.
Not just for me.
The Blaisdel family deserves closure.
Matthew deserves justice.
That's your responsibility now.
You want me to find the real killer,
but I already told you,
it's the FBI's case now.
And I'm telling you, I don't care.
Do your job.
Close the case.
Understood.
Have you seen this?
Oh, more than seen it.
Honestly,
I did not expect the landing strip.
Okay, don't be a perv.
Speaking of pervs,
did you see Robby Reid?
On his way out.
He said he met your boyfriend.
And here I was thinking
that you're not dating
because you're a workaholic,
but you're just multitasking
by screwing your driver.
God, no. I just told him
that so he'd get off my back.
What? It worked.
I'm sorry. It just won't stop.
And what about Kori and Jeff?
Aren't you supposed to swoop
in there and close that deal?
I know. I know. I'll be right back.
I know Fallon has her blind spots.
I hadn't noticed.
But I'm telling you,
if there's one thing she does know,
it's energy.
It's in her blood.
Of course. She's a Carrington.
But that's the problem.
The city of Atlanta is not gonna
be a pawn in their family feud.
This contract will determine
whether people can keep their lights on,
and I don't trust Fallon Carrington
to think of them when it counts.
Do you trust me?
You went into business with her.
That means it's my business, too.
You know I'll do right
by you and by this city.
If you'll at least hear her out,
I promise I'll hold her to her word.
I will, for you.
You know, I think my sister
invited her out tonight.
I'll get us another bottle.
Yo. Where's Fallon?
And why are you drinking?
I thought you were her ride.
- Not anymore.
- Just tell your girlfriend I'm looking for her, okay?
- She's not my girlfriend.
- Sure looked like she was the other night at the gala.
Talk to Fallon, okay?
I've never gotten a
straight answer out of her.
Maybe you will.
Hey, wait up.
Why don't you join us for a drink?
Okay.
Kori, this is Michael Culhane.
He's a... friend.
Mm.
A single friend?
I believe he is.
Can you just admit that we're lost?
Well, I will admit that I should've
paid for street lamps out here,
'cause I can't see a damn thing.
Maybe I should look at the map.
Good luck.
So, the sun set that way,
which means...
we've been going north this whole time.
Blake, I told you we were
going in the wrong direction.
Look, we're probably
all the way over here now.
By this ranger station.
Well, maybe they can help us.
I'd be willing to ask directions.
Do you seriously expect me to believe
that you accidentally led us
straight to the ranger station?
Are you actually that desperate
to check your messages?
I told you it wasn't a good time,
but you insisted.
So you admit it.
You did bring us here on purpose.
God!
I can't believe I thought we could have
one whole day together
without the world pressing in.
Oh. And there it is.
Well, you came all this way for service.
You might as well have a look.
Oh, hell.
Oh, my God.
Did they find the robber?
What is this?
Looks like it's you and Matthew.
- All over the Internet.
- _
Are you... filming me?
Stop. Let me film you.
I want my lawyers here, now.
Waiting in the study, sir.
Perhaps we suggest they move in.
I'm sorry, what?!
Your "friend" did that to me?
- Ow.
- How could you let this happen, Sam?
I don't know.
I guess he had a fail-safe.
Or he lied and he had already sold it.
I'm sorry.
Steven didn't tell me he was
gonna get the cops involved.
You told Steven about this?
About the robbery?
Well, I had to. I didn't have the money.
And I might have fudged
some of the details.
I told Steven I didn't know
they were gonna rob the house.
So that's how you didn't get arrested.
Well, I did it to protect you, too.
If I told him I did it and about my mom,
then he'd ask what you knew.
And if he told Blake...
I-I thought I fixed it, Cristal.
I'm sorry.
What are they saying about me?
Cristal...
Just rip the Band-Aid off, Sam.
"Million-Dollar Tramp."
"Naked Ambition."
And, uh, this one's kind of clever:
"Private Relations."
Like, they crossed out "public."
It's charming.
I'm Atlanta's biggest slut.
Well, I can't speak to that, but...
looks like Fallon can.
Fallon, Fallon!
Can you comment on
the sex tape that's just surfaced?
Uh, well,
I know about as much as you do.
You know, I can't comment on
somebody else's proclivities.
I think those are questions
for the movie star.
That bitch.
Willy.
Uh, I wasn't sure you'd pick up.
I've tried everyone.
Stansfield hung up on me.
The FBI won't even call me back.
The FBI? What's going on?
You've seen this tape of Matthew
and Cristal, haven't you?
Unfortunately.
Has Claudia?
Yeah, she's seen it.
I just got back from her house.
She's a mess.
She may not be able
to fight for herself,
but you can be damn sure
I'm gonna fight for her.
This tape... i-it's motive.
Blake didn't want his new wife's
old boyfriend hanging around.
Wait.
You still think my dad killed Matthew?
It wasn't you.
You were Matthew's friend.
Maybe the only good
one left in that house.
Where are you right now?
I'm coming to meet you.
As I've told everyone else,
this is between my father
and his surprisingly flexible new bride.
It's a private family matter.
About as private as a circus.
Hey.
What happened to you last night?
I came to find you. You were gone.
Well, I had every newspaper in Atlanta
calling me about Cristal's porno.
I texted you.
That's why you bailed on our plan?
To give interviews about
your stepmother's sex tape?
You took your eye off the prize
to take a swipe at Cristal.
You really can't help yourself, can you?
Well, she's not just my stepmother.
She's also the new COO
of our main competition
of this new deal we're trying to strike.
That's right. We.
And I was there for you, Fallon.
I put myself on the line
for a deal you had to have.
But you made me look like an idiot,
because you're only out for yourself.
Must be genetic.
And speaking of our main competition,
congratulations.
Carrington Atlantic lost the contract.
Kori just called me.
- Wait, we got it?
- No. Southern Power did.
The Morell Corp presentation
wasn't concrete enough
for the city council.
That was all you, remember?
I'm guessing you didn't
play team sports as a kid.
But we're supposed to
be in this together.
You're no longer the only one
who pays for your mistakes.
Willy?
It's Steven.
Hello?
I just can't believe it.
Toxicology will confirm
his death looks like a suicide.
He had a bottle of
sleeping pills next to him.
And there was a note
claiming responsibility for
the Windbriar explosion.
That doesn't make sense.
Willy called me,
and I didn't see a note.
One of my detectives
discovered it in the bedroom.
And it seems Willy was
angry at Carrington Atlantic
for twice denying him a promotion.
So he killed Matthew?
Apparently he didn't intend to.
He was trying to sabotage the operation
and damage Carrington
Atlantic equipment.
His friend Matthew
was collateral damage, it seems.
And then seeing his name dragged
through the mud these last 24 hours...
it was too much.
Does the FBI know about this?
They've already been alerted.
And, um, they're confirming his story,
but it's just a formality.
And once the toxicology comes out,
charges against you will be dropped.
The Horse Whisperer rides again.
What about Claudia?
Has anyone spoken to her?
We're sending someone over now.
Oh, my God.
It's not how we expected this to end,
but at least...
she'll finally have some closure.
Hey.
I don't understand.
It's been a rough day, hasn't it?
While I'm here...
I believe you have something for me.
Hey.
You okay?
No.
I was there.
I saw Willy, and I didn't see a note.
And what, then Stansfield's
guy just happens to find one?
That lets us all off the hook?
If anything,
shouldn't I be more of a suspect?
I was the one that found him.
What are you trying to say, Steven?
Just...
It seems off.
A week ago, Willy was in this house,
accusing you of killing Matthew.
Why would he suddenly admit it now?
Guilt is an unpredictable animal.
Or Stansfield is.
I know you're shaken right now.
We've all been through the wringer.
But Stansfield is not a bad guy.
He's only helped this family.
Whoa.
Did someone go a little too
hard at the club last night?
No, I'm just beat.
Ugh. Me, too.
And if I have to take one more
call to comment on this video...
It's not even news anymore.
Even I'm over it.
- Are you?
- Sorry?
Well, you took that phone, didn't you?
You leaked the video.
I didn't take the phone.
You're like a human bulldozer.
- And you'll crush anyone.
- Please.
Cristal's a big girl, Michael.
She doesn't need you defending her.
Maybe someone should defend the
world from Fallon Carrington.
The way you treat her,
the way you treated Kori...
Kori?
You just don't see other people.
Kori just hates me because I
was a bitch in high school.
And I was a bitch because when
your mom leaves in the middle
of sophomore year,
it kind of messes with your head.
I mean, if I didn't defend myself,
who would've?
That is heartbreaking.
But it was almost ten years ago.
Maybe you should stop blaming your mom
and try to figure out why
you're so screwed up now.
Hey.
I'm sorry I didn't get a
chance to congratulate you.
I was actually coming
to apologize to you.
What you said yesterday,
about my privilege...
you were right.
I should have been honest.
I was trying to protect you, but...
I just ended up hurting more people.
Don't feel too bad.
You were right about that guy.
I shouldn't have trusted him.
But the thing is...
I should've been arrested, too.
What? Why?
Because I set it up.
I told him to steal my aunt's ring.
Are you kidding me?
I know.
But my mom needed money,
fast, and I panicked.
You're the reason that
all of this has happened?
It got out of control.
And I needed you to help me,
and I didn't think you would
if I told you the truth.
- You're damn right I wouldn't.
- I know how much
you hate being lied to;
that's why I wanted to come clean.
What, you think that fixes this?
I did all of this help you,
and now you're telling me
that it's all your fault?
I know. I'm sorry.
Well, I don't accept that.
And I get now why your
aunt didn't want you here.
The press isn't going away.
I think I need to make a statement.
I'm not gonna make you do that again.
Let the FBI tell them about Willy.
It's not about Willy.
I didn't get a say in
this thing getting out.
I should have told you about the phone.
I should have told
you about the robbery.
After the fact,
Sam told me that it was his friend
and that he was involved.
And I should have told you,
but he's a good kid, Blake.
He made a mistake.
Well, on any other day,
I would probably be upset,
but... I made a mistake, too.
Do you remember the day
we took our engagement photos
and Matthew came to the house?
Of course.
And I told you we didn't argue.
Well, he threatened me with blackmail.
He said that you would not marry me
if you knew what kind of man I was.
Blackmail you with what?
Steven. Look, you know
that before Steven ran off
to dig wells in Haiti that
he was with the company.
He didn't want the job,
and I pushed him up the ladder too fast.
Out in the field one day,
he missed a faulty pressure valve,
and he signed off on the inspection.
Oh, my God.
Later, when they put it online,
the pressure shook the rig,
a man fell off
and snapped his neck.
How come I never heard about this?
Matthew was the field engineer on site.
I asked him to write it
off as a structural defect.
You covered it up.
And Matthew claimed to have
a record of it on his phone.
So, I knew if Steven ever found out
he had something to do
with the man's death,
he would never have
stopped blaming himself.
But the victim is described as...
I was trying to protect him.
I-I ended up sacrificing you.
I'm-I'm so sorry, Cristal.
I understand.
I was just trying to protect Sam.
That's what family does.
No matter how hard or how much it hurts.
We stand by them.
But you and I...
...I don't want us to have secrets.
I want to trust you,
and I want you to trust me.
Can we start again?
Clean slate?
No more lies.
- synced and corrected by sot26 - www.
addic7ed.com