( Sighs ) Blake, wouldn't it be wonderful
if we never had to go back?
If we found an island,
just the two of us?
No worries. Barefoot.
- Nothing but you and me alone.
- Well, not-not quite alone.
How about the mosquitoes?
( Pilot On Intercom ) For you,
Mr. Carrington. From Denver. Mr. Laird.
Says it's urgent.
( Chuckles )
Andrew? Yes, yes, I'm fine.
Hawaii was fine too.
So was Samoa and Tahiti.
A wonderful honeymoon. It--
What is it? What's wrong?
Blake, I don't know whether
you've heard the news yet...
but the colonel was just murdered--
assassinated by those damn barbarians.
Well, what did our friends in the State
Department have to say about that?
They expect the rebels
to take over momentarily.
Period? That's it?
Andrew, we've got a fortune
tied up there in proven reserves.
They've blockaded
all tanker traffic, Blake.
Well, damn it, we've got
five tankers in that port.
All right. Yes.
Mm-hmm. Bye-bye.
Trouble?
I promised you six weeks,
and we're going to make that.
Blake, there'll be
other times.
- No--
- Come on, you've got to do what's important.
Let's go back. Please?
( Sighs )
All right.
I'll make it up to you.
( Car Approaching )
There's the car.
They're coming.
- I'm sorry. Are you all right?
- I know you're not happy
about Krystle coming back...
but there's no reason to kill me.
- Welcome home, Mr. Carrington.
- Hello,Joseph.
Put these in Mrs. Carrington's
dressing room, please.
- Welcome back, Mrs. Carrington.
- Oh, thank you,Joseph.
My, it all looks somehow
bigger than I remember it.
We've tried to keep it
exactly as it was.
Oh, uh,Joseph.
I want Mr. Laird over here...
and Brickmore,
Chernin and Maruzzella.
I'll do that right away.
- Hello, darling!
- Daddy! Welcome home.
-Jeff, how are you?
- Oh, pretty good.
- Taking good care of her?
- I've been trying to, sir.
- It's good to have you back.
- Oh, thank you,Jeff.
- By the way, how is Cecil?
- Oh, fine.Just fine.
I imagine he'll be getting
together with you soon.
- Hello, Fallon.
- Hi.
Oh, that's really nice. Maybe you could
have it wired for a lamp or something.
Oh, that's an idea.
( Chuckles )
Something the matter?
What are you keeping
him around for?
Jeff Colby?
I'm just keepin' him around
till I can beat him in tennis.
Then I'll throw him away and get
somebody I can't beat. ( Chuckles )
( Matthew )
Now, keep your eyes closed.
Okay.
She's all yours, Claudia.
It's a month today
since you got home from the hospital.
How do you like it?
- You don't like the color.
- ( Sighs ) It's beautiful. Really.
Well--
Look, um, we've got so many bills to pay.
We've still got my therapy.
- You're trying to start a new business. This is--
- I got it at a steal.
A real steal. I got it
from a friend of mine.
So don't worry.
How 'bout it? One time around
the block, the two of us together.
Claudia, don't.
Please don't be afraid to come back.
All the way back.
This is only a machine, and beyond it
out there is only traffic.
- Real world stuff.
- ( Sighs )
- And honey, you gotta be able to--
- Confront.
- Yes.
- Right.
It's a month.
You said it's a month.
It's not a long time.
You know that, Matthew.
Here, you take these, and, uh...
use 'em or use it
whenever you feel like it--
today, tomorrow, whenever.
- Agreed?
- Right!
That's just the way Dr.Jordan
speaks to his patients.
That's the way he talks to me.
""Agreed, Claudia?''
Why don't we go in the house
and have some coffee?
What for? Why?
Am I shaking? Am I talking too loud?
All right. I'll take the car back tonight.
I'll do whatever you want.
Don't you do that, Matthew.
Don't you walk away from me.
Don't treat me
like damaged goods.
Look, I didn't ask to come
back here. You asked me to.
And if we've got something to fight about,
I'm gonna fight with you.
So don't you walk away from me.
If you're angry with me,
shout at me. I don't care.
I'm not gonna fall apart.
I promise you.
All right.
We've been married how long?
Fifteen years?
And we still can't exchange a lousy present
without punishing one another, can we?
- Meaning what?
- Meaning--
Meaning a couple of kids
fell in love and had a baby.
And had to grow up
faster than was fun.
That's not it, Matthew!
It's just the car.
I'm just not ready to handle it yet.
Well, then you better get ready. Because I
don't like being married to a mental patient...
anymore than you like bein' one.
I mean it, Claudia.
I'm not drivin' you around anymore.
Let's go, honey. We're late for school.
( Car Door Closes, Engine Starts )
- Bye.
- Bye, baby.
( Engine Starts )
( Gasps )
I know where
I can find some pipe.
What are we gonna do
with it after you find it?
Bring in the richest field
this side of Spindletop.
At least that's what you said when you
dragged me into this damn fool operation.
Well, that was before
the crew walked off.
- Who'd you hit this time?
- I didn't hit anybody.
Sometimes you forget
who owns what in this company.
Uh-uh. I remember.
We each own 50% of nothing.
What happened?
The bank turned me down
on a loan. ( Chuckles )
I went back out there to tell the crew
there wouldn't be no payday...
and they all walked off.
What I like about the oil
business is the loyalty.
- Come on. I'll buy you a beer.
- ( Engine Starts )
Matthew?
- ( Gasps )
- Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't mean to frighten you.
You did, a little.
Do you know where everybody is?
No, I don't. I came here
looking for Matthew Blaisdel.
Well, so did I.
I'm Claudia Blaisdel, his wife.
- You're Matthew Blaisdel's wife?
- Yeah.
Steven Carrington.
It's very nice to meet you.
- We talked on the phone once.
- Yes, yes.
Your father's wedding.
That trouble with Walter.
My husband appreciated
that call very much.
( Sighs )
This was dumb of me.
I mean, I wanted to have a little surprise.
You know, make a celebration.
- I should have telephoned first.
- What are you celebrating?
My conquest of man over machine.
Well, I mean it's
woman over machine, but--
It was an important moment.
What are you doing for lunch? I mean,
I have sandwiches here and wine and--
Oh, no, I won't be able to stay.
I've got to find your husband.
It's kind of important.
They're probably at Meadsburg.
If you really want me to stay--
No, it's okay, really.
Steven.
Would you like a sandwich
or something for the road?
Yeah.
Okay.
- Ham and cheese.
- Thank you.
( Engine Rewing, Tires Screeching )
- Andrew.
- Hi, Philip.
-Jasper. Doug.
Eddington is on the phone.
Talk to him, stall him.
Good to see you. Go on in.
Blake?
*( Country )
*( Continues )
( Inhales Sharply )
- ( Grunts )
- ( Cheers )
- Well, looks like you did it, Amos.
- Not bad, huh?
How about me, Matthew?
Now that you're on a losing streak.
Hey, Russell to Garvey here.
( Laughs )
Losing streak, huh?
I wouldn't be too sure about that, Bobby.
Because I think he made me win...
so's I'd go back on the job--
in appreciation.
No, you won.
And as far as appreciation goes...
I'm not asking for anything.
I mean, uh--
Just because we're having
a little run of bad luck--
rig falling down on us-- well,
if you guys don't understand that--
Oh, come on. We've heard that speech
before. So save the tears.
You don't pay us.
We don't work for you.
Hey, we like you, Matthew.
But we don't like you that much. ( Laughs )
( Chuckling )
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
What are you babying this bunch for?
Oh,you're looking at
the dregs of Meadsburg here.
In fact, you're looking at the dregs
of the whole state. They're bums.
Now you. You looking to get
a recommendation when you leave here?
Sure as hell don't need one
from you, Lankershim.
Yeah, well, you sure as hell
ain't gonna get one either, buster.
Not from me, not from anybody else
in this state in his right mind.
Cleaned out the jails,
cleaned out the flophouses.
Tried to give them a start, yeah.
That's the way they repay us--
stabbing us in the back, walking out.
- Well, they're bums. Scum!
- Hey, come on! Hold it, hold it.
You think I can't take him,just 'cause
he's got two or three years on me?
More like 20, but who's counting?
Now take it easy.
Bum!
All right.
Okay, you guys all know me.
So I tell you what.
I got some new pipe coming,
and I got a loan from a bank over in Pueblo.
So, uh, come on back to work...
and you'll still get paid
for a full day today.
How about it?
I'll work for you, Matthew.
Just tell me what you want me to do.
I've been around oil rigs all my life.
- Hey, you're Carrington's kid, aren't you?
- I'm Steven Carrington.
( Chuckles ) You know,
you get that black stuff all over you...
that made your daddy so rich,
you're gonna take a whole week to wash it off.
( Rigger ~2 ) You'd go home
stinking ofkerosene and gasoline oil.
Those nice clothes all sweaty.
Hey come on, guys, get off him.
Leave him alone.
( Rigger ~ 1 ) What's your daddy gonna say
when you get that nice $200 shirt all sweaty?
He don't wash 'em, dummy.
He throws them away.
( Whistles )
Hey, come on, you guys.
- You're forgetting the real question around here.
- Huh?
It's who his old man is. How he probably
sent him over here so's he could be his spy.
Now, we might be rabble and dregs...
but your old man is the biggest crook
who ever lived.
- My father's not a crook.
- You better go on home now, son.
He never walked off on a job.
He never let down
his friends in a jam.
Well, ain't that
just wonderful, boys, huh?
( Clapping )
Now you tell me that.
( Object Clatters )
Now you show me that.
I can't help you
with this one, Steven.
This is one-on-one.
You either fight him or you walk.
I didn't come here to fight.
I came here to help.
( Shouting )
You better stop it.
Hey, man.
Stay down, will you, boy?
Matthew, come on. I don't want to kill him.
Tell him to stay down here.
All right, all right. That's enough.
That's enough. Come on.
Did I get the job?
Yeah. You got it.
That makes three of us. Come on.
- Come on.
- ( Grunting )
- What did you have to hire him for?
- Ow!
Well, you gotta admit.
He showed some spunk.
Yeah, but you can't go around hiring everybody
just because they show a little spunk.
Walter, can't you find
anything good in somebody?
I mean he's not Blake Carrington.
He's his own man.
Okay. You win.
But we get no bucks by next Friday...
and that's gonna have to be it.
We'll take the kid back with us.
Take good care of him, will ya?
( Engine Rewing )
( Blake ) And what does
the State Department expect me to do?
- Invade the damn country to get my oil out?
- ( Chattering )
Well, I suppose it's a lot easier to be patient
when it's not your ox that's being gored.
All right.
Call me when you hear something.
- What does he recommend?
- ""Wait and see.''
Everything depends on which
one of those fanatics...
manages to kill off all the others
and come out on top.
Well, maybe he'll be a gentleman,
and turn those tankers loose.
Maybe he'll just nationalize
the whole shooting match...
and trade it to the Russians
for MiG-21 's.
Andrew--
What kind of advances can we get
while our crude is tied up?
Twenty cents on the dollar.
Maybe.
- Where would that leave us?
- Bankruptcy. And that's the upside.
Six operational offices
from Tangiers to Cape Town.
Payoffs to every swindling five-percenter
in sight, and we get caught like this?
What dimwitted office boy thought
we ought to go in there in the first place?
As I recall, Blake, it was you.
( Fallon )
Well, I still think it was a good idea.
Fallon. How did you get in here?
Oh, I told the guard at the door
I was C.I.A. Undercover.
Look. Daddy, I believe
your analogy at the time...
had to do with
the grasshopper and the ants.
""The government isn't putting
anything by for a rainy day,'' you said.
""Maybe Denver Carrington should.''
Be a good girl and run along, will you?
I'm busy.
Andrew, while we're ""waiting and seeing,''
is there anything else that I should know?
Uh, about that
Lankershim-Blaisdel property.
We haven't quite got
a hook into that one yet.
We try to stop their supplies,
they find new sources.
We attempt to cut off their money,
they get new backing.
Every time we knock them down,
they get right back up.
- Spare me the details, Andrew.Just handle it.
- I understand, Blake.
Well, your understanding isn't gonna
help us a hell of a whole lot...
if we've got nothing to show our stockholders
when that other thing comes crashing down.
So if your present methods are not working,
perhaps you'd better try--
- A little Carrington hospitality.
- Fallon, would you please--
Okay, okay, I'm going.
I'm only trying to say...
that you might catch more flies with honey
than you are with buttermilk.
- Out. Out, please.
- Daddy.
- Out!
- Daddy, will you listen to me?
Matthew Blaisdel
was your friend once.
What would it hurt for you to invite him
into your home like a human being...
and explain to him the advantages
of coming back into the company.
And bringing his leases with him.
Or are you so bloody jealous of
what went on between he and Krystle...
that you'd really rather bust
Blaisdel than win him over?
You may just have an idea.
You mean a brilliant idea.
I mean, you've made your point.
Now, will you get out of here?
-Jeanette, who is it for dinner this evening?
-Just you and Mr. Carrington.
I'm setting a bit early because
there's a dance over in Magordo...
and Joseph gave me
permission to go.
Oh, of course.
This room's so big, and
it'll be beautiful out tonight.
I'd like to eat
out on the terrace.
Well, you see, ma'am--
Joseph prefers all evening meals
be served in the dining room.
He-- He's liable
to have a snit if you--
We'll eat in here.
It'll be fine.
- Have a good time this evening.
- Thank you.
You're not staying
for dinner, Andy?
No, I have some things
to attend to this evening.
Daddy's really in trouble
this time, isn't he?
Well, you were there.
You heard. Or, rather, you overheard.
What would it take
to bail him out?
- More than your allowance, I'm afraid.
- How much?
Forget it, Fallon.
There isn't anything you can do to help.
You're pretty sure of that, aren't you?
You could be wrong, you know.
- You love him a lot, don't you?
- You know I do.
But you don't love Krystle a lot.
You really fixed her good
this time, didn't you?
Got your father to thinking about
inviting Matthew Blaisdel over here.
It's the smartest thing for him to do,
Andy. I don't have to tell you that.
It will also make Krystle crazy.
You don't have to tell me that either.
And you figure that by chipping away
at her, little by little...
you'll be able to drive her out
of this house, hmm?
She's no good for him.
She'll just drag him down.
You know, Fallon--
most little girls realize by the age of six...
that they can't grow up
and marry their daddies.
Friends shouldn't fight.
You're right. Bye, Andy.
You know, honey?
I've been thinking. I was--
Well, I was kind of rough
on you this morning. So--
Well, I thought I'd take
the car back and then...
well, when you're ready,
you'll be ready.
I was out at the rig
to see you today.
- You were?
- Uh-huh.
- How'd you get there?
- ( Chuckles )
I-- I drove.
( Laughing )
Come on.
- Come on.
- I drove. You got me a car, didn't you?
- That's good, honey. That's real good.
- Mm.
What's real good...
is that I felt like myself today
for the first time.
Slugging it out with you
this morning helped.
So.
I want to thank you for
letting me fight with you.
( Sighs )
Fighting. Driving.
All in one day.
Anything else you care to try?
I don't know.
Maybe I'll think of something.
( Chuckles )
- You're getting me all wet.
- Oh, I'm sorry. I'll just--
No. I'll take your towel.
- ( Chuckling ) No, no, no.
- Yeah.
Hold on a minute.
Don't we know you?
Morning, Dad. Krystle.
Hi, Steven.
What happened to your face?
Uh, nothing.
Just a little accident.
Where've you been? We haven't seen you
since we've been back.
- I've been around.
- New means of transportation?
Yeah,just a little
something I picked up.
By the way, when are you gonna let me
know what job you're going to take?
I already have a job.
But not with your company.
- Oh? Who's it with?
- You're not going to like it.
Let me be the judge.
I'm working for Matthew Blaisdel.
You're right. I don't like it.
Dad, I thought you'd appreciate it...
that I'm trying to learn the business.
You see, I don't want to be
just Blake Carrington's son.
LikeJeff, standing around,
waiting to be Cecil's gofer.
You were brought up
the hard way, right?
Well, I want to be the same.
You've got to appreciate that.
Yes, yes. I do.
But why him?
Well, why not him? Unless what Walter
accuses you of is true.
That you tried to wreck the rig...
and that you're trying to run them
out of business.
All right, you want
to work on a rig. Fine.
I've got 22 of them.
I'll put you on one of mine.
- No.
- Why not?
Because I have finally
done something on my own.
Being your son,
it wasn't that easy.
It wasn't easy for me, either,
being your father.
( Engine Starts )
You were pretty hard on him, Blake.
He's young.
And he's my son.
And I'll deal with him. My way.
- Mrs. Carrington.
- Peter, may I talk to you for a moment?
- Of course, Mrs. Carrington.
- First, the dinner last night was wonderful.
- Thank you, Mrs. Carrington.
I was looking over the rest
of the menus for the week.
Is there something
you don't like?
Oh, no,
not that I don't like it.
It's just that I think that duck
is a little heavy this time of the year.
Well, the fact is,Joseph has always
had me prepare duckling...
on the first Friday of each month.
Of course, we could substitute squab,
if you would prefer squab.
Yes, I would.
- Settled, then?
- Yes, thank you.
Good evening, darling.
What are you doing in here?
We were just substituting
one favorite for another.
- No problem, Mr. Carrington.
- Oh,Joseph?
Yes, sir.
We're having a party here next
Saturday night. Prepare dinner for 1 0.
Yes, Mr. Carrington.
I'm afraid you're not going to like this
any more than I do.
But it's business, and it's important.
I've invited Walter Lankershim.
And Matthew Blaisdel and his wife.
- Can I drop you off somewhere?
- No. I have a date.
MasterJeffrey again?
You're warm.
Well, what about us?
We've been known to be pretty warm
on... quite a few occasions.
- Are you gonna let me go?
- I asked you something.
I'm late. Now let go of me.
One of these days, lady,
you're gonna want me.
I'm not gonna be here.
Good evening, Mrs. Carrington.
And how has your day been?
That good, huh? Come on now.
Don't you think we ought
to talk about this?
What is it?
This morning, with Steven?
I know I was rude to you, but
my kids are-- Well, they're not easy.
- It's frustrating.
- It's not only Steven.
- What is it then? The party?
- It's not the party.
Joseph will take care of the party
just likeJoseph takes care of everything.
Come on, now.
What is it? Let's talk about it.
Are you really inviting
Matthew Blaisdel to this house?
Yes, I am.
Everybody who's coming to the party
knows about Matthew and me.
Are you that intent
on embarrassing me?
I told you that it was important to me
to have Matthew come here.
Important to you. To you.
The children are yours. The house
is yours. The servants are yours.
The servants?
Now what is this about the servants?
- Nothing. Never mind.
- Well, come on now, what about them?
Oh, Blake. It's not important.
It's just that everything's so new.
Now, what about the servants?
It sounds stupid, but it hurts when you can't
get a maid to serve you on the terrace.
When I fold my own clothes,
and another maid is offended.
The chef has menus that are carved in stone,
and when I ask about them, he puts me off.
I can't get the gardener to put flowers
in the bedroom without an order...
- from you in triplicate.
- Well, why didn't you tell me about all this?
Because you have problems, and I didn't
want to bother you with nonsense.
And that's what it is.
It's nonsense.
I should be able to
handle it. But I can't.
I don't know what to do
or what not to do.
You want to know
the truth?
I'd feel more comfortable here
as one of the staff.
Joseph. Assemble the staff.
Yes, now!
Good of you to come.
I thought all of you knew my wife.
Apparently that was an oversight, and I'll
rectify that by making proper introductions.
To begin with, this is
Mrs. Blake Carrington.
My wife.
And the mistress of this house.
Blake, please. I don't want
to go through with this.
This is Michael.
He's ambitious.
He listens in on conversations
which do not concern him.
But he drives well.
And he might last the year out.
Gerald pads the grocery bills.
Jeanette forgets instructions.
Mrs. Gunnerson's several relatives
eat well at my expense.
However, they all do good work, and that
outweighs their small deficiencies.
- Blake, please. Could we stop?
- My wife is concerned for you.
Now is there anyone here
that's uncomfortable?
Good. Good.
Then I'll go on.
Leon, how long have
you been with me?
- Ten years, sir.
- Working my gardens.
The man in charge of all the other labor
we bring in to help you.
Yes.
And did you recently have a conversation
with my wife about flowers?
Uh, I think so, yes.
And did she ask you
in the course of that conversation...
to place some flowers
in our bedroom?
Uh, that's right, she did.
And did you tell her that I do not like
flowers in my bedroom?
Yes, you've always said
that you don't.
Mrs. Carrington loves
flowers in her room. I do not.
But I'll get used to that.
What I'll not get used to is rudeness.
So pack your bags.
I want you out of here in the morning.
The rest of you will understand that
what I've tried to convey...
is that you are all
dispensable to me.
My wife is not.
( Sighs )
How could you do that?
- I know that you're feeling a little--
- I didn't want that man fired.
- That was the last thing I wanted.
- Tomorrow morning...
Joseph will come to me and
say that Leon has apologized...
and would like to have
his job back.
And I will give him
And the others will all say:
""That Mr. Carrington is
a hard man, but a fair man.''
Krystle, I can't expect you to
know about all this right away.
About how this house is run.
About who comes to this house
as guests and why.
But I will teach you.
And you will learn.
Come on. Let's go to bed.
If I hadn't called you, Cecil, I guess
I never would have heard from you again.
No, probably not. You were
a momentary indulgence, Fallon.
You see, I really prefer
slightly more mature women.
Oh. Well, I've decided that it's time
to put away childish things.
Which makes me, ergo,
available.
And?
Fallon, if we were going
to proceed with this...
I'd have whisked you off somewhere
less damp, more intimate.
But, you see,
this is a sort of...
out-in-the-open business meeting
between the two of us.
Your father is in deep trouble.
You want me to help him.
I never said that.
There's a half-Oklahoma,
half Walton-on-Thames...
gypsy streak in me
that reads minds.
Just as you are
reading mine right now.
- Am I?
- I believe so.
I want you to marryJeff.
You know something?
I'd rather marry you.
That's very sweet.
But each of us is here for a reason beyond
what we really want for ourselves.
Yours being your nephew.
He adores you.
I want him to settle down
with someone smart, even brilliant.
You. As for the wedding
gift, what I have--
- Aren't you rushing this a little?
- I don't think so.
You'll bail out my father.
Exactly.
You can't not likeJeff.
He's bright enough. He's good-looking.
Caring. Quite a catch,
some would say.
Sort of a Denver version
Prince of Wales.
Cecil, when I marry,
what I want...
is to lie beside
a man who excites me.
And I have.
You listen to me, my dear.
Passion dies.
Power remains.
There are very few young men in this world
who'll be as powerful as Jeff Colby.
If he gets direction...
to direct his drive.
It's there. It just needs
guidance, stirring up.
Stimulation--
that's the word.
Something I obviously
have been unable to provide.
Fallon, most important
to you is Blake.
I know that.
Just as we both know that I'm the one
who can help him most.
- When?
- Immediately.
- He'll find out.
- No, he won't. Nor willJeff.
What if I change my mind,
and I don't keep my end of the bargain?
Let's just say that,
at my age...
vengeance is
as sweet as sex.
Well, what do you say?
Do we have a deal?
( Car Door Closes )