(indistinct chatter)
WOMAN:
Nice room, fancy.
MAN:
It's not bad.
I stay here
whenever I'm in town, so...
WOMAN:
That's nice, baby.
Now, let's get that
silly jacket off.
MAN:
Maybe...
50 bucks says
he chickens out.
No way. He just shelled out
like a month's salary.
He's locked and loaded.
He's way over his head.
Look how fidgety he is.
It's his first time
with a working girl.
You're some kind
of mind reader?
We've watched a million videos
like this,
giving me disturbing insight
into the male psyche.
WOMAN:
Let's get to business.
MAN:
Really? Whoa...
(silenced gunshots)
No, wait!
(panting)
Please.
You don't have to do this.
(silenced gunshots)
♪ Boom, boom, boom, boom ♪
♪ Bang, bang, bang, bang ♪
♪ How, how, how, how ♪
♪ Hey, hey ♪
♪ You gotta come on. ♪
(door opens)
(door shuts)
(nearby clattering)
(faint blips and beeps)
Whoever's there,
identify yourself!
Ow!
(groaning)
Sorry. It's me.
It's Sebastian.
First day on the job,
I got a little excited,
I couldn't sleep,
so I figured
I'd just come in.
At 5:00 in the morning.
Thought I'd just
get a head start on things,
maybe unpack my stuff.
Anyway, where should
I put my stuff?
I haven't gotten you a desk yet.
Still figuring out logistics.
Okay. All right, that's fine.
I'll just,
uh...
I'll just hold
onto this for now.
We'll find a place for you.
Oh, totally. Yeah, yeah.
I know, I know.
Just, I'm so nervous,
you know?
Like, "first day at school
and you don't know anyone"
kind of nervous,
but that's strange, right?
'Cause I,
I know everyone here.
Never easy taking a new job.
Especially
on an experienced team.
But you're here for a reason.
You'll do great. I promise.
And...
...I got something
for you.
Your service weapon.
Welcome to NCIS.
Forensics Agent Lund.
This is...
this is really happening.
(phone beeping)
So's this...
Four dead bodies...
Including a sailor.
Yes! All right.
Man, that's insensitive.
I'm sorry.
Just first case as an agent,
you know?
Yeah. Gonna be great.
(sirens wailing)
LASALLE:
Lieutenant Annabelle Shaw.
Computer specialist
out of Belle Chase.
Navy sent her here to help
install a software update,
along with her co-worker,
Eric Smith.
DoD contractor.
Killer or killers
come through that door,
guns blazing.
Takes out
the guard,
Mr. Smith and Lt. Shaw?
What exactly is this place?
It's a federal data sharing...
Well, some short of data farm...
I'm sorry. Do--?
Is it my turn?
Just trying to figure out
the-the briefing etiquette.
Go for it, my friend.
All right.
It's a Federal server farm,
where different agencies at DoD
and DOJ share and analyze intel.
Yeah. FBI, CIA, Navy Intel--
all of them store
their files here.
High-value target.
Assuming data was stolen?
Yeah. Over a thousand terabytes
worth, according to this log.
We're talking about a massive
breach of national security.
Oh! I just can't get over it.
(chuckles)
Aww. You're all grown up...
Okay. All right. You know,
I'm trying to work here.
Oh, right. Yes, of course.
(clears throat)
There's a fourth victim outside.
Also shot twice.
How many suspects we looking at?
Uh, it's too soon to tell,
but I'd say just one.
Each victim has a double
tap to the chest.
Someone was very handy
with a weapon.
Handy with electronics, too.
Entire security system,
including surveillance
is taken offline.
Oh. I'm sorry about that.
Trying to work out
the timing, still.
Okay. All right. So we've got
what could be one man
who breaks in,
undetected, kills four,
steals massive amounts
of sensitive government data.
Probably espionage.
Should talk to DoD
and DOJ, ASAP.
Yeah. I'll have Sonja and
Gregorio contact them now.
In the meantime,
Christopher. Let's start--
excuse me--
Hmm? Yeah.
pulling surveillance footage
from other buildings
in the area.
You got it.
Oh, I'll go with Lasalle.
No, no, no. You're okay.
You stay here.
Work with Loretta. Lot
of evidence to process.
That's a good idea. Not just
physical evidence, either.
Whoever did this must've
left a digital trace.
Patton's out of town at
some I.T. conference,
but we should probably
contact him.
Good idea. Do it now.
We need to find whoever did this
before the stolen data
gets in the wrong hands.
(moaning over video)
That just looks uncomfortable.
Everything about it.
I know we keep
it casual at NCIS,
but it seems
like you're pushing it.
We're workin' here.
(taps key, moaning stops)
Thought you were contacting
DoD and DOJ.
Well, both agencies
reported an attempted hack
of the facilities
two weeks ago.
That's why Lieutenant Shaw was
sent here to update software,
strengthen cyber defense.
Any idea who the hacker was?
None. But it's our guess,
it's the same person
as the killer.
This is part
of what he was stole.
Surveillance from FBI
of a major prostitution ring.
I know him.
It's Councilman Long.
Well, how'd you find this?
We didn't.
It went viral
an hour ago.
GREGORIO:
A long with eight other videos
of prominent New Orleanians.
All a part of the stolen files.
And each of our subjects
are under some form
of investigation.
Internet's blowing up.
Videos are getting thousands
of hits.
It's straight up
public humiliation.
Doesn't sound
like espionage to me.
(computer beeps)
Ah, hey. It's the new guy.
I can say that,
'cause I've been here a week.
Welcome aboard, newbie.
You got something for us?
I'd say. Found epidermis cells
at the scene that didn't
match any of our victims.
But they did match
a very likely suspect.
Ethan Beck.
PRIDE:
Ethan Beck?
So. All right. So you've heard
of Anonymous, right?
Of course.
Okay. Well, Ethan Beck
and his people
are, like, ten times better.
And their mission
is to expose corruption
wherever it is.
So where do we find this guy?
Well, that's the thing.
You don't really find him.
He finds you. He's like a...
like a phantom.
I'm expecting a "but"
right about now.
But there was a failed hack
attempt on the facility
a couple weeks back...
And Patton was able
to find out
where that hack came from.
And I'm gonna send you
those details right now.
The abandoned restaurant
on Lake Pontchartrain.
Yeah. Actually, there's activity
on the I.P. address right now.
Somebody's still there.
Could be our killer.
Gregorio, you're with me.
NCIS!
Hands where we can see 'em.
Slow!
(short laugh)
Elvis!
Dwayne Pride.
Of all the gin joints
in all the towns, and look,
you brought your little buddy
with you, too.
Should've guessed,
if we had a major hack
job, we'd run into you.
I know what you're thinking.
This looks really bad for me.
but this time I swear
I did not do it.
Right.
GREGORIO: Hands where
I can see 'em.
I am having a raging bout
of déjà vu right now.
Dwayne, tell her
I'm not dangerous.
Last time we dealt with
you, you were armed
and almost shot a woman.
She's got a point, Elvis.
Out of context, unfair.
And that woman
sort of had it coming.
Can I cuff him, please?
Not yet, New York.
Elvis,
this restaurant
was the source of a hack attempt
on a Federal server farm.
A facility where four people
were killed this morning.
Right. So you think it's, uh,
suspicious that I'm here,
considering my past
miscommunications
with the law.
Um, by miscommunications,
do you mean
multiple felony convictions?
Then, yes.
I'm not the felon
you're looking for.
His name is Ethan Beck.
How do you know that?
'Cause I'm looking for him, too.
He runs a hacktivist group
called the Collective.
More like a terrorist
organization,
exposing people's dirty secrets.
No. The Collective was founded
to create transparency
and expose corruption.
Well, right now, it's exposing
prominent folks' personal lives.
Yeah, and that's
really pissing me off.
Why do you care?
Because my reputation's
at stake.
Because he created
the Collective.
Yeah. I created it with Ethan.
He was my protégé.
But he let his ego
get the best of him,
and it's not
about the cause anymore.
It's about Ethan proving
how powerful he is.
And that's why you guys have
to let me help you find him.
Talk about ego.
We can handle this, all right?
Dwayne, you don't have any idea
who you're dealing with.
Do you? He's hard to track.
Listen.
He's taken down
Fortune 500 companies.
He's brought government agencies
to their knees.
And he's never
been caught.
He's dangerous.
Elvis, Ethan Beck
murdered four people,
including a Navy Lieutenant.
We know he's dangerous.
Good point.
But you got to let me
help you find him.
(phone beeping)
I taught him every trick
he knows.
I am the one guy
who could track this dude down.
Please.
Gregorio?
Yeah?
Take Elvis back to NCIS.
Set up him up with
whatever he needs.
For real?
Don't look so upset.
(chuckles)
I don't bite.
(laughs)
Unless you ask real nice.
Where are you going?
Summoned by the mayor.
TV REPORTER:
Mayor Douglas Hamilton...
They got my e-mails, Dwayne.
Do you...?
They got my e-mails!
All right?
Posted them online.
Hundreds of private messages.
You're not the only one.
Come on, the reporters
asking que--
They're all over the place.
You've seen them, right?
...intimately involved
with your press secretary.
Uh, I have nothing to say...
I've got nobody, though,
to field questions for me,
because my press secretary's
husband made her resign.
I've got multiple
homicides to solve,
can we cut to the chase?
You're enjoying this,
ain't ya?
(laughing):
I can see.
You're enjoying this,
just a little bit.
Your point, Mr. Mayor?
Now, I know you think
that I'm a bad guy.
Right? That, uh...
I'm only interested in myself.
If history is any guide.
I'm screwed, Dwayne.
Oh, yeah. I'm done.
And there's nothing I
can do about that now,
but innocent people
are getting hurt.
Private lives
are getting exposed.
And this could be very bad
for a lot of good people.
We agree on that
much, don't we?
I can be useful to you.
I can pull strings.
I could give you access
to resources if you need them.
Whatever you need.
Just say the word.
Let's fix this together.
Might be something you can do.
Uh... you...
you're, uh...
(chuckles)
I mean...
Are you having a stroke, kid?
Seriously, do I have
to give you mouth to mouth?
I'm Elvis.
Oh, yeah, yeah,
I know exactly who you are.
You're-you're a personal hero.
I hope that
doesn't sound strange.
No, no, that's not
creepy at all.
It's just, your work
is pretty much the reason
I got into computers
in the first place.
Okay, now I feel old,
but also a bit flattered.
Thank you.
What are you doing here?
I'm trying to track
down Ethan Beck.
Sorry, I didn't know
this is your office,
but you got a
killer setup here.
Oh, yeah, it is killer,
but it's not mine.
I don't really have
an office, per se.
I-I'm kind of new.
Okay.
Actually, I'm very new.
Although,
I've also been around a lot,
so, it's all
very complicated.
Anyway, I'm-I'm supposed
to find Ethan Beck, too.
Okay, good.
Cop a squat.
Let's get at it.
All right.
Um, uh, over there's good.
That's probably good.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Now, Ethan is a hard guy
to track down, you know?
Not easy to trace, but, uh,
we got a work-around here.
We got all the Internet
traffic for the entire city.
Whoa, how did you--?
Not me,
your mayor.
He took a break from bedding
his employees to help us out.
Thanks to your boss.
So... so, if Ethan's sifting
through all these stolen files,
and he's posting them online,
then he's gonna need
a high concentration
of bandwidth, right?
Right, and Ethan
doesn't do the grunt work,
so one of his minions
does it for him.
So, if we trace
the low-hanging fruit...
We can trade up to the big dog.
That's right.
All right. Yeah!
This is fun.
Yeah, yeah,
eyes front. Yeah.
Okay.
I've got some heavy traffic
coming from a coffee shop
in The Quarter.
Good job, kid.
Call in the cavalry.
Actually, I am the cavalry.
Actually, I need you to help me
find the other Collectives.
Oh, okay, yeah.
Let's do it.
Yeah. Right.
By here, I mean of course...
Back over there. Sure.
I'm gonna call Lasalle.
Pretty much always over there.
Oh, this is great.
Like Batman and Robin,
except a cooler Robin.
Coffee shop's up here
on the corner.
It's official.
Mayor Hamilton's sex tape
just went wide.
They got him with
his press secretary.
No. Someone else.
A friend's wife.
I feel bad.
For Hamilton?
For him, the woman, anybody
who has their privacy invaded.
I mean, we all
have secrets, no?
Not everyone.
Agreed.
Okay, you got
a couple of saints here.
Well, you live a decent life,
you got nothing to hide.
SONJA:
Check out Mr. Robot.
LASALLE:
Yeah, Mohawk, piercings,
could be our guy.
Excuse me.
Federal agents.
Need to ask you
a few questions.
We got a rabbit.
Easy now.
Get off me.
(grunts)
Attica! Attica!
I'm gonna let you ladies
handle this one.
PRIDE:
Thank you, Roy.
You're in a lot of trouble,
Aviva.
Assaulting a Federal agent.
Your guy manhandled me.
You got bigger problems.
We know that you're connected
to a major security breach
at a Federal facility.
That you've released
sensitive data to the public.
You're a member
of the Collective,
and you work for Ethan Beck.
Prove it.
Everything we need to know
is right here in your computer.
Boot it up.
Try and access the hard drive.
See what happens.
Booby trapped, huh?
Wow.
Smart.
AVIVA:
At a level you can't even
begin to contemplate.
The Collective
isn't afraid of laws
or consequences or cops.
That's fair enough.
But... I'm not the one you
need to worry about right now.
Do you know who I am?
I'm Elvis Bertrand.
No way.
And your worst nightmare
is coming true in real time,
because I don't care
about laws or rules
or pathetic booby traps
on your hard drive.
You are gonna cooperate with us,
or I'm gonna expose
every move you've made
as a so-called hacktivist
to the whole world.
(scoffs)
(sighs)
What do you want?
Want you to contact Ethan Beck.
Just reach out to him,
and I will do the rest.
Okay.
I hope you know
what you're doing,
'cause he doesn't
like to be found.
ELVIS:
Now, I'm just running
a little, elegant,
backtrace program I devised,
and it will attack his computer
before he knows what hit him.
(chuckles)
Ooh.
That's not good.
Elvis.
Any idea what's going on?
I did not do it. I swear.
ELVIS:
You didn't do this.
Ethan did.
I heard you were looking for me.
Can you trace his location?
I'll try, but he's got
control of our whole network.
You've uncovered
the hornet's nest
and woken a sleeping giant.
Okay, I'm gonna ignore
your agregious overuse
of mixed metaphors, Ethan,
and ask you, "What the hell
is your problem, buddy?!"
Elvis, you're a traitor
to the cause.
I refuse to speak to you.
What cause justifies
the murder of four people?
I won't listen to your lies.
You have no idea
what you're talking about
or who you're messing with.
(shouts)
Sebastian!
How is he doing that?
I don't know,
but it's kind of cool.
(shouts)
Okay, Ethan, Ethan,
listen to me, buddy.
This isn't you.
I need you to come in here.
Stop looking for me.
Sorry, we can't
oblige you of that.
Then you'll all pay for it.
(shouts)
Okay, well...
that could've gone better.
This whole Wizard of Oz
act doesn't exactly mesh
with a suspect willing to kill
four people in cold blood.
Well, contradiction we can try
to explain after we find him.
Please, tell me you have another
way of tracing Ethan Beck?
Not off the top of my head.
He's gone deep underground,
probably unplugging
completely.
So we don't trace
him digitally.
Never gonna outsmart
him online, anyway.
Ooh, that hurts my feelings.
Focus on who he is
in the real world instead.
You're talking
about pattern of life?
Um, what is this
"pattern of life"?
Profiling technique.
We gather every detail
we know about a suspect.
What he eats,
what he wears,
kind of music he likes.
Especially irregularities.
Any unusual traits or habits.
Okay, where to start?
Well, you got a guy that sits
alone at home in front
of a computer screen.
Weirdness comes
with the territory.
We put it all
into an analytical program,
and then we got a good shot
at finding him.
And you actually think
that'll work?
We tracked your sorry ass
not too long ago.
You know, I think if you gave
me a shot, we could become pals.
Really?
Yeah.
We're about
to find out.
Elvis, sit with Gregorio.
(cell phone beeping)
Tell her everything she
needs to know about Ethan.
Okay. Got the power going.
The Internet's booting back up,
so all in all,
we're in business.
Good work, Sebastian.
Loretta's got something,
so, Sebastian,
you're with me.
Let's go.
Sorry, excuse me.
I'm gonna be honest.
I'm a little afraid of you.
Just a little?
You got to learn
to take a compliment.
Wait, what are all
these e-mails?
Some kind of glitch
or something?
Those aren't your e-mails.
That Ethan sure works fast.
Works fast at what?
At-at creating chaos.
Yo, the Internet's back up.
I know.
I just got a crazy
amount of e-mails.
Yeah, me, too,
and it's not good.
These are ATF files
from your undercover days.
Whoa. Are you kidding me?
How'd that happen?
Well, I'm assuming
it's Ethan Beck
making good on his threat.
Well, you need
to get rid of those.
Yeah, I'm all over it.
Hey, and you might
want to do the same
with whatever's
in your inbox.
Yeah.
(gasps)
Yeah, I probably should have.
Oh, boy.
What'd you get?
Just an e-mail from you to Pride
saying that you don't think
I should be added to the team.
Your undercover identity
was just exposed
and you're pissed
about an e-mail
taken completely out of context?
Oh, by all means,
give me the context.
Well, I didn't know you yet,
and couldn't tell
how you would mix
with the team dynamic.
I took a bullet for the team.
How's that for dynamic?
And you proved yourself
a hundred times since, to me.
And me to you, right?
We should probably
stop reading these
before someone else gets hurt.
Well, since Sebastian's busy
waging cyber-warfare,
I had another tech
analyze the bullets
from Lieutenant Shaw's murder.
Well, those slugs
were in fragments.
You were able to get
a ballistics match?
No, something
far more intriguing:
traces of ink.
Ink? What kind of ink?
Printer, pen? I mean, there's
literally hundreds
of classifications.
I don't know, Sebastian,
but the sample was so small,
I wouldn't want anyone
to touch it, except you.
That's a good call.
Capillary electrophoresis
is not for the faint of heart.
This Ethan Beck is proving to be
as elusive as he is dangerous.
He threw us all
for a loop.
And I've never seen Elvis
afraid of anyone.
Worried Beck will come back,
guns blazing.
PRIDE: It's not just guns
I'm afraid of here.
WADE:
A scandal then?
Like with
Mayor Hamilton?
PRIDE:
Well, not just him.
A lot of New Orleanians
are reeling today
because of Ethan Beck.
I'm gonna go, uh,
process this in my lab.
No need to wait, which
should come as a relief to you,
since you won't have to
worry about
my inability in the field
for a while.
Okay, what was that about?
Not a clue.
(phone beeps)
Rains, it pours.
TV REPORTER: Mayor Hamilton is
once again in hot water.
A sex tape featuring the mayor
and an unidentified woman has
been released online...
They got videos, Dwayne.
Of me
with different women.
More staffers?
(TV turns off)
Well, that's not the
point now, is it?
Why the hell
is there video?
Couldn't say.
Couldn't or won't?
My e-mails are on a Federal
law enforcement database.
Okay.
This day and age,
that happens.
We live with it.
But the video--
well, that means that I'm...
actively under
investigation, right?
I'm not investigating you,
if that's your question.
Not... currently, at least.
Well, you've thrown
a lot of accusations my way.
You know, the Javier Garcia
case, most recently.
Garcia was murdered.
You know that.
(smacks lips)
But,
if there's something specific
you want to confess,
I'm all ears.
(sighs)
Well, Dwayne,
if this day
has proven anything,
it's that everybody
has a secret, even you.
And if someone were motivated
to look hard enough,
who knows what they would find?
Here we go.
GREGORIO: Look,
you've seen what you've seen.
You can't take it back.
That's your response?
You told Isler we were a pair
of cartel imbeds.
I said it was possible!
And that we were
sleeping together? Ew!
Look, you got a vibe, that's
all I'm saying. Honestly?
It's kind of obvious.
Have you watched yourselves?
No, but you have.
Been surveilling us
for weeks, taking photos.
That's why the FBI
brought me here,
to investigate you.
You know that!
Yeah, but that's
our personal lives.
Do you know what
surveillance entails?
And I cleared you
both anyways, so...
Oh, I feel so much better.
Good! 'Cause now we can
talk about what I got.
What about what we...?
Enough!
You understand
this is exactly
what Ethan Beck wants.
Throw us off our game,
confuse us.
So he can get away.
You gonna let that happen?
It's called Shadenfreude.
I'll say.
It's an algorithm
I created years ago
to go after mouthy CEOs.
It culls e-mails,
looking for sensitive
information about coworkers.
And I created it to
expose corruption.
But Ethan has used it
on you guys.
Any progress locating him?
We aggregated every detail
we can find
on Ethan Beck's personal habits
and idisyncrasies.
There's a lot.
He's afraid of heights,
so he's not living
in a high-rise.
He's also a recovering
heroin addict,
a big believer
in the twelve steps.
Okay, so he needs
to be near meetings.
ELVIS: And then
you add to that,
the paranoia that goes
with the territory,
going after the
very powerful.
He likes mobility,
has to be able to escape
at a moment's notice.
Okay, well around here,
water's the fastest
way out, so, a boat.
Okay, how do we narrow it
further?
ELVIS:
Pizza.
Ethan is obsessed
with wood oven pizza.
And he has to have it delivered
at all hours.
PRIDE:
We got a hit.
Shell Beach Marina.
Gregorio, with me.
Let's move.
(seagulls cawing)
High-speed Internet satellite.
This is the place.
NCIS, hands where I can
see 'em, right now.
Syringe.
Pride, you need to see this!
Suicide note.
This guy's in the
middle of a crusade,
exposing people
left and right
and just offs himself?
Does that seem right to you?
Nothing about this seems right.
Ethan Beck had
a hundred milligrams
of nearly pure heroin
in his bloodstream.
No one would have been able
to inject that much.
He would have passed out
before completing the dose.
This man was murdered.
Yet someone wants us to think
he committed suicide.
You think he had an accomplice?
Beck may have released
confidential files
and videos on
the Internet,
thrown my team
into disarray
by hacking our e-mails,
but breaching a
federal facility?
And expertly killing
four people?
Yeah, Mr. Beck was not
in the pink of health.
He would have gotten winded
answering the front door,
let alone storming
the gates.
Well then, what?
Someone planted Ethan's DNA
at our crime scene?
Set him up to
take the fall?
Why go to all that trouble?
Elvis and the rest of the team
are searching through
Ethan's computer right now
for the answer,
provided they aren't at
each other's throats again.
Mm.
Still dissention in the ranks?
Honestly, I'm surprised
how little it took
to throw us off our game.
No one's off their game, Dwayne.
We're family, families bicker.
(scoffs)
(door opens)
Oh, Pride,
I didn't realize you were here.
I was about to call you
with some information.
PRIDE:
Well, here I am.
What do you got?
Well, I analyzed the ink
found on the bullet
from Lieutenant Shaw's body.
Turns out,
it's tattoo ink.
Special proprietary blend
called "Chimera."
Sold in limited supply
and only used
by one shop in the area.
Guessing you're gonna take one
of your more experienced agents
to go check it out.
And I'm guessing
your behavior right now
is about something
I said in an e-mail.
Out with it!
You told the director of NCIS
that I was inexperienced
and that you're unsure of
my ability in the field.
That's right.
Because you are inexperienced,
Sebastian. And you haven't been
out in the field that much,
but you know what else I said?
I'd be willing to bet
you'd make a fantastic agent
if given a chance.
SEBASTIAN: Oh.
Well, I-I guess they didn't
send the whole e-mail then.
Exactly.
So, now you know.
May we please go to
the tattoo parlor?
Yeah.
(tattoo gun buzzing)
Chimera ink? Yeah, I think I
bought some a few months ago.
Up sell it to the tourists
when they want to
bring a part of New
Orleans home with them.
Barely ever use it.
Can we see your supply?
(chuckling):
Why?
It's in connection
with an ongoing investigation.
It's somewhere in the back room,
you know, I don't really have...
Oh, don't worry,
I-I can go check it out.
Wait, hold on, man.
I got it organized in a very
particular way, all right?
I'll just show you.
Okay, all right,
look, I still have a few more
questions for you first.
Sebastian, go ahead.
You ever seen this man?
SEBASTIAN:
This is organized?
Oh, hey, man, I'm sorry.
I-I didn't realize
you were there.
Yeah, no worries, man.
Catching some Z's, huh?
Rough night?
You could say that.
Uh, any chance
that you could help me
find the Chimera?
The what now?
The ink.
Oh, right. Yeah, sure.
Chimera.
Yeah.
I'll help you look.
Okay.
I imagine, uh, most people
get tattoos at night, huh?
It's not often you wake up
first thing in the morning
and saying, "Hey, I want a
naked lady riding a dragon
across my chest."
Yeah, sounds
about right.
Looking for this, right?
Uh, yeah. That's
great, thank you.
I'm just gonna ask you
to move out of my way...
Yeah, I can't do that.
Okay.
It's not really a request.
See, I'm a Federal Agent.
(both grunting)
Sebastian!
You all right?
I think it was the killer.
He got a gun,
he went out the back.
GREGORIO:
Pulled DNA
from the tattoo parlor,
identified our suspect
as Damon Yang.
He's affiliated with
the Seven Eagles Triad.
They're based in Shanghai
and San Francisco,
where Damon is
from originally.
Looks like he's been in
New Orleans the past few months.
Holing up at a tattoo shop
and Triad front.
The manager of the shop's
not affiliated.
Knows nothing about
Seven Eagles business.
That's because there is no
The FBI busted
them last year.
Shut down their
entire leadership.
Including Damon's father,
Derek Yang.
PRIDE: What's the connection
between Damon and Ethan Beck?
There doesn't seem
to be one.
Except for the fact that he
specializes in cyber crimes,
identity theft,
credit card fraud.
He was prodigious.
And look at
his neck tat.
438.
Triads use numeric codes
to distinguish their ranks.
Mean something to you?
Well, I was looking through
the Collective message boards
for other suspects.
There was someone whose
handle was "438."
Thinking Damon was
a Collective member, too?
Maybe he joined up to get close
to Ethan Beck.
They worked together
on breaching
the Federal server farm.
Then he kills Beck after
the files were stolen?
What was he after?
Elvis is working on
Ethan's computer,
downloading all
the stolen files.
Should check with him.
Keep digging into Damon.
We find out what
he was after, we find him.
And, hey.
No matter what any e-mails say,
we're a team first.
We got each other's backs,
right?
Yeah.
Totally.
We're good, King.
Got to work on that enthusiasm.
How you doing here, Elvis?
I'm pissed.
I mean, Ethan was
a son of a bitch.
He was arrogant,
he was entitled,
he thought he could start
world anarchy all by himself.
But he did not deserve
to die this way.
I mean, it's humiliating.
Ethan made his own choices.
That's not on you.
No?
When I met him,
he was a professional
game tester, all right?
I'm the one that put all those
ideas into his head.
Okay.
Then let's find his killer.
What have you learned?
Not much.
I gave his computer
a full cavity search.
I found hundreds of
thousands of classified files.
But I wouldn't even
know where to start.
O-Okay. Sit down, Elvis.
Let's start
with, uh, Damon Yang.
Seven Eagles Triad member,
probably responsible
for all five murders.
I got nothing on Damon Yang.
But there is a Derek Yang.
Damon's father.
Former Triad leader.
He was arrested
and is awaiting trial.
Yes, he was arrested.
But there was
no trial, Dwayne.
These are different files
that I'm looking at.
Triple encrypted, super secure.
Of course Ethan broke the code.
That's probably why
Damon needed him.
What do the files say?
It says that, uh,
Derek had ties
to some pretty nasty
radical groups in Central Asia.
So the CIA decided that
he could be a valuable asset.
And they whisked him out of the
country before the indictment.
Extraordinary Rendition.
Does it say
where he was taken?
No, it's a black site.
But they do give the name
of the clandestine operative
that interrogated him.
PRIDE:
Jordan Harper.
Yeah, and he lives in a cabin
in the middle of
nowhere, Louisiana.
Damon's going after Harper
to find his father.
Right, and he's got a head start
on you, so you better hurry.
Harper's still not
answering his phone.
Any word from the state troopers
we sent to check up on him?
They aren't picking up,
either.
This isn't good.
Damon Yang could
be there already.
PRIDE:
But Damon needs Harper alive
to tell him where his father is.
So it gives us
a fighting chance.
Cabin's 50 minutes up this road.
We're running out of time.
Yeah, but if we take
the ATV through the woods,
we'll be there in less than 30.
Let's do it.
You're good to go.
(engine starts)
(engine revs)
Let's roll.
LASALLE:
Two dead, troopers.
I see Harper.
No sign of Damon.
Well, he's got to
be here somewhere.
Let's move.
(Lasalle grunts)
Damon Yang!
NCIS!
You got nowhere to run!
Then I guess we'll
all die here together!
Damon, listen,
we all want to end this
peacefully.
Look, no one has to get hurt.
Just put down your weapon,
and let us have Harper.
You want him?
Come and get him.
Where you guys at?
Ten minutes out. What's up?
We're pinned down
and we're taking fire.
Damon's got Harper
barricaded in the cabin.
We need a way in.
SEBASTIAN: That cabin is a
survivalist's dream house.
Walls are fortified, electricity
and security system run on
their own dedicated
network off the grid.
I mean, if he doesn't want you
in, you're not getting in.
Maybe, but maybe not.
Give me something, guys!
I'm say we do to that cabin
what Ethan Beck did to us.
You're gonna hack the system?
I'm setting up a virus to infect
the cabin's dedicated network.
That should give you guys
about 90 seconds
before the system reboots.
Whatever you do, do it fast.
Man, it's like watching
da Vinci.
Again, creepy.
Last chance to tell me
where they're keeping my father.
ELVIS:
Okay, guys.
Here goes nothing.
(gasps)
LASALLE:
You stay with Harper!
I'm getting Damon!
(panting)
Put the weapon down now!
LASALLE:
No where to go, Damon.
We got you covered!
HAMILTON:
Honestly, there are no excuses.
I made some bad choices.
And I'm not proud of them.
Look, Amy, I'm human.
Flawed like anyone.
But you know what else I am?
Grateful.
That I was able to provide
valuable assistance to NCIS
and put an end to this madness
before anyone else got hurt.
(TV turns off)
Oh, Hamilton the hero.
What a snake.
He's gonna walk away from
this whole thing unscathed.
You think so?
Ooh, I know that tone, Dwayne.
You've gone a few rounds
with the mayor,
haven't you?
(soft chuckle)
And I have a few more
rounds left to go.
Well, brother,
if the time ever comes,
I'd love to help you take that
creep down a notch or three.
Until then,
I'm out of here.
Leaving without
a good-bye drink?
Oh, I raided your cabinet
when I was planning my exit.
What? At least come down
(laughs)
to the bar, all right?
Celebrate with the team.
Come on.
Team? Team is
your thing, my friend.
My thing is different.
By the way, I'm sending your
people a little something
to remember me by.
Well, that sounds ominous.
Nah.
It's just my way
of saying thank you.
Stay frosty, my friend.
♪ ♪
♪ Yeah, on what
you're starting to doubt ♪
♪ So you could give me
all you got ♪
♪ You could throw it
all at me ♪
♪ Never, ever, ever gonna stop
till I'm free ♪
♪ I'm sticking to my guns ♪
♪ Till my work is done ♪
(whoops)
What's up, party people?
Who's ready to celebrate
my first case as an agent, huh?
♪ Till my work is done ♪
Yeah, it's gonna be a...
gonna be a crazy night.
(phones chime)
Not again.
Why are we still
getting e-mails?
This case is over.
Yeah, we've already
been through this.
We've apologized to
each other ad nauseam.
Look, the best solution
is for us all to agree
to erase them all
without looking at them.
SEBASTIAN: I think that's
a great idea.
Okay.
GREGORIO:
Oh, wait.
These are different.
Oh, yeah,
these are nice.
Gregorio,
that's so sweet.
You think you can learn
a lot from me?
Don't go getting mushy
on me, okay?
(Sonja chuckles)
I'm guessing you receieved
Elvis' good-bye present.
He must've reverse engineered
the schadenfreude algorithm
to only search out
the good things
we wrote about each other.
Which I am sure far
outnumbered the bad.
PRIDE:
All right.
Let's get down to business.
Here's to Sebastian
for getting through
your first case
with minimal injuries.
Well done, dear.
To Sebastian!
(laughter)
♪ Till my work is done. ♪
Captioning sponsored by
CBS
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org
Uh-oh.