Wondermutt, go get Bob.
Hey, guys! You all got
your grade cards, right?
OK.
What have we learned this year?
Teamwork, sportsmanship,
how your friends look naked.
You'll notice your
grade cards are blank.
Who better to evaluate a student's
progress than the student himself?
Good morning, young people.
Vice Principal Gills has
some words for you. Mr. Gills.
Thank you, Principal Kelban.
Well, well, I suppose you all remember
the English skills test last month.
- No.
- I had English?
- The dot-to-dot puzzle?
Yeah, that was it, yeah.
No, I don't remember.
I'm not surprised.
All of you failed.
However, in accordance with policies
on minimum academic proficiencies,
you'll have the opportunity
to retake the exam.
- Great.
- Oh, joy, I have a boner now.
- Hi. I'm all packed. Are you ready?
- One minute to go.
Your parents have been notified
you'll be retested after completing
the mandatory course in remedial
English. In summer school.
- What?
- We just finished a whole semester
and we gotta go
to summer school?
- You're crazy. I ain't going.
- My grandmother's gonna kill me.
Twenty, 19, 18, 17, 16, 15,
fourteen, 13, 12,
eleven, ten, nine, eight,
seven, six, five, four,
three, two, one!
I won! I won!
Gills, Kelban. I did it, I did it.
Look at this puppy.
50,000 big ones.
Know what this means?
No summer school.
Wait, you gave me your word.
That was the old word.
My new one is "money".
You would let 50 grand weaken
your commitment to education?
Lesser men win millions,
go right back to busing tables!
They're frigging morons!
Let me out of here!
Don't look at me.
You're in charge of summer school.
- May I speak with you a minute?
- Sure.
I need you to teach summer school.
Dearadorian just quit.
- Didn't he teach remedial English?
- Well, yes... Winnick!
Musway!
Stop! Stop!
Mary!
I have to talk to you.
Kim, get in the car.
It's OK. I'll meet you at the airport.
I'll get a cab. Take Wondermutt.
Shoop.
All right.
Mr. Shoop. Oh, Mr. Shoop.
Congratulations. You've been chosen
to teach summer school.
Shoot.
If only I'd known sooner.
- We're going to Hawaii.
- May I remind you, Mr. Shoop,
you're up for tenure.
You want a job next year?
Come on, Mr. Gills.
Look, we got leis on and everything.
You'll be teaching remedial English.
Remedial English?
Look, I ain't no English teacher.
See? Double negative.
No, I hand out basketballs, check for
jockstraps. I'm, like, very challenged.
- I'm not a real teacher.
- That's all right.
These aren't real students.
They're unmotivated, irresponsible.
- They'll relate to you.
- I appreciate that.
No, the reason I got into this whole
teaching gig was to get summers off.
No, I'm afraid my answer
has to be no.
No, thank you?
Bottom line, you need
my recommendation for tenure.
This is blackmail.
We call it school spirit.
Kim.
Have you ever seen
The Wizard of Oz?
- Oh, I love that movie.
- Yeah. Yeah, me too.
And my favorite part is when Dorothy,
she clicks her heels together
and she says,
"There's no place like home.
"There is no place like home."
Oh, Shoop, I understand.
You do? You're not disappointed?
No. I'll just go by myself.
- What, alone?
- I'll make friends.
Look, Kim, if you love me, even if you
just like me a lot, you won't do this.
If I didn't like you, I wouldn't ask you
to drive me to the airport, now would I?
Guess not.
You're in room 43.
Files on your students.
A word to the wise, Mr. Shoop:
Right off the bat,
you show them who's in charge.
Great.
Who is in charge?
Very cute.
Thanks. So are you.
Oh, you meant...
Jeez, I'm so embarrassed.
But you are cute.
I'm all right. I'm Robin Bishop.
I teach American history next door.
Hi, Freddy Shoop.
Remedial English, right here.
Everybody calls me Shoop.
OK, Shoop.
Why am I here? Oh, thumbtacks.
Could I borrow some?
Sure. I was just gonna get my
summer bulletin board going here.
Jackpot. Whole box.
Here you go, my treat.
- But what about your bulletin board?
- Oh, yeah. Give me one.
Remedial English, huh?
I got it easy, I have honor students.
They're here voluntarily.
- Believe it?
- No.
I've seen some of your students.
Very scary.
You must be a good teacher.
Shucks, Robin, I don't know.
Heck, inside every so-called
bad kid is a good kid
waiting for someone to reach down
through the sleaze and slime,
pick him up
and hose him off.
If we fail with even one child, we
might be losing the next Ted Koppel.
We're the unsung heroes
doing God's work.
You're not wearing
a wedding ring.
Yeah, my mother noticed that too.
So you're single. In love? Involved?
What's the story here?
The story is that I've been
seeing someone.
But we just started dating,
so you do what you think's right.
- OK.
- I better get going.
Well, here, I'll walk you.
So you're free to see
other people, then?
Are you asking me out?
- Well, if I was, would you say yes?
- I might.
Well, I might be asking you out.
- You like Chinese?
- I hate it.
Me too. I can't stand it.
Wanna go out and not eat Chinese?
I might.
Why don't we talk
about that after school.
I'm in love again.
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
The crowd goes mild.
- Hey, wow.
- Kevin?
- What happened to football, buddy?
- Yeah.
I was kicked off the team
for being stupid.
All right, it's about time.
Congratulations, bud.
Sorry I'm late.
Hey, Mr. Shoop, wow.
You in this class too?
- I'm teaching it.
- No way!
Party all the time
My girl likes to party all the time
All right, have a seat.
Let's see who the lucky winners are.
Larry Kazimias. Where's Larry?
He's nocturnal.
Oh, OK.
Try and keep it down.
Francis Gremp?
Don't ever call me that.
The name is Chainsaw.
- As in Black & Decker?
- As in Texas Massacre.
- Oh, yeah, that's in here.
- It's in there.
- They got files on us.
- Pam House.
Says here you lack concentration.
Pam?
Never mind.
Jerome Watkins.
Computer said
I failed that test.
The computer made an error.
I recommend this time, I pass.
You're gonna do well, Jerome.
I can feel it.
- Alan Eakian.
- Present, sir.
Four brothers, two sisters,
all straight-A students.
What are you doing here?
I assume there was some sort
of a baby mix-up at the hospital.
- Rhonda Altobello.
- Here.
You went from C's to F's.
What happened?
Any other questions?
No.
- Denise Green.
- What's that file say about me?
It's a lie. You wanna know about me,
ask me. What you want to know?
- Where are my car keys?
- How would I know?
What, does that thing say
I'm a thief too?
All right, where are my car keys?
- Chainsaw?
- Somewhere in this room.
Right now you're very cold.
- You're really cold.
- I want those keys.
Oh, God, you're freezing.
OK. OK, I'm a fun guy.
I'll play along.
- Getting warmer.
- You are getting hot, man.
- Oh, I see smoke.
- You are on fire!
Oh, you're walking on the sun!
Ouch! Oh, wait.
My mistake, I forgot where
I put them. You're ice-cold.
Enough of this shit.
Does that mean
we can swear in class?
- Shit, yes!
- Hey, watch your fucking language!
Watch your language, fart-face!
- Where are my keys?
- There's the dick-brain that knows.
If I knew anything,
would I be in this butt-hole class?
Suck my loggerhead.
Damn it!
- Jizzum-head!
- Jizzum-head. Yeah, good one.
One of my all-time faves.
Psychology.
You give a child the license
to swear, they lose all interest in it.
- I certainly did.
- You're full of bull.
It's OK, you can say "bullshit" in here.
I'm grateful.
I'm sure you're aware
that I'm teaching next door.
And this swearing
is getting a little loud.
You think you could concentrate on
some obscene gestures for a while?
Yes! Yes, that's the idea.
Thank you.
I don't think she likes you.
I want my car keys.
I'm using the lavatory.
- This is worse than a gas station.
- Yeah, I think I have to go too.
Wait a minute. Hey, wait a...
My keys.
Thattaboy, Mr. Shoop.
Hey. Hey!
OK, I'm calling roll
and then I'm gonna...
Where's my roll sheet?
It's somewhere in this room.
Hey. Sorry about the noise.
I'm really a gym teacher.
I don't belong in a classroom.
Apology accepted.
See you later.
Let's start all over.
Hi, I'm Freddy Shoop.
Look, you're a semi-charming guy
and a snappy dresser.
- You're not the kind of guy I date.
- Yeah? What kind are you dating?
- Oh, the kind who wears socks.
- I got a pair somewhere.
White ones. So about dinner,
you like Italian? Mexican?
Hey, maybe you'd rather cook.
I'm not having dinner with you.
- OK, lunch.
- Robin.
Excuse me just one second.
Robin, about tonight,
the concert starts at 8.
I thought we'd go to the beach
and have a picnic.
- Watch the sunset.
- Sounds wonderful.
Oh, bye-bye, Freddy.
I'll be darned.
You're a heterosexual.
And a damned good one.
- Good luck, honey.
- Thanks, Mom.
OK, start her up.
Make a right, please.
These photos suck.
Weddings, graduations.
- Hoffman came in.
- Yeah.
It's more of the redhead
with the tattoo.
This time he's got her making
breakfast stark raving naked.
Oh, Hoffman, you're so sick.
Check out this composition.
Round English muffin, square butter,
triangular bush. The man is an artist.
- Reprints.
Hi, I'd like to sign
up for Lamaze classes.
OK, how are Tuesday nights
for you and your coach?
- Perfect, but I don't have a coach.
- Well, what about the father?
Well, that's sort of confusing. It's either
David Lee Roth, who's on tour,
or Sean Penn. And I'd really hate
to upset Madonna.
Fill this out.
OK. How far did we get yesterday?
You took roll.
Right. That shouldn't
take as long today.
Pam.
- Mr. Shoop, I gotta book.
- What? You just got here.
Yeah.
- It's a female thing.
- Oh, yeah, I understand.
Oh, man, she's going surfing!
I'm sure.
Fuck. This menstruation deal,
it's such a scam.
Girls are so lucky.
What? Oh, we're so lucky?
You think being on your period
is some picnic? Are you crazy?
You get PMS, there's no room
in your purse for no hairbrush
because you got these mini pads.
You are so ignorant!
This whole class
is jammed with ignorance.
Yes, it is. Come in here, please.
Mr. Shoop, this is our new
foreign exchange student,
Anna-Maria Mazarelli.
Anna-Maria is from Milan, Italy.
She would like to brush up her English
skills before the fall semester begins.
Well, I'll let you return
to your rigorous pursuit
of academic excellence.
Please.
Anna-Maria, welcome to America.
You can sit wherever you want.
You looking for a seat?
Well, now, this desk
appears to be unoccupied.
Grazie.
OK, let's see what we got here.
"Rules of grammar."
"Writing paragraphs."
God, I hate this stuff.
"Book reports."
Wanna get out of here?
Go to the library?
- Yeah.
Let's go.
I am Chainsaw.
Hi, Chainsaw.
- Hi, I'm Dave.
- Ciao.
- Well, we love Italy.
- Yeah.
- The pizza.
- Mussolini.
- And Tony Bennett.
- The Mafia.
Yeah. Chef Boyardee.
- Pinocchio.
- Fellatio.
Oh, I don't like that.
- Well, have you ever tried it?
- Sure.
Chef Boyardee, spaghetti in a can.
It's so mushy.
Anna-Maria?
Have you seen the movie
Texas Chainsaw Massacre?
No. It is good?
Oh, I gotta tell you,
I love this film.
It had passion and a plucky spirit.
And the characters had integrity.
Like when Leatherface went
on a strict diet of human flesh.
- He had to cut out chicken and fish.
- I agree with you.
I'll go a step further. Leatherface
wore a mask made out of human skin,
he hung people on meat hooks,
but we've all got quirks.
I've got them. You got them.
That's what makes
this character so compelling.
- Thumbs up from me.
- Same here.
- To sum it up, I'm Chainsaw.
- I'm Dave.
We'll see you at the movies.
- OK.
- Let's go, people.
I found them at Winchell's.
Here, we all chipped in.
Hey, jelly. I'm touched.
This one was in the parking lot
with a surfboard.
This is so humiliating.
Pam.
You know, I grew up
surfing those same waves.
Today was phenom.
Three to four, breaking out of the
south, glassy, light offshore breeze.
Had to go for the ditch.
Thanks.
You're very spiritual.
But the rest of you clowns...
Hey, I gotta say something.
This whole thing is a joke.
There's a very valid reason
for summer vacation.
The human brain needs rest.
Yeah. I mean,
what are we doing here?
- Really. I don't wanna be here.
- Hey, look, this wasn't my idea.
You guys aren't fired up about English.
I wouldn't know what to do if you were.
But we're stuck here.
We're trapped like rats.
Anybody got any ideas?
Why don't we take some field trips?
- Can we do that?
- Sure, yeah.
I got permission slips right here.
OK, take these home,
have your mom or dad sign them,
I'll see what I can do.
- Done.
- Same here.
Good.
The Screwdriver
was a disappointment.
I was hoping for a headache
or pounding temples,
a blackout, but, you know,
I feel fine.
Actually, my headache is gone.
Thumbs down.
I'm surprised. I found
the Screwdriver simply delightful.
Fast corners.
That third loop was a surprise.
The line moved fast.
Is he OK?
No, it appears
that he's vomiting.
That's a sure sign
of a good ride. Thumbs up.
Eakian, what did you eat?
Don't be a pig. No.
Hey! Hey, you slime.
Stones' first farewell tour, '69.
Get out of here.
- Oh, wait.
- He ripped my T-shirt.
Oh, I can sew that.
It's not necessary.
Go away!
Nothing's necessary.
I want to.
Great, I'll let you.
Get them off! Get them off me!
The bunnies from hell!
Oh, God!
Get away from me!
Oh, dear!
- Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
- Thank you very much.
What is this? It's a lie.
- We did this for you.
- How did you like it?
It's disgusting!
I love it.
- What is that?
- Oh, it's foam latex.
Keep it.
You guys.
Next field trip,
it's gotta be at the beach.
We gotta see Anna-Maria
in a bikini. It's very important.
I understand.
Girl, this ain't the Riviera.
Thank you.
That was... That was...
That was cruel.
You OK?
Come in, come in, Mrs. Eakian.
Now, how can I help you?
Yesterday Alan came
home nauseous, sneezing,
wheezing and itching,
with goat hairs on his clothes.
He said he was at the museum,
- but I found this in his pocket.
- Grandma...
Is going on throw-up rides
and rubbing barnyard animals
your idea of quality education?
- Grandma...
- Certainly not.
We'll talk to Mr. Shoop
about this right now.
I may have used poor judgment.
You actually used judgment.
Do you realize if anything happened
to these kids, the lawsuits?
You could've bankrupt
the entire district!
And mess up your chance
at election to state assembly?
- Yes.
- Don't wet your pants. Watch this.
All you had to do was
babysit some social deviants.
Those deviants are great kids.
I'm sure they'll grow up
to be wonderful criminals.
- They're as smart as you and me.
- You and I.
All of us.
You're suspended until Kelban
returns and fires you.
What?
Hey, this is your fault.
You knew I couldn't teach.
Goodbye, Mr. Shoop.
Gills, what if I become
a model teacher?
This is gonna be fun. OK.
You get every kid left in your class
to pass that skills test
and I'll forget
about your field trips.
Done.
- They all have to pass?
- It's called teaching.
If you don't know how to do that,
then I guess you don't
deserve tenure. Do you?
I'll teach.
Morning, class.
Nice tie!
Oh, baby.
Mr. Shoop, what's with the
threads, man? You getting married?
No, must be laundry day.
Nothing else was clean.
- Funeral?
- Could we come?
Please take your seats.
- Where should we take them?
- Sit down, Francis.
From this moment forth, you people
eat English, sleep English.
You are English.
Oh, then pass the crumpets, old boy.
I'm not kidding around.
Anyone not interested in passing
that exam can leave right now.
The guy's been pretty cool.
He called me Francis.
Hasta luego, Placido Domingo.
Chainsaw, Dave, wait a minute.
Look, Gills is having a cow
about our field trips.
Unless you guys all pass
that test, my job? Memorex.
Anybody got any ideas here?
Get yourself some want ads.
I don't care what your files say.
You are not that dumb.
Actually, Mr. Shoop, those files
are usually right on the money.
- You all feel that way?
- I do.
- I may as well go home.
- Mr. Shoop?
Look, we don't want
you to lose your job.
Think about what you're asking.
- You want us to study?
- The thought did cross my mind.
- Well, what's in it for us?
- Literacy.
Oh, sorry, that's...
- I'd like to help. What can I do?
- Give me your car.
- Your house.
- And your dog.
- See you.
- Wait, wait! Mr. Shoop, wait!
There's room to negotiate.
What if you granted
each one of us one wish?
What do you mean, "wish"?
You know, like a favor.
Does anybody need anything?
I need somebody to work out with,
in case I get back on the team.
- I could use a Lamaze coach.
- I need some driving lessons. Bad.
OK, there's two of us.
Therefore, we get two.
All right. One, a party, your house,
Fourth of July weekend.
In Anna-Maria's honor.
Number two, you arrange
a screening, in class,
of the greatest movie ever made.
The 1973 Tobe Hooper classic
The Texas Chainsaw Massacre.
- That is also in Anna-Maria's honor.
- Thank you.
Now, then, is there
anything that you desire?
Oh, I don't deserve a wish.
I don't take the test anyway.
God, she is so honest.
We'll take hers.
Chauffeur service for Dave and I,
every day, to and from work.
Pam, what's your wish?
I'll tell Mr. Shoop
when the time is right.
Larry?
- Larry, what do you want?
- Bed.
He wants a bed.
As for myself, I just wanna be
invited to the party.
- We'll see.
- Good enough.
I think these are fair
and reasonable requests.
In return, we'll show up,
we'll pay attention
and we'll even do a little homework.
- Is this contract acceptable to labor?
- No doubt.
- Yeah.
- Does management agree?
- You sure I'm management?
- For our purposes here, yes.
Do we have a binding agreement?
We got something.
All right. Well, we put
that baby to bed.
Let's do lunch.
I always wanted to say that.
- Well, go ahead. Teach.
- Right.
Teach.
Don't anybody move.
- The Non-Proliferation Treaty.
- Beagman?
- Excuse me, Miss Bishop.
- Mr. Shoop.
Shouldn't you be planning
a field trip to 7-Eleven?
I need your help.
I know how you feel about me,
but something really bizarre
has happened to my kids.
- Please.
- All right.
If I get next door and there's a
candlelight dinner, I'm calling security.
- Continue.
- The 1970 Seabed Treaty.
Do you own that suit?
- What did you do, pass out Valiums?
- This is a natural lull.
Interesting phenomenon.
What do you want from me?
How do you teach?
- If you're serious, I'll help you.
- Great.
Meet me after school.
We'll make plans for the weekend.
For the weekend?
Big guy. OK.
The easiest thing to do
is base your lesson plans
on the students' own experiences.
- I can do that.
- Your life is probably very similar.
Hardly. I'm telling you,
you gotta try these Pop-Tarts.
No, thanks.
I'm sticking with the Chocodiles.
The best teachers are the teachers
who entertain while they teach.
- So you should do just fine.
- You think I'm entertaining?
To children.
- I gotta go. Time's up.
- I know why you're helping me.
- Professional courtesy.
- No. You like me.
- No, I don't.
- Yes, you do.
- Yeah, you do.
- Do not.
- Do too.
- Don't either.
- Come on.
- Don't you like me just a little bit?
- No.
Not even that much?
I like you that much.
It's a start.
Now, someone tell me why
learning how to write is so critical.
- It's a form of communication.
- Amen. And it can get you free stuff.
- Free?
- Free. I'm writing the word...
...free. Here's how it works.
All of us have been ripped off, right?
Pay phone steals money,
not enough cheese on your pizza.
- My shades keep falling apart.
- Perfect.
You're gonna write that company.
You'll see action,
if your letter is clearly written
and threatens to hurt their business.
And is signed, forgive me, Chainsaw,
"Mr. Francis Gremp, president,
Consumer Against Faulty Eyewear."
You want me to lie? OK.
Anyone interested
in learning the correct form,
please turn to page 46
in your textbook.
The shit works.
Damn!
Stupid son of a...
- I'm not cut out to be a linebacker.
- No, you're looking at my shoulders.
Don't. Focus on my waist.
OK? My waist.
All right, try it again. Go on.
That's good.
Remember, I'm your teacher.
You wanna learn how to surf?
- You sure you wanna do this?
- Absolutely.
Lamaze class,
great place to meet girls.
OK, Denise, slide over.
Oh, no, no, no.
Is this some kind of sick, twisted joke?
No, I'm combining Denise's driving
lesson with your ride to the beach.
We took driver training
with Denise. Call us a cab.
Get your grisly butts in the car.
Man, let me drive.
I'm going for my license next week.
- Chainsaw, you've been drinking.
- No, it's cough medicine.
Check out this phlegm.
Save the phlegm.
You're not driving anywhere.
I'll tell you something. You know why
so many drunk drivers get in wrecks?
- They don't learn to drive drunk.
- Fact: Alcohol kills brain cells.
You lose one more, you're
a talking monkey. Come on, get in.
Come on.
OK, Denise, start her up.
Signal left. Pull on out.
Can I call my folks
and say I won't be home... ever?
I'm not used to this car.
I think it's safe.
Move it out.
Nice and smooth. Oh, yeah, that's...
Fine. Good.
- Why did you do that?
- A car was coming.
Well, it'll happen from time to time.
Come on, Denise,
he won't bother us.
We just got lapped
by an old lady with a walker.
- See that space between those cars?
- Yeah.
- Pull in.
- Parallel park? That's my weak spot.
Listen to her.
OK.
- I'm sober now.
- That's good for today.
- We live!
It's beautiful.
Enough safe and sane.
It's time for dumb and dangerous.
These are Mexican. You do not
know what's in these babies.
Hey, get me a brew.
Coming through.
Anna-Maria, as far as we know,
this has never, ever been attempted.
Anna-Maria, we dedicate
these cantaloupe to you.
You make fruit bombs for me?
Oh, how sweet.
- Melon balls, coming up!
- We're gonna make these babies fly!
Excuse me. Excuse me. Excuse me.
You're awake. I wanna talk.
- Not now, babe, I'm late.
- Late for what?
What's it like being pregnant?
- Bizarre.
- Yeah, that's what I thought.
My body is out of control
and it's big and ugly.
- I think you look great.
- Sure, in the dark.
How much longer?
About five weeks.
- It's gonna be amazing.
- Yeah, I know.
You'll be a mother.
Yeah.
Eakian, this party's getting weak.
Do something wild.
Take all your clothes off.
Why? You want everyone
to go home?
You're almost fun tonight.
Almost.
- You all right?
- Yeah. Come on in.
I'm just resting up. Too much fun.
It's all sewn.
Hey, thanks. That's great.
- I feel so at home here.
- Yeah, me too.
Yeah.
The grunion are running tonight.
In the dead of night,
under a full moon,
thousands of horny little fish
swim hundreds of miles
to ball their brains out in the sand.
It's so romantic.
You ever do that
with one of your students?
No. I swim hundreds of miles,
I'm ready for a nap.
Who's that?
Oh, it's Kim.
She's sort of my girlfriend.
- "Sort of"?
- Well, she's in Hawaii.
So you're all alone
and you like young girls.
Kim's not that young. She's 21.
I'm 16. And you should
consider that.
Because there's, like, no difference
between 21 and 16 now,
but when she's 66,
I'll only be 61.
And I'll be 75
and it won't matter anyway.
Yeah.
Come on, Pam. Time for more fun.
Wondermutt!
Out of my way!
Watch your ass, folks! Banzai!
- Oh, shit.
- Fire!
Do something!
- Jesus Christ, my couch is on fire!
- Come on, Dave.
What? What? What?
- All right, we took care of it.
- My fish!
- How many were there?
- One.
Poor fishy.
Get rid of that couch.
That is a definite fire hazard.
- Definitely.
- Party's over.
It was just getting good.
We got a fire...
Good night!
One little fire.
Big deal.
- Minors drinking on the beach.
- Seriously, we never do this.
Boy, never, ever. There's our
English teacher, let's ask him.
Mr. Shoop, sir, could you come here
just a moment, please?
- Hey, guys.
- Hi.
- What's up?
- Found these boys with alcohol.
That alcohol, officer?
Oh, that's not theirs.
Whose is it?
It's mine. See, I live
in that house right there
and they were just
watching my stuff.
That's right. It's his.
We should never have taken those
little baby sips. That was wrong.
God, so very, very wrong.
I think they learned
one hell of a lesson, officer.
Next time you boys encounter alcohol,
remember you're underage.
- Yes, sir, we will.
- Yeah, of course, thank...
Thank you.
- Well, we're off to do our homework.
- Yeah. Thank you. Bye.
- We shouldn't have tried this.
- It was a mistake.
That was bad.
We should've just said no.
- You guys are good men.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
You're under arrest for contributing
to the delinquency of a minor.
- Officer, that's not really my vodka.
- Is that your dog?
- Yeah.
- No dogs on the beach, $50 fine.
He's not really my dog.
He just thinks he's my dog.
No, he's a neighborhood dog.
He hangs out at my place
because there's garbage there.
He's a scavenger. He'll eat anything.
He's a beach dog, really.
Go away, beach dog.
Do you have a cell for beginners?
- Boogie boy.
- Bunk in here.
- Moondoggie.
- Yeah.
Who wants gum?
Leave your message
after the beep.
Robin, it's your pal, Shoop.
I can't leave my number
because I'm downtown in jail.
- Jail?
- What, you're surprised?
I got arrested in my swim trunks, so
I need 50 bucks and a pair of shoes.
Listen, please don't mention
this to that bite in the ass Gills.
You're an angel.
Dinner, dancing, Paris...
Hello, Mr. Shoop.
- Who is this?
- The bite in the ass.
When I say "bite in the ass", I mean
that in the nicest possible way.
Can I talk to Robin?
I'm afraid Robin and I
are on our way out of town.
But don't worry, we'll be right over.
He's still a human being, Phillip.
We have a very long drive.
If we go downtown now,
we'll be stuck in traffic.
And that's OK with me,
because we'll be helping Shoop
and you won't think I'm a shit. Right?
Am I in really big trouble?
Arrested for contributing
to the delinquency of minors?
You're not a hero.
What is this?
I made a new friend.
Mr. Shoop, I do hope we can get you
out of this ugly mess. And it is ugly.
Mr. Shoop's been making
a lot of progress in his class, Phillip.
It's true. I've been handing out
assignments and the kids turn them in.
- It's almost like school in there.
- I've heard. And I'm proud.
Confirms all my instincts
about him. He's my boy.
Robin, let's get out of here.
We're on our way to wine country.
You kids have fun.
See those waves, Wondermutt?
They're from Hawaii.
Kim's in Hawaii.
Robin's in the wine country.
You know what we need?
I mean, besides bread.
We need a woman
who will appreciate
what we have to offer.
A woman of culture...
...intellect.
Shake those buns, baby!
Bring those buns over here. Mama's
got some software for you, baby.
Excuse me.
I'm with Playgirl magazine.
Survey me later, I'm trying
to concentrate. Come on, baby.
Thanks for your time.
Shoot them buns over here.
Hey!
Hey, cowboy! Don't I know you?
Hey, back off, hair-bag,
this is ladies' night.
I love him, I love him, I love him.
Larry!
Mr. Shoop. What are you doing here?
What am I doing here?
You do this every night?
Well, we have Mondays off.
Listen, man, you can't tell
anybody, OK? They think I'm 21.
You were fabulous.
This is from both of us.
I'm in the wrong business.
But about school,
if you could sneak in a couple
hours' sleep, you'd catch up.
Mr. Shoop, man,
think about what you're saying.
I mean, if you could be 17 again,
only you knew then
what you know now.
- Yeah.
- Well, I know.
I hate that kid.
"Who we admire most
in the world and why.
"The person we admire most
in the world is makeup artist
"and creature creator Rick Baker."
"His wonderfully gruesome slime
bladders and slobber tubes
"in American Werewolf in London
won him a richly deserved Oscar.
"That is why we admire makeup artist
and creature creator Rick Baker
"very, very, very,
very, very, very..."
"Very, very, very, very, very..."
"Very, very, very, very, very,
very, very, very, very, very..."
"Very, very, very, very, very much."
- It's 100 words on the nose.
- You can count if you want.
"It is not easy to pick
the person I admire most.
"I admire people
for different reasons.
"The way they surf or teach English
from the heart or help the homeless.
"To pick one person
is so unfair to everyone else.
"Isn't there enough pain
in the world?"
Since there's no one I admire most,
this is about a person I admire least,
my ex-boyfriend, Andre.
If he tells you he broke up
with me, he's lying,
because I told him
to get out of my face first.
You know how I could tell
when he's lying? His lips move.
I'm serious. He's so in love with
himself, he ought to be dating a mirror.
He's in skin-tight leather pants,
thinking he's Rick James' little brother.
Give the world a break.
- Denise, can I have your paper?
- No.
- No?
- Well, I had to memorize my essay
due to the fact
I was mugged by a gang
looking for money and homework.
That happens.
OK, gang, mark your calendars.
Field trip next Monday.
Where are we going, cockfights?
Courthouse.
Your teacher was arrested
for giving vodka to some kids.
You and Dave won't want to miss it.
- You went to jail for us?
- On roller skates.
Thanks, man.
Pam?
Hi.
What are you doing here?
Remember I said I'd tell you my wish
when the time was right? It's right.
- Your wish is to move in with me?
- I'm a great cook.
I won't get in your way.
You know we connect.
- Pam, look, my place is very small.
- It's perfect.
Look, Tommy, that's my brother,
he had another kid
and Angela, she's his wife, wants to
move the twins back into Gail's room
and put Sally in the den,
so I lose the couch.
- Yeah, well, my couch is barbecued.
- The floor is fine.
Mr. Shoop, everybody else
got their wish.
OK, Pam.
If I let you stay here,
it's only temporary
until you find another place, OK?
I can stay.
Who are you talking to?
This is Tommy and Angela
and Gail and Sally and Sly
and the twins, Chuck and Bob,
and Tommy, Jr.
This is Mr. Shoop.
- How are you?
- Pleased to meet you.
She screams so well.
Oh, don't be a wuss.
Shut up!
Run, run.
Larry! Larry, wake up,
you're missing this.
Larry's not missing a thing.
Let him sleep.
- There he is.
- Leatherface, Leatherface.
Oh, no.
That's not a real person.
It's a stuntman.
OK, now, this... This right here
isn't gonna bother him,
because he's insane, OK?
Good Lord.
- What are you watching?
- Do the dance.
A new film from the district,
Safe Use of Power Tools.
Delivery. I don't want
to know what this is, do I?
No, probably not.
Come on.
- What a finish, ladies and gentlemen.
- It was great.
What did you think of that?
- God, it was really American.
- American, yes.
It's an American masterpiece.
Talk about gutsy endings.
The girl gets away
and our hero, Leatherface,
chainsaws his legs.
- Two thumbs up.
- Make that four for gore.
Listen up, I wanna
read you something:
"Dear Mr. Francis Gremp,
thank you for informing us
"of your problem with our
Cool Dude sunglasses."
It worked.
"Please accept these
Cool Dudes with our compliments."
All right, it's Christmastime.
Free glasses.
- Are these free?
- Yes.
"We know you'll find them
well-constructed
"and we hope your organization
will see no need to boycott.
"Sincerely, Wayne Appleton,
president, Cool Dude, Inc."
- All right, the power of the pen.
- Hey, thanks, Chainsaw.
Hey, Eakian. Eakian. Man, you think
you can help me with my letter,
make it sound official?
Sure, Denise.
You wanna give it to me?
OK, tonight, for homework,
write a review of
Texas Chainsaw Massacre.
Rhonda?
If you're not doing anything tomorrow,
I thought we could do something.
Oh, I have Lamaze class
tomorrow night.
- Do you wanna go with me?
- What about Mr. Shoop?
Oh, he won't care. I mean,
if you don't mind being my coach.
- I wouldn't mind at all.
- Great.
Great.
See you, Eak.
Mr. Shoop...
...you should see this, but you can't
let Denise know I showed you. OK?
OK.
Shoop, this girl's dyslexic.
What? That's not in her file.
This is serious.
You gotta get her some help.
How could she get this far
with no one finding out?
She slipped through the system.
What happens when
she gets out in the real world?
Wait! Is this the same guy that took
his English class to the petting zoo?
- How'd you get those kids to work?
- Bribed them.
What would it take to have dinner
with you?
That would be very expensive.
- I'm having dinner with Gills.
- Big Phil again, huh?
Robin, be honest,
isn't he a bite in the ass?
No, he's not a bite in the ass.
He happens to be very...
...articulate... cultured...
...extraordinarily tidy.
Tall, dark and tidy.
That's a magic combination.
- You're not in love.
- None of your business.
- Sure, it is.
- No.
Tell me you love him,
I'll stop asking you out.
How am I gonna tell you
I love him when it's so new?
I knew it. See, Robin,
he is not the guy for you.
You need an intelligent,
sensitive man who can skate.
- Do you know such a guy?
- Oh, they're hard to find.
But now that I know,
I'll keep my eye out.
Would you?
Looking good, Denise. Good luck.
Sir, you are really gonna
earn your money today.
- Francis Gremp?
- Call me Chainsaw.
- You're up next.
- Can you hold on a sec?
Dad's late. He's so irresponsible.
I said, "Dad, 3:00 sharp." But no,
it's just in one ear, out the other.
I need your car.
- You wanna use my car?
- I'm under adult supervision.
Chainsaw, you take your test
and you bring my car
right back here to me.
You make me proud to be
an American. Dave, kiss this man.
You, come with me. No, no, you
stay there. I'll bring the car to you.
Can you back this up? I'm taking
a test. Just move all the way back.
- What? What'd I do?
- Don't worry about me.
See those cars on the right?
Go ahead and park in between.
What do you mean?
You mean parallel park?
- Something wrong?
- No, nothing.
Yeah.
We going on the freeway?
I think we'll just stay
in the neighborhood.
Why are you driving
with only one hand?
Oh, this hand's gotta be free
to put around the babes.
- Are you marking me off for that?
- Watch the dip!
That dip?
Hey, you crazy?
Don't you ever, ever yell at the driver!
Do you hear me?
- Where are you going?
- Back. The test is over.
No way!
That was your fault.
This is bullshit. Come on.
I stayed sober for this.
You can't do this.
Come back, you dumb dildo.
Wait, no, you're not a dildo.
I was joking. That was a joke.
Come on, be cool. One more chance?
Wait.
You lost points for driving too slow
and not accepting the right of way.
- Failed again.
- 70 is passing.
Seventy-two.
- I passed?
- You passed.
I passed! Oh, I passed! I passed!
Shoop, I passed!
I passed!
- I passed! God, I passed! Thanks!
- I'm proud of you. Congratulations.
- I couldn't have done it without you.
- Now, you drove the car.
- Look, I owe you one, all right?
- Yeah?
Yeah.
OK. Tell you something
you can do for me.
- What?
- Get help with reading.
- Man.
- Listen, Denise.
What you have is a learning disorder
called dyslexia.
You need to retrain your brain
to deal with information.
- There's a specialist.
- I'm doing fine.
Yeah, you are.
But you could be doing so much better.
But that's up to you.
Hey.
- Think about it, OK?
- OK, free film.
Free developing.
Come on, what more could you want?
Here.
Look, my dad's a butcher. You like
veal cutlets from Minnesota? Milk-fed.
Hi, honey, how was your day?
Hectic.
- Boy, something smells good.
- The manicotti.
Perfect timing. Why don't you
start on the cheese and crackers.
Yeah. It's open.
- Hi.
- Hey.
I just brought this Ray Bradbury book.
- Maybe I should come back later.
- Why?
- Hi, Miss Bishop.
- Hi.
Oh, Robin, Pam House,
one of my students.
Pam, Robin Bishop.
- Hi.
- Hi, Pam.
Freddy, I didn't make enough for three.
If you plan on inviting company,
- I wish you'd let me know.
- No, he wasn't.
I stopped by to help him with a lesson.
- But we can do that in the morning.
- Morning's much better.
I'll make French toast for us.
Do you like French toast?
I bet she makes great French toast.
- I actually meant morning at school.
- Oh, fine.
- It was nice to meet you, Pam.
- You too.
Robin?
I know this is none of my business,
but what the hell is going on in there?
There's nothing going on in there.
Remember those bribes?
- Well, Pam needed a place to stay.
- How long has she been here?
A couple of days.
My laundry's never smelled so good.
Here, take a whiff.
Oh, I'm sure it's April fresh.
I just hope having a maid
is worth the damage
you could do to that young girl.
See you tomorrow.
- All ready.
- Great.
- French or Italian?
- French.
I knew it.
- Pam, we gotta talk.
- Sure. What's up?
- I think you are a great girl.
- And I think you're a great guy.
God, this is hard.
Freddy, go ahead.
You can tell me anything.
OK. You know how,
when you're on your board,
and you see the perfect wave rolling in
and you think you got it?
Only, something happens
and you don't get it.
I mean, the key
to the whole thing is timing.
If you're even a little out of sync,
you're grim,
you're blowing the barrel,
you're seaweed.
But then you look outside
and you see an even more perfect
wave than the first perfect wave
and that's the one you catch.
- Do you know what I mean?
- Yeah. Yeah, I get it.
Surfing metaphors. You're
the perfect wave and I'm seaweed
- and if you want me out, just say it.
- No, no, I'm not the perfect wave.
And it's not just that I want you
out of my house.
No, you want me out of your life.
- Pam, look, I'm your teacher.
- No.
Any time one person lets themself
care deeply about another person,
that person runs the risk
of being rejected and destroyed.
- I'll go get my things.
- No, wait. You cooked dinner.
It looks beautiful.
Let's sit down, eat.
It's just food.
OK. I'm gonna collect
your book reports.
Then we are on our way to court.
Homework, Pam?
You expect me to relate
to the written word
after the hell you put me through?
Talk about shallow.
I've stepped in deeper puddles.
You're excused.
Mr. Shoop, don't you want mine?
Larry, you're awake, with homework.
What's wrong with you?
I got fired.
They found out my real age.
- Hey, I didn't say a word.
- No, my mom came to a show.
- Your mother?
- It was a nightmare.
I mean, before she knew who I was,
she put 5 bucks in my G-string.
And then my Aunt Edna,
she kisses me.
With tongue.
And rips off my mask.
Mom freaked out.
She made me put on her coat.
- I'm sorry.
- You're sorry?
I'm at my sexual peak.
Once a guy hits 18,
it's all downhill.
But it's a lovely ride.
Mr. Shoop, why did you tell
the arresting officers
that the vodka found
in the possession
of Mr. Gremp and Mr. Frazier
belonged to you?
Your Honor, to keep
a couple of students out of trouble.
David and Francis
have enough problems as it is.
- It's true, Your Honor.
- Our lives are a mess.
Guys, don't help.
Where did you young men
obtain the vodka in question?
- From Murray.
- Who's Murray?
You know Murray.
Everybody knows Murray.
From Murray's Liquor.
Didn't this Murray ask
to see proof of age?
Well, I come off pretty mature.
- Did you show him proof of age?
- Yeah, I guess I did.
May I see it, please?
- I'd rather you didn't.
- I'd rather I did.
You were a black Marine in 1968?
Vietnam.
A war puts a man through
many, many changes.
Young man, the possession of false
identification and of alcohol by a minor
are serious crimes.
You've just confessed to both of them.
- I didn't mean to.
- However, since the arresting officers
let you off with a warning,
I'll probably do the same.
- Is this guy bitchen or what?
- Now, Mr. Shoop...
Your Honor?
My name is Robin Elizabeth Bishop
and I'm also on the faculty
with the defendant.
I submit that this man
went to jail for his students.
Very few teachers ever exhibit
that degree of dedication.
Therefore, Your Honor,
I move that...
Don't move, Miss Bishop.
You're out of order.
And you're also correct. Mr. Shoop,
these charges will be dropped.
- Case dismissed.
- All right!
All right! That's so...
Shoop! Let me tell you something.
The judge bought
that dedicated teacher crap,
but you covered up,
thus condoning student drinking.
I am filing a report for Kelban
with the entire story. Face it.
The test scores won't save you,
because they're losers, just like you!
Hi.
I was just congratulating
our good friend Mr. Shoop.
- Now, about lunch, sweetheart.
- Tell you what, sweetheart,
why don't you go ahead, order
two lunches and eat them yourself.
One for each face.
OK. Today we take a practice test.
Pinpoint each of your weak spots.
Then we work
a couple hours after school.
Wait, wait.
Practice tests, extra class time?
Not in the contract.
Eakian, get him.
The test is in two weeks.
You need the extra work.
Then I'm afraid we're gonna need
some extra incentive.
- Yeah. Like a party with a band.
- I could use some wheels bad.
And get me a job, man,
doing strip-o-grams.
- I don't believe this greed.
- Believe it, man. I need a houseboy.
It's a simple matter
of renegotiating our contracts.
Renegotiate? Who do you
think you are, Teamsters?
Yeah, Teamsters!
Strike! Strike! Strike! Strike!
Look! For the past four weeks,
I have given up all of my free time.
Had my body used for a tackling
dummy, my house trashed,
my couch set on fire,
my goldfish murdered,
my butt thrown in jail
and my car wrecked.
All I'm asking for is a little extra effort.
You know, what's sad is
you guys could all pass that test.
But you're just so happy being failures
that you just don't know...
Why am I doing this?
Tell you what.
You guys drop out and be illiterate.
I'm going to Hawaii and be tan.
Have a cow.
Damn.
Hey. Thanks for the help.
Good luck.
- Where are you going?
- To quit.
- You can't quit.
- Sure, I can.
- I never got through to anybody.
- Not true. They were learning.
- You're not a quitter.
- I am.
I turned you down for dinner
at least a dozen times
- and you haven't quit bugging me.
- Wanna go out to dinner tonight?
- Can't.
- See?
Everybody take a seat.
You, in the cot, out of bed.
- Where's Mr. Shoop?
- He has tendered his resignation.
Now, sit down.
Would someone tell me what
Mr. Shoop had planned for today?
- Yes?
- Group sex. No, that's tomorrow.
Today's independent study,
right after our midmorning nap.
Don't think you can pull
this BS with me.
Everybody take their textbooks out
and turn to chapter seven.
Read it again.
Who's making that noise?
What noise? I don't hear any noise.
What, you got dog ears?
- Chainsaw, stop doing that.
- Stop doing what?
You know, I hear it too
and it's annoying.
Find the hooligan that's responsible,
because I am trying to read
chapter seven. Again.
Mr. Gills, I cannot study.
I'm going to the library.
Chainsaw, sit down.
You can hum till your lips fall off,
I could care less.
Wait a minute.
You're not dismissed.
Now, I promise you, you people
act like psychopaths tomorrow
- and you will be sorry.
- We will be sorry?
Mr. Gills sure does know
his child psychology.
Miss Cura, I want to let you know that
the children are a little hyperactive,
but I'm sure that you'll
enjoy their joie de vivre.
So far, I've only subbed
at grammar schools,
so this should be a nice change.
Help, Mr. Gills!
Denise! Denise! Take it easy!
What happened?
Don't go in there without a gun.
It's terrible.
- Is this my classroom?
- Yes, it is.
Whose blood is that?
Is that your blood?
No.
My God.
We're back!
What is wrong with you people?
It's like you said, Gills!
We're psychopaths!
Somebody better call the school nurse!
I am not amused!
Turn off those motors!
Everybody get up. Now!
I'm not ready for high school.
- Why'd she leave? Didn't she like us?
- Where's her sense of humor?
I have seen some sick things before.
But this... This is...
- Devilishly clever.
- Vomitous!
- Thank you.
- We take a lot of pride in our work.
Look, we want Shoop back.
Why would Shoop come back?
So Kelban can fire him?
He might surprise you.
- We did today.
- And we've got more for tomorrow.
Do we have a deal?
Wondermutt, I do not want to play.
Not now. I'm busy.
- Tough day?
- We've been torturing Gills.
Yeah.
He said you could have your job back.
Now, why would I want my job back?
Hey, my life is sailing.
I got a radio, blanket, beach chair,
dark glasses, dog.
Why would I wanna go back?
How about we can't pass that test
without you?
Me and Chainsaw, we been sober for
two days, four hours and 15 minutes.
- No kidding?
- Swear to God. Reality is so unreal.
- But a nice change.
- Truly. Thumbs up.
I think you should know
that you were a phase.
I've outgrown you.
But I do wanna be friends,
if you can handle it.
And Shoop...
...I'm seeing that reading specialist
this afternoon.
Look. We'll study in school,
after school, whatever it takes.
But we need a teacher.
What do you say, Mr. Shoop?
Please?
How can I say no
to these cute little faces?
Your practice test scores were great.
Hey, come on,
you been here 12 hours.
I want you to go home,
forget about this test,
get a good night's sleep.
I'll see you tomorrow,
8 AM, the lecture hall.
Hey, trust me. Come on, you're gonna
kick ass and take names. Believe it.
- Are we really that ready?
- Ready? What time's the test?
- Eight AM.
- See, the correct answers do not stop.
Now, go on, get out of here,
all of you,
before the college recruiters show up
and try to drag you all off to Harvard.
Hey, I mean it.
Wondermutt, look. I found Bob.
Go get it.
Yeah!
- Morning, Mom.
- Morning, sweetheart.
Morning, Dad.
How do you want your eggs, honey?
Fried, scrambled?
I don't know.
- What are eggs?
- I'll surprise you.
How do you spell "cat"?
- I don't know!
- Honey, what's wrong?
I don't know what's wrong.
Every... Everything's blank.
I don't know anything.
I don't know anything!
Chainsaw! Chainsaw! Chainsaw!
Are you all right?
- I had a nightmare.
- About what?
I don't know.
- Great day for a test, huh?
- Yeah.
Hey, Shoop.
- An apple.
- For the teacher.
Give them hell.
- Hey, we're testing in here.
- I know, I'm in your class.
I remember you.
Where you been?
Bathroom.
- Six weeks?
- My zipper got stuck.
"Do not open the test booklets
until you are told to do so.
"Using a number two pencil, take your
answer sheet and fill in your name.
"Last name first, first name second,
middle initial last on the first line.
"Do this now."
This officer is here to see
that there is no cheating.
Festival of screwups and their king.
Mr. Gills extends his warmest
personal regards and best wishes.
Hey, thanks for caring, man.
OK. Break the seals
on your test booklets now.
And turn to the section titled
Reading Vocabulary.
"You will have 20 minutes
to complete this section."
Everybody ready?
No!
Tension breaker, had to be done.
Anybody else?
Good luck, gang.
Ready.
Begin.
Sorry.
Kevin.
It's starting.
Now?
Shit.
How far apart?
Twelve minutes.
Try and slow it down.
Forget about the...
- Thirty seconds left.
- Come on, come on.
C, C,
C, C, C,
C, C, C, C.
- And...
- Wait 20 more seconds.
- Twenty seconds.
...stop. Pencils down.
C, C, C.
Drop them!
Stay seated until Anna-Maria
picks up your tests.
Miss Mazarelli, may I have those tests
after you collect them, please?
- Yeah.
- Can Rhonda and I be excused?
She's having a baby.
- She's having a baby?
- Oh, I wanna see this.
Calm down! Everybody just stay
in your seats. No problem here at all.
Rhonda, why didn't
you say something?
- I wanted to finish my test.
- You need hot water, a ride?
- All we need is a hospital.
- What can I do?
- Get out of my way.
- I can do that.
Carmine, get out of her way!
Get the door.
- Save the umbilical cord.
- And the afterbirth, if convenient.
Good thinking.
Oh, easy, easy, this way. Watch out.
- You look terrific.
- Well, I'm feeling pretty good.
That's great.
The baby is healthy and happy.
And my coach was incredible.
Yeah, well, I couldn't
have done it without you.
No cord, huh?
When do we get to see
the whippersnapper?
Rhonda, don't let those two
near the baby, please.
Well, it won't be a problem.
I'm giving her up for adoption.
- She's going to a really good home.
- That's nice.
I'm not ready to be a mom.
- Mr. Shoop.
- Ciao.
Ciao, gang. How's it going?
- All right.
- OK.
Bad news?
Gills says he's mailing you
your scores.
- We failed.
- He just said the average grade
- was below passing.
- So we failed.
Hey, you didn't fail.
I failed.
Field trips to the beach, a bed in your
classroom, drinking at the beach,
a screening of
Texas Chainsaw Massacre 1.
- Quite a summer, Mr. Shoop.
- I tried to keep it interesting.
I have his dismissal
ready for your signature, sir.
Before I sign anything,
I understand there are some people
waiting to speak in Mr. Shoop's behalf.
- Really?
- Come in.
Mr. Kelban, you're not actually
going to listen to these delinquents?
No. I'm gonna listen to their parents.
I'm Principal Kelban.
- Is there a spokesperson here?
- I guess I am. I'm Howard Gremp.
You're Chainsaw's father.
- Interesting boy.
- No, you can say it. He's a lunatic.
Dad.
You know, six weeks ago, I thought
he had the IQ of a salad bar.
His only interest in life
was to make people sick.
If my mother came to dinner, he would
give the dog a third eye or an extra leg.
Because of him,
we stopped having kids.
I mean, you can imagine the feeling
when I saw him studying.
The wife and I almost burst into tears.
- David was doing his homework too.
- It makes sense,
they share the same brain.
Not only did Mr. Shoop
get my daughter to read,
he taught her to drive.
He showed Kevin there's more to life
than just football.
- I'm not sure I agree, but it's possible.
- This man should not be teaching.
Proof is here in these test results.
Look for yourself, Mr. Shoop.
Passing is 70.
Average score here was 63.
- They failed.
- That is not true, Mr. Gills.
- We passed?
- No, not all of you.
But that's not what's important here.
Larry.
Went from an 18 to a 51!
If I'd only seen you strip
a week sooner. You!
- Mom, my hair.
- Rhonda.
From a 29 to a 43
and she gave birth.
Isn't childbirth
grounds for a makeup test?
It always has been.
This woman thing never fails.
Eakian. A 51 to a 74.
I passed!
I am an Eakian, Grams.
- All right, Eaker.
- Denise.
No previous test score because
you ditched every test, but a 38.
- Honey, that's terrific.
- We'll get them next time.
- Kevin.
- Yeah?
From a 48 to a 75!
Yeah! I'm back on the team!
- Yeah! Kill!
Chainsaw. Last score was a 6.
This time, 59. Monster comeback.
- All right.
- And Dave.
From a 26 to a 70.
I passed!
- You made it!
- You passed?
You passed and I failed, asshole!
How could you do that to me?
It was an accident.
I'll take it again. I can fail, I know it.
And Pam went from a 53 to an 82.
- Was that the highest?
- Well, almost.
I mean, that guy who spent six weeks
in the bathroom got a 91.
But look, there's more going on here
than test scores and grades.
You all worked hard
and you improved.
And that's very nice, Mr. Shoop.
We are here to discuss
his flagrant violation of school policies.
Hold it, Gills.
According to my numbers,
the average scores here
increased from 28 to 63.
That's 125 percent improvement.
Now, that's teaching.
- Absolutely.
- Yeah.
Mr. Shoop, I'm granting you tenure.
He's back, ladies and gentlemen!
This is the last time I ask. I promise.
Will you have dinner with me?
I'll think about it.
Can I use some of that lip stuff?
Does this mean we can
have dinner tonight?
I didn't say that.
We'll just talk about it over breakfast.