Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
- Do you think I look fat?
- Too skinny.
Anthony Ramos was gonna do this.
The guy from In the Heights.
He was going to do the "Rebound" number
with me. "The Glass House."
And he was like,
"Ah, I'm friends with Marc."
I'm not even playing me in this.
There's a protagonist, this woman,
that goes on this journey.
He's like, "Yeah, I think that people are
gonna think that... You know how media is."
Shit, what happened? She fall apart again?
Elaine is the quiet one in my universe.
She doesn't talk.
We don't have 200,000 extra,
because we're gonna need 200,000 extra.
We're going to need
the extra money for post.
You want me to do it like you just did it?
Is that what you do?
Don't make me cry.
You put all this together yourself.
No "we" about it.
No fucking "we" about any of it.
Love is not something that you do,
it's something that you can become.
It's lifelong.
It goes on...
Whether you like it or you don't like it,
you'll end up loving something,
if not somebody.