Peter, are you okay?
You're up early today.
CURSE - GRUDGE
Hi.
Excuse me.
Hi, Emma.
It's good to see you again.
Do you remember me?
It's Yoko.
- Sorry. Did I wake you?
- Bottom drawer.
Thank you.
- You know me so well.
- Come back to bed.
I can't. I'm gonna be late
for my architecture midterm.
Check your watch.
I set the clock an hour ahead last night.
Maybe you know me too well.
I'm really glad you decided
to come here with me.
- Me, too.
- You sure?
Of course. Why?
- It's a big deal, you know.
- Lots of people go abroad.
Besides, you've been dreaming
about coming here forever.
I'm just glad we could be together.
- Don't you have class today?
- Nope.
Just have to pick up a book
I left at the Care Center.
Come on, you could spare 10 minutes.
I promise I'll get you to class on time.
- Where are you going?
- Come here. I wanna show you something.
It's a Buddhist ritual.
The incense smoke carries the prayers
to the spirits of their ancestors.
It's to help them find peace.
They must have lost someone they loved.
Excuse me.
Come on.
- Karen?
- Yes, Alex?
- Are you free this afternoon?
- Just a test to study for. Why?
Your wish has been granted.
Your first visit alone.
Just make sure she has what she needs,
and help out around the house.
It's Yoko's case, but she didn't show up
for work this morning.
I can't get her on the phone.
She must be sick or something.
And she has the damn house key.
What's this phrase?
That's "severe lethargy with mild dementia. "
Apparently,
she sleeps through most of the day.
Her daughter-in-law doesn't work,
so she'll probably be there.
It's an English-language house,
so you should be fine.
Here's the address.
You can use the wall chart
if you need help...
and don't forget to bring a map, okay?
Don't worry, Karen. You're ready.
Hello?
Is anybody here?
Oh, my God. Are you all right? Come here.
Okay, Emma.
My name's Karen Davis.
I'm from the Care Center.
I'm substituting for Yoko, just for today.
Hello?
Yes, he was shut in the closet.
There was tape all around the door.
They're not home yet.
I don't know.
Emma still hasn't said a word to me.
No, he won't come down.
I know. I'm sorry, Alex. Okay.
Just get here as soon as you can.
Toshio.
Matthew and Jennifer aren't around.
Leave a message.
Hey, guys, it's Susan.
Matt, are you there? Pick up.
Okay, I'm leaving work now,
so you can try my cell...
or give me a call at home later.
I just want to make sure Mom's okay.
So just call me when you can, okay?
Who are you talking to?
I just want her to leave me alone.
You need to get some rest, okay?
LOOKING FOR OCCUPANT
Happy Home Sect. Ltd.
Welcome. What do you think?
Your shoes.
- Even in your own house?
- Even in your own house.
It's perfect for Mom.
She won't even have to deal with the stairs.
- Hey, where's Mom?
- I'll look for her.
Mom?
Where are you?
Come on, Mom.
You know what the doctor said about stairs.
- Is she okay?
- Yeah.
Hey, Mom.
What?
Mom, are you all right?
Suzuki-san?
- We'll take it.
- Okay.
Morning.
I hope Mom's okay.
She's been sleeping ever since we got here.
Not at night.
I've told you, Matthew,
you can sleep through anything.
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
I'm sure it was just the move.
She'll get back on schedule.
- Have you seen my travel mug?
- I haven't unpacked it yet.
Maybe you should say something
to the helper.
- What's her name?
- Yoko.
Who knows?
Maybe she can suggest something.
Maybe.
I miss seeing this.
I guess now we're
gonna have to talk in the morning.
Hey, kiddo, you okay?
Jen? Sorry, honey, are you all right?
What's up?
I went for a walk yesterday.
Just to explore.
And I got so lost.
And I couldn't find anyone
who spoke English that could help me.
This will get easier soon. I promise.
Or else?
Or else I tell the company
it's just not working out.
And we're going back to the States
with or without my old job.
They can find somebody else
to crunch their numbers.
But until then...
promise me you'll give it a good try,
okay, Jen?
Deal.
If you want something,
all you have to do is say so.
Who's there?
Hey, Jen?
What the hell...
Mom?
Are you all right?
Mom, where's Jennifer?
Come on.
You scared...
Jen? Honey?
What is it? What's wrong?
What happened? Honey, what is it?
I'm gonna call an ambulance, all right?
Who are you? What are you doing here?
Excuse me, Mrs. Williams.
INVESTIGATION
I am Det. Nakagawa.
This is Det. Igarashi, my assistant.
Is Karen okay?
She is very shaken.
We would like her to stay
in the hospital tonight under evaluation.
Do you know these people?
Yeah, that's Matthew Williams
and his wife, Jennifer.
He's the son of the woman
Karen came here to see.
When was the last time you saw them?
When they came in to register.
It's standard procedure...
although the visits were arranged
by his employer.
- I think he works at...
- We've spoken with his employer.
He hasn't shown up for work today.
If you could please come by tomorrow
and make a statement.
The address is there at the bottom.
- Yoko.
- I'm sorry?
Karen's a substitute.
Yoko's the girl
who's normally in charge of Emma.
She's also been missing from work.
For how long?
Since yesterday.
I think I saw her bike outside.
Hey, guys, it's Susan.
Matt, are you there? Pick up.
Okay, I'm leaving work now,
so you can try my cell...
or give me a call at home later.
I'm just a little worried about Mom.
I just want to make sure she's okay.
So just call me when you can, okay?
Thursday, 8:27 p. m. End of messages.
It's okay. I've got you.
Your boss told me what happened.
I'm sorry.
I'm not even sure what did happen.
An old woman passed away in her sleep.
- It's sad, but that's all it is.
- Is that how they're saying she died?
That house.
There was something...
It's okay, Karen.
Matthew and Jennifer aren't around.
Leave a message.
Hey, guys, it's Susan.
Matt, are you there? Pick up.
Okay, I'm leaving work now,
so you can try my cell...
or give me a call at home later.
I'm just a little worried about Mom.
I just want to make sure she's okay.
So just call me when you can, okay?
Matthew, stop it.
Is anyone there?
Excuse me!
Please. There was something on the...
- Sit down, please.
- Please, just help.
Hello?
It's me.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah, I'm downstairs.
What number are you again?
1601. I'll buzz you in.
I don't know what you're up...
How are you feeling?
Okay. Tired.
- You are an exchange student?
- Yes.
And you have been volunteering
at the Care Center for...
Three months.
I needed a social welfare credit.
You said this was the first time
you'd been in that house?
Yeah.
About the Japanese boy
you said you saw there...
- Did you find him?
- No, not yet.
You said the boy had been taped
into the closet?
That's right.
And there was a book, a journal.
Did it belong to the boy?
I don't think so.
I think it belonged to a woman.
The writing looked feminine.
Did you speak with the boy
after you opened the closet?
Briefly.
I asked his name. He said it was Toshio.
One more question, please.
We found this in the hallway.
This is him.
This is the boy.
Detective Nakagawa?
The whole time I was in that house...
I felt something was wrong.
What happened there?
The bodies of the son and daughter-in-law...
of the woman you were caring for
were found in the attic.
It seems that the son killed his wife,
and then himself.
Please excuse me for a moment.
What are you doing here?
I thought they weren't gonna let you go
until tonight. Did you escape?
I just had to get out of there.
I didn't wanna be alone.
Okay, Karen.
Hold on a second.
What's wrong?
Talk to me.
I think I saw something in that house.
Emma and I were alone in that room...
but I think there was something else
there with us.
Karen, what is it?
I just wanna go home.
Hello?
What happened, Yoko?
My name is Karen Davis.
I'm really sorry to bother you.
I was wondering
if I could ask you a few questions.
Questions about what?
I realize this is really awkward.
I'm here because...
I need to ask you a few questions
about your husband.
This is all his stuff from school.
This is from our first date.
My God.
Peter!
Hey, Shimizu.
- Happy Monday.
- Yeah, right.
Here's your mail.
- Another one?
- Yeah.
I have no idea.
She says she used to be
in one of my classes...
but I don't know who the hell she is.
- Thanks.
- No problem.
- Have a good one.
- Thanks.
Hi.
Detective Nakagawa,
I need to speak with you.
The woman who was murdered in that house
three years ago knew this man.
He committed suicide
the morning after she died.
I don't believe he killed himself.
I don't understand. What's happening?
Three years ago...
three of my colleagues, my friends...
began investigating a case.
Two died mysteriously,
and one disappeared.
They had been investigating the murders
at that house.
Are you saying the detectives died
because of that house?
I've been in that house. So have you!
It is said in Japan...
that when a person dies
in extreme sorrow or rage...
the emotion remains...
becoming a stain upon that place.
The memory of what happened
repeats itself there.
Death becomes a part of that place...
killing everything it touches.
Once you have become a part of it...
it will never let you go.
I'm sorry.
Corpses abandoned in garbage bag
INVESTIGATION - KEEP OUT
METROPOLITAN POLICE DEPARTMENT
KEEP OUT
Karen, it's me.
Look, where have you been all day?
I'm really worried about you.
The Care Center called.
Alex and Yoko are dead.
I found your research and...
Did you go to that house?
I'm coming to find you.
- Did you get my message?
- Doug!
Don't worry...
It isn't any problem.
I'll call you before I leave.
Ten minutes.
Yeah, I'll be home soon.
Yeah, love you, too.
Guess your mom's gonna be late.