You sleep?
No, why?
In your opinion ...
- What?
She thinks what, Ghislaine, when
she'll know I died a martyr?
That is to say?
It will be sad? Happy?
How does it take?
ll are plenty in paradise.
Ghislaine of hundreds,
thousands ...
Mark them!
Cover the ground, guys!
Fouad! Fuck
not let them shoot!
Watch out!
Guys, he's all alone!
Goal!
- It is not intended!
If you're not a fag,
tell him she's home!
It's purpose, I say!
Who's the fag now?
Editing my brother
and I send you to the hospital, got it?
Out!
Run, you!
The next approaching,
I cut his tendons!
Move it!
They'll give us the skin!
Faster, guys!
Come on, bitch!
Go for it!
Fuck you!
Rub your hands thoroughly
asshole.
What you looking at?
It's not too early!
Okay, father?
Hi, Said.
- What's that smell?
You went in the garbage?
You have brought still play
in the dirt? Brats!
Najat, shut up!
Mell-your own business!
- You breakages us your ears!
And you'll stop your silliness?
This is not ...
- Stop lying!
Come on, sit down.
I always get yelled at
because of you.
Mom, there is what for dinner?
There's six maids.
I'm too old. The boss wants me
more than twice a week.
One only has to find you
another plant.
l can not, with all these young
looking.
It does what Karim, the Sahara?
They say nothing on the news.
It is happening there.
Your brother will be back soon.
I want it back now.
Why not return it?
Eat and shut up.
- At your service, sir.
Yes, sir!
Right away, sir!
Yashin!
You'll find anything on this side.
If you want to help me,
looks in this bunch.
Nabil Homo!
The son Tamou, the bitch!
You're the fagot!
Beat it, motherfuckers!
Fuck, shit!
You hide behind your guy.
I just fuck you!
Clear, dirty bastards!
If I see you here,
I'll blow your head!
Viewing Hamid
I found a piece of engine.
This is good, stop.
The trucks were stripped
before arriving.
Come here, you.
Stop following him around
like a monkey.
Améne this piece to Ba 'Moussa
he'll give you 10 dirhams. Got it?
Do not get conned.
Not trust his beard,
is an asshole.
Do not worry.
- Watch out. Go.
Well the empaffé,
are you kidding me?
You'll spend your life
Own motor?
What do you want?
My brother Hamid wants 10 dh.
Tell me first ...
Who the fuck else?
What is this shit?
My brother Hamid said:
'' 10 dh, if you give it back.''
Fuck it,
your brother Hamid.
Released or I'll put a beating
p'tit con.
And you, says hello
to your mother.
Tell him I keep him
a beautiful piece.
What?
My brother Hamid
dh wants 10 or nothing.
Your brother Hamid?
Get out!
I'll tell my brother.
- Fuck you and your brother!
He takes it for? Tarzan?
Brats!
And you magnez your ass!
Stop messing around,
Be a man.
Do not worry, Real.
You will not be disappointed.
Emerges.
Madani!
Coffee.
Ba 'Moussa gave me 2 dh
instead of 10.
And besides he kept the piece.
Asks Nabil.
- I do not have time.
I did what you said,
asks Nabil.
It's okay, I get it.
- I did everything you told me.
I get it, I say.
I'm busy.
Go home.
I have an errand to run for Real.
Can I come with you?
Hamid!
It is I, the great Lev Yashin!
And this one?
His name is Lev Yashin.
This is a Russian.
You know what is a Russian?
I always carry with me.
You've never shown me.
This is the best goalkeeper
of all time.
You will become like him.
- You have not seen Fouad?
Ghislaine, are you okay?
I am looking for my brother.
Do not worry.
My girlfriend will be home soon
United States.
It will give you
the worst beating of your life.
You beg to opt-on.
I'll go see.
Advance.
It is not there, go ahead.
Stand erect.
Thank you, Yashin.
They lost against Saudi Arabia.
Morocco has been more humiliated like this
since its debacle in '79 against Algeria.
Listening.
Said, shut up.
Thank you, my God.
Where you been?
You want to make me mad?
You want to kill me?
Why are you yelling?
I was with my friends.
Your friends, it's bums
and criminals!
You spend your days with them!
You saw what time it is?
Your little brother
has just returned.
Where were you?
You know Younis, the son of Khadija,
was attacked yesterday?
I know.
- Why are you home so late?
Nobody can touch me here.
And who are you, you?
Too class pumps!
- They like you, Mom?
And that pleases you?
Perfume. I'm happy
to have you, my son.
I have a man by my side.
Will eat.
Take it to buy us
meat tomorrow.
I have not forgotten you, Mom.
God bless you.
You still think of Ba 'Moussa?
I'm stupid for letting
make fun of me.
Ba 'Moussa is too big for you.
I can try?
They too are
too big for you.
Father, you feel no
smell good here?
Hamid does not exaggerates.
All those in the first row
come from the medina.
The neighborhood where I grew up.
And swarthy?
This is the bodyguard
Sheikh of the UAE.
What is he doing here?
- He is the cousin of the groom.
If it is,
he has a gun under his jacket.
He spent five years
Germany.
It is there
he learned the trade.
It is broke party
and look at him.
Your father calls you.
So Nabil not you dance?
Where is your mother?
It should already be there.
Everyone expected.
I do not know.
- Go get it.
And you stopped to follow
like a monkey.
This is good. Let him go
with his friend.
Go.
And bring us our Tamou.
Motherfucker cop.
Do you think he emméne
marriage?
Where you want it to emméne?
One day, I will have her skin.
Watch the bodyguard
how he moves his ass.
Sheikh for whom he works
must like it.
What he Commissioner?
- Pitbull, who cares.
Guys, I found it.
We'll drink with me?
My mother is busy.
You hear? We're going to fete
Tamou on the bed.
Go ahead, I'm right here.
We go.
What acorn that.
Do not move, you!
This is good, léve up.
Congratulations to the newlyweds!
Goodbye and see you soon!
Our King Hassan II died today
I'hôpitaI to Ibn Sina Rabat.
God rest his soul!
I return.
Are open to anyone!
And now, Ie speech
Our new King Mohamed VI.
Hamid!
Come here.
Where is your brother?
- What happens?
You ask me what's happening?
Where is your brother?
- He's a game.
Go get it
and go home!
Cover the area well!
Mark it!
Fouad, not let him shoot!
Yashin!
Nabil!
Nabil, watch out!
Hey, easy!
You calm down!
What's your problem,
son of a bitch?
Beat it!
Clear!
Move it!
It failed me fart eye
this dog!
Wait for me!
- Khalil, you're shit.
You guys know that the king is m ...
- We know!
Move it!
Yashin, your coffee.
Thank you, Madani.
A new postcard?
- To Italy this morning.
You know who sent it?
- Who?
Adnan and Omar, in Milan.
You remember them?
They came up Italy?
- Yes.
Why are you telling me this?
Did you hear?
Adnan and Omar are in Italy.
Where they found the wheat?
They had to bump someone.
If I had signed with a club,
I have a great life.
You remember Azzedine? If he had
arrested for drink, it would be the star of Raja.
For you, it's not too late.
- You're crazy.
Not too late, my ass.
You got something to smoke?
- What slab.
You never have anything.
Come on breaks.
Come on!
The son of a bitch, in Italy!
And the coffee?
- Tomorrow.
That is,
take me for a fool!
Fouad!
It is not there.
- Are you okay, Ghislaine?
It's okay.
- He's where?
I do not know.
- We'll see you more.
I go to the center
to learn dressmaking.
That is good. And your grandmother?
- It's okay.
Ghislaine, come help me!
I gotta go.
Fouad is not there.
Come on breaks.
You're not stupid, you know
Fouad was not there.
Anything.
Do not take me for a fool.
Mi Lalla surely a plan for it.
And not with a clueless like me.
Its pumps shone
as a mirror.
And he gave me
a ticket 20 dh brand new.
If they were all like him,
I'd gone
typing me
nazes your mouths.
It is your father the lame.
- Seriously, guys ...
I have two friends who rent
in the medina.
They live like kings.
Loose us with your Medina.
You're stupid.
This is real life there.
You find everything you want
in the medina.
Even their shit, it's top.
Wanna taf?
The harbor is within walking distance.
Not like those bastards who build
a factory next door
and bring workers elsewhere.
As if we had leprosy!
I not bump at the factory.
If you want to save money,
bump with your brother.
He wants it.
- He is bosser Amine and not you?
He says I have to sell oranges.
- Oranges!
Oranges?
He does not care about your face.
It's good.
You just added me?
The cops!
Get him one that bar!
Adds.
- It is as usual.
Rates have increased.
- That's all I have.
Advance!
Get off me!
Hurry up.
Come out!
Hurry up, we're in a rush.
I have a sore head,
I slept badly.
Why?
I'm tired of this job.
Want to sell more oranges?
Want to become a lawyer?
I want to work with you.
Amine and why not me?
It was something more than me?
Answer me.
I already answered you.
It is not for you.
If this show one day
should not we both plunged.
Who will take care of the house?
And our mother?
You've figured it out?
Go bosser now.
You still do not want
you store, Tamou?
When I'm hungry, you think of me?
- One day we will stone you.
It is you who made me eat?
We will stone you to death.
- Get off me!
We want more of you here.
- It is you who will feed my son?
Mind your business!
This is my livelihood!
I also fear God.
That's right, bitch, fuck off!
Not bad, Yashin!
Khalil, a head!
Speedez why you like that?
- Pitbull repackages its business!
Now?
- Yeah, now!
Hurry up, Nabil!
Pitbull, mutated!
It is good for us, that.
The bastard, I will miss him!
Transferred? Look at how
I'm going to mutate me.
Son of a bitch!
Lance, if you got the balls!
You're a chick?
It has not got the balls!
- If I do, you take off your pants?
Go to see.
- You take off your pants?
Do it or shut up!
- Look good band nazes.
So, I have balls?
- They will roast you if you stay here!
Come back, we know them!
Climb!
Pitbull! Pitbull!
It's on me, guys!
Round!
Himself or another, is the same.
The problem is when there is
more police here.
And they will leave us
with these thugs.
Pitbull!
Adios!
He'll kill you
if you mug.
Repeats?
- You sent him in the mouth.
In the mouth, so what?
And you ...
You have done in your pants,
little pissy.
What?
Peed in my pants?
I'll blow you, motherfucker!
Hamid, calm down!
This is good, Madani.
We have fun.
You call that fun?
Take a sip.
In health Pitbull!
Hamid, get some fresh air.
Madani, let me go!
You should say thank you!
For having broken the mouth!
Sit.
- Get off me!
Police! Open!
What's going on?
What has he done?
It did nothing!
Get off me!
Let go of my son, he did nothing!
My son!
Mom!
- Get off me, you!
He has done nothing, my son!
My son!
Hamid!
This is not the price
you did to my brother.
I can not make you less.
Why you could with him?
At this price, I'm not doing.
I can not.
You do not want is not the same.
It's like that.
Take it or leave it.
Make up your mind,
My clients expect.
Want. You want to ruin me.
This is my place.
Aziz told me to put me there.
This is my place forever.
I'm not the head,
see-it with Aziz.
Business is good?
- We're not complaining.
Kid!
Who do you work now?
For my brother.
Which one? The crazy
the soldier or the Sahara?
Ah yes, the one who is in jail.
This is my place.
- If you want it, you work for me.
Otherwise I guarantee you nothing.
I work for anyone.
- In person?
You think you're hard?
We will see this.
What's going on?
Answer me.
- Nothing.
Tell me what you have.
- I think your brother.
This house is not the same
since his departure.
I'm afraid for him,
I have no news.
And I have not even
will visit him.
Do not worry about it,
it will come out.
How can you be sure?
He at least
he brought money.
Too soon,
I can help you.
Are you laughing at, asshole?
Father, okay?
Can not you see that choking?
Améne him a glass of water.
A glass of water!
- I can not stand!
Aziz lurking here. If you mug
in this state, it'll break your face.
Fuck it,
he and his oranges!
Come work with me on the site.
Pay me this orange!
I pay with shoe polish.
If you want, I'll wax ass
with cream.
Try to see!
You move?
- I move anywhere.
That's it?
You want to ride me, asshole?
That's all I won,
I swear.
Sort of miscreant,
you swear more?
You're a bum.
You do away customers.
Still drugged.
I'm not an addict.
It is I who am con
I made you work here.
Get out.
Will wash you, you stink!
Come on, move!
What did you
to watch me like that?
I want more bosser for you.
See repeated?
- Put yourself in the ass, your job!
Son of a bitch, I'll kill you!
Get off me!
I'm going to fuck your mother
in this motherfucker!
I'll teach you
to pay like the others!
Get off me!
Come on, if you're a man!
I'll kill you, motherfucker!
Do not touch me!
Get out of here.
Go ahead and shoot.
- Tell him to back off.
The match will start.
A shot and I'm going.
- Get out!
You are the black, not the reduced!
I do not move if you pull it.
Get out, we told you!
You know who you talking about?
Lev Yashin!
Fuck,
Even if you're Maradona!
It struck him, the bastard!
Leave him alone!
Always fight.
- Do not bother.
Head mule!
They have beaten three.
It's none of your business.
This is worse.
We see nothing.
I'll find you someone.
I do what I can.
Yes, it is.
Stop screaming,
You decentralized me!
Still nothing!
Tarek, you hear me?
It's worse, like that!
In the other direction!
There's nothing!
You hear?
Tarek?
Goodbye.
- Take care of yourself.
Here, Nabil.
I spoke with Ba 'Moussa.
You start with him tomorrow.
Pay attention to this work,
that's all you have.
I do not like this guy.
- Think only at work.
You think I like it, me?
God help you, my daughter.
- Thank you.
It is you, Tamou?
- Yes.
Look at me, my son.
You will not forget me?
Do not forget me.
I'm your mother.
Come see me from time to time.
It here.
I'll wait.
You come?
Goodbye, my love.
- Goodbye.
Take care of yourself.
You're lucky,
a house all to yourself.
Your mother has worked,
the poor.
Khalil, let me go.
- Take it easy.
I told you what happened
my friend Adil Medina?
His father was a baker.
He went to Spain
and found an old
paid for everything himself,
Even his papers.
Now they live together.
- You could do it, you?
You have a good look at me?
Nabil, he could.
It has smooth skin,
chewable.
It is you who are always talking
to leave.
It tells you nothing
setting sail?
There, at least, you have rights.
Even if you work it,
you're paid.
If I wanted to go,
I should have gone with my mother.
Your mother? The fact that change
slum.
This is the lipstick Tamou?
- His dear mother.
Not kidding, put it down.
Let him, we laugh.
You're blocked or what?
You shit!
Beat it!
You've seen, it looks
a chick.
Here, the red of your mother.
It drives us to his villa
the bastard!
You spend your days
a damn thing!
Come on, fuck off!
Noureddine?
What's going on?
What sick one!
Ba 'Moussa, what he has,
Noureddine?
He's gone. Will work!
ll come back more?
Why do you ask?
My friend could take Yashin
its place. It pleases you.
His brother is still in jail?
- Yes.
It took for how much?
- 2 years.
It is good in mechanical?
No, but it's a hard worker,
you'll see.
You can take the test?
- This is good.
Work not scare him.
- All right, I said!
You let alone bosser
on the moped?
He quickly learned.
You'll see, it will start.
And if he can not do it,
what do I win?
- It is I who will repair.
You want to ride me
crafty.
Too much!
Let us have a look.
- Go ahead.
Come on, roll!
Madani!
We go to school embroidery
Ghislaine.
Ghislaine? It is always
in your head?
She was never released.
For my friend
I would go to the end of the world!
I just see a girl.
- Nobody gets.
Just two words.
If you want to talk to him,
expect July 1 h.
It's like his brother,
will not you imagine things.
I guess nothing.
Brother or not, no in between.
Do you think you are? Looks like
you keep a bank.
It breaks.
Fucking goalkeeper
How old fart!
He thinks he's a cop.
Accelerates!
I see,
he likes it or not.
Fouad, you dog.
Afraid to your sister?
Fouad, okay?
- Yashin, what are you doing here?
A race for Ba 'Moussa.
Ghislaine, okay?
- It's okay.
What kind of race?
It is true that you learn
sewing?
Ba 'Moussa sends you on an errand
with these clothes?
It asks you a problem?
I learned a lot.
It was full of customers,
bosser they want with it.
That's right, I'm busy.
- It's nice.
Our grandmother wants to find her a husband.
- What are you talking about?
Do not believe it delirium.
- Are you kidding?
I look? It takes someone
to get us out of this dump.
Why do you think
I accompany?
For no lousy
not defile his honor.
She's right.
Do not believe
he said anything.
Instead, he wants your good.
And your grandmother too.
Hello. Advance you.
Hello.
The Russians bombed Grozny!
Hush Said!
You did not open
perfume I brought you.
Mother, you did ...
- I'm open.
According to our initial information,
an armed commando
have hijacked a plane Iine
to one of the towers jumeIIes
New York.
A second plane
just hit I'autre turn.
They had them!
Pius 3,000 people
travaiIIent in this tower.
Support for Al Qaeda
is a religious obligation!
Fatwa of Sheikh Abu Oubaida
Moroccan!
Two Sikh men
were killed yesterday
in the State of Callfornle,
the United UNlTED.
According Ies investigators
iI would be racist crimes.
The assassins thought
Ies that victims were musuImanes.
Yashin!
Your brother is back!
It is near the coffee.
Go!
And work?
- I'll finish it later.
You're not moving from here.
Come on, it's good.
You grew up.
You've become a man.
When she returns?
Usually, it is
at this hour.
You're in a hurry?
You know what?
It was the parable now.
A ton of channels is captured
without any understanding.
You want to watch?
- He told you that he was interested not.
It does not matter.
Get away from me.
Everybody out!
- Calm down, father.
What do you want?
No, sir.
Okay, sir.
You Who are you?
What do you want?
Who's that?
My son ...
Thank you, my God.
I missed you so much,
My Hamid.
Congratulations!
- Thank you, Najat.
Sit down, my son.
You want to eat?
No thank you.
Tarek gave us tea.
You know that your brother works
in this debauched Ba 'Moussa?
Did you tell him?
- Yes.
I'll ask him
to find you a job
with friends in it,
mechanics.
That is, ask him.
It's not worth it.
My Friends
I have already found a job.
You work?
- Yes, in a drugstore.
Thank you, my God.
You've lost weight,
you do not eat in jail?
I'll make you
a good tagine.
Your brother bought
meat.
Another time.
Tonight I dine with my friends.
Who is this friend?
You can not really
dine with us?
They called me after the prayer.
As you wish, my son.
Najat no longer works.
Her husband forced her to stop.
To keep it at home.
That's what they say anyway.
Hamid, too
you treat your wife like that?
Answer. Why would you say anything?
My son ...
May God enlighten you, mother.
I have something important
to tell you.
Tell me.
I will move
my friend Noceir.
It's not a bit rushed?
I really have to go, mother.
It does what it Noceir?
- This is a serious and grown boy.
Tarek knows it may be.
He was goalkeeper Zriba slum.
I would not know.
He's my age.
He remembers very well of you.
I do not know him, I say.
What you got?
- Nothing.
We can meet
Nabil in tonight.
He now lives alone.
Fouad Khalil and will be there too.
It's been
that is not all together.
I can not.
Why do not you come
in Noceir?
I can tell you,
it is easy to find.
To pray with you?
If I want to pray,
I do alone.
Excuse me,
I'm late for work.
Your brother got weird.
He told you about the prison?
Not.
- How does it not?
No! Are you deaf or what?
Welcome, my son.
Right on time for dinner.
Thank you, my God.
I brought you fruit and vegetables.
- Thank you, my son.
Tomorrow, God willing,
I bring meat.
Are you hungry? Mange.
Thank you, mother. I've dined.
Father came out?
- God help him.
Said, you have listened to the tape
I gave you?
I listen to the news.
Arabic, French and English.
You want me to make?
Listen to it, you'll like.
You know where it comes from?
Of Mecca.
Hamid, you know Yashin
wants to like you?
He wants to live
his friend Nabil.
What? Nothing to see.
We talk for a long time.
- Calm down.
No need to argue.
You do not want
off the TV?
Why do you turn off?
You miss an episode ever!
Follow your soap!
It does not matter, mother.
I was just passing.
I have to meet my friends.
- Stay with us a little.
I'll be back.
Welcomes father to me.
Stay a little longer.
I can not make them wait.
I'll be back.
Goodbye, my son.
May God protect you.
Why you did it go?
- It's my fault?
Since returning,
it eludes us.
It is now reasonable
and you do not agree that it has changed.
Reasonable?
He wants to see us,
that's become reasonable?
We're almost done.
A loose connection to the spark plug.
Almost finished?
That's why I came.
Look at this beauty.
Kiss me.
Are you drunk or something?
- Kiss me, I tell you!
Leave him alone!
Get out!
- Get out!
You've pushed me.
You think you're hard?
So what ...
Do you believe?
I'll show you
is that hard here!
Son of a bitch!
Get off me, you dog!
I'll take care of your little ass
son of a bitch.
Do not move here, you hear?
Help me.
Tomorrow you will go to the garage
as usual.
Wait until a customer arrives
then open.
At the end of the day,
close and go.
As if nothing had happened.
Included?
He does nothing happened.
Hamid. Open.
I told you to go to the garage.
Dress up and follow me.
- Where?
Dressed.
We will see the brothers
who saved you.
You hurry.
Enter.
You feel better?
- Yes. Can we go?
Where?
- In the garage, as you told us.
After.
It's good that you came.
Me is Zaid.
He is Noceir.
We met yesterday.
But no longer think of the past.
God forgives
the sins of the repentant.
Come on.
Abu Zubair wants to talk to you.
Hamid told me your nickname.
But Rather
your real name, Tarek.
Please.
Here, you will find your way
practicing prayer.
The collective prayer strengthen
your confidence.
I also grew
in this neighborhood.
Like you, I've made mistakes
Youth. And I paid dearly.
But through prayer
and with the support
your new brothers,
you learn courage.
Today Hamid is strong.
You too can become strong.
Your brother Zaid guide you,
with God's help.
I'll come pay the patron.
What are you doing?
Come on, get the hell out.
Hamid said
to stay until the evening.
I do not want to stay here.
Nabil, hurry up!
Your soup disgusting
was fucking me the runs.
You always had the runs.
- Never before you know.
You'll dine?
That is good.
I will not be long.
You were not seen at the mosque.
Tomorrow morning, if God wills,
Hamid will pick you up at 7 am.
I have things to show you.
Be on time.
- What things?
It is you, Khalil?
- Yes, it's me.
And you Fouad?
- Yes.
What things?
I'll teach you
to defend yourself.
That nobody bothers you.
- Nobody bothers me.
And I have to work with my father.
- As you wish.
But if you can come
you will not regret it.
Fouad?
- I will come.
I leave you in peace.
See you tomorrow at 7 am.
Did you hear?
Bed early
to get up at dawn.
He wants us to léve at dawn.
It's crazy!
I'm going, anyway.
Me too.
That is, learning
to protect your little ass.
Shut up!
- Stop, Fouad!
There's not just me here.
What is this circus?
What are you talking about?
- You stop the play.
You think you're at the movies?
In real bastons,
this crap does not work.
You want to continue to shine
pumps as a slave?
And you, what do you do?
Stay.
Where you going?
We must get back to work.
- The program has changed.
You'll stay with us.
We will pray and we have lunch together
with the will of God.
I do not have time.
Fouad, here we go.
Fouad, you're welcome.
You decide what?
I remain.
Hi, guys.
Please.
We are faithful
and believe in the oneness of Allah.
We reject the idols
and do not believe in Allah.
We are committed
neither land nor a tribe
or even in the area.
Our loyalty is to Allah,
his prophet and faithful,
wherever they are.
The Jews, the Crusaders
and apostate governments
attempt to weaken
Islamic nation.
But they will fail.
Allah has promised victory
Muslims
and defeat and punishment
for the disbelievers.
The victory will go to those who follow
the way of the prophets
and apply the precepts
the prophet of lslam.
Stay with me.
Just your brother.
Tarek.
Take your place.
Make a place for our brother.
I remember you well.
You played with the team the Stars.
I said Hamid.
I was also goalkeeper.
I liked your style.
You still play?
Not.
Neither do I.
But I sometimes attends games.
You always have
this photo of Yashin?
You kept?
Where'd you get it?
- Azzedine had given me.
What Azzedine? Touhami?
He was a friend
our big brother Karim.
It was the star of the neighborhood.
It would be in the national team
if he had been disciplined.
You have heard, my brothers?
Discipline
is the key to success.
You're not out?
I met your mother.
She was worried.
I reassured
but you should go see.
And Hamid?
I have not seen.
Nobody asks questions.
The police arrested her research.
You knew Ba 'Moussa
had a brother?
It is he who takes care of the garage.
He'll sell everything.
Zemama provides more than him.
- The referee kidding, there was penalty.
Go ahead, Aboucharouane!
Tire, asshole.
Do not you think it odd
Tarek they call you?
lmagine Hamid reapplies.
So what?
- It will not please him.
It is not his business.
- And if he said to Abu Zubair?
Not break my head with it!
There, you happy?
- Are you crazy? Pass me that joint.
You have seen how
Zaid broke the board?
All of a sudden, and he felt nothing.
Like that!
It must be black belt.
At least! Even Bruce Lee
would not the weight.
Noceir said
he learned in Belgium.
It was in Belgium?
- Damn, you're fucked up the joint.
Smoke and shut up,
head of cabbage.
Go!
That is a shot!
He told you what Abu Zubair
when you were alone?
He talks too much.
I know what you did.
But I'm not here
to judge you.
And it is not your fault.
You lived with poached
and libertines.
They are criminals,
not you.
This would have happened if you had grown up
in a healthy environment,
with faithful who fear
the anger of Allah?
I do not think so.
But today,
you can
to atone for your sins
and start
a new life
as if nothing had happened.
Recite your incantations.
They will be useful
for your learning.
Glorify Allah.
How the potatoes?
- 3 dirhams.
Put me two pounds.
You saw Amine?
- Yes.
Since Real left
nobody dares to sell shit.
It happens even
to look at ourselves.
May God guide.
I'll see you later.
- God willing.
I only listen to the news,
Arabic, French and English.
Do not listen to these more silliness.
They will disturb the mind.
Come with me to the mosque,
you'll feel better.
And stop shave.
You think you're a woman?
Said, sit down!
Calm down.
Do not blame him.
This is because he does not see you anymore.
I'm proud of you, you took
the same way as your brother.
This is not the way
my brother.
This is the real Muslims
who fear Allah.
You're right.
But why
you do not come to see us?
Even more
for couscous Friday.
We thank You, God,
for this food.
What a delight.
Who cooked?
Our brother Nabil.
A real cook.
And a real man.
I decided to move
in and Tarek Nabil.
That is good.
Group life
is very important.
Our brothers should learn
to live in community.
The problem is my sister
and my grandmother.
They will be alone.
My grandmother is sick.
- May Allah heal.
Do not worry.
We have a doctor sister.
She will visit him.
Allah bestows you.
- Solidarity is a duty.
Why are we brothers?
We help each other.
And help our families
if necessary.
Abu Zubair has an eye on you.
He knows that you are
at the beginning of learning.
And, thank God,
You are on the right path.
Hurry.
I do my ablutions and I arrive.
Wait.
Only you.
You come too Abu Zubair.
- What?
All brothers have noticed.
- This is the Emir, this is normal.
This is our Emir all.
Now you sit
and as you listen to everyone.
Included?
It's not my fault that Abu Zubair
does not care about you.
Excuse me,
I must wash.
Stop it!
Greet.
Greet!
Come dressed up!
Nabil, and Tarek Fouad.
I have good news for you.
You will work with us.
I talked to Abu Zubair
and he agreed.
Do not be angry
and get paradise.
The enemies of Allah said
war lslam
and Muslims.
They talk about peace and justice
in the world.
The truth is that the disbelievers
apostates and their vassals
want to deceive the Islamic nation,
destroy the appeal of lslam.
They rusent but Allah triumph
for His ruse is unstoppable.
Our brothers and sisters are
persecuted in Bosnia, Palestine,
lraq in Chechnya,
Kashmir, Afghanistan ...
Our children are slaughtered!
Until when will we accept
the indignation?
Until when?
Allah is our only recourse!
You okay, Ghislaine?
- Yes, thank God.
You always go
school of embroidery?
No, I work at home.
And I sell.
That is good.
Ghislaine, what do you do?
Come and help us.
I'm coming.
I saw you near the mosque.
You sell tapes?
You saw us?
You should have come.
I do not want to disturb you.
- On the contrary.
Ghislaine!
What?
May Allah reward.
Since grandmother is sick,
they send us to eat.
You know that a cousin of Rabat
asked Ghislaine hand?
This is a brother too.
It sells computers
and it was his apartment.
Thanks be to God.
Fight corruption
and depravity in this country!
Flee!
Apostates police!
God is great!
They struck you too?
No, it's okay.
God be praised.
Who fears Allah
not afraid of men.
You're right.
Yesterday, your brothers
corrected a drunkard,
an apostate who insulted
the majesty of Allah.
Apostates police
some brothers were arrested.
But we are on the right track.
They are depraved.
The power is in the service
the enemies of Allah.
We will not let
prohibit us
encourage virtue
and combat vice.
And those arrétés?
- Most have been released.
We are stronger than they
and they know it.
Death does not scare us.
We are not afraid
Allah Almighty.
They know that we love death
as they love life.
They are terrified
by our movement
that continues to grow.
And you, my children,
are part of this wave.
With God's help,
they can not reach you.
Look at your brother.
Even experienced,
it prefers to hide.
01:16:01,760 -> 01:16:05,673
It is the prerogative of the great warriors
whom Allah carries in his esteem.
01:16:06,400 -> 01:16:10,109
This is the state of mind that allows
better preparation for martyrdom.
01:16:12,080 -> 01:16:16,039
You have these qualities,
and God is with you.
01:16:34,520 -> 01:16:36,636
What do you want?
- I want to talk to Nabil.
01:16:38,720 -> 01:16:41,359
Why?
- I gotta tell you something.
01:16:41,520 -> 01:16:43,351
Speak!
- To you alone.
01:16:48,880 -> 01:16:50,791
What did she tell you?
- She wants to see you.
01:16:53,080 -> 01:16:56,470
Tell him to leave the neighborhood
immediately. Do you understand?
01:16:57,720 -> 01:17:00,712
Tell him that if I want to see,
I know where to find it.
01:17:33,560 -> 01:17:35,790
It is not lawful,
regardless of its content.
01:17:36,480 -> 01:17:38,232
You're right,
should not be open.
01:17:38,560 -> 01:17:41,632
Ask Zaid.
- Yes, let's ask him.
01:17:42,080 -> 01:17:44,469
One day, I heard:
'' The money from adultery is illegal.''
01:17:45,800 -> 01:17:47,233
What can it hold?
01:17:47,960 -> 01:17:49,871
Whatever.
It is not halal, that's all.
01:18:02,000 -> 01:18:03,115
Who is it?
01:18:07,960 -> 01:18:09,712
Remember, children lslam,
01:18:10,280 -> 01:18:13,397
the imperialist-Zionist conspiracy
is winning our country
01:18:14,160 -> 01:18:16,628
to destroy the last vestiges
our Islamic civilization.
01:18:17,800 -> 01:18:19,472
And every Muslim to fight
01:18:19,880 -> 01:18:22,348
who refuses to resign
against this evil plot.
01:18:23,120 -> 01:18:26,476
See how they have decimated
Islamic state in Afghanistan.
01:18:27,440 -> 01:18:30,671
You surely follow, through
media, their preparations for invasion
01:18:30,840 -> 01:18:33,559
Baghdad, Mesopotamia,
cradle of Islamic Caliphate.
01:18:34,520 -> 01:18:36,078
As for our chére homeland
Morocco,
01:18:36,240 -> 01:18:38,515
Mujahideen
are persecuted,
01:18:39,400 -> 01:18:40,753
tortured in prisons,
01:18:43,520 -> 01:18:45,192
no one responds.
01:18:46,640 -> 01:18:48,073
Have we lost so much faith?
01:18:48,560 -> 01:18:51,393
What happened to
our love for lslam?
01:18:52,360 -> 01:18:55,079
Is not it time to inflict
a lesson to these traitors?
01:18:56,000 -> 01:18:58,878
Allah says:
'' Oh, you believers
01:19:00,080 -> 01:19:02,355
fight the unbelievers
around you
01:19:02,640 -> 01:19:04,392
and they feel you
hardness''.
01:19:04,640 -> 01:19:06,995
And the Holy Prophet, the salvation of Allah
be upon him ...
01:19:09,200 -> 01:19:11,350
... Says:'' If you give
Jihad,
01:19:11,720 -> 01:19:15,633
Allah will plunge you into the indignity
until you resume the fight.''
01:19:16,560 -> 01:19:17,913
Take care,
children lslam,
01:19:18,200 -> 01:19:20,350
not to become
like this
01:19:20,600 -> 01:19:24,275
clinging to life on earth and
afraid to join the afterlife as martyrs.
01:19:24,920 -> 01:19:28,196
So fly, God horses,
and the gates of heaven will be opened to you.
01:19:28,480 -> 01:19:30,311
May Allah accept us
martyrs
01:19:30,840 -> 01:19:32,193
and opens
the gates of paradise.
01:19:32,560 -> 01:19:34,278
Amen.
- Amen.
01:19:35,160 -> 01:19:36,752
I pray to Allah
make you triumph
01:19:37,080 -> 01:19:38,354
unabated.
01:19:57,800 -> 01:19:59,597
This night is not
a night like any other.
01:20:00,000 -> 01:20:01,831
I tell you
great news.
01:20:02,720 -> 01:20:05,075
Thanks to Allah,
you have been chosen
01:20:05,400 -> 01:20:07,197
among many
our brothers
01:20:08,200 -> 01:20:10,760
to make his pride
the nation of lslam
01:20:11,600 -> 01:20:13,397
and to die as martyrs.
01:20:14,360 -> 01:20:17,318
You are the hopes of lslam
on this earth.
01:20:17,840 -> 01:20:20,877
And, God willing, the gates of heaven
will be wide open.
01:20:21,720 -> 01:20:22,869
I'm happy for you.
01:20:24,000 -> 01:20:24,989
Allah is great!
01:20:25,480 -> 01:20:26,799
Allah we will triumph!
01:20:33,240 -> 01:20:34,116
Allah is great!
01:20:35,120 -> 01:20:36,473
Allah we will triumph!
01:20:55,560 -> 01:20:57,790
God horses
are virtue
01:20:57,960 -> 01:20:59,837
up to
the resurrection.
01:21:00,800 -> 01:21:02,995
The Hi Allah be upon you.
01:21:15,320 -> 01:21:17,151
It does not tell us
how this man was.
01:21:17,760 -> 01:21:19,637
You saw how Abu Zubair
before him?
01:21:20,200 -> 01:21:21,474
Me too, it surprised me.
01:21:23,160 -> 01:21:24,388
It was he who chose us?
01:21:25,200 -> 01:21:28,078
Abu Zubair had to tell him about us
and obtained his consent.
01:21:31,000 -> 01:21:31,989
You can go out with me?
01:21:33,440 -> 01:21:35,396
Why?
- I want to talk to you.
01:21:53,560 -> 01:21:54,310
What?
01:21:55,000 -> 01:21:55,955
You gonna go?
01:21:57,120 -> 01:21:58,109
Are you really gonna do?
01:21:59,280 -> 01:22:00,599
You thought our mother?
01:22:01,320 -> 01:22:02,435
She will never recover.
01:22:02,600 -> 01:22:03,635
They have chosen us.
01:22:03,800 -> 01:22:04,835
Chosen?
01:22:06,160 -> 01:22:07,673
You did not hear
Abu Zubair?
01:22:08,200 -> 01:22:09,713
It was chosen for martyrdom.
01:22:10,560 -> 01:22:12,551
Are you scared?
- That's not the point.
01:22:12,720 -> 01:22:15,154
I'm talking about our mother.
- And I'm talking about martyrdom.
01:22:18,480 -> 01:22:19,469
I do not fear me.
01:22:20,880 -> 01:22:21,790
Not afraid?
01:22:26,040 -> 01:22:27,519
Looks like you're shaking.
01:22:29,880 -> 01:22:31,996
If you're scared,
stay with our mother.
01:22:33,080 -> 01:22:34,433
I do fear Allah.
01:22:35,160 -> 01:22:36,195
You got it?
01:22:53,640 -> 01:22:55,232
May 9, God willing,
01:22:55,800 -> 01:22:58,268
in a few days,
01:22:58,680 -> 01:23:00,875
you will become
the heroes of this nation
01:23:01,120 -> 01:23:02,712
and will be welcomed in heaven
01:23:03,440 -> 01:23:07,228
with the martyrs
who have sacrificed for our nation.
01:23:07,760 -> 01:23:10,320
Right now, they bask
delights in the gardens of Eden.
01:23:10,520 -> 01:23:12,078
But to achieve this honor,
01:23:12,320 -> 01:23:13,799
it will be on your guard.
01:23:15,160 -> 01:23:18,232
In the coming time,
be careful
01:23:19,480 -> 01:23:21,516
and follow
security measures.
01:23:22,840 -> 01:23:26,150
Do not leave the area,
avoid discussions in public,
01:23:26,520 -> 01:23:28,556
avoid talking to strangers.
01:23:29,320 -> 01:23:31,515
You can visit
your loved ones,
01:23:31,680 -> 01:23:32,715
but you linger.
01:23:33,200 -> 01:23:35,316
Do not worry
for the future of your family.
01:23:37,120 -> 01:23:38,997
Your brothers will take care of them.
01:23:57,200 -> 01:23:59,430
You could remove
when your brothers are there.
01:23:59,960 -> 01:24:00,676
You hear?
01:24:02,120 -> 01:24:03,519
Removed these headphones!
01:24:09,520 -> 01:24:10,475
We have to go.
01:24:11,280 -> 01:24:13,919
Stay a little, it's been
I've not seen together.
01:24:14,520 -> 01:24:15,589
We gotta go.
01:24:15,960 -> 01:24:18,030
Wait at least
your father home.
01:24:18,200 -> 01:24:20,589
ll surely be back later.
Or not at all.
01:24:23,040 -> 01:24:25,190
Oh, and if you go
near a pharmacy,
01:24:25,400 -> 01:24:27,118
Buy Me
two boxes of medicines.
01:24:34,800 -> 01:24:36,028
Like this.
01:24:36,400 -> 01:24:37,753
Here the order.
01:24:40,480 -> 01:24:41,754
What do you have?
01:24:44,760 -> 01:24:45,795
Okay, mother.
01:24:46,240 -> 01:24:47,958
Do not make me wait,
I need it.
01:24:48,800 -> 01:24:50,074
May Allah bless you, my son.
01:24:50,720 -> 01:24:51,789
Goodbye.
01:24:53,240 -> 01:24:54,639
God bless you.
01:24:58,920 -> 01:25:00,911
Goodbye, mother.
- God bless you, my son.
01:25:04,360 -> 01:25:06,078
May God preserve you!
01:25:08,240 -> 01:25:09,309
Take care of yourself.
01:25:11,800 -> 01:25:12,949
How do I know?
01:25:14,760 -> 01:25:15,556
Okay.
01:25:18,160 -> 01:25:19,115
God willing.
01:25:20,440 -> 01:25:21,668
Guidelines is expected.
01:25:25,080 -> 01:25:26,308
Zaid.
01:25:36,400 -> 01:25:40,188
The operation was postponed
at a future date.
01:25:41,400 -> 01:25:43,994
Zaid will explain.
I must go.
01:25:45,200 -> 01:25:46,679
Soon, God willing.
01:25:48,640 -> 01:25:50,551
The transaction must take place
under the best conditions.
01:25:51,320 -> 01:25:52,958
Tomorrow we hit the road at dawn.
01:25:53,400 -> 01:25:55,516
We need to prepare ourselves
for martyrdom.
01:25:56,920 -> 01:25:58,319
May Allah give us strength.
01:26:11,440 -> 01:26:14,398
We thank you, God,
and to Thee we return.
01:26:24,400 -> 01:26:26,038
This is the first time
I'm in town.
01:26:42,800 -> 01:26:44,199
It is great!
01:26:45,240 -> 01:26:46,514
God alone is great.
01:26:52,800 -> 01:26:53,630
Watch!
01:26:56,000 -> 01:26:56,989
Look at these villas.
01:26:58,560 -> 01:27:01,552
These good these drivers,
this luxury comes from Europe.
01:27:03,160 -> 01:27:06,118
Where would that their wealth
if they do not steal the people?
01:27:07,200 -> 01:27:10,590
They exploit your sweat,
yours and mine.
01:27:12,240 -> 01:27:15,471
But they will burn in hell with
their entire fortune amassed here below.
01:27:16,320 -> 01:27:18,993
And it is for us the doors
paradise will open.
01:27:20,760 -> 01:27:24,355
Ie Seion protocoIe RoyaI,
Ie his Majesty King Mohammed VI
01:27:24,520 -> 01:27:27,956
decided prénommer
Ie future heir MouIay Hassan
01:27:28,160 -> 01:27:30,958
in honor of his father,
Ie late King Hassan II.
01:27:31,240 -> 01:27:34,437
The UK is preparing to céIébrer
joy in the birth Ia.
01:27:35,800 -> 01:27:39,554
Throughout Ia capitaIe, festivities
important were organized ...
01:28:08,600 -> 01:28:09,635
You've seen those trees!
01:28:10,200 -> 01:28:11,155
What kind!
01:28:12,040 -> 01:28:13,189
Come, my brothers.
01:28:14,080 -> 01:28:15,149
Hamid, come and help me.
01:29:08,440 -> 01:29:10,795
You abandoned
famiIy and money
01:29:11,040 -> 01:29:14,157
and you went to
Ie round earth Ia
01:29:15,040 -> 01:29:19,113
Paroies your and your actions towards AIIah
were sincere
01:29:27,920 -> 01:29:32,118
Your heart is not attached to Iife,
IUI does not value
01:29:32,680 -> 01:29:36,878
You're like Abu Dujana, hero
charismatic large bataiIIes ...
01:29:45,320 -> 01:29:46,753
In winter, it is covered with snow here.
01:29:48,120 -> 01:29:49,109
Everything is white.
01:29:50,080 -> 01:29:51,991
We no longer distinguish
earth from the skies.
01:29:53,120 -> 01:29:54,269
Allah is unique.
01:29:56,760 -> 01:30:00,275
These wonders on earth are nothing
next to those of the above
01:30:01,200 -> 01:30:02,599
full of wonders
01:30:03,360 -> 01:30:04,998
you've never seen
01:30:06,080 -> 01:30:07,479
nor heard.
01:30:13,280 -> 01:30:14,998
God willing,
the operation will be
01:30:16,440 -> 01:30:17,998
Friday, May 16
01:30:22,480 -> 01:30:23,435
Hamid, okay?
01:30:25,400 -> 01:30:26,355
It's nothing.
01:30:27,520 -> 01:30:29,476
I just drank
a little too much coffee.
01:30:35,200 -> 01:30:36,349
Allah is with us.
01:31:04,520 -> 01:31:05,396
You sleep?
01:31:07,640 -> 01:31:09,073
No, why?
01:31:10,680 -> 01:31:11,590
In your opinion ...
01:31:12,600 -> 01:31:13,476
What?
01:31:16,000 -> 01:31:19,072
She thinks what, Ghislaine, When
she'll know I died a martyr?
01:31:20,040 -> 01:31:21,109
That is to say?
01:31:22,840 -> 01:31:26,150
It Will Be Sad? Happy?
How does it take?
01:31:28,000 -> 01:31:30,036
ll are plenty in paradise.
01:31:30,920 -> 01:31:33,639
Hundreds of Ghislaine,
thousands In ...
01:31:52,000 -> 01:31:52,955
Tarek!
01:31:56,000 -> 01:31:58,195
Who is it?
- That's me. Come on.
01:32:00,160 -> 01:32:01,957
What are you doing?
- Nothing sleep.
01:32:06,480 -> 01:32:08,118
What are you doing?
- Do not shout.
01:32:08,600 -> 01:32:10,272
Tell me what happens.
01:32:12,320 -> 01:32:13,389
Do not do it.
01:32:14,080 -> 01:32:16,071
Tarek, listen to me.
Do not do it.
01:32:16,880 -> 01:32:18,108
Do not get explode.
01:32:18,640 -> 01:32:19,868
What are you doing?
01:32:20,400 -> 01:32:21,469
It's martyrdom that is,
01:32:21,880 -> 01:32:24,075
it is on the verge of heaven.
01:32:24,960 -> 01:32:27,428
We talk about us
it will be remembered.
01:32:28,080 -> 01:32:30,958
What do you want more?
- I will not let you.
01:32:31,960 -> 01:32:33,109
You know where we're going?
01:32:33,840 -> 01:32:34,750
It will explode.
01:32:35,280 -> 01:32:36,713
You realize it or not?
01:32:39,440 -> 01:32:40,668
You can leave if you want.
01:32:41,800 -> 01:32:43,358
But you heard
what was said by the Emir.
01:32:44,160 -> 01:32:46,549
Whoever retracts after having learned
the details of the transaction
01:32:47,440 -> 01:32:48,634
can not stay alive.
01:32:52,760 -> 01:32:53,715
A problem?
01:32:55,560 -> 01:32:56,356
No, it's okay.
01:32:57,200 -> 01:32:58,474
I had discomfort.
01:32:59,600 -> 01:33:00,669
I feel better now.
01:33:02,760 -> 01:33:04,671
Tarek, go back to your tent.
01:33:05,840 -> 01:33:07,478
We're going for a ride
your brother and me.
01:33:28,120 -> 01:33:28,950
Take.
01:33:35,800 -> 01:33:36,710
Strike.
01:33:55,720 -> 01:33:56,709
Not bent.
01:33:58,080 -> 01:33:59,479
And hardened your heart.
01:34:12,280 -> 01:34:13,269
Wait.
01:34:19,960 -> 01:34:21,109
May Allah reward you.
01:34:23,640 -> 01:34:25,153
We are all counting on you.
01:34:26,440 -> 01:34:27,668
Abu Zubair first.
01:34:28,520 -> 01:34:30,954
Moreover, it made you
head of the operation.
01:34:32,760 -> 01:34:33,875
I will not disappoint.
01:34:34,640 -> 01:34:35,709
I have no doubt.
01:34:49,960 -> 01:34:50,836
GB
01:35:22,480 -> 01:35:23,515
The address of my mother.
01:35:24,560 -> 01:35:26,118
It may be that she moved.
01:35:26,840 -> 01:35:29,035
It will have all your stuff
do not worry.
01:35:30,160 -> 01:35:31,309
We go.
01:35:32,120 -> 01:35:33,269
Leave your bags here.
01:35:38,640 -> 01:35:39,755
After you.
01:35:45,080 -> 01:35:46,354
Straight.
01:36:01,400 -> 01:36:02,310
Go ahead, my brothers.
01:36:28,120 -> 01:36:29,678
Welcome.
01:36:49,680 -> 01:36:52,592
Some think it is
with practice.
01:36:52,840 -> 01:36:55,957
I tell them iA
to this conviction aside.
01:36:56,440 -> 01:36:58,829
iI must Pius
to succeed in this type of action.
01:37:01,760 -> 01:37:03,193
Knowledge and harmony
01:37:03,360 -> 01:37:06,432
Ies among members of a ceIIuIe,
who must learn
01:37:06,840 -> 01:37:08,956
living ensembIe
and to know.
01:37:09,720 -> 01:37:11,358
You have an idea
the place of the operation?
01:37:13,240 -> 01:37:14,912
I heard we were going
blow themselves
01:37:15,440 -> 01:37:16,953
purpose I do not know
not exactly where.
01:37:17,160 -> 01:37:18,559
I think it's a bar.
01:37:18,920 -> 01:37:21,195
On after you, there will be
that Jews and Christians?
01:37:22,240 -> 01:37:24,276
In my opinion, there will also
Muslims.
01:37:24,640 -> 01:37:26,517
It will be martyrs
if Muslims are killed?
01:37:26,800 -> 01:37:27,915
I do not know.
01:37:28,240 -> 01:37:30,754
A Muslim who drinks
is a Muslim, right?
01:37:31,360 -> 01:37:32,475
What is the problem?
01:37:33,680 -> 01:37:36,558
Those who drink alcohol and combine
Jews and Christians are Muslims?
01:37:36,760 -> 01:37:37,875
They are apostates.
01:37:38,520 -> 01:37:41,956
And even if they were Muslims,
they help us to achieve our enemies.
01:37:42,960 -> 01:37:45,269
It is therefore permissible to kill them.
01:37:47,040 -> 01:37:48,553
Join the group.
01:38:54,400 -> 01:38:56,152
Set your watches 10:52.
01:40:23,920 -> 01:40:25,148
Go to heaven.
01:40:32,600 -> 01:40:33,919
Hamid, okay?
01:40:34,280 -> 01:40:36,999
You are beautiful kids like that
and there are taxis waiting for you.
01:40:37,240 -> 01:40:39,879
Take us with you
one air exchange.
01:40:43,760 -> 01:40:45,591
It was not the right
have fun, too?
01:40:46,800 -> 01:40:47,994
I'll remember.
01:41:47,840 -> 01:41:48,909
God willing.
01:42:36,760 -> 01:42:37,829
Fouad.
01:43:05,240 -> 01:43:06,559
Join us
in two minutes.
01:43:20,600 -> 01:43:21,635
Get off me.
01:44:15,480 -> 01:44:16,196
Yes, sir?
01:52:46,040 -> 01:52:49,919
Subtitle:
Tongues Untied