Mommy!
Bad dreams?
- Mommy.
- It's all over.
Come here.
It was in my closet.
Something's in my closet.
Oh, too much junk food.
Too much of the tube, guys.
He's in there.
Tad, now, there's nothing in this house
that's going to hurt you.
Look what I see in the closet here.
I see clothing.
I see a pile of blankets on a chair...
a lot oftoys
that weren't put away...
and your favorite
over-the-hill teddy bear...
who would probably be
a lot happier-
Who would probably be
a lot happier in bed with you.
And that's it.
- Nothing else.
- I saw him, really.
He's in the closet.
He has yellow eyes,
and his mouth is about this long...
and he has teeth,
and they're curled like this...
and he made sounds.
What kind of sounds?
Come on, try.
What kind of sounds? Like what?
- That would scare me pretty good.
- Really.
But he's all gone now,
champ, see?
He's in there. I saw him. Really.
Tad, you saw him in
your dreams—
in your head, nowhere else.
See, Tad,
there aren't any real—
Tad, listen to me,
there's no such thing as real monsters...
only in stories.
There's no real monsters.
- Really?
- Really.
Really.
Okay, over, done with,
gone, right?
Over, done with, gone.
What a guy.
Okay, snuggle in.
Good night, sleep tight,
don't let the bedbugs bite.
- You have good dreams now, okay?
- I will.
There aren't any monsters, Tad.
Except for the one in my closet.
Please.
Please. Please.
Hey, Tadder.
You know, it looks like someone
was moving furniture around...
up in your bedroom last night.
Any idea who that might have been?
- Do you know, Donna?
- It wasn't me.
It wasn't me, either.
Wasn't me.
Yeah, come on in, Steve.
Morning!
- Mrs. Trenton.
- Morning.
Here you go, Tadpole.
Just like I promised—
Brought your horse back.
Looks pretty good stripped,
doesn't it?
- Do we have a check for him?
- Listen.
Why don't you just wait
until I bring your table back?
Thanks.
I can't stay for a cup
of coffee anyway.
Sorry. Would you like a cup?
Just teasing.
Hey Tad, maybe it was Mr. Kemp
who moved all your furniture around, huh?
Okay, what did I do now, huh?
No, the monster did it.
The monster?
Oh, no. Come on,
remember what I said.
There aren't
no such things as monsters.
There aren't any
such things as monsters.
Not in the daytime anyway.
Come here, you!
Not in the daytime?
I'll show you what a monster
would do in the daytime.
He's grab your knee
is what he'd—
- I know a lot about cereal.
- Daddy! Daddy! Look!
Because I'm
the Sharp Cereal Professor.
Sharp cereals: Twinkles,
Cocoa Bears, Brand 1 6.
My daddy invented that.
He made them all up.
- Who?
- The professor.
And they're good for you.
Well, your daddy's
real smart, isn't he?
As well as being a hell
of a tennis player.
Ready for a rematch
any time you are.
- Sure, sure.
- Gotta go.
Bye.
Thanks.
Nothing wrong here.
That's game, set, and match.
- Good game.
- Oh, yeah, what was the score?
- 6-love, 6-1 ?
- Yeah.
You're not getting tired
ofthis, are you?
What, are you kidding me?
Getting my ass handed to me every week.
No, I love it, I'm a masochist.
- Well, whatever turns you on.
- Yeah.
...the onlyjeans that-
Turn that off, please.
It's dinner.
Turn it off, Tad.
This marriage is definitely
running out of conversation, isn't it?
Maybe we should talk
about having another baby.
I got you!
Oh, no, he's got me.
He's got me!
Watch my chair!
Hi.
Excuse me.
I have a problem with my front wheel.
I wonder ifyou could look at it.
Park it next to the Datsun.
Leave the keys in it.
Well, I was kind of hoping
I could wait for it today.
You're kidding.
See you later, Harry.
Joe Camber will do it for you.
What's that?
Joe Camber.
Do a real good job,
and he won't rob you blind.
Where's Joe Camber?
You take 1 1 7 here
straight out of town...
6 mile, give or take.
All the way out to the end.
You'll see Camber's mailbox.
You can't miss it.
Thanks.
See you later, Harry.
Hi.
Pa!
Tough time finding this place.
How are you?
My name is Victor Trenton.
You're Mr. Camber, right?
Afternoon.
You folks want anything to drink?
No, thank you. Thanks.
Vic?
Come on, Cujo.
Come on, boy. Come on.
Get going. That dog.
Look at that dog.
Don't worry about it, ma'am.
Cujo won't hurt him.
He likes kids.
- He's safe.
- Run me down the hill.
- I want to have a listen to her.
- Yeah, okay.
- Vic?
- It's all right.
Yeah, it's all right.
Don't worry, Mr. Trenton.
Your boy will be all right.
Gently.
Cujo. His name's Cujo.
Cujo?
How you doing, Cujo?
Hey, boy.
What kind of dog is he?
St. Bernard.
He's a great dog.
Yeah, he's a pretty smart one, too.
Monsters, stay out ofTad's room.
You have no business here.
No monsters in Tad's closet.
It's too small for you in there.
Where else?
Under the bed.
Under the bed? Okay.
All right, no monsters under Tad's bed.
You cannot fit under there.
No monsters outside Tad's window.
Can't hold on out there.
Nothing will touch Tad.
Nothing will hurt Tad...
all through this night.
Okay?
They have no business here.
Oh, my God, 1 :30?
What?
You're just really good
with him, that's all.
How am I with you?
Wonderful.
Good night.
Nothing wrong here.
Well, that's not entirely true.
This morning, thousands of
people across the country...
reported internal hemorrhaging
after eating Sharp Cereal products.
The scare, however,
proved to be a false alarm.
- Hi!
- Hi.
- Hi, Tad.
- Hi, Dad.
Despite that fact, the scare
has reached alarming proportions.
Sharp Cereal has been
unavailable for comment.
Nope, nothing wrong here, folks.
Cute.
That's our ad campaign.
They've recalled
the whole goddamn cereal.
- There's no harm done, is there?
- No harm done?
Donna, that guy comes into
America's living room...
and he says to kids, "Trust me!"
- Yes, I understand.
- No, I don't think you do.
We created that guy-
Roger and me.
- He's our brainchild.
- I understand.
These kids, they go out,
and they buy the cereal.
All the Sharp cereals.
All of them.
Brand 1 6, All-Grain,
Cocoa Bears, Twinkles.
And now, kids
all over the country...
are peeing
and puking red dye...
and scaring the hell
out oftheir parents...
and we told them to buy it.
The Sharp Professor is us!
That's our ass, Roger's and mine.
You'll work it out.
You always have before.
Look, I appreciate
this isn't a world crisis—
- This is not a mass suicide.
- That'll be Roger.
Hello.
Yeah, sure, Roger, hold on.
It's Roger.
Hi, Rog.
Roger! Rog, calm down.
Calm down.
We'll work it out.
We always have before.
Well then nobody got hurt, right?
What we're talking about here
is a lot of scared people.
We're talking about recalling
the whole goddamn cereal.
Well, that's not too bad.
I mean, it certainly could be worse.
Hey, buddy, don't yell at me.
- It's your dye, not my-
- Roger!
...like there's
nothing wrong here!
Look, no harm was done...
and I'm sure, given time,
this whole thing will blow over.
We're having a special
board meeting next week, okay?
Special board meeting?
We're going to reassess our
position re the Professor.
- Sure, we can be there.
- You better be there.
You better start taking this
a little more seriously, too.
- I'm not kidding!
- Right.
To reassess our position
re the Professor.
We lost the Sharp account.
Brett!
- Hi.
Come here.
I can't see you anymore, Steve.
Well, it's a little late
for that, isn't it?
Just came by to tell you that.
Okay.
Can you tell me why?
Jesus, I don't know.
I got this terrific husband
and this terrific kid...
and here I am, screwing
around with the local stud.
No offense intended.
None taken.
What the hell's the matter?
It's just over, that's all.
I want it over.
It's not your fault.
It was just a stupid mistake.
Okay.
Whatever you want.
Sorry.
Hi, Punkin'.
Hi! Look what I made.
Hey, that's really nice.
What happened to you?
- Nothin'.
- Yeah? It doesn't look like nothing.
I got hit by a swing.
Come here. Let me make it better.
Well, over, done with, gone, right?
- Over, done with, gone.
- Okay, strap in.
Oh, you like this, huh?
It's fun!
Bum, bum, bum, bum
I see your heinie
It's nice and shiny
Ifyou don't hide it
I think I'll bite it
Daddy's home.
Yeah, so I see.
Okay, everybody out.
- Hi.
- Daddy!
My big guy.
- Home early, huh?
- Yeah.
- What happened to your head?
- Fell off the swing.
Pinto's doing that thing again.
I'll have to take it up to Camber's.
- Yeah, I've heard that one before.
- Come here.
- Would you like to play some baseball?
- Yeah.
- Would you?
- There's a load of groceries here, Tad.
That's yourjob.
No. Not today.
Go on. Go get your mitt.
You left it on the front lawn again.
- Go on.
- Okay.
So what did you do today?
Oh, you know, the usual.
Groceries, errands.
Yeah?
Roger come in today?
No, he's still in mourning
for the account.
What the hell is that?
It's an engine hoist.
You wanted one.
It's the new hydraulic hoist
you wanted.
You kept telling me you need one.
You tell me what the fuck
is up here, Charity.
Sit down and eat, and I will.
Can't you use it?
Damn well can't afford it.
I won the lottery.
$5,000.
When do we get it?
Two weeks. A little less.
Thanks.
I got you a present.
You give me one, Joe. Okay?
I want to go away
for a week with Brett...
to see my sister in Connecticut.
Boston?
What the hell
are you gonna do in Boston?
What makes you think
I could afford to go anyway?
Shit! You're rollin' in it.
You might have to dig out something
from the mattress is all.
You're kicking up your heels a little,
aren't you, Joey?
You're go right
to the Combat Zone...
see a couple of dirty movies
and try to get the clap.
You better look out, pervert,
or I'll sic my dog on you.
That dog?
You couldn't sic that dog on me...
if I was coming at you
with a straight razor in each hand.
What does your wife say about it?
She don't know.
She don't have to know.
Sure.
She's going to take the boy to visit
her sister. Gonna be gone a week.
You're going to spend the lump
ofthat lottery money, eh?
- Shit.
- Broads, booze, baseball.
I don't want to do it alone.
It's no fun. Come on!
I don't give a shit if I do.
Now you're talking.
Now you're talking!
You've come to get me!
How's my boy? You having
a good time at summer camp?
It's yucky.
Your mom said
you were having fun.
Well, you want
to go home, then?
- Yeah.
- All right, let's go. Over the shoulder.
Yeah. Home we go.
Think you can beat me
to the Jaguar?
Think you can beat me?
Come on.
God, you scared
the shit out of me.
I'm sorry.
How'd you get
in here anyway?
Finished with your table.
I brought it back.
It's all stripped, and it's
a beautiful piece ofwork.
Leave it on the back porch.
I already did.
Where's Tadpole?
He's upstairs sleeping.
Steve—
I miss you, okay?
You know, I miss touching you.
Please, Steve. Please.
Quit it!
Steve?
- God, it's my home!
- Stop it! What?
It's my goddamn home,
you bastard!
Bastard, it's my home!
What the hell
are you doing?
Who the hell do you
think you're talking to?
Just get out of here, okay?
Mommy! Mom—
- What happened?
- The milk spilled.
- Go out and ride your bike.
- Are you okay, Mommy?
- Go on.
- Yeah, honey, I'm okay. Go ride your bike.
I brought your table,
but I spilled some—
Steve.
Yes or no?
Yes.
Don't, you son of a—
What is it, Tad?
I don't want you to go.
Well, I'll be back.
I'll be back in ten days.
But I don't want
to go to day camp.
Well, why don't you give
that another day or two, all right?
Who's going to say
the monster words?
Mommy don't know them.
Come here.
See, Tad, the thing
about the monster words...
is they're written down.
That's the only way
your dad can know them...
so what I'll do
is copy them for you...
and then I'll tack them
on your bedroom wall...
and that way, your mom
can read them to you every night.
- Will you?
- I will.
I promise I'll do it
for you tonight.
Okay, Tad,
time for your nap.
I love you, sport.
Come on.
Did you fix it?
No, I don't have the tools.
Take it up to Joe Camber's.
It's only 7 miles.
Yeah, maybe.
I'll try and run it up Saturday
if I can get the time.
It's okay. I'll take care of it.
Cujo?
Cujo, what's the matter?
Cujo, it's me, Brett.
Take it easy, boy.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
I don't want you to go for ten days.
I don't want you to go for one day.
Tad, I'll be back before you know it.
Now give me a kiss.
I forgot to take
the Pinto into Camber's.
I'll take care of it.
Well, I'll see you.
Vic! Stay there!
I just wanted you
to know it was over.
I just wanted to be
sure that you knew that.
I can't make that it
never happened, Vic.
I can't make like it never
happened either, Donna.
I know. I know that.
So I don't know what
I'm going to do yet.
I don't know.
Get the rest
ofthe bags, Brett.
Mom?
Mom, I'm worried about Cujo.
I saw him this
morning in the fog.
He was all bloody.
He was dripping foam
at the mouth.
Think I better tell Dad.
No, you do no such thing.
Your father would just jump
on something like that.
You just leave him be, and he'll
come mooching around your dad...
and your dad will take care of him.
He loves Cujo.
- Yeah. I guess he would.
- Tell you what.
We'll call your
father tonight.
When you talk
to him, you say...
sort of casually...
"You feeding my dog, Daddy?"
- Then you'll know.
- Yeah.
Brett!
Cujo.
What are you growling at?
Come on!
I don't give a shit!
Hear me?
You ought to be dead,
you stupid son of a bitch.
Cujo!
Shit.
Gary!
Hey, Gary!
Gary?
Gary!
Oh, shit!
Gary.
Cujo.
Oh, my God, you're rabid.
Easy, boy. Easy, Cujo.
One rolled over
And the other one said
Bum, bum, bum, bum
I see a heinie
It's nice and shiny
Ifyou don't hide it
I think I'll bite it
Alice stepped in the bathtub
Pulled out the plug, and then
Oh my goodness!
Oh, my soul!
There goes Alice
down the hole!
Glub, glub, glub
Come on, baby.
Just a little more to go.
Well, I think
we've arrived, Tadder.
Yeah, but is anybody home?
I don't know. We'll see.
Hello?
- I can't get my seat belt off.
- Hello!
Just great. This is great.
I can't get my damn
old seat belt off.
All right. I'm coming.
You're so impatient.
Damn button's stuck again.
Everything in this car is broken.
I wish Daddy'd get a new car.
Well, sounds good to me.
Damn this car.
You pull while I push.
Oh, I can't get it.
Pull!
It's okay. It's okay, honey.
It's the monster
from out of my closet!
Oh, there's no monster.
He got out of my closet!
Oh, baby.
How'd the monster
get out of my closet?
Listen to me. It's not a monster.
It's just a doggy.
Okay.
Okay, the doggy's gone.
See, the doggy's gone.
All right, we're going
to go home right now.
- I want to go home!
- We're going right now.
Oh, God.
Damn this car!
- Oh, I want to go home!
- Okay, listen to me!
We can't go home
right now, okay?
- We have to wait—
- I want to go home!
Tad, we have to let— Okay.
We have to let the engine—
I want to go home!
Okay. We'll go home.
Okay, we're going to go
home in a few minutes.
We'll go home
in a few minutes.
Mom, aren't we going?
Ma!
Yeah, okay. We'll try it.
Cross your fingers.
Come on, baby. One more time.
Great! It's fixed!
We're gonna go home!
Fuck you, dog.
Come on, damn it, turn over.
God damn you! Come on!
God, why didn't you
get this car fixed!
Mommy, are you okay?
Yeah.
I thought you were mad at me.
No, baby, never at you.
Can he get us in here?
Can he eat his way in here?
Can he?
I wish he would die.
Me, too.
Mommy?
What?
I gotta go pee.
- Yeah? Tadder, you gotta go bad?
- Yes.
Real bad?
Okay, look. We're going to open
this doorjust a little crack, okay?
You pee right outside here.
- Why can't we go outside?
- Because it's too cold.
Get your pants down. Ready?
Okay.
Okay, go quick.
Zip up your pants, Tad.
Don't open the window.
Just gonna open a little
bit for some air.
What's that?
The monster words.
Oh, let me see.
Please?
I'll give them right back.
- Is there any more drink?
- Oh, baby.
We gotjust a little bit left,
and I think we ought to save it, okay?
Can you wait? Just for a while?
- Yeah.
- Good. Thank you.
Can I have my
monster words back?
Okay.
"You have no business here.
No monsters under Tad's bed.
You can't fit under there.
No monsters hiding
in Tad's closet.
It's too small in there.
No monsters outside
ofTad's window.
You can't hold on out there.
No vampires, no werewolves...
nothing that bites.
You have no business here."
Maybe it will start now.
I'm afraid to try it
because the battery is so weak.
What does it matter
ifthe battery's weak or not?
We're just sitting here.
Try it.
Please?
Okay.
Told you.
Don't worry. When the mailman comes,
we'll go home.
Just lay them out like this.
Okay.
- George.
- Yeah?
Hold mail until notified.
The Cambers.
Remember, George?
My mind's going.
Thanks, Roger.
You saved me a trip.
Get back in that barn, damn you.
Oh, my God.
It makes him angry.
Baby.
Quiet. Please be quiet.
I want to go home.
Oh, Mom wants to go
home very much, too.
I know, baby.
Nothing wrong here.
This is ridiculous.
We need a whole new campaign.
Start from scratch, huh, Vic?
What? I'm sorry.
Cut it, Frank.
We're wasting our time.
Where are you going?
I need some sugar.
Tadder?
Oh, shit.
Mommy! Mommy!
Let me see!
Mommy!
Okay, baby.
I want to go home.
Listen.
Listen, Tad.
- Tad, listen.
- I want to go home.
Don't get out of the car.
- Do you have any idea what time it is?
-Just wanted you to know.
- Roger, I have to go back.
- Go back? Go home?
You can't do that.
This whole damn thing was your idea.
- You can't do that to me.
- I know, Roger.
- I'm sorry. But I can't stay.
- Look, Vic, I understand.
I know what you're going through.
- You do?
- Of course.
You think I'm so wrapped up
in my own problems...
I can't see what's happening to you?
I see it, believe me.
- It happens to everyone.
- Not to me, it doesn't.
Oh, you can't come up with an
answer to the Sharp account...
so you think you're through.
You think the creative juice is gone.
It's panic, that's all, just panic.
Hey, what did I say?
Vic, what is eating you?
Donna's been having an affair.
Before I left, she told
me she had quit it.
Roger, she hasn't answered
the phone in two days.
Shit.
I'm going back.
I'm sorry.
Look, maybe she's spending
the night with a friend.
Oh, I can't believe I said that.
Call someone. Call the police.
- Have them go over and take a look.
- That's not the point.
Goddamn it, Vic, you can't
run out on the Sharp account.
Wanna bet?
Please, God, get me out of here.
Please get me out of here.
Tad.
Tadder, wake up.
Oh, my God.
Tad, wake up.
Now breathe. Breathe!
Give me your tongue.
Come on, breathe. Breathe!
Breathe! Come on!
Tad, talk to me!
I want to go home.
Tad, talk.
Four little monkeys
Laying on a bed
One rolled over
and the other one said
I see your heinie
Nice and shiny
Right?
Then I think I'll bite
Okay.
Is anybody home?
Donna?
We got two of everybody on that list,
didn't we, Bannerman?
Did we ever reach Missus—
What was her name?
- Her friend in Reardon.
- I said yes.
I am telling you, it was Kemp.
All right?
This was Kemp who did this.
Where's your wife's car,
Mr. Trenton?
Her what?
Bothers me.
Kemp came here, right?
He grabs your wife and son.
Why? Well, he's crazy,
which is reason enough.
Where's her car?
It's in the shop at Camber's.
The needle valve is sticking.
-Joe Camber's?
- Yes. Joe Camber.
- She was going to take it in.
- When would that have been?
- I don't know.
- I'll check it out.
Wait. What are you
going to do about Kemp?
We've got an MV alert out on him.
We'll pick him
up soon enough.
Kemp is taken care of.
Oh, Tad.
Not now!
Oh, please, not now.
Please. Please.
Breathe!
Not now!
I want my daddy.
- Okay. Okay.
- I want my daddy.
I'll get your daddy.
Oh, my God.
I want my daddy!
I want my daddy.
All right, I'll get your daddy!
Mr. Trenton?
They picked up Kemp.
Are they all right?
Well, your wife and son
weren't with him.
He claims that he
never even saw them.
Oh, bullshit.
You don't believe that, do you?
Not after what he
did to the house.
Well, that's the thing.
He admits that he
trashed the house...
and his story checks.
Tell you the truth,
I believe him.
What did Bannerman say?
Well, he—
He's probably following up some lead.
We'll be hearing
from him any time now.
Wait a minute.
You haven't heard from him yet?
He hasn't even called in?
Tad, baby.
Oh, baby, wake up.
Dear God, save my baby.
I'm losing my baby.
Well, come on, then!
Oh, my God.
Oh, breathe!
Oh, yes!
Yes, baby!
Yes, my baby!
Donna?
Donna!