(♪ "Iko Iko" by The Belle Stars)
sittin' by the fire
♪ My grandma and your grandma
"I'm gonna set your flag on fire"
♪ My grandma said to your grandma
♪ Talkin' 'bout hey now, hey now
♪ Iko iko unday
♪ Jockamo fina anane
♪ Look at my king all dressed in red
♪ Iko iko unday
he'll kill you dead
♪ Bet you five dollars
♪ Jockamo fina anane
♪ Talkin' 'bout hey now, hey now
♪ Iko iko unday
♪ Jockamo fino anane
♪ Jockamo fina anane
sittin' by the fire
♪ My flag boy and your flag boy
"I'm gonna set your flag on fire"
♪ My flag boy said to your flag boy
♪ Talkin' 'bout hey now, hey now
♪ Iko iko unday
♪ Jockamo fina anane
♪ Hey now, hey now
♪ Iko! ♪
(woman speaking Italian)
(men talking loudly)
How many times you wash out with EPA?
- Just one or two more days. - Three times? You're on a roll.
Four cars, three times each.
That's zip for 12. What are you, a mechanic or a NASA engineer?
I told you I'd never dealt with Lamborghinis.
You assured me you could deliver these cars with that time frame.
Don't tell me that, 'cause I'm not listening.
Sir, I hardly think that's necessary!
I'll explain that to my swing loan. I'm into him for 200,000.
That's thousand. Three zeros.
I got all my money in these cars, and if I don't get my money out, I am finished.
You have to understand our situation.
I got the sharks snapping at my heels here.
They could've taken my business 11 days ago.
I had to hold them off with a whip and a chair.
I know delivery is way overdue...
Fucking EPA! The world is choking on smog,
and they're gonna correct the situation by keeping my four cars off the road?
- (phone ringing) - Babbitt Collectibles.
Have you tried cash? How much can one of these EPA guys earn in a week?
- Mr. Wyatt. - Wyatt?
About the swing loan. He doesn't get the money by 5:30, he'll seize the cars.
- I'm gonna have to call you back. - Talk to Mr. Babbitt on this.
Tell him you watched me sign the check, then you gave it to the mail girl.
Come on, come on. I need this!
I wouldn't do that, sir, until you talk to Mr. Babbitt.
A number for him? No, he's on the road.
- He wants you to call him... - Charlie!
Tell him I'm on my way to Barbados, can he leave a number.
- Charlie! - What, Lenny? I'm here. Talk to me.
Mr. Bateman wants to back out on his car and wants to take Mr. Webb with him.
They found two cars at Valley Motors.
Tell him that was me on the other line. The paperwork will be here momentarily.
- You paying attention? - Yeah, I'm listening.
Tell them also I'm knocking off five grand for their patience, understand?
- Are you sure that you've got it? - I've got it!
Mr. Bateman? That was Mr. Babbitt on the other line.
As it happens, the cars are passing emissions...
I mean, the cars have passed emissions. We're waiting for the EPA paperwork.
We'll have that momentarily, and because of your incredible patience,
we're going to knock off $5,000 on each car.
Yes, you've been most patient. We really appreciate your patience.
Well, thank you. Thank you.
- Ready for Palm Springs? - Charlie, you still want to go?
We're seconds away from closing this deal, clearing 75 grand.
- Not bad for a couple of phone calls. - Not bad at all!
- You know where to find us, right? - Right. I got it under control.
by Johnny Clegg)
(♪ "Scatterlings of Africa"
Listen, I don't wanna be demanding you,
but could you possibly say ten or 12 words before we get to the hotel?
Hmm? Consider it foreplay.
Can you include me in some of your thoughts?
I'm just thinking. You know, nothing special.
Maybe it's something we can talk about it, make a little conversation.
If there's something to talk about, Susanna, we'd be talking.
What's the big to-do about me thinking?
I just feel, I'm going away for a few days with someone. Call me crazy.
- OK. You wanna talk, let's talk. - I don't wanna talk!
I feel you're excluding me from what's going on. It's not that I wanna talk.
One of these again. How did we get back to one of these?
I don't know why I put up with all this.
You wanted to go to Palm Springs, and we're going.
- But I didn't want to go alone. - Susanna, you wanna talk, let's talk!
- Let's talk. - This is not talking, this is you...
(phone rings)
Yeah?
Charlie, this is Lenny. I've been trying to contact you for a while.
I got a long-distance call from Mr. Mooney, your father's lawyer.
He's been trying to reach you.
Your father has died, Charlie.
- Charlie? - Uh-huh?
I'm sorry. The funeral's tomorrow in Cincinnati. He said you'd know where.
- I've got his number. - That's not necessary. Anything else?
No, that's it. If there's anything I can do...
- All right. - (hangs up)
- Sorry about the weekend, hon. - Charlie, the weekend?
I told you before, we had a falling-out a long time ago.
My mother died when I was two. Him and me, we just didn't get along.
- You're going to the funeral, no? - Yeah.
- I'm coming with you. - That's really sweet,
- but there's no point. - I want to. That's the point.
All right. Sorry, I forgot who I was talking to.
...our believed neighbor, for our memory, admiration and respect for him
will live beyond the years of his life on earth.
Let us consecrate ourselves to follow his example of zest for life,
dedication to family and charity to all.
And now, with sure and certain hope of resurrection life,
we commend to you the soul of our departed friend...
Just have to go over the details of the will tonight, then we're outta here.
I can wait in the car if you like.
(Susanna) Somebody should be watering those roses. They're dying.
I knew this car my whole life. Only drove it once.
It's a 1949 Buick Roadmaster convertible.
Only 8,000 production models made.
Straight Eight. Fireball Eight.
The first full year of the Dynaflow transmission.
Know it by rote.
(Susanna) You were his only child.
You came along when he was, what, 45 or something?
He probably thought he was never going to have a son, so he had to love you.
I think you're exaggerating. You were his child, his son, his blood.
He doesn't look like a man who doesn't love his son.
What are you doing looking at this? Put that away! You wanna hear a story?
- Don't get mad. - The convertible in the garage?
- His baby. That and the goddamn roses. - Buick.
The car was off-limits. "That's a classic," he'd say.
"It's not for children."
Tenth grade, I'm 16 years old, for once I bring home a report card full of A's.
I go to my old man. "Can I take the car out?"
Take the guys out, sort of a victory drive.
He says no. I take it anyway. I steal the keys, I sneak it out.
You took the car with no permission? Why? Why then?
Because I... I deserved it.
Nothing I did was good enough for this guy! Don't you understand?
We're on Columbia Parkway, four kids, we get pulled over.
An accident?
Uh... Pulled over... Whoo-whoo-whoo!
- What is "pulled over"? Police? - Yes, police.
- Can I finish? - Yes.
He called in to report a stolen car, not his son took the car without permission.
Just stolen.
The other guys' dads bail them out in an hour. He left me there two days.
- He left you in prison for two days? - Two days.
Were you scared?
Yeah, I was scared.
Left home. I never saw him again.
Charlie, after a year we've been together,
this is the first time I've heard this story.
It's strange. I mean, how can you keep all this inside you
and not say anything?
When I was a kid and I got scared, the Rain Man would come and sing to me.
The Rain what?
One of those imaginary childhood friends.
- What happened to him? - Nothing. I just grew up.
Not so much.
"And I remember, too, the day you left home,
so full of bitterness and grandiose ideas, so full of yourself."
Being raised without a mother, your heart's hardness is understandable."
Your refusal to even pretend that you loved or respected me,
all these I forgive,
but your failure to write, to telephone, to re-enter my life in any way,
has left me without a son.
I wish you all I ever wanted for you. I wish you the best.
I hereby bequeath to my son, Charles Sanford Babbitt,
that certain Buick convertible,
the very car that unfortunately brought our relationship to an end.
Also, outright title to my prize-winning hybrid rose bushes
to remind him of the value of excellence,
and the possibility of perfection.
As for my home and all other property, these shall be placed in trust,
in accordance with the terms of that certain instrument executed herewith."
What does that mean, the last part?
It means that the estate,
in excess of $3 million after expenses and taxes,
will go into a trust fund for a beneficiary
to be named in this document.
- Who? Who is that? - I'm afraid I can't tell you that.
- Who controls the money? You? - No, he's called a trustee.
What is that? How does that work?
Forgive me, but there's nothing more I can say.
I'm sorry, son. I can see you're disappointed.
Why should I be disappointed? I got rose bushes, didn't I?
I got a used car. Whatshisname... What'd you call him?
- The beneficiary. - Right.
He got $3 million, but not the rose bushes!
I definitely got the rose bushes.
- Charles... - I definitely got the rose bushes.
- There is no need to... - To what? To be upset?
To be upset?
If there is a hell, sir, my father is in it,
and he is looking up right now, and he is laughing his ass off.
You wanna be his son for five minutes? Did you hear that letter?
- Were you listening? - Yes, sir, I was. Were you?
No. Could you repeat it? 'Cause I can't believe my fucking ears.
I was looking for you. How did it go?
I got what I expected.
Susanna, this could take a few minutes.
Can I help you?
Yes, I think you can. I have a problem with a private trust...
- That's a terrific suit! - Thank you.
My father was Sanford Babbitt...
(Charlie) Is this Wallbrook?
Excuse me, is this Wallbrook? Excuse me.
(woman) Dr. Bruner is in conference.
Would you like to wait in his outer office?
We'll stay here. Thank you.
Maybe we're not supposed to be looking around.
(man on TV) Good to have you here. Good luck to all three of you.
$20 starts you all off on a very important match.
In what 1980 comedy film did Goldie Hawn get away from it all?
Excuse me, please. I want to watch the TV. Please.
For whose grandson was the presidential retreat Camp David named?
- Lisa? - Eisenhower.
For David Eisenhower. And you've got another five. Ten-dollar lead for Lisa.
In days of yore, what would a swashbuckler keep in his sheath?
- (indistinct chatter) - (woman singing)
(sighs) Whatever this is, I don't understand the point of secrecy.
This patient is an old girlfriend of my father's?
- I knew your father since you were two. - The year my mother died.
I'm trustee of the fund, but this hospital receives nothing.
Maybe that's something we could discuss.
I took on this burden out of loyalty to your father.
That's where my loyalty ends.
And you think I should feel that loyalty?
I think you feel cheated out of your birthright
by a man who had difficulty showing love.
I think if I were in your shoes I'd probably feel the same.
I was hoping you'd help me understand the right in what my father's done.
Because failing that, I have responsibilities of my own,
and they have to be met, even if that means a fight.
(Susanna) This is not your car, it's my boyfriend's.
(man) My dad lets me drive slow on the driveway. I'm an excellent driver.
- Are you sure you drive this car? - 'Course, only 28 miles on the odometer
since I drove it a week ago last Saturday.
- Should be more than 28 miles. - My boyfriend is coming.
'Course, today's Monday. I always drive the car on Saturday, never Monday.
- Who is this guy? - I don't know. He jumped into the car.
- He can jump out. - I'm an excellent driver.
That's good. Come on! I don't have time for this shit.
Why'd you let him get in? It's not a toy.
He says he drives this car.
Dad lets me drive slow on the driveway.
'Course, the seats were originally brown leather. Now they're pitiful red.
You know, these seats were brown leather.
- You know this car? - I know this car.
How do you know this car?
A 1949 Buick Roadmaster Straight Eight. Fireball Eight.
Only 8,095 production models.
Dad lets me drive slow. But not on Monday. Definitely not on Monday.
- Who's your dad? - Sanford Babbitt.
10961 Beechcrest Street, Cincinnati, Ohio.
That's my address. What is it with this guy? Hey!
- Who's your mother? - Eleanor Babbitt.
Died January 5th, 1965, after a short illness.
- Who the hell are you? - Uh-oh!
- Wait a second. Where are you going? - 13 minutes to The People's Court.
- Hold it. I want to ask you a question! - "What you are witnessing is real."
- Hey, I'm talking to you! - (muttering)
Bruner, who is this guy?
Raymond is your brother.
(Raymond muttering)
My brother? I don't have a brother.
..have your dispute settled in our forum of People's Court. Dah-dah-dah-dah.
People's Court. Dah-dah-dah-dah. The People's Court.
(man on TV) The People's Court.
Hello. I'm Doug Llewellyn, and welcome to The People's Court.
- (Charlie) Is he crazy? - (Bruner) No.
- Is he retarded? - Not exactly.
- But he's here. - He's an autistic savant.
I don't know what that means.
They used to be called "idiot savants".
They have certain deficiencies, certain abilities.
- He's retarded. - Autistic. Actually, high-functioning.
What does that mean?
There's a disability that impairs sensory input and how it's processed.
English here. You're talking over my head.
He has a problem communicating and learning.
He can't express himself, or understand his own emotions in a traditional way.
...with the clipboard, and after that, the dog bit him.
I yelled at my dog. The dog lay down...
There are dangers everywhere for Raymond.
Routines, rituals, it's all he has to protect himself.
Rituals. That's a good one.
It's the way he acts, sleeps,
eats, uses the bathroom, walks, talks, everything.
Any break from the routines, and it's terrifying.
- How long has he been here? - Let's see. I came here in 1960...
- No, how old is he? - He was 18 or 20 then.
I'd have to check.
- You've been here that long? - That's when I started.
'65, '75, '85...
I was almost three years old, and you knew I was his brother.
Yes, but what's the point?
The fuckin' point is, why didn't anyone tell me I had a brother?
- What would you have done about it? - I don't know.
Does he know how much money he's been left?
No, he doesn't understand the concept of money.
He doesn't understand the concept of money?
He's just inherited $3 million, he doesn't understand the concept?
That is fuckin' poetic, don't you think?
Good old Dad.
(Raymond) Then who's playing first?
Yes. I mean the fella's name playing first base.
- Who. What are you asking me for? - What is this? Why is he doing that?
Whenever he gets nervous, he does "Who's on First?", Abbott & Costello.
It's his way of dealing with you touching his books and stuff.
- So he memorized "Who's on First"? - Yeah. That among other things.
Raymond. Ted Kluzevski.
Kluszewski. Ted Kluszewski. "Big Klu". First base.
- (Susanna) He played for Cincinnati. - He was traded for Dee Fondy, 1957.
- Lifetime batting average 298... - He reads, huh?
Reads and remembers whatever he gets his hands on.
Oh! Oh!
Oh, Vern! V-E-R-N! 'Course, these people are going to be here all day.
This is an unannounced visit. This is definitely not a weekend visit!
He's getting anxious. It's OK, Ray!
Vern! Oh... Uh-oh. You're...
This is an unannounced visit.
He said not to touch the books.
- Not to touch books. - You like Shakespeare?
I don't know.
- Did you read all this? - I don't know.
- Did you read Macbeth? Hamlet? - I don't know. Vern!
- Twelfth Night? - Stop it!
- Yes. - Yes?
You read all the stories in this book,
and you don't know if you read the book?
- I don't know. V-E-R-N. - You don't know?
Maybe you'd better put it back.
You don't know. OK. No, Ray, take it easy, I'm not gonna...
I won't touch anything else.
It's OK, Ray. Come on. My main man!
Vern, my main man. My main man, Vern.
- (Vern) It's OK, Ray. - Yeah.
- My main man. - Yeah, my main man.
Here are your cards.
I'm sorry. I didn't know where you wanted me to put them.
Are you taking any prescription medication?
He likes you. That's just his way of showing it.
- Uh-oh. - But I touched him, he pulled away.
Don't take it personal. He never touched me.
I'm closer to him than anybody. I've known him for nine years.
(chuckles) It's not in him. If I left town tomorrow
and didn't say goodbye, he'd never notice.
- (Susanna) He wouldn't notice? - (Vern) I'm not sure,
but I don't think people are his first priority.
Hey, Ray, you want to go take a walk? Hmm? Ray?
Ray? Can he hear us when he's like that?
You want to show your brother your ducks?
'Course, it's 27 minutes to Jeopardy.
Don't worry, Ray. We'll bring you right back.
- Practically 26 minutes to Jeopardy. - We'll bring him right back.
(Susanna) I won't do it. I won't do it!
First of all, because of this tone of voice, this commanding...
You're upset. Just calm down. Raymond, I'm gonna talk to Susanna.
- Bye, Raymond. - Susanna! Just hold on.
I'll be right back. No, just stay.
Just stay there.
No, Raymond. Raymond. Raymond! Raymond! Just stay there.
Just stand still, OK? That's... that's good.
I'll do it if you tell me why. Why do I do... Ohh!
- What? - Why do I have to take the car
and go down there and wait for you again at the gate?
I've been waiting for you for days. Why?
It's for Raymond. The car disturbs him.
- That's why? - That's why.
- (Susanna mutters in Italian) - OK, Raymond.
What are you looking at, Ray? The ducks are over here.
I don't know.
Listen, our father died last week.
- Did they tell you? - I don't know.
You don't know if they told you, or you don't know what dead is?
That means he's gone. He's at the cemetery.
- Wanna go see him at the cemetery? - I don't know.
- Does that mean maybe you wanna go? - I don't know.
I live in Los Angeles. I thought maybe you'd like to see a Dodgers game.
- Go... go see the Dodgers play. - Today's an off day.
- We don't have to go today. - No game scheduled.
I just thought maybe you'd like to go see Fernando Valenzuela pitch.
Fernando Valenzuela's not scheduled to pitch till Wednesday.
He's gonna pitch on Wednesday? I'm not doing anything on Wednesday.
- Wednesday. - Let's go to LA.
- Yeah. - Come on, Ray.
'Course, it's a long way to California,
and I'm definitely not supposed to be off the grounds for more than two hours.
- Have to be back in two hours. - Wait till you get there.
- People, crowds cheering. - Definitely not supposed to be.
- You'll love it. - Have to be back in two hours.
(tires drone)
(hums in monotone)
Here's the presidential suite.
- Dinner's at 6:30pm. - And to the left is Raymond's room.
- Look at this big beautiful room. - This is definitely not my room.
- It's just for tonight. - I have to go back to Wallbrook.
Little guy! Whoa! This is gonna be terrific. We're brothers.
Dr. Bruner wants us to spend time together. We're gonna have some fun.
'Course, we have tapioca pudding for dessert.
We can work tapioca pudding. I'm gonna call Lenny.
'Course, this is not my room, and the bed's in the wrong place.
- That's definitely not my bed. - You can move it.
- Where do you want it? - Should be near the window.
'Course, I don't have my books. 'Course, there are no bookshelves.
I'm definitely... I'm going to be bookless.
Here's a book. Big telephone book. Lot of words.
Lenny, pick up, will you?
I got $200,000 about to go in the shithouse
and he won't answer the phone.
- Six here means it's nine there. - No, three.
6:30pm is dinner...
It's three o'clock, and he doesn't answer the phone?
Orange soda.
Has to be in a can with a straw...
Bruner told you that you should do this? It doesn't make sense to me.
I know what's good for him.
Uh-oh! Uh-oh! V-E-R-N!
Oh, God. Go see what he's doing, will you?
- Ray? - V-E-R-N!
- What is it? - What's happening, homes?
- Uh-oh. - Everything is fine.
- Charlie, let's take him home. Come on. - No, he's OK.
Get him some dinner, he'll be OK. What'd you say, you wanted hamburger?
- Hamburger, Ray? Huh? - We have pepperoni pizza
Monday night.
Pizza? You get pizza in the institution?
'Course, Monday night's Italian night.
- (woman) Mitchell and Mitchell. - Get me Stu. It's Charlie Babbitt.
I'm sorry, he's not here.
- Where is he? I got a legal problem. - He's out of town until tomorrow.
All right, I'll call him tomorrow.
We're not allowed to watch TV during dinner.
- Definitely not. - We can watch TV here.
- We're allowed. - Yeah.
Wheel... of... Fortune! Look at this studio,
filled with glamorous merchandise,
fabulous and exciting bonus prizes.
A pair of cars for today's busy couple,
thousands of dollars in cash.
Over $150,000 just waiting to be won
as we present our big bonanza of cash
on... Wheel... of... Fortune!
Room service? 321. I'd like to order a large pizza. Pepperoni, right?
I don't want pepperoni.
That's right, a large pepperoni. How long's it gonna take?
Bring some beer for two, and an orange soda.
- You got tapioca pudding? - (man) No, sir.
Just bring the closest thing. All right. Right.
Here, Ray. Take this. Food is coming shortly.
- I'll be right back. - Yeah.
'Course, I'm going to be here for a long time, a very long time.
'Cause I'm gone for good... gone for good from my home.
(faint moaning)
(Susanna moans)
(Charlie grunts)
(imitates Susanna's moans)
(moans)
- (Charlie grunts) - Ohh! Ohh!
(Susanna) Oh! Si! Si!
(Raymond) Si.
(moaning continues)
- (Susanna) Ohh! - (Raymond groans)
- (Charlie) Uhh! - (Raymond) Uh-huh.
- What is that? - I think Raymond is in the room.
- What? Raymond, are you in here? - Charlie... Charlie Babbitt.
Well, get out! Get out!
- Go! - Stop it!
Uh-oh.
- Jesus... - Stop it. Go in there with him.
Charlie, he's your brother. He's afraid.
He doesn't understand this. Come on. Go in there!
What were you doing in my room? What were you doing in my room?
- I don't know. - You don't know?
'Course, there were noises.
Those noises are none of your business. You understand? Huh?
Put the phone book down. Stop acting like an idiot and go to sleep.
- Go to sleep! - It's nine minutes to 11.
- Lights out at 11. - Yeah? Well, new rules.
You don't listen to me! This is...
- What are you talking about? - I asked you to apologize.
- You insulted him again! - Am I supposed to tuck him in?
You're his brother. They tell you today for the first time you have a brother.
I don't see in your face one reaction.
I'm not saying joy, I'm saying something!
You don't know what I'm going through.
No, you don't tell me anything.
- You just give me lies! Lies, lies! - Lies? What lies?
This thing that Dr. Bruner asked you to bring him here, this is bullshit.
So why don't you tell me. Why is he here?
- Because I'm pissed at my father. - So you bring Raymond here. Why?
- 'Cause I got him, and they want him! - This makes no sense!
Raymond was left all the money, $3 million, every penny of it.
- So? - So I'll keep him till I get my half!
I deserve that!
What is this? Huh? Susanna?
- Take it easy. - I've had enough!
You've had enough? What does that mean?
- I'm leaving. - You're leaving?
You're leaving me now? I need you. I need you now!
- You need nobody. - What does that mean? What?
Just take it easy. What is my crime here? Huh?
You use people! You're using Raymond, you're using me!
- You use everybody! - Raymond! Raymond, am I using you?
- Am I using you? - Yeah.
Shut up! He is answering a question from a half-hour ago!
What good is $3 million to him?
It's gonna sit there for the rest of his life.
I need that money! You know I do.
You need it, so it's hardly like stealing!
Then what happens to Raymond?
He'll go back to Wallbrook, or a better place. I'll put him in a better place.
What's the difference? He'll be just the same!
- Only you'll have his money! - His money?
That man was my father, too. Where's my fucking half?
- I'm entitled to it! - You've kidnapped this man!
I did not take him. I did not take him. I took my half!
- You're crazy! - It runs in the family.
You're soaking wet and you're gonna leave in the middle of the night? Wait!
My father stuck it to me all my life. What do you want from me?
I want out. Out!
(muttering "Who's on First?")
(Raymond mutters "Who's on First?")
(muttering)
- Stop it. - Good morning!
- Coffee? - Yes. That'd be good.
Sally Dibbs. Dibbs, Sally. 461-0192.
- How did you know my phone number? - How'd you know that?
You said read the telephone book. Dibbs, Sally. 461-0192.
He remembers things, little things, sometimes.
Very clever, boys. I'll be right back.
- How'd you do that? How'd you do that? - I don't know.
- Did you memorize the whole book? - No.
- How far did you get? - "G". Gottsaken.
William Marshall Gottsaken.
- You memorized to "G"? - Yeah, "G".
- A, B, C, D, E, F, G? - "G". Half of "G."
- That's good, Ray. - Yeah.
- I like that. - Yeah.
- Are you hungry? - Yeah. Tuesday we have pancakes.
- That sounds good. - With maple syrup.
- You bet your butt. - Bet your butt.
- Uh-oh. Uh-oh... - They got pancakes.
- What is this, Ray? - 'Course, I don't have my toothpicks.
You don't need them. That was OK in the hotel with the pizza.
In here you eat with a fork.
- I don't have my toothpicks. - You don't need them.
- You're gonna eat with a fork. - I don't have my maple syrup either.
You don't see any pancakes, do you?
The problem is, maple syrup is not here.
Ray, when we order the pancakes, they're gonna bring the maple syrup.
Maple syrup is supposed to be on the table before the pancakes.
We haven't ordered yet.
When they bring it after, it'll definitely be too late.
How is that going to be too late? We haven't ordered the pancakes yet.
We'll be here the entire morning with no maple syrup and no toothpicks.
I'm definitely not gonna... not gonna have my pancakes without...
- Ow! - Don't make a scene.
- Ow! - Stop acting like a fucking retard.
Uh-oh.
What is this? What are you writing?
What is it? What the fuck is this?
"Serious injury list. Charlie Babbitt."
"Serious injury list"? Are you fuckin' kidding me?
Number 18 in 1988.
"Squeezed and pulled and hurt my neck in 1988."
Squeezed and pulled and hurt your neck in 1988?
- Dr. Bruner, it's Charlie Babbitt. - (Bruner) Where are you, son?
What matters is who I'm with.
You have to bring him back, Mr. Babbitt.
No problem whatsoever. That'll be $1 .5 million. I just want my half.
- Raymond, don't touch that. It's dirty. - I can't do that. You know I can't.
Just bring him back, and bring him back now. This is where he belongs.
I'm his brother. It's... it's not kidnapping here, is it?
He's always been a voluntary patient, but that's beside the point.
This is where he can get the best care. We're talking about his well-being.
Let's cut through the bullshit, OK?
I'm entitled to part of my father's estate.
If you don't want to cut a deal, I'll fly him to Los Angeles,
stick him in an institution out there, and we can have a custody battle.
Miss? He needs toothpicks. Can you help him? Thank you very much.
You want to battle me in the courts? Think about that, Dr. Bruner.
- Or we can cut a deal right now. - I don't think you have any idea...
Toothpicks. He needs some toothpicks. Can we just get him some toothpicks?
And I cannot make any money deals with you.
Then I'll see you in court.
I'll have the check. Sorry about the toothpicks.
Eighty-two, 82, 82.
Eighty-two what, Ray?
- How much is this? - Toothpicks.
It's a lot more than 82 toothpicks.
- 'Course, 246 total. - Keep the change.
- How many toothpicks were in there? - Um...
- Two-fifty. - Pretty close. Let's go, Ray.
Two hundred forty-six.
- There's four left in the box. - 'Course, I have to get my backpack.
(man on radio) 97-X, the future of rock and roll.
(Ray) 97-X. Bam!
The future of rock and roll.
97-X. Bam!
Ray, Ray, Ray. Enough already.
- Change the channel. - 97-X. Bam!
The future of rock and roll.
97-X. Bam!
Lenny, I don't care what you think. Did they say that?
You're gonna have to be more forceful. Lenny, shut up! I am in serious trouble.
I can't get to these cars. I can't get the money.
Do you understand that? My loan is past due!
(Lenny) I'll call the loan office and tell them we have a little problem.
- Charlie. Let me talk to Wyatt... - Lenny, just listen.
I'll be in LAX in three hours.
Remember, the Buick is in A-3, main terminal.
Make sure they pick it up. All right. See you in a few.
(woman over PA) Will Dr. Baker, Dr. Angus Baker,
please pick up a white courtesy phone.
Raymond, let's go. Come on.
Ray! Ray! Let's go. Come on.
- What were you watching? - I don't know.
- You don't know? - No.
(PA) Final call for flight 1559,
service to Salt Lake City and Los Angeles.
- Now departing at gate 15. - Uh-oh.
- Uh-oh. There's an airplane out there. - And everybody's boarding. Let's go.
- Airline travel's very dangerous. - Don't be silly.
You're gonna love this. Trust me. Come on.
Oh, no.
Ray, we're in an airport. People fly out of airports.
What did you think we were doing here?
In 1987, there were 30 airline accidents.
211 fatalities, 230 definitely passengers.
This plane is very safe.
I've got to get to LA, and I don't have time for this shit.
- I-I-I don't know. - You don't know?
- No. - Is it this airline?
- Yeah. - Is it this airline?
OK. Fine. We can, uh... There's an American plane.
American flight 625 crashed April 27th, 1976.
- We don't have to take American. - Yeah, pick another airline.
Continental.
Continental crashed November 15th, 1987.
Flight 1713. 28 casualties.
- This is very serious. - Very serious.
I have to get to Los Angeles. So you're gonna get on that plane, understand?
- You're gonna have to get on a plane. - Yeah, get on a plane.
- Now, there's a... there's a Delta. - Yeah.
It leaves at midnight. But how's Delta?
Delta crashed August 2nd, 1985. Lockheed L-1011.
Dallas-Fort Worth. Terrible wind shear...
All airlines have crashed at one time or another.
- That doesn't mean they are not safe. - Qantas.
Qantas never crashed.
- Qantas? - Never crashed.
- That's going to do me a lot of good. - Never crashed.
Qantas doesn't fly to LA out of Cincinnati.
You've got to get to Melbourne, Australia,
to get the plane that flies to Los Angeles!
Canberra's the capital, 16.2 million population, very lovely beaches.
You and I are gonna get on this fucking plane!
(screams)
We're not gonna take the plane. He's OK!
We're not gonna take the plane. Just...
Just relax. He was upset.
We're not gonna take the plane. We're not gonna fly, OK?
No flying.
- We're not gonna fly. - No flying.
- You tire me, Ray. - Yeah.
We're gonna drive to Los Angeles. We're gonna drive to LA. OK? Come on.
Ray, come on. Come on. Here.
- No flying. - Just grab the fucking bag.
No flying.
You're killing me, man. I just want you to know, you are killing me.
I gotta be in LA in three hours, it's gonna take me three days.
Come on.
- No flying. - No flying.
- 'Course, I got Jeopardy at 5:00. - Don't start with that, Ray.
Got Jeopardy at 5:00.
- Dispatch, this is 109. - Go ahead, 109.
See if you can get another unit up here for point control.
10-40.
Uh-oh.
- Ray? - Yeah, there's a...
Get in the car!
There's a lot of danger on this highway.
Just get in the car. Are you crazy? We'll be out of this in a second.
That's good. It's OK.
That's right. We'll be out of here in a few seconds. That's good, Ray.
- Definitely a fatal accident. - Uh-huh. Ray?
Hey! We don't need your help. Go back to your car.
- (honking) - Just a minute!
Ray! Ray! Ray!
Ray!
There's nothing to see here. Go back and get in your car.
- Yes, sir. - Go back and get in your car!
Just stay there by the side, OK, Raymond?
- Listen, Ray. Just stay there! - Yeah. Definitely a lot of traffic.
Hell of a lot of work for $3 million. I should just get the hell outta here.
- (honking) - Yeah, I hear you!
Stay in your cars, please!
- What's it gonna be, Ray? - This is a very dangerous highway.
How am I gonna get to LA?
'Course, this interstate's very dangerous.
- You want to get off the highway? - Yeah.
Well, you gotta get in the car!
In 1986, 46,400 male drivers were definitely involved in fatal accidents.
I got an idea. I got a great idea.
Stay in front of the car till we get off the exit.
You'll get in, and we'll take a not-so-dangerous road.
- Is that an idea? - Yeah.
Give me five, Ray! That's a great idea! Give me five! Yeah.
This guy's a fucking fruitcake.
I'm asking you who's on first. That's the man's name. Whose name? Yes.
Well, go ahead and tell me. Who. The guy on first. Who.
The first baseman. Who is on first.
Whose wife? Yes. After all, the man earns it.
Who does? Absolutely. What's the guy's name on first base?
No. What is on second base. I'm not asking who's on second.
Who's on first. That's what I'm trying to find out.
- Get the hell in the car! - Yeah, get in the car.
Get in the car. 'Course, I have to be in bed by 11.
Lights out at 11. Have to watch TV.
'Course, now it's almost 19 minutes to 11. I have to be in bed at 11.
Don't start. We're not on the interstate.
I'm on some shit secondary road, I gotta make up some time.
I gotta get to LA. I should have been there this afternoon.
My business needs me.
Definitely watch TV, but you have to be in bed at 11.
- Forget it. - Uh-oh. Nineteen minutes to 11.
This is a good one. "We don't go out when it rains."
I hope you appreciate this,
because my business is going down the fucking toilet.
I should be in LA.
Instead, I'm in the Honeymoon Haven Motel, Bumblefuck, Missouri,
because you won't go out when it rains.
It's mystifying. Fuckin' mystifying.
What is this? Good news, bad news?
We passed DOT but failed EPA.
It all ends up the same. I can't get my money.
I'm stuck in Cincinnati since the funeral. So many left over details.
My family is, needless to say, quite overwhelmed.
Well, thank you. I appreciate it. It is a shock, to say the least.
Thank you. Can I get an extension on that loan?
Just a couple of days would make a world of difference.
"We don't go out when it's raining."
(rock music soundtrack on TV)
What? Speak up, Lenny. I bought time. I didn't buy that kind of time.
- You're gonna have to... How much? - It's 12:30.
- What? - Lunch is 12:30.
- What do you want for lunch? - Wednesday's fish sticks.
- Green lime Jell-O for dessert. - You want another apple juice?
Orange soda. Oh! It's 12:31.
I gotta go. He's starting to rock and moan.
- Definitely 12:31. - It's OK.
- You'd better give me that gun. - Where is he?
- Where is he? - How did you figure to frame him?
Framed? Who's been framed?
Four fish sticks. There's supposed to be eight. There's only four.
Eight? There's eight.
Take a shower, Ray? Hm?
- Ray. You take a shower, right? - Yeah.
It's the same thing as the rain. You get a little wet. What do you say? Huh?
'Course, the shower's in the bathroom.
That's the end of that conversation.
- Go again. - British Poetry for 200, please.
Shakespeare wrote over 150 poems in this 14-line form.
"What is a sonnet?"
What is a sonnet? Let's try Double Letters for 200, please.
The last word in the pledge of allegiance.
- Mark. - What is "stands"?
Stu, legally, Bruner never established
a conservatorship of Raymond?
He didn't figure anyone would contest his authority.
If that's the case, I definitely will get custody and the $3 million.
You set up a date... you set up a date for the custody hearing.
Stu, I want a firm date, and I want it early.
It wasn't an original record, because the original song had two verses...
Lenny, she hasn't come in? She hasn't called?
If you see her or hear from her, tell her to call me.
(banging on TV)
The Air Alpha Force. From Nike.
Would you look at that. 1957 Studebaker Golden Hawk.
Zero to 60 in under eight seconds, 275 supercharged horsepower.
- Beautiful. - I'm an excellent driver.
- You know how to drive? - Yeah.
- When did you drive? - I drove the Buick
when my dad came to Wallbrook.
- Was Dad in the car, Ray? - Yeah.
- He let you drive the Buick? - Yeah, slow, on the driveway.
We'll have to let you drive sometime.
- (Raymond sounds horn) - Raymond!
Never touch the steering wheel when I'm driving! You hear me?
Yeah. 'Course, I don't have my underwear.
- What? - I'm definitely
not wearing my underwear.
- I gave you a fresh pair of mine. - Not my underwear.
I told you to put them on. Where are they?
They're in the pocket of my jacket.
- Where? - Here. These... these are too tight.
- I don't want them back. - These are not boxer shorts.
- What's the difference? - These are Hanes 32.
My boxer shorts have my name in. It says "Raymond."
We'll pick you up a pair of boxer shorts.
I get mine in Kmart, Cincinnati.
We're not going back to Cincinnati.
- Four hundred Oak Street. - You don't have to go to Cincinnati.
- That's Oak and Burnett. Kmart. - What did I say, Ray?
You hear me. I know you hear me! You don't fool me with this shit.
- Yours are too tight. - Ray, did you fuckin' hear what I said?
- Shut up! - Yeah.
Cincinnati's a long way off. We're getting further away from Kmart.
You don't have to go to Cincinnati to get underwear.
- Kmart. 400 Oak Street. - We are not going to Cincinnati.
- I get my boxer shorts at Kmart. - Did you hear me?
I don't wanna be shortless.
(Charlie yells)
I'm going out of my mind! Out of my mind!
What difference does it make where you buy underwear?
What difference does it make? Underwear is underwear!
It is underwear wherever you buy it! In Cincinnati or wherever!
- Kmart. - You know what I think, Ray?
I think this autism is a bunch of shit!
'Cause you can't tell me you're not in there somewhere!
(Raymond) Boxer shorts. Boxer shorts at Kmart.
These are Hanes 32. Mine are boxer shorts.
You're driving me crazy. We'll have to make a stop, find a psychiatrist.
- 'Cause you are driving me crazy. - Oak and Burnett.
We have to buy them at Kmart. Oak and Burnett.
Uh-oh! 'Course, your shorts are on the highway.
Let's go back to Cincinnati and Kmart.
(train horn)
(bell ringing)
Good luck trying to find a shrink in this town.
Raymond?
(honking)
Hey, you! Dipshit! Move it!
You ain't gonna move, I'll move you. Hey, buddy! Hey, you!
- You're gonna get run over. - Whoa! Whoa! Hey!
You're gonna get hurt. Hey, you hear me? Hey! Hey!
- Move it! - Hey! It's all right! It's all right!
I'm sorry. He's from out of town. Raymond, come on.
- It's all right. - Got to get to Kmart.
Raymond, Raymond, Raymond. Come on.
Kmart. 400 Oak Street.
- It said "Don't Walk." - Yes, it's broken.
(honking)
I have to get to Kmart. 400 Oak and Burnett. Oak and Burnett.
He said, "Young man, go West. Go West."
This is the way our country developed, from the East Coast to the West Coast.
During that period of time...
(camera clicks)
...there was initiated
what is known as the Pony Express.
I'm sure all of you have read something about it.
I may not have the days exactly right, or the years,
but I'm more or less familiar with the history of the United States,
- and I'd love to tell you the story... - He's artistic?
- No. He's autistic. - I'm not familiar with that.
What is the exact nature of the problem?
Well, he lives in a world of his own.
I'm sorry, but what's wrong with him?
- It was a problem getting mail... - Raymond, do "What's on First?"
Who's on first. What's on second.
They set up a national program,
where a Pony Express would ride
for approximately 20 miles...
(Charlie) What am I supposed to do? There's gotta be something I can do.
I'm not a psychiatrist,
but I do know his brain doesn't work like other people.
If he's getting on your nerves, just take a break.
Spend some time away from him.
- Sure. I'll just send him back. - Sorry?
Nothing. It's just an... inside joke.
You're telling me I just have to deal with this stuff?
- I just got to deal with it. - Yeah, that's about it.
(Charlie sighs)
Out of curiosity, does he have any special abilities?
He's got a pretty good memory. He counts toothpicks.
- Huh? - They spilled a box of toothpicks,
and he took one look at 'em and counted them in seconds.
- Ray! Raymond! - Yeah.
- Are you good with numbers? - Yeah.
I want to try something here.
- Kmart, 400 Oak Street. - I told you, after this. After this.
- Ray, can we try something? - Yeah.
Do you know how much 312... times... 123 is?
38,376.
- He's right. - What?
He's right.
Ray, how much is 4,343
times 1,234?
5,359,262.
- He's a genius. - That's right.
He's a genius.
Ray, do you know how much the square root of 2,130 is?
46.15192304.
- (Raymond) 2304. - (Charlie) That's amazing.
That is amazing. He should work for NASA or something.
If you had a dollar, and you spent 50 cents,
how much money would you have left?
About 70.
- Seventy cents? - So much for the NASA idea.
- Kmart. Should go to Kmart. - After this, Ray.
- Ray. - 400 Oak Street.
Ray, do you know how much a candy bar costs?
- About $100. - $100, huh?
- Yeah. - How about a new compact car?
About $100.
In his case, he's pretty well-off. He's very high-functioning.
Most autistics, they can't speak and they can't communicate.
- Ray! - Yeah.
- Do you know what "autistic" is? - Yeah.
- You know that word? - Yeah.
Are you autistic?
I don't think so.
No, definitely not.
(Charlie) Lenny, shut up. Let me see if I understand this.
- (Raymond) Very small here. - It's $10,000 additional for each car?
- 'Course, it's very crowded. - Ray, please. One little second.
Huh? What?
They want to take out the manifold to put in a fuel injection system? Now?
That is nonsense!
What are you doing? Just leave this on!
It's gonna cost $40,000 just to meet EPA now! What?
No, no, no. You give me the number, and I'm gonna call the conversion shop.
That's my pen and my book.
Taking your book is not a serious injury.
- Serious injury goes in the red book. - Forgive me. I've lost my decoder ring.
- 4-5-4-5. - You're already number 18.
- In 1988. - 'Course, that's my book.
That's my pen.
Uh-oh. Twelve minutes to Wapner. It's definitely very small in here.
Small and safe. You don't wanna miss the party.
- "What you are witnessing is real." - There's a party in your honor, Ray.
When we get to LA, a little custody hearing. Know why there's a party?
- 'Cause you're the $3 million man. - "What you are witnessing is real."
- Ken Aldorf. Charlie Babbitt. - Uh-oh. Fart.
Charlie Babbitt. I'll hold.
Did you fart, Ray?
- Did you fucking fart? - Fart.
Oh, man!
- How can you stand that? - I don't mind it.
- Yeah, Ken? It's Charlie Babbitt. - Ten minutes to Wapner.
We're definitely locked in this box with no TV. The People's Court.
- How could this happen? - People's Court starts on the...
They start on the button. Definitely on the button.
I got a problem. I'll have to call you back.
We're definitely not gonna make it. We're not gonna make it.
- We definitely have to go now. - Yes, we're going. Just take it easy.
- Where am I gonna find a television? - Three minutes to Wapner.
We've got eight minutes to Wapner.
(Charlie) Come on. You want to get in there and see the show? Huh?
Want to get in there and see the show? Then listen up.
Not another farmhouse in sight. This is it, man.
You act weird, we don't get in. Are you listening to me?
I want you to look normal. As normal as possible.
- Just... Put your hands down. - Four minutes to Wapner.
Just shut up. Shut up and stand there.
Raymond? Don't rock and moan. Put your hands down.
Good afternoon, ma'am. I'm from the AC Nielsen Company.
- You're familiar with our work? - You mean the TV ratings?
That's exactly it. You're a preliminary candidate to be the next Nielsen Family.
- My husband's not home... - You'll share the responsibility
for shaping television programming viewed by our entire nation,
in return for which you'll receive a check in the amount of $286 each month.
- Who's he? - That'd be my partner, Mr. Bainbridge,
- who does... - Dah-dah dah-dah dah-dah...
- (TV) Stay tuned for People's Court. - That's it! You blew it.
- It's finished! - One minute to Wapner!
One minute to Wapner, one minute to Wapner. I had you in there, Ray!
- Dad-dah dah-dah... - You had it all!
They are in there making legal history!
(moans)
- Legal history! - Oh, boy!
- Oh, boy! - What is going on out here?
I'm sorry, ma'am. I lied. I'm very sorry about that.
That man is my brother. If he doesn't watch People's Court, he'll throw a fit.
You can help me, or you can stand and watch it happen.
We like to watch cartoons. Do you think he'd settle for that?
...then she sees an identical twin.
True, he didn't have his shirt on. The other one did.
But they sure look alike to me.
- (woman) Honey, I've got Monkey Man. - (child crying) I want my daddy!
Daddy's not here right now, darling.
Come here. Here, sweetheart.
Listen, Ken, work with me on this one. I'll take care of it.
- (sings) You know that song? - ...so my judgment
is for the defendant.
We'll be back right after these messages.
connected from your neck bone
♪ Well, your head bone's
from your shoulder bone
♪ Your neck bone's connected
connected from your back bone
♪ Your shoulder bone's
from your hip bone
♪ Your back bone's connected
connected from your thigh bone
♪ Your hip bone's
from your knee bone
♪ Your thigh bone's connected
connected from your leg bone
♪ Your knee bone's
from your ankle bone
♪ Your leg bone's connected
connected from your heel bone
♪ Your ankle bone's
- My credit card's been rejected? - Yes, sir.
- How much is this gonna cost? - $20, sir.
♪ Hear the word of the Lord
dem dry bones
♪ Dem bones, dem bones,
♪ Now hear the word of the Lord
dem dry bones
♪ Dem bones, dem bones,
♪ Now hear the word of the Lord ♪
'Course, I'm never going back. It's definitely a long journey.
- Just a couple of more days. - Yeah. Then who's playing first?
The fella playing first base for St. Louis?
You gonna start with this again?
- You gotta do this every time? - That's the man's name. Whose name?
What are you asking me for?
I'm not asking you, I'm telling you. Who's on first.
No. You know, Ray, this is not... It's not a riddle.
You know the fella's name? Then who's playing first?
You're never gonna figure out who's on first base, 'cause Who is on first base.
That's the joke. It's comedy.
Sometimes his wife comes down and collects it. Whose wife?
Every dollar of it.
- Have you got a first baseman? - It's an Abbott & Costello routine.
When you do it, you're not funny. You're the comedy team of Abbott & Abbott!
Sometimes his wife comes down and collects it. Whose wife? Yeah.
Ray. Ray, Ray, Ray. You are never gonna solve it. You know why?
'Cause it's not a riddle, man.
And if you understood that, if you understood that it's funny,
you might get better.
All I'm trying to find out is what's the guy's name on first base?
What's the guy's name on first base? No, What's the guy's name on second base.
Have you got a first baseman on first? Yeah. Then who's playing first? Yeah.
Who's playing... You know the fella's name? Yeah.
Then who's playing first? Yeah. The fella playing first base for St. Louis.
Who? The guy on first. Who, the first base? Who is on first.
What are you asking me for? Have you got a first baseman on first?
All right, come on. We'll put the bed by the window the way you like it.
We've got your apple juice,
we'll take the pens and paper out and put it on the table.
- What's the matter? I forget something? - Cheese balls.
- Definitely cheese balls. - I forgot cheese balls.
I have to have 12 cheese balls. Have to get my tartar control toothpaste.
- I got that a couple of days ago. - Where's my toothpaste?
Raymond.
Remember when that doctor asked you the number questions?
- Yeah. - How did you do that?
- (mumbles) I see it. - Huh?
- I see it. - What's that?
- Would you stop that for a second? - I see it.
Put that down. I'm trying to talk to you.
When I say stop, why don't you stop? Why do you have to act like an idiot?
- Huh? - Yeah.
- You think that's funny? - Yeah. Funny Rain Man. Funny teeth.
- What did you say? - Funny teeth.
Rinse.
Why did you say... why did you say "Funny teeth"?
You said, "Funny teeth, funny Rain Man."
- "Rain Man"? I said "Rain Man"? - Yeah, "funny Rain Man."
Was I trying to say "Raymond" and it came out "Rain Man"?
"Funny Rain Man."
You? You're the Rain Man?
- Who took this picture? - D-A-D.
And you lived with us?
Yeah. 10961 Beechcrest Street, Cincinnati, Ohio.
When, uh... when did you leave?
- January 21st, 1965. - You... you remember that?
It was Thursday. Very snowy out. 7.2 inches of snow that day.
- That's just after Mom died. - Yeah. Mom died January 5th, 1965.
And you remember that day that you left?
Short and sudden illness.
- You remember that day? - Yeah.
Was I there? Where was I?
You were in the window.
You waved to me. "Bye-bye, Rain Man. Bye-bye."
So you... you... you were the one that sang to me?
Yeah.
What... what did you sing? What was that song...?
What did you sing?
♪ She was just 17
♪ And you know what I mean
♪ And the way she looked
♪ Was way beyond compare
(both)
♪ So how could I dance with another
♪ Ooh
♪ When I saw her standing there?
(Raymond) ♪ Da-da-da-da da-da-da-da
- Did I like it when you sang to me? - Yeah.
Did we sing any other songs... like the Beatles?
Yeah.
Ohhh!
Scary! Scary bad! Scary bad!
Scary bad!
(screams)
- Scary bad! - What... what's scary bad?
Hot water! Hot water burn baby!
- Water! - "Hot water burn baby"?
- What baby? Me? - Yeah.
- Yeah. - Easy, easy.
- Hot water... hot water burn baby. - I'm not burned.
I'm not burned. Look at me.
- Water burn baby! Hot water burn baby! - I'm not burned!
- Tub burn baby. - I'm not burned.
Yeah.
I'm not burned. It's OK.
- Yeah? - Yeah.
It's OK.
Time for Wallbrook now.
That's why they put you away. They thought you would hurt me.
(whispers)
What? What?
(whispers) What, Ray?
What?
- Come on. It's 11:00, Ray. Lights out. - Yeah.
Never hurt Charlie Babbitt. Never, never hurt Charlie Babbitt.
Here you go. Right where you like it, at the end of the bed.
Come on, Ray.
(Charlie) Hi, it's me. You didn't hang up. Does that mean we're engaged?
Listen, I, uh...
I just want to hear it's not over. I mean, uh... I'm scared it's over.
(Susanna) Don't ask me tonight. I don't know what to say.
- Let it sit. - That's something I'm not real good at.
There's a lot of things you're not good at.
- I'll call you when I get back, OK? - Uh-huh.
- I'll see you. - Ciao.
What are you looking at that for?
I spend $200 on a TV and you're watching a dryer.
I don't know.
At the shrink hearing, we'll have to prove
that you prefer to watch this little TV as opposed to the clothes dryer.
- Are you listening to me? - Yeah.
Turn this off when you're not watching it.
You run down the batteries, where are you gonna be when Wapner's on?
Yeah, the red one always falls the same.
Why aren't you listening to me?
You want to go back to Wallbrook, is that it? Huh?
I gotta make a phone call.
Yeah, Lenny, it's me...
I've been sitting here for three hours!
- I had some things to do. - Charlie, we are in serious trouble!
- Serious trouble! - Just take it easy.
I'm in Tucumcari...
They repossessed the cars to pay off the loan.
The cars are gone, Charlie. Gone!
Bateman wants his down payment back. They all do. That's 80 thou, Charlie!
Eighty thousand... I don't have it.
You gotta pay these people back, or it's all over. We're out of business.
- What am I gonna I tell them? - I don't know.
(hangs up telephone)
Son of a bitch!
(Charlie) Son of a bitch!
♪ Beyond the blue horizon
♪ Lies the rising sun
♪ Waits a beautiful day
This'd be a lot easier if you'd let me put the top up.
Wouldn't have to fry. Put this lotion on so you don't burn.
Ray, don't start with that. You want me to put the top up?
- Definitely like the top down. - I know. Now, I don't want you to burn.
Definitely like it when the top's... Ow. Ooh...
It's all right. Just take it easy. It's almost over.
- Uh-huh. Now, how's that feel? - Very slippery.
("People's Court" on TV)
(man on TV) Maldonado swings, and hits a hot shot into center field.
One runner's in. Here's Brenly going to third. The throw by Davis.
Not in time! Brenly in safely
at third base on Maldonado's single.
(man 2) Looks like he held that ball out a little too long, Ed.
(Ed) We'll take a look at it once again.
Treadwell, of course, playing way over towards the right side.
- (man 2) Shading it to pull. - (Ed) OK, here's Davis.
Yeah, he seems to hold it there just a bit, Tom.
(Tom) Sort of double-pumped it. Watch it here on the replay again.
(Ed) He loses all chance of a play on Brenly,
even though Brenly doesn't exactly pick 'em up and lay 'em down.
(Tom) And the throw into third base, finally,
is a little bit high. Just a tad.
(clattering)
by Bob Luman plays on jukebox)
(♪ "Lonely Women Make Good Lovers"
(clattering continues)
- Will you give me a break with this? - I can't.
Ray, stop it.
♪ Cos lonely women make good lovers...
J7.
- K7? What's that? - J7.
What's J7?
What's J7? The song? The song's J7?
Yeah.
Look out there.
No, Raymond, out here.
18 Wheels and a Dozen Roses. What's the number?
E5.
Cheating Heart, Hank Williams.
Your Cheating Heart. 'Course, that's Hank Williams Junior. D1.
D1.
Blue Moon in Kentucky, Bill Monroe.
And the Bluegrass Boys. T5.
How many toothpicks came out of that box?
Two hundred forty-six.
- Yeah. - Two hundred forty-six.
- Are you paying attention? - Yeah.
- You watching that? - Yeah.
You seeing that, Ray? You catching that?
Yeah. Falling on the ground.
OK. Now, what... what do I have left?
Two jacks, one eight, one king, one six,
two aces, one ten, one nine, one five.
One five. You are beautiful, man!
- (Raymond) I'm an excellent driver. - (Charlie) You can't drive now.
Listen, this is very important.
When there's lots of tens left, it's good for us.
- Say it. "Tens are good." - "Tens are good."
- And you're gonna bet one... - One if it's bad,
- two if it's good. - That's right.
- Now, casinos have house rules. - Yeah.
The first one is, they don't like to lose.
So you never, never show that you are counting cards.
That is the cardinal sin, Ray. Are you listening? That's very important.
- Yeah. Counting... counting is bad. - Yes, counting is bad.
- I like to drive slow on the driveway. - You get this right, Ray,
you can drive wherever you want, as slow as you like.
I'm an excellent driver.
(PA) Miss Sue Morgan, please pick up the hotel courtesy phone.
Raymond.
(bell rings)
- Rain Man, let's play some cards. - Yeah.
- You want a hit? - No, you don't. You've got 18.
- I want a hit. - Sir, you have 18.
- He doesn't want a hit. - I want a hit.
- Hitting 18. - Hit me, hit me, hit me!
Don't...
You took my queen. I've got a ten. I needed that queen. I can't take it!
- Sir, please don't touch the cards. - I need my own queen.
There's lots of them.
- There's lots of them? - Lots and lots.
Hold on here for a second.
I'm gonna double down.
(Raymond) Queen, queen, queen.
Yes, sir, you gotta love this town.
- I'm going for it, Nick. - It looks like it.
It certainly looks like it.
- Wanna bet one chip or two chips? - Bet two.
Bet two?
- Hey, what's your secret, guys? - We cheat.
(laughter)
This is Sam. Tape table 47.
- About 85,000. - 85,000?
- Did you call the eye in the sky? - Sam did.
- OK, I'll take over. - All right.
All right!
You're doing well. I'm happy for you, sir.
- What do you see? - He's not catching the hole card.
- He's not past posting us. - I don't see him using a computer.
He's not, but something's not right. No one can count into a six-deck shoe.
Hold it. Hold it here. Uh...
Watch my chips. I'll be back in a second.
Go ahead, sir.
Ray, we're in the middle of a hand. You don't leave in the middle of a hand.
Come on! We are hot. The Babbitt brothers, kicking ass in Vegas!
- Wheel of Fortune. - Cleopatra and Caesar are waiting!
- "Look at this glamorous merchandise." - One for bad, two for good.
- Twenty. - Twenty?
- You mean it's gonna hit on 20? - Yeah, 20. Definitely 20.
$3,000 on 20.
- Definitely 20. - Definitely 20?
Yeah.
Uh-oh.
It's not your game, Ray. I just lost $3,000.
- Yeah. - That's $3,000 I lost. Come on, Ray.
A little black...
No? Easy. Don't start banging yourself.
- Maybe we'll play a little bit later. - Yeah.
- Let me cash in. - Yeah. Cash in.
You make me sad, Ray.
Twenty.
We won $86,000 and some change, right, Ray?
- $86,500. - $80,000 refund on the car payments,
and I owe... What'd I say I owe to get the Rolex back?
- $3,500. Six months to pay. - $3,500.
We don't have to pay for the room, that's comped. I'm free and clear.
I'm gonna take a celebration piss.
Don't go anywhere. Until I get back, the sign says "Don't Walk."
- "Don't Walk." - "Don't Walk."
Hey.
You looking for a date? Are you?
- I don't know. - What's your name?
- Raymond. - My name is Iris.
- Raymond, you like me? - I don't know.
You don't know? I think if you gave me a chance, you would.
Why don't we try to get to know each other?
- Yeah, get to know each other. - He doesn't have any money, honey.
That's all right, sugar, 'cause we are just talking.
- Yeah, we're just talking. - Let's go upstairs. What are you doing?
Getting to know each other. Just talking.
- What room? I'll bring him up. - That's all right.
Is that what you wanna do? Get to know each other?
Yeah. Get to know each other. Just talking.
This will be interesting. I'll be over here just in case.
- He doesn't seem to like me. Who is he? - He's my brother.
- He seems young to be your brother. - He was born August 12th, 19... 1962.
It was a Sunday.
What exactly do you guys do here?
- We're counting cards. - You're counting cards?
- We're counting cards. - Uh-huh.
- We're counting cards. - What else do you do?
- We're counting cards. - I know. What else do you do?
Are you taking any prescription medication?
Whoa. Look, I'm outta here.
- 'Course, what time is the date? - Later.
- What time? - It's 10:00!
I have to be in bed at 11. Lights out at 11.
10:00, daylight saving time. 10:00, daylight saving time.
10:00? You like her, Ray? You think she's pretty?
- Yeah. She's very sparkly. - Definitely very sparkly.
Very sparkly.
He did a great job on that suit. You don't realize how good you look.
- Do you like it? - It's not Kmart.
How could you not like that suit? You look fantastic. How can you not like it?
- It's not a Kmart suit. - I'll let you in on a secret.
- Kmart sucks, OK? - Yeah.
There you go, Ray. It's the high-rollers' suite.
This is for you. You ever seen a room like this before?
- Yeah. - What's up there?
What's up there? Ray, you're not even looking.
- Yeah. Bed. - That's a bed. That's your bed.
I had 'em put it up there. Right by the window, the way you like it.
- Go on up. - Yeah.
- Just the way you like it, isn't it? - Yeah.
Look at you with all those lights. Mr. Vegas. You are Mr. Las Vegas now!
- What do you think? - There's a lot of lights.
- It's very sparkly. Very twinkly. - We made a lot of money today, Ray.
We made a lot of money!
Forgetting the $3,000 we tossed away at that wheel of fortune.
- Yeah, Wheel... Wheel of Fortune. - I'm sorry about that.
I got a little carried away. I got a little hot, OK, Ray?
Yeah.
I'm saying I'm sorry, and I just want you to know that I am sorry.
I'm apologizing. I got a little carried away.
The money... I got a little... I got a little greedy.
- You wanna say something? - I have to be at the bar at 10:00.
'Cause I got to thank you, man. You, uh...
You did it. You did it. I was just there.
You saved my ass. I'm just... just along for the ride.
Have to be at the bar at 10:00. Have to go to a date with Iris.
Iris, that's her name, yeah. Big date. Gonna go dancing.
Yeah, dancing. Have to go to a date with Iris at the bar dancing.
- You know how to dance? - I don't know.
- You ought to learn some time. - Yeah.
Have to learn to dance for the date.
- Have to learn to dance for the date. - I was just kidding.
- You're not gonna have to dance. - I have to learn to dance.
- Definitely. Now. - You don't have to dance now.
I'll teach you how to dance sometime.
- Definitely have to. - No. You won't have to dance.
- Definitely have to learn. - I'm sorry I even brought this up.
- All right, Ray. My mistake. - 10:00.
You got the only famous dancing hooker in Vegas.
Stand over there.
(♪ "At Last" by Etta James)
- Come over here. - Yeah.
- You hear the music? - Yeah.
Just watch my feet. Raymond, watch my feet.
Just do what I'm doing.
OK? You feel the rhythm of the music? We're just moving our feet like that.
OK. Now, you're the guy, so you're gonna have to lead.
And I'm the date, so you want to, uh...
You wanna put your left hand up like this.
Don't stop moving.
- You paying attention? - Yeah.
Put your left hand up like this.
That's good. Don't stop moving. Just keep moving. That's good.
Now, you wanna take this other hand, put it around behind my back.
- You wanna learn how to dance? - Yeah.
Cos you gotta touch someone when you dance. I'm not gonna hurt you.
Just put it right there. I take my hand, I put it up here.
Watch my feet, Ray. Watch my feet. The rhythm, the rhythm.
All right?
Now, when you dance, you can't watch my feet, so you'll have to look up.
When I tell you to, I want you to just look up, real slow.
Just keep moving.
- OK, you ready? - Yeah.
- All right, start looking up. - Yeah.
A little more. Keep moving. Just a little more.
A little more, Ray. All the way up.
- There you go, Ray. - Yeah.
- You're dancing. This is it. - Yeah, dancing.
You wanna close your hand. Just...
Pull like that, you're gonna turn me like this, OK?
- Turning. - That's good.
- This is dancing, Ray. - This is dancing.
I don't know about you, but I'm starting to feel a little silly.
That's it. All right! All right!
Beautiful! You are a good dancer! Wanna give me a hug?
- Yeah. - Yeah?
(screams)
I just wanted to give you a hug, Ray. I...
I just felt like giving you a hug.
What are you doing here?
- I'm unemployed. - What do you mean?
- You don't know about the business? - Yeah, I know. Come on in. It's OK.
I'm glad to see you.
Ray, look who's here.
It's not right what you're doing to Raymond.
- He's fine. - I know he's fine.
He's in Las Vegas in a suit, in a big room.
- It makes me sad. - Six minutes to my date.
- Six minutes to Iris. - He has a date?
Raymond, it'd be nice if you didn't carry that TV everywhere we go.
What have you gotta bring a Watchman for on a date?
- The man's dancing. - But what does your date look like?
She's very sparkly. She looks like a holiday.
- I don't think I've heard that one. - Mr. Babbitt?
- Mr. Kelso would like to see you. - I don't know Mr. Kelso.
He's director of security. Would you come with me, please?
- Sure. Susanna, stay with Raymond. - Right this way.
♪ Oh, come on, sugar
♪ I hope this takes all night
- 10:01. She's not here. - She'll come. She will.
(man) Congratulations. Counting into a six-deck shoe is quite a feat.
I don't understand what you're talking about.
We make videotapes, and we analyze the tapes
and even share some of the information with other casinos.
These tapes suggest you should take your winnings and leave the state.
Mr. Kelso, someone has a good day and you accuse them of illegal activities?
Is this how you treat all your guests?
All you have to do is close your mouth and go home.
And those are the best odds you're gonna see for a while. I'd take 'em.
- Did you want to dance on your date? - Yeah.
There'll be other chances. Many pretty girls would love to dance with you.
- It's gonna be OK. - Yeah.
(Fred Astaire on TV)
♪ The way you haunt my dreams
take that away from me
♪ No, no, they can't
♪ We may never, never meet again
Uh-oh.
- I like this music, Ray. - Elevator's stopped.
It's OK. You think you could show me how you were going to dance with Iris?
- Yeah. - Yes?
- Would you like to dance with me? - Elevator's on hold.
- It's OK. Give me this. - Yeah.
♪ The way you hold your knife
- Show me. Show me how. - Yeah. Charlie Babbitt taught me.
- Charlie Babbitt? - Yeah.
Dancing in the elevator.
It's nice.
You're very good.
♪ They can't take that
♪ Away from me
- Iris missed a beautiful dance. - Yeah.
- And a kiss. - Yeah, and a kiss.
- Have you ever kissed a girl? - I don't know.
You don't know?
Open your mouth. Open.
- Yeah. - Like this.
Like you are tasting something very good,
and very soft.
Yeah.
Like this. Close your eyes.
- It's OK, Ray. - Yeah.
- How was that? - Wet.
- Then we did it right. - Elevator's definitely stuck.
No, it's not stuck.
Fred Astaire and Ginger Rogers.
- Like us. - Yeah, like us.
(Charlie) What'd I tell you? I promised you you could drive. This is it.
- I drive slow on the driveway. - This is OK? He can drive?
- 'Course, I'm an excellent driver. - He's very good in a driveway.
Ray, why don't you get in the front seat?
So I'll wait to hear from you after Raymond's meeting?
- Don't worry. It's going to be fine. - I'm nervous.
- I know. - Listen, I'm happy you came to Vegas.
I know.
Ciao.
Ray, thank you for the date in the elevator. It was really nice.
- Yeah. - Ciao.
- Yeah. - Thank you for the what?
- Nothing. Something between us. - Between us?
"Us," Ray?
Here we go, Ray. This is your bedroom up here.
(Raymond) 'Course, there's no bed there.
(Charlie) No, this is a magic bed. You just watch and see.
We got the table over here. We got the television.
I went to the video store. I got a little surprise for you.
Picked up a video.
- (mumbles "Who's on First?") - Don't start with that, Ray.
It's not just another place, Ray. This is my place.
Who's on first? That's the man's name. That's whose name? The first baseman.
Who is on first. You got a first baseman?
Certainly. Then who's playing first?
When you pay off the first baseman, who gets the money?
(TV) Why not? The man's entitled to it.
Who is?
- So who gets it? - Why should he?
- Sometimes his wife collects it. - Whose wife?
- Yes! - Oooooh.
- After all, he earns it. - Who does?
Absolutely.
All I'm trying to find out is what's the guy's name on first base?
What is on second base.
- Don't you think this is funny? - Yes, this is funny.
- Where'd you see this first? - Dad gave me a book of baseball trivia.
- Guess it didn't read as funny. - Definitely not.
Hello, this is Dr. Bruner. I'd like you to call me.
- Yeah, what is it? - I thought I got the machine.
- No. - I just got into town.
As you know, the psychological interview is tomorrow.
- Yes, sir, I know that. - We should get together and talk.
I really think it might be in your best interests to meet me.
When?
I'm at the Bonaventure. How about tonight at 8:30?
spring and fall
(stereo) ♪ Winter's passed,
♪ You never wrote me
♪ You never called
you've been gone too long
♪ Nathan Jones,
Tomorrow you'll meet Dr. Marston, who's in charge of the psychiatric evaluation.
- I gave him boxes of files on Raymond. - Well, good luck.
Look, this isn't a close call. It's a formality.
Your brother's a very disabled individual.
So Marston's gonna rule against me?
I'm telling you it's always been a lost cause.
Then why did you call me?
Your father put me in charge of all the money, all right?
And it doesn't matter whether or not you win custody.
I won't have to pay you a dime. It's at my discretion, not the court's.
- What, so you can't lose? - I can lose. I can lose Raymond.
And I care about his life and the treatment he receives.
I made a commitment to your father, and I'm not willing to gamble with that.
- What is this? - It's a very big check.
$250,000.
And no strings attached. You just walk away, Charlie.
You know, this isn't about you and me. It's not about winning or losing.
When I asked you why didn't anyone ever tell me I had a brother,
you didn't have an answer.
I don't know...
It's funny, I just realized I'm not pissed off
that my father cut me out of his will.
You were his friend. You probably knew he tried to contact me.
I never called him back. I was a prick.
If my son didn't return my calls, I'd have written him out. Fuck him.
But it's not about the money anymore. It's...
I just don't understand. Why didn't he tell me I had a brother?
Why didn't you tell me? Why didn't anyone ever tell me I had a brother?
Because it would've been nice to know him
for more than just the past six days.
(smoke alarm)
Ray, Ray, Ray!
- (alarm stops) - Ray! Ray!
Ray! Come on.
It's stopped! It's all right.
V-E-R-N... Vern...
Vern... Main man... My main man. Vern.
Ohh... V-E-R-N... Vern.
Uh-oh.
My main man Vern.
V-E-R-N. Vern, my main man.
Raspberry, strawberry, blueberry, Pink Caddy, whole wheat, Peachy Keen,
beernut, Rocky Road, buckwheat, Bellybuster.
- What kind do you want? - Pancakes.
- Yeah, but what kind? - Pancakes.
'Course, maple syrup's supposed to be on the table...
- Ray? Ta-da! - (chuckles)
- Charlie Babbitt made a joke. - I made a joke.
Step back a little.
Hello?
Why don't you go sit down over there?
In this kind of legal proceeding, there's no lawyers, no judge,
just the people who care about Raymond.
Raymond, have a seat over there.
Mr. Babbitt, the other side of the table.
Raymond, right here. Take this seat. OK?
Ray, put your knapsack on the floor.
This is a good opportunity to be honest...
And the TV, Ray. Ray, the TV? On the floor.
- I'm sorry. - Yeah...
I don't know any easier way to say this, Mr. Babbitt...
Say what? Have I lost already?
No, you haven't lost. I'm just a doctor making a recommendation to a court.
I must tell you that Dr. Bruner is a very respected professional.
Raymond's case has been meticulously documented,
and Wallbrook is one of the finest institutions we have.
You guys have made up your mind. See you in court.
My brother came further with me in a week than he did with you in 20 years!
You don't know anything about us!
I don't think it's necessary to challenge Dr. Bruner.
What happened this past week, Raymond?
- We... - I was asking Raymond.
Raymond? What happened this past week? What did you do?
- Counted cards in Las Vegas. - Counted cards?
- Your brother took you to Las Vegas? - $3,000 on the wheel of fortune.
- He gave you $3,000 to gamble with? - Lost $3,000 on... pitiful 20.
- What else did you do? - Bet on number 20.
- What else did you do? - Danced with Charlie Babbitt.
Danced with your brother?
Danced in the elevator with Susanna. Kissed Susanna.
- You kissed Susanna? - In the elevator.
- Did you enjoy kissing a woman? - I don't know.
- How did it feel? - It f-f-felt wet.
- Wet? - Yeah.
- Quite a trip, huh? - Yeah.
- Do you enjoy being on the road? - I'm an excellent driver.
- You drove? - Yeah.
- Brother let you drive on the highway? - Slow on the driveway.
- He didn't drive on the highway. - Uh-huh.
- Did he have any emotional outbursts? - Such as?
Things they tend to do. Inflicting bodily harm on themselves...
- OK. Yeah, a couple of times. - A couple of times.
OK. He had what you call an outburst because he didn't wanna fly.
- So we didn't fly. - When was the last outburst?
- This morning. - This morning?
This is bullshit.
I could tell you anything, you'd never know the difference.
This morning the smoke alarm went off. He got a little nervous, but...
- Don't feel that I'm placing blame. - We went out for pancakes.
Look at him...
- You don't have to be defensive. - I'm just being honest.
- I think you're missing the point. - I think you are.
The point I was trying to make is I'm not placing blame.
I had a father I hardly knew, a mother I never knew,
I find out a few days ago I have a brother, I'm supposed to give him up?
- No one is saying anything... - I didn't hurt him,
he's not hurting me, we're not hurting you.
Why are you interfering? This is my family.
- My family. Do you understand? - I understand.
You do have a brother,
but he's not capable of having a relationship with you.
That's your opinion.
Did you spend 24 hours a day, seven days a week with him?
You cannot take on that responsibility without guidance.
- That's your opinion, Dr. Bruner. - Yes, it is.
There's a couple of things I'd like to go over. Dr. Bruner states a week ago,
you stole Raymond out of the institution to trade him for $1 .5 million.
My father died. I was upset. That was wrong.
So you've suddenly found some devotion to your brother,
- and you wanna take care of him? - Yes.
Mm-hm.
So the beginning was like a kidnapping.
That's very strong. I didn't kidnap my brother.
But in the course of the week, you came to have an understanding with him?
- Yes. - Mm-hm.
Look, that... I understand that this sounds irrational to you.
- Yes, when it started out... - Don't feel compelled to be defensive.
- Can I talk? I'd like to talk. - Yes, you can.
- Thank you. - There's no accusations. Go ahead.
No accusations?
(sighs) You have to understand that when we started out together,
that he was only my brother in name.
Mm-hm.
And as...
And this morning, we had pancakes.
Maple syrup. Maple syrup on the... maple syrup on the table.
- And pancakes. - And Charlie Babbitt made a joke.
You see, we...
I made a connection.
That's very admirable, but the purpose of this meeting
is to determine whether Raymond is capable of functioning in the community,
and what he wants, if that's possible to determine.
- I'm all for that. - Raymond can't make those decisions.
- You're wrong. - You know he can't decide for himself.
- He's capable of more than you know. - Why don't we ask Raymond?
- Can I ask you a few questions? - Ray, the doctor's talking to you.
- Can I ask you a few questions? - Yeah.
Do you want to stay with your brother Charlie?
Raymond, would you like to stay with Charlie in Los Angeles?
Ray? The doctor's asking you a question,
- so you listen, OK? - Yeah.
Raymond, do you want to stay with your brother Charlie?
- Do you want to stay with your brother? - Yeah.
- You do? - Yeah.
- You wanna stay with your brother? - Yeah. Stay with Charlie Babbitt.
- That's what you want? - Yeah.
- You wanna stay with your brother? - Yeah.
- Can I ask you something else? - Yeah.
- You wanna go back to Wallbrook? - Yeah.
Can you make a distinction between your brother and Wallbrook?
- Yeah. - Hm?
Raymond, do you want to stay with Charlie here in Los Angeles,
or do you want to go back to Wallbrook?
- Yeah. - They're two separate things.
Stay with your brother or go back to Wallbrook? Make a choice.
(Raymond) Go back to Wallbrook. Stay with Charlie Babbitt.
- Make that choice. One or the other. - Stay back to Wallbrook.
All right, all right, just hold on a minute!
- Stay back to Wallbrook... - All right. You've made your point.
You don't have to humiliate him. Ray, it's OK.
- It's over. - Yeah.
Stay back at Wallbrook with Charlie Babbitt.
- Stay back at Wallbrook. - It's over.
- Raymond? - Yeah?
Dr. Bruner, can I talk to you? Excuse me.
- You OK, Ray? - Yeah.
- You don't want any more questions. - No.
I don't know.
Don't worry. There's not going to be any more questions. No more questions.
Yeah. Main man.
- What? - My main man.
Listen...
I really don't know if I'm gonna have a chance to talk to you again.
Because, you see, these... Dr. Bruner really likes you a lot,
and he'll probably gonna want to take you back with him.
- You know? - Yeah.
I just want you to know that what I said
about being on the road with you I meant. Connecting?
- I like having you for my brother. - I'm an excellent driver.
Yes, you are.
I like having you for my big brother.
Yeah.
C-H-A-R-L-I-E.
Main man.
(PA) Your attention, please.
Amtrak train number 36, the Desert Wind eastbound,
now boarding, track number three.
Ray? Ray!
...Las Vegas, Salt Lake City, Denver, Omaha, Chicago...
- Charlie. - Dr. Bruner.
Hello, Raymond. Wouldn't you feel more relaxed in your favorite Kmart clothes?
- Tell him, Ray. - Kmart sucks.
I see. I have the tickets, and I'll be on this car right here to the right.
Why don't you take a couple of minutes? See ya, Charlie.
- You made a joke, Ray. - Yeah. Ha-ha-ha-ha!
I guess I'd better give this to you. You're gonna have to carry this now.
It's... It's got your cheese balls, your apple juice,
notebooks, pens and the "Who's on First?" video that you like.
- "Who's on First?". Very funny. - I told you, it's funny.
All aboard!
- You'd better get going. - Yeah. Very shiny train.
Yeah, it sure is.
Listen, Ray. Dr. Bruner only has custody of you.
That doesn't mean I can't visit. I'm coming to see you in two weeks.
- How many days is that? - Fourteen days. Today's Wednesday.
Hours?
- Three hundred thirty-six hours. - Mystifying!
'Course, that's 20,160 minutes.
1, 209,600 seconds.
Ray?
Ray!
- Ray! - Yeah?
I'll see you soon.
Yeah. One for bad, two for good.
- Bet two for good. - Yeah.
'Course, three minutes to Wapner.
You'll make it.
Yeah.