Don't give up.
Oh, I never do.
May I?
You work with your
hands, don't you?
- Redhead.
- Luther.
Your life would be a
whole lot simpler
if you could learn
to operate a VCR.
True. Truer words
were never spoken.
What's that?
Here we go.
That is nice.
It's okay. He's not here.
Anyway, I told him
that I was sick.
So you can relax.
Cheers.
I'll be right back.
You like that? Do you?
Oh, yeah.
So you wanna play, huh?
You okay?
How would you like that?
- You slap...
- Don't slap me.
You little bitch.
Alan, what are you doing?
Alan.
Alan, you're hurting me.
I'll hurt you, goddamn it.
Alan.
You're hurting me.
Goddamn you.
You wanna be hurt?
I'll hurt you.
Ow.
You like this?
- Let go.
- Do you?
You like that?
Goddamn you.
God...
- Son of a bitch.
- Get away.
Get back here.
Stop it.
Stop it. Alan.
What are you doing?
Bitch...
you wanna play? I'll show you how.
You fucking bastard.
You bastard.
You like that?
- Come back here.
- Don't. Let go of me.
Bitch, you cut me, goddamn it.
Fucking asshole.
I'm gonna kill you.
Help. Help.
Help.
Did you kill her?
No choice in the matter, sir.
What am I gonna do?
Jesus, Tim. What do we do?
No choice in the matter.
What the hell was that?
Oh, shit.
Oh, my God.
Do you realise what a
shitstorm we're in?
Go on, tell me.
Nothing to tell. He
screamed for help.
You heard no sounds of
violence till then?
Nothing we haven't heard before.
Maybe I should call
the police now.
Oh, Jesus. What?
Bill...
why don't you think about that?
Just take a second...
and think about that.
Think real...
fucking...
hard.
Probably not a good idea.
Okay.
Here's what happened.
Poor Christy...
came home alone and
interrupted a burglary.
Sound logical?
- Yeah.
- Sure.
We have to sanitise this place.
Alan. Did you have sex with her?
I don't know.
Bill, you're gonna
have to examine her.
- I'm no gynaecologist.
- I just made you one.
Christ.
I'll take that.
- It has both fingerprints.
- Thanks for sharing.
Gloria.
Did I kill her?
Everything's gonna be fine, Alan.
Just don't worry about it.
- Oh, God.
- Now be careful.
Just don't get blood on you.
I'll take care of everything,
okay? Just like I always do.
- Oh, shit.
- What?
Madame's purse.
- Miss Russell, let me get him.
- Thank you.
- I got him, Bill.
- All right.
Nice and easy, sir.
Oh, my God.
No knife.
- What?
- Where's the knife?
In the bedroom.
- Come on.
- Get up there.
- Shit.
Go.
Excuse me.
I got the number.
Gee, guys, maybe it
was the bogeyman.
Don't forget to check under the
bed. You may have buried us.
Look, I got his licence number.
You think he'll sit
around waiting for us?
Look, take it easy.
Everybody, shut up, all right?
What have you got?
Oh, boy.
Wow.
Two-way mirror.
We better get cracking
on that licence number.
That's all we've got.
He's got the letter opener.
Blood...
fingerprints.
Jesus.
Think what he can do.
The man's a thief. A thief
who witnessed a murder.
It looks like he stole a
whole bunch of money.
I'll tell you what he's gonna do.
He's gonna run like hell.
They beat us by seven.
By seven?
Who'd have thought that?
Oh, Kate.
Kate.
I guess it'd be a
little late for me.
The jogging, I mean.
Kind of dumb way to
start, isn't it?
But I did want to talk to you.
About?
The weather, actually.
It's getting cool in the evenings.
That happens this time of year.
I was thinking...
of moving to a kinder,
more gentle climate.
I thought I'd talk with you, since
you're the only family I have.
Luther, you don't have me.
Kate...
You know what it's like
to be the only kid...
who got to talk
about visiting day?
This move, it would be a
permanent one, you understand.
We never see each other anyway.
We haven't since Mum
died. That's a year.
Look, you chose your life.
You had that right.
You were never
around for me. Fine.
I have no plans to
be around for you.
Kate...
Wait a minute. Wait.
You're lying, aren't you?
No.
Are you active again? Is
that why you're here now?
No.
I don't believe you.
Oh, Christ.
Father, what have you done?
Christy Sullivan?
Wife of Walter.
Most likely came home,
stumbled onto a burglary.
Some burglary. I wish my
carpets were this clean.
I couldn't find a single
decent fingerprint.
- Are you serious, Laura?
- It's like Mary Poppins was here.
Where's Mr Sullivan?
Sorry, Seth.
The entire Sullivan household
went to Barbados two days ago.
Thanks for your support.
Oh, no, wait. It gets worse.
The shots came from here.
If she stumbled on a burglary,
she should've been here.
But she was killed
exactly where she is.
See, the blood patterns
indicate that.
What is she doing here?
Looks like someone sat here, but
I couldn't find any prints.
So you think old man Sullivan
holed up in this chair...
and watched his wife perform?
God, I hope not.
For his sake. You know,
he's such a great man.
Be careful digging that out.
Looks like he tried
to strangle her.
Then he went to the door
to shoot her from behind?
He also inspected her vagina.
He did what?
Why?
Maybe he didn't remember
that he did her.
A strong burglar with a weak mind.
Obviously, it's another
open-and-shut case.
We can expect tomorrow's
temperatures...
to climb into the 70s
with lows around 50.
Turner will start things
off for the Cougars.
The kick... Nice kick.
Kirby, back to receive, takes
the ball at the 12-yard line.
He's got a wedge in front of him.
- One man to beat.
- He's going all the way.
Nothing but clear sailing now.
Six points.
Mr Sullivan.
Sorry to bother you.
I'm Seth Frank, senior homicide
detective, Middletown County.
My client is in no mood
for conversations.
It's all right, Sandy.
You're in charge of
the case, Mr Frank?
Yes, sir.
I've gotta ask you
a few questions.
What do you want?
Positive identification?
Yes...
that was my wife.
Anything else?
You'd been in Barbados
for two days.
I took the staff, always
do this time of year.
Your wife didn't come with you.
Well, she was.
Had it all planned.
But you know women.
She changed her mind.
I'd been married to my
Rebecca for 47 years.
When she died...
I decided I never
wanted that pain again.
One thing I knew about Christy...
she was going to outlive me.
I think that's enough for today.
Sir, I have to ask
you about the vault.
You mean, the contents
of the vault, of course.
Sandy, you go on.
- Walter.
- No, really.
I'm all right. You go
on to the reception.
Obviously, I can't make it.
I'm sure everyone will understand.
You don't mean the contents.
No.
You mean the chair.
You must ask about the chair.
Yes, sir. I do.
Why? Are they connected?
Someone may have been
sitting in it and
may have been involved
in the murder.
I have the deepest respect for
you. I'm sorry to have to do this.
I promise you, none of this
will make my highlight reel.
Well, I hoped I could satisfy her.
But, you know...
she had needs.
She didn't want to
go behind my back.
She suggested the chair.
She hoped I might get
to like sitting there.
I didn't.
For 80 years, I've
tried to live...
a decent life.
I've given a billion
dollars to charity.
If this comes to trial...
none of that will be remembered.
I'll just go out...
the joke of the world.
I understand, sir.
I'll do what I can.
Would you listen to me whine?
I apologise, Mr Frank.
Just do your job and
I'll try to do mine.
Yes, sir.
I'm sorry, sir.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the president.
Sandy.
Mr President.
- Take a walk with me.
- Certainly, sir.
Tell me about Walter. How is he?
Well, he's 80 and
alone, Mr President.
He understands that
officially my hands are tied.
Yes, but he's very moved
by your concern, sir.
- Any news of the killer?
- No.
Why isn't there? Who's
in charge of this?
The top man.
He spent eight years,
homicide work, in New York.
I understand how you feel.
It's hard to be patient.
No one understands how I feel.
I'm supposed to have
all this power...
and I can't even help
my oldest friend.
You and I know, more than any man
alive, Walter
Sullivan put me here.
Now when he needs me most...
Well, he must feel abandoned.
I'll have a press conference.
I'll have Walter come and I'll
embrace him in front of the world.
He'll treasure that, Mr President.
What a generous gesture.
Thank you, sir.
Tennis elbow.
This thing is getting
worse, Gloria.
I need to see a doctor.
The country would have to
be informed, Mr President.
What happened to my
rights to privacy?
I think she nicked a tendon.
Bill says it's a flesh wound.
Since when did you
become an expert, Bill?
You ever been wounded?
Yes, sir. A few times.
You're serious about this
press conference, Alan?
Of course I am.
Walter's like a father to me.
Shall I bring Mrs
Richmond home for it?
I don't think Mrs
Richmond's mission...
to help the poor in Asia
needs to be interrupted.
What do we know so far?
We've checked his licence plates.
He stole the car from a
police impoundment lot.
We're not dealing with
a fool here, are we?
Has he initiated contact?
Burton doesn't think he will.
I agree.
I apologise for my behaviour.
Won't happen again.
Consider it a blip on the screen.
As far as I'm concerned,
that's all he is too.
He could be a little
more than that, Alan.
He saw.
He saw nothing. He
saw a drunk woman
who liked rough sex too much.
He's a burglar. Who's
gonna believe him?
After all, it's not as if he
has any evidence or anything.
He's a burglar. Who's
gonna believe him?
After all, it's not as if he
has any evidence or anything.
Boy, you always did
disappear good, Luther.
What you're trying to say is
I have a weak face, right?
No, I'm saying
you're lucky is all.
Some of my customers, no matter
what I do, they still stand out.
How many passports you want?
Four ought to do the trick.
You want different looks, matching
international driver's licences.
Since it's you, I'll throw
in some dummy credit cards.
How are the rugs I
made you holding up?
Good. The moustaches
and the beards also.
Well, we try to give
quality for our money.
You leaving the country
for permanent?
That could be, yeah.
Does it matter where
you've been? I
hate doing Asian passport stamps.
No. Make it European.
Caribbean in the wintertime. How
long is all this gonna take?
It usually takes some time.
For you, I'll rush it.
You were always
dependable, Valerie.
Listen, Luther...
I don't wanna know
what you're into.
I do, but I'm not
gonna ask you. But
leaving the country forever...
What is it?
I just never figured
you for a runner.
Thirty percent of my runners kill
themselves within five years.
Right now, five years
doesn't sound too bad.
Take care.
See you.
Okay, see if this makes any sense.
I am Christy Sullivan.
I come in the bedroom and
I surprise a burglar.
Okay. Okay, now you're the burglar
coming out of the vault
being surprised.
Gold star. I draw my gun. Boom.
Then why bother to strangle her
when you could just shoot?
Why do I bother to strip her
and put her clothes back on?
There, I can help you out.
You used to be a dry cleaner and
you love beautiful clothes.
Thanks a lot. And you
dress her because...
She was a good customer
and you didn't
want her embarrassed
when police came.
She had a 0.21
blood-alcohol level.
Not that that makes
any difference.
She didn't drive.
The chauffeurs, they keep
exact mileage on these cars.
They haven't been driven
since they went to Barbados.
I checked every cab
and limo service
in the area. Nobody knows a thing.
Somebody drove her home. Who?
Why haven't they come forward?
Maybe because whoever drove
her home killed her.
Maybe. I love this case.
Lieutenant?
Sorry to bother you, but
the phone problems?
- I just took care of them.
- Thank you.
Just part of the job.
I hate people who
say that. It's not
part... It is your fucking job.
Remember the bullet
hole in the wall?
- Yeah.
- Guess what.
No slug.
Why take a slug out of the wall
when there's one
stuck in her head?
Different from the
one in her body?
Two different guns
means two burglars.
Two guys broke in?
They both went out the
window? Bullshit.
By the way, why did
he or they go out
the window in the first place...
when he or they got in by breaking
a zillion-dollar security system?
- Hey, Seth.
- Yeah?
Bill Burton from the Secret
Service in the parking lot.
Thanks, Bob. What's he
doing in the parking lot?
Bill Burton. Hi.
Hi. Seth Frank. To what
do I owe the honour?
I know you must be going crazy...
but the boss is very interested
about your progress.
Maybe we could help
each other out.
What do you have in mind?
Well, you know how close
he and Sullivan are.
Right.
The minute anything breaks, if you
call me, I'd tell the president.
He'd be the first to
alert Mr Sullivan.
- It'd mean a lot to him.
- Okay.
Any red tape you want cut, done.
Here's my numbers.
Any leads?
We're still trying to
figure out what happened.
- I love playing Sherlock Holmes.
- You guys do that?
I was a state trooper before
the government got me.
Wait. You're that Bill Burton?
- I was younger and dumber then.
- I was younger. I'm dumber now.
Keep in touch.
My chef makes them
especially for me.
I promise you, they're sinful.
You're a salesman, Mr Sullivan.
This is a new arena for me.
But from what I'm told, you
have a flawless reputation.
Which is why I need to
employ you, Mr McCarty.
Understood.
I don't know who it
is I'm after yet.
Until I do...
you'll have to wait in
Washington for instructions.
Afraid that's out of the question.
Mine is not creative work.
I only do it because I enjoy
living beyond my means.
I can't afford to just sit around.
My father died when
I was 10 years old.
He was a miner. He
died of lung disease.
I became rich at 25.
The first thing I did was buy
that mine, close it down...
and give every miner
$50,000 to retire on.
You will wait in
Washington, Mr McCarty.
And I will put 1 million
dollars' expenses...
in a Swiss bank of your choosing.
And when the time comes...
2 million dollars a bullet.
You are a salesman, sir.
Selling sin is easy.
- Who is he?
- It's Luther Whitney...
one of the great
thieves of the world.
I've been going nuts.
I was up all night.
I remembered your notion how
maybe it was two burglars.
Around dawn, I thought, "What
if it's not two burglars...
but just one guy trying to
make it look like two?"
I called my buddy at the
Bureau. They keep track.
There's only half a
dozen guys alive who
could've pulled off
the Sullivan job.
I've been tracing all six.
Whitney's the only
guy that lives here.
So why is it I never heard of him?
He hasn't been
arrested in 30 years.
So, what's this? His graduation
picture from Harvard?
That's ancient history. He was
just a punk, part of a gang.
Three-time loser.
Since he got out last
the last time...
no one's touched him.
When something big comes up, they
question him, but
nothing ever sticks.
Oh, Seth. We can make this stick.
I bet you this is our guy.
He's a local. You can't
ask for anything more.
Yeah, well, we got a problem.
What?
He hasn't killed
anyone in 45 years.
Korea.
So what? He's a veteran.
Not just a veteran,
he's a wounded veteran.
I got his war record here.
Battles, commendations,
decorations up the kazoo.
He lives alone on his disability.
That's what he says anyway.
But I just don't see this guy as a
killer. He's just a great thief.
And besides, I don't
do war heroes.
Boy, you must be smart.
Pardon me?
It usually takes you guys
a week to get to me.
Oh, Seth Frank.
I recognise your picture
from the newspaper.
Luther Whitney.
Nice to meet you.
Would you like a signed
confession now...
or would you like to have
a little coffee first?
Before I send you away for life, I
should probably check
out your alibi.
I was watching a
football game with
an old friend of
mine, Red Bransford.
He owns a saloon here in town.
You can ask me about the game.
I could be lying.
You been following the case?
Yeah, I have.
I love true crime.
FBI says there's only a few guys
who could have handled this job.
I got a list here. You're on it.
How I wish it were true.
This person, they go
in the front door...
and out a window, and down a
rope in the middle of the night?
Now, if I could do
something like that,
I'd be the star of
my AARP meetings.
- What's that? The American...
- Association of Retired Persons.
Luther, why was this so difficult?
You want me to help
you solve your case?
Just looking for insight.
How would you?
Scratch that. How would
one go about it?
What kind of person
should I be looking for?
Well, except for the rope trick,
an older person, like me.
Because?
Well, you need patience.
The secret is research, research
and research. I've read that.
What kind of research?
Well, from what I saw on the tube,
this is a rather large home.
Must be an architectural office.
You'd go to the library, go
through public records...
find out where that architectural
office is and break in.
And then you Xerox the plans
and get them back by morning.
Why not just steal them?
Anyone can break into an
office, but breaking in...
without having people know you
were there, that's the trick.
Then there's the
general contractor.
And then there's the
security company.
Do you realise the
skill of breaking
the security of a
security company?
I don't know how those guys do it.
Why go to all that
trouble, Luther?
There's a vault in
the house. There
must be a secret way into it.
Yeah, there was. That's
what I don't get.
How do you mean?
This guy obviously did the
research you're talking about.
So why does he take a crowbar...
to open up this vault when there's
a clicker sitting right there?
A clicker?
Well, a gizmo, like a VCR remote.
Sounds amazing to me.
Must've been a lot of
valuables in that vault.
Close to 5 million total value.
Is that funny?
Why do I feel like you're
trying to surprise me?
I was trying to surprise you.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
There you go again.
Would the burglar use a disguise?
Yeah, he might.
You gotta get with the program
if you're gonna catch this guy.
It is a guy, we think, anyway.
Some sort of a loner? Weirdo?
Maybe like you.
Well, I'd be the perfect
prototype, actually.
Except you see a
person's face around
long enough and put
things together.
That's why these top
guys have disguises.
Some of them, I even understand,
become make-up experts...
hire wigmakers and
things like that.
Why don't you go on
about the wigmakers?
Well, I would.
I've gotta go have my
pacemaker checked.
It's been so exciting
talking to you.
A, you don't have a pacemaker.
And B, I'll be back tomorrow.
Tomorrow is promised to no one.
Goodbye.
Pacemaker, my ass.
Oh, Katie.
You gotta start eating
better than this, darling.
I'm having this press
conference here...
because it is here,
at this courthouse...
that Christine Sullivan's killer
will be tried for his crime.
As you know, I came from
an impoverished family...
in an impoverished town.
We lived with our doors...
unlocked.
We all lock our doors now.
- That's not what concerns me.
- A ginger ale.
We are also locking our hearts.
And could you turn that off?
- That is the sadness.
- In a second.
That...
is the loss.
We are locking our hearts
to the cries of the weary.
We are locking our hearts...
to the poor and their pain.
Sisters and brothers...
we are locking our
hearts to ourselves.
Turn it back on.
- But you just said...
- I know, but turn it on.
We feel that savagery and violence
must be allowed a place at table.
That is wrong. That
is not America.
I shall fight that battle.
Dear friend...
old friend...
we shall fight that battle.
Who can explain the
ways of chance?
If we had not met...
I would not be president today.
If Christine had not taken ill...
she would be with you
in Barbados even now.
Walter, you've been
like a father to me.
I would give the world
to lessen your pain.
Thank you.
You heartless whore.
I'm not about to run from you.
Thomas Jefferson used the
Green Room as a dining room.
The walls are covered
with green silk...
just as they were when James
Monroe was president.
Many valuable objects and
paintings in this room.
We'll be moving on
to the Blue Room.
James Hoban built the
Blue Room as an oval...
to please President Washington.
During the holidays, the
chandelier is removed...
and the White House Christmas tree
stands in the middle of the room.
The view from the window
includes the Jefferson Memorial.
We'll be moving on
to the Red Room.
The walls of the Red Room
are covered with red silk.
Many musical gatherings took place
here back in the 19th century.
He was in the building.
He took a guided tour.
I've never dealt with
blackmail before.
He doesn't want money.
Oh, you're a mind reader too now.
No, I just looked on the back.
See?
"I don't want money."
This guy sure has the guts of
a burglar. Wish we had him.
Finished your recruiting speech?
Because I'd like to
know how I handle this.
Like you handled
the letter opener?
Gee, Bill...
that could be construed
as criticism.
You really want me for an enemy?
Ms Russell, I should've called the
police that night but I was weak.
You convinced me to stay
silent. I regret that.
Every time I see your face, I
wanna rip your throat out.
Fine.
You win the pissing contest.
What do I do?
Nothing.
Because he's making
a terrible mistake.
He thinks he has time. He doesn't.
Seth Frank's too good.
He'll bring him in.
Then what?
Then I kill him.
Miss Whitney?
Thanks.
I'm Seth Frank. Excuse me.
Hi.
Thanks.
For a tough prosecutor, you sure
don't resemble your reputation.
Is that good or bad?
I don't know.
Look, lieutenant, I
told you on the phone.
I'm not involved with my father.
So this may not be a waste of
time for you, but it is for me.
What do you expect me to do,
get up and walk out of here?
All right.
Your father disappeared.
- I need your help.
- Look.
Lieutenant, I don't know the man.
He was in jail.
When he got out, my
mother and I went to
live by ourselves.
We don't make contact. He
doesn't care about me.
I've seen him all of
once this past year.
Yeah, when?
A couple days ago.
He said he might be leaving town.
There, I helped you.
Can I work now?
- Any idea where he might've gone?
- Quit wasting my time.
He doesn't want you to
find him, you won't.
You're saying, what, he
skipped the country?
I'm saying you won't
recognise him.
He could be right
around the corner.
- He always had a safe house.
- Where?
- He never said.
- How do you know he had one?
My mother loved him, all right?
Even after she left
him, even when she
was dying, he was all
she talked about.
"If only he hadn't done this.
- If only he hadn't done that."
- What else?
- How long has he lived here?
- Years.
Never been.
This is a strange place for
a thief to leave a key.
He always did that.
He sure left in a
hurry. I wonder what
scares a professional
thief like that.
He wasn't at these places.
My college graduation...
my law school graduation, the
night my mother and I...
we went out to celebrate because
I'd gotten my first job.
Me alone on the steps. I'd
just won my first case.
I used to think, sometimes...
Sometimes I'd come
home and I could
sense that he'd been
in the apartment.
Looking at my things,
checking the refrigerator...
shaking his head because he
never thought I ate right.
I mean, I know it sounds
crazy, but I've always...
I've always felt
that he was around.
You can do a good thing.
Help me bring him in.
Just leave a message
you're worried about him.
No.
It's true. You are worried.
This is not a normal case.
His life could be in danger. You
make the call, you can save him.
He won't come.
Of course he'll come.
You're all he has.
He's on the run and he's scared
because he's gonna get caught.
- You don't know the heat on this.
- He's not a murderer.
Maybe he is innocent.
If that's the case, I'll have
him home in a few hours.
What happens if
some hotshot trying
to make a reputation
tracks him down?
I can guarantee his safety.
You make the call,
I'll make a promise.
You'll have your father back.
- Seth Frank.
- Hi.
I called. I left a
message on his machine.
He called me back
within the hour and
I'm meeting him
tomorrow afternoon.
Where?
Open-air place near my
office, Cafe Alonzo.
What time?
Four o'clock.
It'll be deserted then.
Sounds good. Thanks a lot.
- Bye.
- Bye-bye.
Dad, hi.
It's Kate calling.
I was wondering if you
could call me, please.
There's some things I'd like
to talk with you about...
and maybe even get together,
if that's possible.
Okay?
Thanks and talk to you soon. Bye.
Dad, hi.
It's Kate calling.
I was wondering if you
could call me, please.
There's some things I'd like
to talk with you about...
and maybe even get together.
You all know where
you're supposed to be
and when you're
supposed to be there.
This guy's slippery.
He's like an eel.
He gets a whiff of a cop,
he's gonna disappear.
Nobody moves until you
get the order from me.
Then we move in on him.
Expect Whitney to
show up at 4:00. His
daughter will be waiting for him.
The important thing is to
stay in your positions...
until you hear the order
to move in on him.
- Here you go, sir.
- Thanks. Could I have some cream?
Gather around, gentlemen.
Nobody makes a move till
the suspect's in place.
Any questions?
See you at the Alonzo.
Boss is grateful.
I figured he'd appreciate an
eyewitness at the capture.
This is our guy.
If he isn't, he sure disappeared
awful fast. See you over there.
All right.
Tums?
I got my own.
Come on, Kate.
- She gonna show?
- Yeah, she'll be here.
Miss?
What you want, please?
Nothing. Thank you.
Got to.
Pardon?
You sit, you eat, please.
Jeez, this guy wasn't
part of my master plan.
Unbelievable.
I'm waiting for someone.
Oh, he must eat too, please.
He will. We will. We're gonna...
We'll order half the
menu. Just not now.
Maybe that's him
disguised as a Chinaman.
Check out this guy in the hat.
I believe that's our man.
All units, suspect's approaching.
Stay in place. Wait for my signal.
Kate...
I did not kill that woman. I
want you to believe that.
Just hold on. Let him get settled.
You've gotta believe that.
- I think we're ready.
- Okay.
Damn it.
Almost.
You okay?
What was that?
Anybody see where those
shots came from?
- Did you do that?
- No, we didn't do it.
Anybody see where those
shots came from?
Where's Whitney?
Quit standing around
here. Go find him.
Take it easy.
Take it easy, now.
Stay calm. Stay calm.
There's no reason to panic.
If everyone will just
kindly take it easy.
Messy.
I like that in a woman.
Here.
I got a few numbers here.
The top one's...
local police. That's my
office, my home, beeper.
I live alone too. You
can call anytime.
Want me to get somebody
to spend the night?
No, I wanna get some sleep.
Surveillance is outside
until this is over.
I've got a feeling he's
gonna try to contact you.
You're on a hot streak, I guess.
Listen, I'm sorry.
Anything unusual at all...
call right away.
It's not a bother.
I live alone.
You said.
Feeble, huh?
Listen, you want
something for the road?
I got water and water.
Deal.
A Pellegrino would be great.
- What's so funny? I say it wrong?
- No. No, I'm...
I'm tired.
I'm just tired.
Listen...
there's one thing...
I forgot to tell you.
I live alone.
Lock up behind me.
- How's that?
- Real good.
Now get some sleep.
Thank you.
I betrayed you twice, Luther.
You should know that.
You're not the first.
Why'd you come?
I couldn't have my daughter
thinking I was a murderer.
No, I mean this afternoon, to
the restaurant. Why'd you come?
You suspected something or you
wouldn't have been prepared.
My daughter wanted to see me.
The robbery was going
fine until they came in.
They were drunk.
I was hidden in the vault.
And the sex had started
getting rough...
and he started beating her...
started strangling her. I
thought he was gonna kill her.
Then she somehow got
the upper hand.
She was gonna stab
him with a letter
opener and two guys
came in and shot her.
The same two guys who tried
for you this afternoon.
Possibly. I don't know.
Unless Walter Sullivan
was taking a shot at me.
It's a pretty powerful enemy.
That's very good going.
Not as powerful as the president
of the United States.
That's right.
Alan Richmond, he was the drunk.
The two guys were Secret Service.
Chief of Staff Russell,
she handled the cover-up.
Well, then you go to the police.
That's what innocent people
do. They go to the police.
Sure.
That young man who
was just here...
he'd believe me over the
president, wouldn't he?
Why should I believe you?
Because I swear to you, Kate.
I swear to you on Mattie's grave.
Yeah, that's right.
Your mother's grave. I'd kill
myself before I'd lie about that.
Oh, Jesus, Luther.
- Yeah. I know.
- They'll kill you.
- I know.
- Can you run?
I was all set to. I was at
the airport ready to go.
Then there was that
press conference.
And there was Richmond
using old man Sullivan.
You know, I might not
have been able to...
save Christy Sullivan...
but I didn't even try.
What are you gonna do?
I don't know, but I'll
think of something.
I watched you argue
a case last year.
You won it.
Thank God you got
your mother's brains.
Dangerous outside.
It always is.
Excuse me.
Could you give this package
to Gloria Russell?
- Anything for me to sign?
- No, you have an honest face.
What?
Oh, my God.
Ms Russell, you're
a vision tonight.
Thank you, Mr President.
And thank you, Mr President.
For...? Come again.
You know.
You sent it to me this afternoon.
Of course.
Would you excuse me, all?
I'm overcome with a desire to
dance with my chief of staff.
Look after this for me, would you?
What is this nonsense?
I'm hoping there's an explanation.
Your gift, Alan. I was...
overwhelmed.
And, you know, your
note was so gratifying.
I sent a note?
Yes, yes.
You think I don't
know your writing?
I assumed you wanted
me to wear it tonight.
- Gloria, it's lovely.
- Yes.
And you know what else?
What, Alan?
Christy Sullivan wore it
the night she was killed.
Know what this means?
No.
Whitney's been heard from.
It's not precisely the
first time, Mr President.
You been keeping things from me?
Well, you know, it's just that
you have so much on your plate.
We wanted to spare you.
He sent me a Polaroid...
of the letter opener yesterday.
I have to give this some thought.
Come to my office in the morning.
This'll make an interesting
chapter in my memoirs.
Do we know who the forger is?
I talked to Seth Frank,
sir. Apparently,
Whitney learned how in prison.
A gifted man.
How close are we to stopping him?
We're working around the clock.
Well, that's good to know.
He'll make a mistake.
Well, that's good to know too.
There is...
one other thing...
that we need to take care of.
He has a daughter, doesn't he?
You sure you wanna do that?
Sir?
She's a young prosecutor.
Prosecutors ask questions.
Maybe she knows what he knows.
Let's get cracking, boys.
Show that you love your country.
How's Kate doing?
Where are you?
I won't hang around long enough
for you to trace the call.
Just answer the question.
Well, she couldn't
be in better hands.
I got a call from
the Secret Service.
They're taking over surveillance.
Hello?
It's entered in the chart.
We've upped her from
250 to 500 milligrams.
Nurse, I need you
right away, please.
He's having a seizure.
Dr Kevorkian, I presume.
My guess is that this is right in
your carotid artery about now.
You're gonna get a little woozy.
But if I give you
the rest of this...
it's gonna fry your brain
down to the size of a peanut.
Drop that.
Luther...
he was my president.
Right or wrong.
Well, he made a mistake.
You made a mistake.
When you went after
my little girl,
that was entirely unacceptable.
Mercy.
I'm fresh out.
Daddy?
Go to sleep, darling.
Oh, Jesus.
Just one question.
Did Walter Sullivan say why
Christy didn't go to Barbados?
Just that she changed her mind.
You know who did it, don't you?
So will you. Check your phones.
Good night, Mr Sullivan.
You're taking a shortcut, Tommy?
I'm your substitute driver
tonight, Mr Sullivan.
Don't worry about
Tommy. He's just fine.
Very unusual.
What do I call you?
Luther, sir.
And are you familiar with how to
get to my town house, Luther?
Oh, yes, sir.
I know where all your houses are.
I'm the man who robbed you.
You're the man who
tried to kill me.
I'm sorry I missed.
I believe in the Old
Testament, sir.
There's nothing wrong
with an eye for an eye...
when a terrible
deed has been done.
A deed such as yours.
Yeah. Well, you'd like to
believe that, wouldn't you?
That'd be simple for
you to believe that.
What do you think I have
to gain by being here?
I have no idea.
You going to rob me again?
Oh, I don't need your
money, Mr Sullivan.
Did you check your vault lately?
I put everything back.
I'm afraid we're a little late
for an attempt at leniency.
A lot of crap's coming
down tonight, sir.
You wanna be a player or not?
You wanna know what happened
that night or don't you?
Because I was there.
I want to know.
You think you can stand
hearing about it?
How he beat her, tried
to strangle her?
You really wanna know about that?
I could walk through fire.
I was in the vault
when they came in.
They were drunk.
He started knocking her around.
She fought back.
He started getting really rough.
She tried to defend herself.
Well, he started screaming...
snivelling simp he is.
Who else was in my house?
Secret Service. They're
the ones who shot her.
Nonsense.
Gloria Russell, she
handled the cover-up.
Stop this.
Don't you wanna know who it was?
It was you.
Come on, Mr Sullivan. We're too
old to bullshit each other.
Who was it, then?
You know.
Don't shake your head at me.
When you're alone and your rage
takes over and you want revenge...
what face do you put
with your enemy?
Stop the car.
No, we're going straight ahead.
No.
This is too terrible.
Yes, it is.
I know about Alan's reputation
as a philanderer...
but he'd never dream
of betraying me.
I gave him the presidency.
Remember that press conference?
Where he put his arm
around you and said...
if Christy hadn't been sick, she'd
have been in Barbados with you?
Well, how the hell did
he know she was sick?
You didn't tell anyone.
It's because she told him
that night. I was there.
I was right there watching.
That's not real proof.
Well, maybe this is, then.
You could've stolen this.
I did steal it.
But that's not my blood on there
and that's not my prints.
Mr Sullivan.
I did love her, you know.
Jeez, Burton.
Is he working late?
I don't have an
appointment but I would
like to see him.
You don't need an
appointment, Mr Sullivan.
Let's go, Ms Russell.
Walter.
Come in.
We interrupt this program
with a breaking story...
one that is shocking the
nation and the world.
Information is just coming out of
the White House about a tragedy...
that's taken place
within the hour.
We go now to our White
House correspondent.
Diane, what can you tell us?
Sources say Sullivan...
had seen President
Richmond tonight.
That was for an unscheduled
private meeting.
You're still here.
I'm still here.
I would not be president.
If Christine had not taken ill...
she would be with you
in Barbados even now.
Walter, you've been
like a father to me.
This is the president's most
recent news conference...
where he clearly outlined...
his loyalty to philanthropist and
dear friend Walter Sullivan.
Sullivan's wife was murdered. The
president vowed to
find the killer.
Again, Sullivan had
a meeting with the
president. Unknown
what they discussed.
We go now to the White House
for a live interview.
Mr Sullivan, have
you no idea why the
president would take his own life?
I know he's been
feeling the pressure
of office more than ever lately.
He talked about it a great deal.
But why would he stab himself?
That's a question that
will haunt me forever.
Of course I tried to stop him.
Alan...
was like a son to me.
Was that Seth?
I think he'd like to come over
for supper when you get well.
You don't have to fuss.
I know.
Am I gonna be all right?
Yeah.
We're gonna be just fine.