Why did you take my squad lieutenant
out of commission on a day's notice?
This is the best arson investigation
training program in the world.
It's the opportunity
of a lifetime for Severide.
Carver, is it?
- Sam.
- Hi, Sam.
You know, it's not my fault
I didn't make it home.
Maybe if you weren't
so distracting and fun.
I'm worried that everything
you've been feeling lately
isn't really about me.
You think it's about Evan.
I'm sorry.
Your mom has cancer,
and that really, really sucks.
It's okay to talk about it
and cry about it.
Can't keep it bottled up.
So I've been thinking about the fact
that tomorrow is your
last chemo treatment.
At least for now.
I think we should celebrate,
have a little party at Molly's.
What if I have to go
through another round?
We don't know yet.
Well... come on.
That's then, this is now.
Cin, we don't get a lot
of good news these days.
You made it through that round
like a champ.
You deserve to celebrate.
No.
I... I don't wanna go out
looking like this.
You look great.
Don't even try it.
It's a very sweet idea,
but I'm not great company
right now for anyone.
Let's put a pin in that, okay?
Okay. Whatever you want.
Dylan and I did a dive bar tour.
It was fun. How about you two?
I was laid up with the flu.
My weekend was worse, I guarantee it.
That girl Alyssa, she turned
out to be a complete psycho.
She...
Hey, guys. How was the weekend?
- Lame.
- Amazing.
Wow, lucky you.
I can't do this with you two again.
Carver, you're crowding the driveway.
Don't get a ticket, man.
I'd rather risk a ticket
than lose my tools.
Figure nobody will break in
if I'm parked
right in front of the firehouse.
I got a construction gig
right after shift.
Oh, I thought you quit construction.
I did, but then my brother
cleaned me out,
so I need the cash.
Is it just me, or is this
the manliest car on the planet?
This thing's like
an environmental disaster.
No offense.
So how are you enjoying the view
from the front seat of Squad, Joe?
Huh, uh, feels good, Chief.
I, uh, like it.
Well, you really handled your
crew during that stable fire.
Thank you, Chief.
But, um, it may be a while
before Severide is back.
If the additional responsibility
is getting to be a burden,
I can shuffle schedules,
bring in a relief lieutenant.
No, no, Chief.
I got this.
Glad to hear it.
I got a floater in
to fill in your empty seat,
a Keith Bamford.
Do you know him?
No, I don't think so.
Well, he's out there somewhere.
Why don't you go
and make his acquaintance?
Will do.
Thanks, Chief.
Go get 'em.
Bachelor party!
No, listen. No, for real, though.
I swear I've seen you around somewhere.
You ever spent any time in Squad 1?
- No.
- Wait a minute.
You know what it is?
I've seen you on TV.
Capp? On TV?
You mean like on the news maybe?
- At a scene?
- Oh, you know what?
You know who I'm thinking of?
I'm thinking of Uncle Fester.
Honest mistake.
Oh, listen, where is
Lieutenant Severide, anyway?
The man, the legend?
I'm dying to meet this guy.
Oh, Severide's on furlough.
We've been taking our orders from Cruz.
Oh, hey. Joe Cruz.
I'm just acting up for a while.
All right. Good for you. Bamford.
- Welcome aboard, Bamford.
- Thanks.
Truck 81, 1349 North Edna.
- That's me.
- Wellness check.
Enjoy your wellness check, truckie.
Main, this is Truck 81
on scene at 1349 Edna.
Do you have an apartment number for us?
Okay, thanks.
So someone just called,
asked for the fire department,
and then hung up.
Let's do a quick walk through.
All right, Gallo, Carver,
you start at the top,
work your way down.
Me and Mouch,
we'll work our way up from one,
meet in the middle.
Copy.
Fire department. Anybody home?
Fire department.
Hey, somebody called in
and asked for help.
Do you know any...
Fire department.
Hello?
Did you call 911, ma'am?
My boy. He needs help.
Excuse me, ma'am. Stand over there.
Lieutenant, we have
an injured child upstairs.
Stand by while we check him out.
Copy that.
Hey there, buddy.
I'm Sam. What's your name?
Tyler.
Let's have a look at you.
What happened to you, Tyler?
I got shot.
Synced & corrected by -robtor-
www.addic7ed.com
- Sure looks like a GSW.
- It can't be, can it?
Ma'am, what happened to him?
Can't you just patch it up?
He needs a doctor to look at this.
Tell Kidd to roll an ambulance.
- Got it.
- Wa... wait, please.
No sirens.
Ma'am, what's going on here?
Please, I just need you to fix him.
He's okay.
We just need to stop the bleeding.
Gallo, grab the jump bag.
On it.
- What's your name, Mom?
- Ariel.
Ariel, this isn't a grazing injury.
This is a penetrating wound.
If he was shot, the bullet
is still in there somewhere.
Lieutenant.
- We need an ambulance.
- What's going on?
A little boy said
he got shot in the head.
He said he got shot in the head?
Yeah. I mean, he's alert and talking.
- Is he why we were called?
- I don't know.
But I gotta get the jump bag.
Okay, go.
All right, 81 to Main, we need
an ambulance at 1349 Edna.
Vice should send a squad car too.
Copy that.
Hey, throw me that cloth,
would you, Fester?
His name is Capp.
It's a joke, dude. He knows that.
It's cool.
Finished already, Bamford?
Yep.
I don't mess around.
Ambulance 61, 1349 North Edna,
- person injured.
- Edna?
Ain't that where Truck just went?
Is it? I don't know.
I guess they caught
some action after all.
Good for them.
How'd this happen? Where were you?
Right here.
The shot came from next door?
Fire department, open up.
It's gonna be okay. We got you.
We got you.
Gallo.
- Yeah.
- Shh.
Oh, damn.
The wall must have
slowed the bullet down.
That's why Tyler here
is still on two feet.
Tough as nails.
But we have to get him to the hospital.
Ambo's on the way.
I just... I just
didn't wanna cause a fuss
'cause it wouldn't start
nothing but trouble.
Ma'am, what's really going on here?
It's just a fight over turf.
What else?
So go back outside, wait for the medics,
and I'll find Gallo and Carver.
Gotcha.
Gallo, Carver, where you at?
Apartment 3-D, Lieutenant.
Hey, guys.
Take it somewhere else, huh?
You better get lost.
Lieutenant, you got trouble
headed your way.
You guys need to clear out now.
Okay, we're coming.
Whoa.
Gallo, Carver, take cover now.
Hey, cops are on their way.
You better clear out.
Shh.
Where the hell are those cops?
They're on scene now.
I got three firefighters
pinned down by gunfire
on the third floor, some kind
of gang war activity.
- How many shooters?
- I saw four go in.
No idea how many were already in there.
Dispatch 9-13, I need
a 10-1 at 1349 Edna.
Shots fired.
Play baseball?
Catch mostly, when there's
anyone to play with.
Played football when I was a kid.
When I was scared, and I'm scared a lot,
I would just think about
being on the field
throwing that ball around.
Can you do that?
Just imagine you're outside
with your friend playing catch.
Not got a thing in the world
to worry about.
Gallo, Carver, let's go.
- All clear. North stairs.
- All right. Let's go.
Okay. Stand up, buddy.
I got you. Come on.
- Come on, let's go, baby.
- I got you.
Go, go.
North stairs, go.
Stay low.
61, stay with your vehicle.
We're bringing a victim to you,
a young boy.
Get him far away from here.
Okay.
Carver, you go with them
so you can fill in the details.
We'll follow you to Med.
Copy that.
What are we looking at?
GSW to the head.
Entry wound, but no exit.
Let's get him on the stretcher.
What's your name, hon?
- Tyler.
- How old are you?
- Eight.
- Give my fingers a squeeze.
Okay. Good.
- GSW?
- Yeah.
The bullet ricocheted through a wall,
so maybe it's not too deep.
But he's been conscious
and aware the whole time.
And brave as hell.
Okay.
The doctors are gonna take care of you.
- I have to blow my nose.
- I don't know if now's a good time.
Please, I really have to blow my nose.
Tyler, you just sit there
and do what she says, okay?
Okay, let me have a look,
just see if I...
can you grab me the pen light?
Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
- Okay. Lean back.
Wait a second.
Don't move.
Okay. Hold still.
Oh, that feels so much better.
Wow.
It's incredible.
Tyler, you and your mom
should buy a lottery ticket
because you're one lucky kid.
Seriously.
- Oh, my God, what is that?
- What? What?
He fell down!
Capp, what the hell are you doing?
You wanna break the couch again?
I'm sorry, Cruz, they got me good.
I had nothing to do with it.
Cruz.
Sorry, Chief.
I told them to knock it off.
Okay, um...
your fire report from last shift.
It got bounced back by HQ.
Really? How come?
You didn't follow the format.
It's okay. Just, um,
make the corrections, resubmit.
Ask Kidd or Hermann
to walk you through it.
- Will do.
- Okay.
Sorry about that, Chief.
When those bullets were flying,
it felt like we were
in the middle of a movie.
It wasn't even real. It was crazy.
I mean, we're lucky to be alive.
- All of us.
- Mm-hmm.
And for what?
A turf war.
Tragic, you know?
No doubt about that.
You guys okay?
- That was no joke.
- Yeah.
We were just saying
we're lucky to be alive.
Mm.
Yeah, when we came out of the building,
that boy had an iron grip on your coat.
Seems like he got pretty attached.
Tyler, yeah.
Brave little kid.
I don't know what you said to him
when you guys hit the ground,
but worked like magic.
I'm gonna go check on the
medics, see if they're back.
Mm-hmm.
So you got a gift with kids, huh?
Hmm.
I don't know about that.
Well, you made a real
connection with Tyler,
that's for sure.
No child should have
to be scared like that.
Ever.
I'm just glad he's okay.
At least for now.
Hey, is that kid really okay?
- I can't believe it.
- It's crazy. He's fine.
The bullet skirted
the outside of his skull
and wound up in his sinus cavity.
They did a CAT scan.
There's no real damage.
That's more than a miracle.
That's a higher power at work.
I've never seen anything like it.
Uh, I don't want it
to be weird between us.
Neither do I.
Like, I'm...
I shouldn't have said anything
about my feelings the other day.
It... it's not like it's a
huge issue for me, it's just...
You don't have to explain yourself.
We had a thing, and there's
always been some
of that thing still there.
But, um, by now,
we've learned we're better
when we ignore that thing
and are just friends, you know?
Yeah, yeah, I do.
I couldn't have made it
the last few months
without the friendship part,
so I'm never letting it go.
That's good by me.
Getting caught in that kind of crossfire
sounds terrifying.
It was, but we handled it.
Lieutenant Kidd is who handled it.
Took down a bunch of gangbangers,
gave us a chance
to get that kid out of there.
Team effort.
I'm just glad you're all safe.
If you need to talk to peer
support, you let me know.
Absolutely, Chief.
- Hey, Seager.
- Hey, guys.
Final report on that stable fire.
I'm bringing it, uh, to Boden.
Great to see you, as always.
I heard you guys had a rough one.
It was, yeah,
but the victim's doing good, so.
Well, maybe we can grab a drink later
and you can fill me in?
I'd love that.
And then I can make you
forget all about it.
That sounds even better.
Hey. What are you doing in here?
I'm drinking tea.
Why?
Well, tea is supposed to relax you,
and after that call, I need it.
Why are you drinking it in here?
Ah, I wanted a little peace and quiet.
Eh, well, sorry to interrupt,
but I could, you know,
use your help.
I wanted to have a party for Cindy
to celebrate her last round
of chemo, you know.
I think it would be good for
her mental health, you know,
to feel something good about, you know?
That makes sense.
But she's...
You know, she's feeling
really self-conscious
about the way she looks these days,
and she doesn't wanna do it.
Huh.
And there's only
one person that I know of
that could convince anybody
to do anything.
Who?
Ah.
Hey, uh, oh, um,
Chief said that I could use this office.
It's just there's so much paperwork.
Of course. You should.
Yeah.
Funny, I actually
came in here on instinct.
That's what I always do
when there's a rough call
or I just need to talk.
You can talk to me, if you want.
I know there's no comparison,
but come on in.
Gallo was telling us about that call.
That sounds like something.
I really miss him.
I bet.
I know it's partly because
I didn't have time to prepare, you know?
The slot came up so suddenly.
Yeah.
It feels like he just disappeared.
I think it shook everybody up
a little, me included.
He really jumped at the chance.
And I don't know why, honestly,
because I always thought
that arson was his side gig.
Now suddenly, it's center stage.
It's still a great
experience, no matter what.
It is.
And I did this last year.
I went away, got wrapped up
in Girls on Fire,
and got a little distant, so I get it.
Throwing yourself
into a project for a while
can be great.
I just hope I'm not missing something...
that there's not something
more serious going on.
That's all.
So the weirdness
between Violet and Gallo
seems to have died down.
Do not jinx it by saying that.
Oh, who are we kidding?
No matter what we say or do,
that weirdness is gonna
come and go forever.
I won't survive it, I'm telling you.
Lieutenant.
Hey.
Sorry I... I laid out
that on you yesterday.
I think the call hit me
harder than I realized.
I am sure everything's fine with Kelly.
It's really no problem.
I'm here any time.
Thanks, Cruz.
You got it.
Hey, Lieutenant.
Yeah?
I just gotta say,
I've never seen two people
more perfect for each other
than you and Severide.
Besides you and Chloe.
Well, duh.
Uh, Cruz?
Did Dubitsky in training
call you about certification?
No.
Ah, damn.
He should have.
It turns out if you wanna keep
running Squad,
you need your
Instructor II certification.
You need to report to the
academy right after shift.
As in now.
Oh, but Javi's got a game today.
I'll call Chloe. I'll let her know.
Really sorry about Dubitsky's screw-up.
No sweat, Chief.
Hey, I'm back.
How's it going here?
Making progress.
I'll have it framed out
by the end of the day.
Fantastic.
Say, is that your Bronco out front?
Yeah. Is it in your way?
No. I was admiring it, actually.
Is that a '96?
That's right.
It's the last generation 5.8 liter V8.
Well, she's a beaut.
Whoa, Ethan.
Whoa, you gotta stay out of Sam's way
or he'll never finish
the entertainment center.
It's fine.
He's been keeping a respectful distance.
Oh, sorry, sorry.
It's all good.
- I should get back to it.
- Yeah. Come on, Ethan.
Let's stay out of Sam's hair.
Mom!
- Trudy.
- Hey.
What are you doing here?
I've been assigned to your case.
My case?
The chemo party you don't wanna have.
Oh.
I hear you're not
feeling at your sexiest.
Uh, no.
Because I'm not.
And to be honest, you, Donna,
and a few other girlfriends
are the only ones who've
seen me in this condition
besides family.
You know what you look like?
A woman who's been through chemo,
who deserves to celebrate the end of it.
We don't know it's the end.
- That's part of the problem.
- Okay.
But say it is.
When else are you gonna have
the perfect chance
to go hog wild with hair and
makeup, just change it all up?
What?
Oh, come on, honey, I love you,
but we both know
you're not a big risk taker
when it comes to your look.
And you are?
Uh, gray is bold.
And I got some bold ideas for you too.
This is...
this is gonna get spicy.
Damn.
Looks like the distraction
was temporary.
It was perfect, is what it was.
I know this was an intense call,
but you've been a firefighter
for a while now.
So what's sticking with you
about this one?
I'm not really sure.
Well...
I consider it my civic duty
to continue this distraction work
on behalf of the
Chicago Fire Department.
I don't know what the CFD
would do without you.
Mm.
The good news is,
Kidd said she's flying out
- to visit him next week.
- Oh, that's great.
Phone calls only get you so far
when you're trying to stay connected.
Yeah.
We need help.
Oh, wow.
I'm a coach at Sarton Academy,
just a few blocks away,
and we were getting ready
for the game tomorrow.
It's humiliating.
All right. Well, let's take a look.
Katy's not usually the mascot.
She was just trying it on.
- Yeah, that's pinned in tight.
- Yeah, let's get her inside.
I pass by here every day
on the way to school.
- I knew you guys could help.
- Smart move.
Let's sit her down in the common room.
Katy!
Oh, she's cyanotic.
Her oxygen must be tanking.
- She's suffocating in there.
- Oh, my God.
Capp. Capp!
Grab the tin snips, we have
a trapped victim in here.
- Copy.
- I'll get the BVM.
You got it.
She's bradycardic, heart rate 50.
All right, hold the mask steady.
I'm gonna do release cuts on both sides.
You got it.
Bag her, I'll put the
pulse ox and the leads on her.
You got it.
Okay.
- Okay. I'll pull it off.
- I got her.
Ready? Easy.
Coming in.
Hey. It's okay. They'll take care of it.
Oh, come on, Katy.
Tighten your seal.
- Yep.
- Thanks.
Heart rate's coming up.
Oxygen levels in the 80s.
- That's good.
- Oh, thank God.
- Hey.
- Whoa.
- You know where you are, Katy?
- Yeah.
Coach Julia brought me here
to the firehouse.
Ugh, stupid mask.
- You feel okay?
- Yeah.
Breathing and heart rate are normal,
but I wanna take her to Med
to get her checked out just to be safe.
I have a chem final today.
I'm sure they'll let you retake it.
Well, chem is my favorite subject,
so we'll have a lot
to talk about on the ride.
Beware, she's obsessed.
Thank you for getting
that mask off so quick.
- That was pretty awesome.
- We're just glad she's okay.
I wonder if I can fix this.
- Hey.
I am gonna need your honest assessment.
Of course.
What about?
When Severide took furlough and we knew
that it wasn't gonna be a quick one,
HQ pressured me into bringing
in a relief lieutenant.
I argued for letting Cruz act up
in the interest of continuity
and house morale.
Makes perfect sense.
Cruz doesn't seem to be enjoying
the added responsibility.
Squad is an elite unit.
He's got very big shoes to fill.
HQ is watching him like a hawk.
That is a heavy burden
to put on someone who didn't ask for it.
So what are you thinking?
Why not take the pressure
off, thank him for filling in,
bring in a relief lieutenant,
let Joe go back to doing
what Joe does best.
Chief, whether Joe wanted
the job or not, he's in it now,
and he needs to handle it on his terms.
If it's snatched away from him,
you'll shake his confidence.
He may never try again.
Okay.
Hey. How you feeling?
You know, same day-after crap as usual.
But I'm okay.
I'm sorry I don't wanna
do the party, honey.
You don't got to apologize.
I... I get it.
Hey, you know, moving on.
So we got doctors appointments
to set for next week.
I'll get on that today.
Okay. Sounds good.
- Thanks.
- You bet.
I'll see you tomorrow after shift.
Mouch. Hey.
Will you, um, tell Trudy thank you
for talking to Cindy about the party?
- I sure will.
- All right.
I'm glad she tried, you know,
even if it didn't work out.
Oh, I think it worked out.
Robert.
Hey, you really have taken
great care of this thing, Sam.
I'm only the second owner.
Are you ready to be the third?
Hell yes, I am.
You know, my dad and I go fishing
down at Devil's Kitchen.
Gravel roads do not agree with my BMW.
Here's that cashier's check.
You got a pen?
- Hey.
Okay, guys, let's hustle.
We got a chance to shave 15
seconds off of our last time.
Nice work, Capp. There you go.
Good job. Here we go, guys. Come on.
Come on, don't slow down.
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
Come on, boys.
Come on.
And through.
Good effort, guys. Really good effort.
Let's, uh, let's put the dummy back.
We'll try it again.
You like how he says "we"?
I vote we take a break.
Vote?
Well, what do you think this is?
Look, okay, guys.
I know that this is a pain in the ass,
but we gotta buff up the teamwork.
We got a change in personnel.
We gotta make sure that
the gears are meshing.
Yeah, good luck meshing
with Mutt and Jeff here
pulling in two different directions.
What?
He's a bad fit, Joe.
I didn't pick him.
Well, you need to set him straight.
And you... you're not helping matters,
laughing at his jokes all the time.
- Oh, this is my fault now?
- Hey.
I'm taking a water break.
No wonder Severide
hightailed it out of here.
Cruz.
Your guys are out there waiting for you.
Yeah, let them wait!
Whoa. Hey.
What's the matter?
I can't do it.
I haven't slept in a week
from the stress of all of this.
You... you come back from
nearly being shot to death,
and everything is fine.
Meanwhile, my whole company
is falling apart
because I can't handle one joker.
I'm no Severide.
I never will be.
I don't know who the hell
I thought I was kidding.
Sit.
You ever heard of imposter syndrome?
It's when you're afraid that everyone
is gonna find out that you're a fraud
when, in fact, you are not.
What's it called when you really are?
Your job is not to be Severide.
Your job is to be yourself.
This is what Kelly
texted me when he heard
that Boden was keeping you on
as acting lieutenant.
"That's great.
"Joe is the best man for that job,
not just smart and competent,
but tough as they come."
So, you tell me.
Does he have it wrong?
Is Kelly Severide
a poor judge of character?
I had plenty of self-doubt
when I became lieutenant too.
So I speak from experience when I say,
don't second-guess yourself, Cruz.
Because nobody else second guesses you.
Yeah, I don't think
Bamford got that memo.
Then make sure to give it to him.
Yeah.
Hey, what are you doing here?
How's Tyler?
He's real good.
He's in a bath, but he'll
definitely wanna see you,
so come on in. I'll rush him along.
No, I can't stay.
I just wanted to bring you something.
Ariel, you guys have to get out
of this neighborhood.
It's not enough
to solve all your problems,
I know, but it should cover
first and last month's rent,
security deposit, maybe a little extra.
Where'd this come from?
I... I can't take this.
Could it help you?
Could get you away from all this?
- Of course, but...
- Then take it.
I wish somebody had gotten me
out of my bad situation
when I was his age.
So please, let me do this for him.
I...
I'm going to pay you back.
If you want. But take your time.
I'll just blow the money
on bad decisions, anyway.
Good luck.
Okay. I'm here.
Have a seat, Bamford.
Appreciate it. Thanks.
What's the occasion?
I can't have you smack
talking Capp and Tony anymore.
It's called ball busting, Cruz.
You do know you work
in a firehouse, right?
Not just any firehouse.
51.
Look, jokes are fine.
Pranks, gallows humor, blowing
off some steam, it's all good.
But we don't knock each other
down here in the process.
We lift each other up.
So you're gonna have to try and
do it our way while you're here.
Got it?
Okay.
I can do that.
Good.
Look at this.
Oh, she had heart eyes
for him from the jump.
Aw.
They actually make
kind of a cute couple.
What? They do.
Hey there.
- Hi.
- Is Carver here yet?
Haven't seen him. What can I get you?
I'll take a Manhattan, please.
You got it.
So how's that going?
Is... is that a thing, you two?
Overstepping, Violet.
It's fine.
We're very casual.
Um, I mean, he's not
a settle down kind of guy,
and I'm not a settle down kind of girl.
But if I was,
I wouldn't let him get very far.
Mm.
This is great. Thanks.
So what's the latest
with our friend Severide?
Speaking of very far.
Oh, I didn't mean it that way.
I'm gonna see him next weekend,
might just drag him back home with me
because I am not handling this so well.
Mm, do it.
They had a dress up date.
She looks so... happy.
Does anybody wanna buy
a couple of hotties a drink?
It would be my privilege.
You look beautiful.
Ah, it's just silliness, but we had fun.
Hey.
That's all I want, you know,
for you to feel good again.
Maybe that party was a stupid idea.
No, it wasn't.
We're gonna do a party,
but it'll be when we get the news
that all this is really over.
Because that is going to happen.
I believe that.
I love you something awful,
redheaded lady.
I know.