Good morning.
(JET ENGINES ROARING)
- Morning, Colonel.
- Oh, hi, Bill.
Well, did you make our
reservations for lunch at the club?
You and your easy living.
Boy, you better cut down
on some of that weight,
- or I'm gonna ground you.
- Oh, yeah? Look who's talking.
You know, Marty,
you're just jealous.
You're after my job,
and I know it.
You know, you may be right.
Okay, hero, let's get you
into your flight suit.
Right.
(TYPEWRITER CLACKING)
MARTIN: The flight is divided
into three phases.
Ground to maximum altitude,
maximum speed
and controllability
in the upper, thin air,
and reentry.
Now, the turbo jet engine
will lose its efficiency
at around 50,000 feet.
Allison will coast on up
to 75,000 feet,
and then cut in
the new rocket engine.
He'll level off at around
500,000 feet,
one hundred miles above
the earth, gentlemen.
For all practical purposes,
Major Allison will be in space.
Now, at this altitude,
he'll lower
the ventral stabilizers
and make his high-speed
stability flight,
progressing from position
one to 20.
Now, we know the X-80
is capable of a speed
of 5,000 miles per hour.
In the thin air
of 100 miles altitude,
with no resistance, who knows?
What we learn from this flight
will pretty well determine
our next step into space.
The satteloid...
A man in orbit.
You all set, Major?
Yes, sir.
Excuse me, gentlemen,
I'll join you
in Flight Control shortly.
MAN: Hello, tracking
station number two.
This is Sands Flight Control.
X-80 standing by for takeoff.
ALLISON: With your
permission, tower.
Am I clear to roll?
MAN: Weather clear.
You have a green light.
Good luck.
(ENGINES REVVING)
(ROARING)
(WIND WHIPPING)
ALLISON: X-80 to Sands Control.
Approaching altitude
40,000 feet.
Airspeed 1,200,
angle of flight
85 degrees, over.
Fifty thousand feet, Colonel.
Turbo power cutting out.
Hello, Control,
approaching 75,000 feet.
Cutting in rocket engine.
Hello, Sands, this is X-80
approaching altitude
400,000 feet.
Okay, Colonel,
there's a new record for you.
Good work, Allison.
How do you feel?
How's she handling?
No, pain, no strain.
Leveling off.
Proceeding with
Phase Number Two, over.
When you're ready, kid.
When you're ready.
This is X-80 to Sands Control,
approaching Position Number One.
Altitude 500,000,
airspeed 1,000-plus.
Central stabilizers in position.
You ready, Colonel?
Ready any time you are.
And the Lord be with you, over.
Sands Control from X-80.
Position Number Four.
Airspeed 2,000, 2-0-0-0.
We're going all the way.
X-80 to Sands Control,
position Number Eight.
Airspeed 6,000, 6-0-0-0.
Position 10, airspeed 7,000.
No instrument leaks.
(STATIC)
- What is it, Martin?
- I'm not sure.
(ELECTRONIC DRONING)
We've lost radio contact.
Colonel Martin, he's off
the tracking field!
Keep trying. Keep trying.
Sands Control to X-80.
Sands Control to X-8-O.
Come in, X-80.
Sands Control to X-80.
Sands to X-8-O. Come in, X-80.
(ELECTRONIC DRONING)
Reentry glide successful.
This is X-80 preparing
for a landing.
Are you reading me?
Come in, Sands Control.
(WIND WHIPPING)
Hey! Anybody here?
(MEN CHATTERING)
ALLISON: Did you make our
reservations for lunch at the club?
MARTIN: You and your
easy living.
Boy, you better cut down
on some of that weight,
or I'm gonna ground you.
ALLISON: Yeah, look
who's talking.
You know, Marty,
you're just jealous.
You're after my job,
and I know it.
MARTIN: You know,
you may be right.
Okay, hero, let's get you
into your flight suit.
ALLISON: Right.
(PIANO CHORDS CRASH)
Where is everybody?
Hey! Anybody here?
(HIGH-PITCHED DRONING)
(PINGING)
(FAINT ELECTRONIC WHIRRING)
(DRONING)
(BEEPING)
Who are you? Who are you?
What are you doing to me?
I said what are you doing to me?
Can't you hear me?
Get me out of this thing!
(ELECTRONIC WHIRRING)
Who... Who are you people?
Where am I, in a hospital
or something?
Where am I?
What's wrong with you?
Can't you understand me?
Say something!
I said answer me! Can't you...
Let go of me!
Oh, I'm... Sorry.
I didn't mean to do that.
(DRONING)
The new prisoner has been
cleansed of radiation,
my Master.
That is well.
Let us hope we find him
more cooperative
than the previous prisoners.
I hope Trirene has learned
something from his thoughts.
We must be very careful.
He will use all the known
tricks.
We can depend on that.
We will proceed with
the usual caution, Captain.
Who are you?
Major William Allison,
US Air Force.
Won't you sit down Major?
Sir, I'd like to ask
some questions.
I'm very confused
about what's happened to me.
Yes, of course, Major.
Ask your questions.
I'd like to know where I am
and how I got here.
And who all you people are.
And the air field...
What has happened to it?
The air base, my Supreme.
Yes, I left there
at 8:00 this morning.
A half hour later,
it was in shambles, deserted.
Where are Colonel Martin
and the others?
I... I don't understand.
You are from a nation
of speaking peoples.
How glorious that must be.
Our society's less fortunate.
Your society?
Yes, you see,
we here in our citadel,
save for my captain and myself,
are deaf-mutes.
Even my own grandchild, Trirene.
Deaf-mutes?
You mean, everybody?
I don't understand.
There will be time
for understanding,
if you are cooperative.
Now, tell us of your nation.
I don't know what you're
talking about, sir, I'm sorry.
You know very well
what we're talking about.
You're not the first spy
we've ever captured.
What do you mean, "Spy"?
I asked some simple questions.
I expect some simple answers.
I want some answers.
What is this you're wearing?
This symbol... What is this?
New devices to deceive us,
my Master.
We have seen such guises before.
They do not fool us.
It would be wise to tell us
all you know.
I'm Major William Allison,
United States Air Force, sir.
Serial number 03564629.
That's all I'm required
to tell you.
I will use other measures,
Supreme.
I will get to the truth.
Wait, Captain.
Major, we have saved your life.
You could have been
captured by the mutants.
Won't you cooperate with us?
With your permission, sir.
What was your purpose
in coming here?
I don't have any purpose.
You lie, you were spying on
our solar energy installation.
How did you find us?
Find you? I don't even
know where I am.
You're searching for
Karl Kruse and Dr. Bourman.
You're one of them, aren't you?
I never heard of them!
Where are your people living?
Would you really
like to know, Captain?
Yes, of course I want to know!
Well, at this very minute,
I don't know myself.
Captain...
He's impossible.
You're one of the scapes.
Admit it.
I'm an officer of
the United States Air Force.
I'd like someone to tell me
something that makes some sense!
Other nations, mutants...
What kind of talk is this?
He is very clever, my Supreme,
but I have a plan.
I can use him to our advantage.
Trirene does not approve
of your plan, Captain.
She has found some truth
in the major's thoughts.
I do not trust him,
especially his thoughts.
Even Trirene could be deceived.
Follow through with
your plan, Captain.
Yes, Master.
It will be done.
Let go of me! Let me go!
What are you doing?
What are you...
It appears you have more
than the usual interest
in this young Captain, Trirene.
He's very young-
This young man is an enemy.
We must be very careful.
I understand your wish, Trirene.
(MEN SHOUTING)
MUTANT: We see you, Captain!
We see you up there!
(MUTANTS LAUGHING)
Captain is alone! (LAUGHING)
Who are you?
I can't see you!
Good Lord.
What's wrong with you?
We will kill you, Captain!
Mutants! I'm not the captain,
you understand?
(MUTANTS GRUNTING)
Who are you?
You can talk! Answer me!
Yes, I... I... I will talk.
Stay back! I'll break his arm.
Now... The captain and his
people are your enemies.
Why?
They are listening.
They are listening
and watching us!
I don't care,
I want some answers!
Who are these people
in the citadel?
They are hiding from us!
They have food.
They have everything!
But we will find them.
All of them!
And kill, kill, kill them!
Why are they hiding?
They are infected, too.
They cannot escape!
Escape? Escape from what?
You are a scape...
Like Karl Kruse.
Who are the scapes?
You... You and Kruse,
you are scapes!
- We know!
- You left us to die.
You ran from the plague!
What plague, when?
Long ago... Long ago,
you left us here to die.
You did this to us!
We will find your hiding place
and we will kill all of you!
I did this?
Has the whole world gone mad?
(MUTANTS LAUGHING AND SHOUTING)
Young man, my granddaughter
has chosen to protect you.
She has expressed faith
in what you've told us.
My captain and I will
trust her judgment.
Trirene has a gift
we do not possess.
She has an extrasensory power.
She's able to perceive
every thought
within our minds.
Go with her, young man.
You will have the freedom
of our citadel.
And our child will be happy.
Oh, thank you.
Uh... Thank you.
Hey... Am I starved.
That looks great.
Uh, thank you.
Uh... Thank you.
Oh, I...
I... I was just looking around.
I mean, uh...
Trirene, I want to thank you
for rescuing me.
But, you know, that captain
seems determined
that I'm an enemy.
If you could only talk.
If I could only
make you understand.
I... I'll go out of
my mind if I...
You know what I'm thinking,
don't you?
You know how important
it is for me to find out
exactly what happened,
and how I got here.
The City?
You and all the people here
once lived in this city,
is that right?
No?
Hmm.
Oh, your grandfather,
the Supreme.
He lived in the city?
I see.
Your father?
And your mother.
They came here
before you were born?
Then you've never lived in the
air and sunlight, have you?
Trirene, tell me.
Why did they abandon that city
and move to this
subterranean world?
The mutants?
The plague? Was it the plague
they told me about?
Trirene, try to understand this.
I was on an air field
this morning.
In less than an hour,
everything had changed.
All the people I knew were gone.
There was no plague
where I came from.
What happened?
What happened to your
father and mother?
(TRIRENE CRYING SOFTLY)
The mutants killed them?
Oh, I'm...
I'm very sorry.
You know my thoughts
before I express them, so...
You know I'm going to ask you
about Karl Kruse.
Is he here in the citadel?
Look, would you take me to him?
I think if I can
get to Karl Kruse,
he can help me
understand all this.
(DOOR HISSING)
(HIGH-PITCHED WHOOSH)
Trirene gives me to understand
that you are one of us.
I don't know, I'm not sure.
I think you are.
How long have you been here
in the citadel?
Since this morning.
Well, I'm not certain.
I don't know.
I've lost track.
Time has very little meaning
here in the citadel, I fear.
Trirene informs me
that you have been here
for three turns of the earth.
That is three days.
I've only been in this place
a few hours.
I took off from the field
at 0800 this morning.
I had hoped that you'd
be able to explain this...
Do not excite yourself.
We will explain.
There'll be plenty of time.
Let me introduce myself.
I'm Karl Kruse.
Used to be General Karl Kruse.
This is Professor Bourman.
How do you do?
Major William Allison,
United States Air Force.
Did you say United States
Air Force?
Why, yes... What's so
unusual about that?
Major Allison, what year
was your flight in?
I told you, today...
This morning.
But what day and what year,
Major?
It is important we know.
March 5, 1960.
1960?
He's from before the plague.
How is this possible, Professor?
What is this plague
I keep hearing about?
You really don't know, do you?
No, I don't know...
I don't know where I am
or how I got here,
and I don't know
who these people are
in the citadel, either.
Well, Trirene has found herself
a big, good-looking playmate.
And a fiery one, too.
Major Allison,
this is ex-Captain Markova.
I don't know that I like
what you have on your mind,
Captain.
Maybe when you find out
what she has on hers,
you'll like that better.
What are you driving at?
They've giving you the run
of this place, haven't they?
Yes...
So little Trirene here
can get busy and...
(MARKOVA LAUGHING)
What kind of female are you?
I had to do it.
Don't you understand?
You mean, she was
reading your thoughts?
Things you didn't
want her to know.
That's right.
(BLOOPING TONE)
(TONE RISING)
(TONE DESCENDING)
We can talk now,
but not for long.
The captain will be
up here any minute
to see what's happened
to his gadgets.
Watch out for him.
He rules this place
with an iron fist.
Yes, so I found out.
He's determined
I'm an enemy spy,
a, uh, "Scape," he called it.
That's the name
they have given us...
We who escaped
the cosmic plague.
They hate us
for leaving them behind.
Luckily, we convinced them
they needed us.
Otherwise, we'd still be down
in the pit with the mutants.
We keep the solar power system
operating.
All their skilled men
have died off.
Then the mutants are the ones
who did not escape the plague.
- Is that right?
- No, the people here,
in this citadel, didn't either.
They are all first-stage
mutants themselves.
Is that why
they're deaf and mute?
And sterile.
Except for Trirene, perhaps.
Sterile?
Yes... They are a dying race.
There hasn't been a new birth
in this citadel
for the past 20 years.
That's where you fit
into the plan, Allison.
Make no mistake about it.
- What do you mean?
- Regeneration.
Trirene has chosen you
as her mate.
You're the last hope
of this society.
I don't understand it.
There wasn't any plague
this morning.
When did it happen?
Major Allison, have you any idea
what year this is,
right here, right now?
Well, of course I know
what year it is.
What's that got to do with it?
Everything...
Major, this is 2024.
- It's what?
- 2024.
Sixty-four years into
the future for you, Major.
The plague we are talking
about, it hadn't happened
in your world in 1960.
It began in 1971.
(STAMMERING)
An atomic war?
No, no.
The feared nuclear war
never occurred.
When man set foot on the moon,
all nations started
to work together
to push on into space.
By 1970, colonies had been
established on both Mars
and Venus.
Then, if it wasn't nuclear
war, what did cause it?
A bombardment
of cosmic radiation
from outer space.
Bombardment from outer space?
Oh, now, wait a minute.
You wait...
Now, listen to me, Allison.
The people of your world
are concerned
about nuclear fallout.
Well, heh, the danger is
in the other extreme.
The tons of radioactive dust
that have mushroomed up
into the ionosphere
since the very first
A-bomb test.
That dust has remained up there,
and it's slowly destroying
the protective screen
that has filtered deadly
cosmic rays from space
since time began.
Do you understand, Major?
Yes.
And all the nuclear explosions
that have ever taken place
on Earth
have contributed to this.
Yes.
And every human being left
has become mutant...
Or sterile...
Or a combination of both.
If what you say is true,
then Colonel Martin
and all the others
were caught up in it.
What's happened to them?
How can I find out?
There isn't any way.
Let's only hope they were
amongst the lucky ones
who could evacuate.
Evacuate?
Yes.
In 1973, the mass
evacuation began
to the planet colonies.
Only the uninfected ones
were permitted to go.
The ones left behind
moved underground
as fast as possible
and started building
networks of tunnels...
Like this one.
More than half the population
of the world was wiped out
during the first year.
I see.
When I landed on the air base,
it was completely destroyed,
demolished.
Deserted.
You landed? You didn't crash?
- (BEEPING)
- MARKOVA: The captain!
When they found you,
they destroyed your ship?
No, no... I left the air base.
They captured me afterwards.
Then your plane is in
operating condition,
sitting out there
on the air base?
Well, I suppose so.
Unless the mutants
have found it.
Well, Kruse, I see you've
become acquainted
with our new prisoner.
Yes, Captain.
And it is your good fortune,
as well as ours,
Major Allison has an excellent
technical background
and he's eager to help us.
And, as you know, Captain,
we are in dire need
of skilled help.
Well, we shall see.
Where's Trirene?
I believe she's returned
to her chambers, Captain.
I think she's expecting
a visitor.
Come along with me, Major.
We have some things to discuss.
Kruse, I'm warning you,
I'll tolerate
no more of your scheming.
If you persist, I'll see that
you're back in the dungeon.
We've got to get to the major
before they convince him
we're his enemies.
(HIGH-PITCHED WHOOSH)
But, unfortunately, I do not
understand such things.
I am not a scientist.
My concern is a military one.
I must save the last
of my people.
Then it is true...
Your society is doomed.
Major Allison, I must warn you.
Karl Kruse and his group
are shrewd.
They'll use you... They're
the most dangerous scapes
I've ever encountered.
It would be wise for you
not to associate with them.
Come, I'll show you
your chamber.
(ALLISON SIGHS)
Major, I must
tell you the truth.
Understand, it's not an easy
thing for me to do.
What they say about us is true.
We are sick and dying.
You cannot imagine with the
envy that I look upon you,
Kruse, and Dr. Bourman.
I myself am in the first
stages of mutation.
You?
For this reason, I have no love
for you who have
escaped the plague,
but as the Supreme has told you,
we will trust
in Trirene's judgment.
Major Allison, I ask you,
do nothing that will
bring harm to her.
For Trirene is our only hope.
(KNOCKING)
Trirene?
Trirene.
Trirene...
I want to talk to you.
Look, I... I'm very sorry
about the things.
Markova said to you.
I don't believe any of
the things they told me.
You know I'm telling
the truth, don't you?
You know, you're very lovely.
I keep forgetting
you can read my thoughts.
I wish you couldn't.
What can I say?
You're not angry?
You know, you have an unfair
advantage over every man.
(GASPING)
What are you doing here?
Ah, take it easy.
Don't you think I know what'll
happen to me if I'm caught?
You were spying on us.
Don't be foolish...
I couldn't care less.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Come here.
- I better get back.
- Wait...
Kruse has to see you.
He has a plan.
I don't know whether I'd better
be seeing any of you or not.
We may be able
to get you out of this
and back to your own time.
How can I possibly go back
to my own time
if I don't know how I got here?
You don't, but Kruse
and Bourman do.
Look, why should it be me?
Why not Kruse or Bourman?
Or... Even you, Markova?
There'd be nothing to be gained
by returning to our time.
It's different with you.
You're from before the plague.
You may be able to...
I may be able to prevent it,
is that what you mean?
Of course.
You've got to take this chance.
If you can get back to your
people and prevent the plague,
all this will never happen.
Let's go talk
to Kruse and Bourman.
Come on.
(BUBBLING)
(TICKING)
ALLISON: Yes, I agree...
I have to get back
to my time, to 1960.
Oh, we have
a very good chance, Major,
if we can reverse the phenomenon
that brought you here.
What phenomenon
did bring me here?
It is what we know
as a relativity paradox.
It's another dimension,
a fifth dimension.
Fifth dimension?
Professor Bourman's principle
of gravitation propulsion
brought it about.
By 1970, it became
the standard system
used to travel to the planets
at the speed of light.
The speed of light?
I thought 10,000 miles an hour
was fast.
(CHUCKLING) Yes, but there
is a pitfall
in the system.
At speeds approaching
that of light,
it is possible to break
the time lock.
The, um, barrier
that holds all things
in a normal time relationship
to each other.
That's what
happened to all of us.
We have slipped out
of one time sphere
and into another.
Captain Markova
broke through in 1973
during her third flight.
She was transporting supply
from Central Europe
to the Venus planet.
The captain's men
destroyed her ship.
It happened to Kruse and I
years later.
We had returned to earth
for an observation flight
in 1994.
Our ship crashed.
1994?
But the speed I approached
in the X-80
was nowhere near
the speed of light.
That may be.
But it was just enough
to create certain
mathematical conditions.
Let me show you.
Here, these symbols
represent the earth,
the sun, and your ship.
Now, consider these known facts.
The earth is rotating
at 1,000 miles per hour.
But it is also revolving
in orbit around the sun
at 66,000 miles per hour.
Time as we know it
is relative to these movements.
But the entire solar system,
together with other systems
of our galaxy,
are moving through space at
over six million miles per hour.
Theoretically,
you had a velocity
approaching the speed of light
before you ever left the ground.
Yes, but everything is moving
at that speed together,
as one unit...
The air, the earth,
according to the law of gravity.
Time is not affected
by the laws of gravity.
This is what happened to you.
At some point during
your high-speed flight,
you approached escape velocity,
Twenty-five thousand
miles per hour.
It was at this time that you
altered your flight angle.
If you hadn't, probably you
would have gone on into orbit.
It was this angle at a
specific altitude and velocity
that broke the time barrier.
For a fraction of a second,
you were suspended in space,
no longer interlocked
with the time spheres
of the sun and the earth.
Now, during this split second,
our galaxy moved onward in time
for what amounted to 65 years.
An instant later, you had
rejoined our solar system,
and the rest you know.
Yes.
Then, if I repeat
the altitude, angle of flight,
and speed, in directly
the opposite direction,
I should go back into time
65 years.
Mmm-hmm.
(DRONING)
Precisely.
Dr. Bourman is working
on the formula.
The three factors must be exact.
Then we must locate
an escape from the citadel,
- so I can find my ship.
- Right.
We must obtain an early map
of the citadel
with the tunnel work.
Your air base surely
must be included.
They began construction
as early as 1972.
The maps are on file
at the Supreme's chamber.
There is only one way
to get them, Major.
You mean Trirene?
- That's the only way.
- No.
No, I won't turn her
against her own people.
You have to do it.
- It's up to you, Major.
- (BEEPING)
KRUSE: You haven't much time
to decide.
Very well...
I'll do it.
You stay here.
I'll find my way back.
(WHIRRING)
(WATER SPLASHING)
Trirene, I've got
to have your help.
It's very difficult for me
to know what to do,
but there's something...
What would I do without you?
Trirene...
Tell me you know
I'm doing the right thing.
I've got to try and go back.
You do understand that,
don't you?
There won't have to be
any citadel.
You and your people can live
on the surface of the earth
without fear of any
cosmic plague.
They're waiting.
I made this tracing
from the original map.
Then Trirene returned it
to the archives.
Here, let me show you.
Now... Here's the citadel.
I remember a wooded area
and a hill.
The solar antenna
was atop the hill.
They must have hit me with
that paralyzing ray about here.
This outlet must be
Perimeter 22-B.
Here's the highway...
If I can find that,
I can follow it directly
to the air base.
We need the gun we have hidden.
- And your flight suit.
- Yes.
What about
the time lock formula?
I'm working on it now.
I'm almost finished.
If nothing goes wrong, Allison,
you can be on your way
within a few hours.
It should be no great problem.
Trirene will lead us
by the guards.
Good.
(DRONING)
(DRONING FADES)
No, it is not
the equipment, Master.
It's another one
of their devices
to prevent us
from watching them.
They're planning an escape,
and I know it.
I'll put a stop to this scheme.
Just say the word.
They will only try again.
Trirene is helping them.
I fear our future is done,
Captain.
We have returned to the cave
where men first lived on earth.
We have returned
to our birthplace to die.
Through Allison and Trirene,
there is hope, Master.
Perhaps it is too great a hope.
There may be some truth
in what they say.
Some chance that this young man
could return to a time
before the plague.
No, it's a trick.
We must not
let the major escape.
Do not forget, Master,
our observers
sighted mutant scouts
again yesterday.
This is a time
for great caution.
I will speak to him.
Perhaps I can persuade him
to accept our way.
Yes, my Supreme.
Let me bring him to you.
(WHIRRING)
(HIGH-PITCHED WHOOSH)
(GRUNTING)
What's the meaning of this?
Don't ask me questions.
The Supreme and I trusted you.
We're aware of your scheme.
I could explain to you forever.
You'd never understand!
I warned you to stay away
from those three.
Now you'll answer
to the Supreme.
Then you don't
believe it's possible
for me to return to my own time?
Kruse and Bourman think
the plague can be prevented
if I can go back
and inform my people.
I truly wish I could
believe your reasoning.
But they are using you
for their own purpose.
They'll bring others.
They'll destroy our citadel.
But you don't understand.
I'm from a time before
any of this has ever happened.
I must go back.
Such things do not exist.
Kruse has created these
illusions in your mind.
Look... As far
as I'm concerned, it's 1960.
You people can believe it's
2024 or any time you please.
None of this is real.
It's all an illusion to me.
No, my son.
You're wrong.
Here, touch my hand.
Is that not real flesh?
And these walls...
Are they not solid stone?
And Trirene...
You have touched her.
Can you say she's not real?
Yes, they are all
very real things!
But you can't prove
that what you say is true.
SUPREME: The only proof
I can offer is the fact
that here we are in this room.
Can you prove that
you are somewhere else?
Supreme...
Trirene believes
in what I'm trying to do.
You have faith in
her judgment, haven't you?
Yes, but Trirene
has fallen in love.
Please, I ask you...
Give up this futile scheme.
Remain here.
You will inherit our domain.
I'm sorry, I...
I value my freedom
more than this.
(MUTANTS SHOUTING AND LAUGHING)
Hear me, fellow prisoners!
Hear me, fellow prisoners,
you're free!
The citadel is yours!
Hear me, mutants!
Come out of your pit of death.
Our time of vengeance has come!
Follow me, soldiers of revenge.
I'll lead you to the captain,
to food, to freedom!
(MUTANTS SHOUTING)
So you will attempt this escape,
even though we'll
try and stop you?
Yes.
I'll try to escape,
even though the captain
offers all resistance.
You will never leave
the citadel alive.
Well, uh...
That's a chance
I'll have to take.
I didn't think for one minute
the Supreme would
change your mind.
Now you're my responsibility.
And I'm gonna take charge.
You're going back to the pit.
(MUTANTS SHOUTING)
They'll tear them to pieces!
Are you out of your mind?
You set them free!
It's part of the plan.
Get to your room
for your flying suit... Move!
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
Where are Kruse and Bourman?
We're meeting them
at the elevator up.
You'd better go in
and get Trirene.
We don't need her anymore.
The citadel's in chaos. The
guards won't bother with us.
You don't think I'd leave her
here to face this, do you?
I'm taking her with me.
You can't, Allison, you can't
take her back with you.
Ru try.
(DISTANT MUTANT SHOUTING)
Don't you understand?
You can't take her back through
the time barrier with you.
Your world is before
she was born.
I'll try anyway!
No.
From now on, it's you and me.
I'm going back through
the time barrier with you.
We're going back to my time.
1973.
The formula...
You're double-crossing
Kruse and Bourman.
Not for long!
(GUNSHOT)
(MARKOVA GROANING)
Leave her, Major.
There's no time, come on.
(DISTANT GUNFIRE)
(GUNSHOTS)
(SHOUTING AND GUNFIRE CONTINUE)
(GUNFIRE)
We're in luck.
The guards are being withdrawn.
ALLISON: What did you do?
BOURMAN: I had to do it!
You see?
He would have killed us all.
Like Markova, he wanted
to your plane, Allison.
I think you're lying, Bourman.
I think you're the one who
wanted to make that flight.
That will be all, Major Allison!
The Supreme was right
about you and Kruse.
Because we wanted
to return to 1994? Yes.
But you said I could prevent
the cosmic plague
if I could go back.
You could... But your people
won't believe you.
This is mass murder.
You're letting these people die!
I will never break
through the barrier
in 2024 again.
I will never know
anything about it.
Get out of your flight suit,
Allison.
You'll have to take it off me.
(GUNSHOT)
Trirene...
I'm sorry.
We're going back to my world.
We're free now.
I... I understand.
I'll take you
to your grandfather.
Now the shadow of death
darkens the halls
of our citadel.
Our bright ray of hope is gone.
It is the end of us.
No... No, it's not the end.
As long as we believe,
there is always hope.
I'll return to my time
and my people.
We will prevent the plague.
You'll not live
in a world of darkness.
I pray that this you believe in
is not a dream.
No, it isn't... I promise you.
I believe in you.
I lead you safely
to the surface.
I believe.
(ENGINES ROARING)
(ELECTRONIC DRONING)
(ROCKET BLAST)
Sands Control to X-80.
Sands to X-8-O.
Come in, X-80.
ALLISON: Hello, Sands,
this is X-80!
I'm in serious trouble!
Coming in for a landing.
Are you reading me?
Alert all crash detail
to stand by.
(SIREN BUZZING)
(SIREN WAILING)
(PLANE WHOOSHING OVERHEAD)
What room is he in, Sergeant?
Operating Room Two, sir.
How is he?
I haven't... Good Lord!
(NURSE GASPS)
What's happened to him, Doctor?
What could have caused this?
I don't know.
I have no explanation.
Not one word of this to anybody.
Keep me informed, Doctor.
I'll be in my office.
All right, Colonel.
Call the duty officer, Sergeant.
I want a guard posted
outside this door.
This is now a restricted area.
Yes, sir.
This is the office
of the Chief of Staff.
Connect me with Secretary
Lloyd Patterson's office.
Urgent.
ALLISON: Trirene was dead.
The Supreme gave me her ring.
He showed me the way out
of the citadel.
I got to my plane, and...
That's all I remember.
Thirty minutes later,
Allison brought the ship in
for an emergency landing.
Now the odd thing
about it is this...
Right after he reported in
at, uh, Position Six...
Major Allison is feeling
much better.
Good.
Mr. Secretary, General,
as you know, Bill Allison
is our leading research pilot
here at the test center.
We've always considered him
fully competent
and rational.
Dr. Richman and I have
been with him
for the past eight hours.
Dr. Richman and I are convinced
that he is as mentally sound
right now
as any normal,
well-balanced person can be.
I suggest we go in.
Mr. Secretary, General...
Mr. Secretary.
Thank you.
How 'bout it, kid?
Feel like talking?
ALLISON: I'm ready, Colonel.
Now, if you feel like
you need more room,
just say so.
ALLISON: Yeah, okay.
Any questions, gentlemen?
Mr. Patterson?
No, I... I don't believe so.
The plague... The cosmic plague!
None of us should go through it.
We've got to prevent it.
Prevent what, son?
The cosmic plague!
Marty, we've got to stop it!
Mr. Secretary,
from Intelligence.
They've run a check
on Professor Bourman
and Karl Kruse.
Kruse is enrolled
in a West German university.
He's a leading student
in astronautics.
And Bourman,
another student of physics
and mathematics in Amsterdam.
He's written papers
on new propulsion systems
that have astounded
the scientific world.
Colonel Martin...
This is Trirene's ring...
The Supreme gave me.
Gentlemen, we have got
a lot to think about.