Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
BLACK - ARAB - BITCH
I FUCK ALL BITCHES
Rondier,
is there a problem in the ER?
Yeah, there's a man without papers.
He won't budge,
he's on the floor drunk.
We're going to throw him out.
OK, coming.
Yes, hello?
Yes? You paged me?
It's the ICU resident.
You need me to bring the patient
from the ortho unit?
OK, I'll bring him right over.
It's funny, this woman
already had renal cancer, right?
- Yes.
- She's had kidney cancer.
Oh yeah, it's her. Renal cancer.
She was obese
and has had bypass surgery.
- It seems like...
- Some people...
They're lightning rods!
They get it all...
She had a hematoma.
It bled, spontaneously.
A blood vessel suddenly ruptured.
Either because of an aneurysm
or because of age or...
And this was a horrible spot.
The brain is like a funnel.
And the hematoma was
in the smallest point of the brainstem,
the major command center.
And it's only 5 cm thick.
It's surgically inaccessible.
If they hadn't operated on the bruise,
they'd have redirected the CSF fluid.
So it wouldn't swell in the brain.
Basically,
she could be brain-dead
in 48 hours.
It's a plumbing problem.
The surface fluid won't evacuate,
crushing her brain,
which still functions.
But its connection
with the rest of the body doesn't.
Like locked-in syndrome.
You know,
when someone is paralyzed?
Their eyes are open,
they hear, see,
but have lost the connection.
But hers is worse,
because it's larger.
She could be brain-dead in 48 hours.
Otherwise,
we'll extubate her on Monday.
And...?
And take her off assisted breathing,
but she can't breathe on her own,
so she'll die.
Her family understands.
Her daughter is a doctor, which helps.
We're also thinking of
potential organ donations.
But we're in no rush
for anyone to die.
Let's give it the weekend.
If she isn't brain-dead
in the next 48 hours,
she doesn't stand a chance.
If I'm ever locked-in,
pull the plug, I beg you!
Yes.
We've had a young tetraplegic in here
for 118 days now.
He went to the café
for the first time today.
118 days is long for a 25-year-old.
But he seems in good spirits.
He's a fighter. Still...
his life was turned upside-down.
From a car accident.
It's why we work in the ICU,
we can't get attached.
Most patients
only stay here about 10 days.
Having a patient
for 117 days is rare.
Yes?
Perfect.
OK. See you later, Nazim.
A patient got out of the O.R.
He's coming to the ICU.
It's a sad case.
He's a young 22-year-old
with colon cancer...
in palliative care.
It's sad.
At least we're improving
the last days he has left to live.
But it's untreatable.
He has a huge tumor
that can't be removed
in the colon.
And nodes in his peritoneum
are crushing
what's left of his intestine.
He probably weighs about 35 kilos.
In two weeks,
another node will crush
another part of the tube and...
I'm not religious or crazy,
but I believe in karma.
Some people drink, smoke,
and live to excess.
And live to be 100.
And you have
21-year-old kids like him...
He had a stomach ache
6 months ago and now...
No luck.
I don't know how many deaths
we've had in room 5...
Certain rooms,
for some strange reason...
- It's pure chance.
- It's true, room 5...
Yesterday, no, today,
someone died.
She's going to die.
She'll be replaced by someone else.
Some rooms are like that.
They're cursed.
That's why there's no room 13.
It's silly, but...
Working in the ICU
you develop a carpe diem attitude
because of the horrors you see.
You try to enjoy life.
And you have a very clear vision
on death and dying.
"What will be will be."
I do what I can for families,
but sometimes
I make them wait 1.5 hours
because I want to eat or smoke...
It's abuse.
Not deliberate abuse.
Thankfully, for most medics,
except for a few crazy ones,
it's never intentional.
We don't do it
to hurt the patients, but...
It drives me crazy.
In recovery,
if a patient's family calls,
I put the patient on the phone
whenever I can.
To talk with their family.
That alone is worth
all the medical briefs on earth.
The wife we saw earlier
had to wait 1.5 hours this morning.
I was caring for her husband,
I was busy, but...
there was no one there, poor lady.
No secretary at the reception.
She was all alone.
Imagine if I'd told her he'd died.
1.5 hours! It's just horrible.
We used to have a medical secretary
at the reception
to bring them water, to...
to give them updates:
"The doctors are with him."
But this lady was alone.
She'd see us running around.
It isn't right. It just isn't.
It's awful.
No-one left at the reception.
It's not the current policy.
It's about budget cutbacks,
downsizing personnel.
At night, you'll have
one hospital nurse for 20 patients.
Conditions are going downhill.
For four years,
this is the fifth year now,
we've been the top polytrauma center
in Île-de-France.
We're the number one center
in the capital, Paris.
And we get nothing.
We never get credit.
Not financially,
but for the sleepless nights spent
checking in injured patients,
because it can be
physically and emotionally exhausting.
Whether we have 0 or 600 patients,
it's all the same.
We just get an email saying:
"That's nice."
Sure, it's nice.
We didn't sleep for 320 nights.
But yeah, nice.
You stay up night after night
just to be given a badge
or a pen from the Public Hospitals.
- Quentin, go sleep.
- I was going to ask.
Go on, no worries.
- Page if you need me.
- Yeah? OK.
- Tomorrow at 8?
- Yeah.
To check the charts?
7:30 to look over
the 6 o'clock check-ups?
We'll call you if anything happens.
Goodnight, Quentin.
Ready to do the rounds?
I can feel it.
Does it hurt?
Or can you just tell
I'm doing something?
A bit of both.
It isn't very pleasant.
I'm pressing down hard.
Like I just told you,
I'm in the external cortical bone.
It's quite dense.
I'm using a self-tapping screw.
I hear noises too...
It's holding in place.
I'll add some smaller screws
to keep it in place.
I liked playing Meccano
when I was a kid.
- Me too.
- Not much has changed.
Yeah, it's a fun...
It's a really good game.
I've liked playing Meccano
since I was four.
Same here.
It forged my love of mechanics.
Aren't you a chemist?
Yes, but...
my passion and hobby...
Wow, it hurts a lot!
This one hurt?
Is the pain going away?
Yeah...
A bit.
I'd say 4 or 5.
Maybe it's too close.
Are you OK?
Kind of.
It hurt when I pushed?
Yes, I can really feel it.
There, I'm done.
We have a little problem
with the lens.
There's a little crescent
that's not right.
There seems to be another membrane here.
It's pretty unusual.
I think I see the pituitary gland.
It's like cotton candy.
Now you remove the tiny membrane.
And then...
you grab this.
There we go! Wonderful.
"Nice move", as they say.
Exactly! You just peel it off.
And now it's moving a lot more.
See? It's flowing now.
Try to remove some more.
It's a bit unusual.
That bit is really teasing you.
Well done.
It's a game! It's a game.
Let's take another look inside?
Hello? Turn on the light, please.
We saw the flap, possibly.
We can tell that...
the operation is going fine.
We saw the clivus' dura mater,
the basilar artery,
and that the edges
are beating properly.
So the ventriculostomy
is functioning well.
The structures are beating now,
but they weren't before.
We're now entering
the small cortical tunnel,
the little hole we made in the brain.
It isn't very deep, but it's real.
We're checking
we didn't cause too much bleeding.
It looks fine.
We'll start to see it
beating on the surface.
It isn't moving much now.
The closer we get to the cortex,
the harder it'll beat.
Now it's beating.
And it usually comes out...
And now we're outside.
There were quite a few blood vessels.
On the surface.
Oh yes.
And now our cortical chimney
is closing up.
Slowly.
Nurses in the O.R.
are also hair dressers.
Nice, right?
- Are you OK?
- Unfortunately, no.
My shoulders automatically tense up
the more...
the more I tense up.
I'm going to go. I'm going.
Goodbye.
Hurry up.
The lady is here.
She isn't nice.
Who?
Who isn't nice?
That lady...
I don't understand.
Yes, the lady. The lady there.
Which lady?
She's here.
Hurry up.
Please.
Hurry.
You can stop if you want.
You don't need to hold her hand.
No.
You were told to hurry up.
You don't need to hurry.
Hello, ladies.
Are you going on a walk?
You're nice.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
It's funny...
what you say
frankly doesn't affect me.
There's a lady sitting over there.
We know her.
Let's go see her.
The lady's here.
Can you hurry up, please?
Madam, can you hurry, please?
You should stop talking.
I'll be the prettiest dancer
At the ball tonight
The lady is here.
Everything OK?
I'm going to get my uniform
for Monday.
She's the one who's very important.
The most important.
I'm waiting for my husband to come.
A man you used to know.
What time is it?
Move along, ladies.
- 11:30.
- 11:30?
He's going to arrive soon.
Roland is here.
My husband Richard is coming.
Roland's here.
You aren't nice.
Where are you off to?
We aren't going far.
Hurry up.
You need to hurry.
Hurry.
The gentleman is here.
Shut up. Shut up.
Shut up.
The lady isn't here.
The lady is there.
There?
The lady is here.
No, she isn't here.
She's nice.
Let's go sit.
Hurry up. Hurry.
She's nice.
Hurry.
Hurry up.
Stand up!
They told you to stand up.
- What?
- They told you to stand up.
Come on. Come.
Grandpa, shut up.
In the small intestine
there's no sign of...
atrophy.
It's on the boulevard.
Near Louis XIV's hunting pavilion.
The population's changed a lot.
Rent has gone up in Clichy.
We don't charge our tenants much.
How big is it?
90m2 for three tenants,
with a 10m2 terrace,
parking space, basement...
And we charge less than...
1,800 a month.
But it's in Clichy.
It's fully equipped, brand-new.
In Paris, you'd get 50m2.
Cortex.
Polish.
Can you still see the light?
Three dots.
Look straight ahead, sir.
Turn down the light, please.
It's on the machine-gun setting.
I can set it to...
The Kalashnikov setting? Whatever.
Try the ballistic setting.
See if it's better.
You know the difference
between a phallus and a penis?
The penis isn't erect
but the phallus is?
That's why they say "nice phallus".
Lots of people have told me,
"You have a nice phallus!"
I'm going to stop here.
Because I'm tired.
This shit is so tiring.
We should get organized to know if...
I don't know! Ask your boss.
I want to finish with this patient.
And to do that,
we need to get organized,
instead of asking questions.
It's exhausting to have to push people
all day long.
- You're overreacting.
- Am I?
Listen...
You know, between two patients,
your crew is pretty fast.
- I know, I said so.
- Then don't say you have to push us.
I have to push everyone in the O.R.
Or we never finish!
One out of two Mondays,
we don't finish.
One Thursday out of two,
one Wednesday out of two...
Because the team isn't doing enough?
I don't know.
Or is the schedule too tight?
I don't know!
There are no tight schedules.
A tight schedule...
I need a vacation.
We're understaffed,
not enough nurses.
We aren't understaffed.
We have a thousand nurses.
They stand around smoking all day.
Oh stop it, just stop it.
And I'm not understaffed?
I see 100 patients
and operate on 20 every week.
100 patients, 3 consultations a week.
I'm a robot.
- Eddy's alone in the afternoons.
- Oh, stop.
They could do 3 in the a.m.,
3 in the p.m.
The problem is the organization,
not us.
We only need two nurses for this unit.
How often does he end up alone?
Easy for you to say,
we're the ones making up for it.
In 5 years of surgical nursing,
I never had to clean up.
But since coming here,
I usually do it
because I see how they're overworked.
- Then hire some porters.
- Exactly!
We have 5 million unemployed people
in this country.
That's what I'm saying!
- We'll hire a porter.
- We agree.
Otherwise we can't operate.
But management just tells us
to use temp workers.
I'm on the verge of a heart attack.
I'll try doing yoga, it'll help.
Yoga must be good for you.
I shouldn't feel
this constant pit in my stomach.
It isn't normal.
I haven't even had an erection today.
That's even less normal.
You can feel so lonely.
Roland's here.
There he is.
Hurry up, OK?
You were told to hurry up.
"Hu"...?
"Hurry up."
"Hu up?"
Hu... hu...
Come on, come with us.
Come with us, OK?
You're coming with us?
You're coming with us.
He's here, he's here, the gentleman.
He's here. Roland is here.
Roland is here.
Hurry up.
Look! We're on drugs!
Can you smell it?
No way!
We're not good here.
Then come with me.
We can't even see each other.
Drugs! Drugs!
I'll be right back.
We don't care about pink elephants.
I like elephants the way they are.
Yes, the gentleman is here.
Stop... stop.
How are you, sir?
You're... You're kind.
- You're kind.
- Thank you.
Yes.
OK...
The gentleman is over there.
But there's nothing we can do.
Nothing we can do.
Yaya, yaya, talk!
Transmit!
Affirmative.
Go straight up to the ER, Yaya.
Remember the guy with the red jacket?
The police have brought him back again.
No idea what's going on.
Just check everything's OK in the ER.
We need to examine you
because there's some bleeding, Madam.
I'm going to make sure
there are no anomalies.
Don't worry,
the baby's heartrate is normal.
There aren't any...
Was the placenta intact?
Can you move a bit?
Let your legs go down.
There you go.
Would you go out a few minutes?
We're going to examine you.
Just while we check the bleeding, OK?
Don't go too far.
Sit in the waiting room.
- I don't feel the sac.
- You don't feel it?
I don't feel the sac.
Oh, yes I do.
I'm going to press down
on your baby's bottom.
Now there's a contraction.
Do you feel something?
Do your contractions hurt?
What I'm doing is uncomfortable.
There are anomalies.
We're going to the O.R.
We're going to the O.R.,
the baby's heart has an anomaly.
Nothing major, but there's
some serious bleeding down below.
I don't want to take any risks.
- Let's test.
- OK. Testing.
Do you feel that, ma'am?
Yes.
Does it pinch?
They're big pinches.
Let's go.
19...
Everything OK?
Can we have more light?
Does that hurt?
There's a placental abruption.
- There's a RPH?
- There's a RPH.
There's a RPH, huh?
OK, let's go.
Your baby's coming, OK?
Push.
OK, great.
OK, your little sweety's coming.
Super. OK, Clamps!
Yes, super!
You sure wanted to scare us.
Hi!
That's right, my kitten.
What are you doing to us?
Huh, kitten?
I know.
Congratulations, Madam!
She's smaller than expected.
The placenta had separated.
That's why there were anomalies.
That's why there was bleeding.
- She's tiny, tiny!
- A little shrimp.
- You tiny shrimp!
- A pretty little shrimp.
Congratulations.
She was born at 21 minutes past.
6:21 p.m.
Let's see the pediatrician.
Give her a kiss before I take her.
Let's clean this up.
Don't worry...
The Synto is wearing off...
Good idea!
It had already separated anyways.
You don't say!
You and your jokes...
Come here, little one.
Let's go see the pediatrician.
You're so tiny.
You have the right to be mad.
You have the right.
What's going on here?
My little kitten.
It's all perfect.
That's right.
I know, I know...
Yes, everything's fine.
Everything's fine.
Everything is all right.
OK?
That's right.
Don't cry, everything is just fine.
Is it all right if I examine you?
Yes.
I know, I'm bothering you.
I'm bothering you.
Five little fingers.
You're strong.
Wow, what strength!
What strength.
There are three vessels in the cord.
I don't know if they noted it.
Sorry?
There are three vessels.
It's OK if they didn't write it down.
It says "2 edematous vessels"
but 3 vessels.
"Presence of three vessels."
Which is normal.
This is the placenta.
The baby is on this side.
Sorry, what am I saying?
The baby is on this side,
with the cord,
and this side
is attached to the mother's uterus.
OK.
This is the sac
that holds the amnion.
This is what ruptures
when your water breaks,
triggering labor.
Sometimes, you'll find vascular lesions
all over the parenchyma
when you cut it open.
This can indicate
miscarriages or delayed growth.
The lesion is in
the lower outer quadrant.
The tumor is located
in the lower outer quadrant.
"The tumor is located
in the lower outer quadrant: LOQ."
Right.
It measures...
It's bigger than I said earlier.
4...
by 2.5...
by 3.
Inner margin.
1.2.
And description of distance
to the lumpectomy margins.
And ink.
What does "inner margin" mean?
Upper inner quadrant.
Distance to margins...
Inner margin...
Write "1.2" here too, please.
- Black ink?
- Yes.
Inner quadrant.
Upper inner quadrant.
Wait, is that right?
That's wrong.
It's weird.
Do you weigh breasts here,
Jean-Pierre?
- Sorry?
- Do you weigh breasts in Macro?
Is it on the specs sheet?
"Tumor, nipple...
size, depth of margins..."
No.
There's nothing about weight.
Write in full:
"Location: union of inner quadrants."
It's lopsided.
The upper quadrant.
Upper margin: 2 cm.
"Upper margin: 2 cm."
Ink...
There's no ink.
This is atrocious.
Whoever did this did a horrible job.
Ask for a new slice
of the first one, please.
The slice is completely...
It's full of holes.
This can't be analyzed.
If I say there's no metastasis,
but it's in the hole...
Here, we have some hyaline tissue.
There are practically no more
tumor cells.
There are leftover tumor cells here.
These are tumor cells.
But I'll just say there's a tumor.
I won't go further into it than that.
It was too modified by chemotherapy.
The cells are too atypical to be...
The non-tumoral cells in this area
are these spindly cells, here.
This fibrous tissue neoplasm
holds it all together.
To support the...
the breast.
There are a few tumorous cells left,
but some areas have a lot more.
So, indeed...
That being said,
I sometimes write:
"Indicative degree after treatment."
It's dumb.
Very dumb.
I'll do it. We'll see if...
Anyways,
it's too hard to differentiate,
the atypia is pronounced,
there isn't much mitosis, so...
Do as you like.
Is it lobular, 3+2+1?
Yes.
The cells here are...
These are giant cells.
And these aren't tumorous.
They're cells
that reacted to foreign body cells.
The cells died during chemotherapy
and these cells clean up
the tumor necrosis.
After cleaning everything up,
it'll look like this.
You'll see a fibrous orange scar.
Like this.
Here, we have all the aspects.
It doesn't always work perfectly.
So you probably have
some residual tumor cells.
Unfortunately, it doesn't always work.
But this is a granuloma.
It's the intermediary step
before scarring.
These are tumor cells.
- Is that normal?
- No. They aren't normal.
They've been modified by chemotherapy.
They often get very big,
like those that survive chemotherapy.
Here, you have tumor cells.
They get into the nerve sheath.
It's called nerve sheathing.
It means the prognosis is bad.
It means the tumor
has managed to slide...
Although...
I'm not sure there is one,
because the vessels are so small.
- It might be a lymphatic embolus.
- Perhaps.
This woman had tissue removal.
Did she have metastases?
I don't think so.
They didn't give us any information.
It's a pain.
- As usual.
- That's gynecologists for you.
I'm not sure we have emboli.
Do you see any?
I don't know.
I'd say we have 30% residual tumors.
Maybe even 20%.
In the breast.
She was born in 60... 42.
That's why she has so many lobules,
she's still young.
Here is the nipple.
Cutaneous tissue.
The mucous membrane.
Cutaneous tissue of the nipple,
that's the surface.
And here, we have
the large lactiferous duct,
which brings...
or would have brought milk
to the surface.
It's a large caliber.
- It's a bad slice.
- A very bad slice.
You stuffed the cassette.
You should've done 2 slices.
You could've done more.
I do a lot for...
after chemo.
We have a good idea of
what you did, but...
I would take some more.
Can you do another slice?
It's a weird view, isn't it?
It's a weird view.
Yeah.
The only problem is that
in the video I watched
there was no medial lobe.
This one had one on the MRI.
Of course,
what you find online isn't always...
If we manage to do it in 1.5 hours,
that's not bad for the first time, right?
Yeah.
Careful with the forceps, Idir.
Want me to take them?
What forceps?
We can't let it bleed.
We need to be close to the Retzius.
Go ahead, bridge them.
Let me go under.
Go over me.
Over me.
Are you above me?
Pass above me and hold the bladder.
There you go.
- I'm above you.
- Like this.
I'm above.
Super.
I'm coming in closer...
I'm lost.
- What?
- I'm a bit lost.
Can you brief me?
We zoomed in too much, I'm lost.
It's getting a bit abstract.
It's a big prostate.
Can you clean an eye?
Can you see?
Yeah, I'm a bit lost.
Can you clean an eye?
This prostate is massive.
Here.
Pass me the...
the bag, please.
Clean up your table, it's a mess.
Do you see the medial lobe?
We'll look at the col
and you'll handle the rest.
Go ahead.
Can you pull the third arm up
a bit more?
It's super big!
It might not fit inside.
It'll fit inside.
Hold on, I'll go behind.
This guy's weirdly put together.
What's in my way?
I think it's your arm.
Can you pull on this crap?
- And don't pull from 15 miles away.
- No, no. I'll manage.
What are you doing?
Why are you irrigating?
- Olivier, are you irrigating?
- I think so.
- What are you doing?
- I don't know.
What do you mean?
Why are you looking at the screen?
- Look at the hole.
- The hole and between your hands.
Hold on.
- What are you doing?
- I don't know.
His dick is super swollen.
You really get on my nerves.
He has a horrible penile edema...
It's normal. It's called air.
What I'm doing is very complicated.
Plus, I'm not an expert in this field.
Now you're going to suck up
the fluids from the bottom.
Where is the suction tube?
- It fell on the floor.
- Fuck!
Damn it!
Is it clean?
Yes.
Take the suction tube
and get that corner, please.
I'm putting it together.
They gave me a shitty one.
Shut up.
Give him a fucking suction tube!
What are you doing?
We need another suction tube.
- I know, we're all out.
- Are you serious?
What's going on?
Give him the suction tube!
He's playing LEGO.
I'm not playing LEGO.
Right here.
And screw it, like this. Yes.
Take the big one.
And plug one end into each hole.
One for sucking, one for rinsing.
It's the same tunnel system.
He dropped the tube.
Give us the other one.
I'm out of 45's.
- What do you have?
- Just this.
I know it's not the same,
but it's all we have.
Careful...
We have a problem.
We'll see if it's Niagara Falls or not.
It's leaking right here.
Stop! I see it clearly.
It's leaking really bad.
Let's do an X stitch
with the big V-lock needle.
Will this work?
- What just happened?
- It's nothing, don't worry.
What a nightmare!
We're going to try something.
I don't know what, but...
It won't work.
We'll need more sutures.
But for now...
I'll back up
so you don't stick in just anywhere.
OK, go.
These forceps are screwed up.
Why are you sucking now?
I'm not, it's just the...
OK, let go.
Make sure the thread
is completely through.
Nothing is coming out.
OK, stitch the edges.
Hold on...
- You need to hurry, Olivier.
- I know, I know.
- I'm stitching.
- Do it, fuck it!
Yes, it's in. I'm coming.
Come on, Olivier.
This is bad. Very bad.
I never should have started this.
I really shouldn't have started.
We need to change the probe
to check the drained bladder.
This patient will need a catheter.
I watched the Master Class
by that Indian guy.
He said patients with medial lobes
aren't good cases.
- Hi, Rachid.
- How are you?
- Really bad, man.
- Why?
This prostate almost killed me.
It's a bad one. I wanted to do
a Retzius-sparing from behind,
but it's my first time.
And an anastomosis on a big prostate
is really tough.
- Did you open the front?
- No, I didn't.
Stop the insufflation
and set it to the side.
Watch his face.
Cover his face.
Normally, it should be... For security.
Right, security!
Look, it's too big.
Give us some light.
Can I use this?
Yes, it's ours.
Hand me the electric scalpel.
I hope it didn't fall.
- It's on the floor.
- Yes.
- It's on the floor?
- I didn't check.
- Olivier?
- I don't know.
If it fell, it fell.
Strange he hasn't peed.
Last time, it didn't turn out well.
PARIS HOSPITALS 2008
PUBLIC ASSISTANCE
So you locked him in?
He's coming out.
Yes. Yes.
The door's open. Super. Super.
Really super.
We can leave it like this.
Yes.
- Oh yes.
- There.
This is the façade.
I'm off.
I say, "see you later."
All right.
What time does she leave?
I think she's the last to go.
Are you comfortable?
Everything is all right?
It's funny,
there's a vein in the pedicle.
When we draw back, it bleeds.
We had another case like that.
The 4th or 5th patient.
There was a lot of bleeding.
And the curves were...
There's been a huge increase.
That's why we have 22 perfect cases.
We can't explain why
it's increasing so much.
There's no gap.
Yes, we're seeing
pedicles with vessels.
Vessels or an angioma.
Or remainders of the growth plate,
which should be...
- But he's big, right?
- Yes.
But even with pigs.
We operated on a little pig
which had some cartilage.
It's really increasing.
In contact with growth plates.
Poor animal.
It's all in the name of science!
Always.
More, more, more.
Stop.
I'll let you cut.
I assembled some furniture
instead of children.
I ruptured my biceps.
- Perfect.
- A real rupture?
I only have 10% tissue left
on my biceps.
Near the elbow?
I lifted a 50-kg box and felt a...
Careful,
some bits of bone are falling off.
Are you going to have surgery?
You kidding?
May God preserve me from hand surgeons!
I'd be 10 years younger
if you'd operated on me.
You should ask the manufacturer
to fix this.
We can't adjust it anymore.
I tried fixing it last week, it's stuck.
It's a pain.
And so... Go ahead, have at it.
We have an advanced stage
of kyphosis.
Hand me that.
I'll straighten it out.
And now...
Hand me a screwdriver.
We're going to change our...
Let's change our gloves.
A bit more water, please.
Wake up, big guy! Open your eyes.
It's over now.
You're all tangled up, big guy.
Hang on, just a few more seconds.
Chief, do you receive me?
I'm listening.
Send someone up to the 15th.
A man in the hallway
is saying his prayers.
5th floor east wing?
15th. 15th floor, east wing.
OK, message received.
An old man in a black suit.
We put it on backwards.
Are you serious?
Let's start again.
How to jump into your briefs
without touching the elastic!
I don't know if they're his size.
Yes, they are.
Are you serious?
Look at those hands!
Right? If he hit you,
you'd definitely feel it.
Give me his hand.
His sweater is too snug.
It should be on top.
Let him do it.
Excuse me, ladies, gentlemen.
Let him try.
He wants to try, let him.
You want help?
Yes. Ground floor.
- Are you managing, sir?
- Ground floor.
We're going down. Down.
Will you come back? We tried.
We're going down.
Going down here. Here.
No, no, no.
Yes.
- Let's keep moving.
- Wait, we're going down.
Come with me, it's stuck.
- Going down here.
- Let's go.
We're going down here.
To see if it goes down.
- We'll need to put you in the room.
- If it goes down.
- We need to put you in your room.
- Not the room.
Then come with me.
- Not yet.
- Yes.
Not yet.
I'm going to get my colleague.
- Listen...
- Yes, I'm a man.
I'm warning you.
Come with me,
or you're going to your room.
- In my room.
- We'll come back.
In my room.
We'll come back.
Come on, let's go.
- To my room.
- I have work to do.
- Let's go, please.
- Yes, we're going.
You usually come.
- Let's try the other side.
- Let's try this side.
This side.
I'm going to get my colleague.
Let's keep trying here.
Who is your contact? Your contact?
- He's over here.
- Yes? Who is it?
- Hervé. You know him?
- Who is Hervé?
Who is Hervé?
You were good this morning.
We didn't have any problems.
- Let's go.
- Yes. Yes.
He's here.
Sir?
Hervé is coming.
We're putting you in your room. OK?
In my room? My room?
Because you won't listen.
- It isn't worth it.
- Come, sir.
- Hello, sir. How are you?
- Hello, Mr. President.
- Come this way.
- I'm trying to touch it.
- We're leaving with Régis.
- I don't want to do room.
I don't want to do room.
Yes, but you always try to leave.
That's the problem.
- I try to leave.
- What can we do?
Our hands are tied.
Why the hell am I here?
You're waiting for the doctor.
He's just going to come
and tell me that I'm fine.
He's not a real doctor.
I want to die.
I don't want to live.
I want to leave.
I want to die!
We'll put him in his room, Régis?
- In his room?
- Yes.
I don't want to do...
I want to work, like you.
This way.
We need to finish the dishes.
So you'll go to your room
for 30 min. OK?
Yes.
Is that all right?
- Half an hour?
- Half an hour, as promised.
As usual.
- That's all. Then you can come out.
- That was fun, right?
- It was a nice walk.
- Half an hour?
Yes, and then we'll come back.
- Just 30 min.
- 30 minutes, for sure?
- We promise.
You'll open in 30 min?
- What time will it be?
- 30 min?
- 11... 11:25.
No, that's 1 o'clock. It's 1:30.
So we'll open at 2 o'clock.
2 o'clock.
No, 2:25. It's 25 now.
- How long is that?
- That's one hour.
That's too expensive.
- You mean, too long.
- Too a lot.
OK, 2 o'clock, then.
That's in 35 minutes.
OK, let's do that.
OK? Thank you, sir.
We'll do that.
See you soon, in 35 minutes.
I'll clean up, because it's new cloth.
Yes, you do that.
OK, take care of that.
- 14 min.
- See you soon.
35 minutes!
See you soon.
Thanks, Hervé.
One day, it all became too much.
Too much suffering, death,
and distressed families.
You went back through the O.R. doors,
returning to anesthesia.
Even though you mix up
Sufenta and noradrenalin,
otherwise, you're doing great.
You try your hand
at philosophy and ethics in general.
The Ethical Café in Beaujon,
whose posters makes France's
Depressed Anonymous green with envy.
But you get a kick out of it.
And one day, you get the call:
Canada wants you.
OK, they got a little mixed up,
thinking you're an expert
on liver transplants.
Some say
it's the score of the century,
like Armand and me in New England.
But you can't lie
and now you're in RHD
to finally understand
how the liver works.
Your mustache twirls.
You stand before 4 lobes, 8 segments,
arteries and veins all over.
But you hung on
and became an expert on everything.
With your bags full of knowledge,
memories, and friends for life,
you're off on new adventures.
On behalf of 1,009 of us,
we wish you, dear Pierre, all the best.
I'll end with a quote by
Antoine de Saint-Exupéry.
Stan, I know you expected a quote
from Maître Gims or Patrick Sébastien.
"The challenge is not
to foresee the future,
but to make it possible."