Savree maranun
verabonun verobotay.
Barooch ata adony
elohaynou melech aholam.
Borah pree hagafan.
Barooch ata adony
elohaynou melech aholam.
Asher kideshano bemitzvotaiv...
verazha banou veshabat kodsho...
behava hencheel lanoe.
Zecaron lemase berashit
ke hoe yome...
techelah lemekray kodesh...
zecher letziat mizraim.
Kee banoe bacharta
veotano kedashta mekol hameem.
Veshabat kodsho
behavat razone.
Henchaltanoe.
Barooch ata adony mekadesh
hasabat.
September 1939, the German forces
defeated the Polish Army in two weeks.
Jews were ordered to register all family members and relocate
to major cities. More than 10,000 Jews from the countryside arr
- Name?
- Horowitz, Salomon.
Schneider, Sarah.
Birnbaum, Olga?
Over there. Over there! Kommen Sie Doch.
- Isak Hudes.
- Hudes, Isak.
Zucker, Helena.
Hirsch, Salomon? Mandel,
Maria. Hirsch, Salomon.
- Hauptman, Chaim!
- Weisman! Weisman, Marcus!
- Feber, Ludwig!
- Feber, Ludwig.
Elsa Bauman.
- Josef Klein.
- Klein.
- Davidowich, Ignacy. - Paula
Biffer. - Nadel, Rachela.
Steiner, Gertruda.
Steiner, Hilda.
Jerzy, you know who that
man is? I don't know.
Let's get together,
please.
Smile. Good.
Yes, sir.
Bring them over
a round of drinks.
Very good, sir. And who
shall I say th-they are from?
You can say
they are from me.
From the gentleman.
Where?
Do you know him?
Find out who he is.
Yes, sir.
Agnieszka, I would
give anything...
to hear you
sing tonight.
But I know you won't.
You embarrass me.
What's he doing?
Stay here.
How are you doing?
You'd leave a woman alone at
the table in a place like this?
Sweetheart, you're the
picture of loneliness.
Oh.
Mmm, what a lovely fragrance.
You are breaking my heart.
An extra chair, please.
Vodka for my friend.
And for the lady?
Pernod.
# Im Grunewald, im Grunewald
ist Holzauktion #
# Ist Holzauktion #
# Im Grunewald, im Grunewald
ist Holzauktion #
Come to the table, girls! Drink
with us! # Ist Holzauktion #
# Links um die Ecke 'rum,
rechts um die Ecke 'rum #
# Ueberall ist heute
Holzauktion #
Come to us!
Marry us!
# Der ganze Klafter
Suessholz kostet 'nen Taler #
# 'Nen Taler, 'nen Taler #
# Der ganze Klafter Suessholz
kostet 'nen Taler #
# 'Nen Taler... ##
Thank you. I'll tell you
what I mean by cooperative.
Two days after the law is passed
that allJews have to wear the star,
theJewish tailors are turning
them out by the gross...
in a variety of fabrics
at three zloty each.
Tell me about
your cellar wines.
I have an excellent German
Riesling. 1937. Mmm, French.
A Bordeaux. Chateau Latour,
'28, '29? No, I'm sorry.
It's as if they have no idea
what kind of law it is.
As if it's the emblem
of a riding club.
A Margaux, '29? No,
no, we don't have that.
Burgundy then? A
Romanee-Conti, '37? Yes.
It's human nature.
"We'll do this to avoid that. "
That's what they have done
since thousands of years.
It's what they do.
They weather the storm.
But this storm is different. This is
not the Romans. This storm is the SS.
# Wem Gott will
rechte Gunst erweisen #
#Den schickt er
in die weite Welt #
# Wem Gott will rechte
Gunst erweisen #
#Den schickt er in die
weite Welt #
#Faleri, Falera #
#Faleri
Falera-ha ha ha #
#Faleri, Falera #
#Den schickt er
in die weite Welt #
Martin?
Yes, sir.
Who is that man?
That...
That's Oskar Schindler!
#Faleri
Falera-ha ha ha #
#Den schickt er
in die weite Welt #
#Faleri, Falera #
#Den schickt er
in die weite Welt ##
To Krakow!
An alleJuden!
Ab sofort ist es allen Juden
untersagt...
Fleisch aufkoscher Art
zuzubereiten.
Meldung an alleJuden.
Ab sofort...
THE JUDENRAT The Jewish Council comprised of 24 elected Jews
personally responsible for carrying out the orders of the regime
Rabbi... Private property
cannot be confiscated.
How long are the schools going
to be closed? I do not know.
Article 47: Pillage is formally
prohibited. You don't know anything!
I am familiar with the Hague
Convention. Religious...
They come into our house and tell
us we don't live there anymore.
It now belongs
to a certain SS officer.
Please. I only know
what they tell me.
And what they tell me
changes from day to day.
Aren't you supposed
to be able to help?
I mean, what if I just
took this thing off?
What are they going to do
about it? They will shoot you.
Why don't you stop this
silly talk? Itzhak Stern!
I'm looking
for Itzhak Stern.
Are you Itzhak Stern
or not?
I am.
Where can we talk?
There's a company you did the
books for on Lipowa Street.
Made what?
Pots and pans?
By law, I have to tell you,
sir, I'm a Jew.
Well, I'm a German.
So there we are.
A good company, you
think? Modestly successful.
I know nothing about enamelware. Do you?
I was just
the accountant.
Simple engineering though,
wouldn't you think?
Change the machines around,
whatever you do,
you could make other
things, couldn't you?
Field kits, mess kits.
Army contracts.
Once the war ends, forget
it, but for now it's great.
You can make a fortune,
don't you think?
I think most people right now
have other priorities.
Like what?
I'm sure you'll do just fine
once you get the contracts.
In fact, the worse things get,
the better you'll do.
Oh, well, I can get the signatures
I need. That's the easy part.
Finding the money to buy
the company, that's hard.
You don't have
any money?
Not that kind of money.
You know anybody?
Jews, yeah.
Investors. You must
have contacts...
in theJewish business
community working here.
What community? Jews can
no longer own businesses.
That's why this one's in
receivership. But they wouldn't own it.
I'd own it. I'd pay them back
in product... pots and pans.
Pots and pans. Something they can use.
Something they can
feel in their hands.
They can trade it on the black
market, do whatever they want.
Everybody's happy.
If you want, you could
run the company for me.
Let me understand.
They'd put up all the money,
I'd do all the work.
What, if you don't mind
my asking, would you do?
I'd make sure it's known
the company's in business.
I'd see that it had
a certain panache.
That's what I'm good at,
not the work. Not the work.
The presentation.
I'm sure I don't know anybody
who'll be interested in this.
Well, they should be,
Itzhak Stern.
Tell them they should be.
Achtung! Achtung!
An alleJuden...
Ab sofort ist es verboten...
Vere dignum et justum est,
aequum et salutare,
nos tibi semper et
ubique gratias agere,
Domine Sancte, Pater Omnipotens,
Aeterne Deus.
I've got a client who'll sell
marks for zloty at 2.45 to 1.
Wool, mink collar.
It's a nice coat.
She'll trade it
for ration coupons.
Wicks, for lamps. You
have a truckload of wicks?
What am I going to do with a truckload
of wicks? Nine by 12, nine by 14.
I don't know.
Big, beautiful, Persian.
Lumen aeternum mundo effudit...
Psst.
What?
You don't recognize this?
It's shoe polish.
In metal containers? You
asked for shoe polish.
In metal containers. This is
glass. In metal containers.
It's not what I asked
for. What's the difference?
What's the difference?
Shh! My client sold it to his client,
who sold it
to the German Army.
Only by the time it got there, because of
the freezing cold, it broke. All 10,000 units.
Mmm, ooh, ooh, ooh.
This is not my problem.
This is not his problem.
This is not your problem?
This is not my problem. All right.
The German Army wants to
find out where it came from.
I am going to make sure they
find out. Now it's your problem.
You be quiet!
Metal
containers.
Hello.
Pardon me for interfering,
but that's a nice shirt.
Nice shirt.
Do you know where I can
find a nice shirt like that?
...laudare, benedicere
et predicare.
Like this?
It's illegal to buy or sell
anything on the street.
We don't do that.
We're here to pray.
Jesum Christum Dominum Nostrum...
Do you have any idea how much a shirt
like this costs? Nice things cost money.
...adorant Dominationes,
tremunt Potestates.
Coeli coelorumque
virtutes ac Beata Seraphim...
socia exultatione
concelebrant...
How many?
I'm going to need some other
things, too, as things come up.
This won't be a problem.
From time to time.
Achtung! Achtung!
MARCH 20, 1941
DEADLINE FOR ENTERING THE GHETTO
Edi
- Name? Adresse?
- Formular ausfuellen!
Weiter, weiter!
Nicht draengeln!
Kommen Sie hierher!
Stellen Sie sich doch an!
Achtung, achtung!
AlleJuden sind verpflichtet...
im abgesonderten
juedischen Bezirk zu wohnen.
Nichteinhaltung der Meldepflicht
bei der Einwohnerbehoerde...
verstoesst gegen das Edikt 44/91
und fuehrt zur Anzeige...
beim Militaergericht.
This is obviously the right place.
How are you doing? Herr Schindler.
Good-bye, Jews!
This iz the vechteka, Moyshe. Ojciec.
Nyne, this kan
neash zyane.
Oh, my God.
Oy, God.
It could not be better.
It could be worse.
How? Tell me.
How on earth could it
possibly be worse?
Dzien dobry.
Hey, Goldberg.
Poldek.
What's this? Uh, the Judenrat
has its own police now.
You don't say.
Ordnungsdienst.
I'm a policeman now, could you
believe it? It's hard to believe.
Oh, no, it's not hard to believe.
It's a good racket, Poldek.
The only racket here.
Look, maybe I could put in a good
word for you with my superiors.
Your superiors? Come on, they
are not as bad as everyone says.
Well, they're worse than everyone
says, but it's a lot of money.
A lot of money.
Give me my
housing assignment.
Come on. You look funny
in that hat, Goldberg.
You look like a clown,
you know?
He's a very important man.
Just give him
two minutes of your time.
Since when did time cost money?
Just sit down and listen.
Please.
Sir?
For each thousand you invest,
I will repay you with...
Two hundred. 200 kilos
of enamelware a month,
to begin in July and to
continue for one year.
After which time, we're even.
That's it. It's very simple.
Not good enough. It's not good enough.
Not good enough?
Look where you're living. Look where
you've been put. "Not good enough. "
A couple of months ago you'd
be right, not anymore.
Money's still money.
No, it is not.
That's why we're here.
Trade goods...
that's the only currency...
that'll be worth
anything in the ghetto.
Things have changed,
my friend.
Did I call
this meeting?
You told Mr. Stern
you wanted to speak to me.
I'm here.
I've made you a fair offer.
Fair would be
a percentage in the company.
Forget the whole thing.
Get out.
How do we know that you
will do what you say?
Because I said I would.
You want a contract?
To be upheld by what court?
I said what I'll do.
That's our contract.
...mielismy racje.
Piec, szesc, siedem...
osiem, dziewiec.
The standard SS rate for Jewish
skilled labor is seven marks a day,
five for unskilled
and women.
This is what you pay
the Reich Economic Office.
TheJews themselves
receive nothing.
Poles you pay wages. Generally,
they get a little more.
Are you listening? What
was that about the SS?
The rate? The what?
TheJewish worker's salary... you pay it
directly to the SS, not to the worker.
He gets nothing.
But it's less.
It's less than what I
would pay a Pole. It's less.
That's the point
I'm trying to make.
Poles cost more.
Why should I hire Poles?
An enamelware factory
over at, uh, Lipowa Street.
It, uh, it, um...
It's owned by a German.
But it's outside the ghetto, so
you can barter for extra goods...
for eggs, I don't know
what you need...
with the Polish workers.
You can't get it here.
Also, he's asking for ten healthy
women for the... I am healthy.
Bring your sister, okay?
Chodz.
You need to convince them you have a
trade, something valuable to the war effort.
Like what? What if you
don't? I'm a musician.
Your name goes on a list.
And they put you on trucks...
No, no, no, that's not
true. You're a musician?
Yeah. I'd find a good
hiding place if I were you.
I'm not going to hide like some
animal. There are places to hide.
Der Naechste!
I'm a graduate
of the University of Lwow.
I used to work at the
hydroelectric station in Roznow...
Blauschein.
I'm gonna get the necessary papers
because this card is no good anymore.
You can stay in this line all
day, you'll still get one of these.
They are no good. You'll
have to leave the line now,
then you'll get a blue card, a Blauschein,
to say that you are an essential worker.
I'll get these papers
for you at Pankiewicz.
Pharmacist.
Just there, look.
Guess who is here?
Poldek! Enjoying
the weather, Poldek?
Enjoying the lines?
Need some shoe polish?
In a metal container
maybe?
Not essential? I think you
misunderstand the meaning of the word.
No Blauschein, sir.
Stand over there.
Move. Next!
What do you mean,
"Not essential"?
I teach history and literature.
Since when is not essential?
He's a metal polisher.
It was not right? It's very
good. He's 53 years old.
It's too new. Mmm. Thank you.
You're crazy. You
left it in your drawer.
How many times
have I told you?
Your work certificate you keep
in your pocket at all times.
And you leave everything
in your drawer.
How many times I've told you?
I'm a metal polisher.
Take the round sheet of tin,
dip it in soap emulsion.
Then place it centrally
in the press.
We obtain the soup pot.
The soup pot.
Soup pot.
Grosz, Mrs. Grosz,
stay together.
Sir, I have ten work permits here
for the Deutsche Emailwarenfabrik,
cosigned by Mr. Bankier
and myself.
If it's carbonized,
clean it with a file.
But don't touch both the
electrodes at the same time.
You'll get electrocuted.
Here, have a try.
Roll the metal
under the press,
but be very careful
unless you want your fingers...
to become part
of the teapot.
Occupation? I'm a
writer. I play the flute.
But Moses is
a skilled metalworker.
He can make tin pots.
He can make tanks.
He can make whatever
Mr. Schindler asks.
He's highly skilled.
Give him your card.
Moses, give him your card.
Now, dip the basin
with the tongs...
into the enamel solution.
And after swiveling it around,
carefully place it aside to drip dry.
And whatever he asks you, allow me
just to represent you and speak for you.
Don't say a word.
Filing, billing, keeping track
of my appointments, shorthand.
Typing, obviously. How is
your typing? Uh, all right.
Please.
You need a secretary.
Pick one.
I don't know how. They're
all so... qualified.
You have to choose.
Prosze sie ladnie usmiechac.
Big smile. Big smile.
Uwaga.
If you would,
look after my guest.
Um, boxed teas are good.
Coffee, pate, um...
kielbasa sausage, cheeses,
Beluga caviar. Yes.
And, of course, who could live
without German cigarettes?
Get me as many
as you can find.
And some more fresh fruit.
The real rarities...
oranges, lemons, pineapples.
I need several boxes of
Cuban cigars. The best. Yes.
And dark, unsweetened chocolate. Not in the
shape ofladyfingers, the chunk chocolate.
Yes. Big as my hand, you
sample at wine tastings.
We're going to need lots
of cognac. The best, Hennessy.
Dom Perignon champagne.
Um, get L 'espadon sardines...
and, oh,
try to find nylon stockings.
It is my distinct pleasure
to announce...
the fully operational status
of Deutsche Email Fabrik...
Patrzjakies szmaty!
Manufacturers of superior
enamelware crockery...
expressly designed
and crafted for military use.
Utilizing only
the most modern equipment,
D.E.F. 's staff of highly-skilled and
experienced artisans andjourneymen...
deliver a product
of unparalleled quality,
enabling me to proffer, with
absolute confidence and pride,
a full line
of field and kitchenware...
unsurpassable in all respects
by my competitors.
See attached list
and available colors.
Anticipating the enclosed bids
will meet with your approval.
Made in Havana, Cuba. Looking forward to
a long and mutually prosperous association.
Look at this. I extend to you in
advance my sincerest gratitude...
and very best regards.
Oskar Schindler.
Yeah, I need 700 gross
from here for next Thursday.
Nine hundred... No, make
it ten for Wednesday.
All this stuff here goes to Madritsch's
factory on Tuesday of next week.
My father was fond of saying,
"You need three things in life:
"A good doctor,
a forgiving priest...
and a clever accountant. "
The first two...
I've never had much use for.
But the third...
Just pretend,
for Christ's sake.
Is that all?
I'm trying to thank you.
I'm saying I couldn't
have done this without you.
The usual thing would be
to acknowledge my gratitude.
It would also, by the way,
be the courteous thing.
You're welcome.
Get out of here.
Klonowska, who is it?
She's so embarrassed.
Look at her.
You know something?
You would like her.
Oskar, please.
What?
I don't have to like her... just
because you do. You would, though.
It doesn't
work that way.
You've done well here.
You look wonderful.
Be careful of the step,
miss. Mrs. Schindler, Marek.
It's not a charade, all this?
How could it be a charade?
The clothes, the car, the
apartment. Wait a minute.
Take a guess how many people
are on my payroll. Oskar.
My father, at the height of his
success, had 50. I've got 350.
350 workers on the factory
floor, with one purpose.
To make pots and pans?
To make money.
For me.
Does anyone
ask about me?
Back home?
Everybody.
All the time.
Hmm.
They won't soon forget the name
Schindler here, I can tell you that.
"Oskar Schindler,"
they'll say.
"Everybody
remembers him.
"He did something
extraordinary.
no one else did.
"He came here
with nothing...
"a suitcase...
"and built a bankrupt company
into a major manufactory.
"And left with
a steamer trunk...
"Two steamer trunks
full of money,
all the riches
of the world. "
Hmm.
It's comforting to see
that nothing's changed.
You're wrong, Emilie.
There's no way I could have
known this before,
but there was always
something missing.
In every business I tried, I can
see now, it wasn't me that failed.
Something was missing.
Even if I'd known what it was, there's
nothing I could have done about it...
because you can't
create this thing.
And it makes all the difference in
the world between success and failure.
Luck?
War.
Should I stay?
It's a beautiful city.
I asked you
if I should stay.
It's up to you.
Promise me, Oskar, no doorman
or maitre d' will ever presume...
I'm anyone other than Mrs.
Schindler, and I'll stay.
Good-bye, darling.
I could try to read this or I could
eat my lunch while it's still hot.
We're doing well?
Yes. Better this month than last?
Yes. Any reason to think
next month will be worse?
The war could end.
What? There is a machinist outside...
who'd like to thank you
personally for giving him a job.
Every day he comes. He's very
grateful. It'll just take a minute.
Mr. Lowenstein?
I want to thank you, sir,
for giving me
the opportunity to work.
You're welcome. I'm sure
you're doing a great job.
The SS beat me up.
They would have killed me,
but I am essential to the
war effort, thanks to you.
That's great.
I work hard for you.
I'm sure you do. I'll
continue to work hard for you.
That's great.
Thanks.
God bless you, sir.
All right.
You are a good man.
He saved my life.
Yes, he did.
God bless him. Yeah. Come on.
God bless you.
I'm sorry, Herr Direktor,
but you're running very late.
This is for the
Obersturmbannfuehrer, sir.
And this is for his niece,
Greta. It's her birthday.
Greta as in Garbo. By the way,
don't ever do that to me again.
Go. Go, go, drive!
Don't bow.
Did you happen to notice that
that man had one arm? What? Did he?
What's his use?
Very useful.
How?
Very useful! Success!
#Achrar kach loe nedah #
Besen und Schaufeln
werden ausgeladen...
jeder nimmt sich eine und dann
wird die Strasse gereinigt.
We'll be late for work.
You shouldn't think of them
as yours, Oskar.
You need to understand that
some of the officers here...
don't give a damn
about production.
To them, it's a matter of,
um, national priority...
thatJews
be made to shovel snow.
It's got nothing to do
with reality, Oskar.
You know it and I know it.
Jews shoveling snow...
It's got a, um,
ritual significance.
Come with me.
I am an essential worker.
Essential worker?
Yes.
I work for Oskar Schindler.
Essential worker for Oskar Schindler.
A one-armed Jew? Twice
as useless! Yes, yes.
I lost a day
of production, Rolf.
I work for Oskar Schindler.
Danka, look at the snow. Look
at the snow. Look at the snow!
I lost a worker.
I expect to be compensated.
File a grievance with the
Economic Office. It's your right.
Would it do any good? Of course not.
A big shot from the SS Budget and
Construction Office came to lunch...
and he told us that to believe
theJewish skilled worker had a place...
in Reich economics
was a treasonable idea.
A one-armed machinist, Oskar?
He was
a metal press operator.
Quite skilled.
Herr Direktor?
Shit.
I don't believe it.
Stern, is that you?
No, it's Poldek.
It's about Stern.
Leave your luggage
on the platform.
Clearly label it.
Given name first,
then your surname.
Do not bring
your baggage with you.
It will follow you later.
Leave your luggage
on the platform.
Clearly label it.
Lassen Sie Ihr Gepaeck
am Bahnsteig.
Stern?
He's on the list.
He is?
Well, let's find him. I'm
sorry. You can't have him.
He's on the list. If he were an essential
worker, he would not be on the list.
I'm talking to a clerk.
What is your name?
Sir, the list is correct. I
didn't ask you about the list.
I asked you your name.
Klaus Tauber.
Tauber.
Hauptscharfuehrer, this gentleman
thinks a mistake's been made.
My plant manager is
somewhere on this train.
If it leaves with him on it,
it'll disrupt production...
and the Armaments Board
will want to know why.
Achtung, dieser Zug
faehrt jetzt ab.
Is he on the list?
Yes, sir. Itzhak Stern.
Well, the list is correct,
sir. There is nothing I can do.
What is your name?
Close and secure all doors.
My name? My name is Kunder.
This train is now leaving.
Kunder.
Hauptscharfuehrer Kunder.
K- U-N-D-E-R.
And what's yours?
Schindler.
S- C-H-I-N-D-L-E-R.
Gentlemen,
thank you very much.
I think I can guarantee you
you'll both be in...
Southern Russia before the
end of the month. Good day.
Zamykac dokladnie drzwi.
Dokladnie zamykac drzwi.
Stern!
Itzhak Stern!
Stern! Stern!
Stern!
Sir?
Herr Direktor.
My apologies.
Stop the train! He's here! I apologize.
- Stop the train!
- Stop the train! Stop it!
Sign here.
Initial there.
Makes no difference to us, you
understand. This one, that one.
It's the inconvenience
to the list.
It's the paperwork. I somehow
left my work card at home.
I tried to explain them
it was a mistake, but...
I'm sorry, it was stupid! What
if I got here five minutes later?
Then where would I be?
Shechel.
Sacrean,
sacrean end tzukeer.
Tzukeer end sacrean.
"JEWISH TOWN"
KRAKOW GHETTO WINTER '42
I woke up from a dream
this morning.
I was broke and sharing a room
with 12 people I didn't know,
only to discover I was broke and sharing
a room with 12 people I didn't know.
You laugh about it?
I have to laugh.
You are living
behind walls.
The walls I can deal with. It's the
restrictions to my life I'm tired of.
Those walls keep them out.
That's all I care about.
I like it here. There's
a kind of, I don't know,
ancestral squalor
to it all.
You are a slave to these
people. No one envies us anymore.
I'm smart. Oh, yes, you're smart.
You're a real genius.
You had your chance.
Today, today I actually found
time to organize a thought.
I can't remember
the last time I did that.
When's the last time
we did this?
we stood around and talked?
No one ordered me
onto a truck today.
No one took my business
away from me.
You don't really have
a business to take.
There's nowhere
down from here.
This is it.
This is the bottom.
The ghetto is... liberty.
This street divides the
ghetto just about in half.
Right side, Ghetto A:
Civil employees,
industrial workers
and so on.
Left side, Ghetto B:
Surplus labor,
the elderly
and infirm mostly.
Which is where you'll
want to start, huh?
UNTERSTURMFÜHRER AMON GOETH Which
is where you'll want to start, huh?
UNTERSTURMFÜHRER AMON GOETH
Do you have any questions, sir?
Ja, why is the top down?
I'm fucking freezing.
PLASZOW FORCED LABOUR CAMP UNDER CONSTRUCTION
We expect a labour force of 25,000 to 30,000.
PLASZOW FORCED LABOUR CAMP
UNDER CONSTRUCTION
PLASZOW FORCED LABOUR CAMP UNDER CONSTRUCTION Segregated,
of course. The men in the barracks near the quarry.
PLASZOW FORCED LABOUR CAMP
UNDER CONSTRUCTION
The women on the other
side of the wire.
My place is where?
There, sir.
There? You call that a
villa? Yes, the villa.
Their synagogue, can you
see it? That's not a villa.
We're planning to turn it into
the camp stables. It's a house.
What's that over there?
Kindergarten.
Fifty-one.
And we have a dentist,
shoemaker, practical physicians.
There they are, sir.
Hmm.
One of you is, uh,
a very lucky girl.
There is an opening
for a job,
away from all this...
backbreaking work,
at my new villa.
Uh, which of you has...
domestic experience?
Ja, on second thought, I don't
really want someone else's maid.
All those annoying habits
I have to undo.
I don't want
to give you my cold.
Uh, what's your name?
Helen Hirsch.
What?
What? I can't hear. Helen Hirsch.
Ja.
Take it all down!
To work!
Take it down!
It is not safe!
She says the foundation was poured
wrong. She's got to take it down.
I told her it's the barracks,
not the fucking Hotel Europa.
Fucking Jew bitch engineer.
You fucking bitch!
Herr Kommandant.
The entire foundation...
has to be torn down
and repoured.
If not, there will be
at least a subsidence...
at the southern end
of the barracks.
Subsidence,
and then collapse.
And you are an engineer? Yes.
My name is Diana Reiter.
I'm a graduate...
of Civil Engineering
from the University of Milan.
Ah, an educated Jew,
like Karl Marx himself.
Unterscharfuehrer!
Jawohl?
Shoot her.
What?
Herr Kommandant,
I'm only trying to do my job.
Ja, I'm doing mine.
But, sir, she's foreman of construction.
We are not going to have
arguments with these people.
Okay.
No. Shoot her here,
on my authority.
It will take
more than that.
I'm sure you're right.
Take it down, repour it,
rebuild it. Like she said.
We have more to see, but we
have only one more hour of light.
Today is history.
Today will be remembered.
Years from now, the young
will ask with wonder...
about this day.
Today is history,
and you are part of it.
Six hundred years ago...
When elsewhere they were footing the blame for
the Black Death, Kazimierz the Great, so-called,
#Ke laolam chasedo # told
theJews they could come to Krakow.
Chaja, bread.
They came.
Not that fat. No, less. They trundled
their belongings into the city.
Yes, a bit less.
They settled.
They took hold.
They prospered...
in business, science,
education, the arts.
They came here with nothing.
Nothing.
And they flourished.
For six centuries
there has been a Jewish Krakow.
Think about that.
By this evening,
those six centuries
are a rumor.
They never happened.
Today is history.
LIQUIDATION OF THE GHETTO
MARCH 13, 1943
Absitzen und in Zweierreihen
antreten!
Kameraden!
Schneller!
I think we will start...
with Ghetto B.
Hopp, hopp, hopp, hopp!
All right? Start from both sides?
I would like you to start
there. The right side?
The right side, yeah. And
then move around. Okay.
Beschriften Sie es deutlich.
Es wird Ihnen nachgeschickt.
Lassen Sie
Ihr Gepaeck stehen.
Beschriften Sie es deutlich.
Es wird Ihnen nachgeschickt.
Aufmachen!
Lakoom.
Loe ani loe yodahat olay kaday lehachnese
at hayladeem mitachat la shoolchan.
Mitacht la meeta.
Bohow.
Hopp, hopp, hopp, hopp!
'Runterkommen!
'Rauskommen, Juden!
Ziehen Sie sich warm an!
Kommen Sie 'raus!
Na Platz!
Gold, Chaim!
Platz Chodi.
Yes, Chaim Gold.
Shoot him.
Nie zabijaj!
Ziehen Sie warme Kleidung an
und begeben Sie sich zum Platz...
Keine Koffer!
Gehen Sie durch!
Keine Koffer! Keine Koffer!
Hey, little boy.
Wie alt bist du, huh?
Na, wie hiesst du?
Wie heisst du, huh?
Keine Koffer,
hab'ich gesagt!
Packt keine Koffer!
Keine Koffer!
'Rueber zum Platz Chodi!
Koffer hierlassen!
Blauschein.
Platz Chodi!
Was soll
der Koffer hier?
Alles 'rueber
zum Platz Chodi!
We're getting out
through the sewers.
I have to check
if they're clear.
Mila, pack some things. Nothing bigger
than this. I can't go in the sewers.
I told you I won't go
in the sewers.
You can go.
Yes, you can.
I won't go in the sewers.
Move! Over there!
Over there! Move!
Your card, Jew!
Deine Papiere,
Jude!
Deine Papiere, Jude!
That line.
Deine Karte!
Ich geh'nicht 'rauf
wegen Deiner verdammten Karte!
Deine Scheisskarte!
Was soll denn die Scheisse?
Bist du denn verrueckt geworden?
Mit diesem Scheissgewehr haettest
du mich erschiessen koennen!
Du hast so nah an mir
vorbeigeschossen!
Was heisst hier Entschuldigung.
Du bist wohl verrueckt geworden!
Zurueckbleiben!
Nicht sprechen, nicht sprechen!
Einfach zu den Lastwagen gehen!
Weiterlaufen! Weiterlaufen!
Nicht sprechen!
Komm her, du Judensau!
Bleib stehen, hab'ich gesagt.
Bleib stehen!
Chodzcie tu szybko!
She's good as dead.
Leave her.
Give me a moment.
Just let me bring her inside.
You can join her...
or join the line.
Women to the left! Wilhelm! Rose!
Men to right.
Women to the left.
Women to the left. Let me
go! I won't leave my husband!
Women to the left, and men to
the right. Promise me, be safe.
Your government
is in the wrong country!
Mama! Mama!
Mila!
Oh, God, Danka!
You have a Blauschein.
Blauschein doesn't matter anymore.
They are cleaning out the ghetto.
There's not enough room for you.
What are you talking about? We tried it
before. There's more than enough room.
- I changed my mind!
- Mama!