Everything involved in an abortion
is sin. and it's wrong.
I actually believe it's evil.
And so there's no value
in things that are evil.
The child is ripped limb from limb
while it's still alive,
while his heart is still beating.
I'm a mother.
I loved my pregnancies.
I love my children.
I'm now a grandmother of four.
When a woman becomes pregnant...
she loses a part of herself
to someone else.
Most of us want that
because it's beautiful.
It is not that way for everyone.
We can sit here self-righteously
and decide
that we always know best
for every person, but we do not.
There's no reason to come back here,
session after session,
and make it more and more difficult
and drive women back into the shadows
of illegal abortions,
because it's exactly what this will do.
They will not stop having them.
They've always had abortions. We've always
had abortions. Women always had abortions.
And that will always be something
that will be sought.
If you want to stop abortions,
then help me stop unwanted pregnancies.
Question occurs on the adoption of the amendment.
- -Representative Klick voting aye.
Representative Oliverson voting aye.
Have all members voted?
There being 92 ayes and 42 nays,
the amendment is adopted.
A bill has moved forward
in the legislature,
placing more restrictions on abortion…
They're trying to get something in place…
Texas will have new abortion regulations.
...so that there's less
and less opportunity to have an abortion,
till, perhaps, there is no option at all.
I was a young woman prior to Roe v. Wade,
when abortion was illegal.
I know the difficulties
of that period of time.
The idea that we would go back to that
was just unbearable to me.
The bill banned one of the most common
types of second-trimester abortions.
This bill prohibits
one specific procedure.
But we made it very clear
from the beginning
that the legislative priority needs to be
something that will stop abortions.
The legislative priority
needs to be something
that reveals the truth about abortion,
and the legislative priority
needs to be something that will get us
closer to overturning Roe v. Wade.
My goal is to make abortion at any stage
a thing of the past.
This bill
actually protects human life
beyond 20 weeks here
in the Commonwealth of Kentucky.
I am pro-life,
and I very strongly believe
that we must promote life, defend life…
My goal is to end abortion
in Mississippi.
There is a steady chipping away
of the right to abortion in America.
There are places in the country,
it's as if Roe versus Wade never happened.
The Supreme Court today
legalized abortions.
Since 2010, 300 abortion restrictions
have been passed in this country,
and I think many people are unaware
of how restricted abortion has become.
The Republican Party's
the party of life,
'cause people want life,
they don't want death.
We want to end abortion.
If we're gonna do it through
continuous legislation,
then we're gonna go back again and again
and again, until we win.
I think the feeling was that
with the climate as pretty tense
around the abortion issue in Missouri…
Missouri used to have
several places
where you could get an abortion,
but over the last decade,
more and more laws and regulations
have been passed…
Planned Parenthood
confirmed the Columbia clinic
has stopped performing abortions.
...and because of that,
it becomes harder
and harder to provide that care.
Thursday was the last day women
could have an abortion at the clinic.
And now there's just
one abortion clinic in Missouri.
She's the lady that does the abortions.
The Planned Parenthood
in Saint Louis.
God does love you.
Please, think about what
you're doing today and not do that.
These babies
don't want to die today, Colleen.
When I started out,
I thought abortion would just be
part of my practice; that, you know,
just like people need hysterectomies,
people need abortions,
and I will take care of my patients
who need those.
But I realize that in conservative states
it can be very hard to get an abortion.
And so I became a physician
who really focuses on abortion care.
I live in Saint Louis, but... three out of four weeks,
I'm traveling somewhere.
And it might be Monday and Tuesday
in Oklahoma,
Friday and Saturday back to St. Louis.
Then the following Monday in Wichita,
which is one of the four places
where I provide abortions.
They kill people for a living here.
We cannot stand by and say, "Well,
we're just gonna let that happen,"
or it's the woman's choice and so on.
I'm happy with what we're doing,
and I'm gonna continue doing it.
And we're gonna win.
I'm a big-time Trump supporter,
and we're gonna win this.
It's-- The time is coming. The truth
is coming out, that's what's happening.
Well, I've had
these people out here ask me
what my thoughts and opinions
of abortion itself is.
And I give 'em the same answer.
"My opinion." I keep it that way.
The main reason I'm here is that girl
that flies up there on that flagpole.
What I have against these people
more than anything
is that they keep trying to push
their religion up on someone else
in a nation that's supposed to have
religious freedom.
You know, you can think
whatever you want about it.
But, in America,
one in four women will have an abortion
in their life.
So, to me,
abortion is just basic health care.
We're gonna remove the pregnancy, okay?
And when I think about
how politicized this has become…
I wonder, you know,
well, how did this happen?
In all the soul-searching
I have done,
I sincerely feel that if they do it now…
that they are only disengaging from me…
a kind of mass of tissue.
In the early 1960s,
abortion was illegal.
And there was a woman
named Sherri Finkbine.
She was a children's television hostess
in Phoenix.
Miss Sherri.
Uh, she had four children,
and she was pregnant
with a much-wanted baby.
But she had taken this drug
called thalidomide.
And she went to her doctor and said,
"What about this?"
And he said, "I recommend
that you have an abortion."
He said, "I can arrange an abortion
for you in the hospital here."
Hospitals did some what they called
"therapeutic abortions,"
only to save the life of women.
But if the doctor wanted to help the woman
out, he would interpret that very broadly.
The woman might say,
"I'm gonna kill myself."
Then he could say, "Her life is at stake."
If therapeutic abortion is done,
it's usually done on the basis
of the mental and emotional disturbance
to the patient.
Women had to go before
a committee of male doctors
to ask for an abortion.
And women were often treated
very badly. Like,
"Well, we'll do the abortion for you,
but if you agree to be sterilized."
It was a common procedure.
"We don't want to clean up your mess."
They would say things like that.
But if you were a wealthy white woman,
you could probably find a way
to get access to the procedure,
and it would be called
a therapeutic abortion.
Sherri had an appointment
at the hospital for the abortion.
And she felt that she had an obligation
to let this be known
so that other women in the same position
would have the same option.
But once the...
the word kind of got out
into the local newspaper,
you know, the hospital said,
"Oh, no, we can't give you an abortion."
She couldn't find a place for an abortion
any place in the country.
She had to go to Sweden.
I just want to do
what's right for myself and my family,
and I don't feel bitter towards people
who oppose this religiously.
I think we're doing the right thing.
I'd like to really emphasize.
We're not making a decision
for other people.
This is right for our family
and in our particular case.
This became a big story.
It was in Life magazine.
I remember as a very young kid reading it
and thinking, "Hmm, what's this about?"
So, it focused people's attention.
If you were pregnant and did not
want to be, in the '50s and '60s,
you had very few options.
So, if you didn't want to have a child,
either you were lucky enough to have
a family doctor who would help you,
or to have enough money to go
to Puerto Rico or some other country,
where you could get an abortion.
After I graduated from college,
I was pregnant
and I was in England.
I didn't know what to do and...
was terrified. And I found a doctor
in the phone book in London.
And he said, "Promise me two things.
One, you will not tell anyone my name.
And two, you will do what you want
to do with your life."
And I'm grateful to him to this day.
I didn't know anything about abortion
until I became the chaplain
at Skidmore College in 1966.
And I told my wife at one point,
I said, "You know, 1,400 young women.
What kind of problems could they have?"
And she said, "You're a dope.
You're gonna find out."
Students who were pregnant,
but didn't want to tell their families,
would come to me.
And I'd send the student
to a doctor in Schenectady,
who always found it necessary
to do an abortion.
And that's how I learned
that I wasn't just a chaplain.
I learned I was an abortion counselor.
There were many other college chaplains
doing the same thing around the country.
This is the Clergy Consultation
Service on problem pregnancy.
The first public
organized group
was the Clergy Consultation Service.
This was 19 Protestant ministers
and two Jewish rabbis.
Clergymen counseling this week
are Reverend...
And I was a part of that.
We would not ask them why they were having
the abortion. That was not our business.
But most of the women wanted to talk
about it. They wanted to tell me why.
And so it was quite an education
for a young male minister
into the lives of women.
We went into this apartment,
and it was dark, dingy.
He apologized. He said, "I'm sorry
you have to be treated like a criminal."
This 24-year-old girl had
an illegal abortion less than an hour ago.
The laws which govern abortion are broken
an estimated one million times a year.
Even though
they suffered great indignity,
wealthy women often had a safe way
of ending an unintended pregnancy.
But during my clinical training
at Harlem Hospital,
I really was thrust
into an environment
where women were from a very poor
and deprived background.
And then I saw that African-American women
who were disproportionately poor
were the most directly hurt
by the restrictive policies of the time.
There were some pretty sad cases
of women attempting
to terminate their pregnancies themselves.
The facts are astonishing.
350,000 women a year suffer complications.
5,000 of these women die.
There were many terrified women
who were using coat hangers
and knives and throwing themselves
down stairs.
And going to an illegal abortion doctor
was often unsafe.
It was just a piece of hanger,
an ordinary hanger.
Not a whole one. Just a piece.
When you have an abortion,
you have to pay $700
to go through
this cloak-and-dagger business
to find you some guy who's willing
to stick a hanger up you.
I heard that there was
a meeting.
It was being held in a church
in the Village.
What I'm talking about,
more than likely, look at your neighbor.
She had an abortion.
And, you know,
women just got up and told their stories.
Those men offered me a deal:
I couldn't have an abortion
if I wasn't sterilized...
And I had never, ever in my life
heard women telling the truth
about something
that only happened to women,
and saying, "This doesn't have to be
this way. We have to change it."
'Cause the laws are made
to keep that woman in her place.
And suddenly, you know, that was
a great "aha." You know, I thought,
"Okay, I had this experience.
One in three American women
has had this experience.
Why, why is it illegal and dangerous?"
That was kind of the beginning
of the unraveling.
You got something to hide?
I'm not sorry I did it and I would do it
again, and I think it should be legalized.
The issue is
reproductive freedom,
and that means the right to have children,
as well as the right not to have children.
Something really profound is happening.
Mainly that women
have caught onto the game.
We don't know it completely yet.
You know, we haven't really discovered
the total anatomy of our oppression
and of what they've been doing to us.
But we do know that it's happening.
We're on to it.
Free choice!
This is going to be a battle,
and we will not give up
on the right of a woman
to achieve abortion.
Early feminists... understood immediately
that abortion was a central issue
of feminism and to women's rights.
-What do we want?
-Free choice!
-When do you want it?
-Now!
If you didn't have control
over your own body,
what kind of right could you ask for?
It is a political issue,
and the state means to control our bodies.
We produce the soldiers,
we produce the workers,
and they fear the loss of that control.
It's the basis of democracy
that you control your own body.
And it's the basis of hierarchy
and totalitarian regimes that you don't.
Safe legal abortions
are not available to our--
All right. Will you please sit down
or be removed--
No, we aren't gonna sit down.
Why don't you--
A woman gets pregnant
and she's treated like a criminal.
She can't get an abortion.
She has to go through having that child,
whether she wants it or not.
Before the courts
got involved in the abortion issue,
it looked as if the matter
would be settled in politics.
California passed a new liberalized
abortion law today.
California Governor Ronald Reagan
actually signed a reform bill.
I think one thing that people
don't realize today
is that it was the Republican Party
that was the pro-choice party.
And there were states with Republican
governors who passed abortion reforms.
And then New York totally repealed
the old 19th-century abortion law.
…one of the nation's
most sweeping abortion control bills.
The New York law said
you can have an abortion
throughout the first two trimesters
just if you wanted.
You don't have to give a reason
or anything. It's your choice.
And on July 1st, 1970,
the first legal abortion clinic
in America
was opened by the clergy of New York City.
And that clinic did over
a hundred abortions a day
for 13 months,
until other clinics had formed.
This is the first radical step.
And that set off the Catholic Church.
I have set before you
life and death.
Therefore, choose life.
The unborn
child has no choice.
Does the Catholic Church give you
as much help as you need in this issue?
The Catholic Church
was very strategic
in its opposition to abortion.
They set up the Right to Life committee,
and the cardinal and the church
pushed back vigorously.
Legal abortion in New York
has already claimed
almost a half million innocent lives.
And the New York abortion law
came up in the legislature.
…to abort a human fetus in the womb,
you oughta get sick to your stomach!
There were a lot of
Catholic voters in New York,
and the church was saying,
"We're against abortion."
Ours is a nation
with a Judeo-Christian heritage.
Republicans were in control
of the legislature.
None of this justifies abortion.
And now they were repealing
legalized abortion.
The Republicans I knew got angry about
taxes and how big the budget's gonna be.
I think that the traditions
of the Republican Party are the traditions
of an individual person to choose
what he wishes,
as long as it doesn't infringe
upon other people.
We were the party
that believed in individual liberty.
Congratulations.
Governor Rockefeller
was pro-choice.
One more committee...
And we felt, "Why should the state
be telling women whether or not
they could have an abortion?"
Rockefeller vetoed the bill…
and abortion stayed legal in New York.
There was a Gallup poll
in the summer of 1972
that asked people to answer the question,
"Do you believe that abortion should be
a matter between a woman and her doctor?"
Republicans by about two-thirds
said yes to that question,
"Abortion should be a matter left
to a woman and her doctor."
Not the government.
I think I'm probably
the oldest provider
of abortion services in the country.
I did my first abortion in 1967.
Illegal abortion.
The Clergy Consultation called,
and they asked me,
"Curtis, would you
consider doing abortions?"
Do you have any problems
you want to discuss with me?
So, that's where it started.
And I thought I could go to prison,
I could lose my medical license.
And I grew up religious.
I became an ordained minister
my senior year in high school.
And I think the basic Christian teaching
is compassion and service.
My head and my heart and my hands
said to do this. I can make a difference,
and I'm going take the risk.
I've done this work ever since.
I'm now 80 years old.
And after 80 years, I've decided
I'm not moving on to another career.
I think this is it.
I mean, I'm still needed.
Thank you for calling
the Southwestern Women's Surgery Center.
I'm Alicia. How may I help you?
Okay. I have availability
for tomorrow afternoon...
I've been urged by people
to pass on
what I have learned and experienced.
So, that's what I'm doing, trying to teach
as many young doctors as I can.
…dilate carefully…
My philosophy is that the goal
in providing abortions
is to assist the woman in making
the best decision she can
for her and her life...
in whatever that takes.
The most important moral question of
the abortion debate
is what is in the womb?
Is it a person? Does it deserve our
moral attention and protection or not?
That is the most important question.
In the pro-life movement,
we're outraged, because we believe
that elective abortion is
the taking of an innocent human life.
That is an act of injustice that
we can stop and we need to stop.
-This is Doctor Boyd.
-Dr. Boyd.
If you have questions,
we want you to let us know.
And we'll take good care of you
and make this...
Women continue a pregnancy
and have a baby,
because they want a baby at that time.
And they have an abortion
because they don't want to be pregnant
at that time in their life
for their own sufficient reasons.
The state of Texas requires
that you be seen at least 24 hours
before your abortion.
And then I'm gonna show you
this sonogram.
That looks like
between five and six weeks, okay?
Sonogram technology is one of the best
friends of the pro-life movement.
It is changing a generation's mind about
what's going on in the womb of a woman.
It is very common for expecting mothers
to have sonograms
on their fridge for children to know what
that picture is. That is their sibling.
And so this was a great tool that we
wanted to tap into and to use,
and we saw that abortion clinics
were already using sonogram technology
before an abortion.
Good morning, everybody.
John Seago with tech...
We think very deliberately about what are
we doing that is taking a step forward
to challenging the very foundations
of Roe v. Wade.
And the sonogram bill was an important one
because we were pushing how much
we can require a physician to do.
All right. So Chapter 171 of the Texas
Health and Safety Code require that
I provide you with this information
at least 24 hours prior to your procedure.
We wanted the sonogram
not just to be performed,
for the sake of the abortionist,
but also to be displayed
for the woman to see.
That was the whole goal.
This little blurry thing right here.
If you focus kind of right there
and you see a little flicker.
-Yeah.
-That's the heartbeat. Cardiac activity.
The law says
a doctor has to describe
what she sees on the screen
to the patient,
giving her a chance to change her mind,
to see the error of her ways
and realize what she's about to do.
That's the idea.
This is the state
imposing it upon the woman.
She has engaged a doctor
to discuss this with her
and help her come to a resolution.
She did not engage
the legislature of the state of Texas.
It is the strong conviction
of Texas Right to Life
that the legislature should work
to stop abortions.
In the capitol, we have the capacity
to direct the conversation.
All elective abortion is a violent act
of injustice and should be rejected.
Hey.
If you're running in Texas
as a Republican...
An inhumane action
to a human child in the womb.
...you have to claim to agree
with pro-life principles.
Sid Miller helped pass powerful
legislation to protect the unborn.
Thank you and God bless.
You can be elected
as agriculture commissioner.
You can be elected as the chief financial
officer of our state because of abortion.
Not because of your skills with numbers.
We must pass one of the strongest
pieces of pro-life legislation.
But because of your skill
at getting legislation passed
to obstruct access to abortion.
That's how powerful
this issue is in Texas.
That's how powerful pro-life
advocacy groups have become.
I signed a sonogram law so mothers facing
that agonizing choice can actually see.
And I know it...
works.
We want to see all unborn children
protected, and we believe that
what we've been doing is still
the best way to approach it.
Yet another round in
the abortion battle has been fought on...
But our roadblock
has always been the Supreme Court.
The Court declined
to overrule Roe versus Wade.
We're gonna keep plugging away
to overturn Roe v. Wade
because we believe this country
shouldn't be killing its babies.
Is it a legal question,
a constitutional question,
a medical question,
a philosophical question,
a religious question, or what is it?
There had been other cases
around the country
trying to challenge local abortion laws.
But our case was the first
to get to the US Supreme Court.
The law in Texas was that abortion
was illegal,
and we had a woman who was
already pregnant who didn't want to be...
and she didn't want her name public.
So, we thought,
"Well, John Doe, Jane Roe."
And Henry Wade
was the district attorney in Dallas.
And it was clear that so many women
were affected by this issue.
There was a flight that left Dallas
every Thursday going to California,
and there were usually ten
or a few more women on that flight
going out to California for abortion.
People were going to Colorado.
And a lot of people
were flying to New York.
And there were thousands of women
who had had illegal abortion,
who had done their own abortion.
And so we filed a class action
to say that this is a case for all women
who are or might become pregnant
and want the option of abortion.
I was 26.
And I was the youngest person ever
to argue a case in the Supreme Court.
We are not here to advocate abortion.
We do not ask this court to rule
that abortion is good,
or desirable in any particular situation.
We are here to advocate for the right
of a woman to determine whether or not
she would continue
or terminate a pregnancy.
Roe against Wade was argued
to nine middle-aged-to-elderly men.
It was a conservative Court.
It was a Court with four Nixon appointees.
Their presence is expected
to make the Court
more conservative than at any time
in recent memory.
But abortion was not
a partisan issue at that time.
It was a medical problem,
it was a social problem.
Basic constitutional question is
whether or not an unborn fetus
is a person, isn't it?
At one point
a justice had said to me,
"When do you believe human life begins?"
And I said, "Well, Your Honor,
we did not try to say exactly
what moment that was."
There is no one answer to that.
Different religions
have different answers to that question,
but there is no legal standard that said,
"At this point the fetus becomes a human."
So, the question is,
who gets to make the decision?
Is it the woman,
or is it the government?
And my position has always been
it's not the government.
Good evening. In a landmark ruling,
the Supreme Court today
legalized abortion.
The Court split seven to two
with Justices Byron White
and William Rehnquist dissenting.
The decision made abortion
largely a private matter
and ordered the states
to make no laws forbidding it, except possibly during the final months.
When Roe went through,
it was a shock to everyone.
To go so far over to the other side,
to put everything in the woman's hand
and essentially dismantle the laws.
Now, in any other state,
you couldn't pass laws against abortion,
not forbidding it directly.
It was a constitutional right.
The Roe decision held
that women have the right
to terminate a pregnancy
in the first two trimesters,
and then it's only at the third trimester
that the state has the right
to prohibit abortion
except when necessary to preserve
a woman's life or health.
When the Roe v. Wade decision
was handed down,
Planned Parenthood had been devoted
to women's reproductive health
and access to contraception.
And the local chapters
had to ask themselves,
"Are we gonna provide abortions
now that they are legal?"
It was really a moment of reflection
that was very tough
for the organization.
March 11th is...
When it first became legal,
Planned Parenthood was not keen
on abortion.
Various affiliates around the country,
a lot of them didn't want to do abortions.
They really didn't.
The board would be divided.
Half the people would want to,
the other half wouldn't.
Now, after the doctor's
examined you and everything is all right,
the first thing he's going to do
is use the speculum. This is the...
But one by one,
they swung over to the active side.
And when they did, the people who didn't
like abortion would resign from the board
and other people would come on,
and it's committed now,
committed to this right,
given by the Roe v. Wade decision. No court opinion
can change the law of God.
Every legal possibility must be explored
to challenge the opinion
of the United States Supreme Court.
Life begins at conception.
Protect the life of the unborn.
So, as long as there was
no New York law or no Roe v. Wade,
the woman was really, you know, an outlaw.
She was moving around, trying to get
some procedure that was against the law.
And nobody really tried
to stop her very much.
But when the Court said,
"You have the right to make this decision.
You have the right to define your life.
Not religion."
That was unacceptable.
Get out!
There won't be any murder here today.
So, the Catholics were already
involved with various pro-life things.
But for Operation Rescue,
the genesis really was more evangelical.
We rejoice, Lord. Hallelujah.
Glory to God.
The name comes from Proverbs 24:11.
The Biblical verse that says,
"Rescue those unjustly sentenced to die."
Someone else
can be hooked up to this pipe.
There'll be no abortions in here today.
No abortions in here today.
Amen.
And so our motto was,
"We're here to rescue the innocent child
sentenced to die today."
People out into the street.
There's hundreds more...
It was a very immediate thing.
Almost militaristic. Operation Rescue.
We're here to rescue these babies.
The judges, the politicians,
they're getting the signal,
as is Planned Parenthood.
Legalized child killing's days
are numbered. We will win.
This is a phenomenon.
It was really an outworking
of our Christian faith.
So, this is the epicenter
of Operation Rescue.
This is a former abortion clinic.
We actually took this place
that was an abortion mill.
We closed it down, we remodeled it,
and now we've made it our headquarters.
Before we closed the place down,
the property line
is right down on this crack.
And we would stand right here
and minister to the women
that were going in this abortion clinic.
If we stepped over the line,
we'd be arrested.
Just like that, be arrested.
Operation Rescue
has targeted Wichita
with virtually all of its resources,
attempting to close
the city's three abortion clinics.
Thousands of people
came to Wichita,
and that's because of George Tiller.
George Tiller's Women's
Health Care Services clinic
is just one of three in the nation
which perform late-term abortions.
The issue is a moral imperative
from God Almighty
to rescue those led to slaughter.
The pro-life movement here
looks bigger than ever.
Federal marshals were escorting patients
through the protesters, into the clinic.
Operation Rescue
had really caused a shutdown in that city.
And I received a message saying
that Phil Donahue wants you to do
a show in Wichita,
and he wants to do it with Randall Terry.
And so, you know, to go to Wichita
in the midst of this,
we were kind of going
into the belly of the beast.
Faye Wattleton, I'm saying this to you.
You have betrayed your race.
When you think-- Absolutely.
To say that abortion for black women
is somehow a favor to them
to kill their offspring...
To be characterized
as being engaged in black genocide
is just what it is.
It's incendiary rhetoric
that was designed to inflame the debate.
-Let me finish, Faye.
-I do not need you
to tell me what my choices are
about my life
and my body
because I am a black person.
Planned Parenthood does
a hundred thousand abortions a year.
They've killed more children
than any organization in the country.
I think this really is
about women's status in society,
controlling women's behavior
and the limits of that behavior.
Any contraceptive
that is an abortive agent,
such as the IUD or the pill,
I believe should be banned.
Mr. Terry has in fact revealed
the ultimate agenda
-of Operation Rescue and all of its type.
-No.
The emotion
and the hot emotion is around abortion.
It's murder, Phil.
That's what we have laws for.
It raises a lot of conflict
around sexuality, and...
without any question, it's formidable.
…must be decided by the woman
and her physician,
and not by Randall Terry and other people
trying to make that decision.
But the ultimate decider here
must remain women.
And that's what we're really fighting for.
If abortion is illegal,
what happens to those who perform
the abortion? Mr. Terry?
Let me say this. Dr. George Tiller's
gonna do hard time when this is all over.
He is a mass murderer.
He is an enemy of humanity.
The abortion battle
has taken a violent turn.
It was just one round after another.
Boom, boom, boom, boom, boom.
Dr. George Tiller shot by a protester. We take no blame for this.
The blame rests
with the child-killing industry.
They're the ones that are killing children
and breeding such frustration in people.
We didn't know where the gunshots was
coming from. Just shootin' and shootin'.
Two women were killed in Boston.
A doctor was killed in Pensacola.
Then a doctor and an escort were killed.
Two bombs rocked
an abortion clinic in Atlanta.
Every abortion clinic is a potential
target for those who would do this.
And at that point, I think, there was
a gravity that came out of the movement.
We lost another doctor in '98.
And we lost Dr. Tiller... in 2009.
Dr. George Tiller was shot dead
at his church in Wichita, Kansas.
A man shot him
in the Lutheran church,
in cold blood.
The suspect is in custody,
and right now the police...
And you really
have to think about this,
that you would do this kind of thing.
That's really astonishing.
That's just astonishing.
Did there come a point in time
where your faith,
your religious beliefs changed?
Yes.
I had been watching
The 700 Club regularly.
'Cause that baby is made
in the image of God Almighty.
I was alone in my living room, and...
that day I kneeled down and I did
accept Christ as my savior at that time.
Religion can
make people crazy. It really can.
And it can be wonderful, but it can
also be just incredibly intolerant.
All those people who shot
these people at the clinics and so on,
they were all religious.
The tie that
this clinic has to Dr. Tiller
is really important to me.
You know, that even in the face
of assassinating one of our providers,
we were still gonna provide that care
because women still deserve that care.
And we do a checkup for you,
make sure everything's okay.
Right.
There's a lot of traumatic memory of
things that have happened
in the abortion movement,
of clinics being bombed,
providers being targeted.
You are a killer,
condemning your own soul to hell.
You know, the potential
that your family will be targeted.
Dr. Johnson
has been killing children in our city.
That people may show up
at your home or at your kids' school.
And you layer all of this difficulty
of actually practicing medicine
with the threat to safety
or harm to you or your family,
it becomes a really difficult choice
to make for many people.
And one of the strategies
of the antichoice movement
is to shame people.
They kill your baby.
They won't let you...
People who provide abortions
and people who have abortions.
If you don't kill your baby!
If you think about controlling when and if
and how many children somebody has,
it's sort of the absolute
demonstration of patriarchy.
Because controlling
people's fertility can affect
what education they can get
and what career they can have
and sort of how far they can go in life.
The weak link
in the abortion chain
is the person doing the actual abortions.
And there's fewer and fewer abortionists
that are doing them
here in the United States.
And they're retiring
and they're moving on.
And so we've been very effective
in targeting particular abortionists.
If they don't have an abortionist,
the place closes down.
And when abortion clinics close,
babies get saved.
These are abortion clinics we've
closed down, put them out of business.
This is in San Diego, Oceanside.
Lawrence, Kansas.
I like to look at it as a trophy wall.
We have probably closed down hundreds
of abortion clinics,
and it's the one thing I'm most proud of.
Right now, there are seven states
that have only one abortion provider,
and those states have been under siege
in terms of restrictions
on women's health care.
So, we are constantly monitoring
the patterns in the states
in terms of legislation that restricts
women's access to abortion…
We've seen a lot of state moves
to defund abortion providers.
...thinking about what we need to do
to block legislation from passing.
We got that law preliminarily enjoined.
And then if it does pass,
we consider bringing a court challenge.
So, for Kentucky TRAP...
And Kentucky is a perfect example.
We are going to do the best that we can
to usher in a new day for Kentucky.
Before Governor Bevin took office,
there were three abortion providers
in Kentucky.
I'm unapologetically pro-life.
And he sprung right into action
to pick off abortion clinics one by one.
Governor Matt Bevin has ordered
a Louisville Planned Parenthood clinic
to stop performing abortions immediately.
For the second time, Bevin administration
has sued a clinic over abortion.
And we gave them
an immediate cease and desist.
We said that we would seek
an injunction if necessary.
The Republicans now have
control of both the House, the Senate...
We had three abortion clinics.
We are now down to one.
And now Governor Bevin
is trying to shut down
the last remaining clinic,
EMW Women's Center.
...Bevin administration's
new rules for abortion clinics.
And at the ACLU, we think
what Governor Bevin is doing
is blatantly unconstitutional.
If a judge sides with
Governor Matt Bevin,
Kentucky will become
the only state in the nation
without an abortion clinic.
The situation in Kentucky
really is unprecedented.
We have never seen a situation
where we have been on the cusp
of a state that has no abortion provider.
It's incredibly dire for women.
Close this place down!
Governor Bevin, close this place down.
It's exciting to see
pro-life activity at
the last abortion clinic in Kentucky,
because I have been looking so forward
to the moment when we have
an abortion-free state.
And let's see if we can't put
the final nail in the coffin
of the abortion clinic there.
We in the Commonwealth of Kentucky
respect the sanctity of human life...
And Governor Bevin's been fantastic.
Republicans stand against abortion,
stand for the Ten Commandments,
and they stand for marriage
between a man and a woman.
And the Republican Party has
kind of become the party of morality.
And there's a war
for the heart and soul of America.
This debate is about little babies
who haven't given their consent,
and it's about time we said
enough is enough.
Nobody's saying
that Planned Parenthood can't be
the leading advocate
of abortion-on-demand in America,
but why do I have to pay for it?
Washington needs to defund them,
send a clear message.
I come here today
to ask my fellow senators
to vote to defund Planned Parenthood.
Because this language and
messaging
around defunding Planned Parenthood
has been so pervasive,
I think the general population believes
that defunding Planned Parenthood means
not paying for abortions.
But in fact, and by law,
no federal dollars go to pay for abortion.
Two and a half million patients
depend on Planned Parenthood
every single year
for birth control,
for testing and treatment
for sexually transmitted...
We don't want our tax dollars
going to that organization
for any service that they provide.
Planned Parenthood
is a mega abortion provider. It's about a third of all abortions
performed in this country
are done by that one organization.
We just see them as...
um, as baby killers.
Please join me in welcoming
the President of the United States,
Barack Obama.
And when it comes to abortion,
they pretty much get to control
the agenda in the Democratic Party.
Planned Parenthood is not going anywhere.
It's not going anywhere today,
it's not going anywhere tomorrow.
And it's a known fact.
Republicans will pass
pro-life legislation.
We voted to defund Planned Parenthood.
Republicans made huge gains,
not only in the House,
but in governors' races
and state legislative campaigns. We now have Republican...
majorities in state legislators
and I believe 33 Republican Governors.
We've had a game plan for many years,
we're following it,
and I think it's coming to fruition.
What's so important for us to stand up
for the cause of pro-life?
I cancelled their vacations and I brought
them back for a pro-life special session.
And I'm convinced
that we're going to get the job done.
The general assembly is
heavily Republican.
They have a two-thirds majority in both
Chambers.
I provide abortion care
in several clinics in the Midwest.
and the clinics have to be able to comply
with the layers and layers and layers
of regulations that have been put on them.
Legislation is on its way to the House
that would require inspections
of abortion clinics
and enact other new restrictions
on the procedure.
And now we're facing
more legislation, more regulations,
new bills being introduced,
new laws going into effect, and...
on an almost day-to-day basis,
what we can do might change.
Missouri lawmakers have
enacted one of the nation's
longest abortion waiting periods.
Governor Greitens calls
a special session.
State lawmakers are back--
And there's so much
factual inaccuracy in
these bills and in hearings,
I felt that somebody really needs
to be a voice.
A voice for medicine
and a voice for science.
Okay. Good afternoon.
I'm Dr. Colleen McNicholas. I'm an OB-GYN.
I practice in St. Louis.
There shouldn't be a pro-life
or pro-choice law.
There should be a law in healthcare policy
that is important and science-based.
-But every single time I've testified...
-Why is your opinion
so much different than theirs?
...lobbyists from the anti-choice group
will also testify.
-Here's some written testimony--
-And they can say whatever they want.
...case by case, to protect the health
and safety of women in Missouri.
Is it Dr. Lee?
No, Senator.
So, you're not a physician.
Are you a pathologist?
Not at all.
Which is infuriating.
Especially from sort of the standpoint
of science and evidence and...
just facts.
The abortion clinic in St. Louis
has not been complying with the law
in terms of turning over
complication reports.
Every year we have
dozens of pro-life bills introduced.
Lawmakers who come to me and say,
"Sam, what can I do?"
What type of bill can I introduce
to reduce abortions?"
It's a bit of a cat and mouse game
between the pro-life pro-choice side,
...is not turning in complication reports. Once again a bill on
abortion regulations
moved through the legislature.
They have to have a complication plan.
This is how I feel.
Okay? We're not
in the field of medicine here.
When did the government start approving
complication plans?
I thought the doctors
or the physicians would do that.
Our complaint is that
that should be for all clinics.
if abortion facilities have to comply
with certain things, then
so too should other clinics that are
providing similar levels of care.
Are you putting plans together
for anything else?
I mean, you could eat too much pork!
And have a gallstone
and you'd have to go through surgery.
Why is it that we're just doing this
when it comes to individuals
wanting to have an abortion?
-Well, I mean it is--
-It sounds so ridiculous.
Abortion is different
than just any other medical procedure.
I know that the Democrats
and Planned Parenthood
want to treat it that way. I know
they want to talk about in that way.
But talk to your average person
on the street.
And they're going to tell you
that abortion is not the same as having
a colonoscopy or having your tooth pulled.
It's something unique and different.
There is no other medical procedure, none,
not one, that is legislated
in the way that abortion is.
Enough is enough.
I'm ready to go down fighting,
because I'm tired of the Republican Party
bullying women when it comes
to their right to choose.
I'll tell you what.
I am proud to be with so many people
standing for life here in Missouri.
Message received. Thank you--
You know,
from the perspective of today,
I think it's important to remember that
abortion was not always so partisan and it wasn't always a requirement
for the Republicans to be pro-life.
In fact, it took years of cultivation...
We're concerned that
a million babies are dying...
...by very smart Republican strategists.
It took years to bring about
that kind of party realignment,
the placing of abortion
front-and-center as
a social, cultural issue in our politics.
We're concerned about the moral problems,
the breakdown of the family.
We've come to seek
the welfare of America's children.
God bless you and have a great day.
And it was accomplished in
the 1980s, by this coalition
of social and religious
and political conservatives.
And it was done
with the rise of Ronald Reagan.
The 1980 election is when abortion
really becomes a political issue
and particularly a Republican issue.
We have
a threefold primary responsibility.
Number one, get people saved.
Number two, get them baptized.
Number three,
get them registered to vote.
Falwell saw evangelical Christians
as the basis for a political movement.
Falwell wanted to organize evangelical
voters, who up until that time
had not been politically active.
It's always seemed to me
we haven't improved by one iota
on the Ten Commandments.
Falwell and the religious right
identifies
Ronald Reagan as a candidate
who would push their agenda,
their socially conservative agenda.
Religious America is awakening,
perhaps just in time,
for our country's sake.
But what got evangelical leaders
interested in politics
was this notion that the Bible
mandated the separation of the races.
And several so-called segregation
academies were applying
for tax-exempt status.
And the district court ruled
that any organization that engages
in racial segregation, or discrimination,
cannot claim tax-exempt status.
That was the catalyst
for the religious right
becoming politically active.
We have a fight going on...
on the question of tax exemptions
for Christian schools.
Paul Weyrich
was one of the chief strategists of
the New Right movement.
Questions involved
are religious liberty questions.
It was a movement that said
we are going to win the presidency
through bigotry, but we are not going
to come right out and say it.
This coming election's gonna be
a big test for us...
This election is to make America
great again.
I have told the Republicans
that you are loyal to a certain set
of moral precepts
in which you deeply believe.
Weyrich recognized
the electoral potential
of evangelical voters,
but he needed a populist issue
that would appeal more generally
to religious voters.
And he was savvy enough to recognize
that overt racism probably wouldn't work
on a wide scale.
The pro-family movement
and the American people do not want
the women's lib ideology forced
upon all the rest of us.
Phyllis Schlafly had been able
to mobilize
voters around moral issues.
Well, I am certainly opposed to abortion,
because I think it's killing
an unborn child.
And as the presidential election
begins to take shape...
What are the key issues?
In our judgment,
the right to life,
protect the unborn. These are key issues.
Weyrich says, in effect,
"We found our issue.
Abortion is going to work for us
as a political issue."
Millions of unborn defenseless babies...
When you are trying to
change the dynamic
of the political system in the country,
you have to do it
through emotional issues.
In our Washington studios
is Jerry Falwell.
America has violated the principle
of the dignity of life since 1973.
And we're very strongly pro-life.
Our first order of business--
And what is more emotional
than motherhood and babies?
At that point the Reagan campaign begins
to embrace abortion as a political issue.
I believe that...
that when you interrupt the pregnancy,
you are taking a human life.
Which they ride through
the 1980 election.
It's interesting.
One of the nation's leading pollsters
says Reagan is winning the votes
of the white electors,
who are followers
of the evangelical preachers,
the so-called Moral Majority,
who have been active in the election.
This group is providing Reagan
with his clear margin
in the election.
Ronald Reagan's overwhelming victory...
Reagan won 44 states,
with 479 electoral votes.
They set out to change
the dynamic in the Republican party.
So they nominated somebody
that would be useful. And they succeeded.
It was now eight years
after Roe versus Wade.
And it seemed
like the future of ending abortion
was going to be in the Republican party.
And Reagan really gave a lot of hope
to the pro-life community.
Can a person be a Christian
and support federal funding of abortion?
I believe in an abortion
you are taking a human life.
If you believe that, it very definitely
has a religious connotation.
He just reaffirmed his support of
everything the pro-life
movement represents.
There's never been any question
that he was with us.
We love life! We want life!
In the mind of the pro-life
community, the right to abortion
was an aberration in the law.
So, with the election of President Reagan,
we thought the next step would be
to try to reverse Roe versus Wade.
We want life!
It is the Supreme Court
that has abolished prayer
and the Ten Commandments
from the public schools.
It is Supreme Court decisions
that have brought upon us forced busing
and put our children on buses
and send them across town to some school
that their parents don't want them
to go to.
It is Supreme Court decisions
that have unleashed the pornography
that has invaded our newsstands
and our television.
It is Supreme Court decisions
that have abolished capital punishment
and deterrents against crime.
And, of course,
it is the Supreme Court decision
that has brought about
this tragic evil of our time.
A Supreme Court decision, in 1973,
that invented this new right of a woman
to kill her unborn baby.
If abortion is
a constitutional right,
the most important thing was
to overturn Roe versus Wade.
In order to do that, you had to change
the justices on the Court.
There's no other way.
You need, as quickly as possible,
a reconstituting of the Supreme Court.
We just didn't think that the current
justices would have changed their minds.
I will send to the Senate
the nomination
of Judge Sandra Day O'Connor, of Arizona.
The first woman on
the Supreme Court,
Judge Sandra Day O'Connor.
She told the Senate today
that she is firmly opposed to abortion.
In the area of abortion is
that I am opposed to it
as a matter of birth control.
So, President Reagan
appointed O'Connor,
then appointed Justice Scalia
and Justice Kennedy.
And in the pro-life community there was
the hope that Roe versus Wade
may get overturned.
And we thought the Court was moving
much closer in that direction.
Are you getting the feeling
that some sort of movement is under way
that would ultimately erode Roe v. Wade?
I'm not only getting a feeling.
I'm part of it.
- It's happened?
- It's happening.
The Americans United for Life
is one of the main players in this.
They have a strategy of one anti-abortion
restriction at a time
which could pass state legislatures
and maybe get up to the Supreme Court
and overturn Roe against Wade.
And it looked
like it actually might happen
in an abortion case in 1989.
But Justice O'Connor surprised the world
by sustaining Roe against Wade.
And that was a matter of
extreme frustration
to the Court's conservatives.
I think Justice O'Connor
didn't want to be
the first and lone woman on the Court
taking away
a settled constitutional right.
And so she upheld Roe versus Wade.
But Justice Blackmun made
a very, very important statement, and he read it from the bench and he said,
"Roe versus Wade is hanging by a thread.
We are in a very tenuous circumstance.
We're only one vote away.
The next case could do it."
And after that,
the political situation really changed.
Like a thousand points of light
in a broad and peaceful sky.
When H.W. became president,
we thought that he would be
a pro-choice president.
Abortion divides. We have room
in our party for people that feel
one way, pro-life, or pro-choice.
This is an issue that divides.
When he was a congressman,
he had been known as a big supporter
of family planning, to the point that
some of his colleagues
called him "Rubbers."
Do you favor a constitutional
amendment against abortion?
I oppose such an amendment.
The 35th Republican National Convention.
What's the big challenge here this week?
I really don't know. I-- Abortion, mostly.
People really need to understand
that the pro-lifers
are now the backbone that is holding up
George Bush.
George Bush has to take
a strong pro-family position.
And frankly, that means
a strong position on abortion.
And Bush turned against choice,
and he took on a position
that was stronger than...
than anything Reagan ever did.
I believe that abortion is wrong.
I believe that we should work
to overturn Roe vs. Wade.
And I believe that states should have
the right to prohibit abortions.
I don't make many guarantees,
but I'll make you one.
Pennsylvania will be
the first state in the Union
to end the nightmare once and for all
and to outlaw abortion.
Supreme Court case number 91-744.
Planned Parenthood
of Southeast Pennsylvania versus Casey.
Planned Parenthood versus Casey.
That went up to the Supreme Court
in 1992.
...one of the most
restrictive abortion laws in the nation.
And a lot of pro-life people thought
this was going to be the case
that would overturn Roe versus Wade.
The Bush administration asked
the Supreme Court
to support further limitations
on a woman's right to have an abortion.
President Bush
has done all he can do
to ensure that my arguments
are likely to fall on deaf ears.
I was totally convinced
that we were going to lose.
For he has packed the Court
with justices who are hostile to a woman's
fundamental right to choose abortion.
Abortion litigation is a lot
like Sesame Street.
You got to learn to count.
And the only number
that's important is five.
Are there five votes on the Supreme Court?
Five votes that would overturn Roe.
He is the best person for this position.
The president nominated Clarence Thomas
to the Supreme Court.
And I thought he would be the fifth vote
to overrule Roe.
And I remember there was a silence
in the courtroom that was palpable.
Ms. Kolbert.
Mr. Chief Justice,
and may it please the Court.
Whether our Constitution endows
government with the power to force a woman
to continue or to end a pregnancy
against her will
is the central question in this case.
And then the Solicitor General
of the United States stood up and argued
that Roe versus Wade
ought to be overturned.
...the State does have
a compelling interest
in the potential life, in fetal life, and
that interest runs throughout pregnancy.
But I wanted the Court
to understand the implications
of changing a standard
that was very protective for women.
This Court has recognized
that the rights of autonomy,
bodily integrity, and equality are central
to our notions of ordered liberty.
Roe lies at the heart of those interests.
Because, ultimately,
abortion is not about whether or not
women should have
particular medical procedures.
It's about equality.
It's about a view of life,
about who should make important decisions.
It's very rare that you know the date
that the Supreme Court is going
to issue a decision.
You know that the case will be decided,
but you don't know when.
But this time we knew when,
because every other case
that they heard that term
had already been decided.
We're waiting outside
the Supreme Court now
for the announcement
of the Court's decision.
So, there were media trucks
parked outside.
Everybody was ready and waiting
for the overturning of Roe.
Release 91-45 Standing Orders.
The clerk of the court handed me
a copy of the decision.
And frankly I was confused
in many respects.
You know, it's a 50, 60 page opinion.
It's complicated.
You have to read it and understand it.
At the same time,
I'm shepherded out to talk to
American media about what just happened.
I am Kathryn Kolbert.
I am counsel of record on behalf of
Planned Parenthood and the other
abortion clinics in Pennsylvania.
It was a very ambiguous decision.
Three Republican-appointed justices
had gotten together,
and they decided that
rather than overturn Roe against Wade,
they were going to reformulate it...
with what they called
the undue burden standard.
So the Court upheld the right to abortion.
But the new standard meant
that states can undertake
to persuade a woman to carry
a pregnancy to term,
but they cannot prevent a woman
from choosing abortion.
Under Roe versus Wade,
most abortion restrictions
were unconstitutional.
In Casey, the Court basically said that
states had the latitude to restrict
abortion in more ways than under Roe.
Many, many kinds of restrictions,
waiting periods, informed consent.
Things found unconstitutional under Roe
have been validated by this Court.
And therefore we are much worse off
than we have been in the past.
At the time, I thought, you know,
this is really horrible.
...to place roadblocks
in the path of women...
But whatever problems
the undue burden standard gave us,
it was still preferable
than a total outlaw of abortion.
For a woman in need
of a medical procedure,
there's a big difference between having
to jump through hoops
and not being able
to get the procedure at all.
Four justices have said
Roe versus Wade must be overturned.
All it's going to take is one more
and I can only hope
that President Bush gets reelected.
It makes a difference
whether the president believes
in a woman's right to choose. And I do.
There was some momentum
around the Clintons
and support for abortion rights.
I am proud to nominate
Judge Ruth Bader Ginsburg to
the Supreme Court.
It is essential to woman's equality
with man
that she be the decision-maker.
I'm proud to nominate
Judge Stephen Breyer
to serve on the United States
Supreme Court.
And there were bills pending
at the federal level
to protect access to abortion.
The Clinton team has begun
to systematically wage war
against unborn children.
And abortion opponents were looking
for a way to stop this momentum.
So they came up with this new idea and they honed in on later abortion.
Specifically they came up
with the term "partial birth abortion."
Some of you stay on this side,
some of you go on the other side, okay?
Not everyone. Try and spread out and get
the signs as many places as possible. Partial birth took off like
wildfire inside the pro-life movement.
It so horrified and shocked the conscience
and stripped this veil of respectability
from Planned Parenthood
and the abortionists.
It's terrible. Which side of the fence
are we gonna be on?
We had to educate the public.
Are we gonna continue to support child
killing in America and call it choice?
We made it an issue.
We forced it on America.
This is partial birth abortion.
The abortionist grabs the live baby's legs
with forceps.
The Republicans introduced
the partial birth abortion law,
even though there's no such thing.
They made up the word
and it was a strategy
that really went to challenging
the question of when late abortion
would be permitted.
With the idea that,
if you could push it earlier and earlier,
you could eliminate a number of abortions
And we knew immediately
that this was going to be a huge issue.
Abortion advocates are claiming that,
by banning partial-birth abortion,
we are mounting a direct attack
on Roe versus Wade.
For them, there is never an instance
when abortion is inappropriate.
For them,
the right to abortion is absolute
at whatever time, for whatever reason,
and in whatever way,
a woman or an abortionist chooses.
Ninety percent of women who have an
abortion have it in the first trimester.
That's the vast majority of women.
And then a smaller proportion have it
before 20 weeks.
Between 20 and 24 weeks,
we're at probably about one percent.
And then, as we get further along, we're
getting to smaller and smaller numbers,
exceedingly low numbers.
So the majority of abortions
are in the first trimester.
But we spend most of our time
talking about
abortions that happened
in the second and third trimester.
And this is one of the strategies
of the anti-choice movement.
Why do we call something
the partial-birth abortion,
when really that's not a medical term.
You always go after your enemy
where they're the weakest.
And they know that,
once we win, in the ninth month,
the rest of the card house
comes crumbling down.
We destroy their arguments.
They created a narrative that
women late in pregnancies were
killing their babies 'cause they,
you know, wanted to go to the gym instead.
Totally false. Doesn't happen.
But there's no 30-second sound bite
to counter that image.
They were very good at creating optics,
creating language that supported
their point of view.
And so we had to figure out
how to challenge it politically.
And we were able
to introduce President Clinton
to women who would be affected
by the law.
Women who were
losing pregnancies very late
or finding themselves
carrying a pregnancy
with very severe fetal anomalies.
Good morning. I'd like to thank
the subcommittee for inviting me here.
I went in for
a routine seven-month ultrasound.
They were saying,
"This looks good. This looks good."
Then suddenly, they got really quiet.
The doctor said,
"Your daughter has no eyes,
and her heart...
and other major organs are also failing.
And your child will not live."
I remember just looking out the window.
I couldn't look at anybody.
So my mother-in-law asked, "Do we go on?
Does she have to go on?"
This terrible problem affects
a few hundred Americans
every year,
who desperately want their children,
are trying to building families and are
trying to strengthen their families.
And they should not become
pawns in a larger debate.
And therefore I had no choice
but to veto the bill.
- I vetoed it just a few minutes ago before I met with these families.
-  Bill Clinton vetoed it, but it really spread.
And we started to see
new iterations of these bills,
using slightly different language,
in order to withstand a legal challenge.
It's a shame that child sacrifice
can be allowed in this country.
We are being arrested for speaking
and showing the truth of abortion.
Okay, careful. Walk carefully.
We need to ban
partial-birth abortions. I believe
banning partial-birth abortions would be
a positive step toward reducing
the number of abortions in America.
We were able to get George W. Bush
elected with the promise that,
if we got another ban,
he'd pass it again and sign it.
And he signed the federal ban into law,
and it went to the Supreme Court.
Hey, hey! Hi, ho!
Anti-choice has got to go!
The issue of abortion's
before the Supreme Court.
Justice Sandra Day O'Connor announced
this morning that she will retire.
Chief Justice William Rehnquist has died.
The nomination power is one
of the most serious responsibilities
of a president.
I will nominate Judge Roberts
to the Supreme Court.
And Chief Justice Roberts will have
as his colleague
a proud member of
The Federalist Society,
Judge Sam Alito, Jr.
In a 5-4 landmark decision,
the Court's new conservative majority
today upheld a nationwide ban
on a procedure critics call
partial-birth abortion.
In court, an angry
Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg
took the unusual step of
reading her dissent aloud.
I strongly dissent from today's opinion.
The Partial-Birth Abortion Ban Act
cannot be understood
as anything other than an effort
to chip away at a right
declared in Roe v. Wade.
Roe versus Wade
prevents us from prohibiting abortion.
But it does allow us,
the states, to...
do some things to protect life,
if they can show there is
a compelling state interest.
Governor Rick Perry wanted to end
access to reproductive health care.
And because the legislature is
so disproportionately
uh, led by the Republican party,
they proposed abortion restrictions, which
were the most extreme in the country.
House Bill 2 was a good example of these
kinds of laws that were being passed in
many states controlled by the Republicans.
Laws that really focused
on where the abortion could be performed
and regulations to either the doctor's
office or a surgical center.
Thank you for calling
the Southwestern Women's Surgery Center.
This is Alicia. How may I help you?
This is what are known as TRAP laws: Targeted Regulation of Abortion Providers.
And the purpose of these laws is
to make it as difficult as possible
to provide abortion services,
prohibit as many abortions as you can,
make the ones that do occur
as expensive as possible.
It's so obvious what they're doing.
My goal is to make abortion,
at any stage, a thing of the past.
So these restrictions would shut down
dozens of women's health centers
all across Texas.
And that's why Senator Wendy Davis
decided to stand up and fight
for the rights of women.
So this bill went to the Senate.
But, because it was the final day
of the session, the clock was ticking.
And that gave me an opportunity
for the filibuster.
Members, I'm rising on the floor today...
That meant I had about 13 hours of talking
to make sure that this bill did not pass.
The rules in Texas say
that you cannot have a sip of water,
you cannot have anything to drink,
you cannot lean on your desk
and you certainly cannot leave the floor
to go to the restroom.
So I had a pair of running shoes
on my feet and I had a catheter bag.
A doctor had come over
at about six o'clock that morning
and inserted a catheter so that
I'd be able to make it through the day.
Senator Wendy Davis must make it
to midnight.
That is the end of the special session.
Essentially she's wasting time,
running out the clock.
The way she's doing that? Right now,
she's reading letters from Texas women
who oppose this legislation.
...in order for their voices to be heard.
- ...told me any pregnancy will be very...
- And the filibuster went viral.
Not only was she a woman
opposing the bill, but she was one
of the only women in the room.
It was an internet moment. People had left their kids
with their neighbors
and driven hours to Austin to be there.
Students had left their college campuses
and came to Austin
to hear Wendy filibuster.
These are Texans who relied
on the minority...
I'm a Texan.
Never seen the outpouring of activism
like we saw there.
You literally could not get
in the capitol.
Every annex was full, every room was full.
It was extraordinary.
...another ruling she made
was if there was a...
And about 15 minutes
before midnight,
procedural rules of order were broken...
...and the third...
...in order to bring
my filibuster to an end.
And the people who were there
understood
that rules were being broken
in order to silence opposition to a bill.
After consultation
with the parliamentarian and after...
- And they'd had enough.
- ...well taken and is sustained.
Bullshit!
The chair recognizes Senator...
Let her speak!
Let her speak! Let her speak!
Wendy! Wendy! Wendy! Wendy!
Wendy! Wendy!
And as they began to scream,
everyone up and down the hallways
began to scream,
and at every level of the rotunda
and outside on the capitol lawn.
And I could literally feel
the vibration of their voices
and their energy
and the pounding of their feet.
If I can have order.
We are in the middle of a vote.
The secretary has started the vote.
It ate up enough of the clock
that the final vote wasn't taken
until 12:03.
Members, it's now past midnight. And so...
And it became known
as the people's filibuster. Rightly so.
This is straight from
Senator Wendy Davis, okay?
Hold your applause.
First, "I love you guys." Okay? -
- We love you, too, Wendy!
"So the lieutenant governor has agreed
that SB-5 is dead."
The woman who filibustered
the Senate the other day,
she was born into difficult circumstances.
She's the daughter of a single woman.
She was a teenage mother herself.
She managed to eventually graduate
from Harvard Law School
and serve in the Texas Senate.
It's unfortunate
that she hasn't learned
from her own example
that every life must be given a chance
to realize its full potential
and that every life matters.
We had successfully
killed the bill.
But we were called right back
within a few days.
And, of course, this time
there was no way to filibuster.
♪ Where have all the babies gone?♪
♪ I pray to heaven for every one♪
Get ready to do it all again.
Governor Rick Perry called
a special session early this evening.
We talked about the choice.
Do you think if the mother had
a conversation with the baby and said,
"You know, this just isn't really
convenient to give birth to you right now.
Do you mind dying?"
I can't take it anymore!
-I think--
-That was very offensive!
I think that baby would say--
This is an assault on women!
I don't get mad with those folks.
I pray for her.
You are failing Texas!
In just a few moments,
we are going to vote on a bill
that has deeply and profoundly divided us.
Separating us by political party...
by gender...
by life experience...
by what our religious beliefs bind us to.
Not in this life!
We all believe in the beauty
and the wonder that is human life.
But I also believe that women already here
are beautiful.
And that they deserve to live,
they deserve to determine
the direction of their lives,
they deserve to be recognized
as full people...
fully capable
of making difficult decisions
with the help of their family,
their doctor and their God.
Wendy! Wendy! Wendy! Wendy!
Wendy! Wendy!
No woman should be judged by someone else,
someone who believes
they would have made a different decision.
No woman should be judged by someone else,
because these decisions
are never ever easy.
They're not made casually or quickly.
And those of us in the Senate
should refuse to make this decision
casually or quickly.
Because the fight for the future of Texas
is just beginning.
Thank you, Mr. President.
Thank you, members.
There being 19 ayes and 11 nays,
House Bill 2 is finally passed.
We won't go back! We won't go back!
We won't go back!
Come on!
We won't go back! We won't go back!
It is our responsibility to improve
the quality of care for women
in the state.
Of course, the argument was made
all along that somehow
this is being done in the interests
of women's health.
And in spite of incredible scientific
pushback to that statement,
House Bill 2 passed.
Shame! Shame! Shame!
The law went into effect and over half of
our abortion clinics in the state closed.
We went from 41 clinics to 19
as a consequence
of the implementation of the law.
In central Texas,
there were no clinics left open.
And that was pretty demoralizing.
But there was something really important
that had happened.
We as a state woke up to the reality
of an assault on women.
We woke up to the reality of our power.
And it's a power that has continued
to grow.
The first major abortion case
in almost a decade.
It centers on a case in Texas
that has already forced clinics to close
and could force even more
to close down as well.
The stakes are huge. And they're not just
huge for Texas women.
They're huge for women
all over the country.
Anti-choice! Anti-women!
If the Court affirms
the law in Texas,
I have no doubt that other states
will immediately follow suit.
And so many women will no longer
have access
to abortion care.
It's almost like a perfect
controlled experiment, isn't it?
It's like you put the law into effect,
twelve clinics closed. You take the law
out of the fact, they reopen.
That's absolutely correct.
I went to the argument,
and I was struck by
the difference between a Court
with one female justice
and a Court with three.
Can I walk through the burden?
She has to travel 200 miles
to get two days of treatment.
How many women
are located over 100 miles...
The women could reinforce
each other's viewpoints.
There has to some tie between
benefit and burden, doesn't there?
I think they were very good
at throwing aside
all of these specious arguments,
that the state was making that
really all they cared about was women.
There are benefits for the ASC
and admitting-privileges...
What is the benefit...
What evidence is there...
Just said, "You know, what's going on here
is you are making it more difficult
for women to exercise their choice...
This is one of the lowest-risk procedures.
...and we are going to respect
her decision."
...this law was targeted at abortion only.
...many procedures
are much higher risk:
colonoscopies, liposuctions.
We could go on and on.
And I have to tell you,
they took over that argument.
What it's about is that
a woman has a fundamental right
to make this choice for herself.
Today the Supreme Court struck down
a Texas law
that imposed strict requirements
on clinics and doctors,
finding those limits place an undue burden
on the constitutional right to abortion.
For me, the highlight of that decision was
the justices' incorporation
of actual medicine and science.
We've seen a decision about abortion that says,
"If you're going to make a claim,
the claim must be factually accurate."
But the reality is
that the appointing of our justices
is highly political.
And so, at any time, the balance
of the Court can change.
And the decision may be different
next time.
The Supreme Court decision in Hellerstedt
motivated pro-life people,
reinforced, once again,
that if we want to change the laws,
we have to change the Supreme Court.
Donald Trump meeting privately
in New York with leading evangelicals.
Donald Trump came and had a conversation.
Now we don't agree on everything.
I've been working on national elections
for a number of years
and there's always been an effort
to try to consolidate
conservative evangelicals.
It is a critical voting block
for any Republican candidate.
To win in November, Donald Trump needs
75, maybe even 80 percent of evangelicals.
Our goals are very simple.
It is to advance faith in public policy
and in our culture as a whole,
from a Christian world view.
We are unapologetically Christian.
Evangelicals have been under constant
attack by the Obama administration.
And quite frankly, they're tired of it.
And under Barack Obama,
this heavy hand of government tried
to force society to accept things like
abortion and the redefinition of marriage.
These things run counter to nature.
They run counter to the moral law of God.
And so what you saw is pushback.
Obviously, there's not many choices here.
The choice is between Hillary Clinton,
and we know exactly
what she will provide to America.
Or we have Donald Trump.
He's considered
the least religious of the candidates.
If Ivanka weren't my daughter,
perhaps I'd be dating her.
You know about
sexual predators and things like that.
- You are one!
- All right, wasn't gonna say that.
I'm very pro-choice.
I just believe in choice.
Evangelical Christians
aren't fully onboard yet.
Some say they may sit home come November.
You cannot ignore
this constituency.
But remember,
George H.W. Bush was pro-choice,
became pro-life.
Mr. Bush has something to think about.
Human life is precious, born or unborn.
Ronald Reagan signed the most liberal
abortion law in America in the late '60s,
and was a pro-life hero by 1980.
I think when you interrupt the pregnancy,
you're taking a human life.
So all Donald Trump has to do is,
as those prior nominees did,
make it clear.
We came together in a national crusade
to make America great again.
-And to make a new beginning.
-Make it clear.
"I changed my views."
The justices that I'm going to appoint
will be pro-life.
The pro-life constituency is absolutely
essential for a Republican victory.
Donald J. Trump.
Make it clear that if he becomes
president, he'll fight for those things.
It's not only about Roe v Wade.
It is about what's happening right now
in America.
So many states are putting
very stringent regulations on women that
block them from exercising
that choice...
I believe what sold the pro-life
community on Donald Trump
was the final debate in Las Vegas.
I will defend Roe v. Wade,
and I will defend women's rights to make
their own health care decisions.
I was in the audience.
I was watching him. ...which divides you--
a woman's right to abortion?
And when he went into a discussion
of partial-birth abortion,
late-term abortion...
If you go with what Hillary is saying,
in the ninth month, you can take the baby
and rip the baby out of the womb
of the mother. ...I knew those were Donald Trump's words.
Now, you can say that that's okay.
Those were not the words
of some speechwriter.
It's not okay with me.
Because based on what she's saying...
It was clearly Trump speaking
at that moment.
You can take the baby and rip the baby
out of the womb, in the ninth month,
on the final day!
And that's not acceptable.
And when he did that,
I believe he sealed the deal
with pro-lifers across the country.
And will,
to the best of my ability,
...preserve, protect, and defend...
...preserve, protect,
and defend...
...the Constitution of the United States.
-So help me God.
Congratulations, Mr. President.
When I became a physician,
the oath that I took was that I was gonna
provide the best medical care
for all patients who needed it.
And patients need access to abortions.
And they need care delivered to them
with dignity and respect.
All right, you ready?
So if that means getting on planes
or driving hundreds of miles,
I'm going to continue to do that,
because that's what's needed right now.
Women have built their lives
around the ability to make decisions
about pregnancy.
So, we have to make sure
that their right is protected.
And we have to remain vigilant.
Because there is a very real concern
that the Trump administration is going
to appoint anti-abortion judges.
President Trump announced
nearly a dozen new nominees
for the lower federal courts.
Hundreds of seats are going
to be filled by this administration
thoughout the judicial system.
These people will be serving
for the rest of their lives.
It's life term. It's generations
of impact on American law.
The Court of Appeals,
circuit judges...
whether it be district judges...
When you really think about
the way we're going,
years from now, picking good judges
even at the district level
is extremely important.
And that's how we're going to finish this
to overtun Roe vs. Wade.
Today I am keeping
another promise,
by nominating Judge Neil Gorsuch
to the United States Supreme Court.
We're putting out strong
pro-life bills and so, eventually,
the Supreme Court will weigh in
on the issue.
I don't know
how long it will take
to overturn Roe v. Wade,
or when it will be overturned.
I have no doubt it will be.
All across the nation,
life is winning again in America.
In a monumental moment
for the Supreme Court,
Justice Anthony Kennedy is retiring
from the Court.
The crucial swing vote
is now stepping down
and President Trump will get the chance
to shape this Court for a generation.
This is an opportunity to restore
a culture of life in this country.
This is a historic moment.
And we have a chance
to take down Roe v. Wade.
I think this supercharges
the president's base.
Seven out of ten of his evangelical voters
said that the Supreme Court has
an effect on their daily lives.
And I think he should put forth
a candidate that is above reproach
on this issue of the sanctity
of human life.
And I think Roe can be overturned.
I do believe it could be overturned
and I think it goes back to the states.
And I think that the states will decide
what policies to handle. And I think...
we will be
a predominantly pro-life nation.
You're gonna see 20 states
pass laws banning abortion outright.
Because they know
that there are now going to be
five votes on the Supreme Court
to overturn Roe v. Wade.
If Roe v. Wade is overturned
by the Supreme Court,
we will see some states that will say
abortion is not allowed,
there will be some states
that are going to...
probably not place many limits
on abortion at all,
but we are not going to stop.
We will keep working
to protect the unborn babies.
Whether or not Roe
is overturned, the rights granted by Roe
are almost gone for many women already.
So, if doctors can't perform
the procedure,
or clinics can't keep their doors open...