♪ Happy holiday ♪
♪ Happy holiday ♪♪
Merry Christmas, bud. Thank
you. Merry Christmas to you.
Okay.
Hi, chief.
Come in.
Hello, honey.
Well, this is our last night in
show business. Some feeling, huh?
Some feeling. I got the
ring and the license.
Honey, we're ready.
Oh.
Say, there's a hook leftover
at the top here. Should that be?
Never mind that, dear.
I'll take care of it.
Jim.
Huh?
Well, I think that
tie is terrible.
Well, who cares? Tomorrow I'm a
farmer. You'd better go change it.
Listen, honey, when you flip on those twinkle
toes, who's going to be looking at my tie?
You only have five minutes.
Hurry. Okay, I'm on my way.
What'd he say?
I didn't tell him.
Why not? We love each other.
You want to continue dancing.
I know, but...
he gets a look.
Oh, he's always had that look. It
doesn't mean anything emotionally.
It has to do with his liver.
Tell him you've made a mistake.
You don't want to give up
your career and live on a farm.
But he's already bought the farm
and the license and the ring.
Oh, I can't tell him.
All right. I will.
Right after our number.
Listen, darling, don't weaken.
Think of our life together.
Think of diamonds, of sables,
of your own little penthouse.
Is that a promise? Well, just
think about them for the time being.
<i Ready, Miss
Dixon. Oh, thank you.
This thing didn't come
out even. Oh, I'll fix it.
We have to hurry.
I love you.
I love you...
and Jim.
I loveJim too. But after all,
I mean, let's not be too chummy.
♪ Here she comes
down the street ♪
♪ My, oh, my ain't she sweet ♪
♪ W hy, here comes
my hot toddy ♪
♪ Over my dead body ♪
♪ I'll capture
her heart singing ♪
♪ Just wait until she gets
a load of my dancing ♪
♪ Just wait till
I start singing ♪
♪ I'll take her strolling
down the road with my dancing ♪
♪ I can't go wrong
A tender song ♪
♪ A nd she'll discover
my charms ♪
♪ Some fancy taps
and she'll collapse ♪
♪ A nd fall right
into my arms ♪
♪ I'll capture
her heart singing ♪
♪ Oh, no you haven't a chance ♪
♪ W hen I go into my dance ♪
♪ I'll take you
through life singing ♪
♪ La-da-da-di
La-da-da-di La-da-da-di ♪
♪ Boom boom
boo-boo-boo-boo-boo-boom ♪
♪ I'll make you
my wife dancing ♪
♪ If you could dance
instead of sing ♪
♪ I'd learn to love you
somehow ♪
♪ If you could sing
instead of dance ♪
♪ I'd take you home
with me now ♪
♪ Boom boo-boo-boo-boom
boo-boo-boo-boo-boom ♪
♪ Boo-boo-boo-boo
bo-ba-bi-bo-bo ♪
♪ T he way you sing
don't mean a thing ♪
♪ Y ou'd better stick
to your dance ♪
♪ A nd as for you
Your dance won't do ♪
♪ Y ou'll have to sing
for romance ♪
♪ I'll capture her heart ♪
♪ Singing ♪ ♪ Dancing ♪
Not much of a Christmas
present for you, is it?
I mean, both of us
walking out on you.
Don't worry about me, kid.
I'll do all right. What a chump.
Can't you see what we're walking
out on? The grind, 365 days a year.
When was the last time you had a day
off? I don't know. Maybe last year.
Did you ever hear ofThanksgiving
or Labor Day or the Fourth ofJuly?
Vaguely. You know what
they are, don't you?
They're holidays, days of
rest. There's lots of'em.
They mark 'em in red on the
calendar so you can't miss 'em.
What happens in show business when a holiday comes along?
You give an extra performance.
Not for me, brother. Lila and I are
going up to that farm in Connecticut.
We're gonna liv
by the calendar.
Say, Jim, uh... there's something
you should know. Hmm?
Oh, I know, Ted. I feel
the same way about you.
You know, we've had
our ups and our downs.
We've fought a little over
women, but... I know, but...
Sorry, Jimmy boy,
but that's life.
If I'm not the best manager in the
business, I'll eat a mechanic's shirt.
Fifteen weeks at the Park Club,
sight unseen, for you and Lila.
Two hundred dollars a week more than you
were getting with the farmer thrown in.
What's the matter?
I haven't told him.
You haven't told him?
Haven't told me what?
What's the news?
Well, don't be upset, Jim dear.
It isn't that I don't love you.
I do.
I love everybody.
But when Ted explained
how much he loved me and...
All at once we both realized
that we belonged together.
The two of us,
dedicating our lives...
to making people happy with
our feet. The two of you, huh?
Dedicating your lives to making
people happy with your feet.
That's sweet. Well, I guess that
kick I just got was a good start, huh?
Sorry, Jimmy boy,
but that's life.
It's best you found out now. You
wouldn't want to make Lila unhappy.
Oh, no, no, I wouldn't
want to make Lila unhappy.
Not now, now that I
really know her.
What a narrow squeak that was.
What do you mean by that? Oh,
nothing, honey. I'm happy you're happy.
That little speech sounds like
the crackle of confederate money.
Well, kids, I'm still
going to rejoin the human race.
I hope you get a lot of work,
holidays included.
Dance yourselves into
beautiful nervous breakdowns.
If you ever want to look me up, you know
where to find me. Midville, Connecticut...
under a large shady tree,
just being lazy.
♪ Lazy ♪
♪ I want to be lazy ♪
♪ I long to be out in the sun ♪
♪ With no work to be done ♪
♪ Under that awning ♪
♪ They call the sky ♪
♪ Stretching and yawning ♪
♪ And let the world
go drifting by ♪
♪ I want to peek
through the deep ♪
♪ Tangled wild woods
Counting sheep ♪
♪ Till I sleep
like a child would ♪
♪ With a great big
valise full ♪
♪ Ofbooks to read
where it's peaceful ♪
♪ While I'm killing time ♪
♪ Being lazy ♪
Whoa! W hoa!
So lazy acres was a snare
and a delusion, huh?
Oh, brother! There's the
hardest work in the world.
Maybe you'd be happier
back in town, Jim.
If you get that agricultural urge
again, you can raise a geranium.
Oh, no.
Wait till you hear.
I think I've dreamed up the greatest idea
I ever had. And you've had some pips.
Oh, but this can't miss. I'm
turning the farm into an inn!
But what an inn.
Here, read up, brother.
"Holiday Inn.
Midville, Connecticut.
"Get off the highway
and relax on a farm.
Dancing, entertainment, home
cooking. Open holidays only."
Open holidays only? How many
of those are there? Mm-hmm.
Oh, there's about 15.
That gives me 350 days a year to kick
around in. You would think of that.
Did you get your discharge
from that sanitarium?
Oh, don't you worry. This is going to
work. I'm having auditions every day.
If you run into any talent,
will you send 'em out?
Sure, as soon as I get back.
I'm flying down to Miami Beach tonight to
set an engagement for Ted and Lila. Lila.
You forgot the flowers.
Don't get excited. There's a
flower shop out at the airport.
I guarantee to have orchids
before her first number.
Boy, you'd better. This kid even
expects presents on Father's Day.
Well, good luck, Jim.
So long, Ted.
Have a nice trip. I mean,
yeah, thanks, I will.
That reminds me,
I forgot to give him...
a little Christmas
remembrance I brought along.
Got one here for each of you.
Say, this is swell.
What is it?
Homemade peach preserves. I put 'em up
myself before I went into the sanitarium.
Boy, do I go for those!
Why, they're great on...
on, uh... or even plain.
They're nonfattening too.
Well, it's a long trip.
I think I'll get along.
Will you say hello to Lila for
me? You've got to catch the act.
We've got some new routines.
And then after the show...
I don't think they like
this nightclub air.
Wait. You'd better
wait for Lila's.
I think Danny's was the
loudest. It was a different tone.
Dawn patrol, huh?
Hello.
Am I too late?
You would've been
in another minute.
Danny Reed.
Listen, I have to wait
on that man. But, uh...
I'll work five nights free. Anything.
Just leave me alone and don't butt in.
What would you like? Orchids.
The finest you've got.
Corsage?
No, no, a dozen.
Loose, looking like
they don't care.
All right. There. "Lila... love, Ted."
Have them delivered to Miss Lila Dixon
at the Club Pierre before 11:00.
Oh, I'm sorry, but our delivery
truck is on its last trip...
and won't be back
until after 11:00.
How about a messenger boy?
It's impossible to guarantee
delivery this late on Christmas Eve.
But to help you out, I'll
take them. Oh, there you are.
A dozen orchids, please.
Lady, you're a lifesaver.
Here. Here's $5.00. Take your
boyfriend out and show him a good time.
Let's consider this
a personal favor.
Well, I can't leave town
indebted to a stranger.
Would you like to see the floor
show at the club? I'd like to, but...
Now you just give
this card to Francois,
and he'll seat you at the entertainer's
table. Why, you're Mr. Reed!
Uh-oh.
I'm Linda Mason.
This is a part-time job.
Actually, I sing and dance.
Mr. Reed, I want... I know, I know. You've
studied dancing since you were a child.
You spent long, weary hours
in every agency on Broadway.
But just now I happen to be
catching a plane to Mi...
Once you told me I was no good, I could get
a job in a bargain basement and like it.
Now look, honestly,
as soon as I get...
Oh, of course, sure.
You worked hard.
You want a chance. So what?
So I'm going to give it to you.
Ajob? Uh-huh. A friend of mine is opening
a place in Connecticut: Holiday Inn.
You take that card out there, tell
him I sent you and you'll be all set.
Mr. Reed, how could I
possibly thank you? Don't.
Just deliver those orchids
and let me catch my plane.
This table's reserved
for the band. Excuse me!
Fussy, isn't he?
I think I'll have
a bowl of coffee, huh?
And the lady?
Coffee.
- We seem to be on the 40-cent
tour here. - It is embarrassing.
I'm Jim Hardy.
Linda Mason.
Got a friend in the show? Well,
I'm here at Mr. Reed's invitation.
Oh, Danny.
Then you know Ted Hanover?
Why, yes, naturally.
Oh, my. He's quite a man
with the ladies, that Ted.
Well, after all, he's a very
attractive man. Do you know him?
Oh, yes. As a matter of fact, I've been
considering Ted and his partner for my new club.
- Oh, you have a place?
- Oh, yes, yes.
I don't know though. His act might not
go so well in a place as large as mine.
Well, I've found that the size
of a place doesn't matter...
if one has
sufficient personality.
That's what you've found, huh?
You in show business?
Oh... I'm Linda Mason.
Oh, Linda Mason!
♪ I could dance nightly ♪
♪ Just holding you
tightly, my sweet ♪
♪ I could keep right on ♪
♪ Because you're so
light on your feet ♪
♪ Y ou're easy to dance with ♪
♪ There is no doubt ♪
♪ In the way we stand out
in a crowd ♪
♪ Though it's called dancing ♪
♪ To me it's
romancing out loud ♪
♪ Y ou're easy to dance with ♪
♪ Loving you the way I do ♪
♪ Makes you easy
to dance with ♪
♪ T hat is why I'm always
right on the beat ♪
♪ A ll those times
in one man's arms ♪
♪ Make you easy to dance with ♪
♪ I can hardly keep
my mind on my feet ♪
<i ♪Let's dance forever ♪
♪ Come on, say we'll
never be through ♪
♪ It's so easy
to dance with you ♪
♪ Y ou're easy to dance with ♪
♪ It's so easy
to dance with you ♪
<i ♪It's so easy to dance ♪
♪ It's so eas
to dance with you ♪♪
That was wonderful. It's a great
act, isn't it? Here they come.
Who?
Ted and Lila.
Hey, what's the matter?
Hello, Lila. How are you? Jimmy
boy! I'm so glad to see you.
I thought you were alone. Who's
your friend and what's her hurry?
- Don't ask me. She's your friend.
- Mine?
- What is she afraid of, facing me?
- Darling, I swear I never...
"Darling, I swear." You lie. If
you don't... You're on. Take a bow.
Encore!
So this is Holiday Inn.
Yeah, will be
if it ever opens up.
Why shouldn't it open? I ain't
one to talk, but you could buy...
a half interest in this
place for a barrel of apples.
Next train for New York's at
7:43 if we can flag her down.
Say, I'm looking for a job.
Where's the boss?
Right here. I'll
be down in a second.
So you're the big shot
that didn't know whether...
Hanover and Dixon were
good enough for your place.
That wasn't exactly hay you were
throwing, either. "I'm Linda Mason."
Merry Christmas.
All right, you're a fake and I'm
a phony. And we're both soaked.
Are you hurt?
I'll check later.
Come on, let's get out of this
before you catch cold. All right. Oh!
Well, here's what cooks.
Oh!
Why, this is darling. Was it as large
as this when it was a farmhouse?
Yeah, it was built by a fellow who felt cramped in New York.
He ran out of lumber, though.
- Oh, Mamie!
- Coming!
Is your names Mamie? No. No.
Get back in the kitchen.
My, my, what's happened?
Oh, we had a little accident.
Mamie, this is Miss Linda
Mason. How do you do?
Pleased to know you, Miss Linda.
And these are her children.
There's Daphne and there's
Vanderbilt. How do you do?
Mamie, will you take Miss Mason
up to the guest room...
and change her into anything
that'll fit her?
Sure thing, Mr. Jimmy.
Come on, honey.
I'll see about getting a fire
ready in the living room.
Is your names Miss Linda?
No.
I don't know. It sounds like
something you'd dream about at night.
It would be wonderful. Then you'd wake
up and realize it couldn't work.
Oh, it'll work if I can sell
the idea to some performers.
They seem to think that profit
sharing means taking bows...
on an empty stomach. So that's
why you're not open tonight.
Well, I'm also particular about
the kind of talent I'm going to use.
Fifteen holidays a year.
Mm-hmm.
You're a lazy fellow.
No, not especially.
Just have my own ideas
about living.
My father was like you.
Just a man with a family.
Never amounted to much,
didn't care.
But as long as he was alive, we always had
plenty to eat and clothes to keep us warm.
Were you happy?
Yes.
Then your father was a very
successful man. Hope I can do as well.
I came out here for a job.
Could you use me?
I might find a spot for you.
What can you do?
Oh, I sing a little and dance.
Couldn't guarantee
any salary at first.
Right now I've got
the ledger in an iron lung.
I don't care if you pay off in eggs. Just
give me a chance. Let's see what you can do.
Thanks a lot. I've written
special music for each holiday.
This gives me a chance to keep a
little promise I made to myself.
I said I was going to sing
this song at the inn tonight.
♪ I'm dreaming ♪
♪ Of a white Christmas ♪
♪ Just like the ones ♪
♪ I used to know ♪
♪ W here the treetops glisten ♪
♪ A nd children listen ♪
♪ T o hear ♪
♪ Sleigh bells in the snow ♪
♪ I'm dreaming ♪
♪ Of a white Christmas ♪
♪ W ith every Christmas card ♪
♪ I write ♪
♪ May your days ♪
♪ Be merry and bright ♪
♪ A nd may all your ♪
♪ Christmases ♪
♪ Be white ♪
♪ I'm dreaming ♪
♪ Of a white Christmas ♪
♪ Just like the ones
I used to know ♪
Where the treetops glisten.
♪ W here the treetops glisten ♪
And children listen.
♪ And children listen ♪
♪ T o hear ♪ ♪ To hear ♪
♪ Sleigh bells in the snow ♪
♪ I'm dreaming ♪
♪ Of a white Christmas ♪
♪ With every Christmas card ♪
♪ I write ♪
♪ May your days be merry ♪
♪ A nd bright ♪
♪ A nd may all ♪
♪ Y our Christmases ♪
♪ Be white ♪ ♪
<i ♪Happy holidays ♪
♪ Happy holidays ♪
♪ W hile the merry bells
keep ringing ♪
♪ May your every wish
come true ♪
♪ Happy holidays ♪
♪ May the calendar
keep bringing ♪
♪ Happy holidays to you ♪
♪ If you're burdened down
with trouble ♪
♪ If your nerves
are wearing thin ♪
♪ Park your load
down the road ♪
♪ A nd come to Holiday Inn ♪
♪ If the traffic noise
affects you ♪
♪ Like a squeaky violin ♪
♪ Kick your cares
down the stairs ♪
♪ A nd come to Holiday Inn ♪
♪ If you can't find
somebody who ♪
♪ W ill set your heart awhirl ♪
♪ Get in your car
and motor to ♪
♪ T he home of boy meets girl ♪
♪ If you're laid up
with a breakdown ♪
♪ T hrow away your vitamin ♪
♪ Don't get worse ♪
♪ Grab your nurse ♪
♪ A nd come to Holiday Inn ♪
♪ Happy holidays ♪ ♪♪
♪ Happy holidays ♪
♪ May the calendar
keep bringing ♪
♪ Happy holidays to you ♪ ♪
Happy New Year, Ted.
No!
Francois, have you seen
Mr. Hanover? Twice, sir.
What happened?
The first time, sir,
he came from his room with
a telegram in his hand.
He ordered scotch and soda, a
bottle of each. I know. What then?
The second time, he asked
which way is "Connect-I-cut."
Connecticut.
"Connect-I-cut."
He said he has a friend there
who knows about women too.
Why didn't you stop him?
How could I stop him, sir, when I
don't know which way is "Connect-I-cut"?
Who said Holiday Inn
wouldn't work?
We're gonna divvy up a stack
of money tonight, huh? Man, man!
I've got a landlady who's gonna
ask for your autographed picture.
Everybody get somethin'
All right, go to bed now.
It's gettin' late. Good night.
Good night.
Look, it's almost time.
It's practicall
straight up, isn't it?
♪ One minute to midnight ♪
♪ One minute to go ♪
♪ One minute to say good-bye ♪
♪ Before we say hello ♪
♪ Let's start
the New Year right ♪
♪ T welve o'clock tonight ♪
♪ W hen they dim the light ♪
♪ Let's begin ♪
♪ Kissing the old year out ♪
♪ Kissing the New Year in ♪
♪ Let's watch
the old year die ♪
♪ W ith a fond good-bye ♪
♪ A nd our hopes as high ♪
♪ A s a kite ♪
♪ How can our love go wrong ♪
♪ If we start
the New Year right ♪ ♪
That's it, that's midnight. I'll
see you out on the floor. All right.
Come on, everybody! Happy New
Year! Get your partner and dance.
Happy holiday.
Happy New Year.
I forgot my check. You won't need
that, but you'll need your coat.
Happy New Year. Happy New Year.
Same to you. Many of them. I gotta...
Come on, Jim, you gotta dance.
Oh, you gotta dance with me. Come
on, you gotta dance. No, I can't. Oh!
Why, Mr. Hanover!
That's Ted Hanover.
Wait a minute. I gotta go.
I don't want Ted Hanover.
I want you. This is
New Year's, kid. I know.
Ted!
He wasn't drunk. It's
a gag. What happened?
Ted Hanover with his new
partner. They were great!
New partner?
You'd better get back. I'm
sorry. If I'd known how he was...
Oh, he'll be all right in a week
or ten days. You'd better hurry.
Ted! Ted!
Ted! Oh. How is he?
He's out cold.
Hot or cold, he can keep
his dancing shoes in my office.
Did you hear that applause?
Yeah, it went pretty good.
And I was worried about his
losing Lila. Losing Lila?
Yeah, she eloped tonight
with some Texan from Texas...
with Ted's engagement ring
on her finger.
But who cares? You lose one girl,
you find another. That's life.
That's good, huh?
Here we go again.
Come in! Oh.
Good morning, Ted.
Good mor... Ooh.
Got a little head?
Say, where am I?
You're in Holiday Inn. How'd
I get here? Who brought me?
You were clinging to the
undercarriage of a jeep, I think.
Here, have a slug
out of the mug.
You mean, you don't
remember anything? Uh...
let's see,
I had a wire from Lila...
telling me she was gonna marry
some millionaire or something.
Yeah. I remember that all
right. Uh, then I had a drink.
A drink?
Boy, you were fractured.
And then, uh, I decided
I had to talk to my old palJim.
You don't remember anything
else? No, that's all.
Except that I... must have been killed
on the way out here or something.
You really come up empty, huh?
Too bad about Lila.
I think you're better off doing
a single. You're a born soloist.
Oh, no, no, Jim. I've got to have
a partner. And when I find her...
Yeah, I know, you'll
fall in love with her.
Happy New Year!
Oh, don't do that.
Why didn't you tell me?
Letting me worry
about his losing Lila,
and all the time he's got
this girl on the leash.
What girl?
Boy, you must've been high.
Doing a complete dance routine
with your new partner and you...
You don't know who she is?
I danced with a new partner?
When? Where?
Here! Last night!
Think, Ted.
Remember?
Wait a minute I remember.
I got here just about midnight.
There was a girl.
We danced.
What'd she look like?
Oh... I don't know.
All I sa was a vague outline.
Can't you remember
anything about her?
Well, I remember
dancing with her.
If I ever dance with her again,
I'd probably recognize her.
Great. That takes care of
everything but finding her.
You were here. Why ask me how she
looked? I only saw her from the back.
She was a... About this...
She had a...
If I ever saw her from the
back again, I'd recognize her.
Well, that's fine.
After I've danced with her,
I just turn her around
for your okay.
This should be a cinch.
You saw her.
Describe her. Who, me? Well,
I wasn't watching very closely.
She was a medium... medium-built
sort of a girl with a medium face.
She had a... a nice evening
gown on with a belt in the back.
She was built just like
a girlfriend of mine,
a girl you don't know, but...
her name was Consuela Schlepkiss.
She used to play the pinball
machine at the drugstore.
She was high ma
three weeks in a row.
Thanks.
Thanks a lot.
That's nothing at all.
Happy to do it for you.
Say, I've got a hunch, fellas, we're
gonna find this girl eventually.
And when we do,
we'll be glad we waited for her.
Listen, I'm not interested in
getting any other partner, understand?
A chance meeting in the night.
Destiny.
She'll be back.
Here's where we'll find he
on the next holiday. Here?
Here.
I've got to go turn the roast.
Now don't worry.
We'll find her.
If I see her from the back
again, I'll recognize her.
It's kind of a roundabout way
to go at it, but let's try it.
<i Are you decent?
Yes, come in.
What's that?
Well, I thought it over,
and I believe our number
would go better in blackface.
Oh, I thought we were
gonna do it like this.
Well, that was before I...
before I thought it over.
I'll look terrible in the stuff. No.
I don't even know how to put
it on. I'll put it on for you.
I broke in as a bootblack,
you know. Here we go.
Oh!
For a month and a half...
I've been dreaming how pretty
I was going to look tonight.
Well, here's my punishment
for thinking so well of myself.
Oh, you'll have plenty
of times to be pretty.
I was just going to ask you to be
in the rest of the shows out here.
You were?
Will you?
Will I?
Fifteen nights a year...
Cinderella steps into her pumpkin
coach and becomes queen of Holiday Inn.
What's the matter?
I wish I didn't have to work all the other
days in the year to make these few possible.
Maybe a little later on
when we start doing better,
you can stay out here
all the time.
Did you hear
what you just said?
Yeah.
Was it a proposal?
Well, it will be when I get
a few bucks in the bank.
Well, you're a strange duck.
You don't even give me a chance to say
"darling" and throw my arms around you.
You'd better save that
till you see the bank book.
Well, I guess
I'm sort of engaged.
Say, what is this,
a daisy chain?
Uh... well...
we were just looking for the
back of a girl we don't know.
♪ Upon a February morn ♪
♪ A tiny baby boy was born ♪
♪ A braham ♪
♪ W hen he growed up
this tiny babe ♪
♪ Folks all called him
Honest Abe ♪
♪ A braham ♪
♪ In 1860 he became ♪
♪ T he 16th president ♪
♪ A nd now he's in
the hall of fame ♪
♪ A most respected gent ♪
♪ T hat's why we celebrate ♪
♪ T his blessed February date ♪
♪ A braham ♪
♪ W hen black folks
lived in slavery ♪
♪ W ho was it set
the darky free ♪
♪ A braham ♪
That's right, child.
♪ W hen troubles come down
from the shelf ♪
♪ W hose heart was bigger
than hisself ♪
♪ A braham ♪ Yeah, man!
♪ A braham ♪
♪ T he country's
going to the dogs ♪
♪ T hey shouted
loud and strong ♪
♪ T hen from a cabin
made out of logs ♪
♪ T he right man came along ♪
♪ A nd that is why
we celebrate ♪
♪ T his blessed February date ♪
♪ A braham ♪
♪ U.S.A.' United thanks ♪ Yeah!
♪ T o one whose name was
Nancy Hanks ♪ Tell me!
♪ A braham ♪
♪ She gave this land the finest
son ♪ That's what she did.
♪ W hoever went to
Washington ♪ Who dat?
♪ A braham ♪
♪ W hen someone told him
General Grant ♪
♪ W as drinking every night ♪
♪ He answered go on
out see if you can't ♪
♪ Get all my generals tight ♪
♪ A... ♪ ♪ That's why we celebrate ♪
♪ bra... ♪ ♪ This
blessed February date ♪
♪ ham ♪ ♪ Abraham ♪
♪ W as a real fine man
that Abraham ♪ ♪ Abraham ♪
♪ W as a great man Great man ♪
♪ A braham ♪ ♪
Good night.
I give up.
She's not here tonight.
You wait here. I'll go up
and see ifJim's seen her.
Gus is waiting to take you
to the station.
Remember, day after tomorrow,
St. Valentine's Day.
Someone's coming. Use the
other stairway. Well, who is it?
Bill collector.
Oh.
Good night.
Good night, Jim.
You'd better get inside before you
catch cold. You haven't got a coat.
Well, I...
Go on.
I don't need a coat now.
Hey, Ted did you find the girl?
This is terrible. I wish we could
recognize her from the front.
I feel like a wolf.
Ted!
She's here! I saw her!
This way! Let go! Who?
Shortcut, come on!
Giddap!
Why, it's locked. It's never
been locked before. Oh, me!
Let's try the other stairway.
Let go of me!
Go ahead.
Well, we've lost her again. Did you
get a look at her face this time?
No. We're still
working from the rear.
How do you know it was
her? She had an overcoat on.
I don't care if she ha... How do
you know she had an overcoat on?
Well, she... If she didn't,
look for a girl with pneumonia.
Come on, let's get inside.
Say, um, Jim,
when's your next show?
Next show? Uh, St.
Valentine's Day, I think.
Ooh, the day after tomorrow, huh? Is it?
That's a break. We'll get here
early and stay until we find her.
We'll make an announcement
asking her to identify herself.
We won't miss next time. No. Say,
fellas, how'd you like the show?
Well, we were so busy we
didn't see much of it, Jim. Why?
Thought the people seemed to like
the blackface routine. Yeah, they did.
Don't you think a blackface number
on St. Valentine's Day'd be novel?
A what? It's no good,
huh? Just an idea I had.
Well, good-bye.
Good-bye. So long, Jim.
Hey, lady!
Yes?
We open in an hour. You
haven't even had a rehearsal.
Coming.
Oh, very smart.
You'll have to talk Gus into
buying a horseless carriage.
I spend half my life between
here and the station.
Gus'll have to face the machine
age sooner or later, won't he?
Did you escape those bill collectors
the other night? Bill colle...
Oh, yes, temporarily. That reminds me,
I got a surprise for you downstairs.
Well, thanks. What reminds you? Nothing.
It's just, uh, I want you
to remember the surprise...
when those doggone
bill collectors move in.
You sound sweet, but
you don't make sense.
Oh, the inn is
so romantic-looking!
I posed for
those Cupids myself.
Hello, boys.
Hello, Linda. Hi, Jim.
A lot of paid-up
cards here tonight.
Where's the surprise?
Aha, right here.
A little home cookin'
I whipped up.
Beautiful.
"Be careful it's my heart."
And I ain't kiddin' either. I
wrote this just for you, honey.
♪ Be careful ♪
♪ It's my heart ♪
♪ It's not my watch
you're holding ♪
♪ It's my heart ♪
♪ It's not the note
I sent you ♪
♪ T hat you quickly burned ♪
♪ It's not the book
I lent you ♪
♪ T hat you never returned ♪
♪ Remember ♪
♪ It's my heart ♪
♪ T he heart with which
so willingly I part ♪
♪ It's yours to take
to keep or break ♪
♪ But please before you start ♪
♪ Be careful ♪
♪ It's my heart ♪
That's the girl.
♪♪
♪ Be careful ♪
♪ It's my heart ♪
♪ It's not my watch
you're holding ♪
♪ It's my heart ♪
♪ It's not the note
I sent you ♪
♪ That you quickly burned ♪
♪ It's not the book
I lent you ♪
♪ T hat you never returned ♪
♪ Remember♪
♪ It's my heart ♪
♪ The heart with which
so willingly I part ♪
♪ It's yours to take
to keep or break ♪
♪ But please before you start ♪
♪ Be careful ♪
♪ It's my heart ♪
Sorry, Jim,
I couldn't resist it.
Wonderful! She's perfect.
Light as a feather.
You found her. Jim, you're a pal. Yeah!
Do you realize we've been
searching for you for weeks?
For me?
Yes! Ever since...
The girl in the flower
shop. Yes, Mr. Reed.
Where have you been working
since New Year's Eve? Here.
- Would you min letting me in on your secret?
- It's no secret.
Ted Hanover is looking for a dancing
partner. We've decided to give you the job.
Now wait just a minute!
No hard feelings, Jim.
I don't blame you for trying. She's wonderful.
I feel as if I'd known her for months.
Oh, same old feeling, huh?
Washington's Birthday is the
next show. That'll give us a week.
- We can open the act here.
- I'll take car of the invitations.
Strictly formal. I'll get all the newspaper
boys from New York. Hold everything.
This is my inn and I'm not running
it for a bunch of stuffed shirts.
What would you like,
the dungaree set?
That'd be better than that bunch of chowderheads
you'd drag in. Maybe I can't use the act.
- Not use Ted Hanover?
- Well, the show is pretty well set.
You're in, but he's out. You could change
the show for a special occasion like this.
Of course he could. He's just
trying to hide his gratitude.
Jim, you'd better
think up a number for us.
Well, just what do you
visualize, Ziggy?
Uh, let's see, um...
for Washington's Birthday, I see
a sort of a romantic costume thing.
Naturally. Something that just
reeks with grace and charm, you know.
Mm-hmm. I think the music
should be sweet and gentle to...
Well, to create the mood each time
I take her into my arms and kiss her.
That's it. Don't you think it's
getting a little stuffy in here?
♪ I could say
that you're homely ♪
♪ Just as homely as pie ♪
♪ But this is
Washington's Birthday ♪
♪ A nd I've got to say
you're beautiful ♪
♪ ' Cause I can't tell a lie ♪
♪ I could say
that you're stupid ♪
♪ Nothing up in your crown ♪
♪ But this is
Washington's Birthday ♪
♪ A nd the truthful he
of the cherry tree ♪
♪ W ould look down on me
and frown ♪
♪ I could say that I hate you ♪
♪ If I try ♪
♪ But I've got to say
I love you ♪
♪ ' Cause it's
February the 22nd ♪
♪ A nd I can't tell a lie ♪
Hit it!
Come in!
In spite of what good old Jim tried to do
to us, your future starts as of tonight.
Now, where would you like
to go from here? From here?
Yes. New York? Havana? Rio? We
have our pick of engagements.
But I can't be your partner if you
leave the inn. Of course you can.
There's no reason for
you to remain buried here.
There's a very good reason.
I've promised to be in Jim's holiday
shows for the rest of the year.
He tricked you into that while
he was hiding you from me.
No matter how he did it,
I promised.
Besides, we're...
Well, we're going to
be married. Married?
Now wait a minute! Let's be
fair. He didn't give me a chance.
After all, I love you too.
From the very first moment
we danced together,
I knew you were to be
the one girl in my life.
But you... you didn't
even know my name.
Please! All right, forget
about me, then. Forget aboutJim.
Think of yourself. Here's your chance
to do the one thing you like best.
Not only for 15 days
a year, but always.
Sorry, but I promised.
Well... I guess I should apologize
for hoking up your number, huh?
Oh, forget it. I'm the one
that should apologize to you.
Here I've been trying to
take Linda away from you,
not knowing you two were
going to be married. Married?
Yeah. Aren't you?
Yes. Sure. Uh...
I mean, naturally
we're sort of engaged.
Oh.
Well, um, anyway, I've decided to
bow out of here. Linda's all yours.
Well, you're a pretty game
guy to take it this way.
It's happened so often I'm
getting used to it, that's all.
Good-bye, kid.
Lot of luck, Ted.
Thanks.
How are we doing?
Two minutes ago, I would've
sold my chances for a tired dime.
But when a man is surprised to
hear that he's going to be married,
that's when I go to work
with a clear conscience.
Everything's good, huh?
Everything is perfect.
♪ In your Easter bonnet ♪
♪ W ith all the frills
upon it ♪
♪ Y ou'll be
the grandest lady ♪
♪ In the Easter Parade ♪
♪ I'll be all in clover ♪
♪ A nd when
they look you over ♪
♪ I'll be the proudest fella ♪
♪ In the Easter Parade ♪
♪ On the Avenue ♪
♪ Fifth Avenue ♪
♪ T he photographers
will snap us ♪
♪ A nd you'll find
that you're ♪
♪ In the rotogravure ♪
♪ Oh, I ♪
♪ Could write a sonnet ♪
♪ A bout your Easter bonnet ♪
♪ A nd of the girl I'm taking ♪
♪ T o the Easter Parade ♪
♪ On the Avenue ♪
♪ Fifth Avenue ♪
♪ T he photographers
will snap us ♪
♪ A nd you'll find
that you're ♪
♪ In the rotogravure ♪
♪ Oh, I ♪
♪ Could write a sonnet ♪
♪ A bout your Easter bonnet ♪
♪ A nd of the girl I'm taking ♪
♪ T o the Easter Parade ♪ ♪
Hello.
I didn't exactly expect
the welcome mat,
but I thought somebody
might say hello. Hello.
What brings you here on this
bright and uninviting day?
- I've discovered something, my friends, about life.
- Meaning what?
Well, I don't want success.
I want the true happiness you
people have found here at the inn.
You're not gonna stay
in the inn?
Not just stay. I want to be part of
your shows, help you in your work,
share your simple pleasures.
I asked you once
not to interfere, Ted.
Please believe me, I'm a
tired, lonely and unhappy man,
but I could be happy here helping
the two people I like the best.
Will you take me in? My motherly
intuition tells me to throw him out.
Well, at least give him the benefit of
the doubt. I've given him plenty of doubt.
Are you kidding with that"
Sharing life's simple pleasures"?
May I go inside with
you? Why, of course.
My trunks will arrive
this afternoon.
What do I do, move
in the broom closet?
That's no way to talk to a man who's here
to help you. The world doesn't change.
A gentle smile often breeds a kick in
the pants, but for your sake I'll be big.
Hmm.
I'll give you a tip, Gus: They'll
go up and back, but not sideways.
I keep forgettin' this blame
thing can't see where it's going.
Yeah. Well, unload the rest of
this stuff in the back, huh? Yeah.
Hey!
What'd you do get up before
breakfast? Oh, every morning.
When I found out how late you got
in, I told Mamie to let you sleep.
Life on a farm.
Can't beat it, huh?
Jim, you've made me
very happy. That's fine.
How about you making me happy? You sound
like a landlord with eviction papers.
This is good news. Lila's back in
New York. I got a letter from her.
What happened to her
millionaire? Slight mistake there.
He didn't own millions, he
owed them. Poor girl.
Always straying to greener
pastures and finding spinach. Yeah.
She was wondering if you'd be interested
in taking her back as a partner.
I think it'd be a great
idea. Naturally, you would.
But I like it here with you and
Linda. Yes, we love having you too.
Uh, when are you leaving?
Oh. Oh.
Why didn't you say
something? You look so silly.
Where's Jim?
Inside.
Good. I fixed it. Here's the news
in one luscious word: Hollywood.
I told you I'm not leaving
until Linda goes with me.
But this is the setup you
needed to get her away from Jim.
There are gonna be two Hollywood
men here tonight. One's a director.
If they like your dancing, you and
Linda will be on a train tomorrow.
We'd better find out
if Linda's interested.
We let her know when there's a contract
staring her in the face. Look...
I know you're in love but forget
it until we get her away from him.
This is no time to be honest.
Well, what should I do?
We have to convinceJim that he'd be a heel if
he stood in the way of a chance like this.
Well, that'll be easy.
Like peeling a turtle.
Mamie says these go up here.
Yes. Set 'em right down.
Say, Gus, how'd you
like to earn a slow $10?
Don't care how slow, but sure.
It's sure, all right.
Here's the wrinkle:
I want you to go to the station, pick up a party
and start for Holiday Inn, but never get here.
- Could you handle that?
- Wouldn't be surprised.
Hello? Long distance. That's what
I want you to do with Linda Mason.
Miss Mason?
Our friend?
You're not supposed
to understand it, Gus.
With that kind of money, you oughta
be able to go by way of Medicine Hat.
Hello? Yeah.
Just a minute.
Long distance. I want to get
Parkway Hotel, New York City.
Miss Lila Dixon.
Didn't Linda say she'd
be here for rehearsal?
Oh, relax. Our audiences
aren't professional critics.
Gus, you made a wrong turn. Shortcut.
Gus! Shortcut... to the shortcut.
How could you possibly
expect to drive through this?
I never had no trouble
with a horse.
You'd better carry me to shore,
and I'll walk back to the highway.
I think you'd be better off
waitin' right here.
Gus, will you please
do as I say?
Oh, all right.
The other way! Turn around! Huh?
Gus, turn around! Oh! Oh!
Oh!
Gus!
Oh! Oh!
Oh, my hat!
Ya pushed me!
Get my hat!
I swear the show will start any
minute now. You said that an hour ago.
Yeah, but this time
I'm sincere. Excuse me.
Who started the show? I did. You're on.
What about Ted's partner? You've
kept this crowd waiting long enough.
He can go on without her. Have you
gone nuts? I rehearsed a double dance!
♪ Let's say it
with firecrackers ♪
♪ A nd banners held high ♪
♪ Let's have a real
old-fashioned ♪
♪ Noisy Fourth ofJuly ♪
♪ Let's say it
with firecrackers ♪
♪ Down south and up north ♪
♪ Let's have the kind we used
to call a glorious Fourth ♪
♪ Let's salute
our native land ♪
♪ Roman candles in each hand ♪
♪ W hile
a Yankee-Doodle band ♪
♪ Gets hotter
than a firecracker ♪
♪ Don't need
any long speeches ♪
♪ Or shouts of hooray ♪
♪ No words can say as much
as firecrackers can say ♪
♪ Freedom ♪
♪ Here comes the freedom man ♪
♪ On this day of independence ♪
♪ On this Independence Day ♪
♪ Listen to
an American troubadour ♪
♪ From the U.S.A. ♪
♪ I'm singing a song
of freedom ♪
♪ For all people
who cry out to be free ♪
♪ Free to sail the seven seas ♪
♪ Free to worship
as we please ♪
♪ If the birds up in the trees
can be free ♪
♪ W hy can't we ♪
♪ I'm bringing a song
of freedom ♪
♪ T o all people
wherever they may be ♪
♪ Free to speak
and free to hear ♪
♪ Free from want
and free from fear ♪
♪ Sons of freedom
far and near who agree ♪
♪ Sing with me ♪
♪ T hat all God's people
shall be free ♪
<i ♪I'm singing a
song of freedom ♪
♪ For all people
who cry out to be free ♪
<i ♪Free to sail the seven seas ♪
♪ Free to worship
as we please ♪
♪ If the birds up in
the trees can be free ♪
♪ Why can't we ♪
♪ I'm singing a song
of freedom ♪
♪ To all people
wherever they may be ♪
♪ Free to spea
and free to hear♪
♪ Free from wan
and free from fear♪
♪ Sons of freedom
far and near who agree ♪
♪ Sing with me ♪
♪ That all God's people
shall be free ♪
♪ All God's peopl
shall be free ♪♪
Will you give me a lift?
Sure. Hop in.
Aren't you Ted Hanover's
former dancing partner?
Yes, although I wouldn't
exactly say "former."
I'm dancing with him
at the inn tonight.
But I... Doesn't he
have a new partner?
Oh, she won't be there tonight.
I didn't know that.
I-I work at the inn.
Oh? Waitress?
Yes. I know your boss,
Jim Hardy, quite well.
Quite well.
He's responsible for your
rejoining Mr. Hanover? Uh-huh.
By the way, if I were you,
I'd look my prettiest tonight.
Jim says there'll be men there from Hollywood
to consider Ted and me for pictures.
Mr. Hanover's other partner will be
missing this chance to go to Hollywood.
Yes, although she can't be very talented
or they wouldn't be working at the inn.
Ted and I played
only the best places.
Listen, you're late
for the show already.
If you'd care to let me drive, I know a shortcut
that'll get us there 15 minutes sooner.
There's a farmhouse near here, and I'll
have us towed out in a couple of minutes.
For the love of mud,
hurry! Wait right here!
What else can I do?
You're on now.
But Linda isn't here yet.
You've got to save the pieces.
Keep those men interested now
and do a number with Linda later.
What can I do?
Well, fake something.
Fake something.
There's your cue! Don't
fail me! Keep 'em flying!
I'll keep 'em flying.
Linda! What happened to
you? Bad job of sabotage.
Excuse me.
Well, Jim, you deliberately kept me from
working at the inn tonight, didn't you? Yeah.
You knew there would be men here from Hollywood
who might offer me a chance in pictures.
You decided I shouldn't have that opportunity,
not even the opportunity to refuse.
I was afraid the offer might be
too important for you to turn down.
The point is you don't trust
me to make my own decisions...
because they might interfere
with your own selfish plans.
I've had about enough
of that, Jim.
Ted! Linda!
Mr. Parker, Mr. Dunbar, I want you to meet
the greatest dance team in show business:
Hanover and Mason
and the owner, Jim Hardy.
Nice little place
you've got here.
Even though you haven't seen Miss
Mason dance, I can assure you...
Hardy, Hollywood is always interested in
new ideas and we think this is a honey.
We'd like to do a picture
based on Holiday Inn.
The idea behind it, how it
works, the special holiday songs.
It's purely a speculative thing, far from
foolproof and we can't afford to pay too much.
You don't have to start talking it
down because the idea is not for sale.
We expect to use Mr. Hanover
and his partner in the picture.
I don't know how the others feel, but I'd
like to keep this setup just the way it is.
Jim, would you be decent just once and
let somebody else here have a chance?
Wait a minute, Danny. The place
belongs to him. He can do as he wants.
I guess it was just
too good to last, huh?
A simple little layout where we could
do our best at the work we know...
without having
any illusions of glory.
But I can see now that I'm the
only one who could be happy here.
Go ahead, take the idea. Take the music,
take Linda, take the whole darned thing.
But what about you? We'll need you in
Hollywood to write the rest of the music.
Oh, no. I work right here. I'll
send you the music when it's written.
And don't bother me
before, huh?
I guess maybe I was
a little selfish, huh?
Is that the deal you wanted, or
should I have thrown in my shirt?
Chummy sort of a fella,
isn't he?
Listen, Linda, if you
really want to stay here...
Don't talk that way! This is
the chance you wanted, isn't it?
Of course!
Boy, are we happy!
Happy Thanksgiving,
Mr. Jim.
Same to you, Mamie...
and staff.
Didn't I tell you children
to stay in the kitchen?
Those wings ain't gonna
fly away. Now shoo! Git!
Everything's ready and hot,
Mr. Jim. Thank you, Mamie.
♪ I've got plenty
to be thankful for♪
Are you kidding?
♪ I haven't got
a great big yacht ♪
♪ To sail from shore to shore ♪
♪ Still, I've got plent
to be thankful for♪
You're loaded, Dad.
♪ I've got plent
to be thankful for♪
Like what? ♪No private
ca No caviar♪
♪ No carpe on my floor♪
♪ Still, I've got plent
to be thankful for♪
You know, you're better off
than I am.
♪ I've got eyes to see with ♪
You need glasses.
♪ Ears to hear with ♪
Or fly with.
♪ Arms to hug with
Lips to kiss with ♪
♪ Someone to adore ♪
You're a little flat too.
♪ How could anybody
ask for more ♪
♪ My needs are small
I buy them all ♪
♪ At the five-and-ten-cent
store ♪ Sing it.
♪ Oh, I've got plent to be
thankful for♪♪ Sing it pretty.
Why, you ain't et a
bite. I'm pouting, Mamie.
Who is this?
That's Mr. Jones.
Jonesy? I'm sorry.
I knew him too well.
But you've got to eat. The trouble
ain't with that turkey. It's you!
I feel all right.
I'm riding high, Mamie.
Why'd you close the inn and sit around
like a jellyfish with the misery?
'Cause a slicker stole your gal and you
ain't got fight enough to get her back!
Um, excuse me,
Mr. Jim, but...
I tried to keep her here. What kind
of keeping is that? Nothing but tricks!
If you went to Hollywood and told
Miss Linda how much you loves her,
and told her that the way
a lady likes to hear it told,
I'll betcha she'd be the quickest
ex-movie star that ever ex'd.
You're crazy, Mamie.
I'm crazy?
I knows Miss Linda. I knows
her like I knows my own kids.
Why, she ain't the fancy type
no more than you are.
What she wants is
what you got right here.
But women has to have them
things told to 'em the right way.
You could melt her heart
right down to butter...
if you'd only turn on the heat.
Mamie, you don't, you don't try to
take a fella's gal away from him...
after he's bought the ring.
Or, as I recall, do
you? Now you're talkin'
Sure! Women has to be told
things the right way. Yes, sir!
At last! The night I've been
dreaming about, actually here.
This is my wedding. You
make me feel like a kibitzer.
Don't misunderstand me. I'm happy
because this marriage means...
that we can all settle down
and stop worrying.
I wish I had your confidence
without your viewpoint.
My fingers are crossed until Linda
and I are on that plane bound for Yuma.
What's worrying you? I've been
this close to marriage before,
only to wake and find myself
with no bride and a hangover.
Look, the girl has said yes, the
picture finishes tonight.
Come in. Everything
is all set and ready.
What could possibly happen...
Hi, fellas.
Jim! Wh-What
brought you here?
Train. Chug-chug-chug-chug.
Wedding? When is it?
Wedding?
Yeah.
Uh, well, we hadn't set
an exact time.
Have you seen Linda?
No. No, not yet.
Say, I saw your director. He told me
he was shooting the finale tonight.
Thought I'd like to see how you
make pictures. Uh, he wouldn't...
Y - You wouldn't like what
they're doing tonight. Why not?
That's dull, technical stuff. Well,
I'm a dull, technical sort of a fella.
Perhaps if you'd wait and
see Linda tomorrow. Oh, no!
I want to see the finish. The success
of you and Linda means a lot to me, pal.
Say, why don't you be
yourself? What are you up to?
Well, I'm a son of a gun.
This is a beautiful hunk of welcome
for a guy who comes coast to coast...
just to wish you a merry
Christmas and a happy wedding.
Remember how I suspected you when
you came to the inn on Easter morning?
That was silly, wasn't it? Now
I know he's up to something.
Wait a minute. Let's not be unfair. Huh?
We're treating Jim like a poor country
cousin. He doesn't mean any harm.
No. No. He just wants to see Linda.
Let's show him Linda! Good
will on earth toward men!
Where are we going?
What's this? Hey!
Hey, Ted, what is this?
I was afraid you'd gone
crazy. I'll keep him here...
till you get Lind
on that plane.
<i
I'd better get my clothes on.
I'll go on the set and see how near ready
they are. My clothes are in there!
- Merry Christmas!
- Jim! Pal!
Wait! Stop! We were only fooling!
Only you could think
of a thing like that.
Who're you calling?
Nobody.
The operator's gone.
Take it easy.
Don't break your neck.
It's one of the most authentic
reproduction jobs we've ever done. Is it?
And all worked out from those photographs
we took of your place in Connecticut.
Oh! Well, Mamie and the kids oughta
see this. They'd never believe it.
Anything wrong? Well, that Christmas
tree is a little out of place.
I guess nobody'd notice that
but me or... Linda.
We're going to start rolling. Come along
with me where you can see everything.
No. I'll just stay in the background.
I don't want to get in your way.
Well, suit yourself.
I'll see you later. Right.
All right, we're going to follow you
on the boom from here inside the inn.
When you get in the
other set, do your song.
I think you have the mood. Your
Hollywood success was empty,
you've lost the one man you
love; you know, the usual hoke.
Just make me cry and you
can get to that wedding.
All ready for rehearsal!
No, please. Let's shoot it.
Okay.
It's a take!
All right, everybody, quiet
on the stage. It's a take.
Close 'em up!
Come on over there. Quiet down.
Let's get settled, everybody.
Come on, everybody, let's get
settled now. It's the picture.
Get out of here with your
brooms. Hit your snow!
All right, roll 'em!
Sorry, but when the red light's on, you
couldn't get in even if you owned the studio.
But, pop, this is important.
I know. So is the light.
Hit your playback!
Music!
<i All right, action!
♪ I'm dreaming of
a white Christmas ♪
♪ With every Christmas card
I write ♪
♪ May your days be merry ♪
♪ And bright ♪
♪ And may all
your Christmases ♪
♪ I'm dreaming of
a white Christmas ♪
♪ Just like the ones
I used to know ♪
♪ W here the treetops glisten ♪
♪ A nd children listen ♪
♪ T o hear sleigh bells
in the snow ♪
♪ Dreaming of a white ♪
♪Christmas ♪
♪ With every
Christmas card I write ♪
♪ May your days be merry ♪
♪ And bright ♪♪
Jim! Cut it! Cut it!
That's it!
All right, gentlemen.
How could he get that far in five
minutes? The lady must've been willing.
But the world
can't do this to us.
♪ Here she comes
down the street ♪
♪ I'll admit my defeat ♪
♪ I've won my hot toddy ♪
♪ Over my scarred body ♪
♪ I knew that I'd win ♪
♪ Singing ♪ ♪ But wait until
she gets a load of your dancing ♪
♪ W e'll stay at the inn
Singing ♪
♪ A ll by myself I'll have
to stick to my dancing ♪
♪ Oh, no, my friend
I'm here to end ♪
♪ Y our dancing trouble and
strife ♪ Oh, this will be fun.
♪ Miss Hit-And-Run has
come back into my life ♪
♪ W e'll stay at the inn
♪ ♪ We'll have to begin ♪
♪ Singing ♪ ♪ Dancing ♪
♪ W e've each other
to cling to ♪
♪ Y ou'll be easy to
sing to ♪ ♪ And you're ♪
♪ Easy to dance with ♪
♪ So let the old year die ♪
♪ W ith a fond good-bye ♪
♪ A nd our hopes as high
as a kite ♪
♪ How can our love
go wrong, dear ♪
♪ If we start
the New Year right ♪ ♪