(♫ HAPPY HOLIDAY PLAYING)
♪ Happy holiday ♪
(♫ PLAYING HARMONICA)
Merry Christmas, Bud.
Thank you.
Merry Christmas to you.
Okay. Hi, Chief.
(BELL RINGING)
(♫ JIM WHISTLING TUNE)
Come in.
Hello, honey.
(KISSING)
Well, this is our last
night in show business.
Some feeling, huh?
Some feeling.
I got the ring and the license.
Honey, we're ready.
Oh.
Say, there's a hook left
over at the top here.
Should that be?
Never mind,
I'll take care of it.
Jim?
Huh?
(SIGHS)
Well, I think that
tie's terrible.
(CHUCKLES) Well, who cares?
Tomorrow I'm a farmer.
You'd better go change it.
Listen, honey,
when you're flipping those twinkle toes
who's gonna be
looking at my tie?
You only have
five minutes. Hurry.
Okay, I'm on my way.
What'd he say?
I didn't tell him.
Why not?
We love each other.
You wanna continue dancing.
I know, but he gets a look.
Oh, he's always had that look.
It doesn't mean
anything emotionally.
It has something to do
with his liver.
Simply tell him
you had made a mistake.
You don't wanna give up your
career and live on a farm.
But he's already
bought the farm.
And the license, and the ring.
Oh, I can't tell him.
All right, I will.
Right after our number.
Listen, darling, don't weaken.
Think of our life together.
Think of diamonds, of sables,
of your own little penthouse.
Is that a promise?
Well, just think about
them for the time being.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
MAN: Ready, Miss Dixon.
Well, thank you.
Say, this thing
didn't come out even.
Oh, I'll fix it.
We have to hurry.
I love you.
I love you...
...and Jim.
I love Jim, too. But after all,
I mean, let's not be too chummy.
(LAUGHS)
(♫ BIG BAND MUSIC PLAYING)
(♫ I'LL CAPTURE YOUR HEART PLAYING)
(♫ SINGING) ♪ Here she comes ♪
♪ down the street ♪
♪ My, oh my, ♪
♪ ain't she sweet? ♪
♪ Why, here comes ♪
♪ my hot toddy ♪
♪ Over my dead body ♪
♪ I'll capture ♪
♪ her heart singing ♪
♪ Just wait until she gets ♪
♪ a load of my dancing ♪
♪ Just wait till ♪
♪ I start singing ♪
♪ I'll take her strolling down ♪
♪ the road with my dancing ♪
♪ I can't go wrong, ♪
♪ a tender song ♪
♪ And she'll discover ♪
♪ my charms ♪
♪ Some fancy taps ♪
♪ and she'll collapse ♪
♪ And fall right ♪
♪ into my arms ♪
♪ I'll capture ♪
♪ her heart singing ♪
♪ Oh, no, ♪
♪ you haven't a chance ♪
♪ When I go ♪
♪ into my dance ♪
♪ I'll take you ♪
♪ through life singing ♪
(SCATTING)
♪ I'll make you ♪
♪ my wife dancing ♪
♪ If you could dance ♪
♪ instead of sing ♪
♪ I'd learn to ♪
♪ love you somehow ♪
♪ If you could sing ♪
♪ instead of dance ♪
♪ I'd take you home ♪
♪ with me now ♪
(SCATTING)
(♫ WHISTLING)
♪ The way you sing ♪
♪ don't mean a thing ♪
♪ You'd better stick ♪
♪ to your dance ♪
♪ And as for you, ♪
♪ your dance won't do ♪
♪ You'll have to ♪
♪ sing for romance ♪
♪ I'll capture her heart... ♪
♪ Singing ♪
♪ Dancing ♪
(SCATTING)
(BOTH SCATTING)
(CONTINUES SCATTING)
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
Not much of a Christmas
present for you, is it?
I mean,
both of us walking out on you.
Don't worry about me, kid.
I'll do all right.
(CHUCKLING) What a chum.
Can't you see what we're walking out on?
The grind.
365 days a year.
When's the last time
you had a day off?
I don't know.
Maybe last year?
Do you ever hear of Thanksgiving
or Labor Day
or the Fourth of July?
Vaguely.
You know what they are, don't you?
They're holidays.
Days of rest.
There's lots of 'em.
They mark 'em in red
on the calendar
so you can't miss 'em.
What happens in show business
when a holiday comes along?
You give an extra performance.
Not for me, brother.
Lila and I are going up to
that farm in Connecticut
and we're gonna live
by the calendar.
Say, Jim?
Mmm?
There's something
you should know.
Oh, I know, Ted.
I feel the same way about you.
You know,
we've had our ups and our downs
and we fought a little
over the women
we swiped from
each other, but...
I know, but...
Sorry, Jimmy boy, but that's life.
Ted, if I'm not the best
manager in the business
I'll eat a garage
mechanic's shirt.
Fifteen weeks at the Park Club,
sight unseen, for you and Lila.
$200 a week more than you were
getting with the farmer thrown in.
What's the matter?
I haven't told him.
You haven't told him?
Haven't told me what? What...
What's this? What's the news?
Well, don't be upset, Jim, dear.
It isn't that I don't love you.
I do.
I love everybody,
but when Ted explained how
much he loved me and...
All at once, we both realized
that we belong together.
The two of us,
dedicating our lives
to making people happy
with our feet.
The two of you, huh?
Dedicating your lives to making
people happy with your feet.
That's sweet.
Well, I guess that kick I just
got was a good start, huh?
Sorry, Jimmy boy,
but that's life.
Yeah, it's best that
you found out now, Jim.
You wouldn't wanna
make Lila unhappy.
Oh, no. No, I...
I wouldn't want to make Lila unhappy.
Not now, now that
I really know her.
(♫ WHISTLES)
What a narrow squeak that was.
What do you mean by that?
Oh, nothing. Nothing, honey.
I'm just happy
that you're happy.
That little speech sounds like
the crack of a confederate money.
Well, kids, I'm still gonna
rejoin the human race.
I hope you get a lot of
work, holidays included,
dance yourselves into
beautiful nervous breakdowns.
You ever want to look me up,
you know where to find me,
Midville, Connecticut,
under a large shady tree,
just being lazy.
(♫ SINGING) ♪ Lazy ♪
♪ I want to be lazy ♪
♪ I long to be out ♪
♪ in the sun ♪
♪ With no work ♪
♪ to be done ♪
♪ Under that awning ♪
♪ They call the sky ♪
♪ Stretching and yawning ♪
♪ And let the world ♪
♪ go drifting by ♪
♪ I want to peep ♪
♪ Through the deep ♪
♪ Tangled wildwood ♪
♪ Counting sheep ♪
♪ till I sleep ♪
♪ Like a child would ♪
♪ With a great ♪
♪ big valise full ♪
♪ Of books to read ♪
♪ where it's peaceful ♪
♪ While I'm killing time ♪
♪ Being lazy ♪
(ALARM RINGING)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
So Lazy Acres was a snare
and a delusion, huh?
Oh, brother,
there's the hardest work in the world.
Maybe you'd be happier
back in town, Jim.
Of course, if you get that
agricultural urge again,
you can always raise a geranium.
Oh, no. Wait till you hear.
I think I've dreamed up the
greatest idea I ever had.
And you've had some pips.
Oh, but this can't miss.
I'm turning the farm into an
inn, but what an inn.
Here, read up, brother.
"Holiday Inn,
Midville Connecticut."
(TED READING)
Open holidays only?
Mmm-hmm.
Say, how many
of those are there?
There's about 15.
That gives me 350 days a
year to kick around in.
(LAUGHING) He would
think of that.
Did you get your discharge
papers from that sanitarium?
Oh, don't you worry,
this is gonna work.
I'm having auditions out
at the farm every day.
Say, if you run into any talent
that's willing to work
for a share of the table,
will you send them out?
Sure, soon as I get back.
I'm flying down to
Miami Beach tonight
to set an engagement
for Ted and Lila.
Lila.
You forgot to order the flowers.
Now, don't get excited,
there's a flower shop out at the airport.
I guarantee to have orchids in her
dressing room before her first number.
Oh, boy, you better.
As I remember, this kid even
expects presents on Father's Day.
(LAUGHS) Yeah.
Well, good luck, Jim.
So long, Ted. Have a nice trip.
I mean, yeah, thanks, I will.
That reminds me,
I forgot to give him a little
Christmas remembrance
I brought along.
Got one here for each of you.
Say, this is swell.
What is it?
It's homemade peach preserves.
I put them up myself,
just before I went into the sanitarium.
Boy, do I go for those.
Why, they're great on...
Or even plain.
They're non-fattening, too.
Well, it's a long trip back to the
farm, I think I'll get along.
Will you say hello
to Lila for me?
But you gotta wait
and catch the act.
We got some new routines and
then after the show... (BURSTS)
I don't think they like
this nightclub air.
(BURSTS)
Wait. Wait. You better
wait for Lila's.
(BURSTS)
I think Danny's was the loudest.
Well, different tone.
Dawn patrol, huh?
Hello! Am I too late?
You would have been
in another minute.
Danny Reed.
Listen, I have to
wait on that man.
But... I'll work five nights for you.
Anything.
Just leave me alone
and don't butt in.
What would you like?
Orchids, the finest you've got.
Corsage?
No. No. A dozen.
Loose, looking like
they don't care.
All right.
There,
"Lila, love, Ted."
Have them delivered
to Miss Lila Dixon
at the Club Pierre
before 11:00 tonight.
Oh, I'm sorry, but our delivery
truck is on its last trip
and won't be back
until after 11:00.
How about a messenger boy?
Oh, it's impossible to guarantee
delivery this late on Christmas Eve.
But to help you out,
I'll take them.
Oh, there you are.
A dozen orchids, please.
Lady, you're a lifesaver.
Here. Here's $5. Take your boyfriend
out and show him a good time.
Oh, thank you, but let's
consider this a personal favor.
Well, I can't leave town
indebted to a stranger.
Would you like to see the
floor show at the club tonight?
Oh, I'd like to
very much, but...
All right, now you just
give this card to Francois
and he'll seat you at
the entertainer's table.
Why, you're Mr. Reed.
Uh-oh.
I'm Linda Mason.
Well, this is just a part-time job.
Actually, I sing and dance.
Mr. Reed, I want...
I know. I know, you've studied
dancing since you were a little child.
You spent long weary hours in every
theatrical agency in Broadway.
But just now I happen to
be catching a plane to...
Of course,
once you told me I was no good,
I could probably get a job at
a bargain basement and like it.
Now look, honestly,
as soon as I get...
Oh, of course. Sure, you worked
hard, you want a chance.
So what?
So I'm gonna give it to you.
A job? Uh-huh.
A friend of mine
is opening a place
in Connecticut, Holiday Inn.
You take that card
out there tomorrow,
tell him I sent you
and you'll be all set.
Mr. Reed,
how could I possibly thank you?
Don't. Just deliver those orchids
and let me catch my plane.
(♫ BIG BAND MUSIC PLAYING)
This table's reserved
for the band.
Excuse me!
Fussy, isn't he?
(CHUCKLES)
I think I'll have
a bowl of coffee, huh?
And the lady?
Coffee.
We seem to be on
the 40-cent tour here.
It is embarrassing.
I'm Jim Hardy.
Linda Mason.
Got a friend in the show?
Well, I'm here at
Mr. Reed's invitation.
Oh, Danny.
Then you know Ted Hanover.
What?
Yes, naturally.
Oh, my.
He's quite a man with
the ladies, that Ted.
Well, after all,
he's a very attractive man.
Do you know him?
Oh, yes. Yes.
Matter of fact,
I've been considering Ted
and his partner for my new club.
Oh, you have a place.
Oh, yes. Yes.
I don't know, though.
His act might not go
so well at a place
as large as mine.
Oh.
Well, I've found that the size
of a place doesn't matter,
if one has sufficient
personality.
That's what you found, huh?
You in show business?
I'm Linda Mason.
Oh, Linda Mason.
(♫ YOU'RE EASY TO DANCE WITH PLAYING)
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(♫ SINGING)
♪ I could dance nightly ♪
♪ Just holding you tightly ♪
♪ My sweet ♪
♪ I could keep right on ♪
♪ Because you're so light ♪
♪ on your feet ♪
♪ You're easy ♪
♪ to dance with ♪
CHORUS:
♪ There is no doubt in ♪
♪ The way we stand out ♪
♪ in the crowd ♪
♪ Though it's called dancing ♪
♪ To me it's romancing ♪
♪ out loud ♪
♪ You're easy ♪
♪ to dance with ♪
♪ Loving you ♪
♪ the way I do ♪
♪ Makes you easy ♪
♪ to dance with ♪
♪ That is why I'm always ♪
♪ right on the beat ♪
♪ All those charms ♪
♪ in one man's arms ♪
♪ Make you easy ♪
♪ to dance with ♪
♪ I can hardly keep ♪
♪ my mind on my feet ♪
CHORUS:
♪ Let's dance forever ♪
♪ Come on, say we'll never ♪
♪ be through ♪
♪ It's so easy ♪
♪ to dance with you ♪
♪ You're easy ♪
♪ to dance with ♪
♪ It's so easy ♪
♪ to dance with you ♪
♪ CHORUS: ♪
♪ It's so easy to dance ♪
♪ With you ♪
(ALL APPLAUDING)
That was wonderful.
Oh, it's a great act,
isn't it? Here they come.
Who?
Ted and Lila.
Hey, what's the matter?
Hello, Lila.
Jimmy boy.
How are you?
I'm so glad to see you.
It's good to see you.
I thought you were alone, Jim.
Who's your friend,
and what's her hurry?
Don't ask me, she's your friend.
Mine?
Yeah.
What is she afraid of?
Facing me?
Darling, I swear, I never...
"Darling, I swear."
You lie...
You're on.
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
So this is Holiday Inn.
Yeah.
Will be if it ever opens up.
Well, why shouldn't it open?
Well, I ain't one to talk,
but you could probably
buy a half interest
in this place for
a barrel of apples.
Next train for New York's at
7:43, if I can flag her down.
Say, I'm looking for a job.
Where's the boss?
Right here,
I'll be down in a second.
So, you're the big shot
that didn't know whether
Hanover and Dixon
were good enough for your place.
(LAUGHS) Well, that wasn't exactly
hay you were throwing, either.
(MIMICKING LINDA)
"I'm Linda Mason."
(LAUGHS)
Merry Christmas.
All right,
you're a fake and I'm a phony.
And we're both soaked.
Are you hurt? I'll check later.
Come on, let's get out of
this before you catch cold.
(CHUCKLES) All right. Ooh.
Well, here's what cooks.
Oh.
Well, this is darling.
Was it as large as this
when it was a farmhouse?
Yeah, it was built by a fellow
who felt cramped in New York.
He finally ran out of
lumber, though.
Oh, Mamie.
MAMIE: Coming.
MAMIE:
Is your names Mamie?
No.
Get back in the kitchen.
My, my.
What's happened?
Oh, we had a little accident.
Mamie, this is Miss Linda Mason.
How do you do?
Please to know you, Miss Linda.
And these are her children.
That's Daphne,
and that's Vanderbilt.
LINDA: How do you do?
Mamie, will you take Miss
Mason up to the guest room
and change her into
anything that'll fit her
while we get her clothes
dry, huh?
Sure thing, Mr. Jimmy.
Come on, honey.
I'll see about getting the
fire ready in the living room.
Is your names Miss Linda?
No.
(LAUGHS)
LINDA: I don't know, it sounds like
something you dream about at night
and it would be wonderful,
then you'd wake up in the morning
and realize it couldn't work.
Oh, it'll work, if I can sell
the idea to some performers.
They seem to think
that profit sharing
means taking bows
on an empty stomach.
So that's why you're
not open tonight.
Well, I'm also,
sort of, particular
about the kind of
talent I'm gonna use.
Fifteen holidays a year.
Mmm-hmm.
You're a lazy fellow.
No, not especially.
Just have my own
ideas about living.
My father was like you.
Just a man with a family.
Never amounted to much,
didn't care.
But as long as he was alive
we always had plenty to eat
and clothes to keep us warm.
Were you happy?
Yes.
Then your father was a very successful man.
Hope I can do as well.
Say, I came out here for a job.
Could you use me?
Well, I might find
a spot for you
in my first show.
What can you do?
I sing a little and dance.
Couldn't guarantee
any salary at first,
right now I've got
the ledger and an iron lung.
I don't care if you pay off in
eggs, just give me a chance.
Well, let's see what you can do.
Thanks. Thanks a lot.
You know, I've written special
music for each holiday.
This sort of gives me a chance to keep
a little promise I made to myself.
I said I was gonna sing this
song at the inn tonight.
(♫ PLAYING PIANO)
(♫ SINGING)
♪ I'm dreaming ♪
♪ Of a white Christmas ♪
♪ Just like the ones ♪
♪ I used to know ♪
♪ Where the treetops glisten ♪
♪ And children listen ♪
♪ To hear sleigh bells ♪
♪ in the snow ♪
♪ I'm dreaming ♪
♪ Of a white Christmas ♪
♪ With every ♪
♪ Christmas card I write ♪
♪ May your days be ♪
♪ merry and bright ♪
♪ And may ♪
♪ all your Christmases ♪
♪ Be white ♪
♪ I'm dreaming ♪
BOTH:
♪ Of a white Christmas ♪
♪ Just like... ♪
♪ Just like the ones ♪
♪ I used to know ♪
♪ Where the treetops glisten. ♪
♪ Where the treetops glisten ♪
♪ And children listen. ♪
♪ And children listen ♪
♪ To hear ♪
BOTH: ♪ Sleigh bells ♪
♪ in the snow ♪
♪ I'm dreaming of ♪
♪ a white Christmas ♪ (♫ WHISTLING TUNE)
(♫ HUMMING)
♪ With every ♪
♪ Christmas card I write ♪
BOTH: ♪ May your days ♪
♪ be merry ♪
♪ And bright ♪
♪ And may all your ♪
♪ Christmases ♪
♪ Be white ♪
(♫ HAPPY HOLIDAY PLAYING)
(♫ SINGING)
♪ Happy holiday ♪
♪ While the merry bells ♪
♪ keep ringing ♪
♪ May your every wish ♪
♪ come true ♪
♪ Happy holiday ♪
♪ May the calendar ♪
♪ keep bringing ♪
♪ Happy holidays to you ♪
♪ If you're burdened ♪
♪ down with trouble ♪
♪ If your nerves ♪
♪ are wearing thin ♪
♪ Park your load ♪
♪ down the road ♪
♪ And come to Holiday Inn ♪
♪ If the traffic ♪
♪ noise affects you ♪
♪ Like a squeaky violin ♪
♪ Kick your cares ♪
♪ down the stairs ♪
♪ And come to Holiday Inn ♪
♪ If you can't find ♪
♪ somebody who ♪
♪ Would set ♪
♪ your heart a-whirl ♪
♪ Get in your car ♪
♪ and motor to ♪
♪ The home ♪
♪ of boy meets girl ♪
♪ If you're laid-up ♪
♪ with a breakdown ♪
♪ Throw away ♪
♪ your vitamin ♪
♪ Don't get worse ♪
♪ Grab your nurse ♪
♪ And come to Holiday Inn ♪
♪ Happy holiday ♪
♪ May the calendar ♪
♪ keep bringing ♪
♪ Happy holidays to you ♪
(ALL CHEERING)
Happy New Year, Ted.
No!
Francois, have you
seen Mr. Hanover?
Twice, sir.
What happened?
The first time, sir,
he came from his dressing room
with a telegram in his hand.
He ordered Scotch and
soda, a bottle of each.
I know, I know.
What then?
The second time he came
from his dressing room
he asked which way
is Connecticut.
Connecticut?
Connecticut.
He said he has a friend there
who knows about women, too.
Why didn't you stop him?
How could I stop him,
sir, when I don't know
which way is Connecticut.
Which way is Connecticut.
Who said Holiday Inn
wouldn't work?
Well, we're gonna divvy up a stack
of important money tonight, huh?
Man, man.
I've got a landlady who's gonna
ask for your autographed picture.
No.
Everybody get something?
(LAUGHS)
All right, come on, now.
Go to bed, now,
it's getting late.
Good night.
Look, it's almost time.
JIM: Say, it's practically
straight up, isn't it?
(♫ SINGING)
♪ One minute to midnight ♪
♪ One minute to go ♪
♪ One minute ♪
♪ to say good-bye ♪
♪ Before we say hello ♪
♪ Let's start ♪
♪ the new year right ♪
♪ Twelve o'clock tonight ♪
♪ When they dim the light ♪
♪ Let's begin ♪
♪ Kissing the old year out ♪
♪ Kissing the new year in ♪
♪ Let's watch ♪
♪ the old year die ♪
♪ With a fond good-bye ♪
♪ And our hopes as high ♪
♪ As a kite ♪
♪ How can our love ♪
♪ go wrong if ♪
♪ We start ♪
♪ the new year right? ♪
(LOUD CHEERING)
That's it.
That's midnight.
I'll see you out
on the floor, all right?
All right.
Come on, everybody.
Happy New Year.
(ALL CHEERING)
Happy holiday.
Happy New Year.
I forgot my check.
You won't need that,
but I think you'll need your coat.
Happy New Year.
Same to you.
You got to dance.
Oh, you got to dance.
Come on, you got to...
(♫ BIG BAND MUSIC PLAYING)
Why, Mr. Hanover.
Mr. Hanover.
That's Mr. Hanover.
Wait a minute, I got to go.
Oh, no, I don't
want Ted Hanover,
I want you.
This is New Years, kid.
I know.
(INAUDIBLE)
(ALL LAUGHING)
(ALL CHEERING)
Ted!
He wasn't drunk, it's a gag.
What happened?
Ted Hanover with
his new partner.
They were great.
New partner?
You better get back.
Well, I am sorry,
if I'd have known how he was...
Oh, he'll be all right in a week or 10 days.
You better hurry.
Ted!
Oh.
How is he?
He's out cold.
Hot or cold, he can keep his
dancing shoes in my office.
Did you hear that applause?
Yeah, it went pretty good.
And I was worried
about his losing Lila.
Losing Lila?
Yeah.
Yeah, she eloped tonight
with some Texan from Texas,
with Ted's engagement
ring on her finger.
But who cares?
You lose one girl, you find another.
That's life.
That's good, huh?
(SIGHS)
Here we go again.
(♫ WHISTLES)
Come in.
Good morning, Ted.
Oh. Good morning.
(GROANS)
Got a little head?
Where am I?
You're at Holiday Inn.
Well, how did I get here?
Who brought me?
You were clinging to the
undercarriage of a jeep, I think.
Here, have a slug
out of the mug.
You mean you don't
remember anything? Uh...
Let's see.
I had a wire from Lila
telling me she's going to marry
some millionaire or something.
I remember that all right.
Mmm-hmm.
Then I had a drink.
A drink?
Boy, you were fractured.
And then I decided I had
to talk to my old pal, Jim.
You don't remember
anything else?
No. That's all,
except that
I must have been killed on
the way out here or something.
You really come up empty, huh?
Too bad about Lila.
I think you're better off
doing a single.
You're a born soloist, you know.
Oh, no, no, Jim,
I've got to have a partner.
And when I find her...
Yeah, I know,
you'll fall in love with her.
You haven't missed yet.
Happy New Year!
Oh, don't do that.
(LAUGHS)
Why didn't you tell me?
Letting me beat my brains out
worrying about his losing Lila
and all the time,
he's got this girl on the leash.
What girl?
(LAUGHS)
Boy, you must have been high.
Doing a complete dance routine
with your new partner and you...
You don't know who she is?
I danced with a new partner?
When? Where?
Here. Last night.
Think, Ted. Remember?
Wait a minute.
I remember.
I got here just about midnight.
There was a girl.
We danced.
What she look like?
I... I don't know.
All I saw was a vague outline.
Can't you remember
anything about her?
I remember dancing with her.
If I ever dance with her again,
I'd probably recognize her.
Great, that takes care of
everything but finding her.
You were here,
why ask me how she looked?
I only saw her from
the back. She was...
About this...
She had a...
If I ever saw her from the back
again, I'd recognize her.
Well, that's fine.
After I've danced with her,
I'll just turn her around
for your okay.
This should be a cinch.
You saw her, describe her.
Who, me? Well, I wasn't
watching very closely.
She was a medium...
Medium-built sort of a girl,
with a medium face.
She had a nice evening gown on
with a belt in the back.
See, she was built just
like a girl friend of mine.
A girl you don't know but her
name was Consuela Stupkis.
She used to play the pinball machine
a lot down at the corner drugstore.
I remember one time she was high man.
Three weeks in a row.
Thanks. Thanks a lot.
That's nothing at all,
happy to do it.
See, I got a hunch, fellas.
I've got a hunch we're going
to find this girl eventually.
And when we do we'll be
glad we waited for her.
Listen, I'm not interested in getting
any other partner, understand?
A chance meeting
in the night. Destiny.
She'll be back.
Here's where we will find
her on the next holiday.
Here?
Here.
I've got to go turn the roast.
(♫ BIG BAND MUSIC PLAYING)
Now don't worry, we'll find her.
If I see her from the back
again, I'll recognize her.
It's kind of a roundabout way to go at
it, but let's try it.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
JIM: Are you decent?
Yes, come in.
What's that?
Well, I thought it over
and I believe that our number'll
go a little better in blackface.
Oh. I thought we were
going to do it like this.
Well, that's before...
Before I thought it over.
I look terrible in the stuff.
No.
I don't even know
how to put it on.
I'll put it on for you.
I broke in
as a bootblack, you know.
Here we go.
Oh.
For a month and a half
I've been dreaming
of how pretty I was
going to look tonight.
Well, here's my punishment for
thinking so well of myself.
Oh, you'll have plenty
of times to be pretty.
I was just going to
ask you if you'd like
to be in the rest
of the shows out here.
You were?
Will you?
Will I?
Fifteen nights a year Cinderella
steps into her pumpkin coach
and becomes queen
of Holiday Inn.
Well, what's the matter?
I wish I didn't have to work
all the other days in the year
to make these few possible.
Maybe a little later on
when we start doing better
you could stay out here
all the time.
Did you hear what you just said?
Yeah.
Was it a proposal?
It will be when I get
a few bucks in the bank.
You're a strange duck.
You don't even give me
a chance to say darling
and throw my arms around you.
Better save that till
you see the bankbook.
Well, I guess
I'm sort of engaged.
(♫ BIG BAND MUSIC PLAYING)
Say, what is this?
A daisy chain?
(NERVOUS CHUCKLE)
Well, we were just looking for
the back of a girl we don't know.
(ALL APPLAUDING)
(♫ ABRAHAM PLAYING)
(♫ SINGING)
♪ Upon a February morn ♪
♪ A tiny baby boy was born ♪
♪ Abraham ♪
♪ When he growed up, ♪
♪ this tiny babe ♪
♪ Folks all ♪
♪ called him Honest Abe ♪
♪ Abraham ♪
♪ In 1860, he became ♪
♪ The sixteenth president ♪
♪ And now he's in ♪
♪ the hall of fame ♪
♪ A most respected gent ♪
♪ That's why we celebrate ♪
♪ This blessed February date ♪
♪ Abraham ♪
♪ When black folks ♪
♪ lived in slavery ♪
♪ Who was it set ♪
♪ the darkie free? ♪
♪ Abraham ♪
♪ That's right, child. ♪
♪ When troubles come ♪
♪ down from the shelf ♪
♪ Who's heart was ♪
♪ bigger than hisself? ♪
♪ Abraham ♪
♪ Yeah, ma'am! ♪
♪ The country's ♪
♪ going to the dogs ♪
♪ They shouted loud and strong ♪
♪ Then from a cabin ♪
♪ made out of logs ♪
♪ The right man came along ♪
♪ And that is why we celebrate ♪
♪ This blessed February date ♪
♪ Abraham ♪
♪ The U.S.A.'s ♪
♪ united thanks ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ To one whose name ♪
♪ was Nancy Hanks ♪
♪ Tell me! ♪
♪ Abraham ♪
♪ She gave this land ♪
♪ the finest son ♪
♪ JIM: That's what she did. ♪
♪ Who ever went ♪
♪ to Washington ♪
JIM: ♪ Who dat? ♪
♪ Abraham ♪
♪ When someone told ♪
♪ him General Grant ♪
♪ Was drinking every night ♪
♪ He answered, ♪
♪ "Go see if you can't ♪
♪ "Get all my generals tight" ♪
♪ That's why we celebrate ♪
♪ This blessed February date ♪
♪ Abraham ♪
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
Good night.
I give up.
She's not here tonight.
You wait here,
I'll go up and see if Jim's seen her.
Gus is waiting to take
you to the station.
Remember now, day after tomorrow, St.
Valentine's Day.
Someone's coming,
we better use the other stairway.
Who is it?
Bill-collector.
Good night.
Good night, Jim.
You better get inside before you catch cold.
You haven't got a coat.
Well, I...
Go on.
I don't need a coat now.
Hey, Ted.
Did you find the girl?
This is terrible, I wish we could
recognize her from the front.
I feel like a wolf.
Why, Ted.
(EXCLAIMS)
Ted!
She's here!
Who?
I saw her!
This way.
Let go of my coat.
This way, shortcut,
shortcut. Come on.
Giddyap.
It's locked,
it's never been locked before.
Let's try the other stairwell.
Let go of me, let go.
Go ahead.
Well, we've lost her again.
Did you get a look
at her face this time?
No, we're still working
from the rear.
How do you know it was her?
After all, she had an overcoat on.
I don't care if she had...
How do you know
she had an overcoat on?
Well, she...
If she didn't,
look for a girl with pneumonia.
Come on.
Let's get inside.
Say, Jim, when's your next show?
Next show? St.
Valentine's Day, I think.
Day after tomorrow, huh?
Is it?
That's our break.
We'll get here bright and early
and stay until we find her.
We'll make an announcement
asking her to identify herself.
We won't miss next time. No.
Say, fellas, how did
you like the show?
Well, we were so busy we didn't
see much of it, Jim. Why?
I thought the people seemed
to like the blackface routine.
Yeah, they did.
Don't you think
a blackface number
on St. Valentine's Day
would be novel?
A what?
It's no good, eh?
Just an idea I had.
Well, good-bye.
Good-bye, Ted.
So long, Jim.
JIM: Bye, Dan.
Hey, lady.
LINDA: Yes.
You know we open in an hour.
You haven't even had a rehearsal.
LINDA: Coming.
Oh, very smart.
You'll have to talk Gus into
buying a horseless carriage.
I spend half my life between
here and the station.
(CHUCKLES)
I think Gus will have to face the
machine age sooner or later, won't he?
Did you escape those
bill-collectors the other night?
Bill-collectors?
Oh, yes, temporarily.
Say, that reminds me,
I have a surprise
for you downstairs.
Well, thanks.
What reminds you?
Nothing, it's just...
I mean, I want you to remember the surprise
when those doggone
bill-collectors move in.
You sound sweet,
but you don't make sense.
The inn is so romantic looking.
Nice? I posed for
those cupids myself.
Hello, boys.
ALL: Hi. How are you?
Paid-up cards here tonight.
Where's the surprise?
Aha! Right here,
a little home cooking I whipped up.
Beautiful.
LINDA: "Be Careful
It's My Heart."
And I ain't kidding, either.
I wrote this just for
you, honey.
(♫ BE CAREFUL IT'S MY HEART PLAYING)
(♫ SINGING) ♪ Be careful, ♪
♪ it's my heart ♪
♪ It's not my watch you're holding, ♪
♪ It's not the note ♪
♪ I sent you ♪
♪ That you quickly burned ♪
♪ It's not the book ♪
♪ I lent you ♪
♪ That you never returned ♪
♪ Remember, ♪
♪ it's my heart ♪
♪ The heart with which ♪
♪ so willingly I part ♪
♪ It's yours to take, ♪
♪ to keep or break ♪
♪ But please, ♪
♪ before you start ♪
♪ Be careful, ♪
♪ it's my heart ♪
(MOUTHING)
(SCATTING)
♪ Be careful, ♪
♪ it's my heart ♪
♪ It's not my watch you're holding, ♪
♪ It's not the note ♪
♪ I sent you ♪
♪ That you quickly burned ♪
♪ It's not the book ♪
♪ I lent you ♪
♪ That you never returned ♪
♪ Remember, ♪
♪ it's my heart ♪
♪ The heart with which ♪
♪ so willingly I part ♪
♪ It's yours to take, ♪
♪ to keep or break ♪
♪ But please, ♪
♪ before you start ♪
♪ Be careful, ♪
♪ it's my heart ♪
I'm sorry, Jim,
I couldn't resist it.
Wonderful, she's prefect,
light as a feather.
You found her, Jim.
You're a pal.
Yeah.
Young lady, do you realize
that we've been searching
for you for weeks?
For me?
Yes, ever since...
The girl in the flower shop.
Yes, Mr. Reed.
Where have you been working
since New Year's Eve?
Here.
Would you mind letting
me in on your secret?
Oh, it's no secret.
Ted Hanover is looking
for a new dancing partner
and we've decided
to give you the job.
Oh, here now.
Wait, just a minute.
Oh, no hard feelings, Jim,
I don't blame you for trying.
She is wonderful.
I feel as if I've
known her for months.
Oh. Same old feeling, huh?
Let's see, Washington's
Birthday is the next show.
That will give us a week of rehearsals.
We can open the act here.
DANNY: I'll take care of the invitations.
Strictly formal.
I'll get all the newspaper
boys from New York.
Now hold everything.
This is my inn,
and I am not running it for
a bunch of stuffed shirts.
What would you like,
the dungaree set?
Well, that would be better than the
bunch of chowder heads you drag in.
Maybe I can't use the act.
Not use Ted Hanover?
Well,
the show is pretty well set.
You're in, but he's out.
But you could change the show
for a special occasion like this.
Of course he could.
He's just trying to hide his gratitude.
Jim, you better think
up a number for us.
Well, just what do you
visualize, Ziggy?
Ah, let's see.
For Washington's birthday I see,
sort of, a romantic costume thing.
Naturally.
Something that just reeks
with grace and charm, you know?
Mmm-hmm.
I think the music should
be sweet and gentle to...
Well, to create the mood,
each time I take her into my arms and kiss her.
That's it.
Don't you think it's getting
a little stuffy in here?
(♫ I CAN'T TELL A LIE PLAYING)
(♫ SINGING) ♪ I could say ♪
♪ that you're homely ♪
♪ Just as homely as pie ♪
♪ But this is ♪
♪ Washington's birthday ♪
♪ And I've got to ♪
♪ say you're beautiful ♪
♪ 'Cause I can't ♪
♪ tell a lie ♪
♪ I could say ♪
♪ that you're stupid ♪
♪ Nothing up ♪
♪ in your crown ♪
♪ But this is ♪
♪ Washington's birthday ♪
♪ And the truthful he ♪
♪ Of the cherry tree ♪
♪ Would look down on me ♪
♪ and frown ♪
♪ I could say that ♪
♪ I hate you if I try ♪
♪ But I've got to say ♪
♪ I love you ♪
♪ 'Cause it's February ♪
♪ the twenty-second ♪
♪ And I can't tell a lie ♪
♪ Hit it. ♪
(♫ SWING MUSIC PLAYING)
(♫ MINUET MUSIC PLAYING)
(♫ CONGA DRUMS PLAYING)
(♫ SWING CHANGING QUICKLY TO MINUET)
(♫ SWING MUSIC PLAYING)
(♫ FAST DRUM SOLO PLAYING)
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Come in.
Well, honey, in spite of what
good old Jim tried to do to us,
your future starts
as of tonight.
Now where would you
like to go from here?
From here? Yes.
New York, Havana, Rio?
We have our pick of engagements, you know.
But I can't be your partner
if you leave the inn.
Of course you can. There's no reason
for you to remain buried here.
There's a very good reason.
I promised to be in Jim's holiday
shows for the rest of the year.
Ah, but he tricked you into that
while he was hiding you from me.
No matter how he did
it, I've promised.
Besides, well,
we're going to be married.
Married?
Now wait a minute, let's be fair.
He didn't give me a chance.
After all, I love you, too.
Linda, from the very first
moment we danced together,
I knew you were to be
the one girl in my life.
You didn't even know my name.
Please.
All right, forget about me, then.
Forget about Jim,
think of yourself.
Here's your chance to do
the one thing you like best.
Not only for 15 days a
year, but always.
Sorry, but I promised.
Well?
I guess I should apologize for
hooking up your number, huh?
Oh, forget it. I'm the one
that should apologize to you.
Here I've been trying to
take Linda away from you
not knowing you two were
going to be married.
Married?
Yeah, aren't you?
Yes, sure.
I mean, naturally,
we're sort of engaged.
Oh.
Well, anyway, I've decided to bow out of here.
Linda's all yours.
Well, you're a pretty game
guy to take it this way.
Well, it's happened so often I'm
getting used to it, that's all.
Good-bye, kid.
A lot of luck, Ted.
Thanks.
How are we doing?
Two minutes ago, I would have
sold my chances for a tired dime.
But when a man is surprised to
hear that he's going to be married,
brother, that's when I go to
work with a clear conscience.
- Everything's good, huh?
- Everything is perfect.
(♫ SINGING)
♪ In your Easter bonnet ♪
♪ With all the frills ♪
♪ upon it ♪
♪ You'll be ♪
♪ the grandest lady ♪
♪ In the Easter parade ♪
♪ I'll be all in clover ♪
♪ And when ♪
♪ they look you over ♪
♪ I'll be ♪
♪ the proudest fellow ♪
♪ In the Easter parade ♪
♪ On the Avenue ♪
♪ Fifth Avenue ♪
♪ The photographers ♪
♪ will snap us ♪
♪ And you'll find ♪
♪ that you're ♪
♪ In the rotogravure ♪
♪ Oh, I could ♪
♪ write a sonnet ♪
♪ About your Easter bonnet ♪
♪ And of the girl ♪
♪ I'm taking ♪
♪ To the Easter parade ♪
♪ On the Avenue ♪
♪ Fifth Avenue ♪
♪ The photographers ♪
♪ will snap us ♪
♪ And you'll find ♪
♪ that you're ♪
♪ In the rotogravure ♪
♪ Oh, I could ♪
♪ write a sonnet ♪
♪ About your Easter bonnet ♪
♪ And of the girl ♪
♪ I'm taking ♪
♪ To the Easter parade ♪
Hello!
I didn't exactly
expect the welcome mat,
but I thought somebody
might say hello.
Hello.
Thanks.
What brings you here on this
bright and uninviting day?
I've discovered something,
my friends, about life.
Meaning what?
Well, I don't want success,
I want the true happiness you
people have found here at the inn.
You're not gonna
stay in the inn?
Not just stay,
I want to be part of your shows,
help you in your work,
share your simple pleasures.
I asked you once
not to interfere, Ted.
Please believe me, I am a
tired, lonely and unhappy man.
But I could be happy here,
helping the two people I like the best.
Will you take me in?
My motherly intuition
tells me to throw him out.
Well, at least give him
the benefit of the doubt.
I've given him plenty of doubt.
Are you kidding with that
"sharing life's simple pleasures"?
May I go inside with you?
Why, of course.
My... My trunks will
arrive this afternoon.
What do I do?
Move in the broom closet?
Jim, that's no way to talk to
a man who's here to help you.
The world doesn't change.
A gentle smile often
breeds a kick in the pants.
But for your sake,
Linda, I'll be big.
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
I'll give you a tip
about these things, Gus.
They'll go up and back,
but not sideways.
Yeah, well, I keep forgetting
this blind thing can't
see where it's going.
Yeah, well, unload the rest of
this stuff in the back, huh?
(ENGINE STARTS)
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
TED: Hey! What did you do,
get up before breakfast?
Why, every morning.
I trust you slept well.
When I found out
how late you got in,
I told Mamie to let you sleep.
(LAUGHS) Life on a farm!
Can't beat it, huh?
Jim, you've made me very happy!
That's fine.
Now,
how about you making me happy?
You sound like a landlord
with eviction papers.
Oh. This is good news,
Lila's back in New York.
I got a letter
from her yesterday.
What happened to
her millionaire?
Slight mistake there.
He didn't own millions, he owed them.
(CHUCKLES)
Poor girl, always straying to
greener pastures and finding spinach.
Say, she was wondering if you'd
be interested in taking
her back as a partner.
I think it'd be a great idea.
Naturally, you would.
But I like it here
with you and Linda.
Yes, and we love having
you, too.
Uh, when are you leaving?
Why didn't you say something?
You look so silly.
Where's Jim? Inside.
Good. I've fixed it.
Here's the news
in one luscious word: Hollywood!
Now, I told you, I'm not leaving
here until Linda goes with me.
But this is the setup you
needed to get her away from Jim.
Now, there are going to be
two Hollywood men here tonight
to see the show.
One's an important director.
If they like your
dancing, you and Linda
will be on a westbound
train tomorrow.
- We better find out if Linda's interested.
- Ooh.
We let her know when there's a
contract staring her in the face.
Look... Now I know you're
in love with the girl
but forget her until we
get her away from here.
This is no time to be honest.
TED: Well, what should I do?
All we have to do
is to convince Jim
that he'd be a heel if he stood
in the way of a chance like this.
Oh, that'll be easy,
like peeling a turtle.
Mamie says these go up here!
Yes, set them right down.
Say, Gus, how would you
like to earn a slow $10?
Well, I don't care how
slow, but sure.
(CHUCKLES) It's sure, all
right, here's the wrinkle,
I want you to go
down to the station
pick up a party and
start for Holiday Inn
but never get here.
Could you handle that?
Wouldn't be surprised!
Hello, long distance.
That's what I want you
to do with Linda Mason.
Miss Mason? Our friend?
You're not supposed
to understand it, Gus.
For that kind of money you ought to
be able to go by way of Medicine Hat.
Hello, yeah.
Just a minute.
Long distance,
I want to get Parkway Hotel,
New York City, Miss Lila Dixon.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Didn't Linda say she'd be
here for final rehearsal?
Oh, relax, our audiences
aren't professional critics.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Gus, you made a wrong turn.
Shortcut.
Gus!
Shortcut, another shortcut.
How could you possibly
expect to drive through this?
Well, I never had no
trouble with a horse.
Oh, you'd better
carry me to shore,
and I'll walk back
to the highway.
Well, I think you'd be better
off waiting right here.
Gus,
will you please do as I say?
Oh, all right.
- The other way.
- Huh?
Turn around. Gus, turn around!
Oh!
Gus!
- My hat!
- You pushed me.
Get my hat!
I swear the show will
start any minute now.
You said that an hour ago.
Yeah, but this time I'm sincere.
Excuse me.
(♫ LET'S SAY IT WITH FIRECRACKERS PLAYING)
Who started the show?
I did. You're on.
But what about Ted's partner?
You've kept this crowd waiting long
enough, he can go on without her.
Have you gone nuts?
I've rehearsed a double dance.
♪ (♫ SINGING) Let's say it with firecrackers ♪
♪ and banners held high ♪
♪ Let's have a real old-fashioned ♪
♪ noisy Fourth of July ♪
♪ Let's say it ♪
♪ with firecrackers ♪
♪ They'll jump at up North ♪
♪ Let's have the kind we used ♪
♪ to call a glorious Fourth ♪
♪ Let's salute ♪
♪ our native land ♪
♪ Roman candles ♪
♪ in each hand ♪
♪ While a Yankee Doodle band ♪
♪ Gets hotter ♪
♪ than a firecracker ♪
♪ Don't need ♪
♪ any long speeches ♪
♪ Or shouts of "Hooray!" ♪
♪ No words can say as much ♪
♪ as firecrackers can say ♪
♪ Freedom! Freedom! ♪
♪ Here comes the Freedom Man ♪
♪ On this day ♪
♪ of independence ♪
♪ On this Independence Day ♪
♪ Listen to an American ♪
♪ troubadour from the U.S.A. ♪
♪ I'm singing a song ♪
♪ of freedom ♪
♪ For all people who ♪
♪ cry out to be free ♪
♪ Free to sail ♪
♪ the seven seas ♪
♪ Free to worship ♪
♪ as we please ♪
♪ If the birds ♪
♪ up in the trees ♪
♪ Can be free ♪
♪ Why can't we? ♪
♪ I'm bringing a song ♪
♪ of freedom ♪
♪ To all people ♪
♪ wherever they may be ♪
♪ Free to speak ♪
♪ and free to hear ♪
♪ Free from want ♪
♪ and free from fear ♪
♪ Sons of freedom ♪
♪ far and near ♪
♪ Who agree ♪
♪ Sing with me ♪
♪ That all God's people ♪
♪ shall be free ♪
CHORUS: ♪ I'm singing a song ♪
♪ of freedom ♪
♪ For all people who ♪
♪ cry out to be free ♪
JIM: ♪ Free to sail ♪
♪ the seven seas ♪
♪ Free to worship ♪
♪ as we please ♪
♪ If the birds ♪
♪ up in the trees ♪
♪ Can be free ♪
♪ Why can't we? ♪
CHORUS: ♪ I'm bringing a song ♪
♪ of freedom ♪
♪ To all people ♪
♪ wherever they may be ♪
JIM: ♪ Free to speak ♪
♪ and free to hear ♪
♪ Free from want ♪
♪ and free from fear ♪
♪ Sons of freedom ♪
♪ far and near ♪
♪ Who agree ♪
♪ Sing with me ♪
♪ That all God's people ♪
♪ shall be free ♪
CHORUS: ♪ That all God's people ♪
(ALL APPLAUDING)
Will you give me a lift?
Sure, hop in.
Aren't you Ted Hanover's
former dancing partner?
Yes, although I wouldn't
exactly say former.
I'm dancing with him
at the inn tonight.
But I...
Doesn't he have a new partner?
Oh, she won't be there tonight.
I didn't know that!
I work at the inn.
Oh?
Waitress?
Yes.
I know your boss, Jim Hardy, quite well.
Quite well.
Then he's responsible for
your rejoining Mr. Hanover.
Uh-huh.
By the way, if I were you,
I'd look my prettiest tonight
when I'm waiting on tables.
Jim says there will be a
couple of men from Hollywood
to consider Ted and
me for pictures.
And Mr. Hanover's other partner
will be missing this
chance to go to Hollywood.
Yes, although she
can't be very talented
or they wouldn't be
working at the inn.
Ted and I played
only the best places.
Listen,
you're late for the show already,
if you'd care to let me drive
I know a shortcut that'll get
us there 15 minutes sooner.
There's a farmhouse near here
and I'll have us towed out
in a couple of minutes.
Oh, for the love of mud, hurry!
Wait right here!
What else can I do?
(ALL APPLAUDING)
(♫ BIG BAND MUSIC PLAYING)
You're on now.
But Linda isn't here yet.
You've got to save the pieces,
keep those men interested now
and do a number
with Linda later.
What can I do?
Well, fake something.
Fake something, okay.
There's your cue.
Don't fail me, keep them flying.
I'll keep them flying.
(FIRECRACKER BURSTS)
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
Linda!
What happened to you?
A bad job of sabotage.
Excuse me!
Well, Jim,
you deliberately kept me
from working at the inn
tonight, didn't you?
Yeah. You knew there
would be men here
from Hollywood who might
offer me a chance in pictures.
You've decided I shouldn't
have that opportunity.
Not even the
opportunity to refuse.
I was afraid the offer might
be too important for
you to turn down.
The point is you don't trust
me to make my own decisions
because they might interfere
with your own selfish plans.
I've had about enough of
that, Jim.
Ted, Linda!
Mr. Parker, Mr. Dunbar,
I want you to meet the
greatest dance team
in show business,
Hanover and Mason.
And the owner Jim Hardy.
Glad to know you, Hardy.
Nice little place you've got here.
Gentlemen, even though
you haven't seen
Miss Mason dance,
I can assure you...
Hardy, Hollywood
is always interested
in new ideas and we
think this is a honey.
Frankly, we'd like to do a
picture based on the Holiday Inn.
The idea behind it, how it
works, the special holiday songs.
Of course, it's purely a speculative
thing, far from foolproof
and we can't afford
to pay too much.
You don't have to
start talking it down
because the idea
is not for sale.
Well, maybe I haven't
explained enough.
We expect to use Mr.
Hanover and his partner in the picture.
Well, I don't know
how the others feel
but I'd like to keep this
little setup just the way it is.
Jim, would you be
decent just once
and let somebody else
around here have a chance?
Wait a minute, Danny, after
all, the place belongs to him
he can do as he wants.
I guess it was just
too good to last, huh?
A simple little layout,
where we could do our best
at the work we know without
having any illusions of glory.
I can see now that I'm the only
one who could be happy here.
Go ahead, take the
idea, take the music,
take Linda,
take the whole darn thing.
But what about you?
We'll need you
in Hollywood to write
the rest of the music.
Oh, no, I work right here.
I'll send you the music
when it's written.
And don't bother me before, huh?
Guess maybe I was
a little selfish, huh?
Is that the deal you wanted or
should I have thrown in my shirt?
Chummy sort of a fellow,
isn't he?
Listen, Linda,
if you really want to stay here...
Don't talk that way.
This is the chance you wanted, isn't it?
Of course.
Boy, are we happy!
Happy Thanksgiving,
Mr. Jim.
Same to you, Mamie.
And staff.
Didn't I tell you children
to stay in the kitchen?
Those wings ain't going to fly away.
Now shoo!
Everything's
ready and hot, Mr. Jim.
Thank you, Mamie.
(♫ I'VE GOT PLENTY TO BE THANKFUL FOR PLAYING)
I've got plenty
to be thankful for
Are you kidding?
I haven't got a great big yacht
To sail from shore to shore
Still I've got plenty
to be thankful for
You're loaded, Dan.
I've got plenty
to be thankful for
Like what?
No private car
No caviar
No carpet on my floor
Still I've got plenty
to be thankful for
You know you're
better off than I am.
I've got eyes to see with
You need glasses.
Ears to hear with
Or fly with.
Arms to hug with
Lips to kiss with
Someone to adore
You're a little flat, too.
How could anybody ask for more?
My needs are small
I buy them all
At the five and ten cent store
Sing it!
Sing it pretty.
Oh, I've got plenty
to be thankful for
Why, you ain't ate a bite.
I'm pouting, Mamie.
Who is this?
That's Mr. Jones.
Jonesey! I'm sorry,
I knew him too well.
But you got to eat.
The trouble ain't with that turkey, Mr.
Jim, it's you!
I feel all right.
I'm riding high, Mamie.
Well, why you close
the inn and sit around
like a jellyfish
with the misery?
'Cause a slicker stole your gal
and you ain't got fight
enough to get her back.
Excuse me, Mr. Jim.
I tried to keep her here!
What kind of keeping is that?
Nothing but tricks.
If you went to Hollywood
and told Miss Linda
how much you loves her,
and misses her,
and told her that
the way a lady
likes to hear it told,
I'll bet you she'd be the quickest
ex-movie star that ever exed.
You're crazy, Mamie
I'm crazy?
I knows Miss Linda.
I knows her like
I knows my own kids.
Why, she ain't the fancy
type no more than you are.
What she wants is
what you got right here.
But women has to have them things
told to them the right way.
You could melt her heart
right down to butter,
if you'd only turn on the heat.
Mamie, you don't try
to take a fellow's gal
away from him after
he's bought the ring.
Or as I recall, do you?
Now you're talking!
Oh, sure, women has to be
told things the right way.
MAMIE: Yes, sir!
At last, the night I've been
dreaming about actually here.
This is still
my wedding, you know.
You make me feel
like a kibitzer.
Now don't misunderstand me,
I'm happy because this marriage means
that we can all settle
down and stop worrying.
I wish I had your confidence
without your viewpoint.
My fingers are crossed
until Linda and I
are on that plane
bound for Yuma.
Now what's worrying you?
I don't know, except I've been
this close to marriage before
only to wake up next morning
and find myself with
no bride and a hangover.
Look, the girl said yes,
the picture finishes tonight,
there's a judge waiting in Yuma.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Come in!
Everything is all set and ready.
What could possibly happen to...
Hi, fellows!
Jim, what brought you here?
Train.
Chug chug chug chug.
The wedding, when is it?
Wedding?
Yeah.
Well, we hadn't
set any exact time.
Have you seen Linda?
No, no, not yet.
But, say, I saw your director,
he told me he was shooting
the finale tonight,
thought I'd like to see
how you make pictures.
He wouldn't... You wouldn't
like what they're doing tonight.
Why not?
Oh, no, that's dull,
technical stuff.
Well, I'm a dull,
technical sort of a fellow.
Perhaps if you'd wait
and see Linda tomorrow.
Oh, no, I want to
see the finish.
The success of you and Linda
means a lot to me, pal.
Say, why don't you be yourself.
What are you up to?
Well, I'm a son of a gun.
This is a beautiful hunk of welcome
for a guy who
comes coast to coast
just to wish you a merry
Christmas and a happy wedding.
(CHUCKLES)
You remember how I suspected you
when you came to live at
the inn on Easter morning?
Silly, wasn't it?
Now I know he's up to something.
Oh, wait a minute now
let's not be unfair.
No?
No, we're treating Jim
like a poor country cousin.
He doesn't mean any harm! No!
No, he just wants to see Linda.
So let's show him Linda.
Goodwill on earth toward men.
This... Where we going?
What's this?
Hey, Ted! What is this?
TED: I was afraid
you'd gone crazy.
DANNY: I'll keep him in here
till you get Linda on that plane.
TED: I better hurry
and get my clothes on.
DANNY: Yeah, in the meantime
I'll go down to the set
and see how near ready they are.
TED: Wait a minute,
my clothes are in there.
Merry Christmas!
Jim, pal! Wait!
Stop!
We were only fooling!
Only you could think
of a thing like that.
Who you calling?
Nobody, the operator's gone.
Take it easy.
Don't break your neck.
It's one of the most authentic
reproduction jobs we've ever done.
Is it?
And all worked out
from those photographs
we took of your place
in Connecticut.
Uh-huh.
Well, Mamie and the kids ought to see this.
They'd never believe it!
Anything wrong?
Well, that Christmas tree's
a little out of place.
I'd guess nobody would
notice that but me or Linda.
We're going to start rolling
in a couple of minutes.
Come along with me where
you can see everything.
No, I'll just sort of
stay in the background.
I don't want to get in your way.
Well, suit yourself.
I'll see you later.
Right.
All right, darling,
we're going to follow you
on the boom from
here inside the inn.
And when you get in the other
set, do your song.
Let's see, I think
you have the mood,
your Hollywood
success was empty,
you've lost the one man you love.
You know, the usual hope.
Just make me cry and you
can get to that wedding.
All ready for rehearsal!
Please! Let's shoot it.
Okay, it's a take!
All right, everybody,
quiet on the stage, it's a take.
(ALARM RINGING) Close them up.
Come on, over there,
quiet down, let's get
settled, everybody.
Come on, everybody, let's get settled now.
This is the picture.
(INAUDIBLE)
Hit the snow!
All right, roll 'em!
(BELL RINGS)
Sorry, Mr. Hanover,
but when the red light's on
you couldn't get in even
if you owned the studio.
Oh, but, pop, this is important.
I know, so is the light.
Hit the playback.
Music!
(♫ SOFT ORCHESTRAL MUSIC PLAYING)
All right, action!
(♫ WHITE CHRISTMAS PLAYING)
(♫ SINGING) ♪ I'm dreaming ♪
♪ of a white Christmas ♪
♪ Just like the ones ♪
♪ I used to know ♪
♪ Where the treetops glisten ♪
♪ And children listen ♪
♪ To hear sleigh bells ♪
♪ in the snow ♪
(♫ JIM WHISTLING TUNE)
♪ ...dreaming of a white ♪
♪ Christmas ♪
(♫ JIM HUMMING)
♪ With every ♪
♪ Christmas card I write ♪
♪ May your days be ♪
♪ merry and bright ♪
Jim!
Cut it! Cut it!
(BELL RINGS)
That's it!
All right, gentlemen!
How could he get that
far in five minutes?
The lady must have been willing.
But the world
can't do this to us.
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(♫ SWING MUSIC PLAYING)
(♫ SINGING) ♪ Here she comes ♪
♪ down the street ♪
♪ I'll admit my defeat ♪
♪ I've won my hot toddy ♪
♪ Over my scarred body ♪
♪ I knew that ♪
♪ I'd win singing ♪
♪ But wait until she gets ♪
♪ a load of your dancing ♪
♪ We'll stay at ♪
♪ the inn singing ♪
♪ All by myself I'll have ♪
♪ to stick to my dancing ♪
♪ Oh, no, my friend, ♪
♪ I'm here to end ♪
♪ Your dancing ♪
♪ trouble and strife ♪
♪ This will be fun, ♪
♪ Miss Hit-and-Run ♪
♪ Has come back ♪
♪ into my life ♪
♪ We'll stay at the inn... ♪
♪ We'll have to begin... ♪
♪ Singing! ♪
♪ Dancing! ♪
♪ We've each other ♪
♪ to cling to ♪
♪ You'll be easy ♪
♪ to sing to ♪
♪ And you're easy ♪
♪ to dance with ♪
♪ So let the old year die ♪
♪ with a fond good-bye ♪
♪ And our hopes ♪
♪ as high as a kite ♪
♪ How can our love ♪
♪ go wrong ♪
♪ If we start ♪
♪ the new year right? ♪