{\fad(1500,1000)\fnFZHuaLi-M14S\fs27\bord0\shad1.5\fsp8\pos(196,278)\fscx85\fscy120\1c&H3F6692&\3c&H000B34&\4c&H121C2D&\b0}米高梅电影公司
米高梅电影公司\N出品
{\fad(800,1000)\blur2\fnFZChaoCuHei-M10S\fs51\bord1.5\shad7\fsp1\pos(137.5,125)\fscx90\4c&H14120A&\b0}史蒂夫·麦奎因
{\fad(500,500)\blur2\fnFZChaoCuHei-M10S\fs51\bord1.5\shad7\fsp1\pos(136,126)\fscx87\4c&H14120A&\b0}詹姆斯·加纳
理查德·阿滕伯勒
{\fad(1000,800)\blur2\fs62\bord1.5\shad7\fsp15\3a&H24&\pos(193,180)\4c&H14120A&\b1}大逃亡
原创音乐 Original Music\N埃尔默·伯恩斯坦
摄影 Cinematography\N丹尼尔·法普
编剧 Writer\NPaul Brickhill - (book)\N詹姆斯·克莱威尔 James Clavell - (screenplay) and\N\NW.R. Burnett
制作 导演 Director\N约翰·斯特奇斯
本片改编自真人真事，
尽管角色是真实人物的综合，
时间与地点亦经过更改，
但是逃亡的细节，完全符合事实。
进去\NGo inside.
赶快\NHurry up.
走这边\NThis way.
房间还可以\NYeah, this'll do.
- 你要哪一张床？- 我…\N- Which one are you gonna have? - I...
不行 那是我的\NNo, that's mine.
丹尼 树林有多远？\NHow far are the trees, Danny?
至少六十米以上\NOver 200 feet.
我看有一百米\NYeah, I'd say 300.
有得挖了\NLong ways to dig.
叫卡文迪斯测量一下\NWe'll get Cavendish to make a survey.
真希望大X在这里\NI wish Big X were here.
威利 你认为他逃成了吗？\NWillie, you think X got away?
如果他逃成了 应该会送消息给我们\NHe'd have sent us word somehow if he had.
被盖世太保抓了？\NGestapo, you think?
要不然就是死了\NEither that or he's dead.
- 是蓝姆西上校吗？- 我是\N- Group Captain Ramsey? - Yes.
我是斯塔赫维兹士官长\NI am Hauptfeldwebel Strachwitz.
请跟我来\NWill you accompany me, please?
- 我会照顾你的东西  - 好的\N- I'll look after your gear, sir. - Right.
蓝姆西上校到了（德语）\NGruppenkommandeur Ramsey.
上校 早安\NGood morning, Group Captain.
我是鲁格的副官波森上尉\NI'm Captain Posen, Von Luger's adjutant.
你是最高阶的英国军官\NSince you're senior British officer
现任你为战俘与上校间的联络人\Nyou are to be liaison between the prisoners and the colonel.
他希望你能明白几件事…\NHe wishes to make clear to you certain matters of...
正确的词是"政策"吗？\Nthe word is "policy"?
对\NYes.
谢谢你\NThank you.
这是蓝姆西上校（德语）\NGruppenkommandeur Ramsey.
我是鲁格上校 请坐\NI am Colonel Von Luger. Please sit down.
蓝姆西上校\NGroup Captain Ramsey
四年以来 第三帝国不得不花费大量时间\Nin the past four years the Reich has been forced to spend an enormous amount of time,
精力、人力与装备\Nenergy, manpower and equipment
追捕脱逃的军官战俘\Nhunting down escaping prisoner-of-war officers.
至少你们有活干 不是件好事吗？\NAt least it's rather nice to know you're wanted, isn't it?
这不是儿戏\NFor us it's not a matter for levity.
这个战俘营不准逃亡\NThere will be no escapes from this camp.
鲁格上校 所有军官都宣誓 有责任要试图逃亡\NColonel Von Luger, it is the sworn duty of all officers to try to escape.
如果逃不成 他们也有责任\NIf they can't, it is their duty to cause the enemy
造成敌人派遣重兵 来看守他们\Nto use an inordinate number of troops to guard them
他们还宣誓有责任 尽他们的能力扰乱敌人\Nand their sworn duty to harass the enemy to the best of their ability.
是的 我知道\NYes, I know.
在你麾下的人员是最成功的\NThe men under your authority have been most successful.
例如这个人 艾希利·皮特\NThis man, Ashley-Pitt, for example.
他在北海被俘\NCaught in the North Sea,
然后逃脱 再度被俘 再逃 再被俘\Nescaped, recaptured, escaped, recaptured.
阿奇巴德 "阿奇" 艾弗斯\NArchibald "Archie" lves:
11次企图逃脱\N11 escape attempts.
他甚至企图 在搭卡车来这里的路上跳车\NEven tried to jump out of the truck coming here.
狄克斯·威廉\NDickes, William.
参与挖掘11条逃亡地道\NKnown to have participated in digging of 11 escape tunnels.
威林斯基上尉 四次逃脱\NFlight Lieutenant Willinski: Four escapes.
麦唐纳 九次 美国人韩德利 五次\NMacDonald: Nine. Hendley, the American: Five.
海因斯 四次 塞奇威克 七次\NHaynes: Four. Sedgwick: Seven.
名单几乎念不完\NThe list is almost endless.
其中有一个 曾经17次企图逃脱\NOne man here has made 17 attempted escapes.
上校 这近乎疯狂\NGroup Captain, this is close to insanity.
差不多了\NQuite
这种事必须停止！\NAnd it must stop!
上校 难道你期待 军官忘掉他们的责任？\NColonel, do you expect officers to forget their duty?
不是\NNo.
我们预料你们不会忘记责任 所以才把你们运来这里\NIt is because we expect the opposite that we have brought you here.
这是新的战俘营\NThis is a new camp.
是造来关住你和你的部下\NIt has been built to hold you and your men.
这里集中了我们知道的所有安全措施\NIt is organized to incorporate all we have learned of security measures.
至于我 你要对付的可不是普通狱卒\NAnd in me, you will not be dealing with a common jailer,
而是德国空军最高当局…\Nbut with a staff officer personally
亲自挑选的 负责这一任务的参谋军官\Nselected for the task by the Luftwaffe high command.
我们把所有的坏蛋 都放在一个篮子里\NWe have in effect put all our rotten eggs in one basket
而且我们要严密看守这个篮子\Nand we intend to watch this basket carefully.
很聪明\NVery wise.
你们可以使用一般的设施\NYou will not be denied the usual facilities.
运动场、图书馆、休闲厅\NSports, a library, a recreation hall,
我们会给你们园艺的工具\Nand for gardening we will give you tools.
我们信任你们 会把工具用在园艺上\NWe trust you to use them for gardening.
把你们的精力用到这些事情上\NDevote your energies to these things.
放弃你们没希望的逃脱企图\NGive up your hopeless attempts to escape.
如果你们识时务的话\NAnd, with intelligent cooperation,
我们全都可以舒服地\Nwe may all sit out the war
等待战争结束\Nas comfortably as possible.
你在卡车旁做什么？\NWhat do you do here by the truck?
我在偷工具\NI'm stealing tools.
- 偷工具要关禁闭  - 我只是开玩笑\N- For stealing tools, cooler. - I was only kidding.
你是美国人\NOh, you're American.
- 我是 你是德国人  - 当然\N- Yes, and you're a German. - Of course.
你为什么来德国？\NWhy do you come to Germany?
为啥为你的敌人英国战斗？\NWhy fight for England, your enemy?
敌人？你在说什么？\NEnemy? What are you talkin' about?
英国在1812年烧了美国首都\NIn 1812 they burned your capital.
那是宣传\NThat's propaganda.
- 历史书里有  - 我读过\N- It's in the history books. - I read it.
现在赶快走开\NNow go away from here.
如果你偷工具 就关禁闭\NIf you steal tools, cooler.
好 不偷工具\NYeah. No tools.
嘿 维吉\NHey, Virgil.
你有没有看到禁闭室？\NHey, did you see the cooler?
老兄 它可真大！\NBoy, is it ever a big one!
- 他们预期要关很多人  - 大概吧\N- I think they expect a lot of business. - Yeah.
我找不到在以前的营地 和我们一起住14号房的那两个人\NThose two guys who were with us in the old camp, in hut 14, I can't find them.
卫兵把他们留在那边？\NYou think the goons left 'em behind?
我猜是的\NI guess.
他们姓什么？一个是杰克森 还有…\NWhat were their names? It was Jackson and...
德克斯特\NAnd Dexter
德克斯特 没错\NDexter. That's right.
我去看看还能找到谁 待会儿见\NI'm gonna see who else I can find. I'll see you later.
丹尼 他们是什么人？\NHey, Danny. Who are they?
俄国战俘 他们是砍树的\NRussian prisoners. They cut down trees.
他们被关在这里吗？\NThey keep them here?
不 德国人要把他们运走\NNo, they take them out.
威利 香烟\NWillie, cigarettes.
丹尼和我要逃走\NDanny and I have a blitz in mind.
你们能分散警卫的注意力吗？\NCould you put on a brief show for the goons?
当然能 你要全体出动吗？\NSure, man. What'll it be? An all-out go?
要吵闹吗？\NChoir practice?
还是要打架？\NKnuckles, eh?
- 好 打架不错  - 外套给他\N- Yeah. Knuckles will be fine. - Give him the coat.
你拿我的外套做什么？\NWhat are you doing with my coat,mate?
什么？这是我的外套！\NWhat you talk ? It's mine!What? It's mine!
你敢推我？\NAre you pushing me?
那是我的 你这个狗养…\NThat's mine, you son of a...
同志（俄语）\NTovarich
谢谢（俄语）\NSpasibo.
停止！\NStop it!
停止胡闹！\NStop this nonsense!
没事\NIt's all right, mate.
我们只是在善意地争论\NWe're just having a friendly little argument.
- 不准打架 不准！- 好的\N- No more fighting. No more! - All right.
- 各自回房  - 是的 长官\N- Back in your huts. - Yes, sir.
你也回去！\NYou, too!
走开！回到房间里！\NGet away! Get back in your huts!
走啊！\NGo on!
希尔兹\NHey, Hilts.
看来营地里 只有另外一个美国人\NLooks like there's only one other American in the whole camp.
参加英国皇家空军老鹰中队 叫韩德利的家伙\NSome guy named Hendley in the RAF Eagle squadron.
你已经有计划了吗？\NHey, you got something goin' already?
看到瞭望塔的分布位置吗？\NSee the way the goons got those towers placed?
中间有一个盲点\NThere's a blind spot through the middle.
盲点？\NA blind spot?
站在铁丝网旁边 两个瞭望塔都看不到\NA guy could stand at that wire and not be seen by either tower.
尤其是晚上 绝对看不到我\NThey'd never see me, especially at night.
你疯了\NYou're crazy.
是吗？我们马上来证明\NYou think so? Let's find out right now.
下一步稍微困难\NNow, the next step's a little tricky.
- 你不会出去吧？- 他们瞭望时我不出去\N- You're not goin' out there? - Not while they're lookin', I'm not.
我要去散散步\NI think I'll take a little walk.
同志（俄语）\NTovarich
- 丹尼 你会说俄语？- 只会说一句\N- Danny, you speak Russian? - Only one sentence.
快教我\NLet me have it, mate.
（俄语）Ja vas lublu\NJa vas lublu.
是什么意思？\NWhat's it mean?
我爱你\NI love you.
我爱你？那有什么用？\NI love you? What bloody good is that?
我不知道 我自己也不打算用\NI don't know. I wasn't going to use it myself.
立正！\NHalt!
出去\NOut.
出去！\NOut!
不 不 他是同志（俄语）\NNyet nyet Tovarich
- 你们是朋友吗？- 啊？\N- Your friend, yes? - Huh?
同志（俄语）\NTovarich
威林斯基上尉 谁来担保你呢？\NAnd who vouches for you, Lieutenant Willinski?
塞奇威克 滚出去\NGet out, Sedgwick.
谢谢（俄语）\NSpasibo.
等一下 等一下！\NHold it, hold it!
你姓什么？\NYour name?
艾弗斯\NIves.
艾弗斯 对了\NIves. Oh, yes. Archibald lves.
苏格兰人 你比相片好看多了\NScots. The photograph doesn't do you justice.
看看你们处于类似情况时的模样\NI'd like to see one of you under similar circumstances.
我现在不采取行动\NI will not take action against you now.
这是第一天\NThis is the first day here
出现了很多愚蠢和大意的事 双方都有\Nand there has been much stupidity and carelessness, on both sides.
嘿！回来！\NHey! Get out!
不要开枪！\NDon't shoot!
笨蛋！越线就死定了！\NYou fool! To cross the wire is death!
什么线？\NWhat wire?
这条线！警告线！\NThis wire! The warning wire!
是吗？\NOh?
绝对不准越过这条线 你是知道的\NIt's absolutely forbidden to cross it. You know that.
我的棒球滚到那边去了\NBut my baseball rolled over there.
该怎样拿回来？\NHow am I gonna get my baseball?
你应该先请求准许\NYou first ask permission.
好吧\NOh, OK.
- 我要捡棒球  - 停止！立刻回到线这边！\N- Gettin' my baseball. - Stop this! Get over the wire immediately!
- 好-站住别动！\N- OK. - You stay there!
让路\NOut of the way.
让路\NOut.
你在铁丝网旁边做什么？\NWhat are you doing over here by the wire?
我跟麦克斯说过 我要捡…\NLike I told Max, I was trying to get my...
你在铁丝网旁边做什么？\NWhat were you doing by the wire?
我跟麦克斯说过…\NWell, like I told Max...
我想逃出去 所以试图剪断铁丝网\NI was trying to cut my way through your wire, because I wanna get out.
搜一搜（德语）\NDurchsuchen sie ihn
- 你会说德语吗？- 非常好 上校（德语）\N- Do you speak German? - Jawohl, Herr Oberst
- 剪线器？- 非常好 上校（德语）\N- Wire cutters. - Jawohl, Herr Oberst
我很高兴…\NI have had the pleasure
在这场战争中 认识好几位英国军官\Nof knowing quite a number of British officers in this war.
让我感到高兴的是 双方互相理解\NAnd I flatter myself that we understand one another.
希尔兹 你是我遇到的 首位美国军官\NYou are the first American officer I have met.
对吗？\NHilts, isn't it?
请叫我希尔兹上尉\NCaptain Hilts, actually.
17次企图逃脱\N17 escape attempts.
- 是18次  - 地道专家 工程师\N- 18, sir.- Tunnel man, engineer.
飞行员\NFlier.
我猜就是美国军方说的 红牌飞行员\NI suppose what's called in the American army a "hotshot pilot."
不幸的是 你被击落了\NUnfortunately, you were shot down anyway.
战争期间你我都停飞了\NSo we are both grounded for the duration of the war.
上校 你说的是你自己\NWell, you speak for yourself, Colonel.
你有别的计划？\NYou have other plans?
我还没从空中或地上看过柏林\NI haven't seen Berlin yet.
我计划在战争结束以前去看看\NI plan on doing so before the war's over.
美国军官都像你这样没礼貌？\NAre all American officers so ill-mannered?
大约九成九是这样\NAbout 99 percent.
或许和我们一起的时候\NPerhaps while you are with us,
你可以学一点礼貌\Nyou will have a chance to learn some.
希尔兹 关禁闭十天\N10 days isolation, Hilts.
叫我希尔兹上尉\NCaptain Hilts.
关20天\N20 days.
关就关\NRight.
我出来的时候 你还会在这里吗？\NOh, you'll still be here when I get out?
禁闭室\NCooler.
姓氏？\NName?
艾弗斯\NIves.
艾弗斯中尉\NFlying Officer lves.
禁闭20天\NCooler. 20 days.
- 艾弗斯 去禁闭室  - 是我的荣幸\N- Cooler, lves. - Pleasure.
希尔兹\NHilts.
什么事？\NYeah?
你在美国做什么？打棒球吗？\NWhat did you do in the States? Play baseball?
不是 我是大学生\NNo, I was in college.
- 艾弗斯  - 什么事？\N- Say, lves. - Aye?
你试过几次逃脱？\NHow many escapes have you tried?
地面四次 地下七次\NFour over, seven under.
地道专家 是吗？\NTunnel man, huh?
不敢当\NSure, I am that.
艾弗斯 你有多高？\NHow tall are you, lves?
162公分 干嘛？\NFive feet four. Why?
只是好奇问问\NOh, just wondering.
你在大学念什么？学体育吗？\NWhat did you do in college? Study physical education?
学化工 但是爱骑车\NChemical engineering. Did a little bike riding, though.
骑脚踏车？\NBicycles?
骑摩托车\NMotorcycles.
赛车 表演会\NFlat tracks, county fairs.
到处赚一点小钱 帮助缴学费\NPicked up a buck here and there. Helped pay my tuition.
我也参加过比赛\NI did a wee bit of racing myself.
在苏格兰\NIn Scotland.
摩托车？\NBikes?
不 是赛马\NNo, horse racing.
我是骑师\NJockey.
骑师\NJockey.
希尔兹？\NHilts?
希尔兹 你还在听吗？\NAre you there, Hilts?
我在听\NYeah, I'm here.
难道美国没有骑师吗？\NDon't you have them in the States? Jockeys?
当然有\NSure.
那些日子真好\NThey were the days.
在马瑟堡和汉弥顿的周六夜\NSaturday nights in towns like Musselburgh and Hamilton.
妞儿直往你身上挤\NYou had to fight off the birds.
知道吗 妞儿耶\NYou know, birds.
女孩子 老兄 就是女孩子\NGirls, man. Girls.
难道美国没有女孩子吗？\NDo you not have them in the States?
希尔兹？\NHilts?
希尔兹 你还在听吗？\NAre you there, Hilts?
艾弗斯\NLves.
什么事？\NWhat?
你懂得营地里的黏土和碎石吗？\NYou know the kind of clay and gravel we got here in the compound?
你认为八小时之内 能够挖多少呎？\NHow many feet do you think you could get through in eight hours?
我可以像钻头一样 轻易挖穿这里的土\NI could go through this dirt here like the bit on an end of an auger.
但是挖土并不难\NBut you know it's not the digging.
用木头支撑地道\NIt's the shoring up with wood
还要把土运出来\Nand getting the dirt out
那才是难题\Nthat's what you've to worry about.
不 艾弗斯 你不需要担心\NNo, it isn't, lves. You don't have to worry about that.
你怎么把土运出来呢？\NHow are you going to get the dirt out?
你们在苏格兰怎么称呼地鼠？\NWhat do they call a mole in Scotland?
就叫地鼠\NA mole.
原来如此\NAye.
你认为怎样？\NWell, what do you think?
最初20分钟很有意思\NI must say, it's an interesting first 20 minutes.
我认为我们出了洋相\NI'd say we made fools of ourselves.
就像那个士官说的\NAs the sergeant out there says,
这只是第一天\Nthis is only the first day.
艾利克\NEric.
不要引起太多注意 警卫可能不知道他是谁\NDon't take too much notice. The goons may not know who he is.
我去传话\NI'll pass the word.
我去告诉老头子\NI'll tell the old man.
他到了\NHe has arrived.
鲁格上校 战俘巴特利交给你看管\NThe prisoner Bartlett is discharged into your custody, Colonel Von Luger.
我建议把这个战俘\NI suggest this prisoner be kept
永久关在警卫最严密的地方\Nunder the strictest security confinement permanently.
记录库恩先生的建议\NMake a note of Herr Kuhn's suggestion.
我们有理由相信他是\NWe have reason to believe he is
多次脱逃企图的领导人\Nthe leader of numerous criminal escape attempts.
你们看管了巴特利三个月\NSquadron Leader Bartlett has been three months in your care,
但是盖世太保只是 "有理由相信"吗？\Nand the Gestapo has only "reason to believe"?
如果他再次落入我们手里\NIf he once more falls into our hands,
就不会这么幸运了\Nhe will not be so lucky.
空军军官战俘\NAir-force officer prisoners
是由德国空军看管\Nare the responsibility of the Luftwaffe,
不是由党卫军看管\Nnot the SS,
也不是由盖世太保看管\Nor the Gestapo.
上校先生 目前是这样\NAt present, yes, Herr Oberst.
所以他暂时归你看管\NThat is why he is returned for the moment to your care.
当然 如果空军没有能力\NOf course, if the Luftwaffe is not up to the task,
就由我们全权处置战俘\Nthe prisoners will find themselves totally in our charge.
我们就不是那么体谅\NWe regretfully are not so professionally understanding.
巴特利少校\NSquadron Leader Bartlett
如果你再次逃脱被抓到\Nif you escape again and be caught
就会被枪毙\NYou will be shot.
- 希特勒万岁！- 希特勒万岁！\N- Heil Hitlei! - Heil Hitlei!
希特勒万岁！\NHeil Hitlei!
库恩先生\NHerr Kuhn.
把他手铐取下来（德语）\NHandcuffed him down
- 艾利克  - 你好 罗杰\N- Eric. - Hello, Roger.
他们把你也扔到这里来了\NThey dumped you here, too.
这里情况如何？\NWhat's this one like?
这里是新的战俘营\NWell, it's new.
给你找一个床位\NHere. Let's find you a bed.
谢谢\NThanks.
请进\NCome in.
罗杰\NHello, Roger.
长官\NHello, sir.
我把行李放在你房里\NI'll put your bag in your room.
艾利克 谢谢\NThanks, Eric.
你好吗？\NHow are you?
马马虎虎\NAs well as can be expected.
弟兄们想为你办欢迎会 但是稍后再谈\NThe fellows wanted to put up a welcome committee, but that's for later.
我看到威利、威林斯基和麦克\NI saw Willie and Willinski with Mac.
这里有很多老朋友\NA lot of old friends here.
你来这里多久了？\NHow long have you been here, sir?
今天来的\NArrived today.
新营地 优秀的警卫 精英\NNew camp, expert guards, the elite.
你见过指挥官吗？\NYou met the commandant?
我见过\NYes, I did.
盖世太保和党卫军 找你有什么事？\NWhat were the Gestapo and the SS doing with you?
他们想知道谁帮助我抵达边界\NThey wanted to find out who helped me to the border.
- 这里还有谁？有卡文迪斯吗？- 有的\N- Who else is here? Cavendish? - Mm-Hm
尼莫和索伦呢？\NNimmo and Sorren?
葛裹菲斯 海因斯\NGriffith, Haynes.
- 布莱斯呢？- 有的\N- Blythe? - Yes.
几乎整个X组织都在\NAlmost the whole X organization.
差不多\NAlmost.
德国人清理所有的营地 把我们都扔在这里\NThey cleaned out all the other camps and dumped us in this one.
就像鲁格说的 "所有的坏蛋都在一个篮子里"\NAs Von Luger put it: "All the rotten eggs in one basket."
他们的方法有点疯狂\NThere's madness in their method.
汤米布裹斯托呢？\NWhat about Tommy Bristol?
不在 但是有美国人韩德利\NNo, but there's an American - Hendley.
他擅长敲诈吗？\NIs he a scrounger, blackmailer?
麦唐纳说他是最行的\NMacDonald says he's the best.
好\NGood.
在红十字物资再来以前 这是最后的茶了\NLast of the tea until the Red Cross gets through again.
我从塞奇威克敲来的\NI scrounged this from Sedgwick.
盖世太保有没有让你受罪？\NDid the Gestapo give you a rough time?
没有我想要他们受的多\NNot nearly as rough as I now intend to give them.
罗杰 个人恩怨…\NRoger, personal revenge
不能和我们要做的事混为一谈\Nmust be kept out of what we have to do here.
攸关的人命太多了\NToo many lives are at stake.
我个人的感觉…\NWhat my personal feelings are
并不重要\Nis of no importance.
你派我领导X组织\NYou appointed me Big X
我的责任是尽力扰乱\Nand it's my duty to harass, confound and confuse
困惑与混淆敌人\Nthe enemy to the best of my ability.
没错\NThat's true.
那就是我要做的事\NThat's what I intend to do.
我要在他们的帝国里 制造极大的麻烦\NI'm gonna cause such a terrible stink in this Third Reich of theirs
牵制好几千部队来寻找我们\Nthat thousands of troops'll be tied up here looking after us.
怎么做呢？\NHow?
派出更多的人…\NBy putting more men out of this
逃出他们自认为完美的战俘营\Nperfect camp of theirs than have ever escaped before.
不是二三十人 而是二三百人\NNot two or three or a dozen, but 200, 300.
让他们散布到德国各地\NScatter them all over Germany.
- 能做到吗？- 这里人才济济\N- Think that's possible? - The men are here to do it.
你自己说的 他们把全德国 每个逃脱专家都关在这里\NThe goons have put every escape artist in Germany here. You said so yourself.
你想过可能的代价？\NHave you thought of what it might cost?
我想过如果我们就此温顺屈服\NI've thought of the humiliation if we just tamely submit,
对他们卑身屈膝\Nknuckle under and crawl.
长官 你当然不提倡屈服吧？\NSurely you don't advocate that, do you, sir?
罗杰 我必须指出一件事\NI have to point out one thing to you, Roger.
不论这个营地多糟\NNo matter how unsatisfactory this camp may be,
德军高层仍然让德国空军 来看管我们\Nthe high command have left us in the hands of the Luftwaffe,
不是盖世太保与党卫军\Nnot the Gestapo and the SS.
长官 你提到德国空军高层\NLook, sir, you talk about the high command of the Luftwaffe
还有党卫军与盖世太保\Nthen the SS and the Gestapo.
我认为他们都是一样的\NTo me they're the same.
我们要对抗他们全体\NWe're fighting the bloody lot.
一言概之\NThere's only one way to put it, sir.
他们是每个信仰自由的人的公敌\NThey are the common enemies of everyone who believes in freedom.
如果他们不认同希特勒\NIf they didn't approve of Hitler,
为什么不推翻他？\Nwhy didn't they throw him out?
罗杰 我不与你争议\NI have no argument with you, Roger.
身为高阶军官 我只是指出有关的事实\NAs senior officer, I'm merely pointing out a pertinent fact.
X 你什么时候召开会议？\NWhen are you calling a meeting, X?
今天晚上\NTonight.
各位 你们无疑都听过 新指挥官的不朽名言\NGentlemen, no doubt you've heard the immortal words of our new commandant.
"把你们的精力用在 逃脱之外的事情上"\N"Devote your energies to things other than escape
"舒服地等待战争结束"\Nand sit out the war as comfortably as possible."
那就是我们要做的\NWell, that's exactly what we're going to do.
我们要把精力用在运动与园艺\NWe're going to devote our energies to sports and gardening,
还有他们认同的种种文化活动\Nall the cultural pursuits as far as they're concerned.
让他们放松警戒\NIn fact, we're going to put the goons to sleep.
同时…\NMeanwhile...
我们也要挖地道\Nwe dig.
只要稍微观察一下营地\NNow, even a superficial look at the compound
就会发现104号与105号营房 最接近树林\Nshows us that huts 104 and 5 are closest to the woods.
第一条地道从105出发\NThe first tunnel goes out from 105,
向东穿过禁闭室与铁丝网底下\Ndirectly east under the cooler and the wire.
罗杰 那有九十多米\NBut that's over 300 feet, Roger.
- 丹尼斯 你测量过吗？- 只是初步测量\N- Did you make a survey, Dennis? - Only a temporary one, sir.
估计有一百多米\NI make it just over 335 feet.
有精确数字再告诉我\NTell me when you've got an exact one.
威利 我们这次向下挖十米 然后再转水平方向\NWillie, this time we'll dig straight down 30 feet before we go horizontal.
那就可以排除 声响或者探针的探测\NThat'll rule out any question of sound detection or probing.
好的 罗杰 但是…\NAll right, Roger, but
你是不是说第一条地道？\Ndid you say the first tunnel?
是的 总共有三条\NI did. There'll be three.
我们叫它们汤姆、狄克与哈利\NWe'll call them Tom, Dick and Harry. Tom goes out directly east from 104.
汤姆从104直接向东 狄克从厨房向北\NDick goes north from the kitchen,
哈利从105出发与汤姆平行\Nand Harry goes out parallel to Tom from 105.
如果警卫发现一条地道 我们就转移到另一条\NIf the goons find one, we'll move into the other.
罗杰 你计划带多少人出去？\NHow many men do you plan to take out, Roger?
250人\N250.
这一次要有充份准备\NThere'll be no half measures this time.
人人都要有身份证件\NIdentification papers for everyone.
葛裹夫 我们需要服装\NAnd, Griff, we'll need outfits for the lot.
250个人的？\N250?
大部份是平民便服\NMostly civilian clothes.
但是…\NYes, but...
罗杰 好的\NOK, Roger.
麦克 徒步的人要有地图 毯子、口粮、罗盘\NMac. Maps, blankets, rations, compasses for all the walkers.
每班火车的时刻表\NTimetables for every train.
好的 罗杰\NRight, Roger.
抱歉我迟到了\NSorry I'm late, Roger.
柯林 没关系 请坐 我们要挖地道\NIt's all right, Colin. Sit down. We're going to tunnel.
好极了\NSplendid.
威利和丹尼负责地道\NWillie, you and Danny'll be tunnel kings.
丹尼负责设立活门\NDanny, you'll be in charge of traps.
塞奇威克制造工具\NSedgwick, manufacturer.
葛裹夫做裁缝\NGriff, as I said, tailor.
尼莫和海因斯分散警卫注意力\NNimmo and Haynes, diversions.
麦克当然是负责情报\NMac, of course, will take care of intelligence.
韩德利\NHendley.
幸会\NWe haven't met.
- 敲诈专家？- 是的\N- Scrounger? - Right.
丹尼斯负责地图和测量\NDennis, maps and surveys.
柯林的任务与以前一样\NColin, you'll take your usual job.
艾利克 你要怎样解决废土？\NEric, how are you gonna get rid of this dirt?
老地方\NUsual places.
我没料到有三条地道 但是事在人为\NI hadn't anticipated three tunnels, but we'll manage.
罗杰 谁负责保密？\NRoger, who's going to handle security for all this?
你负责\NYou are.
我需要监视系统\NI want a system of stooges covering this compound
前后兼顾 涵盖整个营区 跟踪每个警卫的动静\Nfrom front to back, checking every goon in and out.
我需要完美的信号系统\NI want a signal system so perfect
如果警卫走近工作营房15米内\Nthat if ever a ferret gets within 50 feet of any of the huts in which we're working,
我们就能无声无息 及时停止工作\Nwe can shut down without a sign.
今晚讨论到此为止\NWell, I don't think there's much point in discussing anymore now.
我与各位在运动场见面\NI'll meet each of you on the exercise circuit,
敲定细节\Nand we'll pound out the details.
没别的事了 麦克？\NNothing else, is there, Mac?
没有了\NI shouldn't think so, Roger.
你好\NOh, hello.
我是布莱斯\NMy name's Blythe.
我是韩德利\NHendley.
看鸟用的\NFor birds.
我以前也打猎\NI used to do a little hunting myself.
不是打猎 是观赏\NOh, not hunting. Watching.
是…\NOh...
赏鸟者？\NA bird watcher?
是的 赏鸟与画鸟\NYes, that's right. Watching them and drawing them.
美国应该也有赏鸟者？\NI suppose you have bird watchers in the States?
有一些\NYes, we have some.
喝茶吗？\NTea?
我只在住院时喝过一次茶\NI only drank tea once, in the hospital.
你的东西在哪里？\NWhere's your kit?
就这些\NThis is it.
其他的在上次大检查时被没收了\NThe rest was confiscated in the last shakedown.
警卫不喜欢我的某些…\NThe goons didn't appreciate some of my more...
私人物品\NPersonal items.
比如说这个\NSuch as.
你是敲诈专家\NYou're the scrounger.
是的\NYes, that's right.
我需要一架照相机\NI'll need a camera.
什么类型？\NWhat kind?
好用的\NA good one.
35毫米镜头 2.8焦距 和焦平面快门就可以了\NA 35mm f2.8 with a focal-plane shutter should do all right.
好的\NAll right.
还要胶卷\NAnd film, of course.
当然\NOh, of course.
韩德利 我需要大型尖嘴锄\NOh, Hendley. I need a pick. Big heavy one.
只要一个？\NOnly one?
两个更好\NTwo would be better.
这杯茶恐怕淡得很\NI'm afraid this tea's pathetic.
这些烂茶叶 我一定泡过大约二十次了\NI must have used these wretched leaves about 20 times.
不是我过份挑剔\NIt's not that I mind so much.
但是没有牛奶的茶太不文明了\NTea without milk is so uncivilized.
对\NYeah.
我去找木头\NI'll get our wood.
关窗！关窗！\NClose up! Close up!
关窗！\NClose up!
- 听不懂 请说英语  - 关窗！\N- No me sprechen the English. - Close up!
太好了\NSplendid.
布莱斯 你在这里做什么？\NBlythe, what are you doing here?
我在解读空中侦照的单位\NI'm in Photographic Aerial Reconnaissance Interpretation.
顺便搭飞机亲自去看看\NWent for a joyride to see for myself.
都是我不好\NIt's my own silly fault.
飞机被打中击落了\NThe aircraft bought it. Got shot down.
真可怕\NTerrifying.
不 我是说在营里做什么？\NNo, I mean, what do you do here?
战俘营里？\NHere?
我是伪造专家\NI'm the forger.
伪造专家都在休闲厅里\NForgers are installing themselves in the recreation hut.
- 塞奇威克呢？- 我在110号营房\N- Sedgwick? - I'm in 110.
葛裹菲斯\NGriffith.
我想在109号工作\NWell, I'd like to work in 109, Roger.
109？好的\N109? Right.
我在107\NI'll work in 107.
丹尼、威利和活门队员在104\NFor now, Danny, Willie and their trap team will be in 104.
麦克 我想在地道方面冒险\NI want to take a chance on the tunnels
不用支撑就向前挖掘\Nand press ahead without any shoring-up.
我们需要木材支撑竖坑和进出室\NWe will need timber for the shafts and the entrance chambers.
韩德利算过有36个空床位\NHendley figures there are 36 empty bunks.
我们柝掉15个 然后调动人员 以免被警卫发觉\NWe can tear up 15 and move the men around so the goons won't miss them.
其他的木材要靠柝墙板\NThe rest will come from strips off the wall.
韩德利在亲自处理吗？\NIs Hendley taking care of this himself?
还没有\NNot yet.
他正在设法帮丹尼弄到 尖嘴锄的钢材\NHe's working on some steel for a pick that Danny needs.
这里在搞什么鬼？\NHey! What the hell is going on here?
把水关掉！把手拿开！\NTurn the water off! Get your hands away!
滚开！\NGet away!
嘿！这里在搞什么鬼？\NHey! What the hell's going on there?
停止胡闹！\NStop this nonsense!
滚开！\NGet away!
把水关掉！\NTurn the water off!
滚开！\NSomewhere!
我们让炉子一直燃烧\NIn the stove, we keep fire burning always.
警卫就不会发觉炉子被搬开了\NThe goons will not feel like moving it.
- 好的  - 韩德利 两块磁砖破了\N- Good. - Hendley, two tiles, they are chipped.
我们需要新的\NWe need new ones.
113的盥洗室里有一些\NThere's some in 113's washroom.
- 应该会天衣无缝  - 好极了\N- Should match perfectly. - Good.
丹尼 这件事有点难度\NIt's going to be a bit tricky, Danny.
麦克 有组织就不难\NNot when you're organized, Mac.
我们准备好了\NWe're ready.
够大吗？\NBig enough?
好极了 正好穿过地基的中央\NIt's perfect. Right through the middle of the foundation.
丹尼 祝我们好运\NGood luck to us, Danny.
为什么写17？\NWhy 17?
这是丹尼开挖的第17条地道\NThis is the 17th tunnel Danny's started.
没事吧？\NAll right?
情况还可以\NIt's good.
很好\NIt's very good.
- 从这里滚出去！- 出去！\N- Raus hier! - Get out!
- 出去！- 从这里滚出去！（德语）\N- Get out!  - Raus hier!
# 信神的人们来吧 #\N# O come all ye faith #
怎么不在你的营房里？\NYou're not in your hut?
你在这里做什么？\NWhat are you doing here?
拖地\NMopping up.
你呢？\NAnd you?
淋浴 我需要洗澡\NShower. I need a wash.
我在照顾他 我是救生员\NI'm watching him. I'm a lifeguard.
滚！（德语）\NRaus!
穿上保暖的衣服 你可能整晚都在外面罚站\NPut on warm clothes. You might be outside all night.
我反对\NNo. I vote no.
我们已经完全 照你说的让警卫松懈\NLook, we've put the goons to sleep exactly like you said.
但是这样的小问题 足以使我们陷入困境\NBut just one little thing like this and we're up the creek without a paddle.
艾弗斯 坐下 还好吗？\NIves, sit down, won't you?
你好 长官\NHello, sir.
这是巴特利少校 希尔兹上尉\NHello. Squadron Leader Bartlett, Captain Hilts.
麦唐纳上尉\NFlight Lieutenant MacDonald.
我听说你们俩个想逃出去\NI understand you two are contemplating a blitz-out.
长官…你从哪里听说的？\NWhere'd you hear that... sir?
麦唐纳说的 他有责任知道每一件事\NMacDonald. It's Mac's job to know everything that goes on.
我们想好好谈一谈\NWe thought perhaps we might talk it over.
为什么？这只是两个人的事\NWhy? It's only a two-man job.
营里每个人都应该 事先向巴特利少校\NEverybody in the camp is supposed to clear all escape attempts in advance
申请获准逃脱的企图\Nwith Squadron Leader Bartlett here.
我们不想干扰你们\NWe don't necessarily want to interfere.
只不过…\NIt's just that...
你们计划怎样逃脱？\Nwell, what sort of blitz were you contemplating?
我们晚上溜出去 到铁丝网旁边我发现的盲点\NWe sneak out at night to a spot I found near the wire - a blind spot.
然后我们向下挖一米 把土散开以免堆起来\NThen we dig down, take the dirt, spread it on top so it won't make a pile
然后一直挖出去\Nand then straight out.
艾弗斯是地道专家 他在前面挖 把土推到后面\NIves here is a tunnel man, so he digs in front, pushes the dirt behind him.
我把土推到后面\NI stash it behind me
然后我们像两只地鼠一样 钻过泥土\Nthen we burrow through the dirt like a couple of moles.
天亮时 我们从铁丝网底下 越过空地\NBy dawn we're under the wire, across the open space
进入树林逃走\Ninto the woods and gone.
这个嘛…\NWell...
- 你打算何时试看看？- 嗯？\N- When do you intend to try this? - Hmm?
你打算何时试看看？\NWhen do you intend to try it?
就在今晚\NOh, tonight.
希尔兹 现在可能不是…\NHilts, this may not be quite the right time
做这种事的适当时机\Nfor this sort of thing.
长官 我被关已经快三年了\NLook, sir, I've been in the bag nearly three years now,
我快要疯了\Nbloody close to being wire-happy.
我要逃出去 其他免谈\NIt's a blitz-out for me, or forget it.
会成功的 我知道会成功的\NIt'll work. I know it will.
祝你好运\NGood luck.
谢谢你\NThank you.
希尔兹 你们怎么呼吸？\NHilts, um... how do you breathe?
我们有一根附铰链的钢棒\NWe got a steel rod with hinges on it.
前进时 把它向上推 戳出通气孔\NWe shove it up and make air holes as we go along.
长官 晚安\NGood night, sir.
为什么以前没人想到那一招？\NNow, why didn't anybody think of that before?
这真是简单到了高明之至\NIt's so stupid, it's positively brilliant.
但是会使营地里 每个警卫紧盯我们\NBut it'll bring every goon in the camp down on top of us.
不一定 或许我们聪明过头了\NI don't know. Perhaps we're being too clever.
如果我们阻止所有的逃脱\NIf we stop all the breakouts
警卫反而会认定 我们在挖地道\Nit may only convince the goons that we must be tunneling.
我希望他们成功\NI hope it works.
否则他们会在禁闭室呆很久\NIf it doesn't, they're going to be in the cooler for an awful long time.
好吗？\NGood, huh?
丹尼 这美极了\NDanny, it's bloody beautiful.
这是营地里的土\NThis is the dirt from the compound.
这是地道里的土\NThis is from the tunnel.
不论把土放在哪里 他们大老远就能看见\NWherever we put it, they're going to spot it a mile away.
或许可以放在营房底下 那里的土色比较深\NMaybe we could put it under the huts. The dirt's dark there.
那是警卫首个检查的地方 我昨天看到他们在测量\NIt's the first place the ferrets would look. I saw one measuring yesterday.
或许可以烘干到同样颜色\NMaybe we could dry it to the same color.
但是有50吨的土\NThere are 50 tons of it.
我只是想到什么就说什么\NI was just thinking out loud.
如果你要思考 就想清楚一点\NIf you must think, for God's sake, think clearly.
艾希利·皮特在哪里？\NWhere the devil is Ashley-Pitt?
我们无法摧毁、吃掉废土\NWe can't destroy the dirt and we can't eat it.
唯一的方法就是掩饰\NThe only thing left to do is camouflage it.
我只能想到这么多\NThat's as far as my thinking takes me.
皇家海军没有教你要迅速吗？\NDidn't they teach you promptness in the RN?
你们绝对不会相信 但是我有解决的方法了\NYou'll never believe it, but I think I have the solution.
我们要想办法把地道废土 散布到营地各处\NThe problem is somehow to get rid of this tunnel dirt over the compound.
当然是的\NWell, of course.
请让一下好吗？\NWould you mind?
现在…\NNow...
将地道的废土装满这些袋子\Nyou fill these bags with the dirt from the tunnel.
然后把袋子穿在长裤里面\NThen, wearing them inside your trousers,
你在营地里闲逛\Nyou wander out into the compound
拉动裤袋里的绳子\Nwhere you pull these strings in your pockets.
废土就会掉下来\NOut come the pins.
艾利克 好办法\NEric, it's good.
你只要用脚混合泥土\NAll you have to do is kick it in.
除非你是傻瓜 否则警卫不会看到的\NUnless you're a fool, the ferrets won't see a thing.
这真是鬼聪明 罗杰 你认为好不好？\NIt's indecently brilliant. What do you think, Roger?
明天一早试试看\NWe'll try it first thing tomorrow.
我已经试过了 而且成功了\NI already have. It works.
麦克 我们要采取这些行动\NMac, this is what we'll do.
- 汤姆送的小礼物  - 谢谢你\N- A little present from Tom, sir. - Thank you, Nimmo.
长官 菜园真不错\NNice garden you've got, sir.
注意 好好表现一下\NAll right. Let's look sharp.
表现得很好\NThat looks sharp.
长官\NSir.
各位先生 请继续\NPlease, gentlemen, continue.
这只是例行检查\NThis is merely a routine inspection.
- 上校 早安  - 长官 早安\N- Good morning, Squadron Leader. - Good morning, sir.
很抱歉这里的土镶…\NI am sorry the soil here isn't
不适合种植\Nbetter suited to your men's purpose.
我们能应付\NWe'll manage, sir.
上校 我对园艺的规模大感意外\NI must say I am surprised with the extent of this activity, Group Captain.
既高兴又惊奇\NPleased, of course, but surprised.
怎么会惊奇？\NSurprised, Colonel?
飞行员是绅士\NFliers are gentlemen
不是农人 居然在挖土\NNot peasants to dig in the earth. So I am surprised.
英国人一向热爱田艺\NThe English are keen on gardening.
但那是说种花\NOh, yes, but flowers.
不是吗？\NIs this not so?
花不能吃\NYou can't eat flowers, Colonel.
有道理\NGood point.
我有不祥之感 他好像完全知道我们在做什么\NI have the nasty feeling he knows exactly what we're doing.
也许吧\NMaybe he does.
不是真的吧？\NYou don't really think so, do you?
很快就会知道谜底了\NIf he does, we'll find out soon enough.
- 鲍伯 早安  - 安迪\N- Morning, Bob. - Andy.
东西到了\NHere we are.
我们清点一下\NNow, let's see.
两包饼干\NBiscuits, two packets.
两罐咖啡\NCoffee, two tins.
一瓶牛肉汁\NBovril, one jar.
六包香烟\NCigarettes, six packets.
索伦的草莓酱 卡文迪斯的黑醋粟酱\NStrawberry jam, Sorren's. Black currant jam, Cavendish.
还有我的橘子酱\NAnd marmalade, mine.
鲁格的丹麦奶油\NDanish butter, Von Luger's.
我从他的补给品收复来的\NI liberated it from his mess supplies.
噢\NOh, yes.
还有两条荷兰巧克力\NAnd Dutch chocolate. Two bars.
整个组织的食物礼品 都捐出来了\NThat cleans out the gift food for the entire organization.
我们需要的第一样东西 就是新式通行证\NNow, the first thing we need is the new form of travel permit.
伪造专家从未见过新式通行证\NThe forgers have no idea what it looks like.
我来想想办法\NI'll see what I can do.
还要其他你能弄到手的身份证\NAnd, of course, any other identity cards, personal papers,
个人证件和文件\Ndocuments you can put your hands on.
- 好好利用它们  - 是的\N- Anyway, put 'em to work, Bob. - Right.
祝好运\NGood luck.
# 信神的人们来吧 #\N# O come all ye faith #
# 欢欣又鼓舞 #\N# Joyful and triumphant #
# 大家来吧 #\N# O come ye #
# 来到伯利恒 #\N# O come all ye to  Bethlehem #
# 来见证他 #\N# Come and behold him #
# 天使之王的诞生 #\N# Born the King of Angels #
# 我们来崇敬他 #\N# O come let us adore Him #
路易 鼓风机在什么鬼地方？\NLouis, where the hell is the air pump?
耐心是一种美德\NPatience is a virtue, Roger.
我知道 但是只有打开活门 挖地道的人才能工作\NYes, I know, but the diggers can only work when the trap's open,
这严重阻碍了进程\Nand this is holding us up very badly.
鼓风机完成了吗？\NIs it finished?
当然\NOf course.
为什么没装进去？\NWhy isn't it in?
因为正在制造通风管\NWorking on the air ducts now.
- 通风管何时完工？- 一、两天\N- Well, when will they be finished? - One or two days.
有用吗？\NDoes it work?
当然\NOf course it works.
- 能提供足够的空气吗？- 绰绰有余\N- Will it give us enough air? - As much as you'll need.
麦克\NMac.
好极了\NExcellent.
明天晚上以前装进去\NHave it in by tomorrow night.
# 我主基督 #\N# Lord the Christ #
有火吗？\NGot a light?
有\NYeah.
多谢\NThanks.
- 真不赖 是吗？- 是不赖\N- It's pretty, isn't it? - Yes.
抱歉\NOh, I'm sorry.
你要一根吗？\NWould you like one?
我下岗后再抽 谢谢\NI'll smoke it later when I'm off-duty. Thank you.
你或许有两个室友\NYou probably have a couple of roommates, huh?
- 好天气  - 是啊\N- Beautiful day. - Yes
可能会下雨\Nbut I think it might rain later.
不会 不会\NNo, no.
早晨的天空发红\NRed sky in the morning
水手就紧张 晚上的天空发红 水手就高兴\Nsailor takes warning. Red sky at night, sailor's delight.
昨晚的天空是红的\NIt was a red sky last night.
我从没听说过\NI never heard that before.
我在童子军学的\NI learned it in the Boy Scouts.
- 你以前是童子军？我也是  - 真的？\N- You were a Boy Scout? So was I. - Really?
是啊 我有19个奖章\NYes. I had 19 merit badges.
我有20个\NI had 20.
我正在争取第20个时 政府废除了童军制度\NI was working on my 20th when the government abolished scouting
并把我送进希特勒青年团\Nand sent me into the Hitler Youth instead.
韦纳\NWerner
战后你会留在军队里吗？\Nyou think you'll stay in the army after the war?
不会 我身体不好\NNo. I'm not a well man.
我的牙齿…\NAnd my teeth...
你的牙齿？\NYour teeth?
对了 关于我牙齿的故事\NYes. I could tell you stories about my teeth
会让你毛骨悚然\Nthat would make your hair stand on end.
这里的牙医是屠夫 不要告诉别人我这么说\NOur dentist here is a butcher. But don't tell anyone I said so.
军人有抱怨的权利\NIt's a soldier's right to complain.
也许你的军队就行 这里嘛？\NMaybe in your army, but here?
提出一点批评 就被送到…俄国前线\NOne little criticism, and... to the Russian front.
是这样吗？\NIs that so?
真可怕\NTerrible.
那太可怕了\NThat's terrible.
韦纳\NWerner.
到我房间去谈好吗？舒服些\NWhy don't we go into my room?
最好不要\NI'd better not.
如果斯塔赫维兹看见…\NIf Strachwitz should see me...
我只是要泡咖啡\NI was just gonna make some coffee.
真正的咖啡\NReal coffee.
咖啡 咖啡 咖啡\NCoffee, coffee, coffee.
咖啡在哪里？\NWhere is it?
果酱 棒极了（德语）\NMarmelade . Lst ja wunderbar
我祖母老是寄这种东西给我\NMy grandmother keeps sending me this stuff.
哦 天呐 巧克力（德语）\NAch du lieber Gott. Schokolade.
来 拿一个\NOh, yeah. Here. Take one.
鲁格的奶油（德语）\NVon Lugrs Butter.
是啊 收下吧\NYeah. Keep it.
不行 我该走了\NNein. I must go.
没关系 拿去吧 我们是朋友\NIt's OK. You can keep it. We're friends.
你关禁闭 我们还是朋友？\NWith you in the cooler, will we be friends?
我必须报告这件事\NI must report this.
报告什么？\NI don't understand you. Report what?
说你和我在我的房间聊天？\NThat you and I were chatting in my room?
我必须走了\NI must go.
拿着 没问题的\NOh, here. It's OK. Look, keep it.
我反正吃不了这么多 我已经够吃了\NI'll never be able to eat it all. I've got all I could eat.
对不起\NI'm sorry. All right.
算了 算了\NForget it. Forget it.
相信各位都记得\NAnd that, I'm sure you'll all remember
那是莺鸟的鸣声\Nis the voice of the Nelles warbler.
现在看看这一位 花面伯劳\NLet's turn our attention to this gentleman - the masked shrike.
又名屠夫鸟\NLanius nubicus. The butcherbird.
伯劳把敌人钉在 棘树丛的刺上面\NThe shrike impales his foes on the spikes of thorn bushes.
个性不怎么招人喜爱\NNot a very lovable character, you see.
看看他的色彩\NLet's have a look at the coloring.
背面从头到尾是黑的\NUniform black above, from head to tail.
黑臀部 黑冠有清晰的白斑\NA black rump, a black crown with a bold white flash
眼睛上方有白线 伯劳栖息在稀疏林地…\Nand a white line over the eye. The shrike lives in lightly wooded country...
韩德利\NAh. Hendley.
请坐 桌上有绘画材料\NSit down. You'll find drawing materials on the table.
伯劳栖息在稀疏林地 橄榄园和果园里\NThe shrike lives in lightly wooded country, olive groves and gardens.
韩德利 你也赏鸟吗？\NWell, Hendley, have you taken to birds too now?
是的 别走开 学点知识\NYeah. Stick around. You might learn something.
我有比画鸟更重要的事可做\NI have better things to do than draw birds.
鸣声是单调连续的音符\NThe voice is a monotonous succession of scratchy
粗糙又难听\Ncomplaining notes.
仔细看看这只鸟 他有圆形的…\NNow, let's have a good look at this bird. He's got a round shape...
越过边界的许可证\NAn Urlaubsschein. Permission to cross a frontier.
这里还有一张\NHere's another one.
哪一张是伪造的？\NWhich one's the forgery?
那一张\NThat one.
对\NThat's right.
两张都是伪造的\NThey both are.
现在阻碍进度的是 新式通行证\NWhat's holding us up now is the new form of this travel permit.
我们不知道它们是什么样子\NWe've no idea what they look like.
这里有一张 还有一张军人身份证\NHere's one. And a military identity card.
还有…\NAnd a...
出入证\NAn Ausweis
对\NYeah.
可以进入官方地点\NPermission to be on Reich property.
到奥登的火车票\NA ticket to Oden.
似乎是侦探警卫 下星期要去的地方\NWhat appears to be the ferret assignments for the next week.
你这次得满分了\NYou get 10 out of 10 for this, old boy.
谢谢 小心保管\NThank you, sir. Take good care of that.
你从哪里弄来的？\NWhere did you get this?
暂时借来的\NIt's on loan.
为了制造足够的服装\NIn order to get the right amount of outfits, Roger
我建议以改造军服为主\NI suggest that we work mainly from service uniforms.
我会做双排扣 单排扣\NI can do double-breasteds, single-breasteds,
还有很好看的普通西装\Nand rather nice lounge suits.
我会做多种花样的翻领\NLapels. I can do quite a lot of things with those.
可以做得那么低\NI can have them deep like that
或者那么高\Nor high ones like that.
我们正在做这一件\NHere's one that we're working on right now.
纽扣怎么办？\NOh, yes. What about buttons?
看看那些\NTake a look at those.
我做好这件\NHere's one that I've finished, Roger.
还有…\NAnd
这是我用蓝墨水染的\Nhere's one that I dyed with a bottle of blue ink.
挺好看的\NIt's rather good.
罗杰 什么事？\NWhat's up, Roger?
如果警卫查到这些就大丰收了\NThe goons'd have a field day if they crashed in on this lot.
那是索伦负责的\NThat's Sorren's department.
我已经开始利用其他材料\NNow, I've started working on the other materials.
这床毯子\NThis blanket.
尤其是条纹 好极了\NParticularly the stripes. Marvelous.
- 做外套？- 对\N- Coats. - Yes.
我已经叫手下在营地各处动手\NI've got the chaps working on these all over the compound.
那些战斗服\NThose battle dresses
恐怕稍微短了一点\NI'm afraid they're a bit too short.
我会叫手下把它们做成 工人服之类\NI'll have to get the chaps to make those into some sort of workingman's outfits.
毯子布套\NBlanket ticking.
我把它们做成漂亮的背心\NNow, I've made these into rather nice little waistcoats.
很帅气\NVery dapper, yes.
- 当然是染色的  - 当然\N- Dyed, of course. - Of course.
看看这个\NJust take a look at this, Roger.
我们把毯子刮得很平滑\NNow, this blanket material, we scrape this down until it's really smooth
然后用鞋油染色\Nand then dye it with boot polish.
韩德利弄来的灯心绒\NCorduroy scrounged by Hendley.
但愿有更多这种衣料\NI wish we had more of this.
- 你从哪里弄到这些东西？- 是韩德利\N- Where in God's name did you get these? - Hendley.
他从哪里弄到的？\NWhere did he get them?
- 我问过他  - 他怎么说？\N- I asked him that.- What did he say?
他说"别问"\N"Don't ask."
给你看一些我正在做的大衣\NLet me show you some of the overcoats I've been working on.
- 希尔兹 早安  - 早\N- Good morning, Hilts. - Uh-oh
如果你想知道我会不会再逃 我会\NWell, if you're here to find out if I'm going out again, I am.
- 什么时候？- 17天后 7月7日\N- When? - 17 days. 7th of July.
- 没有月光  - 对\N- Dark of the moon. - Correct.
艾弗斯跟你一起逃吗？\NIs lves going with you?
如果他要的话 可以\NYeah, if he wants to.
你知不知道艾弗斯快崩溃了？\NYou know that lves is close to cracking?
知道\NYeah.
最好让他用地道逃出去吗？\NBetter for him to go out in the tunnel?
比较安全\NSafer.
有道理\NRight.
单独行动有可能穿越铁丝网 甚至逃走\NIt's possible for one man to get out through the wire even get away,
但是除了你之外 营地里还有很多人\Nbut there are in fact a considerable number of people besides yourself
正在试图逃走\Nin this camp who are trying to escape.
我了解\NI appreciate that.
有事情要发生了 我有感觉\NSomething's coming, I can feel it
而且就要发生在我身上 少校\Nand it's coming right around the corner at me, Squadron Leader.
我的名字是罗杰\NMy name's Roger.
好的 罗杰\NAll right, Roger.
你叫维吉吗？\NYours is Virgil, isn't it?
希尔兹\NHilts.
叫我希尔兹好了\NJust make it Hilts.
好 那么…\NYes, well, um...
希尔兹 我要说的是…\Nas I was saying, Hilts,
我们有德国地图 普通的地图\Nwe have maps of Germany - general maps, that is.
我们有逃离德国的全部资讯\NWe have all the information we need for the escape routes out of Germany.
但是我们没有…\NBut what we do not have...
树林外面五百米的详细情形\NIs a clear idea of what's 500 yards beyond those trees.
我们试过营里每个警卫 全都失败\NWe've tried every goon in the camp. No go.
我们必须知道 本地城镇的确切位置\NWe must know the exact position of the local town.
我们想知道 在哪裹连接主要道路\NWe want to know where we hit the main roads.
警察局在哪里\NWhere the police stations are
军事检查哨在哪里\Nwhere they've got their roadblocks.
最重要的是\NAnd most important of all
我们必须知道如何从这里 去火车站\Nwe've got to know how to get from here to the railway station.
绝对不行\NNo. Absolutely not.
我穿越铁丝网之后 绝不会回头帮你们画地图\NWhen I get through that wire, I'm not gonna be making maps for you guys.
我要远走高飞\NI'm gonna be so far away
就算他们用大炮打我 你们也听不见\Nyou won't hear if they're shooting at me with howitzers.
- 可以理解  - 完全理解\N- Understandable. - Completely.
我乐于帮忙 但是…\NI mean, I'd like to help, but...
很有趣的主意\NInteresting idea.
- 你要带多少人出去？- 250人\N- How many you taking out? - 250.
250人？\N250?
对\NYeah.
你疯了 该进疯人院 你也是\NYou're crazy. You too.
250人大摇大摆走在路上？\N250 guys just walking down the road, just like that.
有些走公路 有些搭火车\NWell, some on the road, some by train,
还有一些走小路\Nsome cross-country.
他们有伪造证件、服装\NThey'll have forged papers, clothes,
地图、罗盘、口粮\Nmaps, compasses, rations.
想过你会引起全德国所有警卫的注意吗？\NYou're gonna alert every goon in the country.
连农人都会拿着草又来找你\NAnybody that can carry a pitchfork is gonna be out looking for you.
他们会全面扫荡 很快将你们全抓起来\NThey're gonna swoop down and scoop you up so fast it'd make your head swim.
嗯 总之 多谢了\NYes, well, thanks, anyway.
如果地道要我帮忙 尽管说\NIf I can help on the tunnel, let me know.
你真好心\NThat's good of you.
听候差遣\NAnytime.
等一下\NWait a minute.
你不是真的 想我穿越铁丝网\NYou aren't seriously suggesting that if I get through the wire
弄清楚外面的情况\Nand case everything out there
躲避追捕\Nand don't get picked up,
然后回来自首关禁闭几个月\Nto turn myself in and get thrown back in the cooler
好让你得到需要的资料？\Nso you can get the information you need?
是的\NYes.
我的任务使我 不得不提出奇怪的要求\NOne has to ask some very strange things in the job I have.
我们让你优先使用地道\NWe'll give you a front place.
- 连我亲娘也别妄想  - 我不怪你\N- I wouldn't do that for my own mother.- I don't blame you.
- 那么 请便  - 我们完全谅解你\N- Well, OK, then. - It's completely understandable.
那么 请便\NWell, OK, then.
好吧 多谢了 希尔兹\NYes, well, thanks, Hilts.
将军…\NCheck.
韩德利 我…\NHerr Hendley, I...
不要紧 布莱斯是朋友\NOh, it's all right. Blythe's a friend.
韦纳 什么事？\NWhat's the matter, Werner?
我的皮夹、证件、身份证 不见了\NMy wallet, my papers, my identity card. Gone.
我的东西全丢了\NI lost them. Everything.
他的皮夹掉了\NHe lost his wallet.
如果斯特赫维兹发现了 你知道会怎样吗？\NDo you realize what would happen if Strachwitz found this out?
- 去俄国前线  - 太糟了\N- The Russian front. - Dear, dear.
我找遍每个地方\NI've looked every place, every place.
一定是在这里弄丢的\NI must have lost them while I was in here.
- 不会吧  - 一定是\N- No. - Yes.
我说过我们是朋友\NLook, I told you we were friends.
我们会替你找到的\NWe'll find them.
韩德利先生 谢谢你\NOh, thank you, Herr Hendley.
韦纳\NWerner.
现在别找\NNot now.
看起来有点奇怪\NIt might look a little peculiar
如果有人看见你和我这么晚探头探脑\Nif you and I were seen probing around at this time of night.
我保证会找到失物\NLook, I'll find them.
就算柝掉房子也要找到\NI promise you I'll find 'em if I have to tear this room apart.
谢谢你\NThank you.
别客气\NForget it.
- 韦纳  - 什么事？\N- Werner. - Yes?
请你帮个小忙\NThere is one small favor.
我要一架照相机\NA camera.
我们想拍几张快照 当作…纪念品\NWe want to take some snapshots. You know, keepsakes.
35毫米镜头 2.8焦距和平面快门\N35mm with a 2.8 lens and a plane shutter.
是焦平面快门\NFocal-plane shutter.
韦纳 是焦平面快门\NWerner, that's a focal-plane shutter.
弄到了就告诉我\NLet me know when you got it.
韦纳是个浑小子\NHe's a crazy, mixed-up kid, that Werner
但是我喜欢他\Nbut I like him.
将军\NCheckmate.
鼓风机何时准备好？\NHow soon's our air pump going to be ready?
明天给你\NI'll have it for you tomorrow.
你落后进度太多了\NYou're badly behind schedule.
丹尼 情况怎样？\NHow's it coming, Danny?
- 不好  - 不好？\N- No good.- No good?
今天塌了三次\NToday, three times.
威利 你还好吧？\NWillie, you all right?
拉！\NPull!
你必须支撑整条地道\NYou're gonna have to shore up the whole bloody tunnel, Roger.
全部一百米都要支撑\NAll 335 feet of it.
今天塌了四次\NFour times today.
这样永远挖不通\NThis way we never get through.
我们需要更多木材\NWe must have more wood.
需要很多木材\NIt's a lot of timber, Roger.
能弄到手吗？\NCan you get it?
会弄到的\NWe'll get it.
非弄到不可 我会派韩德利\NWe've gotta get it. I'll put Hendley on it
和今早新加入的人去办\Nand the new man we got this morning.
好的 威利\NOK, Willie.
# 在耶诞的第一天 #\N# On the first day of christmas #
# 我的挚爱送给我 一只站在梨子树上的鹧鸪 #\N# My ture love sent me a partridge in a pear tree #
# 在耶诞的第二天 我的挚爱送给我 #\N# On the second day of christmas my ture love sent me #
# 两只斑鸠 还有一只站在梨子树上的鹧鸪 #\N# Two turtle doves and a partridge in a pear tree #
# 在耶诞的第四天 我的挚爱送给我 #\N# On the forth day of christmas my ture love sent me #
# 四只会唱歌的鸟儿 三只法国母鸡 #\N# Four calling birds, three French hens #
# 两只斑鸠 还有一只站在梨子树上的鹧鸪 #\N# Two turtle doves and a partridge in a pear tree #
# 在耶诞的第五天 我的挚爱送给我 #\N# On the fifth day of christmas my ture love sent me #
# 五个金戒指 #\N# Five gold rings. #
上面木板的情况怎样？\NHow's it going with the rafters up there?
每四块抽掉一块\NTaking out one in four.
继续进行\NStay with it.
# 五个金戒指 #\N# Five gold rings #
# 四只会唱歌的鸟儿 三只法国母鸡 #\N# Four calling birds, three French hens #
# 两只斑鸠 还有一只站在梨子树上的鹧鸪 #\N# Two turtle doves and a partridge in a pear tree #
# 在耶诞的第七天 我的挚爱送给我 #\N# On the senveth day of christmas my ture love sent me #
# 七只游泳的天鹅 六只躺着的鹅 #\N# Senve swans a-swimming, six geese a-laying #
# 五个金戒指 #\N# Five gold rings #
# 四只会唱歌的鸟儿 三只法国母鸡 #\N# Four calling birds, three French hens #
# 两只斑鸠 还有一只站在梨子树上的鹧鸪 #\N# Two turtle doves and a partridge in a pear tree #
# 五个金戒指 四只会唱歌的鸟儿…\N# Five gold rings. Four calling birds...
真难听 我从没这么辛苦过\NBloody singing. I've never worked so hard in all my life.
- 希尔兹  - 卡文迪斯…\N- Hi, Hilts.- Say, Cavendish...
三只法国母鸡 两只斑鸠\NThree French hens, two turtle doves
还有一只站在梨子树上的… 上床！\NAnd a partridge in a pear... Allez hup!
没事\NNever mind.
我们的朋友韦纳送的礼物\NHere's a present from our friend Werner.
好极了\NSplendid.
实在好极了\NSimply splendid.
这个应该很合用\NThis should do very nicely.
那是艾希利·皮特的部下 他请求准许\NThose are Ashley-Pitt's men. He requested permission
在阁楼上堆放一些废土\Nto dispose of some of his dirt in our attic.
汤姆已经挖到超过那堆木头了\NTom has reached just beyond that pile of wood, sir.
哈利没那么远\NHarry, of course, isn't as far as that.
离树林还有多远？\NHow much further to the trees?
估计有15米\NWe make it 50 feet, sir.
- 没有月光的晚上是7号… - 8号和9号\N- Dark of the moon is the 7th... - 8th and 9th.
8月份提早一天\NA day earlier in August.
早安\NMorning.
他又来了\NThere he goes again.
他为哈要买 营地里所有的洋芋？\NWhy is he buying up all the potatoes in the camp?
我探听过 但是无法找到答案\NI've been working on that, but I can't find out.
希尔兹与韩德利 每天晚上都混在一起\NHilts and Hendley lock themselves in every night.
地鼠有时候和他们在一起 有时在外面放哨\NSometimes Goff's with them. Other nights he's on guard outside.
麦克 我们要关闭狄克与哈利 把它们封起来\NMac, we'll close down Dick and Harry. Seal them off.
全力以赴将汤姆推进到树林里\NPut the entire effort into Tom and press on into the trees.
是的 罗杰\NRight, Roger.
好\NWow.
好喔\NWow.
向后转！\NAbout face!
齐步走！\NForward march!
这是做什么？\NWhat is it?
他们在庆祝美国革命\NThey're celebrating the revolution.
今天是7月4号\NIt's the 4th of July.
这到底是怎么回事？\NWhat the devil's this?
我们邀请各位免费喝酒\NGentlemen, you're invited for free drinks.
美国国庆 这是殖民地的小礼物\NA little present from the colonials.
打倒英国人\NDown the British.
说得对\NQuite right too.
为汤姆喝一杯\NAnd a little drink to Tom.
为回家喝一杯\NAnd to getting home.
很好 我们接受\NVery well. We accept.
- 支持叛军！- 打倒英国人！\N- Up the rebels! - Down the British!
各位 请跟我们来\NGentlemen, follow us.
向后转！\NAbout face!
立…定！\NCompany, halt!
在这里排队！\NAll right, let's line up down here!
各人拿一个杯子！\NAll right, grab a cup!
排队！开始了\NLine it up! Here we go.
原来洋芋有此用处\NThat explains what happened to the potatoes
汤姆停工一天不要紧\NNo harm in closing down Tom for one day, Roger.
轻松一下对我们都好\NI suppose it'll do us all good to let off a bit of steam.
只剩下14呎了\NThere's only 14 feet to go, sir
整个营地都能感觉到\Nand you can feel it throughout the whole camp.
- 我们应该喝一杯  - 遵命 长官\N- I think that calls for a drink. - Hear, hear.
干杯！\NDrink it up!
- 希尔兹 这是什么？- 私酒 美国私酒\N- What is this stuff, Hilts? - Moonshine. American moonshine. Moonshine.
喝个痛快 干杯\NMake my mustache grow. Cheers.
向前走\NKeep it moving.
艾利克\NHello, Eric.
不要洒出来\NDon't spill any of that.
- 给你  - 打倒英国人\N- There you go. - Down with the British.
好 老兄\NAll right, old cobber.
向前移动\NKeep it mo...
- 不要洒到衣服上  - 干杯！\N- Don't get any on your clothes. - Cheers!
- 不要洒出来  - 喝酒不嫌太早吗？\N- Don't spill any of that. - Before your morning tea?
向前走\NKeep it moving.
长官 不要洒在衣服上\NDon't get any on your clothes, sir.
美国私酒 酒精很多 抽烟会起火\NAmerican moonshine. Don't smoke right after you drink it.
不要抽烟 喝酒时不要抽烟\NNo smoking. No smoking while you're drinking.
朋友 喝个酩酊大醉\NGet good and stoned, my friend.
向前走\NKeep it going.
向前…\NKeep it...
没有国会代表权就不缴税\NNo taxation without representation.
小伙子 向前移动 向前…\NKeep it going, boys. Keep it...
伙计们向前走 喝个痛快\NKeep it going, fellas. Enjoy yourselves.
我们敬汤姆一杯\NWell, let's drink to Tom.
敬汤姆\NTo Tom.
我关在战俘营三年七个月\NIn the three years, seven months
又大约两星期\Nand two weeks that I've been in the bag
那是我尝过最美味的东西\Nthat's the most extraordinary stuff I've ever tasted.
味道真呛\NIt's shattering.
我认为还不错\NWell, I think it's rather good.
长官 如果你准许的话 我去艾弗斯叫…\NWell, with your permission, sir, I think I'll all on kive.
我是说 去叫艾弗斯\NCall on lves.
韩德利 敬你！\NCheers, Hendley!
你知道那是什么吗？\NYou know what that is?
我知道这不是什么\NI'll tell you what it isn't.
这不是拿破仑白兰地\NIt isn't Napoleon brandy.
长官 你喜欢这酒吗？\NHow do you like it, sir?
这个嘛…\NWell, it's...
敬殖民地\NTo the colonies.
敬独立\NIndependence.
你们两人相处还好吗？\NHow are you managing over there without us? Getting along all right, are you?
我们相处挺融洽的 掌…长官\NWe seem to be getting along all right, shir... sir
说到这个酒嘛…\NYes, well, it's...
希尔兹 这是好酒\NIt's good stuff, Hilts.
长官 谢谢你\NThank you, sir.
丹尼！\NDanny!
这一杯敬…\NHere's to...
罗杰 警卫在105号营房\NRoger, goons in 105.
哪一个？\NWho?
斯特赫维兹\NStrachwitz.
我们必须装作若无其事\NWe have to ignore it.
否则警卫就知道那里很重要\NIf we pay attention, the goons'll know the hut's important.
祝回家\NHere's to going home.
丹尼 别紧张\NCome on, Danny.
他们搜过一百次了 回家！\NThey've searched it a hundred times. Home!
很高兴你和我们合作挖地道\NAnyway, I'm glad we've got you in the tunnel with us.
敬汤姆 好吗？\NTo Tom, eh?
别担心\NAch, never mind.
两星期后 你就会在亚吉尔逛大街\NYou'll be walking down Argyle Street in a couple of weeks.
敬汤姆\NTo Tom.
我现在才开始有那种感觉\NYou know, Sandy, I'm just beginning to realize that myself.
当然应该有那种感觉 我们几乎要到树林了\NWhy shouldn't you, man? We're nearly at the trees, boy.
我们几乎要到树林了 是吗？\NWe're nearly at the trees, eh?
士官长！士官长！\NHerr Hauptfeldwebel! Herr Hauptfeldwebel!
士官长！\NHerr Hauptfeldwebel!
所以 这是（德语）\NDas ist  es also.
快去报警！\NLos , holen sie die wache!
不敢想象\NLch hab's doch geahnt.
老天！他们发现汤姆了\NOh, my God! They've found Tom.
地道被发现了\NIt's the tunnel.
成功个鬼\NSuccess.
艾弗斯！\NIves!
站住！\NHalt!
长官\NSir
请告诉我 你需要什么资料\Nlet me know the exact information you need.
- 我今晚逃出去  - 好的\N- I'm going out tonight. - Right.
打开哈利\NOpen up Harry.
我们一天24小时挖掘\NWe dig. Around the clock.
禁闭室\NCooler.
关就关\NRight.
没想到他们这么快抓到他\NWell, I didn't think they'd catch him so soon.
他不是被抓到的\NHe wasn't caught.
希尔兹 欢迎回家\NHilts, welcome home.
丹尼？\NDanny?
丹尼 你没事吧？\NAre you all right, Danny?
没事\NYes.
我没事\NAll right.
拿铲子来 我没事\NAll right. Bring some shovels. I'm all right.
老天爷 你漏掉了整个飞鹰标志\NFor God's sake, you've left out a whole eagle.
那不可能\NThat's impossible.
是漏掉了\NYes.
四天的辛苦白费了！\NFour days' work up the bloody spout!
柯林 对不起\NI'm sorry, Colin.
史密斯 不要紧\NIt's all right, Smithy.
已经很晚了\NIt's getting late.
你去睡吧 我来收拾这里\NYou push off to bed. I'll pack up here.
是的\NAll right.
柯林 晚安\NGood night, Colin.
史密斯 晚安\NGood night, Smithy.
我什么都看不见\NI can't see a bloody thing.
脱帽（德语）\NSehr gut.
很好 行了\NIn ordnung. Danke schn.
- 从这儿进去  - 来\N- Bitte schon.   - Herein.
希特勒万岁！\NHeil Hitler!
- 你叫什么名字？- 埃里希·斯塔索 来自慕尼黑\N- Wie hei? en sie?  - Erich stressel, aus Munchen.
你怎么在这儿？\NWarum sind sie hier?
我可以有段假期 我妈妈病了\NIch habe Urlaub bekommon. Meine Mutter ist trank.
- 你的德语很好  - 谢谢 我花了很多…\N- Your German's very good. - Thanks, Mac. I've put in a lot of...
注意！那是最容易的一招\NWatch it. That's the easiest way to trip up a suspect.
不要被那个老套招式骗到\NDon't fall for that old gag.
- 对不起  - 记住永远说德语\N- I'm sorry, Mac. - OK. But remember, German always.
l 2…\NOne, two
…3 4 5\Nthree, four, five.
罗杰\NRoger.
不是 是我\NNo, it's me.
你喜不喜欢这套逃亡装？\NHow do you like the old escape suit?
很好\NFine, fine.
柯林\NColin.
你喜欢我的吗？\NHow do you like mine?
看起来好极了\NIt looks splendid.
丹尼 你要去哪里？你会被枪毙的\NWhere are you going? You'll get yourself shot.
怎么回事？\NWhat's the matter with you?
我要从铁丝网出去\NI'm going out through that fence.
丹尼 我们从地道出去 我就要出发了\NDanny, we're getting out through the tunnel. We're almost clear.
威利 别管我\NPlease, Willie, let me alone.
我无法再进那个地道\NI can't go in that tunnel anymore.
我要从铁丝网出去\NSo I'm going out through the wire.
丹尼 想清楚 我们要出去 但不是从铁丝网\NDanny, think. We're getting out, but not through the wire.
我们要从地道出去 地道已经完工了\NWe're getting out through the tunnel. It's finished.
- 我现在就出去  - 不要\N- I go out now. - No.
丹尼 你从铁丝网出去 会被射杀\NDanny, you go through that wire and you'll get killed.
不要那样\NDon't do that.
威利…\NWillie...
从我小时候\NSince I was a boy,
我就讨厌…而且害怕小房间\NI hate... and feared little rooms,
橱柜、山洞\Nclosets, caves.
丹尼 你挖过17条地道 不只17条地道\NDanny, you've dug 17 tunnels. Over 17 tunnels.
我必须逃出去\NBecause I must get out.
我藏起恐惧 努力挖掘\NI hide the fear, and I dig.
但是明天晚上在地道里 有这么多人\NBut tomorrow night in the tunnel with all those men
我怕这次会丧失理智\NI'm afraid maybe this time I will lose my head
毁了大家的计划\Nand ruin the escape for everybody.
所以我现在就逃\NSo I go now.
丹尼 我会照顾你穿过地道\NDanny, I'll see you through the tunnel.
我会照顾你\NI'll look after you.
我会一路跟着你\NI'll stick with you all the way.
好\NAll right.
晚安\NGood evening.
哈罗 罗杰\NHello, Roger.
你认为我们看起来怎样？\NWell, how do you think we look?
晚上好 先生（德语）\NGuten abend, mein herr, Wie geht es lhnen?
怎么了 我德语那么糟吗？\NIt's as bad as all that?
柯林 我首先要说如果没有你\NColin, I want first of all to say that without you
我们就不能准备好\Nwe would not have been ready.
别客气 我有很多帮手\NThat's all right. I had lots of help.
很多很好的帮手\NLots of very good help.
罗杰 什么事？\NWhat's the matter, Roger?
你不能参加逃脱\NYou can't go.
- 你是什么意思？- 我不能让你出去\N- What do you mean? - I can't allow it.
- 为什么？- 你连眼前的手都看不见\N- Why? - You can't see your hand in front of your face.
你逃不出十米就会被抓到\NYou'd be caught before you got ten yards.
那太可笑了\NThat's ridiculous.
我从没听过这么荒谬的事\NNever heard anything so absurd in my life.
我视力没问题 我视力没问题！\NI can see perfectly. I can see perfectly!
我能够看见…\NI can see...
那边那根针 你满意了吗？\Nthat pin down there. Does that satisfy you?
什么针？在哪里？\NWhat pin? Where?
柯林 你看见门槛吗？\NColin, do you see the foot of the door?
当然看见了\NYes, of course.
把这根针放在那里 好吗？\NPut the pin down there, will you?
可以\NAll right.
没事了 过来\NAll right. Come on.
过来 坐下\NCome on. Sit down.
坐下 你努力试过了\NSit down. It was a good try.
我不想最后一刻让你失望 但是有人告诉我\NI hate these last-minute letdowns, but I've only just been told.
太冒险了\NIt's too risky for you.
你不认为要让柯林来决定吗？\NDon't you think that's Colin's decision?
我不认为\NNo, I don't.
罗杰 别这样 我们都知道是怎么回事\NCome on, Roger. We all know the score here.
至少…大部份人知道\NWell, at least, most of us do.
这次逃脱的构想 是开辟另一条战线\NYour idea of this escape is to start another front
在防线后方扰乱德国人\Nto foul up the Germans behind the lines.
没关系 那样很好\NAll right, that's fine.
但是只要我们越过铁丝网\NBut once we get past that wire
迫使他们到处寻找我们\Nand have them looking all over Germany for us
任务就完成了\Nthat mission is accomplished.
完成任务之后 我们有自己的想法\NAfterwards, we have some ideas of our own.
你是说回家？\NYou mean getting home?
回到家人身边？\NBack to your family?
对\NThat's right.
你真的以为我不想回家吗？\NDo you really believe I haven't thought about that too?
我相信你想\NI'm sure you have.
我知道柯林想\NI know Colin has.
我也想\NAnd, Roger, I have too.
我们认为能够一路逃回去\NWe think we can make it all the way.
柯林不能 他会严重危害整个计划\NNot Colin. He'd be an appalling hazard to the escape.
必须由我来决定\NThat must be my decision.
让我们来谈谈危害 先谈谈你\NLet's talk about hazard. Let's talk about you.
你是我们最大的危害 盖世太保已经锁定你了\NYou're the biggest hazard we have. The Gestapo has you marked.
但是没人说你不可以逃\NNo one has said you can't go.
你说的对\NThat's true.
我已经考虑到盖世太保 但是如果你问我\NI have thought about the Gestapo. But if you're asking me
一个指挥官可以做或者胆敢做…\Nhow far a commanding officer is allowed to go
多大的冒险\Nor dare go
或者他可不可以扮演上帝？\Nor should be permitted to play God
我无法回答你\NI can't answer you.
但是我能够告诉你\NBut I can tell you
盲人对于自己和整个计划都是不必要的危害\Na blind man is an unnecessary hazard to himself and the whole plan
必须排除在逃亡计划之外\Nand must therefore be eliminated from the operation.
柯林和我一起就不是盲人\NColin's not a blind man as long as he's with me
他会和我一起\Nand he's going with me.
柯林 你愿意吗？\NIt's all right with you, Colin?
很愿意\NOh, yes. Quite.
很好\NVery well.
我会安排你和柯林一起逃脱\NI'll arrange for your escape numbers to be altered accordingly.
俩位 晚安\NGood night, gentlemen.
其实…\NActually...
他说的很对\Nhe's quite right.
他说的完全正确\NHe's completely right.
我真的不应该逃\NI really shouldn't go at all.
我的视力最近愈来愈差\NMy eyes have been getting worse and worse lately.
这好像叫作恶性近视\NI think they call it progressive myopia.
我能看见这么近的东西\NI can see things up here. Close to.
我能够用眼力工作\NI can see to work
但是…\Nbut...
看你只是一团模糊\Nyou're just a blur.
我知道\NI know.
管它的 我们会很顺利的\NOh, hell. We'll make it in great shape.
柯林 你有茶吗？\NColin, do you have any tea?
当然有\NYes, of course.
我们喝一点\NThen let's have some.
好极了\NSplendid.
希尔兹\NHi, Hilts.
麦克\NHey, Mac.
什么时候？\NWhen?
今天晚上 以为他们永远不放你出来\NTonight. We thought they'd never let you out.
我也以为是 我们谈正事吧\NMe, too. Let's get at it.
- 巴特利在等你  - 我会到的\N- Bartlett's waiting for you. - I'll be there.
现在什么时间？\NWhat time?
丹尼 只剩八分钟了\NOnly eight minutes now, Danny.
你没事吧？\NYou OK?
卡文迪斯\NCavendish.
葛裹夫 去那边\NGriff, down there.
戈福 去那边\NGoff, there.
史密斯 福尔斯 右边第三床\NSmith, Foles, third on the right.
布莱斯 韩德利 左边第三床\NBlythe, Hendley, third on the left.
灯亮了\NThere are the lights.
丹尼 分秒不差\NRight on the tick, Danny.
丹尼 顺着地道看 它真美\NLook down the tunnel, Danny. It's lovely.
像是旅游旺季的黑潭海滨\NIt's just like Blackpool at the height of the season.
丹尼 你去过黑潭吗？\NYou ever been to Blackpool, Danny?
去过\NYes.
没去过\NNo.
我不知道\NI don't know.
罗杰 时间到了\NIt's time, Roger.
巴特利 麦唐纳 艾希利·皮特\NBartlett, MacDonald, Ashley-Pitt.
长官 可以走了\NIt's all clear, sir.
罗杰 全准备好了\NAll set, Roger.
罗杰\NRoger.
祝好运\NGood luck.
丹尼 他们正从竖坑下来\NThey're coming down the shaft now, Danny.
然后他们会顺着地道过来\NAnd then they'll be coming right up the tunnel.
威利…\NWillie...
我不能等了\NI can't wait.
我必须出去\NI must get out.
丹尼！丹尼！丹尼！\NDanny! Danny! Danny!
丹尼！\NDanny!
什么事？\NWhat is it, Danny? What's the matter?
丹尼！过来！\NDanny! Come here!
罗杰\NRoger?
丹尼和我等一下才走 我们排后一点\NDanny and I'll go later. We'll take another place.
丹尼 告诉我怎么回事 快点！\NDanny, tell me what this is and tell me quickly!
这地道是大家的也是我的\NThis tunnel is mine as much as anybody.
我挖的 我造的 我被埋过很多次\NI dug it. I built it. I was buried many times.
我想走就走 让我出去\NI go when I want. Let me out.
让我出去\NLet me out.
带他出去 威利 带他出去\NTake him out, Willie. Take him out.
丹尼？怎么回事？\NDanny? What is it?
丹尼 出了什么事？\NDanny, what's going on?
塞奇威克 没事 我们等一会再走\NIt's all right, Sedgwick. It's all right. We're going later.
丹尼 没事的 没事的\NDanny, it's all right. It's all right.
我们可以排后一点 没事的\NWe can take another place in the line. It's all right.
柯林 该你下去\NAll right, Colin. Down you go.
坐下\NSit down.
用右脚找梯子的第一级\NFeel the top rung of the ladder with your right foot.
找到了吗？向下爬\NGot it? Down you go.
丹尼退出吗？\NDanny cut out, huh?
威利带他上去\NWillie took him up top.
希尔兹 我…\NHilts, I...
- 记住 别抬头  - 好的\N- Remember, keep your head down. - Right.
很好\NRight.
巴特利\NBartlett.
没事吧？\NAll right?
糟了 差了6米\NHold on to yourself. You're 20 feet short.
是什么意思？\NWhat do you mean?
差6米才到树林\N20 feet short of the woods.
地道出口在空地上\NThe hole is in the open.
警卫在我们和探照灯之间\NThe guard is between us and the lights.
怎么会这样？\NHow could that happen?
现在争论也没意思 生米已经煮成熟饭\NWhat the hell difference does it make? It's happened.
罗杰…\NRoger...
别吵 我要想一想！\NDamn it, Mac! I'm trying to think!
我们可以延期 挖到树林\NWe could postpone it.
所有文件日期都是今天 时机一去不回\NAll the documents are dated today. It's now or never.
只有一个机会\NOne chance.
趁警卫走到那边时 你就有机会逃出去\NWhen the guard goes to the far end, you might be able to move out.
我能跑进树林 用信号通知你们\NI think I can make it to the woods, set up a signal when you're clear.
瞭望塔怎么办？\NWhat about the towers?
必须冒险\NHas a change you're gonna have to take.
他们监看的是营地 不是树林\NThey're gonna be watching the compound, not the woods.
麦克 传话下去 送十米的绳子过来\NMac, pass the word. Send down 30 feet of rope.
送十米的绳子过来！\NSend down 30 feet of rope!
送十米的绳子过来\NSend down 30 feet of rope.
- 什么？- 十米的绳子！\N- What? - 30 feet of rope!
- 要绳子做什么？- 我怎么知道？快拿绳子来\N- What do they want that for? - How should I know? Get the rope.
情况怎样？听说了吗？\NHow's it going? Have you heard?
长官 我猜是出了麻烦\NSome kind of foul-up, I think, sir.
他们还没进入地道吗？\NHaven't they moved into the tunnel yet?
长官 还没有\NI don't think so, sir.
他进树林了\NHe's over there.
好 艾利克 你先上\NRight. You go first, Eric.
我在这里等到一切顺利进行\NI'm staying here till we get moving.
- 毕卡第利大街见  - 史考特酒吧\N- See you in Piccadilly. - Scott's Bar.
好\NRight.
谢谢你\NThank you.
- 祝好运  - 好的\N- Good luck. - Right.
该我们了\NWe're moving.
丹尼 他们在通过地道 他们正在逃出去\NDanny, they're moving through the tunnel now. They're getting out.
华沙沦陷时\NWhen Warsaw fell
你是飞行员 逃到英国\Nyou escaped and came to England because you're a flier.
你逃过来是想与我们一起 在天空对德军战斗\NYou came because you wanted to fly with us and fight the Germans.
我们现在能够逃出去\NWe can get out now.
可以回到英国\NWe can get back to England.
如果你不从地道逃走\NIf you don't go through that tunnel
你做过的每一件事 都会变成无意义！\Neverything you've done will have been for nothing - nothing!
- 麦克 布莱斯在后面  - 知道了\N- Blythe's behind, Mac. - Right.
柯林 来这里\NIn here, Colin.
坐下\NSit down.
塞奇威克 该你了 我来接手\NYou're up, Sedgwick. I'll take over.
- 裹面装了什么？钢琴吗？- 你真会说笑\N- What have you got in here? A piano? - That's very funny, mate.
这东西过不了地道\NYou won't get this thing through.
我自有办法\NI'll cope.
塞奇威克和他的箱子吗？\NWas that Sedgwick with his trunk?
还会是谁？真希望他留在澳洲陪袋鼠\NWho else? I wish he was home with his kangaroos.
- 地道短了6米  - 什么鬼…？\N- We're 20 feet short. - How the hell...?
短了6米 希尔兹在树林里 控制绳子的另一端\NHilts is on the other end of that rope in the woods.
感觉绳子拉两下时就出去 让柯林趴下\NAs soon as you feel a couple of tugs, off you go, but keep Colin low.
- 柯林 祝好运  - 麦克 多谢\N- Good luck, Colin. - Thanks, Mac.
那是什么声音？\NWhat's that?
是空袭\NIt's an air raid.
天哪！不要！警卫会关掉电源\NOh, God! No! The goons'll pull the switches.
地道就没有灯光了\NWe'll lose the lights in the tunnel.
柯林 来吧 趁熄灯的时候出去\NCome on, Colin. We can get out when the lights go down.
威利\NWillie.
威利！\NWillie!
是空袭 探照灯关了 赶快！\NIt's an air raid. Searchlights are out. Come on!
叫他们出去\NGet 'em out.
- 地道要塌了！- 丹尼 丹尼 没事的\N- It's gonna give! - Danny. Danny. Danny, it's all right.
丹尼 是灯熄了\NDanny, it's the lights.
点燃底下的油灯！\NLight the lamps down there!
是空袭 他们熄了灯\NThere's been an air raid and they've cut the lights.
丹尼 听我说 地道没事的！\NDanny, it's all right. Listen to me!
丹尼 你看\NDanny, look.
伙计们 快点啊！\NCome on, fellas. Move! Move!
可以趁黑逃走几十人\NWe can get dozens out in this darkness.
究竟怎么回事？\NWhat the hell's going on?
你走\NYou go.
丹尼 不要\NNo. Danny.
走啊\NGo.
- 威利 什么事？- 是丹尼\N- What is this, Willie? - Danny.
- 他卡在里面吗？- 他没事\N- Is he stuck in there? - He's all right.
叫他赶快出来！\NGet him out fast.
快点\NCome on.
丹尼 快点 前进\NCome on, Danny, move.
上去\NUp you go.
袋子给我\NGive me your bag.
我们等绳子信号！\NWe're on the rope!
你和我最好出去 否则没机会赶上任何火车\NYou and I had better get out, or we won't have a chance of any of the trains.
进展顺利 我们只要交待指示就行了\NIt's moving. We'll just have to pass the instructions from man to man.
- 好的  - 我在你后面\N- Right. - I'll be right behind you.
快拉啊 快拉啊\NCome on, come on.
快拉啊\NCome on.
- 嘿！- 不要开枪！\N- Hey! - Don't shoot!
不要开枪！\NDon't shoot!
快让开！我们要回来！\NGet off! We're coming back!
老天 上面枪声热闹极了\NOh, boy. There's a hell of a lot of shooting going on up there.
德军在他们爬出去时开枪吗？\NThink they've been shooting them as they came out?
不是 否则我们早听到枪声了\NWe would've heard the shots before.
拉！\NPull!
等等我\NWait for me.
出来\NOut.
出去\NOut.
上校 花名册（德语）\NDie Aufstellung, Herr Hauptmann.
- 76人？- 对\N- 76?  - Jawohl.
- 他说逃走多少？- 76人\N- How many did he say? - 76.
- 76人  - 76人\N- 76. - 76.
- 解散  - 敬礼！（德语）\N- Dismissed. - Ten hut!
立正！（德语）\NHalt!
没赶上火车的人 有一半都挤在这里\NHalf the guys who missed their trains are piled up here.
艾希利·皮特、罗杰 麦唐纳、尼莫\NAshley-Pitt, Roger, MacDonald, Nimmo.
真是一大群人\NMakes quite a group.
我们怎么办？\NWhat do we do?
等火车\NWait for the train.
能载我一程吗？\NKonnen Sie mich mitnehmen?
很乐意 上车吧！\NAber gerne. Steigen Sie ein.
谢谢！\NDanke schon!
有情况\NTallyho.
- 为公司出差？- 对（德语）\N- Sie reisen fur eine Firma?  - Ja.
我的…\NFur mein...
我的公司\NFur eine Geschaft.
- 谢谢  - 谢谢\N- Danke.  - Danke.
警察在火车上吗？\NAre the police on the train?
还有盖世太保 我们跳车\NThe Gestapo are with them. Let's jump.
好\NAll right.
我告诉你何时跳\NI'll tell you when.
我宁愿你猛推我一把\NI'd prefer you just to give me a firm push.
- 你没事吧？- 我没事\N- Are you all right? - Yes, I'm fine.
真刺激\NThat's quite exciting.
火车没有停下来\NIt isn't stopping.
没有 我们没被看到\NNo, we're all right.
瑞士\NSwitzerland.
嘿！\NHey!
你要去哪儿？到这儿来（德语）\NWo willst du hin? Komm mal her.
你要去哪儿？出示你的证件\NWo willst du hin? Zelg mal deinen Ausweis.
巴特利\NBartlett.
所有人趴在地上！（德语）\NAlles auf den Boden.
卡文迪斯 你要去哪里？\NWhere were you going, Cavendish?
我…我还没决定\NI... I hadn't quite decided.
你在路上搜集什么资料？\NWhat information were you to collect on the way?
没有\NNone.
你收到什么破坏指令？\NWhat sabotage directions did you receive?
你利用文件做了什么事？\NWhat have you done with your papers?
什么文件？\NPapers?
伪造的文件和身份证\NForged papers and identity cards.
不要装傻\NDon't be so stupid.
你利用文件做什么？\NWhat did you do with them?
我只是从战俘营逃出来\NAll I did was escape from a prison camp.
如果你被关了三年 你也会逃的\NYou'd do the same if you'd been locked up for three years.
我想回家\NI wanted to get home.
你无法与妻儿重聚\NI don't think you'll see your wife again.
你们抓错人了 我还没结婚\NYou've got the wrong man. I'm not even married.
你穿的是平民服装\NYou're wearing civilian clothes.
你是间谋\NYou're a spy.
间谋应该被枪毙\NSpies are being shot.
这是我的军服\NThis is my uniform.
我瘦了 所以改小\NI had to recut it when I lost weight.
我用鞋油染色来遮住我被击落时沾到的油污\NI dyed it with boot polish to cover some oil smears I picked up when I was shot down.
你的军阶符号也磨掉了？\NAnd you lost your insignia over the years?
对\NThat's right.
把他交给别人（德语）\NBringen Sie ihn zu den anderen.
- 听我说… - 卡文迪斯 没别的事了\N- Look... - That's all, Cavendish.
弟兄们\NHello, boys.
哈罗 大卫\NHello.
哈罗 海因斯\NHello, Haynes.
哈罗 卡文迪斯\NHello, Cavendish.
我但愿能说很高兴看见你\NI wish I could say I was happy to see you again.
刚被抓到？\NJust picked up?
今天早上\NYes, this morning.
那里有一架我会开的教练机\NThere's a trainer out there I can fly.
- 有卫兵吗？- 有 这是个问题\N- Any sentries? - Yeah, it's gonna be a problem.
柯林\NColin
我说"转"时 就顺时钟方向转这个\Nwhen I say go, crank this clockwise.
发动机起动后 不要动\NWhen the engine catches, don't move
否则你就会撞上螺旋桨\Nor you'll get a mouth full of propeller.
转！\NGo!
下一站 就是端士！\NNext stop, Switzerland!
阿尔卑斯山\NThe Alps.
太好了\NSplendid.
过了这座山 再飞20分钟\NOver this range, then 20 more minutes
我们就成功了\Nand we've got it made.
什么问题？没汽油吗？\NWhat is it? Petrol?
我不知道 有油但是没动力\NI don't know. We're losing power.
往那边走！我会跟上来\NGo that way! I'll follow.
韩德利\NHendley?
柯林！\NColin!
不要！不要开枪！\NStop! Don't shoot! Please!
柯林…\NColin
对不起 我弄砸了\NI'm sorry I fouled things up.
没关系\NThat's all right.
谢谢你…\NThank you for...
带我…\Ngetting me...
出来\Nout.
快点 起来！（德语）\NLos aufstehen.
举起手来\NHande hoch.
先生们 你们好 一切顺利吗？\NBonjour, messieurs. Comment ca va? Ca va bien?
你好\NBonjour
象往常一样 三杯波诺德？\NComme d'hadbitude, trois Pernod. n'est-ce pas?
老爹 三杯波诺德\NTrois Pernod, Papa.
这里是苏珊酒馆\NCafe Suzette.
对\NOui.
- 先生们 三杯波诺德  - 谢谢\N- Et voila, messieurs,les trois Pernod - Merci.
两杯…\NDexu...
三杯 这是水\NEt trois, Et voila de l'eau.
- 祝你们喝好  - 谢谢\N- Bon appetit, messieurs. - Merci.
嗯…先生 您的电话\NMonsieur. Telephone pour vous.
- 我的电话？- 是的 先生 电话\N- Telephone pour moi? - Oui, Monsieur, Telephone.
这边\NPar ici.
电话 那边\NVoila, Telephone.
谢谢！\NMerci!
喂？\NHello?
敬反抗军\NResistance.
反抗军？\NResistance?
你是英格兰人？\NYou are English?
我是澳大利亚人\NI'm Australian.
你可以说英语\NYou can speak English.
- 我听得懂  - 好极了\N- I understand. - Bloody good.
我是英军军官\NI'm a British officer.
刚从德国的战俘营逃出来\NI've just escaped from a prisoner-of-war camp in Germany.
我正在试图前往西班牙\NI'm trying to make my way into Spain.
你明白吗？\NYou understand me?
你能帮我吗？\NCan you help me?
- 我知道有人能帮你  - 好极了\N- I know someone who can. - Bloody good.
盖世太保 请出示你们的证件\NGeheime Staatspolizei. Ihren Ausweis, bitte.
- 啊 法国人？- 是 先生\N- Ah, Francais? - Jawohl.
- 是商人吗？- 对 先生 你会说法语吗？\N- Commercant?  - Mais oui. Parlez-vous Francais?
- 哦 一点儿  - 你说的不错\N- Un, peu. - Votre accent est tres bon.
我以前曾经学过一点儿\NJe l'ai etudie dans l'ecole superieure.
很好 走吧\NTres bien. Passez.
再见 先生 再见\NAu revoir, monsieur.  Au revoir
祝好运\NGood luck.
谢谢你\NThank you.
站住！\NHalt!
两个英国人！\Nzwei vom Lager sind geturmt. Englander!
快追！\NLos!
全部上车！\NAlles einsteigne!
上车\NEinsteigne.
站住！站住！\NHalt! Halt!
等等！举起手来！\NStehen bleiben!  Hande hoch!
- 怎么了？- 你是英国人？\N- Was soll das?  - You are Enghlish?
英国人？\NEnglander?
所以你们用枪指着我？\NSie drohen mir mit einer Pistole?
- 把枪收起来  - 哦 你是德国人？\N- Nehmen Sie die weg.  - Ach, Sie sind Deutscher?
- 当然  - 好吧 抱歉\N- Selbstverstandlich. - Schon gut, Entschuldigung.
巴特利先生？\NHerr Bartlett?
我叫弗洛里克\NIch heiBe Frolich.
你的德语很好\NYour German is good.
听说你的法语也不错\NAnd I hear also your French.
举起…手来！\NYour arms... up!
好极了！\NAusgezeichnet!
巴特利先生…\NHerr Bartlett.
还有麦唐纳先生\NAnd Herr MacDonald.
我们又见面了\NWe are together again.
你会后悔给我们找这么多麻烦\NYou are going to wish you had never put us to so much trouble.
罗杰 烦恼什么？\NWhat's troubling you, Roger?
我只是有一点意外\NI'm just a little surprised.
我认为要不是审问很久\NI expected either a long stay
- 就是很短的旅程  - 原来如此\N- or a very short trip. - Yes.
我必须承认有一点担忧\NI have to admit, I'm a little worried, though.
我祈求上帝 我没有害了七十多个人\NI hope to God I haven't blotted 70-odd ledgers.
别担心\NAch, no, no.
我们全都已经成年 行动自由而且无牵无挂\NWe're all over 21, footloose and fancy-free.
要是没有你 我们不可能逃这么远\NWe'd never have got as far as we did without you, Roger.
我认为你表现出色\NFor what it's worth, I think you did a damn good job.
我们都表现非常出色\NI think we all do.
对啊\NYes.
你们现在可以下车 舒展筋骨五分钟\NAll right. You can get out now. Stretch your legs for five minutes.
还要好几小时才抵达战俘营\NIt will take hours before you reach the camp.
你知道 麦克 这一切…\NYou know, Mac, all this...
逃亡组织、地道、汤姆与哈利\Nthe organization, tunneling, Tom and Harry
让我活得有意义\Nkept me alive.
虽然我们…\NAnd even though we...
但是我从来没这么高兴过\NI've never been happier.
麦克…\NYou know, Mac...
11位你的部下今天被送回来\N11 of your men are being returned today.
是哪些人？\NOh, who?
我没有相关的资料\NI do not have that information.
我…\NI...
上级让我通知你…\NI am directed by a higher authority to inform you that...
你麾下的50位军官 在脱逃时遭到枪击\N50 of your officers were shot while escaping.
枪击？\NShot?
他们的…\NTheir...
个人物品会送回这里\Npersonal effects will be returned.
其中有多少人受伤？\NHow many of them were wounded?
这张名单是…\NHere are the names...
死者\Nof the dead.
50人中有多少人受伤？\NHow many of the 50 were wounded?
半个也没有\NNone.
上级他们…\NThey, the higher authority...
只让我通知你…\Nonly directs me to inform you that...
50人被…\Nthat 50 men were...
我明白了\NI see.
约翰·艾迪生\NAddison John.
彼德·艾拉岱尔\NAlladale Peter.
爱德华·班克罗夫特\NBancroft Edward.
罗杰·巴特利\NBartlett Roger.
丹尼斯·卡文迪斯\NCavendish Dennis.
大卫·艾德利\NEldridge David.
威廉·费尔顿\NFelton William.
亚瑟·方萧\NFanshaw Arthur.
- 在这儿吗？- 对 先生 在这儿\N- Ici? - Oui, Monsieur. C'est ici.
那么 再见\NAlors, au revoir.
- 谢谢你 先生  - 不用谢 再见\N- Merci beaucoup  Monsieur. - Pas de quoi, Au revoir.
- 再见  - 祝好运！\N- Au revoir. - Bonne chance!
先生 我是你的向导\NI am your guide, senor.
去西班牙？\NSpain?
西班牙\NSpain
- 真高兴看到你们都平安  - 长官 谢谢你\N- Glad to see you're all safe. - Thank you, sir.
多少人被抓回来？\NHow many have been brought back?
你们是第一批\NYou're the first.
- 你知道多少人逃成了吗？- 还不知道\N- Do you know how many got away? - Not yet.
布莱斯呢？\NWhat happened to Blythe?
长官 他没成功\NHe didn't make it, sir.
罗杰说的对\NRoger was right about that.
恐怕罗杰也没成功\NI'm afraid Roger didn't make it, either.
我刚贴出名单 他们枪杀…50人\NI've just posted the list. They shot... 50.
盖世太保谋杀了他们\NThe Gestapo murdered them.
50人？\N50?
麦唐纳 艾希利·皮特？\NMacDonald, Ashley-Pitt?
死了\NYes.
丹尼和威利？\NDanny and Willie?
没有 他们不在名单上\NNo, they're not on the list.
- 海因斯？- 死了\N- Haynes? - Yes.
我很难过\NI'm sorry.
罗杰的构想是尽可能还击敌人\NRoger's idea was to get back at the enemy the hardest way he could.
扰乱敌人的运作\NMess up the works.
从我们听到的消息 我认为他完全做到了\NFrom what we've heard here, I think he did exactly that.
你认为值得吗？\NDo you think it was worth the price?
那要看你的观点而定\NThat depends on your point of view, Hendley.
是的 长官\NYes, sir.
敬礼！\NAchtung!
不要向他敬礼\NHe is not to be saluted.
他已经不是指挥官了\NHe's no longer in command.
工作不顺利 是吗？\NThe job just didn't work out, huh?
希尔兹 你很幸运\NYou were lucky, Hilts.
幸运？因为我没有…\NLucky? Because I didn't...
多少人？\NHow many?
50人\N50.
看起来好像 你会比我先看见柏林\NIt looks, after all, as if you will see Berlin before I do.
长官\NSir.
希尔兹 接着！\NHey, Hilts!
本片献给丧生的五十人 。
{\fad(800,1000)\blur2\fs37\bord1\shad8\fsp12\pos(275,150)\fscx95\fscy105\4c&H010300&}剧终