The Terrorizers
It's almost daybreak!
I'll be done soon
Did I bother you?
Take this to the wash
It's gotten warm
What's wrong? Can't sleep again?
Thinking of the other rewrite
The closer the deadline
the less inspired I get
Another rewrite?
I've never seen you this distressed
Relax
Writing a novel
shouldn't be this life-consuming
Thought it was a small gambling den
But they are armed with guns
How many pieces they've got?
Not sure.
Should've called the Assault squad
I did. Should be here soon
Who blew the whistle?
It was the landlord
Freeze!
Spread'em out!
Don't move!
It happened on the first day of spring
If you truly feel for the seasons
you'll discover that changes are
merely endless rebirths of the past
This spring, it is no different
To this married couple
their most serious problem was...
Chief died of a stroke last night!
We heard
We were just talking about it
Everyone is shocked!
Well, I sort of suspected
something would come up
But I didn't expect it
to be a stroke though
Didrt you notice
he acted kind of weird lately?
His life was so boring
small incidents
would turn into big troubles for him
I heard he had an affair
with another woman
and his wife found out
It's all hearsay though
Well, I doubt it
You can never tell
He really smoked too much
A can'ton only lasted him 2 or 3 days
What I'm concerned about is his family
like his childrers educational funds,
the funeral, etc...
Well, I feel the late Chief
had made great contributions
to the hospital
and I feel from now on...
We do have our policies
regarding all these
We'll make all the arrangements
accordingly
Yes, yes. I see...
By the way, who has seniority
between you and Jing?
Well, we started at the same time
We graduated the same year
from the same school
We were employed together
by the hospital
I was like him no family connections
totally on our own.
I like my job. It's stable...
I had an offer elsewhere
with much higher pay...
But I felt it was less secure,
so I turned it down
I'm used to this job
and I deeply believe if I work hard
I'll be rewarded
with career advancements
Sir, are you saying that...
Oh, nothing, I just wondering
Anything else?
No, nothing
Thank you, Sir
Sir, there's this one thing...
Since the Chief has passed away
I felt obliged to let you know
about the scandal of cheating
at the last open bidding
The late Chief
shouldn't be held responsible
It was Jing
Why wasrt I informed before?
Jing's my good friend
I shouldn't have said anything
Ridiculous!
One shouldn't protect a friend
when a dead man has to shoulder
the blame to his grave.
That exactly how I feel
I'll look into this right away
Oh... please take care of
the late Chief's workload
You'll be acting Chief for now
Yes... of course
Thank you, sir
Do you need someone
to teach you a lesson?
Why don't you leave?
Just like your father!
And don't come back!
You've changed...
A lot
No. I'm not sure about that
Why don't you come work for me?
Am I qualified?
Qualified or not, I want you
I still remember how good you were
If not you, then who?
That was a long time ago
I haven't worked for years
You've been writing since then?
After 3 years,
this is all I've got to show for it
I know this book
I also know that
I was in one of your short stories
Shen got divorced
He left his old job
and came out on his own
I went to his new office today
He asked me to go work for him
He even said it's really a waste
to have someone like me at home
It might not be a bad idea
It's always nice
to have jobs come to you for a change
I'm about to become Section Chief
What about Jing?
He got himself in trouble
Some big, big trouble
Fucking bitch!
What the...? You're still alive?
You're the only one that got away?
Heard it was the landlord who snitched
Old Y's too much
running tables
without giving the landlord a piece
Didrt even pay rent!
Of course you can't find them
They've all split town
Some have gone down south
Shun? Shurs in the slammer
Old Y's put away for life
Are you looking to hide out?
Come over here then
Crowded places are the best
Let me tell you
the more crowded a place
is the safer it is
Don't you get it, dummy?
It is now 11:31 and 10 seconds
It is now 11:31 and 20 seconds
It is now...
No, you made a mistake!
Well, this is the right address
the girl on the phone said
You need 50 lunches and said
you're filming a movie here
Does it look to you
like we are filming a movie?
Take them away!
Get out of here!
Movies my ass...
Young man, looking for a flat?
Come, I'll let you rent it cheap
No
What do you mean, no?
Then what are you here for?
Checking the meters?
Fuck, ever since the shoot out
no one wanted to rent this flat
Damn
people even started
playing jokes on me
3 fire trucks came last night
said this place is on fire
When will this end, goddamn it!
It's too late
You're the only one that cared
I'm so hurt, so very hurt...
I don't want to live anymore!
I've already taken
a bottle of sleeping pills
I am notjoking, I don't want to live
There's no sense in living
There's no point
Thank you... Good bye
Hello, give me Dick!
Don't give me shit
If you don't get him
I'll break both your legs!
I don't know what to do anymore
You know, at first
I counted on some writing skills
some real-life experiences
whether they happened to me
to my friends
Characters, plots, that I heard about
I jotted them down in my notebook
But it's become so meaningless
to write this way
I feel I've used up of my emotions
My past 30 years
I've used up it all so quickly
Now I only know how to write
about things between man and wife
I can't think of anything else
Because my world
has become smaller and smaller
Do you understand?
I don't know how others see your work
When I read your stories
I want to see you
The you in the past
We become youthful again
These things do not fade with time
I've always had faith in you
What are you thinking about?
Nothing
Does Li Jong know about our past?
You've never mentioned to him
about your past relationships?
He has never asked me
Then he really trusts you
Yes
No, that's not it
What I mean is
That's not trust...
He never seemed to have cared
You've got me all confused.
Your ex-wife, what was she like?
I didn't realize
how hard it was for you
to take my sudden wedding announcement
until I read that story of yours
It gave me a deep sense of guilt
Novels are novels.
Don't take it too seriously
No need to confuse it with reality
I'm going now
Better find someone else
to work for you
Don't waste your time on me
I have nothing to do
with the open bidding
Listen, I've been to Personnel Office
yesterday
The director has told me all about it!
He just told me that...
Keep your mouth shut!
Listen to me
You, be careful!
Shit, I quit!
I'm leaving today
They put me under investigation
They said I cheated
on the last open bidding.
I don't even know the date
when the bidding took place
Now that the Chief's dead
who knows what actually happened?
It must be that punk kid who framed me
Besides you, he's the only one
that knows the details of it
You think so?
Director is holding me responsible
Shit. Just because the chief died.
Doesrt mean he was perfect
I'm not going to be the scapegoat!
What... you're smoking again?
Didrt you quit?
It's OK.
Take it easy.
You can always rewrite it tomorrow
You haven't been drafted yet?
So where have you been hiding?
The whole world's been here
looking for you
Your girlfriend was here
Your old man was asking for you too
Well, not bad, huh?
I told you it was won'th the trip
My stuff is the best in town
I've no money, bill my old man
Come on, your old man told me
he's not going to pay your bills
Hello
He's gone to work. Who's this?
Yes, I'm his wife...
Who are you?
So he's not home.
I have something urgent
to talk to him about
Actually maybe
it's better if I talk to you directly
There's something to be settled
Could we... could we meet?
Name a place, and I'll be there
Hello
Oh... it's you
How come the study is so messy?
Where's Li-Jong?
I haven't seen him for 2 or 3 days
He might have taken leave
Sir, someone's here to see you
You piece of shit
Where have you been hiding?
How long has it been?
My wife hasn't been home for 3 days
Have you asked her friends?
I don't want people to know
Not even her family
What can I do?
Unless it's a kidnapping
or something how can I be of help?
Has there been anything
unusual about her recently?
For instance...
Besides being unappy with her writing
Nothing really unusual
Editor's not in until 6 or 7
There's no one at the newspaper
Speaking
It was the editor
He said he talked to her
Said she may be somewhere
finishing her novel,
maybe she needs quiet to concentrate
I feel much better now
She'll be back in a few days
A while back, she wanted a child
It didn't work out.
She was quite depressed
and started writing all day
I went along with it
Lately, she seems
to have grown a bit restless again
No one believed she'd marry you
I guess it must be my fault
I knew she likes fancy things
And a more comfortable lifestyle
Luckily, I'm about to be promoted
to Section Chief
Maybe it will help the situation
We'll see
Buddy, you need to call more often
Come by only when you need help
What am I to you?
You're home
How come you left without a word
not even a phone number
Did you finish it?
Just at the deadline
What are your chances of winning?
I'm happy enough
just to have finished it
We can clean up this mess finally.
I wouldn't dare touch it
while you werert here
No need to bother.
All I need is a few books
Doesrt it bother you,
looking at this mess?
I'm moving out
I've already found a place
I'm moving out tonight
I need new surroundings
A change of lifestyle
I've already started working
I've given up writing
I'm not the type to begin with
If it was going to be like this
why bother giving up such a good job
to stay home
and write in the first place
What have I done wrong?
I have always gone along
with your decisions
Look at this house
Every bit and piece you chose
Say something!
Talk to me!
What is the matter with you lately?
If you know it was going
to end up like this
why did you bother?
When we got married
you promised to give up writing
Who knows what got into you
First you quit yourjob
then locked yourself into writing
It was driving me up the wall!
I'll tell you I wouldn't even dare
to take one step
inside that study of yours!
You know,
if it wasrt for the baby
This would have happened long ago
I was so sick and tired of my job
I was afraid that
my whole life would pass by like that
You know,
when I locked myself in the study
Thinking up those pretty lines
It was to forget
those painful memories
to forget about the lost baby
If you don't understand by now
You'll never understand!
Every time,
you misunderstand me or blame me
Maybe I wasrt fair to you
but I know what kind of life I need
When we got married
I thought it would be a new start
To try and have a baby
was also a new start
To try writing again
Was yet another new start
Leaving you now
Is also a new start
What good is all this?
Do you understand?
All you know are those routines
Repetitions, day in, day out,
Do you know why I lock myself
in there all day?
It's the only way to hide from it!
Do you understand? You don't!
This is the biggest difference
between you and me
This is why...
Remember that day when
cops were busting up this place?
I saw you leap from the balcony
I called the ambulance for you
Later, when I went to the hospital.
You had already left
So you were the one
Who sent those fire trucks, lunches...
And the young housewife...
Is it really fun to play tricks
on others like this?
Is it really fun
to take pictures of others?
Hey, what I do is serious stuff!
The guy at the physical said
I have perfect eyesight
Once I serve the army,
I'd make top grade marksman
I've a friend who was a loudmouth
Later he became popular singer
I suppose
I'll become a photographer one day
This is a darkroom
How many days have I been here?
I've no idea
Is it day or night out there?
I don't know
I bet it must be daytime.
Want to bet?
You lost
I'll bring your pictures with me
to the army
I'll write you everyday
Stay with me. Wait for me
Going to Kaohsiung?
What are you going to do there?
3,000 dollars
Take it or leave it
3,000 dollars, take it or leave it?
It's plenty for you
to spend in Kaohsiung
You want to play tough?
If you play tough, it's 2,000!
If you play tough, it's 2,000
Say something!
Don'tjust stare!
Don't try to play tough.
Big Shun is now locked up!
Say something. Don't forget,
Big Shun is now...
I heard Shun got out ofjail
Young master, you've come back
I'm broke. Where else can I go?
This came a few days ago
[Draft Notice]
I've heard you're having troubles
at home lately. Is that true?
No, it was nothing...
Really?
I also heard your wife left you.
Is that true?
No,
she needs a lot of peace and quiet
She needs concentration for her work
She's a writer, you know. Novels...
What does she usually write about?
I'm not sure
I never read novels
Hello?
The editor was just on the phone
said the Writer's Award
has been announced.
I've won First Prize
Gee, does this mean
you'll switch professions again?
First I thought for me
to become a good novelist
was impossible
I was almost going to give up
The story is about an ordinary couple
then there is a crank call
The wife only hears
the voice of this woman
without being able
to see her in person
I was trying hard to explore
some new approach
I guess I was influenced
by Japanese suspense literature
Try to write in a honest and sincere way...
I've seen this face before,
I know I have!
Oh, her!
She won First Prize with this novel.
Not bad.
So... she's a writer
"Notes from a Marriage"
What's it about?
It's about a couple
they have some problems
not that happy together
Then the wife gets a call
from the husband's mistress...
It gets painful...
Everything changes...
The husband can't figure out
what happened...
He's under a lot of pressure
goes nuts and murders his wife
before killing himself
Ends everyone's torture
One member of the jury said
The story is so real
and suspenseful
that it sends chills up your spine
It was completely unexpected
So... now...
Do you think you'll move home?
I just can't figure this out
We now both are doing well
in our careers.
Why is...
I've said all I had to say...
and you still don't understand
Let's not waste
each other's time anymore
I don't mean to hurt you
This you must understand
It's only a novel!
And you're letting it consume you!
It's terrible!
And I'm the only one on earth
that knows what actually happened!
Novels are fiction. They aren't real!
So now you know novels aren't real
So, what do you think you can do?
O. K...
No one's at the newspaper
They don't open till 6 to 7
Still no answer
Let's go
Don't get involved
Hello?
She's not in
Who is this?
Who are you?
Name a place, I'll be there
Are you tied up?
What's up? Excuse me a minute.
Have you been seen these two before?
Sure, I know him well.
They call him Shun in the streets
and this here Eurasian girl
is his woman...
They call her the White Chick
What about them?
Where did you get these?
A young man called up
said we should meet immediately
He said the White Chick had something
to do with my wife leaving me
He said it's all in this novel
Novel? What novel?
This one here Itjust won First Prize
I haven't read it.
No kidding.
Let me finish with the novel first.
You go ahead.
Have a seat.
Do you know where to find
these two then?
Mr. So-and-so... Exports Manager
What is this?
Don't you understand?
She's my sister!
What were you going to do with her?
You better wise up, man!
She's under-aged.
She's only 14!
Go ahead. Call the cops!
You didn't tell me
How would I know?
Things like this don't happen
It's that girl
who played the joke on you
I've even found her for you
Here she is. Look at her!
Long time no see
I'm here to have a talk with her
to discuss a few things
Come in
Wait for me in the conference room
Maybe that phone call
made me suspect you
but that's not the point!
Don't you understand?
Novels are novels.
Can't you tell fiction from reality?
Shut up!
You're coming back with me!
Hey, cool it!
Sorry, I'm late
Got tied up on the way over
The director has just announced
his decision this morning
He picked me
to be the new section chief
The director's not in
I'll page you once he returns, O.K.?
No, I'll just wait for him
He refuses to leave.
He insists to stay and wait
What're we going to do?
When did you get here?
I'm here to let you know
the director made his decision
on who's going to be
the new Section Chief.
He picked me.
From now on,
I'm officially the Section Chief!
That's great! You've been waiting
for this a long time
It calls for a celebration.
Let's go have a drink
Boy, finally you're in a good mood
I was real fortunate.
My superiors appreciated my hard work
especially the director
From now on, I'll work ever harder
For a man, a successful career
is the most important thing
all the rest is meaningless
So my wife left me...
To hell with her. Who gives a shit?
For this, I was real lucky...
Otherwise, wouldn't I be left up
the creek without a paddle?
Less talk... Drink up
Sir, about the wife's boyfriend
he's in stable condition
after emergency surgery
The wife is also at the hospital
She's still in a state of shock
You better cover the hospital
I bet he's bound to show up
Have we met somewhere before?
You think so?
Damn
What's wrong?