[Thunderclaps]
[Horse Whinnying]
[Metal Scraping]
[Swishing Sound]
[Panting]
[Thunderclaps]
- [Gasps]
- [Thunderclaps]
[Horse Snorts]
[Metal Scraping]
[Alarm Bell Ringing] [Man]
HELP HERE! LEND A HAND HERE!
[Ringing] ANYONE!
CONSTABLE CRANE!
ICHABOD CRANE!
IS THAT YOU?
NONE OTHER. NOT ONLY ME.
I HAVE FOUND SOMETHING,
WHICH WAS LATELY A MAN.
- BURN IT.
- YES, SIR.
JUST A MOMENT. WE DO NOT
YET KNOW THE CAUSE OF DEATH.
WHEN YOU FIND THEM IN THE RIVER,
CAUSE OF DEATH IS DROWNING.
POSSIBLY SO, IF THERE IS WATER
IN THE LUNGS. BUT BY PATHOLOGY,
WE MIGHT BE ABLE TO
DETERMINE WHETHER OR NOT
HE WAS DEAD BEFORE HE
WENT INTO THE RIVER.
I WILL NEED TO EXAMINE
THE BODY.
CUT HIM UP.
ARE WE HEATHENS?
WHAT HAPPENED TO HIM?
NOTHING, SIR.
ARRESTED FOR BURGLARY.
[Screaming]
[Trap Door Slams Shut]
GOOD WORK.
[Crane] THE MILLENNIUM
IS ALMOST UPON US.
IN A FEW MONTHS, WE WILL BE
LIVING IN THE 19th CENTURY.
YET OUR COURTS CONTINUE TO RELY
ON MEDIEVAL DEVICES OF TORTURE.
- STAND DOWN!
- I STAND UP FOR SENSE AND JUSTICE.
OUR JAILS OVERFLOW WITH
MEN AND WOMEN CONVICTED
ON CONFESSIONS WORTH
NO MORE THAN THIS ONE.
CONSTABLE CRANE!
THIS IS A SONG WE HAVE HEARD
FROM YOU MORE THAN ONCE.
NOW, THERE ARE TWO COURSES
OPEN TO ME.
FIRST, I CAN LET YOU COOL
YOUR HEELS IN THE CELLS...
UNTIL YOU LEARN RESPECT
FOR THE DIGNITY...
OF MY OFFICE.
I BEG PARDON.
BUT WHY AM I THE ONLY ONE
WHO SEES THAT TO SOLVE CRIMES,
TO DETECT THE GUILTY,
WE MUST USE OUR BRAINS...
TO RECOGNIZE VITAL CLUES...
USING UP-TO-DATE
SCIENTIFIC TECHNIQUES?
WHICH BRINGS ME
TO THE SECOND COURSE.
THERE IS A TOWN UPSTATE, TWO DAYS'
JOURNEY TO THE NORTH...
IN THE HUDSON HIGHLANDS.
IT IS A PLACE CALLED
SLEEPY HOLLOW.
HAVE YOU HEARD OF IT?
I HAVE NOT.
AN ISOLATED FARMING COMMUNITY,
MAINLY DUTCH.
THREE PERSONS HAVE BEEN MURDERED
THERE, ALL WITHIN A FORTNIGHT.
EACH ONE FOUND
WITH THE HEAD...
LOPPED OFF.
LOPPED OFF?
CLEAN AS DANDELION HEADS,
APPARENTLY.
YOU WILL TAKE THESE EXPERIMENTATIONS
OF YOURS TO SLEEPY HOLLOW,
AND THERE YOU WILL DETECT
THE MURDERER.
BRING HIM HERE TO FACE
OUR GOOD JUSTICE.
WILL YOU DO THIS?
I SHALL.
REMEMBER, IT IS YOU,
ICHABOD CRANE,
WHO IS NOW
PUT TO THE TEST.
[Animal Howling]
[Knocking]
[Music]
[Excited Chattering]
THE PICKETY WITCH.
WHO'S GOT A KISS FOR THE PICKETY WITCH?
THE PICKETY WITCH. WHO'S GOT
A KISS FOR THE PICKETY WITCH?
IS IT THEODORE?
YOUR PARDON, MISS.
I'M A STRANGER.
THEN HAVE A KISS
ON ACCOUNT.
I'M LOOKING FOR
BALTUS VAN TASSEL.
I'M HIS DAUGHTER,
KATRINA VAN TASSEL.
AND WHO ARE YOU, FRIEND?
WE HAVE NOT HEARD YOUR NAME YET.
I'VE NOT SAID IT.
EXCUSE ME.
YOU NEED SOME MANNERS.
BROM!
COME, COME.
WE'LL HAVE NO RAISED VOICES.
IT IS ONLY TO RAISE SPIRITS
DURING THIS DARK TIME...
THAT I AND MY DEAR WIFE
ARE GIVING THIS LITTLE PARTY.
YOUNG SIR, YOU ARE MOST WELCOME,
EVEN IF YOU ARE SELLING SOMETHING.
THANK YOU, SIR.
I AM CONSTABLE ICHABOD CRANE
SENT TO YOU FROM NEW YORK...
TO INVESTIGATE MURDER
IN SLEEPY HOLLOW.
THEN SLEEPY HOLLOW IS GRATEFUL
TO YOU, CONSTABLE CRANE.
AND WE HOPE YOU WILL HONOR US
BY REMAINING IN THIS HOUSE.
WELL SPOKE, DEAR.
COME SIR, WE'LL GET YOU SETTLED.
PLAY ON!
[Music Continues]
EXCUSE ME, PLEASE.
THANK YOU.
PLEASE TELL MR. VAN TASSEL
I WILL BE DOWN IN A MOMENT.
I WILL, SIR.
THANK GOD YOU'RE HERE.
[Door Creaking]
AH, EXCELLENT!
COME IN.
LEAVE US, MY DEAR.
WE ARE JOINED BY
DR. THOMAS LANCASTER,
REVEREND STEENWYCK,
OUR ABLE MAGISTRATE
SAMUEL PHILIPSE,
AND LASTLY, THIS FINE FELLOW
IS JAMES HARDENBROOK,
OUR NOTARY.
AND YOU, SIR?
A SIMPLE FARMER
WHO HAS PROSPERED.
THE TOWN LOOKS TO ME
AS FRIEND AND COUNSEL.
AND LANDLORD, AND BANKER.
CAN WE PROCEED?
THANK YOU.
SO...
THREE PERSONS MURDERED.
FIRST, PETER VAN GARRETT...
AND HIS SON,
DIRK VAN GARRETT.
BOTH OF THEM STRONG,
CAPABLE MEN,
FOUND TOGETHER,
DECAPITATED.
ONE WEEK LATER,
THE WIDOW WINSHIP.
ALSO... DECAPITATED.
NOW, I WILL NEED TO ASK YOU
MANY QUESTIONS.
BUT FIRST, LET ME ASK:
IS ANYONE SUSPECTED?
HOW MUCH HAVE YOUR SUPERIORS
EXPLAINED TO YOU, CONSTABLE?
ONLY THAT THE THREE
WERE SLAIN IN OPEN GROUND,
THEIR HEADS FOUND SEVERED
FROM THEIR BODIES. HMM.
THEIR HEADS WERE NOT FOUND SEVERED.
THEIR HEADS WERE NOT FOUND AT ALL.
THE HEADS ARE... GONE?
TAKEN.
TAKEN BY
THE HEADLESS HORSEMAN.
TAKEN BACK TO HELL.
PARDON. I DON'T--
PERHAPS YOU HAD BETTER
SIT DOWN.
YES.
THE HORSEMAN WAS
A HESSIAN MERCENARY...
SENT TO THESE SHORES
BY GERMAN PRINCES...
TO KEEP AMERICANS
UNDER THE YOKE OF ENGLAND.
BUT UNLIKE HIS COMPATRIOTS
WHO CAME FOR MONEY,
THE HORSEMAN CAME
FOR LOVE OF CARNAGE.
WHEN BATTLE WAS JOINED,
THERE YOU'D FIND HIM.
HE RODE A GIANT BLACK STEED
NAMED DAREDEVIL.
AAH! AAH!
HE WAS INFAMOUS FOR RIDING
HIS HORSE HARD INTO BATTLE,
CHOPPING OFF HEADS
AT FULL GALLOP.
HE HAD FILED HIS TEETH
DOWN TO SHARP POINTS...
TO ADD TO THE FEROCITY
OF HIS APPEARANCE.
[Snarling]
[Gunshot]
THIS BUTCHER DIDN'T FINALLY REACH
HIS END UNTIL THE WINTER OF '79,
NOT FAR FROM HERE
IN OUR WESTERN WOODS.
[Gunshot]
[Gunshots Continue]
- SHH.
- [Twig Snaps]
[Panting]
THEY CHOPPED OFF HIS HEAD
WITH HIS OWN SWORD.
EVEN TODAY, THE WESTERN
WOODS IS A HAUNTED PLACE...
WHERE BRAVE MEN
WILL NOT VENTURE.
FOR WHAT WAS PLANTED
IN THE GROUND THAT DAY...
WAS A SEED OF EVIL.
[Whinnying]
AND SO IT HAS BEEN
FOR 20 YEARS.
BUT NOW
THE HESSIAN WAKES.
HE'S ON THE RAMPAGE, CUTTING
OFF HEADS WHERE HE FINDS THEM.
ARE YOU SAYING--
IS THAT WHAT YOU BELIEVE?
SEEING IS BELIEVING.
THEY TELL ME YOU'VE BROUGHT
BOOKS AND TRAPPINGS...
OF SCIENTIFIC
INVESTIGATION.
THIS IS THE ONLY BOOK
I RECOMMEND YOU READ.
[Crane]
I SEE.
REVEREND STEENWYCK.
GENTLEMEN.
MURDER NEEDS NO GHOSTS
TO COME FROM THE GRAVE.
WE HAVE MURDERS IN NEW YORK WITHOUT
BENEFIT OF GHOULS AND GOBLINS.
YOU'RE A LONG WAY
FROM NEW YORK, CONSTABLE.
THE ASSASSIN
IS A MAN OF FLESH AND BLOOD,
AND I WILL DISCOVER HIM.
[Owl Hooting]
[Bleating]
COME OUT, DEVIL.
[Hoofbeats Approaching]
[Gunshot]
[Horse Whinnying]
[Thunderclaps]
[Quacking]
HIS NAME'S GUNPOWDER.
HE SHOULD DO JUST FINE,
MR. KILLIAN. THANK YOU.
GOOD LUCK, SIR. IF YOU
NEED HELP, CALL MY NAME.
MUCH APPRECIATED.
DON'T YOU WORRY
ABOUT A THING.
EVERYTHING'S GOING TO BE
JUST FINE.
THOMAS! INSIDE!
RUN ALONG
FOR YOUR BREAKFAST.
KISS YOUR MOTHER ONCE FOR
YOU AND TWICE FOR ME.
[Gunshot] MURDER! THE HORSEMAN'S
KILLED AGAIN!
ALL RIGHT, GUNPOWDER,
WE'RE OFF.
COME ON.
NO, NO.
COME ON, THE OTHER WAY. NO, NO.
TURN AROUND. HYAH!
GOOD HORSIE.
MR. MILLER,
RIDE BACK FOR THE COFFIN CART.
YES, SIR.
THE REST OF YOU,
KEEP A SHARP LOOKOUT.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
I'M HERE NOW.
THE FOURTH VICTIM,
JONATHAN MASBATH.
I SEE.
AND... THE HEAD?
TAKEN.
INTERESTING.
VERY INTERESTING.
WHAT IS?
IN HEADLESS CORPSE CASES
OF THIS SORT,
THE HEAD IS REMOVED TO PREVENT
IDENTIFICATION OF THE BODY.
BUT WE KNOW THIS WAS
JONATHAN MASBATH.
PRECISELY. SO WHY
WAS THE HEAD REMOVED?
WHY?
RIGHT.
YOU HAVE MOVED THE BODY? I DID.
YOU MUST NEVER MOVE THE BODY!
WHY NOT?
BECAUSE.
THE STRIDE IS GIGANTIC.
THE ATTACKER
RODE MASBATH DOWN,
TURNED HIS HORSE.
CAME BACK. CAME BACK
TO CLAIM THE HEAD.
[Powder Sizzling]
YES. THERE'S
A CHEMICAL REACTION.
IT SHOWS THERE WAS A POWERFUL,
SINGULAR THRUST TO THE NECK.
NOW.
[Gasps]
INTERESTING.
WHAT IS IT?
THE WOUND WAS CAUTERIZED
IN THE VERY INSTANT...
AS THOUGH THE BLADE ITSELF
WERE RED-HOT.
AND YET, NO BLISTERING,
NO SCORCHED FLESH.
THE DEVIL'S FIRE.
[Reverend Steenwyck] "BE VIGILANT,"
AS IT SAYETH IN THE BOOK OF PETER,
CHAPTER 5, VERSE 8.
"BECAUSE YOUR ADVERSARY,
THE DEVIL,
"AS A ROARING LION,
WALKETH ABOUT,
SEEKING WHOM
HE MAY DEVOUR."
GOD REST,
JONATHAN MASBATH.
MR. CONSTABLE, SIR.
AH.
YOU'RE YOUNG MASBATH.
I WAS YOUNG MASBATH,
BUT NOW THE ONLY ONE.
MASBATH, AT YOUR SERVICE.
IN HONOR BOUND
TO AVENGE MY FATHER.
WELL, ONE AND ONLY MASBATH,
I THANK YOU VERY MUCH,
BUT YOUR MOTHER
WILL NEED YOU MORE THAN I.
MY MOTHER
IS IN HEAVEN, SIR.
SHE HAS MY FATHER NOW
TO CARE FOR HER.
BUT YOU HAVE NO ONE TO SERVE YOU.
I AM YOUR MAN, SIR.
YES, AND A BRAVE ONE TOO. BUT I
CANNOT BE THE ONE TO LOOK AFTER YOU.
I'M SORRY FOR YOUR LOSS,
YOUNG MR. MASBATH.
CONSTABLE CRANE.
MR. PHILIPSE.
SOMETHING YOU SHOULD KNOW.
JONATHAN MASBATH WAS NOT THE
FOURTH VICTIM, BUT THE FIFTH.
THE FIFTH?
AYE.
FIVE VICTIMS
IN FOUR GRAVES.
YOUNG MASBATH!
FIND A PLACE IN THE VAN TASSEL'S
SERVANTS' QUARTERS. WAKE ME BEFORE DAWN.
I HOPE YOU HAVE
A STRONG STOMACH.
PETER VAN GARRETT.
DIRK VAN GARRETT.
JONATHAN MASBATH.
FIVE VICTIMS,
FOUR GRAVES.
THE WIDOW WINSHIP.
[Groans]
[Crane]
BRING THE WIDOW IN.
THIS IS MOST IRREGULAR,
CONSTABLE.
I SHOULD HOPE SO,
BUT IN THIS CASE, NECESSARY.
WE NEED TO OPERATE
IMMEDIATELY.
OPERATE?
SHE'S DEAD.
WHEN WE SAY "OPERATE," WE MEAN, OF
COURSE, I WILL NEED THE OPERATING TABLE.
ONCE MORE,
THE NECK WOUND CAUTERIZED.
THE... SWORD THRUST
TO THE STOMACH, THE SAME.
BUT TO WHAT PURPOSE?
TO WHAT IS YOUR
PURPOSE, IS THE QUESTION.
WHAT MANNER OF INSTRUMENTS
ARE THESE?
SOME OF MY OWN DESIGN.
ALL RIGHT, THEN.
STEP OUTSIDE, YOUNG MASBATH.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH
FOR YOUR HELP, MR. KILLIAN.
AND IF YOU DON'T MIND,
DOCTOR.
MY CONCENTRATION SUFFERS
GREATLY WHEN I'M OBSERVED.
[Indistinct Chattering]
I AM FINISHED.
WHAT, IN THE NAME OF GOD,
HAVE YOU DONE TO HER?
WE ARE DEALING
WITH A MADMAN.
WHAT DID YOU FIND OUT?
THE WIDOW WINSHIP
WAS WITH CHILD.
[Owl Hooting]
[Hooves Clopping,
Horse Snorting]
[Frogs Croaking "Ichabod"]
[Croaking Continues]
[Horse Whinnying]
[Hooves Clopping]
WHO'S THERE?
[Whinnying]
[Laughing]
[Laughing Continues]
[Woman's Voice]
ICHABOD
[Thunderclaps]
[Gasps]
OH.
PARDON MY INTRUSION.
I SAW A LIGHT.
IT IS NO INTRUSION.
I COME HERE TO READ
WHEN I AM WAKEFUL.
- TO READ BOOKS WHICH YOU MUST HIDE?
- THEY WERE MY MOTHER'S BOOKS.
MY FATHER BELIEVES
TALES OF ROMANCE CAUSE
THE BRAIN FEVER THAT
KILLED MY MOTHER.
SHE DIED TWO YEARS AGO
COME MIDWINTER.
THE NURSE WHO CARED FOR HER DURING
HER SICKNESS IS NOW LADY VAN TASSEL.
THERE WAS SOMETHING ELSE
TOO.
WHY DID NO ONE THINK TO MENTION THAT THE
VAN GARRETTS ARE KIN TO THE VAN TASSELS?
BECAUSE THERE IS HARDLY
A HOUSEHOLD IN SLEEPY HOLLOW...
THAT IS NOT CONNECTED TO EVERY
OTHER BY BLOOD OR MARRIAGE.
I SEE.
THIS LAND WE'RE LOOKING AT
WAS VAN GARRETT LAND,
GIVEN TO MY FATHER
WHEN I WAS IN SWADDLING CLOTHES.
THE VAN GARRETTS WERE THE RICHEST
FAMILY AROUND THESE PARTS.
WHEN MY FATHER BROUGHT US
TO SLEEPY HOLLOW,
VAN GARRETT SET HIM UP WITH AN
ACRE AND A BROKEN-DOWN COTTAGE.
MY FATHER WORKED HARD FOR HIS FAMILY,
AND PROSPERED AND BUILT THIS HOUSE.
I OWE MY HAPPINESS
TO HIM.
I REMEMBER LIVING POOR
IN THE COTTAGE.
- SHOULD I SHOW YOU?
- YES.
TAKE THIS.
IT IS MY GIFT FOR YOU.
NO, I HAVE NO USE
FOR IT.
ARE YOU SO CERTAIN
OF EVERYTHING?
IT WAS YOUR MOTHER'S.
KEEP IT CLOSE TO YOUR HEART. IT
IS SURE PROTECTION AGAINST HARM.
ARE YOU SO CERTAIN
OF EVERYTHING?
THESE ARE STRANGE, THESE MARKINGS.
WHAT ARE THEY?
I'VE HAD THEM
SINCE I CAN REMEMBER.
I USED TO PLAY BY THIS
HEARTH AS A CHILD.
IT WAS MY FIRST DRAWING SCHOOL,
AND MY MOTHER WAS MY TEACHER.
LOOK.
SEE?
CARVED INTO THE FIREBACK?
THE ARCHER.
I'D FORGOTTEN IT.
THIS WAS FROM LONG BEFORE
WE LIVED HERE.
- ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
- YES, THANK YOU.
[Bird Chirping]
A CARDINAL.
MY FAVORITE.
I'D LOVE TO HAVE A TAME ONE, BUT I
WOULDN'T HAVE THE HEART TO CAGE HIM.
WELL, THEN, I...
HAVE SOMETHING FOR YOU.
CARDINAL ON ONE SIDE.
AN EMPTY CAGE.
AND NOW--
YOU CAN DO MAGIC.
TEACH ME.
IT IS NO MAGIC.
IT IS WHAT WE CALL OPTICS.
SEPARATE PICTURES WHICH
BECOME ONE IN THE SPINNING.
IT IS TRUTH, BUT TRUTH
IS NOT ALWAYS APPEARANCE.
[Inaudible Arguing]
WHAT ARE YOU RUNNING FROM,
MAGISTRATE PHILIPSE?
DAMN YOU, CRANE! YOU
HAD A MIND TO HELP ME?
YES, AND IT'S PUT ME IN
MORTAL DREAD OF-- OF WHAT?
OF POWERS AGAINST WHICH
THERE IS NO DEFENSE. COME.
HOW DID YOU KNOW THE WIDOW
WINSHIP WAS EXPECTING A CHILD?
SHE TOLD ME. THEN I DEDUCE
YOU ARE THE FATHER.
I'M NOT THE FATHER.
DID SHE TELL YOU THE NAME
OF THE CHILD'S FATHER?
YES, SHE DID.
SHE CAME TO ME...
FOR ADVICE AS TOWN MAGISTRATE TO
PROTECT THE RIGHTS OF HER CHILD.
I WAS BOUND BY MY OATH OF OFFICE
TO KEEP THE SECRET, BUT--
- DO YOU BELIEVE THE FATHER KILLED HER?
- THE HORSEMAN KILLED HER.
HOW OFTEN DO I HAVE TO TELL YOU
THERE IS NO HORSEMAN.
[Thunderclaps] NEVER WAS A HORSEMAN,
AND NEVER WILL BE A HORSEMAN.
WHAT IS THAT THING?
MY TALISMAN. IT PROTECTS
ME FROM THE HORSEMAN.
YOU, A MAGISTRATE AND YOUR
HEAD FULL OF SUCH NONSENSE.
TELL ME THE NAME OF--
[Sheep Bleating]
[Bleating]
[Thunderclaps]
[Squeaking]
[Owl Hooting]
[Horse Whinnying]
OH, MY GOD!
[Knocking]
CONSTABLE CRANE?
HAS HE NOT COME OUT
AT ALL?
IT WAS A HEADLESS HORSEMAN.
YOU MUST NOT EXCITE YOURSELF.
-BUT IT WAS A HEADLESS HORSEMAN.
-OF COURSE IT WAS.
THAT'S WHY YOU'RE HERE.
NO, YOU MUST BELIEVE ME. IT WAS A
HORSEMAN, A DEAD ONE. HEADLESS!
-I KNOW. -YOU DON'T KNOW BECAUSE
YOU WERE NOT THERE! IT'S ALL TRUE.
OF COURSE IT IS. I TOLD YOU.
EVERYONE TOLD YOU.
I... SAW HIM.
I SUPPOSE IT'S BACK
TO THE CITY, THEN.
[Door Creaking]
[Gasps]
ALL RIGHT, THIS TIME
I'LL GET TO NEW YORK MYSELF.
I WON'T BE FOBBED OFF
WITH AN AMATEUR DEDUCTOR.
THIS TIME, IT'S
A MAGISTRATE THAT'S DEAD--
GENTLEMEN, I NEED ABLE MEN TO GO
WITH ME INTO THE WESTERN WOODS.
YOU? WE THOUGHT
YOU'D SHOT YOUR BOLT.
I HAVE FACED MY
FEARS, AND COME OUT
DETERMINED TO LOCATE
THE HORSEMAN'S GRAVE.
IN SHORT, TO PIT MYSELF
AGAINST A MURDERING GHOST.
WHO'S WITH ME?
ME.
THE VAN GARRETTS.
WIDOW WINSHIP.
YOUR FATHER
JONATHAN MASBATH.
AND NOW PHILIPSE.
SOMETHING MUST CONNECT THEM.
DID YOUR FATHER HAVE DEALINGS
WITH THE VAN GARRETTS?
HE WORKED FOR THEM.
WE LIVED IN THE COACH HOUSE.
IT'S NOTHING.
BUT THERE WAS SOMETHING THAT HAPPENED
ONE NIGHT A WEEK BEFORE THE MURDER.
AN ARGUMENT UPSTAIRS
BETWEEN FATHER AND SON.
AND MY FATHER WAS LATER SENT
FOR BY MR. VAN GARRETT.
AN ARGUMENT BETWEEN
FATHER AND SON.
AFTER WHICH THE ELDER VAN GARRETT
SENT FOR HIS SERVANT MASBATH.
- LISTEN.
- I HEAR NOTHING.
NOR I.
NO BIRDS.
NO CRICKETS.
IT'S ALL GONE SO QUIET.
QUICKEN PACE.
[Door Creaking]
PARDON OUR INTRUSION.
BUT PERHAPS YOU COULD HELP US.
YOU'RE FROM THE HOLLOW.
YES, IN A WAY.
I SHOULD LIKE TO SAY, I MAKE NO
ASSUMPTIONS ABOUT YOUR OCCUPATION.
NOR YOUR WAYS,
WHICH, WHICH--
WHICH ARE NOTHING TO ME,
WHATEVER YOU ARE.
EACH TO HIS OWN.
OH.
DO YOU KNOW
OF THE HORSEMAN, MA'AM?
THE HESSIAN?
[Makes Slicing Sound]
THAT'LL BE HIM, MA'AM.
YOU, COME WITH ME.
GO OUT CHILD.
KEEP AWAY.
WHATEVER YOU HEAR,
WHAT MIGHT HE HEAR
THAT HE MUST KEEP AWAY FROM?
HE RIDES...
TO THE HOLLOW AND BACK.
I HEAR HIM,
I SMELL THE BLOOD ON HIM.
DO YOU?
WELL,
I'M HERE TO FIND HIM
AND MAKE HIM STOP.
[Bat Chirping]
YOU SEEK KNOWLEDGE OF THE NETHERWORLD?
I CAN SHOW YOU.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- [Sniffing] DON'T MOVE OR SPEAK.
- WHEN THE OTHER COMES, I WILL HOLD HIM.
- THE OTHER?
SILENCE. [Sniffing] HE COMES NOW.
MADAM?
MADAM, DO YOU HEAR ME?
[Growling]
YOU SEEK THE WARRIOR BATHED IN BLOOD.
THE HEADLESS HORSEMAN.
FOLLOW THE INDIAN TRAIL
TO WHERE THE SUN DIES.
FOLLOW IT TO
THE TREE OF THE DEAD.
CLIMB DOWN TO
THE HORSEMAN'S RESTING PLACE.
WE'RE LEAVING.
WHAT HAPPENED?
WE'RE LEAVING NOW.
WE TAKE THE INDIAN TRAIL
TO THE TREE OF THE DEAD.
HOW WILL WE RECOGNIZE IT? WITHOUT
DIFFICULTY, I RATHER FEAR.
THEN CLIMB DOWN TO THE
HORSEMAN'S RESTING PLACE.
HIS CAMP?
HIS GRAVE.
STAY HERE.
HALT AND TURN.
I HAVE A PISTOL AIMED.
KATRINA.
I MIGHT HAVE KILLED YOU.
WHY HAVE YOU COME?
BECAUSE NO ONE ELSE
WOULD GO WITH YOU.
I AM NOW TWICE THE MAN.
IT IS YOUR WHITE MAGIC.
PARDON MY INTRUSION.
I THINK YOU'D BETTER COME
AND LOOK AT THIS.
THE TREE OF THE DEAD.
BLOOD.
STAY WHERE YOU ARE.
- WHAT IS IT?
- JUST STAY WHERE YOU ARE. DON'T MOVE.
THIS TREE IS A GATEWAY.
A GATEWAY
BETWEEN TWO WORLDS.
THIS GROUND HAS BEEN DISTURBED.
THE SOIL IS LOOSE!
BRING THE SHOVEL.
THE SKULL IS GONE.
TAKEN.
THAT IS WHY THE HORSEMAN
RETURNS FROM THE GRAVE.
TO TAKE HEADS TILL HIS OWN
IS RESTORED TO HIM.
[Thunderclaps]
ICHABOD?
[Whinnies]
[Whinnying]
HYAH! HYAH!
[Thunderclaps]
[Horse Whinnies]
SPLIT UP.
GLENN. THEODORE.
DON'T PICK YOUR TEETH.
YOU'LL TEACH THOMAS BAD HABITS.
I AM A BAD HABIT.
THERE'S NOTHING FOR IT.
OH, ISN'T THERE?
[Chuckles]
[Wind Howling]
COME ON, LET'S GET READY
FOR BED. YES.
[Thunderclaps]
BETH, RUN!
STAY QUIET.
[Panting, Gasps]
[Door Opens]
[Beth Gasps]
[Sword Slashes]
[Thunderclaps]
[Thomas Screams]
[Screaming]
[Whinnying]
WAIT! HE'S NOT AFTER YOU.
I'LL GET HIM!
WE CANNOT WIN THIS.
[Loud Footsteps]
[Footsteps Continue]
AAH!
[Thunderclaps]
REMARKABLE. A WOUND LIKE
THIS SHOULD'VE KILLED HIM.
BUT IT NEEDS NO STITCH, AND THERE'S
HARDLY A LOSS OF BLOOD. [Gasps]
YOU MUST BE STILL.
THE FEVER IS ON YOU.
KATRINA.
NOSTRADAMUS, MEDIAMUS,
MILK OF MERCY,
IN MEDIA NOS LAUDAMAS.
KATRINA, I TRIED
TO STOP BROM, BUT--
SHH. DRINK THIS DOWN.
IT'LL MAKE YOU SLEEP.
THE HORSEMAN WAS NOT SET
TO KILL BROM OR ME.
HAD BROM NOT ATTACKED HIM--
LATER.
REST NOW.
I'VE DISCOVERED SOMETHING. THE
HORSEMAN DOES NOT KILL AT RANDOM.
HIS VICTIMS ARE CHOSEN BY
SOMEONE WHO CONTROLS HIM.
BY THAT VERY PERSON
WHO TOOK HIS SKULL.
SOMEONE WHO KNEW WHERE
TO DIG.
SOMEONE OF FLESH AND BLOOD,
AS I'VE ALWAYS SAID.
- THESE ARE RAVINGS.
- SHH. DRINK.
[Lady Crane's Voice]
ICHABOD.
[Gasps]
SHH.
YOU WERE DREAMING.
YES.
THINGS I HAD FORGOTTEN.
- AND WOULD NOT LIKE TO REMEMBER.
- TELL ME WHAT YOU DREAMT.
MY MOTHER WAS AN INNOCENT.
A CHILD OF NATURE.
CONDEMNED.
MURDERED...
BY MY FATHER.
MURDERED BY--
MURDERED TO SAVE HER SOUL...
BY A BIBLE-BLACK TYRANT
BEHIND A MASK OF RIGHTEOUSNESS.
I WAS SEVEN...
WHEN I LOST MY FAITH.
WHAT DO YOU BELIEVE IN?
SENSE AND REASON.
CAUSE AND CONSEQUENCE.
I SHOULD NOT HAVE COME
TO THIS PLACE...
WHERE MY RATIONAL MIND HAS BEEN SO
CONTROVERTED BY THE SPIRIT WORLD.
WILL YOU TAKE NOTHING FROM SLEEPY
HOLLOW THAT WAS WORTH THE COMING HERE?
NO.
NO, NOT NOTHING.
A KISS FROM
A LOVELY YOUNG WOMAN...
BEFORE SHE SAW MY FACE
OR KNEW MY NAME.
YES, WITHOUT SENSE
OR REASON.
FORGIVE ME,
I SPEAK OF KISSES...
AND YOU HAVE LOST
YOUR BRAVE MAN, BROM.
I HAVE SHED MY TEARS
FOR BROM.
AND YET MY HEART
IS NOT BROKEN.
DO YOU THINK ME WICKED?
NO.
PERHAPS THERE IS A BIT
OF A WITCH IN YOU, KATRINA.
WHY DO YOU SAY THAT?
BECAUSE YOU HAVE BEWITCHED ME.
OH.
YOU SLEPT LIKE THE DEAD.
YOU'RE TOO KIND TO ME.
I DO NOT LOOK TO BE SERVED
BY THE LADY OF THE HOUSE.
NOR WOULD YOU BE, BUT THAT THE
SERVANT GIRL HAS VANISHED.
- SARAH?
- RUN AWAY LIKE SO MANY OTHERS.
THEY'RE ALL LEAVING
IN FEAR.
WHERE IS KATRINA?
SHE WATCHED OVER YOU TILL DAWN.
NOW IT IS HER TURN TO SLEEP.
WELL, I'M FIT FOR ANOTHER DAY,
I THINK.
FIT ENOUGH TO FACE
A MORTAL ADVERSARY.
DR. LANCASTER.
REVEREND STEENWYCK.
HMM.
NOTARY HARDENBROOK.
AND MAGISTRATE PHILIPSE.
WHO TRIED TO CUT AND RUN
AND LOST HIS HEAD.
ALL FRIGHTENED MEN,
ARGUING TOGETHER...
ON THE VERY NIGHT MAGISTRATE
PHILIPSE WAS KILLED.
THERE IS CONSPIRACY HERE.
THE DOCTOR, THE REVEREND,
THE NOTARY AND THE MAGISTRATE.
WHAT IS THIS SECRET
THAT UNITES THEM?
MAGISTRATE PHILIPSE KNEW...
THERE WERE FIVE BODIES
TO FOUR GRAVES.
HE KNEW THE WIDOW
WAS PREGNANT.
HE COULD NOT TELL ME
THE NAME OF THE FATHER.
WHAT DOES THIS POINT TO?
WE MUST PROCEED
BY A PROCESS OF ELIMINATION.
I SHALL MAKE A LIST OF EVERY MAN
AND WOMAN IN SLEEPY HOLLOW...
STARTING WITH ITS CHIEF CITIZEN,
BALTUS VAN TASSEL.
I FEEL WE'RE GETTING
VERY CLOSE.
YES, I SUPPOSE BALTUS
IS THE CHIEF CITIZEN
NOW THAT OLD VAN
GARRETT IS DEAD.
YES, THE VAN GARRETTS.
I'D ALMOST FORGOTTEN THEM.
COME WITH ME.
- WHERE?
- TO NOTARY HARDENBROOK'S.
HAVE YOU THOUGHT OF SOMETHING?
YES.
I HAVE.
HOPELESS.
MY FATHER'S SATCHEL.
WHY IS IT HERE?
[Gasps]
- LEAVE ME ALONE.
- NOTARY HARDENBROOK.
LEAVE ME ALONE!
JUST AS SOON AS YOU
SHOW ME THE LAST WILL
AND TESTAMENT OF OLD
MAN VAN GARRETT.
THE WILL LEAVES EVERYTHING
TO HIS SON.
WHO DIED WITH HIM! SO THE ESTATE
PASSES TO THE NEXT OF KIN.
NATURALLY.
ALL LEGAL AND ABOVE BOARD.
SIR?
I'M A DEAD MAN.
NO, NO.
VAN GARRETT'S SEAL...
BROKEN!
SEEMS VAN GARRETT MADE A NEW
WILL JUST BEFORE HE DIED.
NAMING...
WIDOW WINSHIP?
AND HERE, LOOK.
A MARRIAGE CERTIFICATE.
AHA!
OLD VAN GARRETT
SECRETLY MARRIED THE WIDOW.
LEFT EVERYTHING TO HER
AND HER UNBORN CHILD.
SO THE NEW WILL STOOD BETWEEN
THE VAN GARRETT FORTUNE...
AND THE PERSON WHO WOULD HAVE
OTHERWISE INHERITED EVERYTHING.
IT'S TRUE. BUT WE FOUR WERE
DRAWN IN AGAINST OUR WILL!
- YOUR WILL?
- HE MEANS--
OF COURSE.
THE FOUR TOWN ELDERS.
NOW I SEE WHAT PARTS
YOU HAD TO PLAY.
REVEREND STEENWYCK KNEW THE SECRET
BECAUSE HE PERFORMED THE MARRIAGE.
DR. LANCASTER ATTENDED
THE PREGNANT WOMAN.
MAGISTRATE PHILIPSE
GAVE PROTECTION OF THE LAW.
AND NOTARY HARDENBROOK CONCEALED
THE DOCUMENTS,
WHICH HAD BEEN ENTRUSTED BY VAN
GARRETT TO HIS FAITHFUL SERVANT.
THE FOUR CONSPIRATORS
DRAWN INTO THE PLOT.
WE DID NOT KNOW
IT WAS A MURDERING PLOT.
BUT I HAVE NOT FINISHED,
SIR.
FIRST, THE VAN GARRETTS, FATHER
AND SON, SLAIN BY A HORSEMAN...
RAISED FROM THE GRAVE
TO CHOP HEADS!
NOW, UP POPS A WIDOW WITH
A CLAIM ON THE FORTUNE.
OFF WITH HER HEAD!
BUT MURDER BEGETS MURDER.
IT WAS THE SERVANT,
JONATHAN MASBATH.
THE NIGHT FATHER AND SON
QUARRELLED OVER THE NEW WILL,
JONATHAN MASBATH WAS SUMMONED
UPSTAIRS TO BEAR WITNESS.
HERE IS HIS SIGNATURE. IT WAS HIS
DEATH WARRANT, YOUNG MASBATH.
THE HORSEMAN
CAME FOR HIM.
CAME FOR HIM AT THE BIDDING OF
SOMEONE WHO HAD POWER OVER HIM.
SOMEONE WHO DUG IN THE EARTH IN THE
WESTERN WOODS AND STOLE THE SKULL!
THE MISSING HEAD WHICH
MUST BE RESTORED TO
THE HORSEMAN BEFORE HE
WILL RETURN TO HELL!
SOMEONE WHO STOOD TO GAIN
OR LOSE A FORTUNE.
NONE OTHER THAN VAN GARRETT'S
NEXT OF KIN,
BALTUS VAN TASSEL!
KATRINA?
WHY ARE YOU IN MY ROOM?
BECAUSE IT IS YOURS.
WAS IT WICKED OF ME?
NO, NO, NOT AT ALL.
I MISSED YOU.
WHERE DID YOU GO?
TO THE NOTARY. I HAD QUESTIONS
TO ASK HARDENBROOK.
DID YOU LEARN ANYTHING
OF INTEREST?
PERHAPS.
- MY FATHER--
- YOUR FATHER?
YES. MY FATHER THINKS YOU
SHOULD RETURN TO NEW YORK.
REALLY?
WHY IS THAT?
I DON'T KNOW.
PERHAPS HE LOOKED IN YOUR LEDGER
AND DID NOT LIKE WHAT HE SAW.
- WHAT HAVE YOU THERE?
- EVIDENCE. I'M SORRY, I MUST ASK YOU--
THEN I'LL LEAVE YOU
TO YOUR THOUGHTS.
[Gasps]
- IT'S JUST A SPIDER.
- KILL IT! KILL IT!
NO, NO, STOMP IT!
- THERE'S SOMETHING UNDER HERE.
- WHAT IS IT?
HELP ME MOVE THE BED.
NO, I MUSTN'T. YOU DO IT.
THE EVIL EYE! IT IS SOMEONE
CASTING SPELLS AGAINST YOU.
THE EVIL EYE?
[Thumping Sound]
WAIT HERE.
KATRINA, YOU TOOK THE EVIDENCE
AND BURNED IT.
SO YOU WOULD NOT HAVE IT
TO ACCUSE MY FATHER.
I ACCUSE NO ONE.
BUT IF THERE IS GUILT,
I CANNOT ALTER IT NO MATTER
HOW MUCH IT GRIEVES ME.
AND NO SPELLS OF YOURS
CAN ALTER IT, EITHER.
YOUR FATHER HAS THE MOTIVE. IT IS HE WHO
STANDS TO PROFIT FROM THESE MURDERS.
IF YOU KNEW HIM, YOU WOULD NOT HAVE
SUCH HARSH THOUGHTS ABOUT HIM.
NOR IF YOU FELT ANYTHING
FOR ME.
I AM PINIONED BY A CHAIN
OF REASONING! WHY
ELSE DID HIS FRIENDS
CONSPIRE TO CONCEAL--
YOU ARE THE CONSTABLE, NOT I.
SO FIND
ANOTHER CHAIN OF
REASONING AND LET ME BE.
I CANNOT. NOR THE ONE OR THE OTHER.
AND I AM HEARTSICK WITH IT.
I THINK YOU HAVE NO HEART. AND I
HAD A MIND ONCE TO GIVE YOU MINE.
YES, I THINK YOU LOVED ME
THAT DAY...
WHEN YOU FOLLOWED ME INTO THE WESTERN
WOODS TO HAVE BRAVED SUCH PERIL.
WHAT PERIL WAS THERE IF
IT WAS MY OWN FATHER
WHO CONTROLLED THE
HEADLESS HORSEMAN?
GOOD-BYE, ICHABOD CRANE. I CURSE
THE DAY YOU CAME TO SLEEPY HOLLOW.
[Whinnies]
SHE WILL NOT SEE YOU.
DID SHE SAY ANYTHING?
[Sighs] ONLY THAT SHE
WILL NOT COME DOWN.
I SEE.
THANK YOU.
CONSTABLE?
YOU HAVE NOT ASKED ME HOW I HAVE
HURT MY HAND SINCE YESTERDAY,
WHICH WOULD
HAVE BEEN POLITE.
IN FACT, YOU HAVE
BEEN AS CAREFUL...
NOT TO LOOK AT IT
AS NOT TO MENTION IT.
YES. I'M SORRY.
HOW DID YOU--
I KNOW YOU SAW ME.
WHAT?
I KNOW YOU FOLLOWED
LAST NIGHT,
AND YOU MUST PROMISE NOT TO
TELL MY HUSBAND WHAT YOU SAW.
PROMISE ME!
THE TOWN IS IN FERMENT.
HORROR PILED ON TRAGEDY.
HARDENBROOK IS DEAD.
- OH, NO! THAT HARMLESS OLD MAN?
- HANGED HIMSELF IN THE NIGHT.
HANGED HIMSELF? REVEREND STEENWYCK'S
CALLED A MEETING IN THE CHURCH TONIGHT.
EVERY MAN, WOMAN AND CHILD IS
GOING TO SPEAK OUT AGAINST YOU.
IF YOU ARE WISE,
YOU WILL LEAVE THIS PLACE.
WHAT IS THAT?
I WAS CARELESS
WITH THE KITCHEN KNIFE.
[Baltus]
THE WOUND LOOKS ANGRY.
I WILL BIND IT LATER WITH
WILD ARROWROOT FLOWERS.
I KNOW WHERE SOME GROW.
[Church Bell Ringing]
[Humming]
COME ON, HURRY UP.
THE MEETING BELL
STARTED TOLLING.
[Thunderclaps]
[Bell Ringing]
THE HORSEMAN!
- KATRINA, THE HORSEMAN SAVED ME.
- FATHER?
HE KILLED HER. THE HORSEMAN
KILLED YOUR STEPMOTHER.
[Thunderclaps]
[Horse Whinnying]
OH, GOD!
[Man]
FIRE!
[Whinnying]
[Shouting, Screaming]
YOU'LL KILL US ALL! YOU'RE
THE ONE THE HORSEMAN WANTS.
HE CANNOT ENTER.
THE HORSEMAN CANNOT ENTER.
WHY SHOULD WE DIE FOR YOU?
HE CANNOT CROSS THE GATE.
WE HAVE TO SAVE OURSELVES!
THE NEXT PERSON THAT LAYS A
HAND ON ME WILL GET A BULLET!
HE'S COMING BACK!
[Whinnies]
ENOUGH HAVE DIED ALREADY.
IT'S TIME TO CONFESS OUR SINS.
- WHAT IS IT THAT YOU KNOW?
- YOUR FOUR FRIENDS PLAYED YOU FALSE.
WE WERE DEVILISHLY
POSSESSED BY ONE WHO--
- [Gunshot]
- [Gasps]
GET OUT OF MY WAY!
STAND BACK! STAY BACK!
BACK! STAND BACK!
THERE IS A CONSPIRACY HERE,
AND I WILL SHAKE IT OUT!
[Screams]
IT WAS AN EVIL SPIRIT
POSSESSED YOU.
I PRAY GOD IT IS SATISFIED NOW,
AND THAT YOU FIND PEACE.
THE EVIL EYE'S
DONE ITS WORK.
MY LIFE IS OVER, SPARED FOR A
LIFETIME OF HORRORS IN MY SLEEP,
WAKING EACH DAY TO GRIEF.
GOOD-BYE, KATRINA.
[Hoofbeats]
WHOA.
YOU THINK IT WAS KATRINA,
DON'T YOU?
THAT CAN NEVER BE UTTERED.
A STRANGE SORT OF WITCH, WITH
A KIND AND LOVING HEART.
- HOW CAN YOU THINK SO?
- I HAVE GOOD REASON.
- THEN YOU ARE BEWITCHED BY REASON.
- I AM BEATEN DOWN BY IT!
IT IS A HARD LESSON FOR A HARD
WORLD, AND YOU HAD BETTER LEARN IT.
VILLAINY WEARS MANY MASKS. NONE SO
DANGEROUS AS THE MASK OF VIRTUE.
FAREWELL.
RETURN THE COACH.
TURN AROUND NOW! WHAT?
WHOA.
[Knocking]
PARDON MY INTRUSION.
NO BLOOD FLOW, NO CLOTTING,
NO HEALING.
WHEN THIS CUT WAS MADE,
THIS WOMAN WAS ALREADY DEAD.
DEAR STEPDAUGHTER.
YOU LOOK AS IF
YOU'D SEEN A GHOST.
YAH!
RISE UP ONCE MORE,
MY DARK AVENGER.
ONE MORE NIGHT OF BEHEADING.
RISE UP
WITH YOUR SWORD.
A HEAD... FOR A HEAD.
MY UNHOLY HORSEMAN, RISE!
[Lady Van Tassel] COME NOW FOR...
KATRINA!
[Whinnying]
AWAKE AT LAST.
DID YOU THINK
IT WAS ALL A NASTY DREAM?
FATHER SAW
THE HORSEMAN KILL YOU.
HE SAW THE HORSEMAN COME TOWARDS
ME WITH HIS SWORD UNSHEATHED,
BUT IT IS I WHO GOVERN
THE HORSEMAN, MY DEAR,
AND BALTUS DID NOT STAY
TO WATCH.
YAH! YAH!
- BUT THERE WAS A BODY.
- THE SERVANT GIRL, SARAH.
[Lady Van Tassel's Voice] AND I
ALWAYS THOUGHT SHE WAS USELESS.
BUT IT SEEMS
SHE HAD A PURPOSE AFTER ALL.
WHO ARE YOU?
MY FAMILY NAME
WAS ARCHER.
THE ARCHER.
[Whinnying]
I LIVED WITH MY FATHER AND MOTHER AND
SISTER IN A COTTAGE NOT FAR FROM HERE.
UNTIL ONE DAY MY FATHER DIED.
THE LANDLORD, WHO HAD
RECEIVED MANY YEARS OF
LOYAL SERVICE FROM MY
PARENTS, EVICTED US.
NO ONE IN
THIS GOD-FEARING TOWN...
WOULD TAKE US IN BECAUSE MY MOTHER
WAS SUSPECTED OF WITCHCRAFT.
BUT SHE SCHOOLED HER
DAUGHTERS WELL WHILE
WE LIVED AS OUTCASTS
IN THE WESTERN WOODS.
SHE DIED WITHIN A YEAR.
MY SISTER AND I REMAINED
IN OUR REFUGE,
SEEING NOT A SOUL.
UNTIL ONE DAY,
WHILST GATHERING FIREWOOD,
WE CROSSED THE PATH
OF THE HESSIAN.
- SHH.
- [Twig Snaps]
I SAW HIS DEATH.
AT THAT MOMENT, I OFFERED
MY SOUL TO SATAN...
IF HE WOULD RAISE THE HESSIAN
FROM THE GRAVE TO AVENGE ME.
- AVENGE YOU?
- AGAINST VAN GARRETT.
THE LANDLORD WHO SHOWED US NO
MERCY AND LEFT US TO STARVE...
WHILST BALTUS VAN TASSEL
AND HIS SIMPERING
WIFE AND GIRL CHILD
STOLE OUR HOME.
I SWORE I WOULD MAKE MYSELF
MISTRESS OF ALL HE HAD.
THE EASIEST PART WAS THE FIRST.
TO ENTER YOUR HOUSE
AS YOUR MOTHER'S SICK NURSE,
AND PUT HER BODY INTO THE GRAVE
AND MY OWN INTO THE MARRIAGE BED.
NOT QUITE SO EASY
WAS TO SECURE MY LEGACY.
THE WIDOW HAD TO GO,
OF COURSE,
AND THE SERVANT MASBATH.
AND JUST THE OTHER DAY,
THAT SILLY MIDWIFE, KILLIAN,
TOLD ME THE WIDOW HAD
TOLD HER A BIG SECRET.
AND SHE TOLD ME THIS
RIGHT IN FRONT OF HER HUSBAND.
WHAT A GOOSE!
SO, ANOTHER LITTLE JOB
FOR THE HORSEMAN.
BUT LUST DELIVERED THE REVEREND
STEENWYCK INTO MY POWER.
FEAR DID THE SAME
FOR THE NOTARY HARDENBROOK...
AND THE DRUNKARD PHILIPSE.
AND THE DOCTOR'S SILENCE
I EXCHANGED...
FOR MY COMPLICITY IN HIS FORNICATIONS
WITH THE SERVANT GIRL, SARAH.
YES, YOU HAVE
EVERYTHING NOW.
NO! YOU HAVE, MY DEAR,
BY YOUR FATHER'S WILL.
I GET EVERYTHING
IN THE EVENT OF YOUR DEATH!
OH, MY SISTER, BY THE WAY,
SADLY PASSED AWAY...
QUITE RECENTLY.
[Katrina] YOU KILLED
YOUR OWN SISTER?
SHE BROUGHT IT ON HERSELF BY
HELPING YOU AND YOUR MASTER!
[Laughing] YOU'RE JUST IN TIME
TO HAVE YOUR HEAD CUT OFF.
THE HORSEMAN COMES,
AND TONIGHT HE COMES FOR YOU!
KATRINA!
THANK GOD!
[Horse Whinnying]
WATCH YOUR HEAD.
TO THE ROOF!
I HAVE AN IDEA.
JUMP FOR THE SAILS.
[Crane]
JUMP!
HURRY!
IS HE DEAD? THAT'S THE PROBLEM.
HE WAS DEAD TO BEGIN WITH.
HYAH!
[Horse Whinnies]
WHERE ARE WE GOING?
ANYWHERE BUT HERE.
HERE.
TAKE THE REINS.
[Gunshot]
ICHABOD!
YAH!
MY BAG!
JUMP!
[Whinnying]
STILL ALIVE?
RUN, KATRINA!
YES, DO RUN, AND JUMP,
AND SKIP!
- NO!
- [Gasps]
[Thunderclaps]
HERE! TAKE HER!
SHE'S YOURS!
SIR, YOU'RE NOT DEAD!
[Screams]
HORSEMAN!
[Whinnies]
HYAH!
[Gasps]
[Whinnies]
AHH. JUST IN TIME
FOR A NEW CENTURY.
YOU'LL SOON GET YOUR BEARINGS,
YOUNG MASBATH.
THE BRONX IS UP,
THE BATTERY'S DOWN.
AND HOME IS THIS WAY.