Joe, you're under arrest.
Maybe so, but don't turn around, sheriff.
Now what're you gonna do, sheriff?
You can do just about what you want,
Chance.
Anybody else you want besides Joe?
No.
Give me a hand.
- What is all this?
- Hello, Mr. Wheeler.
Tell your men to stay with the wagons
till they're told different.
Who the devil do you think
you're ordering around here?
First Burdette's men stop me and
now you stand there and try to...
- Say, seems like I ought to know you.
- I think you do, Mr. Wheeler.
Yeah, I remember you now.
That star you're wearing
kind of threw me off for a minute.
Aren't you the fellow
the Mexicans used to call borrachín?
That's nearly right. Only it's borrachón.
I don't think I've ever seen you
like this before.
You mean sober? You're probably right.
You know what "borrachón" means?
My Spanish ain't too good.
It means drunk.
Now if the name bothers you,
they used to call me Dude.
Now are you gonna tell your men or do I?
I'll tell my men.
Stand by the wagons, everybody!
Pass the word.
Chance, what's going on here?
People stopping me. Everybody telling me
what I can and can't do.
Next thing,
you'll be telling me what to do.
- Pat, I will tell you.
- What?
- Stop your wagons.
- Oh, I give up.
Now don't tell me what's going on.
Just leave me wandering around in the fog.
I like it. I'm getting used to it.
It makes me feel so good.
You better look out, Pat,
you'll blow up and bust.
Oh, listen, Chance, remember me?
Your old friend Pat Wheeler.
- Now, will you please...?
- Hey, Chance!
What do you wanna do about this outfit?
Do you wanna take their guns?
Got any new men with you, Pat?
No, nobody except Colorado here.
- Where'd you take him on?
- Fort Worth.
- What does he do?
- I speak English, sheriff...
...if you wanna ask me.
All right, buster, what do you do?
I'm riding guard.
- Pretty young for that, aren't you?
- Just how old do you have to be, sheriff?
You remember Ryan from Denver,
don't you?
- Rocky Ryan?
- Well, that's his boy.
He tells me the kid's faster than he was.
Well, he better be,
packing a pair of guns.
Now, sheriff, if it's the two guns that
bother you, I could give you one of them.
I could let you have them both.
They wouldn't do me too much good.
That fellow in the door there
has a shotgun on me.
- Stumpy, didn't I tell...?
- I know. I'm going. I'm going.
You can keep your guns, Colorado.
Thanks, sheriff. I don't want any trouble.
Well, then don't start any.
I won't, unless I tell you first.
That's good enough.
Pat, you can put your wagons
in that corral.
I ought to do just that.
- What?
- I'm just guessing, you understand.
It seems to me that you've already
got some trouble here.
You're guessing right.
It so happens that part of our load
there is fuel oil and dynamite.
Would you like to have that
sitting next to you?
No, I wouldn't.
They could put them over there
by the creek.
Near the Burdette warehouse.
If it's gonna blow
that's just as good a place as any.
Show them the way, Dude.
You can go along, Colorado.
Is that the way you want it, Mr. Wheeler?
Go ahead.
Well?
Let's get out of the
middle of the street.
Well, now that you're satisfied
and that the kid's got his guns...
...would you mind telling me
what this is all about?
We've got Joe Burdette in here.
- Joe Burdette in jail? Nathan's brother?
- That's right.
What are you holding him for?
They were about to bury the reason
when you were coming in.
- Murder?
- No other word for it.
No wonder this town's in such a mess.
What does Nathan say about this?
Nothing. He's not talking. Just doing.
You saw part of it.
He's got this town so bottled up
that I can't get Joe out or any help in.
Those men over there watching us...
...they're his.
I can't make a move
without him knowing it.
Who you got helping you?
You met half of them.
You mean that fellow with the badge
that stopped me, and who else?
Stumpy. You know him.
He's watching Joe and guarding the jail.
A game-legged old man and a drunk.
That's all you got?
That's what I got.
If I ever saw a man holding the bull
by the tail, you're it.
It's a good idea putting my wagons
where they're safe.
Guess I better see they did it.
I'll see you later.
Better get back up there
and watch the road.
You don't look so good.
I feel worse.
Think I'll stop off and get a beer.
I thought you would.
Got some in here. Cold.
Just as long as it's beer.
Stumpy, didn't I tell you
to stay out of sight?
There you go. I never can please you.
I was just covering you in case of trouble.
I'd be in more trouble if you'd have gotten
picked off while standing at that door.
You'd be in trouble?
What about me
if somebody gunned me down?
Don't you never think of me?
Dude, I guess we better get used to it.
Here's a fellow don't think of nobody
but himself.
I told you why I want you back in there...
...and you're gonna stay there with
that cage locked when I'm not around.
- You hear me?
- I heard you.
Those windows, did you fix them?
Them shutters is nailed up
tighter than a drum.
Nothing could get in here now.
- Not even some fresh air.
- That's the way I want it.
You can help to change my life.
Can't help it.
Five, six days breathing the same air as
Burdette is apt to make a killer out of me.
You can hear me back there,
can't you, Joe?
I hear you all right, but I won't have
to listen to you for very long.
Now, Joe, that's gratitude for you.
After me fixing up all your cuts
and bruises like I done.
I hope it happens again.
I won't do it, that's all.
- Shut up!
- I take it back, Joe.
If it does happen again,
I'll do just like I done before...
...only I hope you have
more cuts and bruises to fix.
Hey, Dude. Dude, come here a minute.
What do you want?
Why don't you sit in here
in place of Stumpy?
I'd rather listen to a drunk than him.
How you holding up, borrachón?
Got the shakes yet?
That beer won't do you no good. You'll
have to get something stronger than that.
If you're still broke,
I think I got another dollar.
- Chance, you gonna let him do that to me?
- I'll do better than that.
I'll let him have the key to your cell
anytime he wants it.
It'd be too easy.
He's got nobody to back him up.
If he talks out of turn,
throw a bucket of water on him.
I'll throw one in the middle of his bed
and leave him sleep in it.
Want another beer?
You kind of wasted some of that last one.
No, it wasn't wasted,
except I missed him.
- I don't need any more.
- Hey, in the jail.
That's far enough. What do you want?
Mr. Wheeler said to bring this package
to the sheriff.
Hey, Chance, you expecting a package?
Be right out.
- Stumpy?
- Yeah?
Going over to the hotel for a few minutes.
If you don't come back,
me and Joe'll have us a good cry.
Just keep that door locked.
- Thanks for your trouble.
- No trouble at all.
Wheeler said, "Just be careful coming up."
Looks like our friend's still on the job.
Yeah.
There's another one over by the church.
Any use in arresting them?
For just standing around?
All I'd do is get another one.
The jail isn't big enough
to hold all of them.
As a matter of fact,
they'd like to get a few in jail.
Remember that.
Señor Chance. I've been looking for you.
I have a message for...
What you have here?
The package you've been waiting for.
Just in time, señor.
- Carlos! Carlos! Where are you at?
- I'm over here.
You keep it. Consuelo, she comes now.
If you break the dishes, you'll see what
happens. Every day is the same thing...
Carlos. Oh, Señor Chance.
I just ask Carlos if he's...
Carlos, what is wrong?
You look like the cat
who swallows the chicken.
What have you been doing?
What have I been doing?
I've been talking to my friend the sheriff,
that's what I have been doing.
We have important business.
You say I look like the cat
who eats too much.
Consuelo, look at me. Am I fat?
- I did not say you are fat.
- Please, Consuelo, do not say more.
You already say too much.
Me and my friend
will make our business alone.
Come, señor.
The thing is if he ate the chicken or not.
I'm going to see.
You take chances, my friend.
Because I know woman.
She will be mad or she will be sorry.
If it is mad,
she will be much pleasure to make right.
And if she is sorry,
it will be the same pleasure.
You do not have women.
So you do not know, señor.
But me, Carlos Robante, I know.
Wait till I show you
what is in this package.
Then you tell me
if I do not know about women.
If I had bought this myself, señor,
everyone in town would have known.
And it's not the sort
of thing that Consuelo
would like to have
known by everyone.
You see?
And they're not beautiful, señor?
Can you make the picture
how she will look?
You sure you want me to do that?
No. No, señor.
Do not make the picture.
It is best for me to do it.
I beg your pardon, gentlemen,
but I'm looking for a...
Those things have great possibilities,
but not for you.
What are you doing here?
Until I saw those things, I was looking
for a towel. I'd like to take a bath.
- Didn't you come in on the stage?
- That's right.
Why aren't you on it?
Whoever heard of a stagecoach
having a bathroom?
Chihuahua! I forgot.
I start to tell you and I forgot.
- The stage, she did not go.
- Why?
- Something happened with the wheel.
- Where's Jake?
Near the corral.
He must fix the wheel
before he can leave.
That's just fine.
Hey, sheriff, you forgot your pants.
You reckon they'd try anything tonight?
Could be. Nathan Burdette's smart.
Don't underrate him.
That ain't no kind of answer.
How or what he'll do, I don't know.
- Your guess is as good as mine.
- Well, what I wanna know is when.
I wish he'd hurry up and do it.
Have a bottle of beer, Dude?
I'm full of beer.
It doesn't do any good.
It'll start working on you tomorrow
or the next day.
Stumpy.
We're gonna take a turn
around the town.
- You be all right?
- Of course I'll be all right.
Then get in there where you belong.
I'm going. I'm going.
But you remember one thing:
When you come back,
you holler before you open that door.
I'm liable to blast you
just for the heck of it.
We'll holler.
You got any particular reason
for going out tonight?
Usually do.
Don't wanna do anything different,
they might think we're scared.
Well, aren't we?
I just can't take it sitting in there.
You mean you saw I couldn't take it.
Don't set yourself up as being so special.
You'd think you invented the hangover.
I could sure take out a patent
for this one.
Take that side.
- Good evening.
- Yes, sir.
Hold it, Dude. Stairway.
Don't shoot, sheriff.
Just getting a little air.
I'm getting jumpy.
I'll walk along with you
and hold your hand.
- Get back over there where you belong.
- Yes, Papa.
- Carlos.
- Señor Chance. I been looking for you.
- It is very bad, señor.
- What's wrong?
- Your friend Señor Wheeler.
- What about him?
He is a good friend
and he wishes good for you, so he talks.
He talks to people. He talk to everybody.
He say, "Why they don't help you?"
That you should have some more help.
He's right, Señor Chance.
But is no good to say such things
to the wrong people.
- You tell him.
- ls he in there?
Sí, I think.
Chance, he's over there.
- The queens full.
- That's good. Beats me.
Spare a minute, Pat?
Good evening, sheriff.
- Deal me out.
- Evening.
- You two know each other.
- Yeah.
No, thanks, Carlos.
- Chance, I've been wanting to talk to you.
- You've been talking too much, Pat.
- What do you mean "talking too much"?
- Anybody that...
...sides in with me
right now's liable to
find themselves up to
their ears in trouble.
Is that why you haven't asked
for any deputies?
Give me a new deck of cards.
I'm not having any luck with this one.
I was talking about why you haven't asked
for any new deputies. You could get some.
How about my drivers?
You could use them.
Suppose I got them, what'd I have?
Some well-meaning amateurs.
Most of them worried
about their wives and kids.
Burdette has 30 or 40 men,
all professionals.
Only thing they're worried about
is earning their pay.
No, Pat, all I'd be doing is giving them
more targets to shoot at.
A lot of people'd get hurt.
Joe Burdette isn't worth it.
He isn't worth one of those
that'd get killed.
Then what are you gonna do?
All you got for help's that old man
down at the jail and this...
Borrachón's the name, Mr. Wheeler.
I'll go outside
so you can talk more freely.
Wasn't good, Pat.
- Let's sit down.
- Yeah, I know.
I shouldn't have said it.
I meant nothing by it.
But I'm so used to stumbling
over that fellow.
I don't think I ever saw him
standing on his own two feet...
...without something
to help hold him up.
How long you been coming here?
Going on two years.
If you'd have come through three years
ago, you wouldn't have stumbled over him.
Dude was good.
He was my deputy.
Best man with a gun I ever worked with.
That's pretty hard to believe, Chance.
- What...?
- A girl.
Just a girl that came through on the stage.
She was no good,
but couldn't tell him that.
I tried and he damn near killed me.
Anyway, he was hooked.
Went away with her.
Six months later
he came back without her.
That's when the Mexicans
started calling him borrachón.
- That's Spanish for...
- Yeah, I know.
He told me.
So for two years he's been drinking...
...all he could buy, or somebody'd
buy for him till last night.
And how long do you think that'll last?
I don't know.
So in the meantime,
you have to take care of him, huh?
He's been doing a pretty good job
of taking care of me.
I'm supposed to be your friend too.
Why don't you let me help you?
Deal me in.
- You're not good enough.
- I don't know! I'm as good...
If you're so good,
why did you have to hire Colorado?
- No, thanks, Pat, you keep out of it.
- Hey, that's an idea.
- What?
- Ryan. Colorado you call him.
He's young, Chance, but he's good.
Real good.
I could use him if he's good.
But that's up to him.
We'll see what he says.
- Good evening, sheriff.
- Any luck, kid?
- It's a pretty fast game.
- Son, I...
...asked you over here
because the sheriff's a friend of mine.
He's got trouble. He can use a good man.
- To go against the Burdettes, sheriff?
- That's right.
I told him you were one of the best.
Well...
I'll tell you what I'm a lot better at,
Mr. Wheeler.
That's minding my own business.
No offense, sheriff.
No offense.
Well, I never expected that.
He showed good sense.
- I'd like to have him.
- I don't see why you...
Quit stewing, Pat. You tried.
I appreciate it.
If you don't want me,
I'll round up my men...
...and get set for an early start
in the morning. See you before I go.
Enough for me for a while.
You leaving?
- Maybe I'll have some luck now.
- Maybe.
If you play your cards right.
Hope you leave
some of your luck with me.
I'll come back
and give it to you next time.
We'll ante up.
- Dude?
- Yeah?
I'll be out in a couple of minutes.
Oh, hi, sheriff.
I'm sorry about those pants.
Carlos told me they weren't yours.
You're in trouble, lady.
I'd like to talk to you.
Sure.
Well, sheriff, what is it?
I was looking through the deck of cards
you people were using.
It's three cards short.
Pretty obvious ones, aces.
Why...?
Well, why do you tell me?
I know everyone in that game except you
and the fellow in the checkered vest.
- And did you talk to him?
- He's still there.
You were leaving.
And I was a winner.
Is that all you've got to go on?
No. Here's a handbill...
...about a gambler
they're interested in catching up with.
You know him?
It says he had a girl with him.
Says the girl's about 22,
5 foot 5 inches tall...
...good figure, brown hair,
and wears feathers.
Now, the man isn't our...
...friend in the checkered vest
but you could be the girl.
Yes, I could be.
As a matter of fact, I am.
Make sure you're on the stage
in the morning.
You'd better give me
the money you won.
I'll see that it gets
back to the right people.
It's pretty easy, isn't it?
Just give you the money
and get on the stage.
But I'm not gonna make it that easy.
You've made me mad, sheriff.
You didn't ask me if I took those cards.
So you're gonna have to prove
I've got them.
The only way I know you can do that
is to search me.
- Search you?
- That's right.
Isn't that what a sheriff usually does
to a prisoner?
Let's see,
the cards could be in my purse...
...but they're not.
They could be in my shoes,
my stockings, garters.
All right, all right.
I don't wear anything
like those red pants.
And my sleeves are too tight,
but there's my waist.
You've got a job to do,
where do you intend to begin?
- That's about enough.
- You have to prove I've got those cards.
- You keep going and I'm apt to do it!
- I'm not so sure.
I think you're embarrassed.
- And if you're not...
- If he's not...
...he ought to be.
What're you doing here?
I don't think she has the cards.
If that's what you're looking for.
How do you know?
I think the fellow in the checkered vest
has them.
Well, why didn't you find out?
I said I wouldn't start anything
till I told you first.
Now I'm telling you.
I'm gonna see if he's got them.
Wait a minute.
- You wanna come along?
- I do.
I'm interested too.
Ace high straight.
Looks like I got the lady's luck.
How come...?
All right, keep your hands on the table.
Right where they are.
Put your hands back.
Where they were.
Hold out.
He's all yours, sheriff.
Get up.
Get up!
We don't like tinhorns around here, mister.
Carlos, lock him in his room.
Let him out in time for the stage.
You losers can help yourself
to what's on the table.
Thanks, Colorado.
Sheriff, aren't you forgetting something?
I guess I was wrong about you
having those cards.
Is that all, sheriff?
Well, I'm not gonna apologize,
if that's what you mean.
We haven't gotten past that handbill,
have we?
That's right.
You haven't done anything
to make me think we will.
Idea of being searched
didn't bother you much.
Made a joke of it.
Instead of me being embarrassed,
you were.
Tell me, sheriff,
what should I have done?
- Well...
- I'd like to know.
This isn't the first time
that handbill has come up.
I'd like to know what to do about it.
Well, you could quit playing cards...
...wearing feathers.
No, sheriff.
No, I'm not gonna do that.
You see, that's what I'd do...
...if I were the kind of girl
that you think I am.
Dude, you seen Wheeler?
Not since he went up the street.
I think that's him coming now.
Get him out of here!
Watch the stable.
That's where the shot came from.
Got him in the back.
He's dead.
Didn't take them long,
less than an hour after he offered to help.
Don't get many friends like that.
You were smart, Colorado.
- No one's come out of the stable.
- I wanna go with you.
Wanna help get the man
that killed your boss?
- Wouldn't you?
- I wouldn't have let him get shot.
You had a chance to get in this
and you didn't want it.
Stay out, we don't need you.
You wanna do something,
get him out of the street.
Get around to the side
where you can see front and back.
How you going in?
Right through the door.
If he comes out, you can have him.
There's no sense in me
telling you to cool down.
- No, there isn't.
- I thought so.
I'll let you know when I get there.
Chance, you all right?
Chance, out here.
You all right?
Just dirt in my eyes. Did you get him?
He came out the door, running fast.
- You missed him.
- I couldn't get a good shot.
- Might've winged him.
- Don't worry. It's my fault we lost him.
He hasn't got away yet...
...or I wouldn't be standing here.
He went in the saloon.
- He's still in there.
- How do you know?
Can see both doors from here.
And there ain't any others.
I'm an expert on saloons.
- Get a chance to see who he was?
- No, but we'll know.
He'll have muddy boots.
He stepped in that puddle by the trough.
You figure we're going in there after him?
- Aren't we?
- We used to.
There's eight or ten Burdette men in there.
Maybe more.
You take the back door,
I'll go in the front.
- I'd like to try...
- You'd like to try what?
I been going in the back door.
They haven't been letting me in the front.
- Think you're good enough?
- I'd like to find out.
So would I.
I'll let you know when I get around back.
Begin with you, Charlie.
That shotgun you keep under the bar.
Pick it up by the barrel.
Easy.
Thought you were gonna ask for a drink.
It's been a long dry spell.
Shotgun first.
Set it down.
Back up.
Jim, Pedro, get over there.
All right, the rest of you,
I'm not gonna tell you twice.
You're gonna stand up
and stand real still.
Now!
All right, now one by one,
start with you, unbuckle your guns...
...drop them and step back.
Come on.
There's no reason
for you to move, Charlie.
- What's this all about?
- We're looking for a man that ran in here.
Nobody's run in here.
We'll remember you said that.
Man we're looking for has muddy boots.
Now, one by one, hold up your feet.
Who saw a man run in here?
I did.
Almost forgot about you, Charlie.
Come on out.
Clean as a whistle.
Dude, you been seeing things again.
You better have a drink.
Dude. Maybe this'll help.
Guess I'll take that drink now, Charlie.
I thought you would.
You want that gun, pick it up.
I wish you would.
He stepped in a puddle, all right.
He's the fellow we wanted.
I guess this is his.
A nice, fresh $50 gold piece.
It's just about what Burdette would figure
a man's life was worth.
That's earning money the hard way.
Paid killer.
Nice, fresh $50 gold piece.
You, mister, you got one in your pocket?
Nobody paid me.
Nobody!
And nobody run in here, either, huh?
Chance.
Oh, I'm not gonna hurt him.
Get up!
You're all in it.
The whole lot of you.
You're gonna get out of town.
Take your boy here with you.
You can tell Burdette you got Wheeler.
You can tell him anybody else he sends,
he'd better pay them more...
...because they're gonna earn it.
Charlie, I want you to...
You finished yet, Dude?
- You in a hurry?
- Not especially.
You threw the silver dollar, didn't you?
- Yeah, Dude, I...
- You want it back?
- Sure.
- You know how to get it?
Yeah.
That's all for me, Chance.
- Charlie, come here.
- Yeah, sheriff.
You're going with us.
Why pick on me? Why choose me?
You're carrying these guns
down to the jail for us.
All right, back up and give him room.
I guess they'll let you
in the front door from now on.
You mean to tell me you followed him
into Burdette's saloon?
Why, you're crazy!
And you are too. What happened?
He was hiding in the loft.
- Who got him?
- Dude did. One shot.
I wish I could've seen that.
I wish Wheeler could've too.
Wheeler didn't think
Dude and me was much good.
Leastways it would've showed him
he was wrong about Dude.
He was wrong about Dude, all right.
You were good in there tonight.
Good as you've ever been.
But you know one reason
why you got by with it?
They were laughing at you.
Borrachón talking big.
You surprised them.
But next time they'll be ready for you.
Next time they'll shoot first
and laugh afterwards.
- Listen to him.
- Don't get too cocksure.
What a stinker!
Spit in his eye, Dude.
Never mind him,
he's always been a stinker.
If he were to change,
that would worry me.
You'd think I could get one
out of a whole sack.
How'd you know
that fellow was in the loft?
He was losing blood.
It was dripping into a drink on the bar.
Just when I couldn't find anybody
with muddy boots.
I could've sure used a drink then.
If he was bleeding that means
you hit him on the run outside.
You did, Dude? Say, that ain't bad.
That ain't bad at all.
Ain't good either.
We had to go in after him.
Chance, nobody please you no how?
You got a light, Stumpy?
Hey, in the jail! It's me, Colorado.
Let him in.
Come on in.
I hear you got the man who shot Wheeler.
Dude did.
Thanks, Dude.
Gonna bury him in the morning.
I've just been to the undertaker's
with him.
Here's the money and the papers
he had on him.
I took out $60 he owed me.
You got yours.
How about the rest?
Did he owe them too?
Probably did.
I didn't think about that.
I can't turn anything over to you
till I get a court order.
- Does that mean you hold the wagons too?
- That's right.
Meantime, I'm broke.
If you or any of the rest are
short eating money...
...I'll go good for it.
I'll tell them at the hotel.
I wish you'd do that soon,
before anything happens to you.
No offense again, sheriff.
It's nice to see a smart kid for a change.
Yeah, he ain't like
the usual kid with a gun.
I wonder if
he's as good as Wheeler said.
I'd say he is.
I'd say he's so good,
he doesn't feel he has to prove it.
- Don't you ever sleep?
- I was beginning to think you didn't.
I wanted to talk to you.
Don't tell me you're still looking
for an apology.
No. No, I was thinking of making one.
I was pretty much of a...
I got out of line tonight
and I'm not proud of it.
My only excuse is...
...I didn't know about all
the trouble you were in.
I'm gonna have a drink. How about you?
Thanks, I'd like one.
I'm sorry about Mr. Wheeler.
Carlos told me he was a friend of yours.
That's why he got shot.
Or did Carlos tell you that too?
Yes, he told me.
How does...?
How does a man get to be a sheriff?
Gets lazy. Gets tired...
...of selling his gun all over...
...decides to sell it in one place.
I'd say you made a poor sale.
A lot of people around here
will agree with you.
But it's still a sale
and it's too late to back out.
Not to change the subject, but how does
a girl get herself on a handbill?
She gets married.
- Handbill says he was a cheat.
- He wasn't a cheat then.
That came later, after his luck turned.
It was probably my fault he cheated.
He liked to buy me things.
- Then why did you leave him?
- I didn't.
He left me rather suddenly.
He was caught just like that man tonight...
...only his luck had run out.
He was shot.
You've had a rough time.
You're wrong, sheriff.
I've had a good time.
I liked gambling.
We went everywhere,
had the best of everything.
I didn't know that he was cheating
until they caught him.
If I had known, it might have been rough.
That's probably why he didn't tell me.
When did this happen?
About four months ago.
Since then I've been working...
...to get enough money for stage fare.
- You going home?
- I haven't any.
Señor Chance!
I didn't know you were here.
Why do you not tell me?
You should be in bed.
Last night you slept just a little bit.
But tonight, señor, you will sleep well.
I will watch.
No, Carlos, you stay out of it.
Don't want anybody else helping me.
Señor Chance, this is my hotel...
...and you are a guest under my roof.
And I will not be told what I shall do
and what I shall not do, señor.
- All right, Carlos.
- What you do?
- I'll sleep in the jail.
- But you can't sleep...
There's no need to watch.
I'm a light sleeper.
I'll lock the door
and hook a chair under the knob.
Anybody tries to get in, I'll hear them.
- One thing.
- What?
If I'm asleep at sunup, wake me.
- But it's not enough.
- Will you?
I say no more.
Have a good sleep.
I don't want to meddle in your business.
I'm gonna turn in.
If I don't see you in
the morning, so long.
So long.
By the way, where are you going?
Some place where
there aren't any handbills.
That thing keeps popping up.
That's why I'm a little touchy about it.
I know the sheriff that got these out.
I'll write him a letter,
get them called in.
Then you won't have people like me
making trouble for you.
Well...
Thanks.
- Carlos!
- Señor.
It's after 7. Why didn't you wake me up?
You said you would.
- The girl.
- The girl?
- That one with the feathers.
- What's she got to do with it?
She told me not to wake you.
She was sitting outside your room
in a chair.
- Sitting outside my room in a chair?
- All night long.
She was still there
two, three minutes ago.
Most likely she hear you get up.
She told me not to wake you, señor.
Well, you can tell her...
- The fool!
- Tell her she's a fool?
No! I'll tell her myself.
You tell her she's a fool?
I didn't say I was.
He say, "Not to wake him up."
She say, "To wake him up."
Me, I'm in the middle.
- Who is it?
- It's me, the sheriff.
Oh, just a minute.
Come on in.
Hi.
- Did you get a good night's sleep?
- Who, me?
Yes, you.
There's nobody else in the room.
Carlos had to go and talk.
I couldn't sleep anyway.
I was just as well off
out there in the hall.
If anybody had come in, you'd have yelled
before they shot you. Is that it?
Fool women.
- Didn't you hear me say that...?
- I know.
You don't want anyone to help you.
I heard you tell Carlos.
- Why did you do it?
- You weren't supposed to know.
Why didn't you just go out
and not talk to Carlos?
- He didn't wake me up!
- Don't blame him, that was my fault.
All right, nothing happened,
nobody got hurt.
You got some sleep, I lost some.
Now I'm tired and you're mad
and I'm getting mad. So...
...you'd better go on.
I'm gonna get some sleep too.
Well, you can't go to bed now.
I can't?
Well, you just see whether or not
I can go to bed now...
You've got to get on that stagecoach.
- What did you say?
- The stage, it leaves in an hour.
- Well, why didn't you tell me?
- I just did!
Well, then you better get out then,
so I can get a bath and pack my things.
I can't do it if you stand around talking.
You're doing most of the talking.
That's right. And I can't do that
and bathe and pack.
- Will you just go on and go?
- I'm going.
Then do it, don't talk any more.
I'm doing enough
and neither of us are saying anything.
So, just go on
and let me get on the stage.
Oh, hell! Goodbye.
But I just wanted to...
You could have at least let me finish.
You try to help someone
who doesn't want any help.
I guess I talk too much.
You tell her?
- Tell her what?
- That she's a fool.
She's going on the stage?
She's going on the stage.
You make sure she does.
You say she was going,
why should I make sure?
Because I say for you
to make sure she does.
I hold you responsible.
Responsible, me? Yes.
Dude, he's up the street.
He told me to tell you he's gone.
So I see.
There's a lot of people in town today.
Did you hear why?
A man say he hear maybe Nathan Burdette
will come to see you today.
Most likely they here to watch.
Well, if he does,
they may see something.
- I don't like it.
- Neither do I.
Tom, hang your gun on the fence.
You'll pick it up when you leave.
Sure enough.
That's far enough.
I got orders to take your guns.
Suppose we don't wanna give them up?
Think you're good enough
to take them against six of us?
For a smart man, Mr. Burdette,
that's pretty stupid.
You won't need a gun no more
because you'll be the first man I'd get.
Come on, let's go.
Harris, you're pretty good right there.
- Hold it, Harris!
- He cut my rein.
I'd say he did it on purpose.
And I'm telling you to hold it.
Now just hang your guns on the fence
and you can pick them up when you leave.
Hang up your guns.
You're pretty good with that gun
when you're sober.
- Not bad, Mr. Burdette.
- How does that happen?
If you mean being good with a gun,
I've had a lot of practice.
If you mean being sober...
...I'm getting practice on account
of your brother.
I don't follow you.
You don't have to follow me,
Mr. Burdette. Matt!
Didn't you hear the boss say
that I was sober?
That extra gun in your vest,
lay that on the fence too.
- You're enjoying yourself, aren't you?
- All right, Mr. Burdette...
...let's get going.
I got no more to talk to you about.
You should enjoy it, Dude.
Every man should have a little taste
of power before he's through.
Stumpy!
Burdette and his men are coming in.
Well, don't put down
no red carpet for them.
And I'm staying right
where I'm supposed to.
You do that.
Good morning, sheriff.
Hello, Burdette.
Been expecting you.
I want to see my brother.
You can come in.
But that doesn't mean the rest of you.
He's not your brother.
Go on across the street with the others.
Do as he says.
What're all those people doing in town?
I didn't ask.
Didn't ask them to come,
or ask them why they're here.
But I think they're watching to see
what you're gonna do.
You don't like that, do you?
Too many witnesses.
Now do you wanna keep talking to me
or see your brother?
See my brother.
We're coming in, Stumpy.
Well, come ahead.
Don't wait for me to carry you.
All right, Stumpy, open up.
What's the password?
- Come on.
- Oh, I'm coming. I wouldn't miss this.
Just want him to see how we're set up.
Well, look who's here.
Place is getting all cluttered up
with Burdettes.
Come right in, Mr. Burdette.
That fellow round the corner
with a banged-up face is your brother.
Nathan.
Well, Joe.
Looks like they gave you a going-over.
Our friend here.
Why?
He didn't take too kindly
to being arrested for murder.
It wasn't murder.
If he says it wasn't murder,
why do you say it was?
Man gets shot that's got a gun,
there's room for reasonable doubt.
Man gets shot that hasn't got a gun,
what would you call it?
But you knew that already...
...otherwise you wouldn't have
set things up the way you did.
Just what have I done?
You're a rich man, Burdette.
Big ranch.
Pay a lot of people to do
what you want them to do.
And you got a brother.
He's no good, but he's your brother.
If he committed 20 murders,
you'd try and see he didn't hang for them.
I don't like that kind of talk.
- You're accusing me...
- Let's get this straight.
You don't like.
I don't like a lot of things.
I don't like your men sitting on the road
bottling up this town.
I don't like your men watching us,
trying to catch us with our backs turned.
And I don't like it
when a friend of mine offers to help...
...and 20 minutes later he's dead!
And I don't like you, Burdette,
because you set it up.
What're you gonna do about it?
I thought you'd get around to that.
I'm gonna sit here
with your brother in my lap...
...until the United States marshal
gets here.
That'll be about six days.
He may ask a few questions
about that busted wheel.
But I think you're too smart
to have stopped that stage completely.
Now I'm running out of breath.
You talk if you want to.
He talks awful big for a man
that's all alone...
...except for a barfly and a cripple.
- You can get me out of here any...
- Shut up, Joe!
You're not as smart as your brother, Joe.
He sees Stumpy here sitting around
the corner locked in with you.
And if that isn't plain enough,
I'll tell you why.
If any trouble starts around this jail...
...before anybody can get to you,
you're gonna get accidentally shot.
I can practical guarantee that.
I see you still have
a little grudge against us.
Four hundred and sixty acres
might be little to you, Nathan.
But it was a lot of country to me.
Don't take no chances, Nathan.
He looks just crazy enough to shoot me.
He's smarter than I thought.
You know,
a court might just call that murder too.
Oh, hell, what's the difference?
We'd all be dead by then.
You got anything else
you wanna say, Burdette?
Just one thing. Joe has friends.
You can't hold Joe
or me responsible for them...
...what you say they've done
or what they might do.
I want to make that clear.
Well, I'll help you make it clear.
I don't think
Joe's got a friend in the world.
And he won't have any unless somebody
buys them for him at $50 a head.
Like the fellow that shot Wheeler.
You made it clear.
All right, Stumpy.
- Nathan.
- Just sit tight, Joe.
Send me a bottle before you leave town.
You do that, because part of my job
is to see that it ain't poisoned.
Now sometimes it takes
quite a spell to find out.
- He didn't have much to say, did he?
- No.
What'd you leave him go for?
You had plenty to hold him on.
Anything they're gonna do...
...is planned already,
or he wouldn't have come in here.
Throwing him in with Joe would give him
an alibi for whatever happens.
I never thought of that.
- What do you think'll happen?
- I don't know.
You can think, can't you?
Any man can...
I think I told you to get back in there
and stay with that door locked.
Careful how you talk to me.
You hear what Joe said.
You're alone except for a barfly
and an old cripple.
Calling me an old cripple.
I like hearing you say that, Joe.
I gotta fix your supper for you tonight.
Señor Chance. Señor Chance.
It's me, Carlos.
Come on in.
- What do you want?
- I wanna talk to you.
Did the girl get...?
What happened to your eye?
- You told me to put the lady on the stage.
- Oh, she did that? What did you do?
- She did not do it.
- I thought you said she did.
I say, "You tell me to
put her on the stage.
" Consuelo, she hit
me in the eye.
- Wait, I'm a little mixed up.
- Do not talk. I tell you.
- Go ahead.
- It is better if I tell you.
You told me to put her on the stage.
The stage is ready, but she don't come.
I yell at her, "Come down."
She said she ain't coming.
- I go and get her, she said she don't go.
- Did she go?
I tell her you say go.
I tell her I am responsible.
She say, no, she is responsible.
And I say, "That may be."
I pick her up. Then Consuelo say,
"What are you doing with that woman?"
I say, "I take her to the stage."
The woman said she don't want to go.
- Did she go on the stage?
- Please.
Consuelo tell me, "Put her down."
I said, "I am responsible."
Consuelo thinks that mean something else.
So she give me this eye.
- What did you do?
- "Do"? What can I do?
My arms is full of the lady.
I can do nothing.
I drop her on the floor.
She yells.
And she said I tried to kill her.
Did the girl get on the stage?
No, she did not go!
But Jake say he couldn't wait.
- Why?
- He say he must leave.
I mean the girl.
Did she say why she wasn't going?
No. She didn't say.
How can I know if she don't say?
Please, Señor Chance. You come and tell
Consuelo what "responsible" means.
Stumpy, we're going out.
Fine. I like to be left alone.
I'm getting used to it.
The door's unlocked.
Well, I didn't go.
I can see that.
I don't know...
...I had everything all packed,
then Carlos yelled the stage was ready...
...and I heard somebody saying
they weren't going.
It was me saying it.
And you want to know why I didn't go,
don't you, sheriff?
What's your name, anyway?
I don't even know that.
Chance, John T.
"T" for trouble.
I always make you mad, don't I, John T.?
Well, then, don't make me
tell you why I stayed.
I won't make it any harder for you.
I won't get in your way. I'll just be here.
You don't owe me a thing.
And you won't owe me when it's all over.
When that happens,
just tell me to go, and I'll go.
No, you won't even have to tell me.
I'll know by then, and I'll just go.
Is that fair, John T.?
You don't have to answer me now
if you don't want to.
But just say something.
If I weren't in this mess,
it might be different.
But I am.
That's all I wanted to hear.
I'm glad we tried it a second time.
It's better when two people do it.
Well, I've kept you long enough.
You'd better run along now
and do your job.
Hi, Chance.
It's getting too dark to do any good
out there. I'd just be a sitting duck.
Anything happen when Burdette left?
Nice as pie. Didn't say a word.
What was the shot when they came in?
- That gunslinger of his was on the prod.
- What did he do?
Nothing, just grunted and growled,
made a few faces.
I took care of that.
What happened here?
Not much.
That tune, it's been playing it all day.
What is it?
It's some Mexican piece.
I heard it farther south.
Evening, sheriff.
Colorado. What do you want?
Just curious again.
How'd you come out with Burdette?
He wanted to talk to his brother.
- What'd he have to say?
- Nothing.
You mean he didn't say anything?
Why are you so interested?
Because he's talking now.
Hear that music?
He told the man to play it.
What is it?
They call it "The Deguello,"
"The Cutthroat Song."
The Mexicans played it
for those Texas boys...
...when they had them
bottled up in the Alamo.
Played it day and night
till it was all over.
Now do you know what he means by it?
No quarter.
- No mercy for the losers.
- You'll be hearing a lot of it.
I guess we made him talk after all.
Just thought you'd like to know, sheriff.
Stumpy!
- What?
- They don't need any help with that tune.
What's the matter,
is it getting through to you?
By the way, the stage got off all right.
I watched it clear through the valley.
In about six days
the marshal will get here.
That's what I figured.
Oh, the girl wasn't on the stage.
I know that.
Tell her she could stay?
No, she...
Yes, I did. What about it?
Nothing, nothing at all.
You were going to say something.
I remembered in time.
I remembered another girl came through
on a stage that stopped over.
I remember you told me she was no good.
I didn't believe you, but you were right.
So naturally I figured you're an expert.
And you know just
what you're doing all the time.
I just hope
you have better luck than I had.
You know, that's the first time
I've been able to laugh about that.
Maybe there's some hope for me yet.
Maybe.
But I doubt it.
That's what I like about you,
you're such an encouraging man.
If you go by the hotel pick up
some coffee and sugar, would you?
Joe complaining?
Him? He don't get no sugar.
His coffee's water poured
over the old grounds.
I'll learn him to talk out of turn.
Before I forget, your gun's a little stiff.
You mind if I file the action a bit?
I don't want you to file no action
on my gun.
I don't want no easy pull. I might
shoot myself. Get somebody else's.
Why don't you give him his own guns?
- I forgot all about them.
- Your memory is no better than mine.
They been locked up over a year
except when you...
...took them out
to clean them and oil them.
Where'd you get these?
Bought them off the fellow
you sold them to.
I didn't...
I don't know how to...
Let's take a turn around the town.
Get Stumpy his coffee.
Ain't you gonna tell me
to get back in there?
No, stay out here and get shot.
I might do that just for spite.
Might get a laugh out of you.
What I put up with for $30 a month.
- Feels good.
- Come on.
By the way, am I drawing pay?
Same as before.
In that case take out
what you gave for these guns.
No hurry.
If you're feeling so generous,
I could use an advance.
Buy a new pair of pants, new shirt.
Something without all these holes in it.
No need of that.
When you lit out,
you left some things behind.
I got them at the hotel.
You been keeping them all this time?
Been waiting till they fit you again.
You could use a bath and a shave too.
I don't know about the shave.
I'm liable to cut my own throat.
- Chance?
- Yeah?
They'll fit.
Thanks.
There you are.
Thank you.
How about you, John T.?
Shall I work on you?
I do my own shaving.
I thought you did.
I was just reminding you.
Sure buy a lot of drinks with that.
You sure could.
I'll let you keep it for me.
Feathers, thanks for the shave.
Might call on you again.
Anytime, because I'll be here.
Oh, I didn't tell you, John T.,
Carlos is giving me a job.
Good for Carlos. Shall we take Stumpy
his coffee and things?
You in a hurry, John T.?
I'd like to talk to you.
- I'll wait for you.
- Thanks, Dude.
- I just wanted to ask you...
- What's this about a job?
Carlos says he's not sleeping very well.
Says I can help out downstairs.
Tending bar?
Among other things.
You...
- You think I shouldn't?
- Why ask me?
The way you said "tending bar."
- All right, I won't do it.
- I didn't say not to.
But you don't like the idea.
Why should it be up to me?
Why should I care?
I don't know why you get mad
when I ask you.
- I'm not mad.
- You're not?
- You'd make anybody mad.
- I suppose I would.
Well, as long as you haven't anything
against it, I'll take the job.
Well, go ahead.
Thanks, I will.
What were you gonna ask me?
- Never mind. You're in too bad a humor.
- What were you going to ask?
Whether you were gonna sleep
in the hotel tonight.
Get one thing straight. There'll be no more
chair-sitting outside this door.
Oh, I know. I've given that up.
Anyway, I have a better idea.
Tonight you sleep in my room.
Anyone looking
wouldn't look there first.
You'd have more time
if anything did happen.
Besides, I have a rocking chair,
it's more comfortable.
Just an idea. You can think about it.
When you're in a little better humor.
Chance! Señor Chance!
The shot came from the jail.
Chance, look out!
Don't go in there.
That idiot just took a shot at me.
Stumpy! You all right?
Sure I am, but there's a feller out there
with a black hat that ain't.
And I'm that fellow.
Coming in.
Look what he did to my hat.
Stumpy, that was Dude you shot at.
Dude? I didn't know.
Didn't look like Dude.
- Fool almost blowed my head off.
- How'd I know it was you?
You get yourself dolled up
like Astor's pet horse...
...and then stick your nose in that door
and don't say nothing.
Look at this hat.
If you hadn't ducked,
that's what your head would look like.
I never would have fired
if I knew it was you.
Okay, I know.
Just stop talking, will you?
The shot didn't bother me.
I've been shot at before.
You could have hollered.
Just because you get cleaned up
don't mean you can't talk.
It's my fault. I should have yelled.
I shouldn't have taken a bath.
Just stop talking. Just let it be.
You been going around for years
like something the cat dragged in...
- ...and now you expect...
- Shut up!
I told you, Stumpy, I've had it.
Don't let me tell you again.
You're getting a little touchy, aren't you?
I've been listening to
that old fool talk until I...
All right, I'm wrong.
That old fool is talking
because he nearly killed you.
He's the one that's scared.
We've been pampering you too much.
You better get some sleep.
You know, he acts like I done it
on purpose. And I didn't.
You see that door there?
That look like I done it on purpose?
It's gonna get cold here at night.
And I'm gonna leave it get cold.
Because I ain't gonna fix that door.
It wasn't my fault.
Were it?
I know.
I'll fix the door.
Hi, sheriff.
Well, how do you like your new job?
They've been keeping me pretty busy.
You through for the day?
Going to bed?
I thought I would.
- Can I make you some coffee?
- No, thanks.
- Anything to eat?
- Nope.
How about a drink?
I'll take a drink.
Carlos says this is for special guests.
Tired, aren't you, John T.?
I can fix you a nice hot bath.
All I want is that drink.
Then this is all I can do for you?
I thought you said I could think about it.
You're right. I did.
Put it on the tab.
And in case you make up your mind,
I left my door open.
Get a good night's sleep.
You're not helping me any.
- Good morning, Dude.
- Good morning.
Have a good night?
All right, I guess.
- Eat anything?
- Well, I...
This morning?
Stumpy fixed something.
I asked you a question.
You didn't answer it.
All right, I'll answer you.
I didn't sleep good...
...didn't eat anything.
I had a beer and it didn't do any good.
Think you can stand your watch?
When I can't do that I'll let you know.
- That's enough.
- Yeah.
Where's his hat?
Get out there.
We'll be along as soon as we get him tied.
Stumpy, did Dude have a bad night?
Oh, he's suffering thunderation, Chance.
His mind's just beginning to work again,
and he sees what he done to himself.
Well, ain't pretty.
He's gotta sweat it out.
And don't let him cry
on your shoulder either.
He ain't done it yet.
Why are you so goddarned ornery?
Always picking on Dude.
- You got any tobacco?
- No, I give the last there was to Dude.
He used it up fast.
You gotta get some for yourself.
But what I'm asking you
is why are you picking on Dude?
All right, be nice to him
and he'll fall apart in small pieces.
Maybe you're right.
You know him better than I do.
I guess some folks is built that way.
But that wouldn't work with me.
You could at least have a kind word
for me now and then.
Considering what I have to do around here.
The sweeping, and the cooking, and
the nursemaiding that killer back there.
Not even a "thank you" do I get.
Maybe you're right, Stumpy.
You're a treasure.
Well...
- I don't know what I'd do without you.
- Yeah, well...
Go back to being yourself.
Leastwise I'm used to that.
He's coming down the street now.
Good morning, sheriff.
Colorado.
I been hearing a lot of talk.
Thought you might be interested.
About what?
Mostly about you telling Burdette
what would happen to Joe...
...if trouble started around the jail.
Guess he didn't expect to hear that.
Kind of new to me too.
- Would you have said it any different?
- No.
He was doing to me what he's doing
to you, I'd tell him the same thing.
He can't take a chance
on whether you'd do it or not.
I don't suppose so.
But you can be sure
he's gonna try it a different way.
Got enough left there for another?
Sure. Help yourself.
You always keep that carbine cocked?
Only when I carry it.
How come you carry a rifle?
I found some were faster than me
with a short gun.
I don't suppose you have a match either?
All out of them too.
I'll get some.
Sheriff, we ran into some trouble
on the road.
Al here is hurt. His horse threw him.
Your deputy said we could find a doctor.
Around the corner.
About three or four doors to the right.
Stay away from that rifle, sheriff.
You can see we've still got our guns.
That ain't your deputy up the street.
Unloosen that belt.
- What've you done to him?
- Don't worry about him.
Worry about yourself. He's all right.
He ain't gonna be and neither are you
unless you do as you're told.
- Stay back here.
- We're going down to the jail.
You'll turn Burdette loose...
...or you and your deputy are gonna
quit worrying about this whole thing.
Take your choice.
Are you just gonna stand here?
If you wanna get him shot,
just go out there.
What'll it be?
If you wanna do something,
when I get out on the porch...
...take that flowerpot and throw it
through the window.
And duck after you throw it.
Just keep coming, mister.
- Who, me?
- Yes, you.
Grab that horse.
- Colorado, where's he going?
- He's gonna see if Dude's all right.
Chance, over here.
You look a little used.
What'd they do? I heard shooting.
They had me cold.
Gonna make me open the jail.
What happened?
I didn't have to. Colorado helped me.
If you'd have had him here,
this wouldn't have happened.
I can get up by myself!
I let them get me.
I let them walk right up
and stick my head in the water trough...
...and it was easy for them.
I'm good when I'm sober.
Boy, real good.
I should have known better.
A man ought to have sense enough
to know when he's no good no more.
- Where're you going?
- Get your hands off of me.
I said, where're you going?
You've got no use for a man
you can't depend on.
One bad night and I'm done for.
An old man takes a potshot at me
and I'm finished.
I tried and I tried hard,
and where did it get me?
Look at me.
I got them so bad.
What can a man do with hands like that?
- I'm through. I quit, John. I quit.
- All right, quit.
Nobody's trying to stop you.
If you wanna quit, quit.
Go on back to the bottle, get drunk!
One thing, though.
Somebody throws a dollar in a spittoon,
don't expect me to do something about it.
Just get down on your knees
and go after it.
I'm sorry.
"Sorry" don't get it done, Dude.
That's the second time you hit me.
Don't ever do it again.
Maybe you're right.
Maybe you aren't much good anymore.
Here are your guns.
Fellow that took your hat
must have left this.
You get something out of it.
Now come on down to the jail, and
I'll give you the money you got coming.
- I think this is your horse, señor.
- Yeah, that's mine. Thanks.
I guess Dude's all right.
Anyway, he's walking.
I'm so glad. I was afraid.
My stomach seems...
Come on, maybe a drink'll help.
Go on up to the jail and wait for me there.
Tell Stumpy to give you a drink.
Oh, Señor Chance.
What do you wish me to do
with this three dead men?
You're the undertaker, Bert. Bury them.
There's another one
down by the bridge.
Send in your bill and
the county'll pay you.
No need for that.
Each one of them had two new $50
gold pieces in his pocket.
Price is going up.
- What?
- Nothing, Bert.
Bring their guns and other stuff
to the jail.
- It will be done.
- Here is your gun, señor.
Thank you, Carlitos.
Where's Colorado?
He's inside the hotel.
He took the girl, Feathers.
Better give me another, Colorado.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Look at me, Colorado. Take a good look.
Would you say my head is soft?
Would you say I'm an idiot?
No, ma'am.
Yeah, well, you'd be a liar then.
Better go easy on that stuff.
- That makes three you've had.
- Yep.
You'd be lying because that's what I am,
a softheaded idiot.
There isn't any other explanation
for staying around here...
...and inviting myself into this.
He told me...
Hi, sheriff.
We saw you coming back.
Dude was all right, wasn't he?
He's all right. So am I, thanks to you.
Thank the lady here.
Sure, thank the lady.
She did a big thing.
She threw a flowerpot through the window
and helped get three men killed.
Or was it four?
Why'd you make me do it?
- I made you do it?
- Sure, you did. Didn't he, Colorado?
He wasn't gonna do
what those men told him.
Not him.
You were just gonna get yourself killed,
that's all.
Somebody had to...
What were you gonna do, sheriff?
I'm glad I didn't have to
make up my mind.
You weren't going down to that jail,
John T.
So somebody had to help you.
But you don't want anybody to do that,
do you?
You're right, you didn't make me help you.
It was my own idea.
It was my idea to stay.
You told me to get on that stage.
I know you did.
- I'm glad you didn't.
- What?
I'm glad you didn't go.
What'd you...? What'd you have to
say a thing like that for?
You know, just when we get one thing
settled you have to go bring up another.
You just don't make any sense, that's all.
And neither do I.
And neither do you, Colorado.
What're you doing in this?
You don't have the excuse that I have.
I better go before I make a fool of myself.
I don't know why I should go though,
because we're all fools.
We ought to get along very well together,
all of us.
Well, I'm going, anyway.
We're just a bunch of idiots, that's all.
Just a bunch of idiots.
How did she get mixed up in this?
She didn't feel too good.
- She had a couple of drinks.
- I don't mean this. I mean out there.
Oh, she was going outside to help you.
How, I don't know. And neither did she.
I told her to throw that flowerpot through
the window and I went out instead.
And that's your reason
for throwing in with me?
She's right. It doesn't make any sense.
Wheeler just talked about helping me.
But you saved my neck.
Burdette isn't gonna kiss you for that.
So you're in.
Now, don't tell me you didn't think
about that. Before you did it, I mean.
If I'm gonna get shot at,
I might as well get paid for it.
How do I get a badge?
Come on, I'll get you one.
Oh, I ought to tell you. Dude's quitting.
I'm sorry for that.
But I figure why is not my business.
You've got peculiar ways of choosing
what is your business.
You telling me they was gonna bring
Chance in here to make me turn Joe loose?
Why, they're crazy.
Goddarn fools.
Chance brings in three strangers,
tells me to unlock the door...
...what do they think I'm gonna do?
You know what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna start blasting.
Where'd you get that hat?
- Chance gave it to me. For a souvenir.
- For a what?
- Stumpy, we're coming in.
- Well, come ahead.
See, he ain't too proud to yell.
Stumpy, where do you keep
the deputy sheriff badges?
In the right-hand drawer there.
You know where the book is,
the one with the oath?
No! If you can't take care of your own
truck don't look for me to do it.
We'll have to do without it.
Raise your right hand.
Do you solemnly swear to take
on the duties of a sheriff's deputy...
Found yourself another knothead
who don't know when he's well off?
...in the county of Presidio
of the great state of Texas?
I do.
And that includes taking orders from me.
All right, sheriff.
How about giving me one?
Get over at the hotel
and pick up your stuff.
Move in here.
What're you laughing about?
What I got myself in for.
Cheerful about it anyways, ain't he?
- How good do you think he is?
- He's all right.
You think he's as good
as Wheeler said he was?
He threw me my gun and while it was
in the air, he got one of them.
- Then he got another one.
- Good enough. Good enough.
Is he as good as I used to be?
It'd be pretty close.
I'd hate to have to live on the difference.
Then you got the best of it. Him for me.
What's he talking about? "Him for me"?
Nobody never tells me
nothing around here.
You heard him, he's quitting.
What's got into you?
Look at me. Ain't that pretty?
Shaking worse all the time.
What can a man do with hands like that?
Tell me, what?
Take a drink! You said Chance told you to.
You did, didn't you, Chance?
He can take the whole bottle.
Well, go ahead.
Stumpy.
Don't close it.
Didn't spill a drop.
Shakes are gone...
...just because of a piece of music.
Till they played that piece,
I forgot how I got into this thing.
Keep on playing it,
I don't think I'll ever forget again.
Chance, give me another shot at it...
...Stumpy can take the bottle away.
You heard him.
Bring it out, put it back.
Nobody ever asks me if I need a drink.
I ain't gonna wait for them to ask me,
because I do.
You two's enough to drive a man to it.
I think I'll go watch the road again.
Unless you need me for something else.
Did you forget this?
You could clean up a little.
Yeah, you're a heck of a looking deputy.
I'm better than I look.
I'll do that tonight.
If you think of it, send me some food.
I think I could eat something.
Nothing in his stomach.
Nothing but guts.
You can quit worrying about him
and start thinking about me.
We know about him.
He's gonna be all right, but I ain't.
That got my goat.
I can't watch a man get down.
Where're you going?
To get Dude something to eat.
And you'd better...
I know, get back in my hole.
No, you'd better watch out for Colorado
when he comes back.
I forgot to tell him
how trigger-happy you are.
We get a good man, he has to watch you
to keep from getting shot full of holes.
Close the window!
Still talking about that little accident
last night.
Never can satisfy him.
The sun is sinking in the West
The cattle go down to the stream
The red wing settles in her nest
It's time for her cowboy to dream
Purple light
In the canyon
That's where I long to be
With my sweet girl companion
Just my rifle, pony and me
Gonna hang my sombrero
On the limb of a tree
Coming home, sweetheart darling
Just my rifle, pony and me
Whippoorwill
In the willow
Sings a sweet melody
Riding to
Amarillo
Just my rifle, pony and me
- No more cows
- To be roping
- No more strays
- Will I see
Round the bend
She'll be waiting
- For my rifle, pony and me
- For my rifle, my pony
- And me
That's real pretty.
Go on, play some more.
Why don't you play something
I can sing with you?
I wish I was an apple
That's a good one.
Hanging in the tree
And every time my sweetheart'd pass
She'd take a bite of me
She told me that she loved me
She called me "sugar plum"
She threw her arms around me
I thought my time had come
Get along home, Cindy, Cindy
I'll marry you sometime
I wish I had a needle
As fine as I could sew
I'd sew her in my pocket
And down the road I go
Cindy hug and kiss me
She wrung her hands and cried
She swore I was the prettiest thing
That ever lived or died
Get along home, Cindy, Cindy
I'll marry you sometime
That's nice. Ain't it, Chance?
It's better than being out
in the street and getting shot at.
I can't argue with you.
- You're right, Stumpy.
- Right about what?
- I should have thought of it before.
- Thought about what?
Burdette's shown his hand.
He isn't gonna rush this jail.
Everything he's tried has been outside.
We could sit here and wait for the marshal.
Only be three or four days.
How much food you got, Stumpy?
Enough for all of us?
Yeah, if you can eat what I eat.
- Water and firewood?
- Filled up this morning.
We do need some blankets and tobacco,
and matches.
- Less you got plenty.
- He ain't.
- And a few bottles of beer, Dude?
- Thanks, Stumpy.
There's another thing now...
...if we're all gonna be in here
three or four days, close together like...
...it might be a good idea if a certain
party, not to mention no names was to...
...do what he said he'd do.
A horse barn's a good place but it ain't
a place for a fellow to roll around in.
All right, Stumpy.
Me, I like roses, but this fellow ain't
no rose this fellow I'm talking about.
I'm gonna take a bath. I said I would.
Dude, I never had no idea you wouldn't.
I was just wondering when.
He'll keep talking till we get out of here.
I'll take a bath
while you gather up the stuff.
Yell when you get back, because
you look different when you're clean.
How do you do that?
It's easy, Carlos.
You just weren't watching.
Carlos, open up.
Coming. Coming.
Buenos tardes, Señor Chance.
I think it is best to lock the door.
Yeah. Carlos, I'm sleeping
over at the jail tonight. All of us are.
We'll need some blankets,
plenty of tobacco, and matches.
- And some beer too.
- You feeling better?
Much better.
- That's all you need?
- That's all.
When you get the stuff together,
let us know. I'll be upstairs.
Now don't make any noise.
Open your mouth.
Hi, Feathers.
Have you got any soap
that smells like roses?
I have some soap,
but it doesn't smell like a rose.
Won't do. Won't do. Stumpy likes roses.
Who's Stumpy?
The fellow that likes roses.
No, he watches the jail.
- Hurry it up.
- Right away.
Yeah, what's all this
about moving down to the jail?
Something I should have done
two or three days ago.
Are you sorry you didn't?
Are you?
I know an easy way of telling you.
Can't you talk plainer than that?
Chance, give me a towel, will you?
- I'm busy.
- What'd you say?
Somebody's telling me something.
I can't hear...
Give me a towel, will you?
He's a big help.
I'll finish telling you later.
Purple light
The Dude went in to take a bath.
I couldn't see,
but I don't think he has his guns.
The sheriff's upstairs talking to the girl.
He has his gun.
I don't wanna go up and get him.
- Burdette wants him alive.
- Then don't talk so loud.
He'll come charging here with that rifle
and we'll have to kill him.
- That might just work.
- What?
The stairs are pretty dark.
We stretch a rope across them.
Let him hear something.
Give me that piece of rope.
Come on, give me a hand.
The sun is sinking in the West
- Hurry it up, will you?
- Be right out.
Well, if you're leaving,
I might as well get some sleep.
I don't suppose I could come by
the jail once in awhile...
- ...and see if you needed anything.
- I don't want you anyplace around there.
I was afraid of that.
That means I won't see you
for three or four days.
That's a long time, you know.
You'll live through it.
Yeah, you do the same.
All ready. You both better get out there.
You too, Pedro.
Leave the door open a little.
Get the gag out of her mouth.
Now, lady, we want you
to call the sheriff down here.
No! No!
Maybe this'll help.
Please don't. Don't!
- He's out cold.
- Get upstairs, quick!
- Hold it, Dude.
- Watch him.
Just keep coming, lady.
All right, everybody downstairs.
All right, get on your feet.
Come on, get up!
Can you walk?
- Where are we going?
- That's up to you.
We go to the jail and you let Joe go.
Or we tuck you two away
and make a trade with Stumpy.
Take your choice.
You won't make any deal with Stumpy.
- You'll just get Joe killed.
- Not if he knows we got you two.
Chance, they got us. We're licked.
Go on, take them over to the jail,
and tell Stumpy to open up and let Joe go.
- Are you out of your mind?
- I'm telling you to do it now.
Stumpy couldn't hold out. He hasn't got
water or food and he's all alone.
Nobody to get him any water.
Now go on, do it.
- Do you know what you're saying?
- I do.
I'm thinking good too.
Now do what I tell you.
And then after they get Joe,
what happens?
All we want is Joe.
- You still think it's a good idea?
- I still think it's good.
We'll go over to the jail.
Take the shells out of his gun.
I unloaded his pistol.
Steve, you and Harry come along with me.
Now look, sheriff,
we're going out of here natural-like.
You carry your gun
and don't do anything to make anybody...
...think something's wrong.
If you have to explain to Stumpy,
tell him we put up bail for Joe.
Burdette's got it figured out pretty good.
If it was up to me,
you'd have never got up off the floor.
Some of those you killed were
friends of mine.
Give him his rifle.
You first.
Hold it.
Yell to Stumpy you're coming in.
We've been watching you.
Stumpy, this is Chance.
It took you long enough.
Steve, cover from out here.
All right, open up.
We're gonna let Joe go.
How come?
His friends here put up bail.
Give me the keys then.
They're on your desk there.
I forgot.
Easy.
- This fellow'll talk all right.
- Watch him. I'm going after Dude.
You go along with him. I'll watch him.
Now watch yourself.
There's two of them holding Dude.
The window.
All right, Colorado.
- In here, Señor Chance.
- They've gone.
They took Dude
when they heard the shooting.
They went out the back door.
They had horses. I heard them.
They've gone all right.
We gonna go after them?
I told Nathan Burdette what'd happen
if he came after his brother.
You ought to remember that.
You thought it was funny.
What do you think he'd do
if we went after Dude?
I didn't think.
Think the shoe's on the other foot now.
The men who took Dude,
they were very angry.
They say Dude set a trap for them.
He sent them over there, all right.
He knew what he was doing.
Knew what Stumpy would do too.
That's why they're not happy about it.
- What're you gonna do?
- It's what Burdette'll do.
Carlos. Get ahold of Burdette.
I don't care how.
Tell him I wanna talk to him.
Tell him to set the time and the place.
But I wanna talk to him.
We'll be at the jail.
Aren't you sorry now
you didn't get on the stage?
Come on, Colorado.
Let's wake up the Chinaman again.
Señor Chance. It's me, Carlos.
What's the matter? What'd he say?
He say he don't wanna talk to you.
He say if you want Dude back,
he'll make a trade.
- A trade?
- Dude for Joe.
He'll be in his place over by the creek.
- The... What you call...?
- Warehouse?
He'll be there half an hour after sunup.
He'll have Dude.
If you'll bring Joe, he'll be waiting.
He said to let him know.
Tell him we'll be there.
Chance! You're crazy! You can't do that!
- Not even if Dude was your own brother.
- What can I do?
What we figured on doing.
Hole up till the marshal comes.
When the marshal takes Joe,
what'll happen to Dude?
Dude knew what he was in for
when he sent you over here.
I'd like to add my two
cents worth, sheriff.
Go ahead.
From what I hear,
you and Dude are the only witnesses.
Let's say we're the only ones
that'll talk.
After Nathan gets Joe back,
he's still got to live here.
Which means you two can't, and
if you don't have Joe, what'll stop him?
The brakes'll be off then.
That ought to be as plain
as the nose on your face.
You're right, Colorado.
But you and Stumpy didn't see the killing.
I don't think he'll bother you two.
- I'm not worried.
- Me neither.
You'll just wait for the marshal to come.
- He's still gonna want you and Dude.
- I'd say so.
You can't get out of town
because he's got it bottled up.
When you make the trade then
Burdette's gonna get the both of you.
After a little argument.
- But why at all? Why the both of you?
- Dude ought to have a chance.
He won't get one the other way. Will he?
Will he?
You're gonna have me crying.
Fellow's gotta be a drunk to get anywhere
around here. I might as well start now.
Go ahead, Carlos.
Well...
Burdette's here.
About time to go.
How about I go ahead,
see if they'll play any tricks?
Look out here.
We're drawing quite a crowd.
There won't be any tricks.
At least not till we make the trade.
Besides, you're not going.
When you decided to make the trade
for Dude, I went along with you.
I'm going along now.
Why?
Let's just say I'd like a closer look.
Up to now I thought you were smart.
Stumpy, you're not going.
Why? Why ain't I going?
Give me one good reason why.
I'll give you one.
You've done a good job in here because
you haven't had to move around much.
But out there if anything happens,
you'll have to move, and move fast.
I'd feel better if you weren't there.
It's plain enough.
Old cripples ain't wanted.
Well, you give me a reason.
Now, do you want that I should bring
Joe out, or you wanna do that yourself?
Bring him out.
I think I'll take along a rifle,
some extra shells.
Yeah.
I told you I'd get out of here.
Open your mouth again
and we'll carry you out.
See you, Stumpy.
See you.
That's far enough, Joe.
Through the barn.
Just sit down over there
on those grain sacks.
You want a closer look?
This is close enough.
Take that window.
Watch Joe.
Burdette!
Nathan Burdette!
We're ready. Joe's here.
We're ready too.
Start Dude.
I'll start Joe.
Go ahead.
All right, Joe.
You can start walking very slow.
And stop if I say stop...
...or I'll stop you.
Bring him out.
Go ahead.
Slow.
Look out!
You want me to go help Dude?
He'll take Joe all right.
He's got a strange way of doing it.
He'll take him.
You're right. He did.
Hey, Chance, I got Joe.
He can't walk, but I can drag him.
Stay right where you are.
We'll throw you a gun.
I'll do it. I'm closer.
Wait till we start shooting, Dude,
then make a grab for it.
Let's make a little noise, Colorado.
That ought to start something.
It will.
On your left!
Two of them made it to that shack.
If they get across that creek, we'll be
in bad shape. They'll get behind us.
I don't know how
we're gonna stop them from here.
Is that who I think it is?
Old Stumpy.
The fellow I left behind.
Hey, Señor Chance.
Don't shoot, it's me.
Carlos, what are you doing here?
I bring you some more shells.
You might need them, señor.
Who'll turn up next?
Maybe the girl with another flowerpot.
Chance, Stumpy's sitting in a bad place.
That wagon's got dynamite in it.
I go tell him, señor.
You stay here. I'll go get him.
Give me those shells.
Stumpy, get out of there.
No. Come on, I got a front seat.
It's a good one.
You got a good seat, all right.
That's wagon's full of dynamite.
Jumping Jehoshaphat.
Why don't nobody never tell me nothing?
Get away from that wagon
or you won't be around to hear anything.
Stumpy, hurry up! What are you doing?
What do you think I'm doing?
Taking a siesta?
I brung us some dynamite.
That's a good idea.
Let's get farther away from that wagon.
Can you shoot
as good as you say you can?
- Can you throw?
- Near as far as you can shoot.
We'll find out. Get that box open.
Dude!
Over here.
Get ready.
Let her go!
That was a good one.
Oh, stop cackling.
Get one a little farther out there.
There you go again!
What would you do
if I wasn't throwing them for you?
I'd throw them myself.
Yeah, I guess you would at that.
You ready?
Let her go.
Hey, Dude, how do you like them apples?
Hey, that's all right.
Throw one for me.
Go ahead, but throw it harder this time.
There you go again.
You never can satisfy you.
Throw it!
Here you are, Dude.
Took you two.
I didn't allow for the wind.
Can't you throw them any farther?
I can if you wanna blow
the whole place down.
That's the general idea. Throw it!
Don't shoot. We've had enough.
That got them.
That took the fight out of them.
Look at them quit!
Sure is quiet out there.
Did you find anything?
There isn't a Burdette man left in town
outside of those who got locked up.
Rest of them all cleared out.
We won't have any trouble.
- You're welcome.
- Thank you.
What do you wanna do about them?
Want to take them to Presidio
or wait for the marshal?
- We'll wait for the marshal.
- Wait for the marshal?
I'm glad you agree, since you have
to cook for them and watch them.
That ain't the way I said it.
I said, "Wait for the marshal?"
And that's a question.
I'm fed up feeding them.
I ain't gonna watch them neither.
I've been sitting back there so long
in the dark that I feel...
...like a gopher or a burrowing owl
or something.
When I went outside,
couldn't hardly see in the daylight.
I'll watch them for you
if you wanna go out.
- Would you?
- Sure.
I guess it's dark enough I can go outside,
it wouldn't hurt my eyes none.
I don't think it would.
Maybe get myself slicked up a smidge and
have a drink, it wouldn't hurt me neither.
I don't think it would.
Well, should I go?
Go ahead.
- You ain't gonna give me an argument?
- No.
Don't care whether I go or not.
- Chance.
- Yeah?
Have you seen that girl yet?
I said, have you seen that girl yet?
No, I...
The job.
Didn't have time.
Well, the Fort Worth stage is in.
They run at night.
Should be leaving soon.
- You mean she's going on it?
- I don't know.
I don't think you do either.
But if it was me, I'd find out.
I wouldn't walk around wondering about it.
She might be leaving and she might not.
She might need help making up her mind.
But you're the expert.
Me, I don't know anything about women.
Next thing you'll be telling me
you don't remember one.
Well, a man forgets.
Sometimes...
Sometimes it isn't easy.
Something happens, he just forgets.
In case you're interested, I have.
I don't even want a drink.
It's about time.
I was getting awful tired
of taking care of you.
If you wanna jump in,
I'll take care of you.
What is this now?
You're gonna take care of him.
- Tell me about it.
- Sheriff's got himself a girl.
Shut up.
We ain't gonna go through that again?
You gonna do the same thing Dude done?
- Keep still.
- Why don't somebody tell me these things?
- Where you going? Where you going?
- Let him go, Stumpy.
No fooling,
has the sheriff got himself a girl?
I think so, but he doesn't know it yet.
- She got him on the run?
- She sure has.
I can just see him.
Laying down the law to her.
"I told you to get back in there!"
And then getting told off hisself.
Señor Chance.
Everything is all right?
- I am so happy.
- Thank you, Consuelo.
You look for the girl?
She's in there.
"No got time."
Hi, John T.
Just a second while I get my shoe tied.
There.
Well, it's all over, isn't it, John T.?
Where'd you get those things?
I wore them the last place I worked.
Well, why are you wearing them now?
Tonight's a big night.
Consuelo thought
a little entertainment might help.
I'm gonna do a song.
You need a rig like that to sing?
You haven't heard me sing.
My legs aren't so bad.
Consuelo thought these tights might help.
But you don't like them.
- I didn't say that.
- You don't want me to wear them.
I didn't say that either.
- Is it because they show so much of me?
- They certainly do that.
You're a stubborn, stubborn man, John T.
Sometimes I know what you're thinking.
And other times...
You just can't make up
your mind about me, can you?
You like what you see.
You like kissing me.
You like what you touch.
But you decided in the beginning
what kind of a girl I was.
And I haven't helped much.
I wore these before I met you.
I wanted you to know it.
To know what kind of a girl
you were getting.
I wanted you to get that funny look
on your face and tell me not to wear them.
But it didn't work.
You didn't even get mad.
I told you once
you wouldn't have to say anything.
That I'd know, but I don't know.
So you're gonna have to talk.
I'm hard to get, John T.
You're gonna have to say you want me.
- Where you going?
- Downstairs.
You better not.
Why had I better not?
Because I'm still sheriff.
You wear those things in public,
I'll arrest you.
John T.
I've waited so long for you to say that.
I thought you were never...
You have the funniest way
of saying things.
Just when I think
you're gonna say one thing...
Get those darn things off.
I'll wait outside.
No, you don't have to go.
I can use this screen.
Besides I want you to stay here...
...because the other thing is all over now,
isn't it?
I'm trying to hurry, but I'm all thumbs.
What I had to go through!
Put on these tights,
ask a lot of questions...
...start to walk out.
I thought you were never gonna say it.
- Say what?
- That you loved me.
I said I'd arrest you.
It means the same thing, you know that.
You just won't say it.
Oh, we're different.
I'll have to get used to you.
Me, I just talk all the time.
You most certainly do.
You'll get used to that. You'll have to.
Either that or start talking too.
Tell me something.
These tights, now why didn't you
want me to wear them?
Because I didn't want anybody
but me to see you in them.
Oh, I like that.
You're getting better already.
Shall I...? Shall I save them
and wear them just for you?
Do you think I'll ever
get to be a sheriff?
Not unless you mind
your own business.
[ENGLISH]