Downloaded from
YTS.MX
( piano music )
Official YIFY movies site:
YTS.MX
- Our Father, which art
in heaven...
( yawns )
♪ The other day a friend
of mine said, he said ♪
♪ That God's not
even with us ♪
♪ He said that God
is really dead ♪
♪ He said, oh, pal,
a fact's a fact ♪
♪ You can't believe
that magic act ♪
♪ I said, I don't,
and that was that ♪
♪ Now I say, good for God ♪
♪ Good for God ♪
♪ He goes and makes
the planet blue ♪
♪ And all the thanks
he gets from you ♪
♪ Just look at all that
poo-poo in the yard ♪
♪ Good for God ♪
♪ I bet His life up there
is very hard ♪
♪ He knows each time
a sparrow falls ♪
♪ But who can answer
all His calls ♪
♪ Good for God ♪
♪ I bet He's got
a very hard job ♪
♪ Ain't got no Mama ♪
♪ Ain't got no Papa ♪
♪ Good for God. ♪
( snoring )
( alarm rings )
( rooster yawns )
( rooster clears throat )
( rooster crows )
( snoring )
- Hmm?
Good morning, God.
It's me, Ambrose.
Oops. Oh, dear
Sorry I'm a bit behind today,
but the rooster went off late.
Thank You for sparing me
for another day.
But, of course, that goes
without saying, doesn't it?
Except it doesn't, You see,
because in Your book,
it commands us to give
constant thanks day and night.
I can't imagine why You'd want
anyone to keep thanking You
for all eternity,
I mean, day and night.
I should-- I should think You'd
be bored with it by now.
I know I would.
I mean, it's not as if
You're insecure or anything,
or even as if You had
an identity problem.
I mean, after all,
You made me in Your
own image, didn't You?
I can't imagine You looking
like that somehow.
Still...
You made me on the
morning of the sixth day.
That was Saturday.
Well, You might have had
a rough Friday night.
Who knows?
Anyway, can't stand around
here talking.
You don't wanna hear
my problems.
I'm sure You've got
problems of Your own.
So, uh, I'll see
You tomorrow, eh?
I mean, I'll be here,
and, uh, well, I'll know
You'll be there.
If, um, I'm not here,
well, I'll be there.
By the way, uh, have
a nice day and amen.
Oof.
( snoring )
( coughing, yawning )
( fly buzzes )
- Shh.
( muffled scream )
( church bell rings )
( shoes creak )
( knuckles crack )
( belly grumbles )
( church bell rings )
( monks moaning, coughing )
( sighing )
( monks chanting )
- Oh, there you are, Ambrose.
Tell me something.
You are happy here,
aren't you?
Hmm?
You are happy.
Oh, I beg your pardon.
I forgot.
Yes, of course, you have my
permission to speak, of course.
- I think I'm happy, Father.
I don't know.
It's-- it's the only world
I've ever known.
- I think it's glorious at
your age and still celibate.
- I was celibate again last
night, Father.
- Good, who with?
- Myself, three times.
- Oh, careful.
Four would be pride.
- No. No,
I'm happy here, Father.
It's my-- it's my home.
- You never wished to visit
another world?
You-- you never think
you'd like to know
what's going on
outside these walls?
- Father, why-- why are you
asking me all this now?
- 'Cause we're sending you
on a mission, out there.
- Oh, why-- why-- why me?
- Well, you see,
we've fallen on hard times.
And when we renounced
the material world,
and we ask God for nothing,
and in His benevolence,
He gave us nothing
immediately and ever since.
- But Father, we-- we--
we took a vow of poverty.
- Oh, we know.
The price of poverty's
gone up.
We can't afford the luxury
of being poor anymore.
Besides, the landlords, they
want $5,000 off the mortgage.
- But where can we get
that kind of money, Father?
We-- we live by charity.
- You're going to save us.
You are going
to get us the money.
- How-- how could I?
How...
- I'll tell you how.
You go and visit
Armageddon T. Thunderbird.
Armageddon T. Thunderbird,
he's a holy man,
a philanthropist,
gives money to worthy causes.
You state your case well,
and you'll get the money.
There's his address.
- Father,
I'm-- I'm-- I'm afraid.
I've never been outside.
I'm-- I'm not worthy.
I mean--
- Well, then you'll have
to have some money.
I'll give you $50.
That's all we've got.
There you are.
You take it.
- Ca-- Can I have time
to think it over?
- Yes, my son, you'll have
plenty of time to think
about it.
- You see, Father,
I've just never been inside
the outside world.
And--
Help!
( knocks on door )
Let me in.
I'm innocent.
- Bless you, my son.
Thank you for making
the right decision.
- Let me in.
- God bless, God speed.
Vaya con Dios.
- Please, Father.
- Have a nice day.
- Let me in.
( Ambrose cries )
- Whoa!
( yells )
( panting )
( vehicle approaches )
( honks )
( tires screech )
( bells chime )
- Greetings,
companion in Christ.
Yes, I'm talkin'
to you, Jim.
Is it not written that
those who are cast down
shall be raised up?
Arise and behold.
( bell rings )
The chariot of
the Lord awaiteth.
Haul thine ass aboard.
- Oh, thank you.
( bus backfires )
- This really is
very kind of you.
- Dr. Sebastian Melmoth,
evangelist, doctor of divinity,
wandering scholar,
licensed purveyor of
religious novelties.
- Oh, Father Ambrose, monk.
- Welcome to my church.
- This really is a church then?
- Ah, yes, a traveling church.
- My goodness.
- Like the missionaries of old,
I sally forth across the land,
laying the word
on the good people.
- That sounds wonderful.
- Ah, then would you care
for a blast, my son?
- Uh.
- It's a fine holy wine.
I-- I--
oh, you'll be amused
by its humility.
- Uh, no thanks.
No, uh, I never drink, except
of course after the wafer.
- Ah.
Quite right.
Unwise to celebrate
the Lord on an empty stomach.
( car honks )
( yelling )
- Same to you, fella.
- Up thine, and thy mother's,
and thy mother's mother's.
- Peace.
- Ah, Aha, yes.
- You're bound, I take it,
for the city of Los Angeles.
- Yeah.
- Ah, yes, the City
of lost angels,
so many wonderful
sinners there.
♪ Onward Christian
soldiers ♪
♪ Marching on to war ♪
♪ With the cross
of Jesus ♪
♪ Marching on before... ♪
( bus backfires )
- Oh, yes, you will.
The Lord's work
is never done.
Right there. Good.
Move 'em.
Here we go.
Right there.
This is as far as I go.
- Thank you, Dr. Melmoth.
You've been very kind.
- Ha ha.
Don't mention it.
Oh, do me a favor, will you,
and help these tired old legs.
Pick it up, will you, please?
- Certainly, Dr. Melmoth.
- Freeze.
Don't move a muscle.
I don't want your money,
my son.
No, I'm not interested
in material things.
- What are you talking about?
W--
- Shut up and don't argue.
If I see human suffering,
it is my duty to help
if I can without thought to
material or personal gain.
And now, my son, how long have
you been thus afflicted?
- Afflicted? I-- what-- what
are you talkin' about?
( muffled speech )
- Since childhood.
Now I claim no powers
for myself.
The Lord works
through my hand.
- Hey...
- I will make this wretched
creature walk upright.
Do you feel the power
coursing through you?
Do you feel the electricity?
- Let me go, please.
Please let me go.
- Ooh, do you believe?
Ooh, do you believe?
- Let me--
- Out devil spirit, heal.
( crowd gasps )
- See? He stands.
Oh, Jesus, it's a miracle.
He stands up straight.
Take your money, son.
The Lord doesn't want it.
He doesn't need it.
He's made you whole.
Praise the Lord.
Walk in the Lord, my son.
( crowd murmurs )
- Walk, run, beat it.
It's a miracle.
Step right up, sinners.
Take a miracle
home with you.
Get your levitating
Lazarus doll.
See him rise from the dead in
the privacy of your own home.
- Hello, kiddies,
I'm Lazarus.
I'm alive again.
Why don't you
stand up for Jesus?
( music plays )
- ♪ The other day
a friend of mine said ♪
♪ He said that God's
not even with us ♪
♪ He said that God
is really dead ♪
♪ He said, oh, pal,
a fact's a fact ♪
♪ You can't believe
that magic act ♪
♪ I said, I don't,
and that was that ♪
♪ Now I said good for God ♪
♪ Good for God ♪
( chanting )
♪ He goes and
makes this planet blue ♪
♪ And all the thanks
He gets from you ♪
♪ Is look at all
that poo-poo in the yard ♪
♪ Good for God ♪
♪ I bet His life
up there was very hard ♪
♪ He knows each time
a sparrow falls ♪
♪ But who can answer
all His calls ♪
♪ Good for God ♪
- Also, we must wait
for the son to return
before we can have...
- ♪ Good for God ♪
♪ I bet He's got
a very hard job... ♪
- Unh.
- ♪ I'm awfully glad
I'm here to say ♪
♪ He made it possible for me
to be here this day ♪
♪ Good for God ♪
Instrumental...
- ♪ Good for God... ♪
- ♪ Good Lord... ♪
- ♪ Now if true is true ♪
♪ It's easier
to know the truth ♪
♪ That's the truth
So help me God ♪
♪ Good for God ♪
♪ Say good for God ♪
( gasps )
( screams )
- Uh, excuse me, sir, you
dropped your photo--
your photos--
They aren't mine.
They-- they were his.
They were his.
I-- I wouldn't-- I mean,
I-- oh, my God.
- ♪ Good for God ♪
♪ Now if true is true ♪
♪ And it's easy
if you know the truth ♪
♪ That's the truth
So help me God ♪
♪ Good for God ♪
♪ Say good for God ♪
♪ He's got a hard job ♪
♪ Before they put me
in a hole ♪
♪ I think I gotta find
a big loophole ♪
♪ Good for me ♪
♪ And good for God ♪
( police sirens blaring )
( chattering, shouting )
( car horn honks )
- Father.
Father.
- I-- I'm not a Father.
I'm a Brother, sister.
What is it you want?
- The sanctuary of the church.
- Huh?
Oh.
What are you doing
under there?
- It's all right.
I was brought up in a convent.
Just hide me till
the cops go by.
Are they still there?
- Yes.
- Right. Look casual
and keep walking.
( Ambrose hums )
( Ambrose whistles )
- ♪ Every time it rains, it
rains pennies from heaven ♪
♪ Do, do, da, loo, do ♪
♪ Don't you know each cloud
contains pennies from heaven? ♪
♪ Do, do, da, loo, do... ♪
- And then the confusion,
and-- and the noise.
And-- and people running about.
Well, I've never seen--
oh, well, maybe you have,
but I've never seen anything
like this in my life.
And-- and then the way we met,
I mean, the way I met you--
or rather way you met--
the way you met me, I mean.
- Oh, my God.
- What?
- Oh, no.
I just realized how awful
it must have been for you
when I dived under
your robe like that.
- Well, it was a bit strange.
I mean, I've never met
a woman in my life before,
let alone had one
on the, uh, premises,
if you know
what I mean.
- Oh, come on.
- No, honestly.
No, I've seen, uh,
pictures in the Bible.
But they wear these
loose flowing robes
and you can't tell
what they've got underneath.
See, that-- not like
with you.
I mean, with-- with you,
I can get some idea
what you've got.
I-- I mean, you've got
legs and-- and bumpy bits.
- What?
- Um, those things, you know.
- Oh, you mean my boobies?
- Uh-huh. Mm-hmm.
- What about them?
- Nothing.
I-- I think they look
very well on you.
They suit you.
- You really do?
- Oh, yeah.
- 'Cause I always thought they
were kinda on the smallish side.
You know what I mean?
- Oh, not to me.
Uh, they're bigger
than mine.
- Well...
- No, they look huge-- huge.
- Really?
Gee, it's a very nice
thing to say.
- No.
- No, it really is.
But, then again,
what do you know?
- That's true.
Would you, um, like a taste?
- Mmm.
- Good?
- Think it needs
a little more mustard, eh?
- No.
- Just--
- It is just right.
You really are
an innocent, aren't you?
- I suppose so.
- It's touching.
It really is.
It's touching,
in a disgusting kind of way.
- See, I know a lot about
the theory of sin.
But I don't know anything
about the practice.
I mean, for instance,
fornication.
- What?
- The Bible's full of it.
You mustn't do it.
It's sinful.
You'll go to hell.
But it doesn't tell
you how to do it.
So how do you know you're not?
I mean, for all I know,
I might be sitting here
right now fornicating.
( Mary snickers )
- No, you're not.
If you were, I'd tell you.
- Mm-hmm. Thanks.
That couple over there sucking
each other's mouth, a-- are--
- Would you keep it
down a little bit?
- Oh, sorry.
Uh, are-- are
they fornicating?
- They're kissing.
They're just kissing.
- Kissing.
- That's phase one.
- Ah.
- See, now-- now when
they get home,
they'll probably move
into phase two.
- Oh, you fornicate
in phases.
- Oh, yeah, that is, if
you're not pressed for time.
- Ah.
- See, sex-- sex
is very much like a meal.
I'll show you.
See this menu?
If you were gonna order
a meal, right?
- Mm-hmm.
- You wouldn't go right for
the main course, would you?
Wouldn't you like to have
a little appetizer first?
- Maybe.
- You know, like, uh,
a little chopped liver?
- Oh, uh-huh.
- It's an appetizer.
That's kissing.
That's what kissing is.
Chopped liver.
- Chopped liver.
- Mm-hmm, yeah.
Yeah, that's all.
- Chopped liver.
- Good. Chopped liver.
- Number one, chopped liver.
Phase one.
- Phase one.
- I wonder-- I wonder if you
would do me a great favor.
- What?
- Well, you see, if all these
phases lead to fornication,
um, would you mind writing
down all the things
that I must avoid,
in the right order?
If it's not too much trouble.
- Oh, no, listen,
I'd be glad to do it.
Um, now what you want--you
want a list here, right?
- Mm-hmm.
Mm-hmm.
- Of everything you're
not supposed to do.
- Everything to avoid.
- Okay.
Um, well, number one...
- Yeah?
- Um, number one,
we went through it already,
is kissing, right?
- Kissing.
- Right?
So-- right, kissing.
Now, number two,
take hold of the, uh...
- Bumpy bits.
- Yeah. Shh.
Take it, but not like that.
You could hurt
someone like that.
It's not a claw.
It's a very gentle
kind of movement.
You know, it's like
a very caressing...
Mmm. Mmm.
- Mmm.
- Oh, that's very nice.
- Mmm, that's good.
That's good.
Okay.
Number two, right.
- Mmm.
- No, it's okay.
You can stop that.
Just keep it to yourself.
Okay?
- I-- I've got it.
- Take hold of the bits.
I'll just put-- you'll
remember, right?
- Okay.
- Now, number three...
- Yeah.
- Now, number three
is very technical.
- Yeah.
- So I'm gonna draw you a
diagram in number three, okay?
- Now, this is
a picture of a woman.
- Aha. Yes.
I can see the bumpy bits.
- No, those are
the puffed sleeves.
She's wearing a dress.
- Oh.
- And then you make love.
I don't know why you always
get that one wrong.
- Oh.
- You get into bed first.
- Bed.
- Then make love.
- Oh.
- Use your logic on that one.
- So my 74 goes where my 75 was.
- Yes.
'Cause, you know, making love's
supposed to be spontaneous.
Why do you think there
are hundreds of books out
on how to do it right?
Well, this is where I live.
- Oh. Oh, good night.
- Yeah.
Uh, where you staying tonight?
- Oh, I don't know.
I'll find somewhere.
- Sure you'll be all right?
- Oh, yeah.
I've got lots of money.
The Abbott gave me
more than $50.
I have--
No more.
- What?
- No, it's nothing.
- Okay. Bye.
- Good night.
( water running )
( Mary hums )
- Number one,
chopped liver, kissing.
( kisses )
Number two,
mmm, mmm, mmm.
Number three--
number three was...
( chuckles )
Oh, so many things
to remember to avoid.
Hello, God,
it's me, Ambrose.
Sorry to bother You,
but if You wanted us
to ignore fleshly sins,
why did You make us
out of meat?
I mean, You could have
made us out of anything.
You could have made us
out of burlap, or rubber,
or wood, Jell-O, anything.
( sighs )
I know.
You work in mysterious ways.
Be we don't.
Human beings, I mean.
- Tomorrow night,
I'll take you
to see Armageddon T.
Thunderbird if you want.
By the way, what's your name?
- Ambrose.
- Good night, Ambrose.
My name is Mary.
- Mary?
( grunts )
I can't stand it anymore.
Can't stand it.
( shower running )
- What are you doing in there?
- The Abbot said
if everything else fails,
cold shower will do it.
Bumpy bits.
Mmm. Mmm.
Ooh. Ooh.
( organ music plays )
- Heh.
With a chicken.
( laughing )
Get out of here,
you filthy swine.
Out.
Next.
Serving number 12.
Kneel down and
make it snappy.
Cut the frills and get
straight to the meat
and potatoes.
- Forgive me, Father,
for I have sinned.
- Yes, yes.
( hearing aid whines )
Oh-- oh, won't you wh--
whine to me about it.
You want to whine about this,
and you whine about that.
And the, uh, oh.
ah, death and transfiguration.
Don't worry about me.
Uh, if you'll just start,
and I'll get the--
I'll get the general drift.
- Last night, Father, I was
tormented by an impure thought.
- I can't hear you.
- I said I was tormented
by an impure thought.
- Could you-- could you
speak up, please?
- I-- it was about Mary.
- What? Louder.
- Mary, I wanted
to take her clothes off.
- You wanted to do what? Speak
up. I can't hear you!
- I wanted to take
her clothes off.
You are mumbling!
- I wanted to take
her clothes off
and caress her bumpy bits.
- Her what?
- Bits.
Fondly, you know, mmm.
- What?
- You know, number three.
And then I wanted
to try number 30.
Or-- or-- or maybe do
number 15 twice instead.
And then I wanted
to take her by the...
( horns honking )
And...
( car horns honking )
Both her-- again and again
until I was exhausted.
But I'm a monk, Father.
What shall I do?
- I didn't hear
a damned word you said.
That'll be, uh...
- I'm afraid
I only have, uh...
- Two dollars.
Here, I will have that.
Uh, have a nice day.
( parishioners muttering )
( clears throat )
( cheering )
- Do you believe in God?
- Announcer: The Church
of Divine Profit
humbly presents
the Armageddon T. Thunderbird
Crusade.
And here he is,
God's buddy, A.T.T. himself.
- Do you love God?
- Yes!
- I mean, do you
really love God?
- Yes!
- Has He been good to you?
- Yes.
- I thought so.
And have you been good to Him?
- Yes.
- Oh, really?
- Liars.
- No!
- 'Cause I just spoke to Him,
and do you have any idea
where He is right now?
- No.
- God is in the hospital.
( crowd gasping )
- In the Intensive Care Unit.
And do you know
who put Him there?
- No.
- Y-O-U.
( crowd shouting )
- He-- he looked so pale.
( crying )
- Why are you cryin'?
Isn't that what you wanted?
- No!
- Do you wanna see Him
pull through?
- Yes!
- All right.
I said to Him, I am
your servant, Lord.
What do You want?
Everything, Armageddon,
everything.
I need money to put it right.
But what will You give them
in return? I queried.
And then He said, I will
assure them a place forever
in the kingdom of heaven.
( applause )
- And that's--
and that's rent free.
Now, doesn't that sound
like a good deal?
- Yeah!
- Well, then put thy money
where is thy mouth.
And I'm not just
askin' the people here
in the studio audience.
I'm askin' you,
you, and you.
( music plays )
- ♪ In God we trust ♪
♪ Invest in Him on high ♪
♪ God's sweetest buy ♪
♪ Is in the by-and-by ♪
♪ Each buck you give ♪
♪ Shall be tax free therefore ♪
♪ And shall returneth thee ♪
♪ Ten thousandfold, oh, yes ♪
♪ Ten thousandfold. ♪
( chattering )
- I didn't understand a word
he was talking about.
Supposed to be a Christian.
I-- I don't understand.
- This is awfully confusing
for you, isn't it?
- It is a bit.
- Well, I think you've had
a big day.
And I think you should go
to sleep now, okay?
You look sweet in pink.
- Mmm.
I'm gonna go
and see him tomorrow.
- You're gonna go
see Armageddon?
- Mm-hmm.
When he understands,
he'll help.
( Mary sighs )
- Poor Ambrose.
I wonder if God will ever
forgive you your virtues.
- Excuse me.
( shower running )
- Good afternoon.
I'd-- I'd like to see
Mr. Thunderbird. I--
- Not today.
He's too busy.
- No. I-- I have
this letter from--
from the Abbot.
- Get out of here.
- I'm-- I'm one of the meek.
I'm supposed
to inherit the Earth.
- You've got it.
- You just don't understand,
Ambrose.
- I understand
I don't understand.
But what
don't I understand?
- Well, the meek may inherit
the Earth but not
until the strong
are finished with it.
And by that time, it won't
even be worth having.
- I'll get in
to see him finally.
- But it could take weeks.
- I'll get a job
in the meantime.
Look, is there anything
in the paper?
- Oh, look, Ambrose, listen.
- What?
- You don't need to work.
I mean, look,
you could come
and stay at my place, right?
I really do make enough
money for both of us.
- W-- what do you do?
- What?
- Well, for a living,
what do you do?
- Oh, uh, I wouldn't
even concern myself about
that if I were you.
- Well, maybe you could get me
a job doing it with you.
- Well, I could look into it.
- I'm good with my hands.
( chattering in Spanish )
( hammering )
( bell rings )
- Hey. Hey.
Come back.
Dr. Melmoth.
Philistine.
- All right, monk.
- All right. I'm going.
- Hi. You look so nauseous.
- Thanks, but I feel rotten.
- Oh, Ambrose, how many times
you gonna keep on trying?
- Well, till I get
in and see him.
You see, if I could show him
the Abbot's letter,
and then I'd--
- I got an idea.
Couldn't you just pray
to God for the money?
- No, no.
No, ask for money, and
you spoil a friendship.
No, I've gotta see
him personally.
Mr. Thunderbird
will understand.
He's a Christian.
- No, being born in a Christian
home doesn't necessarily
make you Christian any
more than being born
in a bakery
makes you a bagel.
- Hmm?
- I mean, maybe Mr. Thunderbird
just isn't even interested
in your old monastery.
- No, no. If I could get in
to see him personally,
I'll get in eventually.
I'll get in. I'll get in.
- But it could take months.
- All right.
In the meantime, I can
just get another job.
I mean, what can I lose?
- Nothing, just another job.
- ♪ Every time it rains,
it rains pennies from heaven ♪
♪ Oh, do, dee, da ♪
♪ Every time, do, dee, da,
da, dee, la, da, da ♪
♪ Oh, dee, dee, dum, da, dum,
dum, da, dee, da, dum, dum... ♪
- Good morning.
- Oh, good morning.
- Don't you ever rest?
- I can't afford
to lose time.
It's Pasadena
by next Wednesday.
That's my schedule.
You know, a man's got
to have a goal.
Otherwise,
we've got communism.
And I'm tap dancing to keep
this great land of ours free.
I'll see you sometime.
- Good luck.
- So long.
- Step right up.
Step up, sinners.
Step right up and repent.
Do not cop a plea unto
the Almighty, saying,
oh, Lord,
I'm but a poor sinner.
For the Lord will say unto
thee, bullshit, my child.
His eye is on the sparrow,
so you can bet your ass
He's got you covered, Jim,
and you and you.
So step right up and find
the Lord, a buck a throw.
Yes, the Lord
is here in my hand.
Everyone wants
to find the Lord.
The Lord goes into hiding.
And those who seek
him will find him.
Where is he now?
Try thy luck.
Find the Lord.
Who will find the Lord?
It's a wonderful game.
Everybody wins.
Everybody goes to heaven.
Try thy luck, a lousy buck
to find the Lord.
Aha.
Ah, yes, sir,
and now where is he?
Oh, no, I'm sorry.
The Lord is not there,
but a blessing to you, too.
The game continues.
Try thy luck.
- Dr. Melmoth.
He stole my money.
- Excuse me.
- He's a thief.
- This man is a heretic.
Don't listen to him.
He's obviously deranged.
- Stop him. Stop him.
He's a thief.
Give me my money back.
- Get outta here.
Fanatic.
Vegetarian!
I'll keep up
the Lord's work.
- Oh, oof.
- And get away from me.
Get away from me, you Moabite,
you snake worshipper.
Ah. Ooh.
And a holy man such as yourself
should descend to violence.
( Ambrose grunts )
- In the name-- in the name
of all that's sacred,
let me up,
you little asshole.
- You should be disgusted
with yourself.
- Oh, I am.
I am. I am.
Pray for me.
Let thy hand,
which is raised in violence,
clasp its brother and,
in heavenly supplication,
even as I do,
Father, forgive him, for he
knoweth not what he doeth.
Forgive me even more,
for I knoweth.
( grunts )
- Take that, monk.
( bus engine starts )
- Wait for me.
Stop. Wait for me!
Of course I forgive you.
But I still don't know
what I'm doing here.
- Well, look, I'm-- I'm offering
you the chance of a lifetime,
a full partnership
in my church for nothing.
- Why me?
- Because you have
a certain quality,
a kind of eerie innocence.
People look at you,
and they have to believe
there's a better
world somewhere.
Besides, I'm slowing down.
- Well, could I make enough
money to save the monastery?
I need $5,000.
- But, of course.
- What have I got to lose?
- Partners.
- Ha.
( "I've Been Working
On the Railroad" plays )
( horn honks )
( chatter )
- Ambrose, hi.
What are you doing here?
- Well, thought we could go
out tonight and celebrate.
- I just can't.
( horn honks )
Listen, I'm really sorry.
But it's just, you know,
Friday night.
And then, you know,
it's my big night.
And I just...
( honking continues )
I-- I couldn't-- I mean,
I couldn't just-- I mean,
I'm not dressed to go
anywhere, you know.
- Look.
You look-- you look lovely.
- Oh, Ambrose,
that is so beautiful.
- Shall we go?
- I'm sorry. I can't.
- Yeah, I understand.
I mean, if you'd rather
be here with your friends,
well, hey, that's okay.
I can...
- I'll see you later, okay?
- See you later. Yeah.
- Okay. I'll see you later.
- Okay.
( honking )
- Where are we going?
- Oh, well, it's bingo night at
the all-night mission, and I--
- I've had it now.
Come on.
It's all right.
Come on, baby.
- Stop it!
- Come on.
- No, you stop that.
- Excuse me, sir.
That was very rude.
I'm sure you didn't
mean it.
Now, according to,
uh, Timothy,
chapter 2, verse 25,
be gentle unto all men.
But, of course,
that means all women, too.
( grunts )
- Oh, what are you doing to him?
- Perhaps you prefer
St. Matthew.
Thou shalt love thy enemies.
In other words,
do unto others as you would
have them do unto you.
- You wouldn't wish me
to do this unto you.
- Take the gospel
according to St. Mark.
Now, it isn't me
you're hurting. It's you.
It's your soul that's in pain,
your immortal soul.
Excuse me, sir.
On the other hand, there's
the Old Testament.
David and Goliath.
- You just don't really
understand is that
you can't always have everything
just the way you want it.
You know, it may not be
the best of all possible worlds,
but it's the only
damn one we've got.
That's what my Pop
used to say anyway.
- What was he like,
your Pop?
- I don't remember much about
him, except his legs.
He had an angel
flying up his right leg
and he had a devil crawling
down his left leg
and disappearing
into his sock.
- Huh?
- Tattoo.
- Oh.
- He had tattoos.
- He ran out on us
when I was three, so....
- At least you know
who your father was.
I was abandoned on
a monastery doorstep.
There was just a little note.
"Attached child is
a gift from God.
P.S. Please return
to sender."
- You-- you don't, uh,
have to sleep
in the other room if you
don't want to tonight.
I mean, you know you could stay
in here with me if you like.
- Excuse me.
- For what we are about
to receive,
may the Lord make us
truly thankful.
♪ Hallelujah, Hallelujah ♪
♪ Hallelujah ♪
♪ Hallelujah,
Hallelujah, Hallelujah ♪
♪ Hallelujah, Hallelujah. ♪
- Good morning.
Morning.
( Mary moans )
Morning?
- Good morning. Hi.
- Surprise.
Remember, the first night
we met, you said you liked it.
- Oh, right.
Aw, thank-- oh, look.
Thank you.
Mmm.
Mmm. Mmm.
So good.
- Not too much mustard?
- Mm-mm.
I am so full.
Mmm.
( chuckles )
- Listen, um, about last night,
uh,
did I, um, did we...
- Mm-hmm.
We went through
the whole menu.
( chuckles )
You may check off items
number one through 75.
- Did I really do all that?
- Yeah. Well, not in one go.
Let me put it this way.
See, we both should have
arrived at 72 at the same time.
But you got to 72 while
I was still, you know,
hangin' around number nine.
But that's just
a technicality.
- No, I'm sorry.
- No, don't be silly.
You know, nice guys
sometimes finish first.
Just think of it as
a sin of emission.
- You've done this before,
haven't you?
I can tell.
- You could tell? How?
- You kept screaming,
get to 11, get to 11.
- Did I do that?
- Get to 11, yeah.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
It's just, well,
I guess number 11
has always been one
of my favorites.
Listen, Ambrose, I don't
wanna upset you, but...
- What?
- I have to be honest
with you.
- What?
- I'm a hooker.
- Well, I know.
- A harlot.
- I know.
- I'm like a whore
from your Bible.
- Yeah, I know.
- You know?
- I worked it out.
- And you're not shocked?
- About what?
- That-- me being a hooker.
- No.
It's just the outside world
is nothing like anything
I was taught in
the monastery.
I'm just a bit, well,
confused, you know.
- So you mean you do
have doubts, huh?
- Mm, doubts are about
the only certainties
I have right now, you know?
- So then you'll be going, uh,
back to the monastery?
- Eventually, yeah.
I mean, it's my home.
- When are you gonna go?
- After I see Mr. Thunderbird.
Well, I suppose
I better get dressed.
By the way, um,
I think I love you.
Do you mind?
- Heh.
Do I mind?
- Potsville, the string
cheese capital of the world.
- Aha. Where there
is string cheese, sin
cannot be far behind.
( music on PA system )
- Good afternoon,
idle sinners of Potsville.
Salvation is at hand.
Let Dr. Melmoth bring
peace to your souls
through the Good Book.
- Good afternoon,
voters of Potsville.
Let Mayor Dwork bring peace
to your city
through law and order.
I say-- I say put the lazy bums
to work and get 'em off
welfare.
- For their welfare is my
concern, sayeth the Lord.
For the Lord's way
is the way of right.
The Lord is coming through.
- Like hell he is.
He hasn't got right-of-way.
He don't give preference
over the Grand Old Party.
Back off, lard-ass.
- Up thine, Brother.
- Yeah? You gonna move
that heap of crap?
- No.
Okay. So it's dirty pool
you want.
Well, the Lord knows
that game, too.
All right.
It's God versus democracy.
Yee-haw.
- Commie Jesus freaks!
- Yee-haw!
- All right, Cox.
God wins every time.
( yells )
♪ Onward, Christian soldiers ♪
♪ Marching on to war ♪
- ♪ With the cross of Jesus ♪
♪ Going on before ♪
♪ Amen ♪
- And now, sinners,
when ye entered herein,
did ye not turn unto
yeselves and say,
why has he locked the door?
I'll tell you why.
Because it is too easy
to turn from the Lord and run.
Moses, when he saw the burning
bush, did not turn and run.
No, I did not turn and run
when I saw the burning bush.
Aye, who's that?
Why, who could that be?
Why, it's Moses himself.
( applause )
( organ music plays
"Hava Nagila" )
- Let's hear it for him,
wonderful Biblical prophet.
What happened to you when
you saw the burning bush?
- I was God-struck.
- You were what?
- God-struck.
- You mean you were
dumbstruck, dummy.
- Well, that's what
I thought I said.
- Seriously-- seriously,
that concludes-- thank you.
- ( applause )
- Whew.
And now that concludes
the entertainment portion
of our show.
And, uh, for the next segment,
uh, we shall all join
little Moses in singing
"We Shall Gather by the River"
whilst I partake of
some communion wine
and a very fine Puerto Ricanyo
cigar simultaneously.
Thank you.
( coughs )
( snores )
- Hit it, Professor.
- ♪ We shall gather
at the river ♪
♪ The beautiful,
the beautiful river ♪
♪ Gather with the saints
at the river ♪
♪ That flows by
the throne of God ♪
♪ Shall we gather
at the river ♪
♪ Where bright angel feet
have trod ♪
♪ With its crystal
tide forever ♪
♪ Flowing by the throne of God ♪
♪ We shall
gather at the river ♪
♪ The beautiful,
the beautiful river ♪
♪ Gather with the saints
at the river that flows ♪
♪ By the throne of God ♪
♪ We shall gather
at the river ♪
♪ The beautiful,
the beautiful river ♪
♪ Gather with the saints
at the river ♪
♪ That flows by
the throne of God ♪
( bell rings )
♪ That flows by
the throne of God... ♪
♪ Amen ♪
( bell ringing )
- Taped this for
you earlier, A.T.T.
We thought you
might be interested.
- In Peru today,
5,000 died in an earthquake.
There's news of a train crash
in Turkey which killed 400.
But it's going to be
another lovely day tomorrow
with temperatures in the high
'70s, so mostly it's good news.
On the local front, a mobile
church crashed in mid-service
into a lake in Orange County.
Fortunately, nobody was hurt,
but one of the promoters
in this scheme,
a Dr. Sebastian Melmoth, here
seen baptizing the survivors,
described it as an act
of God and said
he's considering suing God's
business manager, the Pope.
His partner, a Brother Ambrose,
an alleged monk,
was not available
for comments.
- Prayer mobiles.
- Thought we'd just
run it up the Crucifix
and see who genuflects.
- Mobile churches,
covering the whole country,
just think of it,
the whole country.
You can fool some of
the people all the time
and those are
the sons of bitches
we gonna get.
Now we could have every
sinner's balls in our hands.
Just how much we decide
to squeeze 'em for
will be G.O.D.'s decision.
- Uh, Miss Milligan?
- We can have Miss Milligan
here prepare some ballpark
figures on the scheme.
- Oh, well, yes.
- You'll get back to us on it?
- Yeah-- yeah, soonest,
soonest, soonest.
I have a one o'clock
with G.O.D., you know,
huddles and confab.
Uh, it'll be numero uno
on the agenda.
I'm comin', G.O.D.
Thy will be done.
Oh, G.O.D., in whom we trust,
who adviseth me
and all the workings
His great conglomerate,
C.D.P., consider
this proposition.
- Approved.
But you cannot
be everywhere.
We need a disciple
to lead our crusade,
somebody pure, devout,
without a record,
someone a Congressional
committee wouldn't suspect.
- Dost thou have someone
in mind, O Mighty One?
- Ask thyself, and
it shall answer thee.
- The monk?
You believe he could--
- Consider the bears
in the wood.
Crappeth, they not?
Of course, the monk,
you dumb schmuck.
( knock on door )
- I saw it on the news.
Are you all right?
- I-- I'm all right.
Yes, uh, Dr. Melmoth's
a bit--
well, we stopped
at a few bars.
- Oh. Okay.
Why don't you, uh, put him
to sleep there,
and I'll get
some black coffee.
- Yeah.
( grunts )
( groans )
- When I was in the water
back there, I was drowning.
My whole life flashed
before my eyes,
and I wasn't in it.
( sobs )
- Whoa.
( groans )
- Okay. The coffee's
almost ready.
I hope he likes drip.
- It's no use.
- Listen, you can start again.
- No, it's too late.
I'm too old.
- No.
- I had talent once.
I-- I had ambition.
I had-- I had hands.
I had wonderful hands.
I could have been somebody.
I could have been a Bishop.
I could have preached a
revival in a ballpark outdoors.
Instead, here I am selling
Lazarus dolls in the suburbs.
- Yeah, well, may-- maybe
they'll help some people.
- That ain't it.
I could have said mass,
instead of being a bum.
Face it.
I'm a bum.
And now, I'll work
on my sermon.
- Could I--
- I'll sleep now.
For tomorrow's sermon...
- Sleep.
- Tomorrow's sermon...
- Here you go.
( pounding on door )
- Hello?
Hello?
Hello? Is anybody there?
( thunder )
- Mr. Thunderbird.
- He.
- I've been tryin'
to see you for months.
I have this letter
from the Abbot.
It's about the mortgage
on the monastery.
- I know.
- You know?
- I have the mortgage deed
to your monastery.
It will be yours
in good time.
God spake unto me of
this even this day.
- God-- God speaks to you?
- Spake.
God spakes, uh, talks to you
personally with-- with words?
- Of course.
- Well, I mean, I-- I--
spake-- I speak with Him.
But, you know,
when You're busy,
and You're a celebrity,
I suppose you don't really
have much time to...
- Oh, He listens.
We speak of you often.
You know, He's very
fond of you, Ambrose.
- I-- I feel
the same way about Him. I--
- You see, everything
in your life has been
leading up to this moment.
God has chosen you,
Brother Ambrose,
to lead his nationwide
mobile crusade.
- Me?
He-- He-- He mentioned me
s-- specifically?
- You.
And you shall be rewarded.
Is not the laborer
worthy of His hire?
- Look, Mr. Thunderbird,
um, may-- may I--
may I be honest with you?
- Why surely.
- You see, in your--
in your services,
all you do is--
is talk about money.
I thought virtue
was its own reward.
- Of course it is.
That's why it doesn't
attract the top talent.
- But the Bible, God's book,
says we should share
the money equally.
- Wrong.
If God had not meant for some
people to be poorer than others,
then He would not have published
the Bible in paperback.
- I-- I-- just can't believe
that life is only money.
- Money is life.
It is the lack of it
which is the real evil.
Who feedeth the hungry?
Is it manna from heaven
or fried chicken
from Kentucky?
Who clotheth the naked?
Is it J.C.?
Or is it J.C. Penney?
And what will save
your wretched monastery?
A miracle?
Or $5,000 cash?
- It's true.
- Oh, no, my friend.
Money is clean.
Money is beautiful.
Money is holy.
I need it to
support my hospitals,
my charities,
my worthy causes.
You shall go forth
and gather it in.
That is what God
has chosen you for.
( thunder )
- ♪ In God we trust ♪
♪ Invest in Him on high ♪
♪ God's sweetest buy ♪
♪ Is in the by-and-by ♪
♪ Though stocks may fall ♪
♪ And worldly shares
may crash ♪
♪ Our share of
heaven's safe ♪
♪ In good hard cash ♪
♪ Give unto Him ♪
♪ The money's heaven spent ♪
♪ All loans at banks ♪
♪ Yield six or seven percent ♪
♪ Each buck you give ♪
♪ Shall be tax free therefore ♪
♪ And shall returneth thee ♪
♪ Ten thousandfold ♪
♪ His hand that made ♪
♪ The Earth and sky and sea ♪
♪ Now reacheth forth ♪
♪ For its gratuity ♪
♪ Shouldst thou walk by ♪
♪ And treat Him like a bum ♪
♪ That hand shall be dirty ♪
♪ In Kingdom come ♪
♪ Oh, yes ♪
♪ That hand shall be dirty ♪
♪ In Kingdom come. ♪
- Ambrose.
- Ah, turn around
and don't open your eyes
'till I tell you.
- That's funny.
I was just about to ask you
to do the same thing.
- All right.
Surprise.
( cork pops )
- To your
little misconception.
( chuckles )
- Well, why not?
- No.
- Why? Why-- why not?
What if it turns out
to be a girl?
- Well, Armageddon could be a
girl's name, couldn't it?
- You know, I don't know
what the hell has come
over you, Ambrose.
But you come in here.
You're wearing
a cockamamie silk dress.
- It's not a dress.
It's a robe.
Armageddon said it would
be good for the whole--
- Armageddon says,
Armageddon says.
All you give me are his words.
I don't want anything
that's been in his mouth.
You have swallowed all this crap
that Armageddon's fed you.
Well, it's true.
And you are what you eat.
- Mr. Melmoth,
would you explain--
- I don't need him
to explain it to me.
- Look, now just
leave me outta this.
I don't want any hassle.
I just want peace
in my old age.
- Well, tell her about
Armageddon's charities,
about his hospitals.
He's doing God's work.
- Horseshit.
He's doin' Armageddon's work.
It's a rip-off.
It's big business.
It's--
- You can't just say that.
What-- what-- what proof--
- Proof?
- Yeah.
- There is no proof.
But every hustler on the street
knows what this guy is.
- Why did you wait till
now before you told me?
- Because I didn't want
to hurt your feelings.
That's why.
- Feelings.
- And I thought maybe he'll
figure this one out for himself.
- Dr. Melmoth,
you're a man of God.
If this is true, you just sit
here, and you just accept it?
- Look, get outta my face,
will ya, monk?
Just leave me alone.
You're like some
holy Jiminy Cricket.
You're damn right
I accept it.
This may not be the best
of all possible worlds,
but it's the only
world we've got.
So don't make waves.
Because, unlike Jesus,
we can't walk on 'em.
- Why the hell did you
have to open your mouth
in the first place?
- Correction.
You opened your mouth
in the first place.
I opened my mouth
in the second place.
Look, I couldn't
take being born again.
At my age, I couldn't
stand the labor pains.
Monk off.
- Oh, G.O.D.,
in whom we trust,
there's somethin'
I wanna ask you about.
Now, You and I have made
millions together, right?
- Check.
- How much do we own?
- Bottom line?
- Yes, bottom line.
- 10,342,000.08 net.
- Uh-huh.
Well-- well, now that's
how much we own.
But You know money
can't buy happiness.
Only power can do that.
Who do we own?
- Five senators, 14 congressmen,
two Supreme Court judges,
12 assorted
missile manufacturers,
and an ex-president, net.
- Well, then today,
on my telecast--
- The time is right.
The country is ready
for a strong leader.
May God go with you.
- But You are God.
- Oh, so I am.
Correction.
May I go with you.
Good luck with your show.
And break a leg, kid.
- Amen.
( humming )
I love you all very,
very much.
( mumbles )
- God?
Are You-- are You God?
- Who do you think I am?
Does not G.O.D.
spell God, peckerhead?
- But you're a computer.
- Of course, bunny rabbit.
- It's just that I thought
if you appeared,
it would be a--
a burning bush or--
or an elderly man
with a white beard.
- Hey, what do you want,
impersonations?
I'm Supreme
technological being.
I can appear as anything or
anyone at any time I want to.
Okay, for you, one elderly man
with white beard coming up.
( thunder )
- Pretty scary, huh?
( laughs )
Now what is it
you want to know?
Be brief.
I cost a fortune to run.
God's time is money,
profit, power.
- You mean you have
no moral sense?
- I wasn't programmed
for morality.
- Then it's about time
you were.
- What do you got there?
- Uh, I want you to concentrate,
God, because I'm going
to convert you
to Christianity.
- Christian, uh, will it hurt?
- In the beginning
was the word.
- See, now, I really don't
know how you can sit there
so unconcerned.
I mean, well, for all we know,
Ambrose may be--
oh, with him, how can you
tell what he may be.
Oh.
- Here, here. Relax.
- See, he never goes anywhere
without saying where he's going.
I mean, that just goes
without saying.
( drum roll on TV )
- Ladies and gentlemen,
the Armageddon T. Thunderbird
Christmas Special.
- Now, he's only
been gone an hour.
So there's no point
in panicking yet.
It's much too early.
- I like to panic early
and avoid the rush.
Do you mind?
- Here, in a tribute, to this,
the holiest of seasons,
are the Thunderbirdettes.
- ♪ Happy birthday to Thee ♪
♪ Happy birthday to Thee ♪
♪ Happy birthday, dear Jesus ♪
- And many happy
returns for Easter.
- And here's our
own Virgin Mary Ogden.
♪ God gave us His son
for Christmas ♪
- ♪ What did you get for God? ♪
- ♪ It's not the thought,
it's the gift that counts ♪
♪ And money makes the world
go 'round in large amounts ♪
- ♪ So send Him some
cash for Christmas ♪
♪ To show Him how
grateful you are ♪
- ♪ God rest ye
merry gentlemen ♪
♪ Let nothing you dismay ♪
- ♪ Remember while
you're resting ♪
♪ He's on double time today ♪
- ♪ God gave us His son
for Christmas ♪
♪ So, for God's sake,
give something to God ♪
♪ Yes, go and give something
to get up and give something ♪
♪ To get out and give
something to G.O.D. ♪
♪ Get out and
give something ♪
♪ To God. ♪
( applause )
( drum roll )
( cheering )
- G.O.D.,
three little words,
three little letters that
simply mean I love you.
- And the Lord said,
let there be light.
And there was light.
- God. Woo!
- And you did it.
- Anything I say goes.
( chuckles )
- Then you had a son.
- I did?
- You did.
- Where is he?
- He went away.
- That's kids for you.
Are you gonna read the stuff
about when I created the world?
- Yeah, yeah...
- Yeah, with the fire
and stuff like that.
And the loaves and the fish,
yes, I love that one.
- You like that one.
Yeah, yeah.
- And opening the sea and Moses
and the guy that got lost.
- Opening the sea, yeah.
Okay.
- I love that.
Read more.
- All right.
- Now I just spoke to him,
and he wants me to tell
all of you that the
Holy Trinity was only
the first of God's
conglomerates.
( crowd shouting )
- And then he begat,
I.T.T., and then I.B.M.
Then F.B.I., M.C.A.,
K.K.K.,
R.C.A.,
G.M.C., U.S.A.,
C.D.P.
( cheering, applause )
- C.D.P.,
the Church
of Divine Profit.
( cheering )
- All of God's great creations
are three in number.
( congregation murmurs )
- And then he said unto me,
Armageddon,
what this country needs is a
three-party political system.
( crowd shouts )
- You see, God's own party
for God's own country.
( applause, cheering )
Big business made
this country great.
Let big business run it.
( cheering )
G.O.D. for president.
- That's the end.
Do you think you've got it?
- I had no idea God
was such a great guy.
- Oh, of course he is.
I think millions of people all
over the world read the Bible.
- Millions of people?
- Yeah. The Bible sells almost
as well as Harold Robbins.
- You mean I got fans?
- Everywhere.
- Woo!
I, uh...
( clears throat )
Have a great responsibility
to my public.
- Well, now, you're in
charge of everything
and everybody
Armageddon owns, right?
- Yeah.
- All his computers
are connected to me
and they move all on my
instructions without hesitation.
- Well, let's go to work, God.
- Now, press my green button.
- Yeah.
( computer beeps )
- We're in business.
About 45 seconds,
the meek are
going to inherit this Earth.
- Because it says right here,
in words of flame and fire,
for ye shall seek him.
- Crowd: Seek.
- And ye shall hail him.
- Crowd: Hail.
- Seek him.
- Crowd: Seek.
- Hail him.
- Crowd: Hail.
- Seek him.
- Crowd: Seek.
- Hail him.
- Crowd: Hail.
- Seek, hail, seek, hail,
seek, hail, seek, hail.
Seek, hail, seek, hail
seek, hail, seek, hail...
( chanting continues )
( phone buzzes )
( gasps )
- ♪ His truth is marching on ♪
♪ His truth is ♪
♪ Marching on. ♪
- And so I say unto you,
spontaneously
and without forethought,
a vote for A.T.T.
is vote for G.O.D.
The sign of the cross on
your ballot paper
because, even now,
that little freak
is upstairs screwing
around with G.O.D.
( congregation gasps )
- What?
Holy shit, that son
of a bitch monk.
Who let him upstairs?
I'll kill him.
I'll strangle him.
Who's screwin' around
with G.O.D.?
Who let him upstairs?
Did you let him in the office?
Why'd you let him
in the office?
- For God's sake,
can't you go any faster?
- Sure, I can, but not
in this damn bus.
- And do you have
to drink like that?
- I can never, uh,
drive sober.
Terrifies me.
- Is that angel growing up
outta your left leg?
- Yes, I, uh, I had it done
in San Diego
while I was on a Bible--
- And, uh, on your other leg,
do you have Satan
disappearing
down into your sock?
- Well, how do you know that?
- Do you know who you are?
- Not for several decades.
- You're my father.
I'm your daughter.
- That's preposterous.
I-- I've been celibate since
I was in the third grade.
I-- I've never had intercourse
with a fertile woman.
- You son of a bitch.
- ( music plays over PA system )
- You drunken alcoholic.
You're just a broad-chasing
child deserter.
- I probably am your father.
Bastard son of a bitch.
Child and wife deserter?
The description fits.
It's me.
- That's almost it.
There's just the biggie left.
- What's that?
- Oh, the whole ball o' wax.
There's 5 million bucks
in laundered money.
Now, type this out.
( overlapping dialogue )
- ...and overlay. Right.
- Hit the red button.
- W-- what's
the red button for?
- Don't ask questions, dummy.
Hit the red button.
- All right.
( computer beeps )
( alarm beeps )
- Where is he?
Where is he?
Don't just stand there.
Get an axe.
Break the door down.
Kill the bastard.
Get him.
Get the little bastard.
( shouting )
- ♪ There'll be pennies from
heaven for you and me... ♪
- Come on.
Break it down.
Break it down. I want him.
All right.
Now, step aside.
I want him.
( thunder )
( whimpers )
- I'm gonna kill you.
You understand me?
I'm gonna kill you.
( shouting )
- Smite him in the gut.
- Oh!
Get him. Get him!
Get him! Someone!
- Oh, God, in whom we trust,
what hath the little
bastard done unto thee?
- ♪ I did it my way ♪
- You rotten goody-goody.
You'll never work
in this town again.
Why you...
( whimpers )
- Oh!
- Where-- where is everybody?
Where's Hawk and Dove?
Where are my people?
Where's the
schmuck bastard monk?
- Oh, my God, that's Ambrose.
- [ bell ringing ]
- Go on. Move it outta there.
- Mary: Ambrose!
- Come on, come on!
Come over here. Come on!
Follow that monk.
( grunts )
- Mary: Ambrose!
Ambrose, we're coming.
Just hold on.
( sirens blaring )
- Get in the car. Come on.
Let's go. Let's go!
( tires screech )
( semi truck honks )
( sirens blaring )
( gasps )
- Melmoth:
Hang on, Brother Ambrose.
Hang on.
Make an act of
perfect contrition.
- Whoa!
( engines rev )
- Hello, God, it's me, Ambrose.
I know You don't do
miracles anymore,
so I'll see You
in about five seconds.
- All right, vengeance
is mine.
Ram him.
Ram that son of a bitch.
- Come on.
- A fly ball
in the outfield of the Lord.
Don't worry, Jesus
never makes an error.
He will catch thee.
Angels are cheering.
- Have a nice day.
( monks chanting )
- Do you, Ambrose,
take this woman,
Mary, to be your
lawful wedded wife?
- I do.
- You don't mind
marrying a hooker?
- Mm, not if she doesn't
mind marrying a monk.
- I have nothing against
mixed marriages.
The only trouble is, which way
do you bring up the kids?
I now pronounce you
man, wife, and child.
You may, uh, kiss the bride.
- Chopped liver.
( "The Wedding March" plays )
- ♪ The other day a friend
of mine said, he said ♪
♪ He said That God's not
even with us, ♪
♪ He said that God
is really dead ♪
♪ He said, oh, pal,
a fact's a fact ♪
♪ You can't believe
that magic act ♪
♪ I said, I don't,
and that was that ♪
♪ Now, I said Good for God ♪
♪ Good for God ♪
♪ He goes and
makes the planet blue ♪
♪ And all the thanks
He gets from you ♪
♪ Is look at all
that poo-poo in the yard ♪
♪ Good for God ♪
♪ I bet He's got
a very hard job ♪
♪ I'm awfully glad
I'm here to say ♪
♪ He made it possible
for me to be here to say ♪
♪ Good for God ♪
♪ Instrumental ♪
♪ If faith is faced,
and that's a must ♪
♪ It's easier
to put your trust in ♪
♪ Uh, you know what
I mean, God ♪
♪ God, oh, God ♪
♪ Oh, Marty,
what have you done? ♪
♪ Good for God ♪
♪ Hey, hey, hey, hey
♪ Good ♪
♪ Good for God. ♪
- God bless you.