[music plays]
- [giggling, cooing]
- There. That's better.
- [# Seals & Croft:
Summer Breeze]
- [laughing]
- # Summer breeze #
- All clean.
- [giggling]
- # Make me feel fine #
- # Blowing through
the jasmine in my mind #
- [sighs]
# He sees you
when you're sleepin' #
- # He knows
when you're awake #
- What are you doing here?
- What are you talking about?
- I'm talkin' about Santa Claus!
There's only 159 days
left till Christmas,
so you better be good.
I'd better be good?
How 'bout this? You better
be scarce. Now go on.
I don't care
about Christmas.
- # Jingle bells, jingle bells
Jingle all the way #
- Ah!
- Donkey!
- 51 days left
till Christmas.
Get your green butt in gear
and go get your marshmallows,
because without marshmallows,
sweet potatoes are nothin'!
Aggh! Enough! I don't care
about any of this nonsense.
- Now shoo!
- OK, OK. But don't say
I didn't say I told you so.
[sighs]
- # Smashing through the snow #
- Ah!
- # And laughin' all the way #
Ha-ha-ha!
- [sighs]
It's finally here.
Tomorrow's Christmas Eve!
You got everything ready?
- [Shrek] No.
- Trimmed stockin's
- or hung your chestnuts
or roasted the tree?
- No!
- Or figgified your puddin'?
- Donkey!
Will you get it through
your thick head?
No one here gives
a hoot about Christmas!
A white Christmas!
Oh, how perfect.
And it's our first one
together as a family.
Isn't this exciting?
Uh, oh, yeah!
How 'bout that?
There's somethin'
Shrek needs to tell you.
Don't ruin the surprise
for her, Donkey.
Surprise?
Oh, I love surprises!
You're the best. Come on,
let's go make some cookies.
[door closes]
OK, you a dead man.
You know that, right?
Um, hold that thought.
I'll be right back.
[# Carl Orff: Carmina Burana]
- [ringing]
- Oh, good, you're still open.
No, no, uh, we're closing now.
Merry Christmas.
Wait, wait, wait!
I need your help.
I have to make a Christmas,
and I have no idea
what it is or how to do it!
Why didn't you say so?
That's super.
I know all about Christmas,
and I have just
the book for you.
Christmas for Village Idiots.
It's all spelled out. See?
One: decorate house.
Two: the stockings
by the fireplace.
Step three:
the Christmas feast. Mmmm!
- What's that?
- Step four?
That's the Christmas tree!
The tree goes inside the house?
Anyway, step five:
The telling
of the Christmas story.
This is the step
that says I created
the perfect Christmas
for my perfect family perfectly.
See? Family by the fire,
everyone cozy and warm.
Happy, happy. Voila!
- Um, sure.
- Look, long story short,
it's all right here.
It's no problem.
- Oh, perfect.
- I mean, how hard can it be?
- [shouting]
- I didn't get the eggnog!
- Closed?! What do you mean?
- We're closed.
- Dwight the Knight
action figure?
- Marshmallows!
- Sweet potatoes are nothing
without marshmallows!
- Bye-bye.
- Have a super Christmas.
- [moaning]
- [rattling]
- Wha...? Oh.
- [Shrek] Ooh!
- Honey, is that you?
- [Shrek] Ah! Oh!
- [gasps]
Fiona! What are
you doing up so early?
- [grunts]
- Wait, are you OK?
- I'm all right. [chuckles]
- What are you...?
- Uh, I...
- Are you decorating?
Uh, yeah, that. Surprised?
- Yes. [giggles]
- Well, this is our first
Christmas together as a family,
and, you know, I just want to
make sure that it's perfect.
Shrek, I think...
it's beautiful.
- It's passable.
- It's horrible!
- Oh! Donkey!
- They usually toilet paper
and run away.
Whoever did
this means business!
Get rid of all this junk
and get some tinsel
and doilies and ribbons
- and maybe some of those
plastic reindeer.
- What is it you wanted today?
Come on,
it's Christmas Eve! And I've
brought you a little somethin'.
Go ahead, take a couple.
I bought plenty for everybody!
Oh, isn't that... nice.
Well, thanks for stopping
by for that brief visit,
but as you can see,
there's a lot of work to do.
Just like him
to wait till the last minute.
Don't worry,
if there's one thing I know,
it's Christmas.
Shrek's gonna want help, my
advice, and he's definitely...
Actually, I think
what he really wants
is a nice family Christmas.
Oh, a family Christmas.
Yeah. It's the
first one with the kids.
Don't say another word.
I know exactly what you mean.
- I got a lot to do now,
so I better get movin'.
- Thank you, Donkey!
- Uh, and Merry Christmas!
- All right. Merry Christmas!
# Love and joy come to you
and to me some waffles too #
Donkey's right.
It's Christmas Eve.
How am I ever gonna
get this done in time?
This is gonna be the best
Christmas ever. And we're going
to do it together, so come on.
[# The Waitresses:
Christmas Wrapping]
# 'Cause it is
my favorite holiday #
# All this
year's been a busy blur #
[belches]
# On with the boots
Back out in the snow #
# To the only
all-night grocery #
# When what to my
wondering eyes should appear #
# In the line is that guy
I've been chasing all year #
# Then suddenly
we laughed and laughed #
# Caught on
to what was happening #
# That Christmas magic's
brought this tale #
- # To a very happy ending #
- Everything looks so good!
Oh, nice job, honey.
Well, we all did it together.
And now what would the
perfect Christmas be
without a Christmas story?
- [giggling]
- Ahem.
'Twas the night
before Christmas
and all through the house
- Not a creature
was stirring... What?
- [crashing]
- Merry Christmas, Shrek!
- Oh, not you!
We're here to smother you
with Christmas love!
Absolutely not!
Bad Donkey! Go home!
How are you gonna have
Christmas without family?
- Seasons greeting!
- Happy Holidays!
- Merry Christmas!
- Well, what a nice surprise!
Oh, yeah. Ooh!
[cooing]
OK, I will
assume the position.
[squealing, laughing]
- I am the joy-filled swine!
- Yay for the season of love!
Don't you know this is
where stockings go?
You can't be hanging laundry up!
Donkey! Don't touch anything.
- [shouting]
- How we gon' roast chestnuts
on this little bitty fire?
Hey, baby, you mind?
- Oh, boy!
- This way, gents.
[laughs] That was our supper!
Ow! Hey! Ow!
Did you hurt yourself
when you fell out of heaven?
- [pig] Where are we
going to put it?
- I don't know.
Let's put it over here. No,
that is not with the feng shui.
Come on, everybody,
let's dance!
# Yes, we can, can, can
Can, can, can, can dance #
[dance music plays]
- [indistinct chatter]
- [Shrek] Occupied!
It's me. Shrek?
- [Shrek] Yes?
- Come back to the party.
Please?
[Shrek] I don't think
that'd be such a good idea.
Come on. It's not that bad.
OK, I know you're
not a party person, but...
But what? This is not the kind
of Christmas I had in mind.
They're our friends, Shrek.
They all mean well.
- [glass shatters]
- [pig] How many babies
did Fiona have?
- [pig 2] She has babies?
- [pig 1] Don't know.
I better get back
to the house.
I'm surprised we have
a house to go back to.
- Are you coming?
- Oh, I can hardly wait.
- Ah, finally!
- [crashing]
- [humming Ride
of the Valkyries]
- Ja, look at him go!
- Excuse me. Excuse me!
- Excuse you for what?
I don't feel very good.
[gagging]
- Ahh, I feel better now.
- Ooh, a chocolate chip! Mm!
- Sweetheart? [giggles]
- [# Journey:
Don't Stop Believin']
- Mind if I cut in?
- Oh!
# Don't stop believing #
# Ooh, up and down
the boulevard #
[giggling, cooing]
[Pig] I am
a little Christmas angel!
- Hey there, my sweeties.
- [belches]
Aw. Would you like Daddy
to finish the story for you?
- [squeals]
- Yeah?
The children were nestled
all snug in their beds
- Visions of sugarplums...
- Were you tellin' 'em
The Night Before Christmas?
That's the best
Christmas story ever!
- And I'm the best teller ever!
- Donkey...
I got it committed
to memorization!
- Gather round!
- Donkey! Wait!
I'm supposed to tell
the Christmas story.
'Twas the night
before Christmas
and I spent all the day
Finishin' up
on my Christmas display
Now, missin' all this
would be nothin' but tragic
So just follow me
and I'll show you the magic
Now, out in the yard
in a glorious clutter
Is a spectacle there that'll
make your heart flutter
With 20-foot cheese balls
and a big eggnog fountain
And yodelin' elves
on an ambrosia mountain
A stage where acrobats
jump, leap and prance
And honor the day
through interpretive dance
- [all shout]
- But just when you think
the display is complete
The Christmas parade
comes right down the street
With holiday floats
all in silver and blue
With sugarplum fairies
and a reindeer or two
There's a baton-twirlin'
snowman all happy and perky
Magical peacocks
and a dancin' roast turkey
- # Everybody dance now #
- [# C+C Music Factory:
Gonna Make You Sweat]
[Donkey] And right when you
think that you've just
seen it all
Comes a huge waffle Santa
that's 50 feet tall
Ho, ho, ho!
With syrup and butter
the sight just amazes
As it's flanked by a choir
all singin' his praises
# Oh, Santa #
# Oh, Santa
Oh, Santa #
- # Santa #
- Donkey.
- # Oh, Santa #
- Santa?
- Donkey!
- Santa!
- Oh.
Very inappropriate, amigo.
Please, allow me.
- Oh, Puss, not you too.
- In my homeland,
we tell a very different tale
of the Santa Nicholas.
He's not made of waffles.
- This Santa was suave
He was nothing like that
- [giggling]
The Santa I know
was a hot Latin cat
He was dressed all in fur
from his head to his paws
And he stood there heroic
A real Santa... Claws
Red are his boots
- And so is his cape
- Ol?
His sword is a cane
that tastes like crab cake
He wears a fine belt
and a leather cravat
And there's a cute fuzzy thing
which hangs down from his hat
[jingles]
[purring]
- [crickets chirping]
- I have shamed myself.
- [all] Ol?
- All right, everybody,
if you leave now, you can
beat the holiday traffic.
Aw, phooey with all your
sunshine and lollipops!
Where I come from,
Christmas is a nightmare.
- [sighs]
- [clears throat]
'Twas the night
before Christmas
and the prettiest sights
Were my sweetheart
beside me in the bright
Christmas lights
...until they got home.
When they looked at the car door
handle, and they found a hook!
- [shrieking]
- [laughing]
Gingy, cut it out! You're
really givin' me the creeps!
Oh, come on,
I was just teasin'.
- Come here, you.
- [chuckles]
(giggles) Oh, Gingy,
I couldn't stay mad at you.
- [rustling]
- What was that?
Oh, no, you don't. I'm not
fallin' for that again.
No, I'm really, really
seriously not kidding.
- Whoa!
- Oh, Gingy!
- [makes Godzilla shriek]
- Oh!
[shouting]
- [screaming]
- Oh! Suzie!
- [crunching]
- No! No! No!
That's the most ridiculous
thing I've ever heard.
- You know
that's not how it goes.
- You weren't there!
All right, everyone,
I've had just about enough!
All I wanted was a nice
Christmas with my family.
And that's exactly why
we're all here! Now, come on,
let's finish tellin' my story.
Oh, no, Donkey,
that's not what I meant.
And get out of my chair.
- Oh, hey, what's this?
- Donkey, let go of the book.
- Why are you whisperin'?
- I'm not kiddin', Donkey.
Give me the book!
- Heimlich!
- Ja?
- No, Heimlich!
- Oh, ja!
- [shouting]
- Uh!
Whoa! Ah!
- [gasping]
- Ow! My eye!
- Ow!
- Oh, boy!
- Oh!
- Ah!
- [shouting]
- [giggling]
- Ah!
- Drop and roll, Shrek!
- Somebody get some water!
- I got it! I got it!
Don't worry, Shrek,
everything is under control!
- Oh, boy.
- [kettle whistling]
- Ooh! The tea is ready.
- [Shrek] Out!
- I want everybody out
of my house right now!
- [shouting]
Ah! Ow!
Yeah, well, that's
a real nice way to treat
your guests on Christmas!
And if you think I'm gonna
give you a present now,
you are sadly mistaken!
You want to give me a present?
Then go away!
- That's all I wanted!
- Fine! I'm going!
- Good, then go!
- You go and have yourself
a merry Christmas,
- Ebenezer Shrek!
- And a "Bah, humbug"
to you too!
- We could come to our house.
- Ja, we have
plenty of schnitzel.
Now maybe we can...
Fiona? Where you going?
Shrek, you just kicked
everybody out on Christmas.
Well, that wasn't Christmas.
That was chaos!
Look, I know it didn't
go like you wanted.
What I wanted was a perfect
Christmas for me and my family.
- That was our family.
- You call that a family?
That was a natural disaster!
On Christmas, that's how it
works. Yes, it was crowded.
Yes, it got
a little out of hand.
- Fiona, they lit me on fire!
- Shrek...
I had everything under
control until they showed up
and ruined my Christmas!
- Your Christmas?
- I mean our Christmas.
- For you, and the babies.
- [sighs]
Christmas is not just about
you or me. Or even the babies.
You just don't get it.
I have to go. I need to
apologize to our friends.
Fiona, wait.
[sighs]
[# eels: The Stars Shine
in the Sky Tonight]
# December is a lonely month #
# In a year of lonely days #
# It's hard to tell
which way is up #
# Or down or out
or through the haze #
# It's not where
you're coming from #
# It's where you're going to #
I still don't understand
why Shrek had to be
so mean and cranky.
We were tryin'
to do what you wanted us to do!
- What are you talking about?
- What you said this mornin'.
You know, you and Shrek
wanted to have a big old
noisy family Christmas.
No, I said it was our first
Christmas together as a family.
A family, right.
That's me and everybody else.
Then he lost
his temper like that.
You know, Donkey,
none of us really
asked Shrek what he wanted.
Well, I must agree with the
Princess. And you, especially,
were no Christmas angel.
- You know, I don't remember
askin' you anything!
- Donkey.
[sighs] I'm sorry, Princess.
You're right.
- Even still, Shrek
didn't have to be so...
- What?
- [yelling]
- [meowing]
Pigheaded? Stubborn? Mean?
Well, maybe I am all those
things, but I'm an ogre, OK?
So here's the thing.
[clears throat]
I'm sorry you took
getting kicked out
of my house the wrong way.
No, wait.
What I meant to say is
I know you're all just trying
to be helpful in your
own irritating fashion...
- Ay, caramba!
- Uh, some people
can't help being annoying.
- Shrek!
- Look,
I shouldn't have lost
my temper back there.
- Apology accepted. Let's eat.
- Wait a minute.
Now, there's somethin'
more to this. Come on now,
what's goin' on?
Look, all I wanted was to make
this perfect for my family,
but I don't even know
what Christmas means.
The thing is,
this is my first Christmas too.
Whoa, hold up, Shrek! You mean
to tell me that you never had...
- No.
- Not even one?
- No!
- You mean no chestnuts,
no Santa, no presents,
no stockings?
- [gasps] No nut cakes?!
- Donkey!
No, none of that.
Ogres don't celebrate Christmas.
Ogres don't celebrate anything.
Oh, man, now I'm all emotional.
- Come here, Shrek, gimme a hug!
- All right,
that's close enough.
OK, all right, I just...
guess I got... a little
excited about Christmas and
all the presents and mistletoe
and [sniffs] everything,
and I forgot that it's...
It's about us all bein'
together, and I'm...
I'm sorry, Shrek.
I know, Donkey, and...
and I'm sorry it ended up
in a great big fight.
Oh, Christmas
is all about big fights.
My mama used to say,
"Christmas ain't Christmas
till somebody cries."
- Usually that someone's me.
- Boss,
- there is no right way to
do Christmas. You just do it.
- Ja, with schnitzel!
- [laughing] And eggnog!
- [all] And cheese!
- And family.
- Yeah. And family.
So despite the fact that you
drive me crazy at times...
Yes, Donkey,
I'm lookin' at you.
...it would mean a lot to me if
you'd all come back and join us.
[chuckling] OK,
I guess I deserved that.
- Don't push your luck.
- [laughing]
They got you good, Shrek!
That wasn't even funny!
Who did that?
[babies cooing]
[Fiona] Well, that's the last
of the spare blankets.
Uh, sorry, but this is my spot.
I never get the good spots,
so I specifically...
[shrieks]
So we are pigs,
pigs in the blanket, ja?
- Ja.
- So this is funny then, ja?
- Ja, ja.
- This is funny.
- Ja.
- Yep, that's a good one.
- Good night, everyone.
- It's time for lights out.
- Lights out?
We can't go to sleep yet.
We haven't heard a bedtime
story. Right, everybody?
- Shrek, yeah!
- [all shouting]
All right. All right.
- [sighs] Don't need this.
- [babies giggle]
OK.
'Twas the night
before Christmas
Not a swamp rat did creep
As mother and babe played kazoo
in their sleep
[kazoo sounds]
Now, the sight of the house
would make any ogre droop
For 'twas sickeningly sweet
as unicorn poop
Yet who was arriving
to help this lost cause?
The foul, the vile
and handsome Ogre Claus
Hey. How's it goin'?
He looked all around
and scratched at his beard
And said...
This place is worse
than I thought... uh, feared.
So he grabbed up his belly
and screwed up his face
- And let loose a...
- [loud belch]
That transformed the place
With a gleam in his eye
His work here was done
And then to the babies he gave
One by one
A festering bottle
of stinky swamp juice
And for mommy a kiss
and a good Christmas goose
- Ooh!
- 425 degrees,
20 minutes per pound.
Then digging a finger
inside of his nose
And giving a nod
Up the chimney he rose
And I heard him exclaim
as he drove out of sight
"Smelly Christmas to all,
and to all a gross night"
- [bells jingling]
- Ho, ho, ho!
Ho, ho, ho!
- Santa?! Ah!
[# The Fairy Tale Creatures:
Deck the Halls]
# Shrek the halls
with Puss and Donkey #
# Fa-la-la-la-la
La, la, la, la #
# Christmas time
can be so wonky #
# Fa-la-la-la-la
La, la, la, la #
# As we all descend
on Shrek's place #
# Fa-la-la, La-la-la
La, la, la #
# Fill his swamp
with tinsel and lace #
# Fa-la-la-la-la
La, la, la, la #
# Christmas time can be
such a hassle #
# Fa-la-la-la-la
La, la, la, la #
# When your friends
invade your castle #
# Fa-la-la-la-la
La, la, la, la #
# Join us here
for Christmas leisure #
# Fa-la-la, la-la-la
la, la, la #
# Trashing Shrek's house
is our pleasure #
# Fa-la-la-la-la
La, la, la, la #
# Push the chairs back
cranks the dance tunes #
# Fa-la-la-la-la
La, la, la, la #
# We'll be house guests
until next June #
# Fa-la-la-la-la
La, la, la, la #
# Eat the turkey
and the cheese log #
# Fa-la-la-la-la
La, la, la, la #
# Guzzle punch
and tea and egg nog #
# Fa-la-la-la-la
La, la, la, la #
# Hail be Shrek through
Christmas season #
# Fa-la-la-la-la
La, la, la, la #
# Seems to be
against all reason #
# Fa-la-la-la-la
La, la, la, la #
# Christmas time we're
sure to be here #
# Fa-la-la-la-la
La, la, la, la #
# Filling Shrek with
lots of good cheer #
# Fa-la-la-la-la
La, la, la, la #
[# I'm From Barcelona:
Here We Come Wassailing]
# Love and joy #
# Come to you #
# And to you #
# Your wassail too #
# Love and joy #
# Come to you #
# And to you #
# Your wassail too #
# And here we come
a-wassailing #
# Among the leaves so green #
# And here we come
a-wandering #
# So fair to be seen #
# Our wassail cup
is made of #
# The rosemary tree #
# And so is your beer #
# Of the best barley #
- # Love and joy #
- # Come to you #
- # And to you #
- # Your wassail too #
# Love and joy
come to you #
# And to you your wassail too #
# And we wish you #
# A happy new year #
# We are the daily beggars #
# That beg from door to door #
# But we are
neighbors' children #
# Whom you have seen before #
# Good master
and good mistress #
# As you sit by the fire #
# Pray, think of us
poor children #
# Wandering in the mire #
- # Love and joy #
- # Come to you #
- # And to you #
- # Your wassail too #
- # Love and joy #
- # Come to you #
- # And to you #
- # Your wassail too #
# Love and joy
come to you #
# And to you
your wassail too #
# And we wish you #
# A happy new year #
[# The Donnas:
Chrstimas Wrapping]
# "Bah, humbug!"
No, that's too strong #
# 'Cause it is
my favorite holiday #
# But all this year's
been a busy blur #
# Don't think I have
the energy #
# To add to my
already mad rush #
# Just 'cause it's
'tis the season. #
# The perfect gift
for me would be #
# Completions and
connections left from #
# Last year, ski shop #
# Encounter most interesting #
# Had his number
but never the time #
# Most of '81 passed
along those lines #
# So deck those halls
trim those trees #
# Raise up cups
of Christmas cheer #
# I just need to
catch my breath #
# Christmas by myself
this year #
# Calendar picture
frozen landscape #
# Chilled this room
for 24 days #
# Evergreens, sparkling snow #
# Get this winter over with! #
# Flashback to springtime
saw him again #
# Would've been good
to go for lunch #
# Couldn't agree
when we were both free #
# We tried, we said
we'd keep in touch #
# Didn't, of course
till summertime #
# Out to the beach to his boat
Could I join him? #
# No, this time it was me #
# Sunburn in the third degree #
# Now the calendar's
just one page #
# And, of course
I am excited #
# Tonight's the night
but I've set my mind #
# Not to do too much
about it #
# Merry Christmas!
Merry Christmas! #
# Could've missed
this one this year #
# Merry Christmas!
Merry Christmas! #
# Could've missed
this one this year #
# Merry Christmas!
Merry Christmas! #
# Could've missed
this one this year #
# Merry Christmas!
Merry Christmas! #
# Could've missed
this one this year #
Subtitles by LeapinLar
Uploaded By
:: w e R c z ::
www.subscene.com