(choir) # Hark! The herald angels sing
# Glory to the newborn King
# Peace on earth and mercy mild
# God and sinners reconciled
# Joyful, all ye nations rise
# Join the triumph of the skies
# With th'angelic host proclaim
# Christ is born in Bethlehem
# Hark! The herald angels sing
# Glory to the newborn King
# Hail the heav'n-born Prince of Peace
# Hail the Sun of Righteousness
# Light and life to all He brings
# Ris'n with healing in His wings...
- Oh. This is very kind of you.
- It's a privilege.
(tyres squeal)
- Which way are you going?
- Over there. The Mutual Building.
- My doctor is in there. I have hopes.
- Fine.
- I'm all right now.
- Good luck to you.
- Thank you. Merry Christmas to you.
- Merry Christmas.
Mother, please lift me up! Please.
All right then. Just for a minute.
Look at that doll.
Look at the funny choo-choo train.
Come on now, darling. We have to go.
Oh, my baby! Oh, my baby!
Oh, my baby. Oh, you saved her.
Oh, thank God you saved my baby.
How can I ever thank you?
- Don't try. Just don't let it happen again.
- I promise I won't.
- Remember that. Now on your way.
- Yes.
It closely resembles its noble cousin -
the California red fir.
It's botanically dissimilar.
Pay me heed, Maggenti.
This is a specimen of the white fir -
Abies concolor.
Surely you, a native Roman,
know your Latin?
You wanna buy or not?
- Well, if it isn't my dear, beautiful Julia.
- Hello, Professor.
- What are you doing in this part of town?
- Buying a Christmas tree.
- Hello, Mr Maggenti.
- Mrs Brougham.
How much do you charge
for this miserable weed?
- $1.85.
- $1.85! For this half-hearted twig?
I shall pay you ten cents a branch
or take my trade elsewhere.
- What can I do for you, Mrs Brougham?
- You can save me that tree.
- The big one right by the door.
- OK.
Every Christmas for the past 18 years,
Maggenti and I have been
re-enacting the same argument.
I didn't know you celebrated Christmas.
I thought you had no religion.
That's true, my dear,
but I like to have a Christmas tree
because it reminds me of my childhood.
I feel, for some reason, that this is a good
time of year for looking backwards.
Can you imagine me
ever having been a child?
How's Henry?
I haven't seen him for some time.
Oh, he's well, thank you.
He's terribly tired and worried.
Is he having difficulty
raising money for the cathedral?
Yes. It's slow work.
- How's your book coming?
- Oh, splendidly.
Greatest history of Rome since Gibbon.
But, of course, nobody will read it.
Now, my good man, I do not choose to
prolong this tawdry bickering any further.
All right. Ten cents a branch.
- It's $1.40.
- Very well, my venal friend.
Here is your blood money.
Mr Maggenti, will you send the tree up
on Christmas Eve?
- But I don't want my daughter to see it.
- Don't worry.
I send it when the bambino goes to bed.
Merry Christmas.
- Merry Christmas!
- Merry Christmas! Come on.
There's something I'd like you
to give Henry for his cathedral fund.
That has been my lucky piece - not that
it's brought me luck, except knowing you.
It's an old Roman coin. I picked it up
years ago in Brindisi. It has little value.
- It's a wonderful contribution.
- Nonsense.
It might be called the "widow's mite" if
it weren't for the fact that I'm not a widow.
Why, Julia, this is no occasion for tears.
It's stopped snowing.
If only we could spend Christmas
back here where we were so happy.
- With you and all of our old friends.
- Now, now, now.
Good night, Professor.
I'll see you again very soon.
It can't be soon enough. Good night, Julia.
Why, Professor! How fine to see you again
after all these years. How well you look.
- How are you?
- Never better. And you?
Quite well also, thank you.
- I don't think you remember me.
- Of course I do. Where did we meet?
- Professor, after all these years...
- Just a moment.
- It wasn't Vienna, was it?
- Beautiful old Vienna.
The university. When I
was lecturing there on Roman history.
And what great lectures they were.
And what a one you were with the ladies.
Fancy you remembering that.
- I must confess, I had my moments.
- And still have.
- Where are you going?
- That car.
I couldn't help noticing
your tender parting from Julia.
- You know Julia?
- In a way, yes.
- Poor child.
- She's unhappy?
- When were you in Vienna?
- Oh, I've been there many times.
I'm interested in Julia and Henry.
What seems to be their trouble?
I never see Henry any more.
He has no time for riffraff like me.
He now consorts with the vulgar rich,
like Mrs Hamilton.
You know she had me fired from
the university here? Said I was a radical.
I, who have never taken any interest
in politics since the death of Nero.
Look at that. Henry's old church,
perishing from neglect.
- It's such a nice little church.
- Too little, I'm afraid.
It can't stand up
against the march of progress.
Well, I must be pushing on.
- Delighted to have seen you.
- A pleasure.
We must have a drink
to those old days in Vienna.
By all means!
- Good evening, Professor.
- Oh, Pat?
Have you any idea who that man is?
No. He's a stranger to me.
- Good evening.
- Good evening, Matilda. Hello, Queenie.
- Is Debby in bed yet?
- Yes, ma'am.
Mrs Hamilton and the committee
are in there with the bishop.
The dinner's been waiting a long time.
We didn't know what to do about it.
- We'll have dinner as soon as they leave.
- But what about the chicken?
Don't worry about it, Matilda, please.
Thank you.
Oh, Matilda. My bag.
Oh, I'm terribly sorry I'm so late.
Good evening, Mrs Hamilton.
I was delayed Christmas shopping.
Good evening, Mr Perry, Mrs Trumbull.
Hello, Mrs Ward.
I hope you've been having
a good meeting.
We have not. I've never in my life
encountered such fuzzy thinking.
- Do you think we've made any progress?
- No.
- Mr Perry was about to tell us something.
- Merely a suggestion.
If Mrs Hamilton approves,
we can place the George B Hamilton
Memorial Chapel here on the north-east.
It will be out of sight there.
I won't stand for it.
Mrs Hamilton, this cathedral cannot be
designed for the glory of an individual.
- It has to be created for all the people.
- I'm very displeased at your attitude.
I was instrumental in making you Bishop,
although others thought you too young.
- Is that an exaggeration?
- Oh, yes, Mrs... I mean, no.
- You were the guiding spirit.
- I distinctly remember...
I had confidence in you when you were
a poor little parson in the slums.
I confess my confidence is weakened.
I regret I've been a disappointment.
Regrets are no good whatsoever.
You give me the impression of being
confused, indecisive and ineffectual.
That is not the kind of leadership
we expect of our bishop.
You'd better remember one thing.
You will build that cathedral as I want it
or you will not build it at all.
That's all I have to say.
- Someone get this dog out of the way.
- Julia?
Queenie.
- Goodbye, Mrs Hamilton.
- Good evening, Mrs Brougham.
- Can we serve dinner now?
- Yes, Matilda.
- The chicken will be burned to a crisp.
- We'll be right in.
Julia, you knew Mrs Hamilton
was expected this afternoon.
I know, Henry. I'm sorry I was late.
What a ghastly afternoon.
What a ghastly woman.
I have no intention
of being strangled by her purse strings.
I was proud of you.
I had a most un-Christian impulse to give
her a good whack over the... mink coat.
I thought you stood up
to her magnificently.
I appreciate your appreciation
but what about my cathedral?
May I make a suggestion, Henry?
Why not postpone the cathedral
till after Christmas?
Impossible. The House of God
can't be put off. This cathedral must rise.
Plenty of rich people in this town. I'll have
to take advantage of their Yuletide spirit.
I can see it all now.
The McWhirters, the Hornes, the Van
Deusens, the lunches, the meetings
and you there flattering them.
- Kowtowing to them, begging.
- It's got to be done.
Oh, Henry. If you could see
your poor harassed face.
- You haven't done very much to help it.
- Miss Cassaway, what is it?
- Mr Trevor on the phone, Bishop.
- Tell him the bishop will call him back.
Yes, Mrs Brougham.
Henry, what's happened to you?
What's happened to our marriage?
We used to have such fun,
you and Debby and I.
We used to be happy
and make other people happy.
Henry, that was your gift.
You're no financier or promoter.
Julia, I want this cathedral to stand
like a great beacon. I want its light...
Oh, never mind. Keep that
for your next committee meeting.
- Here's a contribution I collected.
- What's that?
It's an old Roman coin. Professor
Wutheridge sent it. Wasn't that sweet?
Old fool. What does
he think I can do with that?
Well, it's a beginning.
Now all you need is another four million.
Julia, don't be flippant about this!
- Is dinner ready?
- Yes.
Let's go in and get it over with.
I have a lot of work to do.
For what we are about to receive, may
the Lord make us truly thankful. Amen.
- Julia?
- Yes?
I was just thinking... tomorrow
maybe we could go out together.
Where?
Well, just walk around
the way we used to.
We could go and call on the professor,
go to the park and watch the skaters -
that sort of thing.
Maybe we could have lunch together.
At Michel's. Do you remember that?
Michel's. Oh, it's been years
since we've been there.
(door opens)
Forgive me.
I've been trying to explain to Mr Trevor,
but he insists upon speaking to you
personally, Bishop.
Excuse me, darling.
(rings bell)
Matilda, keep the soup warm.
The bishop's been called to the phone.
- And we'll be out for lunch tomorrow.
- Yes, ma'am.
Of course, Mr Trevor. Yes, but...
I appreciate your difficulties, but...
Very well. I'll be there.
10:30 tomorrow morning,
then on to the board meeting.
All right. Yes. Goodbye.
Mr Trevor's office, 10.30, then the board
meeting in the Banker's Club at eleven.
- Yes, sir. Tomorrow. Thursday.
- You might as well go home.
- But there's a great deal to do.
- You must be tired.
Thank you. Don't forget tomorrow
you speak at the Junior Assembly.
- What time is that?
- One o'clock.
You made the appointment
over a month ago.
- Good night, Bishop.
- Good night.
Oh, God, what am I to do?
Can't you help me?
Can't you tell me?
Oh, God, please help me.
(door shuts)
Yes?
- Good evening.
- Good eve...
- What can I do for you?
- That isn't the question.
Well, what is the...?
What can I do for you?
I must ask you to telephone my secretary.
I'm in the middle of dinner.
I know, Henry. Your soup will keep warm.
You asked for help.
I? I... Who told you I asked for help?
Well, you were known to be a good man,
Henry, and you were heard.
I was instructed to come here
in answer to your prayer.
- Who are you?
- I'm an angel.
- I beg your pardon?
- No wings at the moment, but...
- You're an angel.
I knew it. I've been working too hard.
I understand, Henry.
It's hard to believe, even for you.
I'm not one of the more important angels.
I just happen to be assigned
to this district temporarily.
You see, we're everywhere,
helping people who deserve to be...
...to be helped.
As you're walking through the city,
you may look into a strange face.
It may be the face of a murderer
or it may be the face of an angel.
You have some problems
with the building of this cathedral?
- Yes.
- It's a fine cathedral.
Ought to look magnificent up there
on top of Sanctuary Hill.
Well, Henry.
Do you believe I am what I say I am?
How can I? I've only got your word for it.
But you're a bishop.
You can trust the word of an angel.
I'd like to.
What do you propose to do?
- Perform a miracle?
- If necessary.
Why don't you? Create the cathedral
with one wave of your hand.
- How would you explain it?
- Well, I...
Tell the world
you're being visited by an angel?
You can't do that.
Henry, is anything wrong? I...
- Oh. I'm sorry. I didn't know you had...
- Julia. If you don't mind...
How do you do, Julia? I'm Dudley.
Henry is engaging me
to help him with his work.
- You're going to be his assistant?
- That's it.
I'm going to help Henry
to rest and get some relaxation.
- That's what I've been praying for.
- You too?
Henry. I'm so relieved. Isn't it wonderful
you've found someone to help?
- Yes, but...
- Where do you come from?
- All around.
- Yes. But where?
Julia, to tell you the truth,
he says that he's an a...
I've been doing some
social service work down town.
Now you'll be with Henry permanently?
For as long as may be necessary.
Julia, if you don't mind. I must talk to this
gentleman alone. I'll see you in a moment.
We were just having dinner.
Won't you join us?
That's very kind of you,
but I have a number of things to do.
You can understand, Henry.
So many people making mistakes.
- Yes. I see.
- Then we'll see you tomorrow?
- Oh, yes. Bright and early.
- Good.
Whenever you're ready, Henry.
Good night, Dudley.
Good night, Julia.
Are you sure you're an angel?
I know it isn't easy,
but you've got to take me on faith.
- Yes, but for how long?
- For just long enough.
Until you can utter another prayer and
say that you have no further need of me.
Then I'll be gone and forgotten.
But now Julia's waiting for you
at the dining table. You must go to her.
Yes.
But I don't...
- Henry?
- Yes?
What's the rest of Dudley's name?
- I don't know.
- Oh.
(ice clinks)
Are you nervous, dear?
No.
- The bishop didn't eat his breakfast.
- No. He took only his prune juice.
Prune juice? Is he sick?
He looked perfectly awful.
He said he had a very bad sleepless night.
Passing up a breakfast like that.
It just ain't normal.
Nobody expects him to be normal.
He's a bishop.
- Could I get you something, sir?
- No, thank you, Matilda.
- Maybe just a cup of tea?
- Nothing, thank you.
- Good morning, Miss Cassaway.
- Good morning, Bishop.
Did anything come
for the Cathedral Fund?
Mr and Mrs J Thurston Ward.
No contribution.
- Mrs Gerald Wilmarth. $15.
- 15? We had her down for ten thousand.
There's a letter explaining that this year...
I know. The same letter they all write.
I've put your personal mail on the desk.
The rest I'm taking to the office.
I'll be there after the meetings.
Oh. Matilda, I think
there's someone at the door.
Yes, sir.
Good morning, Matilda.
I'm Dudley, the bishop's new assistant.
Good morning, Henry.
I'm afraid I'm a little late,
but I stopped to chat to a traffic policeman
who was worried about his wife.
Thank you, dear. So I directed the traffic
while he telephoned the hospital.
- I see.
- She's doing fine. So's the baby.
Why, you must be Mildred Cassaway.
How do you do?
- How do you do?
- We're going to be working together.
That's very nice.
Oh, thank you.
- Thank you very much.
- See you later, Mildred.
Well. Ready for duty.
Completely at your service.
- No, no.
- I feel that...
No.
- Good morning, Julia.
- Good morning, Dudley. It's a lovely day.
- Lovely.
- Henry and I are going out.
- I'm sorry, but I have some appointments.
- You what?
There's Mr Trevor, then the board meeting
and the Junior Assembly.
- But, Henry, you promised.
- I know I did.
Well, Dudley could represent you
at those meetings, couldn't he?
Could I?
No. They expect me. It would never do
if I sent an a... assistant.
Excuse me.
Now...
Oh.
- The trouble is I can't explain.
- You needn't try to explain.
This is the way it is
and the way it will always be.
We've just got to get used to it, that's all.
I'll tell Matilda she can have the day off
and I'll take care of Debby.
I see that Mrs George B Hamilton
has pledged $1 million
- but has not yet sent her cheque.
- Never mind.
That's work for a bookkeeper,
not an ange... Work for a bookkeeper.
Aha. So you're beginning
to believe in me?
I don't know who you are,
where you came from or who sent you.
I just wish you'd make haste.
- Because the cathedral must be built?
- That's the most important thing.
Or because Julia must be happy?
It's going to be difficult to help you
until I'm sure what you want.
Well, I've got the...
Then there's... Oh.
Would you mind telling me
what you intend to do now?
This card index file is in an awful mess.
I'll reorganise it.
You're wasting time
on unimportant details.
Nothing's unimportant. We are
interested even in the lowliest sparrow.
- Hello, Debby.
- Are you Dudley?
- Yes. How did you know?
- Mummy told me.
She said you came to help Daddy.
- That's right.
- Mummy said you were very nice.
Well, that's extremely kind of Mummy.
Mummy said that maybe with you here
we will get to see Daddy sometimes.
- Maybe we will.
- That'll be enough out of you, Debby.
I asked Matilda
to put your lunch on a tray.
- Thank you, Julia. I'll get along very well.
- I'm sure you will. Come on.
- Goodbye, Dudley.
- Bye-bye, Debby.
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
Oh.
- Oh. Thank you, Matilda.
- Aren't you going to wear a hat?
- I never use one.
- It's very cold out.
- Oh, the cold never affects me.
- I think you should wear this.
I bought it for the bishop last Christmas,
but he's never worn it.
It's a lovely scarf. I'm sure the bishop
will appreciate it when he sees it on me.
- Thank you. Goodbye.
- Bye.
Goodbye.
- What's the matter, honey?
- They don't want me.
- Why not?
- I guess I'm too little or something.
Oh. Now, now.
Why, that's the most ridiculous thing
I've ever heard.
Why, Dudley.
Come on, Debby.
We'll show them how wrong they are.
Hey, fellas. Hey, fellas!
Who's the head man around here?
- I am.
- What's the idea of this game?
- This isn't a game. This is a battle.
We attack the fort
and they try to defend it. See?
I see. Well, this young lady
would like to get into it.
- Who, her?
- She can't fight. Her father's a bishop.
What difference does it make? Are you
high-hat? You like her on your team?
She couldn't throw a snowball
as far as I could spit.
Oh, couldn't she? Come on, Debby.
You show them what you can do.
- But it's true. I can't throw.
- Nonsense. Of course you can.
Pack it tight, put it in that hand,
throw the arm back, aim it and let it go.
- Hey!
- Beautiful! A bullseye.
- She pitched a curve.
- Did you see that?
Come on, kid. You're in our army.
We've broken their morale.
Charge!
- Will she get hurt?
- Probably, but she'll love it.
- May I?
- Surely.
Dudley, what are you doing out here?
- I'm just admiring the scenery.
- But aren't you supposed to be working?
I always take a walk before lunch.
A good idea - relaxing.
Oh. I wish you could
persuade Henry to do that.
I'll try.
By the way, I told Miss Cassaway to go
home and Delia not to bring me a tray.
What will you do about lunch?
I thought I'd go to Michel's.
Ever heard of it?
Michel's. That's a lovely place.
We used to go there.
That was years ago.
Well, how about
you and I going there today?
You and...? To Mich...?
Oh, no, I couldn't.
Why not? Surely you don't think
Henry would mind?
- I'd explain to him that we just...
- No, it isn't that, but...
Matilda's off Christmas shopping
so I have to look after Debby.
Well, here's Matilda now.
- Hello. If you wish... Oh, hello.
- Hello.
- If you wish, I'll take Debby home.
- But, Matilda, your shopping...
I finished it. I finished it so quick
it was just like a miracle.
Mummy! We won!
Oh, Debby, that's wonderful!
Congratulations.
- Come on! We're giving out the medals.
- Put up your hood, dear.
- Madam, welcome.
- Oh, Michel.
- It's been a long time.
- Much too long.
- But you know my husband's work.
- Yes.
He doesn't come to see us any more,
but we understand.
We understand.
This way, please.
- Is this satisfactory, monsieur?
- Fine, thank you.
- Friends of yours?
- Yes.
They're members
of the Cathedral Committee.
- Madam. Monsieur.
- No, thank you, Michel.
Julia, don't bother to look through that.
Michel, just bring us
the best lunch you can think of.
I see monsieur is a gourmet.
Perhaps you would be interested
in a guinea-hen a la Michel?
- J'ai les truffles Francaises. Exquise!
- Je prefere les Italiennes.
Prefere les Italiennes?
Quel sacrilege!
Please, Michel,
let's leave heaven out of this.
Je prefere les Italiennes
surtout pas de cayenne, du paprika.
Du paprika? Du paprika.
You speak French beautifully.
I've had quite a bit of work to do in Paris.
- Dudley, I've been wondering about you.
- Wondering about me? Why?
You know so much.
Makes me feel uncomfortable.
Well, in that case,
I'm sorry I learned anything.
But I'm glad you knew about Michel.
Oh, it's so nice to be back here again.
So nice.
You have memories of this place, Julia?
- Did you and Henry come here often?
- Yes.
This is where we became
engaged to be married.
Ah. Then I can understand
why you love it.
- Oh, hello.
- Pardon me.
Thank you. What about that?
My. Would you care
to have your palm read?
Oh, no, thank you.
Would you?
No, thanks. I know too much
about myself as it is.
You are different.
I know so little about myself.
Really? May I look at your hand?
- Can you do that too?
- It's not too difficult.
- You can read the future?
- Within limits.
He's holding her hand.
Well, what do you see?
Well, I never noticed.
Your eyes are green.
I see a great deal of happiness.
I see a woman who's adored.
I see a rich, full life.
- Do you see Henry's new cathedral?
- No. There's a fuzziness about that.
- Oh. And Debby?
- No need to worry about her.
Just thinking. The world changes
but two things remain constant.
- What?
- Youth and beauty.
They're really one and the same thing.
- Yes. The trouble is people grow old.
- Not everybody.
The only people who grow old
were born old to begin with.
You were born young.
You'll remain that way.
- Oh, I wish I could believe you.
- You may.
You haven't looked at my hand once.
I never know what to make of you. I never
know whether you're joking or serious.
I'm at my most serious when I'm joking.
Excuse me, Julia.
Gotta do something about that.
Do forgive me coming to your table.
My name is Dudley.
I believe you're all friends of Julia's.
Would you care to join us?
- Oh, no, thank you.
- Well, join us for some coffee?
How about that? Do come over.
Julia would be delighted.
- All right.
- Well, that'd be lovely.
- That's very nice.
- Just over here.
Hello, Mrs Caster.
How are you? Nice to see you.
Hello. How are you?
Michel, bring us three Benedictines.
- No, no. Make it three Stingers.
- Oui, monsieur.
Julia?
Julia!
- Matilda, is lunch ready?
- We thought you were out for lunch.
I cancelled my appointment.
Is Mrs Brougham home?
- Debby's here, sir.
- And Mrs Brougham?
Why, sir, she went out to lunch
with Mr Dudley.
- With Dudley?
- Why, yes, sir.
I thought you knew, sir.
Yes, of course.
(door slams)
That's awful. Merry Christmas.
Santa Claus doesn't really look like that.
- You know Santa Claus?
- Certainly. Nice chap.
You must tell Debby about him. She's
just beginning to be a little bit doubtful.
- You like that hat?
- Yes, I'm crazy about it.
- Well, let's go in and buy it.
- Oh, no, I couldn't.
- Why, it's much too...
- Too what? Too attractive?
- My old friend, the professor.
- Hello, Professor.
- Julia! Are you with this man?
- Yes, of course. It's Dudley.
The professor knows me well.
University of Vienna.
I've been thinking about that.
I don't believe you've ever been to Vienna.
He always pretends
he's never seen me before.
I don't know who he is,
but I don't trust him.
- Professor, he's Henry's new assistant.
- Oh.
- You know this fellow?
- Of course I do.
Well, in that case, how about dropping in
for a bit of Yuletide cheer?
No, no. I have to go home. I...
Well, perhaps just for a few minutes.
Good. Come along.
There's a little sherry left.
It's rather inferior grade, but potable.
Professor, I see you're a religious man.
- What makes you think that?
- You have an angel on your tree.
Julia gave me that years ago.
- Your tree is beautiful.
- It's disgraceful.
However, it gives me the illusion
of peace on earth, goodwill toward men.
- To a charming lady.
- Lovely.
- You've noticed?
- Isn't it remarkable that you have?
Remarkable? When you want to know
about a woman, ask the old men.
They know.
Why don't you show us
the manuscript of your book?
- My book?
- Yes.
- Oh, no, no.
- You're writing one?
Yes.
- You didn't know?
- You didn't tell me.
I described that book in detail at the
lectures I gave at the University of Vienna.
All my pupils heard me.
Now I'm certain this fellow's an impostor.
That book?
I thought you'd finished that years ago.
I'll tell you... I'll tell you about my book.
For 20 years I've been talking about it
and promising the publishers
it'll be delivered next spring.
The funny part is
that I haven't written one word.
- Not one word.
- Why not?
I couldn't think of anything original to say.
Just the same old monotonous history.
Dry as dust.
That's the whole story of my life.
Frustration.
It's a chronic disease and it's incurable.
Once I was madly...
Once I was madly in love with a girl.
My friends, she was a vision of delight.
A pure enchantress.
- You never told me about it.
- That's the trouble.
I never told her about it either.
I couldn't find the words.
So she married an athlete.
A great hulking oaf who never
even reached the eighth grade.
But he knew how to say "I love you."
Same trouble with my book.
Can't find the words.
Even when you had this coin
to inspire you?
Why, that's the one
that you gave to Henry.
- Yes. I stole it off the table.
- You wasted your time. It's worthless.
On the contrary, this is
one of the rarest of all antiquities.
Only one hundred of these coins were
minted by Julius Caesar 2,000 years ago.
That was when Cleopatra visited Rome.
Presumably, these were used
to pay her hotel bill.
- I never knew that.
- Nobody knew except Caesar's wife.
- She was suspicious?
- Definitely.
She did not share her husband's
admiration for Cleopatra.
So she had these coins destroyed -
melted into ornaments.
This is the one she missed.
It's an unwritten chapter in history
and you, Professor, will write it.
- Do you know any more stories like that?
- Any number of them.
- You're a curious fellow, Dudley.
- Have you just begun to notice?
- What's your background?
- My background?
- Where do you come from?
- Well...
And don't tell me more about Vienna
because I won't believe it.
All right. If I told you I came from
another planet, would you believe me?
- I don't know.
- I'd believe you, Dudley.
And you'd be right, Julia, as always.
We all come from our own little planets.
That's why we're all different.
That's what makes life interesting.
We don't seem to be
making any headway.
First star I see tonight.
You must make a wish, Julia.
Oh, it's getting dark. Must be late. Henry
will be worried. We must be leaving.
- Oh, no.
- Yes. I'm sorry, Professor, but we must.
- Dudley?
- Yes, my friend.
- There's one thing that troubles me.
- What's that?
I'm an old man.
That history is a tremendous task.
I wonder... will I have time to finish it?
You'll finish your history, Professor.
You'll have time.
I believe you, Dudley.
For quite a while now,
every time I passed a cemetery,
I've felt as if I were apartment hunting.
Goodbye, Professor.
You've given an old man
a very happy afternoon.
- God bless you both.
- Thank you.
I'll pass that recommendation along.
(clock chimes)
My, that's pretty.
Why don't you take some of that pink stuff
and make little curlicues?
- I hope the dinner won't be spoilt.
- No, sir. I had a feeling they might be late.
Yes... Very considerate of you.
What's that cake for?
- What cake?
- That cake behind you.
That cake. Oh, for anybody
who might like cakes, sir.
But neither Mrs Brougham nor myself
like elaborate desserts.
But we've baked you an egg custard, sir.
(door opens, voices)
Hello, dear.
I'm sorry we were late for dinner.
- Good evening.
- We've had a marvellous time.
- I wish you'd been with us.
- Debby told me about the snow fight.
Did she? We went to see Professor
Wutheridge and we had lunch at Michel's.
- Is Debby in bed?
- No. She's waiting to see you.
Good. I'll just go up and say good night.
I won't be a minute.
I just want to see if she's all right.
- I trust you spent a profitable afternoon?
- Oh, yes.
Did you have a profitable afternoon?
Not very. I'd like to see you...
for a moment.
Certainly.
Excuse me.
Can you prove to me
that you are an angel?
Proof? You mean a document?
Surely you of all people should know
that an angel needs no passport.
I want to see you perform a miracle.
- What kind?
- Well...
Make this desk fly around the room.
Please. I didn't come down here
to do silly tricks. I'm surprised at you.
I don't believe you're an angel.
- I think you're a demon right out of...
- Oh, Henry. Don't say that.
- Well, anyway, you know how I feel.
- Yes.
Wait a minute.
There's another thing.
Oh. Dinner is served, Bishop.
Thank you, Dudley.
For what we are about to receive, may
the Lord make us truly thankful. Amen.
Pass the celery, Henry, please.
- Hm?
- The celery.
Thank you.
(happy humming)
What's that you're humming?
I don't know, dear.
Is it anything?
- It's rather gay.
- Well, I feel gay.
I like to watch you brushing your hair.
Thank you, dear. Is that a compliment?
Yes. You do it so... so capably.
Thank you.
In fact, now I come to think of it,
everything you do is capable.
I pride myself on the fact that we lead
a well-ordered life. The family, I mean.
Of course, the credit for that is due to you
much more than to me.
- I think you're an excellent wife.
- Thank you.
- Do you think I'm an excellent husband?
- Of course.
We're having an early supper
so we get to St Timothy's on time.
- St Timothy's?
- The rehearsal for the benefit.
- Oh, yes.
- You've been looking awfully tired lately.
I hope you're going to take it easier
now that Dudley's here.
- I think that he's very able.
- You do?
- Yes. He knows so many things.
- What, for instance?
You should have seen him
with Professor Wutheridge.
He knows more about history
than the professor.
He's been at it longer.
(laughter)
- (Dudley) Let's do that again.
- No. Tell me a story.
- What, now?
- Don't you know any stories?
- I know hundreds of stories.
- Tell me one. Please.
All right. Let me think.
This happened many, many years ago.
That's not the way to begin.
Stories start "Once upon a time".
Yes, that's true.
Once upon a time there was a little boy
and he lived in a little town.
- What was his name?
- His name was David. He was a shepherd.
The town was called Bethlehem.
I know Bethlehem.
That's where the star was.
That's right.
Only David lived long before the star.
One night, David was out in the hills
tending his sheep.
- He was playing the harp and singing.
- Was he singing "Jingle Bells"?
No, no. "Jingle Bells"
hadn't been written then.
David was singing songs
that he wrote himself.
Suddenly, an angel came down
and spoke to David.
- How did David know it was an angel?
- He didn't know.
And that's the way it always is.
Angels come and put ideas
into people's heads
and people feel very proud of themselves
because they think it was their own idea.
This angel said to David
"One of your lambs has strayed."
So David put aside his harp and went
into the darkness to find the lamb.
The angel guided him.
And when David found the lamb,
he saw a great big ferocious lion.
Oh!
So David said to the lion
"You get away from that lamb."
And the lion said "You get away from me
or I'll eat you too."
- Did David run away?
- No.
You know why? Because the angel
put another idea into his head.
So David took out his sling
and he hurled a stone
and hit the lion right between the eyes.
I bet that lion was surprised!
Yes. And so was David because
he didn't know an angel had helped him.
Well, he picked up the lamb
and took it back to the fold.
Then he felt so happy that he made up
another song. It started out:
"The Lord is my shepherd.
I shall not want."
"He maketh me to lie down
in green pastures."
"He leadeth me besides the still waters."
"He restoreth my soul..."
You can tell the rest of this, Henry.
- Some other time.
- Hello, Daddy.
Miss Cassaway, will you get
Mrs Hamilton on the telephone?
- Miss Cassaway? Mrs Hamilton.
- Yes, Bishop.
- Good morning, Julia.
- Dudley.
I'll see you in a few minutes.
I have to see Matilda.
- Bye, Debby.
- Goodbye, Dudley.
- Thank you.
- Oh. Pretty.
Are you expecting a letter?
One never knows. If I should get one,
the stamp will be worth saving.
I'll have Mrs Hamilton in a moment.
- Are you seeing Mrs Hamilton?
- I hope to.
- May I come along? I'd like to meet her.
- Mrs Hamilton? Bishop Brougham.
Hello, Mrs Hamilton. How are you?
I'm glad to hear it.
Mrs Hamilton, I'd like to see you today.
This afternoon, if possible.
Yes, it is. It's very urgent.
- Oh, that's too bad.
- Terrible.
You can? Oh, that's splendid.
Thank you so much.
I'll be there. Five o'clock this evening.
Thank you, Mrs Hamilton.
Henry, you didn't make
an appointment for this afternoon?
Yes. It was the only time.
You can't do this to Reverend Miller.
The rehearsal's just for you.
They'll get along without me.
There are other things more important.
- Mr Miller will be delighted to see you.
- But it's not the same. You're his bishop.
I don't like going alone.
It's the big house
at the end of this street, driver.
Dudley, I take it that...
that you have the money for the taxi.
No. What makes you think I have money?
Oh, I just thought that you being an a...
Oh, goodness!
- I'm sorry.
That's all right.
Thank you.
- I won't be late. I may even join you.
- Please try.
I'll see you in front
of St Timothy's in one hour.
- Try.
- I will be there.
- Good.
- This is it, driver.
- Good evening, Bishop.
- How are you, Stevens?
- Mrs Hamilton's in the drawing room, sir.
- Thank you.
Well, Bishop Brougham.
My dear Mrs Hamilton,
I've come to tell you...
- You've come to apologise, I trust.
- Exactly.
Upon consideration,
my objections seem petty
compared with the generosity
of your gesture.
I'm very much relieved.
Sit down, Mr Brougham.
What hurt most was to think
that my instinct had betrayed me
in recommending you for your position.
I'm unceasingly grateful.
Now, I'm taking it for granted
that the George B Hamilton Memorial
Chapel shall be located...
Just where you specified.
You no longer feel the effect will be
that it was built in my husband's honour?
That was said in dispute.
What matters is the cathedral be built.