×ÖÄ»
This is an outlaw regime.
The Sandinistas have even involved themselves
×ÖÄ»
in the international drug trade.
I know every American parent
×ÖÄ»
concerned about the drug problem will be outraged
to learn that top Nicaraguan government officials
×ÖÄ»
are deeply involved in drug trafficking.
This picture, secretly taken at a military airfield
×ÖÄ»
outside Managua,
shows Federico Vaughan, a top aide to one of
×ÖÄ»
the nine comandantes who rule Nicaragua...
Fuck!
×ÖÄ»
loading an aircraft with illegal narcotics
Motherfuckers! That's your fucking face, Barry!
×ÖÄ»
This is a outlaw regime.
Oh, my God.
×ÖÄ»
Just as you said, Pablo.
That son of a bitch.
×ÖÄ»
Pablo, we must face it immediately.
- Go on. - Yes, sir.
×ÖÄ»
I am truly sorry, Barry. North jumped the gun.
Well, you boys fucked me good.
×ÖÄ»
We all got fucked.
Those photos weren't supposed to be released.
×ÖÄ»
And certainly not until we had the Colombians in custody.
Yeah, well, he ain't gonna be comin' for you.
×ÖÄ»
Barry, you knew the risks
when you took those pictures.
×ÖÄ»
You knew what you were doing.
Barry?
×ÖÄ»
Barry, you there?
Let's go get some ice cream.
×ÖÄ»
The Feds. They're gonna try to take everything.
When they come...
×ÖÄ»
you gotta put on all your jewelry.
All your rings. Your bracelets.
×ÖÄ»
Necklace.
If you wearin' it, they can't take it away from you.
×ÖÄ»
You understand?
And that's insurance for you and the kids.
×ÖÄ»
All right?
I understand.
×ÖÄ»
All right, don't forget that. It's gonna be all right.
- It's gonna be all right, I love you. - I love you.
×ÖÄ»
Sure enough, they came.
And they took it all.
×ÖÄ»
Hey, you know, Luce, honey...
I was thinkin'...
×ÖÄ»
that you might like to move back to Baton Rouge.
You ain't gonna find nothin' in those drawers.
×ÖÄ»
Try the hat boxes, third shelf up.
I mean, you loved it there.
×ÖÄ»
What about you?
I mean, I...
×ÖÄ»
Me... Listen, see...
Look, if I run, they're uh...
×ÖÄ»
They're gonna come for you and the kids. I mean...
That's how a thing like this goes.
×ÖÄ»
But in Baton Rouge, you're safe.
No.
×ÖÄ»
No, I ain't goin' nowhere.
We're a family, and we're stayin' together.
×ÖÄ»
- I know, but... - No, sir!
- I ain't doin' this. No. - Listen, Luce...
×ÖÄ»
No, no. Honey, no. Don't do this now.
Sir, sir, I'm sorry, no, no, no.
×ÖÄ»
Come on, sir.
Excuse me, she's wearin' this now.
×ÖÄ»
Luce, you gotta stop. Hey.
You know, fellas! Sorry, hey...
×ÖÄ»
Can I just have a moment?
Can I just have a moment with my wife?
×ÖÄ»
It's been a hell of a day.
- Okay, Barry. - Yeah.
×ÖÄ»
You got one minute.
All right, Luce? Honey, honey...
×ÖÄ»
- Honey, listen to me. - Let's give him a minute.
- Baby, baby, listen to me. - All right, fellas, head on out.
×ÖÄ»
Listen to me now.
Ima go to prison.
×ÖÄ»
I'm gonna do just- just a little time.
And Ima be fine there.
×ÖÄ»
And we'll work everything out.
But I gotta know you gonna be safe.
×ÖÄ»
It's gonna be all right.
You gotta trust me.
×ÖÄ»
You trust me, right?
Fuck no!
×ÖÄ»
All right.
Luce and the kids finally did move to Baton Rouge.
×ÖÄ»
How can we have a war on drugs...
when the biggest enemy of the state
×ÖÄ»
is being protected by our side?