Lord Albert is dead.
He was first with the symptoms.
Amazing he lasted as long as he did.
We must choose a new magistrate.
Let us at least bury the man
before we talk of his replacement.
We don't have the
luxury of time.
Decisions need to be made.
I for one have made mine.
Then your lot is cast
with Henry Bartlett.
He is the only one
who offers a solution.
Yes, but the risk is too high.
The risk of doing nothing is worse.
We're dying!
All of us.
How do we know his sorcery
hasn't brought the
pestilence on us?
How could you think that?
All I'm saying is that it's
dangerous, he's dangerous.
I'm no danger
to you, Franklin.
I meant no offense, Bartlett.
But this is not rain for our
crops. This is life and death.
You're our magi, Bartlett.
If you can rid the town of the plague,
then let it be done.
He speaks for the town.
Not for all of us.
Enough of us.
We'll be dealing with
the darkest of powers.
Even to invoke
such an incantation...
There will be consequences.
Only someone with my mastery will be
able to hold sway over these matters.
And in order to do this, you
feel you need to be magistrate?
If I am to act, Franklin, I must
certainly have full authority to do so.
Sir Henry, sir.
You interrupt me, boy!
But, sir, it's
your daughter.
Father.
What is it, my child?
I have the spots now too.
Come with me, my child.
As I said, what higher price is there?
You must decide.
I, for one, will
not sit idly by
while my daughter
wastes away to nothing.
Then you will accept
the consequences?
Yes.
We are not complete
without you, Frankiln.
You must speak for
the rest of the town.
Yes.
Then so be it.
It is done.
No! No!
Every year, on this
day of the winter solstice,
one of us must be chosen.
He will be set at the
center of the town,
the stockade, bound
by chains and shackles.
The chosen one will wear a brand,
and he shall wait.
This will protect you
from all that is evil.
The disease, this plague
that I will pull forth
from each and every dying soul
won't be cast out entirely.
Everything evil,
everything malignant,
and everything wretched
about what has befallen us,
will rise anew, take shape,
a hideous beast spawned
from Hell itself.
Our fate is now left to the
mercy of that which must be fed.
This manifestation of our diseases,
what is this hideous
beast you speak of?
The ogre.
Ah! Ah!
This looks like a good place to camp.
Not yet.
Well, at least we gotta let
the girls catch up anyway.
We're getting close.
Close to what?
Not a cell tower, that's for sure.
Would you put that away?
We're roughing it.
Roughing it? From the
guy who walks into a tree?
You look like
you got punched out.
That tree came
out of nowhere.
Put that away!
You're like a child.
A guy can't rough it and still
know the score of the ballgames?
Hold up, Mike.
Does that look like the
entrance to a path to you?
Where'd you get this thing, anyway?
I bought it.
Not off the Internet?
It's authentic.
No, that's not a path.
You don't know,
you don't even care.
Hey, I care, I care.
It's a great story.
"A town lost in time."
A fun excuse to go camping.
It's not gonna be any
fun if you don't relax.
I'm relaxed.
Jessica, does that
look like a path to you?
No.
Not at all.
Both you guys are no fun.
Terry, you know it's unlikely
we'll actually find anything.
There was a town out here.
There were lots of towns
out here in the 1850's.
There's documented cases.
Documented cases,
Jess. Oh, hey, the book.
Documents!
Look. 1947. Hiker finds a
vintage musket lying in the woods.
Spotless, like brand new.
1964, two hunters are hunting,
and they see people in
Civil War era clothes.
And then those people
simply disappear.
It's written
right there.
Okay, I'm done with the trees.
Oh God, not the
stupid book again.
Why come if you don't believe this?
You know what? You guys are
sucking all the fun out of this.
Okay, Terry,
give me the map.
What? No.
Give me
the map.
No. Why?
Give me the map!
North.
There.
Let me see that.
You actually found it!
Terry...
If this is the path then
we need to go... Ugh!
That was a
spectacular display.
You alright?
Oh, oh, I can't.
It hurts.
Are you really hurt?
Oh.
Ooh!
Let me see.
Is it broken?
I can feel the edge of the bone.
Great, so what
do we do now?
We are in the middle of nowhere.
So if that's broken, you
can't walk out of here,
and we're not gonna get
far dragging your ass.
You're serious?
We should be smart.
You guys set up camp.
I'm gonna hike on, see
if I can find anything.
Like what?
A ranger's station,
a hunting lodge.
I'll go with you.
No, I'll be faster by myself.
Let's be safe, buddy system.
We'll split up.
You two set up camp.
We'll be back as soon as we can.
Okay? You guys will be fine.
You guys will be okay together.
Don't do anything I wouldn't.
I don't know how
to "set up camp!"
This is great.
What the hell is this?
Maybe there is
a town out here.
Do you think it's "Ellensford"?
Absolutely. it's also
a UFO fueling station.
Big Foot, the Loch Ness Monster,
they hang out here sometimes.
It's a huge party.
How do you close a town?
You don't.
Mike, it says no trespassing.
Yeah, but it doesn't
say "please." You coming?
How do you go on a camping trip and
not even know how to put up a tent?
It's an expedition.
They don't put up
tents on expeditions?
What do you think
I bring Mike for?
This is ridiculous.
I'm freezing.
I'm sorry.
Next time I'll break my ankle
next to a nice little cottage
with a potbellied stove.
What's that?
Mike, what if this is a ghost town?
Like I said,
we'll camp for the night and
I'll hike back out in the morning.
Well, it's not a ghost town.
Mike, wait! Shhh!
Listen, listen!
...one life for all life...
Uh, okay, creepy.
Creepy.
But it's people.
They could help.
They could be creepy people.
C'mon.
How about we go back.
How about no.
Can you help me up?!
Fine.
Oh, I slipped!
Whatever.
Looks like some kind of a trap door.
It's underground.
You're going too fast!
Stop being such a baby!
You're a baby.
I wonder why I never saw this before.
I don't know, it's freaky.
Look at that!
What do you
think it is?
I don't know!
It's creepy if you ask me.
Hey, watch it!
You're leading!
Just keep hobbling.
You have got to be kidding me.
It's the symbol, it's burnt in.
Werewolves.
No, it's not werewolves.
Don't you watch movies? That's
the symbol for a werewolf.
In pre-Christian paganism, the
five pointed star was the symbol
of the sacred feminine.
Read a book!
You're such a nerd.
What are you doing?
I'm trying to open the door.
What does it...
I'm not going in there.
This is the same symbol
that is on the map.
And?
We may have actually found
something connected to Ellensford.
Worst case it's a place
to get out of the cold.
And I'll stop hurting
myself on branches.
Ohhh, what is that smell?
I really try to like you,
you're hot, but open yourself
to something other than...
Terry?
Well, there is a town.
If there's a town,
must be a doctor, right?
Let's go.
Let me see, let me see.
Shhh!
Many years ago,
a plague took hold of our town.
Our young children lost
the very breath of life,
our women lost
their husbands,
our men, their
loving wives.
What was once a town of
several hundred strong
has been whittled down to
those of us in this room.
We are all of who remain.
As we start today's ceremony,
I suggest it is more important
today than ever before
to remember the pain and the
suffering that we all endured then,
so that perhaps we might
more fully understand
the pain and suffering that
we must certainly endure today.
Another life, for another year.
So it says in
the sacred pact.
We must ask the orb,
as we have in so
many years past,
to give us a name.
To tell us who is
the brave heart
that we will offer up.
One life, for all life.
Okay, let's go.
Yeah!
Ahh!
We have decided, and the
chosen one is Stephen Chandler!
We must stop this!
This is wrong. All of you!
We must fight the beast!
End the pact!
Search your hearts,
you know I am right!
No, Father, no!
Let us all offer a blessing
to Stephen Chandler.
May he have strength,
honor and peace.
No, Father, no!
Please Father, no!
Please don't!
Sorry, it's out of my hands!
Okay, guys, this is a
big misunderstanding.
What the hell is your problem?
He is coming.
Who's coming?
Good day, young travelers.
Good day for who?
Are we under arrest?
That remains to be seen,
you're trespassing.
I don't know if you're the mayor
or something but we need your help.
It was unwise of you
to ignore our sign.
We didn't see a sign.
What sign?
There is one road in
and out of Ellensford.
Otherwise it's surrounded
by forest. You saw our sign.
Did you just say
this is Ellensford?
Okay, we're sorry, you
know what, we saw your sign.
My friend's hurt. He possibly has
a broken ankle. He needs help...
You know what help is?
You should've gone
somewhere else.
We do not welcome
outsiders in Ellensford.
We have no way of knowing
what you have seen or heard.
Look, we get it. You've been
hospitable but we're gonna take off.
I do not think so, young man.
Now it's impossible for you to leave.
I'd like you to take our
guests to the waiting place.
Send men out to get their
friends in the woods,
and bring them to me at once.
Okay, guys.
Run!
Ahh!
Seriously get your hands off me!
Let go of me!
Any idea how many penal codes
you broke in the last five minutes?
Don't push me! My father's
a prominent attorney.
Okay, you're not even
allowed to do that.
You're not even a cop!
You guys are in
so much trouble!
We get a phone call, or
don't you guys have phones!?
It's in Sir Henry's hands now.
He makes the rules.
I bid you good luck.
And I bid you an idiot!
Mike, how can they leave us here?
I didn't do anything wrong!
Jess, relax, okay.
I'll get us out of here.
Not likely.
What'd they get you
for, jaywalking?
Jaywalking?
No.
I am the Chosen One.
That's pretty. Chosen for what?
It doesn't matter.
You should not have come here.
Really? Because we didn't
get that sense at all yet.
It's all in Sir Henry's hands now.
The guy with the stick?
You've got to be kidding me.
This is no joke.
You people cannot be serious.
Please, don't be serious.
Is this an actor's hamlet?
This whole thing is a play?
You pretend to be from
this mythical town?
Yeah?
I don't understand.
This is no play. No myth.
It is our plight.
Ah.
What's the Chosen One?
Chosen for what?
Sacrifice.
Ah, okay.
I don't believe this.
Sacrifice? They're gonna kill us?
Offer us to the gods,
that kind of thing?
Not you.
Me.
One life for the
prosperity of the many.
You got a bum rap.
These are very
serious matters.
A powerful spell
governs our land.
Oh, come on?
Come on to what?
She doesn't believe any
of this. Neither do I.
Whether you choose
to believe it or not,
tomorrow, I will be offered
as the sacrificial meal.
They're gonna
eat you?!
Not them.
Okay, who is
gonna eat you?
The ogre.
Hope, over the years we've
all lost those we love.
Including you and your father.
Yes, my mother was one of the first.
I remember it as if it was yesterday.
But at least she
died of the plague.
At least she died
of natural causes.
I don't know how natural
the plague was to begin with.
Never mind that. I've misspoken.
No, I've heard the rumors, Franklin.
I am not deaf.
We were all there that day.
Your father did what he had to do.
We all agreed.
You didn't. They forced
your hand, I remember it.
That was years ago.
What's done, is done.
Why are you here now?
You know I can't save Stephen.
Some people in the
town talk of ending it.
Stephen was the most
outspoken of them all.
But I understand that you share
his feelings. I do as well.
Not to offer sacrifice would
mean the death of us all.
We're already dead!
We're the living dead who each
year live in fear of being chosen.
Who can't leave this cursed town,
who don't age, don't marry,
don't have young.
Who calls this a life?
Please. I understand your
concerns, but there was a pact.
It is not easy to change that.
The people will follow you.
They trust you.
Look at me. Just by being here
I am opposing my own father.
You must speak to him.
If not for us, then
for the travelers.
I fear my father
has ill intentions.
Please, Franklin.
You must talk to him.
If they've crossed the boundary,
there's no following them.
What in God's name...
The doors are open.
It'll come for us all.
We must head back
and warn the others.
Ah! Ah! Ah!
Sir Henry?
How can I help you, Franklin?
I've come to talk
about these travelers.
What about them?
May I ask, what
are your intentions?
My intentions?
Why are you holding them?
Well, because they have seen too much.
What are you going to do
with them? Sacrifice them?
If such a possibility exists.
The outsiders have
not made this bargain.
It's wrong to punish them with
a curse we brought on ourselves.
It's murder.
How dare you?
So it is your intention.
My intention is, as always,
to do all that is necessary
to protect this town.
Should I do this thing,
then Stephen Chandler,
will have the opportunity
to live another two years,
perhaps even four if
we find the others.
How can you argue with that?
Are you telling me
the ceremony is rigged?
That the chosen one can be
changed at will? Your will?
The audacity you have to
question me on these matters.
I am this town's magistrate...
Don't throw that title at me!
I was there.
But it was given to me!
It was taken!
Get out.
A magi wanted to be magistrate.
Then suddenly a mysterious
plague befalls our town,
forcing our hand to anoint the only
one who has the power to stop it.
That is enough! Be
careful, Franklin!
Or what?
You'll choose me next?
You walk a very
dangerous line, my friend.
There is a growing number of
us who feel this should end.
We should stand up to
the ogre once and for all.
Kill the ogre and stop
making the sacrifice?
It's the ridiculous dream of a child.
Every year one of us is eaten.
That is a nightmare.
That is why I was made magistrate.
I knew none of you would have
the will to do what is necessary.
And what's that?
We sacrifice for your eternal life?
We are all in
this together.
Lest you forget, we don't
grow in number. I too will die.
Who will be the one to
chain you to the stockade?
## Swing low ##
## Sweet, sweet ogre ##
# Coming for
To carry me home #
Mike!
Shut up!
# What, Jessica? #
Don't you think maybe
we should do something?
I'm open to suggestions, sister.
Terry and Leah
are still out there.
They're in a better
position than we are.
I'm serious. Mike,
what about the...
you know...
Le ogre?
You serious?
You believe this guy?
He's a nut case!
Everybody in this town
is out of their freaking mind.
You shouldn't
have come here.
How could I not? I am regretful
for the actions of this town.
Indeed, as we are. Please doth
grant us swift exit from here
and we promiseth never
to returneth... again-eth.
He seems to be a jester of sorts.
I find him quite amusing
considering the dire circumstances.
It's Sir Henry's intention
to let young Stephen go
and offer up you as
the sacrifice instead.
Hope, we can't let that happen.
I'd listen to young
Stephen on this one.
I have learned things today.
An awful truth, my father...
What is it?
Know that even Franklin is
growing more brave by the minute.
Has he spoken to your father?
Yes. There is
no convincing him.
Hang on, is your
father Henry Bartlett?
Stick dude?
My condolences.
What the hell was that?
I must go.
Father!
Looking for something?
No. Well, yes.
A book.
Something I could help you with?
A book of stories,
from when I was small.
You're no longer
a child, my dear.
What possible curiosity could
such a book hold for you now?
It used to comfort me at
night when I was scared.
I want to give
it to young Stephen
to comfort him as
he awaits his end.
And what if young Stephen were
not to be chosen this year?
Or next, isn't that
what you mean?
There are two travelers
in the cell with Stephen.
I thought this would make you happy.
So you did this for me?
To make me happy?
Father, I am not happy!
None of us are! We don't know
what happiness is anymore!
Use your powers and put an end
to this. That'd make me happy.
I cannot do that.
Have you even tried?
Hope, even if I could reverse
such dark magic, I wouldn't do it.
Not if it meant I had to
sit by and watch my daughter
waste away to nothing.
I won't do that.
But these travelers were
not part of that pact.
So you would prefer this
happen to young Stephen?
I'd rather it be no one!
It is not possible!
If the ogre does not accept
the intended sacrifice,
he will exact his revenge
over the entire town,
a wrath only imaginable in
the very depths of hell itself!
I cannot and will not
preside over such an event!
How is one death
different from any other?
The men never returned.
I fear the worst.
What if the lair
has been disturbed?
We must send another search party.
No, it's too late for that.
Their fates have
already been sealed.
But, if the beast has eaten...
perhaps we need not
sacrifice tonight.
It's the very act of sacrifice,
of being chosen and
submitting to the beast itself
that fulfills our end of the bargain.
These travelers
have not been chosen.
But still, if the lair
has been disturbed,
we'll have to make a
sacrifice right away
to keep it from coming after us all.
Do you see?
Do you see now?
These travelers have brought
undue pain onto us all.
Because of them, two
more of us are dead.
It would appear that the
decision has been made for us.
The plague, it is true.
I hope Terry and
Leah are smart enough
to realize that we need help.
Maybe they can get us out of this.
You know, I bet Terry is
hopping to it right now.
Mike, I'm serious.
I'm just getting a little bit
scared here. it's not funny.
No, it's not funny!
It's ridiculous.
Stevie, this whole town of
yours, you are all freakin' nuts.
You should do what normal
kids do and run away.
We can't.
Why not?
I'd be so far gone right now.
That's you.
But we cannot leave this town.
And therein lies the rub.
Okay, Stevie, what happens
if you leave this town?
Awful things.
Night has fallen.
They will come for me soon.
Now I thought they
were coming for me.
Ohhh!
Mike, what is it?!
Shutter your windows!
Lock your doors!
Young Stephen.
The eyes of good fortune
look upon you this evening.
It is my time!
I am indeed the Chosen One.
Bring forth the boy.
Don't touch her.
Get your hands off her... oh!
Do not do this!
It is my turn! I am chosen!
Please, you don't understand!
No, please,
he didn't do anything!
I didn't do anything!
My friends are still out there!
They're calling the cops as we speak!
Your friends
are dead.
Dead at the hands of the beast.
You don't know that!
You are all at the mercy of the
ogre now and he shows no mercy.
Bring the boy!
Mike!
Jess, he's lying!
Jess!
Mike!
Get back here! Move!
Let go of me!
Let go!
Mike!
Stop it!
That's enough!
Cut it out!
This isn't funny!
Stop it!
I am warning you!
Stop this!
Mike!
Jess? It's okay!
Alright, it's cool.
You people are crazy.
All of you!
If anything happens to him...
Hope? Stay
inside now.
Let me go!
Take this off now!
I'm warning you!
This has gone way too far!
Dude, let me go!
Let me go! Let me go!
That's enough!
Get back here!
Hope?
Hope!
You risk everything.
Everything that
is worth risking.
Oh, God, shut up.
Where's Mike?
Let's go get him then, shall we?
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm great, I'm great.
We must hurry!
We must go.
This way.
Hope Bartlett!
Wait.
From here, you
must go on alone.
You're coming with us.
If you go back,
they're gonna feed
you both to the thing.
Maybe so,
but we cannot leave this place.
We cannot cross
the boundary.
If you weren't planning on
coming with us, then why...?
Because it's time.
You two aren't part of this.
We're a good people.
We've just lost our way.
Run! Run for your lives!
He can't cross it!
Stephen!
Hope?!
Stephen, no!
No!
Go! Get away from this place! Go!
The bell hasn't rung.
All is not well.
Sir Henry!
Sir Henry,
are you there?
He's gone?
I don't understand.
There was no sacrifice?
How could that be?
Could he have escaped?
Not without help.
Franklin, maybe this was your doing.
How could you suggest that?
We must assemble
the town immediately.
The prison cell is empty.
Treason! We must set
out and find them!
No! We must assemble. Now.
Where's Sir Henry?
We can right this wrong.
All of you, fair to the town hall.
In Sir Henry's absence,
it is my word.
It is my word.
Hope?
Hope!
Okay, I'm sorry, I know,
But did you see that?
The way he just... pft!
I know, Jess.
Look, this is gonna turn out okay.
We're gonna make it
through, believe that.
Oh, yeah, okay,
and what if what
that guy said was true
and Terry and Leah
really are dead?
I don't know, Jess.
We have to believe otherwise.
Oh my God!
Yes! Yes!
You see!
I'm so happy!
Okay.
We're okay.
What the hell are
we gonna tell people?
What?
The truth.
What truth?
The truth about an ogre?
A town lost in time,
that doesn't age?
The imaginary line that
disintegrates people in seconds?
Which one do you want to lead with?
We'll just have to
take them back there.
Never thought I'd say this,
but we need to find the cops.
We explain everything and
then we take them there,
and then we'll prove it!
Uh-huh.
Look, there's our ride.
This is not gonna go well.
Hello!
Where is Sir Henry?
And why was there no sacrifice?
What do we do now?
The ogre will seek revenge on us all!
Everyone, please!
We must remain calm.
We must use our wits, and not
be driven by fear or anger!
Where is Sir Henry, Franklin?
What kind of trickery is this?
I don't know where the others are.
What I do know is the
pact has been broken.
The ogre's wrath
may be set upon us.
There is still time!
Henry Bartlett could not just have
disappeared, he wouldn't do that!
I already went to his home.
He was nowhere to be found.
Perhaps then Sir Henry has gone
to capture the outsiders himself!
Perhaps, but we must move
on without Sir Henry for now.
Where's Hope?
And Stephen?
I don't know!
Do you know anything?!
Quiet, please!
Hope Bartlett!
Hope!
What are you doing out here, child?
I was worried sick.
You used to teach me
the craft once, remember?
We have no time for that, Hope.
I must offer up another
sacrifice before it is too late.
If we must sacrifice,
then choose me.
No. You'd never do that.
Who shall it be this time?
You don't understand.
Not Stephen.
He's already dead.
The outsiders are gone. Who's next?
Franklin? Is he your biggest threat?
You watch your
tongue, young lady.
Maybe you can waive your staff and cause
another plague, one worst then the last.
We can't wait!
We must sacrifice now.
It is our only chance!
And who is to choose?
You, Giles?
Or are you volunteering
yourself for sacrifice?
If the travelers made
it past the border,
then we should find Stephen
Chandler, as first planned.
And what if he is never found?
Enough!
This is pointless, people.
This is a sign.
The travelers were not
a harbinger of doom.
We need to look upon
them as a beacon.
An example that exposed
the ills of this town,
that have gone on for far too long.
Henry Bartlett lied
about the Chosen One.
No!
How much further
did his lies go?!
We must find him, then.
Accusations like this should
not be slung in his absence.
He is not here now.
Without him, it is my say.
I have found the book.
I have seen the spells!
You are a monster!
Hope, it wasn't
supposed to be this way.
It was only supposed
to be one... Lord Albert.
The town needed a new leader.
I knew what the town needed,
the town needed me.
The spell couldn't be controlled
and it spread. I did all I could.
You did what you wanted.
I gave you eternal life!
All you gave us was death.
Your gift, "This will protect
you from all that is evil."
Those were
your words, remember?
Hope...
Father... you are evil.
Evil or not, this town
needs me now, more then ever.
What could you possibly do?!
What we should have
done years ago.
Find a way to destroy the
beast without your help.
It can't be done!
Don't you understand!
That is the true
plague of Ellensford!
Kill the beast or not, it doesn't
matter, you will all perish!
I will rejoice the day.
We all will.
Hope.
Hope!
We need to take
arms against the beast.
Fight it once and for all.
That's like signing
our own death warrant!
Something is moving in the trees!
Hope!
Hope, you have given
us all a horrible scare!
Where is your father?
I do not know.
We all must listen to Franklin now.
There will be no more sacrifices.
If the ogre is to set his
wrath upon us, we must be ready.
We can't defeat the ogre.
I cannot stop the ogre, not yet.
But I can buy us some time.
Hope, what are
you talking about?
What is all this?
Years ago, my father passed
on some of his craft to me.
As a precaution should
this day ever come.
Do you want to live
through this night?
Then listen to me.
Everyone grab one candle.
Take only as many as you
need to last the night.
Franklin and I will
come to your homes
and teach you the magic of the candles
and how to use them against the ogre.
Henry Bartlett is alive, Lawrence.
His daughter and Franklin
are up to no good,
and it is up to us now
to restore the order.
What do you
suggest we do?
We've got to find Sir Henry.
But the ogre? Going into
the woods now is suicide.
And to follow the plan of
some impetuous young girl.
I say we find our leader.
Done.
Ahhhhhhh!
Unclean beast.
Really, thank you very much.
Are we really gonna do this?
I don't know.
Are you sure you got
that punch line right?
Help you?
Yeah, we were hiking in the woods!
Our friends got hurt!
...happened to our friends.
Whoa! Let's take this one at a time.
Why don't you both
sit down and slow down.
Our friends are lost.
This isn't gonna
be easy to explain...
Two of
our friends...
We were hiking...
Hang on, you're gonna
give me whiplash. You. Go.
We were on a hiking trip with two
of our friends, Terry and Leah.
Terry hurt, and he probably
ended up breaking his ankle.
So we left him to get some help...
Left him, huh?
No, we didn't "leave" like abandon.
They were okay when we left them.
"Were" okay?
Are okay.
"Were" or "are"?
Are!
You're not from
around here, are ya?
No, we're from...
Listen bro, this
is important...
Sheriff!
I'm sorry. Sheriff.
Know that town
out in the woods?
Like an Amish village?
Ellensford.
You hear that, Anderson?
They're looking for "Ellensford".
We're not looking for
Ellensford, we were there.
Son, I've lived here all my life. There's
no town out there. That's an urban myth.
We're not crazy!
We were there!
They kidnapped us and
locked us in a jail cell!
Kidnapped, huh?
Do you know what an ogre is?
Ogre? What the hell
are you talking about?
An ogre, okay? A beast, lives
in the woods, eats people?
Sure I know what an ogre is.
Anderson, you know what
an ogre is, don't you?
Yeah, sure do.
Name's Patty.
Been married 12 years.
We're raising a little ogre too.
I am not joking
around, this is serious!
Are you guys gonna
help us? We need help!
Sure we'll help ya.
I'm gonna go get the paperwork,
we'll take your statement, then
we'll see about finding your friends.
Okay, please hurry.
It'll just be a moment.
You two go sit over there.
Mike, no, no way.
They don't believe a word of it.
Would you?
No. No turning back now.
Anderson...
I got to go, bye!
Where'd they go?
Sheriff, I just turned away...
Son of a...
Sir Henry?
Sir Henry!
You hear something?
No.
Sir Henry?
Sir Henry!
Keep your voice down!
Why don't you set a table for the
ogre before you send him to dinner?
Giles, this is foolish.
We should go back.
And do what?
We must find Sir Henry.
What if something else has
already found Sir Henry?
Wait.
Giles!
We're stuck.
Yeah, no kidding. I told you
this thing couldn't go off road.
It's not a freakin' SUV.
Stop, stop!
Let me get out and check it.
Okay, go.
Mike!
Stop!
Feel better now?
Well, they're gonna come looking for it.
We wanted them out here anyways.
Yeah, but without the grand theft
auto charges would have been nice.
It's cute.
There we go.
Whoa, okay, do you know
how to work that thing?
No.
Okay, that's scary.
More shells.
You know, if we go back in
there, we may not come out.
Yeah, I know,
but, we have to try.
I told Leah and Terry
I was coming back for them.
Just making sure we're
working with all our faculties.
After everything I've
seen in these woods so far,
I'm winging it.
At best.
Okay.
Pour a circle of salt
around your house.
The circle will act as
protection against the ogre.
This is our barrier, keeps
us from leaving this town.
Once your candle is lit, you
must keep the candle burning.
Now repeat these
words with us.
Within this circle, all
things material and human,
shall be safe and untouched
from the evil within the forest
until the flame burns no more.
Within this circle, all
things material and human,
shall be safe
and untouched
from the evil within the forest
until the flame burns no more.
Don't worry, Mother. We will be
safe now until Father returns.
Your father would be proud.
Don't worry, he'll return.
I'm sure he's all right.
My father is dead.
Dead?
It will be okay, Franklin.
One way or another this
shall all come to an end.
It is time for all of us
to face our destiny.
Heaven help us.
Maybe Father has
already slain the ogre,
on his way home with the good news.
Yes, I should pray so.
Here we are.
Oh, my God.
Jess!
What?
It's Terry.
Oh my God.
Mike? Where are you going?
I'm going back to that town!
You can't.
It killed Leah and Terry.
And that thing killed them!
That guy Stephen saved your life.
And Hope saved mine.
So I'm going back there.
If there's a way to kill
this thing, I'm gonna find it.
No! Mike!
Oh. A nail of the beast.
Shh, child.
The spell will work.
See? Better now.
It's alright.
I have it now.
We've been walking for hours.
What if we can't
find that place again.
The sheriff didn't
even know it existed.
That sheriff doesn't know his own
stench exists, never mind this place.
We're close, okay?
Okay, but what if we're walking
in circles this whole time?
Mike...
Jess!
Enough!
I'm sorry.
We're close.
How are we even
going back again?
Shh.
Go.
Mike!
I think we're back.
Everyone, quiet.
Please.
Give the travelers
a chance to speak.
Alright,
we encountered your
ogre and we lived.
Shots from my gun chased
it clean through the woods.
If it ran, it means it was hurt.
If it was hurt, it can be killed.
Bullets won't kill the ogre.
We need more than
your gun to destroy it.
We need more candles,
more powder from hope.
It is the only reason that the beast
did not take more of us last night.
No. William is right.
We need more than a gun.
There is a chance I can undo my
father's spell but it's gonna take time.
If there was a way to kill the ogre,
why haven't we tried it before?
Where was our will before?
My father had
us living in fear.
Now we have to be brave.
This is our only chance.
The ogre will need to be distracted.
Distract the ogre?
How do you plan on doing that?
With bait.
And just what?
Or dare I say who is
going to be that bait?
Me.
The traveler is right.
They're the only ones that can
cross the line and come back.
That is our
advantage. Alright.
We need as many men as
we have weapons.
Where's Giles?
Where's the keeper of arms?
Matthew, where's your father?
Where is Giles, my boy?!
This is not a time
for secrets!
He and Lawrence took
arms from the supply
and went into the woods
to find Sir Henry.
He's not returned?
You must be strong.
Like your father.
How many more sons, daughters,
loved ones must be sacrificed?
How many lives have we all
lived confined by this curse?
The time has come to face our fear.
Defeat the ogre,
no matter the consequence.
I need men.
Good.
The rest of you will take
refuge here in the town hall.
You'll only be safe by combining
what candles we have left.
Matthew, will there be any
remaining arms in the keep?
There was not many to begin with.
Then we will make with our
hands what else we need.
Not what you'd call an arsenal.
We'll have to do.
Do they work?
Giles polished them everyday.
He kept them in prime condition.
Rock and roll.
These are too small.
How about this one?
That's the one.
Yes.
I'm back!
Come get me!
Come and eat me, you beast!
No turning back.
Hold.
Get him!
Now!
Hope! Now!
Ahhh!
Hope!
Ahhhh!
Hope needs more time!
We don't have more time!
Jess, run for the line, now!
Meet us at the line!
Come on, Jess, keep going!
Come on, run!
Come get us now.
Hit him.
Hope! Let's go!
Hope!
The spell... it's broken.
Then... it is over.
Hope?
It's time to go.
What the hell are you talking about?
What's going on?
It's okay.
Don't worry.
What just
happened to them?
The spell is broken.
We're free.
We killed that thing.
It's done.
It's okay.
Our time came long ago.
This is the only way.
Thank you.
Without you, we may never
have found the strength.
Hope, this...