Stupid, I don't want to play with you.
- Don't fool around.
Let me eat your pudding.
- No way.
You're nothing special.
What's the matter?
What are you sitting here for?
Your brothers and sisters have pudding.
You don't have any.
Your aunt always beats you.
She won't give you money for pudding
I have twenty cents.
If you take off your sister's pants...
I give you the money.
Don't be scared.
Your brothers and sisters always
asperse you in front of your aunt.
This is your chance to revenge. My father
says every good man should revenge.
You're useless.
- Give it to me.
What are you doing?
- Take off her pants! Take off her pants!
I beat you. I beat you.
What's that noise?
- Mom, he took offmy pants.
What the hell?
Why do you bully my kid?
If you want to take off
pants, take somebody's else.
Why did you take off
your sister's pant? Crazy.
Mrs. Lin, why are you so harsh?
- You better go inside.
What's the matter?
Why so noisy? What's the matter?
Your son took off
my daughter's pant.
Never mind. It's alright
to show it to brother.
Why are you so exited?
What did you say?
Are you crazy?
He's growing up. He's curious.
It's yourmatter if you
want to misdirect him.
You can't ruin my kids.
- Aren't these my kids, too?
Your kid isn't mine.
What did you teach him?
He's so bad.
So comfortable. Be quicker.
Lower your voice.
Nobody should hear us.
Nobody can hear.
Turn around.
You sit on me.
So good.
You're wonderful.
Slow down.
No, no.
I'm coming. I'm coming.
It's coming.
Who is it?
It's you!
You're a peeper.
I'm going to beat you up!
What's the matter?
- He peeped you the whole time.
Are you sure?
Of course. Beat him!
He'sjust curious. Get in.
He's bad.
- He's a curious kid.
I don't care. He's not
allowed to have dinner.
Get in, bugger.
Mom, if you were here,
lwouldn't be beat up.
Dr. Lamb
Why did you pretend innocent?
- I didn't pretend innocent.
What are you looking at?
Fuck off. Get lost.
Mr. Li!
Where are the colleagues?
- Upstairs.
Take me up.
- Yes, Sir.
Don't you think there is something
wrong with these photos?
Morning, Sir.
- Morning.
He's the manager.
Something is wrong with these photos.
He reported to the police.
These photos are so terrible.
- Yes, they really are.
Have you seen these photos before?
I saw it few times. It's terrible.
Why didn't you report to the police?
- I thought that they're fake.
Where did they come from?
- From Mongkok Shop.
Have you seen these photos before?
They're awful.
All these vaginal orifices.
Yes. Sometimes bunged with something.
- With what? - Looks like broomsticks.
Which parts are bunged?
- Vaginal orifice.
The backside isn't bunged up.
When does the shop open?
9AM.
Sergeant?
- Yes, Sir.
Take a set of photos for record.
Get a report from the manager.
Fat Bing.
- Yes, Sir.
Go to the shop with
colleagues tomorrow morning.
Get a set of photos as evidence.
- 0.K.
You heard him.
Let's get to work!
Ifwe take the photos how
can he come and get them?
Ask him to develop
one more set, you fool.
Understand?
Understand? Go and get them.
Get me cards.
Let's play poker.
Fat Bing, do we play cards in the morning?
- Don't we have to wait tonight?
Brother Bing, do you need some help?
- Don't lhave enough experience?
You don't look like a cop.
- What do I look like? Superman?
Two pairs.
Brother Bing, you have
no luck. Only 65 points.
Never mind.
Ten dollars per point.
That makes 650$.
The game is not over yet.
- You lost 650$. Let's go.
It's not over yet.
- It's six o'clock. We should go.
Let's count the point. Brother Bing.
- There are still three minutes left.
You want to take advantage.
- Brother Bing, after counting,
it's six o'clock sharp, is it?
- Stop nonsense. Keep cool.
Last round.
I double up the point. I will win.
You double up the
point after seeing cards.
It's not fair.
I didn't double up the
point after seeing cards.
It's fairto you.
100$ per point. It's unlimited.
Show cards. I have three pairs.
What are you doing?
I also have three pairs.
I'm sure I'll win. Come on.
It's so coincident.
- So coincident.
I can't win with such
a good combination.
I'm lucky to have you. Show cards.
Wait a minute.
I also have three pairs.
It's so coincident.
It's five minutes past six. Let's go.
Take the photos.
Wait.
These photos are beautiful.
Where did you take them?
Freeze!
Fat Bing.
- Wait a minute.
Police. Freeze.
Get him.
What were you
waiting for all the time?
I was waiting for your signal.
We arrest you.
We suspect you're a bootlegger.
You have the right to keep silent.
Every word speak will be used as evidence.
Whose photos are those?
They're not mine.
I get it for somebody else.
Whose photos are those?
A guy named Chan.
He gave me thirty dollars.
Take usto him.
Let's go.
Look carefully.
Are those the guys?
No.
- Ls it the one who holds a briefcase?
- Lwarn you. Don't try to trick us.
When will Chan arrive?
Let's lock him up.
Bullshit.
We have waited a whole night.
Whomever you asked him,
he says "no" without hesitation.
He's playing games with us.
You're calm.
How long do you want to fool us?
Fat Bing, your instinct is sharp.
This is not instinct.
I put money in your pocket.
- What?
Money in your pocket is
better than giving away any.
Her body is crooked.
Yes, a dead body
can be crooked like this.
Enlarge her pupil.
According to the enlargement of pupils.
The victim was dead more than five hours.
Hello? Laboratory.
Please wait.
Mr. Li, yourtelephone.
Thanks.
Hello?
I come immediately.
Wait for me downstairs.
Mr. Li... he's in the car.
Get him out.
Get out.
Did you see me before?
I saw you on TV.
Which floor?
Third floor.
Let's Go.
Who is it?
Is this Lin's house?
Yes.
What's the matter?
We're cops.
Do you know this guy?
He's my son.
We have to search your house.
- We have warrant. Don't be in the way.
Get out.
Excuse me.
What's the matter?
- Your son is a suspect.
Where do you sleep?
- Don drUben.
You check that side.
- Yes, Sir.
Who are you?
We're cops.
- Cops? What's the matter?
Who isthis kid?
- She's my daughter.
Turn on the light.
You know how to develop photos?
- Yes.
Hey!
What's the matter?
What are you doing?
No need to speak loudly.
We're cops. Get down.
Get down. Hurry up.
Come on!
Who is he?
- My brother.
Get out.
What are you doing?
Cops beat me.
- You better cooperate with us.
Of course I can beat you.
I beat you, so what?
How many family
members do you have?
Two sons, one daughter
and a son-in-law.
I also have a grand-daughter.
I've got internal injuries.
Did you developed photos at home?
Yes.
- How about the color one?
Itook out to the shop.
Come.
Whose cupboard is it?
- It's mine.
Open it.
- No key.
- I lost the key.
What is this for?
What is your name?
- Lin Gwao-chang.
Louder.
No need to speak so loud.
Where do you work?
Mr. Li.
I've found something. See.
Sit properly. Don't move.
Take these photos back
to the police station.
Yes, Sir.
Don't move.
Do you know what you're doing?
- Sit.
What?
This is his sister.
Her husband is at work.
Page him at once.
Ask him to go to the station.
Yes, Sir.
Come here.
Nobody can come here
without my permission.
Cops beat me.
Don't shout. I beat you.
I haven't touched you.
I have to go to thetoilet.
My bladder is injured.
You better hold it.
Change your clothes
and go to the station with me.
But...
Get changed.
What do you do here?
Don't shout. Go and get changed.
What a fucking son ofa bitch.
Excuse me.
Don't push me.
Fat Bing, bring him to the
Deposition Room. - Yes, Sir.
Eric, take the other
suspects to main room.
Yes, Sir.
Take them to the main room.
- Yes, Sir.
Get in.
Get two colleagues
to watch the door.
Mr. Lin, these photos have gone wrong.
So you're under detention.
Listen. You're confined from now on.
Whatever you say.
It will be used as evidence.
Are these photos yours?
- I got them for somebody.
Mr. Chan.
Have you finished playing games?
When will you tell us the truth?
Calm down.
You should have said that you
got so many photos at home.
Will you say it?
The tiles in the picture
are the same as at your house.
Were they taken at your place?
Say it.
Bully Hung.
Yes, Sir.
- Get a deposition from him.
Sit.
You beat me.
- Who beats you?
That Big Eyes beat me thirty times.
He saw it.
They beat me thirty times.
I accuse them.
They beat me.
Don't shout. Don't shout.
Take him out.
- Yes, Sir.
I have to accuse you.
Cops are not superior.
Where do you take my father?
What are you doing?
- L will beat you if you shout again.
Cops are not superior.
Why did you beat me?
Check his rap sheet
from the CRAB department.
Eric. You go to the
Missing Person department.
Get the Missed Girls
record from this year.
Get me the whole record.
- Yes, Sir.
Besides, Fat Bing.
The photos you have brought,
you better sort them out.
Don't waste time to
check if they're useless.
Keeping silent cannot
make you acquitted.
Say it.
Did you do it?
Bully Hung, stop it.
How can you beat him?
We're sorry.
How went the deposition?
What? Nothing?
Yes, he didn't say a word.
According to my
experience, you better...
I have said it all.
I'm sorry. l can't help.
I didn't come in.
L saw nothing.
I'm invisible.
You better start talking.
Tell me. Did he take
girls home to take photos?
Sir, l really don't know.
I'm innocent.
Innocent? You two live in one room.
How can you be innocent?
I never minded his business.
I work in this part of town.
He's a night shift taxi driver.
I work at daytime.
He works at nighttime.
I don't know what he does.
Stop beating.
I'm innocent.
Sir, what have I done wrong?
I suspect you of murder.
- Murder? I'm innocent.
Do you know what your brother does?
- I don't know.
He goes to his room
immediately when he comes home.
We never talk.
He has a toilet inside of his room.
I don't know what he does.
You brother is abnormal.
Did he do something abnormal?
Or he did something extremely weird?
No. I think he's normal.
If you hide anything...
I can accuse you.
You think about it.
He peeped dad and mom.
What?
- Making love.
You still say he's normal.
Did he sexually abused you?
He peeped me when I took a bath.
Do you have two wives?
- Yes.
Your eldest son's mother
is your first wife? - Yes.
Did he have a girlfriend before?
He did have one.
However, they blew up.
Is he nuts?
My son is normal. Idiot!
He likes to take photos.
Did he take lots of photos?
Yes, a lot.
He bought many cameras.
Why does he like to
take pictures of naked girls?!
Like to shoot women's
pussies and breasts.
Sir, what's wrong with it?
This is art. You can
see it everywhere.
Is it illegal to take these photos?
- Did your son break the law?
No. Never.
Mr. Lin, he has been
previously convicted.
Why did you say he's clean?
He never...
- He molested a girl in 1975.
Had been sentenced to
three months of mental housing.
He was acquitted.
He intimidated the girl with a knife.
- I tell you he was innocent.
Innocent?
You're abnormal as he's.
He's nuts.
I will check it out.
Start the investigation!
- Yes, Sir.
Sir, you have asked me for hours.
When will you let me go?
You lied. We have to
ask you once again.
Bitch! Say it!
Will you say it? Say it!
Damn! Will you be as
tough as my hammer?
Say it! Otherwise you will die.
Say it, bastard! Won't you say it?
Hey! Take a rest.
Won't you feel tired?
How is it? Did he say it?
- He said something.
Of course. You beat him
so hard, he won't live.
What? I'm Lin Gwao-yu.
I'm twenty-eight.
Bing! This is something.
Bullshit.
He got this.
No wonder he won't confess.
You beat him later.
Let's have a meeting.
Get somebody to watch him.
This is a complicated case.
In line with deposition,
this guy is abnormal.
I'm sure that he killed
more than one person.
So I think his brother is involved.
They live in the same room.
So how couldn't he know it?
- Yes, I asked his sister.
She knows nothing about it.
They hardly know each other.
He peeped her when she took a bath.
Sir, his sister asked if she can be bailed.
Her daughter must go to school tomorrow.
- No way. Ask somebody to take her home.
This woman has to stay here.
I'm so tired. I didn't sleep last night.
I take a bath first, and take a nap.
- Sleepy? Everybody is sleepy.
This is a complicated case.
We have to keep our eyes open.
We have to be on the alert anytime.
Nobody is allowed to get off work.
Fat Bing, you're experienced.
You get a deposition from this guy.
- No problem. Bully Hung is a specialist.
Don't pass it to me.
L can't stand this guy.
- I pass him to you. I will help you.
Wow! Wonderful, wonderful.
Most of these photos show breasts.
It's wonderful.
These are upper part and lower part.
Wonderful. It's so wonderful.
- No, I don't want to see it.
You don't have to see it.
- Bastard.
Why do you hit me?
These photos show
the suspect's niece.
I think there's something wrong.
Shit. This guy is abnormal.
Eric. Take these to the
fingerprint department.
Check it out if it belongs
to the suspect. - Yes, Sir.
It must be him.
He just rejects to confess it.
A dumb guy won't say it.
You're too soft to him.
I'm too soft?
I beat him very hard.
You can't force him.
You work as a cop for so many years.
You should do something to
get a deposition from him.
He fools around.
We will fool around with him.
Get in.
Buddy, take a break.
What do you do?
Bing, you really want to
fool around with him?
Stop talking. Go and help him.
Go.
Come on.
Will you say it?
Say it. Say it.
Hurry up. Say it.
Will you say it?
Say it. Say it.
Bastard, I beat you.
Say it.
Son of a bitch.
You son of a bitch.
I will beat you.
Say it. Say it quickly.
Did you do it or what?
Bastard, will you say it?
Will you say it?
Hung, calm down.
Bastard, will you say it?
Bing, Bing, Bing-
What's the matter? Time for lunch?
- No.
Is Hung killing people?
- Hung is going crazy.
Leave him alone.
Damn, what kind of game is this?
I beat him for hours,
he didn't say a word.
Are you an iron man?
Stop nonsense.
How can you be so irritable?
I got a job for you.
What's the matter?
- Nothing.
Nothing?
You go to the taxi company
to get some information.
OK.
Are you alright?
If you want to accuse
Hung, you can tell us.
What do you want to say?
L will get punishment
if I commit a crime.
Cops shouldn't beat me.
Where's your boss?
What's the matter?
- We're CID.
My boss is upstairs.
Do you get along with Lin Gwao-yu?
- No.
See, this is Lin's working record.
- Thanks.
When was the first
case of a missing girl?
The first one was Chan
Sau lan, February 3rd, 82.
February 3rd.
Action.
How about the others?
- Chan Kit-fong, 29 May.
May 29th.
Go on.
- Leung Man-ling, June 17th.
The fourth one is
Leung Wing-yin, August 2nd.
Action.
Mr. Li, it's Lin's fingerprint.
He's abnormal.
He even abused his own niece.
It's unbelievable.
Ms Lin, does your brother
like to take photos?
Yes.
Do you know he takes
photos of your child?
He didn't take photos of my daughter.
Hi! Chit?
Who took these photos for you?
- My uncle.
Your uncle took these photos for you?
- When did he take these photos for you?
He used to take me to
the park and take photos.
I have said to you many times.
Don't stick around with your uncle.
Did your uncle took these photos?
- Yes.
Your uncle took these photos for you?
How many times I told you not
to stick around with your uncle?
Your uncle took
these photos for you?
Come in.
What's the matter with you.
Why do you cry?
Did the cops beat you?
Don't cry.
You can't beat her.
She didn't commit a crime.
How can you beat her?
Mr. Lin, your son likes
to take photos, right? - Yes.
My girl.
Did you know he takes such photos?
What's wrong with it?
It's not against the law.
You don't cooperate with the police.
Nobody tells the truth.
I accuse you're involved.
Are you involved in any way?
No! You accuse me of
murder because of these photos?
I will accuse you.
I will do everything to accuse you.
Dad, what are you doing?
It's not the first time
for him to be caught.
Can't you remember?
He's not a good guy.
Get lost! I'm not talking
with you. Leave me alone.
He peeped metaking a
bath when he was 13.
Do you rem ember?
Leave me alone.
Do you remember when he
peeped me taking a bath?
See.
My girl, taking photos
is nothing special.
Bastard.
Dad.
He's an asshole.
He dares to do this thing.
He took these photos.
He also took those photos.
I give you one more chance
to talk to him. You ask him.
What the hell is the matter?
Make everything clear.
Otherwise I accuse you.
Come in.
Sit down.
Sit properly.
Otherwise I will beat you up.
Everybody is here.
This is your chance to discuss it.
You talk about it.
We will accuse all of
you if there is no result.
Let's go.
Open the door.
- Yes, Sir.
Bastard, you get
me involved in a crime.
You're a bastard.
You dare to do this thing.
Why did you treat me like this?
You're an animal.
I beat you.
You're a bastard.
Why do you beat me?
I'm a family member.
Police beat me. You beat me.
You don't belong to
Lin's family. Bastard.
I kill you.
You're not a man.
I'm going to beat you up!
Bastard! I beat you.
You're not a man.
You should go to hell.
Goto hell.
Everybody wants me to die.
Yes, I confess.
I killed them. I killed them.
I killed them.
See! He confessed everything.
Useless! We need evidence.
This guy is pretty clever.
The game has just begun.
He might try to trick us.
You better be alert.
You better confess everything.
Give us an easy time.
Sit!
Sit here. What do you want?
I sit here.
- You think so?
That is Mr. Li's seat.
- Let him sit.
He can sit there
if he's cooperative.
Let's get straight to the point.
Who was the first victim?
These are the photos
of the missing girls.
Take a good look.
See it clearly. Tell us
if you can recognize it.
Don't confess it if you're not sure.
Don't keep silent if you can recognize.
You see them clearly.
I don't remember.
You don't remember?
This one happened
on February 3rd, 1982.
She's Chan Sau lan.
We suspect that
she's the first victim.
See it clearly.
Tell us if you can recognize it.
Don't confess it if you're not sure.
See them clearly.
Is that she?
Is it your first time?
Bastard. What's wrong?
Don't get a girl if you're useless.
Bitch! When will you buck off?
Don't come back and beg me.
Bastard! What are you looking at?
Where do you go?
Kwun Tong.
Men? All men are bad guys.
Would you stop staring at me?
Never seen a woman before?
You bastard!
All men suck.
You can't smoke in car.
None of your business.
I like it. So what?
Hey! What are you doing?
What kind of water is this?
Do you want to kill me?
I love you, my darling! You love me.
This is Kwun Tong.
Where do you want to go?
Who said that I go to Kwun Tong?
- You said it.
I said to Tsim ShaTsui.
Hit the road.
After you killed Chan Sau lan...
What did you do with her body?
I brought her body home.
I put it inside the sofa.
Then, I cleaned up the taxi.
Good morning, uncle.
- Hey, not so fast!
Good morning, grandpa.
Gwao-chang, are you ready?
Coming, coming.
Why didn't you come home
for dinner last night?
We got lots of left over.
I got over-time work.
Let's go and eat.
It's difficult to get a table.
Go and have some tea.
Let's go.
Throw it. Throw it.
Don't you want to throw it?
I kill you.
Kill you... Kill you...
Bloody bitch.
That's all?
Enough! Sit down!
It seem s... I was too patient with you.
Take it easy.
Asshole.
I ask you...
Did your family know about this?
What did you do with the body?
Uncle, uncle. I got candy.
Do you want it?
Get in and do your homework.
You always have to do
your homework properly...
Hey, wait.
Bastard.
You were much too dirty.
Why did you keep my photo?
You keep this news...
Are you interested in this case?
Not me, it's you.
What? You want to kill me?
I had a premonition
that you will get me.
You know that.
But you still murder girls.
They were bad women.
They deserved it.
Fuck you, man.
Tell me why did you kill that woman?
I forgot.
You find the answer yourself?
OK. I will make you
remember the details.
Bing, Eric, take him
to replay the case.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
No comment.
This is an extremely big case.
We have to replay the case.
Let's get in.
Put her in.
Put inside.
Sir, is it necessary?
Are you scared?
You're a cop.
This is your job. Put her in.
OK. I get in.
Don't move. You're
supposed to be dead.
Yes, Sir.
What are you afraid of?
I'm not afraid.
I can't breathe.
Come here.
Go.
What did you do
after putting in the body?
I took it into my room
after they others had gone.
What did you do after that?
I put a plastic sheet on the floor.
Then, I put the body on the top.
I beg you. Don't touch me.
What did you do after that?
Then I cut it into pieces.
I beg you. Don't touch me.
Get up. It's alright.
Nobody would have married
you if he touched you.
Take him out.
Go.
Fat Bing.
- Yes.
Take these evidences back
to the station. - Yes, Sir.
Ask the fingerprint
department to check all these.
Take these evidences back to the station.
- All of them?
Yes, all of them.
- Yes, Sir.
Take some boxes over here.
Get some people here.
Wonderful.
Fat Bing, come and help me.
Helping you always ends in a mess.
It stinks. My eyes
are unbearably hurt.
What is it? What the hell is it?
Sorry. it's a breast.
- What did you say?
A breast.
Don't move.
What is it on my back?
A breast.
What is it?
How can you do this?
Fat Bing, this is evidence.
It slipped out of my hand.
Why don't you pick it up?
- Pick it up.
Don't move.
What is it?
- A breast.
I smell. Why are you holding me?
Don't be scared. It's alright.
You got your own.
Why are you so scared? Pick it up.
That is evidence. Pick it up.
Pick it.
Pick it up. You like it very much.
I'm used to touch so
many different breasts.
You only know your own.
So pick it up.
This is an important evidence.
Hurry up.
This is an order.
Yes, Sir.
It's rotten. Don't spoil it.
It's slippery. Be careful.
What are you doing?
I help you.
You're mean.
You're disgusting. You threw it to me?
You can complain...
My back is itchy.
Will I get a disease?
You might get sloughing ulcer.
Not sloughing ulcer. It's scabies.
I hit you.
Don't laugh at me.
Idiots.
What's the matter?
Put them against the wall.
The others go and move the stuff.
Yes, Sir.
Without my permission...
nobody touches anything.
Sit.
- Are these yours?
Yes. Will you return them to me?
You fuck!
Sit.
When you see them...
would you rem ember
how many girls you killed.
I don't care you killed one or ten.
We will accuse you for murdering.
Say it. There's no
way to hide anything.
We want to know...
Why did you write Action...
on your shift record?
I can prove that you
have killed four persons.
Why did you kill one after one?
The first killing
was too cruel.
It was not perfect.
I hoped that the second
one would be better.
You think that it was not perfect,
so you bought the dissection books.
He also bought a
scalpel to kill people.
Why did you kill
people on rainy days?
Because I feel excited.
It's raining cats and dogs.
Come. Let's go home.
This side.
You don't have to take me home.
Bye.
Tai Kok Tsui.
Hit the road. Stupid.
You try to legitimate your killings.
All you killed were prostitutes.
Why did you kill this student.
She's only seventeen.
How can you be so hardhearted?
Besides...
Why did you keep her stuff?
But you didn't keep the others'?
I didn't want to kill her.
Didn't want to kill her?
See these photos.
Why did you enlarge them?
Did you a have special
feeling for this student?
She was so pure.
Sai Kung. Thank you.
Bye.
- Bye.
You're so late.
I went to Graduation Dinner.
What will you do after graduation?
I want to be a kindergarten teacher.
It's so happy when I'm with kids.
Teacher is good.
Won't be cheated so easily.
Why did you look at me like that?
Because I think you're
pure and innocent.
What did you say?
Don't be scared. l think it was
fate that we met each other.
I didn't understand what you've said.
I hate dirty people.
In this world...
It's hard to find a
pure girl like you.
Stop the car.
What's wrong? Are you scared?
No.
Everything's... alright.
Don't be scared.
I just want to talk to you.
Don't be afraid.
I won't hurt you.
I don't have an evil mind.
No, let me get off here.
Come on.
Lust want to talk with you.
No. Let me go home.
No. I beg you. Let me go.
I beg you.
- Lust want to talk with you.
No. I beg you.
I won't hurt you.
Let me go. I beg you.
Come on.
- Let me go!
Let me go. Let me go.
Help! Help!
Don't scream! Stop it!
I don't have an evil mind.
I'm sorry.
Did I hurt you?
You're so pure.
I believe in fate.
This is our first time
to meet each other.
It must be fate that
we can befriends.
I also believe in justice.
A pure girl like you must
get a good judgment.
You too. You're a good man.
You will be happy in the future.
No. I'm not happy.
Because nobody understands me.
I understand you.
In this world,
I believe in three persons.
The first one is God.
Second one is my mother.
The third one is myself.
You're too young.
You won't understand.
Yes. My mother worries about me.
You better let me go home.
I talk with you tomorrow.
You're a good girl.
Some music?
Where are you going?
Let me go!
Come in.
No.
Help!
Please help me!
Don't care about her. Let's go.
Don't go away. Help!
Help! Don't go.
No.
Open the door! Help!
Help! Open the door.
Help!
Why did you run away?
Why? Why did you run away?
Don't sleep! Please, don't sleep!
Talk to me... Talk to me!
What are you doing?
Don't create such mysteries.
Sit.
Why didn't you go on?
Do you want to hide something?
You better cooperate with us.
I want to finish work earlier.
Mr. Li, we discovered
something. Have a look.
Shit! What a son of a bitch!
- A fucking animal.
Why did you run away?
I wouldn't have hurt you.
You're pure and innocent.
I want to marry you.
I suppose you agree
if you keep silent.
I will treat you very well.
You're pure and innocent.
We're both virgins.
Our marriage is perfect.
Damn! Man! Such a son of a bitch!
Bastard! He raped
her almost half an hour.
More than that! It's forty minutes.
Lin Gwao-yu,
we accuse you of homicide.
You killed four women.
This is your deposition.
You may take a look.
Please sign it if it's all right.
Lin Gwao-yu was
accused on April 8th, 1983.
He was charged four counts.
First, he killed Chan Sau
lan on February 3rd, 82.
Second, he killed Chan
Kit-Fong on May 29th, 82.
Third, he killed Leung
Man-Ling on June 17th, 82.
Fourth, he killed Leung
Wing-fin on August 2nd, 82.
The jury found the suspect was guilty.
He was convicted to death penalty.
Lin Gwao-yu requested to see Mr. Li.
Mr. Li, please sign here.
You go. I will stay here.
Why me? I go there every time.
What's wrong with it?
I'm not familiar with him.
Please make a trip with Mr. Li.
I go this time.
- OK.
Mr. Li, this side.
Mr. Li, he's in the last one.
Sir, do you have a cigarette?
Give it to me.
Please give me a cigarette.
Give one-to me.
Give me. Sir.
Come on... only one!
Mister, do you have a cigarette?
Do you have a cigarette?
This is the result of your evil deeds.
You will stay here until till death.
Do you have any request?
I will help you if I can.
I want to get back my
photos and video tapes.
I'm sorry. That's impossible.
You're just wasting my time.