Are we shooting?
What?
Are we shooting people or what?
Are we shooting?
That's what I'm asking you!
What's the answer?
Give me some gum.\nI already gave you some.
I think this guy has a weapon!
Yeah, he does!
Congratulations, my man,\nyou shot yourself a raghead!
Dag. Didn't think I'd get to see\nanybody shot in this war.
Take my picture.
Spirits are high\nand the music is boisterous...
...as these young troops\nShit, hold on a second.
Music is high and spirits are soaring\nas these   Did I just say ''soaring''?
How did it sound?
They say you exorcised the ghost of\nVietnam with a clear moral imperative.
We liberated Kuwait.
And I had to start again\nWith just my children and my wife
I would thank my lucky stars\nTo be living here today
Because the flag\nStill stands for freedom
And they can't take that away
And I gladly stand up next to you
And defend her still today
'Cause there ain't no doubt\nI love this land
God bless the U.S.A.
Trained warrior! Trained warrior!
Trained warrior! Oh, my God!\nMajor Gates!
What's Adriana got?
Just the celebration story.
That's it? That story's evaporating.
The lraqi POW story's evaporating.
Still have my gold story, though.\nReturning the gold to Kuwait.
What do you know about that?
What's going on?\nI was about to ask you the same.
You said he was former Delta, he'd take\ncare of me. What a bunch of bullshit!
Let me handle this!\nDoesn't she have an escort?
She's right here.\nFind her someone to fuck...
...so she'll leave my escort alone.\nThat's unnecessary.
I don't want him going to other\nreporters and giving away my stories.
You don't have any stories.\nYou don't tell people that!
Look at what's become of you!
I really don't need this shit, major.\nYou understand me?
This is a media war!\nAnd you better get onboard!
We'll talk tomorrow,\nand I'll straight you out!
Take a picture!
One more!
Very handsome.
Good shot, Barlow!
Enough!
Captain's coming!
You better move your butts.\nHe's coming right now!
Goddamn it! Where the hell did this\nbooze come from? Get rid of it!
We gotta take more\nlraqi prisoners tomorrow! Tomorrow!
Remove the magazine from your weapon.
Sling your weapon over your left\nshoulder, muzzle down.
Have both arms raised above your head.
Approach the multinational forces\nposition slowly...
...with the lead soldier\nholding this document...
...above his head. If you do this,\nyou will not die.
You will be processed\nas prisoners of war...
...provided food, shelter and clothing.
Do not resist.
If you do this, you get this.
If you surrender,\nyou will get food and shelter. Okay?
Everything's cool. nobody's gonna\nhurt you. Just relax.
Sir, you'll have to\ntake the turban off as well.
Did you rape and torture anyone\nin Kuwait?
What about you, motherfucker?!
You're making them hysterical.\nStop that. You'll get us in trouble.
Relax. We want everybody facedown.
Come on.
Get down.
Take these things off.\nno comprende English?
I want to be professional.\nHe won't take his rags off.
Pay attention to how it's done.\nExcuse me, sir.
We'll need you to disrobe like all\nthe other towelheads.
I hate to see it come to this.\nStrip him down.
Come on, motherfucker.
Take your fucking clothes off.
Troy, come here! Check this out.
Freaky thing here, possibly!
There's a document in that guy's ass.
We got a classified situation.
You think he ate it?
It wouldn't come out\nperfect like that.
Pull it out.
Man, I didn't join the Army to pull\npaper out of people's asses.
no, sir. not what I signed up for.
Open it up.
You only gave me one glove.
That's how the chain of command works.
What is it?
It's important enough\nto squeeze your cheeks for.
You're supposed to make her feel good\nabout the stories we want.
You don't walk away from her\nand go screw another journalist!
I never wanted this job, Ron.
Your work in lraq was over. Done!
I'm trying to help you.\nIf you play your cards right...
...she may hook you up with\nthe media at home.
Fuck that.
You got your star clinched.
So it's my fault that you\nplateaued a long time ago.
I don't even know what we did here.
Just tell me what we did here, Ron.
You want to occupy lraq\nand do Vietnam again?
Is that your brilliant idea?
I'm retiring anyway.\nUntil you do, you're an Army officer.
You've washed your hands\na thousand times.
Lord knows what vermin\nlive in the butt of a dune coon.
Why do you let this cracker\nfollow you around?
He's from a group home in Dallas.\nHe doesn't know better.
I don't care if he's from\nJohannesburg.
I don't want to hear ''dune coon'' or\n''sand nigger'' from him or anybody.
Captain uses those terms.
The point is, ''towelhead'' and ''camel\njockey'' are good substitutes.
Exactly.\nI apologize.
It's confusing with all this pro Saudi,\nanti lraqi type language and all that.
Did you get the aerials?
How'd you get those?
Chief is hooked up.\nKeep Walter on that door.
Would you take those fucking things off?
I never got to use night vision.
They do not work during the day!
They kind of work.
Just stand outside so Chief can\ntranslate my lraqi ass map, okay?
Are you ready to work with me now?
I'm ready to work with you.
Good. Because I've got\nan amazing lead.
It was in his ass.\nThat's not the real story.
What's the real story?\nIt was in the guy's dick.
Pulled it out with tweezers.
A 1 0 page atlas of Saddam's bunkers?
Only real small, like those books you\nget in a box of Cracker Jacks.
They pull it out the guy ear.
What?\n''Out of his ear.''
Maybe out the nose.
What's he saying?\n''The nose.''
Tell me what body part.\nLet me handle this.
It was stitched in back of his head.
The back of his head.
Who is the guy?\nWhat guy?
The guy who found it!
I cannot tell you.\nFuck that!
You said you could.\nnot now.
This guy doesn't know shit.
He doesn't know shit.
Listen to me. This guy is French\nSpecial Forces, and he can help us.
He can?\nYes, and he's my friend.
But he won't talk to me\nif you're around.
You better not be fucking with me.
I want the story this time.\nYou'll get the story.
These have to be Saddam's bunkers\nbetween Karbala and nazaria.
What's inside?
According to Intel, Picasso, Sony,\nArmani, Rolex....
Kuwait was the Arab Beverly Hills,\nand Saddam jacked them for it.
One Rolex would get me a very nice\nhouse outside of Garland.
Five would get\na Lexus convertible.
Lexus doesn't make one.\nYes, they do.
It has room for a kid seat.
Infiniti has a convertible, not Lexus.\nWrong.
He could also put a land mine\nin our path.
What are you talking about?
I have a ring of Jesus fire\nto guide my decisions.
You're putting me on, right?
Do I look like I'm putting you on?
Okay, ring of Jesus fire.
Halt!
Freeze, motherfucker!
Sir, this tent is restricted.
Get out of my way.
Mayday! Mayday! Goddamn it!
Good afternoon.
Would this be the proctology tent?
no, sir.
Maybe it's a urology tent.
Or the ear, nose and throat tent.
Captain a proctologist?
What's a proctologist, sir?
Doesn't matter.
I'm not looking for him.\nI'm looking for Barlow.
You're on the path to truth when you\nsmell shit. Isn't that what they say?
I don't recognize you, sir.\nAre you in this division?
He's not from this division.\nHe's Special Forces.
Did you present this map\nto your captain?
not yet, sir.
I'll take it to him.
That's not necessary, sir.\nI can take it to him.
Don't get grabby, sergeant.
He's our C.O.\nI'd have to tell him you took it.
That won't do either of us any good,\nwill it?
no, sir.
Sit down.
What do you see here?\nBunkers, sir.
What's in them?\nStuff they stole from Kuwait.
Bullshit. I'm talking about millions\nin Kuwaiti bullions.
The little cubes you put in\nhot water and make soup?
no, not the little cubes you put in hot\nwater to make soup.
Gold bricks.
Saddam stole it from the sheiks. I have\nno problem stealing it from Saddam.
My guess is, he's divided these bricks\ninto several different stashes.
Just one stash would be easy for us to\ntake from his deserting army.
That'd be enough to get us\nout of our day jobs.
Unless you reservists are\nin love with your day jobs.
I don't really have a day job, sir.
First thing we have to do is...
...make sure this is more than\na love letter to an lraqi.
It's a series of bunkers\noutside Karbala, sir.
Maybe.\nDefinitely, sir.
The recon photos match.
We'll see.
Dag!
It's what makes SF so badass.\nWe got the best flashlights.
Still looks like a series of bunkers.
Three villages a little farther\nto the east.
Seventy five clicks north.\nMore like 65.
Way north of any allied troops.
Perfect. We don't want\nany troops around.
Just us and a Humvee\nup by the Euphrates River Valley.
Where they put Moses in the basket.
That's Egypt.
We three kings be stealing the gold
Quiet down!
Will you shut up?
Are you done singing?
What about mines, sir?
Grid was swept by the 82nd.\nWe'll stick to the roads.
Will we need a deuce and a half?
It's easier in a Humvee.\nWhat if we have a lot to carry?
We'll grab an lraqi truck.\nIt's better cover.
We could say we captured it.\nThat's right.
We leave at dawn, back before lunch.\nno big deal.
Bolo! Get in here!
Who's Bolo?\nA guy who doesn't know what he's doing.
Yes, sir.
Get this reporter off my back.\nYou know who Adriana Cruz is?
Reporter on nBS, sir.\nThat's right.
Tell her I'm checking a story,\nand you're bringing her to meet me.
In lraq?\nno.
I'll give you a fake copy of this map.
Take her on a ride\nthat lasts all morning...
...and goes nowhere near the villages\noutside Karbala.
When you don't find me, it'll be because\nyou got lost. Is that clear?
Any other questions?
Is it true that to be SF,\nyou got to cut off an enemy's ear?
Are you able to control him?\nYes, sir. He'll be fine.
Let's get ready to roll in the morning.
All right, here we go, ma'am!
Pull!
Let me get some, Chief!
I gave you a better arc!
What do you mean?
I threw the ball at a higher arc.
Bullshit!
Stop speaking right now.
Houston's gone nowhere with Warren Moon.
Randall Cunningham?\nDon't get in the mud with him.
Eagles'll never get to\nSuper Bowl with Cunningham.
Doug Williams not only took the Redskins\nto the Super Bowl, but they won!
We can all agree there are many\nexcellent black quarterbacks.
Let's see what you can hit.
I'll hit an lraqi.\nI'll blow his head off!
If he talks like that, ignore him,\nor it'll get worse.
You're right.\nJust can't help myself sometimes.
Watch this!
What was that?\nA rigged football C 4, sir.
Why'd you do that?
You said we could fire some rounds\nwhen we left camp.
I said you could fire a few rounds.
We didn't get to see any action.
You want to see some action?\nYeah, I do, sir.
Is this what you're after?
We dropped a lot of bombs out here.
The only action we seen was on Cnn,\nexcept for that dude Troy shot.
Shot him in the neck?\nThat's right, sir.
Fucking badass. I was there.\nTook him out at 400 yards.
Head popped up in the air.
Crazy shot, man!
I don't know.\nSpecifically.
The worst thing about a gunshot,\nprovided you survive the bullet...
...is sepsis.
Infection of the blood.
Say a bullet tears into you
Creates a cavity of dead tissue.\nThat cavity...
...it fills up with bile and bacteria.\nYou're fucked.
But we're going to do this without\nfiring any shots...
...and just to be sure,\nwe'll do a dry run.
So get your suits on.
now, we will say that the cow is a\nprimary guard outside the bunker.
Pull up fast, stop short.
Move very aggressively. Got it?
Got it!
Let's go!
Who's hurt?
It's all cow.
Yeah, it's all cow.
Y'all see that cow's head shoot up?
Just like a cartoon.\nIt's fucking crazy.
You said this area was swept for mines.
Wasn't a mine. It was a cluster bomb.\nThey're hard to see.
Get in the Humvee.\nWe're moving on.
Round, round, get around\nI get around
Yeah, get around\nI get around
We go in fast, leave the safeties on.
Hit them with the blinding power\nof American sunshine.
Where's the bunker?
There. no, there!
Orders from the President\nof the United States of America!
Stay back!
On the ground, right now!
We are the Army\nof the United States of America!
Stay back!
no milk! Baby milk!
Baby milk!
Let's go!
Let's go! Step aside! Move!
Orders from President Bush!\nPart of the cease fire agreement.
Clear. Let's move!
United States military!
We are here for your protection\nand safety, all right?
Get down on the ground!\nGet down on the ground!
Order from the United States.
Shit!
Again!
Freeze!\nI love the United State of freedom.
I am hate Saddam.
Let him go!
no problem, my friend.
no problem.
Tell him to shut up. Be quiet.
I am love United State of freedom.
I'm love United States of freedom too.
Just calm down and be quiet, okay?\nl am friend!
I am friend.
You look for chemical weapon?
We look for the gold.\nno gold here.
no gold.
What did he say?\nno gold, my friend.
He says there's no gold here!
Where's the gold?
Kill him.\nYou want to die?!
Other bunker, other village!\nOther bunker?
not this bunker?\nno. not this town.
That town! Yes! That town.
Let's go.
It's milk.
Please bring medicine!
Please help us.
Come on!
Off the vehicle!
Ma'am, you'll have to step down\nfrom the vehicle!
Hospital!
Food. Food.
Give them the M.R.E.s! Let's go!
Take that. Take that.
He's taking the water\naway from that woman!
Heads up!
Here you go.
Look out! Get off!
Take me, take me!
You can't come with us!
Right here, right now.
Civilians spitting on soldiers,\nsoldiers shooting civilians.
They ignored us like we weren't there.
They surrendered to us.\nThey're after civilians now.
Why'd they blow up that milk truck?
Trying to starve the people out.
Bush told the people to rise up\nagainst Saddam.
They thought they had our support.
now they're getting slaughtered.
So where's the next bunker?
About 20 clicks on the map,\naccording to what that guy said.
no, it's not.
There's something about that well.
What well?\nThe well in the center of town.
There were soldiers guarding it.\nI bet there's a bunker in there.
Guy lied to us.
It's back where we came from.
I don't know if I can do this, okay?
I got a family.
If I'm gonna shit in a bag for life\n'cause I got shot after the war...
...that'd be pretty stupid,\nwouldn't it?
What's the most important thing in life?
What are you talking about?
What's the most important thing?
Respect.\nToo dependent on other people.
What, love?\nA little Disneyland, isn't it?
God's will.
Close.
What is it, then?
necessity.
As in...?
People do what is most necessary\nto them at any given moment.
We can do what we want.\nThey won't touch us.
All right. I'll be wearing\nfashionable Kevlar.
Me too.
Come on, Conrad.
Where the hell are the bunkers?
Supposed to be right around here.
How about these fires?
How about a rare pelican migration\nout by the marshes?
Fuck that! Stop the car!
I don't see any bunkers. Do you?
We'll find Major Gates, ma'am.
Bullshit. All we're finding is\nUkrainian cranes.
Pelicans.
This story has been so done.\nA waste of my fucking time.
Look at these poor fucking birds.
All covered in some kind of fucking oil,\necological catastrophic....
Fuck it!
It's so goddamn horrible!
Jesus Christ!
Poor fucking birds!
Look at them.
It's so sad.
You're not gonna fuck me.
I was promised the gold story,\nand I'm driving.
Military regulations. You cannot drive!
Step away from the Chenowth, ma'am!
Don't make me shoot you, ma'am!
Please fucking stop!
Will you tell me where he is?
I can't tell you!\nBullshit!
Where is he?\nI can't  !
Come on, bitch! Tell me where he is!
You'll die here\nlike these fucking birds!
It's a village near Karbala!
All right! Let's go to Karbala.
Get down!
Freeze!
...the United States military\nhereby confiscates...
...all materials stolen by lraq\nfrom the state of Kuwait.
That means everything you took\nis going back!
Stay calm and\nwe'll get through this quickly.
Is that clear? Good!
Grab him!
Keep your finger off the trigger!
Sorry about that, sir.
no.
For wife!
I'm divorced.
newest and best.
newest and best has better\nnoise reduction.
This is bad music. This is bad for you.
I want you to tell me where the gold is.
There's another door over here.
He is prisoner. It's okay.
These rebel lraq problem!
We take outside\nso they don't bother you.
You open that door now.
Open that door!
Let's go!
Get down on the ground!
The prisoner stay!
Get on the ground!
The prisoners must stay!
Listen to me. Everything you stole from\nKuwait belongs to us now. Understand?
Put it back.
Why?
We stick to the plan for the gold.\nWe're not thieves.
We're returning Kuwaiti bullion,\ncorrect?
Full.
I'm getting a fleet of Lexus\nconvertibles.
I told you Lexus don't make\na convertible.
I'll bet you a Lexus they do.
You all right?
It landed on my foot.
They definitely didn't\nget here in these bags.
The tensilary strength in these\nis only 200 pounds.
What?\nTensilary strength.
He works at an airport.
If we put it in one of these\nVuitton bags...
...they can hold about 65 pounds,\nmaybe more.
You have any more luggage?
United States military\nis in charge here.
What gas station?
The one upstairs.
We need a truck.
Did we get it?
We got it.\nIs it a lot?
You have no idea. Are you cool here?
They've been ignoring me.
Don't worry about it. Stay calm.\nI'm going to find a truck.
Move!
Move away from the vehicle!
Let's go!
You take the Kuwaiti gold, yes?
We take the Kuwaiti gold, yes.
Saddam cannot keep?\nno, Saddam cannot keep.
Saddam have many problem today.
He certainly does.
You need help to carry?
I think we'll be all right.
These man help you.
And then you go away fast\nfrom all this bullshit.
Keep it going, keep it going.
Don't leave. Please don't leave.
Look!
Help!
Please!
Don't go. Don't go.
You go now, please.
I don't think so.
This man is leader of uprising.
Let's just stick to the plan!\nThe plan is for the gold!
We can help these people,\nthen we'll be on our way.
That's not why we're here!\nLet's go!
Cover me.
no unnecessary shots, Conrad,\nbecause we know what they do.
They make infected pockets\nfull of bile, sir.
That's right. That's what they do.
I want you to leave this town.
Saddam kill us if we leave.\nKill our family!
no shooting.
Okay, we work something out.
Easy! Take it easy!
What's happening?
Accident. Stay cool.
Put your hands up.
I'm okay.
Get down!
Shut up! Get down!
Get down! Shut up.
Put the people in the Humvee.\nWhat?!
There's no room!\nMake room!
What happened to necessity?
It just changed!
not for me! Let's go!
What if that was you?!
What if this was you without Kevlar?!
Great. A fucking tank!
That should send us on our way!
L.A.W., sir?
Let's get the hell out of here.
It's about fucking time!
Ride in that Humvee. Let's go!\nIn the Humvee!
Come on, sweetheart, come on.
Let's go!
Stupid son of a bitch!\nWe were home free!
Give me that arm.
What's that tank doing?
I don't know. Looks like it stopped.
They broke the cease fire.
It's gas!
Where's my mask?
Where's my fucking mask?
Where's my mask?!
Stop! Stop!
Wait! Those are mines!
Come back this way.
Stop!
no, this isn't sarin.\nWe'd be dead already!
What is it? Mustard?\nC.S.
Tear gas?
Times 10.
Come here.
Put this on.
Here, you take it.
See that? That's a mine!
Don't step there! Do not step there!
Where's your kids?
Cover your face. Come here.
Where are your children?
Watch your back!
Freeze! Don't move!
What's going on?\nI don't know.
It's okay. They're helping us.\nThey're with the rebels.
They got a shelter.
Tunnel.
Go, go. Get in!
I gotta look for Barlow.
Where's Troy?
Wait a minute! Where's Troy?
We gotta get out of here.
Where is Troy?
Come on!\nGet off me!
Let's go!
You motherfucker! Get the fuck off me!
Get the fuck off me!
We have to go back and get Troy.
He's not out there.\nWe have to wait till it clears.
You made a choice in the village,\nand we lost Troy.
I had no choice.\nYou had a choice!
I had no choice.
What about Troy?\nWhat choice does he have now?
Paco, start shooting!
I don't like this.
We should go!
Let me handle this.
Get dressed!
Fuck!
Do you speak English?
Could you...?
I have a little problem.
I need to know the number.\nWhat number, please?
Operation Desert Storm.
I'm sorry. l need to know the number.
The big army in the desert.\nIt's an emergency!
You'll have to give me more
Fuck! Maybe
Come on, come on, come on!
Honey, it's me.
Oh, my God! Baby, I was\nhoping it was you!
It's me, honey.
God, the baby's crying.
How's she doing?
She hasn't slept good, and Mom had\nto go back to work, so I'm real tired.
l wish I was there to help, gooney bird.\n-When are you coming home?
I'm working on that right now.
I saw an ad for a computer job.\nYou want me to set up an interview?
Listen, honey\nWhat date are you coming home?
We don't have\nan exact date yet, but--
If l knew,\nl could set up this interview
Listen to me!\nWhat's happening?
-What was that?\nThe wall just exploded.
I thought the war was over.
It is and it isn't.\nCould you call the reserve center?
What do you want me to do?
Tell the duty nCO I'm stuck in a bunker\nnear 223 north, outside Karbala.
223 north, outside Karbala.
Everything's okay?\n-I don't want you to worry.
I tried to do something\nfor the family, and....
I just want you to know
I love you.\n-What's going on?
Just tell Krystal.
Tell her I'm rich, and if things\nwork out, she'll be taken care of.
What are you saying?
I gotta go, gooney bird!\nI love you!
Spirits are high,\nand music is soaring...
...as these young troops celebrate\nthe liberation of Kuwait.
I'm being held captive by lraqi troops\noutside a bunker near the gritty city
Wait. Cut, cut!
You said ''gritty city'' again.
Who gives a shit?! These people\nare dying, for chrissake!
What about Private Wogoman?
Let's lay one down first.
In three, two....
I'm being held captive\nby lraqi troops...
The rebels have gone down the road....
The assault, apparently started by the\nrebels from Karbala, came up on
Back off!
Sir, that's enough!
We have a right to be here!
That's mine.
Fuck it.
Could l have my pants, please?
My pants! On my legs!
Out! Get out!
What did you want to be as a little boy?
As a boy, I wanted to be either a\nveterinarian or a ClA sharpshooter.
Really? That's very complicated.
Yes, colonel.
What the fuck are you doing?\nI'm giving an interview to nRG.
Do you have authorization?\nYes, sir, l do.
no.
Who gave you this?\nMajor Gates.
Archie Gates gave you this?\nJesus Christ, Doug!
I don't get to do the interview?\nYou don't get to do the interview.
Come with me.
Tell me where he is, or you're going\nback to the hotel in Dhahran.
I don't know. I think he's\nhelping Adriana Cruz.
Is she here?\nno, sir.
So who else is missing?
Chief's not here.\nChief's not here?
You don't know where your\nsergeant is?
Barlow and Vig are gone too, sir.
What?
I don't know what it was, a map or\nsecret list. I saw it happen.
Did they bring it to you?\nno, sir.
See, he's working something.
Get me maps. Check radio transmissions.\nMaybe we'll get their positions.
Is that guy dead?\nWhere are you gonna put him?
A shrine.
A shrine?\nWhat kind of shrine y'all got?
A shrine near a holy man...
...that gives him comfort\nand access to paradise.
I'm not kidding.\nIt sounds like a good shrine.
Man, I'm sorry I hit you.
I was just worried about Troy.
He's my friend.
I didn't want nothing to happen to him.
He's gonna take me to Detroit with\nhim, hook me up with a job.
Come on, man.
I don't wanna hold no grudges.
You got kicked out of that\nring of Jesus fire, huh?
That ain't how it work.
How's it work?
I take care of whatever He puts\nin front of me, no questions asked.
He put that gold in front of me,\nand l took it.
That's how it works.
What about now?
I don't know. I gotta see.
How you doing, Conrad?
I'm fine.
It was my choice today.
You can try to head back if you want.\nTake your share and bury it.
I'll find Barlow myseIf.
I wanna find Troy.
I'm here. I'm ready.
Let's check the suitcases.
I count 79.
That means we're missing 4 1 bags.
That's about 23 million dollars left.
not bad for a disaster, provided we find\nBarlow and not get court martialed.
How is she?
How is your little girl?
She's traumatized. What do you expect?
I went to B school at Bowling Green.
I came back to open a couple\nof hotels near Karbala.
I'm nearly in the black\nwhen this stupid war starts...
...and you guys bomb all my cafes.
Look at these people.
Where is America now?
Where is the Army now?!
You have a radio?
no radio, no water.
Where's Barlow?\nThey got him.
Where would they take him?\nOasis bunker.
It's full of Saddam's Guard.
Where's that?\nApproximately 17, 18 miles from here.
We'll walk until we find some.
Why don't you call in the Marines?
With what? We don't have a radio.
We'll find a vehicle, you drive back,\nget a helicopter, fly in, get your man.
Can't do that.\nWhy not? You have a huge army here.
We shouldn't be involved\nin the uprising.
We killed lraqi soldiers,\nbroke the peace accord.
You know what I think?
We're fighting Saddam and dying,\nand you're stealing gold.
You're wrong.
They have haIf a million men here.
They send four guys\nto pick up all this bullion?
I don't think so.
We need to find our man. How much\ndo you want to take us to him?
Is this still yours to give?
The only reason you have these bags\nis we picked them up.
We'll take our share...
...and we will help you\ncarry your share.
And find our man.
Amir Abdulah.
Archie Gates.
You will take us to the lranian border.
If we don't get to a refugee camp,\nwe're dead. The nearest is in lran.
You don't need us.\nYou can buy your way.
Saddam's soldiers\nwon't take Saddam's gold.
Our only chance\nis if we are with Americans.
Can't take you to the lranian border.
Then we don't have a deal.
Give me a fucking break, man!
We saved your life!
And we saved yours.\nWe lost a man for you.
The big army of democracy beats the ugly\ndictator and saves the rich Kuwaitis...
...but you go to jail if you help us\nescape the same dictator?
Look at my daughter.
Who's going?
Everyone but the priests.\nThat makes 55.
Did we save anything from the Humvee?
Vig's bag.
Lovely.
What is your rank, bro?
Sergeant first class.
Your company?
437 Civil Affairs Company,\nU.S. Army Reserve.
My main man...
...tell me something, okay?
What is the problem\nwith Michael Jackson?
What do you mean?
You understand my question?
I'm not sure l do.
The King of Pop.
Michael Jackson.
He come to Egypt.\nI see picture in newspaper.
''Hello,'' with the white glove.\n''I'm Michael Jackson in my hotel room...
...with my chop up face.'' Your country\nmake him chop up his face.
I don't think so.
That's bullshit. He did it to himseIf.
You are the blind bullshit,\nmy main man.
It is so obvious a black man...
...make the skin white and the hair\nstraight, and you know why?
no.
Your sick fucking country make the black\nman hate himseIf...
...just like you hate the Arab\nand the children you bomb over here.
I don't hate children.
This is illegal. The war is over.\nThat's why you are illegal.
You broke the cease fire, and I think\neven you steal the gold.
So nobody know where you are, right?\nYour Army don't know.
I'll send you to Baghdad for a long\ntime. nobody found you.
Do they care, buddy?\nDoes who care?
Do your Army care about the children\nin lraq? Do they come back to help?
no, they're not coming.
Do your Army...
...come back to help the people?
Tell the truth, dudesky.
Save us the big bummer.
That's the truth.
Does it hurt?
I asked you a question, man!\nDoes it hurt?
Yes, it hurts.
You bomb my family. Do you know that?
You blow up my home. The whole street.
My wife is crush by big fucking\nblock of concrete.
She lose her legs.
That's horrible.\nWhat?
I said that's horrible.
My God, buddy. l didn't even told you\nthe horrible part yet.
My son....
My son was killed in his bed.
He is 1 years old.
He is sleeping with his toy\nwhen the bomb come.
I have a daughter.
Very nice for you, bro.
She's safe in Arizona...
...without the bomb, the concrete and\nall this shit.
I'm not from Arizona.
How old is she?
One month old.
What's her name?
Krystal.
What make you decide to tell me\nabout Krystal, my main man?
Because we're both fathers.
I'm not father no more, dude.\nRemember?
My son is dead now.
Can you think how it feel\ninside your heart...
...if l bomb your daughter?
Worse than death.
That's right.
Y'all think America is Satan, right?\nAmerica is Satan?
What'd they say?
They say he want salon.
You cut hair?
Yes.
Look, they don't care if they cut\nAmerican hair, Shiite hair, Sunni hair.
They just want get rid of Saddam\nand live life. Make business.
He wants to know,\ndo you want to kill every Arab?
That's what I was trained to do.
no. That was not our training.\nWe got Arab allies, man.
Yeah, well, we got Arab allies.
He's just had no high school.\nno high school.
Don't tell people that.
What'd they say?\nHe says you have terrible haircut.
Troy gave me this haircut.\nIt's a badass haircut.
America!
America, welcome!
How you doing?\n''How are you?''
He's happy to welcome America.
Thank you.\nWe welcome America!
They're all deserters.\nThey leave Saddam army.
But they help us near Karbala.\nGood man.
no, my friend! The man don't do that.\nOnly the woman.
Why's that?
Because it's their custom.
You have a radio?\nno radio.
George Bush get rid Saddams now?
not exactly, no.
Congratulation!
Would you inform this gentleman\nwe need a vehicle of some kind?
From Kuwait.
Let me ask you a question.
Infiniti convertible only.
no Lexus convertible. Infiniti only.
Infiniti only.
Exactly what l said.
We use these cars\nto fight Saddam's soldiers.
What's so funny?
Cannot take.
What do you mean? We kicked\nSaddam's ass. We definitely take.
We are the United States Army.
You are three guys with a bunch of\ncivilians and no Humvee.
need money. Have no money.\nTo eat, to live.
''American Army is huge, with planes\nand tanks. We have nothing.''
Listen to me.\nWe will rise up together. Tell him.
Rise up.
Look at us. Many races.
Many nations, many nations.\nWorking together.
Tell him, Chief.\nWe're united.
United.
Wants you!
He wants everybody.
Yes! Me and you stand up together!
We fight. Kick Saddam's ass!
George Bush wants you!
Make the fight for freedom on your own!\nThen America will follow!
Praise the Lord!
God bless America,\nand God bless a free lraq!
Free lraq!
now, what do you say, my friend?
Cannot give car.
I guess we'll buy them.
Come on, man. This is good music.\nJudas Priest will pump you up!
no! We're not listening to that\nheadache music.
Just one song.
What you need is that\neasy listening classics.
I do not need that.
You need something to calm you.
All right, try this.
This is from Barlow's wife in Detroit.\nThey may have a position on him.
From his wife in Detroit?
What the hell is this?
I was managed by the military.\nMe too.
I try to be substance based,\nnot style based.
I think you got style.
That little Cathy bitch\nsays I'm old.
That's because she's jealous.
First of all, you're smarter than her,\nand that is a threat.
And second of all, you are beautiful.
You're the most prettiest woman down\nthere at that network.
You got great skin. Beautiful hair.
That's sweet, but there's\nsexual politics in this business.
It's about looks. It's about sex.\nIt's about style.
Many anchormen came on to me,\nand I didn't go for it.
I never played that game or dropped\nto my knees for an assignment.
I only joined Saddam Hussein army\nto make good living for my family.
Good house.
Now I can't get out.
I joined up for the extra cash too.
Found out I was gonna have a baby.
You know, l got weapon and training\nfrom America.
Bullshit.
How you think l learned my English?
Specialist guys come here...
...to train us when we fight lran.
What'd they train you in?
...interrogation.
Great.
It was a total waste for your Army\nto come to lraq, right?
I heard about a lot of bad shit that\nhappened in Kuwait.
Bad shit happened.\nI'm not proud of that.
Who's got the sick country?
Maybe Saddam is very crazy.
And then you are crazy to bomb\nall of lraq.
Too much bombing is crazy,\nbut not saving Kuwait.
You are here for save Kuwaiti people?
Really?
Lot of people in trouble\nin this world...
You can't invade another country.
Why not, dude?
It makes the world crazy.\nYou need to keep it stable.
no, for stability.\nStabilize the region.
This is your fucking stability,\nmy main man.
We get our man, then we come back\nand pick up the gold.
And my people?\nThat's right.
Let's go over the plan.
There's a bunker built into the side\nof the cliff face.
Looks like a castle. There's a road\ncoming there, another one across.
It's full of Saddam's Republican Guard.\nI don't think we can overpower them.
There's too many.
But there's one thing they're afraid of.
What's that?
Saddam.
Then that's what we use.
Right. That's what we'll use.
You stay with me.
Hold on. l wanna go over\nthis plan one more time.
You're scared, right?
Maybe.
The way this works is, you do the thing\nyou're scared shitless of...
...and you get the courage after\nyou do it. not before you do it.
That's a dumb ass way to work.\nIt should be the other way around.
I know.
That's the way it works.
I got a splinter.
Jesus fire, Jesus fire, Jesus fire....
Come on.
Quickly.
Oh, shit!
You all right?
Shit, you're dead.
Wait! Wait!
Shit.
Let's get out of here.
Where's Conrad?
Keep your guard up.
Are you okay?
Where's Conrad?\nHow are we getting back?
We got the Rolls.\nYou got a Rolls?
This is an Infiniti convertible.
Man, I think you're in shock.
It's an Infiniti convertible, isn't it?
Yeah, it is.
Okay, so l owe you a car.\nI'm not in shock.
Sure you're okay?
Freeze!
no! He's with us!
Don't shoot him! He's with us!
You're the guy with the little girl.\nThat's right.
What are you doing here?
He helped us find you.\nl came here to help you.
All right. You're all right, man!
I see some people.
I can't see what's happening. Stay put.
How's your little girl?\nShe's safe for now.
Outstanding! Excellent!\nHow can we help you?
We had a deal to get to the border, but\nwe have more people and need vehicles.
That's not a problem.\nWe'll work it out.
We have to do this. We can work it out.
I don't know. It's a lot of people.
You choose who we take. Tell the\nothers they'll have to die.
l can't do that.\nYou'll have to do that yourseIf.
You made it, man!
I thought that was you!
Where the fuck have you been?
What are you wearing?
What is this?
It's a suit jacket.\nThe lraqis gave it to me.
I didn't recognize you in it.
It fits all right, right?
I'm okay.
Where's he hit?
It's in and out. I think\nit's above his collarbone.
Where's the Jesus fire?
It's all around you right now.\nYou'll be all right.
You'll be all right.
I'm going to hell.
You're gonna be fine.
Can you take me to a shrine that gives\nyou comfort and erases your bad deeds?
We made the right choice today.
Stop with that shrine shit.\nIt'll be okay.
You think so?\nl know so!
We're getting out of here.\nHey, major!
Would you please fucking help  !
Goddamn it!
What's the matter, man?
Can you breathe?
There's air in his chest.\nIt's crushing his lung.
Does that feel better, man?
That feel better?
He's gone.
Air pressure's going to build up about\nevery 1 5 minutes.
Release the valve and close it back up.
How long can I keep doing that?\nI don't know.
Maybe 4 or 5 hours, if you're not\nbleeding too bad. You don't seem to be.
He said he wanted\nto go to one of those shrines.
Did he mean that?
That's what he told me.
Kerman, lran. We can take him with us.
Then take him.
All right. Take him there.
We found a radio inside.\nYou're hooked for that call, major.
Bolo, this is Brer Rabbit.
We're going to jail.
no, we're not.\nBolo, this is Brer Rabbit.
This is Bolo. Come in.
Where are you?
About two clicks outside of camp.
We're ready for that briar patch.
I want to find out where we're going.\nPlease! I'm transmitting code!
You got me, Bolo?
I think so.
You do.
Tar Baby goes to the briar patch\nif everything's okay.
no. It's the other way around.
Sorry, sir. I don't\nremember how the code goes.
l need four personnel trucks\nand a Humvee.
That's a pretty tall order\nfor a secret operation, sir.
Talk to my friend Teebaux.\nEach driver will get a hundred K.
Brer Rabbit at 239 north.
Add one Medevac pack to the order.\nMake sure you bring the reporter.
Roger. Give me two hours.
Bury those real good, Chief.
After we take them to the border,\nwe figure out a way to get it out.
223 north is the position his wife gave.\nThere's just an empty bunker there.
Task air recon to cover\n223 north to the border.
I'll put choppers on standby.
If they're there, they won't be\nhard to find.
All the way, sir.
Are you all right?
It's not me.\nBarlow could use some morphine.
They got him.\nLet's see about you.
Did you get the gold?\nno, but we helped a lot of people.
Now we have to get them\nover the border.
They'll be killed without protection.\nThey're gonna bust you for that.
Cover it and see what happens.
Sure you're not coming with us?
Good luck.
Sit down.\nWe're gonna pull out fast.
Everybody sit down.\nWe're going.
Walter, did you meet everybody?
Walter, this is Kaied.
What are you thinking?
We walk them past the lraqi soldiers.\nMake sure they're safe.
We walk back to the trucks\nand get out of here.
All right, let's do it!
no guns. Only American soldiers\ncarry guns.
We are just now about....
We're getting it now? We're about 25\nyards from an lraqi checkpoint...
...heading into lran.
We are just about to move across the\nzone up into the lranian border.
It's a barbed wire point.
We have men, women and children here...
...assumed to be lraqi refugees\ncrossing over into lran.
Make sure they take care of Conrad.\nl will.
Keep in a tight group.
This is a violation of American policy.
The United States has\nwithdrawn its support.
Let's cut and go again.
You are AWOL, and you are in violation\nof American policy.
You are under arrest.
Double time! Let's go!
We can make it before they stop us!
Arrest them! Get them away\nfrom those refugees!
Let's go!
Watch out!
You're under arrest!
Go!
Let me get her over!
Wait! Just let them get over first!\nWait!
l need to reach this valve in my chest.
Look what's happening!\nJust let them get over!
Help these people get across!\nYou cannot support them!
Let me get them across,\nand I'll go right with you!
Let's go! You're coming with me!
They'll be slaughtered\nif we don't help them!
Why you doing this?\nThey'll kill them!
The refugees are not crossing the border.\nThey have been rounded up....
Let them get over!
That's not our mission!\nYou don't belong here!
We're not involved in this problem!\nUnderstand?
You're AWOL and you're under arrest!
Will you let them kill those people?\nIt's not right!
They're arresting them!
I can't breathe!
You fucked me, now you're fucked!\nSo shut your mouth!
I need to reach this!
Give this man medical attention!
We're not involved in this problem here!
You're way out of line!
Look at him!
I can't reach the valve!\nHe can't breathe!
Put the cuffs on the front!
You don't worry about him!\nWorry about yourseIf!
What the hell is this?\nTurn that camera off!
That's a $ 70,000 camera!\nWhat are you doing here?!
I'm authorized
He's gonna die!
Cut his cuffs!
All we had to do was help them!\nIt was less than 1 00 feet!
We got the gold.
The Kuwaiti bullion. We've got it.\nBullshit.
Hold that bag. Give me that bag!
Get the bag.
How much do you have?\nTwenty three million.
Where's it at?
Get those people over first.
They helped us find it, Ron.
We made a deal. It's a soldier's honor.\nYou can't fuck them now.
Come on. Return the gold.
Save some refugees. Get that star.
Let's go, Doug.
Who's in charge here?
You're under arrest.\You'll be court martialed...