NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous,
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit,
These are their stories,
(SlRENS WAlLlNG
lN THE DlSTANCE)
(GRUNTlNG)
(EXHALES)
What the...
Oh, God.
(GROANlNG)
Oh, my God.
No. No.
(VOMlTlNG)
(CHATTERlNG OVER POLlCE RADlO)
Careful of the emesis.
STABLER: Who puked?
The apartment owner,
when he discovered her.
Dalton Rindell.
He's got a pretty good
gash to the head.
Paramedics are
with him now.
We saw him
on the way in,
but wanted to
get a handle on
what went down here
before we talked to him.
Fluids on her thigh
indicate sexual activity.
Rest of the story's
written on the wall.
Bludgeoned to death
from someone in a rage.
From the impressions
to the skull,
I'd say you're looking
for a hammer.
Rindell called
91 1 at 7:34 a.m.
Do you have
an approximate
time of death here?
I can give you
the exact minute.
She tried to
shield her head
with her hands.
One of the blows
crushed the crystal
on her watch.
(EXHALES)
BENSON: 12:57.
So, Rindell was out cold
for six and a half hours.
That's some
hit to the head.
This might explain
the perp's rage.
(READlNG)
I thought Mr. Rindell's
name was Dalton.
He was having
an affair
with Audrey.
Michael catches
them in the act,
he attacks Dalton,
kills his cheating lover.
STABLER: So the sex
was consensual.
Mr. Rindell,
can you tell us
what happened?
I was hoping
you could tell me.
I don't remember anything.
My head is splitting.
Could his injury have
affected his memory?
Neuro exam
checked out fine.
STABLER: What exactly
is the nature of your
relationship with Audrey?
Who's Audrey?
The dead woman
on your
bedroom floor.
We didn't have
any relationship.
Until I found her
this morning,
I'd never seen her
before in my life.
Melinda,
you got a minute?
I was hoping to
pop her in the fridge
before she goes bad.
I'm thinking
it's Dalton's story
that's stinking.
You like him for it.
Well, there was no
sign of forced entry.
But the victim's clothes,
purse and lD are missing.
Someone must have
taken them.
Someone Dalton doesn't
want us to know about.
Drug dealer, pimp.
We know she had sex.
I need to know if
it was with Dalton.
You mind coming upstairs
and doing a DNA swab?
We letting him
know why?
I don't understand.
Why do you need
my fingerprints?
We take it from
anyone who has
Iegitimate access
to the apartment.
Once we eliminate
the friendlies,
any unidentified print
could be the perp's.
Got you.
We need you
to sign this so we can
search your apartment.
That way, we don't have
to pester a judge
for a warrant.
Why would you
need to do that?
There's no crime scene
exception to the
Fourth Amendment.
We need to keep
our searches legal.
A man killed
someone in my home.
Whatever you
need to do.
But I don't get it.
Why did he pick me?
Have you ever seen
anything like this?
(SlGHS)
If I had a nickel for
every dead prostitute
I ever woke up with...
I've never used
a prostitute.
Sorry, without gallows
humor to cope with
what we see every day,
I'd go stark
raving mad.
What do you
mean, "Go"?
How do you deal
with stress,
Mr. Rindell?
Usually,
I avoid it.
WARNER: Mr. Rindell?
Is it okay
if I take
a DNA sample?
It's just a quick swab
of the inside
of your mouth.
Won't hurt a bit.
Routine procedure?
With your permission.
Of course.
BENSON: Mr. Rindell,
do you own a hammer?
Uh-huh.
It's not in
your toolbox.
Is that
what he used?
I'm going to
be sick again.
I need some water.
We should get you
to the hospital and
have you checked out.
All right, let me
just grab my wallet.
I'm not so sure
he doesn't know
the perp.
If he's hiding something,
we'll find it.
DR. MANNlNG:
Looks like the paramedic
missed a sliver of glass.
Could that have caused
the memory loss?
No, not deep enough.
And your head CT
looks fine.
And you still don't
remember anything?
No. No, and I feel
like crap.
Well, you're dehydrated.
I'll start an lV.
Did you party
last night?
No.
Not at all.
I was working.
Dalton, I can't tell
you how many victims
withhold information
about illegal drug use
because they're scared
they're going to
get into trouble.
STABLER: We're not
looking to jam you up
on a possession charge.
If you had a dealer
in your apartment
or you were partying
with friends,
you just have
to tell us.
I don't do drugs.
I don't even drink.
What if someone
drugged me?
Okay. Like who?
I don't know.
Nayyar, how much longer
you going to keep this
bathroom tied up?
You're worse
than my ex-wife.
Someone let
a sweet talker
like you go?
I'm done scanning.
It's all yours.
Does CSU know
there's bloody
handprints in here?
ANU: They're right behind
you in the lunch line.
You know, those prints
look smeared to me,
but they'll
lift them all.
MUNCH:
Bloody towels, as well.
They're still damp.
Well,
no one from the canvass
saw a bloody maniac,
so you've got to
figure he cleaned up
before he left.
FlN: You didn't look
in the shower?
Washed clean.
He took a shower
while I was passed
out on the floor?
Or maybe you came home
and surprised him
while he was in there.
But why was I naked?
That's the million
dollar question.
You think I raped her.
You think I did this?
STABLER:
We're looking
for answers.
And you're not
providing any.
Well, I don't have any.
BENSON:
Dalton, calm down
and work with us.
We're trying to figure out
how a dead, naked woman
ended up in your apartment.
What time did you
come home last night?
I don't remember
coming home.
You said
you were working.
Where's that?
Did anybody see you?
I'm a developer.
My partner Bill and l
met with the buyers
of these co-op units
we had presold.
About 75 people showed up
to our headquarters.
Any one of them unhappy
with their purchase?
All of them. Construction
hit a little speed bump,
so we threw
this cocktail mixer to
put their minds at ease.
Dalton,
you said you weren't
partying last night.
Trust me.
It was no party.
BlLL: Dalton was
dripping flop sweat.
You have no idea
how crucial it was
to instill the investors
with confidence.
Of course I do.
That's step number one
in The Idiot's Guide
to Flimflamming,
Hey, we're not running
the "Nigerian prince"
scam here.
This is going to be
a landmark building.
When do you plan
on completing it?
Soon as we shore up
new financing.
That was the point
of last night.
You were trying to
suck even more money
out of these people?
Otherwise,
we have to file bankruptcy
and they lose everything.
Well, how much are
they already in for?
Two to four
hundred thousand each.
So they all had motive
to murder both of you.
Or set you up for one.
We were hoping
for a slightly more
enthusiastic response.
That coward, Dalton,
left me to deal with them.
At the end of the cocktail
hour, I called the meeting
to order, and he was gone.
Maybe he didn't
leave on his own.
I'll need a list
of your victims.
I mean, buyers.
Absolutely not.
You can't drag them all
into a murder investigation.
Even if it means
clearing your partner?
BOWMAN: Detectives.
What have we got?
The buildings
are connected.
That's Mr. Rindell's
bedroom window
right up there
and the perp
must have tossed
this out of it.
MUNCH: Oh!
What have we here?
FlN: We've got
ladies clothes,
shoes and a purse.
Why toss it over here?
If he didn't
want it to be found,
he could have
thrown it in the river.
FlN: I don't know.
But I just might have
found a motive
for her murder.
Our victim's a doctor.
(MUNCH READlNG)
They do abortions.
We're so sorry
for your loss.
Our divorce
was finalized
a few months ago,
but I never stopped
loving Audrey.
Friendly divorce?
Is there such a thing?
You can't imagine
the screaming matches.
Me begging her
to leave her job
at the clinic
and her saying
she had a commitment
to uphold
a constitutionally
protected service.
You didn't approve
of your wife's work.
I was afraid
for our daughter,
Clarissa.
Your family
get threats?
A few years ago,
an anti-abortion group
posted hundreds
of doctors' names
and home addresses
and telephone numbers
on the lnternet.
And we started
getting hang-up calls
in the middle
of the night
and nasty letters.
Did you keep
any of them?
No, I didn't
want our daughter
finding them.
And once that
doctor was shot
in his own church
in Kansas this summer,
I petitioned the court
for sole custody,
but lost.
And Audrey was supposed
to pick her up tomorrow.
I told her this was
going to happen.
Mr. Hale, did you
or Audrey have any connection
with an R-T Developers?
No.
STABLER: How about
a Dalton Rindell?
Who's that?
One of those
fanatical nuts?
No, I am definitely
not one of them.
Let's play a little
free association.
You say the first thing
that pops into your head.
Roe v, Wade,
Two ways to get
across a creek.
You consider
Dr. Hale's murder
a joke?
No, no.
It was the most horrific
thing I've ever seen.
But I didn't do it.
I don't know her or
anything about her.
Then how did
she get in your
apartment?
Forget that.
How did she
get in your bed?
Look. I know
it sounds crazy,
but it had to be one
of the co-op owners.
I think
I'm being set up.
Okay. Here comes
the conspiracy theory.
You go.
A guy puts a chunk down on
a three-million-dollar condo
that's never
going to be built.
And he's not going to get
any of his money back.
I can see that making
a guy a little nutty.
Right. So he starts
obsessing about
the ills of the world
and kills two birds
with one hammer.
We're going to need
the investors list
to prove that.
We're hanging on
by a thread.
Could you
at least be discreet?
No problem. Just answer
my partner's question.
Which are you?
Pro-choice or no-choice?
I know it's everybody's
litmus test for picking
a president
or a Supreme Court
justice.
It's not even on
my priority list.
And I was just starting
to believe you, Mr. Rindell.
Abortion is
the one subject
everyone has a strong
opinion about.
Abortion is murder.
You know,
that's what I've been
trying to tell her.
What group
are you with?
Operation
Save and Deliver.
Life begins
at conception.
BENSON: What if
my life is at risk?
It's in God's hands,
not yours.
And what if
I told you
I was raped?
Well, the Lord
wouldn't have brought
a child into this world
if he didn't have
great plans for it.
Even though she'll be
a constant reminder?
You have no idea
the toll that
takes on a woman.
You must have been
happy when Dr. Hale
was murdered.
No, no, no, no.
That was awful.
We don't condone
any killing.
But it is a blessing
there's one less
mass murderer out there.
(lNAUDlBLE)
lronically, the young
women she scares away
are the ones coming
for birth control.
So, yes, she's a danger,
but not a violent one.
So what's with
the bulletproof
glass here?
Well, we had that
put in in '93 after
our sniper attack.
A receptionist
was shot in the arm.
Any more
recent attacks?
Well, not here,
but I monitor
the national stats.
Since the '70s,
there have been
175 arsons, 41 bombings.
Dr. Hale's ex-husband
was telling us
about the hate mail
they received at home.
Yeah, well,
we get plenty
of that here.
I had Beth pulling it
out for you.
This is the first box.
Okay.
How many more
like this?
There are five or six.
(THUDDlNG)
Get down.
STABLER: Get down.
Just a harmless
egging. We get that
from time to time.
Did you do this?
It was a couple of kids.
Which way
did they go?
I don't know.
I had my eyes closed.
But I'm touched
for your concern
for the chicken fetuses.
El, pop the trunk?
Dr. Kittle said Audrey
was meeting a friend
for dinner last night.
Male?
Female.
Let's go see
if she made it.
We had dinner
at Picholine.
We left there around
9:30, shared a taxi.
So Audrey went home?
No, there was
night construction on 5th,
and we were in
standstill traffic.
I saw this bar.
Said we should get out
and have a nightcap.
Audrey didn't want to,
but I dragged her.
Do you remember
the name of the bar?
That's what
I'm looking for.
BENSON:
Anyone there
hassling her?
No, but there
was this guy.
Okay. Linda.
Linda. It's okay.
Calm down.
Just tell us about him.
White, 30s,
really good looking.
Audrey hadn't even
looked at another man
since her divorce.
I'm the one that
got them talking.
Well, could he
have instigated it?
Maybe he followed you
into the place?
No. It looked like
he'd been there
for a while. Oh!
Here it is.
West Falls Lounge.
Okay. That's good,
but back to the guy...
They really hit it off.
STABLER: How did it
end with them?
I don't know.
I just left her there.
I thought I was
doing her a favor.
Did you get
the guy's name?
Something like Barnes.
I just remember
it was the name
of a book store.
Dalton?
Yes.
I appreciate
the lift home.
I'm exhausted.
STABLER: We've just got
to do a quick stop here.
Here it is.
West Falls Lounge?
BENSON: Do you
know this place?
DALTON: No.
It's walking distance
from your office.
I haven't been to a bar
in over a year.
Back in a second.
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
Sure you weren't
here last night?
I'm positive.
Why do you keep
asking me?
Look, I'm in the program.
One year, three months,
eight days sober.
What do you know?
One-year chip.
(SlGHS)
So, Dalton.
You had a headache,
you were throwing up,
you were dehydrated.
I was hit in the head.
Or you had a hangover.
I don't drink.
I need to use the restroom.
Wait a minute.
Hey. Wait a minute.
Dalton.
Yo! Get back here.
BARTENDER:
That's the guy
right there.
Dalton,
what are you
doing in here?
Where's the men's room?
What, you don't remember
from last night?
What are you
talking about?
Well, you were
knocking them back.
What's going on here?
Well, the bartender
says that you were
buying Audrey rounds
after her friend left.
Why would you
say that?
Buddy, you two
left together.
I know a hookup
when I see one.
You're lying.
Who put you up to this?
BENSON: Hey. Hey.
Back. Let go.
Take it easy.
I'm going to be
sick again.
BARTENDER: All the way
back on the right.
(DALTON COUGHlNG)
Wait a minute.
I can't. I can't.
(CELL PHONE RlNGlNG)
Stabler.
Hello? Hello?
Who is this?
Yeah, go ahead.
Lab results.
The bloody print
in the bathroom?
Dalton's.
And the DNA
from the rape kit.
Great, thanks.
Hey, Dalton.
Let's go.
Suck it up
and get out here.
Hey. Let's go.
Where did he go?
Where is he?
Dalton! He's running.
I'll take the front.
I don't see him.
Son of a bitch.
We lost him.
Now, what part of
taking a killer rapist
on a field trip
sounded like
a bright idea?
Dalton wasn't
technically under...
Zip it, John.
They are perfectly capable
of making their own
half-assed excuses.
No excuse.
Liv was interviewing
the bartender.
I was supposed to
have eyes on Dalton.
This one is on me.
It was equally
my responsibility.
Spare me the mutual
stroke-fest.
What are we doing
to fix this?
We sat on his
apartment
all last night.
He was smart enough
not to come home.
Got a subpoena for
his cell phone records.
And somebody's watching
the garage where
he keeps his car.
I put the word out
to the airport, train,
and bus terminals.
His bank has an alert
on his credit and debit cards.
He hasn't
used them yet.
Well, then, somebody
is harboring him.
Girlfriend? Parents?
Dalton told us
he wasn't dating
anybody seriously,
but we did
a little digging.
His parents divorced
when he was a kid.
His father's
in California,
and his mother died from
cirrhosis of the liver.
Appears no one in
the Rindell clan can
handle their liquor.
There were multiple
domestic abuse calls
against a drunken
Dalton Sr.
whaling on
the wife and kid until
he skipped out on them.
PAXTON:
Morning, detectives.
Just when I thought
my day couldn't
get any worse.
Has anyone seen
my missing defendant?
Well, we could
try and find him,
unless you want to
just waste our time
busting my balls.
Oh, I'd never kick
a fellow when he's down.
I'm sure you feel like
a grade-A moron as it is.
Of course, I'm the one
who has to slog
through a Wade hearing
because you tainted
the bartender's lD,
but...
What do you need, Sonya?
On the assumption
you'll retrieve
Dalton Rindell for me,
I'm proceeding
with my trial prep.
I actually
just stopped by
to catch a movie.
Want to join me?
ANU: Here's
your recreation
of the crime scene
based on the
Leica Scan Station,
which you can
show to the jury
from any angle.
Dalton approached
from the left,
wielding the hammer.
Audrey must have seen
the first swing coming,
scrambles out of the bed,
still tangled in the sheets.
Dalton comes around.
CRAGEN:
He's got her trapped.
ANU: She's facing him.
Tries to
ward off the first blow,
which breaks her wrist.
As he hauls back for
the second strike, he...
Wait, wait,
wait, wait.
She was raped first,
right?
You want me
to simulate that?
Actually,
it's looking like the
sex was consensual.
I mean,
they hooked up
in a bar.
They both were
drinking heavily.
Oh, please.
Half the rapists
I've put away
were drunk or high.
It's called Dutch courage.
It doesn't excuse jack.
And stopping her
from crying rape
is a motive to
kill her, right?
Keep going.
ANU: Audrey's
on her side.
He strikes her temple,
causing this arterial
spurting pattern
on the carpet.
Now, she's face down,
covering her head
with her hands.
One of the strikes
breaks her watch.
It's going to be hard
for a jury to watch.
But easy for them
to convict.
Castoff extends
onto the ceiling.
Means he was bringing
the hammer back
all the way
over his head
for each blow.
Well, wait.
This shows him
covered in blood.
There would
have been tons
of back spatter.
Well, do we have
his bloody clothes?
No. He must have
been naked, too.
So, after he cleaned up,
he realized what he'd done,
and he started
banging his head
against the medicine
cabinet mirror.
Bull. He was
staging the scene
to make it look like
he'd been attacked,
as well.
OFFlCER: Captain,
this just came in.
Well, if juries want
a video of the crime,
you're practically
giving them one.
Yeah.
This is really good.
Listen.
Raise the production
values for me.
Spare no expense.
We just got Dalton's
cell phone records.
Dozens of calls
to the partner,
all unanswered.
But he had a nice
long chat with his ex.
CELlNA: I have no idea
where Dalton is,
Really? He didn't mention it
during your 17-minute
conversation last night?
No. He just told me
his insane story.
It end with
a confession?
He swears
he's being set up.
He asked you for
a place to hole up,
didn't he?
He asked.
I said no.
Well, you mind taking us
to your place to verify that?
Not at all. As soon as
my open house is over.
FlN: Well, of course,
you being a rental agent,
you have access
to plenty of apartments
you can stash him in.
You're not going
to make us get
a search warrant
for every one of them,
are you?
After what Dalton
put me through?
I'd never help
that son of a bitch.
Bad marriage?
Varied days of
wine and roses.
I quit drinking.
Dalton couldn't.
Was he abusive?
The real Dalton
is the greatest guy
you'll ever meet.
But when he drinks,
he turns into a monster.
He kicked a lot of
holes in our walls,
but he only hurt me once.
That's when I walked.
Well, be grateful
you're still alive.
Sober, he wouldn't
hurt a fly.
I heard he went on
the wagon after
our divorce was final.
Yeah, well, he fell
off with a big splash.
If you wouldn't
help him, who would?
(SCOFFS)
His old drinking buddy.
His business partner,
Bill Tattenger.
You son of a bitch!
Hey! Police!
Break it up!
Hey! Hey! Police!
What are you doing?
You're only
making things worse.
First, evading arrest,
and now assault?
DALTON: I didn't run
because I was guilty.
I ran because I needed
to prove my innocence.
Admit what you did.
He's out of his
freaking mind.
Now, he's under arrest.
It doesn't matter.
I finally figured out
who's responsible for this.
Tell them.
Tell them!
(SlGHS)
What? Tell us what?
We were dying there!
Back in the day,
you closed million dollar
deals over drinks.
I convinced him
a little liquid courage
would steady his nerves.
You ruined my life!
No, let's go.
Let's go.
There's no way
one drink put me
on my ass.
What did you
put in it?
Nothing! I didn't do
anything illegal.
No, not by
frat boy standards.
"You want to have
your way with them?
Get them nice and drunk."
I swear to God,
I only gave him one.
What harm could that do?
Look, I'm on
a prescription
benzo for anxiety.
You're not supposed
to mix that with alcohol.
Bill kept telling me
one wouldn't hurt.
He must have made
the drink a lot stronger
than he told me.
Well, the thing is,
after you left Bill,
you drank seven
or eight on your own.
That we know of.
Yeah, but I didn't
even know I was doing it.
I don't even remember
leaving the office.
All right?
The combination of meds
and alcohol must have
completely disoriented me.
You had no problem
finding the nearest bar.
And you were the one
who did the ordering.
Not Bill.
Not Audrey. You.
It's only because
Bill pressured me
into that first drink.
That's the reason I quit
in the first place.
Look. Once I have one
in me, I can't stop.
(EXHALES)
What a load of crap.
It's not
that he couldn't stop.
He just didn't want to.
CRAGEN: It's not that
cut and dry, Sonya.
Alcoholism is
a recognized addiction.
That millions of people
have successfully overcome.
I've been sober
over 20 years,
but I struggle
with it every day.
It's not something
you ever overcome.
But you're not
drinking, are you?
Proving my point.
Alcohol is
just a crutch
for weak-willed,
pathetic losers.
How many
coffees and cigarettes
you have today, Sonya?
(SCOFFlNG) Oh, please.
I can quit anytime I want.
And if I committed
a felony,
I wouldn't trot them out
like the old Twinkie defense.
Intoxication
has never been
and never will
be a defense to
rape and murder.
Well, you have at it
on the murder,
but I don't think
you're getting him
on the rape.
Actually, Captain,
there's someone here
you need to talk to.
I used to be
an assistant at
R-T Developers.
A friend who still
works there called
and told me what
Dalton was arrested for.
You don't seem
too surprised.
A little over a year ago,
just after Dalton
and Celina separated,
I was working late and
went in to let him know
I was leaving.
And what happened?
He'd been drinking
in there all day.
He exposed himself.
I tried to leave,
but he cornered me.
He grabbed my breast
and forced his hand
down my pants.
I told you
he was a rapist.
So, let me guess.
You have no memory
of sexually assaulting
your old assistant.
Oh, I took
responsibility
for that.
Paying a girl off
to keep her from
filing criminal charges
is not taking
responsibility.
Ask Glenna when
that happened.
It was the day
I finally admitted
I had a problem.
I quit cold turkey.
I thought the DTs
were going to kill me,
but I never
touched another drop.
Not until Bill practically
poured it down my throat.
Oh, cut the crap.
Geez.
Need something, Sonya?
Yeah. For him to admit
he killed
and raped Audrey Hale.
I got tired of watching
you two play patty cake.
Sorry.
DALTON: How can
I admit something
I don't remember?
Look, I had
a history of blackouts
in my drinking days.
One time, I woke up
in a hotel room in Phoenix.
I had no clue
how I got there.
"The liquor made me do it.
My partner made me do it."
He did.
He admitted it.
Please.
It's not like
he slipped you a Mickey.
And he's not the one
who killed Audrey.
You are.
You lured her
to your place,
found out what
she did for a living,
and then you killed her
in a drunken rage.
I'm not even
anti-abortion.
Okay.
So her profession
was just a fluke.
Then why did
you kill her?
I don't know!
I swear, I have
no memory of what
happened that night.
Fine. Maybe this
will jog your memory.
That's me.
Yeah.
You can't show that
to a jury, can you?
No, not with your likeness,
but everything else.
I made this one
just for you.
(SlGHS)
I want to talk
to a lawyer.
Thanks for your help.
(DOOR CLOSES)
DR. SOPHER: While
the initial decision
to drink is a choice,
there comes a time
when the addiction switch
is turned on
in the brain.
I believe
this is the case
with Mr. Rindell.
Dr. Sopher,
you conducted a study
involving the brain
imaging of alcoholics.
DR. SOPHER: Yes,
and the results...
The People renew
their objection
to this hearing
in its entirety.
Counselor.
It doesn't matter what
voodoo science she trots
out as an excuse.
Intoxication has been
banned as a defense
to rape and murder
dating back...
The People didn't meet
their burden for rape.
That charge was dropped.
Banned as a defense
to murder
dating back to
the 19th century.
Would Your Honor
remind Ms. Paxton
that the entire point
of a Frye hearing
is to consider
the admissibility of
new science at trial?
I do have other
matters to consider.
Objection overruled.
Continue with
your witness,
Mr. Kressler.
What was the outcome
of your study?
Addiction is
a neurobiological disease.
A brain disease.
You have evidence
to support this?
Imaging of
addicted individuals
shows physical changes
in areas of the brain
critical to judgment,
memory and behavioral control.
So while Mr. Rindell
took a drink
of his own volition,
because of his disease,
he was physically incapable
of controlling the urge
to keep drinking.
Which led him to kill.
Dr. Sopher,
do all addicts
commit murder?
No, of course not.
And your findings,
are they generally
accepted
within the scientific
community?
We do have
our detractors.
Huh!
Do you believe
if I had an
inoperable tumor,
that I could
just will it away?
No.
Because a tumor
is a disease.
Not a behavior. Right?
Alcoholics stop drinking
all the time
by sheer willpower alone.
And you know why
they can do that?
Because alcoholism
is not a disease.
Good news, people!
Judge Moredock
isn't allowing
Dalton's cockamamie
"alcoholism is
a disease" defense.
Well, I'm familiar
with Dr. Sopher's work.
The point of her research
isn't to excuse
criminal behavior.
It's to find a cure.
Yeah. Well,
good luck with that.
Imagine if they could.
Crime rate
would be down 50%.
More than that
for sexual assaults.
Some of us might
be out of a job.
Please. People do
bad things because
they're bad people.
Getting drunk to do it
is just an excuse.
(CHUCKLlNG) Olivia, finally,
we agree on something.
Liv, if there
had been a cure
a decade ago,
your mom might
still be alive.
Wait, Mommy liked
her cocktail, or...
My mother was
a falling-down drunk.
She died going down
a flight of stairs.
She started drinking
after she was raped.
To cope.
Yeah, she never quite
managed to do that
with me there.
Well, no offense to
your mother, Olivia,
but you can't hide
behind a bottle.
Now, Dalton is claiming
temporary insanity
due to alcoholic
psychosis.
Well, take it
from somebody
who's been there.
Odds are there will be
a sympathetic drinker
on that jury
who's had a blackout
themselves.
It won't matter.
Not after I show them
the 3D recreation
of Dalton
hammering the brains
out of Audrey's skull.
PAXTON:
Ladies and gentlemen
of the jury, I warn you.
What you are about to see
is graphically violent.
But forensic
evidence proves
that these are the
indisputable actions
of the defendant.
(JURY GASPS)
Objection!
No!
She can't play that.
She told me the jury
couldn't see this one.
Bailiff, remove the jury.
Your Honor,
I have no idea
how this...
Counselors,
my chambers!
What happened?
(SlGHS)
The judge sent
the jury home so we
could have a hearing
on my royal screw-up.
(CHUCKLES)
Payback's a bitch.
Come on. Come on.
Let me have it.
Everyone
makes mistakes.
Not me.
I must be losing it.
What happened
at the hearing?
That weasel, Kressler,
said he knew I was losing
and purposely
played the wrong disc
to force a mistrial.
It was an accident,
wasn't it?
Of course it was.
Geez.
But the judge
isn't convinced.
So he's polling
the jurors tomorrow
to see if they can
disregard the video.
What if some
of them can't?
Then he'll have
to release them.
Even with the alternates,
if the pool dips below 12,
he'll have no choice
but to declare a mistrial.
So, you'll get
him on retrial.
Not if the judge
determines there was
prosecutorial misconduct.
In that case,
double jeopardy attaches,
and there is no retrial.
Party's over.
Everybody just
goes on home.
So, Dalton gets a walk.
You've got to
be kidding me.
Oh, that I were.
Hey, people.
Does anybody work here?
My friends need drinks.
Hello?
I've got to go home.
No, no, no, Stabler.
You need to go over
your testimony with me.
STABLER: I know exactly
what I'm going to say.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Please. Come on.
Actually, why don't
you cut yourself off?
What time do you have to be
at the hearing tomorrow?
9:00. We have a lot
of work to do, Olivia.
I'll probably
be up all night,
re-strategizing.
So can we get started?
Good luck.
(PEOPLE CHATTERlNG)
I'm here!
I'm here, Your Honor.
You're 45 minutes
late, Counselor.
I deeply apologize,
Your Honor.
I was involved
in a fender bender
on my way, and...
MOREDOCK:
Are you all right?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah. I'm fine.
Thank you.
I'm just... Ooh!
I made it. I was just...
(EXCLAlMS)
MOREDOCK:
You don't look
all right to me.
Do you need
medical help?
No, no, no, no, no.
I might have hit my head
in the fender bender,
but I can play hurt.
Alright. I can...
(BREATHlNG HEAVlLY)
I'm ready to proceed,
Your Honor.
MOREDOCK:
I think you need
to be looked at.
She's drunk.
Excuse me?
Excuse me, Dalton?
Are you... Did you
say something to me?
Trust me.
I would know.
Your Honor,
this is outrageous.
Oh, what's your problem,
you tiny little man?
Hey, Dalton?
MOREDOCK:
Ms. Paxton.
Huh?
Have you been drinking?
No, no, no, no,
not at all.
I'm just exhausted,
Your Honor.
I was up all night
preparing.
What? Drinks?
PAXTON: No.
I was going over
Detective Benson's
testimony with her.
Ask her.
Bailiff? Get Detective
Benson over here.
And have her bring
a breathalyzer.
Where would you like me
to administer the test,
Your Honor?
Right at the Defense table?
Guess again.
Unfortunately,
the Prosecution.
BENSON: No.
You can't be serious.
Could you please
clear this up, Olivia?
They're trying to
ruin my reputation.
I have no desire to ruin
your reputation, Counselor.
Detective,
were you drinking with
Ms. Paxton last night?
I wasn't drinking.
Was she?
I saw her consume
two drinks.
So you did lie to me.
How many drinks
did you have after
Detective Benson left?
I object to this
line of questioning,
Your Honor.
MOREDOCK: Then blow.
No. I can attest,
as an officer
of this court,
that I am not
intoxicated.
Sonya, your eyes are
bloodshot and watery.
Your speech is slurred,
and you stink of booze.
Now blow!
I thought
you were my friend.
Just do it.
Don't do this
to me, Olivia.
Please don't
do this to me.
You did this
to yourself, Sonya.
Now, blow.
(SlGHS)
(BLOWlNG)
I got it.
MOREDOCK:
Bring it up here.
Let me see.
I saw it, Your Honor.
It's 0.07.
It's legally sober.
I was hoping
for a zero.
It's still climbing.
MOREDOCK: For the record,
your blood level
count is 0.082.
That's residual
from last night.
I'm fine, Your Honor.
I am ready to proceed.
MOREDOCK: Counselor,
you have a problem.
I'm ordering you removed
from this courtroom.
Detective.
Let's go.
I've got it.
Then go.
A shocking development
in the trial of
Dalton Rindell
for the murder
of abortion doctor
Audrey Hale.
A mistrial
was declared after a
crime scene recreation,
concocted
by the Prosecution,
was shown to the jury
with the defendant's image
Photoshopped onto it.
BENSON: I hope you know that
you're the luckiest man alive.
You think?
No matter
how long I live,
no matter what I do
with the rest of my life,
my obituary is
already written.
"Dalton Rindell,
the man who killed
Audrey Hale."
It's still
all about you.
I've destroyed
so many lives.
You're finally
owning up to it?
You know, you can never
serve time for this,
no matter what
you tell me.
So why don't you
get it off your chest?
Tell me.
After seeing
all the evidence,
after watching
that Prosecutor
falling down drunk,
ruining her own career,
it was like looking
in the mirror.
(SOBBlNG)
I finally realized I had
done it. I killed her.
Why?
I swear I don't know.
I swear to God.
Oh, I had no reason
to hurt her.
My doctor told me that
in an alcoholic blackout,
maybe I might
have known exactly
what I was doing.
But the memory
never formed.
And it never will.
Maybe the stress from
my business going
under made me snap,
and I took it
out on her.
I don't know.
How am I supposed
to live with that?
I don't know.
Dalton. Dalton, can you
give me a statement
for The Ledger, please?
FEMALE REPORTER: Do you
have anything to say
to the victim's family?
Dalton, how does it feel
to get away with murder?
MALE REPORTER: Dalton,
you can't walk away.
Well, at least he walked
because of the video
mix-up, and not Paxton's...
I don't have to mention
the irony of that.
SVU was too much
for her.
The pressure must have
triggered her drinking.
Explains why she was
such a control freak.
White-knuckle drunk just
hanging on by a thread.
What a hypocrite.
She was a good lawyer
with a bad problem.
I definitely saw a lot
of my mother in her.
Well, her career's over.
There's no way
she's coming back from this.
I mean, she's
a walking cluster...
I couldn't have
said it better.
Though I wouldn't
have censored myself.
I just wanted to say
that it's been an honor
working with you.
You taking some
personal time?
No, no, no, no.
I'm actually on my way
to court-ordered rehab.
(EXHALES)
I know that
there is no way
that you will ever
be able to forgive me.
But I intend
to make amends
to each and every
one of you.
I'm sorry.