This is MediaBreak. You give us three
minutes and we'll give you the world.
Good morning. I'm Casey Wong.
with Jesse Perkins.
Top story: Pretoria.
The threat of nuclear confrontation
in South Africa escalated today
when the ruling white military
government of that city state
unveiled a French-made neutron bomb
and affirmed its willingness to use the
device as the city's last line of defence.
The president's first press conference
from the Star Wars Peace Platform
got off to a shaky start when power failed.
causing a brief period of weightlessness
for the visiting president and his staff.
We'll be back in a moment.
Is it time for that big operation?
This may be the most important
decision of your life.
So come down. And talk to
one of our qualified surgeons.
here at the Family Heart Center.
We feature the complete Jarvik line.
Series Seven Sports Heart by Jensen.
Yamaha.
You pick the heart.
Extended warranties. Financing.
Qualifies for health-tax credit.
And remember: we care.
Three dead police officers.
one critically injured.
Police union leaders blame
Omni Consumer Products. OCP.
a firm which has entered
into a contract with the city
to fund and run the Detroit
Metropolitan Police Department.
Dick Jones. Division president. OCP.
Every policeman knows there are
certain risks that come with the territory.
Any cop'll tell you: "If you can't stand
the heat. Stay out of the kitchen. "
Although seriously wounded.
Officer Frank Frederickson escaped
and identified this man.
Clarence Boddicker. Unofficial
crime boss of Old Detroit.
now sought in connection with
the deaths of 31 police officers.
Today he's at large. While doctors
at Henry Ford Memorial Hospital
fight to save the life of Officer
Frank Frederickson. Good luck. Frank.
DETROIT
POLICE PRECINCT: METRO WEST
Attempted murder?
It's not like he killed someone.
This is a violation
of my client's civil rights.
Make it "aggravated assault"
and I can make bail, in cash, now.
Listen, pal. Your client's a scumbag.
You are a scumbag.
Scumbags see the judge
on Monday morning.
Now get out of my police station
and take laughing boy with you!
Hi.
Murphy, transferring in from Metro South.
- Nice precinct.
- Yeah, pretty good.
We work for a living down here, Murphy.
Get your armour and suit up.
Not now. Get a cup of coffee.
- Stark, any word on Frederickson?
- They're still listing him as critical.
His wife must be going out of her mind.
- Murphy, huh?
- Yeah, that's me. Hi.
- What brings you to this paradise?
- Beats me.
I think OCP's moving
a lot of new guys here.
Omni Consumer Products.
What a bunch of morons.
They're gonna manage
this department right into the ground.
- Where are you from?
- Metro South.
Welcome to hell.
Murphy! They cut ten guys loose
over on the East Side.
You try to get back up
when you're in a jam.
Yeah, try to get a medevac
after you've been jammed.
I'll tell you what we should do.
We should strike. Fuck 'em.
The funeral's tomorrow.
The department requests
all officers not on duty to attend.
Any donations for the family
may be given to Cecil, as usual.
I don't wanna hear
any more talk about strike.
We're not plumbers.
We're police officers.
And police officers don't strike.
Murphy, front and centre.
Hello, tiger.
Lewis! Come here when you've finished
fuckin' around with your suspect.
This guy's gonna be your new partner.
Murphy, meet Lewis.
Show him the neighbourhood.
- Glad to know you, Murphy.
- Pretty neat.
I better drive until you know
your way around.
I usually drive when I'm
breaking in a new partner.
Do you really think the Old Man is gonna
be there? Why would they invite us?
All division heads are bringing
their support teams. It's big.
They must be green-lighting Delta City.
Are you kidding?
They never work ahead of schedule.
It's Jones. He's got the 209 series
on line and now he wants to show off.
- That's a tough break, Bob.
- What? What?
When ED-209 ran into serious delays
and cost overruns,
the Old Man ordered a backup plan.
Probably just to light a fire
under Jones's ass.
- Old Bob here gets the assignment.
- Yeah.
Nobody in Security Concepts
takes it seriously.
It's a better plan. Fuckin' Jones.
I'd go to the Old Man if I could.
Don't mess with Jones.
He'll make sushi out of you.
- Be careful. I hear Jones is a real shark.
- Who asked you, twerp?
What about this police thing?
Their union's been bitching since
we took over. The usual nonsense.
We'll turn things around.
Good. Very good. Let's get started.
My friends,
I've had this dream...
for more than a decade now.
A dream which I've invited
you all to share with me.
In six months we begin construction...
of Delta City,
where Old Detroit now stands.
Old Detroit has a cancer.
The cancer is crime,
and it must be cut out
before we employ the two million
workers that will revive this city.
Yes.
Shifts in the tax structure have created
an economy ideal for corporate growth.
But community services, in this case,
law enforcement, have suffered.
I think it's time we gave something back.
Dick.
Take a close look at
the track record of this company.
You'll see that we have
gambled in markets
traditionally regarded as nonprofit.
Hospitals, prisons, space exploration.
I say good business is where you find it.
As you know, we have a contract with
the city to run local law enforcement.
But at Security Concepts,
we believe an efficient police force
is only part of the solution.
No. We need something more.
We need a 24-hour-a-day police officer.
A cop who doesn't need to eat or sleep.
A cop with superior firepower,
and the reflexes to use it.
Fellow executives,
it gives me great pleasure to introduce
you to the future of law enforcement.
ED-209.
The Enforcement Droid, series 209,
is a self-sufficient
law-enforcement robot.
209 is programmed for urban pacification,
but that is only the beginning.
After a successful
tour of duty in Old Detroit,
we can expect 209 to become the hot
military product for the next decade.
- Dr McNamara.
- We'll need an arrest subject.
- Mr Kinney, would you give us a hand?
- Yes, sir.
Mr Kinney is going to help us simulate
a typical arrest and disarming procedure.
Mr Kinney, use your gun
in a threatening manner.
- Point it at ED-209.
- Yes, sir.
Please put down your weapon.
You have 20 seconds to comply.
I think you'd better do
what he says, Mr Kinney.
You now have 15 seconds to comply.
You are in direct violation
of Penal Code 113, section nine.
You now have five seconds to comply.
Four, three,
two, one.
I am now authorised
to use physical force.
Somebody wanna call a goddamn
paramedic? Let's go, Johnson.
Did you pull the plug on this thing?
Don't touch him. Don't touch him!
- He didn't hear the gun drop.
- He didn't hear it?
Dick, I'm very disappointed.
I'm sure it's only a glitch.
A temporary setback.
You call this a glitch?
We begin construction in six months.
Your "setback" could cost us
$50 million in interest payments alone.
Not necessarily. Perhaps you know
of the RoboCop programme,
developed by myself at Security Concepts
as a contingency against this?
- Thank you, Mr Morton. I'm sure this...
- Now wait a minute.
Dick!
Maybe what we need here
is a fresh perspective.
Tell me about your plan.
How long will it take?
We're ready to go. We've restructured the
police department with prime candidates.
I'm confident we can go
to prototype within 90 days.
Good. Get your staff together. I'll
expect a full presentation in 20 minutes.
Thank you, sir.
Yes! That's how it's done in the big
leagues. You see an opening and go for it.
Watch your back, Bob.
Jones is gonna come looking for you.
Fuck Jones. He fumbled the ball
and I was there to pick it up.
Too bad about Kinney, huh?
That's life in the big city.
- When do we start?
- As soon as some schmuck volunteers.
Pretty fancy moves, Murphy.
Yeah, well, my son Jimmy
watches this cop show, TJ Lazer.
This Lazer does this when he takes down
a bad guy. So my kid thinks a good cop...
And you don't wanna disappoint him.
Yeah, well, role models can
be very important to a boy.
OK, OK, I get a kick out of it.
All units. All units. Sector nine.
Well, that's...
Why don't you drive?
Suspects are armed
and considered dangerous.
Shit!
I don't believe it!
You burnt the fuckin' money!
I had to blow the door!
What do you want?
It's as good as marked, you asshole!
You stupid, stupid asshole!
- Clarence!
- What do you want?
We got a cop on our tail.
- Come on, man. Speed it up.
- Move it!
- Hey, this crate won't outrun a cop's!
- Slow down, then.
- Are you crazy, man?
- Shut the fuck up and do it! Just do it!
Central, this is 154. We are in pursuit
of suspect. Request backup.
Roger. 154.
- Backup currently unavailable.
- Give me your piece.
Backup ETA. 15 minutes.
- Bobby, get the door. Everybody load up.
- All right, let's go. Come on!
- OK.
- All right, here we go.
Now!
- What the fuck? Where did he go?
- Emil!
Here! He's up here!
Get 'em!
- Shit, Clarence. My leg.
- Leon, pick him up.
- Ready?
- No. Hang on.
Bobby.
- Can you fly, Bobby?
- Clarence, no.
Hit it!
No!
This is unit 154. We located that van
by the Old Mill in sector 3D.
- Where's that backup?
- Still unavailable.
- Oh, man!
- 20 minutes before units can arrive.
Well, you call it.
- Let's do it.
- OK.
Go.
Stay in touch.
Freeze.
OK, let's see those hands. Nice and easy.
Sure. Mind if I...
zip this up?
- We rob banks but never keep the money.
- Takes money to make money.
We steal money to buy coke, then sell
the coke to make even more money.
- Capital investment.
- Why bother making it? Let's just steal it.
Best way to steal money
is free enterprise.
- Smoke?
- No. You know, those things'll kill ya.
Yeah.
Do you wanna live for ever?
Hey. Don't move.
Go ahead and do it.
Dead or alive, you're coming with me.
Lewis? Lewis!
Lewis, I got a situation here.
OK, tough guy, get up. Turn around.
Spread your legs. That's right.
Lewis. Where are you? You all right?
Put your hands on your head.
Lewis?
Why don't you let us
take over from here, Emil?
- Your ass is mine.
- No.
Not yet it ain't.
Well, what have we here?
You a good cop, hotshot?
Sure you are.
Why, you gotta be some kinda great cop.
Come in here all by yourself.
Where's your partner?
Well, guys. The other one was upstairs.
She was sweet.
I took her out.
I bet that really pisses you off.
You probably don't think
I'm a very nice guy. Do you?
Buddy, I think you're slime.
See, I got this problem.
Cops don't like me.
So I don't like cops.
Well, give the man a hand.
He's all yours.
- All right, look out.
- Turn around, man.
Hey, brave boy! Hey, over here!
- I'm outta ammo.
- Me too.
Hey, Clarence, he's still alive.
Does it hurt? Does it hurt?
OK. Fun's over.
OK, let's get outta here.
Good night, sweet prince.
Hey, wait up, wait up, wait up.
Murphy.
Let's get him over here.
- The ventilator. Get the mask.
- Get him into OR4.
Easy, easy.
Slow down now. Slow down.
OK, get the door.
- Let me get pressure.
- Good. Mask him.
Got a pressure of 60 Pel.
We're gonna have to intubate this guy.
OK. We got it in. Breath sounds?
- You're in.
- Other side.
- OK. Let's get the MAST trousers out.
- Get the clothes off.
Prep him for a central line.
Let's get some blood drawn.
Type and crossing, six units.
- His pressure's dropping.
- OK.
I've got a central line in.
Get the pressure back.
Can you do that, Dad?
I really have to tell you something.
I've got 40 Pel.
- Michelle, we're flat here.
- V-fib.
OK, we gotta shock him.
Let's go ahead and
blow up the MAST trousers.
Stand clear.
Coarse V-fib. Let's shock him again.
Clear.
- Flatline.
- Let's go. Intracardiac epinephrine.
- Let's go.
- OK.
- All right, it's in.
- There's no pulse.
All right. Let's shock
the flatline, then let's quit.
Everybody, clear!
All right, I think that's all we can do.
Let's call it. What's the time?
- It's sharp.
- Yeah, it's startin' to roll.
Ah... shit!
Bring in the LED.
Lock it down.
- He's on.
- What's the story?
We were able to save the left arm.
What? I thought we agreed on total
body prosthesis. Lose the arm, OK?
Jesus, Morton.
- Can he understand me?
- Doesn't matter. We'll blank his memory.
I think we should lose the arm.
What do you think?
He signed release forms when
he joined the force. He's legally dead.
We can do pretty much what we want to.
Lose the arm.
Shut him down. Prep him for surgery.
The entire outer skin will be like this.
It's titanium, laminated with Kevlar.
Go ahead. Shake his hand.
Do you come here often?
Ow! God! He's got a helluva grip.
It's 400 foot-pounds.
He could crush every bone in your hand.
All right, attach it to his shoulder.
I like that.
You are gonna be a bad motherfucker.
Hey, look! Look! He's watching us!
Hi! Happy New Year.
This is for you.
Happy New Year.
We get the best of both worlds. The
fastest reflexes technology has to offer.
Computer-assisted memory.
A lifetime of on-the-street
law-enforcement programming.
It is my great pleasure to present to you...
RoboCop.
Come on, come on.
It's for you.
Go, Robo.
I'm what you call a repeat offender.
I repeat, I will offend again.
I get my orders from a higher source.
Shut up, asshole.
- Bring him in through the side door.
- A cell has been set up for us.
- What's goin' on here?
- Who is this guy?
- Sergeant Reed.
- What's this about?
It's about official OCP business.
So please, get lost.
- We've got four or five days...
- This is bullshit!
I take my orders from...
What is this shit?
When you are at rest,
you will sit in the chair.
Yes, I understand.
- What about tracking?
- We check his location with one of these.
- How does he eat?
- His digestive system is very simple.
This processor dispenses a rudimentary
paste that sustains his organic systems.
Tastes like baby food.
Knock yourself out.
- OK, let's start with tracking.
- Give me a grid.
Target.
Now follow.
Voice-stress analyser.
One, two, three.
Record.
- Now play back.
- Bring it up 50%.
Now play back.
- He's ready.
- We got it.
Clear out.
What are your prime directives?
Serve the public trust.
Protect the innocent. Uphold the law.
That's good. That's very good.
I fuckin' love that guy.
- It's Supercop.
- Look at that fuckin' gun.
Shit.
- This guy is really good.
- He's not a guy, he's a machine.
What are they gonna do? Replace us?
Come on.
Reed! He needs a car.
Thank you.
Sure. Any time.
Oh, yeah. Go get 'em, boy.
I'd buy that for a dollar.
- Will there be anything else, sir?
- Empty the register. Put it in the bag.
Excuse me?
Give me your money, all of it,
and don't fuck with me!
Now, move!
Open the safe, pops.
- Open the goddamn safe!
- We don't have a safe.
Shit. There's your goddamn safe!
Open the son of a bitch!
I'll count to three and you better
open that son of a bitch. Come on!
I'm gonna blow her brains out.
- I'll open the safe.
- Good boy.
You better open that
on the count of three. One, two...
Fuck me.
Drop the gun.
You are under arrest.
Fuck me! Fuck me! Fuck me!
Fuck me!
Thank you for your cooperation.
Good night.
I'll buy that for a dollar!
Don't touch me!
- We don't want your money!
- We want you!
Take it easy! We're not gonna hurt you!
- There's too much hair.
- I know. Give her a haircut.
Hey! There's more hair... down there!
No!
Let the woman go.
You are under arrest.
Shit.
You better back up, pal,
cos he's gonna kill her!
He's gonna kill her!
Your move, creep.
It's OK!
Oh, God, I was so scared.
Thank you! Thank you!
Madam, you have suffered
an emotional shock.
I will notify a rape crisis centre.
All units. Close intersection...
I don't care. Get those men
by the stairs now. Hit it!
Terrorism has never been a factor
in city politics before.
But today, former city councilman
Ron Miller entered city hall with a gun.
He's now on the second floor, holding
Mayor Gibson and his staff hostage.
We do believe that Miller
has killed one of the hostages.
- Lieutenant, what's next?
- We wait. Terrorism is a tricky business.
Massive and immediate retaliation
is the best policy but...
- Excuse us.
- Where are you goin'?
Hey, let's have some crowd control.
Get these people back.
- Where do you think you're goin'?
- Keep him talking.
OK, Miller. Don't hurt the mayor.
We'll give you whatever you want.
First, don't fuck with me.
I'm a desperate man.
And second,
I want some fresh coffee!
And third, I want a recount.
And no matter how it turns out,
I want my old job back.
- OK.
- And I want a bigger office.
And I want a new car.
And I want the city to pay for it all!
What kind of car. Miller?
Something with reclining leather seats
that goes fast and gets shitty gas mileage.
How about the... 6000 SUX?
Yeah.
OK, sure.
What about cruise control?
Does it come with that?
No problem, Miller. Let the mayor go,
we'll even throw in a Blaupunkt.
Lieutenant, don't jerk me off!
When people jerk me off, I kill 'em.
Do you wanna see?
Get up, Your Honour. Get up.
Your public wants to see you.
Nobody ever takes me seriously.
Well, get serious now
and kiss the mayor's ass goodbye.
RoboCop. Who is he? What is he?
Where does he come from?
He is OCP's newest soldier
in their crime-management programme.
OCP spokesmen claim
the fearless machine
has crooks on the run in Old Detroit.
Today. Kids at Lee lacocca
Elementary School got to meet in person
what their parents only
read about in comic books.
Robo. Excuse me. Any special message
for all the kids watching at home?
Stay out of trouble.
More fighting in the Mexican crisis when
American troops participated in a raid
with Mexican nationals against
rebel rocket positions in Acapulco.
Now this.
Red alert. Red alert. Red alert.
- You crossed my line of death.
- Then dismantle your MX stockpile.
Pakistan is threatening my border.
That's it. Buster.
No more military aid.
"Nukem".
Get them before they get you.
Today labour leaders agreed to sanction
construction of OCP's Delta City.
creating an estimated
one million new jobs.
despite questions about worker safety
in dangerous Old Detroit.
Robert Morton. Vice President.
Security Concepts. OCP.
I can't comment on Delta City.
It's not my division. But I will say this.
At Security Concepts. We're projecting
the end of crime in Old Detroit in 40 days.
There's a new guy in town.
His name's RoboCop.
Hey, hey, Bobby boy.
Vice president. Congratulations.
- Handball Tuesday night?
- Bill, I'd love to, but I got a date.
Couple of models coming to my place.
I'd buy that for a dollar.
Welcome to the club, Bob.
You're making a real name for yourself
in Security Concepts with RoboCop.
- We try.
- Let me in on the bottom line, pal.
I hear Jones was plenty pissed.
He's got this killer rep,
but it's a smokescreen.
He's lost his teeth. The guy's a pussy.
Are we talkin' about
the same Dick Jones?
He's old, we're young.
And that's life.
I gotta go.
I got a meeting.
Congratulations, Bob.
Thanks.
I remember when I was
a young executive for this company.
I used to call the Old Man funny names.
"Iron butt."
"Boner."
Once I even called him...
"asshole".
But there was always respect.
I always knew where the line was drawn.
And you just stepped over it, buddy boy.
You've insulted me, and you've insulted
this company with your bastard creation.
I had a guaranteed
military sale with ED-209.
Renovation programme.
Spare parts for 25 years.
Who cares if it worked or not?
The Old Man thought
it was pretty important... Dick.
You know,
he's a sweet old man.
And he means well.
But he's not gonna live for ever.
And I'm number two around here.
Pretty simple math, huh, Bob?
You just...
fucked with the wrong guy.
You're out of your fuckin' mind.
You better pray that that unholy
monster of yours doesn't screw up.
- You hungry?
- No, thanks.
Goddamn rebels blew up
the airport in Acapulco.
Great. We were going there next week.
Hey, what was that?
Hey, look. Bucket boy's on line.
Hey. Hey, halt.
Stop! Wait a minute!
- What the hell's going on?
- I don't know. He just left.
Just left?
Roosevelt!
Rosie, we got a problem.
Out of the way.
Take a look at this.
Shit. Call Bob Morton.
Jerry, book him.
I'll catch up with you later.
Hello. I haven't really had
a chance to introduce myself.
I'm Anne Lewis.
Do you have a name?
How can I help you, Officer Lewis?
That's not really what I meant.
Don't you have a name?
Murphy. It's you.
- You really don't remember me, do you?
- Excuse me.
I have to go. Somewhere
there is a crime happening.
Stop!
- What did you talk to him about?
- Nothing.
- Shit.
Stop! Hey, you there, stop!
You're in a lot of trouble, Officer.
Come on.
I was assured full cooperation
by this precinct.
If it gets screwed up by your grunts,
I'll have your job.
- What's the update?
- It's hard to be 100%.
This system wasn't designed
for a somatic response.
He had a dream. A dream.
- This cop saw fit to question him.
- I didn't question him.
- I asked him his name. He didn't know.
- Oh, great.
Let me make it real clear for you.
He doesn't have a name.
He's got a program. He's product.
- Is that clear?
- Sure.
- I say pull him in, run a systems check.
- Take a week.
You wanna take him off line because
he had a dream? Are you kidding?
Let's get out of here.
Listen, Reed. Try to keep
one thing in mind.
This project doesn't concern cops.
It's classified. It's OCP.
Got it, mister?
- Yeah, I got it.
- Good.
Sorry, Sarge. I fucked up.
Forget it, kid.
This guy's a serious asshole.
Give me all your money, bookworm,
or I blow your brains out.
Now fill it up on number seven.
Don't do nothin' stupid, man.
I'm a good shot.
I could hit you in the eye from here.
Hey, man? What you readin' in there?
You a college boy or somethin'? Huh?
I bet you think you're pretty smart, huh?
Think you could outsmart a bullet?
What do you say we find out? Huh?
I'm talkin' to you!
What do you say? Huh? Huh?
Drop it.
Dead or alive, you are coming with me.
I know you.
You're dead.
We killed you.
We killed you!
You're dead. We killed you.
Who are you?
- Can I help you, sir?
- No.
What is it exactly that you want?
Hey! You can't enter here.
Wait a second. Hey, just a minute.
This is a restricted area.
Murphy. It's you.
Welcome. Shopper. Let's take
a stroll through your new home.
This is a one-family house. Situated
near schools and shopping centres.
This progressive development
has a growth factor of seven.
Wow!
Can you do that, Dad?
It doesn't matter
who cooks in your family.
because this kitchen by Food Concepts
makes everything...
Dad.
Come on, Dad. Come on, Dad.
I really have to tell you something.
I love you.
Hey. Have you thought it all over?
Why not make me an offer?
Where is Clarence Boddicker?
OK.
Let's talk.
You son of a bitch.
There's just something
about the way it sounds.
"Vice president."
It just turns me on.
God, you girls are so great.
I love to be with intelligent women.
Smart is so sexy.
I know. Sometimes I could
just think of something,
and it could just get me so horny.
Yeah, well, a mind
is a terrible thing to waste.
I get bored so easily.
Yeah. And you need
lots of stimulation, Bobby.
Yes, I do.
- Don't move.
- I won't.
- Bob...
- What?
- Bob, save some for me.
- Don't worry.
Must be the champagne. Stay here.
How ya doin'?
Bitches, leave.
Gee, Bobby. Bye.
You gonna call me?
What the fuck are you doing?
Do you know who I am? If you think
you're gonna get away with this...
Goddamn it!
Stop! I'll give you anything you want!
Just please don't kill me, all right?
Hello. Buddy boy. Dick Jones here.
I guess you're on your knees about now.
begging for your life.
Pathetic. You don't feel
so cocky now. Do you. Bob?
Whatever he's payin' you,
I'll double it right now.
You know what the tragedy is here. Bob?
We could have been friends.
But you wouldn't go through
proper channels.
You went over my head.
That hurt.
But life goes on. It's an old story.
the fight for love and glory. Huh. Bob?
It helps if you think of it as a game. Bob.
Every game has a winner... and a loser.
I'm cashing you out. Bob.
I don't wanna pay that, Sal.
I don't give a shit what you wanna pay.
I set the prices here.
Listen, pal. Maybe you haven't heard.
I'm the guy in Old Detroit.
You want space in my marketplace?
You're gonna have to give me
a volume discount.
I'm not into discounts.
Joe, show the man what
we brought him for Christmas.
Think about it, chum.
Good business is where you find it.
OK, let me try to
put this in perspective.
You killed a bunch of cops.
The word is you've got a lot
of heavy connections downtown,
and you make a lot of
my friends nervous.
A lot of people
would love to see a guy like me
and a guy like you out of business.
I don't know. I don't know.
Maybe I'm just not making myself clear.
I don't wanna fuck with you, Sal.
But I got the connections.
I got the sales organisation.
I got the muscle to shove enough of
this factory so far up your stupid wop ass
that you'll shit snow for a year.
Frankie, blow this cocksucker's head off.
Ooh, guns, guns, guns.
Come on, Sal!
The Tigers are playin'... tonight.
I never miss a game.
Just kidding.
Go!
Go.
Come quietly or there will be trouble.
Oh, fuck you.
Clarence Boddicker,
you are under arrest.
You have the right to remain silent.
Fuck you.
Hey, wait a minute. Wait a minute!
I'm protected.
I've got protection!
- You have the right to an attorney.
- What is this shit?
Goddamn it. Goddamn it!
Listen to me!
Listen to me, you fuck!
There's another guy.
He's OCP. He's the senior president.
Anything you say
may be used against you.
It's Dick Jones!
Don't you get it, you cocksucker?
I work for Dick Jones!
Dick Jones!
He's the number two guy at OCP.
OCP runs the cops.
You're a cop.
Cop.
Yes, I am a cop.
- I don't like it either, but listen...
- You listen to me, you asshole!
You're talking about shutting down
a major metropolitan police force!
Without cops, this city
would tear itself apart!
The union thinks you should know
we had a strike vote.
- We lost five guys last week.
- We're gettin' creamed out there.
- Book him.
- What's the charge?
He's a cop killer.
Shit.
Just give me my fuckin' phone call.
I understand. The lawyers'll
have you out in 24 hours.
Just don't say anything else.
Jesus, you really screwed up.
Don't you get it?
I work for Dick Jones!
Dick Jones!
He runs OCP.
OCP runs the cops.
Come in, Officer. I don't usually
see anyone without an appointment.
- In your case, I'll make an exception.
- You are under arrest.
- On what charge?
- Aiding and abetting a known felon.
Sounds like I'm in a lot of trouble.
- You'd better take me in.
- I will.
What's the matter, Officer?
I'll tell you what's the matter.
It's a little insurance policy
called Directive 4.
My little contribution
to your psychological profile.
Any attempt to arrest a senior officer
of OCP results in shutdown.
What did you think?
That you were an ordinary police officer?
You're our product. And we can't have
our products turning against us, can we?
Still a little fight left in you.
Maybe you'd like to meet a friend of mine.
I had to kill Bob Morton
because he made a mistake.
Now it's time to erase that mistake.
Put Lieutenant Hedgecock on the line.
There's trouble in the tower.
Prepare to fire.
- Wait a second!
- He's a cop, for God's sake!
- You can't do that!
- We have orders to destroy it.
- Aw, shit!
- You're maniacs!
Fire at will!
Move in!
Murphy! Murphy, it's me.
Lewis.
Lieutenant, level three!
He's on level three!
Open fire!
It's back.
Big is back. Because bigger is better.
Good evening. I'm Jesse Perkins.
with Casey Wong.
Top story: Santa Barbara.
10.000 acres of wooded residential land
were scorched in an instant
when a laser cannon aboard
the Strategic Defense Peace Platform
misfired today during
routine startup tests. Casey?
It was a day of mourning for the families
of 113 people known dead at this hour.
among them two former United States
presidents who had retired in the area.
A day of mourning for a country.
Police union representatives and OCP
continue negotiations today
in hopes of averting
a city-wide strike by police.
scheduled to begin tomorrow at midnight.
Justin Ballard-Watkins has more.
They're still on duty.
but what about tomorrow?
That's what we asked people in
the crime-plagued Lexington area.
They're public servants. They got job
security. They're not supposed to strike.
It's a free society.
Except there ain't nothin' free.
because there's no guarantees.
You're on your own.
It's the law of the jungle.
Hiya... Barbara.
Listen, I'm here to see Dick Jones.
But when I'm done,
I've got some free time.
Maybe you could... fit me in.
He's expecting you, Mr Boddicker.
You can keep the gum.
Hey, Dickie boy. How's tricks?
- That thing is still alive.
- I don't know what you're talking about.
The officer who arrested you.
The one you spilled your guts to.
Take a look at my face, Dick.
He was trying to kill me.
He's a cyborg, you idiot!
He recorded every word you said.
His memory is admissible as evidence.
You involved me.
You're gonna have to kill it.
Well, listen, chief.
Your company built the fucking thing.
Now I gotta deal with it?
I don't have time for this bullshit.
Suit yourself. But Delta City
begins construction in two months.
That's two million workers
living in trailers.
That means drugs, gambling, prostitution.
Virgin territory for the man
who knows how to open up new markets.
One man could control it all, Clarence.
Well, I guess we're gonna
be friends after all,
Richard.
Destroy it.
We're gonna need some major fire power.
You got access to military weaponry?
We practically are the military.
- Did you bring the gun?
- The precinct was deserted.
Half the force didn't
show up for work today.
Everyone else walks out at midnight.
I guess we're on strike.
I wasn't sure what you needed.
I sort of grabbed things.
Your gun.
You asked for this.
I brought you some food.
No, thank you. I'm not hungry.
You may not like what
you're going to see.
It's really good to see you again, Murphy.
Murphy had a wife and son.
What happened to them?
Well, after the funeral, she moved away.
Where did they go?
She thought you were dead.
She started over again.
I can feel them.
But I can't remember them.
Leave me alone.
Happy birthday. Dave.
She's from me.
Well. Hey. Can I have you both?
Sure! We've had our shots.
I'd buy that for a dollar.
Hey, Emil. How's the "Grey Bar Hotel"?
Not bad. They let me keep the shirt.
And nobody popped my cherry.
Emil, how you doin', man?
Good to see you.
Hey, hey! First they
let me out of jail for free.
Then what do I find in the prison
parking lot but a brand new 6000 SUX?
Still got the factory sticker on it.
Hey, Clarence. Joey's got
a car just like yours, man.
Yo, Clarence.
What do you think, buddy?
What have you got there, Clarence, huh?
Whoa, a new toy! Can I play?
- Watch this.
- Wait a minute. Clarence. Clarence!
Aw, shit!
- Fuck!
- Nice car, Joe.
Let me try that.
The Cobra Assault Cannon.
State-of-the-art bang-bang.
I like it!
- Give it up, faggot. Let a man do this.
- Get your own!
Come on!
Do it, Emil!
Heads up, you guys.
He's in the steel mill. Let's go.
All right, cut the horseshit!
We're movin' out!
- Come on, Emil. Get your ass in the van.
- Come on, lard-ass. Let's move it.
I'll get you, faggot!
What are you doing?
My targeting system is a little messed up.
Can I help you?
Aim for me.
- Are you locked in now?
- Yes.
A little more to the left.
Here.
- I figure that's dead on.
- Thank you.
Come on, man, let's smoke 'em.
The wrecking crew is here!
Where is that metallic motherfucker?
Zip it up, man.
Nothin' fancy. Just kill him.
Emil! In the van.
- You should get out of here now.
- Hey, we're partners.
Get the car.
- Damn it. Shit.
- Looking for me?
Cut him off!
Go on, cut him off!
Go! Go!
OK! Now I gotcha!
Shit.
- Help me.
- Don't touch me, man!
Help me.
Shit.
- Bye-bye, baby.
- Clarence!
OK. I give up.
- I'm not arresting you any more.
- Hey, hey. Now wait a second.
Wait a minute. You're taking this
kinda personal, aren't you?
Come on, man.
You're making me nervous.
You can't do this.
Don't mess around. Hey.
Come on, man, don't get cute.
- Die, you bastard!
- Yeah!
Yeah, all right!
I got him, Clarence!
Sayonara, RoboCop.
Lewis!
Murphy, I'm a mess.
They'll fix you.
They fix everything.
The police strike could work for us.
By the end of the week we can have
ED-209s in place in the city
and expect immediate public support.
I've got one downstairs,
guarding the building now.
You are illegally parked
on private property.
You have 20 seconds
to move your vehicle.
Because this corporation will live up
to the guiding principles of its founder.
Courage. Strength. Conviction.
We will meet each new challenge
with the same aggressive attitude.
- How can we help you, Officer?
- Dick Jones is wanted for murder.
This is absurd. That thing
is a violent mechanical psychopath.
My program will not allow me to act
against an officer of this company.
These are serious charges.
What is your evidence?
I had to kill Bob Morton
because he made a mistake.
Now it's time to erase that mistake.
I had to kill Bob Morton
because he made a mistake.
Now it's time to erase that mistake.
Get up! I want a chopper. Now!
We will walk to the roof very calmly.
I will board the chopper with my hostage.
Anybody tries to stop me,
the old geezer gets it.
Dick, you're fired!
Thank you.
Nice shootin', son. What's your name?
Murphy.