Who's there?
Weasel!
Valerie, forgive me.
Where are her earrings?
Speak!
I lost them, Constable.
- You're lying, Eagle.
- No I'm not.
You can't get out of this.
I'll give you the water torture!
Eagle!
Bend down!
I will jump on your back.
Hurry up.
You brat.
Goodnight, my dark haired girl
Goodnight, and sweet dreams
Grandma, the actors have arrived.
You should be more concerned
that the missionaries are coming.
When?
Today or tomorrow.
One of them will be living with us.
Playing with your earrings, child?
I'm not a child anymore, Grandma.
You see, last night...
At the age of thirteen...
Just like your mother.
I'm warning you...
Get rid of those earrings.
Your mother put them away
on the day she entered the convent.
Your father was a bishop.
As you know, both are now in heaven.
Is there some secret in these earrings?
Oh, no.
I got them at an auction,
with this house, from a certain Constable.
Did you know him?
Grandma, the actors have arrived!
That's just a wedding, dear.
Hedvika is getting married.
Have mercy on her, oh Lord!
Deliver her from thy wrath...
Poor Hedvika.
Why?
She'll be a rich farmer's wife now.
Grandma!
Grandma, a monster!
It can't be.
He's dead, after all.
Who are you talking about, Grandma?
Go and practice your piano scales.
Yes, Grandma.
Beautiful maiden,
It was I who stole your earrings,
and who returned them to your hands again.
My uncle, the Constable,
longs to possess them.
He kilted my father and mother,
and now I fear for you.
In church today,
there will be a sermon for maidens.
Pease leave a dress of yours in the arbour,
so that I can talk to you in disguise.
Your unhappy Eagle
Valerie?
Where are you my child?
It's time to dress for church.
Grandma, may I take
with me a sprig of rosemary?
I, God's servant, a missionary...
I've come before you, dear maidens,
to give you knowledge and God's blessing.
Oh maiden, do you know what you are?
You are an alabaster handshake.
You are an uncut pomegranate.
You are a boat full of leaves,
and an unfurling rosebud.
The coarse hand that touches your breast
would leave an indelible fingerprint.
But I am here with you, dear maiden.
Like your guardian angel, I bow to you.
And I bless with this wine,
your lips, your breast,
your lap.
Amen.
Eagle?
Eagle!
Valerie, is that you?
That monster tortured me.
Valerie, a few words of advice...
- We're in the town square.
- I'm sorry.
Don't look.
Now?
Now!
I'm here.
First of all...
Where is the public poorhouse, dear child?
There, Father.
You have acted out of mercy.
Or do you not like me?
It's not that, Father.
Bless me, please.
You enter first.
Go on, don't worry.
Please.
This is my kingdom.
Valerie?
Come...
Closer...
Look... come closer.
Look.
Oh no!
I know that I don't
appeal to you anymore, my Gracing.
Only five years ago,
when you were last here...
but now!
Go away!
I will lash myself!
Grandma!
Watch!
It's only a dream.
I'm asleep and everything is a dream.
Did he hurt you?
No.
He wants you to love him.
How can I love him when I'm afraid of him?
That's exactly why.
Eagle?
Eagle!
I'm expecting you, Constable.
Damned meddler.
Hands up, burglar, or I'll shoot!
Elsa, it's me.
Don't you remember me?
Richard...
How long since
anybody called me by that name.
Why did you come, Richard?
I missed you so much.
I have never loved another man...
Since the day you seduced me and left.
I'm really sorry about that.
Look at how old you are, Elsa!
You were seventeen then.
I'd give anything
to be young again like you!
Richard, tell me your secret.
I'll give you everything you want.
Give me back this house, Elsa!
Then I'd be robbing Valerie.
You are capable of
deeds much worse than that.
Yes, I'll do it.
Very well, let's make a contra_.
You will be young and beautiful again.
It will happen tonight,
at that miserly farmer's wedding.
You're a devil!
This pearl will save you.
Eagle, where is Valerie?
- I kidnapped her.
- Where?
To the church tower.
Come here, fool!
You will take me there too!
Let us pray.
Hear that?
Three times the bells have tolled,
then gone silent again.
This is excellent.
One enjoys any meal after hardships.
Especially after the things
I saw when I was among the cannibals.
We saved a young black girl.
She was very beautiful.
What happened to her, Father?
We took her to our tent,
and turned her to our faith.
She showed a great talent.
And did she really become a nun?
Unfortunately not.
- We lost her in a certain French port.
- Martha, where's the wine?
One day I'll tell you what happened to her.
She fell into immoral ways,
and sinned against the sixth commandment.
I must give you
a talk on the subject_, dear child.
Thank you, Father.
Your father, the Bishop,
was a sensitive man.
He fainted when prostitutes confessed.
All the beautiful women adored him.
I will tell you more sometime.
And how many children did he have?
You, and a boy named Eagle.
Eagle?
What is it?
I've got a headache. May I go and lie down?
Dinner isn't over yet.
Sorry.
Will you toast with us?
I've never had wine before.
Make an exception today.
In memory of the late Bishop.
Eagle!
I want to talk to you, dear child.
Now, Father?
There is no better time for contemplation.
What beautiful breasts you have.
Please go away, Father!
I want something sweet from you.
You're beautiful!
- You're so lovely!
- Go away!
You're magnificent!
I will resist you, you coward!
You'll be responsible for my death!
What have you done?
The fowl plague is here!
It is done.
My house is yours again.
And now we will wait until midnight.
In the bridal chamber.
Come, come, it is time.
The end of all my dreams.
Come, it's time.
I'm so old.
I will be too.
- Do you love me?
- I do.
Not one drop of blood.
Don't cry.
You look old when you cry.
Valerie!
Eagle!
Eagle...
Valerie!
Please.
- Don't look at me like that.
- What way?
Kneel down!
- Is it too cold?
- No.
I'm like a blind man.
There is an empty guest room at our house.
You can relax there.
He threw me down from the tower.
The bell saved my life.
I heard the strange toll.
I prayed for you.
The fowl plague is our best friend.
If my uncle, the Constable,
doesn't get enough fresh blood,
- He will die a terrible death.
- You're cruel.
He's a hundred years overdue for death.
The monster.
It's nothing, only a man hanging.
Where are we?
Still under your house.
I'm afraid.
Be brave.
Who is in these coffins?
Weasel's victims.
He sucked their blood. Look here.
Grandma!
Valerie!
Excuse me, I wasn't suitably dressed.
This is your room.
I thought that the room was empty.
I came on the midnight coach.
Don't you recognize me?
I'm your second cousin.
Call me Elsa.
Valerie.
And this is... This is my brother.
Eagle.
I have taken your room, it seems.
You may have it.
No, no, you can give me another one.
I'll talk to Grandmother about it.
Your grandmother has gone away, dear child.
Without saying goodbye?
Old people have strange habits.
I hope you will allow me to take her room.
With pleasure.
This room is yours.
Please.
I'd love to ride a horse.
I'll lend you mine.
I'm very tired, I must go to bed.
- You really don't recognize me, Valerie?
- No.
Are you afraid of me?
I'm just joking, my dear.
After all, we've never met before.
My earrings!
Your sister hasn't returned yet?
Where is Valerie? Do you know?
You're handsome when you're angry.
Where is Valerie?
I will tell you on one condition...
You must make love to me.
Never!
Leave this room.
No.
I'm not your guest. You go!
You will regret this.
You will have a glorious death!
Die, maiden! Die!
Eagle! Eagle! Eagle!
Goodnight, my dark haired girl
Goodnight, and sweet dreams
When you awake, my love
Don't reveal your secret
Valerie, you are saved.
I heard everything.
My cousin is in love with you.
Your cousin?
I know. She's really Grandma.
She stole my earrings.
But they were empty.
Here is their secret...
They will protect you
from danger and death.
Beware of Weasel.
Where is he?
He's dying.
Wretch.
He has bewitched you.
Valerie...
I love you.
You can't!
- We are brother and sister.
- But...
- We have the same father.
- That's not true!
Valerie, come back!
Valerie, my father is Weasel!
I will, I won't...
I will!
I'm dying!
Now you know what old age is like.
Valerie? Valerie?
You're wasting your breath.
Valerie's dying.
I sacrificed her for my youth.
You are as lost as I am.
You will fall into the same agony.
Only your granddaughter
could have saved us both.
She has my blood.
How is that?
Her father was the Bishop.
I was the Bishop!
I'm Valerie's father!
You lie.
A drink...
- A drink...
- No!
First tell me how to prolong my youth.
Save Valerie!
Our salvation lies in her blood.
Valerie.
Cursed Valerie.
It's me.
Father!
My child!
Take this.
No, I'm squeamish!
Im only human again, and I must die.
No, you won't die.
You have saved me.
Father!
- Let me go! Please!
- I'm the monster again!
Let me go!
Leave me alone!
No! No! No!
Gracing!
My Gracing!
Your lover sleeps like a log.
Gracing.
Poor Gracing.
I have a certain plan, Elsa.
I need Eagle's heart.
You want to kill Eagle?
His heart will reanimate my daughter
and give her eternal youth.
Richard, place Eagle's heart into my chest.
You are betraying Valerie.
Richard, you will do it.
With a bleeding heart.
Eagle?
Why did I leave you?
Help!
Why are you haunting me, Valerie?
Don't worry, I'm not dead.
Neither are you.
Come on, I'll show you the way out.
The rectory is on the other side, Father.
Sinner, you tempted me to sin!
You will see!
Valerie,
This is goodbye.
You have le_ me,
and the monster has disgraced your lips.
We could have been so happy together...
Believe me Valerie,
Weasel is neither your father nor mine.
You have prolonged his life.
I wanted be your protector,
friend, and husband, but it's too late.
Farewell Valerie, Your Eagle.
Valerie?
Valerie, what happened to you?
Come.
Hedvika.
Hedvika?
Hedvika, what happened to you? Hedvika?
I've wasted away since my wedding.
- You should eat hearty soups.
- No.
No. No. No.
I'm under the spell of a vampire.
Valerie?
Look at my shoulder.
Does it hurt?
Oh no. No.
Do you see anything on my lips?
- No, why?
- Aren't they stained?
You've been eating berries.
I'm not afraid of anything
when you're with me.
I'm so happy.
I've never had a close friend.
Valerie?
Valerie, I'm saved!
- Hedvika.
- See?
The mark is gone.
Your kisses have restored my health.
You're so beautiful.
A witch lives among you!
She tortured me with sinful words.
She rubbed her fawning hips against me.
When she found
that I could resist her seduction,
she threw a noose around my neck.
I thank God that I escaped with my life.
But the witch is hidden among you!
In the name of God, hand her over!
- She should be burned to death!
- That's a lie! Don't believe him!
It's her! The witch!
Don't believe him! I swear he's lying.
Be gone, Satan!
Seize her! To the stake with her!
Confess! You are a witch!
Liar, liar.
Atone for your sins!
Moustachioed comedian!
Eagle, why hast thou forsaken me?
Here she is, she's beautiful...
Our masters, back from their travels,
will give us their hands, their feet,
they'll rest their heads,
and we will kiss them.
Come here, you whore!
Do you want a beating?
Beast!
Drink deeply, Richard.
Disappeared!
Weasel!
I wish for all this magic to end.
Goodnight, my dark haired girl
Goodnight, and sweet dreams
When you awake, my love
Don't reveal your secret
Grandma?
You're back again?
Where would I have gone?
I was in church, my child.
Have the missionaries gone yet?
What missionaries?
What's wrong, my child?
Nothing, Grandma.
Grandma?
There's a strange boy.
It's only one of the
actors who have come to town.
My dearest,
Do not go to the theatre.
Instead,
as soon as possible,
harness horses,
and drive your carriage to the blue lake.
Don't shoot for God's sake!
No!
Miss!
Miss, your grandmother is dying!
Grandma!
Dearest Grandma, how do you feel?
Grandma.
My mirror.
A driverless carriage
has left the courtyard.
That is a good sign.
I never had the
courage to tell you the truth.
Your mother loved a certain young hunter.
And gave birth to his two children.
A boy and a girl.
But Richard, my lover,
insisted that the children were his.
And I, from jealousy,
drove your mother out of this house.
I kept the girl.
That's you.
But Eagle was
stolen away to an unknown place.
I drove out your mother with these words:
"I will only take you in..."
"when the horses
bring you back on their own."
My mother is still alive?
Grandma!
Mother!
My child!
This is your father, my dear.
I know your face from somewhere, Father.
You probably remember it from childhood.
Isn't this only a dream?
If only your grandmother had forgiven me...
Goodnight, my dark haired girl
Don't reveal your secret
Your secret
Goodnight, my dark haired girl
Goodnight, and sweet dreams
When you awake, my love
Don't reveal your secret
Your secret
THE END