Much of our planet still remains unexplored...
for most of it is covered by water.
Every journey below the surface
can reveal something extraordinary.
More than a thousand new species
are discovered here every year.
The ocean is home to eighty percent
of all animal life on Planet Earth.
But today, thriving in this varied world,
sometimes demands the most surprising behaviour.
The shallow seas of the tropics.
This may look like a paradise...
but beneath the surface,
it is an arena for constant life-and-death struggles.
Where not everything is quite as it seems.
A predatory lion-fish...
on the hunt for shrimp and small fish.
With so many places for its prey to hide,
the lion-fish has to be patient...
This shrimp appears tempting...
As the lion-fish closes in,
it fans out its fins to disorientate its prey.
The hunter becomes the hunted...
tricked by one of the shallow sea's
most extraordinary predators.
A clown frog-fish!
On its head, it carries a fishing rod -
a modified dorsal fin,
baited with a lure, easily be mistaken for a shrimp.
But, when the fish stop biting,
it is time to pack the rod away and move on.
And for a frog-fish, that takes time...
Rather than swim, frog-fish walk!
Its fins have in effect become feet...
It may not look pretty,
but what appears to be coral living on its skin
is actually camouflage.
As every good angler knows,
picking the right spot is important.
Jigging the rod sends out pressure waves
to attract the attention of possible prey.
These dragonets are certainly interested.
Almost there...
Hook, line, and sinker...
Like all shallow seas,
the cold waters off the coast of North America,
benefit from the intensity of the sunshine.
Here, that fuels one of the fastest-growing organisms on the planet.
Giant kelp.
Towering forests,
can eventually reach the height of a twelve-story building.
These forests are nurseries for young horn sharks.
As the sun begins to set,
they leave their daytime shelter
and set off into the heart of the kelp forest to find food.
Barely half a meter long, this little shark is extremely vulnerable.
There are monsters here.
A Giant Sea Bass -
weighing over 200 kilograms...
And wolf eels,
with big teeth that can crush little red sea urchins.
But the biggest danger comes from other sharks.
Hound sharks...
and huge Broad-nose Seven-Gills.
In this forest, it pays to keep a low profile...
An Angel Shark...
one of the most deadly sharks in the kelp forest -
and certainly the best camouflaged...
An Angel Shark will lie in wait for days...
But this one, has already attracted too much attention.
It is not welcome here.
Now the coast is clear.
But Angel Sharks hunt around the clock.
Openings for breathing, called spiracles,
blow out sand that helps to cover its body.
The trap is set...
Staying close to the seabed
is a good way to avoid most predators...
Faster than the blink of an eye.
But it's not over yet...
Horn Sharks have a secret weapon.
Sharp spikes
keep them very much off the menu for most.
So this young Horn Shark
can hunt in safety... for now.
Violent winter storms batter these kelp forests.
The plants can be ripped from the sea floor...
and carried away far out to sea.
The open ocean is a vast, feature-less desert...
Even a small piece of drifting kelp
can become valuable.
It is just what these fish have been searching for...
Here, shelter where eggs can be laid unobtrusively is rare.
So they make the most of it.
Each female produces up to a thousand eggs
and the males rush in to fertilise them.
All this activity attracts the attention of blue sharks.
They can travel thousands of miles through the ocean
in search of food.
And they may not have eaten for weeks...
It seems that they are in luck...
But these fish are no easy meal...
They are flying fish!
The blue shark, however, are not here for the fish -
they have come... for the caviar.
But flying fish lay so many eggs,
that the sharks' feasts hardly make an impact...
And in a few months' time,
a new generation will take to the skies.
Floating islands of weed are always attractive to
creatures looking for shelter out in the big blue.
But in today's ocean
they are being replaced by something else.
Plastic...
Twelve million tons of it
end up in the ocean every year.
The deadliest kind are discarded fishing lines and nets.
Each year, it is likely over half a million animals
are ensnared and killed by these 'Ghost nets'.
But some animals are learning
how to take advantage of the plastic rafts...
and use them for shelter, or even as a home.
This male Columbus crab - barely bigger than your thumb nail -
is a castaway.
Clinging to his net,
he may have been drifting on ocean currents for months.
Now fully grown,
he needs to find a partner.
But where?
Certainly not here - alone on the net.
Columbus crabs are not a good swimmers,
so this male is marooned.
Perhaps a passing loggerhead turtle
could be the chance to hitch a lift...
Made it!
But there's more than one passenger here...
A female Columbus crab!
They waste no time in getting acquainted...
and start to mate...
This pair may well stay together for the rest of their lives.
A turtle, after all, makes an excellent home.
In return,
the crabs provide an on-board grooming service.
Finding a partner in the vast ocean,
is not easy...
Dawn in the Sea of Cortez.
Mobula rays.
They gathering here most likely to breed.
No one is sure why they leap,
but the loud splashes certainly seem to attract more rays.
Other creatures however are also listening.
Orca have heard the splashes...
This female specialises in hunting rays.
But today, she is teaching two youngsters
the finer points of mobula-ray hunting.
The rays are fast and can out-manoeuvre an orca.
She knows
she needs to herd the prey into a tight group.
But she can't do that on her own.
It will take teamwork...
and that is today's lesson.
The young orca are quick to catch on.
The rays are surrounded...
They dive.
Only to be forced back up again by the experienced female.
And now, with the exhausted rays trapped against the surface,
she attacks...
And the young ones follow her lead.
This family are the only orca
known to hunt rays like this,
and they are lethally efficient.
But it appears that school is over for today...
For a few battle scarred survivors,
it's a lucky reprieve...
With the orca gone, the rays can resume their courtship...
And they do so in astounding numbers.
Tens of thousands of rays in a single shoal.
Vast areas of our ocean are yet to be explored,
the least known parts of it are its great depths.
Only highly specialised vessels
can take you there.
As you descend, the sunlight rapidly fades.
Two hundred metres down, you enter the twilight zone...
A alien world
inhabited by creatures beyond imagination.
A siphonophore - with a cloak of lethal stinging tentacles.
Siphonophores repeatedly clone themselves
and so grow to immense lengths.
This one measures 45 meters
and is the longest animal ever recorded.
With such deadly predators around,
creatures here go to great lengths to hide...
A glass squid.
Completely transparent - except for its eyes...
and stomach.
So it is extremely difficult to find in the gloom.
Below one thousand meters,
all traces of sunlight have disappeared.
This is the midnight zone.
Catching food in the perpetual darkness is not easy.
The gulper eel.
Its giant, extendable mouth
can engulf prey larger than its own body.
Two miles down,
you finally reach the Ocean floor.
We know more about
the surface of Mars.
The pressure of the water
is three hundred times greater than at the surface...
and it's freezing cold.
Yet amazingly,
there are animals living here...
Muusoctopus robustus, nick-named the Pearl Octopus.
Breeding, in these extreme conditions
poses a particular problem for these animals.
At these low temperatures,
this female's eggs
could take over ten years to develop.
So she travels to a very special place...
This is the largest known gathering of octopus in the world.
She joins twenty thousand other females -
all here to lay their eggs.
Water, heated deep in the earth's crust,
rises through cracks in the seabed.
Raising the temperature to as much as ten degrees Celsius.
A deep sea, thermal spa!
This warmth
significantly speeds up the development of their eggs.
Even so
they will still take nearly two years to hatch.
Once a female is settled,
she won't move from her spot...
not even to feed.
She will constantly tends to her brood -
keeping them clean...
and oxygenating them... with jets of water.
Pearl octopus mothers must surely
be amongst the most devoted.
After almost two years,
the ordeal take its toll.
But the vigil is almost over.
The last of the brood
are gently encouraged to leave.
But this will be a final act.
Like all the mothers here,
this octopus is starved and exhausted.
Her life will soon be over.
But this devotion
means that her offspring are among
the largest and most developed of any octopus -
and have the best chance of survival
in the demanding world of the deep.
We are finding more
of these strange hot springs every year.
In some places, they can be astonishingly violent.
Super-heated water - hot enough to melt lead -
spouts from the sea floor.
Dissolved minerals
condense around them to form towering chimneys
known as hydrothermal vents.
They are home to unique communities of animals
that all rely on the nutrients in the scalding water.
Some suggest that vents like these
could be the places where life on earth first began,
four billion years ago.
And there is now evidence of hydrothermal vents
on the moons of Jupiter and Saturn...
Could they too be supporting life?
Here on earth, the influence of these vents
extends far beyond their chimneys.
The essential nutrients carried in these plumes
can rise all the way to the surface two miles above.
Here, they stimulate the rapid growth of
tiny marine plants...
on an astronomic scale.
This phytoplankton is so abundant,
that it produces half of all the oxygen on earth.
It is also food for a host of minute animals.
Zooplankton.
Together they are the basis of the food-chains
that sustain nearly all life in the ocean.
In the Pacific waters off South America,
they feed anchovy,
that gather here in billions.
This is one of the world's most productive ecosystems.
These South American sea lions are on the hunt...
But the anchovy shoal has already been located...
by the planet's most efficient hunters.
A net over half a mile long encircles the shoal.
It can trap over a million fish.
But the sea lions aren't about to go hungry.
They have learnt to look for holes in the net...
Why waste energy?
When food comes to you as easily as this!
As more and more sealions arrive,
some change their tactics.
They line up on both sides of the net
and wait...
As the net tightens,
the anchovy panic and rush for the surface...
This is the moment the sealions have been waiting for.
It is such an effective way of hunting
that the sealions here are changing their natural behaviour...
and are raiding the fishing nets...
in their thousands.
With the net almost drawn in,
the fishermen beat out a warning signal.
Time is up.
In the confusion
not everyone manages to escape...
The trapped sealions are in danger of being drowned.
Pups are separated from their mothers.
Then at the last minute, the fishermen briefly drop their net...
And the trapped sealions can escape...
But many are not so lucky...
Around the world, millions of animals
are accidently caught and die in fishing nets every day.
And this 'by-catch' - as it is known -
is pushing many species towards extinction.
Animals have evolved in remarkable ways
to the demands of life in the ocean.
But can they now adapt to the new challenge...
living alongside us?
The open ocean is home to some of
the largest and most extraordinary animals on Earth.
But here, off the Canary Islands,
the Planet Earth team are searching
for one of its smaller, and less familiar, residents.
We're looking for a tiny creature called a Columbus crab,
which is only about the size of your thumbnail,
which live on floating objects in the open ocean.
Columbus crabs were once only found on
natural debris like driftwood or seaweed,
but the oceans are changing,
and they have been forced to adapt.
The best place to find Columbus crabs
is in plastic,
because around 90% of the things we see drifting
are plastic.
One of the most common items they find
is discarded fishing gear.
Over a million tons
is left adrift in the ocean each year.
And Columbus crabs
are now making their homes on these unnatural materials.
There's a crab!
Surprisingly,
Columbus crabs are thriving on this new habitat,
but for larger ocean creatures,
these nets can be lethal.
Loggerhead sea turtles are especially vulnerable.
Many times they are very injured
and many times they don't even survive -
it's a sad situation.
As a rule, wildlife filmmakers
observe natural behaviour and do not interfere.
But this is far from natural,
the team feel they must take action.
It seems that the turtle is quite okay.
We'll just finish to cut this plastic
and then we release it.
It's a bittersweet moment,
as this is one of eight turtles they rescued
whilst filming here.
This situation is not natural,
it's something that's being caused by human beings.
Sadly, the crew now
face dilemmas like this on many of their filming expeditions.
Including, when they travelled to the Pacific coast of Chile,
to show how sealions are competing for food
with one of the biggest fisheries on Earth.
Expedition leader Fernando Olivares
takes the team to the fleet.
Diving near fishing nets is extremely dangerous,
so the crew must ensure
they have the full cooperation of the fishermen.
Requesting permission to deploy divers outside the net?
Is that possible?
Yes. Be extremely careful.
Thank you very much, Captain.
Pretty hazardous place to dive.
It's just a case of trying to keep an eye on the divers,
but the sealions also like to go down and blow bubbles,
so you'll think you're following the divers
and then a sealion will pop up.
Taking the utmost care, the divers get a close-up view of
the sheer scale of the operation.
This is one net must have about fifteen tonnes of fish in it
and there's eight or nine boats in this one little bay,
and these are just the small boats.
Out there, there are huge factory ships
that are taking even bigger catches.
How much fish a year from just here?
From a million tonnes a year more or less.
The catches are so vast,
that sea lions have changed their natural behaviour
to collect anchovies directly from the nets.
But it's a risky strategy.
The crew witnessed
sealions caught in nets multiple times.
Woah, it's intense mate,
there are so many in there.
There's a pup stuck in the net
calling to its mother,
and its mother's just on the outside of the net calling back.
That's really hard to watch.
Oh, the pup's really panicking now.
Sometimes, fishermen are able to release trapped sealions,
but not this time,
the pup is in serious danger.
Once again, the crew decide to step in.
He's going to go inside of the net to save him!
Nice, really nice.
It's a relief this time,
but it highlights
the new realities of filming wildlife
in today's changing ocean.