Where are my golf balls?
Anyone seen my sun block?
What's the point of going to Florida
if you use sun block?
I don't care, I'm getting toasted.
Great. Now you can be a skag
with a darker shade of skin.
He's jealous because he can't tan.
His freckles just connect.
Hey, hey, easy on the fluids!
The rubber sheets are packed.
She wants "Ding. "
Behind "Ding" is 200 points!
All right!
That gives you 4700 points.
200 points! All right!
Honey, are you packed yet?
Yes.
Everything I put out for you?
Oh, did you see what Grandma sent you?
Let me guess. Donald Duck唐老鸭 slippers拖鞋?
Close.
Inflatable clown to play with in the pool.
How exciting.
Why Florida? There's no Christmas trees in Florida.
What is it with Christmas trees?
How can you have Christmas without a Christmas tree?
We'll find a nice fake silver one.
Or decorate a palm tree.
Guests of Ding, Dang, Dong
stay at the world-renowned Plaza Hotel
New York's most exciting hotel experience.
For reservations, call toll-free,免费电话
1- 800-759,..
- Where's the camcorder摄像机 battery电池?
I put it in the charger充电器.
How's this?
Oh, much better.
Kevin, put your tie on. We'll be
late for the Christmas pageant.
It's in the bathroom. I can't go in.
Uncle Frank's taking a shower.
He says if I walk in there and see him
naked, I'd never feel like a real man.
Whatever that means他说些什么.
I'm sure he was kidding.
Just run in and get your tie...
...get out, and don't look at anything.
Well
This cat they're talking about I wonder who could it be
'Cause I know I'm the heaviest cat
The heaviest cat you ever did see
When they see me walking down the street
None of the fellas want to speak Hey, hey, hey
On their faces they wear a silly smirk 'Cause they know
I'm the king Of the cool jerks
Get out of here, you pervert, or I'll slap you silly!
Oh, you're cooking, Frankie.
Christmas tree, My Christmas tree
Lit up like a star
When I see my Christmas tree
Can loved ones be far
Christmas tree I'm certain
Wherever I roam
Kevin's solo's coming up. Tell Leslie.
Kevin's solo's coming up. Tell Frank.
Okay. Frank.
Frank!
Christmastime means laughter
Toboggans in the snow
Caroling together
With faces aglow
Stockings on the mantel
A wreath on the door
And my merriest Christmas
Needs just one thing more
Christmas tree
My Christmas tree
Kevin!
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury...
...I'd like to apologize for whatever displeasure...
...I might have caused you. - What?
My prank was immature and ill-timed.
Immature or not, it was pretty darn hilarious.
I also apologize to my brother.
Kevin.
I'm sorry.
Oh, Buzz...
...that was very nice.
Kevin, do you have something to say?
Beat that, you trout-sniffer.
I'm not sorry. I did it because Buzz humiliated me.
He gets away with everything, so I got him.
Since you stupidly believe his lies...
...I don't care if your Florida trip is wrecked.
Who wants to spend Christmas in a tropical climate?
Kevin!
You walk out, you sleep on the 3rd floor.
Yeah, with me.
So, what else is new?
Don't wreck my trip. Your dad's paying good money for it.
Wouldn't want to spoil your fun, Mr. Cheapskate.
What a troubled young man.
They're all a bunch of jerks.
Hi.
Last time we tried to take a trip,
we had a problem just like this.
Yeah, with me getting crapped on.
I don't care for your choice of words.
That's not what happened.
Buzz apologized to you.
Yeah, then he called me a trout-sniffer.
He didn't mean it. He was just sucking up to you.
Okay, why don't you just sit up here
and think things over?
When you're ready to apologize to
everyone, you can come down.
I'm not apologizing to Buzz.
I'd rather kiss a toilet seat!
Then stay up here all night.
I don't want to go down anyway!
I can't trust anybody in this family.
You know what? If I had my own money,
I'd go on my own vacation.
Alone, without any of you. And I'd have
the most fun of my whole life.
You got your wish last year.
Maybe you will this year.
I hope so.
- We did it again! - We did it again!
Our McCallisters here, other McCallisters there.
I shouldn't complain, but you give
the worst wake-up calls.
- Do you have the tickets?
- I've got them. Here's your family's.
- How many do you have?
- Seven.
- We have seven.
- 14!
Seven...
...eight...
...nine, ten.
- How come we're not sitting together?
This time of year, we're lucky to
get on the same plane. 11, 12, 13,
Where's Kevin?
14,
Good thing I have my own ticket,
just in case you try to ditch me.
- Come on. - I need batteries.
I'll give them to you on the plane.
- Here's two more.
- Why not now?
Not now! What's the gate number?
H-17,
Better hurry, it's the last gate.
Dad, what gate is it?
H-17, Buzz. Come on, Kevin.
Kevin, you gonna take my bag? Take my bag.
Come on. Come on.
American Airlines flight 226 to New York...
...is now in the final boarding process.
Come on. Come on!
Dad, wait up!
Wait up!
Wait!
Come on, come on!
Dad, wait!
Here we are! Here!
We made it.
Everybody here? We made it? All right.
Please board, the plane's leaving.
- I'll make sure everyone gets on.
- We'll get everyone on.
Merry Christmas. Have a nice flight.
Bye. - Bye-bye.
Hey, wait up!
Hey, guys, wait for me!
- Cutting it kind of close.
- Yes.
Merry Christmas. Merry Christmas.
Wait!
- I'm sorry.
- That's okay. Are you on this flight?
Yeah. My family's on the plane.
I don't want to be left here.
- Do you have a boarding pass?
- Somewhere...
They're ready to go.
He dropped his pass.
This happened to me last year and almost wrecked my Christmas.
You sure your family's onboard?
My dad ran in right before I bumped into this lady.
Board him. Make sure he locates his family before you leave him.
Okay. Come on.
Do you see your family?
There's my dad.
- Find an empty seat. Merry Christmas. - You too.
In order to push back from the gate...
...all passengers must have their seat belts fastened.
So have you ever been to Florida?
Welcome aboard American Airlines
flight 176 non-stop to New York.
I didn't think we'd make it.
Something wrong?
Honey?
I have that feeling.
We forgot something?
No, I don't think we did, but I just have that feeling.
Just bad memories.
We did everything, brought everything. We have everybody.
There's nothing to worry about.
Yeah. Yeah, you're right. You're right. We're fine.
Nothing to worry about.
Mom?
Dad?
Uncle Frank?
Buzz?
We're the last ones off the plane.
Where are those guys?
Is this Megan's? It's Brooke's.
Give this to Brooke, this to Kevin.
- Give this... Give this to Kevin. - Give this to Kevin.
Give this to Kevin.
- Kevin. - Kevin.
- Give this to Kevin. - Give this to Kevin.
- Give this to Kevin. - Kevin.
- Give this to Kevin. - Here you go, Kevin.
- Kevin's not here. - Kevin's not here.
What!
Kevin!
Excuse me, this is an emergency!
Yes, sir?
What city is that?
That's New York.
Yikes, I did it again!
Something wrong, sir?
I'll be fine.
Oh, no. My family's in Florida and I'm in New York.
Wow.
What's the child's name?
- Kevin. - K-E-V-I-N.
When did you see him last?
Curbside check-in?
No, I saw him at the door.
He was with us in the terminal.
Most people get separated at security.
Did everyone get through security?
I don't know. Peter...
We were in a hurry.
We ran all the way to the gate.
When did you notice he was missing?
When we picked up our baggage here.
- Has the boy ever run away from home? - No.
Has he ever been in a situation on his own?
As a matter of fact, this has happened before.
It's becoming a McCallister family travel tradition.
Funnily enough, we never lose our luggage.
He was left at home, by accident, last year.
That's what my wife meant calling it
a McCallister family travel tradition.
We'll call Chicago and...
...notify them of the situation.
The odds are that's where he is.
Thanks.
Very unlikely he'd be anywhere else.
Watch out, kid!
Yo, where's your manifest?
Here we are, Marv, New York City.
The land of opportunity.
Smell that?
Yeah.
Know what that is?
- Fish. - It's freedom.
No, it's fish.
- It's freedom and it's money. - Okay, okay.
It's freedom.
Come on, let's go before someone sees us.
And it's fish.
Yes, one quick score.
We get ourselves some phony passports...
...and we hightail it to some foreign country.
Arizona?
That's very smart, Marv.
You bust out of jail to rob 14 cents from a Santy Claus?
Every bit helps.
Besides, now we got our new nickname.
We're the Sticky Bandits!
Real cute.
Very cute.
"The Plaza Hotel. New York's most exciting hotel experience. "
Sick!
What's the matter?
Thought I saw something.
Serves you right! Come on, let's go.
I think she likes me.
Ahh.
Excuse me, where's the lobby?
- Down the hall and to the left. - Thanks.
Wow.
Guests of the new Celebrity Ding-Dang-Dong...
...stay at the world-renowned Plaza Hotel:
New York's most exciting hotel experience.
For reservations, call toll-free...
...1-800-759-3000,
I'll do just that.
Howdy-do. This is Peter McCallister. The father.
I'd like a hotel room.
With an extra-large bed, a TV...
...and one of those little refrigerators with a key.
Credit card? You got it.
Plaza Reservations, may I help you?
Howdy-do. This is Peter McCallister.
The father.
Yes, sir. - I'd like a hotel room.
Yes. - With an extra-large bed, a TV...
...and one of those little refrigerators with a key.
You'll need a major credit card.
Credit card? You got it.
Thank you. Enjoy your stay.
Yes, two at eight, Henri. Mr. Yamamoto.
Hold on a second.
I'll call you back.
Hi.
Can I help you?
Reservation for McCallister.
A reservation for yourself?
My feet are hardly touching the ground.
I can barely see over the counter.
How can I make a reservation for a room?
Think about it: A kid going into a hotel making a reservation?
I don't think so.
I'm confused.
I'm traveling with my dad. He's on business.
He's at a meeting.
I hate meetings. I'm not allowed to go in,
only to sit in the lobby.
That's boring.
So my dad dropped me off.
Gave me his credit card and said to have check-in...
...let me in the room so I won't get into mischief.
Ma'am, sometimes I do get into mischief.
We all do.
Merry Christmas.
No sign of him.
We'll need to be in touch. You have hotel rooms?
- Yeah. - Do you have a recent photo of him?
I have one in my wallet.
I don't have my wallet.
My wallet's in my bag.
Kevin was looking in my bag at the airport.
He has my wallet.
- Did you have credit cards? - Credit cards, money...
We'll notify the credit card companies.
If your son has the cards,
we can get a location on him when he uses them.
I don't think he knows how to use a credit card.
Wow! It worked!
- Cedric. - Yes?
- Don't count your tips in public.
- I'm sorry.
And find out everything you can about that young fellow.
Front, please!
Enjoy your stay with us.
Don't forget to remind your dad, when he arrives...
...he must come down and sign a couple of things.
- Thank you, you've been helpful. May I take your bag?
Up here to your left.
Herbert Hoover once stayed on this floor.
The vacuum guy?
No, the president.
This is one of our finest suites, sir.
Wow! A huge bed just for me!
Luxurious and spacious.
How convenient.
Hey.
Did you want the key in the bag?
Or did you want to hang on to it?
I'll hang on to it.
Everything all right?
- Is the temperature okay? - It's okay.
- Do you know how the TV works?
- I'm 10 years old. TV's my life.
Well...