[CHILDREN SPEAKING SAN]
NARRATOR: Anyone
else would die here of thirst
in a few days,
because in this arid desert
that looks like a paradise,
there is no surface water,
but the slender and
graceful little Bushmen
of the deep Kalahari
live here quite contentedly,
and in complete harmony
with their environment.
They have lived
undisturbed for 20,000 years
because they are the
only people in the world
who know how to live
without surface water.
When ivory poachers
in high-tech vehicles
intrude into this
vast thirst-land
to hunt elephant,
they have to drag giant
reservoirs of water with them,
and when the water runs low,
they have to hightail it
out of the Kalahari again...
so the Bushmen work and
play in peaceful isolation,
quite unaware of the
crowded and hectic world
outside their domain,
and even of the wars
that are being fought
on the very fringes
of the Kalahari.
Sometimes Xixo
tells about the time
when he went to look
for the end of the Earth,
and about the
strange heavy people
he met on his journey,
but he finds it difficult
to describe the beings
who live outside the Kalahari,
and he always ends up by saying
that the heavy
people are persons
who seem to know some magic
that can make things
move, and even fly,
but that they're
not very bright,
because they can't survive
without their
magic contrivances.
In the mornings, they
like to read the news.
They can read that the
hyena has a new girlfriend,
that the cheetah has
lost one of her babies,
and the oryx is starting
to migrate to the west.
The older children
teach the younger ones
how to read all the gossip
about their neighbors,
the animals,
because everything that
happens in the Kalahari
gets printed out in the sand.
So it's all printed out here.
This is where they
started infringing
on your client's patent.
Give it to me there.
Now, that I can
present in court.
Go back to frame A...
and give me sales.
Oh, go away, Geoffrey.
Cathy, will you take this?
Okay. Take him off.
Now, cost per unit,
and a printout on that.
Mr. Geoffrey says he has to go
to Hong Kong about the takeover.
Okay, tell him
"Have a good flight."
So he won't make the
ECACL conference.
He can't do that to me.
He said he'd like you
to read the paper,
says you did most
of the research,
so you deserve the honor.
I deserve to be left alone
so I can go to court
on Wednesday.
You'll be back before Wednesday.
Oh, boy.
NARRATOR: That morning,
Xabe came out of the forest
with the news that
some of the animals
had started moving
towards the marula
groves in the north.
He ran up to his
father and shouted,
"The marulas are ripe.
Let's go and collect some."
Then Xisa and little
Xiri ran up and said,
"Can we come too?"
Xixo said, "Let's see if
you're big enough yet.
If you're taller than my bow,
the hyena will be afraid of
you and he'll keep his distance,
but if you're shorter,
he'll take you,"
but Xiri said, "Please
let me come too,"
and Xisa said,
"I promise I'll always
stay close to him."
Where are they having
the conference this year?
In Okakarara.
Where's that, Nebraska?
No, Africa.
Oh, boy.
NARRATOR: They
gathered a lot of marulas,
and on the way home,
they came across the
spoor of a wounded elephant.
Xixo said,
"This elephant is very
weak. It's going to die."
He said to Xisa, "You
and Xiri can go on home.
"Tell your mother we will come
when we've found
the sick elephant."
There was a very strange
and very beautiful pattern
on the ground.
Xisa couldn't read it.
She'd never seen
anything like it in her life.
There was another one,
just as beautiful
as the first one.
She wondered how anything
could make such a
long, unbroken track.
She followed the track
and saw a very
strange-looking thing.
[SPEAKING SAN]
She said, "You see,
"this thing went
round and round,
"and that's how it made
such a long pattern
without footprints."
Xiri saw a beautiful
dewdrop grow,
and when it dropped,
another one began
to grow in its place.
They knew that the gods
always put dewdrops
on plants in the night,
but here they could
see a dewdrop form
in broad daylight.
Xisa said, "I think this
thing is making the water."
Xiri had never seen so
much water in his life.
He didn't know there
was so much water
in the whole world.
[ENGINE STARTS]
They found the elephant,
and they saw the tiny
wound that had made it die.
The tracks told Xixo
the heavy people had been there,
and he wondered
why they had taken
the useless tusks
and had left all the
valuable meat to rot.
He said, "The heavy
people do strange things."
Bo said, "I'll call
Xabo's family
to help us eat the meat.
If I run all day and all night, I
can find them by tomorrow,"
and Xixo said, "We'll
go and call our family."
[♪♪♪]
There were many tusks.
It takes the gods more
than a man's lifetime
to make a full-grown elephant,
and it horrified them to
see that so many had died.
[SPEAKING SAN]
Xixo and Xabe found the place
where Xisa and Xiri's
tracks suddenly stopped.
Xixo said, "Look, Xisa
climbed onto the thing,
and then Xiri went up
too, and it took them away."
He said, "Tell our family
"they must go to
the dead elephant
"and start eating it.
I'll fetch Xisa and Xiri."
I'm sorry you had to come
on such short notice,
but we're very
honored to have you.
I would've liked going
on the safari tour,
but I have to prepare
my presentation.
You're sure you'll
be all right here?
I'll be fine, thank you.
Good, I'll leave you to it.
You know where
Stephen's working?
Yeah, I think I've
got a rough idea.
Well, you may have to
search around for him a bit.
Right.
And Jack?
Yeah?
Tell Stephen we'll send
the rest out to him later.
Right.
What's a nice girl like you
doing in a place like this?
Oh, boy.
You don't buy it.
Uh-uh.
Okay, I'll try again.
Hi.
How would you like
to come fly with me?
I have to work this. That's
why I turned down the safari trip.
Trip's three hours.
I'll show you lots of Africa
in a half an hour.
What do you say?
I have to present
this at 3:30, you know.
Oops.
Only half an hour?
Yes, Doctor.
So, what are you, a
doctor of medicine?
No, corporate law.
What a tiny plane.
We have a smaller
one, but we can't find it.
Can it fly?
In you go.
What are those?
Buffalo.
Look, no hands. Flies by itself.
Safest plane in the world.
Coffee.
Morning, boss.
You only done 80 miles.
Yeah, I slept a little bit.
You stopped.
I was bushed, so
I pulled up and...
You slept more than four hours.
I was real pooped.
I told you we're running late.
I was really pooped, boss.
Move over.
It's okay, boss, I'm fresh now.
Get. Jeez, boss.
Lazy bastard.
Get back to sleep.
I'm wide awake now.
Sleep.
Yes, boss.
I'll be right back.
Mm-hmm.
Hi, Stephen. Hi, thanks.
You're cutting
it fine, you know.
There's a hell of a
cumulus building up.
One of those thermals
grabs hold of you,
it's going to whip you
right over the escarpment.
You'll be 20, 30,000 feet.
See you later.
RADIO: Stephen, is
Geoff there yet? Over.
Hi, Bob.
Yes, he's here. Over.
Can you fly back in with him?
We found a baby giraffe
that looks very sick.
We need your advice. Over.
Okay. Out.
You know you're not supposed
to cart your floozies
around in that.
No, she's not a floozy.
Hi.
Morning.
Do you do some kind
of work around here?
[ENGINE ROARS]
Hello, Stephen. Come in. Over.
Stephen, are you there? Over.
Hi, Bob, this is Jack. Over.
Jack, don't take off yet.
There's a freak storm
moving in very fast
across the escarpment.
Over.
Uh, Bob, they've just taken off.
They? Is there someone
else with him? Over.
Yes. Over.
Who? Over.
Uh, there was this
young lady. Over.
Was she with you? Over.
Uh, sort of. Over.
Boy, you're in trouble. Over.
Over.
Xixo's old friend Waka
was standing there,
looking at the tracks the
heavy people had made.
Xixo greeted him,
and told him that his children
were in the thing that
had made the tracks.
Waka greeted him back,
and said, "I'll come with
you to find your children,"
but Xixo said,
"There's a dead
elephant back there.
"Go there with your family,
so that they can
help my family eat it."
[BEEPING]
[MOTOR SPUTTERING]
They stopped.
I think there's some whiskey
under your seat.
No thanks, I'm okay.
Give it to me.
You're going to start drinking?
Give me.
Can this thing fly on Scotch?
George.
Boss?
Take over.
NARRATOR: Xisa said,
"When this thing gets
tired, it will stop to rest,
then we can follow
the tracks back home."
[ENGINE SPUTTERING]
Running out of Scotch.
This any good? Uh-uh.
We're flying backwards.
[♪♪♪]
I have to read my paper at 3:30.
How do I get back?
We have to find a road
so I can hitch a ride.
So which way to
the nearest road?
This is baobab country.
Oh, it can speak.
We're at least 300
miles from base.
Oh, boy.
Maybe more.
I'm sorry.
Any time.
I have to get to a telephone.
I don't even know
what country we're in.
That was one hell of a storm.
Hey!
Great. Great.
They're not scared of me.
So?
They don't know about people.
We're in the deep Kalahari.
Will they find us here?
Eventually.
Well, how long is eventually?
Maybe a day, maybe a week.
A week? I have to be back
in New York on Wednesday.
You're from New York?
You mean I have to
survive here for a week?
Anyone who can survive in
New York can survive here.
We'll starve to death.
There's enough food around here.
Our problem will be water.
All we have is that
six-pack up there.
NARRATOR: They
were getting quite thirsty,
but they knew where
there was plenty of water.
[SPEAKING SAN]
She said, "No, I'm too
heavy for you to pull me up.
"You come down here
so you can push me up.
Then I can pull you up."
Xiri had never been in water,
but he soon got
used to the idea,
and quite enjoyed it.
Is that water?
Petrol. Gas.
So?
If I can get this thing
down, we can fly out.
Today?
I have to take it
apart, bring it down,
assemble it again.
Eventually.
Maybe by tomorrow,
the next day.
[ROARING]
Was that a lion?
Yeah, I can hear them.
Let down the rope.
I want to get up.
They won't bother us.
You're okay, they're bothering
the hell out of me down here.
Will you let down that rope?
They're not coming this way.
What about eventually?
If you don't bother them,
they won't bother you.
And if they're hungry?
They're far from here.
It's swarming with
wild animals down here.
If don't bother them,
they won't bother you.
I'm not bothering them.
[HYENA LAUGHING]
This one is drooling at me.
It's a hyena. They're
always drooling.
So?
Ignore him. Don't smile at him.
Why not?
He might think
you're threatening him.
Let me get up there.
[ROARING]
You're enjoying this.
Yeah.
Why don't you relax
and enjoy it too?
What's to enjoy?
Wild animals all over the
place, no food, no water.
No room service.
Yeah, no plumbing.
What I need is plumbing, now.
Go behind that thicket.
Alone?
I mean, the lions are that way.
They're very far. If
you don't bother them...
They won't bother
me. I know, I know.
How do I get down?
How'd you get up there?
The lion was roaring.
Wasn't a lion.
It was a hyena sounding off.
Right.
Now, just a minute.
Turn your back.
Pull me up.
I can't. Friction.
Then let me down.
What do you want me to do?
Don't look at me.
Let me down, let me down.
[HYENA LAUGHING]
[LAUGHING]
What's so funny?
Okay, I won't bother you, see?
So don't you bother me.
Watch it!
Go away!
Run, run, run, run, run, run.
Get up a tree!
You okay?
You said if I didn't
bother them...
I see there's a baby
rhino back there.
Maybe the mother thought
you were molesting it.
I only talked to it. I
didn't even smile at it.
They're going. They're
going away now.
I'm not coming down
before you can
fly me out of here.
There's no plumbing up there.
You thirsty?
Yes.
All right, you can
have half a beer.
Great.
Don't open it yet.
Sorry. Oh, my goodness.
Um...
Sorry.
What did I do wrong?
Well, it's warm.
Drink it now.
[LAUGHING]
Right. It's getting late.
We have to find food
before it gets dark.
I saw an ostrich nest.
Do they bite?
No, they kick, but
they aren't very bright.
If you lie down flat,
he can't see you.
That's the male.
He has to guard the eggs,
but if you can distract him...
How do I distract
a male ostrich?
[SPEAKING SAN]
Lie down flat!
[OSTRICH SCREECHES]
For a moment,
Xixo thought he saw
his children's footprints,
but it was only a baboon
that had walked past.
[SPEAKING SAN]
[GUNSHOT]
So, what went wrong?
Nothing. We got the egg.
You mean that was
standard procedure?
Got a match?
The thing came back.
I'm sorry.
You got a match?
I've got a lighter.
Big Ben calling Ramjee.
Do you read me?
Ramjee, come
in. Big Ben calling.
Come in, Ramjee.
Still out of range.
Maybe they're not there yet.
He said he'll meet
us on the ninth.
That's yesterday.
Sorry, boss.
[TUNING RADIO]
it is expected
that 10,000 people
will attend the opening.
Although nine helicopters
and four spotter planes
are taking part in the search,
no sign of Dr. Marshall
and Dr. Taylor
has been found.
Was that us?
I suppose so.
Doctor of what?
Zoology.
You?
Law.
[SINGING]
We have to watch that guy.
The hyena? He's
a hell of a coward.
As long as you're
taller than him,
he'll keep his distance,
but if you lie down,
he'll take a chunk
out of your face
and your leg.
You can take the first watch.
Call me when the
moon gets to there,
and I'll take it to there,
and then you can
take it to first light.
Coming down.
I'm ready.
For what?
You only jumped 25 centimeters.
What happened to
standard procedure?
Maybe next time.
Where are we going
to take off from?
There's a salt pan about
three miles from here.
How many blocks?
Keep the sun over
your right shoulder.
Stay clear of low branches.
What?
It's that damn rhino.
It's a male. It's harmless.
What are you always
climbing up trees for?
I'm not a doctor of zoology.
How am I supposed to know
about males and females?
Damn near wrecked
the nose wheel.
Give me slack.
You only jumped 124 centimeters.
These things are dangerous.
It's very small.
But when it grabs hold
of you, it never lets go.
Kind of cute.
[TIRE HISSING]
Hey. No!
Now we've got a flat.
What do I do with this?
Why don't you throw it away?
It'll just come right back.
Can you change the tire?
Can you undo my boot?
It's the one that
stepped on him.
So?
If I give it to him, he
can have his revenge.
There.
[♪♪♪]
Is there enough gas
to take us all the way back?
If we get it off the ground.
No, it won't work.
Can't you fix it?
No pump.
You want to be the wheel.
You're crazy.
You see that stick?
When I shout, "Now,"
you bring it over this way.
But I can't fly a plane.
It'll lift your
side of the wing,
then you center up. Push
out again, you pull it back.
You see?
Bring it over, center
up, pull it back.
Then what?
Then I'll take over.
But I can't even drive a manual.
Do you want to kill us both?
You're nuts.
I can't fly a plane,
you hear me?
I can't fly a plane!
Throttles.
Shiny ones, push them forward.
Here we go!
Come on. Stick it back.
Center up.
I told you I can't fly.
Pull back.
Not way back.
Pull it, pull it, pull it.
Will you make up your mind?
Bring her down.
What?
We go that way.
You said you were
going to take over.
You should have
gone that way. Oh, shit.
Oh, shit!
Ask a woman to do anything,
and she buggers it up.
So she buggered it up.
[AIRPLANE OVERHEAD]
[ENIGINE DIES]
Just look down and read.
It says "On. Off."
Switch it off, then
you can glide.
Ha ha!
Whoa!
I told you I can't fly.
It says, "Ballistic parachute,"
clearly and distinctly.
Read it, press the
button, and you'll be okay.
I told you I can't
even drive a manual.
"Oh, it's easy."
"Bring it over, center
it up, pull it back,
and get it right, woman."
I showed you so nicely.
I said, "Bring it over."
Not "Bring it over!"
You'll break your silly neck.
You don't explain properly.
I could have broken my neck.
How the hell am
I going to find you
with only one boot?
Better find my boot.
Shoo. Go away.
[ENGINE STARTS]
[ENGINE STOPS]
[GROWLING]
Oh, shit.
[SINGING]
Wait!
Hi.
Do you want to
sell me your bike?
Look, I'll give you money.
I give you money,
you give me the bike.
[SPEAKING SAN]
No, I have to go that way.
There's a man there.
I'll pay you, you
take me that way.
[SPEAKING SAN]
Here. Please, I insist.
Okay, I'll pay you
when we get there.
There?
[SINGING AND HONKING]
Well, why don't we
try something else?
Oh, yeah, sure.
Oh, all right.
Good thinking.
Are you going to
hang in there forever?
There. Lunch.
Go on, try it.
Okay, try that.
[SINGING]
[SHRIEK]
[WHEEZING]
Look, I'm really
sorry. Please take this.
[SPEAKING SAN]
No, come on.
Bye.
[SINGING]
Well, thanks.
Bye. Got to find somebody.
You said you were tired.
[COUNTING]
Hey, go home.
Go back to your family.
Go on, get.
Get. Shoo. Go.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[JEEP APPROACHING]
[THUMP]
[SHRIEK]
[GUNFIRE]
[SPEAKING SAN]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
English?
Okay.
Get up.
Move.
Which way?
To my jeep.
Stop.
Where are you going?
Where is your jeep?
We go to your jeep.
Stop.
March.
Which way?
You know why a compass
has a mirror on back?
Why?
So you can see who's lost.
Okay, we go northwest. That way.
March.
How far did you
fly, for Pete's sake?
How the hell am I
going to find you?
Damn!
Hey!
Hey, you, get away!
Leave it alone.
Get out of here.
Give me back my can.
Scumbag.
You mugger.
Thank you.
You keep away.
Stay there.
See these?
If you dare...
Don't even think about it.
You'll be sorry.
Go away.
Okay, you can have
this one, and no more.
Leave the can.
Do you hear me?
Leave my can alone and go away.
No, don't bring a friend.
I'm not going to water you,
and your friends,
and your relatives,
and I'm not...
Aah!
Excerpts from the
Geneva Convention.
Forget it.
It says here about
how a prisoner of war
ought to be treated.
"No prisoner of war
"shall be subjected
to inhumane treatment.
No outrage shall be committed."
Okay, stop.
You can rest for three minutes.
What's your bloody hurry?
None of your business.
Three minutes.
I'm pooped, man.
Hey! Don't do that!
Come back.
I'm going to report you
to the Geneva Convention.
Come back.
You're my prisoner.
Come out of there
and be my prisoner!
You mustn't do that!
March.
So if you're so smart,
how come you don't even
know what country you're in?
So which way did they go?
I'll just have to wait
till they come back.
[RADIO PLAYING]
Xixo saw a heavy person
dressed in funny clothes
sitting next to the
track, talking to herself.
She looked like a woman,
but she had a man's voice.
[SPEAKING SAN]
Hey.
Oh, it's your way of greeting.
We do it this way.
Sorry.
Okay. I'll do it your way.
Hello.
I'm very glad to meet you.
He said, "Where is your family?"
He looked at her tracks,
and said, "You are alone.
"How did you get here?
He said, "I have
to find my children.
"There are two heavy people
playing some kind of game.
"They went that way,
now I hear them coming.
Perhaps they'll let
you play with them."
You want me to go
with you? Uh-huh.
He showed her the tracks
where he met the two heavy men.
He said, "This is
where they turned back.
"See how angry this one was,
"because the tired one
grabbed the stick from him,
"and then he had to run.
It was very funny."
But, of course, she
couldn't understand.
She was also quite illiterate.
She couldn't read the
signs and tracks at all.
We're waiting for a bus?
Well, what do you know?
Go away. Bugger off.
I don't want to see you.
Stop!
Who are you?
Xixo couldn't understand
what these crazy
people were playing at.
This thing penetrates.
You wouldn't shoot a lady.
He said, "I have to go
and find my children."
He remembered the
men had bad manners,
so he didn't say
goodbye to them.
I don't want to be
involved in your wars.
I'm American.
Okay.
Hey, you can't leave me here.
You want me to die?
Get away from me.
Get away!
Try again, huh?
It's not fair.
You can't both
use me. Let me go!
Let me go! Let me go!
Okay, drop it.
Drop it. Yes, drop it.
Drop it, drop it, drop it!
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Can't we negotiate?
I want to go home.
If I don't get back to
Biera by tomorrow night,
I'm going to miss my
plane back to Cuba,
then I'll spend
another six months
in this goddamn Africa.
And I've got to take
you to my base, now.
Well, I have to be in
New York on Wednesday.
Sit down, and stay clear
of the goddamn Cuban.
I'll stay clear of
goddamn both of you.
I resent being used
as a hostage object.
Got to be in New
York on Wednesday.
You should have stayed there.
I didn't ask you
to come out here.
I have to walk my
ass off to find you.
Well, good.
[HYENAS LAUGHING]
What's so funny?
Switch it on.
Big Ben calling Ramjee.
What are you doing?
What am I doing?
Look at the sun.
You're going the wrong way.
Boss, I'm driving
on the compass.
This thing is made of steel.
You left it there.
Look at the needle.
You buggered the compass,
you stupid bastard.
Jeez, boss, I wasn't thinking.
Stop the bloody truck.
So when did you put it there?
Well, I drank some
coffee just at sunrise, boss.
Five hours.
40 degrees off. Stupid bastard.
Big Ben calling Ramjee.
Do you read me, for chrissakes?
Ramjee, come in.
Big Ben, where the hell are you?
Look, I'm sorry.
This idiot I've got here
bugged the compass.
I've been waiting
three bloody days.
Where the bloody hell are you?
We're way off course.
Now we have to backtrack
for at least five hours
to find our bearings.
We're going back
in our tracks now,
so we'll be out of range again.
I'll contact you
when we come back into range.
Little Xiri saw hyena tracks.
The spoor was very fresh,
so he knew the
hyena must be close,
and it was downwind, so
it was sure to smell him.
He remembered
his father had said,
"If you're taller
than the hyena,
it'll keep its distance."
It couldn't understand
how this small creature
had grown tall so suddenly.
Perhaps the hyena hoped
that Xiri would get small again,
so it followed him...
at a respectful distance.
Well, we got blown
here in a kind of a plane,
and then I kind of lost
Dr. Marshall.
Get in the jeep.
Move.
Wait there. Okay,
but leave your bag.
Why?
You swat people.
No, I won't, I promise.
Look, I'll take out the rocks.
You got rocks in there?
You drive.
In there.
Start her up.
That way.
Xixo saw another track
made by a heavy person,
and the footprints told of a man
who was in a bad way.
He spoke to the track.
He said, "I can
see you need help,
but I must find my children."
Turn right.
Stop.
Hey, that's my jeep.
I know, I knew it.
Go siphon.
Gas? But my tank
was almost empty.
[SPEAKS SPANISH]
Oh, boy.
[SPEAKING SAN]
Hi.
Xixo said, "I don't
know what to do.
"You need someone
to find water for you,
"but I'm worried
about my children.
"I've been running for
two days and a night,
"and I haven't found them.
I think they're very far."
What have you got?
About two liters.
14, 15 kilometers.
How much have you got?
About 20 kilometers.
How far is your base?
60, 65.
Oh, my God.
My base is 20 kilometers.
Shut up. Get up.
Watch it!
Stop it!
I said, stop it!
Stop it right now!
[GUNSHOT]
Lady,
be careful with
that. Give it to me.
I'm the good guy here.
He's a bloody Cuban.
Give it to me.
Jeez, lady.
Yes, make my day.
Okay, señorita.
My base is only
20 kilometers away.
There's going to be a
plane to Cuba tomorrow.
Give me the gun.
I'll take you there.
This guy doesn't
know where he is.
You couldn't even
find your own jeep.
How are you going
to find your base?
You find it. You're so smart.
We're going to my base.
Who says? I says!
Stop it!
You,
get behind the wheel.
No.
No, get back.
You've got to stay together.
Um... take his hand.
I said hold hands.
Okay, get in.
You go around that way.
Okay.
Now, can either
of you fly a plane?
Yeah, I can.
Good.
Drive back to where we started.
Watch it, boss!
[HORN BLARING]
Jeez, boss, we
killed a little kid.
Sit down. We've
got to get out of here.
But, boss, it was a little kid.
He's okay. He's okay.
[SPEAKING SAN]
Jeez, boss, there's another one.
Xiri! Xiri!
Now Xisa didn't
know which way to go.
What if her little brother
had been left back there?
[CRYING]
Stop here.
This is where the
Bushman found me.
That means the plane must be...
[SPEAKING SAN]
That guy's only bad news.
Follow him.
We're low on gas.
[CRYING]
Hi.
Hold hands.
Get out that side.
Go that way.
Stop.
Goodbye. Thank you.
What happened?
It's nothing, just
kind of dehydrated.
Does "W" stand for water?
I don't have to tell you.
Okay, open your mouth.
Who's the little guy
who gave me that stuff?
I don't know.
He just keeps on
appearing and disappearing.
Who are they?
They're soldiers.
They look very affectionate.
No.
Are they your prisoners?
Kind of.
She hijacked my jeep
and she kidnapped us.
You did it to me
first. Both of them.
He did it, then he did it.
She hit me first.
You hit him?
Yeah.
She hit me too.
Damn near killed me.
You hit them? Took
them prisoner with a gun?
Yeah.
No, we're still backtracking.
Keep going.
Yes, boss.
We nearly knocked over
another crazy Bushman.
You're still in Bushmen country?
Oh, it beats me
where they come from.
You said nobody would see you.
Bushmen don't count.
Oh, my God.
Ben, what happened?
Bloody Bushman
was crawling all over.
What do you mean,
"crawling all over"?
What are you doing?
Hey, you okay?
What were you doing up there?
Did he see the ivory?
I don't know. He must have.
Then you can't let him go.
That's right.
You a game warden?
Get him in here.
You come with
us, you get in there.
Here.
Boss?
Make him get in.
You come with
us, you get in there.
You get in there.
Hey, you mustn't
do that. Get in there.
Can't you do anything right?
Jeez, boss.
Get me a tie-down.
What are you going to do, boss?
They did it to me,
and he wants to go that
way, he wants to go that way.
The one who's got the gun
gets to say where we go,
and I've got the gun, and
I say we go to the plane.
Okay.
In the jeep.
When we get to the plane,
you can have your jeep back.
And my gun.
We'll see about that.
What the hell do you
think you're doing?
It's his, boss.
Stop.
Here are those tracks again.
Okay, the plane
must be that way.
How are we going to take off?
I'm not going to
be the wheel again.
Now we can fix it.
I don't see a pump.
Don't! You've got to watch them.
[TRUCK APPROACHING]
Yours? No.
Game rangers.
What do we do,
boss? He's got a gun.
Don't let him see the ivory.
Maybe they've got a pump.
Could you lend us a pump?
What?
Could we borrow a pump with a...
Oh, no!
What have you done to him?
Drop that!
Throw it away!
George...
Get the gun.
What do we do now, boss?
Tie them up. Boss?
Give me that.
Get the tie-downs.
Jeez, boss.
What's this about?
I don't like game rangers.
I'm not a game ranger.
Me too.
This is all I've got, boss.
Tie them two by two.
[HOWLING]
What are we going
to do now, boss?
I've got to talk to Ramjee.
Big Ben calling Ramjee.
Do you read me?
Ramjee, do you read me?
Out of range again.
George, you see that dome?
I'm going to go up
there to get range.
Got to talk to
Ramjee about this.
I'm leaving you in charge.
You watch these people.
Okay, now, you people.
You behave, nobody gets hurt.
Oh, my God.
[GUNSHOT]
Get the gun.
Hey, you mustn't do that.
My boss will kill you.
Got it.
Okay, let's go.
Get in.
What do you mean, "Get in"?
Move it, man.
Mister, come with us.
I'm coming too.
He's going to kill me.
You, give me first gear.
Hurry!
[ENGINE SPUTTERING]
I knew it. I knew it.
I told you we're low on gas.
Let's get out of here.
Move your ass, man.
What a day.
Game rangers, two
soldiers, and a woman.
What did you do with them?
I tied them up.
What the hell?
George!
Yes, boss?
[GUNFIRE]
Your turn.
Your turn!
No, it's not!
It is, it is! No, it's not!
It is!
No, it's not!
Okay, dammit.
I'll get the bastard.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
No, get up. Untie me.
Come on.
[ELEPHANTS TRUMPETING]
[SPEAKING SAN]
Hey!
[SPEAKS SPANISH]
Oh, no, man.
He's not so crazy.
He knows what he's doing.
He's making a firebreak.
Clever little bugger.
It'll burn out now.
That's it.
[SPEAKING SAN]
They're your kids?
Yes, we passed them back there.
There's a tiny one
and then the other one.
Yeah, that way.
Yeah.
Why are you crying?
He lost his kids.
I told him where to find them.
So you have to disappear again.
Goodbye...
and thank you.
Goodbye,
Watch it! He's got a gun!
Out of my way.
I want you to do that again.
Do what? What you just did.
What the hell for?
It's a telescopic sight.
He can't hit a moving target.
No!
When I say, "Go,"
you run around
like crazy, all right?
Go!
Stand still,
you bastards.
[GUNFIRE]
[CLICK]
Throw it away.
Okay, okay, okay. I'm
your goddamn prisoner.
I don't want you.
You're a, you're a...
you're a shitty prisoner.
Xiri!
[ECHOING]
[SPEAKING SAN]
[LAUGHING]
Okay, thank you.
Okay, goodbye.
Bugger off to Cuba
and don't get lost.
See that hill over there?
You head straight for it,
and you'll find your jeep.
Goodbye.
Okay, out.
You drive the jeep.
Where we going, boss?
To my base.
How long will we get?
Maybe you'll get a year,
but this bastard's going
to sit for a long time.
There are 12 spotter planes
and nine helicopters
searching the area in a
radius of 400 kilometers.
[AIRPLANE APPROACHING]
So we are covering an area
of 20,000...
[GIGGLING]
Isn't this where we kiss?
Yes!
Pull me up! Pull me up!
You're tearing my dress!
Let me down.
No, pull me up.
Don't bother.
I can't see!
Oh, boy.
Now can you do it right?
Daddy!
[SHOUTING IN SAN]
[LAUGHING]
[♪♪♪]