HURRY,
THE TRAIN!
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS]
[PLAYS CHOPIN MUSIC]
[DOG WHINES]
[WHINING]
[PLAYS BOOGIE-WOOGIE]
[DISH BREAKS]
HENRY, STOP IT!
I'M SORRY,
MR. ARTHUR.
IT'S QUITE ALL RIGHT.
PLEASE DON'T BE ANGRY.
MY SON'S ONLY JOKING.
MR. ARTHUR.
STOP. I'M GOING
TO KILL YOU.
I'M GOING TO
WORK.
YOU'LL
BREAK
YOUR HANDS
AND NEVER PLAY
CARNEGIE HALL.
I DON'T WANT
TO
PLAY CARNEGIE HALL.
THIS WEEK YOU DON'T.
I'VE TOLD YOU THAT
SINCE I WAS 7.
WHAT
DOES
A 7-YEAR-OLD KNOW?
I GOT TO
GO.
COME BACK
WITH ALL
YOUR FINGERS.
HI, DAD.
HI, ARGUS.
ARGUS IS THE
DOG.
I'M HENRY.
SORRY, HENRY.
FOURTH DOWN,
FIVE SECONDS TO GO.
LUCKMAN
LICKS HIS FINGERS.
EYES THE
DEFENSE.
[GRRR]
HE SETS.
TAKES THE SNAP,
HANDS OFF TO McGROKEY.
McGROKEY KNOCKS OFF FARKAS,
STRAIGHT-ARMS TODD!
BODIES ARE FLYING!
THE CROWD GOES WILD!
TOUCHDOWN! WHOOPEE!
YOU'RE GETTING OLD, BUTCH.
HOP,
LOOK
WHAT I GOT HERE!
HOPPER, WHERE
HAVE YOU BEEN?
SHOOTING DOWN
ENEMY AIRCRAFT.
GOT AN AIRACOBRA
P-39
OVER PLEASURE POINT.
THE AIRACOBRA
P-39
IS ONE OF OURS, HOP.
PICK UP TWO,
WILL YOU?
SHARPEN UP IF YOU
WANT TO BE A MARINE.
UH-HUH.
HEY!
ANYBODY DOWN THERE?
AH,
GATSBY BOYS.
VERY LAME.
WAIT TILL
I GOT THEM SET!
GO TO THE
MOVIES
TOMORROW
WITH ME AND SALLY?
WHAT'S
PLAYING?
WHO
CARES?
GOD DAMN IT!
YOU'VE BEEN
SEEING
HER FOR MONTHS.
SALLY'S DAD
WON'T LET HER OUT
UNLESS SHE DOUBLES.
HER OLD MAN
THINKS WE'RE
MESSING AROUND.
HER OLD MAN'S
SMART.
SO, WHAT DO YOU SAY?
I DON'T KNOW,
NICKY.
I DON'T FEEL
LIKE A MOVIE.
SINCE WHEN DID YOU
WATCH CAROLE LOMBARD?
I ALWAYS WATCH
CAROLE LOMBARD.
BESIDES, I DON'T
HAVE A DATE.
TAKE CINDI.
I LIKE C--
LISTEN, ASSHOLE,
THAT'S THE LAST TIME!
WHAT DID YOU
CALL ME?
ASSHOLE.
YOU HEARD ME.
RICH
BASTARDS.
SO IT'S ALL SET,
RIGHT?
WHAT?
ME AND SALLY,
YOU AND CINDI.
I
LIKE CINDI.
SO?
SO, NICKY,
WHEN I'M WITH YOU,
I DON'T TAKE
SOMEBODY I LIKE.
THAT'S IT,
YOU SON OF A BITCH!
OH, BOY!
OH, SHIT.
GET BACK THERE!
ALL RIGHT.
BREAK IT UP!
NOT ON
THE LANES!
HE TRIED
TO RIVET ME!
HE WAS TALKING
INSTEAD
OF SETTING UP PINS.
NICKY, PLEASE!
HEY, NICKY!
WILL YOU GET HOPPER
OUT OF HERE?
GET HOPPER OUT
OF HERE!
COOL HIM
OFF.
CLEAN YOURSELF UP
IN THE BATHROOM.
LOOK AT MY
CLOTHES.
MY CLOTHES.
OK. TAKE JULIE--
TAKE NANCY.
NANCY?
WHY NOT?
NANCY'S
MARRIED.
ALL RIGHT.
NANCY'S OUT.
IT DOESN'T
MATTER,
AS LONG AS
IT
LOOKS LIKE A GIRL.
WE'LL DRIVE
TO THE LAKE.
YOU CAN USE THE CAR.
ALL THIS BACK-SEAT
STUFF
SEEMS KIND OF JUVENILE.
LISTEN TO THIS
GUY.
I DON'T PAY YOU TO
BE HOPPER'S SHADOW.
IT
DOESN'T HAVE
TO BE A REAL DATE.
BOYS,
I NEED MORE GIN.
TAKE ALBERTA.
I
KNOW--YOU'RE HOT
FOR SALLY KAISER.
WHAT?
YOU
DON'T THINK I'M
GOOD ENOUGH FOR HER.
WHY DOES SHE
DATE YOU?
ONE DAY AT THE DRUGSTORE,
WE MET OVER COKES.
I SAID I'D BE
HONORED--
DON'T YOU
THINK
ABOUT ANYTHING
BUT HIKING UP
SOME GIRL'S DRESS?
LIKE WHAT?
LIKE, I DON'T
KNOW.
LIKE THE FUTURE,
SON.
THE ONLY FUTURE WE GOT
IS GERMANS AND JAPS.
IN THE NEXT SIX WEEKS,
I'M GETTING EVERYTHING
I CAN.
[CRASH]
DO YOU THINK I
DO THIS FOR FREE?
ALL RIGHT, SONNY
BOY!
HEY,
HEY!
WHAT'S GOING ON
HERE, ANNIE?
HE'S RUNNING
OFF
WITHOUT PAYING
HIS TAB.
I'D PAY
IF I WERE YOU.
I SWEAR I
DON'T
HAVE ANY MONEY.
THIS ISN'T THE
USO.
I'LL TAKE THE WATCH.
MY GRANDFATHER
GAVE ME THAT.
I WOULDN'T ARGUE
WITH THE LADY.
GET OUT
OF HERE!
THANKS,
GUYS.
WELL,
I'D
LOVE TO CHAT,
BUT I'VE
GOT TO PAY
THE LIGHT BILL.
HOW WOULD YOU LIKE
TO GO ON A DATE
TOMORROW
NIGHT
WITH HOPPER?
WHAT HAPPENED
TO YOUR EYE?
OLD MAN'S
DRINKING AGAIN.
OHHH!
I GOT A RUN
IN MY STOCKING.
I DON'T THINK
WE'LL
GET AWAY WITH THIS.
YOU AND
SALLY
SHARE CLASSES?
I DON'T THINK
SHE'S MENTIONED YOU.
I GRADUATED
A LONG TIME AGO.
WHERE
DID YOU
GET THAT EYE?
BOWLING,
SIR.
SORRY I'M
LATE.
WHAT HAPPENED
TO YOUR EYE?
I'LL TELL YOU LATER.
GOOD NIGHT!
COULD I HAVE
A DRINK
OR SOME CANDIES?
LET'S GO.
SORRY.
YOU
HAVE SUCH
A LOVELY LIVING ROOM.
GOOD NIGHT.
HERE WE ARE, KIDS.
WE WERE
GOING
TO THE MOVIES.
HOP'S GOT TO
DO SOME
CHRISTMAS SHOPPING.
BYE, KIDS.
IT WAS GREAT, HOP.
DO YOU WANT TO
GO
FOR A SUNDAE MAYBE?
YOU MEAN ICE CREAM?
YEAH.
SORRY. WHEN
DO YOU SHIP OUT?
SIX
WEEKS.
WELL,
LISTEN,
ANGEL FACE,
YOU'RE
WELCOME
TO STOP BY
FOR A FREE RIDE
ON THE OLD
MERRY-GO-ROUND.
THANKS, ANNIE.
OH, I ALMOST FORGOT.
THIS IS FOR
YOU.
OH, THANKS,
HOP.
BUT I REALLY
CAN'T.
I'M ALLERGIC.
ONE, PLEASE.
#ON CAPITOL HILL,
#THE TEENAGE DRAFT BILL
HOLDS THE SPOTLIGHT.
#YOUNG MEN ALL OVER THE
NATION
FLOCK TO THE COLORS.
#THE ARMY AND
THE ADMINISTRATION SAY,
#"WE NEED TEENAGE
MANPOWER NOW."
#AND HERE'S THE
RESPONSE.
#GOODBYE. I'M GOING.
#ALL RIGHT.
#BE SURE
YOU WRITE TO US.
#BYE.
#HERE IS A TYPICAL
REPORT
FROM A TEENAGE SOLDIER.
#I'M 19 YEARS OLD.
#BEFORE I WAS IN SERVICE,
#I WAS A DOORMAN
AT RADIO CITY MUSIC HALL.
#AFTER TWO WEEKS
IN SERVICE,
#I WAS
APPOINTED CORPORAL.
#SHORTLY AFTER THAT...
COME
ON.
HI, SALLY.
HI,
HOPPER.
WHERE'S
NICKY?
WHERE DID YOU TWO
GO LAST NIGHT?
OVER TO THE LAKE.
WHAT'S
YOUR DOG'S NAME?
ARGUS.
WHAT'S HE
WEARING THAT FOR?
HE GOT
IT
FOR HIS BIRTHDAY.
COME
ON, ARGUS.
TIME TO GO HOME.
BYE.
COME ON.
GOODBYE.
#[CHRISTMAS MUSIC PLAYING]
ARNIE, CAN WE
KILL THE ANGELS?
THIS MUSIC REMINDS ME
OF MY AUNT IDA.
I EVER TELL YOU
ABOUT MY AUNT IDA?
BEFORE MY MA DIED,
DURING CHRISTMAS
WE HAD THESE FAMILY THINGS.
MY AUNT IDA
WAS ALWAYS THERE
WITH HER DAMN
MISTLETOE HAT.
EVERY TIME
I TURNED AROUND,
IT WAS HER COW LIPS,
WET AND PUCKERED
ON MY FACE.
IT WAS
AWFUL.
WHEN DID SHE DIE?
SHE DIDN'T.
EVERYONE ELSE DID.
PRACTICALLY EVERYONE
IN THE FAMILY.
I THEORIZED MY AUNT
IDA'S KISSING DID IT,
BECAUSE THEY ALL DIED
IN JANUARY AND FEBRUARY,
AND SHE WAS KISSING
IN DECEMBER.
THERE WAS
A DEFINITE CAUSE
AND EFFECT RELATIONSHIP.
IS HE A FRIEND OF YOURS?
HOPPER, WHY
DO YOU
KEEP LOOKING OVER THERE?
NO REASON.
UH-HUH.
I SAW SALLY.
OH,
YEAH? WHERE?
AT THE
POINT.
HOW DID IT GO?
OK, I GUESS.
I THINK
I SPOOKED HER.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WHO KNOWS
WITH WOMEN?
SWITCH WITH ME.
SWITCH
PLACES!
JESUS, HOPPER!
THERE'S A DRAFT HERE.
WHO
IS SHE?
WHO?
WHO
IS SHE?
JUST A GIRL.
HEY,
ARNIE,
ANOTHER VICTIM.
MAY I HELP YOU?
WHAT KIND OF PIE
HAVE YOU GOT TODAY?
BROWN PIE.
I'LL HAVE A PIECE.
COULD YOU
WRAP IT?
YOU
BET.
ONE PIECE
OF BROWN PIE
COMING UP.
I'D
LIKE SOME,
MISTER.
I'M WAITING
ON THE LADY.
I JUST
WANT
ONE PIECE.
IT'S ON SPECIAL
TODAY.
OH.
THANK YOU.
[HONK]
THANKS. BYE-BYE.
HEY, HOPPER,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
THE
MAN'S
OUT OF HIS MIND.
GOOD NIGHT.
HEY.
WAIT UP.
WHAT THE HELL'S
THE MATTER WITH YOU?
AW, SHE'S A
GATSBY.
SHE WORKS
AT THE THEATER.
HER DAD
PROBABLY OWNS IT.
COME ON, LOVER BOY.
LET'S GO HOME.
COME ON.
HEY.
CUSTOMER'S NOT
GOING
ANYWHERE, YOU KNOW.
LISTEN,
HENRY,
YOU KNOW HOW
YOU AND NICKY WANT
TO GET INTO
THIS THING,
BUT IT'S
DIFFERENT
FOR YOUR MOTHER.
THIS WAR SCARES
HER.
THAT'S WHY
SHE'S
RIDING YOU SO HARD.
NOW, WHEN
YOU
GET OVER THERE,
I WANT YOU TO
WRITE.
JUST A FEW
LINES
SO SHE
CAN SLEEP EASIER.
YOU THINK
YOU CAN DO THAT?
HUH?
I BET SHE
LOOKS
LIKE A ROSE
AND SMELLS
AS SWEET.
WHAT'S HER NAME?
I DON'T EVEN KNOW.
REPUBLIC
P-47 THUNDERBOLT.
BULLET-SHAPED
SPINNER.
STRAIGHT TRAILING...
HOW THE HELL
SHOULD I KNOW?
[HORN HONKS]
OH, CHRIST.
OOH.
OH, MRS. SPANGLER.
MM-HMM?
RELIGION'S A LITTLE SHAKY.
I HAVE TO CALL
SAM O'REILLY ABOUT THAT.
I BETTER DO IT NOW.
DAMN IT, ELMER!
SOMEDAY I'LL TAKE
THAT CANE AWAY FROM YOU!
HA HA HA HA!
HI.
HOW
WAS THE PIE?
OH.
FINE.
CAN I HELP YOU
WITH SOMETHING?
NO, THANKS.
JUST
DOING
COLLEGE PREP WORK.
I CAN SEE.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
WHY?
WHAT DO YOU
MEAN WHY?
I DON'T GO OUT
WITH STRANGERS.
WHO SAID ANYTHING
ABOUT GOING OUT?
BESIDES, IF YOU TOLD ME
YOUR NAME,
WE WOULDN'T
BE STRANGERS.
I DON'T THINK SO.
HEY. HOW DID YOU
LIKE THE FLOWERS?
OH, SO YOU'RE
THE ONE.
WELL, AT LEAST
YOU'RE HARMLESS.
HARMLESS?
WHAT THE
HELL
DOES THAT MEAN?
IT COULD HAVE BEEN
SOME MANIAC.
WHAT MAKES
YOU
THINK I'M HARMLESS?
IT'S NOT AN
INSULT.
WHAT ARE YOU,
SOME DOLT?
FIRST I'M HARMLESS,
NOW...
WHAT
THE HELL IS THIS?
AAH!
I TAKE IT
BACK.
YOU'RE DEFINITELY
NOT HARMLESS.
OH, ISN'T HE A DREAM?
JUST LOOKING
AT HIM
MAKES ME FEEL DIZZY.
WHAT WILL IT BE?
A GRILLED CHEESE SANDWICH
AND A CHERRY COKE.
ME, TOO.
DID YOU THINK ABOUT
IT?
CHRISTMAS EVE?
OH.
OH, GRETCHEN.
OH, I DON'T KNOW.
BLIND DATES AGAIN.
I HATE NEW
TOWNS.
WE'LL HAVE A BALL.
I PROMISE.
JUST ONE
NIGHT,
RIGHT?
HE'S SHIPPING OUT.
YOU'LL NEVER
SEE HIM AGAIN.
AND YOU'LL
BE THERE?
EVERY SECOND.
I PROMISE.
OK.
THANKS,
CADDIE!
HE'S A DREAM.
IF HE
WASN'T
MY COUSIN,
I'D GO
OUT
WITH HIM.
HE LOOKS
JUST LIKE
ROBERT WALKER.
I
BET.
WELL, SORT OF.
WHO ARE YOU
GOING WITH?
I THOUGHT
BOBBY MICHAELS,
BUT HE'S
SWORN OFF WOMEN
FOR THE DURATION.
THIS WAR'S
DRIVING THEM CRAZY.
DATE SOMEONE
FROM THE THEATER.
TOO FRESH.
EDDIE RICHARDS TRIED
TO DRAG ME
BEHIND
THE POPCORN MACHINE.
YOU'RE LUCKY
YOU'RE IN THE BOOTH.
INSIDE IT'S HELL.
HEY,
WHAT ABOUT THIS GUY?
HENRY? YOU KNOW HIM?
WE SORT
OF RAN
INTO EACH OTHER
AT THE LIBRARY.
HENRY NASH?
I DIDN'T THINK
HE COULD READ.
HE'S SORT OF
CUTE,
DON'T YOU THINK?
WELL...YEAH,
BUT I COULDN'T
JUST ASK HIM.
LEAVE IT TO ME.
I'LL DO IT.
WATCH THIS.
UM...HENRY?
I HAVE TO APOLOGIZE.
I WAS RUDE EARLIER.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
MY NAME'S
CADDIE WINGER.
HENRY NASH.
IT'S A PLEASURE, HENRY.
ARE YOU
WORKING
THIS AFTERNOON?
WORKING?
YEAH, YOU WORK HERE,
DON'T YOU?
OH, LAST NIGHT.
I WAS JUST
HELPING OUT.
THAT WAS NICE.
I DO WHAT I CAN.
HENRY, I DON'T SUPPOSE
YOU'RE FREE
ON CHRISTMAS EVE.
YOU'RE
PROBABLY
SPENDING IT
WITH YOUR FAMILY.
MY FAMILY.
RIGHT. NO.
OH, NO?
I MEAN I WOULD
BE,
BUT MY MOM--
THAT'S MY MOTHER--
SHE'LL BE
WORKING
WITH THE USO
THAT NIGHT.
AND DAD...
DAD'S, UH...
DAD'S GOING FISHING.
FISHING?
ON
CHRISTMAS EVE?
YEAH.
AT NIGHT?
YEAH, IT'S KIND
OF
A TRADITION.
OTHER PEOPLE
HAVE
TURKEY ON CHRISTMAS.
WE HAVE FISH.
OH.
OH, THAT'S GREAT.
WELL, THEN YOU
ARE
FREE CHRISTMAS EVE?
DEFINITELY.
YOU WANT TO GO
OUT?
DEFINITELY.
GREAT. I
BELIEVE
YOU KNOW GRETCHEN.
HI, HENRY.
HI.
YOU TWO WILL HAVE
A WONDERFUL TIME.
IT'S
PERFECT.
SO ANYWAY,
WE'LL SEE YOU THERE.
YEAH,
OK.
SEE YOU THERE.
OK...OK.
OH, HENRY,
WE'RE GOING
ROLLER-SKATING.
WE'LL MEET AT
7:00.
YOU DO ROLLER-SKATE,
DON'T YOU?
SURE.
YOU LOOK LIKE A USED CAR
SALESMAN.
WHERE ARE
YOU GOING
DRESSED LIKE THAT?
I GOT A DATE.
WITH WHO?
A GIRL.
WHAT ARE
YOU,
MR. DISTRICT ATTORNEY?
A BOY SHOULD
STAY
HOME WITH HIS FAMILY
ON CHRISTMAS EVE.
I'LL BE HOME
ALL DAY TOMORROW.
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
HEY.
OH, HI, DAD.
THANKS FOR THE FLOWERS.
YOU LOOK
JUST LIKE I DID
THE FIRST TIME
I WORE THAT SUIT.
ISN'T IT TOO
BIG?
YOU'LL GROW INTO IT.
BY 8:00?
OH, THERE HE IS.
I SEE HIM.
HEY,
NASH!
YOU GOT
YOUR SKATES.
YEAH. THEY WOULDN'T
LET ME IN
UNLESS I
PUT
THEM ON FIRST.
THIS IS
MICHAEL.
HENRY NASH.
GLAD TO MEET
YOU.
MICHAEL JUST
GOT HIS WINGS.
OH, CONGRATULATIONS.
THANKS.
WHAT BRANCH
ARE YOU JOINING?
MARINES.
TOUGH GROUP.
I'LL TRY NOT TO
DROP ANYTHING ON YOU.
SORRY, EVERYBODY.
HI, HENRY.
THESE ARE FOR YOU.
OH, THEY'RE BEAUTIFUL!
WHERE DID
YOU GET THEM?
I JUST KIND OF
PICKED THEM UP.
HENRY'S VERY BIG
ON FLOWERS.
AREN'T YOU?
YEAH, SURE.
UM...
WELL, UM...
SHALL WE?
ALL RIGHT.
SOMETHING WRONG?
UH,
NO.
GO AHEAD.
I'M JUST GOING
TO WARM UP.
OK.
HEY, MISTER,
LEAVE ME ALONE.
HEY.
LET GO OF MY HAND!
LET GO OF MY
HAND!
LET GO!
THAT LOOKED SCARY.
ONLY IF YOU
DON'T
KNOW WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
THAT WAS GREAT.
THANKS VERY MUCH.
ANYONE FEEL
LIKE A BREATHER?
I
WOULDN'T MIND.
GRETCH, I GUESS
IT'S YOU AND ME.
YOU DAMN MARINES.
YOU NEED
A HAND, HUH?
I DO, YES.
HEY, BUDDY,
YOU'RE NOT ALLOWED
OUT ON THE FLOOR
WITHOUT ANY SKATES!
RELAX. I'M LEAVING.
HERE.
MUST'VE GOTTEN
BAD SKATES.
YEAH. MM-HMM.
SO TELL
ME
ABOUT MICHAEL.
WHAT DO YOU
WANT TO KNOW
ABOUT MICHAEL?
UH...
LIKE...
LIKE IS HE MY BOYFRIEND?
EXCUSE ME?
SO YOUR DAD'S OUT
FISHING TONIGHT?
FISHING. RIGHT. NO.
NO?
I SORT
OF LIED.
YOU DID?
WHY
DID YOU DO THAT?
WHAT DOES
YOUR DAD DO?
HE'S A GRAVE DIGGER.
IT'S NOT ALL
JUST DIGGING HOLES.
THERE'S THE GRASS
AND FLOWERS TO LOOK AFTER.
TREES ALWAYS NEED
CUTTING BACK.
BEING NEAR THE OCEAN
MAKES EVERYTHING GROW FASTER.
THAT'S WHAT HE SAYS.
HE KEEPS IT REAL NICE.
IT'S A NICE
PLACE.
WHY DON'T
YOU TAKE
ME THERE SOMETIME?
SHE'S
A GATSBY GIRL.
IF YOU
ASK ME,
YOU'RE BARKING
UP THE WRONG
PAIR OF GAMS.
WHO ASKED?
I'M JUST
LOOKING
OUT FOR YOU.
LISTEN TO
THIS.
I HEARD THE
NAZIS
GOT THIS THING.
IT GOES
RIGHT FOR IT.
BLOWS THE
WHOLE
PACKAGE RIGHT OFF.
ONE SECOND
YOU'RE JOHN WAYNE,
THE NEXT,
YOU'RE MINNIE MOUSE.
THERE
ARE
OTHER THINGS.
YEAH? LIKE WHAT?
LIKE OTHER
THINGS.
I HATE SEEING
YOU
WASTING TIME
CHASING SOMETHING
YOU CAN'T CATCH.
GO AWAY.
OH! I GET IT!
YOU WANT A PICTURE
FOR YOUR WALLET,
SOMEONE
WHO'LL SEND
FLOWERS, POEMS, AND--
SHUT
UP!
WHAT'S WRONG
WITH THAT?
NOTHING, BUT I WON'T
BE NO SAP TO SOME SKIRT.
WHEN I FINISH
KILLING JAPS,
I AIN'T COMING BACK HERE.
I WANT NOTHING
TO DO WITH THIS PLACE.
GIVE ME YOUR
HAND.
THANK YOU.
HERE.
WHAT IS THIS PLACE?
DANNY'S TAPROOM...
OR WHAT'S LEFT OF IT.
THIS IS THE STAGE.
THAT USED
TO BE THE BAR.
OVER IN THE CORNER WERE
SOME NICKELODEON MACHINES.
THEY'RE GONE NOW.
MY DAD USED
TO
SNEAK ME IN HERE.
WHAT DO YOU DO HERE?
WHATEVER I WANT.
WHAT DO YOU
THINK?
IT'S KIND OF SPOOKY.
YOU WANT TO
LEAVE?
NO. JUST
FEELS LIKE
SOMEONE'S LISTENING.
WHAT IS THIS?
UH...
THIS IS...
THE BEST
THING
ABOUT THIS PLACE.
A
PIANO.
DOES IT WORK?
PLAYS UP
A STORM.
IT COULDN'T.
IT
COULD.
IT'S MAGIC.
MAGIC.
DO YOU PLAY?
A
LITTLE.
PLAY SOMETHING.
[PLAYING CHOPIN MUSIC]
NOT A KEY
STICKS.
HOW DID YOU
LEARN TO PLAY?
LESSONS.
THE DAY EDDIE RICHARDS
TRIES
TO THROW TOMMY LESTER
OUT AT THIRD BASE--
HITS HIM IN THE HEAD--
I'M DOING THIS.
[PLAYING MUSICAL SCALES]
FOR MR. ARTHUR,
MY TEACHER.
TOMMY GETS A CONCUSSION,
AND I MISS IT.
AND I'VE
NEVER FORGIVEN
MY MOTHER FOR THAT.
I WISH I COULD
PLAY LIKE THAT.
COME HERE.
I'LL TEACH YOU.
COME ON. SIT DOWN.
OK, GIVE ME
YOUR HAND.
OK, YOU DO THIS.
[PLAYS#
HEART AND SOUL]
REPEAT IT.
THAT'S IT?
YOU COULD
TRY MY PART.
WHAT'S YOUR PART?
I THINK I'D BETTER GO.
WHEN DO YOU LEAVE?
NEXT MONTH.
[DOORBELL
CHIMES]
SORRY.
I FORGOT MY KEY.
OH, IT'S ALL
RIGHT.
WHAT'S THIS?
ALICE BROUGHT YOU
A PRESENT.
OH, THEY'RE BACK?
DID YOU GET SOMETHING?
SHE GAVE
ME SOME
SCENTED SOAP, A ROBE...
IS IT PRETTY?
IT'S
PRETTY.
IT'S A SIZE 44.
OH,
MOM!
WHERE IS SHE?
SHE'S UPSTAIRS.
I'M GOING TO
TRY IT ON.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
JUST A
MINUTE.
ALICE, THIS
IS BEAUTIFUL.
I THOUGHT
IT WOULD BE.
IT ANNOYS ME I CAN'T
WEAR THAT COLOR.
I DON'T
KNOW
WHAT TO SAY.
MERRY CHRISTMAS
WILL DO.
MERRY
CHRISTMAS.
CHRISTMAS,
CADDIE.
SIT
DOWN.
I
THOUGHT YOUR
FIRST CHRISTMAS
IN A
STRANGE
NEW TOWN
WOULDN'T BE
YOUR FAVORITE.
THANK YOU,
ALICE.
[KNOCK KNOCK]
HELLO,
CADDIE.
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
DON'T YOU
LOOK PRETTY.
MERRY
CHRISTMAS,
MR. DONNELLY.
ALICE,
THERE'S
WHIPPED CREAM
AND EGGS
ALL OVER THE
PANTRY.
WILL YOU HURRY?
I'M
HURRYING, DADDY.
LIKE THOSE
PEARLS, CADDIE?
BEAUTIFUL.
PLEASE, DARLING?
YES,
DADDY.
HEY, NASH.
HI.
AREN'T YOU SUPPOSED
TO BE IN SCHOOL?
SOMETIMES YOU JUST
DON'T MAKE IT.
HOW COME?
I DON'T KNOW. I
FIGURE,
WHAT'S THE POINT?
IF YOU WERE
IN SCHOOL,
YOU WOULDN'T
HAVE TO LEAVE YET.
I'LL HAVE TO GO
EVENTUALLY.
HOW ABOUT YOU?
I FINISHED UP EARLY
AT MY OLD SCHOOL
'CAUSE
WE WERE MOVING.
THAT'S GOOD.
SO, I GUESS
YOU GOT PLANS
FOR THIS MORNING.
NO.
YOU?
NO, I DON'T.
YOU SURE YOU KNOW
WHERE YOU'RE GOING?
POSITIVE. NICKY PUT AN ARROW
AROUND HERE SOMEPLACE.
THAT TREE.
THERE'S AN ARROW
ON THE OTHER SIDE.
THERE IS!
THAT ARROW POINTS
DIRECTLY TO THE POND.
GOOD
OLD NICKY.
STRAIGHT UP?
NICKY ALWAYS
WAS
A FOOL.
WELL, WE
KNOW
IT'S NOT THAT WAY,
SO IT'S GOT TO BE
THAT WAY
OR THAT WAY.
OR
SOMEWHERE
IN BETWEEN.
RIGHT.
I WISH ARGUS WAS
HERE.
HA HA
HA!
YOU FOUND IT?
OH!
OH, THAT'S BEAUTIFUL.
HOW DID
YOU FIND
THIS PLACE ANYWAY?
MY FATHER
SORT OF GAVE IT
TO ME AND NICKY.
GAVE IT TO YOU?
HE'D MAKE
THESE TREASURE MAPS.
WE'D FOLLOW THEM
AND DIG WHATEVER
WAS UP AT THE END.
ONE TIME
WE ENDED UP HERE.
HE WRAPPED UP
THIS WATCH. SEE THERE?
HE PUT IT OUT THERE
IN THE MIDDLE.
WE SLOSHED AROUND
IN THE MUD FOR AN HOUR,
CRAWLING AROUND.
DAD DIDN'T CARE
WHETHER WE FOUND
THE WATCH OR NOT.
IT WAS THIS
PLACE.
HE SOUNDS WONDERFUL.
WHAT DO
YOU SAY
WE COOL OFF?
IT'S JANUARY.
WHEW,
IT'S HOT.
WE CAN COME BACK
IN SPRING
WHEN IT'S WARM.
I WON'T BE HERE
COME
ON.
WHAT DO YOU SAY?
WHEW, IT'S HOT.
WHEW, HOT.
HOT.
I'M SO HOT.
I DON'T HAVE
MY BATHING SUIT ON.
OH.
WELL...
ME AND NICKY
NEVER USED TO WEAR
BATHING SUITS.
OH.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU CAN WEAR
YOUR UNDERSTUFF,
SEEING THIS IS
JANUARY
AND ALL.
WHOO! WHOO!
COME
ON!
IT'S GREAT!
COME
ON!
HOO HOO!
HURRY UP.
JUST JUMP
IN.
IT'S REALLY COLD.
SO...
DOES ANYBODY
ELSE
KNOW ABOUT THIS PLACE?
I DON'T THINK SO.
I GUESS WE HAVE
IT
TO OURSELVES, THEN.
YEAH. I GUESS
SO.
IT'S THAT NOT
BAD.
I'M GETTING
USED TO IT.
YOUR BODY
JUST
HAS TO ADJUST.
WHAT MADE YOU THINK
OF COMING HERE?
I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S ONE
OF
MY FAVORITE PLACES.
YOU'RE SHAKING.
SO ARE YOU.
SHE'S A NICE
GIRL.
AND MONEY
ON TOP OF IT.
YOU'RE LUCKY, HOP.
I THINK SHE'S
THE ONE, NICKY.
YOU KNOW WHAT I
MEAN?
JOHNNY
LESTER
CAME IN TODAY.
HIS BROTHER'S DEAD.
TOMMY?
HE
DIED
ON AN ISLAND.
GUADEL--OR...
GUODO--
GUADALCANAL.
YEAH.
FUNERAL'S
TOMORROW.
WE'RE INVITED.
WANT TO GO?
I DON'T
THINK SO.
ME EITHER.
YOU KNOW
WHAT I WANT, HENRY?
I WANT AN EAGLE
RIGHT HERE.
A TATTOO. YEAH.
WAIT TILL THOSE JAPS
SEE ME AND MY EAGLE
COME CHARGING
OVER THE HILL.
JUST COME
CHARGING OVER THE HILL.
THERE'S A WAR
OUT THERE SOMEWHERE, HOP.
SO, THEY'RE
IN THIS SUBMARINE, RIGHT?
THE JAPS ARE GOING AT
THEM
WITH EVERYTHING THEY GOT.
GUYS ARE DROWNING, ON FIRE,
AND THEY GOT GUNS,
SO YOU KNOW
WHAT TYRONE POWER SAYS?
HE SAYS "FUCK
'EM!"
JUST LIKE THAT.
TYRONE POWER NEVER
SAID "FUCK 'EM."
THAT'S WHEN HE DOES IT.
HE SERVES A MEAL
IN TOKYO HARBOR.
JEEZ! WHAT BALLS!
MAYBE WE
SHOULD JOIN
THE SUBMARINE CORPS.
PUSSIES.
WHAT?
THEY'RE PUSSIES!
NO.
TYRONE POWER
IS NOT A PUSSY.
YOU WOULDN'T
KNOW A PUSSY
IF YOU SAW ONE.
OH, YEAH?
YEAH. YOU KNOW
WHY?
YOU KNOW
BECAUSE
YOU DRINK TOO MUCH.
ME?
PISSES ME
OFF.
PISSES ME OFF BADLY
'CAUSE WHEN
YOU
DRINK TOO MUCH
IT MAKES YOUR BRAIN
SOFT.
LET ME--I GOT
TO SHOW YOU SOMETHING.
BEFORE I STARTED
DRINKING,
I COULDN'T DO THAT.
WHY WOULD YOU
WANT TO DO THAT?
IT GIVES ME PLEASURE.
OH, WOWIE!
WOWIE!
RIGHT HERE...
CLEAR ACROSS
MY GOD DAMN CHEST.
A REAL PATRIOT,
HUH?
DAMN RIGHT.
IN JUST FOUR WEEKS,
WE'LL BE PROUD
MEMBERS
OF THE UNITED STATES
MARINE CORPS.
LUCKY US.
UH-HUH!
LISTEN, KID.
I'LL DO YOU A FAVOR.
I'M NOT PUTTING
ANYTHING ON YOUR CHEST.
THAT WAY,
IN THE MORNING,
YOU'LL STILL HAVE THAT
WONDERFUL BABY PINK SKIN.
YOU'LL THANK
ME,
BELIEVE ME.
THIS IS
THE BIRD OF FREEDOM
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT.
ANY AMERICAN
WOULD BE PROUD
TO CARRY THAT.
YOU OUGHT TO CUT
DOWN
ON THE NEWSREELS.
YOU GIVE TATTOOS
OR ADVICE?
ALL RIGHT. HOW
MUCH
HAVE YOU BOYS GOT?
I...UH...
UM, I
GOT $1.25.
I GOT 13 CENTS.
$1.38
WILL GET YOU
A SPARROW ON YOUR ELBOW.
A SPARROW?
OR HOW ABOUT A
SNAKE
COMING OUT OF YOUR NAVEL?
YOU'VE
GOT TO BE KIDDING!
HE'S
KIDDING,
RIGHT, HOP?
I'M TALKING ABOUT
THE HIGH-FLYING
BIRD OF FREEDOM!
BIRD OF
FREEDOM
DON'T COME CHEAP.
BAH-HUH!
A SNAKE COMING
OUT OF MY NAVEL.
HE'S PROBABLY
SOME KIND OF NAZI.
HEY...LISTEN.
IT'S THE TRAIN.
TOUCH THE RAIL
WITH YOUR SHOE.
YOU CAN FEEL IT.
LET'S RACE IT,
LIKE WHEN WE WERE KIDS.
WE'RE DRUNK.
WHO CARES?
I WANT TO RACE IT.
WE'LL GET KILLED.
NO, WE WON'T.
THIS TRAIN'S
AN OLD FRIEND.
IT WOULD
NEVER HURT US.
HERE SHE COMES!
COME ON, HOPPER.
RACE
WITH ME!
RACE WITH ME!
[TRAIN
WHISTLE]
RACE WITH
ME!
[WHISTLE]
RACE
WITH ME, HOP!
YA-HA!
NICKY!
NICKY.
HOO-HOO!
NICKY,
WHERE YOU GOING?
HEY,
WAIT UP,
WILL YOU?
YOU ALL RIGHT?
SHE'S LATE, HOP.
WHAT?
SALLY.
SHE'S PREGNANT.
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
THREE WEEKS
TILL WE LEAVE,
AND SHE HITS ME
WITH THIS.
YOU GOT
TO
HELP ME, HOP.
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
TO GET
THE MONEY.
THE MONEY?
FOR AN
ABORTION.
AN
ABORTION?
NICKY.
DIDN'T YOU
USE ANYTHING?
IT JUST
HAPPENED.
YOU'VE BEEN
SEEING THIS GIRL
FOR FOUR MONTHS!
SO?
SO JESUS CHRIST,
NICKY!
SO JESUS CHRIST, NICKY!
JESUS CHRIST, NICKY!
I'M PAYING FOR
IT,
ALL RIGHT?
NO. SHE'S
PAYING
FOR IT, NICKY!
SHE'S PAYING FOR IT.
HOP, SINCE WHEN DID YOU
BECOME SUCH A SAINT?
HUH, HOP?
THE ONLY DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN ME AND YOU
IS YOU'VE BEEN LUCKY,
THAT'S ALL!
THAT'S IT, HOP!
HOW MUCH?
EDDIE SAYS IT
COSTS 150
FOR A CLEAN ONE.
150? WHERE ARE WE
GOING TO GET THAT?
WE'LL DO LIKE WE DID
WHEN
WE NEEDED
A NEW TRANSMISSION.
WE ALMOST
GOT KILLED!
WHAT
OTHER WAY
IS THERE?
I'LL
THINK
ABOUT IT.
COME ON.
MY DEAR FRIENDS IN CHRIST,
WE ARE GATHERED HERE TODAY
TO LAY TO REST THE SOUL
OF THOMAS ALLEN LESTER,
WHO GAVE HIS LIFE IN THE
SERVICE OF HIS COUNTRY.
WE ASK GOD
TO WATCH OVER HIM. AMEN.
TO THE FLAG,
FACE!
HUT!
TO THE FRONT, FACE!
FORWARD...HUT!
HUT!
TO THE FLAG,
FACE!
HUT!
HELLO THERE,
STRANGER.
YOU UP EARLY OR LATE?
LATE.
LET YOUR MOTHER
KNOW NEXT TIME.
OK.
YOU WANT TO TALK?
LET'S HURRY,
NURSES.
WE DON'T
WANT
TO LOSE ANYONE.
MORE VOLUME,
ARNOLD!
#[ROCKET FALLING]
#[BOOM]
REMEMBER, SOLDIERS,
IF YOU'RE WOUNDED,
REMAIN LYING DOWN
UNTIL A NURSE REACHES YOU.
IF YOU'RE DEAD,
REMAIN LYING DOWN.
TRY TO GIVE COMFORT
TO YOUR PATIENTS.
REMEMBER, BLOOD
DOESN'T BOTHER YOU
BECAUSE YOU ARE
PROFESSIONAL NURSES.
HE MIGHT BE DEAD
ALREADY. SORRY.
WHERE
ARE YOU HURT?
HE SLIPPED AWAY.
I'M COMING AROUND.
I'LL
COME BACK
LATER.
WAIT. I'LL SHOW YOU
MY WOUND.
R.D., STOP.
GET ON.
GO TO THE
RECORDS.
OW! OW! OW!
YOU'RE
LOOKING
AFTER SICK MEN,
SO BE CAREFUL.
THAT'S
THE IDEA.
YOU
MIGHT GET
SOME BANDAGES.
YOUR
MOTHER
JUST CALLED.
WHAT ABOUT MY RECORDS?
WE'LL WATCH THEM
FOR YOU.
IT'S
AN EMERGENCY.
BUT--
NO BUTS!
HOP TO IT!
HURRY. BERLIN
BLITZ IS ENDING.
PREPARE FOR THE
WORST
SHELLING YET.
#
# HE WAS A FAMOUS TRUMPET
MAN FROM OUT CHICAGO WAY
# HE HAD A BOOGIE SOUND
THAT NO ONE ELSE COULD PLAY
# HE WAS A TOP MAN
OF HIS CRAFT
WHAT'S GOING
ON HERE?
STOP THAT CARRYING ON!
YOU JUST HOLD IT!
# HE'S THE BOOGIE-WOOGIE
BUGLE BOY FROM COMPANY B
STOP THAT!
OH!
THAT'S NOT
FUNNY.
IT'S A JOKE.
IT'S NOT
FUNNY.
IT'S NOT A FUNNY JOKE?
NO. YOU
KNOW,
YOU'RE REALLY
STUPID SOMETIMES.
WHAT'S THAT
SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
WHAT ARE
YOU
DOING RIGHT NOW?
BLEEDING.
GET YOURSELF CLEANED
UP
AND MEET ME OUTSIDE.
WHERE ARE WE
GOING?
YOU'LL SEE.
IT'S A HOSPITAL.
THAT'S
RIGHT.
SMART.
I'M SMART.
SMARTER
THAN YOU LOOK.
I'M SMARTER
THAN I LOOK.
THAT'S GOOD.
BEEP BEEP!
GOOD
IDEA.
YOU HAVING FUN?
I'M HAVING
A REAL GOOD TIME.
I'M GLAD
YOU'RE HAVING FUN.
HI!
YOU
KNOW
WHO'S IN HERE?
SICK PEOPLE.
YOU WANT TO GO
IN?
YOU BET.
OK.
HERE WE ARE.
[WHISTLES]
WHOO!
HEY!
[WHISTLES]
ALL RIGHT. HENRY NASH
RIGHT HERE.
ALL RIGHT,
HENRY!
HEY, HENRY.
HE'S MY BODYGUARD,
ALL RIGHT?
SO DON'T TRY
ANY FUNNY STUFF.
HENRY, GIVE
EACH PERSON A BOOK.
LEAVE ONE
ON THE EMPTY BEDS.
GOOD.
HI.
OH, GOOD. YOU FOUND IT.
IT WAS
ON ORDER.
WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE?
YOU GOT
ANY HAMMETT?
HAMMETT?
YEAH.
DASHIELL HAMMETT.
I'LL CHECK THE CART.
THAT'S OK.
IT'LL JUST TAKE A SECOND.
RELAX. FORGET
IT.
WHAT'S YOUR
NAME?
HENRY, SIR.
HOW OLD
ARE YOU?
17, SIR.
HOW OLD
DO YOU THINK I AM?
I'M
22.
YOU CALL
EVERYBODY
WHO'S 22 SIR?
NO, SIR.
I MEAN, NO.
MY NAME'S
FRANK.
GUESS
THEY'LL BE
CALLING YOU UP SOON.
FEBRUARY 12th.
GO AHEAD. LOOK AT
IT.
I DO...
ALL DAY
LONG.
SOMETIMES, YOU KNOW,
I CAN STILL FEEL IT.
THAT'S THE GOD'S
TRUTH.
ONLY
HALF-BELIEVE
IT'S GONE.
YOU GET
IT?
HALF?
JUST
GIVE ME
WHATEVER
YOU GOT THERE.
THANKS.
HENRY.
THERE'S A TRAIN
THAT RUNS THROUGH HERE.
A FREIGHT.
ME AND NICKY RACED IT
ABOUT A HUNDRED TIMES.
YOU CAN FEEL THE HEAT
ON YOUR LEGS.
GONDOLA CAR'S
YOUR BEST BET.
IT'S GOT THESE HANDLES.
ONCE YOU GET YOUR GRIP,
IT'S EASY.
PULL UP,
LET HER TAKE YOU.
IF YOU'RE NOT CAREFUL,
THE WIND BLOWS YOU UNDER.
THAT
SOUNDS
DANGEROUS.
THAT'S WHY WE DID IT.
I DIDN'T NEED YOU
TO TEACH ME SOME LESSON.
I'M
SORRY.
SORRY I TOOK
YOU IN THERE.
IT'S
JUST, YOU
MADE ME SO MAD
THIS MORNING.
HOW COME YOU
NEVER
TALK ABOUT IT?
WHAT?
THE WAR.
WHAT'S THERE
TO TALK ABOUT?
YOU
MUST
THINK ABOUT IT.
I THINK ABOUT IT
ALL THE TIME.
I MEAN, BEFORE,
IT WAS JUST THERE.
BUT NOW,
BEING AROUND YOU,
I THINK ABOUT THINGS.
LIKE
WHAT SORT
OF THINGS?
COMING BACK.
I'M GOING TO BE
ALL RIGHT, YOU KNOW?
TANGERINE
SHE IS ALL THEY CLAIM
WITH HER EYES OF NIGHT
AND LIPS AS BRIGHT
AS FLAME
TANGERINE
WHEN SHE DANCES BY
SEORITAS STARE
AND CABALLEROS SIGH
AND I'VE SEEN
TIMES WHEN TANGERINE
HAD THE BOURGEOISIE
BELIEVING SHE WERE QUEEN
YES, SHE'S HAD THEM
ALL
ON THE RUN
BUT HER HEART
BELONGS TO JUST ONE
HER HEART
BELONGS TO TANGERINE
NICKY!
WHY DO I
LET YOU
WORK HERE?
'CAUSE NOBODY LAYS DOWN
A SET OF PINS FASTER THAN ME.
I'M THE BEST YOU GOT.
NO,
YOU'RE NOT.
OH.
WELL, THEN...
YOU GOT ME, BOSS.
SO?
SO WHAT?
YOU SAID
YOU'D THINK ABOUT IT.
ABOUT
WHAT?
COME ON.
SALLY. THE MONEY.
I AM THINKING ABOUT IT.
HOP, WE ONLY
GOT
A COUPLE OF WEEKS.
SHIT.
COME ON. GET UP.
GET UP. WAIT.
GET UP.
COME ON.
OK.
YOU'RE
GOING TO GET IT.
YOU ARE
GOING
TO BE SORRY.
YOU SEE
THIS?
OOH! I'M SORRY!
OH, I DIDN'T--
OH, I'M SORRY.
LET ME SEE.
OH, I GOT YOU
IN THE EYE.
IT HURTS.
OH, LOOK AT THOSE
SHOES.
AREN'T THEY PRETTY?
SEE?
DON'T YOU LIKE
THOSE?
I LOVE THOSE.
AREN'T THEY BEAUTIFUL?
HOW DO THEY FEEL?
I
LIKE THEM.
I LOVE THEM.
#CERTO BENE!# OF COURSE!
THEY WERE MADE FOR YOU.
HOW MUCH ARE THEY?
$25.
25.
NOT UNREASONABLE
FOR SUCH MARVELOUS WORK,
DON'T YOU THINK?
NOT
UNREASONABLE.
WELL,
THANK YOU.
THINK ABOUT IT.
YOU'LL COME BACK,
I'M SURE.
OH,
THANK YOU.
WELL, ANYWAY...
IT'S A PLEASURE.
I LOVE
THEM.
THANKS A LOT.
GOODBYE.
GOODBYE, HENRY.
WHAT
HAPPENED?
HMM?
YOU
DIDN'T
BUY THE SHOES.
OF COURSE NOT.
YOU CAN'T JUST BUY
EVERYTHING YOU WANT.
THAT'S
RIGHT.
I CAN.
I'M
JUST
KIDDING YOU,
GATSBY GIRL.
WHAT? BUT HOW?
I DON'T
KNOW.
IT'S NOT
FUNNY.
IT IS SORT OF FUNNY.
IT
ISN'T.
DID YOU EVER TELL HIM
YOU WERE RICH?
NO.
THEN NO SKIN
OFF YOUR NOSE.
IF HE WANTS TO BELIEVE
YOU'RE RICH, LET HIM.
AS FAR AS I SEE,
YOU'VE GOT NO PROBLEM.
MAYBE
THAT'S
WHY HE LIKES ME.
WELL, SO WHAT?
HE'S LEAVING SOON ANYWAY.
IT'S NOT LIKE YOU'RE
IN LOVE WITH HIM.
UH-OH.
$1.35, PLEASE.
HI,
HENRY.
CADDIE.
I THOUGHT YOU HAD
TO WORK TONIGHT.
I THOUGHT
MAYBE
WE COULD TALK.
KIND OF BUSY.
IS 1
OPEN?
YEAH.
COMING TO MY BIRTHDAY
TOMORROW?
YEAH.
NOT MUCH...
JUST YOU AND NICKY.
I WANTED TO TALK
BECAUSE...
I
GOT--
JUST SIT DOWN
A SECOND, OK?
BALL'S
COMING BACK.
WHAT ARE
YOU
DOING HERE?
I NEED YOU.
IT'S UNDER
CONTROL.
NICKY, YOU PROMISED.
YOU DIDN'T
HAVE TO COME HERE.
YOU PROMISED.
STOP
SAYING
I PROMISED YOU!
DON'T LEAVE ME
BY MYSELF.
I'M NOT LEAVING
YOU
BY YOURSELF.
YOU'RE
GOING TO BE OK.
WOMEN.
THANK YOU.
WHAT'S THE
MATTER
WITH HER?
NOTHING.
HOPPER!
I GOT TO GO.
YOU LOOK
REAL PRETTY.
I'LL
DO IT.
THEY'RE TOO BIG.
WHAT DO YOU
MEAN?
YOU'LL SHOOT
POOL WITH THEM,
NOT WRESTLE THEM.
I'M THINKING ABOUT AFTER
I SHOOT POOL WITH THEM,
AND THEY REALIZE
THEY'VE BEEN HUSTLED.
AND THEY WILL.
THEY'RE JUST
TWO STUPID UNIFORMS.
BESIDES,
THERE'S A FIRE EXIT
RIGHT OVER THERE...
JUST IN
CASE.
AFTERNOON, GENTS.
SOMEONE SAID YOU'RE
LOOKING FOR A GAME.
SOMEONE SAID
WRONG.
YEAH, THAT'S
WHAT I THOUGHT
BECAUSE NAVY BOYS
DON'T HAVE THE SKILL
TO PLAY FOR MONEY.
ALL THAT TIME ON SHIPS
AFFECTS THEIR BALANCE.
THERE'S NOTHING
WRONG
WITH MY BALANCE.
SURE. DON'T LET ME
HOLD UP YOUR GAME.
THAT'S A TOUGH BREAK.
WANT TO
PLAY?
I'LL PLAY YOU.
I GOT A BAD WRIST.
MY FRIEND WILL PLAY.
HOW
ABOUT IT?
SURE.
GREAT.
HEY, WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
BILL.
GLAD TO MEET YOU.
I'M BUD,
AND THAT'S LOU.
NOW THAT WE'RE FRIENDS,
LET'S GET DOWN TO BUSINESS.
HOW'S $5.00 SOUND?
YEAH.
THAT SOUNDS OK.
8-BALL'S THE GAME.
YOU DO KNOW HOW TO PLAY,
DON'T YOU, BILL?
I
KNOW HOW.
TERRIFIC.
8 IN THE
CORNER.
20 BUCKS YOU OWE
ME.
NOW, WILLIAM,
NOT SO FAST.
MY BOY'S
JUST WARMING UP.
HOW ABOUT
IF WE MAKE THINGS
MORE INTERESTING?
HOW ABOUT WE SEE
SOME GREEN ON THE TABLE?
DOES THIS
ANSWER YOUR QUESTION?
NOBODY TOUCHES MY MONEY.
SOME OF THAT'S
MINE.
NOT YET IT AIN'T.
10 BUCKS A GAME,
ALL RIGHT?
SHE DREAMED
ABOUT ME
LAST NIGHT.
SHIT.
NICKY,
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
WOULD
YOU RELAX?
THIS IS PERFECT.
EXCUSE ME, BOYS.
WE'VE GOT A LITTLE
CONTEST
GOING ON HERE.
I THOUGHT
YOU'D BE INTERESTED
IN A LITTLE ACTION.
WHAT KIND OF ACTION?
IT JUST SO HAPPENS
THAT YESTERDAY
MORNING
I SOLD MY CAR--
A DANDY LITTLE
1932 PLYMOUTH.
IT'S ALL HERE. 150 BUCKS.
I DON'T HAVE
THAT KIND OF MONEY.
MAYBE YOUR SHIPMATES DO.
HOW ABOUT IT, GUYS?
WILLING TO BACK
YOUR BUDDY?
HOW MUCH YOU
GOT?
WAIT A MINUTE.
THAT'S A LOT OF MONEY.
WHAT'S THE MATTER, WILLIAM,
YOU LOSING YOUR NERVE?
40.
60.
150 BUCKS.
STRAIGHT POOL.
FIRST ONE TO
100.
THAT OK WITH
YOU,
BUD...
OR WAS IT
LOU?
CALL
IT.
HEADS.
TAILS. YOU
BREAK.
14 IN THE CORNER.
2. CORNER.
5. CROSS CORNER.
YEAH.
SO?
7 IN THE SIDE.
HE'S
GOOD.
HOW GOOD?
A LOT BETTER THAN HE
WAS
FIVE MINUTES AGO.
4 IN THE
CORNER.
12 IN THE
3 IN THE
SIDE.
RACK 'EM.
2 IN THE
CORNER.
13 IN THE SIDE.
4 IN THE
SIDE.
12 IN THE CORNER.
15 IN THE
SIDE.
8 IN THE
CORNER.
3 IN THE
RACK
'EM.
10 IN THE CORNER.
8 IN THE
CORNER.
5 IN THE CORNER.
15 IN THE SIDE.
11 IN THE CORNER.
RACK 'EM.
7 IN THE
CORNER.
1 IN THE CORNER.
12 IN THE
CORNER.
5 IN THE
9 IN THE
CORNER.
14 IN THE CORNER.
RACK 'EM.
6 IN THE CORNER.
2 SIDE.
7 CORNER.
10 CORNER.
14 IN THE CORNER.
OH, EAT MINE, SHITHEAD!
YOU'RE DEAD!
TWO MORE POINTS!
WHAT'S WRONG?
I DON'T
HAVE A SHOT.
WHAT ARE YOU
GOING TO DO?
MAKE SURE
HE DOESN'T EITHER.
3 IN THE CORNER.
OH, NO. HE
CAN'T
MAKE THAT. RIGHT?
RIGHT?
AAH!
7 IN THE SIDE.
WHOO!
YAY!
WELL, FAIR IS
FAIR,
BOYS.
WE'LL JUST
BE RUNNING ALONG.
MIND IF WE COUNT IT?
COUNT
IT.
IT'S NOT
THAT
WE DON'T TRUST YOU.
BAD
IDEA, BOYS.
THERE SEEMS
TO BE A MIX-UP HERE.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I KNOW FOR A FACT
THAT WHEN WE WALKED
INTO THIS ESTABLISHMENT
AND, UH...SHIT!
DUCK,
HOPPER!
WE GOT IT!
GOD,
WHERE ARE WE HEADED?
LET'S GO!
WHAT'S WRONG?
IT TAKES
TIME.
START IT,
OR MY DAD
WILL DIG OUR HOLES.
[ENGINE SPUTTERS]
YA-HA!
HA HA HA HA!
HA HA!
IT'S ABOUT
TIME.
WHAT
HAPPENED
TO YOU TWO?
YOU KNOW
WHAT TROUBLE YOUR
MOTHER'S GONE TO?
YOU CAN'T
EVEN BE ON TIME
FOR YOUR OWN
BIRTHDAY, HENRY.
WHAT HAPPENED?
RUN-IN
WITH THE NAVY.
WHAT? WHERE?
UP
NORTH.
WHAT WERE YOU DOING?
PLAYING
POOL.
IT WAS MORE
LIKE HUSTLING.
WE NEEDED SOME MONEY.
KNOCK IT
OFF.
WHAT?
I KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
SHE'S
OUR
LAST CHANCE.
SHUT UP!
SHOULD I LEAVE
SALLY
HERE PREGNANT?
YOU SON OF A BITCH!
WHAT'S GOING ON?
DAMN IT, CADDIE,
I NEED $150!
YOU'VE GOT
SOME MOUTH!
I TOLD
YOU BOYS
TO GET READY.
SPEED IT UP.
HENRY,
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
WILL YOU SIT
DOWN?
CADDIE, THIS
IS
VERY HARD FOR ME.
THE WAY
I'VE BEEN RAISED,
PEOPLE DON'T
ASK
FOR THINGS.
YOU SEE...
THAT GIRL YOU
SAW
LAST NIGHT...
NICKY
GOT HER PREGNANT.
WE GOT TO GET
HER
AN ABORTION.
A CLEAN
ABORTION
COSTS $150.
NICKY AND I
DON'T HAVE THAT
KIND OF MONEY.
YOU
KNOW
WHAT I'M SAYING?
I'M NOT SURE.
CADDIE...
CAN YOU GET US
THE
MONEY? IT'S $150.
I'LL MAKE
SURE
YOU GET EVERY
BIT
OF IT BACK.
I'LL SEE
WHAT I CAN DO.
[DOOR OPENS]
CADDIE, WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
WHY DO YOU
HAVE MY NECKLACE?
YOU SHOULD HAVE
ASKED FIRST.
LOOK...
RELAX.
IT'S OK, REALLY.
DO YOU WANT
TO TRY IT ON?
COME ON.
OH, NO,
I COULDN'T.
WHAT'S THE
MATTER
WITH YOU?
I WANT
TO GO DOWNSTAIRS.
WHY
ARE YOU
SO NERVOUS?
I WASN'T TRYING IT ON.
WHAT ARE
YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
I NEED MONEY.
I WAS TAKING
THE NECKLACE.
WHY WOULD
YOU DO
SOMETHING LIKE THAT?
CADDIE,
ARE YOU IN TROUBLE?
OH, ALICE.
ALICE...
I'VE MADE A MESS
OF THINGS.
THERE'S SOMEBODY
WHO NEEDS
SOMETHING FROM ME,
AND I JUST WANT
TO GIVE IT TO HIM.
I ALMOST DID
A HORRIBLE THING,
BUT IT'S ONLY BECAUSE
I DON'T WANT
TO LET HIM DOWN.
I WONDER WHAT IT'S LIKE
TO BE YOU SOMETIMES.
I MEAN...
EVERYTHING SEEMS
SO MUCH EASIER FOR YOU.
NOT
SO MUCH.
I'LL
GET YOU
THE MONEY.
I DON'T WANT YOU
IN THERE.
I GUESS THEY SHOULD BE
STARTING IN A FEW MINUTES.
IT SHOULDN'T
TAKE TOO LONG.
THERE'S ANOTHER GIRL
COMING AT 11:00.
BOY, 150 BUCKS A SHOT.
THAT'S SOME BUSINESS, HUH?
YOU
SHOULD
GO IN THERE
AND
HOLD HER HAND.
SHE DOESN'T
WANT ME IN THERE.
I'M
SICK.
#...THE EXACT LOCATION
FROM WHICH I'M SPEAKING.
#OFF TO MY LEFT,
FAR IN THE DISTANCE,
#I CAN SEE THE FAINT RED
ANGRY SNAP OF ANTI-AIRCRAFT
#AGAINST
THIS STEEL-BLUE SKY.
# DOO DOO
DOODLY YA-DA DOO
# HE BLOWS IT
EIGHT TO THE BAR
# IN BOOGIE RHYTHM
# HE CAN'T PLAY A NOTE
# UNLESS THE BASS AND
GUITAR ARE PLAYING WITH HIM
# HE MAKES
HIS COMPANY JUMP
# WHEN HE PLAYS
REVEILLE...
NICKY.
HUH?
WILL YOU STOP, PLEASE?
STOP,
PLEASE.
STOP THE CAR.
WHAT'S THE MATTER,
CADDIE?
I WANT TO GET OUT.
IT'S
ONLY
A FEW BLOCKS.
WOULD YOU STOP
THE DAMN CAR?
CADDIE, WHERE ARE
YOU GOING?
HOME.
I'LL WALK YOU.
I DON'T
WANT
YOU TO WALK ME.
YOU'RE THINKING
THAT YOU COULD'VE
BEEN IN THERE.
I'D NEVER TAKE YOU THERE.
I'D MARRY YOU.
DID YOU HEAR WHAT I SAID?
WELL,
WHAT
MAKES YOU THINK
I'D MARRY YOU?
GET IN THE CAR.
NO.
GET IN THE GOD DAMN CAR!
LET GO!
OH, I'M
SORRY.
I DIDN'T
KNOW
YOU WOULD GO
INTO THAT PLACE.
WHAT DO
YOU WANT
FROM ME?
I DON'T WANT ANYTHING
FROM YOU.
HEY.
I'M TALKING TO YOU.
IT'S THE
MONEY,
RIGHT?
YOU THINK I
TOOK
ADVANTAGE OF YOU.
CADDIE, WE
NEEDED
THAT MONEY.
YOU'RE THE
ONLY
RICH PERSON I KNOW.
YOU ARE
SUCH AN IDIOT.
I'M NOT RICH.
WHAT?
WHAT ARE
YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
YES, I LIVE
IN THAT HOUSE.
DO YOU KNOW WHY?
BECAUSE MY MOTHER
WORKS THERE.
MY MOM IS A MAID.
SHE'S A MAID
IN THAT HOUSE.
GOD DAMN YOU!
I TRIED TO TELL YOU,
BUT YOU'RE SO PLEASED
WITH YOUR LITTLE GIRL
ON THE HILL
THAT I DIDN'T WANT
TO DISAPPOINT YOU.
JUST LEAVE ME ALONE.
LEAVE ME ALONE.
HOP, YOU COMING?
[HONK HONK]
HOP.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
THAT'S MY OLD MAN'S CAR,
YOU CRAZY SON OF A BITCH!
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
YOU, NICKY!
YOU'RE THE MATTER!
I'M ALWAYS
GETTING
YOU OUT OF MESSES!
IT'S OVER.
SHUT UP! SHUT
UP!
SALLY COULD
HAVE
DIED TONIGHT.
THAT EVER
CROSSED YOUR MIND?
BUT SHE DIDN'T!
JESUS, YOU JUST
DON'T
GET IT, DO YOU?
THEN YOU GET HER
MIXED UP IN IT.
I'M SICK OF
YOU
MESSING UP
MY LIFE, NICKY.
I'M SICK OF
IT.
YOU
DIDN'T EVEN
OPEN THE DOOR
FOR HER, NICKY.
THE
GIRL
HAD AN ABORTION.
YOU
CAN'T EVEN
OPEN THE DOOR
FOR HER.
DAMN COLD
FOR FEBRUARY.
LAID A BED OF
THESE
LAST NIGHT.
THIS MORNING
THE GROUND WAS
STILL LIKE ROCK.
YOUR MOM
SAYS
NICKY'S BEEN
BY
THREE TIMES
THIS PAST WEEK.
YOU
KNOW YOUR OWN MIND.
JUST SEEMS
YOU COULD USE
EACH OTHERS' COMPANY
ABOUT NOW.
FOR A TIME
RIGHT
AFTER HIS MOM DIED,
NICKY
BROUGHT
FLOWERS HERE
EVERY DAY.
COME AFTER
SCHOOL,
JUST SIT THERE.
HE'D BE SO
TIRED,
I'D HAVE TO
CARRY HIM HOME.
DID YOU KNOW
THAT?
YEAH, WELL, IT
WAS
A LONG TIME AGO.
DAMN COLD
FOR FEBRUARY.
YEAH.
HOW YOU DOING?
OK. YOU?
OK.
THURSDAY'S
THE BIG DAY.
YEAH, I GUESS SO.
YOU READY?
YOU BET.
ME, TOO.
I WENT
BY
AND SAW SALLY.
YEAH?
JUST TO
SEE HOW
SHE WAS DOING
AND EVERYTHING.
HOW IS SHE?
SHE'S GOOD.
THAT'S GOOD.
YOU KNOW
WHAT SHE SAID
JUST
BEFORE I LEFT?
SHE SAID, "TAKE
CARE
OF YOURSELF, NICK."
CAN YOU BEAT
THAT?
WE GOT TO STICK
TOGETHER, NICKY.
WE GOT
TO STICK TOGETHER.
YEAH.
WHY
DON'T YOU
TRY THEM ON?
I ALREADY
KNOW THEY FIT.
I LOVE YOU,
CADDIE.
I LOVE YOU, HENRY.
DON'T
CRY, MOM.
I'M NOT
CRYING.
COME BACK
AND PLAY FOR ME.
BOARD!
KEEP YOUR EYES
PEELED.
I WILL, DAD.
YOU, TOO, NICKY.
I WILL, SIR.
TAKE CARE, NICKY.
I BROUGHT SOMETHING
FOR YOU.
IT'S FOR YOUR WALLET.
ALL
ABOARD!
BOARD!
YOU BOYS
BETTER
BE GETTING ON.
BE SAFE.
SON,
YOUR TRAIN
IS LEAVING!
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
HENRY!
YOUR
TRAIN!
YOUR TRAIN!
HENRY! HENRY!
HENRY?
HENRY!
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
READY,
BUDDY?
READY.
CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
PARAMOUNT PICTURES CORPORATION
CAPTIONING PERFORMED
BY
THE NATIONAL CAPTIONING
INSTITUTE, INC.
CAPTIONS COPYRIGHT 1991
PARAMOUNT PICTURES CORPORATION