Caesar...
They are close.
Koba!
Now, father?
Son, stay...
Thank you, Koba.
Think before you act, son.
Don't feel bad, Blue Eyes...
Scars make you strong.
Come meet your new brother.
Another son.
Makes me think how far we've come,
Maurice.
Seems long ago.
Still think about them?
Humans?
Sometimes.
Didn't know them like you did.
Only saw their bad side.
Good, bad... doesn't matter now.
Humans destroyed each other.
Apes fight too.
But we are family.
Wonder if they're really all gone.
Ten winters now...
Last two... no sign of them.
They must be gone.
That bear wouldn't get me Blue Eyes. I'm quick!
Shut up, Ash!
They shot Ash! Shot my son!
Rocket, wait...
Koba!
Follow!
Must attack them now!
Before they attack us!
We don't know how many there are.
How many guns they have?
Or why they came up here?
They shot your son, Rocket!
Don't you want to fight?
I follow Caesar.
Koba's right!
They almost killed you, Ash!
If we go to war...
We could lose all we've built...
I will decide by morning.
For years I was a prisoner in their lab...
They cut me...
Tortured me.
You freed me.
I would do anything you ask.
But we must show strength!
We will, Koba.
If they get power, they'll be more dangerous!
Why help them?!
They seem desperate...
If we make them go, they'll attack.
We'll destroy them while they're weak.
And how many apes will die?
We have one chance for peace...
Let them do their human work. Then they'll go.
Koba say...
Apes should hate humans...
Enough!
From humans Koba learned hate...
But nothing else.
You sound sick... You ok?
Just need rest.
You worry about the humans...
Where's Koba?
Still angry.
Said he was going hunting...
Look, humans below!
Why are we here?
Caesar trusts humans...
Koba does not.
Enough guns here to kill every ape...
Must warn Caesar.
Who knows what humans
are really doing up there?
Father, no...!
I will not help!
Just came from the city. Humans very dangerous!
Where is Caesar?
With the humans...
You are my son...
I need you to listen...
You didn't tell Caesar about the guns we found?
Neither will you.
Your father doesn't trust me now.
You need to protect him.
His love for humans...
Makes him blind.
I know...
As long as they are here...
I fear for Caesar's life.
Feeling better?
Mother...?
Human gun!
Go! Get them!
Females and young stay in woods...
We go to the city!
We will avenge your father's death!
Humans escaping! Capture them!
Followed the humans here. Hiding everywhere!
We must catch them all!
Go ahead Ash...
...make humans pay.
Caesar wouldn't want this.
Maurice...?
Koba said...
...we're too loyal to your father.
Protect yourself.
For now.
I'm so sorry...
For everything.
But Koba betrayed you.
On the human tower...
Loyal apes around him.
Prisoners.
Maurice.
Rocket.
Koba killed Ash.
Fear makes others follow.
But when they see you alive...
They will turn from Koba.
Koba sent for the females and young.
They're on their way.
Mother too.