Doctor's log.
It's day 243 in this...
portobello purgatory.
My only companion
is a rock I named Stone.
The question is,
for whom am I narrating this?
It seems I've become a featured
player in the theater of the absurd.
Marooned in deep space
by that wretched blue rodent.
But it's all good,
thanks to a breathable atmosphere
and my supreme intellect,
sharpened against the only
competitor savvy enough to bring it.
Chanterelle to d4. Mmm.
I've been striving to make fungi
into a functional drink of choice...
Mushroom coffee.
With limited...
limited...
success.
But today, day 243,
has brought a new optimism
to my most pressing endeavor...
Planetus exodus to returnicus
and kick blue butticus.
If my calculations are correct,
and there's no reason to say
"if" because they always are...
this quill is going to power
my masterpiece.
Let's light this candle...
and see who comes
a-knockin'.
Greetings!
Klaatu barada nikto.
Agent Stone? Now!
Thank you, Stone.
It's time to say goodbye to
this piece-of-shiitake planet!
Huh?
Where did you get that?
From a little blue menace
on the planet called Earth.
I'd be happy
to show you the way.
Oh.
They're still on us.
This'll slow 'em down.
♪ This speech is my recital
I think it's very vital ♪
♪ To rock a rhyme
That's right on time ♪
♪ "It's Tricky" is the title
Here we go ♪
♪ It's tricky to rock a rhyme
To rock a rhyme ♪
♪ That's right on time
It's tricky ♪
Watch out. Excuse me.
Pardon me. Coming through.
Good evening, gentlemen.
Mind if I drive?
Better buckle up.
How we doing back there?
And now this way.
Whoo-hoo!
Oh, I'm sorry.
I don't speak duct tape.
What the heck are you?
Fear not, citizen.
I am the hero you need
and the hero you deserve.
The blue dawn
that banishes the darkest...
Holy crap!
Don't worry.
Nobody's gonna get hurt.
Huh. What are
those? Bombs. Bombs.
They're bombs! Those are bombs!
Relax. They're not even lit.
So I'll say again,
nobody's gonna get...
I was wrong! We're
all gonna die!
Why aren't you slowing down?
That would require brakes.
Oh, it's hot. Hot, hot, hot!
Why don't you just let
the police handle this?
Because that's not
what heroes do.
Thank you very much.
Please hold your applause.
Do you hear that?
There's one bomb left.
Uh... Uh-oh.
Did you check under the seat?
Of course I checked
under the seat!
You are terrible at this!
You know what? Your negative
attitude is not helping anyone.
It's in your spiky things!
Ha! I can never find
anything in here.
Drained it from downtown!
See? I told you
nobody would get hurt.
Holy sherbet!
Oh, hello.
Don't panic.
This is only a drill.
Come here!
No need to thank me, citizens.
All in a night's work for...
Blue Justice!
You're a terrible hero!
♪ The feelings running deep ♪
♪ Ain't no time for sleep ♪
♪ A second to unwind
Head up in the sky ♪
Morning, Wade!
Morning, Sonic!
Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Good morning, Green Hills!
Ah! Oop! Oh.
Oh, come on.
Uh-oh. Uh...
Oh, Sonic.
I miss you, Longclaw.
I'm trying to make you proud.
And now
for a little shut-eye.
Oh! Blech!
Ozzy, morning breath!
Sonic. Are you still in bed?
You're supposed
to meet Tom, remember?
All right, all right,
I'm up! I'm up.
What a day.
Whoo!
Thanks for coming out, bud.
You know,
I feel like you and me,
we haven't had
much time together lately.
How's it going over there?
You getting any bites?
I can't swim! Help!
If I die,
don't look in my closet!
Hey, hey, you're good.
You're all right. Come on.
It's freezing.
All right, okay. Take it easy.
All right. You're good. Okay.
But now that you've had
a nap and a bath...
I went up to your room last night to
bring you some new comics and, um...
Whoa, whoa,
whoa. Stop right there.
I wouldn't come any closer,
because this little hedgehog
had way too many chili dogs.
Oh, no. Oh, no.
I'm so embarrassed.
Get out of here quick!
Oh, no, here comes another one!
Go. Now. Save yourself.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Stop
right there. I wouldn't come any closer,
because this little
hedgehog had way too many chili dogs.
Oh, no. Oh, no.
I'm so embarrassed.
Get out of here...
Ugh! I knew I should've
used real farts.
How many times
are we gonna do this?
What? Cast your line and not
catch anything? Seems like a billion.
I think you know
what I'm talking about.
The lying. The sneaking out.
The pretending to be Batman.
Blue Justice, trademark pending.
Whatever. You're being reckless.
Ugh!
Not this conversation again.
Hey. It's no fun for me, either.
But if you keep
being irresponsible,
we're gonna keep
having this conversation.
How is it irresponsible
to use my powers?
Sonic, you destroyed
an entire city block!
That block
was already messed up.
Who cares?
Look, I stopped a robbery.
I was a hero.
No, you put people in danger
and that's not what a hero does.
You're supposed
to be my friend.
Stop trying to be my dad.
I can take care of myself.
Sonic, taking care of yourself
is not what being
a hero's all about.
It's about taking
responsibility for other people.
And right now,
whether you want to hear this or not,
you are still just a kid.
You got some more
growing up to do
before you're ready
to be the big hero.
But trust me when I tell you,
there will come a time when
your powers will be needed.
But you don't choose
that moment.
That moment chooses you.
Whoa. Look at you.
Look at that.
I just got goose bumps.
Wait a second.
Did you steal that from Oprah?
No, sir. That is
a Wachowski family special.
Came from my dad,
in this very boat,
on this very lake.
He would always try and steer me
in the right direction.
And that's what Maddie and I
have always tried to do with you.
So, until your moment arrives,
I want you to work on
being a little more responsible.
Comprende?
Comprende.
High five on it.
Yeah! Donut Lord and the
Blue Blur are back at it again!
Hang on.
Speedboat!
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Sonic!
Whoo-hoo!
How excited are you,
going to Hawaii with me? Oh, Hawaii.
Oh, yeah!
Wow.
Welcome to Sonic Air,
the fastest way to travel.
Now boarding groups one and two.
Oh!
Sonic, this is so fun!
I'm sorry, ma'am,
you're group three. Please wait your turn.
Anyone from groups one and two?
Just let him get it out
of his system. Nobody?
Okay, then everybody else
right this way.
Thank you.
And you, sir?
Terrible shirt detected.
There we go.
Okay, you're free to go.
Enjoy your trip.
Bye-bye now.
Okay.
Bring it in.
Tom, I'm about to be hedgehog
of the house for the first time.
I think I'm a little mature
to hug you goodbye.
Okay,
what about a power bump? Power bump?
Yes, power bump.
That's more like it.
Wachowski!
Okay, use this one
to get back home.
Oh!
All right, we're off. Be good.
Yes. You have our number.
Sorry! Can't hear you! You're traveling
through a cross-dimensional portal!
Miss you already! Okay?
Have fun at Rachel's wedding!
Okay, it's 48 hours
until they come back.
We've got TV channels,
streaming channels,
a house full of food
and no supervision.
Let's do this.
♪ Na-na-na-na ♪
♪ Here comes the hotstepper
Murderer ♪
♪ I'm the lyrical gangster
♪ Pick up the crew in-a de area
Murderer ♪
♪ Still love you like that
♪ Extraordinary
Juice like a strawberry ♪
♪ Money to burn, baby
All of the time ♪
♪ Cut to fit is me ♪
♪ Fit to cut is she ♪
♪ Come juggle with me
I say every time ♪
♪ Here comes the hotstepper
Murderer ♪
♪ I'm the lyrical gangster
♪ Dial emergency number
Murderer ♪
♪ Still love you like that
♪ Nah, na-na-na-nah ♪
♪ Na-na-na-na, na-na-na
Na-na-na ♪
♪ Na-na-na-nah ♪
♪ It's how we do it, man ♪
Whoo-hoo!
♪ Na-na-na-na
Na-na-na, na-na-na ♪
♪ Na-na-na-nah ♪
♪ Yeah, man ♪
♪ It's how we do it ♪
♪ Na-na-na-na
Na-na-na, na-na-na ♪
♪ Na-na-na-nah ♪
If these readings
are accurate, he's here.
I found him!
I just hope I'm not too late.
Hmm. He's close.
I just need a way to reach
him without being spotted.
Standard human transport.
Perfect.
♪ This is how we do it ♪
♪ It's Friday night ♪
Uh-oh.
Oh, boy.
Aloha!
- How's it going, bud?
- Oh, you know.
Just a quiet night at home,
settling in with a good book.
And you? What's up with you?
I was just calling
to say we're here.
But now every word out of your
mouth is making me suspicious.
What? You got to relax,
buddy. You're at the Four Seasons Oahu.
Have a Mai Tai.
Enjoy some time with your wife.
Get sunburned
somewhere embarrassing.
This weekend is about you.
You know what? You're right.
We power-bumped on it.
So whatever it is you're doing,
I'm sure you can undo it
by the time we get home, yeah?
Exactly! I mean,
I am deeply offended by such accusations!
So, how's Rachel's fiancé?
Is he as good-looking in
person as he is in pictures?
Hey, baby.
Somehow better-looking.
Wow! You're about to be the
third best-looking dude in the family.
But, hey, still on the podium.
Ha-ha-ha.
All right,
I better go and introduce myself.
Stay out of trouble.
Trouble? Don't worry.
Everything here
is completely normal.
Uh-huh. Night, bud.
Hey! I was just
coming over to say hi.
You've got a lot
of nerve coming up in here
after what you did
to my fiancée.
Wait. What? Totaling her car?
Leaving her tied to a chair?
I should rip you limb from limb.
Oh, my God, look at your face!
Tommy, breathe, baby.
Breathe. I was kidding.
Hey, man,
I was totally kidding. Okay.
You were kidding. Yeah.
I'm sorry.
Rachel put me up to it.
It was totally her idea.
That rascal.
Listen, I don't know
if you're aware.
Rachel does not care
for you at all.
Oh, I'm aware. Yeah.
Seriously, bro,
you got work to do.
Hey! Hey.
Good to see you!
Thanks for coming, Tom.
Really glad you came. Really?
Uh...
Great to see you, too.
Congratulations.
I mean, you guys seem
really happy together.
You know, you're all right,
Thomas Wachowski.
Ah.
Can we Bury the hatchet?
I'd love that.
Yeah? Yeah.
All right,
bring it in! All right! Great.
Oh. And if you screw up my wedding,
I will end you.
All right, Ozzy,
it's movie night at Casa de Sonic,
and it's your turn to pick.
But I am not watching
Snow Dogs again.
That movie is the worst!
Blackout!
Ozzy!
Oh, sorry, buddy.
Everything's okay.
Whoa!
Uh, excuse me.
We did not order a poltergeist.
Um, if this is the pizza guy,
this is really unprofessional.
Eggman?
Hello, hedgehog.
Did you miss me?
I don't know how you got back,
but you made
a big mistake coming here.
Au contraire, mon frère.
The mistake
was thinking you'd won.
But that was just a prelude,
an hors d'oeuvre,
an aperitif, an amuse-bouche.
I get it.
I don't think you do.
But you're about to.
And so will that idiot
sheriff and his wife.
And your little dog too!
Pitiful.
What? Who are you?
Where are my manners?
Sonic, meet Knuckles.
My new BFFAE.
Bestest friend forever and ever!
Look, Robotnik, I don't care
who you brought to help you.
You're never going
to get my power.
Do I look like
I need your power?
So nice when diabolical evil
lives up to the hype.
Where is it?
Oh, you want it? Here it comes.
I was expecting more of you.
You're unskilled.
Untrained.
And unworthy!
You forgot one. Unstoppable.
It is my destiny to do
what my ancestors could not...
To restore the ultimate power
to the home of my people.
Ultimate power?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
You've got the wrong guy.
Ultimate power?
Now you're speaking my language.
Don't play dumb with me,
apprentice of Longclaw.
You knew Longclaw?
Longclaw and her people were the
sworn enemy of my tribe, the Echidna.
We fought and died
at their hands,
and now you will die at mine.
Come on. Get in!
I'm on your side.
I'm sorry. Who are you?
You know what?
It doesn't matter.
Get us out of here!
Go, go, go!
Ah! He's gone rabid!
Gross! Is he licking it?
See ya!
Make sure
to get your shots, Eggman!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Whoa!
Wow. Okay. Let me just say
it is an honor to finally meet you,
Sonic.
Is it okay if I call you Sonic?
Everyone calls me Tails.
You're probably wondering why.
Let me guess. Because of
the extra tail? That's right!
I should've known
you'd get that. Cool.
Also, what is going on?
Robotnik's back?
And who is Clifford
the Big Red Rage Monster?
That's Knuckles,
the last of the Echidnas
and the most dangerous warrior
in the galaxy.
He's obsessed with finding
the Master Emerald.
Are you serious?
The Master Emerald?
That's just a bedtime story.
Well, he believes it's real.
And he must think
you're the key to finding it.
Red light! Give me the wheel!
Hey, what are you...
Move your foot.
I think we lost him.
We did not lose him.
We definitely did not lose him!
I've got an idea.
Do you trust me?
Of course not!
I literally just met you!
Just let me... Come on!
What are you doing?
We're flying.
Uh, did your butt just
turn into a helicopter?
A butt-copter!
Oh, only Sonic the Hedgehog could
come up with something like that.
Foxy move.
You want something done right...
You have to hire someone
you can push around.
All caps.
♪ I waited till I saw the sun ♪
♪ I don't know why
I didn't come ♪
Doctor,
where are you?
Freak.
Oh, I, uh... I'm sorry, folks.
Uh, I have to close early.
Everybody out!
Everybody out. Thank you
for visiting the Mean Bean.
All right, good night.
Good night.
He's back.
He's back!
That's more like it.
I've been re-hatched!
So, my massively
metacarpaled friend,
you mentioned...
Ultimate power.
Back at the house?
The Master Emerald?
It does not concern you.
I got you off that planet and
you brought me to the hedgehog.
We have no more use
for each other.
Well, I hate to be
a contrarian, but...
I think we might.
You think these machines
are a match for me?
I will shatter them
like the bones from a fallen...
Oh, they are stairs.
You see, Earth is my turf, G.
If you don't know how to floss,
you'll be lost without me.
I understand nothing
of what you just said.
I help you retrieve the Emerald,
and you use it to...
destroy the hedgehog!
You're suggesting an alliance.
Around here we simply
grip each other's hands tightly.
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow!
You truculent space bumpkin!
You've crushed my favorite hand!
Really? My hand is uninjured.
Ugh.
But I'm now convinced
of your commitment.
"Oh, goody,"
he exclaimed,
while he reset two of his knuckles.
I'm...
delighted to be
on the same team.
Road trip!
I'll let you stick your
nose out the window.
Uh, Sonic, where are we?
Welcome to the Wade Cave.
Which is something I hope
to someday say to a woman.
A woman who's not my mom.
Wade, focus.
We need to figure out
why Knuckles thinks
I'm the key to finding
the Master Emerald.
And why did he mention Longclaw?
There must be a connection.
Wait a minute. There is.
Look. There's an emerald symbol
on the map Longclaw gave me.
I never knew
what it meant before.
Something's happening.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Longclaw?
Hello, Sonic.
If you're watching this,
then something has happened to me.
And I pray you've made it
to Earth unharmed.
This world has been chosen
for a very important reason.
It's the secret location
of the Master Emerald.
Whoa.
The Emerald has the power
to turn thoughts into reality.
Like the Stay Puft Marshmallow
Man from Ghostbusters.
Shh!
In the wrong hands,
it could threaten
all life in the universe.
Protecting the Emerald
was my sacred duty.
And now I must pass
that responsibility to you.
This is my moment.
Follow the map, find the Emerald,
and keep it safe.
My dear Sonic,
you have a heart like no
creature I've ever known.
I love you so much.
Goodbye.
No, no, wait.
I won't let you down, Longclaw.
So is that y-your dad?
What?
No?
According to this map,
the first clue is in Siberia.
It's a compass that
will lead to the Emerald.
And with Knuckles already here,
it's a race.
Knuckles?
I knew a kid in middle
school named Knuckles.
Could fit his whole fist
in his mouth.
If this is the same Knuckles...
...we are screwed.
This Knuckles,
that Knuckles. It doesn't matter.
We're gonna get there first.
What do you mean, "we"?
You're coming with me.
Oh, no, no, no.
I just came here to warn you.
I'm not a field guy.
Don't worry. I got your back.
I won't let anything
happen to you.
It's a power bump.
On Earth, it means
an unbreakable promise.
Okay, I'm in.
♪ Me and you
Maybe sunshine, maybe rain ♪
Doctor. It's really you.
You look different.
Papa's got a brand new 'stache.
Ha!
I knew it. I knew it!
I knew you'd come back, sir.
I never stopped steaming
your Austrian goat's milk.
Could use some mushroom.
You brought something.
Some kind of, uh,
space porcupine.
Porcupine? I am an Echidna!
Trained since birth in
all forms of lethal combat,
destined to restore honor
to my tribe,
and willing to destroy
anything that gets in my way.
Welcome to the team.
That means he trusts you, Stone.
Now let's renovate this dump!
Latte with steamed
Austrian goat milk!
Good one. Solid.
- Sorry, fellas.
- That's game!
Ha! That's how we do!
That's how we do!
But are they good at math?
Teamwork makes the dream work!
Sorry about that, Big Tom.
Are you good? All good. Fine.
Thanks for inviting me out to
hang with you and your groomsmen.
Good quality bonding.
You know, bro,
those guys right there,
they're way more than my groomsmen.
That's my squad.
Never would've made it
through life without 'em.
Get over here!
Yeah, I'm coming! I'm coming!
I'll catch you later.
Hey. Yeah!
Let me know if you're ready
for some power yoga, huh?
You bet. Come on,
Tommy boy. Let's go.
Don't make me.
What am I doing?
Hey, Uncle Tommy!
Hey, girls!
How you do... Oh!
Are those the
wedding rings? Uh-huh.
May I?
This little ring bearer has been
taking her job very seriously.
She's been practicing
all morning.
I can see that.
How very responsible of you.
Except aren't there supposed
to be two wedding rings?
Uh-oh.
Uncle Tommy?
Hang on. What's going on here?
You're gonna do great, kiddo.
Bye.
Hey, baby. Hi.
That's right!
Groom in the building!
Look at those guys.
I wish Sonic had that.
Muscles? Control yourself.
Mm-hmm.
No. Buddies. Wingmen. A squad.
Sonic doesn't have anything
like that. He's flying solo.
Baby, you got to relax.
You're at the Four Seasons.
Have a Mai Tai. Spend
some time with your wife.
That's what he said.
Seriously, his exact words.
See? He's a
smart kid. All right.
Hmm. He'll find his way.
I absolutely cannot find
my way.
We are completely, totally,
unequivocally lost.
Sonic, in this weather,
there's no way we're gonna get
any readings on this thing!
Should we go back?
No, no, no.
There's a light up ahead.
Maybe we can take shelter
in there.
Ah. Perfect.
Are you sure about this?
We don't know who's inside.
Don't worry. On Earth,
people are very welcoming,
and love taking complete
strangers into their homes.
Run.
Table for two, please!
Two beef stews, please.
Where'd you get
all these cool gadgets?
I invented 'em.
That's kinda my thing.
In fact, my inventions
are how I discovered you.
Remember that night
at the baseball field?
Your energy blast reached
all the way to my home planet.
I saw you save your whole village
from that crazy mustache guy.
Wait, so you've been
watching me this whole time?
Even in the shower?
That's a trick question.
Sonic the Hedgehog
prefers bubble baths.
Man, you're good!
When I learned Knuckles
was on your trail,
I knew I couldn't just sit
back and watch anymore.
I had to come warn you.
Oh, what? Hang on one sec.
Donut Lord is checking in.
"Just chilling. Watching TV."
Dot, dot, dot.
Doctor,
why are we working
with this imbecile?
Because that simpleminded space trash
is the key to something extraordinary.
Something to help you
get revenge on the hedgehog.
Think bigger, Stone.
The emerald he seeks
could power my wildest designs.
My genius wouldn't
just be recognized on Earth.
It would spread virally
to every corner of the galaxy,
allowing me to harness all the
negative forces of the universe
and commune
with Darkness itself.
Wow. That sounds big.
It's been on my vision board for
years. It's the Law of Attraction.
Didn't you see The Secret?
Kaplooey!
Kaplooey.
"Another boring night at home."
The hedgehog has returned home!
Falsa.
Which is Latin for "wrong-o."
According to my worldwide network
cell tower triangulation, he's lying,
all the way
from the majestic hinterlands
of Eastern Siberia.
He's a long-distance liar!
Kuh! Kuh! Kuh!
Nga-nga-nga-nga-nga!
Yeah, there's more
where that came from.
Tiny magic hedgehog destroyed.
Now let's begin our quest.
Wait.
What about your Minion?
The goat milker.
There's no room
on the ship for Stone.
I say we ditch him,
ghost him, blow him off.
Dishonor!
"Dis" is how I roll.
Ugh!
Uh, I'm sorry,
but I asked for the beef stew.
Uh...
Uh, what's going on?
Maybe they think
it's my birthday?
Don't worry,
I'll take care of this.
Okay, everybody, take it easy.
I'm sure there's
a perfectly good explanation
for whatever my friend said
or did.
Uh... meow?
Oh, no, no. Come on, guys.
Take it easy.
Let's talk this through.
Let's talk this through!
Come on, come on.
Scanning Siberian customs.
There's got to be
something in here.
Tails,
whatever you're doing, do it fast.
Ooh! I think I got it!
Pivonka! Pivonka!
Pivonka!
Oh? Pivonka?
Pivonka.
Da.
Pivonka!
Tails, what's a "pivonka"?
It's a Siberian custom
to resolve disputes.
If we win, they let us go.
If we lose...
Okay, we have to grab the map
and get out of here. Where's the map?
Oh, no. I left it
on the table! Look!
What?
Oh, my God, it's a dance fight.
Sonic, what do we do?
We dance and get that map.
Here we go.
Ow!
Okay, now let's do... No,
we're gonna go...
Ah, okay.
Okay, this is not going well.
Channing Tatum
makes it look so easy.
Wait, Sonic. Look!
Opa! Opa! Opa!
The map! Come on, let's grab it!
You want?
Come get.
Freaks!
Freaks! Freaks! Freaks!
What's wrong,
Tails? Come on. I need you!
I can't do this, Sonic.
I'm not brave like you.
My gadget got us in this mess,
and I lost your map,
and we're gonna get
tossed into a fire!
Ah...
New deejay coming in.
Come on, pal. I got an idea.
They called us freaks,
so let's get freaky.
Just follow my moves.
You'll be fine.
♪ Doh-doh-doh, doh-doh Aw, ow ♪
♪ This hit, that ice cold ♪
♪ Michelle Pfeiffer
That white gold ♪
♪ This one for them hood girls ♪
♪ Them good girls
Straight masterpieces ♪
♪ Stylin', wilin'
Livin' it up in the city ♪
♪ Got Chucks on
With Saint Laurent ♪
♪ Gotta kiss myself
I'm so pretty ♪
♪ Break it down
Girls hit your hallelujah ♪
♪ Whoo
♪ Whoo ♪
All right! Backup dancers!
♪ 'Cause uptown funk
Gon' give it to you ♪
♪ Saturday night
And we in the spot ♪
Here we go!
Oh! Ha!
Boom! Ah! Oh!
♪ Don't believe me Just watch ♪
Whoa!
Whoo-hoo! Yeah!
Whoo-hoo!
There's a lot
of me up here!
I love pivonka!
♪ Uptown funk you up
Uptown funk you up ♪
And big dismount!
Whoo-hoo!
Yeah!
I'll take that.
Whoo-hoo! We did it!
That was amazing!
Way to go, Tails.
Wow.
Only Sonic the Hedgehog
could win a dance battle that epic.
Well, stick with me, pal.
Earth can be a scary place,
but I know everything
about this old pale blue dot.
Do you really mean that?
I mean, not everything. But I watch
a lot of Discovery Channel and...
I meant about me being your pal.
Of course, buddy.
Comin' in hot.
Growing up,
I didn't have any friends.
Everyone in my village
thought my two tails were weird.
Hey, I know that feeling.
But then I saw you,
the fastest creature in the galaxy.
You were weird too.
But you were a legend.
That made me think,
maybe being weird isn't so bad.
You inspired me
to leave my village,
to find you and help you
in your mission.
I'm really glad
you're here, Tails.
I'm glad I'm here too, Sonic.
Well, might as well
get some sleep.
This feels like a good
place to spend the night.
You'll be able to get clear
readings on your gizmo thing
once the storm is over,
so I...
Night, Tails.
Tails. Tails. We have
a situation.
Hoo-hoo!
Today's forecast calls for
clear, sunny skies
and a 100% chance of
adventure.
I pinpointed the coordinates.
It's right up ahead.
Wow.
Hey, Tails. Wait up.
Whoa.
Okay,
we got a giant owl door. Seems encouraging.
Whoa.
Check this out.
Can you translate that?
Uh, yeah.
Ages ago,
a fearsome group of warriors,
known as the Echidnas,
forged the Seven Chaos Emeralds
into the most unstoppable
weapon ever created.
The Master Emerald.
With it, a single warrior
could defeat entire armies.
Believing no one should
have such power,
an order of heroes
recovered the Emerald
and swore to protect it
from evil.
Sounds like
the Owls and the Echidnas
have been fighting
each other for centuries.
Like Vin Diesel and The Rock.
Whoa! Wait for me.
Okay, giant owl door,
giant owl. Makes sense.
Whoa.
Wait a second.
I've seen these symbols before.
Here we go.
Well, that did something.
Whoa! The compass!
This will lead us
to the Emerald!
Hey, you got
a little something on your...
Oh, no. Tails, get back.
Run!
That guy again?
Heads up, my little stalagmites.
Someone call an Uber?
Hey, thanks for doing
all the hard stuff.
But we'll take it from here.
Okay, we really gotta talk
about your new look.
It's like Professor X
meets the Monopoly man.
And what kind of genius shows
up to Siberia in a convertible?
The kind of genius
that can turn up the heat...
with a flick of a switch.
Oh! Whoo!
Good one!
I'm sure that wasn't important.
Tails, that's our exit. Come on.
Uh-huh. Let's split up.
You go high, I go low.
Right.
Quick little stretch
and here we go.
Oh, so you want to play?
That's new.
Whoa.
Sonic!
Snowball fight!
It's too easy.
Come on, challenge me!
♪ There's a summer place ♪
We are talking style
and pizzazz.
♪ Where it may rain or storm ♪
Pew-pew-pew!
Pew, pew, pew, pew, pew, pew.
♪ Yet I'm safe and warm ♪
Yeah! I make this look good.
Oh, great. The Winter Soldier.
For a guy named Knuckles,
you are really bad at punching.
Surrender the compass!
You are no match for me.
I've been training for this
my entire life.
And I had no training at all,
yet here I am ahead of you.
That's gotta be embarrassing.
My rings!
Has anyone ever told you
you've got serious anger issues?
You mock me
with your weak jokes,
but you know nothing
about me, hedgehog.
Well, I know you Echidnas have a habit of
showing up uninvited and ruining my life.
Ruining your life?
Another bad joke.
I lost everything
because of you.
My tribe was on the verge
of its greatest victory.
The last of the Owl warriors
had been located.
Soon Longclaw's Emerald secrets
would be ours.
But my father stopped me
from joining the fight.
He said my moment
to honor our tribe would come,
but it was not this moment.
Those were the last words
he spoke to me.
I never saw him again.
We both lost everything
that day.
Goodbye, Sonic. No!
Longclaw!
Sonic! Are you okay?
Deceiver!
No, it wasn't a trick.
Tails, take the compass
and get out of here!
Yeah!
Later, haters!
Tails!
Tails, come on. Wake up.
He chose helping the fox
over pursuing the compass.
Of course he did.
New friend,
same pathetic weakness.
Hmm.
Oh, no. No, no, no.
We're in real trouble here.
Come on, Tails. I need you to fly
us out of here. Time to wake up.
See ya, kids.
Enjoy the fresh powder.
Did you...
These rings signify the...
Sorry.
Thought it was on silent.
These rings...
So help me, Thomas!
Okay, sorry. Sorry.
Excuse me, this is an emergency.
Sorry.
What? This better
be important. I just...
Are you skiing?
Snowboarding, actually.
But I need your help now.
Life or death situation
this very second.
I need you to use the ring I gave
you to save me. Like right now.
Okay,
slow down. I don't even know where you are.
You just gotta picture
where you want the ring to go.
So picture this.
Oh, my God. Okay, okay. Hang on.
What?
Did you throw it?
Oh, God. What? Tell me what "Oh,
God."
I mixed up the rings
when I was teasing Jojo.
What? Where is it then?
You don't want to know.
But I do, Tom.
I very much want to know,
before I become
a hedgehog-flavored snow cone.
Hang tight, buddy. I got this.
With this ring, Rachel...
Hey! Hi.
Uh... Everything okay, bud?
Not really. What are you doing?
This is gonna sound crazy,
but I need to see that ring
for just one second.
Have you lost your mind?
I'm gonna give it
right back, I promise.
Please, Randall, it's really important. No,
bro. Go sit down.
Give me the ring, please? Randall,
don't look at him, look at me.
One second.
Put the ring on my finger.
No, Randall, listen to me.
Randall! Look at me.
Ring on my finger.
Give me the ring! Just
one second. Put a ring on it!
Please, love? Okay?
With this ring... Yes, baby.
I'm so sorry about this.
Snow, my God. Oh, boy.
Incoming!
Oh.
Anybody hurt?
Sonic! Hawaii.
Are you okay?
What's happening?
Are you hurt?
No, no, I'm fine. Okay, good.
Because you're in
so much trouble!
Okay, you calm down.
You talk.
Okay, quick version.
Robotnik is back on Earth
and he's after a magic emerald.
We need to get it back
or the world is doomed.
Tails!
Wait! All this happened
since yesterday?
Wait. Who's Tails?
Tails, can you hear me?
Oh, Lord,
there are two of them now.
Okay, let me think.
Tails, come on, buddy.
Hey!
Randall,
why do all of your friends have weapons?
You really should have taken me up
on that brunch, Mr. and Mrs. Wachowski.
Olive Garden guy?
It's okay, everyone.
We're federal agents.
You, too, Agent. Go ahead.
You mean to tell me
that this entire wedding was a
setup? Rachel, wait a minute.
What?
That's correct, ma'am.
Every single aspect
of Operation Catfish
was a complete fabrication.
Operation Catfish?
So is everyone here an agent?
Are you an agent?
Son of a...
Was the florist an agent?
How about the photographer?
The woman who waxed my...
at the spa?
Is Jojo an agent?
Rachel.
What?
Rachel, listen to me.
I'm done listening!
I am done listening!
I am so sorry. I am
so sorry.
I really am. I am so sorry.
No. Hey, no!
Let him go! Hey!
Sonic, hang on.
Take it easy. It's not worth it.
Tom! Ah-ah-ah.
Sonic is not a threat.
He's on our side.
He's an uncontrolled
extraterrestrial.
And your days of aiding
and abetting him are over.
Secure them in the hotel
until the chopper arrives.
You're making a mistake.
Hold on, Major A-hole!
This is still my day,
and someone is gonna explain to
me what the hell is going on here!
After the events
in San Francisco,
a global task force was created,
devoted to protecting
our planet from alien threats.
That day,
Guardian Units of Nations was born.
G-U-N. Seriously? GUN, yeah.
Look, what about protecting
our planet from Dr. Robotnik?
Robotnik is dead.
You're wrong. He's back.
And you just hauled away the
only ones who could stop him.
Sounds like Robotnik
might be back in play.
If he is,
I want him found immediately.
And cancel my five o'clock
at the Olive Garden.
Aunt Maddie? Yeah.
Sonic and his friend
dropped this.
I have an idea.
And I want to have
a word with my fiancé.
And that word is "murder."
Hey, come on.
You can't just leave us in here.
My friend is hurt! He needs a doctor,
a vet, anyone!
Tails,
you got to wake up, buddy.
Please wake up.
All clear.
All right. Game plan.
I get inside the hotel and find
where they're hiding Tom and Sonic.
Okay.
Then I find Randall, right?
And then I squeeze the breath
from his lying, deceitful,
perfectly manscaped body!
I'm going through
a lot right now.
So let me process this
my own way, okay?
Sure, sure.
No judgment. Should've
brought a journal.
Okay...
Okay. Is this meant to be a
weapon? This is adorable.
Pew, pew! Take that, Randall!
Run, Randall!
All right.
We're about to
find out. All right!
Let's go kick some Booty.
Shh! Shh!
Rachel! No. Rachel!
In a minute.
Mm-mmm! Mm.
Stop right there!
Get the bag.
He's gonna
come back down, right?
I don't know.
Good luck!
Look. Tom and Sonic
have to be inside.
I got a fiancé to
vaporize. Uh-huh.
Watch your back, sis. Okay.
Randall!
We got her.
Move in.
Okay.
I did not mean to do that!
Whoo!
Something bothering you, Agent?
I just feel a little guilty
about what I did to Rachel, sir.
Ah, don't worry about it.
We'll send her a gift card.
Now, I propose a toast.
To a perfectly
executed operation.
Sir, we're under attack.
Randall, wifey's home!
Oh, my God. Rachel.
♪ You lying so low
In the weeds ♪
♪ I bet you gonna ambush me ♪
♪ You'd have me down, down
Down, down on my knees ♪
♪ Now wouldn't you, barracuda? ♪
♪ Oh ♪
What a woman.
You no-good,
lowdown, dirty, lying...
Rachel, just listen to me.
What kind of twisted sicko
tricks someone
into a fake wedding?
Party's over, Bridezilla.
Stop right there.
You son of a...
Have it your way. No!
No!
Oh. Ugh. Oh!
Very disappointing,
Agent Handel.
Ha! Is that supposed
to be a weapon?
I don't know,
but we gonna find out.
Haven't you caused
enough trouble for one day?
I haven't even begun
causing trouble.
Hell hath no fury like
a bride scorned.
Looks like it's real, huh?
Whoa! Uh! Ah! Huh?
No. Right.
Be honest. How bad is it?
Not bad at all.
You got Tased. You'll be fine.
I'm so cold.
You landed on our ice sculpture.
Get up.
Just...
Just tell me the truth,
for once.
Is there anything about you
or about us that was real?
Rachel, look at me.
Before I met you,
I didn't think that I was even
capable of real happiness.
But that all changed when
you walked into my life.
And I ended up breaking the
first rule of undercover work.
Which is?
Never fall in love.
Maddie! Maddie!
We're busting out of here.
How'd you get past the guards?
Because that little fox
is into some crazy stuff.
Come on.
Let's go. You're amazing.
The Owls were fools to think
they could hide this.
Ah.
What's happening?
Wait for it.
Yes. Eureka!
I've found it!
Sonic.
What is that? A big problem.
The compass led Robotnik
to the Emerald.
That's got to be
hundreds of miles away.
All right.
Huddle up.
Let's figure out a plan.
Together.
There's no time for that.
I'm the only one
that can get there fast enough.
Sonic, this is way too big
for you to do by yourself.
You see that little fox
over there?
He came all the way across
the universe to meet his hero.
And what did his hero do?
I practically got him killed.
You know what? You were right.
My moment came and I blew it.
I'm no hero.
Wait. No.
I'm not letting
anyone else get hurt
because of me.
I'm gonna fix this
while I still can.
Sonic!
Sonic, wait!
Hold on. Wait. Don't move.
Take it easy, little guy.
You're hurt.
But we have to help him. You
don't know what he's up against.
You believe us now?
Mm-hmm.
Hey, Bob!
Hey, Maria, how you doing? Hey!
Ah.
Working on my moves.
Just keepin' it green.
No need to burn the fuel.
Speaking of fuel...
Closed?
That doesn't seem right.
Close.
Yes.
Makeover, makeover. Look at you.
Freeze! Police!
Oh, my God, you got robot hands.
No, they're gloves.
Get 'em up.
Now spread your fingers!
Now wiggle 'em!
Wiggle your digits!
Yes! Like you just finished
a big musical number.
Good.
Why is there
a light on your head?
'Cause I'm the sheriff
for the weekend, pal.
Ugh. Water.
Why did it have to be water?
Okay, you can do this.
Gotta go fast.
Oh!
I don't want to die
like this! It's derivative!
Make room for Daddy!
Two and two. Great!
We're still bipedals,
more or less.
Fire in the hole!
I've solved it. There is a
booby trap every seven seco...
That was a little early. Mmm.
Oh! So glad it didn't
cut off my mustache.
Hey, Little Red Wrecking Ball.
I know you're dying
to get your Emerald on,
but can we be a little bit more
mindful of our surroundings?
May I?
In 30 feet, turn left.
Work smarter, not harder.
My pelvis.
Okay, Secret Temple,
let's see what you've got.
Whoa!
No, no, no! No!
No.
Yes!
You have
arrived at your destination.
Wow. That really
opened up the space.
I can't even picture it
with an impenetrable wall now.
And the rubble
is always a nice touch.
At last. The Master Emerald.
Ultimate power.
Soon order will be restored.
All because of what
we have done together.
Such a lovely sentiment,
Knuckles.
I think I feel
a single tear forming.
Sadly...
You're as useful to me now
as a backstage pass
to Limp Bizkit.
Whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa!
Nailed it.
This guy is always trying
to spoil a bad thing!
Ah! You guys are here, too?
Took the long way, huh?
Is everything a joke to you?
Why must you constantly
interfere with my destiny?
Because my destiny is to
protect my friends and family.
I think I just threw up
in my mouth.
And if you want that emerald,
you're gonna have to go through me.
Whoa!
The Echidna's
taking no prisoners today!
Sonic has heart,
but will he lose the quill to live?
I don't want to fight you,
but you're not giving me much choice.
Too easy. Let's do this.
Huh?
Why don't you stand still
and die with honor?
Let me think about it.
Okay, I thought about it
and I pass.
Hi there, beautiful.
You're the real deal,
aren't you?
Say goodbye, hedgehog.
Knuckles, stop.
Robotnik's stealing the Emerald!
What kind of fool
do you take me for?
Just look.
Mine.
Wait! That wasn't the deal.
Oh, you poor, naive creature.
It's not your fault.
A more advanced intellect would
have seen this move coming a mile away.
Or 1.6 kilometers.
But I trusted you!
You were my friend!
I'm sorry.
That just hit me funny.
Let this be
my final lesson to you,
you dim-witted
celestial skin tag.
Friends...
are open, honest
and vulnerable with each other.
Which means X squared times
the hypotenuse of Y squared,
divided by the absolute value
of friendship, equals...
dookie!
Oh, no.
Chaos is power!
Let's get out of here!
Knuckles!
Water again? Come on!
Mmm?
Mmm. Mmm.
You saved me.
Don't talk to me.
I'm not in the mood.
How dare you attack me
in my hour of sorrow!
Why did you save me?
Because you saved me first,
which clearly gave you a tactical
advantage I do not understand.
It wasn't a tactic.
I couldn't just let you die.
Why?
I've been trying to destroy
you since the moment we met.
Because being a hero isn't
about taking care of yourself.
It's about taking responsibility
for other people.
Hmm. Wise words.
An ancient Earth proverb?
No, sir, that's
a Wachowski family special.
I got it from a guy
in a rowboat.
Someone who means a lot to me.
Wait a second.
What's that sound?
Only Sonic the Hedgehog
needs rescuing this much.
That sly little fox!
Come on, Knucklehead.
We're not beat yet.
On the mountain,
you told me you'd lost everything.
The way I did.
But you seem
so hopeful and free.
How did you move forward
despite failing again?
And again. And again.
Okay, I didn't fail that much.
But I didn't do this all alone.
I found a new family.
New friends.
And you can too.
You don't have to be
alone anymore.
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
Are you kidding me
with that handshake?
I'm done
playing games, pal.
You're gonna tell me
what I want to know.
And I am asking you
for the last time...
what would you like
on your bagel?
I'm not telling you anything.
And that is a display bagel.
I don't get it with you!
I mean, I've tried everything.
I was good cop. I was bad cop.
I was cop
who offers you a bagel.
And nothing. It's like...
That is a display bagel. Wow.
Doctor, you're here.
Yes,
I'm here, and yet I'm...
not all there.
Sir, are you feeling okay?
I'm more than okay.
I'm upgraded.
Sinister 3.0.
My game is next level.
Hi.
I can smell the electricity
in your brain.
You smell like a snack plate.
Yeah, no, that's fair.
I had a couple today.
Sit down.
In the chair.
I didn't know.
'Cause he was in the chair,
so I didn't... Okay.
Sir? We have a problem.
- All teams in position!
- Set up a perimeter!
Move! Move! Move!
Incorrectus, my trusty barnacle.
After all these years,
what I finally got...
is a solution.
Commander. Status report.
Robotnik is in there with Stone
and a hostage. Possibly local PD.
I'm not saying he's dumb,
but if he is local PD,
this town's in a lot of trouble.
Wade.
Um...
Okay.
Rockin' that new
spring collection, I see.
Well, if it isn't
the Pastry King.
The Donut Lord.
A real genius would remember
the name of the guy
who helped kick your butt
off this planet.
And I'll do it again
if you mess with Green Hills.
Congratulations on your
oh-so-temporary sense of superiority.
You're finished, Robotnik!
We've taken everything.
Your lab, your drones,
your funding!
Let's see how big of a man you
are without your silly little robots.
Would you like to see how...
big a man I can be?
Welcome to the new norm.
My God!
Doctor! Take me with you!
He's taking everything apart.
He's building something.
That can only be one thing.
The fearsome power
of the Emerald.
If that thing really
turns thoughts into power,
we are in big trouble.
Robotnik has a lot
of bad thoughts.
Hey, Sonic, are you sure
it was a good idea
bringing you-know-who aboard?
Knuckles isn't really a bad guy.
He's just a little mixed up.
I am not mixed up!
I have steely focus.
And I'm complex.
And that's a lot
for some people.
Hope you're not
still mad I hit you with that car.
Pfft!
I was completely uninjured.
And my revenge will come
when you least expect it, fox.
Whoa.
Sir, you're magnificent!
Thank you, sycophant.
Your admiration is inevitable.
I knew it!
Just like the Stay Puft
Marshmallow Man.
World Domination playlist.
Fall back.
Fall back! Quick! Retreat!
How are we supposed
to beat this thing?
We need a plan.
Knuckles, use your strength to...
Jump off the plane. Wow.
Okay, this is what we're
gonna do. Step 1: Light taunting.
Step 2: I have no idea.
Sonic!
Nice action figure, Eggman.
Does it do anything or just
stand there looking ugly?
Like a blister,
he keeps coming back!
He's on the okay-to-kill list. Shoot
the missiles. Make a decision.
I need a moment, sir. I'm
trying to figure out how to do this.
Did you even glance at a manual?
No! I'll do it.
Pardon my lightning.
You might want to
ground yourself.
Uh-oh.
I'm gonna pop that thing open
like a can of chili...
Whoa!
Hang on!
Whoo! Whoo-hoo!
Oh,
yeah! Whoo! Whoo-hoo-hoo! Close one.
Sonic!
Robotnik!
Deceiver!
Die, mosquito.
Ooh! I felt that.
Oh! Whoa!
What just happened?
It's the Stache Masher.
Right here in the manual.
Return to sender.
Stone?
Oh, great.
Next thing you know, there'll be a
report about a hostile work environment.
Those were our best attacks,
and they did nothing!
We can't beat Robotnik as
long as he's got that Emerald.
He's too powerful.
Look, we aren't strong enough
to beat Robotnik on our own.
But there's three of us.
Your strength, your smarts
and my speed.
Together. That's how we win.
So we make our stand here
on the field of battle.
As a team.
This is it.
This is our moment.
Time to fight.
Bad time to say this,
but I don't actually have a plan.
Tails, any ideas?
We have to find his weak spot.
I suggest the groin.
What? No. No!
Traditionally, yes,
the groin is the weakest spot.
Stop saying "groin."
Hedgehog!
Look out!
I know what his
weak spot is. It's me.
I'm the groin!
Think about it. Whoa!
I live rent-free
in this dude's head.
So if I go out there
and rile him up...
He'll focus on only you,
leaving himself open
to a flanking maneuver
from me and the fox!
Hedgehog,
you are a brave and noble warrior.
Go to your certain death
with honor.
We're gonna have to work
on your pep talks, pal.
Yeah. Let's go.
All right, mustache.
You want me? Come and get me.
You don't tell me
about coming and getting.
I am on the cutting edge
of coming and getting!
Coming, getting.
Coming, getting. Coming,
getting. Coming, getting.
Oh, you're really heavy.
That's because I am one million
percent muscle. Faster, fox!
Go! Move, guys! Move back! Let's go,
that's it! Go, go, go!
Keep going! Go! Go!
No, no! Stop! Stop the truck!
Tom, what happened here?
You thinking what I'm
thinking? Let's get our kid.
We need your truck!
Coming,
getting. Whew!
Yoo-hoo!
So what's the
plan here?
Huh?
You gonna build
a big robot house?
Get yourself a big robot wife?
I'm going to enslave humanity and
force them to service my machines.
First, Green Hills.
Then the universe.
Then the multiverse.
Then who knows?
Maybe that'll be enough.
Full disclosure?
You won't be there.
Eye lasers? Really?
Snot rocket!
No, no, no!
Giving up already?
Not so tough when you're fighting
someone 700 times your size, are ya?
You can't beat me!
I'm all-powerful! All-knowing!
All-seeing.
Looks like your fancy robot
has a glitch.
Is it me?
What about me? I'm over here.
Up top! Down below!
Behind you!
I'm
over here. Sorry! Over here.
Too slow! Try again.
You can't outsmart me.
Missed me again.
I'm the outsmarter-er!
I didn't outsmart you.
I'm just the distraction.
Robotnik!
I am also a hologram.
Disloyal.
"Dis" is how I roll.
Where's my Emerald?
No, no, no, no!
Computer, auxiliary power.
Oh.
The Emerald. It's right there.
Move, you hunk of junk!
I have to... reach it.
Come on.
There he is! Go! Go, go, go!
No!
We got you, Sonic.
Hold on!
- You guys okay?
- Yeah.
Okay.
I got the Emerald.
We could still defeat him.
Come on, come on. How does
this thing work? What do I do?
What?
No. No, no, no!
Look at the happy little family.
You have to get away from
me. I'm the one he wants.
Hey.
We're not going anywhere.
We're family.
And families stick together...
no matter what.
I love you guys.
We love you too, Sonic.
No!
I got him!
I finally got him!
What was that?
It's over, Eggman.
I like the
new look. It works for you.
What do you say
we just let bygones be bygones?
I did some things,
you did some things.
There are good people
on both sides.
Surely two intelligent beings
can work these things out!
Come on, buddy.
Get him, Sonic! Come on.
Yeah. Come on.
It's like that?
Okay, we're not friends.
Later, hater!
Sonic! Buddy!
Wait! You cannot touch him!
The hedgehog holds
the power of the Emerald.
I am sorry. He is no longer
the Sonic you once knew.
What?
Mmm.
Oh, you got to try this.
Okay. He is exactly
the Sonic you once knew.
Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
Sonic! Whoa!
Bring it in, bud.
It's good to be back in blue.
The golden god thing was fun,
but blue has always been more my color.
Looks good on you.
Sonic, you were
the most powerful hero
in the universe,
and you let it go.
Why?
Because I still have
some growing up to do.
And I kind of like being a kid.
And you're not just any kid.
You're our kid.
That's right.
Bring it in! Yay. Hugs.
It's a good thing we didn't do
this before. You would've blown up.
Whoa! You fixed it.
I've spent my whole life
questing for this.
Now I have it.
Now we have it.
What do we do with it?
What next?
There were once
two orders of heroes
who protected the galaxy from those
who would use the Emerald for evil.
But they have all passed on to
the great battleground in the sky.
So we start a new order.
The three of us.
This is no light task.
We must make a vow to use our
powers to keep the universe safe,
to watch out for each other.
Our new tribe.
Oh, I know!
A power bump!
Good idea.
It's an Earth custom.
An unbreakable promise.
Very well.
A power bump it is.
Power bump!
It's truly a beautiful day
for baseball here
in Green Hills.
An exciting lineup today
with the debut appearance
of two new players!
On the mound,
rookie sensation from across the galaxy,
Miles "Tails" Prower,
facing off against the powerhouse,
Knuckles the Echidna.
Um, I don't understand.
Why am I angry
at the enemy ball?
You're not angry.
You just want to hit it
as hard as you can
and then run around the bases.
But if my quest ends
where I am standing,
why run at all?
Ugh. I can't with this guy.
Why do I even try?
This is just a game.
We're out here having fun.
Just having some fun.
Fun. Huh.
All right!
Give him the heat, Tails!
Hope you're ready
for my fastball.
Your fastball
will be dishonored.
And so will you, fox.
Easy, guys!
Don't think about it too much.
Just keep your elbow up,
eye on the ball
and give it a ride.
A ride? To where?
Power bump!
Ha! Victory is mine!
Hey, no fair!
That shouldn't count.
First base is also mine!
I think that was our
only ball.
I have conquered
the second of the bases!
Who wants ice cream?
Knocked the cover off that.
Ice cream! Ice cream, yeah!
I am having
the fun! What is ice cream?
It's a dessert. If you like fun,
you're gonna love it.
Oh, yum. Dessert.
Does it have grapes in it?
No, not usually.
I'm proud of our little guy.
I really like his new friends,
especially the red one.
He cracks me up.
Heck of a swing too.
Come on, fox.
Our dessert adventure
awaits. Whoo!
Good job, guys. Yeah.
You too, baby.
Let's go get some ice cream.
Come on, come on.
I'm happy for you, pal.
Got your wingmen.
Perfect friends to grow up with.
Come on,
Knuckles. Ah! My victory chariot!
I've got a lot more
than that... Dad.
Race you to the truck.
One, two, three, go!
No, don't go easy on me.
I want your best.
Sonic, I have just been told
they have sprinkles.
Ice cream and sprinkles?
This is your new destiny.
What a perfect meal to celebrate
my victory over you in base of ball.
What? I mean,
you barely beat me.
Ha! You've never been
beaten so hard.
Can't forget this.
♪ Say I might And sail tonight ♪
♪ I'm home ♪
♪ Say right now, I'll get it ♪
♪ Take my hand, come zone ♪
♪ Come on, catch a ride ♪
♪ And we take it to places
That we only dreamed ♪
♪ I think I'm home ♪
♪ This is my heaven, baby ♪
♪ Day and night in my zone ♪
♪ The feeling Flows through me ♪
♪ Heaven's where we meet ♪
♪ Happy we lovin'
We lovin' our lives ♪
♪ Things I wished to see
Seem to come to be ♪
♪ I seek the truth, I'm honest
Hey ♪
♪ The moon is singin' our song ♪
♪ Say we find
What we're searchin' for ♪
♪ The love that we holdin' ♪
♪ Another adventure unfolds ♪
♪ I been dreamin' about it
Yeah ♪
♪ Dreamin' about it ♪
♪ Goin' for it ♪
♪ I'm out, I'm rollin'
Till the stars in the sky ♪
♪ Babe, I'm home ♪
♪ In the city ♪
♪ I'm out, I'm rollin'
Till the stars in the sky ♪
♪ Babe, I'm home ♪
♪ Say I might And sail tonight ♪
♪ I'm home ♪
♪ Say right now, I'll get it ♪
♪ Take my hand, come zone ♪
♪ Come on, catch a ride ♪
♪ And we take it to places
That we only dreamed ♪
♪ I think I'm home ♪
♪ This is my heaven, baby ♪
♪ Day and night in my zone ♪
♪ We are free of worries ♪
♪ Stressin' aside ♪
♪ Take me home ♪
♪ Free, no worries at all ♪
Agent, I want an update.
Still searching,
sir. We haven't found any sign of Robotnik.
No one could've
survived that crash.
He's toast. Good riddance.
What a mess that lunatic made.
Sir, there's something else.
When we were wiping Robotnik off
our database, we found something.
A file buried deep in our system
and dating back over 50 years.
What was it?
Coordinates, sir.
Coordinates? To what?
A secret research facility.
It was a black site, sir.
Someone worked very hard
to keep this hidden.
My God.
Project Shadow.