Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
Bio readouts are all in the green.
Looks like she's alive.
Well, there goes our salvage, guys.
How are we today?
Ohh. Terrible.
Well, better than yesterday, at least.
Where am I?
You're safe.
You're at Gateway Station.
Been here a couple of days.
You were pretty groggy at first,
but now you're okay.
Oh, looks like you've got a visitor.
Jonesy. Come here.
Hey, come here.
How are you,
you stupid cat?
How are you?
Where have you been?
Guess you two have met, huh?
I'm Burke. Carter Burke.
I work for the company,
but don't let that fool you.
I'm really an okay guy.
I'm glad to see you're feeling a little better.
They tell me that all
the weakness and disorientation...
...should pass soon.
That's just natural side effects
of such an unusually long hypersleep,
or something like that.
What do you mean?
How long was I out there?
Inhalation Therapy, report to-
Has no one discussed this with you yet?
No.
But, I mean...
I don't... recognize this place.
No, I know. Uh-
Okay. It's just that,
uh, this might be...
...a shock to you.
It's long- How long?
Please.
57 years.
What?
That's the thing.
You were out there...
...for 57 years.
What happened was you had drifted...
...right through the core systems.
And it's really just blind luck...
...that a deep-salvage team
found you when they did.
It's one in a thousand,
really.
I think you're damn lucky
to be alive, kiddo. You could...
...be floating out there forever.
You- You okay?
Uhh-
Uuh.
You okay?
Oh-h-h. Oh, God.
Nurse. Please.
God.
Someone get in here now.
Now.
Hold.
- Please.
Hold on.
Kill me.
No.
Uh.
Bad dreams again?
You want something...
...to help you sleep?
No.
I've slept enough.
Jonesy.
Come here.
Shh.
It's all right.
It's all right now.
It's over.
Dr Hirsch, 334. Dr. Hirsch, 334.
Hi. Sorry I'm late.
I've been running behind...
...all morning.
Is there any word about my daughter?
Uh... I really think we should worry...
...about the hearing now.
'Cause we don't have a lot of time, okay?
I read your deposition, and it's great.
If you just stick to that,
I think we'll be fine.
The thing to remember is,
there're gonna be a lot
of heavyweights in there.
You've got feds and Interstellar
Commerce Commission,
Colonial Administration,
insurance company guys-
Do you have any news about my daughter?
Well, we did come up
with some information.
Why don't we sit down?
I was hoping to wait until after the inquest.
Um-
Amanda Ripley-McClaren-
married name, I guess-
Age 66.
And that was at the time of her death,
which was two years ago.
I'm real sorry.
Amy.
She was cremated and interred
at Westlake Repository,
Little Chute, Wisconsin.
No children. I checked.
I promised her...
that I'd be home...
...for her birthday.
Her 11th birthday.
I'd just like to go, uh-...
...back to this point about
the override destruct order.
Is it in the file?
I don't understand this.
We have been here
for three and a half hours.
Now, how many different ways
do you want me to tell...
...the same story?
Look at it from our perspective,
please.
Please?
Now, you freely admit to
detonating the engines of,
and thereby destroying,
an M-class starsreighter,
a rather expensive piece of hardware.
Forty-two million in adjusted dollars.
That's minus payload,
of course.
The lifeboat's flight recorder
corroborates some elements...
...of your account,
in that, for reasons unknown,
the Nostromo set down...
...on LV-426,
an unsurveyed planet at that time,
that it resumed its course...
...and was subsequently
set for self-destruct...
...by you for reasons unknown.
Not for reasons unknown.
I told you.
We set down there
on company orders to get this thing,
which destroyed my crew...
...and your expensive ship.
The analysis team,
which went over the lifeboat...
...centimetre by centimetre,
found no physical evidence
of the creature you describe.
Good.
That's because I blew it...
...out of the goddamn air lock,
like I said.
Are there any species
like this hostile organism...
...on LV-426?
No. It's a rock.
No indigenous life.
Did I.Q.'s just drop sharply
while I was away?
Ma'am, I already said it was not indigenous.
It was a derelict spacecraft.
It was an alien ship.
It was not from there.
Do you get it?
We homed in on its beacon.
And found something
never recorded once...
...in over 300 surveyed worlds.
A creature that gestates
inside a living human host.
Yes.
These are your words.
And has concentrated acid...
...for blood.
That's right.
Look. I can see where this is going,
but I'm telling you that those things exist.
Thank you, Officer Ripley.
That will be all.
Please. You're not listening to me.
Kane, the crew member-
Kane, who went into that ship,
said he saw...
...thousands of eggs there.
Thousands.
Thank you.
That will be all.
Goddamn it,
that's not all.
Because if one of those things
gets down here,
then that will be all.
Then all of this- this
bullshit that you think...
...is so important-
You can just kiss all of that good-bye.
It is the finding
of this court of inquiry that...
Warrant Officer E. Ripley,
NOC14472,
has acted with questionable judgment...
...and is unfit to hold an I.C.C. license...
...as a commercial flight officer.
Said license is hereby
suspended indefinitely.
Now, no criminal charges
will be filed against you...
...at this time,
and you are released
on your own recognizance...
...for a six-month period
of psychometric probation,
to include monthly review
by an I.C.C. psychiatric technician.
These proceedings are closed.
That could have been better.
Look, I think the- Ripley?
Van Leuwen.
Why don't you just check out LV-426?
Because I don't have to.
There have been people there...
...for over 20 years,
and they never complained
about any hostile organism.
What do you mean? What people?
Terraformers.
Planet engineers.
They go in, set up these
big atmosphere processors...
...to make the air breathable.
Takes decades.
It's what we call a Shake 'N Bake colony.
How many are there?
How many colonists?
I don't know- 60, maybe 70 families.
Do you mind?
Families.
Jesus.
[ Woman On P.A.,
I'll be down in maintenance, okay?
Al.
What?
Hey, Al.
Remember you sent...
...some wildcatters...
...out to the middle of nowhere last week,
out past the Ilium Range?
Yeah, what?
- One of them's on the horn,
a mom-and-pop survey team.
He says he's onto something.
He wants to know if...
...his claim will be honoured.
Why wouldn't his claim be honoured?
Well, because you sent them to that
particular middle-of-nowhere...
...on company orders, maybe.
I don't know.
Christ. Some honch in...
...a cushy office on Earth...
...says, Go look at a grid reference.
We look.
They don't say why,
and I don't ask.
I don't ask, because it takes
two weeks to get an answer out here,
and the answer is always-
Don't ask.
So what do l tell this guy?
Tell him as far as I'm concerned, if he...
...finds something, it is his.
Lydecker?
What?
You kids know you're not
supposed to be on this level.
Go on.
Get outta here.
Do too. You go in places we can't fit.
So? That's why I'm the best.
Knock it off. I catch either
of you playing in the air ducts...
...again, l'll tan your hides.
Mom, all the kids play-
Wait a minute.
Annie, come and have...
...a look at this, will ya?
Folks, we have scored big this time.
What is it, Dad?
I'm not sure.
Let's see if we can't get a
closer look at this thing, maybe...
...through that crack there on the side.
Shouldn't we call in?
- Let's wait till we know...
...what to call it in as.
That's about as close as we can get.
Should we take a look inside?
You two stay inside.
I mean it.
We'll be right back.
Okay.
Bye.
Huh?
Timmy, they've been gone a long time.
It'll be okay, Newt.
Dad knows what he's doing.
Mayday, Mayday. This is Alpha Kilo
Two Four Niner calling.
This is Alpha Kilo Two Four Niner.
Alpha Kilo Two Four Niner calling.
Hiya, Ripley.
This is Lieutenant Gorman...
...of the Colonial Marine Corps-
Ripley,
we have to talk.
We've lost contact
with the colony on LV-426.
I don't believe this.
You guys throw me at the wolves,
and now you want me...
...to go back out there?
Forget it.
It's not my problem.
Can I finish?
No.
There's no way.
Ripley, you wouldn't be going in...
...with the troops.
I can guarantee your safety.
These Colonial Marines
are very tough hombres.
They're packing state-of-the-art...
...firepower.
There's nothing they can't handle.
Lieutenant, am I right?
- That's true.
We've been trained to deal with situations...
...like this.
Then you don't need me.
I'm not a soldier.
Yeah, but we don't know exactly
what's going on out there.
It may just be a downed transmitter,
okay?
But if it's not,
I would like you there...
...as an adviser,
and that's all.
What's your interest in all this?
Why are you going?
Corporation cofinanced that colony,
along with Colonial Administration.
We're getting into a lot of terraforming now.
Building Better Worlds-
Yeah, yeah.
I saw the commercial.
Look, I don't have time for this. I've got...
...to get to work.
Oh, right. I heard you're
working the cargo docks.
That's right.
Running loaders and forklifts,
that sort of thing?
Yeah. So?
Nothing. I think it's great
that you're keeping busy.
And I know it's the only
thing that you could get.
There's nothing wrong with it.
What would you say if I told you I could...
...get you reinstated...
...as a flight officer?
The company's already agreed
to pick up your contract.
If I go.
Yeah, if you go.
Come on.
That's a second chance, kiddo.
I think, personally,
for you, it would be...
...the best thing in the world...
...to get out there and face this thing,
get back on the horse.
Spare me, Burke.
I've had my psych evaluation...
...this month.
Yeah, I know. I've read it. You wake
up every night. Your sheets...
...are soaking with sweat-
I said no,
and I mean it.
Now, please leave.
I am not going back.
And I am- I would not be
any good to you if I did.
Okay. Shh.
Would you do me a favour?
Just think about it.
Thanks for the coffee.
Oh.
Hello.
Ripley.
You okay?
Just tell me...
...one thing, Burke.
You're going out there
to destroy them, right?
Not to study, not to bring back,
but to wipe them out.
That's the plan.
You have my word on it.
All right. I'm in.
I think that-
And you,
you little shithead,
you're staying here.
Mmm.
They ain't payin' us enough for this, man.
Not enough to have to wake up...
...to your face, Drake.
What?
Is that a joke?
Oh, I wish it were.
Hey, Hicks. Man, you look just like I feel.
All right, sweethearts.
What are you waiting for?
Breakfast in bed?
Another glorious day...
...in the corps.
A day in the Marine Corps
is like a day on the farm-...
...every meal's a banquet,
every paycheck a fortune,
every formation a parade.
I love the corps.
Christ.
Man, this floor is freezing.
What do you want me to do?
Fetch your slippers for ya?
Gee, would you, sir? I'd like that.
Look into my eye.
Fall in, people.
Come on. Let's go.
I hate this job.
Crowe, Wierzbowski.
Come on. On your feet.
We got some slack coming, right?
You had three weeks on your back, Frost.
What do you want?
I'm talking about breathing,
not this frozen shit.
Yeah, Top. How 'bout it?
All right. First assembly's
in 15, people. Shag it.
Hey, mira.
Who's Snow White?
She's supposed to be
some kind of consultant.
Apparently,
she saw an alien once.
Whoopee-fuckin'-do.
Hey, I'm impressed.
iQue bonita.
Hey, Vasquez.
Have you ever been...
...mistaken for a man?
No. Have you?
Ha, ha.
Oh, Vasquez.
You're just too bad.
Uhh.
Hey, Top,
what's the op?
It's a rescue mission.
You'll love it.
There's some juicy
colonists' daughters we have...
...to rescue from their virginity.
Dumb-ass colonists.
What's this crap supposed to be?
Vasquez.
Corn bread, I think.
It's good for you, boy.
Eat it.
Hey, sure wouldn't mind
getting some more...
...of that Arcturian poontang.
Remember that time?
- Yeah. Except the one...
...that you had was male.
Doesn't matter when it's Arcturian.
Hey, Bishop, man.
Do the thing with the knife.
Oh, please.
Oh, come on. Yeah.
All right. Yeah.
I don't want to see that, man.
- Come on, man.
All right. All right.
Hey, what are you doing, man?
What are you doing?
Come on.
Quit messing around, Drake.
Hudson, shut up.
Bishop, hey, man.
Do it, Bishop.
Hey. Not me, man.
Quit messing around.
Yeah, you. Don't move.
Trust me.
Aah.
All right. Knock it off,
knock it off.
Thank you.
There you go,
short shit.
Enjoy your meal.
That wasn't funny, man.
Lieutenant Gorman?
Mr. Burke?
Yeah, thanks.
Looks like the new lieutenant's
too good to eat with...
...the rest of us grunts.
Boy's definitely got a corncob up his ass.
Thought you never miss, Bishop.
You never said anything about
an android being on board.
Why not?
It never- never occurred to me.
It's just common practice.
We always have...
...a synthetic on board.
I prefer the term artificial person myself.
Right.
Is there a problem?
I'm sorry.
I don't know why I didn't even-
Ripley's last trip out,
the syn- the artificial person...
...malfunctioned.
Malfunctioned?
- There were problems and...
...a few deaths were involved.
I'm shocked.
Was it an older model?
The Hyperdyne Systems 1 20-A2.
That explains it then.
The A2s always were...
...a bit twitchy.
That could never happen now
with our behavioural inhibitors.
It is impossible for me to harm,
or by omission of action, allow...
...to be harmed, a human being.
You sure you don't want some?
You just stay away from me,
Bishop. You got that straight?
Guess she don't like the corn bread, either.
Squad, ten-hut.
Officer on deck.
As you were.
Quickly, quickly.
Settle down.
All right.
Listen up.
Morning, marines. l'm sorry we
didn't have time to brief you...
...people before we left Gateway-
Sir?
What is it, Hicks?
Hudson, sir.
He's Hicks.
What's the question?
Is this gonna be a stand-up fight, sir,
or another bug hunt?
All we know is that there's still no contact...
...with the colony...
...and that a xenomorph may be involved.
Excuse me, sir.
A what?
A xenomorph.
It's a bug hunt.
What exactly are we dealing with here?
Ripley.
I'll tell you what I know.
We set down on LV-426.
One of our crew members was
brought back on board with...
...something attached to his face,
some kind of parasite.
We tried to get it off.
It wouldn't come off.
Later, it seemed to come off
by itselfand die.
Kane seemed fine.
We were all having dinner,
and, um,
it must have laid something
inside his throat,
some sort of embryo.
He started- Um, he- Look, man.
I only need to know one thing-...
...where they are.
Yo, Vasquez.
Kick ass.
Anytime, anywhere.
Right, right. Somebody said
alien. She thought they said...
...illegal alien and signed up.
Fuck you, man.
Anytime,
anywhere.
Are you finished?
I hope you're right.
I really do.
Yeah, okay, right.
Thank you, Ripley.
We also have Ripley's report on disk.
I suggest you study it.
Because just one of those things
managed to wipe out my entire crew...
...in less than 24 hours.
And if the colonists have found that ship,
then there's no telling...
...how many of them have been exposed.
Do you understand?
Anyway, we have it on disk,
so you better look at it.
Any questions?
What is it, Private?
How do I get out of this chickenshit outfit?
You secure that shit,
Hudson.
All right.
Now listen up.
I want this thing to go smooth...
...and by the numbers.
I want D.C.S.
and tactical database...
...assimilation by 0830.
Ordinance loading, weapons strip
and drop-ship prep details...
...will have seven hours.
Oh, come on.
Now, move it,
people.
All right, sweethearts.
You heard the man,
and you know the drill.
Assholes and elbows.
Hudson, come here.
Come here.
I don't care if you are short, Hudson.
Get it done.
Hey, Sarge.
You'll get lip cancer...
...smoking those.
Corporal, I want this loading lock sealed.
Now.
How many more you got,
Spunkmeyer?
Last one.
Good. Take it away.
Clear behind.
Did you check number three?
Let me see that.
Hi. I feel like kind of
a fifth wheel around here.
Is there anything I can do?
I don't know.
Is there anything...
...you can do?
Well, I can drive that loader.
I have a Class 2 rating.
Be my guest.
Where you want it?
Bay 12, please.
All right,
sweethearts. We're a team, and...
...there's nothing to worry about.
We come here,
and we gonna conquer,
and we gonna kick some.
Is that understood? That's what
we gonna do, sweethearts.
Yes, sir.
We are going to go and get some.
Hey.
All right, people.
On the ready line.
Are you lean?
Are you mean?
Yeah. Yeah.
What are you?
Lean and mean.
Hudson.
Get on the ready line,
marine.
Get some today.
Get on the ready line.
Yo.
Move it out.
Move it out, goddamn it.
Get hot. One, two, three.
Get out, get out, get out.
Move it out, move it out,
move it out. Move it out,
move it out, move it out.
[ Barking Orders,
Absolutely badasses.
Let's pack 'em in.
Get in there.
All right. Move it.
Let's go, let's go.
One, two, three,
four, five, six.
All right.
I want combat seating.
You know your places.
Get those weapons stowed.
Let's go.
Come on.
Settle down, people.
Lock 'em in, Hudson.
Ready to get it on?
You know it.
Okay, Bishop,
let's go.
Roger.
I'm ready, man.
Ready to get it on.
Go.
Stand by. Cross-locking now.
Prelaunch autocycle engaged.
Primary couplers released.
Hit the internals.
Shit, man.
Confirm cross-lock...
...and drop stations secured.
Affirmative.
All drop stations secured.
Stand by. Ten seconds.
Stand by to initiate release sequencer...
...on my mark.
Five, four, three,
- We're on an express elevator...
...to hell, going down.
two, one, mark.
Woo-hoo.
Switch to D.C.S. ranging.
240, nominal to profile.
We're in the pipe,
five by five.
We're picking up some hull ionization.
Got it.
Rough air ahead.
We're in for some chop.
How many drops is this
for you, Lieutenant?
Thirty-eight.
Simulated.
How many combat drops?
Uh, two...
including this one.
Shit.
- Oh, man.
Range 014.
Turning on final.
And I'm telling you,
I got a bad feeling...
...about this drop.
You always say that,
Frost. You always say, I got...
...a bad feeling about this drop.
Okay, okay.
When we get back without you,
I'll call your folks.
All right.
Let's see what we can see.
Everybody online.
Looking good.
Drake, check your camera.
There seems to be...
...a malfunction.
That's better.
Pan it around a bit.
Good.
- I'm ready, man. Check it out.
I am the ultimate badass.
Yeah.
That's right.
State-of-the-badass art.
You do not want to fuck with me.
Who here's runnin'?
Check it out.
Hey, Ripley,
don't worry.
Me and my squad of ultimate badasses...
...will protect you.
Hey.
That's right.
Check it out.
Independently targeting
particle-beam phalanx.
Fry halfa city with this puppy.
We got tactical smart missiles,
phase-plasma pulse rifles,
R.P.G.'s.
We got sonic,
electronic ball breakers.
Whoo.
We got nukes, we got knives,
sharp sticks-
Knock it off, Hudson.
All right, gear up.
Two minutes, people.
Get hot.
Somebody wake up Hicks.
Coming around for a 709er.
Terminal guidance locked in.
Where's the damn beacon?
Oh, I see it.
That's the atmosphere processor?
Yep, that's it.
Remarkable piece of machinery.
Completely automated.
You know,
we manufacture those,
by the way.
Okay, Ferro.
Take us in low over...
...the main colony complex.
Storm shutters are sealed.
There's no visible activity.
All right. Hold at 40.
Roger.
Give me a slow circle...
...of the complex.
Structure seems intact.
They still have power.
Okay, Ferro.
Set down on...
...the landing grid.
Immediate dust off on my clear,
then stay on station.
Down and clear.
Ten seconds, people.
Look sharp.
All right. I want a nice,
clean dispersal this time.
Let's go.
Move it out.
Head 'em up.
First squad up on line.
Hicks, get yours in accord...
...and watch the rear.
Vasquez, take point.
Let's move.
Move up.
Hudson, run a bypass.
Second squad, move up.
Flanking positions.
Second squad on line.
You set?
Go on.
Second team, move inside.
Hicks, take the upper level.
Sir, you copying this? Looks
like hits from small-arms fire.
Uh, we got some explosives damage.
It's probably seismic survey charges.
Are you reading this?
Keep it tight, people.
All right. Hicks, Hudson,
use your motion trackers.
Nothing.
Not a goddamn thing.
Quarter and search by twos.
Okay. Dietrich,
Frost, you're up.
It's right in there.
Now.
Haah. Uh-
- Good one, Hudson.
Uh, sir, uh, we have
a negative situation here.
Uh, movin' on, sir
Wait. Wait,
tell him to-
Hicks, back up.
Pan right.
There.
- You seeing this all right?
Looks melted.
Somebody must have bagged...
...one of Ripley's bad guys here.
Acid for blood.
If you like that,
you're gonna love this.
Quit screwing around.
Second squad,
what's your status?
Uh, we just finished our sweep.
Nobody's home.
Roger.
Sir, this place is dead.
Whatever happened here,
I think we missed it.
All right. The area's
secured. Let's go in and see...
...what their computer can tell us.
Wait a minute.
It's not secure.
The area's secured, Ripley.
First team,
head for operations.
Hudson, see if you can
get their C.P.U. on line.
Affirmative.
Hicks, meet me at
the south lock. We're coming in.
Roger.
He's comin' in.
I feel safer already.
Pendejo jerk-off.
Sir, we got the C.P.U. on line.
No problem.
Good. Stand by in Operations.
Okay, let's go.
Are you all right?
Yes.
Sir, they sealed off this wing at both ends,
welded the doors and
blocked off the stairs...
...with heavy equipment.
Mm-hmm.
But it looks like...
...the barricade didn't hold.
Any bodies?
No, sir.
Last stand.
Must have been a hell of a fight.
Yeah, looks that way.
All right, Drake, this way.
We should be able
to cut through the medlab...
...to Operations.
Lieutenant.
Gorman.
Are those the same ones that-
Careful, Burke.
Looks like love at first sight to me.
Oh, he likes you, Burke.
Two are alive.
The rest are dead.
Surgically removed
before embryo implantation.
Subject Marachek, John J.,
died during the procedure.
They killed him taking it off.
Yo, Hicks.
I think we got something here.
Behind us.
One of us?
Apone, where are your people?
Anybody in D block?
Ah, that's a negative.
We're all in Operations.
Talk to me,
Frosty.
Let's keep moving, baby.
It's moving.
Which way?
It's coming straight for us.
Straight up.
Fuck.
Hold up.
Ripley.
Hey. Shh.
It's all right.
Come on.
Just grab her, Corporal.
Don't be afraid. Come on.
We won't hurt you.
Shh. It's all right.
It's okay.
Come on out. Come on.
Easy. Easy.
- I got her.
Ow. Damn.
Watch her.
She's under the grille.
Don't let her go.
Frost, get your light up here.
Where'd she go?
Shine the light.
Here. Here.
There she is.
Keep back. Keep back.
Don't scare her.
Grab her, man.
We're gonna lose her.
Damn it.
Kick it out.
Wait.
It's okay.
It's all right.
Don't be afraid.
See?
Wait.
No, you don't.
It's okay.
You're gonna...
...be all right now.
Shh.
Easy. Easy.
It's gonna be okay.
It's all right.
You're gonna be okay.
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
Easy. Easy.
What's her name again?
Rebecca.
Now think, Rebecca.
Concentrate.
Just start at the beginning.
Where are your parents?
Now, look, Rebecca,
you have to try and help-
Gorman, give it a rest,
why don't you?
Total brain lock.
Physically, she's okay.
Borderline malnutrition,
but I don't think there's...
...any permanent damage.
Come on.
We're wasting our time.
Try this.
It's a little hot chocolate.
There you go.
Whoop.
That good, huh?
Uh-oh. I made a clean spot here.
Now I've done it.
Guess l'll have to...
...do the whole thing.
Hard to believe there's a little girl...
...under all this.
And a pretty one too.
You don't talk much,
do you?
Smoking or non-smoking?
Just tell me what
you're scanning for, Private.
P.D.T.s.
What?
Personal data transmitters.
Every colonist had one
surgically implanted.
If they're within 20 klicks,
we'll read it out here.
So far, zippo.
I don't know how you
managed to stay alive,
but you're one brave kid, Rebecca.
N-Newt.
What'd you say?
- Newt.
My name's Newt.
Nobody calls me Rebecca
except my brother.
Newt?
I like that.
I'm Ripley.
It's nice to meet you.
And who is this, hmm?
Casey.
Hello, Casey.
What about your brother?
What's his name?
Timmy.
Is Timmy around here too?
Maybe hiding like you were?
Any sisters?
Mom and dad?
Newt, look at me.
Where are they?
They're dead, all right?
Can I go now?
I'm sorry, Newt.
Don't you think you'd
be safer here with us?
These people are here to protect you.
They're soldiers.
It won't make any difference.
Need anything else?
Hello, Bishop. Do you need anything else?
No.
That's a nice pet you got there, Bishop.
Magnificent, isn't it?
Yo. Stop your grinnin'
and drop your linen. Found 'em.
They alive?
Unknown,
but it looks like all of them.
Over at the processing station,
Sublevel 3,
under the main cooling towers.
Looks like a goddamn town meeting.
Let's saddle up, Apone.
Aye, sir.
All right. Let's go, people.
They ain't payin' us...
...by the hour.
Let's go.
Head 'em out.
Okay, Frost,
you're driving.
It's okay. Don't worry.
It'll be okay.
I want a straight V deployment,
second team on left flank.
Advance on axial 664.
Tracker on line.
Set the V gain to filter R.F. ambient.
Hudson, tracker on line.
Left and right, little buddy.
Forty meters in, bearing 221,
there should be a stairwell.
Check. Got it.
You want Sublevel 3.
Let's go, people.
Hudson, you got the point.
Hicks, watch our tails.
Nice and easy.
Check those corners.
Watch your spacing.
All right.
You heard the man.
Don't bunch up.
Stay loose.
Uh, your transmission's
showing a lot of breakup.
Probably getting some interference...
...from the structure.
Use those lights.
Next one down,
and proceed on a 216.
Uh, roger. That's a 216.
I'm not making that out
too well. What is it, Hudson?
You tell me, man.
I only work here.
What is that?
I don't know.
Proceed inside.
Watch your fire and check your targets.
Remember we're looking for civvies in here.
Easy.
Tighten it up, Frost.
We're getting a little thin.
Nice and easy.
Looks like some sort of secreted resin.
Yeah, but secreted from what?
Nobody touch nothing.
Busy little creatures, huh?
Hot as hell in here.
Yeah, man,
but it's a dry heat.
Knock it off, Hudson.
Lieutenant, what do those pulse rifles fire?
Ten millimetre explosive-tip caseless.
Standard light armor-piercing round.
Why?
Well, look where...
...your team is.
They're right under the primary...
...heat exchangers.
So?
So if they fire their weapons
in there, won't they rupture...
...the cooling system?
Ho, ho, ho. Yeah.
She's absolutely right.
So? So what?
Look. This whole station is
basically a big fusion reactor.
Right?
So you're talking about
a thermonuclear explosion,
and adios, muchachos.
Oh, great. Wonderful.
Shit.
Look.
Uh... Apone.
Look. We can't have any firing in there.
I, uh, I want you to collect
magazines from everybody.
Is he fuckin' crazy?
- What the hell are we supposed...
...to use, man, harsh language?
Flame units only.
I want rifles slung.
Sir, I-
Just do it, Sergeant.
And no grenades.
All right, sweethearts.
You heard the man. Pull 'em out.
Come on. Let's have 'em.
Come on, Vasquez.
Clear and lock.
Damn.
You too. Give it up, Ski.
Come on. Let's go.
Crowe, I want it now.
Give it up.
Right on, Vas.
Let's go, marine.
Give it up.
Frost, you got the duty.
Open that bag.
Thanks a lot, Sarge.
- Hicks, cover our ass.
Head 'em out, people.
I like to keep this handy...
for close encounters.
I heard that.
Any movement?
Nothing. Zip.
Holy shit.
Newt, go sit up front.
Go on. Now.
Steady, people.
Let's finish our sweep.
We're still marines,
and we got a job to do.
Keep it moving. Easy.
Help.
- What?
Top, get over here.
We got a live one.
You're gonna be all right.
Please... k-kill me.
Just stay calm.
We're gonna get you outta here.
It's gonna be all right.
Give me a hand.
We gotta get her outta here.
What is it, Dietrich?
- Convulsion.
Dietrich, get back.
Get back.
No.
- Frost, flamethrower.
Kill it.
Get back.
Flamethrower. Move.
Movement.
What's the position?
- I can't lock in.
Talk to me, Hudson.
Multiple signals.
They're closing.
Go to infrared, people.
Look sharp.
What's happening, Apone?
Can't see anything in here.
Pull your team out,
Gorman.
I got signals.
I got readings...
...in front and behind.
Where, man?
I don't see shit.
He's right.
There's nothing back here.
Look, I'm telling you.
There's something moving,
and it ain't us.
Oh, shit.
Tracker's off scale, man.
They're all around us, man. Jesus.
Maybe they don't show up on infrared at all.
Frost.
Come on.
Jesus Christ, Apone.
What is going on?
Wierzbowski and Crowe are down.
Dietrich, Crowe.
Sound off. Frost.
Dietrich, Frost, off the board.
Frost.
Wierzbowski?
Let's rock.
Who's firing?
Goddamn it.
Yeah.
I ordered to hold fire.
They're coming...
...out of the walls.
They're coming out of the goddamn walls.
Let's book.
On the right, man.
Uh, Apone,
I want you to lay down
a suppressing fire with the incinerators-
Vasquez, Drake,
hold your fire,
goddamn it.
Apone, are you copying me? I want you...
...to lay down suppressing fire...
...with the incinerators
and fall back by squads...
...to the A.P.C.
Over.
Say again,
all after incinerator.
I said I want you to lay down
a suppressing fire with...
...the incinerators and fall back...
...by squads to the A.P.C.
Over.
Hey.
Sarge. Sarge.
- Apone.
Talk to me. Apone?
Copy. Copy.
Talk to me, Apone.
He's gone.
Get them out of there.
Shut up.
Do it now. Hicks,
whoever's left, get-
Shut up.
Just shut up.
Goddamn it.
It's coming out of the goddamn walls.
Where's Apone? Where's Apone?
The sarge is gone.
Let's get the fuck out of here.
Let's move it.
Let's go, marine.
Hudson? Vasquez?
Hudson, look out.
Get it.
Watch it.
Hicks.
Come on. Behind you.
Fall back.
I told them to fall back.
Fall back, goddamn it, now.
They're cut off.
Hudson, move your ass.
Do something.
Let's go, marine.
Fuck.
Come on.
Keep moving, baby.
Hold on, Newt.
Ripley, what the hell are you doing?
Turn around.
That's an order.
Get off me, damn it.
Goddamn it, that's an order.
You had your chance,
Gorman.
Come on.
Come on. Let's move it.
Let's go. Let's go.
It's blocked, man.
We gotta go around.
Open the door. Hicks.
- Drake, we are leaving.
Get them, man.
Run for it.
Shit.
Go. Go.
Come on, man. Come on.
Drake, come on.
No.
Fire in the hole.
He's gone.
Put it out. Put it out.
Go. Go.
Come on. Put it out.
- Drake's coming, man.
Drake.
No, he's not.
He's gone.
Forget him.
They're in the goddamn door.
Eat this.
Ripley.
Go, go, go.
It's all right.
We're clear.
Ripley, you've blown the transaxle.
You're just grinding metal.
Come on, ease down.
Ease down.
Ease down. Ease down.
You okay?
l'm all right.
Hudson.
Get away from me, man.
Lieutenant.
What happened...
...to Gorman?
I don't know.
Maybe a concussion.
But he's alive.
He's dead.
Wake up, pendejo, and then
I'm gonna kill you.
Back off.
Right now.
Fuck.
Somebody get me...
...a first aid kit.
Hey. Hey, look.
The sarge and Dietrich aren't dead, man.
Their signs are real low,
but they ain't dead.
Then we go back in there and get them.
Fuck that.
We don't leave our people behind
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player