Drake, come on!
Aagh!
- Aaaghhh!
- No!
Fire in the hold!
- He's gone!
- No! Drake's out there!
Put it out!
Drake's coming!
He's gone!
No, he's... not!
Forget him! He's gone!
Get on the goddamn door!
Eat this!
Aagh!
Ripley! Go, go, go!
Whoa!
Oh!
It's all right! We're clear!
Ripley, you've blown the transaxle!
You're just grinding metal!
Come on, ease down.
Ease down.
Ease down!
You OK?
I'm all right.
Get away from me, man!
- Lieutenant.
- What happened to Gorman?
I don't know... Maybe a concussion.
- But he's alive.
- No, man, he's dead!
- Wake up, pendejo! I'm gonna kill you!
- Back off!
Right now.
Somebody get me a first-aid kit.
Hey. Hey, look!
The Sarge and Dietrich aren't dead, man.
Their signs are real low, but they ain't dead.
- Then we go back in there and get them.
- I ain't going back!
You can't help them!
You can't. Right now they're
being cocooned just like the others.
Oh, dear Lord Jesus,
this ain't happenin', man.
This can't be happenin', man.
This isn't happenin'!
We've got seven canisters of CN-20.
I say we roll them in there
and nerve-gas the whole fuckin' nest.
It's worth a try, but we
don't know if it'll affect 'em.
Let's bug out and call it even.
Why even talk about it?
I say we take off and
nuke the entire site from orbit.
It's the only way to be sure.
- Fuckin' A!
- Hold on one second.
This installation has a substantial
dollar value attached to it.
They can bill me.
OK, look.
This is an emotional moment
for all of us, OK? I know that.
But let's not make snap judgments, please.
This is clearly an important species
we're dealing with...
...and I don't think anybody
has the right to arbitrarily...
...exterminate them.
- Wrong.
Yeah. Watch us.
Maybe you aren't up on current events,
but we just got our asses kicked, pal!
Look, I'm not blind to what's going on...
...but I cannot authorize that kind of action.
Well, I believe Corporal Hicks
has authority here.
Corporal Hicks is...
This operation is under military jurisdiction.
Hicks is next in chain of command.
Am I right, Corporal?
Yeah.
Yeah, that's right.
Yeah. Look, Ripley, this is
a multimillion-dollar installation, OK?
He can't make that decision. He's just a grunt.
No offence.
None taken.
- Ferro, do you copy?
- Standing by.
- Prep for dust-off. We need immediate evac.
- Roger. On our way.
I say we take off... nuke the site from orbit.
It's the only way to be sure.
Let's do it.
Let's go! Pick it up, Hudson.
Pick it up, baby.
All right. Set him down here.
Move it, Spunkmeyer. We're rolling.
Hold on a second. There's something...
Just get up here.
I'm in. Ramp closing.
Spunkmeyer.
Goddamn it.
Well, where the fuck...
Run!
Well, that's great.
That's just fuckin' great, man.
Now what the fuck are we supposed to do?
We're in some real pretty shit now, man!
Are you finished?
You all right?
I guess we're not
gonna be leaving now, right?
I'm sorry, Newt.
You don't have to be sorry.
It wasn't your fault.
That's it, man. Game over, man! Game over!
What the fuck are we gonna do now?
What are we gonna do?!
Maybe we could build a fire, sing
a couple of songs. Why don't we try that?
We'd better get back cos it'll be dark soon,
and they mostly come at night.
Mostly.
That's everything, right?
This is absolutely everything
we could salvage out of the APC wreckage.
We got four pulse rifles
with about 50 rounds each.
That ain't so good.
We got 15 of these M-40 grenades.
Don't touch that.
Dangerous, honey.
- Is that the only flamethrower?
- Yeah. It's only half full, but it's functional.
And another one's damaged.
I don't know about that one.
But the good news...
We got four of these robot sentries...
...with display and scanners intact.
They really kick ass. They'll come in handy.
How long after we're declared overdue
can we expect a rescue?
17 days.
17 days?
Hey, man, I don't wanna rain on your parade,
but we're not gonna last 17 hours!
Those things are gonna come in here
like they did before, and...
Hudson! Hudson!
This little girl survived longer than that
with no weapons and no training.
Right?
- Why don't you put her in charge?
- You better start dealing with it, Hudson.
Listen to me.
Deal with it, because we need you...
...and I'm sick of your bullshit.
Now get on a terminal and call up
a floor-plan file. Do you understand?
Construction blueprints. Anything that
shows the layout. Are you listening?
Yeah.
I need to see air ducts, electrical
access tunnels, sub-basements...
...every possible way into this complex.
We don't have much time.
OK.
- OK, I'm on it.
- Hudson...
Just relax.
I'll be in med lab.
I'll check on Gorman, continue my analysis.
Fine.
You do that.
So this service tunnel must be
how they're moving back and forth.
Right. It moves from the processing
station right into the sub-level here.
Come down on that.
OK, come over.
Hold it. Go back.
OK, punch that in right there.
- No. It's back here.
- OK.
Well, there's a pressure door at this end.
Couldn't we put a remote
sentry unit in the tunnel...
...and then seal that door?
- But we gotta figure on them getting in.
That's right, so...
...we repair the barricades
at these two intersections...
...and weld plate steel
over these ducts here, and here...
...and here.
Then they can only come at us
from these two corridors.
Right. Then we put
the other sentry units here...
...and here. Right?
- Right.
- Outstanding.
Now all we need is a deck of cards.
All right, let's move
like we've got a purpose.
- Affirmative.
Do your thing, baby.
Vasquez, let's get the hell out of here.
- A and B sentries are in place and keyed.
- Roger.
Stand by. Arming now.
Test it, Hudson.
- Do it!
- Fire in the hole!
OK! Let's get the hell out of here!
We're sealing the tunnel!
Come on, baby.
For what it's worth...
Here, I want you to put this on.
What's it for?
It's a locator. Then I can find you
anywhere in the complex... on this.
It's just a precaution.
Thanks.
Doesn't mean we're engaged or anything.
All right, what's next?
Last stop.
Get in.
Scoot down.
That's good.
Now you lie here and have a nap.
You're very tired.
I don't want to. I have scary dreams.
Well, I bet Casey doesn't have scary dreams.
Let's take a look.
Nope. Nothing bad in there.
See?
Maybe you could just try to be like her.
Ripley, she doesn't have bad dreams...
...because she's just a piece of plastic.
Right.
I'm sorry, Newt.
There.
My mommy always said there
were no monsters. No real ones.
But there are.
Yes, there are, aren't there?
Why do they tell little kids that?
Most of the time it's true.
Did one of those things grow inside her?
I don't know, Newt.
That's the truth.
Isn't that how babies come?
I mean, people babies?
- They grow inside you.
- No. That's very different.
Did you ever have a baby?
Yes, I did.
I had a little girl.
Where is she?
She's gone.
You mean dead.
Here.
Take this.
For luck.
How's that?
Don't go! Please!
Newt, I'm gonna be right in the next room.
And you see that camera?
I can see you through that camera...
...all the time, to see if you're safe.
I'm not gonna leave you, Newt.
I mean that.
That's a promise.
You promise?
I cross my heart.
And hope to die?
And hope to die.
Now go to sleep...
...and don't dream.
Sneak.
The molecular acid oxidizes after the
creature's death, completely neutralizing.
Bishop, that's interesting,
but it gets us nowhere.
I'm trying to figure out what we're dealing
with here. Let's go through it again.
They grab the colonists and immobilize them
to be hosts for more of these.
So there would have to be
a lot of these parasites.
One for each colonist.
A hundred at least.
Yes, that follows.
Each one of these things
comes from an egg, right?
So who's laying these eggs?
I'm not sure.
It must be something we haven't seen yet.
Hey, maybe it's like an ant hive.
- Bees, man. Bees have hives.
- You know what I mean.
There's, like, one female
that runs the whole show.
- Yes. The queen.
- Yeah, the mama.
And she's badass, man. I mean big.
- These things ain't ants.
- I know that!
Bishop, I want these specimens destroyed
as soon as you're finished with them.
Mr. Burke said they were to be kept alive
in stasis for return to the company labs.
He was very specific about it.
Those two specimens are worth millions
to the bio-weapons division.
If you're smart, we can both
come out of this heroes...
...and we will be set up for life.
You're crazy, Burke. Do you know that?
You really think you can get a dangerous
organism like that past ICC quarantine?
How can they impound it
if they don't know about it?
But they will know about it, Burke. From me.
Just like they'll know you were responsible
for the deaths of 157 colonists.
- Wait a second!
- You sent them to that ship.
I just checked the colony log: directive
dated 6-12-79, signed Burke, Carter J.
You sent them out there
and you didn't even warn them.
What if that ship didn't even exist?
Did you think about that? I didn't know.
So now if I make a major security situation
out of it, everybody steps in...
...and there's no exclusive rights
for anybody. Nobody wins.
So I made a decision and it was wrong.
It was a bad call, Ripley. A bad call.
Bad call? These people are dead, Burke!
Have you any idea what you've done here!
I'm gonna make sure
they nail you right to the wall.
You won't sleaze your way out of this one.
Right to the wall.
Ripley.
You know, I expected more from you.
I thought you'd be smarter than this.
I'm happy to disappoint you.
What is it? What's going on?
- They're coming.
- Where?
In the tunnel.
Here we go.
A and B gun tracking and firing.
Multiple targets.
Look at those ammo counters go.
B gun's down 50 per cent.
It's a shooting gallery down there!
60 rounds left on B.
40... 20... 10.
B gun's dry. 20 on A.
Ten...
...five...
That's it.
Jesus! They're wall-to-wall in there.
They're at the pressure door.
Man, listen to that.
Bishop here. I'm afraid I have some bad news.
Well, that's a switch!
It's very pretty, Bishop,
but what are we looking for?
That's it. Emergency venting.
That's beautiful, man. That beats it all.
How long till it blows?
Four hours...
...with a blast radius of 30 kilometers,
equal to about 40 megatons.
- We got problems.
- I don't fuckin' believe this!
Vasquez, close the shutters.
Why can't we shut it down from here?
The crash caused too much damage.
An overload was inevitable at this point.
Oh, man! And I was getting short!
Four more weeks and out.
- Now I'm gonna buy it on this rock!
- Give us a break!
Four more weeks. Oh, man!
We need the other drop-ship from the Sulaco.
Can't we bring it down on remote?
How? The transmitter was on the APC!
It's wasted!
I don't care how,
but we'd better think of something!
Think of what?!
We're fucked! We're doomed!
Shut up! What about the colony transmitters?
The uplink tower at the other end?
The hard-wiring between
here and there was damaged.
We can't align the dish.
Somebody has to go out there. Take
a portable terminal and patch in manually.
Oh, yeah, sure! With those things
running around? You can count me out.
- We can count you out of everything.
- I'll go.
- Why don't you go, man?
- What?
- I'll go.
I'm the only one qualified
to remote-pilot the ship.
Yeah, right, man. Bishop should go.
Good idea!
Believe me, I'd prefer not to.
I may be synthetic, but I'm not stupid.
How long?
This conduit runs almost
to the uplink assembly. 180 meters.
- Say 40 minutes to crawl down there...
- Right.
...an hour to patch in and align the antenna...
...30 minutes to prep the ship,
and about 50 minutes flight time.
It's gonna be close.
- Good luck.
- See you soon.
Watch your fingers.
Vaya con Dios, man.
This is unbelievable!
20 meters and closing. 15.
How many?
Can't tell. Lots.
D gun's down 50 per cent.
C gun's right behind it.
It ain't stopping 'em.
It ain't stopping 'em!
150 rounds on D.
Come on, baby. Come on!
100 rounds.
Come on, come on!
D gun's down to 20.
Ten.
Damn it!
Wait!
They're retreating.
The guns stopped them.
You're right.
Next time they walk right up and knock.
Yeah, but they don't know that.
They're probably looking
for other ways to get in.
That'll take 'em a while.
- Maybe we got 'em demoralized.
- Shut up.
I want you two walking perimeter.
Move!
Hey, listen.
We're all in strung-out shape...
...but stay frosty...
...and alert.
We can't afford to let
one of those bastards in here.
All right. Vámonos.
How long's it been since you got any sleep?
24 hours?
Hicks, I'm not gonna end up like those others.
You'll take care of it, won't you?
If it comes to that, I'll do us both.
Let's just make sure
it doesn't come to that, all right?
All right.
Hey, I want to introduce you
to a personal friend of mine.
This is an M-41A pulse rifle, 10 millimeter...
...with an over-and-under 30 millimeter
pump-action grenade launcher.
Feel the weight.
OK. What do I do?
Pull it in tight here.
- Right.
- Lean into it.
All right, now it will kick some.
When the counter reads zero here, you...
- I press this up?
- That's right.
Get another one in quick. Slap it in hard.
- Right.
- Now you're ready to rock 'n' roll.
- What's this?
- The grenade launcher.
I don't think you want to mess with that.
You started this. Show me everything.
I can handle myself.
Yeah, I noticed.
How do you feel?
All right, I guess. One hell of a hangover.
- Look, Ripley, I just want...
- Forget it. Excuse me.
Shh, shh, shh.
It's OK. It's OK.
Newt. Wake up.
- What?
- Be quiet.
We're in trouble.
Agh!
Move, Newt!
Hey!
Help!
Hicks!
Say again, Bishop?
You've got it into auto-refuel mode
and it's sequencing right?
That's right.
Good. Stay on it.
Get back to me when you've
activated the launch cycle.
- He's at the uplink tower.
- Terrific.
- Hicks! Hicks!
- Help! Help!
Hicks! Help us!
Break the glass!
Break it, break it!
I'll try.
Ripley, I'm scared.
Me, too.
Stay here.
It's the med lab. Hudson!
Vasquez! Meet me in med lab! We got a fire!
We're on our way.
They're coming, Newt.
Urgh!
Aagh!
Shoot it out!
- Hudson!
- Jesus!
Oh!
Christ, kid, look out!
- Over there!
- Yeah!
- Ready?
Hudson!
Yeah, all clear. Nailed the other one.
It's history, man.
Jesus!
Burke. It was Burke.
I say we grease this rat-fuck
son of a bitch right now.
It just doesn't make any goddamn sense.
He figured that he could get an alien
back through quarantine...
...if one of us was impregnated.
Whatever you call it.
And then frozen for the trip home.
Nobody would know about
the embryos we were carrying...
...me and Newt.
Wait, now. We'd all know.
Yes. He could only do it by sabotaging
certain freezers on the way home.
Namely, yours.
Then he could jettison the bodies
and make up any story he liked.
Fuck! He's dead.
You're dog meat, pal.
This is so nuts. I mean, listen...
Listen to what you're saying.
It's paranoid delusion. It's really sad.
It's pathetic.
Burke, I don't know which species is worse.
They don't fuck each other over
for a goddamn percentage.
All right, we waste him. No offence.
No! He's got to go back...
They cut the power.
How can they cut the power?
They're animals!
I want you two checking the corridors! Move!
Gorman, watch Burke.
Newt, stay close.
- I'll go this side.
- You do that, man.
- Anything?
- There's something.
It's inside the complex.
You're just reading me.
No, it ain't you.
They're inside the perimeter. They're in here.
Hudson, stay cool. Vasquez?
Hudson may be right.
- Get back, both of you.
- The signal's weird.
Must be some interference or something.
There's movement all over the place!
Get back to Operations. It's game time.
Newt.
Seal the door.
Hurry!
Come on! Come on, get back!
Work fast.
Cover your eyes, Newt. Don't look at the light.
Movement. Signal's clean. Range: 20 meters.
They found a way in, something we missed.
We didn't miss anything.
18...
17 meters.
Something under the floor, not in the plans.
- 15 meters.
- Ripley!
Definitely inside the barricades.
Let's go!
- That's right outside the door. Get back!
- This is a big fuckin' signal.
- How you doing, Vasquez?
- Almost there.
That's it.
12 meters.
11...
10...
- They're right on us.
- 9 meters.
- Remember, short controlled bursts.
- 8 meters.
7...
6...
- That can't be!
- It's reading right, man!
You're not reading it right.
5 meters, man - 4!
What the hell!
- Oh, my God!
- Give me the light!
There they go! Get 'em!
- Come on!
- Get 'em!
Do something, Gorman!
Look out! Look out!
There's more of 'em!
Get to medical!
Do it! Now!
Hudson! Look out!
Aagh!
Now!
Burke!
Open this door! Burke! Open it!
Agh!
Let's go! Let's go! Fall back!
Go!
Die, motherfucker!
Burke!
Hudson!
Motherfucker!
Come on! Come on! Come and get it, baby!
I don't got all day! Come on, you bastard!
Come on, you too!
You want some of this? Fuck you!
Aagh!
Fuck you!
- Hicks!
- Hudson!
Come on, Hicks!
Go!
It's locked!
Got it! Let's go!
Go! Go!
Move, Gorman!
Seal it!
Burke!
Goddamn you! Open this door!
Get back!
- Hurry up!
- Gorman, get out of the way!
- Ripley, this way!
- What?
Wait. Get behind me.
Whatever you're gonna do, do it fast!
- Hicks!
- Come on, let's go!
Move!
- Which way to the landing field?
- This way.
Go right!
This way! This way.
- Which way?
- Straight ahead and left.
Bishop, do you read me? Come in. Over.
The ship is on its way.
ETA 16 minutes.
Good! Stand by there! We're on our way!
- Which way now?
- That way.
- No, wait! This way!
- Are you sure?
Vasquez, move!
- Right up here! It's just up here!
- Hicks!
We're almost there!
Newt, wait!
Newt!
Vasquez!
Go!
Ohh! Ohh, no!
Newt!
Up there!
There's a short cut across the roof!
Hicks!
You always were an asshole, Gorman.
Newt!
- Ripley!
- Newt!
Hicks! Hicks, get her! Hurry!
Oh! Hold on, Newt!
- I'm slipping!
- Don't let go!
- Ripley!
- Hold on!
- Help!
- Gotcha!
I gotcha!
Newt! No!
Come on! We can find her with this!
Stay where you are, Newt!
- Ripley!
- We're coming!
Ripley!
This way.
She's close.
Newt!
Ripley!
Where are you! Can you hear me!
- Newt!
- Here! I'm here!
Where?!
Newt, are you OK?
Gonna have to cut it.
Climb down, honey.
We've got to cut through.
Newt?
Now don't move. Stay very still.
OK.
We're almost there. Hang in there, OK?
Hicks! Hurry!
- I know!
- I mean it!
Newt, just stay still!
Aagh!
- Almost there!
- No!
Newt!
No! No!
- Let's go!
- No!
They don't kill you!
They don't kill you! They...
- She's alive! She's alive!
- All right! I believe you! She's alive!
We've got to go! Now!
Hicks...
Get it off!
Aagh!
Here!
Go!
Come on, you can make it!
Bishop! How much time?!
Plenty! 26 minutes!
- We're not leaving!
- We're not?
- Ripley...
- Bishop, she's alive. There's still time.
In 19 minutes this area
is gonna be a cloud of vapor.
- Hicks, don't let him leave.
- We ain't going anywhere.
- See you, Hicks.
- Dwayne.
It's Dwayne.
Ellen.
Don't be gone long, Ellen.
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel must evacuate immediately.
You now have 15 minutes
to reach minimum safe distance.
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel must evacuate immediately.
You now have 14 minutes
to reach minimum safe distance.
Ripley!
Grab on to me!
Hold on!
Let's go!
Behind us!
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel must evacuate immediately.
You now have four minutes
to reach minimum safe distance.
Come on, goddamn it!
Hold on to me!
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel must evacuate immediately.
You now have two minutes
to reach minimum safe distance.
No!
Bishop!
Goddamn you!
Close your eyes, baby.
Look!
Come on! Come on!
Punch it, Bishop!
It's OK.
We're OK.
Hey.
We made it.
I knew you'd come.
He's gonna be all right.
He's just out. I had to give him
another shot for the pain.
We need a stretcher
to carry him up to medical.
OK.
I'm sorry if I scared you.
That platform was becoming too unstable.
I had to circle and hope that things
didn't get too rough to take you off.
Bishop...
- You did OK.
- I did?
Oh, yeah.
Go! Move!
No! Here! Here!
Run!
Here!
Get away from her, you bitch!
Come on! Come on!
Aagh!
Ripley!
Ohh!
Aagh!
Bishop!
- Mommy!
- Oh, God!
Not bad for a... human.
Are we gonna sleep all the way home?
All the way home.
Can I dream?
Yes, honey. I think we both can.
Sleep tight.
Affirmative.
Subtitles by Visiontext