Downloaded from
YTS.MX
♪ ♪
Official YIFY movies site:
YTS.MX
♪ ♪
(insects chirring)
(footsteps)
(insects continue chirring)
(chirring continues)
It's okay.
Relax.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
I'm just gonna learn about you
for a little while.
Is that okay?
(insects chirring)
I'm gonna name you Kerolien
after my friend at school.
She's really nice.
But she farts in class sometimes
and pretends like she didn't.
So, please don't do that,
'cause you're sharing
this jar now,
and the others won't like you
if you smell. Okay?
(footsteps approaching)
♪ ♪
MAN:
Hi there.
I'm not from around here,
but I was hoping to make
some new friends.
Can I talk to you
for a little bit?
I... I don't talk to strangers.
Of course you don't.
You shouldn't. You're smart.
But I'm here to be your friend,
so, hopefully, we won't
be strangers for too long.
What's your name?
Wenling.
But everyone calls me Wen.
Well, it's nice
to meet you, Wen.
My name's Leonard.
I see you're catching
grasshoppers.
Can I help you?
Um, I guess so.
I loved catching grasshoppers
when I was your age.
-Oh, you're really good.
-Thanks, Wen.
Can you pass me the jar
there, please?
Wait.
Let the ones inside
calm down a bit.
We don't want them to panic.
There you go.
Are you just a natural,
or did someone teach you
how to catch grasshoppers?
Daddy Eric taught me.
I'm studying them.
I'm gonna take care of animals
when I grow up.
You call your dad
by his first name?
It's so they know
who I'm talking to.
There's Daddy Eric
and Daddy Andrew.
All the other kids at school
only have one dad.
All the Disney Channel shows
only have one dad, too.
Well, does that bother you?
No.
Except when my
guidance counselor keeps saying
how it's so great
that I have two dads.
For some reason,
it makes me feel like
she's saying the opposite.
(leaves rustling)
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Nothing at all.
How old are you, Wen?
I'll be eight in six days.
Well, happy almost-birthday.
In fact, it just so happens
that I have something for you.
I saw it,
and I thought it was pretty,
so I decided to keep it.
So, consider it
an early birthday present.
And if you don't like it,
we can play a game
with it instead.
What kind of game?
We'll take turns pulling petals
off and asking questions,
and by the time we're done,
we'll know each other better.
-Be better friends.
-Hmm, 'kay.
What's your favorite movie?
Kiki's Delivery Service.
I haven't seen that.
I'll check it out.
Okay, your turn.
Why are you here?
(insects chirring)
Leonard?
Why am I here?
Well, I suppose I'm here
to make friends with you
and your dads.
Maybe catch some more
grasshoppers.
(Leonard breathes deeply)
How'd you get that tiny
little scar on your lip?
I'm so sorry, Wen.
I shouldn't have asked that.
It's... It's too personal,
even for this game.
It's okay.
My lip was broken
when I was born.
My dads said it took a lot
of doctors to fix it.
Well, I don't have a scar
like you,
but if you could look inside,
you'd see that my heart
is broken.
Why is it broken?
Because of what I have
to do today.
What do you have to do?
(footsteps approaching)
Are they your friends?
You're my friend, Wen.
No matter what happens,
I want you to remember that.
The others who are coming are
more like people I work with.
You see, the four of us have
a very important job to do.
In fact, it might be
the most important job
in the history of the world.
♪ ♪
(chain rattling quietly)
LEONARD:
This isn't about you, Wen.
Or your dads.
Okay?
You haven't done anything wrong,
but I'm afraid the three of you
are gonna have to make
some tough decisions.
Terrible decisions.
And I wish with all my broken
heart that you didn't have to.
Wen!
Your dads won't want
to let us in.
You have to tell them they must.
Otherwise, we're gonna have
to find our own way in.
Do you understand?
Wen, tell me you understand!
(breathing rapidly)
(lock clicks)
("Distance" by Emily King
plays quietly)
♪ Oh ♪
-♪ Love is always better... ♪
-(running footsteps)
(Wen breathing rapidly)
-ANDREW: This isn't bad.
-ERIC: The cheese is good.
See? Factual proof.
There she is.
You didn't need to check on her.
You have to come inside
right now.
There's strangers,
and they want to come in,
-and they're scary!
-Whoa, whoa, slow down.
-Hurry, now!
-Okay, okay, I'm coming.
-We're coming inside.
-God, okay.
-Come on!
-Honey, what's happening?
-Tell me what's so...
-Relax, relax. Okay. It's okay.
-It's okay.
-Wen, what's up?
Wen, Wen, it's okay.
Listen, sweetie. What happened?
What scared you?
There... there were four
of them.
The big one, his name's Leonard.
He... he says
we have to help them.
He says they have
the most important job
in the history of the world.
Jehovah's Witnesses?
Great.
They have these weapons.
(seven knocks on door)
(knocking stops)
♪ ♪
LEONARD:
Hello in there.
My name is Leonard,
and I'm here
with some associates of mine.
Can you open the door, please?
(whispering):
This guy is frigging huge.
What do we do?
I don't know. Um...
tell them to go away nicely?
Hi. Uh, hello, Leonard. We...
Is that Daddy Andrew
or Daddy Eric?
I met your delightful daughter
Wen already.
She's so thoughtful and kind.
You two should be very proud.
This is Eric.
Is there something
we can help you with?
LEONARD:
There is.
Why don't you open the door?
It'll be easier if we speak
face-to-face.
WEN:
Tell them to go away.
Please make them go away.
Wen, please.
Uh, we weren't expecting
visitors.
I don't want to sound rude,
but we'd like to be left alone.
I understand.
And I'm sorry to intrude
on your vacation,
especially in such
a beautiful place as this.
Make them go away!
(quietly):
Wen.
You should know that
this isn't easy for us, either.
None of us have been
to this lake before.
And the four of us,
we never thought
we'd be here talking
to you nice people.
(chain rattles)
Who else is out there with you?
I'm here with Sabrina, Adriane
and Redmond.
And the four of us are here
because we're trying to save
a whole bunch of people.
Eric, come here. Come here.
LEONARD: But we need
your help to do that.
We can't do anything
without you,
and speaking through a door
is making a difficult
conversation near impossible.
(whispers):
What?
(chain rattling)
(whispering): There's a woman
carrying something
that looks like a pick
with a chain
and a mallet head at the end.
I'm calling the police now.
(phone pad beeping)
This can't be right.
There's no dial tone.
ERIC:
What?
I checked it when we got here.
Is the battery dead?
ANDREW: The battery's not dead.
It's not dialing.
LEONARD:
Like I said, we need to talk.
We don't have a choice.
Yeah, well,
we don't have a choice, either!
We're calling the cops!
ADRIANE: Hey, um,
we know you can't do that.
None of our phones get service
out here, either.
And sorry,
we had to cut the phone line.
(quiet muttering outside)
(Wen whimpers)
ANDREW (whispering): Wen. Wen.
Wen. We-Wen, give me the phone.
LEONARD:
We don't mean to rush you,
but we're a little pressed
for time.
Please open the door so we can
have a real conversation.
-If you want to talk, then why
do you... -Shh. -Wen, Wen.
-...have those scary weapons
with you? -Shh, shh. Wen. Wen.
LEONARD:
They're not weapons, Wen.
They're tools.
-(pounding on door) -REDMOND:
Just open the goddamn door!
We're coming in either way.
The hell you are! I have a gun!
(whispering):
You brought it here?
Yes and no. It's in the safe
in the back of the truck.
REDMOND:
He's lying.
Show us what you're packing,
Daddy Andrew!
We all like show-and-tell.
You'll see it when I'm
pointing it at your head,
you piece of crap!
SABRINA: What's wrong with you?
You're not helping.
-You're upsetting him.
-REDMOND: What?
LEONARD:
I'm sorry.
Redmond is as anxious
and passionate as we all are.
I'm giving you one last chance
to open the door.
(banging on door)
(rattling)
They're breaking in!
(banging on door)
♪ ♪
(Wen breathing rapidly)
ERIC:
Andrew, couch!
Good job, Wen. Keep going.
Push it.
(grunting)
ANDREW:
Okay.
♪ ♪
(lock rattling)
Daddy Andrew!
(breathing rapidly)
I got you, baby.
(banging)
They're in the basement.
One is in the back,
one is downstairs.
Let's make a run for it
to the car.
I've got the keys.
-(chain rattling)
-(pounding on door)
It doesn't have to be like this.
Get Wen out of here.
(grunting)
(Sabrina screams)
Eric!
Let me help him.
-Wait...
-Don't touch him!
I'm a nurse! He's hurt!
(grunting)
Stop! Stop.
(Redmond grunting)
(shuddered breathing)
Eric.
Daddy Eric.
Please get up.
We have to go, Daddy.
(pounding)
ANDREW:
Eric, wake up.
Wake up, Eric!
(grunting)
(strained grunting)
(Redmond groaning, gasping)
(Wen crying)
Shh.
Shh, you'll be okay.
Andrew, that's enough.
(breathing heavily)
(chain falls to the floor)
("Ac-Cent-Tchu-Ate the Positive"
by Aretha Franklin playing)
♪ To illustrate ♪
♪ My last remark ♪
♪ Jonah in the whale,
Noah in the ark ♪
♪ Tell me, what did they do... ♪
I like your fridge.
Thanks, Mom.
♪ Man, they said we got to ♪
♪ Ac-cent-tchu-ate
the positive ♪
♪ And e-lim-i-nate
the negative ♪
♪ And hang on
to that affirmative ♪
♪ But don't mess,
don't mess with... ♪
They drove for seven hours
and stayed 45 minutes.
I'm sorry.
What do you expect?
(engine starting)
-(sighs)
-(phone ringing)
That's my mom
asking how it's going.
Well, you can tell her
you were wrong.
Andrew.
(phone continues ringing)
Always together.
-(phone beeps)
-ERIC: Hi.
(Strawberry Shortcake humming
on TV)
STRAWBERRY SHORTCAKE:
Thanks, Custard.
This is a very important
cupcake order.
(Custard meows)
SABRINA:
Let me see if this helps.
Is that better?
(Custard meowing)
Try not to move.
Almost done.
STRAWBERRY SHORTCAKE:
I have to finish
this special order
before tomorrow.
It needs to be purr-fect.
(Custard meows)
Can you turn that down?
LEONARD:
We did when you asked before,
but I'll do it again.
(TV continues low, indistinctly)
Is Eric cleaned up?
He's cleaned up, yeah,
but severely concussed.
Hey, Eric.
You feeling any better?
I'm... I'm so sorry.
I've never watched this show
before, but-but I like it.
The characters, um,
they seem curious and good.
I get the sense that it
explores or teaches empathy
and tolerance,
and that's just lovely.
Empathy and tolerance?
Is that what you're here
to talk about
now that you have the queers
tied up?
(sighs):
Oh.
Andrew, I assure you
that we're not here
with hate or prejudice
in our hearts. Not at all.
We don't have one
homophobic bone in our bodies.
I don't hate anybody.
I do have conflicted feelings
about this door.
(door clatters)
LEONARD:
You have to believe that.
But we had no idea
you were a single-sex couple
until we got here.
That one was a surprise.
Well, I guess if you promise,
then I have to believe you.
I mean, we're normal people
just like you.
-We have no choice.
-There's always a choice!
ADRIANE:
He's right about that.
Our choices make our destiny.
I almost got that tattooed.
(laughs softly)
Okay, you're right, Andrew.
There's always a choice.
So we choose to be here.
Can everyone come in here,
please?
It's almost time.
Time for what?
You don't need us tied up.
You said you were here to talk,
so we'll talk.
(Andrew grunting)
(Sabrina exhales)
Hi, Eric, Wen...
(clears throat)
...and Andrew.
My name is Sabrina.
I live in Southern California.
I live in a town
you've probably never heard of.
I have been a post-op nurse
for almost five years.
I used most of my savings
to come out to Pennsylvania,
to come here to talk
with you guys.
(shuddered breathing)
I have a little
half sister back home...
...and, Wen,
you kind of remind me of her.
(Sabrina and Leonard
clear their throats)
(clears throat)
Well, I think you-you guys
already know
my name is Leonard.
And, uh,
I'm good at catching
grasshoppers, right, Wen?
(grunts)
I'm from Chicago.
I'm a second grade teacher,
and I run
the after-school program.
I'm also a bartender. I...
Okay. Me?
Am I next?
Hi there.
I'm Redmond, and I like
long walks on the beach,
-and I like beer.
-LEONARD: Hey.
We already discussed this.
They deserve to know who we are.
We wasted time for this guy
to wake up.
You know, this get-to-know-you
stuff doesn't matter at all.
Doesn't change what we have
to do or what they have to do.
When you say stuff like that,
you sound how you sound,
okay, you just scare them,
you make it less likely
that they'll believe us
or cooperate.
Okay, okay, my turn it is.
I live in Medford,
Massachusetts.
I work for the gas company,
making sure houses
and apartments don't blow up.
I'm single,
if you can believe that.
I've done some time,
as they say.
Did a lot of, uh...
questionable stuff
when I was young and stupid.
But I'm much better now.
And my father used to beat
the shit out of me,
like Andrew just did.
Wish I could go back in time,
give the kid-me this thing.
May I speak now?
I hope I don't sound confusing.
ERIC:
Hold on, hold on a second.
Wh...
We get that you guys
are a part of some group
and it sounds like,
it sounds like you want to...
fix things.
To help.
ANDREW: Eric, you don't have
to try to talk...
I... No, no, I'm okay.
I want to say this.
If you're try...
trying to recruit us,
I mean, why else bother
introducing yourselves to us,
right?
If you're trying to change us
or make us different,
all of this...
(voice breaking):
this isn't the way.
Can someone put the curtain
on the back door?
What's wrong with Eric?
When you have a concussion,
you're extremely sensitive
to light.
Well, there-there's nothing
we can do about that now.
Well, he's only gonna
get better if he rests
in a darkened room
or if we make it dark in here.
We shouldn't move him
until we make our proposal.
He might need to be
in a darkened room for days,
-not just a few hours.
-You're not separating me
from Andrew and Wen.
I'll see what I can do
with the curtains.
So, whatever.
I'm, um, I'm Adriane.
Yeah, I-I've been a lot
of things, but-but right now,
or, um, before I got up here,
I-I was a line cook
at a Mexican restaurant
in-in Dupont Circle, D.C.
I love to feed people.
It feels like it's more
than food to me.
Um, God, what else?
Uh...
Oh, I have, um, I have two cats.
And you'd love them, Wen.
Their names are Riff and Raff.
Do you like cats, Wen?
You don't have to answer her,
sweetie.
LEONARD:
Sorry, Wen.
Maybe I'll put it back on
later, okay?
Forget the curtains.
It's time.
(insects chirring)
The four of us are here
to prevent the apocalypse.
We-- and when I say "we,"
I mean everyone in this cabin--
can stop it from happening,
but only with your help.
Ultimately,
whether the world ends or not
is completely up to you three.
You are having a psychological
break of some kind.
Your family must choose
to willingly sacrifice
one of the three of you
in order to prevent
the apocalypse.
After you make what I know
is an impossible decision,
you must then kill
the one you choose.
If you fail to choose,
or if you fail to follow through
with the sacrifice,
the world will end.
You three will live,
but the rest of humanity,
seven billion plus...
will perish.
(Andrew's breath shuddering)
They're lunatics.
And you will all live
long enough
to witness the horror
of the end of everything.
And you will be left to wander
the devastated planet alone.
Permanently
and cosmically... alone.
ERIC:
Leonard.
We haven't done anything wrong.
I agree with you. You haven't.
You haven't done anything wrong
to... to deserve this burden.
You're just the family chosen
to decide for us in this time.
LEONARD: Look,
we're not here to hurt you.
If we wanted to hurt you,
we would've used duct tape
-instead of ropes.
-You stop.
You have to understand
that we cannot
and will not choose who has
to be sacrificed for you.
And just as importantly,
we cannot act for you.
And you cannot kill yourselves.
We're not choosing anyone.
We're not sacrificing anyone.
Not now, not ever.
Even if it means the death
of everyone else in the world?
Yes. Even if I believe
the world was at stake,
which I don't,
that's what it means.
I would watch the world die
a hundred times over
-before having to...
-REDMOND: Christ.
Waste of time.
They're never gonna choose
to do this.
And I don't blame them.
-Who would ever choose...
-ADRIANE: Shut up, Redmond.
You just vomit
everything you think.
Oh, God, we are so screwed.
(sniffles)
LEONARD:
Okay,
you need to listen
to this part, too.
I've been shown exactly
what will happen
if you choose not to make
a sacrifice.
We've all been shown.
We couldn't stop drawing
the visions we saw.
I actually thought
something was wrong with me,
but the visions were so strong,
so specific and so, so real.
Sabrina, Adriane and Redmond,
they had the visions, too.
So, that led us
to each other and...
and that led us here
to this exact cabin.
We have no idea
why we were picked.
(chain rattling)
First, the cities will drown.
The oceans will swell
and rise up into a great fist
and pound all the buildings
and people into the sand,
and drag everything out to sea.
ANDREW: There is something
wrong with you,
with all of you,
if you believe this.
Then a terrible plague
will descend
and people will writhe
with fever,
and mucus will fill their lungs.
This is psychotic.
It's delusional.
Did you try to get help?
Let us go
and we'll get you help.
The skies will fall
and crash to the earth
like pieces of glass.
And God's fingers
will scorch the earth
and an everlasting darkness
will descend over humanity.
ANDREW:
You need help!
This is going to happen.
And we've been shown that only
your sacrifice can stop it.
Shown by who?
By what?
Are you gonna answer that?
You sound like every
fake doomsdayer
on every corner of every city.
ERIC:
Come on, talk to us.
Dreams can have
many different meanings.
Our part in your visions
is kind of vague.
Almost like you didn't know
who would be here.
Like it was random.
It doesn't make sense.
For every "no" you give us,
we will unleash a plague
for the sins of humanity.
Will you make a choice?
♪ ♪
ERIC:
Wait, stop.
You don't need to do this.
You don't need those things.
You said you couldn't hurt us.
What are you doing?
(grunting)
(breathing heavily)
What are you doing?
Don't touch her.
Don't touch her!
Get off her, get off her!
Get off of her!
Wen, Wen.
Run, Wen. Wen.
WEN:
I can't.
ANDREW:
Run.
(shuddering breaths)
Please, God, just let us go.
♪ ♪
(shuddering breaths)
Fuck.
I'm scared.
Keep looking at me, okay?
Don't you fucking look away
from me.
(Redmond sobbing)
(shuddering breaths continue)
A part of humanity
has been judged.
(chain rattling)
ANDREW: Whatever it is you're
convinced of, it isn't real.
-You don't have to do this.
-This isn't real.
-It's not gonna... No!
-(Eric yells)
(chain rattles)
-(Eric cries out)
-(Andrew gasping)
(Andrew grunts)
(whimpers)
(sniffles)
(people chattering)
You can pray if you want.
I won't make comment.
(Andrew breathes deeply)
(baby crying)
Mr. and Mrs. Brooks?
Yes. My wife couldn't
be here today.
This is her brother.
(babies fussing)
(baby crying)
(crying stops)
(Andrew chuckles softly)
(exhales heavily)
Now tell me
this isn't a miracle.
-(Wen coos)
-(Andrew chuckles)
Hi. Hi, Daddy.
Hi, Wen.
-Hey.
-(Wen grunts)
-Oh.
-(chuckles): Oh.
(gasping)
(breathing heavily)
♪ ♪
(Leonard retching loudly)
(Sabrina gasping)
(weapon falls to floor)
(Leonard breathing heavily)
Adriane,
can you help me out here?
-Adriane.
-Hey, yeah.
What?
Help me take Redmond outside.
(exhales heavily)
We'll cover him with a blanket.
(door creaks open)
(leans weapon against post)
(dragging continues)
(body thuds)
(gasping grunts)
(Sabrina grunting)
(TV plays indistinctly)
Wen, I'm sorry, but I'm gonna
have to change the channel
for a little bit, okay?
Go fuck yourself, Mister Rogers.
MAN (over TV): I want you
to try a piece of this.
I want to see whether
the air fryer oven
-makes it just as crispy...
-Please watch the TV.
-It should be on soon.
-I'm not even gonna kid you,
I really just want this.
(gasps)
-(crunching) -Do you hear
that gorgeous crispy crunch?
-(applause on TV) -Doesn't get
much better than that.
WOMAN (on TV):
Mmm.
And it tastes amazing.
Amazing fried chicken
and a lot less guilt.
(theme music playing)
We continue with our coverage
of the earthquake
centered in
the Aleutian Islands,
which struck more than
four hours ago.
The U.S. National Tsunami
Warning Center
has issued a cautionary advisory
to British Columbia,
Canada, and more than
a thousand miles of coast
along the
American Pacific Northwest,
including the cities
of Seattle and Portland.
The Pacific Tsunami
Warning Center
issued its strongest warning
to the islands of Hawaii.
Is this what we're supposed
to see?
...high schools, malls
and colleges, campuses...
I explained to you
what would happen
as a result of you not choosing.
A plague will be released
by Redmond's death.
You have to listen to me.
I remember,
but this doesn't mean anything.
-It doesn't mean...
-LEONARD: No!
Just watch!
I know I shouldn't yell.
I know you're afraid of me,
of us.
Just... please watch.
(over TV):
...points to a sizable wave
of 15 to 20 feet in height
headed south towards
the Hawaiian Islands.
We do have information that
the tsunami has made landfall.
Now, as you can tell
from our live feed,
this resort on Kauai
has already been evacuated.
SPOKESWOMAN: Our early warning
detection systems
gave plenty of time
to evacuate the coasts
and low-laying areas at
the affected Hawaiian Islands.
No injuries or fatalities
have been reported.
ANDREW: Please let Eric
and Wen go at least.
Eric has a concussion.
(TV broadcast continues)
I'll stay.
And we can talk about doomsday,
or the apocalypse,
or mass traumatic events of
the 21st century all you want.
I don't understand,
this isn't the...
Sabrina, just keep watching.
Until we see what was shown
to us.
NEWSWOMAN:
A second massive earthquake
has struck in the Pacific,
registering 8.6
on the Richter scale.
The epicenter is only 70 miles
off the coast of Oregon
in what's called
the Cascadia Subduction Zone.
That's an area scientists
have long feared
would produce
a catastrophic earthquake.
Unbelievable.
There it is.
We did this.
It's really fucking happening.
Oh, Jesus, God.
...and given the proximity
of the epicenter,
people on the coast
are gonna have mere minutes
to try to find shelter.
A tsunami triggered by a quake
of this magnitude
and proximity to the shoreline
will be massive.
I-I mean, 50-foot-high bluffs
along the coast
are not gonna be safe.
And we've just gotten word.
The tsunami has indeed hit
the Oregon shoreline
and we have footage shot
minutes ago from Cannon Beach.
ADRIANE:
Holy crap, this is what I saw.
(ragged breathing)
The same jutting rocks.
Me, too.
♪ ♪
(people clamoring)
(all breathing raggedly)
(people clamoring,
screaming on TV)
(Sabrina gasps)
(clamoring and screaming
continue)
-(screaming)
-(waves crashing loudly)
Wen,
go to your room
till I tell you to come out.
(water burbling on TV)
(burbling continues)
She didn't need to see this.
Tomorrow morning,
you can make the difficult,
selfless choice of sacrifice
and save the world...
...or you can choose once again
to let the clock move
another minute closer
to permanent midnight.
For the rest of today
and tonight,
we'll tend to your needs
within reason.
But otherwise,
we'll leave you be to reflect...
and talk it over.
We told you.
You have to believe us.
It doesn't matter if we believe
your craziness.
The answer is still the same.
Everyone in the world can die,
as far as we're concerned.
Am I right, Eric?
Eric?
You okay?
I'm okay.
I just need a moment.
ERIC:
I have a little surprise
-queued up for you.
-Ooh. Oh, a surprise.
-Ooh, what's that gonna be?
-Are you ready?
("Boogie Shoes" by KC
and The Sunshine Band playing)
-Oh! -Oh!
-Yeah!
-Are we gonna sing along?
-Yes, of course.
-I think, I think we are.
-I don't know, I don't know.
♪ Girl, to be with you ♪
♪ Is my favorite thing ♪
-♪ Bah, dum ♪
-(scatting)
♪ Bah, dum ♪
♪ I can't wait
till I see you again ♪
(scatting)
Here we go. Ready?
♪ I want to put on ♪
♪ My, my, my, my,
my boogie shoes ♪
-Hey.
-♪ Just to boogie with you ♪
-♪ Yeah ♪
♪ I want to put on ♪
♪ My, my, my, my,
my boogie shoes ♪
♪ Just to boogie with you ♪
ANDREW:
Hey.
♪ I want do it
till the sun comes up... ♪
(music fades)
-(car approaches, stops)
-(shuts off engine)
-(car doors open)
-ANDREW: It's gorgeous.
Except for the... the main road
being further away
than we thought,
I'm officially impressed.
Okay.
-Hey, Wen, come get your bag.
-Wen?
Wen, come on.
Wen, come check out the view.
It's better than the website.
How many grasshoppers
did you catch?
Just one so far.
Her name's Liv.
Oh. You see any bears yet?
Andrew, don't start.
If we joke about it,
she won't take it seriously.
We won't leave the garbage out,
we'll be fine.
Wen, show Daddy Eric
your scary bear face.
-(roaring)
-(Eric gasps)
-(Andrew and Eric shouting)
-(Wen screams)
-Wen, run from... Run.
-(Eric laughing)
Hey, Wenling, sweetie,
not too close.
That dock might have
rusty nails.
Eric, come on
with your rusty nails.
We got so lucky with this place.
Whoo!
-Get in!
-(running footsteps)
-Come on, Wen!
-(Eric chuckles)
-Come on!
-Oh.
-ANDREW: Whoo!
-(water splashing)
Whoa!
(Andrew yells)
-Here I come!
-Eric, come!
He's coming in!
(laughing):
Oh, come on.
Hold on, one second, one second.
-Woo-hoo!
-Coming right at you.
-Here I come.
-Yes, yes, yes!
-(Andrew yells)
-(Wen laughing)
(Andrew grunts, laughs)
ERIC:
Oh. Oh, it's a cold spot.
ANDREW:
Look at you swimming.
-(Wen laughing, fades)
-(water running)
(faucet squeaks, water stops)
SABRINA:
Just applying a little pressure.
(Eric groans)
Told you I'm a nurse.
You may not be on board
with all the
"end of the world" stuff yet,
but at least trust me on that.
None of us wanted it
to go this way.
We need you
in a clear state of mind.
You've got a big decision
to make.
(Eric inhales sharply, groans)
You think I'm some kind
of religious freak, right?
I would, too.
Truth is,
I haven't even been to church
since my grandma forced me to go
when I was little.
I always thought religious stuff
was so tired and boring
from another time, and people
were scared of shadows.
Then the visions started.
I didn't believe it at first,
either.
But you will.
When I was a kid,
my dad used to say to me,
"Trust in something
more than you."
It's sort of become my mantra
these past few days.
I said it
when I saw the visions.
I said it when I built my weapon
exactly the way
it was shown to me.
I said it over and over
as I passed every freeway exit
on my way here.
I said it when I walked out
onto the boardwalk
and I saw the others.
We were all wearing the same
colors we saw in our visions.
That's when I knew
I wasn't alone.
(voice breaking):
And all of this...
...is real.
And I'm saying it
to you now, Eric,
you need to trust something
more than you.
You may not want to believe it,
but we're all on the same side.
I'm on my family's side.
(door creaks open)
(Eric sighs)
(floorboards creaking)
(dishes clattering quietly)
(whispering):
Eric?
You really okay?
My head's still ringing,
but my vision is clearer.
(Andrew breathes deeply)
You know that first
earthquake happened
a whole four hours ago, right?
Before they showed up here.
Leonard's checked his watch
a thousand times.
They've been timing all of this.
I know.
(footsteps overhead)
I just don't want you to...
I don't want you to be spooked
or anything.
You think I believe them?
No.
No, it's just...
With your head and all,
I want to make sure
you're thinking straight.
Without them trying
to manipulate us.
They take you alone in there
and try and talk to you.
I don't believe them.
ADRIANE (muffled):
I'm trying to keep it together.
This isn't gonna work.
They're never gonna
believe us, man.
SABRINA: We have to believe
in what we're doing,
what our goal is here.
ADRIANE: Did you see
Redmond's fucking face?
It was just crazy.
SABRINA: Say whatever it is
you have to say to them.
Convince them.
(Adriane's muffled crying)
-(hinges creaking)
-(gasps)
(footsteps)
(door clatters open)
(birds cawing)
(door closing)
-LEONARD: Wen!
-(gasps)
Wen!
(breathes deeply)
♪ ♪
LEONARD:
Whoa!
-(Leonard sighs)
-(door closes)
I'm afraid the rule is
that no one's allowed to leave.
Were you trying to escape, Wen?
ANDREW:
Leave her alone.
I told her to do it.
You're just scared, Wen.
We all are.
You'll ask us to choose again.
ANDREW:
Don't listen to them, Wen.
We were targeted.
We've always
been targeted. We...
-ERIC: Andrew!
-(glass shattering)
I knew I recognized him.
Redmond...
is the guy from the bar.
What?
Are you sure?
What guy from the bar?
Andrew was attacked by a man in
a bar in Boston many years ago.
The man went to jail
for a short while.
But his name was O'Bannon.
It's him.
He's gained weight
and his beard's different,
but it's him.
His name was Redmond.
We don't know dick about him,
Leonard.
We all met him for the
first time on that boardwalk.
Stop the bullshit!
This is all some kind
of sick scam
to get us to hurt each other.
That's not true.
SABRINA: We don't know
why each of us is here.
It's a coincidence
the man who attacked me
and had me in years of therapy
is one of your group?
Go get his wallet.
I'll show you his name
isn't Redmond.
No, we're not doing that.
Why?!
Because it doesn't matter
what his name is.
Okay? We all had the visions.
This has to be exact.
Everything has to be right.
Didn't he tell us
about this cabin
on the message board first?
And then we all had visions
of the cabin?
LEONARD:
I don't know. It...
No, we had the visions first.
Message board?
(Adriane sighs)
Look, we're not doubting
why we're here.
Go to sleep.
The sun will rise,
maybe for the last time
for all of us.
The premise of your scam
is flawed.
I'm a human rights attorney,
Leonard.
How about I show you
photos of kids
who have been tortured
and killed, lying in piles?
You want to make a case
for humanity to go on,
you're gonna lose.
This is a picture of some
of the kids I coach.
This year, the boys had
a record of three and eight.
The girls, five and six.
So, we're not very good.
If you could hear them laugh,
you'd understand why I'm here.
Maybe you'd sleep better if you
could see each other easier.
♪ ♪
(departing footsteps)
(sighs)
(sighs heavily)
(insects chittering)
("Sugar Town" by Nancy Sinatra
playing over radio)
♪ I got some troubles ♪
-(water running)
-♪ But they won't last... ♪
(water stops)
ADRIANE:
You like it?
Come to the restaurant,
I can make you all kinds
of breakfast burritos.
They say if you can make
an egg great,
you can do anything.
ANDREW (whispering):
Eric.
My hands are a little looser.
I just need to get
to the trunk of the car.
-♪ That liked me some ♪
-(dishes clattering quietly)
♪ Never had a friend
or wanted one ♪
♪ So I just lay back and laugh
at the sun, 'cause I'm in ♪
You're very polite.
♪ Shoo-shoo-shoo,
shoo-shoo-shoo-shoo... ♪
(turns off music)
You're a good person.
-Okay.
-Listen,
you guys met on some kind
of message board, right?
You're having a shared delusion.
That's a uniquely 21st-century
health crisis.
It is real.
You're in an echo chamber,
you know that, right?
You got online,
and you found random people
who had random visions
and you took that as evidence.
Remember the guy
who shot up three people
in an Army base in Louisiana?
He was part of an online group
like yours.
They posted videos about
how the shadow government
was stalking them
and using mind control weapons
in an attempt to destroy
their lives.
LEONARD:
We found each other online
because we said
we had the same visions.
(whispering): Remember what
you did at Thanksgiving?
LEONARD: And then we decided
to meet on the boardwalk.
You're gonna do that if I nod.
Okay, let's continue.
You have the opportunity
to choose.
I don't mean to rush you,
but we're gonna ask for your
decisions very fast now.
I'm gonna be straight up.
I'm the next one to go.
(shuddering breaths)
I'm counting on you, man.
You're, like, my last hope here.
Adriane,
you can walk out of here
right now.
Just walk out and see,
nothing will happen.
None of this can stop
until you make a choice.
Don't you get that already?
(breathes heavily)
You think I want to be here?
I'm just some fucking cook.
I didn't tell you at first,
but I have a son.
I didn't want to speak
his name, but...
here I am, begging you to do
what has to be done
because if you don't,
my son is gonna die.
Over the last few days,
I've had to watch him die
over and over and over again.
I've watched my little boy
burned alive
as I held him in my arms.
Everything was burning.
I can't get the sound
of his screams out of my head,
even right now, so...
(sniffles)
as a mother, believe me
when I tell you
that this is really happening.
And it's up to you.
What exactly did you guys see?
Stop talking to him.
He doesn't believe you.
None of us believe you.
Let your time run out.
We're not gonna do
what you want us to do.
His name is Charlie.
He likes pancakes.
♪ ♪
Very well.
Close your eyes
and cover your ears.
You don't have to do this.
You guys are delusional.
You are part of a suicide cult.
Can't you see that?
Stop!
Please stop this!
-(Andrew grunting)
-(chair rattling)
(Adriane grunts)
(Adriane gasps)
(breathing heavily)
(Adriane gasping)
(wood creaking)
♪ ♪
A part of humanity
has been judged.
(Wen groans)
(blades stabbing)
-(stabbing stops)
-(body thuds)
(insects chittering)
(chain rattling)
(Sabrina gasping)
(weapon falls to floor)
(Leonard breathing heavily)
LEONARD: I'll move her
into the other room
so they don't have to see her.
(muffled whimpering)
(Sabrina gasping)
(Leonard and Sabrina
breathing heavily)
Hundreds of thousands of people
are going to die now.
We've unleashed a second plague.
Bullshit.
Sabrina, put on the TV, please.
(Andrew breathing raggedly)
NEWSMAN: There have also been
new developments
with the novel X-Nine virus,
which is proving particularly
fatal to children.
The X-Nine virus
is highly transmittable
amongst children
aged ten and under.
These outbreaks seem
to be originating
in three distinct pockets
of the world:
Cape Town, Suffolk, England,
and outside Nashville
in Tennessee.
Lockdowns in these areas
have already begun
as numbers rise along with fear
for the safety
of those infected.
Numerous public schools
have been suspended
with some being converted
into makeshift
quarantine facilities.
While there is hope that
the virus will be contained
to the geographical pockets
in question...
(whispering): I think
I saw something, Andrew.
(over TV): ...these communities
are trapped in lockdown.
What?
What are you saying?
I think I saw a person.
Or a figure.
LEONARD:
Turn the TV off.
Where'd you see a figure?
In the light behind you.
In the reflection in the mirror.
When you were standing
behind Redmond.
Right before you struck him.
Eric, look at me.
You have a severe concussion.
She even told you
you would be extremely
sensitive to light.
We're under extreme stress here.
I need you to listen
to the words I'm saying.
Breathe in for a second, okay?
(breathes deeply)
I've been reading about
these X-Nine cases
for months already,
you know that.
It isn't a fucking plague.
It's a news report.
They all knew about it
before they showed up here
and knowingly made it
a part of their narrative.
And this guy has been checking
his watch all morning
just like yesterday.
-Come on, Andrew.
-All four of you have watches.
What, you just showed up here
like that? No.
You knew you were coming
at this particular cabin
where cell reception
wouldn't exist.
Did you see the banner
at the bottom of the screen?
It isn't live.
It's preprogramming.
It's a TV show.
Leonard, Sabrina,
all of them knew
this X-Nine show would be on
-and at what time.
-SABRINA: Andrew, this virus
-is gonna spread everywhere.
-LEONARD: If you...
It's a fucking
preprogrammed show!
They knew this virus show
would be on at this time,
just like they knew
the Alaskan earthquake
and the tsunami warning
had already happened
before they showed up here.
I'm clearheaded now.
Always together.
You don't talk to him
from now on. You talk to me.
I want to watch
Paddington and Chloe now!
Paddington and Chloe!
Wen.
(screaming)
I want to watch a cartoon now!
-(screaming continues)
-Wen, okay.
We're gonna count down from
five together, and we're not
-gonna yell anymore, okay?
-I want to watch it now!
Wen. Five...
-I want to watch Paddington
and Chloe now! -...four...
-Okay, let's try this again.
-I want to watch a cartoon!
Wen, take a deep breath.
-(screaming)
-And five...
-four... -I want to watch
Paddington and Chloe now!
-Wen. Three...
-(Eric grunting)
-Get away from my family,
you fucking losers! -Eric! Eric!
Eric! Eric!
Please stop. Please.
-WEN: Stop! That's my dad.
-LEONARD: Everyone needs you.
ERIC:
No! No, I don't believe you!
-Eric, please. Please stop...
-No. No, no. Back away from me.
Don't you look at me.
Don't you look at my daughter!
LEONARD: Look, you don't
understand what you're doing!
-I don't fucking
believe you! No! -Please!
No! No, I don't believe
a word you say! Fuck you!
(breathing raggedly)
-(door opens)
-SABRINA: Andrew.
-(Sabrina yells)
-(Andrew cries out)
(stifled scream)
I hit you in the knee
just so you wouldn't run away.
This is triage,
like in an emergency room.
We have to make the decision
to save the most lives.
We have to help each other.
(breathlessly):
(Sabrina yelling)
(grunting)
(yells out in pain)
(door handle rattling)
(Andrew cries out in pain)
-(hitting window)
-Open up!
Andrew, listen to me!
Andrew.
-(Sabrina grunting)
-(lock beeping)
Come on.
Please! Come out!
-(beeping)
-Come on.
-(beeping continues)
-(grunting)
Stay away from me.
Stay away from me!
I will kill you!
(Eric grunting)
Please stop!
-(beeps)
-(Sabrina yells)
Leave whatever you're going for,
get out of the car
and come inside!
I don't want to have
to hurt you!
-Come back inside!
-(groans)
Now!
We don't have time for this!
Please!
Andrew, listen.
(Sabrina screams)
(breathing rapidly)
Now, you listen to me,
you crazy fucking bitch.
You drop that thing
and back the fuck up.
(quietly):
Okay. Okay.
-Back the fuck up!
-Okay, okay!
(gasping)
-Keep going!
-Okay, okay.
Move!
Breathe.
(Sabrina panting)
Stop. Stop!
(panting continues)
Fuck. Fuck.
♪ ♪
(clattering inside cabin)
(Andrew panting)
(Leonard and Eric grunting)
Stay back!
I believe you were chosen
because
your family's love
for each other is so pure.
I know you've been through
a lot,
and people haven't been fair
to you.
Drop the weapon
and move away from Eric,
or I'll show you I was chosen
to put a bullet in your head.
Drop it now, Leonard,
or I'll kill you!
You're dooming us all, Andrew.
You're dooming your husband,
you're dooming your daughter...
I'm done with you!
I'm not listening to another
goddamn word you say!
It's time
for the next sacrifice.
(whimpers)
Are you willing
to make a choice?
You're crazy.
I'm taking my family,
and I'm leaving.
-(breathing heavily)
-(running footsteps)
-(Sabrina screaming)
-ERIC: Andrew!
(grunts)
(gasping)
(body thuds)
("Long Train Runnin'" by
The Doobie Brothers playing)
You have a temper.
Not in a scary way, just...
It's there.
You're uptight.
You can...
suck the life
out of any situation.
Hey, we said you have
to qualify things.
I'm sorry. You...
You suck the life
out of some situations.
I'll accept that.
It's not a bad list.
I think most parents would have
a worse list than that.
I can't believe
we're actually gonna do this.
I have never,
for one second of my life,
ever doubted loving you.
The kid'll be washed in that
every day.
How is it you can say stuff
like that out of nowhere?
MAN:
Can you guys keep it down?
Were we being loud?
MAN: I'm trying to have a drink
with my friends.
Oh, we were being too loud?
Is that what it is?
Get your drunk ass
back to your seat.
MAN:
Fuck you.
You shouldn't provoke them.
I wasn't provoking...
ERIC:
Oh, my God! What the fuck?
What the fuck?
Andrew, are you okay?
-Andrew.
-(glass shattering)
Oh, my God! What the fuck!
(people clamoring)
Somebody call an ambulance!
Andrew! Andrew, look at me.
Andrew, look at me.
Are you okay?
Open your eyes. Open your eyes.
Can you hear me? Andrew!
♪ ♪
(machine whooshing rhythmically)
(rhythmic beeping)
(grunting)
MAN: All right, so what
you got here is an HK P30.
German engineered, very light,
very easy to handle.
Um, pretty much good
for any scenario.
Carry, home protection.
Screw 'em, right?
(breathing raggedly)
I'll take it.
No, Leonard.
Are you willing
to make a sacrifice?
No more, you bastard.
LEONARD: A part of humanity
has been judged.
(Leonard grunting)
(blade continues striking)
(weapon falls to floor)
LEONARD: The four of us
can't make this decision.
It's got to be your choice.
Shut your mouth.
Keep an eye on Leonard.
Yell if he does anything.
(grunts)
(sighs)
♪ ♪
It's O'Bannon.
They were here to torture us.
We don't know why
we were chosen.
Don't say another word
of your horseshit!
None of this is real,
and you were targeting us!
I always look for motive,
Leonard.
How about a crazy bigot
meets a bartender
from a bar somewhere,
and they find a woman
from a small town
who has extreme
religious beliefs.
That's not true.
Then they come across
a young woman
who can be persuaded
of anything.
I didn't believe for a second
that Adriane had a kid, Leonard!
Now, I'm not a murderer
like you guys,
so I'm gonna lock you
in that bathroom.
They slashed our tires,
but they must've come
in a... a truck or a vehicle.
(breathing raggedly)
We have to get to that vehicle.
LEONARD:
You're wrong about all of us.
Now get in that bathroom,
Leonard.
And make no mistake,
I will fucking kill you
if I have to.
(whispering): We need something
to tie the doorknob to.
ERIC (whispering):
The lamp.
Here.
(rustling)
(Eric and Andrew
breathing heavily)
Okay. Come on. Come on.
(glass shattering)
(clattering)
He broke the window.
WEN:
He got out.
He's gonna come get us!
He's gonna get to the car
before us.
He could be outside and hurt us.
We have to make sure
he's in the bathroom.
Leonard?
If I open this door and
I see you, I will shoot you.
Leonard!
♪ ♪
(Leonard and Andrew grunting)
ERIC:
Get off him!
(Eric grunting)
(Leonard grunting)
(strained grunting)
(gasping)
(breathlessly):
Fuck. Fuck.
I thought you wouldn't kill us.
I won't.
But I will shoot you in the leg
to keep you from leaving
this cabin.
Turn on the TV
if you want to be convinced.
(breathing heavily)
You'll see that everything
I said was gonna happen
has happened.
-No one's gonna do what you
say... -More terrifying images
as we see yet another
passenger aircraft
-plummet to the ground.
-(explosion on TV)
-(people screaming on TV)
-Eric, what are you doing?
(shuddered breathing)
Why did you turn it on?
(on TV): Local and
international governments
are investigating whether
there's any correlation
between the crashes.
We have yet to receive
death tolls
or receive any statements
from the airlines.
(people screaming)
-(screaming)
-(explosion)
(sirens wailing)
You said it wasn't real.
(sirens continue wailing)
(airplane whooshing on TV)
(explosion)
(people clamoring, screaming)
♪ ♪
(explosion)
(explosions continue on TV)
The skies will fall
and crash to the earth
like pieces of glass.
And God's fingers
will scorch the earth...
and an everlasting darkness
will descend over humanity.
(explosions continue)
NEWSCASTER:
We now have confirmation
of as many as 700 airplanes
having crashed without warning,
without issuing distress calls,
amid fears
and increasing speculation
there may have been
a coordinated cyberattack...
That terrorist stuff
has nothing to do with this.
LEONARD:
I've heard this before.
(on TV): TSA has yet
to issue a statement.
Airports around the globe
are canceling flights.
-It is hard...
-Excuse me.
BOTH: It is hard to describe
the images that we are seeing.
They fill us with disquietude
and horror.
We are witnessing
a collective tragedy
unfathomable
only moments before.
(Leonard breathing raggedly)
We are getting word
of more airline...
How the fuck did you know
what she was gonna say?
Is this some closed-circuit TV?
Did you guys pump this in?
Maybe the truth is...
is that the end was happening
long before
we got to this cabin.
And what we're seeing now
isn't the fireworks.
It's just the final
flickering sparks.
I don't know
what's going on here,
but where are the keys
to the truck you guys came in?
ERIC:
Andrew.
I'm taking my family...
and we're leaving.
Do you really think that
everything that happened today,
everything we've seen...
Do you really think
it's all just a coincidence?
Yes.
I think it's all a coincidence.
Some horrible,
unexplainable coincidence.
Or it has to be a trick.
I have to believe that!
You already don't believe that.
I know when someone's lying.
ANDREW:
Eric...
let's go.
Let's get out of here
and never come back.
Don't listen to Leonard anymore.
(Andrew breathing jaggedly)
Can everyone come out
onto the back deck now?
I'd like to do
this last part outside.
(Leonard sighs)
What are you doing
with that, Leonard?
(Leonard breathing rapidly)
When I'm gone, you'll only have
minutes to stop everything.
After that, it'll be too late.
WEN:
Will all the children die?
Wen, I want you to take
your music and your headphones
and go to that tree house
that we climbed in.
Put your music on until
one of us comes to get you.
Do what Daddy says, okay?
(Wen crying)
I love you, chicken.
WEN:
I love you, too.
Go. Go.
ERIC: Nothing can happen
to the three of us.
You'll be okay.
The worst thing about
the visions was the screaming.
I could hear everyone screaming.
And I knew
when the visions ended,
the screaming was just
gonna go on and on.
(short laugh)
You know what I loved most
about teaching kids?
They believe everything you say.
So you have to be careful.
Say only what you know,
what you know to be true.
It's a big responsibility.
Maybe one of the kids I taught
will do something great
for the world.
What do you think?
Please...
my new friends, Eric, Andrew...
...will you make a choice
and save the world?
(breathing heavily)
All of humanity has been judged.
(Leonard gasping)
(thunder rumbling)
-(gurgling, gasping)
-(rocking chair creaking)
(thunder booming)
♪ ♪
(loud crashing)
(thunder rumbling in distance)
We still have a few minutes,
he said.
Eric.
There was something
in the light.
A figure.
And I feel it now.
(thunder rumbling)
(breathing raggedly)
I believe you.
Let's the three of us leave.
Maybe this is the way
it's always been.
Maybe families have been
deciding this all through time.
Let's just walk the earth, then.
The three of us.
What kind of life is that
for Wen?
(thunder crashing)
Andrew, this wasn't
a home invasion.
They didn't target us.
They came here
to spend time with us...
...for us to get to know them.
They remind us of all aspects
of humanity.
Redmond, malice.
Adriane, nurturing.
Sabrina, healing.
Leonard, guidance.
They're the Four Horsemen
of the Apocalypse.
I believe we had
to see them die.
We had to feel their loss.
Why us?
We're nothing special.
Because I know what I felt when
we saw Wen in that orphanage
and we were together
for the first time.
It's our decision.
(thunder crashing)
ANDREW:
It's our fucking decision?
We're supposed to give up
our love for them?
It's a sacrifice, Andrew.
That we would be willing
to give up
something so beautiful to us
for everyone else.
-They're not worth it!
-(thunder crashing)
They hate us, Eric.
They hate that we exist.
-They're just scared.
-(thunder crashing)
Like all of us.
They're monsters.
They destroy everything.
They hurt each other.
You're not just a prosecutor.
You know there's something
to defend.
That's where your anger
comes from, Andrew.
Kill me.
No, sweetheart.
We're running out of time.
Maybe I saw a figure,
maybe I just made it up,
but it's giving me peace.
My mind is set in its truth.
I won't be scared.
You gotta do it now.
We're out of time. All of us.
I don't believe in them, Eric.
I do.
Do it while I'm thinking
the most beautiful thought
so that I can have that feeling
in my heart to take me
right to wherever it is
I'm going.
(thunder crashing)
It's almost time.
I can feel it.
Kill me, Eric, please.
Please. Please.
I'm thinking about our daughter
in the future.
And she's living her life
exactly as she wanted to.
She's got her own practice.
You're there with her.
You guys are locking up
her office,
because you guys
are going to dinner.
She is everything
we always hoped for.
♪ ♪
She's still got her crazy laugh
She still asks everybody
questions about everything.
She found someone who loves her
and who she loves just as much.
Just like her dads.
(gunshot echoing)
(leaves rustling)
♪ ♪
Eric. (breathing raggedly)
(sobbing):
Eric.
(thunder rumbling)
(rumbling continues)
(footsteps on stairs)
♪ ♪
Did Daddy Eric save everyone?
-(crying)
-(distant thunder rumbling)
(thunder crashing)
(rain pouring)
(Andrew sniffling)
(both crying)
(thunder crashing loudly)
(loud cracking)
♪ ♪
(wood crackling)
(flames crackling)
(flames whooshing)
(wood creaking)
♪ ♪
(man speaking indistinctly
over radio)
WEN:
Did we stop it in time?
ANDREW:
There's a diner over there.
(man on radio continues
indistinctly)
MAN (on TV): The only thing
we could do was climb out
of the u-upstairs window
onto the roof, but...
-(bell jingles)
-...water kept climbing
higher and higher.
I mean, no one could hear us.
Standing on the roof
with my daughters, my girls...
I thought it was the end.
And two of my girls, uh,
they can't, they can't swim.
And the water just...
stopped rising.
WOMAN:
Switch to the other one.
NEWSMAN: The last of the planes
in Australia and Russia
have landed safely.
Families are rushing
to airports,
searching for their loved ones.
Amidst this chaos
are emotional scenes...
We were rolling the bodies
out into the parking lot
because there wasn't room.
This past hour is the first time
in many, many hours
that we haven't had a death
in the ICU.
Actually, we're coming up
on our second hour here
of no deaths.
WOMAN:
I know.
(voice breaking):
I love you so much.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Hmm.
NEWSWOMAN 2:
The sudden lightning strikes
that set fire to many areas
have not returned.
Though several fires have yet
to be extinguished
and the damage to regions
both rural and urban
across Great Britain
is extensive
and remains to be determined,
the worst conflagrations have,
as of this moment...
(door opens)
♪ ♪
(keys jingling)
(engine starting)
("Boogie Shoes" by KC and The
Sunshine Band playing on radio)
♪ Girl, to be with you... ♪
(turns off radio)
(engine idling)
♪ Ah-ha, ah-ha ♪
♪ I want to put on ♪
♪ My, my, my, my,
my boogie shoes ♪
♪ Just to boogie
with you, yeah ♪
♪ I want to put on ♪
♪ My, my, my, my, my boogie
shoes, just to boogie... ♪
(turns off radio)
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ I want to put on ♪
♪ My, my, my, my,
my boogie shoes ♪
♪ Just to boogie with you ♪
♪ Whoo ♪
♪ ♪
♪ Ah... yeah ♪
♪ Boogie down, boogie down ♪
♪ Whoo ♪
♪ I want to put on ♪
♪ My, my, my, my,
my boogie shoes ♪
♪ Just to boogie
with you, yeah ♪
♪ I want to put on ♪
♪ My, my, my, my,
my boogie shoes ♪
♪ Just to boogie
with you, yeah ♪
(fading):
♪ I want to put on... ♪
♪ ♪
(music fades)
(seven knocks on door)
(knocking stops)