Hello, my name is Ekwa Msangi.
I am the writer and director of the film
that you're about to watch, Farewell Amor,
which is my feature film
directorial debut.
We premiered at Sundance 2020
in competition
and I'm so excited
to have you watch it here on MUBI.
Please join me afterwards
for a conversation that I will have
with my dear friend
and colleague John Akomfrah,
as we talk about the film.
I look forward to seeing you then.
Welcome to Terminal Four
at John F Kennedy International Airport.
You should not accept offers
of transportation
from anyone
without prior arrangement.
An unknown driver may not
be licensed, have insurance
and may overcharge you now
or at the end of your ride.
Amor!
Amor.
Here you are.
Oh, Sylvia.
Look at this. Look at this!
- Big girl.
- Uh-huh.
Huh? Yes.
Turn around. Let me see.
Let me see. Let me see.
Wow!
You are here!
Here.
Wow. Sylvia, look.
So, what do you think
of New York?
It's amazing!
We'll have to practice
speaking English more.
Are you okay?
Sylvia, aren't you excited?
This is home. Welcome!
I need to use the bathroom.
Oh, yes.
Let me show you. Esther,
you and I will be sleeping down there.
Kitchen is over there,
and, Sylvia, I've converted
the living room for now
so you can have your own space.
I'm looking for a bigger place
that will be more suitable.
Maybe you'll be like
all the American kids
- and get your own place!
- Eh-ehn. Not yet.
First, we live as a family,
as God intended it.
Yes, of course. Of course.
Oh, Sylvia,
the bathroom is down there.
The light is on the wall to your left.
Bon appétit.
I wish your mother could see this.
Her boy learned how to cook!
I hope you like it.
- Who taught you?
- Ah, you know, I...
I picked up some things
here and there.
Please, eat, before it gets cold.
Let's pray first.
We have a lot to be thankful for.
Yes. Sorry.
Jehova Jaira,
we praise your name in the most high.
Lord, thank you
for bringing us together
after 17 years apart.
We thank you for your
endless blessings and love.
We thank you for our home
and our family.
We thank you because the devil is shamed
and defeated!
We pray all these things
in the holy name of Jesus!
- Amen.
Amen.
Yes.
It's very soft.
Mm. Tender, yeah?
Americans don't like stew
with their food?
The doctor recommended
low-fat meals.
Hmm.
You know, for years
the only food I could eat
was my mother's cooking.
So, when we got married,
I forced your poor mama
to learn how to cook
all of my mama's dishes.
Your poor mama.
She should have never
have put up with me.
My pastor said we must focus
on familiarizing ourselves
in spirit and flesh,
in order to rebuild our family.
I...
- No, wait.
- I'm old now, unattractive.
No, you're not.
Lying is a sin, you know.
That's...
that's not what I meant.
I haven't been with any man
since you left.
Thank you.
I mean, I'm sorry
I wasn't there.
Is this everything?
Linda!
I hope everything works out.
It's just been a long day.
Perhaps we should just
get some... rest... first.
Ready for American school?
Of course she is.
She's going to study hard
so she can get into medical school...
with a scholarship. Mm-hm.
The first doctor in the family,
God willingly.
What kind of medicine
are you interested in?
She wants to treat children.
I like mathematics.
Brilliant like her father, this one.
I keep telling you,
your father was always studying
so many things
when we met in university.
I need to see your backpack.
- Excuse me.
- Sorry, she's new.
Please step back, sir.
I just need to check her bags.
I have this referral form.
Watch out.
Commandante,
you find any change in the seat?
I see you changed
the other picture.
- Yeah.
- They settled in?
Somewhat.
I know the sex must be good.
Whenever I go back home,
my wife is like
she have something to prove.
I can only imagine after,
what is it, nine years?
- 17.
- Oh!
She's supposed to be lucky
that you was with the nurse,
or else you'd be in jail
for homicide.
What?
You know it's the truth, man.
I don't want to talk about it.
My brother,
all I'm saying to you,
you're not the only person
who ever been in this situation.
Okay? Things happen.
Don't feel bad.
I don't. Everything's fine.
Okay.
Well, I guess I better start my shift.
Have a good one.
You too.
- Hey.
Hi!
- Why are you here?
- Shh.
What happened?
I can't be your savior, Walter.
I need love too.
Just one dance.
I...
I can't.
Thank you.
You're early today.
I, um...
I swapped my shift
so I could be home for dinner
and eat with the family
at least once this week.
Great.
Sylviñha, clear your books.
Go set the table.
So... um, how was school today?
Fine.
Ah! Is that how you respond?
It was fine, thank you.
She's so excited to finally
be here with you.
I'm not so sure about that.
Nonsense. Of course she is.
I was thinking, um...
maybe we should plan some things,
as a family,
so we could get to know each other.
Ah, I've just been
praying about this.
- Yes?
- Yes!
Well, perhaps this Sunday we could
go for a drive outside of the city,
- you know, maybe the Jersey Shore or...
- Well, aren't we all going to church?
Well, I... I thought it would be good
to leave the city early
- to, you know, avoid the traffic.
- Oh, that's fine.
That's fine. Perhaps there's
a sunrise service we can attend.
Of course. Um...
- I'll check.
- Mm.
Oh, yeah. I, um...
I brought home some wine
so we can toast.
Alcohol?
It's wine.
But you know we shouldn't drink.
Well, it's... It's just a...
simple wine for...
a special occasion.
♪ Oh, happy day that fixed my choice
♪ On thee, my savior and my God
♪ Well, may this glowing heart rejoice
♪ And tell its raptures all abroad
♪ Happy day, happy day
♪ When Jesus washed my sins away. ♪
Thank you, Jesus.
- Amen!
- Whoo!
♪ Everywhere I go
♪ I'm gonna let it shine
♪ I'm gonna let it shine... ♪
Praise Jesus!
♪ Everywhere I go
♪ I'm gonna let it shine... ♪
Hallelujah!
♪ Let it shine
♪ Let it shine, let it shine. ♪
Yes, Jesus! Praise Him!
...everything.
I thank you for the gifts
of food and shelter
that you have provided
for me and my family.
And I know that you...
As soon as my immigration
paperwork is finalized,
I'll get a job
so I can help with the bills.
I can handle things for now.
You've got a lot
on your plate already.
Thank you, amor.
For what?
Not giving up...
on us.
You shouldn't thank me.
Well.
Don't stay up late, hm?
Oh, and, uh...
did you see the mail
that your neighbor
brought the other day?
I don't know why it's so hard
for the mailman
to put the mail in the correct box.
Sylvia? Sylvia?
Ah!
Are you okay?
Ow.
I'm fine.
Then why can't you move it?
I can. I promise.
I can't let you go to school like this.
You could have broken a bone.
- I'm serious, Sylviñha.
- Are you going to tell Mama?
Come. We'll worry about Mama later.
Uh, yeah,
she's still down with dialysis,
so, that will be...
So, you were practicing
for the dance the...
young man told us about at your school?
Mm-hm.
When you stopped waiting
for my weekend phone calls...
Mama said it was because
you were sneaking out to dance.
That scared her.
Everything scares her.
That's why she prays so much.
You know, I used to be
quite the dancer
as well when I was younger.
It's true!
Okay, maybe not
that style of dance, but...
Your mother would make...
matching outfits for the both of us,
and we'd go to the secret parties and...
dance all night long.
- Mae?
- Yeah.
Eh.
No, we used to dance a lot
before you were born...
and even after.
But you are too young to remember.
And then what happened?
The end of the war.
Paging Dr Bisby to 3B.
Dr Bisby to 3B.
- Ready for the next one?
- No.
Are you ever?
Sylvia D Santos?
Come, wake up. Let's go.
- The nurse is here.
- Hm?
Let's go.
Come on.
And what brings you in today?
She injured her arm.
How did this injury take place?
I fell.
And when did the injury happen?
Mm... yesterday.
Where does it hurt?
Can you show me exactly?
- Anywhere else?
- Mm-mm.
There's a little bruise,
but nothing too unusual.
The doctor is going to be
right with you.
Do you need anything?
- Linda.
- What do you want from me?
You promised you would never
rub them in my face.
She needed help, querida.
- I trust you.
- What do you think...
What do you think this is?
I... I know this is far from ideal, but...
why can't we remain friends,
like in the beginning?
Because this is not
the beginning.
We're far from the beginning, Walter.
This is the end.
I'm serious.
I'll go get the doctor.
Linda.
Papa?
Hmm?
Do you love us?
Yes!
And you left to make a life for us, right?
Well, of course.
Oh, Sylvia.
I was just, um...
taking out the trash.
Do you need anything?
- Oh, Sylvia.
- Wow!
Look at this.
Big girl.
Let me see. Let me see!
Huh? What?
She's grown. She has.
I need to use the bathroom.
The light is on the wall
to your left.
- Hey, girl.
- Hey.
You'll probably be seducing
some hot New York dude
by the time you get this.
I told Rajab to just forget about you.
I mean, please!
- Sylvia?
- Eh!
She's off to greener pastures
called New York.
He's so depressed!
Imagine that I've missed you.
I'm going to keep making
those remixes for my girl
so when you become the most
famous dancer in America,
the rest of us
can at least be in your entourage!
Good morning, Mae.
Hey. Ah!
I thought we talked about those.
I don't know why you insist
on wearing those ugly boots
all the time. You're so pretty.
All the children at your school
will think Africans are tacky.
These are my
comfortable shoes, Ma.
Want me to be uncomfortable?
As soon as I get a job, I'll take you
shopping to get some proper clothes.
We won't bother your father
about that right now.
Hm? Hmm?
Good morning.
Morning.
Yo, so we're having a dance cypher.
I don't know if you want to participate,
- if you dance or anything.
- You guys can go in.
Thank you.
I'm here to enroll my daughter.
Oh, yes. Do you speak English, honey?
Yes, but she's...
she's still adjusting
to the American accent.
Okay. Um, and I see
we're still missing...
an official birth certificate.
- We have this.
- This is... a letter.
Yes.
I explained when I telephoned
that Sylvia was born
during the civil war in our country,
and both the hospital and
Department of Records were destroyed,
so we don't have
any original birth papers.
Okay.
I'll have Ms Tunnie enroll you
and take you to class.
- So, she starts right now?
- Yes!
You can pick her up
at 3:30 after school.
- Office.
- Hi, it's me.
Hey. Yo. You got moves.
Hey, wait. Where you going?
Weren't you just
waiting for your bus?
Yo! Chill out. Calm down.
Why you acting like that?
Yo, yo, yo.
Chill out, will you?
Can we, um, start over?
Hi, I'm Devon,
but most people call me DJ.
Hi, I'm Sylvia.
Everyone calls me Sylvia.
Hey, Sylvia.
From Angola?
Family new to the States or...
Yes. Um, no.
My father was here before.
He's a...
- diplomat.
- Wow. Okay, cool.
- You dance?
- Why do you accuse me of this?
Just, mostly girls
on the step team wear those.
Well, I do know for a fact
that the step team needs another stepper
for the dance cypher if you're interested.
What is this prize?
It's $1,000 for best soloist
and best team.
- No.
- Why not?
- I don't know the steps.
- That's easy.
You just look up videos
on YouTube,
use the videos to practice.
You just have to know
how to dance.
Fine.
If I agree to look at these steps,
will you let me pass?
I'll see you later, Sylvia.
We should go to the market
this weekend and...
get some bananas.
Mm-hm.
Oh, and something without
cholesterol for your father.
Have you seen the way he eats?
Eesh.
Is that Neema?
Did she get married?
Not yet.
One day you'll meet a nice boy.
Hey, maybe in university.
That's how I met
your father, you know?
Yes.
He was studying journalism.
You were studying social sciences,
and you both suspected
each other of being Communist.
He got on my nerves so much,
always talking about politics
the whole night.
I...
Well, I told you this story
too many times.
Mm.
He's a good man, Viñha, loyal.
Yes, Mae.
It's not his fault
that we had to wait so many years.
You know he tried everything.
Why didn't he come back home, then?
Because we wanted you
to have the life
that we couldn't have.
Huh?
I don't want you to suffer anymore.
Look, all those days
are behind us now.
Okay?
Everything is going to be fine, I promise.
God is good.
Hm?
All right, today's topic,
Immigration and emigration, right?
We have two different lists.
I want you all to turn to page 25...
and then go down,
look at the two different lists, okay?
Oh, Mr Jameson, you're late.
Sorry for being late, Mr Uno.
Okay, immigration,
life quality, religious freedom.
Take out a piece of paper,
and I want you
to start writing down
two different definitions...
Hey, DJ, what's your
African girlfriend wearing?
All right, Denise, settle down.
Everybody settle down.
Okay, is everybody
turned to page 25?
Okay. Yes. Mr Jameson,
please turn the pages.
Okay, here we go,
immigration, first list.
Sylvia.
Ah! Ah!
You okay? I tried calling,
but you didn't hear me.
- What were you...
- It's nothing. It's nothing.
You could have injured yourself.
I was exercising.
If we believe,
we shall receive whatever we ask for.
Your mother suggested
that maybe we should...
I mean, I should try and talk to you
just to see if everything was all right.
That you lift me up so that
I may better serve you,
to weather the storm, to continue to...
How long has she been so,
uh, religious?
When we moved to Tanzania.
At first she just wanted us
to have a community,
but then she got really serious about it.
And you?
As long as I'm reading the Bible,
she doesn't get on my case too much.
And do you miss home?
Don't you?
Well, after the war, the...
the home that I knew was gone.
Do you mind
if I snooze in the chair,
while I wait for her to finish?
Oh, Mama will be upset
if she knows I didn't give you my bed.
Oh, no, no, no.
She doesn't have to know.
Thank you, because you...
Lord, I ask...
I can turn off the light.
No, no, no, keep exercising.
I was finished.
Give me the strength
to weather the storm.
Sylviñha.
Yes, Pai?
This country...
is very hard for black people,
especially foreigners.
You always have to...
carry yourself a certain way,
so that white people...
don't feel threatened.
So, when we get to dance,
that's the one place where I can
actually be myself...
...show myself.
So, be yourself.
You are the only one
who knows what you know...
...and who can do what you do.
Yes, Pai.
Because if we ask in prayer...
It's the one that you sent to Mama
when we first moved to Tanzania.
I liked it, so she let me wear it.
Anywhere else?
It's a little bruised,
but nothing too unusual.
Where did you learn this song?
At the Angolan parties
in Dar-es-Salaam.
Everybody would dance to it
and cry, cry, cry.
That's when Mama
stopped going to the parties.
Then she didn't want me
to dance anymore.
Can I get an apartment
for $1,000?
I mean, depends where,
but, yeah, you could.
Why, you planning
on running away or something?
I'm just planning
for the future.
You got this.
Thanks.
- Pay attention.
- Sorry.
Five, six, seven. Here we go.
What are you doing?
What was that?
Oh, nothing.
It was just something...
- Did you see me do that?
- No. I...
Then don't do that.
We have a routine.
All we need is someone
to learn the routine and execute it
the way it needs to be done.
Now, can you do that or not?
- Yo, what the...
- Get away from me.
- What happened?
- I told you I can't step,
but you insisted,
and now you've embarrassed me.
Calm down.
I saw you up there
learning the moves.
You were doing great.
Well, your friend
has a problem with me,
because she keep poking,
poking, poking me like I'm...
like I'm a shish-kebab.
Oh, boy.
Okay, come on.
Let me take
your shish-kebab ass home.
Jesus.
Mae?
- The bathroom is down there.
- Cool.
Sorry it's a mess.
I don't usually have guests.
Nah, it's cool. It's cool.
Who's that?
That's Neema,
my best friend from back home.
She's a DJ.
Huh. Well, word.
You miss it there?
Uh...
my friends think my life is perfect now,
that I'm hanging out
with celebrities and crazy partying.
All my family's down south,
so, you know, I get the same thing.
Nobody here really knows
what it's like there,
so, you just... feel alone.
What about your parents?
They're complicated.
My dad...
he isn't really a diplomat.
I figured.
You know, you don't really hear
about too many diplomats
living in the 'hood, so.
Yeah.
But...
I also grew up without my pops, so...
I know how it feels.
So, uh, what are you going
to do after graduation?
I don't know, maybe start working,
go to a state college or something.
You're not going to continue
with the stage lights and promotion?
Well, not unless you become
a famous dancer, Miss Sylvia.
Sylvia.
Sorry, Mama,
I didn't know you were...
- Um, hi, ma'am.
I'm, uh, Devon Jameson.
How are you, Devon Jameson?
I'm, um... I'm good.
- You have a lovely home, ma'am.
- You've seen my home?
Just... just the bathroom.
Sorry, Mama,
I didn't know you were home.
So, you brought a man home
when you thought I wasn't home?
No, Mae.
I just wanted to make sure
that Sylvia got home safe
after dance try-outs.
Anyway, I probably should be heading home
to do some homework.
Yes.
Oh, say hello to your parents.
Okay.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Excuse me, ma'am.
We didn't do anything, Mama.
He just escorted me home.
Viñha...
your father and I
are going out to dinner tonight.
I don't know what's gotten into you,
but I expected better.
You know I only do this
for your own good
because I can see things you can't.
Your father and I are doing
our best to protect you.
From now on, you go to school...
and you come straight back.
No friends, no activities...
and no dancing.
Are you listening?
This hurts me more
than it hurts you...
but you will repent and seek
forgiveness for what you did.
Our father...
which art in heaven,
hallowed by thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done on earth
as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread
and forgive us our trespasses
as we forgive...
- Esther, what is she doing...
- Nuh-uh.
I will not lose my daughter
to this country.
For thine is the kingdom
and the power
and the glory forever and ever.
Our father which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come, thy will be...
Family is here now.
- This is for you.
- Thank you.
And this one is for you.
Come.
Can you believe it?
For the gifts of food,
for the gifts of shelter
that you have provided
for me and my family.
Praise Jesus for this day,
and may my path
be free from trouble
and the destructive
hand of Satan.
May I return safely from school,
and may Daddy return safely
from America...
I mean, work.
- Amen.
It's a passage of scripture
that's always fascinated me.
Because you disappeared!
I'm the fool, right? I'm the fool.
Like, you're never accountable.
You don't get to drop out
of people's lives for...
What were you thinking?
You know what?
You always do this,
and I should have listened
to my astrologer.
I should have listened to my spirit.
Because this is Aries bullshit,
so narcissistic.
It's so...
And you know what?
I don't have time for this.
I don't have
the psychic bandwidth.
You know what's so effed up?
Is that we have to effing work together!
All right.
You know what? We're done.
Come and get your shit.
Who is it?
Nzingha from next door.
Just a moment.
Oh.
Uh, is Walter...
Walter still live here?
I'm afraid he's at work
at the moment.
- I'm his wife, Esther.
- Oh, okay.
- Pleased to meet you, queen.
- Pleased to meet you too...
queen?
Excuse me.
I was just cleaning the house,
but you're welcome
to come inside.
Oh, no, sis.
I just wanted to drop off
some mail that was put in my box.
I will make sure I give them
to my husband when he comes home.
Okay. Peace.
"He who is brought together in the Lord,
let no man tear asunder."
You know my heart, Lord.
You know my struggles.
It's the word of God
that we need to follow,
taking in his...
Some of us are trying
to lead our families,
which, when the temptation...
- How are you, queen?
- Fine, thank you.
- You been shopping?
- Mm-hm.
Did you go to the Korean market
on the corner?
Sometimes their food
isn't always so fresh.
I was looking
for some millet flour for Walter.
He has the cholesterol, so.
You know, I can take you to the
Egyptian market where I get my food.
- I'm headed there now.
- No, no, no, I don't want to disturb.
Sis, it's really no problem.
The neighborhood
has changed dramatically,
used to have
a lot of our people.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah.
It's very busy.
Yeah, it's very busy.
- As-salaam alaikum.
Mm.
Smell.
Nice.
You eat very healthy?
Ah, you know, I try.
I'm doing much better, though,
now that I'm not in a relationship.
I am just grateful that I am
finally reunited with Walter
after so many years apart.
- Mm.
- He must have struggled a lot.
I was wondering how he learned
how to cook
all these low-fat foods.
Maybe you helped him.
You know how men are.
They know how
to find their resources.
Was there a woman named Linda
who lived in the apartment
before Walter moved in?
- Oh...
- Yes?
Did you get more
ashwagandha powder this week?
- No, ma'am.
- No?
You know what?
Sometimes it takes them
so long to restock their items,
but I really want to support
the local business, you know?
And these brothers are African, so.
You know what?
We should head back.
Did you get your flour?
- Yes, thank you.
- Okay.
Thank you, Lord.
You have 30 minutes for this call.
May your name be praised.
May your name...
Hello?
Sister Redempta?
Ah, my Esther!
How are you settling in?
Oh.
Oh, it is a challenge, my sister.
I'm home mostly by myself,
so, usually, I'm just thinking, thinking,
missing my community there.
How is our Sylvia doing over there?
Oh, she's trying her best.
Show us the Wakanda symbol one time.
In Jesus' name, protect Sylvia.
Please guide her.
And how is Walter?
Oh, he's...
He's working very hard.
His life here is so difficult.
I don't believe we've met.
I usually come on weekdays
because I mostly work on Sundays.
Oh. Welcome to our flock.
But I'm trying my best
to help him and to pray for him.
Protect Walter and guide him, please.
He is the head, father God.
I am proud of you, my sister.
You endured many,
many years of hardship
and stayed faithful to God's command.
Don't forget to send your offerings.
We must always give thanks,
especially when God
answers our prayers.
No, I'm... I'm not hungry.
I thought you might say that,
so I made you a flask of tea
with some rolls today.
Very little sugar.
Oh, you work so hard
to look after us.
Allow me to now look after you, hm?
Thank you.
That's very nice.
No, but thank you.
And you? How was your day?
Oh, you know, the usual things.
I had a question.
I had some money that I kept
in case of an emergency,
and I thought maybe
you could help me
send it to our church
in Dar-es-Salaam.
They have been praying for us
for so many years.
It would be a offering of thanks.
Okay.
I can send it
during my lunch break tomorrow.
There's a transfer place near work.
That's wonderful!
How much money is this?
$1,000.
You're s... you're sending
the church $1,000?
Yes.
This is for several years.
I kept it in case
of an emergency,
but now that God
has delivered us...
He hasn't.
He hasn't delivered us.
Amor... we are here.
Yes, yes, yes, and do you
know what that means?
It means I have to work harder
than before,
and we have less than before.
- But this...
- All this time I have been...
I've been working
double and triple shifts.
Do you know what we could
have done with this money?
This money is for God, querido,
so that he will favor us as...
As we rebuild our family,
our marriage.
I can't deal with this right now.
Here you go.
- Thank you.
- Next.
Yes, I'd like to send this money
to Dar-es-Salaam, Tanzania.
Your ID?
Sister Redempta?
How are you, my child?
I sent the money, but...
Mm. What is the problem?
Tell me what is in your heart.
It's just...
I think...
I... I think we...
might be...
unequally yoked.
Unequally yoked?
Da?
Yes, Sister.
What can I do?
He is the man
that God has given me, and...
why would he do that
if there wasn't a reason for it?
God will not lead you
to the desert and abandon you.
The dutiful wife who prays
for husband and family
will be heard first.
Continue to pray.
Increase your offering.
You cannot give up.
Now, bow your head.
Let's pray together.
Heavenly Father, we come
before you with Sister Esther.
Lord, we ask you to give her peace...
Mae?
You're not going to continue
with the stage lights
and promotion?
Not unless you become
a famous dancer, Miss Sylvia.
Sylvia.
She's a teenager.
It's her job to annoy us.
- Mm.- She'll just calm down.
Let's just take a moment.
Let's... let's go out to dinner
so we can talk.
I don't think you understand,
Walter.
This is not a time
for going out to dinner.
Clearly, we need to be at home
watching our daughter.
- Who?
- Esther.
Who?
Esther!
Walter's wife.
Hey, queen. How are you?
Oh, fine, thank you.
I, um... I wanted to ask you
a favor, please, my sister.
Mm-hm?
I'm going to dinner
with Walter tonight,
and I... I need to borrow
just a purse
to go with this outfit.
Mm-mm. Mm-mm.
Girl, you're... you're gonna need
way more than just a purse.
Mm-mm. Come on.
Come on.
So, where are you
going for dinner?
Well, I'm not sure.
He didn't tell me.
Oh, so, it's a surprise.
All right. That's nice of him!
Well, actually, we have been
talking about this for a while,
but... today's not really
a good day for it.
That's nonsense.
Life is short.
You can't put this on hold.
Okay.
I agree. You are right.
Good. So...
we need you looking royal.
Mm-hm.
Well, actually,
I am a Christian,
so, nothing too...
Mm. Honey,
you're out here worried
about another woman's mail
when you're hiding the essence
of your womanhood
from your own husband.
Is that really what
white Jesus wants?
Sometimes a king needs his queen
to remind him who she is.
Now, come on.
You look...
very beautiful.
I'm glad you like it.
Can I get you anything else?
Oh, coffee, please.
- Ma'am?
- Oh, no. Thank you.
Thank you for bringing me here.
It's... it's very nice.
Remember when life was simple?
When a fancy night
was sitting on the beach,
grilling fish over a fire...
with cheap wine?
Red snapper with jindungo,
of course.
And plantains.
From Dona Magalie's place
on the corner.
Did she survive?
I'm... not even sure.
After we left for Tanzania,
I lost touch
with so many people.
Let's dance.
- Where?
- Here, on the side.
- We can't do that.
- Why not?
The band's warming up.
Shouldn't we wait for them
to start the party properly?
I'm not stopping. Come.
Join me.
You are embarrassing yourself.
Then come rescue me, huh?
We'll be embarrassed together.
See?
It's working!
It's been so long.
I don't even remember how.
You're always the most beautiful...
when you dance.
From the donation box.
Wait, wait, don't do that.
- I'll get rid of them!
- Esther, no.
I've heard you, Walter,
loud and clear.
You don't want me.
You want something else.
This...
This was too big for us
to not lose ourselves.
I... I want to go back home.
Everybody thinks
her father abandoned us,
that she was born from disgrace,
and that's why
you never came back.
She wasn't born from disgrace!
After you left,
my parents disowned me
and took their curses
to their graves!
I need to know who she is.
You ready to kill it
at the cypher tonight?
Yeah. Neema made me
a special dance mix.
Write your stage name on here.
When you get out there,
you forget about your parents.
Forget about everything.
You're gonna kill it.
Thanks, DJ.
For what?
For believing.
You know I got you.
It ain't really nothing.
All, right, well, let's...
Let's get going.
I'm looking for my daughter.
She's a dancer.
Next.
That's Wreckka.
Watch her closely.
She's the one to beat.
All right, all right, all right.
Repping Philly,
we have... Dirty Dozen!
Repping New York,
our reigning champion, Wreckka!
We have a winner.
All right, guys,
let's take a five-minute break
before we get to this next round.
Just stay focused.
I think you got this
competition wrapped up.
The audience is live.
The judges are gonna love it.
You're amazing.
Just focus in and loosen up.
Focus and...
Yes.
Hey, where you going?
- I have to go.
- Wait, what...
- I made a mistake, all right?
- What do you mean?
I have to go.
Sylvia! Hold on.
I have to go find her.
She's all I have.
This is my responsibility, Viñha.
Go.
Fight for your dance, huh?
I'll find her.
Up next, ladies and gentlemen,
our defending champion, Wreckka,
has agreed to a battle
with the new kid on the block,
Young Afrikka!
No.
I've been lost too.
And Linda found you.
She gave me hope, Esther.
She insisted I don't give up,
that I keep petitioning immigration
for us to be together.
- You think it was easy for me?
- Of course not.
We lost so many years.
Look, I'm sorry.
We don't even
know each other anymore,
or ourselves.
When we met...
we didn't know if we'd live
to see the next day.
We didn't know
who was a comrade,
who was an informant,
who was there for the ride.
Words meant nothing.
So, we danced.
When I moved, you followed.
When you hesitate,
I slowed down...
because we could feel
each other.
So...
what do we do now?
Mae?
Pai said you went dancing.
What happened?
The crowd...
they really liked me, Mama.
They saw me.
Of course they did.
We see you.
We do.
I'll make us breakfast.
Which one?
This one.
Your favorite biscuits.
I like it.
Do you want?
Mm-hm. Thank you.
Hi, my name is John Akomfrah.
I'm an artist and a film-maker
and I'm here to talk to you today
about Farewell Amor,
which is a film you've just seen.
And I'm very, very lucky
to have next to me Ekwa Msangi,
who's both a director -the director, rather - and an ally.
Am I okay to say "director and ally"?
Yeah, absolutely.
I should certainly hope so!
When we met,
one of the things I was convinced about
was that you wanted to make projects
about the African experience in New York,
where you were at the time.
Yeah, so Farewell Amor is a project
that's been sort of stewing in my mind
for a long time,
because it's a family story.
It's inspired by an aunt and an uncle
who were married
in the mid '90s, in Tanzania.
And my uncle got a student visa
to come to the US
and had every intention of bringing Auntie
and cousin right behind him.
And, to date, they've still been stuck
in visa applications, visa rejections,
visa application, visa rejections
for decades.
Watching their struggle
for so many years,
I wanted to make the "what if?" story.
I had this image in my mind
of my uncle, you know,
"What if Auntie finally got her visa?
That's no longer the issue.
"They're coming. They're coming.
It's a done deal.
"You know, and so Uncle's at the airport,
at arrivals gate,
"and he's, like, what is he...
what is he thinking?
"What is he feeling?
Would he recognise them?
"What is the first thing to say?"
- Amor!
- You know, for me,
New York is a place
that has all sorts of people like that,
not just African immigrants,
you know?
Everybody is that, and including
a lot of the white immigrants
that came to New York
through Ellis Island, way back when,
who left behind everything
in Ireland and Scotland,
and wherever else they came from,
to start this new place.
As you may be aware,
I'm a child
of one of those exiles in the film.
Yes.
And it is very much in the context
of your unfolding story
that I arrived here, you know,
except that I came with one parent
and one who couldn't join,
because they died in a coup, basically.
And I was really struck
by how different
that story that you have here
is from the other New York Africa stories.
I mean, was that a conscious attempt
to try and avoid the other ones, or...?
Do you know what I mean?
There's a very...
There's a way in which stories
are made about Africans in New York,
and this doesn't feel like one of them.
Most of the films that at least I've seen,
or that tend to be popularised,
certainly funded
through a Hollywood-type system
tend to be about either
the most exceptional African ever,
or the most, sort of, destitute,
struggling African ever.
Yes, it's a story of immigrants,
but I wasn't very much interested
in talking about the political aspects
of their immigration,
which tends to be
the other type of stories,
sort of like the cause, the issue-driven.
You know, what happens
when they got to the border,
and then the racist cop said...
and the racist immigration laws
or anti immigration laws
made them do XYZ, you know,
I mean, that is a story
and it certainly happens,
and it's very serious,
but I really wanted an opportunity
to just, like,
depoliticise the immigrant.
You know, first of all, not giving them
the titles as an immigrant,
but actually, like, names.
Like, we actually know them as people.
You know, I mean,
it's harder for people to... relate.
If it's just about
a very specific political issue,
that I may never have experienced.
And it's like, "Oh, what a terrible thing
is happening to them."
But we've all experienced heartbreak,
you know, we've all experienced longing,
we've all experienced, you know,
being new in an environment
that we're unfamiliar with.
And I feel like the way
to know them as people
is to know their sort of, like,
their heart problems.
- Sorry for being late, Mr Uno.
- Okay. Immigration, life quality.
I was involved with a feature
set in New York,
about a coming-to-America scenario.
And so I know the importance of casting,
and I think, in many ways,
partly why mine didn't go
to the final hurdle was because, like,
we didn't quite get the casting right.
So, tell me something about your cast,
because it's a fabulous one.
Yeah, we... Man, we got really lucky.
I mean, I was very clear...
what I needed them to do.
I needed people who had danceability,
for at least for Walter
and Sylvia's characters.
I needed people who could be
taught an Angolan accent,
not an "African" accent,
because there is no such thing.
But specifically an Angolan accent,
which is a very difficult one.
Lord, thank you for bringing us together.
And then I just wanted them
to actually look
like they could be a family.
So, we started with Sylvia,
and she came through our casting director,
and was just, you know...
There's, there's something about Jayme
that is so striking.
I mean, she's beautiful, yes,
but just, like, even her intensity
in her personality is just so striking
from the minute you meet her.
For the other two, for Walter and Esther,
I know Ntare,
because he's also a wonderful
experimental film-maker
and our short films
have travelled together in some festivals.
And we've been threatening to work
together for several years.
And, so, you know, I reached out to him,
because I know he can do it.
He's an incredible actor,
and I know he can do accents as well.
Let's dance.
I'm not stopping. Come.
Join me.
You are embarrassing yourself!
Then come rescue me.
We'll be embarrassed together.
He did more than anything
I could have even imagined.
Similar to Zainab. She...
I have never worked with her.
She's very big in theatre in New York.
I mean, it wasn't even... It was...
There wasn't even a question about it.
It was just, like, "Of course."
- How is Walter?
- Oh, he's...
He's working very hard.
His life here is so difficult.
I don't believe we've met.
So, I, we really, really lucked out.
There's literally isn't
a single person in our cast
who was sort of like a fly-by-night,
just, like, you know, last-minute call.
Everybody was very deliberate.
And they did such amazing work.
I'm really grateful.
The score is, again,
- unusually, very un-African-movie.
- Uh-huh.
So, I want you to talk a bit about that.
My reason for wanting
these characters to be from Angola,
as opposed to East Africa,
which is where I'm from,
is specifically because of the music
and the dance that goes with the music,
which I love,
and I'm a practitioner of Kizomba,
which is the style that Walter practises.
Kizomba is a very beautiful,
sensual couples dance from Angola,
which... ah... you know, most people
don't think beautiful, sensual
couples dance is from Africa, period.
You know, most African dance
is characterised by drumming
and the fertility dance,
or the rain dance,
or, you know, something like that,
which is great, we have those too.
But we also have these.
The thing about Kizomba,
which makes it very unique for me,
is that there is not
a regular foot pattern to the dance.
The leader is dancing to the music
and to how they feel about the music,
and your job, as the follower,
is to be connected to them
so that you can follow,
because they can change at any moment.
And, so, there is a level of connection
that's required.
It's a very close...
It looks like a really...
A lot of people get very intimidated
because it looks super sexy.
And it is but you actually have
to concentrate quite a bit,
because you really do need to, like,
have some sort of connection
with your partner in order to perform.
And I just thought
it was a really interesting metaphor
for a relationship of these two people
who were in sync,
literally, were in step,
and, because of distance,
because of time have fallen out of step
and are therefore
not able to dance together.
Kuduro, which is the style
that Sylvia practises,
is also out of Angola.
It's kind of harsh and from the streets
and from the youth and,
you know, young people,
it's their way of expressing the things
that they can't say to their elders.
You know, their frustrations
with the economic situation
or, you know,
coming out of a 30-year civil war
and what that's done to the country
and to people and domestic violence
and all these different topics
that people,
you know, have feelings about it,
but don't have a place to express it,
other than through their dance
and their music.
Watch her closely. She's the one to beat.
For Sylvia, as a young African girl,
who is not raised
to speak back to her parents
and tell them off - you know,
that would never happen -
this would be the only way
that she would be able to express herself.
I loved one other quality about the music,
as Walter says at one point, you know,
it's the vehicle of freedom.
Mm-hm, yeah.
Dancing to music,
you set yourself free.
But it's also the way in which...
a very Portuguese affect
comes into the film, really,
because all the music
carries this saudade.
- You know?
- Yeah.
This kind of... not melancholy,
but a sadness.
The longing.
About longing, you know,
and nostalgia for things
which cannot and have not been.
Yeah. Exactly.
It made it a very unique "African" film,
in a way, because it had
this pan-continental feel,
you know, it could easily
have been made in Brazil.
I was born in the US,
my parents were students at the time.
So, this was the way
that parents, you know,
told their children
about where we're from.
And, in my research about,
you know, Angolans in exile,
that was one of the things
that came up was just, like,
the connection, how music,
Kizomba and Samba music in particular,
were so important in terms
of the remembering of home,
but also the transferring
of information to the youth
about what we'd left behind,
because many of them
had never seen Angola.
- Pay attention.
- Sorry.
Tell me what you want to do with it now
and where is it going,
now that it's had its big Sundance...
Or maybe we can talk about Sundance.
Yeah, Sundance was amazing.
We're so grateful that we were...
we had the experience
of being able to show this film
to a live audience,
because, you know,
the world is so different now.
My film career,
making stories about African people,
in a way that's not your typical,
you know,
African story
that Hollywood tends to put out,
or is normally seen on American screens
and that kind of thing,
I've had a lot of no's and a lot of,
like, question marks
and like, "What are you doing?"
and, "Who are these people?"
and, "We don't quite understand,"
and, "Are you sure you want...?"
"Shouldn't they have
some more colourful clothes on?"
and, "I don't quite understand
what they're saying."
All of those kinds of things.
"Too many subtitles!"
"Not enough subtitles!" et cetera.
And, so...
"Why are they speaking English?"
Right!
Or, "They should all speak English."
Exactly. Exactly. And, so,
I had kind of developed
a little bit of a skin you know, around...
"I don't think anyone's gonna get this,
I'm gonna make it anyways.
"But I'm not making it for you,
"'cause I just don't think...
My experience has been
"that most American people
don't get the work that I make."
And, so, to be able to show it,
to get into Sundance,
for one, in competition,
and be able to show it
to all of these audiences
who were just completely floored
and the tears and the gushing...
It was just, like, "Wow!
"This is not what I expected at all."
It was a really wonderful
and beautiful experience.
♪ Everywhere I go
♪ I'm gonna let it shine
♪ Everywhere I go... ♪
And from here, you know,
where we're releasing
in the US, December 11th,
we're releasing on MUBI, December 18,
really excited to be able
to share this work.
I mean, feeling very encouraged
by the feedback
that we've gotten thus far.
It's been really interesting
to see the different reactions.
You know, there's Team Walter,
Team Esther and Team Sylvia.
Team Linda is also...
Really?
There have been a few Team Lindas, yeah!
"What happened to Linda?
Justice for Linda!"
Well, look, whatever happens,
whichever team
people are going to root for,
I just hope they see it,
'cause it is a fantastic film.
Thank you so much. Thank you.
I'm so proud of you.
I can't tell you how proud I am.
You know, when I found out
you got in the London Film Festival,
I was, like, "Yay!"
Thank you, thank you
for your guidance over the years.
It definitely has helped to bring me here.
You and the community at large,
because, you know,
- I stand on many shoulders...
- Hear, hear.
...in terms of being able
to put this work forward
and hopefully continuing
to do so in the future.