That necklace is beautiful.
My boyfriend gave it to me.
Then your assignment is over.
End the relationship
immediately.
Gladly.
Your gift
was a recording device.
Why the hell
are you following me?
This is an off-the-books
account.
- Whose is it?
- United States Secretary of Defense.
I understand you've been
tracking Leon Vance.
I want everything you have.
Six Klowny Kake ice cream bars
were partially cut open and
laced with strychnine poison.
No DNA, no Crum.
No Crum, no confession.
Mr. Crum, you're free to go.
I've spent years in courtrooms
watching people abuse
the system.
A system that's supposed
to protect the innocent,
not free the guilty.
To balance the scales,
sometimes you have
to apply pressure.
Our hit man was paid with money
from SecDef's secret account?
- I'll call Clark.
- Have him meet us.
Gibbs?
Director?
Damn.
Hello?
Gibbs?
Westley,
what are you doing?
I could be asking you
the same question.
You've been following me.
- You taught me well.
- Why?
- Who are you working for?
- You, I thought.
Till you
kicked me out.
I want back in. Whatever it is
you're working on with NCIS,
let me help.
I did teach you well.
Who sent you?
What's wrong with you?
Put the gun down.
I asked you a question.
Stop,
and answer the damn question.
Federal agents!
In here!
- Mallory?
- Leon!
I'm unarmed.
Hands.
It's not what you think.
♪ NCIS 16x22 ♪
'...and Executioner'
Original Air Date on May 7, 2019
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
♪﻿﻿﻿♪
You got to be
kidding me.
It still works.
Mm, didn't it
used to be in color?
- Hey. Morning, McGee.
- Hey.
Hey, how was your, uh,
trip back in from California?
Early. Who is this?
CIA Officer Clark.
It's a shame, huh?
Nick, you didn't say anything
in your text about a dead body.
Tim, why else
would I text you
to come to Gibbs's house
as soon as you landed?
Well, I can think
of a few reasons.
So what happened here?
Clark was meeting Gibbs.
Mallory got here first.
She said Clark
tried to kill her.
What? Why?
Mallory shot back.
Put one in the TV and
one in Clark's heart.
- Self-defense?
- According to Mallory.
Okay. Do we believe her?
I acted in self-defense.
I'm telling you the truth, Leon.
Well, that's a first.
Why were you following Clark?
And don't say it's your job.
After Clark pulled me
off your surveillance,
he had my security clearance
downgraded.
It killed my credibility
at the Agency.
I thought I had done something
wrong, but now I think
there's something
that he didn't want me to see.
And I think you all know
what it is.
I want back in.
This was to save face,
professionally?
Do I really need
to say it, Leon?
Gibbs?
Bourbon.
The last time we talked,
I didn't have a chance
to say I'm sorry.
For everything.
I know.
I really did have
feelings for you.
- I know.
- I was doing my job,
and fell in love.
Which one is wrong?
See? It's not
that easy to answer.
What am I supposed to say
to change all that?
You could say
you feel the same way.
You can say,
in another life,
we'd be planning a vacation
to Cancun right now.
In another life.
But in this one, the CIA
is waiting to interrogate you.
My story won't change.
It's the truth.
Ladies and gentlemen,
thank you for waiting.
I believe we are ready to begin.
Your Honor,
is it wise to meet so soon
after your bailiff
was arrested for murder?
NCIS is getting too
close to uncovering
his connection to this council.
McKinney won't talk.
And all remaining funds
have been relocated.
Plus we are taking one
additional precaution.
Have you all reviewed
the information I sent?
Good. Regarding
the murder
of Pedro Juan Hernandez,
how does this council
find the defendant,
Gunnery Sergeant
Leroy Jethro Gibbs?
- Guilty.
The decision is unanimous.
The verdict is so recorded.
Your Honor, with
Bailiff McKinney in custody,
we'll need to find someone
to carry out the sentence.
I already have.
The ice cream killer,
Stuart Crum,
got off on a legal technicality,
and then was murdered.
The man who killed
Crum was an assassin
paid from a secret
account belonging to
Secretary of Defense.
We don't actually think SecDef
paid for the hit, do we?
I mean, it was his account.
We still don't have proof that
he was controlling it.
So find some.
Follow the money.
It's easier said
than done, boss.
We don't have all the records
on SecDef's account.
And our bailiff
hit man's not talking.
No wife, no friends,
no social media.
He's a breathing dead end.
He has a boss, Bishop.
- Start with him.
- Judge Deakin.
- On it.
- Torres.
Boss. I think the best way
to find proof on SecDef
is to just
confront him.
Easier said than done, Tim.
Well, I know Vance
isn't ready to go all in
on this one,
but you don't want to lose
the element of surprise.
- Too late.
Agent Gibbs.
Maybe you should join us.
Somebody has been accessing
an old offshore account
in my name.
I have no idea who, or why.
Which is why I'm here.
Sunlight is the best
disinfectant, boys.
So, you got questions,
ask away.
The account.
What is it?
Take a look.
Asked you, Mr. Secretary.
I was an undersecretary
back in 2002.
Office of Finance. I opened
that account in connection
with several national
security operations.
Off the books?
Post 9/11, things moved fast.
Bookkeeping was not at the top
of our list of priorities.
That account
got lost in the shuffle.
- Hundreds of millions?
- It's D.C., Leon.
Sir, you have DoD,
FBI and a whole host
of federal acronyms
at your disposal.
Why come to us?
Well... last time
our paths crossed,
I didn't like you
peeking under my hood.
So, I decided to take a peek
under yours.
Did you find
what you were looking for?
What I found was
even worse than dirt.
You really are a good man
who runs a tight ship. You both.
- Last man who said that is dead.
- Yeah, well,
I don't know anything
about Clark's death.
But I'm offering you
everything I have.
The offshore
account records
you've been looking for.
All of them.
Now it's your turn.
Can you tell me
who's been using this account?
Not yet.
But you do know what
they've been using it for.
Gentlemen,
trust is a two-way street.
Yes, sir. I will let you know
as soon as we have more.
♪﻿﻿﻿♪
Whoa. Well, I know where I'm
having my next birthday party.
- Where was the last one?
- ShowBiz Pizza.
I was seven.
Special Agents
Bishop and Torres.
Judge Deakin.
Thanks for meeting
me here, uh...
You called just as I was
on my way out of the courthouse.
Yeah, this place
is incredible.
Isn't it?
Labor of love for a long time.
It's yours?
Indeed it is.
I did most of the
restoration myself.
Working with my hands
keeps me sane.
Definitely more fun
than a boat in a basement.
- What's that?
- Long story.
And it's not why you're here.
Your bailiff, Colt McKinney,
he's been arrested for murder.
I heard.
Awful.
You've worked
with him for six years.
Any signs of this guy
going off the rails?
No.
Although, the job has
its share of frustrations.
Justice is not always served.
Anybody who might want to take
advantage of those frustrations?
We don't think McKinney
was working alone.
Really? What makes you say that?
He got paid for the hit.
Y-You're telling me
my bailiff is a hit man?
For whom?
Well, we were hoping that
you could help us find out.
It breaks my heart
to have the law corrupted.
A bad man gets away
with murder, leading to
a-a man I thought was good
committing it.
Good men don't commit murder.
They shouldn't have to.
The system failed.
That's not exactly what I'd
expect to hear from a judge.
I'm not condoning it.
I'll tell you what,
you sit on the bench for
40 years, and then we'll talk.
Huh?
You two know anything about,
uh, vintage pin setters?
Lane two is on the fritz,
needs a little TLC.
This can't be right.
Check it again.
Because the fifth time's
a charm?
What do we got?
We've been processing
the bank records from SecDef.
- Mm-hmm. And?
Well, what we're finding
is very strange.
I think there's something else
we need to check.
No, we don't.
Just tell him.
Tell him what?
Well, since you asked, follow me.
So, Stuart Crum,
aka...
- Ice cream killer.
Guilty, but he got off
on a technicality.
The next day,
Crum is found dead,
and we know that the
hit man who killed him
was paid out of
SecDef's account.
But check this out,
we found six
other withdrawals
from that same account
over the past
three years.
Each one was sent
to a city that,
just the week before,
had a high-profile murder case
get dismissed
by a technicality.
In each case, the suspected
killer ends up dead.
I mean, holy vigilante
justice, Batman,
but in this case, it's like
a nationwide network
of vigilante justice.
Someone is having
killers killed. Who?
Don't know.
The money's a dead end.
Assuming SecDef
is telling the truth,
there's no way to track exactly
who's controlling his account.
Find a way, Kase.
Boss, you really buying this?
Got anything else, McGee?
Yeah, I'm buying it.
He must be tired.
Anything else, Gibbs?
Nah, just the usual
would be great. Thanks.
Working on that boat again, huh?
Four coffees
coming up.
♪﻿﻿﻿♪
Anybody got staples?
Yeah. Heads up.
A network of
vigilante justice?
No matter how many times
you say it out loud, it still
sounds like every
comic book ever.
Everybody likes superheroes.
Superman doesn't
hire hit men, Nick.
Yeah, but he takes down
criminals
that the system can't catch.
Yeah, but he also leaps tall
buildings in a single bound,
so let's stick to reality here.
Murder is murder.
I agree.
We need to find out who is
controlling this network.
- I agree.
- So we all agree.
So what's
the problem?
The problem is...
where is Gibbs?
I mean, there should be
three cups of coffee
in the trash by now. Zero cups.
Yeah, and how often
do we get
this far into a discussion
before he appears behind...
See, that's why
I didn't say anything,
'cause as soon as I did...
Okay.
Yeah, this is weird.
It's not like Gibbs
to not show up for work.
We should check on him.
- Oh, good luck with that.
- Yeah, that's all you.
I'm-I'm gonna go help, uh,
Kasie find a connection.
Yeah, and I'm gonna
pull case files
on our six murder dots.
Oh, my God.
What are you two scared of?
Gibbs will appreciate the fact
that we are concerned about him.
Yeah. He appreciates when people
are up in his business.
♪﻿﻿﻿♪
So, what do you think?
Well, it doesn't seem like
a matter of opinion, Leon.
Jimmy's autopsy report,
Kasie's forensics report,
the CIA independent
investigation,
they all say
the same thing.
Mallory's story checks out.
For once.
But you didn't need me
to tell you that, Leon,
so what do you need?
Closure.
Oh.
Oh...
You actually fell
for this woman, huh?
Cupid usually shoots arrows,
but you're walking around with
a harpoon in your chest, huh?
It's over. I know that, Jack.
Do you?
The heart wants
what the heart wants.
Could I have done something
a little different?
Oh...
Leon, honey...
This is not your fault.
When I first put together
that she was CIA,
I could've called her out.
You put the security
of this agency
above your
personal feelings.
But I don't think
that's a good foundation
for happily ever after.
Maybe you need
to lower the bar a bit.
If your goal
is "happily ever after,"
I think you got into
the wrong business.
Or maybe you should
just date a librarian,
so you won't have
this problem again.
Stay away from undercover
CIA agents, that's your advice?
I mean, it's practical.
But this isn't about finding
someone new, is it?
Hey, Gibbs, checking in, again.
Hey, Elaine!
- Agent Bishop.
- What happened here?
Gibbs happened.
He didn't tell you?
Tell me what?
Late last night,
Gibbs was heading home.
Next thing I know,
we heard shots outside.
Gunshots?
Gibbs is okay, didn't even
spill his coffees.
So wh-who did the shooting?
What did the police find?
Not Gibbs. He took off
before the cops got here.
And after fielding questions
with these yahoos all night,
I understand why.
I told them I didn't see
who was shooting.
Matter of fact, I didn't
tell them who was shot at.
I assumed Gibbs left
for a reason.
You sure that it was Gibbs'
truck that was hit?
Where did he go?
I-I told you
everything I know.
I just want to say,
any time you guys need a safe,
secluded space for gossip,
Autopsy's all yours.
Gets really lonely down here.
So what are we supposed
to say to Gibbs?
Um, nothing.
We're just gonna ignore this?
- As opposed to...?
- I don't know,
talk to him. I mean,
you had the guts to fire him.
And I lived to talk about it.
You think I'm gonna
push my luck?
So no one's gonna
confront Gibbs?
About what?
Gibbs! These guys
just showed up down here.
I-I told you, I have work
to do, people.
Update.
I left you a couple
messages this morning.
Is everything okay?
Car trouble. Update.
Ah, Agent Torres,
there you are.
- Am I, uh, interrupting?
- Uh, no. I was
just about to tell Gibbs that I
came to you for
some information.
And, clearly,
here you are
- with that information.
- Indeed I am.
I pulled the records of your
six vigilante murder cases,
and I discovered an
intriguing connection.
What kind of connection, Duck?
These six murders
span four states,
each in a different city,
each in a different jurisdiction
with different judges.
However, on closer inspection,
each of these
four judges
have something
in common.
They all clerked for one man.
Judge Deakin.
A federal judge running
a vigilante network?
We can't prove anything.
No, not yet.
Keep digging.
Okay, where is he going now?
Damn good question.
As NCIS historian, I have become
somewhat isolated
down in my new office,
but since when has
Gibbs' whereabouts been
so hotly contested?
Don't ask, Duck.
Wood shifts.
Hard to keep
an even surface.
Preaching to the choir.
Anything beats
synthetic lanes.
Even if it means maintaining
the wood's original shape.
Original shape's a tree.
Funny.
I thought I locked that door.
You did.
I think you dropped this.
Looks like
a charming fellow.
You know him?
I did.
He killed my family.
Now he's dead.
What's this about,
Agent Gibbs?
You want me dead?
Here I am.
Want you dead?
This have something to do
with this photo?
He doesn't look like
he died of old age.
You want to judge me, Judge?
Man up.
Do your own dirty work.
Man up?
Like you did?
You put your thumb
on the scale
and created justice
where there was none,
and made the world right.
No, not even close.
Needed to be done.
But now you want me dead
for it.
You condemn me for something
I did years ago...
while you're still doing it.
That's an interesting theory,
but you can't prove
a word of it.
Maybe that's why you came alone?
Or maybe, deep down,
you really believe
in justice at all costs.
Not about justice.
Justice is your excuse.
Because I'm coming for you...
and you're scared.
And you're alone.
Because they don't know
what you did, do they?
Your team.
And you're too ashamed
to tell 'em the truth.
Agent Gibbs, I think
we're accusing each other
of the same thing.
Maybe we're on the same team.
No, we're not.
Morning, Nick.
Hey, yo.
Was that meant for us?
Or did he just have a stroke?
Excuse me.
The last man who made
that hand gesture at me
is now missing a hand.
What? It means "campfire."
Then just say campfire.
Campfire. Now.
Hey, what's up?
We have a problem.
I followed Gibbs last night.
Uh, that's a you problem.
He's not gonna be happy
about that.
He went to the judge
without telling us.
Why is he cutting us out?
I don't know.
But it has to do with
the shooting at the diner.
- I see how this looks.
- Bad.
Well, what are we supposed
to do? We supposed to step in
every time boss makes
a move without telling us?
This is different.
I mean, the guy's car
just got sprayed with bullets,
and we have no idea why.
We can't do our jobs
if we're always in the dark.
Maybe he's trying to protect us.
From what?
If we're in danger,
wouldn't-wouldn't you want
to know?
McGee, you have to handle this.
Yeah, I can't keep
firing Gibbs.
Just talk to him.
All right, fine.
But if I crash and burn,
you two are coming with.
Update. Go.
Actually, boss, before that...
Nope.
What does he mean, "nope"?
We didn't even say anything.
McGee.
Boss, we should talk.
Look, whatever's going on,
we need to know,
no matter what it is.
It's personal.
Shooting at the diner,
maybe?
Yeah, we know about that.
We're detectives.
But once you talked
to the judge,
you made it about the case.
The two have to
be connected.
Now, I get it if you don't want
to tell us why, boss,
but after all we've
been through with you,
you think there's anything
you could say
that would surprise us?
I killed the man
who killed my family.
Deakin knows.
He's using it against me
to get me off this case.
And don't ever follow me again!
I was just on my way up.
Unless this is a bad time.
What do you got?
I got a whole heap of lies.
I postponed a sit-down
with the Turkish defense
minister for this.
- I hope you have news.
- We do, sir.
- Good.
- Not for you.
- What's this?
- Phone records.
Do you recognize your number?
It seems that you
and CIA Officer
Mallory Madden
have been awfully chatty.
A fact that you both
have failed to mention.
About that two-way street.
Yeah, well,
Mallory came to me,
told me that Clark
had been nosing around
my old account.
Out of the goodness
of her heart, I'm sure.
She'd been demoted and needed
some new friends in high places,
and I wanted to know
what Clark was up to.
So I asked her to find out.
- At all costs?
- No.
I never asked her to kill Clark.
And when I found out
she had,
I came to you.
- Yeah, and you lied.
I withheld,
because it looked bad.
Still does.
- Where's Mallory now?
- I have no idea.
I gave her the
account records,
told her to keep digging,
and then nothing.
She must have found something
more valuable
than friends in high places.
- Such as?
- You tell me.
I was hoping NCIS had something
in the works.
- Hey, Gibbs.
- Yeah, Kase.
- I'm on my way down.
- What's that?
Something in the works.
So I dusted the image
for fingerprints,
and other than yours,
I found none.
- Totally clean.
- The bullets?
You did a great job of
digging them out of your truck.
They're all totally intact.
Also totally clean.
- Gotta have something here, Kase.
- Oh.
Well, that brings me back
to the photo.
You said it was clean.
There's normal forensics
scientist clean,
and then there's
Kasie Hines clean.
So this is the computer
program I ran after making
a super high-res scan.
If there is anything unusual,
this thing will find it.
It could find a flaw in Beyoncé.
- Did it?
- Beyoncé?
No. Photo, yes.
While there are no latent prints
on the image,
I found a partial print
in the image itself.
- In the ink.
- Somebody touched it?
Right after it was printed,
just before the ink dried.
Well, run it.
- I have been.
- Yeah? And?
Still running.
So, uh, this photo was
on your dashboard
while you were being shot at.
You want to tell me
who this man is?
The print, Kase.
Well, it's a partial print,
which greatly increases
the number of potential matches.
But the odds of getting
an immediate hit
on any print are--
Huh. I got a hit.
You got a name?
It belongs to CIA Officer
Mallory Madden.
- Isn't that...
- The director's ex-girlfriend.
Well, the director's
ex-girlfriend tried to kill you.
Mallory doesn't usually miss
her target.
Yeah, I've seen.
Then why are you
still breathing?
I got a lot of questions.
Like why is my ex
trying to kill you?
I'm not the one
who broke her heart.
I'm guessing
it was about money.
She's working
for Judge Deakin.
But how did
she find him?
Same way we did.
SecDef gave her
the account records.
The same records he gave us.
And she followed
those same breadcrumbs
all the way to Deakin? When?
- It doesn't matter.
Yeah, it does. It does to me.
We only need her
to get to Deakin.
Down in the basement, Gibbs,
was she telling the truth?
Did she know what was going on
the entire time?
Leon, you're asking
the wrong person.
Let's find her.
Thanks. Okay, FAA and TSA have
Mallory on a watch list.
Border checkpoints
are on high alert.
Still waiting on a list
of her known aliases.
CIA has me on hold, again.
And no activity
on her Internet accounts,
and her cell phone
is still turned off.
Yeah.
Great. Can you
send me those?
The aliases are on their way.
About time. Where are we?
Mallory's cell hasn't
been used in days.
The Agency hasn't heard from her
since she was cleared
in Clark's death.
Yeah, no hits
on the BOLO, either.
Mallory's a trained
CIA operative.
She knows how to disappear.
Well, she's not
going anywhere
until she finishes
her job.
By job, you mean...
Putting a bullet in my head.
Hey, boss,
I've got something here.
Mallory just turned on her
cell phone and her GPS tracker.
So either our
CIA operative is sloppy,
or it's a trap.
She's not sloppy. Where is she?
She's at your diner.
Hey. Come on, all of you.
Let's go.
That's good.
I like to leave room for cream.
Can I get you anything else?
No. Thank you.
Good coffee here.
Keep both hands
on the table.
I'm not here to fight.
I'm here to turn myself in.
Figured this was
as good a place as any.
Get up.
I screwed up.
Tell Leon
this was just business.
Tell him yourself.
After everything that's
happened with Leon, Clark, you,
this woman turns
herself in? Why?
Hoping to find out.
You think it's wise to send
a jilted lover into that room?
It's not my call.
Gibbs.
You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say can and
will be used against you
in a court of law.
I've been read my rights.
You have the right
to an attorney, and to have
an attorney present
for any questioning.
Leon, stop. What are you doing?
Doing my job.
Which is what you were doing
before you became
a gun for hire.
- I can explain.
- Please do.
Over the past few weeks,
I lost everything
that mattered to me.
My credibility, my job
and then you.
Clark's murder.
It really was self-defense.
Even your own investigation
says so.
But you knew about the account
and you knew about Judge Deakin.
- Yes.
- You lied to me.
You were working for Deakin.
Only after you said
we had no future,
which meant I needed
a way to start over.
As a hit man?
What the hell is wrong with you?
It was gonna be enough money
to leave the country
and put all of this behind me.
Do you know how crazy
that sounds?
I didn't at the time.
But once I learned
the target was Gibbs,
I couldn't go through with it.
Do you really think
I missed by accident?
I made a deal with Judge Deakin
to take Gibbs out,
so I had to make it
look believable.
Otherwise, I'd be the one
with a bullet in my head.
Ah, so you're the victim?
No.
But I did buy Gibbs some time.
And now I have
something else to offer.
Of course you do. There's
always an angle with you.
Okay. No more.
We're done.
Talk.
Judge Deakin.
He hired me personally,
and I'm willing to testify.
Oh, that's great. The word of
a lying, disgraced CIA officer
against that of a
respected federal judge.
You don't have to take
my word for it.
Then whose?
I heard you come in this time.
Welcome back, Gibbs.
Change your mind?
No.
What, then?
Come to kill me, too,
just like old Pedro?
No more games.
You want me dead?
Pick it up,
pull the trigger.
Take responsibility.
- You scratched the wood.
- Pick it up!
And give you a reason
to arrest me?
Is it even loaded?
I'm not gonna shoot you, Gibbs.
You may regret that.
What the hell are you doing?
You're under arrest.
Brought my team this time.
You're gonna put a man
like me in chains,
you better have
a damn good reason.
Oh, we do.
We got Mallory.
She had a lot to say.
Oh, what is this, Gibbs?
You think her word
carries any weight?
No.
But yours do.
What happened?
Why isn't Gibbs dead?
I need more time.
Maybe I need to hire
a better shot.
That recording
was illegally obtained.
Virginia is a one-party consent
state for recording.
You, of all people,
should know that.
You should also know
not to trust a spy.
Recognize this?
You should.
Mallory was wearing it
when you hired her.
She set me up.
Yeah, tell it to the judge.
Your challenge coin.
I had new ones made up
when I was appointed to the job
five years ago.
Highest rank gets
free drinks at the bar.
There's only one coin
higher than this.
I'm supposed to give them out
as a sign of respect
and admiration.
This is my first.
I don't know what to say.
You tracked the missing
funds to Judge Deakin.
Meaning NCIS has officially
saved my ass, again.
We just did our job, sir.
Anything you
need, Leon,
you call me.
- Sir, I...
- Leon.
Anything.
Thank you.
Director Vance.
Wow, nice.
That going on display?
No, that's going in my pocket
for a rainy day.
- Oh.
- What can I do for you, Jack?
How you doing, Leon?
- I'm good.
- Really?
Harpoons can leave
a hell of a scar.
Really.
Really? Good.
Anything else?
I saw that Mallory's plea deal
went through.
You didn't block it.
But I didn't endorse it, either.
Fair enough. Hey.
I know a few librarians,
if you're ever looking
to get back in the game.
Eventually.
Thanks, Jack.
That's great news.
I'll let them know.
Well, that was
the Justice Department.
Deakin's plea was enough to get
the other four judges arrested.
Judge Badass sang like a bird.
I know he's a murderer,
but does anyone else want to go
bowl a few games before
that place gets shut down?
I don't think
his restoration skills
are gonna translate
to cinder blocks so well.
So?
Right.
Anybody want to talk about it?
If Deakin had anything
concrete against Gibbs,
he would've used the actual
justice system, not his own.
Do you guys think that Gibbs
will want us to bring it up?
You know.
Pedro Hernandez.
Who's that?
♪ Oh, Father, tell me ♪
♪ We get what we deserve ♪
♪ Oh, we get what we deserve ♪
♪ And way down we go ♪
♪ Go, go, go, go ♪
♪ Way down we go ♪
♪ Go, go, go ♪
♪ Oh, you let
your feet run wild ♪
♪ Time has come as we all,
oh, go down ♪
♪ Yeah, but for the fall,
oh, my ♪
♪ Do you dare to look him right
in the eyes? ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Oh, baby, yeah ♪
♪﻿﻿﻿♪
♪ Way down we go ♪
♪ Go, go, go, go ♪
♪ Oh, way down we go ♪
♪ Oh-ho. ♪
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man