Ripped By >>SiMoN
I knew Harvey Dent, I was his friend.
And it will be a very long time before
someone inspires us the way he did.
I believed in Harvey Dent.
- Dr. Pavel, I'm CIA.
- He wasn't alone.
- You don't get to bring friends.
- They are not my friends.
- Don't worry, no charge for them.
- And why would I want them?
They were trying to up your price.
They work for the mercenary, a masked man.
Bane?
Get them on board. I'll call them in.
The flight plan I just
filed with the agency,
lists me, my man, Dr Pavel here
but only one of you.
The first one to talk gets
to stay on my aircraft.
Who paid you to get Dr. Pavel?
He didn't fly so good,
who wants to try next?
Tell me about Bane! Why
does he wear the mask?
A lot of loyalty for a hired gun!
Or perhaps he's wondering why
someone would shoot a man
before throwing him out of the plane.
At least you can talk. Who are you?
It doesn't matter who we are.
What matters is our plan.
No one cared who I was
til' I put on the mask.
- If I pull that off, will you die?
- It will be extremely painful...
- You're a big guy. -... For you.
Was getting caught part of your plan?
Of course.
Dr. Pavel refused that
offer in favour of yours.
But we have to find out what he told you.
Nothing! I said nothing!
Oh congratulations! You
got yourself caught!
Sir...
Now what's the next step
of your master plan?
Crashing this plane...
with no survivors.
Mayday! Mayday!
No!
They expect one of us in
the wreckage, brother.
- Have we started the fire?
- Yes. The fire rises.
Calm down, doctor. Now is
not the time for fear.
That comes later.
Harvey Dent's day may not be
our oldest public holiday,
but we're here tonight because
it's one the most important.
Harvey Dent's uncompromising
stand against organized crime,
has made Gotham a safer place than
it was at the time of his death,
eight years ago.
This city has seen a historic turn around
No city is without crime, but this city is
without organized crime because the
Dent act gave law enforcement teeth
in its fight against the Mafia.
Now people are talking about
repealing the Dent act
and to them I say: not on my watch.
I want to thank the Wayne
Foundation for hosting this event,
and I'm told Mr. Wayne
couldn't be here tonight,
but I'm sure that he's with us in spirit.
And now, I'm going to give
away to an important voice...
Who can lay eyes on Wayne
at one of these sorts?
No one has, not in years.
But people put their faith in a
murderous thug in a mask and a cape.
A thug who showed his true nature when
he betrayed the trust of this great
man and murdered him in cold blood.
Sweetheart, not so fast with the chow.
Shrimp balls?
Jim Gordon can tell you the
truth about Harvey Dent.
He get to... Well,
let him tell you himself.
Commissioner Gordon!
The truth...
I have... a speech telling
the truth about Harvey Dent.
Maybe the time isn't right.
Maybe right now...
All you need to know is that...
there are one thousand
inmates in Blackgate Prison
as a direct result of the Dent act.
These are violent criminals essential
thugs in the organized crime machine.
Maybe, for now what I should say about
the death of Harvey Dent is this...
It has not been for nothing.
Did you see the guy who owns the house?
No. You know, I heard he
never leaves the east wing.
You know, I heard he had an accident.
Yeah that he's disfigured...
Mr. Till! Why are your people
using the main staircase?
- And where is Mrs. Bolton?
- She's at the bar, sir. Can I help?
The eastern drawing room.
Unlock the door, put the tray on the table,
lock the door again.
Nothing more.
I'm sorry, Miss Tate. I
tried but he won't see you.
And you know, you mustn't
take it personally.
Everyone knows that Wayne
is hold up in there with
8 inch nails paving into mason jars
It's very good of you
to let me underground.
Why are you wasting your
time trying to talk
to a man who threw away your investment
on some save the world vanity project?
He can't get your money back, I can.
I could try explaining that
the save the world project,
vain or not, is worth
investing in, Mr. Daggett.
But you understand only money and
the power you think it buys.
So why waste my time, indeed?
Second shift report's in,
You should spend some
more time with the mayor.
Oh that's your department.
Anyone showed him the crime stats?
He goes by his gut,
and it continues to bother him
no matter what the numbers.
Must be popular with his wife.
Not really. She took the
kids and left for Cleveland.
We have plenty of time for visits.
The Mayor's gonna dump him in the spring.
Really? But he's a hero.
A war hero. This is peace time.
Sorry sorry.
I'm so terribly sorry, Mr. Wayne!
It is Mr. Wayne, isn't it?
Although you don't have long
nails or facial scars sir...
Is that what they say about me?
It's just that no one ever sees you.
That's a beautiful necklace!
Reminds me of one that
belonged to my mother.
It can't be the same one,
because her pearls are in the safe.
The manufacturer clearly explained
that it is uncrackable.
Oups. Nobody told me it was uncrackable.
I'm afraid I can't let you take those.
Look, you wouldn't beat up a woman,
anymore than I would beat up a cripple.
Of course, sometimes
exceptions have to be made.
Good night, Mr. Wayne!
- Can I have a ride?
- You read my mind!
Let's go!
Ms. Tate was asking to see you again.
- She's very persistent.
- And quite lovely,
- in case you were wondering.
- I wasn't.
- What are you doing?
- Examining print dust.
We've been robbed.
And this your idea of...
sounding the alarm, is it?
She took the pearls,
tracking device and all.
- She?
- One of the maids.
Perhaps you should stop letting
them in this part of the house.
Perhaps you should start
learning to make your own bed.
- Why were you dusting for prints?
- I wasn't. She was.
Sir! The congressman Gilly's
wife has been calling in
apparently the congressman never made
it home after the Wayne Foundation event.
That's a job for the police.
When you and Dent cleaned up the
streets, you cleaned them good.
Pretty soon we will be chasing
down over due library books.
And yet, here you are,
like we're still at war.
- What's your name, son?
- Blake, sir.
You have something you want
to ask me, officer Blake?
It's about that night, this night,
eight years ago, the night Dent died.
The last confirmed sighting of the Batman.
Who murders those people,
takes down two SWAT teams,
brakes Dent's neck and then just vanishes.
I'm not hearing the question.
Don't you want to know who he was?
I know exactly who he was.
He was the Batman.
Let's go see about the congressman's wife.
Master Wayne!
You haven't been down here in a long time.
I'm trying to find out more
about our jewel thief.
I ran her prints.
Unless she's lost a lot of weight,
she was wearing someone
else's fingerprints.
She's good.
She may be, but we have a
trace on the necklace.
We do, so I cross-referenced
the address she went back to,
with police data on I and B and Es,
and Selina Kyle.
Databases are full of close
calls and tips from fencers.
She's good, but the ground is
shrinking beneath her feet.
We should send the police
before she fences the pearls.
She won't. She likes them too much
and they weren't what she was after.
- What was she after?
- My fingerprints.
That was printer toner mixed
with graphite on the safe.
It gives you good pull
and it's untraceable.
Fascinating! You two should
exchange notes over coffee.
So now you're trying to set
me up with a jewel thief?
At this point, I'd set you
up with a chimpanzee,
if it brought you back to the world.
- There's nothing out there for me.
- And that's the problem.
You hung up your cape and your
cowl but you didn't move on.
You never went to find a life,
you'll find some how...
Alfred...
I did find someone.
I know, and you lost them but
that's all part of living sir.
But you're not living, you're just waiting,
hoping for things to go bad again.
Remember when you left Gotham?
Before all this, before Batman,
You've were gone seven years.
For seven years I've waited, hoping
that you wouldn't come back.
Every year, I took a holiday.
I went to Florence, this...
cafe on the banks of the Arno.
Every fine evening, I would sit
there and order a Fernet Branca.
I had this fantasy..
That I would look across the tables...
and I would see you there...
With a wife maybe a couple of kids.
You wouldn't say anything
to me, nor me to you.
But we would both know that you've
made it, that you were happy.
I never wanted you to come back to Gotham.
I always knew there was nothing
here for you except pain and tragedy
and I wanted something
more for you than that.
I still do.
I wash up here a couple of times a month
and more when it gets colder.
Homeless sheltering in the tunnels.
Now we pulled him from the basin but
other than that, we didn't touch him.
What?
His name is Jimmy. He's from St. Swithin's.
It's the boy's home reg.
We coached him some ball.
Jimmy had not been around for months.
- No, why?
- Blake, you know why.
He aged out.
We don't have the resources
to keep boys on after 16.
Yeah but I thought the Wayne
Foundation gave money for them.
Not for the past couple of years.
- He has a brother here, doesn't he?
- Mark. I'll tell him.
I'd like to. If that's alright.
You know what he was doing
down there in the tunnels?
A lot of guys would go in down in
the tunnels when they age out.
They say you can live down there.
They say there's work down there.
Work?
What kind of work you're
gonna find in the sewers?
More than you can find up here, I guess.
- So you know about him.
- Of course.
Do you think he's coming back?
I don't know...
You brought a date?
I like having someone around
to open doors for me.
Right hand, no partials.
Very nice!
Not so fast, handsome!
You've got something for me?
Oh yes.
I don't know what you're planning
to do with Mr. Wayne's prints,
but I'm guessing you'll need his thumb.
- You don't count so good huh?
- I count fine.
In fact, I'm counting to 10 right now.
Okay...
My friend's outside, just... hit send.
- This place is a little dim.
- It'll lighten up in a minute. Trust me.
Is everything okay?
Great. Catch you later.
It would have been a lot easier
to just give me what we agreed.
We can't have loose ends.
And even in that dress, no
one's going to miss you.
No, but my friend over there,
Every cop in the city is missing him.
That's cute! But they're not gonna
be looking in a place like this.
I don't know, you did
just use his cell phone.
Police! Get down now!
Help me!
Keep some pressure on that, sweetheart.
Call me?
- Careful, Miss.
- He's bleeding! You gotta help him!
I've got the congressman.
There!
The manhole! Get this out.
Get the GWPD down here!
You three, down with me!
You two, you go down, cover the next exit!
What? He went down there?
- We're gonna go down there, right?
- That was a gas explosion, kid.
What gas? It's a sewer.
No one goes in there until
we know what's down there.
We know who's down there sir,
the police commissioner.
Someone get this hot head out of here.
And where's that GWP guy?
Why are you here?
Answer him!
I was asking you.
It's a Police Commissioner.
- And you brought him down here?
- We didn't know what to do.
- We just thought...
- You panicked.
And your weakness just cost
the lives of three others.
No. He's a little...
Search him. Then I will kill you.
He's dead!
So show me his body!
The water runs to any one of the out flows.
We'll never find him.
- Follow him.
- Follow him?
Detective! Detective! Hey! Hey!
You awake?
I need to see Bruce Wayne.
I'm sorry, Mr. Wayne doesn't
take unscheduled calls,
even from a police officer.
If I go get a warrant for the
investigation of Harvey Dent's murder,
it'll still count as an unscheduled?
What can I do for you officer?
Commissioner Gordon has been shot.
He chased the gunmen down into the sewers.
When I pulled him out, he was
babbling about an underground army,
a masked man called Bane.
Well shouldn't you be telling your
superior officers about this?
They asked if he saw any giant alligators.
He needs you.
He needs the Batman.
Commissioner Gordon thinks...
Oh he doesn't know or care who you are.
But we've met before.
That was a long time ago, I
was a kid at St. Swithin's...
It used to be funded by
the Wayne Foundation.
It's an orphanage.
My mum died when I was small,
it was a car accident.
I don't remember it.
My dad got shot a couple of years later
for a gambling debt.
Oh I remember that one just fine.
Not a lot of people know what it feels
like to be angry in your bones.
I mean they understand.
The fosters parents.
Everybody understands...
for a while.
Then they want the angry little kid
to do something he knows he can't do
move on.
After a while they stop understanding.
They send the angry kid to a boy's home..
I figured it out too late.
Yeah I learned to hide the anger,
and practice smiling in the mirror.
It's like putting on a mask.
So you showed up this
one day, in a cool car,
pretty girl on your arm.
We were so excited! Bruce
Wayne, a billionaire orphan?
We used to make up stories
about you man, legends...
and you know with the other kids,
that's all it was, just stories, but...
Right when I saw you, I
knew who you really were.
I'd seen that look on your face before.
It's the same one I taught myself.
I don't why you took the
fault for Dent's murder
but I'm still a believer in the Batman.
Even if you're not...
Why did you say that your boy's home
used to be funded by The Wayne Foundation?
Because the money stopped.
Might be time to get some fresh air
and start paying attention to the details.
Some of those details might need your help.
Have you checked that name, Bane?
He's a mercenary. No, I have no names.
Him and his men man were
behind a coup in West Africa.
They secured mining operations
for our friend, John Daggett.
- And Daggett brought them here.
- So it seems.
- I'll keep digging.
- Yeah.
Alfred, why did the Wayne Foundation
stop funding boy's homes in the city?
The foundation is funded by the
profits of Wayne Enterprises.
There have to be some...
Time to talk to Mr. Fox I think.
I'll get him on the phone.
No, no, no. Do we still have
any cars around the place?
Yes, one or two.
I need an appointment at
a hospital for my leg.
- Which hospital?
- Which ever one Jim Gordon's in.
I have seen worst cartilage in knees.
- It's good.
- No.
That's because there's no
cartilage in your knees
and not much of any use in
your elbows or your shoulders.
Between that and the scar
tissue on your kidney,
residual concussive damage
to your brain tissue
and the general scared
over-quality of your body,
I cannot recommend that you
go heli-skiing, Mr. Wayne.
Right.
We used to be in this together.
They say you were gone.
The Batman wasn't needed anymore. We won...
How strong a lie.
Now this evil rises again
where we tried to bury him.
The Batman has to come back.
What if he doesn't exist anymore?
He must. You...
It's my goddamn wallet, is it?
- You took my wallet!
- No I didn't!
- Get out!
- She took my... Aow!
Now!
Crazy!
I don't know what he's so upset about.
There's only 60 bucks in here.
Care with the watch.
Who's that?
Another stiff, can barely
climb out of his sport car.
Well that's Bruce Wayne!
Mister Wayne, over here!
- I'm not sure if my assistant...
- Right through here, Mr. Wayne.
Thank you so much.
Bruce Wayne at a charity ball?
Ms. Tate, isn't it?
Even before you became a recluse,
you never came to these things
Proceeds go to big fat spread.
It is not about charity,
It's about feeding the ego which
ever society hag laid this on.
Actually this is my party, Mr. Wayne.
And the proceeds will go where they should,
because I paid for the
big fat spread myself.
It's very generous of you.
You have to invest if you want
to restore balance to the world.
Take our clean energy project.
Sometimes, the investment doesn't pay off.
I'm sorry.
You have a practiced apathy, Mr. Wayne.
But a man who doesn't care about the
world doesn't spend half his fortune
on a plan to save it.
And isn't so wounded when it
fails that he goes into hiding.
Have a good evening, Mr. Wayne!
Mind if I cut in?
Thank you.
You're don't seem happy to see me.
- You were supposed to be a shut-in.
- I felt like some fresh air.
Why didn't you call the police?
I have a powerful friend who
deals with things like these.
It's a brazing costume for a cat burglar.
- Yeah? Who are you pretending to be?
- Bruce Wayne, eccentric billionaire.
- Who's your date?
- His wife's in Ibiza.
She left her diamonds behind though,
worried it might get stolen.
It pronounced 'Ibitha'.
You wouldn't want any of these
folks realizing you're a crook,
not a social climber.
You think I care what anyone
in this room thinks of me?
I doubt you care what anyone
in any room thinks of you.
Don't condescend, Mr. Wayne. You
don't know a thing about me.
Well Selina Kyle.
I know you came here from
your woke-up and old Town,
a modest place for a master jewel thief.
Which means that either you're
saving for retirement or
you're in deep with the wrong people.
You don't get to judge me just because you
were born in the master
bedroom of Wayne...
Actually, I was born in the Regency room.
I started out doing what I had to.
Once you've done what you had to,
they never let you do what you want to.
Start fresh.
There's no fresh start in today's world.
Any 12 year-old with a cell phone
would find out what you did.
Everything we do is collated and
quantified, everything sticks.
Is that how you justify stealing?
I take what I need from those
who have more than enough.
I don't stand on the shoulders
of the people with less.
Robin Hood?
I think I do more to help someone
than most of the people in this room.
Thank you.
I think maybe you're
assuming a little too much.
Maybe you're being unrealistic about what's
really in your pants
other than your wallet.
Ouch.
You think all this can last?
There's a storm coming, Mr. Wayne.
You and your friends better
batten down the hatches,
because when it hits,
you're all going to wonder
how you ever thought you
could live so large
and leave so little for the rest of us.
You sound like you're
looking forward to it.
I'm adaptable.
Those pearls do look better on
you than they did in my safe,
but I still can't let you keep them.
You scared her off!
Not likely...
I still lost my ticket.
Your wife said you were taking a cab home.
My wife?
Just you, sir?
Don't worry, Master Wayne.
It takes a little time to get
back in the swing of things.
Bruce Wayne! Design, live and breathe
What brings you out of the
prior sleep, Mr. Wayne?
I see you haven't lost your sense of humor,
even if you have lost most of my money.
Actually you did that.
If you file your entire Rn'D budget
into a fusion project
that you get mock ball,
your company is unlikely to thrive.
What are my options?
Well if you're unwilling
to turn on the machine,
I can't. I can't, Lucius.
Well then sit tight.
Your majority keep Daggett at bay
while we figure out a future for the
energy program with Miranda Tate.
She has supported the project all the way.
She's smart and quite lovely.
We all just want what's
the best for you, Bruce.
- Show her the machine.
- I'll think it over.
- Anything else?
- Nope. Why?
Well these conversation used to
end with an unusual request.
I retired.
Well, let me show you some stuff, anyway.
Just for old times' sake.
I figured you had to shut this place down.
Oh, it was always shut down. Officially.
What's the new stuff...
After your father died, Wayne Enterprises
has set up 14 different
defense subsidiaries.
For years, I've been
shuttering and consolidating
all the different
prototypes under one roof.
- My roof.
- Why?
To keep them from falling
into the wrong hands.
Oh now you're just showing off.
Defense department project.
Tight Geometer Urban Pacification.
Rotors are configured to
maneuver between buildings
without recirculation.
What's it called?
It has a long uninteresting
Wayne Enterprise's designation.
I just the took to calling it the Bat.
And yes Mr. Wayne, it does come in black.
Works fine, apart the autopilot.
Takes a better mind than mine to fix it.
A better mind?
Well I was trying to be modest.
A less busy mind. Yours.
It should be a bit painful.
You'll be very welcome to try, Alfred.
Happy watching. Thank you, sir.
Not so bad...
Not bad at all!
If you're seriously considering
going back out there,
you should hear the
rumors surrounding Bane.
I'm all ears.
There is a prison in a more
ancient part of the world.
A pit where men are
thrown to suffer and die.
But sometimes a man rises
from the darkness.
Sometimes, the pit sends something back.
- Bane!
- Right.
Born and raised in hell on earth.
Born in a prison?
No one knows why or how he escaped.
But they do know that once he did, he was
trained by Ra's Al Ghul, your mentor.
Bane was a member of the League of Shadows.
And then he was excommunicated.
And any man who is too
extreme for Ra's Al Ghul,
is not to be trifled with.
I didn't realize I was known
for trifling with criminals.
That was then.
Then you can just strap up your
leg and put your mask back on,
but that doesn't make you what you were.
If this man is everything that you
say he is, then the city needs me.
The city needs Bruce Wayne,
your resources, your knowledge.
It doesn't need your body or your life.
That time is past.
You're afraid that if I go
back out there, I'll fail.
No.
I'm afraid that you want to.
You can't short the stock because
Bruce Wayne goes to a party.
Wayne coming back is change.
- Change, is it good or bad?
- Oh, bad.
- On what basis?
- I flip the coin.
I said no rye, man.
Rookie! Loose the helmet!
We need faces for camera.
Come on let's go scalping.
This is a stock exchange.
There's no money you can steal.
Really? Then why are you people here?
You've got to get in there!
- This is a hostage situation.
- No! No, no, this is a robbery!
They have direct access to
the online trading desk.
I'm not risking my men for your money.
Sir, we're gonna ask you to move.
We have a situation here.
It's not our money, it's everybody's.
Really? Mine is in my mattress.
If don't put these guys down,
that stuffing in your mattress might
be worth a whole hell of a lot less.
Cut the fiber cable and
take out that cell tower.
- Thank you.
- That will slow them down.
They cut the fiber.
- The cell's working.
- For now.
Get all this barriers up.
I want all of them up.
No one gets in or out of
any of these streets.
- Where am I suppose to move it?
- Back it up.
Just stay in your vehicle, okay?
How much longer does the program need?
Eight minutes.
Time to go. Move out.
Everybody up!
You two, move!
Thank you.
Steady!
I've got something!
Hold your fire! They have hostages!
Hold your fire!
Go! Go!
Please, let me go!
Please! Hey!
- Shoot the tires!
- There's no shot.
Now back off! Back off!
They've got hostages!
Police are pursuing the 4 suspects from
downtown in respond to a hostage situation
Gotham PD...
What's going on with the lights?
I can't pick up anything!
Who the hell was that?
Oh boy you are in for a show tonight, son!
Please! Help!
Sorry!
Put that thing away
before you hurt yourself.
Get in!
Let's go. You, get in the car!
We've spotted the Batman!
All everyone in.
Every car patrol, beat
cop and off duty too.
Call them in now!
I'm going to do what Jim
Gordon never could.
- What's that?
- I'm going to take down the Batman.
..The 4 suspect are carrying two hostages
that they kidnapped at the
Gotham Stock Exchange.
Witnesses reported that...
It seems hard to believe.
But report suspects are now being pursued,
what appears to be, the Batman.
Well what do you know..
Sir, what about the armed robbers?
Please! Let me go! Please!
One bike has pulled off.
No hostage. Shall we pursue?
Negative. Stay on the Batman!
- He's getting away.
- Who do you want to catch huh?
Some robber or the son-of-a-bitch
who killed Harvey Dent?
Eight years and he has to pick tonight.
He's drawing the cops off Bane.
Please! Let me go! Please!
TRANSFERRING COMPLETE
We lost him.
How could you lose him?
He's got a lot of firepower.
And what? Then you don't?
He heads back downtown.
Then he's as dumb as he dresses.
Close it up, gentlemen!
Like a rat in a trap, gentlemen!
You might have the wrong animal there, sir!
Sure it was him!
Bane says that Batman interfered,
but the task was accomplished.
And what about the men they've arrested?
He said and I quote: ' They
would die before talking. '
Where does he find these guys?
Open the champagne!
- And can we get some girls in here?
- Be careful what you wish for!
- The Cat got your tongue?
- You dumb bitch!
Nobody ever accused me of being dumb.
You're dumb, for coming here tonight.
I want what you owe me.
- One doesn't get...
- Nice outfit!
Those heels, they may be tough to walk?
I don't know, do you think?
- So where is it?
- Where's what?
The program ' The Clean Slate '.
The Ultimate Tool for a
master thief with a record.
Hold it right there!
- Where is it?!
- ' The Clean Slate? '
Where you type in someone's
name, date of birth
and in a few minutes they're gone
from every database on earth.
Sounds a little too good to be true?
You're lying! RIKEN DATA
took it to prototype stage.
That's why I bought them.
But they had nothing. It
was a gang-lying myth.
Stay back!
I'm not bluffing!
They know! They just don't care.
- You've got to be kidding me.
- No guns, no killing.
Where's the fun in that?
My mother warned me about getting
into cars with strange men.
This isn't a car.
See you around!
You're welcome!
- I had it under control.
- Those weren't street thugs.
They were trained killers.
I saved your life.
In return, I need to know what you
did with Bruce Wayne's fingerprints.
Wayne wasn't kidding
about a powerful friend.
I sold his prints to Daggett.
For something that doesn't even exist.
I doubt that it will get the better of you.
- Hey when a girl's desperate...
- What's he going to do with them?
I don't know but Daggett seemed pretty
interested in that mess
at the stock market.
Miss Kyle...
So that's what that feels like...
I've seen you in the television coverage,
and you've got your taste for
want and destruction back.
There are 3 disks.
Aren't the police supposed
to be investigating them?
They don't have the tools to analyze it.
They would if you gave them to them.
One man's tool is another man's weapon.
In your mind perhaps, well
there aren't many things you
can't turn into a weapon.
Alfred, enough! The police
weren't getting it done.
Perhaps they might have. If you
hadn't made a side show of yourself.
You thought I didn't have it in me.
You don't! You led a bluntly
police force, a merry chase
with a load of fancy new toys from Fox.
What about when you come up against him?
What then?
I'll fight harder. I always have.
Take a look, his speed, his
ferocity, his training.
I see the power of belief.
I see the League of Shadows resurgent.
- You said he was excommunicated.
- By Ra's Al Ghul.
Who leads them now?
Ra's Al Ghul was the League
of Shadows and I beat him.
Bane is just a mercenary. We need
to find out what he's up to.
Trades of some kind. Coded.
And my fingerprints
courtesy of Selina Kyle.
Give this to Fox.
He can crack the code
and tell us what trades
they were executing.
I'll give this to Mr. Fox but no more.
I've sewn you up, I've set your
bones, but I won't bury you.
I've buried enough members
in the Wayne family.
You leave me?
You seek only one end to your journey.
Leaving is all I have
to make you understand.
You're not Batman anymore. You
have to find another way.
You used to talk about finishing,
about a light beyond that awful cave.
Alfred, Rachel died knowing that
we had decided to be together.
That was my life, beyond the cave.
I can't just move on.
She... She didn't, she couldn't.
- What if she had?
- She didn't and I can't change that.
What if, before she died,
she wrote a letter
saying she chose Harvey Dent over you?
And what if, to spare you pain...
I burnt that letter ...?
How dare you use Rachel to try and stop me.
I am using the truth, Master Wayne.
Maybe it's time we all stop
trying to outsmart the truth
and let it have his day.
- I'm sorry.
- You're sorry?
You expect to destroy my world...
and then think that
we're gonna shake hands?
No.
- I know what this means.
- What does it mean?
It means you're hatred, and
it also means losing someone,
who I've cared for since I first heard
his cries echoing through this house.
But it might also mean saving your life.
And that is more important.
Goodbye, Alfred!
Alfred?
- Answering your own door?
- Yeah.
Page three.
Seems you made a series of laud to
put options on the future exchange.
Verified by thumb print.
Those options expired
at midnight last night.
Long term we may be able to
prove fraud but for now,
you're completely broke.
And Wayne Enterprises is about to
fall into the hands of John Daggett.
The weapons...
We can't let Daggett get his
hands on Applied Sciences.
Applied Sciences is all
locked up and off the books.
The energy project however,
it's a different story.
Miranda Tate...
We need to convince the
board to get behind her.
Let's show her the reactor.
We're meeting her there in 35 minutes
so you'd better get dressed.
You brought me out here
to show me this, Mr. Fox?
Bear with me, Miss Tate.
Please keep hands and feet
inside the car at all time.
This is it, isn't it?
The reactor is beneath the river
So it can be instantly flooded in
the event of a security breach.
Is Bruce Wayne really that paranoid?
You want to beat the freak out on that one.
I thought you might like to see
what your investment built.
No fossil fuels, free clean
energy for an entire city!
Three years ago, a Russian
scientist published
a paper on weaponized fusion reactions.
One week later, your reactor
started developing problems.
I think this machine works.
Miranda, if it were operational,
danger to Gotham would be too great.
Would it make you feel better
to know that the Russian
scientist died in a plane
crash six months ago?
Someone will work out what Dr. Pavel
has almost figured out, a way to make
this power source into a nuclear weapon.
I need you to take control of Wayne
Enterprises and this reactor.
- To do what with it?
- Nothing.
- Until we can guarantee its safety.
- And if we can't?
Decommission it, flood it.
Destroy the world's best chance
for a sustainable future?
If the world is not ready, yes.
Bruce, if you want to save the world,
you have to start trusting it.
I'm trusting you.
It doesn't count. You have no choice.
I could have flooded this chamber at
any time in the last three years.
I am choosing to trust you. Please...
Alright ladies and gentlemen, this
meeting will now come to order.
Now, I'd like to point out that
we have a non-board member here.
There is highly irregular, even if
his family name is above the door.
Bruce Wayne's family built this company.
- And he himself has run it...
- Into the ground, sir!
Does anybody disagree?
Then check the share price this morning.
Crazy gambling on future, this does
not only cost Mr. Wayne his seat,
it has cost us all a lot
of money and he has to go.
I'm afraid he has a point, Mr. Wayne.
Now back to business.
How does it feel to be one
of the people, Wayne?
Mr. Wayne, they're towing your car.
I didn't know that you were at the
board, I didn't know what to say.
Looks like you need a ride huh?
How the hell did Miranda Tate get the
inside track on the Wayne Board?
I mean, has she been meeting with him?
Has she been sleeping with him?
Not that we know of.
Oh clearly, you don't know much of
anything, do you? Where is Bane?
- Well, we told him it was urgent.
- Oh, where is that man...
Speak of the devil, and he shall appear.
What the hell is going on?
The plan is preceding as expected.
Really? Do I look like I'm running
Wayne Enterprises right now?
Your hit on the stock exchange,
it didn't work my friend.
And now you have my construction crews
going around the city at 24 hours a day.
How exactly is that supposed to
help my company absorb Wayne's?
- Leave us!
- No! You stay here!
I'm in charge.
Do you feel in charge?
I have paid you a small fortune.
And this gives you power over me?
What is this?
Your money and infrastructure
have been important...
until now.
- What are you?
- I'm Gotham's reckoning.
It'll end the ball of damns
you've all been living on.
You are pure evil.
- A necessary evil.
- No!
Well you've started quite a mess.
To protect the people closest to me.
Yeah but you're a loner, right?
You don't have any family.
There are always people you care about.
You don't realize how
much until they're gone.
The idea was to be a symbol.
Batman can be anybody. That was the point.
- That was damn good to see him back.
- Not everybody agrees.
I'll figure that out in the end.
Have you got anything
on Bane's whereabouts?
Yeah, I've got 500 pages of
tunnel records and a flashlight.
I could use some help actually.
You know what, drop me in the old town.
- Hey, hey, hey, I don't think so!
- I don't think it works, hey!
He's not a mark.
And he doesn't have a
cent to his name anyway.
Yeah. It's not much, but it's
more than you've got right now.
Actually, they're letting
me keep the house.
The riches don't even go broke
like the rest of us huh?
My powerful friend might hope to
change your mind about leaving.
- And how would he do that?
- By giving you what you want.
- It doesn't exist.
- He says it does.
- He wants to meet tonight.
- Why?
He needs to find Bane.
He says you know how.
- Tell him I'll think about it.
- Okay. I like your place.
Mr. Wayne.
I'm sorry they took all your money.
No you're not.
- Can we help you officer?
- Yeah.
John Daggett's body was just
found in a dumpster an hour ago.
Thought you might wanna know.
Why?
Well his name is all over
these permits I just
pulled to half the tunnels under Gotham.
That's MTA maintenance, sewer
construction and others things...
Where did you get to with
the tunnel searches?
Remind me to tell detail
to keep hot heads out.
We've had teams down there.
It's a huge network.
Well, get more men.
Work the grid. I want him found.
Yeah, the masked man. We're on it.
Lose the uniform. You're
working for me now.
We could some hot heads around here.
Sir, Daggett's death could
only be a coincidence.
You're a detective now, son.
You're not allowed to believe
in coincidence anymore.
- Nobody's answering.
- No...
- I'm on my own now.
- Do you have keys?
I wouldn't even know.
I hope you didn't like me for my money.
Suffering this character.
I'll take care of your
parents legacy, Bruce.
Who's this?
Where is Alfred?
He left.
Taking everything...
- What's that?
- Hmm well, power has been shut off.
You're good at that.
When I was a child, we had almost nothing.
But on the nights when we had a
fire, we felt very rich indeed...
I assumed your family was wealthy.
Not always, not when I was young.
- An old mistake.
- I had a few myself.
More than a few.
We could leave tonight.
Take my plane and go anywhere we wanted.
Some day perhaps. Not tonight.
Don't be shy!
Wayne says you can get
me the 'Clean Slate'.
- That depends...
- On what?
On what you want it for..
I've acquired it to keep
it out of the wrong hands.
Still don't trust me huh...
- How can we change that?
- Start by taking me to Bane.
You asked...
From here, Bane's men patrol the tunnels
and they're not your average brawlers.
Neither am I.
- He's behind you!
- Who?
Me!
Where do you think you're...
Just a little forward.
I had to find a way to stop
them trying to kill me.
You made a serious mistake.
Not as serious as yours...
I fear.
- Bane...
- Let's not stand on so moody here.
Mr. Wayne...
Peace has cost you your strength.
Victory has defeated you.
Theatricality and deception...
powerful agents to the uninitiated.
But we are initiated aren't we, Bruce?
Members of the League of Shadows.
And you betrayed us.
Yes. You were excommunicated
by a gang of psychopaths.
I am the League of Shadows.
I'm here to fulfill Ra's Al Ghul's destiny!
You fight like a younger man,
there's nothing held back.
It's admirable, but mistaken.
Ooh, you think darkness is your ally?
You merely adopted the
dark, I was born in it.
Molded by it...
I didn't see the light
until I was already a man.
By then there was nothing
to be but blinded.
Shadows betray you because
they belong to me!
I will show you where I have made my home.
Whilst preparing to bring justice.
Then I will break you.
Your precious armory! Gratefully accepted.
We will need it.
Ah yes! I was wondering
what would weight first...
Your spirit...
or your body?
Get me Commissioner Gordon.
I've got a line on the
congressman's kidnapping.
- Excuse me, miss!
- Yes?
I'm gonna need to see your ticket
and identification, please.
Do you mind?
I showed your picture to the congressman.
Guess what?!
- Don't tell me. Still in love?
- Oh head over heels.
Pressing charges though.
You've made some mistakes, Miss Kyle.
- Girls got to eat.
- And you have an appetite.
Why would run? You can't hide
from us with a record like this.
- Maybe it's not you I'm running from.
- Who then? Bane?
What do you know about him?
About you should be as
afraid of him as I am.
We can offer you protection.
Okay...
When I spotted you, I was looking
for a friend of mine, Bruce Wayne.
Did they kill him?
I'm not sure.
Why didn't you just... kill me?
You don't fear death, you welcome it.
Your punishment must be mastered here.
- You're a torturer?
- Yes.
But not of your body.
Of your soul.
- Where am I?
- Home.
Where I learned the truth
about despair, as will you.
There's a reason why this prison
used to were as hell on earth.
Hope.
Every man who has lotted here over the
centuries, has looked up to the light
and imagined climbing to freedom.
So easy, so simple!
And like shipwrecked men turning to
seawater foregoing uncontrollable thirst,
many have died trying.
And then here there can be no
true despair without hope.
So as I terrorize Gotham,
I will feed its people hope
to poison their souls.
I will let them believe
that they can survive
so that you can watch them
climbing over each other
to stay in the sun.
You can watch me torture an entire city.
And then when you've truly understood
the depth of your failure,
we will fulfill Ra's Al Ghul's destiny.
We will destroy Gotham.
And then, when that is done,
and Gotham is... ashes
Then you have my permission to die.
You're locking her up in here?
The Dent act allows non-segregation
based on extraordinary needs.
First time she broke out of
women's correctional, she was 16.
- Yeah, a little closer!
- Why honey? You want to hold my hand?
She's gonna be fine.
I still don't see the need of a board
meeting for the energy project.
Bruce got a lot of things right,
keeping the board in the
dark was not one of them.
How good of you to join us Chair President.
All I need now is one more
ordinary Board member.
- Mr. Fox, would you like to nominate?
- No. I will volunteer.
Where are you taking us?
You were right, Commissioner!
Would you excuse us, please?
What happened?
Your mask man kidnapped the
Wayne Enterprise's board.
He let most of them go, but he took
three of them into the sewers.
No more patrols. No more hide and seek.
Get every available cop down
there and smoke him out.
- The Mayor won't want panic.
- So it's a training exercise?
I'm sorry I didn't take you seriously.
Not you, you're telling
me the Batman has gone.
So you chase up the Daggett
leads anyway you can.
Yes, sir.
He asks how much you would
pay us to let you die?
I told him... I told him you have nothing.
You tell your friend it's a pleasure!
They pay more than that to keep you alive.
He will try to climb.
Is there any way everybody head?
Well of course not!
He says there is one who did.
A child.
A child born in this hell.
- Bane...
- An old legend. Nothing more.
Whatever it is they want you
to see, it is happening soon.
Fire in the hole!
Turn it on!
I only need one other Board member,
there are eight others waiting.
I won't do it.
Alright stop!
Lucius, you will kill
this man and yourself,
and you'll barely slow them down.
Go on then, do your work!
Take them up to the surface!
People of their status
deserve to experience
the next era of Western civilization.
I've been at half of Daggett
cement plants logged
locations they pour for
underground construction.
Anything strange about the pourings?
Honestly, Commissioner. I don't know
anything about civil engineering.
But you know about patterns. Keep looking!
It's done. This is now a
4 megatons nuclear bomb!
Pull the core out of the reactor!
No! You cannot!
This is the only power source
capable of sustaining it.
If you move it, the core will
decay in a matter of months.
- Five, by my calculations.
- It will go off!
And for the sake of your children
Dr. Pavel, Indeed I hope it does.
Hey, hey!
That was you in front of the
Stock Exchange wasn't it?
When?
When half the city's cops try
to pull onto Castle street
and your truck was shutting them out.
- Oh yeah... you're the cop.
- Detective now.
And, as detective we're not allowed
to believe in coincidences.
What were you doing here?
What are you working on?
Commissioner, it's Blake. I've got two
dead witnesses and a lot of questions.
Call me when...
Wait a minute! Four barrels
of poly-isobutilene.
That looks like motor oil
right next to it. Jesus!
They're not making cement,
they're making explosives!
- Pass me to Foley!
- Foley is overseeing the operation.
They're heading into a trap.
We're seeing literally thousands
of police heading into the sewer.
Mr. Mayor, literally thousands of police...
It's just a training exercise, that's all.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I've got tickets to watch
our boys trash Rapid City.
Foley.
It's a trap. Pull all of them out!
Bane has been pouring concrete
rings with explosives.
Where?
There's a ring around the tunnels!
They're gonna blow it and
trap the cops underground!
Pull them out. Pull them out! Now!
That's a lovely lovely voice!
Let the games begin!
Citizens, take control...
Take control of your city!
- Foley!
- Jesus, Blake!
Every cop in the city is
down in those tunnels!
Not every cop.
Sir, you're okay? I'm a police
officer, I need your car right now.
Play the corners, rookie!
Get the coat, son!
This, this is the instrument
of your liberation.
Satellite shows a radiation spike.
Whatever it is, it's nuclear.
Identify yourself to the world!
Dr. Leonid Pavel, nuclear physicist.
Pavel was confirmed dead, plane crash on an
agency pull out of Uzbekistan
but it looks like it's him.
And what, what is this?
It's a fully prime neutron bomb
with a blast radius of 6 miles.
And who is capable of
disarming such a device?
Only me.
Only you... Thank you, good doctor!
Now, this bomb is armed.
This bomb is mobile and the identity
of the trigger man is a mystery.
For one of you holds the detonator.
Now we came here not as
conquerors, but as liberators
to return control of
this city to the people.
And at the first sight of
interference from the outside world,
or from those people attempting to flee,
this anonymous Gotham-might,
this unsung hero will trigger the bomb.
But now, martial law is in effect.
Return to your homes,
hold your families closed and wait.
Tomorrow you claim what
is rightfully yours.
Go back the fighters! Start high
level reconnaissance flights.
Get the president on the line!
Tanks and planes cannot stop
us from detonating our device.
Send a negotiator to discuss terms
of access for supplies and communication!
How many of you are there, son?
You don't have enough men to stop
12 million people leaving this island.
No, no we don't. But you do.
And why the hell would I try to
help you keep your hostages?
If one person crosses this bridge,
Gotham gets blown to hell.
The people of our greatest
city are resilient
They have proven this before
and they will prove it again.
We do not negotiate with terrorists,
But we do recognize realities.
As this situation develops, one thing
must be understood above all others.
People of Gotham, we
have not abandoned you.
What does that mean?
It means we're on our own.
I have to get in front of a camera.
Well sir, they will kill you
the second you show your face.
Bane says he's giving
Gotham back to the people.
They need to know I could lead.
Bane is not going to let that happen.
- Then he'll show his true colors
- And you'll be dead.
Behind you, stands a symbol of oppression.
Blackgate Prison, where a thousand men have
languished under the name of this man:
Harvey Dent.
Who has been held up to you as
the shinning example of justice.
We'll just keep moving you until
we get you in front of a camera.
You have been supplied with a false idol,
to stop you tearing down this corrupt city!
Let me tell you the truth
about Harvey Dent!
From the words of Gotham's
Police Commissioner,
James Gordon.
' The Batman didn't murder
Harvey Dent, he saved my boy. '
' Then took the blame for
Harvey's appalling crimes, '
' So that I could, to my shame, '
' build a lie around this fallen idol. '
' I praise the mad man who tried
to murder my own child, '
' but I can no longer live with my lie. '
' It is time to trust the people
of Gotham with the truth '
' And it is time for me to resign. '
And do you accept this man's resignation?
And do you accept the
resignation of all these liars,
of all the corrupt?
Those men locked up for 8
years at Blackgate with
denied parole under the Dent
act, it was based on a lie?
Gotham needed a hero.
It needs it now more than ever. You
betrayed everything you stood for.
There's a point,
far out there when the structures fail you,
and when the rules aren't weapons
anymore with you... you shackle those,
letting the bad guy getting in.
One day, you may face
such a moment of crisis
and in that moment I hope you
have a friend like I did!
To plunge their hands into the filth
so that you can keep yours clean.
Your hands look pretty
filthy to me, Commissioner.
We take Gotham from the corrupt.
The rich.
The oppressors who for generation have
kept you down with myths of opportunity,
and we give it back to you, the people.
Gotham is yours. None shall interfere.
Do as you please,
and start by storming Blackgate
and freeing the oppressed!
Step forward those who would serve.
To an army, a world will be raised.
The powerful will be ripped
from their decadent years...
and cast out into the cold
world that we know and endure.
Courts will be convened.
Spoils will be enjoyed.
Blood will be shed.
The Police will survive
as they learn to serve true justice...
This great city...
it will endure ...!
Gotham will survive!
He says you must first fix your back.
How does he know?
He was the prison doctor.
A morphine addict,
who incurred this pleasure
of powerful people,
including your mask friend.
How?
Many years ago, it was a time of plague.
Some of the other prisoners attacked Bane.
The doctors humbling attempts
to repair the damage
left him in perpetual agony.
The Mask holds the pain at bay.
Bane was the child who struck out?
He was born here?
Legend is that there was a mercenary
who worked for a local warlord.
He fell in love with the
warlord's daughter.
They were married in secret,
but the warlord found out.
The mercenary was condemned to this pit.
But then he exiled him instead.
The mess, I understood, that was the
daughter that secured his release.
But what he could not know, was
the true price of his freedom.
She took his place in the pit.
And she was with a child,
the mercenary child.
Innocence cannot flower underground,
it has to be stemmed out...
One day, the doctor
forgot to lock the cell.
But the child had a friend, a protector.
Who showed the others that this
innocence was their redemption.
It was to be priced.
The mother was not so lucky.
This is Bane's prison now. It
wouldn't want this story told.
There's a vertebra
protruding from your back.
It has to be put back.
Stay like this until you stand.
Could you not think I would return, Bruce?
I told you I was immortal.
I watched you die!
Oh there are many forms of immortality.
Once I had a wife. My great love.
She was taken from me.
You were the mercenary.
Bane is your child, your heir.
I'm here to ensure the League of Shadow
fulfills its duty to restore
balance to civilization.
You yourself fought the
decadence of Gotham for years
with all your strength, all your resources,
all your moral authority.
And the only victory you
achieved was a lie.
Now, you understand?
Gotham is beyond saving
and must be allowed to die.
No!
- What's that?
- This was someone's home.
Now, it's everyone's home.
There's storm coming remember?
That is what we wanted.
It's for the bus, in case
there's a chance to evacuate.
- Any news from the commissioner?
- The less you know father..
How are the boys doing?
Well we had more power
on, so they get some TV.
- It's good to see you father.
- Blake, you be careful out there.
They're hunting down cops like dogs.
- Why build yourself?
- I'm not meant to die in here.
Here or there, what's the difference?
I told you it could not be done.
You told me a child did it.
But no ordinary child,
a child born in hell,
forged from suffering,
hardened by pain.
Not a man from privilege.
We got blues in the ground sir.
Just waiting on intel.
- Do you have ID?
- Of course not.
- How can we trust you?
- You don't have any choice.
Commissioner Gordon. Captain
Jones, Special Forces.
- Captain, glad to have you here.
- It's our job sir.
Now how many are there?
Well there's dozens, I'd
rather not say exactly.
But the men trapped underground,
number almost 3,000.
- What kind of condition are they in?
- They've been getting food and water.
- Can we break them out?
- Yes, sir.
Take out the mercenaries guarding the
outflows south of Ackerman Park,
blow the rubble, we can make a
hole big enough for 10 at a time.
Now I'm in contact with my
partner who is down there.
They're just waiting for the day.
Commander, they haven't seen
daylight for three months.
Police officers who haven't
seen daylight in three months.
What about the bomb?
The satellite can't pick up
any radiation hot spots.
How they keep it on a truck? It
must have a lead lined roof.
- They're moving constantly.
- Good, so you know the truck?
Well it's one of those three,
we've been tracking it.
Decoy.
You don't really think
he's coming back, do you?
Doesn't matter what I think.
Actually it does. You should put your faith
in something a little more more real.
But the routes don't vary much.
- Ok. What about the trigger man?
- No leads. It's a bluff.
Bane wouldn't give control of
that bomb to someone else.
We can't take that chance.
Until we have the trigger man,
we just track the device.
And mean while, Gotham
lives under a warlord?
Like some failed state?
Dial it back, officer. The
situation is unprecedented.
We can't do anything to
risk millions of lives.
Can you tell them? Aren't you going to
tell them what is actually going on?
Captain, the situation is more
complicated than you think.
There's someone you need to meet.
I came up stairs looking
for a vantage point.
Found the people who run the
corporation living up here.
What corporation?
Wayne Enterprises.
Mr. Fox would you like
to brief the captain?
Now Ms. Tate is fully
aware of the situation.
As the CEO of Wayne Enterprises, I
have to take responsibility for it.
- Why?
- We built it.
You built the bomb?
It was build as a fusion reactor.
First of its kind
Bane turned the core into a bomb,
and removed it from the reactor.
That is the important part.
As the device's fuel cells deteriorates,
it becomes increasingly unstable
to the point of detonation.
- This bomb is a time bomb.
- And it will go off in 23 days.
Regardless of Bane's revolution or what we
and the outside world choose to do.
So your peace-man plan may not
be as practical as you thought.
Could you disarm it?
I could reconnect it to the
reactor to stabilize it.
Let's move away from this
location and call it in.
Alright let's go!
No, I'll take it from here. You
stay and look after these folks.
Someone sold us out.
I'd die before I talk.
How about a new schedule, Captain.
- There were people living upstairs.
- Round them up for judgment.
And hang them where the world can see.
He says the leap of freedom
is not about strength.
- My body makes the jump.
- Surviving is spirit. The soul.
My soul is as ready to escape as my body.
Fear is why you're afraid?
No, I'm not afraid.
I'm angry.
Bruce...
Why do we fall?
You do not fear death. You think this
makes you strong? It makes you weak.
Why?
How can you move faster than possible,
fight longer than possible,
without the most powerful
impulse of the spirit?
The fear of death.
I did fear death.
I fear dying in here, all my city burns,
there's no one there to save it.
Then make the climb!
How?
As the child did.
Without the rope.
That fear will fright you again.
Ah surprise for your journey,
oh that's wonderful, that's...
- What does that mean?
- Rise.
No.
There's been a mistake. Take me to Bane!
I want Mr. Bane.
Where is Bane?
There's been no mistake Mr. Stryver.
You are Philip Stryver.
Executive Vice President
of Daggett Industries?
Who for years has been living off the blood
and sweat of people less powerful than him!
Call Bane! I am one of you.
Bane has no authority here. This
is merely a sentencing hearing.
Now choice is yours: exile or death?
- Exile.
- Sold!
The man in the cold sweat.
You follow the thick ice. If you try
to swim, you're dead in minutes.
So no one made it?
Where the hell are they?
It's not like we have a lot of time here.
- How long?
- The bomb goes off tomorrow.
We have about 18 hours to do something.
To do what?
To mark the truck. Get a GPS on it,
so we can start to figure
out how to bring it down.
That's it.
Foley!
Where is Foley? Damn it!
You shouldn't be out in the streets.
Jim, he's not here.
You let your wife come to the door,
when the city is under occupation?
What did you do? Bury your
uniform in the backyard?
You saw what they did
to the special forces.
Have you forgotten all the
years we were out on patrol?
When every gang banger wanted to plant
one as soon as our backs were turned?
Now is different and you know it.
This guys run the city.
The government has done a deal with them.
Bane's got their balls in a
vice, that's not a deal.
If you move on Bane, the trigger-man
is going to hit the button.
Do you think he's given control of
that bomb to one of the people?
You think this apart of some revolution?
There's only one man with his
finger on the button, that's Bane.
Look, we've all got to keep our
heads down until they can fix this.
If you had family here...
It'll only get fixed from inside the city.
Look Peter, I'm not asking you to
walk down grand in you dress rules,
but something has to be done.
- I'm sorry, Jim. I gotta...
- Keep your head down?
What good that's going to do
tomorrow when that thing blows.
You don't know that's gonna happen.
I hear you're looking for men Commissioner?
How about me instead?
- Miss Tate, I can't ask to do that.
- Please.
- What did you take?
- Nothing.
I didn't take anything.
You steal from us? You little bastard.
Now you boys know you can't come in my
neighborhood without asking politely.
Never steal anything from
someone you can't outrun, kid!
You're pretty generous for a thief!
- I thought they killed you.
- Not yet.
- If you're expecting an apology...
- It wouldn't suit you.
I need your help.
- And why would I help you?
- For this. ' Clean Slate '.
You trust me with that,
after what I did to you?
I admit I was a little let down.
But I still think there's more to you.
In fact, I think that for
you, this isn't just a tool.
It's an escape, right, you want
to disappear, start fresh.
I can't even get off this island.
I could give you a way off once
you to get me to Lucius Fox.
I need you to find out where they're
holding him and take me in.
- Why do you need Fox?
- To save the city.
Who says it needs saving?
Maybe I like it this way.
Maybe you do.
But tomorrow that bomb is going off.
Get your powerful friend on the case?
I'm trying, but I need Fox.
Once it approaches, flick the switch.
The needle hits 200, you
give me the signal.
I'll will mark truck. Okay?
Heads up! Heads up!
- I got it!
- Mercenaries at your 6.
Stand still! Keep your hands
where we can see them!
Commissioner Gordon, you're under arrest.
On who's authority?
People of Gotham.
No lawyer. No witnesses. What
sort of due process is this?
You guilt have been determined. This
is merely a sentencing hearing.
Now what will it be?
Death or exile?
Crane, if you think we're going
out on to that ice willingly,
you have another think coming.
- Death then.
- Looks that way.
Very well. Death!
By exile.
Bring her to me!
Hey. Going down. Get things ready.
Let's gear on.
Spot this one on the spot.
Got a big day tomorrow.
We all do. Not every day
you bag Bruce Wayne!
- Bruce?
- You okay?
You pick the hell of time to
go on vacation, Mr. Wayne.
How long until that core ignites?
That bomb goes off in 12 hours.
Unless we can reconnect it to the reactor.
- Can you get Miranda out of here?
- Not tonight. I'm sorry.
- Do what's necessary.
- Tonight I need you.
- What for?
- To get me back in the game.
Sorry to spoil things boys but
they want these guys to himself.
- I won't forget about you, Miranda!
- I know.
- I like your girlfriend, Mr. Wayne!
- He should be so lucky.
Any move I make on Bane or the
bomb, the trigger-man sets it off.
But they won't use radio or
cell, too much interference.
Infrared doesn't have the range.
It'll have to be a micro burst, long-range.
- Could you block it?
- Yes.
But I need the EMP canon
guidance mounted on the Bat.
Remember where you're parked?
- Does it fly okay?
- Yeah.
Even without the autopilot. Thanks.
Autopilot? That's what you're there for.
Thing's clear. Come on, quick! No time.
Lock it up!
Who are you?
Light it up!
Mom check it out.
Honey, take a look!
Impossible!
Keep her close! He'll come for her.
- Where's Miranda Tate?
- Bane took her.
He's hold up at city hall,
surrounded by his army.
This blocks servo-detonator
signal to the bomb.
Get it on to it before sunrise.
If I hit the button when it starts.
- When what starts?
- War.
You missed this spy.
If you're working alone, wear a mask!
I'm not afraid of being seen
standing up against these guys.
The mask is not for you, it's to
protect the people you care about.
Count to five and throw.
Hey no offense, but you got
something bigger in that belt?
- What now?
- All out assault on Bane.
But you need to get
people across the bridge.
Why?
In case we fail. Leave an exodus.
Save as many lives as you can.
- You don't need me here?
- You've given me an army. Now, go!
- Hey, thanks!
- Don't thank me yet.
Well I might not get the chance later.
You shouldn't have.
The main town tunnel is blocked by debris.
But the canon have enough fire
power to make a path for people.
Wait until the fighting begins!
You're gonna wage your word to
save your stuck up girlfriend?
To start it, throttle.
I got it.
We have 45 minutes to save the city.
No. I've got 45 minutes to get
clear of the blast radius.
Because you don't stand a
chance against these guys.
With your help, I might.
I'll open that tunnel, but then I'm gone.
There's more to you than that.
Sorry to keep letting you down.
Come with me! Save yourself!
You don't owe these people anymore.
You've given them everything.
Not everything. Not yet.
Disperse! Disperse or be fired upon!
There's only one police in this town,
Open fire!
- Here it comes.
- Get ready!
So you came back to die with your city!
No. I came back to stop you.
Now!
That's impossible.
Come over the fifth!
Oh, hang up. Get on the bus, go ahead.
You come with me! You too!
Hey you, you and you, come here!
Everyone else get on the bus! Okay.
You guys, you're going to knock on
doors and spread the word okay.
The bomb is gonna go off. Then get
out by the south Street tunnel,
or over the bridge.
You go, you do two blocks, you get
back to the bus. Alright? Go! Go!
- Is he back?
- Keep your eyes open. Go!
Cover the doors!
Where's your trigger? Where is it?
You never gave it to any ordinary citizen.
Where is it? Where's the trigger?
Where is it?
Tell me where the trigger is.
Then, you have my permission to die.
I broke you. How did you come back?
You think you're the only one who
could learn the strength to escape?
- Where's the trigger?
- But I never escaped.
But the child,
the child of Ra's Al Ghul's,
who made the climb.
But he's not the child of Ra's Al Ghul.
I am.
Although I'm not ordinary, I'm a citizen.
Miranda?
Why?
Thalia. My mother named me
Thalia before she was killed.
The way I would have been killed
if not for my protector, Bane.
Good bye.
I climbed out of the pit.
I found my father
and brought him back to
exact terrible vengeance.
But by that time,
the prisoners and the doctor
had their work to my friend,
my protector.
The League took us in and trained us
but my father could not accept Bane.
He saw only a monster, whose very existence
was the reminder of the hell
he'd left his wife to die in.
He excommunicated Bane from
the League of Shadows.
His only crime was that he loved me.
I could not forgive my father,
until you murdered him.
He was trying to kill
millions of innocent people.
Innocence is a strong word to
throw around Gotham, Bruce.
I honor my father by finishing his work.
Vengeance against the man who killed
him is simply a reward for my patience.
You see?
It's the slow knife. The
knife that takes its time.
The knife that waits
years, without forgetting,
then slips quietly between the bones,
that's the knife that cuts the deepest.
Please!
Maybe that knife was too slow.
The truck is under attacked.
Gordon. You gave him a
way to block my signal
No matter.
He's bought Gotham 11 minutes.
Come on!
Stay back! What are you doing?
Wait. MCU, I'm getting
these boys to safety.
You're going to get us all killed.
Anyone crosses this bridge,
they'll blow up the city.
It's gonna blow anyway. We
need to open this bridge, now!
Detective, if you take one step
forward, we will shoot you!
If you take two steps forward,
we will blow the bridge.
Ok go back by the bus and wait for me alright!
Just go back and wait.
Prepare a convoy.
We must secure the bomb until it detonates!
Don't kill him. I want
him to feel the heat.
Feel the fire of 12 million souls.
You failed!
Good bye, my friend!
Keep moving forward!
Plague them in the stairs!
Shoot them!
Shoot them all!
We both know that I have to kill you now.
You'll just have to imagine the fire.
About the whole no guns thing,
I'm not sure I feel as
strongly about it as you do.
Pull up!
Stay level.
We have to force the convoyees
to the entrance of the reactor.
I need you underground.
I'll be in the air. Go!
The situation has changed!
Your orders are out of date.
I'm a cop like you and
I'm walking out there.
Please do not shoot me!
Shoot at his feet.
Nothing like a little air superiority.
Detective, please stop!
Please, detective! Stop!
Stop walking! Blow it! Do it!
You have to get that bomb here,
and you've got ten minutes.
They're pushing us to the
entrance of the reactor!
They're gonna try to reconnect the core.
Idiots!
You sons-of-bitches! You killed them.
To follow your orders!
Alright boys get into
circle, bow your heads.
It's on my side.
My father, these guys will
go back on the bus. Okay?
Go! Go! Go! Back in the bus.
There's no where to go!
On the bus!
You've got to turn the truck East!
Stay straight!
Give me a hand! We can get a cable on it!
Fox showed me how to override the reactor.
Oh dear.
Including the emergency flood.
There's no way this bomb will be stopped.
What are you doing?
Protection from the blast!
We're gonna be alright! Get on top! Go!
It's an atom bomb!
You think they need to hear that right now?
To watch let them die without hope?
Come on!
Prepare yourself.
My father's work is done.
- What are you doing?
- I can get it out over the bay.
- Set it to fly over water and eject?
- No autopilot.
You could've gone anywhere, did
anything but you came back here.
- So did you.
- I guess we're both suckers.
- I never cared who you were.
- And you were right.
Shouldn't the people know
the hero who saved them?
Hero can be anyone.
Even a man knowing something as simple
and reassuring as putting
a coat around a young boy
shoulders to let him know
the world hadn't ended.
Bruce Wayne?
Vlad, they go! Go, you too! Come on father.
Hey heads down! This is it!
No! That's Batman!
That's detonation!
It's out over the bay,
it's clear of the city.
' I see a beautiful city '
' and the brilliant people
rising from this abyss. '
' I see the lives, for
which I lay down my life.'
' Peaceful, useful, prosperous and happy. '
' I see that I hold a
sanctuary in their hearts '
' And in the hearts of their descendents. '
' Generations ends. '
' That is the far, far
better thing that I do... '
'... than I have ever done. '
'That is a far, far better
rest that I go to...'
'... than I have ever known. '
I'm so sorry. I failed you!
You trusted me...
And I failed you.
Can I change your mind,
about quitting the force?
You know what you said about the
structures becoming shackles.
You were right and I can't
take it, the injustice.
I mean, no one ever's gonna
know who saved the entire city.
They know.
It was the Batman.
Mr. Wayne's will was not amended
to reflect his more modest estate.
Nonetheless, there are
considerable assets to dispose of.
The contents of the house are to be
sold to settle the estate's accounts,
and the remainders left in its
entirety to Alfred J. Pennyworth.
The house and grounds are left to
the city of Gotham on condition
that they never be demolished, altered
or otherwise interfered with.
That they shall be used for one
purpose and one purpose only:
The housing and care of the city's
at risk and orphan children.
I'm a clerk and I'll help anyone with
the smaller correspondences
and instructions.
- Blake, John?
- Nothing here.
Alright,
Try my legal name.
You should use your full name.
I like that name, Robin.
Thanks!
Why are we even worrying about
stabilization software?
This entire autopilot system
is completely obsolete.
Please, I just need to know
what I could've done to fix it.
But Mr. Fox it's already been fixed,
software patch, six months ago.
Check The ID on the patch.
Bruce Wayne.
- Any news on the missing item?
- Not yet.
We'd better leave no stone unturned,
we can't leave a string of
pearls on the manifest as lost.