Spend all day with us.
There are two...
pardon me...
two of everything in
every Noah's arcade.
That means
two of Zantar,
Bay Wolf, Ninja Commando,
Snake-azon,
Psycho Chopper...
It's really good
seeing you, Benjamin.
You haven't been into
Shakey's for so long.
Well, I've
been real busy.
It's two for you
'cause one won't do.
All this week,
kids under 6
get every fifth...
There's a new pet.
# Ch-Ch-Chia #
Chia Pet...
the pottery that grows.
They are very fast.
Simple. Plug it in,
and insert the plug
from just about anything.
Simple.
Even for our customers
in Waukegan, Elgin, and Aurora...
We'll be there
right on time.
So call!
# Clap on, clap off #
# The Clapper ##
# Wayne's World,
Wayne's World #
# Partytime #
# Excellent ##
[Guitar Riff]
O.K.
All right,
excellent.
Excellent.
Whoo!
OK, extreme close-up!
Waa!
Excellent.
Excellent
extreme close-up.
Now it's time for
Wayne's World's totally amazing
excellent discoveries.
Our guest
is Ron Paxton.
Welcome to
Wayne's World, Ron.
Thanks, Wayne.
Now, you're the inventor
of the Suck Kut, right?
What exactly
is a Suck Kut?
The Suck Kut is a revolution
in home hair cutting.
Wow! What a totally amazing
excellent discovery.
Well, yes.
Fireworks!
Now, Ron, the question that's
on everybody's mind is,
how does it work?
I'm fully prepared to give
a complete demonstration.
O.K.OK, Garth,
just sit there.
He's going to put that
thing on your melon, OK?
Just a trim.
Don't buzz me, all right?
Uhh! Uhh!
Ohh! Ohh!
Tell me, Ron.
Exactly how does
the Suck Kut work?
Well, as you can see,
it sucks as it cuts.
It certainly
does suck.
Ohh! Ohh!
What are we looking at?
Wayne's World. These guys do
their show out of their basement.
Ohh! Ohh! Ohh!
Ohh!
People watch this?
Yeah, lots.
Turn it off, man!
Turn it off!
It's sucking
my will to live!
Oh, the humanity!
You want to hand me
the telephone?
Sure.
Uhh!
Russell, this
is Benjamin.
Are you
watching TV?
Listen, could you
turn it to channel 10?
I want you to find out
who these guys are
and where they
do their show.
I think we can
sell it to Vanderhoff.
Take your Ritalin, OK?
OK, you're
in a forest.
Forest?
You're in a forest
with Heather Locklear.
With Heather?
And you're very warm.
Very...
- Warm?
- warm.
These guys
are so funny.
Oh, they're
obviously brilliant.
Hmm.
Wow! What a totally amazing
excellent discovery... not!
Thanks, Ron.
OK, that's all the time
we have for this week.
Until then, good night!
Party on, Wayne.
Party on, Garth.
# It's Wayne's World,
Wayne's World #
# Partytime #
# Excellent ##
[Guitar Riff]
And...
we're clear!
All right!
Excellent!
Whoo! Whoo!
All right!
Excellent!
Let me bring you
up to speed.
My name is
Wayne Campbell.
I live in
Aurora, Illinois,
which is
a suburb of Chicago.
Excellent!
I've had plenty
of Joe jobs.
Nothing I'd call
a career.
Let me put it
this way.
I have an extensive collection
of name tags and hair nets.
OK, I still
live with my parents,
which I admit
is both bogus and sad.
But at least I've got
an amazing cable access show,
and I still
know how to party.
But what
I'd really love
is to do Wayne's World
for a living.
It might happen.
Yeah, and monkeys might
fly out of my butt.
[Horn Honks]
Ahh, the Mirthmobile.
This is my best friend
Garth Algar.
Hi.
I think we'll go with a little
Bohemian Rhapsody, gentlemen.
Good call.
# I see a little
silhouette of a man #
# Scaramouche,
Scaramouche #
# Will you do
the fandango? #
# Thunderbolts
and lightning #
# Very, very
frightening #
# Galileo #
- # Galileo #
# Galileo, Figaro #
# Let me go-o-o-o #
# I'm just a poor boy #
# Nobody loves me #
# He's just
a poor boy #
# From a poor family #
# Spare him his life
from this monstrosity #
Whoa!
It's Phil.
Phil, what are you
doing here?
You're partied out,
man... again.
What if he honks
in the car?
I'm giving you
a no-honk guarantee.
Phil! Um...
if you're
going to spew,
spew into this.
# Easy come, easy go #
# Will you let me go? #
# Bismillah #
# No! We will not
let you go #
# Let him go #
# Bismillah #
# We will not
let you go #
# Let him go #
# Bismillah #
# We will not
let you go #
# Let me go #
# We will not
let you go #
# Let me go #
# Let me go-o-o-o #
# No, no, no, no,
no, no, no #
# Oh, mama mia,
mama mia #
# Mama mia,
let me go #
# Beelzebub #
# Has a devil
put aside for me #
# For me #
# So you think
you can stone me #
# And spit in my eye #
# So you think you
can love me and leave me #
# To die #
# Oh, baby #
Garth, pull over.
Oh! Oh, man!
Come on!
Not again.
He does this
every Friday.
Stop torturing
yourself, man!
You'll never
afford it!
Live in
the now!
It will be mine.
Oh, yes.
# Ooh #
# Oh, yeah #
# Nothing really matters #
# Anyone can see #
# Nothing
really matters #
# To me ##
Hey, Wayne's world!
Wayne's world! Party!
- Yeah!
- Whoo!
Excellent!
Way to go!
- Whoo!
Party on, Wayne!
Hey, Campbell.
Uno momento, fellas.
Officer Kuharski,
how's it going?
Fine.
Say, I smell bacon.
Does anyone else
smell bacon?
Yeah, I
definitely smell
a pork product
of some type.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I know
what you're doing, Campbell.
Bacon, pig, oink-oink,
police officer.
Ha ha ha.
I said that to cops
when I was your age.
Hey, what
are you up to?
I just pulled over
a tour bus
on its way to Chicago.
We had a tip there was
some drug smuggling going down.
We searched
the entire vehicle.
It was clean, so we proceeded
with body cavity searches.
No way.
Way! I inspected
12 individuals myself...
Inside and out.
Eeew!
Uhh!
Ugh!
OK, this guy needs coffee
and crullers stat!
We got to get him
to Rampart.
Let's go!
This is
Stan Mikita's Donuts.
Excellent munchie post.
This is
the manager, Glen.
He's here
24 hours a day.
I recommend
the sugar pucks.
They're excellent.
Come on.
I'd never done
a crazy thing in my life
before that night.
Why is it if a man kills
another man in battle
it's called heroic?
Yet if he kills a man
in the heat of passion
it's called murder?
Hello! What do you
think you're doing?
Only me and Garth get
to talk to the camera.
Come on.
I don't really have too much
to say right now.
What's that?
Ohh! Ohh!
Hi, Mr. Withers.
How's the amusement park going?
Just great, Wayne.
Four coffees and
a half a dozen crullers, please.
And one jelly donut.
Hey, there's your girlfriend,
Garth. Yeah.
[Tchaikovsky's Romeo And Juliet
Fantasy Overture Plays]
Ow!
Excuse me.
I fell.
Don't you guys ever get tired
of ordering the same thing?
- No.
Uh-oh.
Don't look. Stacy.
Where?
Oh, God.
I made eye contact.
Psycho hose beast.
Happy anniversary, Wayne.
Stacy, we broke up
two months ago.
That doesn't mean
we can't still go out.
Well, it does, actually.
That's what
breaking up is.
You going to go
to the Gasworks tonight?
No!
- No!
Don't you want
to open your present?
If it's a severed head,
I'll be very upset.
Open it.
O.K.
What is it?
It's a gun rack.
A gun rack?
A gun rack.
Yeah, great.
I don't
even own a gun,
let alone many guns
that would necessitate
an entire rack.
What am I going to do
with a gun rack?
You don't like it, fine.
[Slurp]
Wayne, if you're not careful,
you're going
to lose me.
I lost you
two months ago.
Are you mental?
We broke up.
Get the net!
Wayne!
Hey!
How you doing?
Garth!
Tiny, who's
playing tonight?
Jolly Green Giants,
The Shitty Beatles.
The Shitty Beatles...
are they any good?
They suck.
Then it's not just
a clever name?
Who else?
Crucial Taunt,
and they're just finishing the set.
I hear they can wail.
You're right.
Party on.
Yo!
All right!
Now, dig this, baby!
# You don't
care for me #
# I don't
care about that #
This is the Gasworks,
an excellent
heavy metal bar.
Always a babe fest.
And they got
a pool table, too.
# Let me stand
next to your fire #
Party! Whoo!
Yeow! Party!
Excuse me.
Whoo!
# Let me stand
next to your fire #
# Let me stand #
# Let me stand
next to your fire #
Excuse me.
Um, excuse me.
What?
I'd like to get by now.
Get out of my face,
you little dweeb.
Ohh!
Ow!
# I have only one
itchin' desire #
# Let me stand
next to your fire #
# Ohh #
# Let me stand
next to your fire #
[Mission: Impossible
Theme Plays]
# You don't
care for me #
# I don't care
about that #
# You got a new fool,
I like it like that #
# I have only
one burnin' desire #
# Let me stand
next to your fire #
Excuse me.
# Hey, let me stand
next to your fire #
What do you want,
you little dweeb?
# Oh, let me stand
next to your fire #
Aah!
Thank you.
# You say your mama
ain't home #
# It ain't my concern #
# Just don't play with me
and you won't get burned #
# Oh, dream weaver #
# I believe you can
get me through... ##
She's a babe!
Schwing!
# Ohh #
# Yeah #
# Ohh, ohh #
# Ohh #
# Hey ##
Ow, ow! Ha ha!
Hyah!
Yeah.
Ow! All right.
Ohh.
I love this woman.
Hey, Raymond, club soda
with a lime, please.
And would you
get me a towel?
Boy, you really wail.
Thanks.
Hey, you're that
partytime guy on TV.
Wayne, right?
Yes, and you are?
Cassandra.
Rough night, huh?
Everybody's kung fu fighting.
Yeah. Well,
nice meeting you.
Hey, hold on!
Can I call you sometime?
You got 5 bucks,
you can come to the rent party.
It's at my loft.
I'm there.
I got to go.
The club owner's trying to dick me
out of some money.
O.K.O.K.
See how many
people I...
That bass player's
a babe.
She makes me feel
kind of funny,
like when we used
to climb the rope in gym class.
You said I get
cash up front.
She will be mine.
Oh, yes.
Pardon me.
Do you have
any Grey Poupon?
Garth,
just sit there.
He's going to put
that on your melon.
OK, but
just a trim.
Don't buzz me,
all right?
Uhh!
Uhh! Uhh! Uhh!
Oh, no!
Russell, stop the tape.
So, what do you think?
I think it's two chimps on
a davenport in a basement.
I'm not sponsoring this.
I got spots on Love Boat,
but this?
What is this?
Mr. Vanderhoff,
this is your audience.
They're the same kids
that line up at Noah's Arcade.
It looks so cheesy.
That's where
I come in.
Russell's
our best producer.
He does Chicago P.M.
with Elaine Ronkey,
Sunshine Saturday,
The African-American Digest.
Never heard of that.
It's on very late.
It won several awards.
I think I'll stick
with Love Boat.
If I may,
speaking from
a producer/director standpoint,
kids can relate
to this show.
These guys
aren't phonies.
Kids can spot phonies.
They're very smart.
Kids know dick.
I watch them
in my arcades.
They stand like
laboratory rats
hitting the feeder bar
to get food pellets.
As long as they pump in quarters,
who gives a shit?
Let me ask you something.
What's your single biggest problem
in the arcade business?
Well, uh, keeping the customer
informed of new product.
Like, we have a new game
called Zantar.
Zantar is a gelatinous cube
that eats warriors
in a medieval village.
Every time
it eats a chieftain
you ascend
to a higher level.
Beauty part is you can't
get to the next level.
The kids keep
coughing up quarters.
Gelatinous cube
eats village...
I think it's terrific.
You know, I know nothing
about video games.
I found what you
just said riveting.
Well, I do
my own commercials.
I did not know that.
I don't mention the games
in the commercials
because the technology moves
much faster than the advertising.
I did not realize that.
Russell, did you
realize that?
No, I did not
realize that.
So, Mr. Vanderhoff,
let me see if I'm
hearing you correctly.
Are you saying
that if you had a spot,
say on a weekly show,
that you could
come on the show
and update the kids
on exactly what was new
in your arcade?
Yeah, that's it.
I'm impressed.
Wow!
Noah's Arcade presents
Wayne's World.
I think
that's brilliant.
Brilliant.
Well, thank you.
We'll get right to work
on this.
We'll send the contracts
over to your office.
We'll be in touch.
Oh.
I'd like
to think about this.
Oh, of course you would.
I wouldn't have it
any other way.
She'll validate.
Thank you.
He's in.
[Speaking Cantonese]
Stop it!
You're scaring me.
Oh, cool. You're learning
Cassandra's language.
I've never seen you so mental
over a girl before.
You going to marry her?
Marriage is punishment
for shoplifting in some countries.
OK, you passed inspection.
All right.
Just barely.
Uh, OK, that's 42.57, Wayne...
parts and labor.
No way.
Brutal.
Oh, O.K.
There you go.
All right,
we got it.
That's not enough.
What?
We got... that.
That's good,
but I need more.
Oh, man!
Why don't you use a gun?
It's not my fault.
Come on.
I suppose it's
society's fault?
More.
[RRRrrrr]
Cool.
All right.
[RRRrrrr RRRrrrr]
Here's an extra dollar.
You guys should have been
at Gasworks on Friday.
Yeah, we were there.
There was this band...
Crucial Taunt...
They had this megababe
for a lead singer. Unreal!
Phil, we were there.
Have you gone mental?
Hello?
I think we should go now.
Here you go.
Cool!
You think it's wise
to sell a show we don't own?
By tonight, we will.
Ah!
Excuse me.
Do you know where
we could find Wayne Campbell?
That'd be privileged
information.
We just want to know
where they broadcast from.
Are you a friend
or a relative?
We're neither.
Russell, I may not have
grown up around here,
but I understand these people.
This must be the place.
OK, we're just about
out of time, right?
But first let's give
a Wayne's World salute
to the Guess jeans girl
Claudia Schiffer.
Schwing!
Tent pole!
She's a babe.
She's magically
babe-licious.
She tested very high
on the strokability scale.
Mmrreowww!
Ssss.
Are you through yet?
I'm getting tired
of holding this.
Yeah, that's
what she said.
OK, so, Claudia Schiffer,
we salute you.
- Scha-wing!
That's all the time
we have this week.
Until then, good night.
Party on, Wayne.
# Wayne's World
Wayne's World #
# Partytime #
# Excellent ##
[Guitar Riff]
And... we're clear.
O.K. Excellent show,
everyone.
[Garth]
Excellent.
Great show.
Wayne, Benjamin Kane.
Regional program director
for Oliver Communications.
Oh, hello.
I'm Russell Finley.
We spoke earlier today. Hi.
Maybe we can go somewhere
and get acquainted.
Russell,
get to know the crew.
You know anywhere nice?
Hi.
Let me get this
out of the way...
I'm a big fan.
You are?
As I see it, your show's
capable of so much more.
We'll try harder, OK?
Give us a second chance.
Don't cancel us
without a second chance.
Garth, relax, all right?
Your pills?
He can't cancel us.
We're on public access.
Can I be honest?
My job, it's usually
such a bore,
but the other day something
incredible happened.
What happened?
Noah Vanderhoff,
owner of the largest
video arcade chain in Chicago,
is in my office
asking me what's with
this show Wayne's World
I hear so much about?
I have your shows on tape.
I said I'm a fan.
I put a show in.
He literally jumped
out of his seat.
- Cool.
He wants to sponsor
the show,
put you on our station,
and pay you
a huge salary.
He doesn't realize
you're both artists.
You're not interested
in money.
No, we're not
interested in money.
That's what I told him.
But he said take them
two cashier's checks anyway
so they know I'm serious.
I may be wasting my time,
but here I am
with the contract
and two cashier's checks
for $5,000 each.
Exsqueeze me?
Baking powder?
You're going to pay us
for doing Wayne's World?
Give me the word.
I'll tear up
these checks.
[Chokes]
No! No!
He shoots,
he scores!
Want to look
at the contracts?
Yes.
Do you have a lawyer?
Yes. Uh... no.
We're between
lawyers right now.
Our first lawyer
screwed our affairs so badly.
That's right. I walked
right into that office,
I grabbed him
by his big fat head,
and I said I'm not going to jail
for you or anybody.
Exactly.
Can I have an opportunity
to peruse that contract
before we sign it?
Hmm.
Yes.
I like what
you've done here.
Ah. Hmm.
Yes.
Um, I dropped my pen.
I'm not so sure about...
Oh, I see. I see.
Hi. Um, does this seem weird?
Why does this guy
have contracts?
Ever see
The Twilight Zone
where the guy
signed a contract,
they cut out his tongue,
put it in a jar,
and it wouldn't die?
It grew and pulsated
and gave birth to baby tongues.
Pretty cool, huh?
I got to go.
I like this part.
I feel we can work with you
on this project.
You've made Mr. Vanderhoff
a very happy man.
To Wayne's World.
- To Wayne's World.
# We got $5,000 #
- Hey, Wayne.
- Check it out.
# We got $5,000 #
# We got $5,000 ##
# Ain't got no reason #
# For reaction #
Party!
Whoo!
# Ain't got no reason
for distraction #
Great party, huh, guys?
# Love the way
that you love me, baby #
that you stare #
Uh-oh. Stacy alert.
We're being pulled in
by her tractor beam.
I got to go.
We got to go.
# Ooh, if you dare #
# Don't be afraid
to love me #
# Anywhere #
# Dream weaver #
# I believe you can get me
through the night ##
# Don't be afraid
to love me #
# Anywhere #
# Won't you touch me #
# Won't you love me #
# Just let me know #
God, she's amazing.
# I'll be there #
Wayne, Wayne, Garth told me
about the show, man.
I love you, man.
Yeah, and I love you,
too, Terry.
No, I mean it, man.
I love you.
No, I mean it.
No, you don't, man.
# Why don't you love me #
Garth, come over here.
Terry has something
to say to you.
I love you, man.
Thank you.
# Oh #
# I'll be there #
# Oh, I'll be there ##
Your vocals
are incredible.
Thanks.
You have a very
interesting look.
Aha.
Oh, I'm not trying
to pick up on you.
Good thing.
No, I'm producing
a television show.
It's in Chicago.
Very late night.
We're looking
for a musical act.
Here's my card.
Is there a number
I can reach you at?
We got fliers at the door.
Hello.
# So hot and bothered #
# Hot and bothered ##
Wayne?
Hi, Wayne.
Hi.
Want to go somewhere
and talk?
Sure.
What's going on in there?
Just a minute.
We'd like to go
to the bathroom, please.
In this century.
How long
you been waiting?
Like an hour now.
Uh...
Hi, Garth.
hi.
I'm looking for Wayne.
He seems to be going through
this difficult phase.
You know what I think?
That you're mental?
You know him best.
What should I do?
Get over it. Go out
with somebody else.
Yeah, thanks.
OK, great.
Hi.
So who's
this guy Benjamin?
Only one of the most
important producers in television.
He's ahead of his time.
We've signed with him.
He's based in Chicago.
He's interested
in the band.
Of course.
I love your band.
You guys wail.
Thanks.
You guys kick ass.
You're Double Live Gonzo!
Intensity in Ten Cities.
Live at Budokan.
If you got a break,
you could make it.
And if a frog
had wings,
he wouldn't bump his ass
when he hopped.
Interesting.
Where did you
learn English?
College...
and the Police Academy movies.
Ah.
Cassandra...
I've got something
I want to say to you.
[Speaking Cantonese]
Campbell, that's amazing.
You learned to say
I look pretty in Cantonese.
Hi, Wayne.
Hello, Stacy.
Sit right here.
[Stacy] Kiss me.
You make me laugh.
Can I call you?
Anytime.
Look out!
- Aah!
Oops.
[Whistling The Theme
To Star Trek]
Sometimes I wish
I could boldly go
where no man's
gone before,
but I'll probably
stay in Aurora.
What are you
thinking about?
Cassandra.
She's a fox.
In French,
she'd be called la renard.
She'd be hunted with only
her cunning to protect her.
She's a babe.
She's a robo-babe.
In Latin, she'd be called
babia majora.
If she were
a president,
she'd be
Babe-raham Lincoln.
Did you ever find
Bugs Bunny attractive
when he'd put on a dress
and play a girl bunny?
No.
Neither did I.
I was just asking.
OK, OK,
keep looking up.
O.K.
- Aah!
Whoo!
Whoo-hoo!
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Guys, I will be talking
to the cameraman
on the headset.
Terry will give you
hand cues.
Excuse me, Russell,
but I believe
I requested the hand job.
Let's go on.
The cue is...
watch carefully...
5... 4... 3...
You didn't say 2 or 1.
You don't say 2 or 1.
Why not?
You just don't, OK?
Now, it goes...
5... 4... 3...
Good. OK, good.
- Ow!
We're ready
for rehearsal,
unless there are
any questions.
Yeah, um... does this
seem weird to anybody else?
I mean, we're looking down
on Wayne's basement,
only that's not
Wayne's basement.
Isn't that weird?
That's twisted.
That's weird, man,
that's weird.
Garth, that was a haiku.
[Telephone Rings]
- Russell.
- Control room.
Oh, hello, Benjamin.
Just finishing up
with the Vanderhoffs.
They'd like to look
at rehearsal
and make sure we're
not wasting their money.
Not a good idea, sir.
Great.
Come in.
Your landing gear is down.
Just put that down.
Ow.
Just go away, guys.
Hey, hey, hey!
Russell's excited
you're coming to the studio.
Oh, the studio.
That's where
the magic happens.
You've worked
in television?
No, I watch a lot.
Of course you do.
You're creative.
She came up with the name
Noah's Arcade.
I just opened my mouth
and out it came.
You're a lucky man,
Mr. Vanderhoff.
Bring in the blue screen.
Let's try one.
Ready to cue
Wayne and Garth, and go.
O.K.
In 5... 4... 3...
Good, Terry.
Wayne, Garth,
don't count along.
We see your mouths moving.
Again.
In 5... 4... 3...
Guys?
You're nodding.
Once again, Terry.
In 5... 4... 3... 2...
Welcome to Wayne's World.
Party on, Garth.
Party on, Wayne.
We got a new feature
on Wayne's World
which allows us to travel
through time and space.
It's called chromakey,
and it's really handy
if you want
to go to... New York.
We're in New York!
I got a gun. Let's go
to a Broadway show.
I guess kids get this?
Oh, they love it.
Or maybe you prefer Hawaii.
Muka laka hickey.
Come on, you wanna lay me.
Pass the poi. Mahalo.
Or say you want
to go to Texas.
Howdy, partners.
Let's raise and rope broncos.
Let's go down
to the floor.
Howdy, y'all.
Or imagine being magically
whisked away to...
Delaware.
Hi.
I'm in Delaware.
Noah and Mimi Vanderhoff,
say hello to Wayne Campbell
and Garth Algar.
Pleasure to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
Garth, how do you like
being in a real studio?
It's like a new
pair of underwear.
At first
it's constrictive,
but after a while,
it becomes a part of you.
I got to go.
O.K.
No, no, no. Please.
Wayne, I used to be
in meat packing.
Lips and hooves.
One day, I had
a four-hour layover in Tulsa.
These kids in the airport
kept pumping quarters
into a game called Pong.
They must've gone
through 50 bucks.
I sat there watching
and said, "Hell, I'm in
the wrong business."
15 years later,
I'm a millionaire.
It's so huge.
Thanks.
Do I frighten you?
No.
Do you want me to?
Noah, I love you
on that couch.
You think?
Noah does
all his own commercials.
Yeah, I got a new one
where I rap.
# Come bust a move
where the games are played #
# It's chill,
it's fresh #
# It's Noah's Arcade ##
What do you think of that?
I'd have to say...
ass sphincter says what?
What?
A sphincter says what?
Exactly.
We've got a lunch.
That's what I think of it.
It's been a pleasure.
May I say I've had
a thrilling day.
You may.
Shall we?
And may I say
your wife's a babe.
Thank you.
We have a table.
[Woof Woof]
What is it, girl?
[Woof]
Aliens have
kidnapped Wayne?
[Woof]
Oh, I misunderstood.
Wayne's outside.
Thanks, girl.
O.K.
Game on.
He shoots, he scores!
1 for 1.
Crowd is going wild!
[Honk Honk]
- Car.
Game on.
OK, let's go.
Worsley cuts down the angle.
Gretzky shoots!
Oh, Gretzky is denied!
Choked on the open net.
Wayne?
Yeah?
Do you feel Benjamin's
not one of us?
Good call.
It's as if Benjamin
wants us to be liked
by everyone.
Led Zeppelin didn't write tunes
that everyone liked.
They left that
to the Bee Gees.
[Honk Honk]
- Car.
Game on.
Uh-oh. Incoming.
Stacy, 10:00.
Hi, Wayne.
Hi.
Hey, are you all right?
Oops.
[Wayne]
And she's O.K.
Game on.
Yeah, game on.
[Electric Motor Whines]
You know, Garth,
you and I have
never really talked.
O.K.
You know, I love
what you do on the show.
I look at you,
and I just laugh and laugh.
Uh-huh.
Let me run this by you
because you're a sharp guy.
I'm thinking about
giving Vanderhoff
a weekly interview
on the show.
How would you feel
about making a change?
We fear change.
[Electric Motor Starts]
[Motor Slows Down
And Stops]
Cassandra,
I have to say it...
You look excellent.
Thanks. I've been so busy
lately with my band,
I thought I was
getting meningitis.
I thought I had mono
for an entire year.
It turned out I was
just really bored.
# You're so fine #
# You're so fine,
you blow my mind #
Excuse me?
I'm sorry. It's the last song
I heard this morning.
I hate when that happens.
# Hey, Mickey,
you're so fine #
# You're so fine,
you blow my mind #
# Hey, Mickey #
# Hey, Mickey,
you're so fine #
# You're so fine,
you blow my mind #
# Hey, Mickey ##
I think I'm going
to put on some tunes.
Hey, when did you
get the CD player?
When we got the money.
# So big boy said
you are bad news #
# We're tired of mama
bein' confused #
# It's plain to see
we rock 'n' roll #
# If you don't like it,
got to move ##
There it is...
Excalibur.
Wow. '64 Fender Stratocaster
in classic white
with triple single coil pickups
and a whammy bar.
Pre-CBS Fender
corporate buy-out.
I'd raise the bridge,
file down the nut,
and take the buzz
out of the low "E."
God, I love this woman.
[Chimes Clang]
Hi, Garth.
Where's the clerk?
I know. I'll use
the "May I help you" riff.
[Heavy Metal Riff]
May I help you?
Yes, my good man.
I'd like to look at this
Fender Stratocaster, please.
Oh, really? Again?
Yes.
Careful.
No Stairway.
Denied!
Wow.
You're... amazing, dude.
Thanks.
I like to play.
[Ting]
Excuse me. Wayne.
Can I put the Fender
back now, please?
Not today, my good man.
I'm feeling saucy.
I think I'm going to buy it.
Do you accept... cash?
Cha-ching.
Have you spoken to Wayne
about the Vanderhoff spot?
Yes. Briefly.
He was not very receptive.
Oh, really? Well, I'll explain
to him that it's not a choice,
that it's in his contract.
Oh. Well, Wayne
will understand that right away.
Not.
Excuse me.
I mean, there's two
Darrin Stevens, right?
Dick York, Dick Sargent.
Yeah, right, as if
we wouldn't notice.
[Imitating Paul McCartney]
# And her name was Cassandra ##
Well, hold on.
Dick York. Dick Sargent.
Yeah.
Sergeant York.
Wow, that's weird.
Anything wrong, Davey?
Yeah. I got paid today.
Wayne.
Oh, yeah, I know
what that's like.
Listen, we need to have
a talk about Vanderhoff.
No. You don't understand.
They laid me off.
The fact is,
he's the sponsor
and you signed a contract
guaranteeing him
I got one of these.
certain concessions, one of them
being a spot on the show.
I know how that feels.
Know what
I'd like to do?
That's where I see things
just a little differently.
Yeah, I know what
you'd like to do...
Contract or no, I will
not bow to any sponsor.
Find the guy
that did it,
rip his still beating
heart out of his chest
I'm sorry
you feel that way,
and show him how black it is
before he dies.
but basically,
it's the nature of the beast.
Maybe I'm wrong
on this one,
Actually, I was thinking
but for me, the beast
doesn't include selling out.
about filing a grievance
with the union.
Well, the world's
a twisted place.
Garth, you know what
I'm talking about, right?
Hi.