War began between
Germany and France on August 3, 1914.
Five weeks later,
the German army had smashed its way...
to within 18 miles of Paris.
There, the battered French miraculously
rallied their forces at the Marne River...
- and in a series
of unexpected counterattacks —
- Detail, halt!
- drove the Germans back.
The front was stabilized...
then shortly afterwards developed
into a continuous line...
of heavily fortified trenches...
zigzagging their way 500 miles...
from the English Channel
to the Swiss frontier.
By 1916, after two grisly years
of trench warfare...
the battle lines had changed very little.
Successful attacks were measured
in hundreds of yards...
and paid for in lives
by hundreds of thousands.
General Broulard, sir.
- Hello, George. How are you?
Paul, wonderful seeing you again.
Really wonderful.
Well, this is splendid. It's superb.
It's grand, very grand.
Well, I've tried to create
a pleasant atmosphere in which to work.
Well, you've succeeded marvelously.
I wish I had your taste in carpets —
- Oh!
- and pictures.
You're much too kind, George.
Much too kind.
- Sit down, George.
- Thank you.
I really haven't done very much. The place
is much the same as it was when I moved in.
Paul, I've come to see you
about something big.
It's top secret and must go no further
than your chief of staff...
and not to him
unless you can trust his discretion.
Of course.
A group of armies is forming on this front
for an offensive very soon.
Headquarters is determined
to make a complete breakthrough.
- Why are you smiling?
- I'm really sorry.
I thought for just a moment I knew
what you were going to say. Please go on.
I never knew you were a mind reader.
What did you think I was about to say?
- Something about the "Anthill."
- You are a mind reader.
Well, it is a key position.
It's in my sector.
To be perfectly honest,
I've heard some talk.
You know, there's nothing really secret
around headquarters.
- Well, what do you think?
- It's the key to the whole
German position in this sector.
They've held on to it for a year now...
and it looks as though they'll hold on to it
for another year if they want to.
Paul, I have formal orders
to take the Anthill no later than the 10th.
- That's the day after tomorrow.
- That comes pretty close
to being ridiculous, don't you think?
I don't imagine I'd be here
if I really thought that.
Paul, if there's one man
in this army who can do this for me, it's you.
It's out of the question, George.
Absolutely out of the question.
My division was cut to pieces.
What's left of it is in no position
to even hold the Anthill, let alone take it.
I'm sorry, but that's the truth.
Well, Paul, there was something else
I wanted to tell you.
However, I'm sure that you'll misunderstand
my motives in mentioning it.
- What was it?
- Oh.
You'd be bound to misunderstand.
However, as your friend,
maybe I should tell you.
What are you trying to say, George?
Paul, talk around headquarters is that you
are being considered for the 12th Corps.
- The 12th Corps?
- Yes, and with that, another star.
Now, I've pushed it all I can.
The 12th Corps needs a fighting general,
and you're overdue on that star.
Now, we both know
that your record is good enough...
for you to refuse this assignment
on the grounds you've stated.
No one would question your opinion.
They'd simply get someone else
to do thejob.
So you shouldn't let this
influence your opinion, Paul.
- Oh, I'm sorry. Have a cognac?
- No, thanks, Paul, not before dinner.
George, I'm responsible
for the lives of 8,000 men.
What is my ambition against that?
What is my reputation
in comparison to that?
My men come first of all, George,
and those men know it too.
I know that they do.
You see, George, those men know
that I would never let them down.
That goes without saying.
The life of one ofthose soldiers
means more to me...
than all the stars and decorations
and honors in France.
So...
you think this attack is absolutely beyond
the ability of your men at this time?
I didn't say that, George.
Nothing is beyond those men,
once their fighting spirit is aroused.
Paul, I don't want to push you into it
ifyou think it's ill-advised.
Don't worry, George.
You couldn't do that if you tried.
Of course, artillery would make
an enormous difference.
- What artillery support can you give me?
- Well, I'll see.
What about replacements?
We'll see what we can do, but I feel sure
that you can get along with what you have.
- Might just do it.
- Oh, Paul.
I knew that I was right to come to you.
You are the man to take the Anthill.
- Now, as far as that star is concerned —
- That had nothing to do with my decision.
- If anything, it would sway me the other way.
- I realize that perfectly, Paul.
Now, when do you say
you see this coming off?
No later than the day after tomorrow.
We just might do it.
Hello there, soldier.
Ready to kill more Germans?
- Yes, sir.
- What's your name, soldier?
Sir, Private Ferol, Company "A."
- Uh-huh. Are you married, Private?
- No, sir.
- Well, I'll bet your mother's proud of you.
- Yes, sir.
- Well, carry on, Private, and good luck to you.
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
- Good morning, General.
- Good morning.
Hello there, soldier.
Ready to kill more Germans?
- Yes, sir.
- Aha! Working over your rifle, I see.
Well, that's the way.
It's a soldier's best f riend.
You be good to it,
and it'll always be good to you.
Yes, sir.
[Chuckles]
Well, uh, good luck to you, soldier.
- Carry on.
- Thank you, sir.
Hello there, soldier.
Ready to kill more Germans?
Well, is everything all right, soldier?
All right? Yes, sir, I'm all right.
Aha. Good fellow.
Are you married, soldier?
- Married? Me, married?
- Yes. Have you got a wife?
- A wife? Have I got a wife?
Sir, he's a bit shell-shocked.
I beg your pardon, Sergeant.
There is no such thing as shell shock.
- Have you got a wife, soldier?
- My wife?
My wife. Yes, I have a wife.
I'm never gonna see her again.
I'm gonna be killed.
Get a grip on yourself!
You're acting like a coward!
- I am a coward, sir.
- Snap out of it, soldier!
Sergeant, I want you to arrange
for the immediate transfer of this baby
out of my regiment!
I won't have other brave men
contaminated by him!
- Yes, sir.
- Carry on, Sergeant.
You were right, sir. This sort of thing
can spread if it isn't checked.
You know, General,
I'm convinced that these tours of yours...
have an incalculable effect
upon the morale of these men.
In fact, I think the fighting spirit
ofthe 701st derives from it.
No, no, Major.
That spirit was just born in them.
The general is coming, sir.
- Always a pleasure to see you, Colonel.
- I'm honored, General.
It's our privilege entirely.
- Well, quite a neat little spot you have here.
- Colonel.
I reserve comment on the neatness, sir,
but it is little.
- Pretty shy on seating
accommodations though.
More than enough for me.
I never got the habit of sitting.
Like to be on my feet.
Keep on the move.
I can vouch for that, Colonel.
I can hardly get the general behind a desk
long enough to sign an order.
Well, that's the way I am, you know, Dax.
I can't understand these armchair officers...
fellows trying to fight a war
from behind a desk...
waving papers at the enemy...
worrying about whether a mouse
is going to run up their pants leg.
I don't know, General. If I had the choice
between mice and Mausers...
I think I'd take the mice every time.
You'll never make me believe that, Colonel.
Seriously though, if a man's a ninny...
let him put on a dress
and hide under the bed.
But if he wants to be a soldier,
then, by heavens, he's got to be one.
He's got to fight, and he can't do that
unless he's where the fighting is.
That's my credo.
I think I have to agree with you,
presenting your case so convincingly, sir.
And you've never failed
to live up to it, sir.
- I imagine you'd like
a look around, wouldn't you?
- Yes, Colonel.
- Well, here's something to see.
The Anthill. About as good a view
as you can get without actually being there.
Well, that won't be long now, will it?
- Ah.
Ah. Yeah.
Well, I've seen
much more formidable objectives.
Much, much worse.
Well, not something we can grab
and run away with...
but certainly pregnable.
- Sounds kind of odd, though, doesn't it?
- Why?
Well, like something to do
with giving birth.
Oh, yes. Quite. You're right
on your toes this morning, Colonel.
Even sharper than usual.
But we mustn't forget,
the colonel was perhaps the foremost
criminal lawyer in all France.
- Of course, General.
- Gentlemen, you're both much too kind.
Tell me, Colonel, how did your relief
come off last night?
We drew some artillery.
Twenty-nine casualties, sir.
Yes, I noticed it on the road in.
Utterly inexcusable. Stupid.
All swarmed together like a bunch of flies,
just waiting for someone to swat 'em.
Well, they never learn, it seems.
They get in a tight spot under heavy fire,
gang up every time.
Herd instinct, I suppose.
Kind of a lower-animal sort of thing.
Kind of a human sort of thing,
it seems to me...
or don't you make a distinction
between the two, Major?
Oh, yes, uh, very regrettable, of course.
Very. Yes, indeed.
Uh, Major, would you be kind enough
to excuse us for a few minutes?
Yes, sir. Of course.
Colonel.
Well, Colonel, what do you think of it?
- What do I think of what, sir?
- The Anthill.
Colonel, your regiment
is going to take the Anthill tomorrow.
You know the condition of my men, sir.
Oh, naturally, men are going to have to
be killed. Possibly a lot of them.
They absorb bullets and shrapnel...
and by doing so make it possible
for others to get through.
- What support will we have?
- I have none to give you.
What sort of casualties
do you anticipate, sir?
Hmm, say, five percent killed
by our own barrage.
That's a very generous allowance.
Ten percent more
in getting through no-man's-land...
and 20% more getting through the wire.
That leaves 65%
with the worst part of the job over.
Let's say another 25%
in actually taking the Anthill.
We're still left with a force
more than adequate to hold it.
General, you're saying that more
than half of my men will be killed.
Yes, it's a terrible price to pay, Colonel...
but we will have the Anthill.
- But will we, sir?
- I'm depending on you, Colonel.
All France is depending on you.
Am I amusing you, Colonel?
I'm not a bull, General. I don't need a flag
waved in front of me to get me to charge.
I don't think I like your comparison
of the flag of France to a bullfighter's cape.
I meant nothing disrespectful
to the flag of France, sir.
Patriotism may be old-fashioned,
but show me a patriot,
and I'll show you an honest man.
Not everyone has always thought so.
Samuel Johnson had something else
to say about patriotism.
And what was that, may I ask?
- Nothing really.
- What you do mean, "Nothing really"?
Well, sir, nothing really important.
Colonel, when I ask a question,
it's always important.
- Now, who was this man?
- Samuel Johnson, sir.
All right. Now, what did he
have to say about patriotism?
He said it was the last refuge
of a scoundrel, sir.
I'm sorry. I meant nothing personal.
You're tired, Dax. You're very tired.
It's you who are exhausted, not your men.
And it's my f ault. I've given you
one impossible task after another.
- You need rest. You need it badly.
- I haven't said anything
about needing rest, sir.
And you never would either. Therefore, you're
not going to have any say-so about it, Colonel.
As from right now,
I'm ordering you on indefinite furlough.
General,
you can't take me away from my men.
You can't do that to me, sir.
Not to you, Dax. Foryou.
For your good and f or the good ofyour men.
The good of my men, sir?
If a commanding officer lacks confidence,
what can we expect of his men?
Naturally, I don't want to relieve you,
but I must have your enthusiastic support.
Not once have you said
that your men can take the Anthill.
We'll take the Anthill.
If any soldiers in the world can take it...
we'll take the Anthill.
And when you do,
your men will be relieved and get a long rest.
Corporal Paris and Private Lejeune
reporting, sir.
- You took your time about it.
- We prepared as quick as we could, sir.
We had to alert the sentries.
All right. You men, at ease.
This is a reconnaissance patrol —
German wire, machine gun posts...
identification of bodies.
There will only be the three of us,
and we're to avoid a fight if we can.
We go out to the left, and we come back
through Post 6 on the right.
- Is everything all clear at Post 6?
- All the sentries have
been warned up to here.
Number 6 will send up flares
at 10-minute intervals starting at 04:00.
- I wanted them every five minutes.
- I told them that, sir.
The sergeant says
every five minutes is too much.
He says it's certain to draw artillery.
Quite a strategist, this sergeant.
What's his name?
I don't know, sir.
All right. You men wait outside.
I'll join you in a minute.
Would you mind telling us
the password, sir?
- Calais.
- Yes, sir.
- He's fortifying himself.
- It smelled like heaven.
I can always tell when he's had a few.
He gets sarcastic.
Well, at least he could have
passed it around, the pig.
Hey, what's he got against you anyway?
We went to school together
before the war.
He thinks I don't have enough
respect for him. He's right.
If you gentlemen are ready.
- Colonel.
- Everything clear and understood?
Yes, sir.
The lane through our wire
is right out in front here.
Machine guns are pointing
at the opening.
- Good luck, men.
- Thank you, sir.
All right, men. Let's go.
- What's that?
- I don't know.
Lejeune, move out and look that over.
We'll cover you.
Split up a night patrol?
Move out, Lejeune.
- I don't like this. Let's get out of here.
- We haven't given him enough time.
- If we wait any longer, they'll get us too.
- We've got to wait for him.
He must be dead. Where is he?
Roget!
- Well.
- Surprised, Lieutenant?
Yes, I am. Happily surprised.
I thought you'd been killed.
You didn't wait around to find out,
did you, Lieutenant?
Now, look here. What do you mean?
I mean, you ran like a rabbit
after you killed Lejeune.
Killed Lejeune?
What are you talking about?
I don't think I like your tone.
You're speaking to an officer.
Remember that.
Oh, well, I must be mistaken then, sir.
An officer wouldn't do that.
A man wouldn't do it.
Only a thing would.
- A sneaky, booze-guzzling,
yellow-bellied rat —
- Now —
with a bottle for a brain and a streak of spit
where his spine ought to be.
- That's enough, Corporal!
- You've got yourself into a mess, Lieutenant.
Oh, I have, have I?
Well, you've got yourself in a worse one.
First, general insubordination.
Second, threatening your superior officer.
Third, refusing to obey an order
and inciting others to do the same.
Now, how do you think those charges
are gonna look on paper?
Not half as bad as these.
Endangering the lives of your men
through recklessness.
Drunk on duty.
Want on murder of one of your own men...
and cowardice in the face of the enemy.
Philippe, have you ever tried to bring charges
against an officer?
It's my word against yours, you know.
And whose word do you think
they're gonna believe?
Or l-let me put it another way.
Whose word do you think
they're going to accept?
Now, I'll tell you what I'm willing to do.
So far, all I have written in this report...
is that you and Lejeune
were killed while out on patrol.
I'll fix this to read
that you made your way back...
after becoming separated
during the skirmish.
- That'll end the matter once and for all.
- You killed Lejeune.
You know that, don't you?
- I'm sorry. It was an accident.
- You threw that grenade and killed him.
I'd give anything in the world if it hadn't
have happened, and that's the truth.
Honestly, I know you don't like me,
but what kind of a man do you think I am?
- Oh, good morning, Colonel.
- At ease, men.
I've been waiting for your report,
Lieutenant.
Well, I think we found out
a thing or two.
- Everything go well?
- No, sir. Private Lejeune was killed.
- How'd it happen?
- It's all right here in the report, sir.
- Well, let's have it.
- Oh, it isn't quite finished yet, sir.
That's all, Corporal.
You did a good night's work.
Should feel very proud of yourself.
Go get some sleep.
Yes, sir.
- How'd you lose Lejeune?
- Machine gun fire, sir.
He coughed.
Almost got us all killed.
Finish that report
and get it to my dugout immediately.
Yes, sir.
The artillery starts at 051 5.
First Battalion will move out at 05:30.
When the leading elements
have cleared the German wires...
the second wave, consisting of
the Second and Third Battalions —
minus two companies in reserve —
will move out...
in no case later than 05:40.
Well, that's it, gentlemen.
Are there any questions?
Sir, is 15 minutes of artillery preparation
all that we can expect?
The feeling is that any more than that will
give them too much time to get organized.
What's weather supposed to be like
tomorrow, sir?
Too good.
No chance of rain or fog?
The forecast is for sun all day.
If, uh — Perhaps I should say
when we take the Anthill...
how long do we have to hold it
before we can expect any support?
Well, General Mireau, who, by the way,
will be personally observing the attack...
has promised us support from the 72nd
by sundown tomorrow...
which means, ofcourse,
that we'll have to hold all day.
Are there any more questions?
Well, gentlemen, good luck, and I'm sure
you'll come through as you always do.
Let's get some sleep.
I'm not afraid
ofdying tomorrow, only ofgetting killed.
That's as clear as mud.
Which would you rather be done in by,
a bayonet or a machine gun?
- Oh, a machine gun, naturally.
- Naturally. That'sjust my point.
They're both pieces of steel
ripping into your guts.
Only the machine gun is quicker,
cleaner and less painful, isn't it?
What does that prove?
That proves that most of us are more afraid
of getting hurt than of getting killed.
Look at Bernard.
He panics when it comes to gas,
but gas doesn't bother me a bit.
He's seen photos of gas cases.
Doesn't mean anything to me.
But I'll tell you something though — I'd hate
like the devil to be without my tin hat.
But on the other hand, I don't mind
not having a tin hat for my tail.
- Why's that?
- You ought to. That's where your brains are.
Because I know a wound to the head
will hurt much more than one in the tail.
The tail is just meat,
but the head — ah, the head is all bone.
- Ah, speak foryourself.
- Tell me this.
Aside from the bayonet,
what are you most afraid of?
- High explosives.
- Exactly! And it's the same with me.
Because — Because I know that it can
chew you up worse than anything else.
Look, it'sjust like I'm trying to tell you.
If you're really afraid of dying, you'd be
living in a funk all the rest of your life...
because you know you've got
to go someday, any day.
And besides, if it's death
that you're really afraid of...
why should you care about
what it is that kills you?
Ah, you're too smart for me, Professor.
All I know is nobody wants to die.
Through to Division, sir. Through to Polygon.
Everything quiet.
All units report themselves ready.
Zero-minus two.
May I offeryou gentlemen some cognac?
- Thank you, General.
- Thank you, sir.
- After you, sir.
To France.
Minus 15, 14...
13, 12...
11 , 10...
nine, eight, seven...
six, five, four...
three, two, one...
- zero!
- Sergeant, where's "B" Company?
- I don't know, sir.
- Where in heaven's name are they?
- On the left, sir.
Where are the rest?
Zero-plus one, and they're still
in the trenches. They're not advancing.
- Yes, sir.
- Miserable cowards. They're not advancing!
The barrage is getting away from them!
They're still in the trenches!
Yes, sir.
- Captain Nichols.
- Yes, sir?
Order the 75s to commence firing
on our own positions.
Captain, do you fail to comprehend
the meaning of my order?
No, sir, but I respectfully ask to —
Captain, do you fail to comprehend
the meaning of my order?
- No, sir.
- Then carry it out, Captain.
Yes, sir.
Hello, Polygon. This is Division.
Batteries 1 and 2 commence firing...
on coordinates 32-58-78.
Batteries 1 and 2 to commence firing...
on coordinates 32-58-78. Over.
General, the battery commander reports
those are our own positions.
- He says it must be a mistake.
- Confirm the order, Captain.
Yes, sir. There is no mistake.
The order is confirmed.
Battery commander respectfully reports
he cannot execute such an order...
unless it is in writing
and signed by the general. Over.
General, battery commander respectfully
reports he cannot execute such an order...
unless it is in writing
and signed by the general.
- Give me that phone!
- Yes, sir.
- General Mireau speaking!
- Battery commander speaking, sir.
The troops are mutinying,
refusing to advance.
Fire as ordered until further notice!
With all respect, sir, you have no right
to order me to shoot down my own men...
unless you are willing to take full
and undivided responsibility for it.
Captain Rousseau,
are you going to obey my order?
I must have a written order
before I can execute such a command, sir.
Supposing you're killed.
Then where will I be?
You'll be in front ofa firing squad
tomorrow morning! That's where you'll be!
Hand overyour command and report yourself
under arrest to my headquarters!
Roget!
Lieutenant Roget!
Why are your men still in here?
It was impossible, sir.
Major Vignon is dead.
Get these men out ofthe trenches!
Come on!
Let's get ready for another try!
Get these men out of here!
I've tried three times.
Look at all the casualties.
All right! Let's give it another try!
Come on! Let's give it another try!
It's impossible, sir.
All the men are falling back.
Sir, I respectfully submit to the colonel —
Pardon, your remarks to me
were very unfair, sir.
It's just impossible! It's just impossible.
General, according to first reports,
the attack has failed all along the line.
The men are falling back to our own trenches.
Major Saint-Auban, arrange for
the immediate reliefofthe 701 st Regiment.
Have them sent to the Château d'Aigle.
Have Colonel Dax report to my headquarters.
- Yes, sir.
- Major Couderc, assemble
a general court-martial.
Have it ready to meet
at 3:00 tomorrow afternoon.
If those little sweethearts won't face
German bullets, they'll face French ones!
I ordered an attack.
Your troops refused to attack.
Our troops did attack, sir,
but they could make no headway.
Because they didn't try, Colonel.
I saw it myself.
Half of your men never left the trenches.
A third of my men were pinned down
because the fire was so intense.
Don't quibble over fractions, Colonel.
The fact remains that a good part ofyour men
never left their own trenches.
Colonel Dax, I'm going to have 1 0 men
from each company in your regiment...
tried under penalty ofdeath for cowardice.
- Penalty ofdeath?
- For cowardice!
They have skimmed milk in their veins
instead of blood.
Then it's the reddest milk I've ever seen.
My trenches are soaked
with that red skimmed milk.
-That's just about enough out of you, Colonel!
-I'm not gonna mince words
and stand on protocol —
Colonel Dax, ifyou continue in this manner,
I shall have to place you under arrest.
I believe the colonel has a point,
even though he makes it rather bluntly.
This is not a trial,
but it does bear certain aspects of one.
And Colonel Dax, technically,
is cast in the role ofthe defense.
In view ofthe gravity of the charges...
a court of law would grant him
all possible latitude in presenting his case.
Latitude is one thing.
Insubordination another.
I am merely offering an opinion, General.
Please do not feel constrained to accept it.
I am perfectly willing to accept it,
General Broulard.
I'm sorry, sir.
I certainly didn't intend to be insubordinate.
My only aim is to remind you
ofthe heroism these men have shown...
on every occasion in the past.
We're not talking about the past.
We're talking about the present.
But don't you see, sir?
They're not cowards.
So if some ofthem didn't leave the trenches,
it must have been because it was impossible.
They were ordered to attack.
It was their duty to obey that order.
We can't leave it up to the men
to decide when an order is possible or not.
If it was impossible,
the only proof of that...
would be their dead bodies
lying at the bottom of the trenches.
They're scum, Colonel.
The whole rotten regiment —
a pack ofsneaking, whining,
tail-dragging curs.
- Do you really believe that, sir?
- Yes, I do. That's exactly what I believe.
And what's more,
it's an incontestable fact.
- Then why not shoot the entire regiment?
- I'm perfectly serious.
- Now, Colonel, you're missing
the point entirely.
We don't want to slaughter the French army.
All we want to do is to set an example.
Oh, well, if it's an example you want,
then take me.
- Take you?
- Yes, sir, if it's an example you want...
one man will do as well as a hundred.
The logical choice is the officer
most responsible for the attack.
Come now, Colonel.
I think you're overwrought.
This is not a question ofofficers.
Paul, we don't want to overdo this thing.
Suppose wejust make it a dozen.
I was talking ofa hundred men,
and now we're down to 12.
Paul, let's not haggle over this thing anymore!
Let's get it settled once and for all
so that we can all live with it.
Well, perhaps I was a bit too anxious
to see properjustice meted out.
I've spent my entire life in the army.
I've always tried to be true to my principles.
That's the only mistake
I can ever be accused of.
I'll settle for this —
have the company commanders
select one man from each company
in the first wave...
three in all.
Well, that's very reasonable of you, Paul.
The court-martial will meet
at the château at 3:00 this afternoon.
- Will that be convenient foryou, General?
- I won't be there, Paul.
You won't be there?
No, I think it best
that you handle this matter on your own.
- Probably so.
- General Mireau.
If it's at all possible, I'd like
to be appointed counsel for the accused.
I'll take the matter into consideration.
I think we can permit that, can't we, Paul?
Of course we can.
- Consider it settled, Colonel.
- Thank you, sir.
Well, noon straight up, Paul.
I hope that you can stay
for lunch, Colonel.
George, I'm afraid the colonel
won't have time.
Don't deny it, Paul. You've been hiding
this man, keeping him for your own.
I think that was very selfish of you.
Thank you for your courtesy, General,
but I'm afraid there isn't much time
between now and 3:00.
Of course, Colonel. I shall look forward
to the pleasure of seeing you again.
- Yes, Captain? What is it?
- You ordered me to report to you here, sir.
- Captain Rousseau, battery commander, sir.
- Yes, yes, of course.
I wanted to speak to you
about some of your shells falling short.
I haven't time to go into it now.
Report back to your command
until further orders.
- Yes, sir.
- Bad stuff. Demoralizes the men.
- I quite agree with you.
And the best solution
is to shelve him to another outfit.
A court of inquiry
ought to roast him a bit first.
Well, in cases like this —
shells falling short —
I — I always try to avoid an inquiry.
It gets around among the men
and makes a bad impression.
No, shelving will be the best discipline
for him, in my opinion.
- Well, perhaps you're right.
- Oh, uh, would you excuse me for a moment?
A regimental matter
I want to mention to the colonel.
- I'll join you in the dining room.
- Splendid. In a moment.
That will be Captain Sancy,
Captain Renouart and Lieutenant Roget.
- Yes, sir.
- Have them meet me at regimental
headquarters in half an hour.
- Yes, sir.
- Colonel Dax.
- I'd like a word with you.
Certainly, sir.
Let's be sensible about this.
Sensible, sir?
Listen to me, Dax.
Drop this fancy talk with me, understand?
General Broulard seems to think
you're funny. I don't.
- Now, I want you to drop this affair.
- I beg your pardon, sir. Is that an order?
Colonel Dax, when this mess is cleaned up,
I'll break you.
I'll find an excuse
and I'll breakyou to the ranks. I'll ruin you.
And it'll bejust what you deserve...
showing such little loyalty
to your commanding officer.
That's all, Colonel.
Detail, halt!
General Mireau feels that the attack
on the Anthill yesterday morning failed...
because of an inadequate effort
on the part of the First Battalion.
Each ofyou is to select
one man from your company...
place him under arrest and have him ready
to appear before a general court-martial...
no later than 1 500 hours this afternoon.
The charge is cowardice
in the face ofthe enemy.
You have your orders, gentlemen.
Let's carry them out.
But Lieutenant Roget
killed Lejeune on that patrol...
and then blackmailed me
into keeping quiet about the whole thing!
- That's why he picked me.
- Corporal, I understand your feelings.
But that story has nothing to do
with the charges you're being tried for.
- Don't you believe me, sir?
- Yes, I do, but who else will?
You've got no witnesses.
Besides, such charges against an officer
would only antagonize the court.
When we get clear of this,
I'm going into the story of that patrol again.
Sir, in my case, Captain Renouart
had the sergeant draw lots.
I was picked purely by chance.
You're lucky. Look at me.
I was just picked because Captain Sancy
said I was a social undesirable.
Me, a social undesirable, Colonel.
- I didn't act like a coward.
Picking by lots — is that fair?
- Neither did I! Major Vignon —
Gentlemen! You've all
got to understand that the reason
you were picked is immaterial.
Whatever the reason,
you're on trial for your lives.
Stick to the stories you've told me...
and don't let the prosecutor
shake you out of them.
Now remember, you'll be soldiers
in the presence of superior officers.
So act like what you are — soldiers.
And brave ones at that.
Now, I've been in the room
you'll be sitting in.
The afternoon sun will be in your faces...
so don't let it seem as if you're
dropping your eyes in a hangdog manner.
When you answer questions,
look thejudges in the eye.
Don't whine, plead or make speeches.
That's myjob.
Simple statements — short...
but make them so they can be heard
all over the room.
And try not to repeat yourselves.
I'll do that f oryou when I sum up.
Now, we haven't much time.
The court-martial begins in about an hour,
and I've got notes to look at.
Good luck.
- Thank you, sir.
- Colonel, sir.
On the left, ho!
Detail, halt!
Prisoners, right heel!
On the left, ho!
Left face!
The court-martial is open.
The prisoners may be seated.
This is a general court-martial.
We shall therefore dispense
with unnecessary formalities.
These men are charged
with cowardice in the face of the enemy...
and will be tried for that offense.
- Mr. Prosecutor.
- Call the accused — Private Ferol.
Mr. President.
Will the prosecutor question the witnesses
without even reading the indictment?
Please don't take up the court's time
with technicalities.
The indictment is lengthy,
and there's no point in reading it.
The defense has a right to know
the exact accusations —
The indictment is that the accused showed
cowardice in the face ofthe enemy...
during the attack on the Anthill.
Proceed, Mr. Prosecutor.
Call the accused — Private Ferol.
- Private Ferol.
- Yes, sir?
Were you in the first wave
during the attack on the Anthill?
Yes, sir.
- Did you refuse to advance?
- No, sir.
- Did you advance?
- Yes, sir.
How far did you advance?
To about the middle
of no-man's-land, sir.
Then what did you do?
There were machine-gun bullets
landing all around.
Answer the question.
What did you do?
Well, I saw that me and Meyer, sir —
I didn't ask you what you saw.
The court has no concern
with your... visual experiences.
- My what, sir?
- Prisoner will reply to the question.
Yes, sir. What question was it?
You advanced to the middle of
no-man's-land. What did you do then?
- Then, sir?
- Did you go back or forward?
I went back, sir.
In other words, Private Ferol,
you retreated.
Yes, sir.
That's all.
The accused may return to his seat.
Just a minute.
Mr. President, I'd like
to question the witness if I may.
- Proceed, Colonel.
- Thank you.
Now, Private Ferol, when you reached
the middle of no-man's-land...
- were you alone with Private Meyer?
- Yes, sir.
Well, what happened to the rest
of your company?
Well, I don't know, sir.
I guess the rest of them
had been killed or wounded.
And you found yourself in the middle
of no-man's-land alone with Private Meyer.
Yes, sir.
Why didn't you attack the Anthill
single-handed?
Why didn't you storm the Anthill alone?
Just me and Meyer?
You're kidding, sir.
Yes, I'm kidding, Private Ferol.
Thank you. That's all.
I don't see the point
of this line of questioning.
Well, I'm attempting to indicate, sir...
the utter absurdity of the line of questioning
used by the prosecutor.
Mr. Prosecutor.
So you freely admit, Private Ferol,
that you retreated.
Yes, sir. Me and Meyer both.
I knew we should've took Anthill,
but we came on back.
That's all.
The accused may return to his seat.
Private Arnaud, did you advance?
Yes, sir, until I was ordered
back to the trenches by Captain Renouart.
How far did you advance?
Into the wire, sir.
The, uh, enemy wire, I suppose.
No, sir. It was our wire.
You mean to tell me that you didn't
advance any further than our wire?
No, sir, I didn't.
How far would you say that was?
How many meters?
Well, I advanced as far as I could.
Not many.
"Not many."
Now, Private Arnaud,
before you were ordered back...
did you urge your fellow soldiers forward?
Most of them were dead or wounded before
they got three steps beyond the trenches.
Reply to the question.
I didn't urge them on. No, sir.
Thank you.
Private Arnaud —
At ease, please.
Aside from your sad failure to give throat
to spirited battle cries...
was your behavior different in any respect
from that of the other men in your company?
Objection. That's a matter of conjecture.
Sustained.
Did any men in your company
get beyond our wire?
No, sir.
Is it true that you've been
designated a coward...
simply and purely because you drew
a slip of paper marked "X"?
- Yes, sir.
- I don't see that that's significant.
It's accepted practice in the French army
to pick examples by lot.
And since this entire company
advanced only a few meters...
picking by lot
was eminently fair in this case.
Well, I'd like to point out that this soldier
has distinguished himself ...
in some of the bloodiest battles
of the war.
With the court's permission...
I'll read citations f or bravery
that he's already earned on two occasions.
First, citations in the Orders in the Army
for bravery —
That's immaterial, Colonel.
The accused is not being tried
for his former bravery...
but for his recent cowardice.
Medals are no defense.
May I call witnesses to his character?
You may not.
But you may call witnesses to the effect
that he reached the German wire.
Mr. President,
no one in the entire regiment...
got anywhere near the German wire,
including myself .
Call the next accused...
if you're through, Colonel.
Thank you.
Prisoner may return to his seat.
So you never even left the trenches.
- No, sir.
- That's all.
Corporal Paris,
why didn't you leave the trenches?
Major Vignon was shot, and he fell back
on top of me, sir, and knocked me cold.
And were you lying unconscious
in the trenches during the entire attack?
Yes, sir.
That's all.
Have you any witnesses to that?
No, sir. I guess everybody
was too busy to notice me.
And there were so many others
lying dead anyway.
- But you have no witnesses.
- No, sir.
I only have a rather large cut
on my head, sir.
That could have been self-inflicted later.
- Thank you. You may stand down.
Mr. Prosecutor,
you can make your plea now.
Gentlemen of the court...
this case speaks for itself .
All of us witnessed
the regrettable attack yesterday morning.
And I submit that that attack...
was a stain on the flag of France...
a blot on the honor...
of every man, woman and child
in the French nation.
It is to us that the sad, distressing...
repellant duty falls, gentlemen.
I ask this court
to find the accused guilty...
and impose the penalties prescribed
by the Code of Military Justice.
Thank you, Mr. Prosecutor.
Colonel, would you like
to make your plea?
Gentlemen of the court,
there are times when I'm ashamed...
to be a member of the human race...
and this is one such occasion.
It's impossible for me to summarize
the case for the defense...
since the court never allowed me
a reasonable opportunity to present my case.
Are you protesting
the authenticity of this court?
Yes, sir.
I protest against being prevented
from introducing evidence...
that I consider vital to the defense.
The prosecution presented no witnesses.
There has never been a written indictment
ofcharges made against the defendants.
And lastly, I protest against the fact...
that no stenographic records
of this trial have been kept.
The attack yesterday morning
was no stain on the honor of France...
and certainly no disgrace
to the fighting men of this nation.
But this court-martial is such a stain
and such a disgrace.
The case made against these men
is a mockery of all human justice.
Gentlemen of the court...
to find these men guilty...
would be a crime
to haunt each of you...
till the day you die.
I can't believe
that the noblest impulse of man —
his compassion for another—
can be completely dead here.
Therefore, I humbly beg you...
show mercy to these men.
The accused will be escorted
back to the guardroom.
The hearing is closed.
The court will now retire to deliberate.
There will be a guard of six men under arms —
rifles loaded, bayonets fixed —
two men to each prisoner.
Any sign oftrouble,
the prisoners will be instantly covered.
And if the trouble doesn't subside at once,
the prisoner will be shot on the spot.
Everything must go off without a hitch
with the least possible delay...
but it shouldn't be hurried.
There must be no fumbling around.
I've been put in charge
and made personally responsible...
for any lack oforder or for any mistakes.
But you can take it from me that I shall
pass on any blame — and with interest —
to any one of you who fails in his duties.
Execution will take place at 7:00
according to the verdict of the court-martial.
Detail, attention! Dismissed!
This is compliments of General Mireau.
- Duck.
- Well, tell him thanks.
Oh, don't blame me, soldier.
Hey, ugly, what are we supposed
to eat this with — our fingers?
The guard says you can't have
any knives or forks.
Is this supposed to be
our last meal or something?
It isn't "supposed to be" our last meal.
It is our last meal.
Hey, this duck is terrific.
You suppose they put anything in the food?
First they poison us, then they shoot us?
I think they put something in it.
Like what?
Like, uh — Like something
or make us groggy or something.
What would be wrong with that
if they did?
Maybe nothing foryou,
but I'm gonna get out of this somehow...
and I don't wanna be drugged.
How are you gonna get out —
chew your way through that stone wall?
Arnaud.
Colonel Dax, he'll-he'll —
he'll see us through.
Listen, we gotta get out of here. They're
gonna kill us in a few hours if we don't.
- Have you got an idea?
- No, but there's gotta be a way.
How many guards
you think they've got out there?
They may have a couple of squads.
That's what it sounded like this morning.
- Maybe they're some of our friends.
- That's the Third Battalion.
Anyway, right now, we have no friends.
Why kid yourself?
We're not gonna get out ofthis.
Maybe you're not, but I am.
I'll guarantee you of that.
You see that cockroach?
Tomorrow morning, we'll be dead
and it'll be alive.
It'll have more contact
with my wife and child than I will.
- I'll be nothing, and it'll be alive.
Now you got the edge on 'im.
Good evening, my sons.
I'm Father Dupree.
Is there any news?
Yes. I'm afraid I bring you
very bad news.
You must prepare yourselves for the worst.
Colonel Dax asked me to tell you so.
Oh, mercy! No!
He's been in telephone contact
with army headquarters...
but unable to speak to General Broulard
or, for that matter, to anyone in authority.
- Same way at Division.
No one wants to be found.
- How much time do we have?
- You have plenty oftime yet.
Certainly more than enough
to prepare yourselves.
- In nomine Patris...
- In the name of the Father —
et Filii, et Spiritus Sancti.
Amen.
Father, will you take
this letter for me, please?
- Of course, my son.
- It's to my wife.
She won't understand this,
and I tried to explain it to her.
I'll see that she gets it.
Do you want me to hearyour confession?
Well, Father, to tell you the truth,
I'm not very religious.
I know you're trying to help,
and I appreciate it...
but if I started praying now,
I'd feel like a hypocrite.
Oh, that's an error, my son.
God is always ready
to listen to your prayers.
All right, Father.
- Will you please hear my confession now?
- Yes.
Have faith in your Creator, my son.
Death comes to us all.
In the name ofthe Father
and of the Son and of the Holy Ghost.
That's really deep.
"Death comes to us all."
That really is deep.
Say, Ferol, what's the matter—
afraid your luck isn't going to hold out?
Well, look. This is — This is my religion.
O Great Bottle, forgive me my sins,
for now I lay me down to sleep, Bo peep.
May I drink of you first?
Thank you. Amen.
I understand your anguish, my son...
but you must not let it
harden your heart.
May I tell you something, Father?
Back in my hometown,
there was a certain little café...
with an amusing sign over the bar.
It read, "Do not be afraid
to ask for credit...
for our way of refusing is very polite."
- Come on, Arnaud, sit down. You're drunk.
- Oh, Paris, leave me alone.
Come on. Come on, sit down.
And you, get out of here
with your sanctimonious pat answers.
What are you hanging around for —
to torture us?
- No. To help you with all my power.
- Your power? You have no power!
- Come on, Arnaud, take it easy.
- No, but God has power.
- Does he? What a laugh!
- You can be saved.
Saved? I'll be saved!
Cut it out, Arnaud!
Arnaud!
Arnaud.
Father, get a doctor. Quick.
That should keep him quiet long enough.
That's a nasty skull fracture though.
He may not live out the night.
What are we supposed
to do with him?
My advice is to tie him to a stretcher
so that he won't slip when you tilt it vertically.
Surely they won't execute a man
in that condition.
I'm sorry, Father.
The sentence will be carried out.
I've already checked
with the general on it.
If he's still alive in the morning...
pinch his cheeks a couple oftimes
before you take him out on the field.
It may make him open his eyes.
The general wants him to be conscious.
- Yes?
- Lieutenant Roget reporting, sir.
- Come in, come in.
Sergeant Boulanger said
that you wanted to see me, sir.
Yes, Lieutenant.
Looks as if we have a pretty unpleasant thing
on our hands in a few hours, doesn't it?
- You mean the execution, sir.
- Yes, I mean the execution.
Yes, sir. It's very unfortunate.
Oh, very unfortunate.
That's just how I feel about it.
None of us are happy about it, sir.
How'd you happen to pick Corporal Paris?
- Well, I — I had to pick somebody, sir.
- That's right. You did.
Of course, you had no personal motive
in picking Paris, did you?
Oh, no, sir.
You picked him because
he was a coward, didn't you?
- Well, did you or didn't you?
- Oh, yes, sir, I did.
Well —
Like you say,
somebody had to be picked.
- Oh, it was quite a problem, sir.
- Yes, I have the same kind of problem.
I have to pick someone to be in charge
of the firing squad tomorrow.
Do you have any objections
to taking the job?
- Me, sir?
- Yes, you.
- Well —
- What's the  matter? Don't you feel well?
Well, no — Yeah, I-I feel all right, sir.
- It's just that I —
- Is it too hot in here?
- Would you like me to open a window?
- No, sir. No, sir.
We ll, it's — It's just that I've  neve r be en
in charge of a firing squad before, sir.
Oh, there's nothing to it.
First, you help the sergeant
tie the men to the posts.
Of course , you offer the men blindfolds.
And, we ll, if they want them,
you tie them on, see ?
Now, you — you take your position
with the firing squad...
you raise your sword —
"Ready, aim, fire."
Then you draw your revolver out,
you walk forward...
and put a bullet
through each man's head.
Sir, I request that I be excused
from this duty.
Request denied.
- Colonel, I —
- You've got thejob.
It's all yours.
That's all, Lieutenant.
- Colonel, if you could just —
- That's all, Lieutenant!
- Yes?
- Excuse me, sir. Colonel Dax?
- Yes.
My name is Rousseau, sir,
Captain ofArtillery.
What is it, Captain?
I have something to tell you, sir, that may
have a great bearing on the court-martial.
Come in, Captain.
- Well, Colonel, good evening.
- Good evening, sir.
- Good evening. Come and sit down.
- Thank you, sir. I —
I am really sorry
to intrude on you in this way.
Not at all.
Always delighted to see you, Colonel Dax.
- Will you have a cigar?
- No, thankyou, sir, but —
- Well, I —
- I think you'll find it delicious.
I must apologize for not inviting you
to join the party downstairs to night...
but I'm afraid that it's, uh,
a dress affair.
Well, thank you, sir, but I must confess
that, uh, this is not entirely a social visit.
Oh, come, Dax, let's not
go over all that ground again.
Though, uh, I must admit that,
judging from the casualties...
the efforts of your regiment
must have been considerable.
Now, how can you understand that
and allow these men to be shot tomorrow?
Oh, come, Colonel. You're choosing
to take a rather simple view of this thing.
The attack was impossible from the start.
The General Staff must have known that.
Colonel Dax, we think we're doing
a good job running the war.
You must be aware of the fact
that the General Staff...
is subject to all kinds of unfair pressures
from newspapers and politicians.
Maybe the attack against the Anthill
was impossible.
Perhaps it was an error of judgment
on our part.
On the other hand, if your men had been
a little more daring, they might have taken it.
Who knows? In any case...
why should we have to bear any more
criticism for failure than we have to.
Aside from the inescapable fact that a good
many of your men never left the trenches...
there's the question of the troops' morale.
Don't forget that.
- The troops' morale?
- Certainly.
These executions will be a perfect tonic
for the entire division.
There are few things more fundamentally
encouraging and stimulating...
than seeing someone else die.
- I never thought of that, sir.
- You see, Colo nel, troops are like children.
Just as a child wants his father to be firm,
troops crave discipline.
I see.
And one way to maintain discipline
is to shoot a man now and then.
May I ask...
do you sincerely believe
all the things you'vejust said?
It's been a pleasure
discussing this with you, Colonel...
but I'm afraid that I'd better
be getting back to my guests.
Forgive me for having kept you
from your party.
Oh, by the way, sir,
have you heard that General Mireau...
ordered his own battery commander,
Captain Rousseau...
to open fire on his own positions
during the attack?
Well, of course the captain refused
without a written order...
but General Mireau demanded that he
commence firing on our own trenches.
Again Rousseau refused
without an order in writing...
but again he was ordered,
and again he refused —
all in front of witnesses.
Do you actually believe
this fantastic story?
Here are copies of the sworn statements
from all the principals involved —
Battery Commander Rousseau,
Captain Nichols, the artillery spotter...
the telephone clerk and, uh,
my own deposition.
What has all this got to do with the charge
against the condemned prisoners?
A general in a tantrum over the failure
of an impossible attack...
orders his artillery to fire on his own men.
Now, this same officer on the same day...
orders a court-martial in which
three of his men are sentenced to be shot.
General, what would your, uh, newspapers
and your politicians do with that?
Colonel Dax, are you trying
to blackmail me?
Sir, that's an ugly word,
but you are in a difficult position.
Too much has happened.
Someone's got to be hurt.
The only question is who.
General Mireau's assault
on the Anthill failed...
and his order to fire on this own troops
was refused.
But his attempt to murder
three innocent men...
to protect his own reputation
will be prevented by the General Staff.
Will you pardon me, Colonel Dax?
I've been rude to my guests too long.
Detail, halt!
Order arms!
Fall out!
Courage, my son.
The worst is over.
Good morning, Paris.
Good morning, Sergeant.
- How are you today?
- Not too bad.
How are you?
You missed some good chow
in here last night.
What'd you have?
Have you got a drink for us?
Take a swig of this.
It just occurred to me —
A funny thing.
I haven't had one sexual thought
since the court-martial.
It's pretty extraordinary, isn't it?
- Pull yourself together. Act like a man.
- Listen, Paris.
- Are you listening to me?
- Yes.
There will be a lot of dignitaries,
newspapermen out there.
You've got a wife and family.
How do you want to be remembered?
I don't wanna die.
Many of us will bejoining you
before this war's over.
I don't care.
I don't wanna die.
Please save me, Sergeant.
I can't save you. No one can now.
This is the last decision
you'll have a chance to make on earth.
You can pull yourself together, act like a man,
or we'll have to drag you out of here.
In the end, it'll all be the same.
It's up to you.
Well, let's get busy.
You and Ferol take your coats off.
It's no use hanging around here.
...with the help of thy grace
to do penance and to amend my life.
Amen.
Why do I have to die? For what?
Why do I have to die? Why?
I didn't do anything.
We do not question
the will of God, my son.
But I fought. I fought.
I fought on the battlefield.
Why don't they die?
Why not put them to death?
You showed courage
in the face of the enemy, my son.
Show it now before your own troops.
But I'm scared. I'm scared.
Oh, Father, I'm scared. Oh, my God.
Courage. Brace yourself, man.
Brace yourself .
He said, "This day,
thou shalt be with me in paradise."
- Really, Father?
- Yes.
Really, Father?
I don't understand why—
I'll never see nobody again, Father. Please.
Courage, man. Brace yourself.
- I can't help it.
- Brace yourself.
I can't help it, Father.
O God, O Almighty God —
Oh, Christ! Christ!
Grant courage to this man
who is about to die.
Strengthen me, God!
Please strengthen me!
Why do I have to die, Father?
About face!
Secure prisoners!
Detail, attention!
Forward march!
Detail, halt!
Left face!
Please don't.
Please choose me to —
"In the name of the French People...
"Corporal Philippe Paris...
"Private Maurice Ferol...
"and Private Pierre Arnaud...
"of the 701 st Regiment...
"having been found guilty of cowardice
in the face of the enemy...
"are to be executed by rifle fire immediately...
in accordance with the judgment
of the military court-martial."
Right face!
Forward hut!
...and blessed are thou amongst women.
- Do you want a blindfold?
- Blessed art thou —
Yes, Lieutenant. Please.
I don't wanna die.
Do — Do you want a blindfold?
No.
I'm sorry.
Ready!
Aim!
- Fire!
I'm awfully glad
you could be there, George.
This sort ofthing
is always rather grim.
But this one had a kind ofsplendor to it,
don't you think?
I have never seen an affair of this sort
handled any better.
The men died wonderfully.
There's always that chance
that one ofthem will do something
that will leave everyone with a bad taste.
This time, you couldn't ask for better.
Yes?
Yes, Colonel?
You wanted to see me, sir.
Oh, yes, yes.
Come in, Colonel. Come in and sit down.
Oh, Colonel Dax,
your men died very well.
- Would you like some coffee, Colonel?
- No, thank you, sir.
Oh, by the way, Paul,
it's been brought to my attention...
that you ordered your artillery
to fire on your own men
during the attack on the Anthill.
- I did what?
- Who told you that?
- Colonel Dax came to me last night
with the story.
Colonel Dax, I've always known
that you were a disloyal officer...
but I never dreamed that you would
stoop to anything so low as this.
General, I have sworn statements
from Captain Nichols, your artillery spotter...
Captain Rousseau, the battery commander
who refused your order.
I think it's infamous,
absolutely infamous.
Then there's no truth at all
to the charge made by Colonel Dax?
I don't see how you could
even ask me that.
You cannot imagine how glad I am
to hear that, Paul.
I'm certain that
you'll come through it all right.
- I'll come through what?
- There will have to be an inquiry.
- An inquiry?
- But it won't amount to much.
- Those things never do. The public forgets.
- "Public"?
You've got to have the right
to clear your name.
You cannot allow such vile insinuations
against your character to go undenied.
So that's it.
You're making me the goat —
the only completely innocent man
in this whole affair.
I have only one last thing
to say to you, George.
The man you stabbed in the back
is a soldier.
Well...
had to be done.
France cannot afford to have fools
guiding her military destiny.
I'm grateful to you, Dax, for having
brought this matter to my attention.
Colonel Dax, how would you like
General Mireau'sjob?
- His what, sir?
- His job.
Let me get this straight, sir.
You're offering me
General Mireau's command?
Come, come, Colonel Dax.
Don't overdo the surprise.
You've been after thejob from the start.
We all know that, my boy.
I may be many things, sir,
but I'm not your boy.
Well, I certainly didn't mean to imply
any biological relationship.
- I'm not your boy in any sense.
- You trying to provoke me, Colonel?
- Why should I want to do that, sir?
- Exactly.
It would be a pity to lose your promotion
before you get it...
a promotion you have
so very carefully planned for.
Sir, would you like me to suggest
what you can do with that promotion?
Colonel Dax! You will apologize at once,
or I shall have you placed under arrest!
I apologize for not being
entirely honest with you.
I apologize f or not revealing
my true f eelings.
I apologize, sir,
for not telling you sooner...
that you're a degenerate,
sadistic old man...
and you can go to hell before I apologize
to you now or ever again!
Colonel Dax, you're a disappointment to me.
You've spoiled the keenness of your mind
by wallowing in sentimentality.
You really did want to save those men...
and you were not angling
for Mireau's command.
You're an idealist, and I pity you
as I would the village idiot.
We're fighting a war, Dax,
a war that we've got to win.
Those men didn't fight,
so they were shot.
You bring charges against General Mireau,
so I insist that he answer them.
Wherein have I done wrong?
Because you don't know
the answer to that question...
I pity you.
Thank you. Thank you, thank you.
Now, gentlemen, we have a little
special entertainment foryou.
Sort of a — sort of a little diversion
as it were.
And as my wife always says,
"What is life without a little diversion?"
Now, gentlemen, I give you
our latest acquisition from the enemy.
- From Germany.
The land of the Hun.
Gentlemen, a little pearl washed ashore
by the tide ofwar.
Sag den Herrschaften guten Tag.
- Guten Tag.
Hey! Talk in a civilized language.
- It's true the little lady has her limitations.
As a matter of fact,
she has absolutely no talent at all —
except, that is,
well, maybe a little natural talent?
The little lady can't dance,
she can't tell any jokes...
and she can't balance rubber balls
on her little nose.
- Ah, but she can sing like a bird.
She has a throat of gold.
- Come on, baby!
- Come on, honey! Sing us a song!
- Come on, honey! How about a song?
Come on, baby!
Sing us a song!
Louder! Louder!
- ♪♪ [Singing "The Faithful Hussar"
in German]
- Sir.
- Yes, Sergeant?
We have orders
to move back to the front immediately.
- Give the men a few minutes more, Sergeant.
- Yes, sir.