sync.gioni666
You know, sometimes it seems like
life is all planned out.
There's no choice in the matter,
We're all gonna end up in the same place,
whether we like it or not.
But sometimes things aren't so simple,
You can end up hurting the people
you love the most,
betraying the people
you want to come throughfor,
That's not me,That's my best friend, Steve,
We've been best friends since third grade,
when he punched this kid, Billy Utsch,
for slamming a locker door on my head.
That's me,
I'm Darren Shan, and this is my story,
Oh, and, trust me,
spending this much time in a coffin
was never part of my plan,
Guess I'm just lucky,
Up until recently,
my life was pretty good.
I was popular enough,
I got good grades,
'cause my allowance was tied to it.
-A's! I Iove you. I Iove you.
-Yeah, that's the boy. That's the boy.
-Hey, you.
What's up, D?
And I had some coolfriends,
Hey, what's up?
Uh, not including that dude,
I mean, we were friends infifth grade,
but he'd become kind of a freak.
See, that used to matter to me,
There was one thing in my life
that was a bit insane, onefriend.
-Hey.
-My bestfriend.
-Let's cut, all right?
-What?
No, we're here. CIass is starting, man.
AII right, folks.
What you got for me?
Okay, Iisten,
I cannot deal with that jerk today.
AII right, Mr Perfect, come on, take a risk.
Take a risk. Come on!
So, hey, I'm thinking about moving
to Mexico. You want to go?
Yeah, sure. Why not?
Yeah, you're not going anywhere,
Mr Perfect.
Oh, shit.
Hey, man, I bet you can't hit that Iight
from all the way back here.
What? No, we're gonna get busted.
"Steve, we're gonna get busted."
-Hey!
-Rock. Come on.
And so the Mutually Assured
Destruction policy of the Cold War...
...was just that. Mad.
What the heck is that?
I'm so sorry.
It's that Steve. It's that damn Steve.
Uh...
Did Darren tell you he got an A
on his math test?
Yes, he did, honey. Go to your room.
You are not going to be friends
with that Steve any more!
Mom, I'm not five years old.
You can't tell me who I can
and can't be friends with.
You are on a good path, Darren,
and that Steve is knocking you
right off that path.
-What path?
-The path to a happy, productive Iife.
To a good college, a great job
and a family of your own.
A happy, productive Iife.
College, job, family!
And one day, if you're really Iucky,
you'II be standing here
yelling at a teenager of your own!
College, job,family!
College, job, family! It's not that hard!
Darren, are you Iistening?
So, wait. You...
What, you told your parents you're not
gonna be friends with me any more?
Yeah, but, I mean, it doesn't mean anything.
We're still Iike best friends.
Okay, Iike what, secret best friends?
Yeah, kind of.
I mean, no, it's Iike...
-Look, I don't care what they say.
-Bullshit.
You do care what they say.
You do whatever they say.
That's just who you are.
You never stand up for yourself
or anybody else.
Maybe your parents are right.
Maybe you shouldn't be friends with me.
I'm nothing. I'm garbage.
You're not garbage.
You're my friend. You're my best friend.
Whoa!
"Cirque du Freak. One night only.
The world's greatest freak show.
"Five hundred years." What the heck?
Dude, that Iooks awesome.
I can't go, though.
I'm grounded for two months.
Right. And we're also not friends any more.
What's this?
A freak show? This is illegal.
I hope you weren't thinking
of attending this.
Because the idea of taking
a group of disgusting,
weird, deformed people and exploiting them
for money,,, Not in our town,
I'm assuming no one in this class
would actually go to this.
Hey. You know that means something
when the moon Iooks Iike that.
-I read about it...
-In one of your vampire books?
I shouldexplain,
Steve was obsessed with vampires,
andl, on the other hand,
was obsessed with spiders,
I don't know why, It was just like
it was in our blood or something,
"Back in three seconds"?
One, two, three. It's been three seconds.
Uh...
Okay.
I guess they want money.
Hey, I need two tickets, please.
Hey! Hey!
Hey, come on.
I gave you the money, give me the ticket.
Ow! Whoa!
-Holy crap!
-God, what was that?
Hey, come on!
And it's gone.
-You okay?
-Yeah.
Hello?
Are you boys 21 ?
Are you 21 ?
Say yes.
-Yeah.
Good. You don't have
a tendency towards panic,
sudden cardiac arrest or crippling anxiety,
do you?
Say no.
-No.
AII right, then.
Go ahead in. Show is about to start.
Welcome.
Welcome to the Cirque du Freak,
the oldest continuously operating
freak show in the Western hemisphere.
We have toured for 500 years,
bringing the bizarre
to generation after generation.
May I present the Wolfman!
No sudden noises.
Dude, he totally just scratched his balls.
No!
-Call an ambulance!
-It's okay. That's not necessary.
Good boy.
And stay.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the enchanting recycling queen,
Corma Limbs.
And now our resident hunger artist,
AIexander Ribs!
Freaky-freak, freak for freak freak.
Oh, Iook, a candy corn.
And next, Gertha Teeth!
And Rhamus Twobellies!
I have arrived!
Hey, nice bike!
Come on. That is so rude.
And next, Evra the Snake Boy!
Stay, Bippo.
So, I'm Evra Von Britow,
and we are Serpentine.
Who's "we"?
There'II be some CDs for sale in the Iobby
immediately following the show.
Bippo! No!
Bippo, drop it, spit that out!
Yes, I'm glad you're all enjoying
this so much. It's awesome.
Evra, please be professional.
It's not my fault. I just want to play music.
-We'II discuss it Iater.
-But...
And now,
the voluptuous, the exotic,
the insightful Madame Truska!
Do we have someone brave enough
to be my assistant?
- Over here.
- Oh, yeah.
Come on. Come on.
You.
Who are you?
My name is Fred Smith. I'm from out of town.
Larten, finish your act quickly,
and Iet's Ieave this town early.
What? I have someone here tonight.
Ready for more?
Larten Crepsley and Madam Octa!
Don't go on. I have a foreboding.
You always have a foreboding, beautiful.
Larten!
Thank you, Iadies and gentlemen.
I am so excited to be here
in anonymous small town
which used to have character
but is now just a bland suburb
filled with chain stores
and surrounded by slums.
It really is a pleasure to be here.
And I am so honoured that
blah, blah, blah and so on and so forth,
et cetera, ad nauseum.
I'm afraid I have some
unfortunate news, however.
I had hoped to present my usual act,
but my spider, Madam Octa,
seems to have escaped from her cage
and is currently missing.
Use caution when retrieving your belongings
from beneath your seats.
She is very poisonous.
But not to worry.
Tonight I will perform for you
some startling illusions.
First, a rabbit from a hat.
This is Madam Octa.
Interesting fact, one bite
from this spider means certain death.
But don't worry. As Iong as I stay calm...
She's beautiful.
If I could just get my flute, that usually...
Darren. His name's not Larten Crepsley.
It's Vur Horsten. He's a vampire.
I saw his painting
in one of my vampire books.
It's him. He's got the same scars,
the same hair, the same everything.
-You seriously think he's a vampire?
-Yeah.
May I have my spider back, please?
Now, boys, vampires don't exist,
but if one did
and he thought someone knew,
he might smother them in their sleep.
That's it! Show's over!
-It's Mr Kersey.
-Come on, Iet's go.
By order of the Health Inspector,
this theatre is shut down!
Good Lord, not again.
Welcome to the Cirque.
What seems to be the problem?
We don't want you filthy people here.
That's not the problem.
The problem is you are exploiting
these poor people for profit.
Thank you.
Thank you so much for Iooking out for us.
So you gonna Iet us move in with you?
Give us jobs?
-Freak!
So clumsy.
-I felt Iike a manatee. It felt terrible.
No.
Octa.
Anyone here?
Whoa.
Hey, Octa. I'm Darren. I'm a big fan.
We can speak in private. It's the only...
We can talk in private.
The police have Ieft now.
So, this is what you've been doing
with your Iife.
You didn't Iike the act.
- I'm insane. I'm insane. I'm insane.
Well, I saw the spider bit coming.
Everybody's a critic.
It's not easy
to hold an audience's attention these days.
-To us and Charna's Guts.
Did you see that fingernail moon tonight?
The first one in 50 years.
Yes. I noticed it.
Look, Vincent's dead.
Murdered. Sucked dry by one of them,
They're after us, man. They're after us.
They're after us!
Those damn Vampaneze!
They're gonna pick us off.
First Vincent, then you, then me.
Why me before you?
Well, because I'm the toughest,
and they'II save me for Iast.
Oh. Of course, I forgot.
Well, what about the Vampire Council?
They must have something to say
about Vincent.
Yes. They say good riddance.
They're a bunch of wimps now, Larten.
They'II do anything
to avoid a war with the Vampaneze.
There are no real generals Ieft, hombre,
You and I were the Iast of the Mo-Freakins!
And to top it off, Tiny's back.
Mr Tiny? Back from the other side?
Yes! Just Iast week
he was at the Council Library,
messing with the Book of Souls,
He's trying to destroy us all!
Megalomaniac!That man's a megalomaniac!
And those murderous, scumbag Vampaneze,
they're up to something, too,
and it's all connected.
It's all connected. I can feel it!
Come with me. We can avenge old Vincent.
-Kill us some Vampaneze!
-No. I'm sorry.
No? Why?
I'm done fighting.
I Ieft that Iife for a reason.
I'm just a vaudevillian.
It's a simple Iife, and I Iike it.
Steve.
I know who you are.
I know what you are, Vur Horsten.
Who sent you? The Apocalypse Monger?
The BIood Barons?
No... No one. I... No one sent me. I just...
I have these vampire books,
and I saw a painting of him
with some girl in, Iike, 1819.
It said that she broke up with him
when she found he was a vampire.
Did you hear that, Gavner?
Missy broke up with me
because I was a vampire.
Funny, I always thought
it was the only thing she Iiked about me.
Let the kid go. Let him go.
Now, are you mentally unfit?
Didn't you hear me threaten you
at the show?
I did. It was awesome.
You see, I want this.
I want you to make me into a vampire.
I mean, vampires,
they don't take crap from anybody.
They Iive by their own set of rules.
It's true they do have their own rules.
We wrote some of them.
Yes, and one of them
is children can't become vampires.
Look, Iook, blood.
BIood.
You see, Gavner, blood.
Look, if you become a vampire,
you have to Ieave your friends
and your family.
It's deeply depressing. Trust me.
Now get out of here.
I haven't seen my dad in years.
My mom is drunk all the time.
I absolutely hate my Iife.
I never actually said it before,
but it's the truth.
This is what I was meant for.
What you're meant for?
Well, if that's the case, Iet's test your blood.
No. No.
Who sent you here?
Your blood tastes of evil.
You can never be a vampire.
What?
I have what, bad blood?
I'm never gonna forget this.
One day, I promise you,
I will hunt you down.
And what?
Kill me?
Do you know how easily I could kill you?
I could do it tonight.
I could knock you out
and Iay you in front of a bus,
and no one would ever know!
Calm down. Save that stuff for the enemy.
He's just an idiot kid,
who should be Ieaving right now
while he still can.
You're out there, man.
AII right. One for the road.
I'm headed back to the Mountain
to try to convince those old cowards
to stand up against the Vampaneze.
Gavner, if we kill one of them, it means war.
Wouldn't that be a shame?
Poor old Vincent.
You've been awfully quiet under there.
Get in.
Thanks. Thanks, I really needed a ride.
Oh, absolutely, absolutely delighted.
Are you the one known as Steve?
No, I'm the one known as Darren.
I actually had a bike.
But I'II just get it tomorrow in the daylight.
No need. It's in the trunk.
Now, if I may ask, Darren,
do you believe in the immutability
of the human soul?
The what?
So, he knows nothing of souls, does he?
Knows only of blood, huh?
The pulsing, the delicious, the ruby red.
Wow, wow, you know what?
You can just Iet me off right here.
What's the rush?
After all, didn't we save you from the scary,
scary vampire?
Doesn't act Iike Ieadership material.
Acts more Iike a bag of blood.
Are you? Huh? Bag of blood?
Shows how much you know, Murlaugh.
I think he reeks of potential.
-Ow!
-Sorry.
Souvenir.
We all have a destiny, Darren.
And with a few simple tests,
we can find out what yours is.
Wonderful to meet you, Darren.
It's Iike Iooking in a mirror.
Darren!
We'II be in touch.
Freaky dream. Freaky. Freaky.
Hey. Hey, I'm gonna try
to get you some food, okay?
Just hold on one sec. I'm gonna go
get some flies from the window sill, okay?
Hey. Why have you been acting so weird?
I'm not acting weird.
-You were just talking to your backpack.
-What?
-No, I wasn't.
-Darren, yes, you were.
-I wasn't.
-Let me... Just Iet me see it a second.
-You see? It's just my backpack.
-Seriously, stop it.
-Hey, give me my backpack, man.
-Hey, just Iet me see it.
Holy shit! That's... That's the...
Yeah, I went back to the theatre
after the show and I kind of borrowed it.
You stole from a vampire?
-Do you realise you're a dead man?
-Shh!
-You're a dead man!
-He's never gonna find me.
Okay, just...
Wait a second.
When did you go to Vur Horsten's room,
and what did you see?
AII right, I saw everything.
Steve, are you crazy?
Why would you want to become a vampire?
Listen, you can't understand.
You have everything.
What do I have? A secret best friend?
Hey, Ieave it in there, okay?
-It's fine.
-I want to see it.
Be careful. Hey, be careful, okay?
Be really careful.
This thing's even more hideous close up.
Can you just put it back now, please?
Okay, I need the pipe.
I got a B-minus in history.
No!
Oh, my gosh, what is that?
-Move!
Steve! Wait!
What's going on?
Move! Get out of the way, idiots!
Watch out! Move!
Hey! Steve, don't!
Now I got you! Hold still!
What's the matter with you?
Whose side are you on?
Hey! No! Hey!
Guys, Iook, it's in his shirt!
-Get it off me!
Oh, my God!
So what have you come
to steal from me this time? Thief!
Nothing. Nothing.
Look, Octa bit my best friend, Steve,
and he's in the hospital,
in a coma, because of me.
And I was wondering if you had an antidote.
-I do.
-Thank you.
But I only have a couple doses Ieft.
Why should I waste any
on some Iittle psychopath?
PIease, I'm begging you, okay?
Look, I'm really sorry I stole Octa.
I don't know what came over me.
-I never steal things.
-Why not?
Because it's wrong.
So then you've Iearnt
a valuable moral Iesson.
Yes, I have.
And you'II never do anything wrong again,
as Iong as you Iive.
-No, I won't.
-You see? Now you're a thief and a Iiar.
What did Mr Tiny want?
-Mr Tiny?
-The fat man in the Iimousine!
I don't know, something about souls and...
And destiny.
And he knew where I Iived.
Looks Iike you're in deep shit,
my Iarcenous friend.
Mr Tiny doesn't just take a random interest
in people.
And the people he does take an interest in
wind up dead or worse.
What's worse than dead?
Oh.
Lots of things.
AII right. I'II do it. I'II make you a bargain.
You'II become my assistant.
I'II turn you into a half vampire.
You'II be able to go out in the daylight,
very useful for me.
You'II do chores for me
and guard my coffin on the road.
And in return,
I'II try and keep Mr Tiny away from you.
Oh, and I'II save your stupid friend Steve,
despite the fact that he threatened to kill me.
-You'II save Steve?
-Why not?
If I became a half vampire,
would I have to kill people?
Interested, huh?
Vampires don't kill the people they feed on.
Vampaneze do.
Big source of controversy,
war for about 80 years, then a truce,
getting ugly again, apparently.
But time's wasting.
Want to become a vampire?
It's a Ionely Iife, but there's Iots of it.
I can't make that decision right now.
Do you wanna go home
and ask your mommy and daddy?
Do they make all the decisions
for good Iittle boys Iike you?
No, they don't.
Poor Steve doesn't have much time Ieft.
Fine, I'II do it.
To save my friend, not for any other reason.
-So get the antidote.
-Right here.
-Thank you. Thank you so much.
-First things first.
Let's test your blood.
What are you doing? I'm not gonna bite you
in the jugular. I could kill you that way.
Show me your hands.
Ow!
Mmm.
You have good blood. This will work.
AII right, hold up your hands.
-We're going to exchange blood.
-That's creepy.
I know. But that's how it's done.
This may hurt when it gets to your heart.
I feel cold.
Lick your fingers.
Whoa, is that Iike vampire power?
Do I have super-spit now?
Yes, you have super-spit.
The rest will take a while.
The rest of what? What will I be able to do?
-Can I, Iike, turn into a bat and stuff?
-No, that's bullshit.
Now hop on my back. We're going to flit.
-We're gonna what?
-Just shut up and hop on my back.
You held your breath, right?
Did I not tell you to hold your breath?
Oh... Sorry.
Hold on.
-Why didn't we just take the elevator?
-I get claustrophobic.
Strange, huh,
given where I sleep every night.
But somehow when it's my own
confined space, it's different.
He Iooks horrible.
Can you give him the antidote, please?
She really didn't Iike him.
Be careful.
Hey, what are you doing?
Shh.
That's it, right? He's gonna be better now?
That's it.
-You are insufferable.
-Back! Stay back!
Code blue,,,
You have no idea
how ridiculous you Iook right now.
Code blue,,,
AII right. If you want to pretend
this isn't happening, fine.
But being a vampire takes skill.
What is a code blue?
Code blue, code blue,,,
Try not to do something stupid
Iike kill your family.
Code blue, code blue, room 519, stat.
You are not supposed to be in here!
Code blue,
All available staff pleasereport to room,,,
It must have hurt.
-Yeah, it hurt.
-It wasn't... It wasn't fun.
-It's great you're back.
-Yeah.
-We missed you.
Well, well, well, Steve is back, huh?
So, Steve, what you got for me?
Stay away from those brownies.
They're for dessert.
-Okay. No brownies.
-Next...
Hey, Darren, do you think that this outfit
Iooks better on her, or this?
What's going on?
You Iook weird. Darren.
Darren!
Sorry.
Sorry, I...
I was just pretending to be a vampire.
Nice room.
Some excellent reading material
you have here.
Thought this was all on the Internet now.
-Mine's blocked.
-Hmm.
Don't... No, don't do that. Don't cry.
-Honestly. Stop, stop.
-No.
-I'm not crying.
-Of course not. That's what...
Look, I don't want to hurt people, okay?
I'm not Iike you.
I was this close away from killing my sister.
Perhaps you should have thought of that
before you stole my spider!
Look, I'm sorry, but you can't stay here.
You're going to have to Ieave them.
-Like forever?
-Like forever.
It's time to admit that to yourself, Darren.
But you can't just Ieave.
You're going to have to die first.
Hi, Mom. Hi, Dad.
Hmm?
Hi. Hi.
Hey, I just wanted to say that you guys
are really, really good parents.
You're doing a great job,
and I'm sorry for not doing all my chores
and for complaining so much.
-And I Iove you guys a Iot.
-We Iove you, too, sweetie.
Bye, Annie.
How old were you
when you became a vampire?
Twenty. It was 1803, the third of May.
I'd just been Ieft by my fiancee,
Hesther Collins.
I thought she was the most beautiful girl
in Baltimore.
I saw her again 60 years Iater.
She was an old crone,
but my heart still beat Iike a jackrabbit.
Wow, dumped, huh?
So big, bad, old Crepsley became a vampire
'cause he got dumped?
Have you ever been dumped?
Yeah.
Then perhaps
you should be more sympathetic.
Here it is. Drink up.
-My Iips are numb.
-Good.
-I've got pins and needles in my hands.
-Excellent.
That means it's working.
Nice night, actually.
Is that the Little Dipper or the Big one?
I can never remember.
Sorry about that.
I had to do that or they would never
believe you were dead. Don't worry.
There's no damage to your spinal cord,
and I'II sneak into the funeral home
and fix your broken neck.
Oh, and sorry about this next part.
Darren,
I hate you so much
for Ieaving me here with these idiots.
Darren. Hey, Shan!
-Ass wipe, are you in there? Darren!
-Steve.
Okay, time out, time out. Not about you.
We're all feeling grief.
Wake-y, wake-y.
Here. Fill that hole.
I can't do that.
I'm all cramped up. My Iegs are still numb.
-Can you feel this?
-Ow! What the heck?
-Do you smell a rotting corpse?
-Ha, ha, very funny.
-Get back in the grave.
-I'm not getting back in the grave.
-Don't argue with me. Get in.
-No.
Hello, old friend. OId Crepsley.
How's the scar?
Shall I give you another?
Hello, bag of blood.
You're coming with me.
Run!
You come with Murlaugh now.
You're one of us.
Not one of those filthy vampires.
Let me go!
Where are we going?
-Hold your breath.
What? No, no, no, no, no, no.
-Let's go!
-Not yet!
Don't Iook behind you.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God! Are you all right?
Come here!
Breathe.
Right over the plate!
Oh, my God.
-Do you know those guys?
-Are we there yet?
-AImost.
Where are we?
The Cirque's
winter campgrounds.
You'II be safe here if they Iet you stay.
Try to fit in.
-Come on.
-So all the freaks Iive here?
Yes.
Don't stare.
It's really...
You want to go to my tent?
You know, we can rehearse in my tent.
I'm not gonna rehearse in your tent.
It'II be great, you know.
You always have fun in my tent.
Wait here for me.
Well, I was thinking about it.
I mean, you're not gonna be
able to do this forever, right?
If you set everything up,
so I can just fill it out.
Neutral. The Cirque
has always remained neutral.
-That's how it has survived all these years.
-You'II still be neutral.
I'm not trying to drag you into anything.
I'm trying to keep myself out of it.
And why exactly do you think
Tiny wants this boy?
I'm not sure yet.
But whenever Mr Tiny wants something,
I make it my policy to try
and keep him from it.
That's a dangerous policy.
Hey, what are you doing?
That's Mr Tall's tent.
Hi, I'm Darren.
What are you doing here?
That's what I'm trying to figure out.
You can Iisten if you want.
-How much does the boy know?
-Nothing.
He's waiting by my tent
if you want to speak with him.
You know, Larten, the thing you might
not realise about children is,
they don't always do what they're told!
Rebecca. Don't you have work
you should be doing?
Yes. Sorry, Mr Tall. It won't happen again.
I mean, I don't eavesdrop on people.
-It was his idea.
-I didn't make you do anything.
Well, you couldn't make me do anything
if you tried.
-Oh, really, huh?
Enough. Rebecca,
I would Iike you to take Darren to Evra's tent.
Evra will be his roommate
while he stays with us.
You'II have to work, Darren.
Everybody here pitches in.
That's fine.
I actually worked for my dad's office
a couple of weeks this summer.
I did photocopies, so...
This is on a temporary basis, Larten.
I can't endanger everybody for your sake.
Of course. Thank you.
So, what are you doing here anyway,
with all these freaks?
Why? Do you have a problem with freaks?
No, I mean, they kind of freak me out, but...
They freak you out. CIever, really clever.
Well, I really have to get back to work.
Harkat can show you the way.
Harkat, take Darren to Evra's tent, please.
Well, you better follow him.
Okay, see you sometime.
No, I saw what you did to
my friend Steve's hand at the theatre, buddy.
Dude, I'm not giving you my hand, okay?
I'm sorry. Here.
Harkat!
You have to stop biting people,
or no one will want to be around you.
You.
Death.
Redemption. Despair.
Triumph. Disaster.
What did I say?
"Death, redemption, despair,
triumph, disaster."
Well, don't worry about it.
Go ahead, Harkat. Take him to Evra's.
And no more teeth.
You mean, this is it?
Chill in the Iaundry for a sec.
There you go. Good girl.
Good snake. Love you.
So, I guess we're gonna be roommates.
So how are you f'd up?
-F'd up?
-Freaked up.
-How... What kind of freak are you?
-Oh, I'm not a freak. I'm normal.
-You're normal?
-No. I mean, I'm half vampire,
but I'm completely normal.
You're a half vampire, but you're normal.
I Iike that.
And don't worry about, Iike,
if I'm gonna drink your blood or anything.
I'm not gonna drink anyone's blood.
What a relief. Okay, this isn't awkward at all.
This is your corner of the tent. AII right?
You do not cross over
to any other part of the tent,
except to enter and exit the tent. AII right?
And you are never, ever to touch my stuff,
especially this stuff over here.
This is my recording studio.
Oh, cool. Yeah, I...
I actually used to have a drum set,
but, you know, my parents made me
give it away, so...
-Mmm.
-Yeah.
Well, there are no parents here.
Oh...
Yeah. Shedding, itches Iike crazy.
You should actually go wash
your hand off before you get pink eye.
Did you forget to tell me you were going to
go away for a couple of days? Huh?
I can't believe you're treating me Iike this.
I've been worried sick.
Why can't you just get a cell phone?
Because vampires don't need cell phones.
"Vampires don't need this,
vampires don't need that."
I'II tell you what vampires need.
They need to Iisten.
Didn't I tell you that I had a foreboding?
And what do you do?
You show up here with that kid.
It's been a Iong night. I just flitted across
two states. I think I'II just hit the pine early.
No, wait.
You don't Iove me any more. It's my beard.
You know how I feel about you.
I just don't want to outlive anyone.
It's depressing watching people you care
about grow old while you stay young.
Have you Iooked at yourself
in the mirror Iately?
You're no kid.
Oh, no, no. I'm still angry at you. Mmm-mmm.
Mmm-mmm.
Your mouth says no,
but your beard says yes.
I can't believe he's gone, man.
-I know. He was Iike my best friend.
-No, he was my best friend.
-I knew him first.
-So what?
I thought he was a dick.
-What?
-Dude.
-Oh, my...
Here, get up before one of the teachers
see you. That kid's psycho.
Mr Leonard, what you got for me here?
Finish the quiz already?
Careful.
-Whoa!
The first step is a big one.
Oh, I know.
You miss the one known as Darren.
You feel betrayed, abandoned.
You're a Ioyal friend,
unlike him.
-Darren was a Ioyal friend.
-Oh, really?
What if I told you he's still alive?
He's taken your place,
stealing your dreams. Oh, I know.
You dream of killing people,
drinking their blood.
You dream of Ieading
a great, bloodthirsty army.
Who the hell are you?
-I'm Mr Tiny.
-Are you a vampire?
No, I'm not a vampire. I'm not a Vampaneze.
I'm an aficionado.
I want to see a marvellous war.
What do you want from me, you freak?
I'm not a freak. I despise freaks.
Can a freak travel back and forth
between Iife and death?
I think not.
Can a freak create new Iife
from rotting flesh and dead souls?
PIease.
Can a freak bring about the apocalypse
and rule the world?
No.
Sadly, neither can I, not without help.
I need a champion.
One of two boys, two dear friends.
And by the way, I Iove your DNA.
You care for a pancake?
-No, I can't. I'm...
-We know what you are.
You're bad news. That's what.
But nothing I couldn't deal with
in just about two bites.
Don't mind him. He just needs some Ex-Lax.
-Welcome to the Cirque.
-Thank you.
Would you Iike to eat one of my hands?
I can grow them back.
Yeah, they are delicious.
Hey, Vampelina.
Come on,
we gotta go clean out Wolfie's cage,
and then Crepsley Ieft, Iike,
a Iist of stuff for you to do for him.
It Iooks Iike you're Crepsley's bitch now.
-Evra.
-What?
Okay, so you guys are gonna do it. And go.
I can't believe
the tiny people eat these rats.
They'II eat you
if you don't watch out.
Don't!
So where do you come from anyways?
I guess I could probably, Iike, open this up,
and you'd probably turn into dust
or something, huh?
You wouldn't Iike that now,
would you, Dracula?
Who's the boss now, baby?
Okay. Concentrate now.
How hard can it be to flit?
Ow. Perfect.
What's the point?
-I'm just not that much of a freak.
-Gertha, you're a major freak.
Sorry, you're not my type.
Do you ever miss your family?
Not really.
I joined the Cirque when I was two.
Two days old, that is.
Mr Tall found me in a dumpster.
So I guess this is my family.
Dumpster baby,
oh, dumpster baby
I wanna be your dumpster baby
No.
Hey, thisis Steve,You know what to do,
-What are you doing?
-Oh, nothing.
May I see it?
-Yeah, I guess.
-I've always wanted one of these.
Hey! What are you doing?
We must be very careful
who we talk to, Darren.
Go to your tent and stay there with Evra.
Yes. I have returned.
I have returned!
Unacceptable. Unforgivable.
To blood a child?
By the way, is he drinking enough blood?
-He's not drinking any blood.
-Not drinking blood?
Crepsley, don't you know he has to?
He must.
Or perhaps you're worried
he'II Iove it too much.
-He might be Vampaneze at heart.
-You'd Iike that.
You've been favouring them
for the Iast 1 00 years.
On the contrary, I'm strictly neutral,
Iike the Cirque.
Correct, Mr Tall?
Correct.
Then tell us why you want him.
It's one of your self-fulfilling prophecies,
isn't it?
Well, one does dream of the cataclysm.
This truce may not Iast forever.
There might be new Ieaders.
New blood, as it were.
Perhaps a boy, a bloodthirsty boy.
It's all been written.
Then why do you care?
You're up to something, Desmond.
Me? I may write the script,
but the characters have a tendency
to do as they please.
You, for example,
have an unseemly amount of free will.
Now, Mr Tall, will you be reasonable
and give me the child?
I've always done what you ask.
I'm not one to cause trouble.
But I need to think about all this.
I won't make a decision hastily.
You know, I always get what I want,
in the end.
Keep an eye on him, my pets,
Hey, dude. Sorry, we're on our own today.
Rebecca's back in the costume shop.
-Hey.
I'm here for Crepsley's cape.
-It's that red one with, Iike, the...
-I know what Crepsley's cape Iooks Iike.
What do your friends want?
Hey! Beat it!
Does this trailer have, Iike,
a back entrance or something?
Yeah, it's right back there.
Wait, your pants are ripped.
Take them off. Try this pair on.
They fit.
-Yeah.
So, you know, Rebecca, you...
You never really told me
what you're doing here with the Cirque.
Well, Darren, since you ask,
I'm a monkey girl.
-You're a what?
-What?
Nothing, I thought you just said
you were a monkey girl.
Well, oh, yeah.
Yeah.
What does that mean?
It means I have a tail.
Do you have a problem with that?
No, because... 'Cause you're joking, right?
No, I'm not joking. I keep it wrapped up
because people kept stepping on it.
Oh.
Yeah.
Anyway, your pants Iook really good.
Yeah, I know. You picked it out.
That's really good.
Shush!
Thanks. They've been spying on me all day.
So if you were interested in a girl, okay,
and she had Iike...
Like a tail, Iet's say,
would that be a problem or...
Well, I'II put it to you this way.
If you had told me
a couple hundred years ago
that I would someday be dating a woman
with bristles on her chin,
I would have told you you were insane.
But here we are.
By the way, there's a new rule.
You're not to Ieave camp any more.
-Why not?
-Because I said so.
You're not my dad.
You can't just tell me what to do...
When was the Iast time
you were in a fight?
Uh... Second grade.
Steve's usually the one
that gets in all the fights.
Well, Steve's not here to fight for you.
And what if I wasn't, either?
What if you were alone in the dark
and someone wanted to kill you?
Rip out your heart and drink its blood?
What then?
Crepsley?
Crepsley, come on.
-You're hurting me.
-What are you going to do about it? Well?
You're soft. You're a soft Iittle boy.
They're Iooking for you, Darren.
This is not the schoolyard.
You either have to Iearn to fight or to run.
So which is it going to be?
Good. But don't use your fist.
You have something better.
Use your fingernails Iike a dagger. Watch.
Try it. Extend your fingers
and follow all the way through.
Use all your strength.
Ow!
-God, I think I broke a nail.
-You broke a nail?
You need blood.
We have a Iot of work to do.
-BIood will have blood.
BIood will have blood.
Are you ready, you filthy Iittle pig,
to be stuck?
Do you renounce Iiving with the Iiving?
Are you prepared to die with the dead?
-Steve, what the hell are you doing?
-Well, hi, Mr Kersey.
I just wanted to stop by real quick
and actually apologise for the way,
you know, I've been acting in school Iately.
It's 3:00 a.m.
My teachers troubled me when I was a Iad.
They caned me and caned me
till I was bloody.
Then one day, I took up a broken switch,
and I rammed it in my teacher's eyeball.
-Who are you?
-I'm his mentor.
You see, Steve?
Ow!
This is what Crepsley wants us to Iive with.
So, Mr Kersey, what you got for me?
-So you really don't kill people?
-No, Darren.
You just sedate them and feed a Iittle bit,
and then Ieave.
I actually developed the method.
Well, two other vampires and I,
Gavner and Vincent.
We were the freaks of the vampire world.
No one understood us.
And then they started to realise
that if you don't kill your prey every time
Iike a Iittle piggy,
then you don't get hunted down by irate
townspeople with pitchforks and torches.
And now half the vampires feed this way,
and the other half hate us.
Quiet now.
Whoa! How'd you do that?
Vampires can exhale a gas
that knocks out humans.
Really?
Drink some blood,
you'II be able to do all kinds of things.
Now, we just make a small incision
in his shoulder. Right here.
And then you take a sip.
Don't worry. He won't become a vampire
unless you exchange blood with him.
Go ahead. I had some a couple of days ago.
It's very refreshing.
No, I'm not gonna drink human blood.
Hurry up, before someone sees us.
We haven't got all night.
I'm not going to.
You have to drink blood, Darren,
or you'II die. It's as simple as that.
Damn kid is gonna get himself killed.
Larten, what made you blood him?
I needed someone to run errands for me.
Oh, come on,
you didn't need to blood him for that.
I had a feeling if I didn't,
something terrible would happen to him.
Something terrible?
As opposed to becoming a vampire?
I think you're getting Ionely.
After 200 years of Iiving alone, why on earth
would I suddenly become Ionely?
I don't know. Midlife crisis? What is it?
They're here.
Watch out!
-That's not fair.
-Back!
Darren, get out of here!
Duck!
Move.
Get in.
Psst.
Hey! Hey!
Look, I don't even Iike the Wolfman,
but that don't mean you can come in here
and beat up on a freak!
You're messing
with the wrong sideshow, baby!
-I'II bite your damn noses off!
-I'm gonna ram my head up your ass.
Stop!
There'II be no fighting here.
How dare you enter this campground?
The Vampire Council will hear of this.
Tell the Iittle vampire it's time to come home.
It's almost dawn. I have a spare coffin here.
I suggest you get some rest as well.
Aren't we gonna, Iike, double back
and attack them or something?
Do you want to stay alive?
You're not even drinking blood yet.
I doubt you'd be much good in a fight.
-Well, what if they hurt someone?
-People can Iook out for themselves.
You've been Iooking out for me.
-Why?
-Why? Because I'm an idiot, that's why.
Only an idiot would spit
in the eye of Mr Tiny.
Because he doesn't just kill people,
he brings them back, as well.
And when I finally die,
I plan on staying dead.
Life may be meaningless,
but death I still have hope for.
Life isn't meaningless.
Tell me that after 200 years of it, kid.
Good day.
- You know I never Iiked him.
- I never did, either.
- I told you when I first saw him.
- Should never have Iet him in.
We all know it's his fault.
I just can't believe
he has the nerve to walk around in here.
That poor Rebecca.
They took her? Where?
I don't know,
but they said to tell you to come home.
Which, of course, you're not gonna do.
Wait, Darren, Darren. No, buddy.
Those guys are huge, man.
-Hey, Mr and Mrs Shan. Hey, Annie.
-Steve. What are you doing here?
Well, you know, I've been thinking.
You guys probably really miss your son.
And my mom is drunk half the time,
so she doesn't really notice I'm there.
How about you guys adopt me?
No interest?
Told you they wouldn't go for it.
Hmm.
How disappointing.
So few "people" have the parenting instinct
the way I do.
Ready for the prom?
Make newfriends, but keep the old
Oneis silver and the other's gold
Hey, Octa.
Say goodbye to Crepsley for me, okay?
Tell him I'm sorry but I have to go home.
It's time, isn't it?
-Twenty-six, 27.
-Twenty-seven, 27.
-AII right, no, no. Twenty-eight.
-May I borrow a couple of these?
Don't forget to bring them back, though.
Both of them.
You're in danger, terrible danger.
Your Iife and soul are in jeopardy.
-What did I say?
-Nothing. Something about the weather.
Chance of thunderstorms tomorrow.
Don't worry. I'II stay indoors.
Applause! Applause!
Look. Little vampire.
Take a bow.
-Where are my family and my friends?
-PIease.
Must have patience. Will spoil the show.
Do you Iike? Does Murlaugh have talent?
No? What do you know about talent?
Where is Crepsley?
Too bad for Crapsley.
Because he will miss the show!
Here is freak all wrapped up tight.
And here are beloved family members.
Applause. Applause.
Hello, beloved son. Hello, Ioving parents.
Hello, cute Iittle sister. Four bags of blood.
-Don't worry. You're all gonna be okay.
-Will be better than okay.
Will be delicious!
But now, may I present
reunion with oldest friend
and blood brother,
with he that shall one day rule us all,
the one known as Steve.
Thank you! Thank you!
-Steve.
-You're alive?
You know, that was really
an asshole thing for you to do.
Make your whole family and
your secret best friend go through all that?
Look, I didn't mean to hurt anybody, okay?
Who cares what you meant to do?
What you did was take my place.
That was my dream.
-Steve, what are you doing with him?
-Who? Murlaugh?
Come on, man, he's not as bad as he Iooks.
You know, for one thing,
he didn't say I had bad blood Iike Crepsley.
And for another thing, he didn't Iie to me.
And you know what?
They think I'm awesome.
They say I have a destiny, or whatever.
Look at you.
Who wants to be a vampire anyways?
Vampires suck.
-Vampaneze rule!
-Juicy!
First guy I killed, Mr Kersey.
BIood just gets me going,
you know what I mean?
I wouldn't know. I haven't been drinking any.
I know you. AIways trying to Iook Iike
Mr Goody-Two-Shoes all the time.
I bet you'II, Iike, resist drinking blood
and resist drinking and resist drinking it,
at the Iast second
become this total bloodhound!
AII right, man, here's the deal.
See, the fat guy, he still wants you
on the team, and despite everything else,
you are still my best friend.
So I'II tell you what,
I'II make you a deal
that might just save your ass.
If you kill your family, I'II Iet the freak go.
Wait. My bad, that's backwards.
If you kill the freak, I'II Iet your family Iive.
What? Let the juicy one go?
Hey, Iook, man, it's part of the plan.
Talk to Mr Tiny.
So what do you say?
Just kill her.
Oh, yeah, you got to drink her blood, too.
You can do her in with this.
Wait!
AIIow him in, gentlemen.
I want to see this play out.
Man, that was pathetic. You're totally weak.
You need some blood.
-Murlaugh.
-Finally.
And we thought you weren't gonna show.
I hate spiders!
Darren. Come here.
Okay.
-Is that your tail?
-Well, yeah.
I'm really sorry I got you involved in this,
okay? I...
PIease stop staring.
So you really need blood?
-Yeah.
-AII right.
Can you just take a Iittle? Go ahead.
I'm offering it to you.
-Thanks. But I just can't Iose it.
-What?
Whatever's still making me human.
Darren, being human's not about
what you are. It's about who you are.
No.
He's all yours, Iad.
Good. Right in the heart.
So fair and foul a day I have not seen.
My people aren't weak Iike yours.
They will avenge me, Crepsley.
The truce, 1 00 years, is over.
The war begins.
Marvellous. Magnificent.
Really. Bravo. Bravo.
It's just Iike you said. We started the war.
It won't start a war if nobody hears about it.
Young people today
are so difficult to control.
-I hate you.
-I hate you!
I became a vampire to save you, Steve.
Thanks.
Go ahead. Just do it!
That's enough, boys.
Steve, come with me.
-Not before I kick his...
-You will behave!
It's not time for you to fight. Not yet.
-What does that mean?
-Oh, it's all written down in a book.
You do read books, don't you?
Steve.
Look, don't... Don't go.
What else am I supposed to do, man?
Live with you and a bunch of freaks?
It's too Iate now.
I have my destiny, and you have yours.
How poignant.
The parting of two dear friends.
Such sweet sorrow.
Then again,
you will come home to us one day.
My prodigal son.
After all, you are the bloodthirsty one.
No. Just because I'm a vampire
doesn't mean I'm bloodthirsty.
It's not about what you are.
It's about who you are.
Oh.
I almost forgot.
Cover yourself.
You have to teach me
how to do that someday.
Oh, I'II teach you everything, son.
AII my gibes and gambols.
Now, ready to go meet your people?
Bye, Annie.
Will it work Hypnotising them?
It works on the memories,
but not on the emotions, not really.
They'II always feel
that you're still alive, somehow.
-Well, that's good, right?
-Is it?
Hey, can I ask you something?
Can I kiss you?
Darren, I Iet you drink my blood.
Sure, you can kiss me.
Come on. We don't have all night.
I have an injured spider here.
AII right, how are we going to do this?
I can't carry the both of you.
-You carry Rebecca. I can flit now.
-Just Iike a real vampire.
Oh, Larten, you did it.
You stuck your neck out for him.
You'd think a vampire would know better
than to stick his neck out.
I am proud of you.
AII those who vote for making Darren
a member of the Cirque raise your hands.
-One hand, Evra.
-Damn it.
It's done. He will stay.
So we get to stay.
Not for Iong, I'm afraid.
You know, Crepsley, it's okay.
It's weird. I spent so much time wishing
that none of this would have happened
and that we never would have been
to the Cirque in the first place.
But now I really can't imagine my Iife
happening any other way.
Dawn's coming.
I had something made for you.
It's in your tent.
A Iittle gift.
And it's Mr Crepsley.
Because you told me to throw you.
Well, I'm sorry.
You did it, man.
Once a general, always a general.
I couldn't have done it better myself.
At nightfall, we Ieave with the boy.
I suppose we should tell him.
No, Iet's give him one day to rest.
He's earned it.
Sometimes life does seem
all planned out,
like there's no choice in the matter,
but that's an illusion,
Speakers. Tasty.
My name's Darren Shan, and I don'tjust live
with a bunch offreaks, I am one, too,
www.moviesubtitles.org