Hey, Mickey.
-Don't tell Mom.
-Don't tell me what?
Nothing. I forgot to go
to the store. No milk.
Fresh one down in the fridge.
What's that you got
behind your back?
Mom, you should've
seen his face.
You're a pushover, young man.
-Good morning, sir.
-Hey, Ben.
-Sit down.
-Sure.
-How do you feel?
-Good.
-Did you swim this morning?
-Yeah.
What are your holding
for your hundreds?
Fifty plus on the minute-thirty.
Not bad.
I can get it under 45, I think.
Can you do it in time
for the Fillmore meet?
Why?
Stanford scouts are flying down.
For the next 8 days,
I want you living in that pool.
And when you're not swimming,
I want you thinking about it.
I want you dreaming about it.
-You hear me?
-Yeah.
I don't mean to put any
undue pressure on you.
What are we talking about here,
your entire future?
Right. Right.
Go and change.
Alright. Thank you.
California boy, can l
have your autograph?
Nasty.
-Congratulations.
-Thank you.
-Nervous?
-Yeah, a little bit.
-You're gonna kick ass.
-I hope so.
That is, until I outswim
your little punk ass.
And those scouts forget your name
and grant me the scholarship.
I just remembered why
we broke up, Josh.
You couldn't handle me in bed.
No, because you're an asshole.
Ben just got good news.
The response is congratulations.
You're right.
Congratulations, dickhead.
-Let's not be mature today.
-I'm all for that.
Let's make it Opposite Day
and everybody be immature.
Hey, watch it!
Forget about it.
Hey, Dante.
He's crazy. He's a freak.
-Hey, congrats.
-Thanks.
-So...
-So?
It might actually happen?
Can you picture it?
Me in California?
-And me in Rhode lsland.
-Yeah.
-That's 3,000 miles.
-I know how many miles it is.
-I love you.
-I love you too.
Nothing is going to change that.
-I bought you something.
-What?
Open it first.
-That is so beautiful.
-You're beautiful.
-You're so beautiful.
-Thank you.
I would even be here if it
wasn't for you believing in me.
This is a ploy to get laid.
Is it working?
Excuse me?
I can't get this thing open
and I'm late for English.
Do you think you could...?
I can take a look, yeah.
They gave me the combination, but...
I don't need it. I just need...
-...that, right there.
-This?
Thank you.
Can't let you be late
on your first day.
Is it that obvious?
Thank you so much.
-Here.
-Keep it.
You never know when
I might need saving again.
I'm Madison Bell.
Ben Cronin. Hi.
What the letter for, Ben Cronin?
The letter is for swimming,
Madison Bell.
-Are you good?
-I'm okay, yeah.
See you around.
-See you.
-Bye.
-There's my swim champ.
-Mom...
Better get started with Mr. Tillman.
He's been asking for you.
Ben! Give me some good news.
Scouts are coming next week.
Girl Scouts?
No, swim scouts, from Stanford,
to see me.
I asked you to find me a woman.
It's hard to find anyone in
your age bracket still breathing.
Here you go.
I almost forgot...
That's my boy!
Anything else?
You guys okay?
-Did you miss me?
-Like crazy.
Wait. I've been thinking.
What if I didn't go to
Rhode lsland next year?
What do you mean?
What if I went to Berkeley instead?
We'd be closer when you
go to Stanford and...
-we could get an apartment.
-Amy.
-I haven't gotten in yet.
-But you will.
If you hate the idea, it's okay.
No, are you kidding?
It's a great idea.
-Really?
-Really. It's a great idea.
Morning, Benjamin.
-A little early for you, isn't it?
-Yes, it is.
I thought I'd get a little
lane time in before the rush.
Got to look good for the scouts.
Yeah, right.
I know they'll be looking at you,
but the rest of us
will be in the pool.
The more the merrier, buddy.
So... Madison Bell.
What?
She's a senior, originally
from down South.
I plan to hear that Southern accent
when she moans my name.
Or when she applies
the restraining order.
-Do you want to hear or not?
-Sure. What's up?
The reason she's up here
is her family's in Europe.
She's staying here with her cousin.
Guess who her cousin is.
-Who is her cousin?
-Christopher Dante.
You're set. He loves you.
He's gonna put in a good word.
-Do you think he would, seriously?
-He really would.
-Think about it.
-No! No!
Shit!
I'm sorry. Are you okay?
-I'm fine.
-Are you sure?
-No, don't worry about it.
-I didn't see you.
-Really, it's all right.
-Here, here.
Thanks. It's okay.
-Let me give you a ride.
-No, I'm fine.
It's the least I can do.
-I'm fine.
-Please? I insist.
-Well, if you insist.
-I do. Come on.
I wasn't looking at the road.
I thought I saw somebody I knew.
That way?
How's that for service?
You're a handy guy to have around.
Yeah, handy all over the place.
See you at school.
Handy all over the place.
What is that?
It's a boy.
Hello?
Hi, Madison. This is Ben Cronin.
You left your notebook in my car.
Pretty sharp. Got a date?
It's just pants and a shirt.
I'll be back in half an hour.
How's it going?
You don't have to be nice to me.
She's already going out with you.
No, we're not going out.
I'm just returning her notebook.
I'll take it.
No reason to hold you up.
I'm sure you've got
more important things to do.
Christopher?
Why didn't you tell me
I had a visitor?
I had to get out of there.
It's so stifling.
You okay?
Yeah. I haven't really
eaten all day.
-Here's your order.
-Thank you.
You're welcome.
So, I've been dying to know...
How come a nice boy like you knows
how to break into girls' lockers?
I didn't used to be so nice.
That's hard to believe.
It was a long time ago.
Everybody's forgotten about it,
except the cops.
You don't have to tell me.
No, I had a situation
with drugs which
turned into a situation
with stealing.
I spent 6 months in juvenile hall.
It was the best thing
that's ever happened to me
'cause they had a pool.
This shitty lab pool that
hadn't been used in years
and I got assigned to clean it.
Soon I was swimming in it
more than I was cleaning it.
It was easier for me to
jump in the pool and forget about
all the mess going on around me
and just swim.
When I play music sometimes,
I just play cello,
and I float out of my body,
above the music where no one
can touch me,
hurt me....
I can escape.
Do you want to escape?
Yeah, sometimes.
But not right now.
Right now, I like where I am.
I should tell you something.
-You have a girlfriend.
-Yeah. Amy.
-ls it serious?
-Yeah, it is.
She's the other reason
I turned my life around.
Story of my life.
Can't expect the nicest,
most handsome guy to be single too.
Don't worry about me.
I got someone waiting in New York.
A great guy.
A really good shortstop too.
The Mets are pretty interested.
The Mets? Really?
-Yeah.
-Wow!
But until we can live
in the same place,
we agreed to see other people
and that's what I intend to do.
My friend Josh
would murder me and step over
my dead body to be here with you.
Thanks, I'm not interested in Josh.
I should take you home.
-Yeah, you should.
-Yeah.
But...
I'm not ready to say goodnight.
What do you want to do?
Careful. I can't swim.
-Really?
-Yeah.
Show me how?
Yeah.
Come here.
You got to know how to float
and kick, so lean back.
Yeah... very important.
You're a natural.
-Like that?
-Yeah.
The side's right here.
That's easy.
It's okay. I want you to.
Wait, wait.
We can't do this.
It's all right.
It'll be our little secret.
Maybe not so little.
Ben!
Tell me you love me.
What?
You don't have to mean it.
Just say it for me.
I love you.
So...
-Don't think I do this all the time.
-No!
Of course not, no.
I don't want to be
a locker room joke, so...
don't tell anybody, okay?
I won't tell anybody.
Good. Still friends?
See you tomorrow.
You are so busted.
I thought you'd keep me company
in the restaurant last night.
I'm sorry. I had some homework
at Randy's.
How's his mom doing?
She broke her wrist.
Is it still in a cast?
She seemed okay.
I'm trying to...
Didn't seem like she was in pain.
That's good.
-I left you something.
-What?
It's in your locker.
I hope you like it.
-I love you.
-Yeah, I love you too.
Ben, I'm so proud of you.
I love having you in my life.
-Where will your parents be?
-Jamaica.
-Will they be gone all weekend?
-No, all week.
Nice.
I didn't hear Amy invite you.
I'm sorry, I didn't hear anyone
talking to you.
Good time on the over-sleep.
Coach is seriously pissed.
Are these for me?
They're a thank you for the card.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Way to swim, Josh!
Everybody else, keep your focus.
Focus is key.
Are you okay? What's up?
I don't know if it's
this low-carb diet I'm on,
but Ben and I are like this now
in the water.
Josh, he had a bad swim.
Why don't you give it a rest?
What's up, ladies?
What's going on? Everything cool?
-My swimming buddy.
-That's right.
-May the best man win.
-Absolutely.
There you go. I'm sorry.
Let me give you mine, buddy.
Ben, over here!
Oh my gosh!
I missed you. Where have you been?
-Around.
-Yeah?
Yeah. That's so great. Come here.
There's someone I want you to meet.
Madison?
This is my boyfriend, Ben Cronin.
Nice to meet you. Madison Bell.
Nice to meet you.
I already know all about him.
Amy can't stop talking about
her perfect boyfriend.
Even when I beg her to stop.
Excuse me. I gotta use the bathroom.
You want to hold this?
-lt was nice meeting you.
-You too.
Cronin, I'm making a video run
and you're truck's blocking me in.
I'll do it. Just one second.
I'll be right back.
I gotta get more ice first.
Keys?
Yes.
Don't we have English together?
She's really nice.
She's so sweet and uncomplicated.
Madison, this is a little
awkward for me.
We could go somewhere else.
-Not what I meant.
-I know. I'm kidding.
Is it hot in here or is it me?
I know you're tied up tonight,
but when do I see you again?
-I don't know.
-How about tomorrow?
Tomorrow's not good for me.
I should get back to the party.
By the way, do you have my panties?
-Excuse me?
-My panties.
I may have left them in your car.
Let me do it. It's acting funny.
Thank you.
You got to bring your times down.
I'm not seeing Olympic swimming.
And neither will Stanford.
I know. I've got a lot on my mind.
Sorry.
Get your head back in the game.
-Are you listening?
-Yeah.
Sorry.
If you think you'll waltz it through...
No, Coach, no!
I'll be ready on Thursday.
And whatever's going on
between you and your girl,
fix it.
Now go.
-I'm home!
-We're in here.
We?
-He's so cute.
-Yes, I know.
Happy birthday!
Those are beautiful. Thank you.
Madison brought me those.
I'll put these in water.
Surprise!
Can you excuse me for a second?
How long has she been here?
About 20 minutes. Who is she?
It's great to finally
meet your mother.
What do you mean "finally"?
You just met me.
It doesn't feel that way.
How did you know
it was her birthday?
You told me.
At the party, remember?
Madison? I think you're
misunderstanding our relationship
in a fundamental way.
-We're friends?
-Right.
Friends. Exactly.
Friends see each other and are happy
when they stop by with flowers.
What's the problem?
You're coming on strong, you know?
You didn't think so when
we were in the pool.
I have a girlfriend.
I told you I had a girlfriend.
What are you saying?
Making love to me was a mistake?
I guess I am. I'm sorry.
You want to forget about it?
Pretend it never happened?
Maybe I was wrong about you.
Madison?
You won't tell anybody, right?
Tell anybody about what?
Ben, it's not good for him.
It's not good for me either.
Yeah, but don't crap on the carpet
every time you're sick.
Got a point. Sorry, buddy.
-You going into work later?
-Yeah.
-I'll see you.
-Okay. Bye.
Ben!
Now what?
How many times have I told you
to club lock this car?
I guess I forgot. I'm sorry.
Shit, Cronin. Get a grip.
Please enter your password.
You have 81 new emails.
Picture received.
Gotcha!
So here's what I think.
When school's over, we should
go to my empty, parentless house...
I have work.
Maybe afterwards.
My shift starts at six.
Tomorrow?
Is it the meet?
I thought a little release
was supposed to help you sleep.
I just got work. I'm sorry.
I'll let you get back to it.
I'll give you a call.
-I'm Randy, a friend of Josh.
-Right.
-He's told me about you.
-Really?
-Yeah, he did.
-Cool.
Well, I'll see you.
So you and Josh? That's cool.
Could we just sit down?
I want you to know that I know.
-You know?
-I know how freaked out you are.
I know why. It's because of
the other night, right?
Yeah.
I was pushing because
it's senior year.
I was afraid of losing you, but...
but we don't have to make plans now.
We can take everything one step
at a time. I'm fine with that.
I am.
That was my whole speech.
I practiced it and everything.
I don't deserve you.
-Thank you.
-It's true.
I've been looking all over for you.
What are you doing in here?
What's going on?
You're not returning my calls.
Are you mad about Josh?
I'm late for work.
He doesn't mean anything to me.
When I'm with him,
I pretend it's you.
Wow!
Did I do something wrong? Talk to me.
I have a lot going on right now.
Maybe too much.
What don't you get?
I'm trying to drop you.
You don't mean that.
I don't know any other way
but to just say it.
I'm not with you.
I'm with Amy. Amy!
I told you this. Remember?
Sure I remember.
But I also remember
you told me you loved me.
You asked me to!
How are you feeling, sir?
Just get me some Viagra
and a nurse under 70.
Take these, please.
What's wrong?
Is it the swimming?
Pressure getting to you?
Take the pills. I'm running late.
Thank you.
I checked and re-checked
the meds before I left.
Somebody must've switched
the cups around on my cart.
Oh, Ben.
Even if I believed you,
it was your responsibility
to keep your cart with you.
You're lucky.
Mr. Tillman will recover
and no one was seriously hurt.
I'm sorry, Ben, but I have
no choice but to let you go.
I know what you're doing!
I'm telling you now
you better cut this shit out!
You should've told me
you like it rough.
This isn't a game, Madison.
You almost killed somebody.
Here's what you're gonna do.
You're gonna stop calling me,
you're gonna stop paging me.
You're gonna stop visiting me!
Okay?
If you see me in the hallway,
pass by like I don't exist.
-You got it?
-Yes.
Good girl.
I didn't know you were coming by.
-What's wrong?
-We need to talk.
Can you take a break?
No, I can't right now.
Okay. I can wait.
I'm not done till one in the morning.
-You have to rest for the meet.
-Screw the meet.
What's wrong?
We can't talk about it here.
I can skip first period
and we'll go for a drive.
-The morning, okay.
-All right.
-I love you.
-I love you too.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Why?
Excuse me?
Are those the scouts?
Good luck.
-Ben?
-Yeah?
You tested positive for steroids.
-What?
-You heard me.
Steroids are banned
at this school, Ben.
Leave the pool area. Clean out
your locker. You're off the team.
You can't do this to me!
It's a mistake. I don't take steroids!
I don't take...
You did this to yourself.
Now go pack and go home.
Where is she? Where is she?
Dude, you're losing it.
You helped her.
Screw you, Ben.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Ben Cronin has been disqualified.
Ben Cronin will not compete
in this race.
Come on.
The winner is Josh Jefferson
in lane two!
Time is 1 :33:60
Are you taking drugs again?
Would you believe me
if I said no?
This is how it started the last time.
The lying, the screwing up
in school.
Once guilty, always guilty, right?
What I need is for everybody
to just leave me alone
while I figure out how to
get my life back.
Amy?
-Are you okay?
-No.
-And you?
-I can't believe that...
-She did it.
I really think you should go.
Ben.
Ben?
-What's the matter?
-My name is not Ben.
I know that. Josh, come here.
Josh? Josh.
It's all true, isn't it?
What?
Ben was telling the truth.
You want to hurt him because
he doesn't want you anymore.
Don't say that.
I should have known.
Ben would never do steroids.
He doesn't need them.
God.
You know what? Screw you!
How about that?
Josh, get back here!
Josh, come here!
Josh!
It's okay. I want you to. Touch me.
Hold me. Actually, you can't escape.
Tell me you love me.
I have to tell you something.
-Tell me you love me.
-I love you.
Help! Help!
...a loving son, a brother,
a wonderful student, athlete
and friend.
As we remember these words,
if we die with the Lord,
we shall live with the Lord.
If we endure with the Lord,
we shall reign with him.
Let your ears be attentive
to my supplication.
I trust in the Lord;
my soul trusts in his word.
My soul waits for the Lord.
I will consent to His love.
His love is kindness and redemption.
I didn't do it.
You didn't see anyone enter or leave?
-I told you I didn't.
-No, I know.
Take me through it again.
You remember how this works.
Not that long ago.
Your prints are on the bat.
Along with the rest of the team.
I'm a simple man.
I go by the evidence.
So arrest me.
We're not there yet.
But as they say,
don't leave town.
Don't leave town.
I'm never leaving this town.
You shouldn't be in here.
If she found you, she'd kill you.
No shit.
You better come with me.
Come on.
I found this. Here you go.
-Wait! Wait!
-Go!
Christopher? Christopher?
Do you have a guest?
No, that would mean you had friends.
Who's Jake Donnelly?
I want to show you something.
-What?
-Let's go.
Come on. It's not too far.
You coming in?
You go in. I'm staying here.
Go.
-Excuse me.
-Yes.
I'm looking for Jake Donnelly.
Don't worry. I've got someone
waiting in New York.
Can I help you?
I'm sorry. I'm an old friend
of Jake's.
Why you kids don't wear
seatbelts, I don't know.
His girlfriend did.
Walked away without a scratch.
I'll let you spend time
alone with him.
Thank you.
Madison left the room like this.
She was convinced he'd come back
to her one day. Poor thing.
Just throw on his clothes
and go find her.
You take your time, okay?
Mom, I got your page. What's up?
Paramedics just brought Amy in.
Ben, they're saying
you ran her off the road.
They have a witness.
Police are looking for you.
I'm calling you a lawyer.
He can meet me at the hospital.
There's Security everywhere.
They have your picture.
-25 cents.
-Shit!
-Mom, just listen...
-Please deposit 25 cents.
Madison is responsible, okay?
-You got to protect Amy.
-Please hang up.
-Madison is coming!
Shit!
Jake Donnelly, will you
report to the nurses'station.
Paging Jake Donnelly.
Jake Donnelly, please report to
the nurses' station.
Jake Donnelly, come to
the nurses' station, please.
Paging Jake Donnelly.
Jake Donnelly, please report to
the nurses' station.
Jake Donnelly
to the nurses' station.
Jake!
Is that you?
You don't have the guts.
They think I killed Josh.
That I tried to kill Amy!
And I'm going to spend the rest
of my life in prison!
What's one more?
Don't be mad.
I did it for us.
Us?
You don't have it in you.
You couldn't hurt a fly.
How stupid do you think I am?
I don't know, baby.
How stupid are you?
These look like them?
It's them.
If everything checks out
with Ben's statement,
I'll ring your doorbell and
apologize in person. How's that?
Excuse me.
Shit!
Hey, watch the papers.
She's doing fine.
Did you find everything okay?
She can spend the night with us.
Have a safe flight.
See you in the morning.
My dad used to cheat on my mom.
It broke her heart.
I remember swearing to myself
that I'd never be like him,
and that...
when I found somebody I loved,
I would love her forever.
Never thought it was going to
happen so soon.
You're everything I ever wanted.
You're everything I ever could want.
I hate what I did and...
I got it!
Mom?
-Mom, I got it.
-Yeah.
False alarm!
Mom? Mom?
Amy!
Where are you?
See that?
You see that right there?
That's where we made love.
Madison!
Ben?
She doesn't love you like I do, Ben.
No one will ever love you
like I do.
You can stop all this
if you just admit it!
That you love me!
I can't do that.
Tell her, Ben!
Tell her you love me.
I know it!
Good going.