「良医」前情回顾\NPreviously on "The Good Doctor"...
你有什么事瞒着我吗\NIs there something you're not telling me?
当我们一起开会时\NWhen we're in meetings together,
别再说我的想法很荒谬\Ndon't ever call my ideas "Ridiculous."
别这样  我认真的\NCome on. I'm being serious.
我也是\NSo am I.
梅里尔的儿子想征求些个人建议\NMerrill's son asked for personal advice.
-他选了你  -就是说啊\N- And he picked you. - I know, right?
一个外科医生需要懂得沟通  莫菲医生能做到吗\NA surgeon needs to communicate. Can Dr. Murphy do that?
重压之下他能行吗\NCan he do that under stress?
明知别人命悬一线时\NCan he do that knowing that a human life
他能做到吗\Nliterally hangs in the balance?
谢谢你  卡卢医生\NThank you, Dr. Kalu.
不客气  这是特调咖啡\NYou're welcome. It's a special blend.
咖啡豆是我自己烘焙的\NI roast the beans myself.
一股皮革味\NSmells like leather.
没你的份  莫菲\NThen none for you, Murphy.
我不喝咖啡\NI don't drink coffee.
那在这死定了\NIt is dead in here.
所以才叫「销魂大夜班」\NThat's why they call it the graveyard shift.
我称这为「天堂」  你们是我要带的创伤新人吗\NOh, well, I call it paradise. You my trauma virgins?
莫菲医生  卡卢医生  布朗医生\NAh, Doctors Murphy, Kalu, Browne --
这是奥德丽・利姆医生\Nmeet Dr. Audrey Lim,
你们今晚的主治医生\Nyour attending for the evening.
喝咖啡吗\NCoffee?
咖啡豆是他自己烘焙的\NHe roasts the beans himself.
马屁精\NKiss ass.
急诊室\NE.R.
多久  明白\NHow long? Got it.
大家注意\NListen up, everybody!
马上会送来大批伤员\NWe got a mass cas coming in.
大巴车祸  二十四位乘客\NIt's a bus crash, two dozen passengers.
把等床位的病患全转到护理病区\NTransfer all patients waiting for beds up to the nursing units.
让维修人员把折叠床拿下来\NHave maintenance bring down cots.
把候诊室改成分诊处\NWe're gonna convert the waiting room into triage.
事没忙完  谁都不准回家\NNo one goes home till we're all clear!
呼叫所有值班人员  不管是哪个部门的\NPage everyone on call. I don't care what department they are.
今晚全都归创伤科管  戴好手套  站好\NTonight, everybody's trauma. Glove up and line up.
急救员现场已分诊\NEMTs will have triaged onsite,
送来的病患都已贴好标签\Nso the patients are gonna come in tagged.
我喜欢你们大决战前夕的一脸茫然\NI love these blank faces right before Armageddon.
谁知道创伤颜色标签\NTrauma color coding -- who knows it?
绿色代表伤势较轻  黄色代表需要观察\NGreen -- walking wounded. Yellow -- observation.
红色代表立即救治\NRed needs immediate attention.
黑色直接送入太平间\NAnd black go straight to the morgue.
好  红色标签  优先处理\NAll right, red tags, front of the line!
红色标签  优先处理\NRed tags, front of the line.
婚礼大巴爆胎侧翻了\NWedding bus blew a tire and flipped!
26岁  女性\N26-year-old female.
脖子  胸部  左臂二级三级烧伤\NSecond- and third-degree burns to her neck, chest, and left arm.
卡卢  上\NKalu, you're up.
创伤六室\NTrauma Six.
他从车里被甩出九米多高\NGuy was ejected 30 feet from the vehicle.
胸部多处挫伤\NMultiple chest contusions,
当场急性呼吸困难\Nacute respiratory distress on the scene,
瞳孔反应迟缓\Nsluggish pupillary response.
-心肺复苏做了多久  -十二分钟\N- How long have you been doing CPR? - 12 minutes.
-除颤了吗  -三次\N- Have you shocked him? - Three times.
得紧急开胸  布朗医生  这个我来\NWe got to crack him. Dr. Browne, I got this.
下个交给你  好  五区\NYou take the next one. All right, Bay Five.
异物已处理好  血也止住了\NWe secured the foreign object and staunched the bleeding,
不然碰都不能碰\Nbut didn't want to touch it otherwise.
-还好卡住她的颈动脉了  -是什么\N- Good thing. It nicked her carotid. - What is it?
就像荷兰小子堵住堤坝一样让她不会流血而死\NRight now it's a little Dutch boy keeping her from bleeding out.
脉搏血氧值下降到87了\NPulse ox is dropping. She's at 87.
氧饱和度降到83了\NO2 sats down to 83.
别管颈部了  克莱尔\NForget about the neck, Claire.
把她当成一般病患\NTreat her like any other patient.
首先要做什么\NWhat are the first steps?
气道  呼吸  血液循环\NAirway, breathing, circulation.
很好  拿工具包\NGood. Grab a kit.
m 211 -8 b 217 -6 217 -4 217 -2 l 217 24 b 217 26 217 29 211 31 l 31 31 b 26 29 26 26 26 24 l 26 -2 b 26 -4 26 -6 31 -8
m 0 0 b 1 -1 2 -2 4 -1 b 7 1 3 2 5 5 b 6 7 8 7 9 5 l 15 -6 b 18 -7 20 -6 20 -3 b 19 -1 17 2 17 4 b 16 7 20 7 21 6 b 22 4 23 2 25 -1 b 27 -2 29 -1 29 1 b 29 2 28 3 29 5 b 30 7 32 7 33 6 b 34 5 34 4 35 3 b 37 2 39 3 39 5 b 39 6 38 8 37 9 b 34 13 29 13 25 9 b 22 13 17 13 13 9 b 10 13 3 13 0 8
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
m 50 0 l 179 0 b 208 0 229 21 229 50 l 229 179 b 229 208 208 228 179 228 l 50 228 b 21 228 0 208 0 179 l 0 50 b 0 21 21 0 50 0
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载\N请登陆 www.YYeTs.com\N仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
m 38 -1 l 44 6 l 38 13 l 19 13 b 14 12 14 6 14 6 b 14 6 14 0 19 -1
m 200 -1 l 200 13 l 19 13 b 14 12 14 6 14 6 b 14 6 14 0 19 -1
翻 译     Z小花儿       小shy
翻 译     Santolalla      琦小果
翻 译     迷失_绽放      八步半
校 对     Santolalla
快来帮忙  谁能来帮忙\NI need help here! Somebody, help!
莫菲  上\NMurphy, go!
时间轴    海默迷妹念    海默迷姐查
快点\NLet's go.
创伤三室\NTrauma Three.
后 期     斯人
总 监     夕橙
血止不住\NI can't stop the bleeding.
-他快流血而死了  -想想办法\N- He's bleeding out. - Do something.
我需要导尿管  14号针头\NI need a urinary catheter, 14-gauge needle,
动脉导丝  闭塞球囊\Narterial guide wire, occlusion balloon,
二十毫升生理盐水  快\Nand 20 cc of saline, stat.
第一季    第六集
良     医
-他在干什么  -不知道\N- What's he doing? - I have no idea.
没有现成的  我只能自己做个REBOA\NWell, you don't have one, so I'm making a REBOA.
血管内主动脉球囊闭塞术
什么\NA what?
REBOA\NA REBOA.
这是个词吗\NIs that even a word?
REBOA能阻塞受损的动脉  止住血\NA REBOA will occlude the damaged artery and stop the bleeding.
可以放手了\NRelease the pressure.
血压稳住了  90/60\NBP is stabilizing. 90 over 60.
厉害  莫菲医生\NNice work, Dr. Murphy.
我做了个REBOA\NI made a REBOA.
血氧降到89了\NOxygen is dropping to 89.
好  手电筒\NAll right. Light.
嘴张大\NOpen wide for me.
烟尘吸入导致喉咙肿大\NThroat's swollen from smoke inhalation.
环甲软骨切开手术包\NCric kit.
-她的嘴或鼻子内有烟灰吗  -没有\N- Do you see soot in her mouth or nose? - No.
不需要切开环甲软骨  给她做焦痂切除\NShe doesn't need a cric. She needs an escharotomy.
氧饱和度回升到92  还在升\NSats are going back up. 92 and rising.
颈部环状烧伤\NCircumferential neck burns.
正在收缩的焦皮就像绞索\NThe shrinking charred skin is acting like a noose.
切除焦痂就能解除收缩压迫感\NEscharotomy relieves the constriction.
现在呼吸顺畅了吗  女士\NAre you getting enough air now, ma'am?
顺畅了  谢谢\NYes. Thank you.
把她从这细菌滋长的区域\NNow get her out of this petri dish
赶紧送到烧伤科的隔离病房\Nand into an isolation ward in the burn unit ASAP.
好的\NYes, sir.
心音有点低钝\NYour heart's a bit muffled.
我是心脏病发了吗\NAm I having a heart attack?
不  但也不完全是好消息\NNo, but it's not completely good news.
急性心脏压塞\NCardiac tamponade.
得给他做心包穿刺\NHe needs a pericardiocentesis.
对  我知道\NYes, I'm aware of that.
18号针头  55cc注射器  谢谢\N18-gauge and 55 cc syringe, please.
这里需要创伤重点评估超声仪\NWe need a FAST ultrasound in here.
都在用\NThey're both in use.
没有影像你可能会刺伤他的心脏\NYou don't have imaging. You could puncture his heart.
胸骨剑突的位置二十年来会变吗\NIs the xiphoid in the same place as it was 20 years ago?
REBOA\NA REBOA.
有胆量\NBallsy.
可能会惹出大麻烦\NCould've gone really wrong.
对  但并没有\NYes, well, it didn't.
相当冒险\NIt's a cowboy move --
是你做梦都不敢尝试做的事\Nsomething you would never even dream of trying.
肖恩还要证明自己多少次\NHow many times is Shaun gonna have to prove himself
你才愿意给他机会\Nbefore you give him a shot?
洛林戴斯医生  请前往六号手术室\NDr. Rolendez, O.R. 6.
急诊室里怎么回事\NWhat happened in the E.R.?
天鹅女孩进来时你犹豫了\NSwan girl came in and you hesitated.
我没有犹豫  我在想救助计划\NI wasn't hesitating. I was thinking of a game plan.
莫菲是在想救助计划\NMurphy was thinking of the game plan.
你是不知所措了\NYou got overwhelmed.
我没有\NI wasn't.
初次急救  会这样的\NFirst trauma, it happens.
你需要有条不紊并清晰迅速地思考\NYou have to think clearly, quickly, methodically.
你可以学学肖恩的思考方式\NYou need to think a little more like Shaun.
稍微学习一下  不要完全照搬\NA little more. Not identically.
你怎么样\NHow you doing?
抱歉\NSorry.
抱歉  这是个蠢问题\NSorry. That's a stupid question.
你体内的吗啡已被消耗完毕\NYou're maxed out on morphine.
我等吗啡重新起作用后再继续\NI'll hold off until it reloads.
情况有多糟糕\NHow bad is it?
现在进展不错\NWe're making good progress.
我需要清除所有破溃的水疱\NI'll have to... debride any deroofed blisters
避免二次感染...\Nto prevent a secondary nosocomial and then --
给我镜子\NI need a mirror.
既然你都不敢看我的眼睛\NIt's the least you can do
至少能把镜子拿给我吧\Nsince you can't even look me in the eye.
我的天啊\NOh, my God.
你知道这两年内我买了多少\NDo you know how many hideous $300 bridesmaid dresses
丑陋的伴娘礼服吗\NI've had to buy in the last two years?
我决定等自己结婚时\NI decided that when I got married,
要让伴娘们穿小黑裙\Nmy bridesmaids are gonna wear black cocktail dresses
这样她们就能重复穿了\Nso they can use them again, you know?
但现在...\NBut now...
我就像是《猛鬼街》中的恶魔\Nnow I-I'm Freddy Krueger.
谁还愿意娶我呢\NWho's gonna want to marry this?
我去找护士\NI'm gonna find a nurse,
让她帮你调节一下吗啡的滴速\Nhave her adjust your... your morphine drip.
好了\NOkay.
你的脸被撞到了\NYou hit your face.
下巴脱臼  很疼\NYour jaw got stuck. It hurts.
刚才给你打的针会让你晕过去\NSo, this shot I just gave you is gonna knock you out
好让我治好你的下巴\Nso that I can fix that.
请稍等\NHang tight.
-车祸患者状态分级确认了吗  -共有23人\N- Crash patients status check? - 23 people total.
现场死亡一人  急诊室死亡一人\NOne fatality on site, lost one in the E.R.
红标患者全部经过检查\NExamined all the red tags.
候诊室还有十三位黄标以及绿标患者\NGot 13 yellow and green still in the waiting room.
-我负责下位患者  -马尔科・麦哲伦\N- I'll take whoever's up next. - Marco Magallenes...
股动脉断裂  股骨粉碎\Nsevered femoral artery, crushed femur.
我做了REBOA  并安装了临时分流器\NI did the REBOA and then installed a temporary shunt.
这是他的CT和核磁共振结果\NHere are his CT and MRI results.
找别人负责下位患者\NFind someone else for whoever's up next.
终于安静了\NOh, finally.
打扰一下  你们是马尔科的亲属吗\NExcuse me. Are you Marco's family?
是的\NYes.
我们刚知道我表亲没在事故中幸免于难\NWe just found out that my cousin didn't survive the accident.
请节哀\NI'm sorry.
-有点吃不消  -我很遗憾\N- It's a bit much. - I'm so sorry.
我是梅伦德斯医生  这位是莫菲医生\NI'm Dr. Melendez, and this is Dr. Murphy.
我是里尔卡多\NI'm Ricardo.
我是马尔科的父亲\NI'm M-Marco's father.
这是他母亲蕾娜  这是索尼娅\NThis is, uh, his mother, Lorena, and this is Sonia.
他们今晚要结婚了\NThey were getting married tonight.
我儿子怎么样\NHow's my son?
马尔科的股骨彻底粉碎\NMarco's femur was completely shattered,
小腿供血不足\Nand his lower leg isn't getting enough blood.
你能救下他的腿吗\NCan you save his leg?
马尔科股骨粉碎太过严重\NMarco suffered too much bone fragmentation.
我们治不好了\NWe can't fix it.
截肢是唯一的选择\NOur only choice is to amputate.
女儿\NMija.
五区需要三级前房积血检查\NBay Five needs a grade three hyphema.
头部CT和眼科表单吗\NHead CT and page ophthalmology?
你真懂我\NYou read my mind.
有一阵了\NBeen a while.
通宵加班还撑得住吗\NHow you holding up pulling an all-nighter?
还凑合  但你要是能给我来点静脉注射咖啡因\NI'll manage, but if you can find me a caffeine IV,
-借过  -就更好了\N- Please move! - it'd be helpful.
-今晚真辛苦  -是啊\N- Tough night. - Yeah.
谢谢你过来\NThanks for coming.
这是工作的一部分\NIt's part of the job.
大喜日子定了吗\NSo, when's the big day?
我们还没定呢\NWe haven't set it yet.
在哪儿举行婚礼\NOh, where is it gonna be?
我们会再商量的\NWe'll figure it out.
也许在某处的沙滩上\NMaybe a beach somewhere.
我们应该晚点再谈\NWe should talk about this later.
怎么了  我喜欢沙滩\NWhat? I like beaches.
如果你有更浪漫的想法...\NIf you have a more romantic idea...
我家人喜欢教堂\NMy family likes churches.
我们确实应该晚点谈谈\NWe should talk about this later.
利姆医生  你有一位黄标患者要变成红标了\NDr. Lim, I think one of your yellows is about to turn red.
我把婚礼都策划好了\NI've got my wedding all planned out.
婚纱和鲜花都选好了\NI've got the dress, and I've got the flowers.
来个新郎就万事大吉了\NAll I need is a groom.
你愿意吗  莫菲医生\NYou available, Dr. Murphy?
不\NNo.
你不想要爱吗\NYou don't want some love?
不  我不想  我不想要\NNo. No, I don't. I don't want love.
格拉斯曼医生  神经会诊  三区\NDr. Glassman, neural consult, Bay Three.
谢谢你\NThank you.
我先到的\NI was here first.
肖恩\NShaun.
肖恩\NShaun!
我患者的片子很重要\NMy patient's scans are very important.
我患者的也很重要\NWell, my patient's important, too.
我得看看我患者的片子\NI need to see my patient's scans.
你的患者是术前还是术后\NIs your patient pre-op or post-op?
术前\NPre-op.
好吧  我把电脑让给你\NOkay, I'll give you the computer,
但你得先道歉才行\Nbut you need to apologize first.
好吧  对不起  快打开\NOkay, I'm sorry. Turn it on.
为什么梅伦德斯医生告诉马尔科的亲属\NWhy was Marco's family crying when Dr. Melendez
他需要截肢时  他们要哭\Ntold them his leg would need to be amputated?
他们儿子的腿要被截下去了\NWell, their son's leg is about to be cut off.
这很悲伤  哭泣很正常\NIt's sad. Crying is normal.
但在截肢和死亡之间选择的话\NBut when your options are amputation or death,
截肢不是更好吗\Namputation is good news.
人们需要时间消化这种巨变\NPeople need time to adjust to big changes.
马尔科的家人甚至没机会奢求奇迹\NMarco's family didn't even get a chance to pray for a miracle.
这没可能\NIt's not possible.
骨头受损太严重\NThe bone damage is too severe.
无法进行杆移植\NA rod implantation won't work.
没有可供固定的地方\NThere's nothing to anchor into,
并且分流器持续不到重建的时候\Nand the shunt won't last long enough to do reconstruction.
没有其他选择了\NThere are no other options.
也许我们能更换整个股骨\NWhat if we could replace the entire femur?
我们在给他造一根新的股骨\NWe're making him a new femur.
用3D打印机吗\NWith a 3D printer?
3D打印骨骼只成功应用于下颌处过\N3D-printed bones have only successfully been done with the mandible.
我们知道\NWe know.
-那是个非常小的骨头  -我们知道\N- That's a fairly small bone. - We know.
股骨需要支撑全身的重量\NA femur has to support the weight of the entire body.
所以我们用钛合金来打造这根  没问题的\NThis one will be titanium. It can work.
这个想法很有趣\NIt's an interesting idea...
但我仍需考虑一下\Nbut I need to think on it.
现在还有七位黄标患者等待救治呢\NRight now we still got seven yellow tags waiting.
还有什么需要考虑的\NWhat do you have to think about?
-这是个好主意  -非常棒的主意\N- It's a good idea. - It's a brilliant idea.
那孩子很有想法  但并不意味着...\NThe kid has brilliant ideas. That doesn't mean --
不  这是我的主意\NNo, it was my idea,
我也清楚其中的风险\Nand I'm aware of the risks --
感染  凝血  身体机能受损\Ninfection, clotting, hardware failure...
死亡\NDeath.
-这不是你的主意  -就是我的主意\N- It wasn't your idea. - It was my idea!
风险确实很大\NAnd the risks are significant,
但应由他们决定啊\Nbut isn't that their call?
-我们需要... -也许他说了什么\N- Don't we have to... - Maybe he said something,
你接着说了什么  之后你们一起...\Nand then you said something, and together, you --
我的主意  完全是我的主意\NMy idea. Completely my idea.
这个「非常棒」的想法完全来自于我\NThe "brilliant" idea is 100% my brilliant idea.
为什么你不能接受呢\NWhy is that a problem for you?
也许因为我们相识六个月了\NMaybe because I've known you for six months.
我们每天都能学到新东西\NEvery day we learn new things.
今天你会发现我很聪明\NToday, you learned I'm brilliant.
是这个想法很棒\NThe idea was brilliant.
而这想法是我的\NAnd it was mine.
如果有谁能完成这个无与伦比的手术\NAnd if anyone can do this brilliant surgery,
那非你莫属\Nit's you.
恭维\NFlattery --
也很棒\Nalso brilliant.
工作时间睡觉\NSleeping on the job?
只是出来透透气\NJust needed some fresh air.
待在里面快要窒息了\NFeels like I'm suffocating in there.
她很痛苦  痛得天翻地覆\NShe's in pain, spilling her guts out,
每次我说点什么\Nand every time I open my mouth,
听起来都像个笨蛋\NI sound like an idiot.
卡卢医生  没法和女性交流\NDr. Kalu -- unable to talk to women.
这可真新鲜\NThere's a first.
你要是不帮我  克莱尔  就让我自己待会\NIf you're not gonna be helpful, Claire, just leave.
你不用和她交谈  用心倾听就好了\NYou don't need to talk. Just listen to her.
你可以出来透气  理清头绪\NYou get to come out here, clear your head.
她却被困在里面\NShe's trapped in there,
和她的思绪  恐惧为伴\Nalone with her thoughts, her fears.
你以为她不想出来透气吗\NYou don't think she wants to get out?
你是她的救赎\NYou are her escape.
你想在马尔科的腿上安一块假的股骨\NYou want to put a fake femur into Marco's leg?
不是假的  是真的\NIt's not fake. It's real.
不算真正的骨头  我们打算用钛合金来制作\NIt's not a real bone. We're making it out of titanium.
还是真的\NIt's still real.
真是太不可思议了\NThat's incredible.
之后马尔科就可以走路跑步甚至爬山了吗\NAnd Marco will be able to walk, run, climb?
还能游泳呢\NAnd swim.
希望如此  这是我们的手术目的\NHopefully. That's the intention.
你们之前做过类似的手术吗\NWell, have you done the surgery before?
-我没有  -我们将是首例\N- I haven't. - We'll be the first.
之前没有人用股骨这样大的骨头\NWell, nobody has ever attempted this surgery
来尝试过此类手术\Nwith a bone as large as the femur.
我相信此方案可行  但也存在风险\NI believe it's a viable option, but there are risks.
风险  马尔科会死吗\NRisks? Could Marco die?
据我估计  他有10%的可能性撑不过手术\NIn my estimation, there's a 10% chance he won't make it.
那就不做\NThen no.
我不能失去儿子\NI'm not losing my son.
等等  如果我们有可能拯救马尔科的腿\NWait. If there's a chance we can save Marco's leg,
我们应该至少再详细讨论一下\Nwe should at least discuss this some more.
这是他所希望的\NThat's what he'd want.
他想活着\NHe'd want to live.
他想保住性命\NHe'd want to have a life.
我了解他\NI know him.
他会想要抓住机会\NHe'd want to take the chance.
如果因为我做的鲁莽决定而害死马尔科\NI will never forgive myself if Marco died
我将永远不会原谅自己\Nbecause I made a reckless decision.
该由谁来做决定\NWhose decision is this?
他有医疗决策委托人吗\NDoes he have a healthcare proxy?
那是什么\NI don't know what that is.
发生事故时\NWhen the accident happened,
你们是正去往婚礼还是从婚礼回来\Nwere you on the way to your wedding or on the way back?
我们在去婚礼的路上\NWe were headed to the wedding.
那么马尔科的父母是最近的亲属\NMarco's parents are the next of kin.
由他们决定\NThey decide.
求你\NPlease...
给我儿子截肢吧\Namputate our son's leg.
莫菲\NMurphy.
为什么截肢手术中断端的缝合至关重要\NWhy is the primary closure on the stump so vital in amputation surgery?
为了得以装配假肢\NFor a proper prosthetic fitting.
为什么你要和杰西卡结婚\NWhy are you marrying Jessica?
为什么任何人要结婚\NWhy does anyone get married?
我不知道\NI don't know.
我爱她\NI love her.
我不明白为什么对人们来说\NI don't understand why having someone to love
拥有挚爱那么重要\Nis so important to everyone.
你们得停止手术\NYou have to stand down.
-你不能给马尔科截肢  -为什么\N- You can't amputate Marco's leg. - Why not?
我申请了紧急禁制令来阻止手术\NI filed an emergency injunction to stop the surgery.
你发生了车祸\NYou were in a car accident.
你的脖子受伤了\NYour neck was punctured.
修复手术进行得很顺利\NThe repair surgery went well.
再有一周留院观察\NYou're gonna have to stay put for a week
我们才能让你出院\Nbefore we can release you.
你能活下来很幸运\NYou're very lucky to be alive.
我妻子珍娜・亨塞尔  她还好吗\NMy wife, Jenna Hensel -- is she okay?
我能见她吗\NCan I see her?
她不在名单上\NShe's not listed.
这是好事\NThat's a good thing.
她可能还在候诊室\NShe's probably still in the waiting room.
我去找她  把她带过来\NI'll find her and bring her up.
她知道你没事一定会松一口气\NShe'll be relieved to know you're okay.
好\NOkay.
伤腿就像颗定时炸弹的昏迷患者\NWhat the hell am I supposed to do with an unconscious patient
我应该拿他怎么办\Nwhose leg is a ticking time bomb?
辛格法官在路上了\NJudge Singh is en route.
她想听听父母双方以及相关医生的意见\NShe wants to hear from both parties and the doctors on the case.
我也得去作证吗\NI have to testify?
-但愿不用  -但愿不用\N- Hopefully not. - Hopefully not.
我以为你会很高兴\NI thought you would be happy.
你觉得能拯救他的腿\NYou thought you could save the leg,
我不希望因为他的父母不敢做这个艰难的决定\Nand I didn't want that not happening because the parents
而导致手术不能进行\Nare afraid to make a tough call.
这是他们的决定\NIt's their call to make.
如果车祸晚一个小时发生\NAnd if the accident happened an hour later,
就是他妻子做决定了\Nit would be the wife's.
而她想要安装假骨\NAnd she wants the fake leg.
那不是假的\NIt's not fake.
我以为你不会盲目遵守规则\NI thought you didn't believe in just blindly following protocol.
他是他们的儿子\NHe's their son.
没人比他们更爱他\NNobody's gonna love him more than them.
真的吗\NSeriously?
所有父母都比任何人更爱自己的孩子吗\NAll parents love all children more than anybody else?
人们无时无刻不在离婚\NPeople get divorced all the time.
他们多常会放弃自己的孩子\NHow often do they give up their kids?
所以  如果是我们\NSo, if this was us,
你更希望你的父母而不是我来替你决定吗\Nyou'd want your parents to decide over me?
-我不是那个意思  -你就是\N- I didn't say that. - You kind of did.
我是说  需要有规定\NI was saying, there needs to be rules,
需要有明显的界限告诉我们\Nthat there needs to be bright red lines telling us
谁能做这些重要决定\Nwho gets to make these calls.
这是父母的决定\NIt's the parents' call.
现在不是了\NNot anymore.
现在是法官的决定了\NNow it's the judge's.
马尔科的临时分流还剩多少时间\NHow much time does Marco have left on the temporary shunt?
三小时\NThree hours,
然后他的腿就彻底没救了\Nand then his leg will die.
好\NOkay.
「折磨医生」回来了\NDr. Torture returns.
还以为我把你吓跑了\NThought I'd scared you off for good.
选个电影\NPick a movie.
你也应该得以离开房间出去透透气\NYou deserve to get out of this room for a little while, too.
你认为看《偷天情缘》能有用吗\NYou think "Groundhog Day" is gonna make a difference?
「我折磨你  但你可以看个搞笑电影」\N"I'm torturing you, but, hey, you get to watch a funny movie."
我差不多就是这个意思\NThat is sort of what I was going for, yeah.
抱歉\NI'm sorry.
我希望我还能做点什么\NI wish there was something else I could do.
你怎么知道没有\NHow do you know there isn't?
这是规定  这是他们教给我们的东西\NThis is protocol. This is what they teach us.
我真是太走运了\NI lucked out.
我这个烧伤病人遇到了世界上最好的专家\NI got the world's greatest expert on burn victims?
你知道所有能做的事\NYou know everything that can be done.
他喜爱攀岩  深潜  蹦极\NHe loves to rock-climb, scuba dive, bungee-jump.
这太愚蠢了\NThis is insane.
我们在这里回忆时  他的腿正逐渐死去\NHis leg is literally dying while we sit here reminiscing.
我们正努力搞清楚你儿子真正希望的是什么\NPlease. We're trying to figure out what your son would want.
-他想活着  -我也希望他活着\N- He would want to live. - I want that, too,
但如果有办法能救回马尔科的腿\Nbut if there's a way that we can save Marco's leg,
他会希望我同意的\Nhe'd want me to do it.
女儿  你知道他最希望什么吗\NMija, Do you know what he wanted most of all?
他想娶你\NHe wanted to marry you.
他想和你共度余生  与你生儿育女\NHe wanted to spend his life with you, have children with you.
他能做到这些\NNow, he can do all that.
即使装上假肢他也可以很幸福\NHe can be happy with a prosthetic leg.
他还年轻  还很坚强\NHe's young, and he's strong.
女儿  他能度过这个难关的\NMija, he can get through this.
-我们相遇时  -我不在乎你的故事\N- When we met -- - I don't care about your stories.
我不在乎你们是攀岩时\NI don't care that you met rock-climbing
还是泛舟时认识的\Nor kayaking or whatever.
-我只希望... -我们在戒酒中心认识的\N- I just want -- - We met in rehab.
珍娜・亨塞尔在吗\NHey, are either of you Jenna Hensel?
在酒店拍完照后我就没见过珍娜了\NI haven't seen Jenna since we took pictures at the hotel.
但是她上了公车\NBut she got on the bus?
是的  她坐在内奥米旁边\NYeah, she was sitting with Noomi.
我觉得她还在那里\NI think she's still out there.
-各位  我们得回去  -去哪里\N- Hey, guys! We've got to go back. - Where?
去事故现场  立刻去\NTo the crash site. Now.
他不想让你知道\NHe never wanted you to know.
他是个瘾君子\NHe's an addict.
他从酒瘾换到了更健康的癖好\NHe replaced one addiction for another one -- a healthier one.
-但是他需要... -什么\N- But he needs -- - What?
他需要去花式滑水  不然就喝死自己吗\NHe needs to wakeboard or he'll drink himself to death?
-这太荒谬了  -不  这没有\N- This is ridiculous. - No, it's not!
我们谈过很多\NWe talked about it a lot.
在戒酒中心也只能谈话了\NIt's pretty much all you do in rehab.
马尔科在他的人生中第一次清醒\NMarco has clarity for the first time in his life.
他知道什么让他快乐\NHe knows what makes him happy.
他知道自己的弱点\NHe knows his weaknesses.
他并没有你想象的那么坚强\NHe's not as strong as you think.
那也无妨  但是...\NAnd that's okay, but --
马尔科出轨了\NMarco cheated on you.
大约一个月前\NIt was about a month ago.
他被婚礼和策划压得喘不上气\NHe was overwhelmed with the wedding and the planning.
于是他去找了前女友\NHe ran into an ex-girlfriend.
只有那一次\NIt only happened once.
你说谎\NYou're lying.
你是在生气他有秘密瞒着你\NYou're upset that he had secrets from you, so --
不  她没有撒谎\NNo, she's not lying.
女儿  他非常心烦意乱\NMija, he -- he was -- he was so upset.
但他确实是爱你的\NHe does love you.
我们似乎有点偏题了\NOkay, maybe we're digressing here a little bit.
我们真的没有时间了\NAnd we really don't have the time.
这很重要\NIt matters.
她没那么了解他\NShe doesn't know him like --
可能我们也不了解  但是...\Nmaybe none of us do, but...
但我们是他的父母  而你还不是他的妻子\Nbut we are his parents, and you're not his wife. Yet.
叫警察来  检查所有地方\NOkay. Get the cops. Check everywhere --
路的另一边  灌木丛  树下\Nother side of the road, bushes, trees.
如果她从公车上飞了出去\NIf she was ejected from the bus,
她可能落在任何方向的12到15米之间\Nshe could be 40, 50 feet in any direction.
珍娜\NJenna!
我找到她了  我需要帮助\NI found her! I need some help!
她脑出血了\NOkay, she's got a brain bleed.
我们需要立刻带她离开这里\NWe need to get her out of here now!
安德鲁斯医生\NDr. Andrews.
我认为塞拉斯可以胜任\NI think Celez may be eligible
实验性骨治疗\Nfor an experimental bone treatment.
说说看\NSell it to me.
我做了一些研究\NWell, I've been doing some digging.
圣地亚哥社区医院的烧伤科\NSan Diego Community Hospital's burn unit
在遵循一家巴西医院的协议\Nhas been following a Brazilian hospital's protocol
用罗非鱼鱼皮包裹烧伤部位\Nto wrap burns in tilapia skins.
我知道使用鱼皮听起来有点疯狂\NNow -- Now, I know fish skins sound a bit crazy,
但我觉得我们在这里也可以做\Nbut -- but I was thinking we could do the same thing here.
卡卢医生  你的想法很棒\NDr. Kalu, I applaud your thinking.
-但我们  -罗非鱼皮所含胶原蛋白\N- But we -- - Tilapia skins contain more collagen proteins --
比人类皮肤还多  一号三号都有\Nboth types 1 and 3 -- than even human skin,
有助于修复组织\Nwhich aids in tissue repair,
-就不需要移植皮肤了  -卡卢医生\N- negating the need for grafts. - Dr. Kalu.
-并能加速皮肤恢复  减少  -卡卢医生\N- It's shown to accelerate healing, would reduce... - Dr. Kalu.
避免感染的风险并降低了病人切割皮肤之痛\Nthe risk of infection and cut down on the patient's physical pain.
你说完了吗  还是说你想再打断我\NAre you finished, or would you like to cut me off again?
我们这样来  可以吗\NOkay, let's follow this through, shall we?
你得提出一个实验性治疗的可行建议\NYou have to come up with a proposal for the experimental treatment,
机构审查委员会通过之后\Nget it approved by our institutional review board,
你去提取医学级别的罗非鱼鱼皮  然后再...\Nget your hands on medical-grade tilapia skins, and then we...
也许你可以帮助我加快进程\NWell, I thought you could help expedite the process.
你认为我可以帮你从三个月减到两小时\NYou think I could bring it down from three months to two hours?
你做完清创术了吗\NYou finish the debridement?
-之后就交给我吧  -好\N- Okay, I'll take over from here. - Okay.
挣脱思维定势\NKeep thinking outside the box.
有主动性是好事\NInitiative is good.
我来了  给她使用呼吸气囊\NI'm in. Bag her.
你拿来电钻了吗\NDid you get me the drill?
消防车上有  怎么回事\NThe fire truck had one. What's going on?
她的瞳孔扩张\NHer pupil's blown.
她有硬脑膜下血肿\NShe has a subdural hematoma,
导致颅内压增高\Ncausing increased intracranial pressure.
如果现在不减压\NIf I don't alleviate it now,
她肯定撑不到医院\Nthere's no way she makes it to the hospital alive.
好吧\NOkay.
不省人事  女性  连枷胸\NUnconscious female. Flail chest.
我得在现场钻孔\NI had to do a burr hole in field.
氧饱和度只有70多\NHer sats are in the low 70s.
可以把她送去手术室了\NShe's good to go to the O.R.
硬脑膜下血肿\NSubdural hematoma?
她有去大脑姿势  左瞳孔扩张\NShe had decerebrate posturing, a blown left pupil.
当我用钻头在颅骨上钻孔时\NWhen I passed the drill bit through her skull,
涌出了一大堆血\Na whole lot of blood pooled out.
做得好\NGood call.
圣地亚哥社区医院打来了\NSan Diego Community Hospital called.
他们在送罗非鱼皮过来\NThey're sending the tilapia skins.
用救伤直升机送过来\NThey're medevacing them in.
一小时内能送到\NShould be here within the hour.
塞拉斯...\NCelez...
你符合一项实验治疗的标准\Nyou meet the criteria for an experimental treatment
我认为这能让你免受植皮手术之苦\Nthat I think will prevent you from having to undergo skin grafts.
慢着  怎么会有这样的事\NHold up. How did this even happen?
我发现圣地亚哥的试验\NWell, I found out San Diego's trial
允许多站点协作\Nallows for multi-site collaborations.
所以我们不用有自己的伦理委员会\NSo, there's no need for us to get our own I.R.B.
他们把皮给我们  我们提供病人数据\NThey give us the skins, we provide the patient data.
鱼皮吗\NFish skins?
罗非鱼皮已经被清洗和杀菌\NThe tilapia skins have been cleaned and sterilized.
它们非常安全\NThey're perfectly safe.
你会做吧\NYou'll do it?
我会做\NI'll do it.
干得好  卡卢医生\NWell done, Dr. Kalu.
干得好\NWell done.
愿上帝助你\NSo help you God?
好的\NYes.
-梅伦德斯医生可以告诉你  -他说了\N- Dr. Melendez can tell you -- - He has.
但假股骨是你的主意  对吧\NBut the fake femur is yours, though, right?
-你对这个构思有多大信心  -不是假的\N- How confident are you in its design? - It's not fake!
-肖恩  她想知道...-我知道她想知道什么\N- Shaun, she needs to know -- - I know what she needs to know.
她需要知道能不能成功\NShe needs to know will it work.
她需要知道能维持多久\NShe needs to know how long it will last.
是的\NYes.
好吧\NOkay.
他是他的医生吗\NHe's his doctor?
他是外科住院医师  他很有天赋\NHe is a surgical resident. He's very gifted.
他会回答我的问题吗\NIs he going to answer my questions?
肖恩  我真的需要你专注\NShaun, I really need you to focus.
-马尔科快没时间了  -让他回答吧\N- Marco is running out of time! - Just let him answer!
不  我们已经知道答案了  他们不知道\NNo, we already know the answer. They don't know.
以前从未做过这种手术\NThis thing has never been done before.
安静\NBe quiet!
他的脚趾在变色\NHis toes are changing color.
动脉
受损
导致凝血
他在凝血  糟了  马上呼叫梅伦德斯医生\NHe's clotting. That's bad. Page Dr. Melendez stat!
-莫菲  什么情况  -血液分流在凝血\N- Murphy, what do we got? - The shunt is clotting.
它在限制血流  它不行了\NIt's restricting blood flow. It is failing.
好吧  我们现在要做个决定\NAll right, we need a decision now.
要截腿还是换骨\NAre we cutting off the leg or replacing the bone?
我相信马尔科的父母和未婚妻\NThere's no doubt in my mind that Marco's parents
都很爱他  但现在显然...\Nand fiancée all love Marco, but it's become clear --
现在给我个决定\NNow. I need a decision now.
在父母眼中他是孩子\NHis parents know him as their child.
但在索尼娅心中他是成年人\NSonia knows him as a man.
换股骨\NReplace the femur.
走吧\NLet's go!
谢谢  谢谢\NThank you! Thank you.
-那就是出血  看见了吗  -看见了\N- And there's the bleed. See it? - Yes, sir.
你有夹过颅内动脉吗\NYou ever clip an intracranial artery before?
没有\NNo, sir.
来吧\NGo for it.
每个第一次都一样\NJust like every first time --
你有点激动  有点恶心\Nyou're a little excited, a little nauseous.
希望没人受伤\NHopefully nobody gets hurt.
准备好了吗\NIs it good to go?
非常好\NIt's very good.
钳子\NForceps.
你准备好了吗\NYou ready?
是的\NYes.
确保夹子的利片不会碰到有孔动脉\NBe careful the clip blades don't catch any perforated arteries.
我没看见有血管挡着\NI don't seen any vessels in the way.
那你还在等什么\NThen what are you waiting for?
非常好\NVery nice.
谢谢\NThank you.
没有出血\NEverything's dry.
道别完就盖上去吧\NSay goodbye and close the roof.
我们得在一分钟左右\NWe need to get blood back into his leg
让血流回他的腿\Nin the next minute or so,
否则我还是得做截肢\Nor I'm gonna have to amputate after all.
吊了胰岛素  给他输钙\NInsulin's hanging, loaded him with calcium.
尽我所能\NBest I can do.
现在拿掉钳夹\NLet's release the clamps.
检查毛细管充血\NCheck for capillary refill.
血流已修复\NBlood flow is restored.
心电图正常\NEKG is normal.
金  我要听到类似「变化」和「增量」的词\NOkay. Kim, I want to hear words like "Variability" and "Delta".
说给我听\NGive them to me.
我在耐心等待\NI'm waiting patiently.
什么也没有\NI'm not getting anything.
给我看看\NShow me.
检查引线\NCheck the leads.
还是没有\NStill nothing.
也许是神经重塑\NMaybe there will be some neuroplasticity.
她的大脑自己重新连接\NHer brain -- I-it could rewire itself.
不\NNo.
没有脑部活动\NZero brain activity.
我不知道为什么  但她去世了\NI don't know why, but she's gone.
什么\NWhat?
你的神经外科病人今晚死了\NYour neurosurgery patient that died tonight --
有件事你该知道\Nthere's something you should know.
什么\NWhat?
马尔科  我要你尝试动动你的脚趾\NNow, Marco, I want you to try and move your toes.
我不能\NI can't.
他还好吗\NIs he okay?
我们不确定骨...\NWe're not sure if the bone --
他不会死吧\NHe's not gonna die?
他不会被感染吧\NH-He's not gonna get an infection?
-他的身体不会排斥... -不\N- His body's not gonna reject -- - No, no.
我们密切监控他\NWe're monitoring him very closely.
-最大的威胁... -他动了\N- The biggest threat is behind -- - He moved.
他动了\NHe moved.
成功了\NIt worked.
有漫长的复原期等着你\NYou'll have a long recovery ahead --
好几个月的物理治疗\Nmonths of physical therapy.
不过现在  你应该好好休息\NBut for now, all you have to do is rest.
谢谢你\NThank you.
感谢你救了我的命  挽救了我的腿\NThank you for saving my life -- for saving my leg.
-谢谢  -不用谢\N- Thank you. - You're welcome, sir.
准备好接着办完我们的事了吗\NAre you ready to finish what we started?
先好起来再说\NGet well first.
有的是时间办婚礼\NThere's plenty of time for a wedding.
-谢谢  -不用谢\N- Thank you. - You're welcome, sir.
谢谢\NThank you.
你看起来很好\NYou look good.
坚强  就像潜水侠\NTough. Like Aquaman.
我看起来像寿司\NI look like sushi.
大家都爱吃寿司\NEverybody loves sushi.
只需要六个月\NIt's only for six months.
你的新皮肤应该就能完全长好了\NYour new skin should have completely grown in by then.
瘢痕应该会很小\NShould have minor scarring.
谢谢\NThank you.
我误会你了\NI misjudged you.
你对我的评判很准确\NYou judged me just right.
她还在睡吗\NIs she still sleeping?
-你还没告诉她吗  -没有\N- You haven't told her yet? - No.
能出来一下吗\NCan I have a moment please?
当然\NOf course.
你在事故现场发现珍娜后多久\NHow soon after you found Jenna at the crash site
给她插的管\Ndid you intubate her?
几乎是立刻就插了\NAlmost immediately.
我按压她的胸骨\NI did a sternal rub.
她表现出去大脑强直\NShe had decerebrate posturing.
她的左侧瞳孔已经散大\NHer left pupil was blown.
我知道她出现了硬膜下血肿\NI knew she had a subdural hematoma,
所以我插了管  钻了孔\Nso I intubated, did the burr hole.
并且她还有连枷胸\NShe also had a flail chest.
你插管之后检查她的呼吸了吗\NDid you check her breathing after you intubated her?
查了\NYes.
我觉得我应该查了\NWell, at least I-I think I did.
利姆医生说珍娜到急诊的时候\NDr. Lim told me that when Jenna came into the E.R.,
她的呼吸并不正常\Nshe wasn't ventilating properly.
你插管插得太深了\NYou inserted the tube too deep
插进了她伤侧肺的\Ninto her right main stem bronchus
右主支气管\Nof her injured lung.
我们没法估计\NWe had no way of knowing
在做脑电图前她已经缺氧了多久\Nhow long she was hypoxic before we gave her the EEG.
我在她颅骨上钻了一个非常完美的孔\NI drilled a perfect burr hole into her skull
还是在夜里  在马路边\Non the side of the road in the middle of the night,
但我  我插管却插坏了\Nand I-I-I screw up her intubation?
是的\NYes.
即使是高年资医生  当时的情况\NIt was tough conditions for anyone --
也是非常棘手的\Nresident or not.
我们任何人都有可能犯同样的错误\NAny one of us could have made the same mistake.
我曾经在急诊室接诊过一个女病人\NI had a woman come into the E.R. once...
51岁  是个母亲\Na mother, 51 years old.
弗朗辛・帕克\NFrancine Parker.
她有两个儿子\NShe had two boys.
她因为咳嗽来的\NShe had a cough --
很剧烈  但也不过是个咳嗽\Na bad one -- but a cough.
我给她做了检查\NI checked her out,
给她开了点抗生素就让她回去了\Ngave her some antibiotics, sent her home.
六小时后  她被人送来急诊\NSix hours later, she was rolled into the E.R..
她得了心脏病  我没发现  结果\NShe had had a heart attack, and I missed it, and...
她死了\Nshe died.
从那时起\NNot one day...
之后我的每一天我都会想起她\Ngoes by when I don't think about her.
她是你的第一例\NShe was your first.
其实  是第四例\NMy fourth, actually.
你不会忘记这种病例的\NYou're not gonna forget this.
永远忘不了\NYou never forget.
但可能  下次遇到这些病例\NBut I don't know, maybe we're better off for it
我们可以做得更好\Nthe next time around.
你得努力振作起来\NYou got to find a way to keep going.
回家去  去睡吧\NGo home. Get some rest.
我都还没有告诉她\NI haven't even told her yet.
你不准去\NYou're not going to.
你犯了个错误  你与此事关系太大\NYou made a mistake. You're too close to this.
我不能让你去和家属\NI'm not gonna allow you to talk to the family
或院外的任何人谈论这事\Nor anyone else outside this hospital about this.
你听明白了吗\NDo we understand each other?
明白\NYes, sir.
BGM: I Won't Let You Down by Erin McCarley
? I don't have all the words to say ?
? I'm still healing from my mistakes ?
? I'll take the weight if it makes you stronger ?
? I don't want to leave you in this place ?
我给圣地亚哥社区医院打电话谢谢他们\NI called San Diego Community Hospital and thanked them
把我们纳入他们的研究\Nfor including us in their study.
他们说他们非常乐意接纳我们\NThey said they were happy to do it.
并请我转达对你的感谢\NAnd they asked that I pass along their thanks to you
感谢你对他们烧伤科无比慷慨的捐款\Nfor your very generous donation to their burn unit.
我知道你家里非常有钱\NI know you come from a wealthy family.
我也不是嫉妒  但你\NI don't begrudge that, but you...
不能每次病人有需要你就自己掏钱\Ncan't open your wallet every time a patient's in need.
医患之间的关系很快就会变味的\NThe lines can get real blurry real fast.
遵命\NYes, sir.
? Who am I to try and save you? ?
? I ain't gonna hide ?
? You have to fight today ?
这是什么\NWhat's this?
我的医学委托人文件\NMy healthcare proxy.
杰西  不会有事的\NJess, nothing's gonna happen.
是吗  那真是太好了\NReally? That's good to know.
? I won't let you down ?
? No, no, no ?
? But I won't let you down ?
? I won't let you down ?
? No, no, no ?
真是非常忙碌的一晚\NWell, that was quite a night.
即使当了这么久的医生\NBeen a doctor for a long while --
也没经历过像这样的夜班\Ndon't remember a night quite like that one.
为什么法拉尔护士问我要不要爱\NWhy did Nurse Farrar ask if I wanted love?
因为她八卦\N'Cause she's a nosy...
肖恩  你真的不想爱吗\NShaun, you really don't want love?
我以前爱过史蒂夫和我的兔子\NI loved Steve and my rabbit.
现在不爱了\NNot anymore.
你现在不爱他们了吗\NYou don't love them anymore?
不爱了  他们已经死了\NNo, I don't. They're dead.
你没法再爱一个死人了\NYou can't love someone if they're dead.
好吧  我爱的人也有曾经去世的\NWell, I've lost people I love.
我很想他们  这很痛苦  但我仍然爱他们\NI miss them, and it hurts, but I still love them.
我不想要爱\NI don't want love.
好吧\NOkay.
你想要吃早餐吗\NYou want breakfast?
我能吃四个煎饼而不是三个吗\NCan I have four pancakes instead of three?
你可以吃五个\NYou can have five.
我只想要吃四个\NI only want four.
可以\NOkay.
好的\NOkay.