[birds chirping]
So I looked at a bunch of houses
and I think I found the best one.
It's perfect.
I'm gonna send you the link.
And then we should just go ahead
and get it, 'cause it's the best one.
[Rebecca] Abby, the house looks amazing...
and the thought of a trip
is exciting, but...
turning 50 is so not a big deal to me.
I had a patient this week
who's in knots about turning 40.
The feedback I offered her,
as corny as it sounds is,
"Age is truly just a number."
I mean, you're only as old
as you feel, right?
Why stress about it?
Oh, fuck, that's hot!
[Catherine] I always love Hawaii.
Oh, you know what?
I catered Jack Johnson's birthday party
and he said I could use
his beach house there.
Okay, here are my top picks,
Napa...
a resort in Arizona, or Napa.
Well, all I can say
is thank God you're planning this,
'cause you know Brian
is not gonna do shit for her 50th.
You know Brian would just take her
to Macaroni Grill
and then she'd have to drive home
because he had too much to drink.
Fuckin' Brian.
Oh, my God, this trip sounds so fun.
And it's so great
everyone can get together.
- You're coming, right?
- No.
Ugh. Mama needs to rock out
with her cock out.
Also, Mama needs to stop
referring to herself in the third person.
And maybe ease up
on the "cock" drops.
I just want this to feel like
a regular vacation.
You know, like,
just sit around, talk, and...
drink wine and laugh
and wear muumuus.
And just somewhere in there,
I'll just kind of slide into 50.
You know,
I just want it to be super chill...
- [Brian grunts] Die!
- ...no big deal--
Brian, can you turn that down?
No, I'm sorry, Rebecca,
but it is officially a big deal.
It's your half-centennial.
I'm not gonna let this go by
without doing something big.
Okay... I'm gonna cut my bangs.
I really wanna make this work.
I'm just-- Honestly, I'm so grateful
that you guys still want me to come
after I bailed on the last one.
God, it's just, like, the flying,
and that random house, you know,
it just, like, gives me anxiety.
Other people's bathrooms. Oh, God.
Weird bedspreads...
You do still want me to come, right?
Wall-to-wall carpeting, the remote...
You know what? I wish I'd never seen
that Dateline with the black-light
where they show
where all the semen was.
Is a flower in the hair too much
for solo dining?
I need to get out
and take my new knees for a spin.
Val, yes! Work those new knees!
Out, out, out.
[Val] I just wanna meet a nice lady
and I wanna make out for a while
and then spoon a little bit...
And then that spooning can turn
into a real spirited 69-ing.
Have you ever tried a position
called "The 1,000"? It's a sexy one.
It's when a thousand kids
are in your bed,
and the only touch you feel
is a tiny sweaty foot to the back.
Speaking of sexy,
I share my bed with a CPAP machine.
Things we say now.
Woo! I'm in H&M
trying on some party clothes.
I can't wait to see you guys
and pinch all your butts...
with consent.
[Abby] See you soon...
and, you know, we'll figure out money
when we get there.
Keep it in your pants till I see you.
Bye, I love you!
- [man] Huh?
- No, I'm on the phone.
Bye. Remember, don't make this a big deal.
- I just told my driver that I loved him.
- Somebody hang up.
All right, love you, guys, too. Bye.
Still not sure I'm coming.
["Message of Love" playing]
♪ Now the reason we're here ♪
♪ As man and woman ♪
♪ Is to love each other ♪
♪ Take care of each other ♪
♪ When love walks in the room ♪
♪ Everybody stand up... ♪
[Abby] Okay.
Here we are.
I hope it's perfect.
I don't know,
it had very good reviews online.
And let me tell you something,
I had to wade through a lot of shitboxes.
But this one is supposed to be good.
And it's supposed to have a pool.
Does anybody see a pool?
Oh, it is just stunning.
It's just so perfect.
Just... Just release all that worry.
Or swallow it?
Okay, shall we?
- Edible flowers.
- [Naomi gasps] I see that.
- Oh, my God.
- [Jenny] How do you know they're edible?
What, these are edible--
[Val] You wanna be the protector
and the caretaker and everything, but...
just let her deal with it...
- What the hell is she doing?
- Cannot let a stranger stay a stranger.
...you wanna take care of them
and you wanna be the hero, but...
sometimes you gotta back off,
let someone else in the family do it,
you know?
She's probably gonna invite him
to join us on the trip.
- Not, that that would be a bad--
- No, yeah, yeah, it would.
You take care of yourself.
And I really hope that your sister
is able to move your mom's grave.
And I'm gonna try the manicotti recipe.
Thanks.
Ready?
- [Abby] To Rebecca!
- [all] To Rebecca!
[cheering]
Thank you so much
for turning 50
and bringing us all together.
And thank you, guys, I know you all had to
move mountains to make this happen.
- Especially you, Catherine.
- You know, life's a juggle, so...
I really appreciate it.
Rebecca really appreciates it.
Why am I speaking for Rebecca?
- This is a terrible toast. I'm sorry.
- [laughter]
I hope you guys like the house.
Let's get drunk. Happy birthday.
- Happy birthday!
- Yay! Cheers to us!
Oh, if I just may offer
a little bit of feedback,
I just want this to be a fun weekend
for all of us, right? Not just about me.
God, when was the last time
we were all together?
Mm-- Mm--
Was it Abby's wedding?
- Oh. Maybe.
- What? No.
You should've come to my divorce party,
there was a really great band.
- Not that long ago--
- Jesus...
Nice one, kid.
Guys...
time goes by so fast, I'm telling you.
I have needed this... so much.
- You guys have been on my mind--
- Adrian, comma,
please resend the link
to Top Chef, period.
Can't open, period.
New paragraph.
Also, comma, please ask producers
how this show will be different,
question mark, dot, dot, dot.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
I have so much going on
with work right now.
I'm gonna unplug.
Be present, right.
- Send.
- [phone chimes]
[Abby] Anyway, I made itineraries.
[all] Ooh.
I know, and you don't
have to read 'em now.
Just, you know, take your time,
but sort of like a...
loosey-goosey, you know,
sort of like scheduly thing.
Just sort of an overview
of everything we're gonna do
- minute-by-minute on the trip.
- [gasps]
- No worries, just take a look at it.
- So awesome.
- No presh.
- When did you have time to make those?
Oh, well, I've been working
a lot less lately.
- Yeah, right.
- Well, good for you.
[Val] We look so young.
God.
Wow.
Let's take a group picture.
- Yes, yes.
- Yeah.
Yes, yes! Do a pic.
- The night of a thousand selfies?
- Yeah.
Can you go higher?
- Yeah, go higher.
- Try to go higher.
All right, everybody look down
and then on the count of three, look up.
- Fresh faces.
- Fresh face.
[Abby] One, two, three.
- [camera clicks]
- Oh!
[all laughing]
[Rebecca] That's nice.
Wait.
What the...
Is that a ghost?
[Jenny] Oh, my God, it is a ghost.
It's the ghost of Amelia Earhart
and she's holding a small baby.
- What are you guys doing in my house?
- Oh, my God!
Nah, I'm just goofing.
I'm Tammy, I own the place.
Brought you guys a cord of fresh pinyon,
get you started on a fire.
Oh. Oh!
Thank you. Uh...
Guys, this is Tammy.
She's the owner of the place. [stammers]
I'm... Abby,
I'm the one that's been emailing you.
A lot of emails.
Yeah.
So, uh...
which one of you guys
is the blushing bride?
Second time around I'm thinking, maybe?
Maybe third?
[chuckling] Oh, no. We're celebrating
Rebecca's birthday.
It's her 50th, the big five-oh.
Celebrating-with-the-girls weekend, huh?
We're just here for a vacation.
The birthday's not a big deal.
So, what am I looking at here?
High school tennis team,
old dance crew, or...
y'all magically fit
in the same pair of pants?
What brings us together?
Oh, well, we all met in Chicago
waitressing at a pizza place
called Antonio's, and...
and we just-- It was meant to be.
Chi-Town, yeah,
I've been to that place, yeah.
Well, we all came up there together
in the '90s. Kind of our crew.
Actually, um, Catherine here started
her own pizza chain called Cutie Pies.
Holy shit, that's you?
- Yeah.
- I've never been to the restaurant,
but I do love those
frozen pizzas for one that you do.
Thank you.
'Cause, you know,
if I prep a full-size pizza, guess what?
I'm gonna end up eating a full-size pizza.
So, you know.
You prevent a lot of sadness.
- So, you guys want to see the house or--
- Yes.
All right.
Let's stop dicking around.
You got the pool and the hot tub here
if you wanna soak...
or, uh, toke.
We are very discreet, so just, uh...
do whatever the heck you need to do
to get through this weekend.
Okay. [chuckles]
So, Tammy,
how long have you owned the property?
Uh, a few years.
After my husband died,
I sold our company.
We made edible organic soaps.
Got bought out by Unilever. Pretty sweet.
Sorry your husband died. That's sad.
Yeah, he, uh, died
of a heart attack at 49.
- Oh, wow.
- That's so young.
You think?
It was pretty inevitable, though.
We were doing so much blow.
This'll come in real handy.
The little Zen area
when you need that total soul escape.
It's real quiet. It's perfect
for when that roomie situation devolves.
You can just come out here
and watch the hummingbirds,
meditate,
enjoy this beautiful Buddha statue...
Now, this water feature over here,
steer clear, please.
Okay, you wanna know how much money
I poured into this son of a bitch?
- Seven grand.
- [Abby gasps]
Before you suggest it,
no, I cannot just turn it off.
If I do, none of the toilets will work.
Which is ironic
because it's basically a toilet for birds.
And me that one time.
This is the fire pit!
- Ooh.
- Wow.
Light that sucker up,
stare into the flames and contemplate
why in the hell you all came up here
in the first place.
- Also, we have s'mores.
- [laughter]
Hey, Tammy, I'm just having a hard time
getting on the Wi-Fi.
I just have to send
a quick email for work.
Okay, yeah, this is gonna be a rough
weekend if you have to do work stuff.
- The Wi-Fi here is very slow.
- Oh.
So, you're just gonna
have to talk to each other.
- Oh, good.
- While drinking a ton of wine.
What could possibly go wrong?
Just remember, guys,
whatever gets said,
it's probably what the person
has always felt...
and the alcohol just let it out.
You wanna see the view?
It's right through this gate.
Whoa.
Holy triple fucks, this is heaven.
Yeah, well, I didn't work my ass off
to buy a house
on some shitscape property.
- Wow.
- [Jenny] Yeah, that's fake.
There's no way that's real.
It's too pretty.
Ooh. We should sleep out here one night,
under the stars.
You know, like a camping slumber party.
Wouldn't that be fun?
Yes!
Oh, God. Yeah, I don't wanna do that.
I don't know if I want to either.
I have no place
to plug in my CPAP machine.
Things we say now.
[all laughing]
What's everybody laughing at?
Oh, it's just, like, our, you know,
"That's what she said."
You know, "Things we say now."
So, like, uh...
"I gotta go tend my bees.
Things we say now."
I guess.
Well, I say it,
'cause I got a bee farm, so...
Oh, you make honey?
No, I don't make honey.
I get stung a lot.
But you develop, uh, an immunity to it...
and almost a pleasure.
Well, you all obviously have
an entire haunted forest
of toxic jibber-jabber to get through,
- so I'm gonna skedaddle.
- [Val] Bye, Tammy.
[Abby] I have a question about
the cleaning fee when you get a chance.
[Tammy] Love it.
- What else do bees do?
- All right.
Well, guys, you know what,
even if we don't sleep out here,
I love Naomi's idea of just, like,
hanging out, drinking wine,
just talking, connecting...
- Yes, totally.
- Love it.
We are gonna do all of that.
All that is baked into the itinerary.
We're gonna lay around,
we're gonna drink wine,
but first on the docket...
"Unpack and unwind for 20 minutes."
I'm setting a timer.
Psych. But, no. But, I am... Just--
Just take 20 minutes 'cause we have
dinner reservations at 7:15.
[Rebecca] My God, she actually said
"toxic jibber-jabber."
[Naomi] Yes, she did.
[Jenny] God, and what about those bees?
What, does she keep them as pets?
I gotta say something.
I actually really resent it when people,
especially other women,
automatically assume when they see
a group of us, that we're gonna fight.
Yes.
Oh, my gosh, when I was leaving the house
for this trip, Brian's like,
"Oh, have fun crying with your ladies."
I was like...
Anyway, you know, he was just joking
of course, but--
- Ah. Brian and his jokes.
- [inhaling sharply]
- Yeah.
- [Naomi] I feel bad for Tammy, you know.
She clearly just hasn't
had friends like you in her life.
You know, we are so lucky.
I love you turkeys so much.
- Oh, I love you, too.
- [Val] Love you, guys.
So, how much further
is this place, anyway?
Sorry, I thought
it was a little more walkable.
Oh, well, I mean, I'm good.
I got my comfy boots on.
So, no heels for me with my back.
You know you can heal your back
with your mind?
You know that's not true?
[laughing]
How you doing, Val, are you okay?
Yeah.
Oh, you should see what
these new knees can do.
Hold this for a second.
Check this shit out.
[gasping and laughing]
[Naomi] Holy-- Val!
[all] Whoo!
[Jenny] Oh, shit!
[Naomi] Keep going, Val!
- We'll catch up!
- [laughs]
[indistinct chatter]
- Cheers, dears!
- [all] Cheers!
- Aww!
- Love you, love you.
Hello, ladies. My name is Jade,
I'll be your server tonight.
- Hi, Jade.
- Hi.
Uh, Jade, we're really hungry,
so we're gonna order really fast,
and we know what we want,
so maybe get some water and then
I'll tell you about our food allergies.
Okay, sounds good.
Thank you, Jade.
And we appreciate you, Jade.
No prob.
- Am I saying her name too much?
- Yeah.
Guys, I just heard myself talk. I'm sorry.
I know I get weird bossy energy
on these trips.
- No.
- You're fine. Oh, my God. Not even.
- [Abby] Guys--
- No. You don't that much.
- You do not!
- I'm gonna try to rein it in.
I want this to go well
and I'm afraid I'm gonna screw it up.
- It's so fun, we're having a good time.
- It's all good.
You know what,
that's just great self-feedback.
Thank you.
Uh, why are you saying
"feedback" all the time?
Oh, it's this thing
I've been doing at my practice.
It just provides an emotional buffer.
So, rather than just launch
into your take on something,
or just give advice, you say,
"May I offer you some feedback?"
Have you ever...
tried that feedback thing on Brian?
Oh... well... [chuckling]
♪ May I offer you some feedback? ♪
[Catherine]
♪ Offer you some feedback ♪
[deeply]
♪ Ready for some feedback ♪
[harmonizing]
♪ Feedback! ♪
♪ Ready for some feedback! ♪
Ooh, that was good.
[camera clicking]
[Catherine] That is smoking!
[indistinct chatter]
[Jade] So, ladies,
we have lavender-popping corn.
And beside that,
there's a demi cruet of fleur de sel
for you to sprinkle on for a light zest.
[Val] God, this is such
an interesting--
That's... That's not enough.
So where are you guys all from?
Uh, we're from all over.
I'm originally from Chicago.
- We all met in Chicago.
- [Jade] Oh, nice, cool.
My, uh, ex-girlfriend just moved there,
so I'm a little mad at Chicago
at the moment, but...
Aw.
All right, enjoy.
Did you hear the "ex-girlfriend" thing?
Jackpot.
- [cell phone chiming]
- Oh, sweet Jesus, I have service.
- [phones chiming]
- Oh!
- My, God.
- Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Oh, no. They went bowling, you guys.
[all] Aw.
Adrian, comma...
find out how long
I have to decide, period.
Oh, my cat took her pill.
I'm not understanding
this weekend deadline.
Question mark,
exclamation point, send.
[phone chimes]
Ladies, phones down.
Come on. You know what?
We should be looking at each other.
That's right.
Adrian, comma, the pressure to make
a show decision is not--
Oh, I'm sorry. I'll stop.
No, no, stop!
Siri, no, I'm dictating. Dic--
"Dick-tasting."
What the hell is that?
- She suggested "dick-tasting"?
- It's ridiculous.
[all chanting] Rebecca! Rebecca!
Rebecca! Rebecca!
Guys! Not until Sunday! I told you!
I didn't want this to be
all about me, this weekend.
Everybody!
♪ Happy, happy birthday
It's your special day ♪
♪ Have a slice of pizza
What's your favorite way? Hey! ♪
What's your favorite way?
Mushroom and peppers.
♪ Mushroom and peppers
Mushroom and peppers ♪
Mushroom and peppers, hey! ♪
- Jade.
- Yeah?
This is a song we used to sing
at the pizza place we used to work at.
[with Italian accent] Antonio's.
[with Italian accent] Antonio's, hey!
And long story short,
we're giving you a huge tip.
Hey, what's your favorite pizza topping?
- I'm a vegan, so...
- She's a vegan.
Um, smoked tempeh and jalapenos.
♪ Smoked tempeh and jalapenos
Smoked tempeh and jalapenos ♪
- Yeah!
- [cheering]
Ho! Ho! Ho! Merry Vag-mas!
- "Merry Vag-mas"?
- My name's Dilda Claus!
Ooh!
- Jolly old Saint Dick.
- [all laughing]
The first one that gets a gift...
the biggest gift, is Naomi.
Wow. Thank you.
Because she pushed out
four beautiful big babies.
This is true, I--
So it's like ringin' a bell.
Right, Naomi? Enjoy.
It is, it's like a wet paper bag
down there. Thank you.
This one, I call "The Hush Puppy."
You can sit on this one in a coffee shop.
Oh, my God!
- [Val] You there, Abby!
- Who, me?
[Val] I heard you don't care
for a wasted moment.
- So yours has a timer.
- [laughing]
No! No!
Now, this one here is for you, Catherine,
and it's called "The Executive."
Make less deals and more squeals.
Don't turn your bedroom
into the boardroom.
This is for the C-E-Oh!
[all laughing]
Here we go.
Finally, the pénis de résistance.
[Jenny] Jesus.
- Look at this little soldier.
- [all yelling]
- [Naomi] No!
- [all laughing]
This is expensive,
and this is cheap as shit
from the dollar store.
So, remove hat before use.
It also vibrates
to the birthday song, listen.
[vibrates the "Happy Birthday" tune]
[all singing]
♪ Happy birthday... ♪
I don't wanna say it was like the best
time of my life because that's,
you know, sad, but...
[tearfully]
It was the best time of my life.
Life is real.
And we were like...
we were like sisters in the trenches.
Like, the pizza trenches.
We were so brave.
[farts, flutters lips]
Did you just burp or fart?
A little of both, I fear.
Oh, I love that necklace.
Oh, thank you.
- It's vintage.
- Ah.
It's from my vintage store.
- You have a vintage store?
- I do.
- And you live in Portland?
Okay. Fuck, man, you are officially
the coolest person I know.
Oh.
Fuck, man. Come to Portland.
There's so many of me. [laughs]
I doubt that.
- You know what I'm scared of, though?
- What?
I hope these napkins aren't haunted.
[both laughing]
That's amazing.
[laughs]
Oh, you're so fucking funny.
- I can't--
- Oh, I'm funny, that's how I...
that's how I get the ladies.
I do a lot of napkin tricks.
Wait.
- Okay.
- Oh.
- I'm sorry.
- What?
- I have to do this. I'm an artist.
- Yeah?
Can I take your picture?
You just, you look really good
in this light.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Sure, you can take my picture.
- Okay, great.
I'll take the glasses off.
Okay.
[clicks]
Check it. I put this, uh...
- cool filter on it.
- Oh, that's really nice.
- Do you like it?
- I like that.
Here, I'll send it to you.
Put in your number.
Okay.
You're not gonna believe
who's in this restaurant.
You'll never guess.
- Cher?
- No, guess again.
- [Jade] Dua Lipa?
- Who?
- Hillary Clinton?
- [Abby] Better!
Uh, Childish Gambino?
A$AP Rocky?
Is that the one
with the dollar sign "S"?
No, that's Ke$ha.
It's "Keesha."
- Is it?
- Yeah.
- Holy shit, Ke$ha's here?
- No, no, no, ready?
- [both] Brené Brown.
- [gasping]
[both] Brené Brown!
Okay, who is Brené Brown?
[woman] Brené Brown, she did
the famous TED Talk about vulnerability.
She's a researcher, storyteller...
"Shame"? "Courage is Contagious"?
Oprah's SuperSoul Conversations?
Nothing?
No. Is she-- Is she famous?
Yeah, but she doesn't care about that.
Okay, that tracks, I get that.
We get famous people
in here all the time.
- Do you know who was in here last week?
- [Naomi] Who?
Future.
- Wait, did I just miss a bunch of words?
- Future?
Is The Past coming next week?
Holy shit, you guys, let's go meet Brené!
[Abby] Let's not bug her.
Let's let her be.
Hey, Brené, we're so sorry
to interrupt your dinner.
- It's my birthday.
- Look at your skin, it's like marzipan.
We just have, like,
ten or 15 questions for you.
What's the difference between
"braving the wilderness"
- and "becoming the wilderness?"
- Conflict transformation.
How, when, and why?
How can I be generous
in my assumptions of others,
- when I hate most people?
- Hmm, good one.
Here's the thing. We can't be
generous toward other people...
without boundaries.
- Yes, Brené, yes.
- Boom!
- [Jenny] Boom on the boundaries.
- So, boundaries.
- Boundaries. That means--
- Message received.
- Thank you so much.
- Got it, we'll come back later.
What a thrill.
[all singing]
♪ Give me your hand, darling ♪
♪ Do you feel my heart beating ♪
♪ Do you understand? ♪
♪ Do you feel the same? ♪
♪ Am I only dreaming? ♪
- ♪ Or is this burning ♪
- ♪ Burning ♪
♪ An eternal flame? ♪
[cheering]
- [Abby] I don't know.
- [Naomi laughing]
Oh, fuck Ronald McDonald
for making Filet-O-Fish.
Fuck him ten ways from Sunday.
Everybody get their stretchy clothes on,
'cause we're gonna keep this party going.
[all chattering, laughing]
Whoo!
Okay, ladies.
Gorgeous gaggle, sexy klatch,
welcome...
to the next chapter of your evening.
[Abby] Hmm. Is it too early or too late
to have a next chapter?
I feel like it's already tomorrow night.
- [Naomi] Hold up. What is that?
- [Abby gasps]
[whispers] What is that?
- Molly.
- [gasps]
Seriously, before you get all weird
and judge me and stuff like that,
I heard this super interesting podcast
on microdosing.
- Oh.
- Do you know about this? Okay?
So, we take a really small amount of MDMA,
and apparently
it can create this common experience
that's, like, super bonding.
Okay, I'm-- I'm listening.
Anyway, so... we are doing molly tonight.
Oh, I-- Mmm. I hear you.
But I don't think we are gonna do it.
Oh, so, we're... we're gonna do coke?
No, it's like ecstasy.
Like, um... like MDMA.
I thought MDMA was that extreme fighting.
Wait, do they do coke
and then they fight?
You, guys, it's molly.
I mean, I wanna "yes, and" this
but I'm just wondering,
how does molly interact with the drugs
I'm currently taking?
'Cause right now, I'm on Levothroid
and melatonin.
Things we say now.
For reals, though.
I'm on Wellbutrin and Farxiga.
I think it's fine. I'm on fluoxetine
and the Mirena IUD,
and I think it's gonna be totally fine.
I really do.
Guys, I'm on all kinds of stuff.
Zoloft, Singulair...
raw calcium, black cohosh
for night sweats, Zantac...
Mykonos... Who-ya-gonna-call-trex...
Queeffatram.
Cath, I think what we're all trying to say
is maybe this isn't that kind of trip.
You know what I mean? Like--
You know, we have a big day tomorrow.
And this is a marathon, it's not a sprint.
Hmm. I thought it was a birthday weekend.
Well...
Oh, okay.
Yeah, but it's totally...
It's Rebecca's birthday. Anyway...
You should download the podcast,
it's super interesting.
It's this amazing TED Talk, actually.
- Sounds amazing.
- I mean, I would do the podcast.
- I'd love to listen to the podcast.
- I feel bad.
I feel like--
- No, don't be sad.
- No, it's fine.
You know what? Apparently, we're just
not that interested in doing drugs.
Except for the thousands of drugs
we just listed.
I did Molly in college, but...
she went back to her boyfriend.
[all] Hey-oh!
- Let's dance it out.
- Let's dance.
[chanting] Dance it out! Dance it out!
- What should our first song be?
- First song, um...
"Sweet Child o' Mine," Guns N' Roses,
then we'll cascade into "Paradise City."
Um, anything from the Xanadu soundtrack,
anything from Flashdance soundtrack.
I don't want any Quentin Tarantino
soundtracks.
- Never.
- I'm done.
♪ We're coming home on a plane crash
We trip away through the night ♪
♪ We're breaking up on impact
We'll bring it to you live, yeah... ♪
Let's do a whole classic rock.
Let's do Boston, Styx,
Marshall Tucker Band, Lynyrd Skynyrd,
"Tuesday's Gone,"
no "Sweet Home Alabama."
Never. Kid Rock ruined it.
♪ We know what we really want ♪
♪ We know what we really want... ♪
- Natalie Merchant?
- Natalie Merchant, yes.
- Lauryn Hill?
- Lauryn Hill, a hundred percent.
- Bless it. What happened to her?
- Yeah, I don't know.
She didn't pay her taxes. She went crazy.
♪ We're creeping into your living room
We're crawlin' into your bed ♪
♪ We're takin' you all back to school
Bringing you our dead, yeah... ♪
I think we should not play anything...
later than "Hey Ya!"
- Nothing current.
- Nothing current, mm-mm.
- All right.
- Not tonight.
♪ You're broken, you're bleeding, yeah
We're living, we're learning, yeah ♪
♪ We know what we really want ♪
["Magic" playing]
Do you know what?
I wish Prince's ghost...
would come back...
and...
serenade me for, like, two whole hours,
and then make sweet, sweet love to me.
Yeah, no shit.
He fucking glided
into that elevator in Paisley Park,
and that fucking door closed...
And then, poof...
where's my baby?
- Where's my Prince?
- Beautiful-ass Prince.
I love my husband and shit,
but like...
that's the love of my life.
He had eyes like a beautiful newborn fawn.
Mm-hmm.
What was his pain?
His hips.
Oh, God, yeah.
And who knows? You know, life.
Life's-- Life ain't easy.
No.
I feel like the universe
is saying it to me.
I hear the universe saying...
"Your heroes are dying.
You're getting old."
- Dying is my worst fear.
- Same.
I swear to God. If anything...
happened to me...
I just think about--
I just think about my poor kids.
Like...
[Jenny] Mm.
My babies.
- You know? Like...
- I know.
No one's...
No one's gonna love my babies
like I do.
Oh, your sweet peas.
But I'm gonna tell you something.
Remember, how Prince would throw
his guitar up in the air
and his guitar tech...
would always catch the guitar
after a mind-blowing solo?
Yeah.
I'm... I'm that person for you.
I'll catch your guitar. Every time.
I will always catch...
your motherfucking guitar,
'cause you are my...
you are my rock.
I'm here for you. I'm your Apollonia.
I'm your Vanity.
- I love you.
Will you marry me?
Yeah.
♪ And if all your hopes survive... ♪
[man on podcast] I want us now to actually
take a look at the word "microdosing."
"Mi." My experience, my emotions.
"C." I am now going to see
my feelings and my emotions.
There are different levels.
"Ro." Rowing your mental boat
down a different stream.
[chimes]
♪ You have to believe we are magic ♪
♪ Nothing can stand in our way ♪
♪ Don't let your aim ever stray ♪
♪ And if all your hopes survive ♪
♪ Destiny will arrive ♪
♪ I'll bring all your dreams alive ♪
♪ For you... ♪
[dishes clattering]
[heavy metal door creaks]
[clattering continues]
[chopping]
- [screams]
- Ah!
Shit! Fuck! Who the fuck are you?
It's okay, I'm Devon,
I'm a nice person, I'm a nice person.
I'm nice.
- I'm allowed to--
- [screams] What is that?
That's a squid. That's a squid.
For the paella I'm prepping.
Did Tammy not tell you
I come with the house?
[sighs]
No, she gave us the full download
on the toilet fountain,
but she forgot to mention you.
I don't know what
I was planning to do with this.
- [Catherine] What's going on?
- Oh.
- Who's this asshole?
- [Abby] Uh, this is, um--
- Uh, who are you?
- I'm Devon. I'm Devon.
I come with the house.
Uh, think of me as your driver,
your tour guide, your chef.
I'm sorry I wasn't here yesterday.
I was down in Bodega Bay
spearing this little guy.
Devon is making...
What are you making?
My famous paella.
Sorry, I'll just grab this.
- Oh, God.
- It's kind of a process.
It takes a long time
so I was just getting a jump start on it.
Look at that thing, it's beautiful.
I mean, that is beautiful.
[blowing] You hear that?
[blows]
Squid or cuttlefish?
What do you think this is?
- God, that smells.
- It's a cuttlefish.
A cuttlefish is a little bit different,
they're cousins,
but this has actually what's called
a cuttlebone inside of it,
and, uh, a squid is faster, as a predator.
You're gonna see,
it takes on the flavor like a mother.
I mean, it's really sweet.
It wants to be-- It wants to be flavored,
and it's actually a more traditional
seafood protein
to put in the paella with the rice--
- Could you put that on ice, please?
- [Devon] Yeah, absolutely.
Ladies, if there's anything that you need,
let me know. Anything at all.
Because, as always...
[sighs deeply]
...it's an amazing day in wine country.
No, it's not.
[Abby] Oh, uh, yeah, Devon,
can you do me a favor?
Can you help me...
with the wind chimes
over the ceramic frogs?
'Cause they're all tangled
in the dream catchers
and the sound has been
keeping us up all night.
God damn it. I'm so sorry.
Sleep is so important.
Show me.
[Abby] And there's
a really loud bird out here.
[Devon] So sorry to hear.
I'll shut these later.
[Abby] Do you have a key?
How did you get in?
Hey, how are we feeling, ladies?
I feel like hot garbage.
Should we make coffee?
[Rebecca] Yeah.
What the fuck is this?
That's, uh...
That's seafood from... Devon.
- Who's Devon?
- He comes with the house.
Hmm.
Do we...
hit the button?
[Catherine] Gotta push the button.
- Should I push the button?
- Or I could do it.
Wait, did you already take a shower,
or are you about to take a shower?
What?
I don't know.
Does this house have a tea thingy?
Like, um...
You know what I mean, like, um...
[clears throat]
Like a hot water source.
- A kettle!
- Kettle.
A kettle.
Man, I am not doing great.
Y'all, what did I say last night?
I feel like I went on and on about...
somebody's mom.
Oh, wait, did everyone hang out
after I went to bed?
Any inside jokes
I should get caught up on?
No, we all went to bed.
[doorbell chimes]
Devon breaks in at 7:00 a.m.
but now he rings the doorbell?
- Who's Devon?
- He comes with the house.
Oh, it's the tarot card reader.
The what?
- Oh, no!
- On the itinerary.
Ooh! Maybe she can get the coffee to work.
Her name's Lady Sunshine.
Hi, you must be Lady--
This house was impossible to find.
Not marked.
I'm a psychic, not Magellan.
[Lady Sunshine] Oh, boy.
Okay, when I figure out
where I'm gonna place myself,
I'm gonna need you to put this
somewhere where I can see it.
Okay.
No, no, no.
We're gonna have to smudge
the heck out of this space.
The juju es no bueno.
Honey,
take this...
and go all around the room with it,
really wave it around.
- Don't be shy.
- Okay.
Okay, smudging not working.
We're gonna have to go
to a different room.
One that is not contaminated, preferably.
Just let it go.
If I may offer some feedback.
[in unison]
♪ Are you ready for some feedback? ♪
Oh, no.
Are you a singing group?
No, just friends.
We'll see.
[Lady Sunshine] The Chariot.
Oh, my God,
that would make a beautiful tattoo.
The Chariot is a very positive card...
Oh, really?
...when it's rightside up.
Yours is upside down.
The upside down Chariot...
tells me that you are
being dragged through time
with no control over
where life is taking you.
A big change has upended you.
You're free-falling.
You're killing yourself staying busy,
because if you don't,
you feel as if you will literally
break apart.
Still make a killer tattoo. [chuckles]
- Who's next?
- [bird chirping, crashing]
- Oh!
- [all gasp]
Oh, that's not good.
The Five of Pentacles.
Many say this card signifies
financial loss, poverty.
Um, well, I-- I'm lucky
'cause I'm very comfortable, but I...
do have an opportunity I would love
to ask you about, it's, um...
a TV job.
Um, I wonder what the card
says about that.
May I continue?
Yeah, of course.
Many say that this card signifies
financial loss, poverty.
- Okay.
- But not me.
She flipped it.
I find that the Five of Pentacles
points to emotional poverty.
So, nothing about the TV show.
[Lady Sunshine] The Fool.
You want a tattoo of this one as well?
I liked the Chariot better.
The Fool represents
new beginnings, optimism.
Man, I'm really ready to meet somebody.
Well, the Fool has difficulty
seizing on new opportunities
because they're too focused
on the needs of others.
Are you saying I should put my knees...
before others'
needs?
[laughing quietly]
Oh.
They laughed.
Next.
[Lady Sunshine] The Devil.
The Devil represents
the violent forces of nature
that can strain you--
Where did she go?
I don't think this is her jam.
I don't think this is anyone's jam.
[Lady Sunshine] Death.
- Fuck me!
- Jesus Christ.
- You're fired!
- No, no, I love this card, because...
people always think
that this is a very negative card.
They're scared of it.
But the Death card actually indicates
a time of transformation.
The death of the old you
to make way for the new.
A metamorphosis.
You're ready to become a butterfly.
But it can also mean death is coming.
Okay.
- [Lady Sunshine] The Wheel of Fortune.
- [gasps]
[imitating announcer] Wheel... of...
- For--
- The Wheel represents life cycles.
A turning point.
- A big change is coming.
- Her 50th birthday.
Oh.
Half a century...
Wow. [clicks tongue]
That's a long time.
Fifty years of age.
And see how Lady Fortuna
is just standing here,
in the middle of this wheel of change?
She is unmoving.
Right. Tranquil.
Peaceful.
Over.
Done.
And now for the group reading.
Uh, you know? No. I think we're--
This is when we say goodbye.
Yeah, I'm doing-- I've gotta--
- [Abby] We're done.
- [chuckling]
[ominous music plays]
Yeah, you're right. Never mind.
Wait, why? What does it say?
Is it bad?
The Garden looks like a winner.
Usually, yes, but not when it's sandwiched
between the Snakes and the Rocks.
You see, the fighting snakes show me...
that you all surround yourselves
with battles.
People who have been intertwined
and dueling for thousands of years.
You need to help shed the tough skins
that have built up over time,
if you are to remain friends.
A lot of secrets.
Many things unspoken.
And you see the space?
No one's as close as they think.
And you see here with the river stones?
They're gems. They used to be dynamic
and many-faceted.
And they have been worn over time.
And now, they are smooth and dull.
Aged.
From one old lady to another...
get over all your shit,
'cause it is later than you think.
That'll be $475.
[on voicemail] Hello, this is Olivia
from Dr. Melton's office
calling to let you know
that the results--
Move it or lose it. I'm up.
Got it.
Don't wanna fuck up that itinerary.
- We got our marching orders.
- [chuckles]
Bye, you.
[Catherine]
Sorry, is this any better?
So what's going on with the offer?
Is it any--
Hello? Hello?
Shit-balls! Hello?
- Hello? Shit, fuck--
- Sorry.
Not being nosy, just wanted to bring
some of my hangover cure.
Oh, thanks.
Oh, and some of my edible soaps
for you, too.
Sorry, I...
I know I should be enjoying myself
and not stressing about work.
Hey, I'm not judging.
Owning and managing five properties
has its share of shit-fuck days for sure.
[chuckling] But I bet you get to meet
a lot of interesting people, so...
No.
No, you'd be surprised.
People are all the same.
I go whole days without speaking.
Better get to the wine tasting, so...
- A little advice for today.
- Oh?
If you, or anyone around you
starts a sentence with,
"Can I just say something?"
stop right there.
[laughs] Okay. I will keep that in mind.
Thank you.
Try the juice.
It's got kind of a garbage flavor,
but the soap helps with the aftertaste.
- Edible?
- Seventy percent.
I can still taste the soap a little bit.
It's just in your head.
It's 'cause of the shape.
Now, as you can see,
this little beauty is quite spacious
and does come with
4x4 off-road capability.
So if you see some beautiful spot
and you say to yourself,
"I'd like to get up close and personal
with that vista,
but the terrain is clearly a no-go."
Think again. I got you.
Yeah, we got it, man.
This van has everything here.
We got seats like...
- Who's this guy again?
- Abby's worst nightmare.
...cup holders, really nice,
uh, adjustable air and fans,
safety lights,
emergency kit--
Okay, let's get driving.
We have a birthday we need to celebrate.
How old are you turning,
little mama, 21?
Devon, that's none of your business.
No, you know, I'm not ashamed to say.
Actually, I'm turning 50 tomorrow.
- Whoo!
- Yeah!
Great, yeah. You say it, sister!
Okay, can we go?
[Devon] All right.
[plays note on guitar]
[singing out of tune]
♪ Birthday to you... ♪
♪ Your birthday... ♪
[tuning guitar, humming]
Overshot it. I hear things a touch sharp.
Devon. Let's go.
- [Abby] Okay.
- Hold that for me, would you?
All right! Ten-four, cap'n!
[Devon] So, ladies, a little early history
of the Napa Valley.
The first official winery and vineyard
was established by one Mr. John Patchett,
who began planting grape vines in 1854--
So, Val, did that cute waitress
text you back?
- Ooh. Is there romance in the air?
- Devon, don't listen to our conversation.
[Val] No, but she's probably
still sleeping.
That picture she took of you is gorgeous.
- Mm-hmm. Thanks.
- What picture?
Oh, it's on the shared photo site we have.
You probably didn't accept the invite.
No, I didn't get one.
Will you send me an invite? I'll accept.
Probably just the Wi-Fi.
[Devon] Signal is hard to come by
out here.
I'll tell you what's not hard
to come by.
A rich and hearty cab sauv
with healthy levels of tannins.
Which brings me back
to John Patchett in 1854--
Ugh. I do not wanna learn about wine
on this trip.
This is weird, Cat. You're not on here.
Oh, way to go, guys. [chuckles]
Who started the shared site?
Oh, I did, but I didn't intentionally
leave you off.
Oh, remember, let's remain uncontaminated
from Lady Sunshine's negative suggestions.
- Yeah.
- [Naomi] Yes!
- We are uncontaminated.
- Uncontaminated.
All right, added.
- Hey, should we listen to some tunes?
- Oh.
- Oh! Let's do DUI songs.
- [all] Yes.
You guys got DUIs, too, huh?
No, it's a game we play.
It's like guilty pleasure songs
we blast when we're tipsy.
Are you legally allowed to drive?
I will be.
["Kids in America" playing]
- [gasping] Yes.
- Yeah!
[Devon continues lecturing indistinctly]
...less than 4.04% of the wine in America.
Devon, shh!
♪ Looking out a dirty old window ♪
♪ Down below the cars in the city
Go rushing by ♪
♪ I sit here alone and I wonder why ♪
♪ Friday night and everyone's moving ♪
♪ I can feel the heat but it's soothing
Heading down ♪
♪ I search for the beat
In this dirty town ♪
♪ Downtown
The young ones are going ♪
The young ones are growing ♪
- ♪ We're the kids in America ♪
- ♪Whoa ♪
♪ Everybody lives for the music-go-round ♪
Ladies, if cabernet sauvignon
is the king of wine country,
chardonnay is its queen.
It's bold--
Okay, hair of the dog.
All right, fine, go to a wine store then.
I just wanna say...
that we never know
where life is gonna take us.
So let's live for today...
and party till our panties fly off.
Wait, where's Catherine?
I think she had to call her agent.
Please don't say "panties."
Oh, hell to the hell to the hell
to the hell to the no!
I'm gonna go get her.
Anyone picking up on the notes
of honeysuckle?
- Uh, yeah, sure.
- Get a good sniff.
Let me know what you smell.
There's no wrong answers.
Uh, green apple?
- Yeah, very good.
- Yes!
Green apple.
I wanna say...
canned peaches?
No.
You said there's no wrong answer.
Yeah, but... you know.
Peaches. There is no peaches in there.
- Okay.
- What else you got?
- Oh, lemon.
- Yes, very good.
I taste the lemon, yeah.
You don't taste it, you smell it.
Grapes!
Well, yeah. Of course.
Nice. That's smart!
Definitely grapes in there.
Can't go wrong with that.
- Jasmine.
- No, that's... that's egregious.
Pinot-gregious.
- Thank you.
- You're killing it on the wines.
[laughing]
Oh, we lost Mason.
So is it like The Catherine Stewart Show,
or is it like I'm one of three judges,
you know what I mean?
'Cause that's sort of significant
in terms of what...
I'm talking about.
You know what I mean?
Right, if it's Catherine Stewart
of Cutie Pies
or Cutie Pies Featuring
Catherine Stewart and like--
Can you hold on one second?
Something's going on in front on me.
What are you doing?
My God, give me my phone back.
- That's an important phone call.
- My face is an important phone call.
I'm not giving you
your precious phone back...
until you start flossing.
Come on.
All right, fine.
Do it. Do it. Do it!
Okay. Oh, my God, I'm nailing this.
I'm really good at this.
- She'll call you back, she's flossing.
- I gotta floss more when I'm day-drunk.
[Val] Here's the last thing I sent to her.
"I have vintage jade earrings at my store.
Would love to send them to you."
So dumb.
She's Jade.
You know she's got, like,
a million jade things.
I made a mistake.
[sighs]
She's too young for me.
Val.
May I offer you some feedback?
Go for it.
Okay, I mean, when it comes to age,
the number itself truly doesn't matter.
It's, I mean...
I wish Abby could understand this,
'cause she's coming at me like,
"You're 50! You're 50! You're 50!"
It's like, what matters is
how you feel inside.
So...
with all that in mind,
what would you say your soul's age is?
I'd say, like, 12.
I mean, maybe a little older.
Probably old enough to drink... and bone.
Maybe 18... 18 and a half.
Almost out of the house.
Don't have my own car yet.
But I have a bike.
Mmm.
Oh. This one's good.
What's it called again?
- White wine.
- [scoffs] Frickin' love it.
So, can I just say something?
Rebecca is in complete denial
that this is her birthday weekend.
You know, as usual,
she's glossing over everything.
There are so many things
she doesn't deal with.
- Hello? Brian.
- Ugh. Fuckin' Brian.
She's gotta be having feelings
about turning 50.
Where does she put it all?
"This is just another trip,
it's not a big deal." It's like...
Hello? Get into it!
God, you know how hard it is,
by the way...
to make 10,000 reservations
for 400 people
at 55 million different locations?
Oh, I know.
Abby, you've done such a good job
at planning this. You should know that.
Thanks.
It's probably 'cause
it's my full-time job now.
Wait, what?
- This is good, right?
- Oh, yeah.
[Abby] Chug-a-lug, ladies!
We're on the move!
Oh, no, ladies. That is a select cabernet,
meant to be savored...
Yeah, we can get this stuff online.
Let's hit the van.
[Rebecca] Jeez, this is a real
go-go-go kinda trip.
Keep up, Fifty.
My soul age is 28.
[Mason] I'd love to get your names
and socials for our wine club.
Okay, guys, next stop
is biking and shopping.
- Yes!
- And we're gonna get all our stuff in Napa
so we don't have to get anything
at the airport.
I'm gonna buy a really big hat.
Ooh! Naomi, you're up.
What's your DUI song?
My song is gonna be,
"Poison, Po-Po-Po-Poison."
Whoo!
["Poison" playing]
♪ Poison ♪
♪ Yeah, Spyderman and Freeze
In full effect ♪
- ♪ You ready, Ron? ♪
- ♪ I'm ready ♪
- ♪ You ready, Biv? ♪
- ♪ I'm ready, Slick, are you? ♪
♪ Oh, yeah, break it down... ♪
Ooh, pizza.
- ♪ Girl, I must warn you ♪
- [bike bell rings]
♪ I sense something strange in my mind... ♪
Oh, my God.
I just spent $750.
[laughing]
Not only is Morgan Jorng Winery solar,
it is also... [hums fanfare]
...organic!
So no sulfates, no pesticides,
and the beautiful sun powering us all.
[Abby] Mm-hmm.
You'll notice, because it's organic,
there's a lot of sediment
at the bottom of your glass.
- I was wondering what that was.
- Does anybody know the term for that?
For the sediment
at the bottom of the glass.
- [sighing] You can just tell us.
- Sediment?
- Gravel?
- Mud?
- Shavings?
- Wine waste?
- [Jenny] Minerality?
- I'll just go ahead and answer this one.
- Tartrates.
You know what I also
like to call it, though?
Wine diamonds.
- Huh...
- Oh.
[Jenny] Jeez, people really like
to talk about wine around here.
Well, yeah. [chuckles]
It's Napa.
[chuckles]
Right? Why you came here.
- Can we get to the...
- Sure, get to the solar questions?
No, speed this up.
Okay, so how much energy do you think
that our solar panels create here?
- How much energy?
- I don't know.
Mm-hmm.
Ten kilowatts?
Fifty thousand.
[whistles]
I was way off.
You know what I really like
that we do here?
Notice how our wines are not on ice?
What are they on?
- [Rebecca] Soil.
- Soil. Exactly. I...
- Gonna stroll around for a second.
- Oh, okay.
So, just one rule today.
No walking in the vineyards.
Okay?
And have fun.
Can I just say something?
I'm tired of Naomi shaming me
for working all the time.
You know what I mean? It's like, we work,
it's who we are, it's what we do.
Well, I hope I'm more than my work,
or else, fuck.
Oh, come on, yeah.
Okay, let's play "path not taken."
Ooh.
I would work at a bookstore,
like a crunchy bookstore
in Portland or Seattle,
somewhere rainy and moody.
- Ooh, I love it.
- Right?
- Oh, that's so good.
- You go.
Okay, path not taken.
- Zamboni driver.
- [laughing]
I swear to God.
I think it would be so peaceful.
- Clean slate every two hours.
- Hmm.
Start over, nice and simple.
- Really cold, no hot flashes. Come on.
- Ooh.
I think I would also be good
at close-up magic.
- You would.
- Thank you.
- Oh, my God, that's such a good one.
- Yeah. I could...
- maintain fierce eye contact...
- Yes.
- ...while stealing someone's wallet.
- I love it.
Can I just say something?
Why is Naomi treating this trip like...
we're all gonna die immediately after?
Hmm, she loves us so much.
But, yeah, it's a little manic.
Is there scarecrows out here?
'Cause if I see a scarecrow,
I'm gonna fucking shit my pants.
[laughing]
Remember when you shit your pants
in Yankee Candle Company?
Yes. Because whenever I sniff candles,
I always have to poop.
Yeah, but you're around candles,
so it covers up the smell. That's good.
I know, but-- [laughs]
But then it's a vicious cycle.
[both laughing]
[Naomi] Can I just say something?
I got my bikini area lasered,
and now I'm like, "Oh, great.
What's it gonna look like when I'm 70?"
Is it-- Is it gonna be like a...
gray-haired goatee?
- Oh, you got too much off?
- Yes. It's like a--
It's like pencil-thin, I blew it.
- I'm gonna need that hair down there--
- Well, you don't know.
Maybe it'll be a cute little
Colonel Sanders chin going on down there.
That's-- That's what I want,
a cute Colonel Sanders chin.
"Honey. Honey, are you looking forward
to seeing Colonel Sanders tonight?"
Oh, boy.
Maybe it's like, um...
you know, it's like a...
like a Dizzy Gillespie,
like a jazz musician...
- Oh, right.
- ...beav.
- I think he'd love that.
- What about a little Ted Nugent?
No, wait, I shouldn't have said that.
- Fuck that guy.
- No Ted Nugent. Sorry.
Like a Billy Bob Thornton,
that's what you were thinking.
Sure, Billy Bob Thornton.
[imitating Billy Bob] "Hey, honey,
you want some French fried potaters?"
Oh, God! Full-on mud in this bottle!
God, fuck this organic shit.
Well, you better drink up,
'cause Abby's gonna come through
with the Abby-alarm any minute now.
- [snorts] Oh, my God.
- Can I just say something?
- She needs to ease up.
- Yes.
- It's insane.
- Hi!
This is an organic winery,
so we can't have you walking in there.
- Oh.
- Yeah, I think we've put up signs.
Ooh! [laughs] Right there.
- So, yeah, can't walk through there.
- [Rebecca] Oh.
- [Naomi] Sorry.
- Okay, you can follow me out.
- Okay, sorry about that.
- Okay.
- Sorry, not sorry.
- Right?
- The sign is facing the other way.
- Hey, guess what, passive aggressive.
- That wasn't passive. That was aggressive.
- Guess what, also?
- My shoes are clean.
- Yeah.
Hey, you don't know me.
You don't know my shoes.
- You don't...
- You don't know my shoes, bitch!
You don't know my shoes.
Guess what? These are fucking clean.
Can you just follow me out?
Keep coming.
- Okay, no problem.
- Okay, sorry about that.
[laughing]
[soft jazz playing]
- [Brian] Happy birthday, babe.
- [Abby] Technically tomorrow.
- He knows that.
- But I can't call tomorrow
'cause I'll be out on the pontoon boat.
Holy shit.
Have they been here this whole time?
Hey.
I know, I know, guys.
You were thinking something else, right?
Well, guess what, I'm here.
Oh. Funny story.
I had some wine diamonds today,
and I don't feel so good.
Oh, my God. Naomi is loaded.
You know, I wanna sing a little ditty
for my sweet, sweet,
very short friend, Rebecca
who is turning 22 tomorrow.
Wink, wink. [blows raspberry]
[laughing] She's not.
You know...
birthdays are a funny thing,
'cause, like, some people hate 'em
and some people love 'em.
I love my birthday, I'm a Leo,
but, Rebecca, you got it going on, girl.
Don't get it twisted.
You deserve the world.
And since I can't give you diamonds,
and I can't give you pearls,
I'mma give you something
you ain't never had before.
I'm gonna give you a song from the heart.
You guys,
our dear, dear, sweet...
Rebecca Sue is all growed up.
I want to dedicate this song
to my beautiful friend, Rebecca.
This is for you, honey tits.
Hit a ten, boys.
What would you like us to play?
"Eternal Flame."
- [women all gasp]
- Yes.
[band playing]
♪ Close your eyes ♪
[thudding]
Oh, my God.
Naomi?
- [feedback whines]
- I'm cool.
- Yeah!
- Yeah.
A pro. You're a pro.
♪ Darling ♪
♪ Do you feel my heart beating? ♪
♪ Do you understand? ♪
[Devon] I'm sensing a lull.
So my vote is for literally
anything by Sublime.
Absolutely not, Devon.
- Chilis?
- [Abby] Devon. No.
- Bush?
- Now I'm getting upset.
Oh, my God. "Everything Zen."
That changed my life.
- [Devon] Third Eye Blind?
- [Abby] No.
- [Devon] 311?
- [Jenny] No.
Okay, guys! I got the T-shirts
for the drone shot.
Did you say "drone shot"?
Oh, yeah, the drone shot,
it's in the itinerary.
Yes, I said "drone." On the itinerary.
- I don't think my shirt's gonna fit.
- It is. It will.
Okay, follow me guys, let's go.
Can we just stay here a little bit?
It's so nice.
We're gonna go through the wine tunnels
and take the drone shot.
[Catherine] Holy cannoli.
These weird wine caves
would be a good place to try molly.
Maybe we'll do the molly after we get
the drone shot. That'll be more fun.
Wait, I have a few more questions.
Is molly what that kid did
when he ate that guy's face
in his dad's garage?
- I don't think so.
- Is that the one that keeps you up?
Because when I need to sleep,
I need to sleep.
Come on, people, let's just try it.
Are we a bunch of nerds?
- Yes.
- Okay, if we want to do the molly,
maybe we can do it
after horseback riding tomorrow.
I vote no on the horseback riding,
Wait, here's what I don't get, like,
if we were to do the molly,
how long does it stay in your body?
Like, what is the duration of the "trip?"
- [laughing]
- Oh, my God, the quotes.
Whatever we do,
we have to harmonize in here
- 'cause the acoustics are the shit.
- Oh, yes.
[harmonizing]
[Abby] Hey, guys!
Can we put our T-shirts on,
so we can get to the pavilion
and take a super-fun drone shot?
You guys, I'm gonna go follow her
and I'm gonna go offer some feedback.
- I actually think that's a terrible idea.
- Don't do it.
- Please don't.
- No, this is what I do.
Where is she?
Yeah, how does she know her way
around these tunnels?
♪ Where'd she go? ♪
[harmonizing]
♪ Where did she go? ♪
[laughing]
Seriously, where'd she go?
[Catherine] Are we lost?
[indistinct chatter]
[both sigh]
Hey, Abby, the girls urged me
not to offer you any feedback,
but I'm just gonna go with my gut here.
May I offer you some feedback?
Oh, boy.
I feel like the universe
is gently nudging you to chill.
Well, tell the universe that I'm chilling,
and I'm also looking for the drone.
Do you see it?
Okay, just, the schedule you have us on,
I feel like it's keeping you
from having fun.
Like, if you were just to let go,
everything will just fall into place.
Will it fall into place?
Will it, Rebecca? Will it fall into place?
Will someone else take care of me?
Or will I always have to do
everything myself?
Let me know when it falls into place,
'cause last time I checked,
this world's pretty fucking selfish.
Okay. Deep breath. [inhales]
No, let's take some inventory
about how everything's falling into place.
How about my marriage?
Did that fall into place?
What about those texts from that girl
that's gonna hurt you?
That falling into place?
Your obvious midlife crisis.
Is that falling into place?
Your inability to cope
with almost anything...
- is that falling into place for you?
- No.
What about your husband?
Is that falling into place?
What?
Maybe you should take
a good hard look at yourself.
Maybe the therapist should go to therapy.
Am I not getting a falling into place?
- [Naomi] Catherine, enough.
- [sighs]
The whole "left out" thing
is really getting old.
You're the one who's always running away
from us every time you get a call.
- I have work.
- I'm sorry, let's not fight.
This time together
is supposed to be special.
Oh, my God, Naomi, we're not fighting,
we're just talking.
- That's what life is.
- Well, it's very negative.
Yeah, life is negative,
that's what Brené Brown said.
That's exactly what she did not say.
Abby, what is negative in your life,
right now?
Okay, you've got amazing friends,
you got a great career--
No, I don't.
[tearfully] Okay? I lost my job.
All right? And it's really stupid
to even cry about it.
Shit, I mean, people are starving
in the world and there's earthquakes.
And people are shooting at each other,
I'm crying about my stupid poor job.
Oh, Abby, honey. That doesn't mean
your feelings aren't valid.
That's exactly what white privilege is!
Plus, what are we doing
to the environment?
I mean, we can't--
There's no fish anymore!
All the plastic is...
filling up in the ocean.
And... [sobs]
There's like one rhinoceros left!
What the fuck?
Why wouldn't she tell us that?
[sighs] Some things are too scary to say.
Not to us.
You guys don't like Brian?
- Oh, my God, We love Brian.
- Brian?
- Just-- He's a character.
- He's the best.
- So cool.
- Fuckin' prince.
Awesome.
Where to?
[Rebecca] Oh, um...
Well, Abby, what's--
what's on the itinerary?
You know what? Don't look at that,
it doesn't matter. It's stupid.
Do you think throwing the itineraries
out of the window was on the itinerary?
[Jenny] Guess we'll never know.
Guys, left or right?
I gotta make a decision.
[cell phone chimes]
Oh, my God, she texted.
Jade just texted back.
She wants us to come over to her art show.
Aww.
[chuckles] I told you.
- I mean, I knew that she would text.
- Okay, let's go there, then.
Let's go to the art show, right?
That'll be perfect.
[Rebecca] Let's pick a DUI song!
Anybody?
I think silence is good for now.
[indistinct chatter]
This is a major fuck-up.
Abby's gonna hate this.
This wall of shoe boxes
should really snap her out of her mood.
I'll tell you the answer.
"No," and "No, you're not."
Abby, I know you don't want
to talk about it,
but I'm really sorry about your job.
Oh, thanks.
One time I can't figure out
how to get on Snapchat.
One time.
And everybody saw.
[sighs]
Young people blow.
Isn't Jade so ungodly cute?
[Jade] Okay, guys, I'm gonna
just say a couple words.
Um...
Yeah, so, uh...
Art has been my raison d'être since...
literally my first moment
of consciousness.
Um, I can't believe I'm following
in the footsteps of my heroes...
O'Keeffe, Kahlo, Warhol, Basquiat,
with my very own show.
So, thank you.
I'm humbled.
[applause]
Clearly.
Thank you for coming in, too,
like, from the city
in the caravans and all of...
it's fucking so touching.
So, thank you.
Uh... so, yeah.
Let me, uh, get on with it.
The Nanny was more than a sitcom.
Okay, it was a postmodern psychodrama
about classism and ambition in the 1990s.
You know, Fran Drescher's Fran Fine
was an icon, honestly.
I-- I mean, a cultural touchstone.
[crowd applauding]
God. All her art is Fran Drescher.
Why?
Uh, yeah, so yeah, I'd like to just
open up for some questions or comments.
Yeah?
It's so contextual, but at the same time,
wholly independent.
Did you do that consciously?
Uh, you know what, I did. Yeah.
Uh, it's really a lettera d'amore
to The Nanny.
But, more importantly, it's a reaction
to all of our experiences
surrounding The Nanny.
I never saw The Nanny,
but I don't want that to stop me
from participating in this conversation.
It shouldn't.
Um, this piece...
Am I supposed to feel scared?
Yes. I am so glad you got that vibe.
- Also offended. Yeah?
- Very. Thank you.
Have you considered doing
any other sitcom art?
- Like, is ALF an option?
- That's a good question.
Uh, I think I'm focusing more on women
right now.
'Cause, I don't know, I feel like
time is up on ALF, right?
I-- I have a question. Um...
Do any of you watch TV?
Like, is TV still a thing?
Like, do you watch those
judging competition shows?
I've only seen TV in the movies.
- [sighs]
- [Catherine] I knew I was right.
Damn it. Gotta call my agent.
Adrian, comma, confirming I was correct
re, colon, streaming V, period, broadcast.
Shit, I don't have a signal,
I gotta go outside.
Yeah, my oldest kid is 15
and on the verge of becoming...
this.
I just want to know, how do I stop her
from becoming an asshole?
I feel like I'm about to take umbrage.
Are you okay?
[Naomi]
And you know what else worries me?
It is way too easy for you guys
to get porn.
Oh, my God.
I used to drive miles
in the middle of the night
just to go to this little newsstand
by the bus station
just to find lesbo porn.
You guys have it so lucky
on the porn front.
I hadn't thought about it
that way before.
It's so interesting.
Mm-hmm. No wonder
they're so scared of sexuality.
[murmurs of assent]
They associate it with hard work and fear.
- And driving long distances.
- Mmm.
I can't with the confidence
in these people.
Wait. So we're putting 'em down
because they have healthy self-esteem?
I've spent my whole life thinking I suck.
You know what happened
at my first poetry reading?
I completely bombed.
No claps. No snaps. Just total silence.
Until finally this one dude,
way in the back,
he just turned to his girlfriend
and he went,
"Oof."
But you know what?
That was an important oof,
because it confirmed to me
that I'm a complete piece of shit,
and that's what made me
the writer I am today.
I thank God for that oof.
- This girl needs an oof.
- Oof.
Jade, we're not trying
to hurt anyone's feelings.
My God, they were born with hurt feelings.
Why do you not blast your feelings
all over your best friend, the internet?
Please, their parents
are their best friends.
Well, that I do like.
You know who my best friend is?
My best friend.
These women, right here,
who I have known for 20-plus years.
And, yeah, sure, sometimes
I want to tell this one to fuck off.
That's what intimacy looks like.
- You want me to fuck off?
- What?
If you all are friends,
why are you so mad at each other?
[Abby] We're not mad!
- Crazy, mad, grouchy. Look at this one.
- Fascinating.
We're not grouchy.
Guys, please forgive us.
We've been drinking wine all day,
and we're just not right in our heads
right now.
We are exactly where we need to be.
We're doing fine...
Fran Fine.
[all gasping]
- [applause]
- That's brilliant. Did you see that?
Is this part of the show?
That was... incredible.
You are amazing. Moms, you're amazing.
[woman] I mean it.
[Jade] Context within context, like,
it's exactly what we're talking about.
Excuse me. Do you have Wi-Fi in here?
And then there was one.
Tammy, hi.
I'm just trying to get a little work done
while the girls are at this art show.
- Art show?
- Yeah.
Oof, things must have gone
really sideways.
Here. Give me your phone.
I'll get you online.
Oh, my God. Awesome, thank you.
Pedro, is the password still
"penis_grigio72"?
[chuckling]
Thank you.
We need a couple of beers here also.
Ooh. Cool.
Are you guys good pals?
We are acquaintances.
Ah.
Do you ever get lonely up here,
living by yourself?
No, I love it. Loneliness is for suckers.
'Cause you know who I can trust? Me.
You know, who's never gonna bail on me?
Me.
Anyway, get your shit done,
bring people joy
with that fantastic pizza.
I'll be over here hitting bull's-eyes.
Hey, Tammy, can I ask your advice
on something?
Shoot.
- I'm being offered this TV show--
- No, shoot the dart.
I'm uncomfortable in any one-on-one
situation unless I can win.
Oh.
Sure. Right, okay.
Thanks, Val.
Do you think you can carry
this one over, too?
You got it.
- Okay, just be very careful.
- Oh, of course.
Okay.
Oh, that smile is so infectious.
I know, it's so ironic, right?
Sorry about my friends.
Oh, no! I love them.
People are really liking my show.
Do you think you guys could come back
and do that whole...
"I'm mad at young people" thing again?
I can ask. But to be clear,
we're not mad at young people.
Or I'd be mad at myself, right?
- You're so funny, Val.
- Aw.
I'm happy we met.
Me, too.
I like you.
I like you, too.
Can I ask you something?
[sighs]
I think I know what it is.
I usually charge $800, but...
I'm gonna give it to you for $600.
Talking about the painting?
[Jade chuckles]
That's great.
'Cause I love your art so much.
- It's gonna look great.
- I can't wait to hang it.
Ah. So happy.
As a business owner, you can't join in
in the same way.
You know, you can't worry
about if people like you or not.
Yeah, I mean, I...
Oh, shit.
I get that with my employees,
but we're talking about
my oldest friends, I mean...
of course I'm gonna worry
about what they think.
That's where you're fucking up.
Why?
Because I don't think your friends
even invited you on this trip.
Did Abby tell you that?
Did she say five people were coming?
What? No.
I'm saying is work
is a big part of who you are.
So if they don't let you talk about work,
then they're not letting you
be on this trip.
Yeah, okay. Can I just say something?
No. Ah-ah. Remember what I said?
About the phrase
"Can I just say something?"
- Just walk away from that phrase.
- Fuck, right.
[sighs]
When I was a kid,
I was always alone, you know?
My mom was a single working mother,
that whole deal, right?
And it really wasn't until I met
these girls that I...
experienced family.
That's powerful.
Friendship is powerful.
You gotta do that show.
Stay busy, pizza for one,
be honest with yourself,
work is your best friend,
and you gotta get contestants
on that show that are kids,
because I love watching
kids with knives.
Yeah.
This weekend is a mess.
I can't even plan a fun birthday trip.
[Devon] Can I quote one of my favorite
song lyrics?
"Self-doubt is self-worth
in another universe."
What song is that?
My own.
Of course.
Is the paella ready yet?
Just about.
Maybe another four hours or so.
Oh, Jesus.
- How are you gonna get that thing home?
- [Val] I don't know. I'll fuckin' fold it!
You know what?
Today was not an amazing day
in wine country.
So suck on that.
Hm.
- [man] So how is it? Are you having fun?
- This trip is three nights too long.
But the trip is only three nights.
Oh. I get it.
Wish I was there.
[on voicemail] Hello, this is Olivia
from Dr. Melton's office
calling to let you know
the results from your blood work are in.
If you could please give us a call back
at your earliest convenience...
[sighs]
Ah! Fuck!
Oh!
Oh, my God.
Oh, my back.
[whimpering]
[thuds]
My back.
[groaning]
Oh, no.
Oh, my God, no.
No.
Guys? Guys!
[knocking]
Hey.
So, quick update,
the paella is still simmering, it's gonna
take a little longer than I thought.
Whatever, Devon.
Any chance we could have sex?
Fine.
Morning, sunshine.
I'd love to stick around and snuggle,
but the paella is probably peaking.
Devon, get the fuck out.
To be continued.
Rebecca?
[gasps]
What's going on?
Are you okay? Did you pass out?
No, I'm not okay.
- I threw my back out.
- Oh, no.
- Okay, let me call Tammy.
- No, Naomi, shut up, shut it.
- Just help me up here.
- You got it.
- Okay, just get me up.
- Okay, you got it.
- Ready? One, two, three...
- No problem.
[groans]
Oh!
Oh, honey. Are you okay?
I was lying here all night.
And I realized...
Abby was right about me.
I did need to take
a good hard look in the mirror,
or in this case, the door.
And as I was lying here,
I saw every truth about myself.
Soon...
a trio of raccoons joined me.
Right there.
Yeah.
I locked eyes with the dad.
Once you've looked in the eye
of a raccoon,
you know your truth.
How did you know he was the dad?
He was just the leader, I could tell.
You didn't, like, look at--
They were all with me, though.
They stayed here. It was amazing.
- You saw a family of raccoons?
- Yes.
And you communicated--
I connected with them
more than anyone this whole weekend.
Honey, did you take that molly?
They helped me see what I really am.
- An old lady.
- What?
Yes, it's true. I'm old, 50.
- That's half a fucking century.
- Listen.
We are all getting older and
maybe our bodies aren't working--
Fuck feedback,
I don't want any feedback right now.
- Okay.
- I need to make some big changes.
Number one.
I'm in a shitty marriage.
Brian is a world-class ding-dong.
Thank God.
Brian sucks.
[gasps]
Hey, what's going on in here?
Rebecca threw her back out
and Brian sucks.
What? No.
Val, she knows.
- Oh, thank God.
- [Abby] We don't like him.
- [Jenny] Such an asshole.
- I'm done lying to myself.
I'm ready to tell like it is.
It's just like Lady Sunshine said.
It's later than we think, so--
[moans]
Okay. Get me up off this floor.
'Cause we are gonna do everything
on that goddamn itinerary
and we are gonna do it now!
This is really good news, 'cause
I have planned some exciting things.
Where's Catherine?
Has anyone seen her this morning?
Oh, my God, did she leave early
to do that stupid-ass cooking show?
Unbelievable, she full-on bailed
on Rebecca's birthday.
- Oh, happy birthday by the way.
- [all] Happy birthday!
- Load me up!
- Okay.
Let's go! Go! Move! Move! Move! Move!
Ooh. Get me out of this bathrobe, though.
It's really depressing.
Put me in my finest muumuu!
Hey. Good news.
Two hours and counting on the paella.
Oh, how in God's name
is that paella not ready?
I got a little sidetracked last night.
Stop.
[Rebecca] Okay, you know what? It's fine.
We don't even want the paella.
No, I can't wait to taste it, Devon.
No, no, let's not bullshit him.
We don't want the paella.
Life is too short to wait for the paella!
Ladies, we are gonna grab this day
by the motherfucking balls.
I'm gonna get this wheely chair
onto this senior van
- and I'm going to my birthday brunch!
- Yeah! All right, let's do it!
Move it! Ah!
[cheering]
- Okay, I feel every bump.
- Oh, so sorry.
- Okay, no, it's all right.
- [Naomi] How you wanna do this?
My work here is done.
[Abby] Okay, are you ready?
- Lay it on me. Big five-oh.
- Okay, here we go.
- Keep your eyes closed.
- Okay.
♪ Happy, happy birthday ♪
♪ It's your special day ♪
♪ Have a slice of pizza ♪
♪ What's your favorite way? Hey! ♪
This is like end of A League of Their Own
where the baseball ladies show up
at the Hall of Fame.
So check it out.
I just want to show you what I--
What we did, okay.
- We got the original sign from Antonio's.
- [Rebecca gasps]
- Whoa.
- It says "Happy Birthday, Rebecca."
There's pictures of us.
These are the prices...
- Oh, my God.
- That we had when we were waiting tables.
Here is the mural
that somebody did a copy of.
But what's different about the face?
[Rebecca yelps]
- You didn't! How did you do that?
- We had Antonio's pizza flown in.
- Oh, my God.
- And these...
are the original bread baskets we used,
everyone can take one of these home.
Wow. That is--
So, Antonio could not be with us
'cause he's dead.
But, um, we have our DJ
dressed up like Antonio
and he is ready to get this party started!
- ♪ Bust it ♪
- [Abby] Whoo!
["Bust a Move" playing]
♪ This here's a tale for all the fellas ♪
♪ Trying to do what
Those ladies tell us ♪
♪ Get shot down 'cause ya overzealous ♪
♪ Play hard to get
Females get jealous... ♪
Well, doesn't this look fun.
- Hey, Catherine!
- Cut it, cut it.
- [music stops]
- Catherine! Hey! Catherine!
Sorry, we thought you left.
I have a shirt for you.
- Did you guys even notice that I was gone?
- We tried to contact you.
- The Wi-Fi here is really...
- The password is so long.
I just shouldn't even have
come on this trip. I'm clearly not wanted.
And, Abby, can you just be honest?
Did you get a five-bedroom
because I wasn't really invited?
What? No, I honestly thought
Jenny wouldn't show.
- Same.
- Whatever, I don't care anymore.
Don't worry, you clearly won't notice
that I'm gone.
[clap]
Wow.
♪ She's dressed in yellow... ♪
Hey, cut it.
[music stops]
I thought she was clapping.
- It was a slow clap.
- She's clapping sarcastically.
[Rebecca] Wait, who's talking?
I can't see. What's happening?
- Okay, what's going on here?
- Oh, what's going on here
is I threw my back out 'cause I'm old.
Oh, my God, Rebecca, you are not old.
Oh, please, just don't throw the word
"vivacious" at me or I will lose it.
[clapping]
Naomi, what is with the slow clap?
Oh, I'm just applauding
the greatest self-fulfilling prophecy
of all time.
What are you talking about?
You always think that you're not invited
or we leave you out.
So you bury yourself in your work,
but then you're so buried in your work
that you are left out.
I'm busy, okay? I can't just take off work
whenever I feel like it,
and I shouldn't have to apologize
for being successful.
We are not asking you to apologize
I'm proud as fuck of you.
But have you ever considered
that we might really need you here?
We all need all of us here.
I need to know that we're all
going to be there for each other,
because this group is sacred to me.
And if we can't get through
a weekend together,
well, then I'm completely lost.
I am going through a really hard time,
and...
I... You know what?
Cock-fuck it!
Fuck.
Fuck. DJ, play that fucking song.
- [music starts]
- Cut it.
[music stops]
What hard time?
I finally took the BRCA gene test,
and my results came back,
and I'm too afraid to call
because I'm not ready to hear
that I'm dying of breast cancer. Okay?
My God.
Why isn't anybody telling anybody shit?
Because Lady Sunshine was right.
No, she wasn't.
[Abby] Maybe I should go after her.
There's a slideshow coming up
that I think's gonna
really lift her spirits.
Abby, Abby, do you really think
a slideshow
is gonna make her fears go away?
What? I don't know. Maybe.
Look, Rebecca.
I'm just trying to fix this birthday,
so you can have fun, okay?
Why is this so difficult?
All right, Abby.
Abby, let's get real here, okay?
You got fired, right?
And-- And this planning this birthday
is probably the first sense of control
you've had in years.
That's totally okay,
but you asked me over and over,
what I wanted for my birthday,
but you didn't listen.
so let's stop pretending
that this weekend is about me,
because it's all about you.
Don't come after me.
I'm not coming after you,
this is a dual storm-out.
Where are we going? You see them?
Naomi, stop!
Leave me alone. I want to be by myself.
I wanna be by myself!
Naomi, wait, you're not dying.
You're gonna be fine.
Oh, really? How do you know, Val?
What are you, an oracle?
Are your eyeballs a mammogram?
You just scan me
and you know I'm gonna be fine?
I don't know, okay?
I'm trying to be a nice person.
[Abby] Can I ask you something?
Why did you tip Lady Sunshine?
She charged, like, $500
to tell all of us that we sucked.
I can tip whoever the hell I want
as much as I want.
- I'm a grown-ass woman.
- Good. You know what?
Tip the whole world,
see how that works for you.
This is a nightmare.
Then go home, Jenny.
We all know you want to.
All weekend, all these withering glances
making me feel like two cents.
Well, what do you want?
A round of applause for most planning?
Naomi, be a grownup and call your doctor.
You are acting like a millennial!
- How dare-- Ow!
- [gasping]
- Something bit me!
- What?
Oh, my God! A snake!
[all screaming]
- Oh, my God!
- No!
- Someone tell me what's happening?
- Naomi got bit by a snake!
Oh, my God, it's like the cards.
- [Val] Old rocks, snakes.
- [Catherine] My God.
It's happening.
Lady Sunshine was for real.
I bet if we looked her up on the internet
we'd find out that she's been dead
for 50 years.
Oh, my God! Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
My leg is seizing up. Fuck!
Everything stay really calm.
We need to elevate it, we need to ice it.
We need to call 911.
We're gonna call 911.
We're calling 911.
Fuck me, there's no signal.
- Fucking never service.
- Okay, does anyone have a hot spot?
- Does anyone know how to get it brighter?
- [Jenny] I took three pictures.
Then look for brightness...
- This Wi-Fi is so slow!
- [Naomi] Oh, my God. I'm gonna die.
No, you're not going to die, Naomi.
You're not going to die, Naomi,
and you know why?
'Cause I'm gonna get help.
Val 2.0!
- [gasps]
- Val. Val!
Ah!
- Oh, no!
- Oh, my God!
[Val screaming]
[Abby] Shit.
[Rebecca] It sounds like Val's
getting smaller!
Ow!
[grunts]
Wait!
- Wait!
- What's going on?
- What was that?
- Val fell down the hill.
- I'm going.
- What? You're going?
[Rebecca] Wait, Jenny's going?
[panting] Someone's gotta help her.
Why don't we just go back
the way we came in?
No, hell no. There's snakes back there.
- No, Jenny!
- What's happening?
- [Catherine] Jenny? Jenny?
- Jenny, no!
Jenny!
[Jenny whoops]
[Abby] Jenny? Oh, my God!
How is she not falling?
[Naomi] Yeah, Jenny!
Wow. Did she ski as a kid?
[Jenny] Whoo!
Man, she's keeping that wine safe.
[both cheering]
I'm not gonna die
of a poisonous snake bite
on the top of this hill.
Not today, Satan. I got this.
What?
- I'm goin'!
- Okay, now Naomi's going!
Roll me out of this cart!
I need to go down the hill!
What about your back?
- You know what, it's my birthday. Ah!
- Oh, God.
And I'm not going to lay here
and watch the fucking clouds go by.
Now, get me off this cart!
- Whoa!
- Hold on.
- [Val] Naomi, you can do it!
- There's wine down here!
[Rebecca] Go, go, go!
[yelling]
- Oh, boy.
- Oh, cripes.
- No, no, no...
- Jump!
- [Catherine] Naomi!
- [both grunt]
[Naomi] Fuck.
[grunts]
Is everybody okay?
[panting]
Oh, my God.
That fixed my back!
- [Rebecca laughs]
- [Naomi] Oh, God.
[Naomi groans]
I'm gonna take the easy way.
- Really, that was crazy.
- [Rebecca] We did it.
Oh, my God.
Easy, easy.
Whoa.
Just get to the bush
and you're fine from there!
That's what she said.
[squealing]
[whimpering]
[panting]
Just let go! We're here for you!
You got this, Abby.
- I'm gonna let go.
- [Rebecca] You can do it!
[screaming]
You're braving the wilderness, Abby!
[grunting, yelling]
- [Naomi] Whoo!
- [Rebecca] You got it!
Of course I'm the last one left.
[cell phone ringing]
- [Jenny] Oh, my God!
- [Abby] That was fun!
Hello? Oh, hi!
Oh, hey, hi! The whole team's there.
Hi, guys!
- [Abby] Cath, come on!
- Yeah!
Great. Go ahead.
Are you kidding me? She's taking a call?
Okay.
So you're saying that you think
I'd be stupid to pass on this offer.
Well, I'm gonna be stupid. I'm gonna pass.
You know what, life is just going by me
faster than I thought it would,
and I'm tired of chasing
the next big thing.
It's kept me from living in the present.
Okay, I'm gonna hang up
before I change my mind.
In case you're wondering,
I said no to the job.
- What is she saying?
- We can't hear you!
I wanna be able to go on vacation,
you know?
[faintly] Go to weddings...
[indistinctly yelling]
I'm so sorry, we can't hear you.
But here's the thing
you do have to know about me.
I love working.
I do. I love it.
But I'm gonna come down there.
I'm coming down now...
because I choose you.
- [Val] Should we nod?
- I can't hear a word.
[Jenny] I didn't get one word.
Adrian, comma, send ambulance
to Sacred Moon Winery, period.
Friend bitten by snake, exclamation point,
question mark.
Snake emoji. Send.
Whoa!
[yelling]
Swan dive maybe wasn't the best idea.
Gonna feel that one tomorrow.
But it was glorious.
Thanks.
[sighing]
Okay, so the snake wasn't venomous.
We treated it with
some antibacterial cream and...
you're all good.
Wh-- Whoa. I'm definitely not all good.
Little condescending.
So, we almost died on that hill
because of a non-venomous snake?
You know, honestly, I think
it might have been a sharp twig.
Sometimes those catch you
at the wrong angle.
Uh, no, it was a snake, we saw a snake.
[Naomi] Also, I'm a grown woman.
I think I know when I've been bit
by a snake.
Let me guess, Dr. Dick-swing.
It's because of her period.
This is the problem
with the medical establishment.
- Nobody listens to women.
- Right.
This is why more women die
of heart attacks, right here.
[Naomi] Also, I don't appreciate it
when you grin at me
while giving me my results.
'Cause I could have died.
When I get home,
and if there is venom in my ankle,
I'm gonna come back here
and make sure you personally suck it out.
- Yeah.
- Suck it.
I'm not... entirely sure
what's happening here.
- Thank you, that'll be all.
- Okay, thank you.
Also, tell your mom to pick you up
after your shift, Doogie!
- [Naomi] Fuckin' dickweed.
- Wow.
So should we, um...
head on back to the house?
We need to make a call.
[Siri chimes]
Call Doctor...
Melton.
[Catherine] Call Dr. Melton.
[line ringing]
[woman] Hello, Dr. Melton's office.
Hi, this is Naomi Reid.
I'm calling for the results
of my BRCA test.
Yes, let me get the results for you.
Let me put you on a brief hold, okay?
Yeah.
That was a really good Naomi.
No matter what this news is,
we got you, okay?
Hi, Mrs. Reid?
Hi, yes, your blood work
came back negative.
Thank you. Thank you.
[sighing]
[Catherine] Thank you so much.
And what were the, uh,
results of my fart test?
[all laughing]
I don't have it.
Hey, Janiece.
How's your son? Still on the chess team?
- Oh, yeah, big nerd.
- It's the only way to raise 'em.
Hey! Tammy's here!
How'd you know where we were at?
Well, I heard on the scanner that
six middle-aged ladies went to the ER.
Figured it had to be you guys.
[cell phone ringing]
[Janiece] So, do you still want me to call
that taxi for you?
Uh, no. My friend will drive us.
Hmm. Did not know
we were using the f-word.
[Val] I am deleting Jade.
I'm too cool for her, I think.
- Indeed.
- Poor thing.
Well, at least you got a great painting
of The Nanny out of the deal.
What did that cost you? Like, 50 bucks?
Yeah, about that.
- Let me take that plant off your hands.
- You deserve it, Janiece.
Okay, come on, truck's out front.
What happened to you guys anyway?
- Fell down a hill.
- Seems about right.
["Message of Love" playing]
♪ Now the reason we're here ♪
♪ As man and woman ♪
♪ Is to love each other ♪
♪ Take care of each other ♪
♪ Oh, it's good, good, good ♪
♪ Say I love you... ♪
[laughter]
- Thank you, Tammy.
- [Tammy] De nada, de nada. Now...
I'm just gonna remind you
to ping-pong between water and wine
- because that helps with the hangover.
- [Abby] Mm-hmm.
Oh, is that a... "things we say now"?
- Absolutely.
- Yes, it is.
Oh, good one, Tammy!
- I'm gonna let you guys get to it.
- Tammy, stay and hang with us.
- No, that's all right.
- Yeah!
- Are you crazy?
- Sit right there. Come on.
- Park it. Drop your can.
- Park your pooter.
- [Tammy] Thank you very much.
- All right, ladies, I just want to say...
thank you for a great birthday.
Aw, Rebecca. Happy birthday to Rebecca.
Come on, give it to me, give it to me!
It's all about me!
- It's all about me!
- [yelling]
- [Jenny] Happy birthday, love you.
- Cheers.
[clinking]
Mmm.
- [Rebecca gasps]
- [Val] Oh, my God.
- [Naomi] Oh, wow.
- [Abby] It's cool, right?
Abby, did you plan this?
[gasps] I love it.
I'm so glad you like it.
Guys, I fucked Devon.
- What?
- Excuse me?
I fucked Devon. I had sex with him.
I fucked Devon.
- Paella Devon?
- Yeah.
[laughing]
- Oh, my God.
- [Jenny] No.
[Naomi] This is mind-blowing.
Oh, yeah.
- [laughing]
- [Jenny] Damn.
Ew, they're cheers-ing to it.
[laughter]
[Val] Oh, my God.
- I, too, fucked Devon.
- [Catherine] What?
[snorting]
- No!
- I did.
- [Jenny] Don't do that right now.
- Did everybody fuck Devon?
Did I fuck-- Did I fuck Devon?
[laughing]
Guess he really did comewith the house.
Tammy likes that one!
You know, I'm really glad
I came on this trip.
Oh, my God.
[indistinct chatter]
["I Would Die 4 U" playing]
[all singing in unison]
♪ I'm not a woman, I'm not a man ♪
[all laughing]
♪ I am something
That you'll never understand ♪
♪ I'll never beat you
I'll never lie ♪
♪ And if you're evil
I'll forgive you by and by ♪
♪ 'Cause you, I would die for you ♪
♪ Darling, if you want me to ♪
♪ You, I would die for you ♪
♪ I'm not your lover
I'm not your friend ♪
♪ I am something
That you'll never comprehend ♪
♪ No need to worry
No need to cry ♪
♪ I'm your messiah
And you're the reason why ♪
♪ 'Cause you, I would die for you ♪
♪ Darling, if you want me to ♪
♪ You, I would die for you ♪
♪ You're just a sinner I am told
Be your fire when you're cold ♪
♪ Make you happy when you're sad
Make you good when you are bad ♪
♪ I'm not a human
I'm a dove ♪
♪ I'm your conscience
I am love ♪
♪ All I really need is to know that
You believe ♪
♪ Yeah, I would die for you, yeah ♪
♪ Darling, if you want me to ♪
♪ You, I would die for you ♪
♪ Yeah, sing it one more time ♪
♪ Darling, if you want me to ♪
♪ You, I would die for you
Two, three, four, you ♪
[vocalizing]
[laughter]
♪ You ♪
♪ I would die for you ♪
♪ Darling, if you want me to ♪
♪ You, I would die for you ♪
♪ Sing it one more time ♪
♪ Darling, if you want me to ♪
♪ You, I would die for you ♪
[Naomi] Are we singing that
last partwrong? Are we singing...
- [Jenny] I beefed it so many times.
- [Catherine] I beefed it many times.
- [Val] I did, too.
- [Abby] I did it perfectly.