- No, your name.
- Please tell me your name.
My name is
Charles ruchowski.
No!
Say the name,
Mr.... Mr. lake!
Tell me, Mr. lake.
Tell me, what is his name?
Huh? What is
the name of the spy?
What is the name
of the double?
My name is
Charles ruchowski...
- Okay.
- A representative
- for spirit systems.
- Uh-huh.
- One more time.
- A representative...
Well, you tell me...
Just tell me,
Mr. lake...
- Charles ruchowski.
- - ...What I
need to know!
This... this doesn't end.
No no no.
It ends
when you die!
- Every year at this time,
- it is my pleasure...
An honor, really...
To introduce
former deputy
station chief, Beirut,
chief of station Kabul,
holder of the Donovan award,
the distinguished
intelligence medal
and the only
living recipient
of the intelligence star,
Evan lake.
Evan.
What the hell
are you doing here?
Haven't you heard?
The c.I.A. Fell
from the Berlin wall
and all the president's men
can't put it back
together again!
It's broke!
Not reliable.
Not trustworthy.
Can't stand up
to the white house.
Backstabbers.
Watching porn,
tapping phones.
Best and brightest
quit or retired.
What in the name
of Jesus Christ nailed
to the cross
are you doing here?
Because you heard
the call.
That's why.
Your future
spread out before you
like a cruise-ship buffet.
You were teaching
in a classroom,
working in a kitchen,
training in a gym
and you heard the call.
For some
it was adventure.
For some, mystique.
For all, it was 9/11
and you heard the call,
and it was
the call of duty
and love of country.
Why?
Because you have values!
Thanks again, ev.
We appreciate it.
- - Think they believed
a word of it?
- I did.
- You were always
an easy touch.
I won't be here next year.
On my way out.
What? You're a pup.
What are you, 40?
- Got an offer
from the private sector.
- You'll miss it.
Maybe I'll come back
next year just to hear
your speech.
- Die!
It ends...
- When you die!
If you were
a reasonable man,
you and I
could talk about America.
You would drink
something,
you would... you would...
You would be set free.
But no no no.
- You want to...
- He wants to die, huh,
like, what? Crusader!
Huh? No.
No, Mr. lake.
No, it's better
that you don't die.
- Charles ruchowski.
- No, you don't die.
- No no no no no.
Today, you suffer.
- I was talking to someone
- down at the farm.
They said you gave
a real barn burner
this morning.
What's on your mind?
When I started
riding a desk,
it was supposed
to be temporary.
That was six years ago.
- You've made your country
very proud.
I've gone through
all the proper channels,
I've submitted the paperwork,
but I can't seem
to reach anyone.
And I am sorry
to bother you with this.
How long have you been
in government service?
Marines six years.
Agency 30.
S.I.S. Three.
36 years,
last three years
at medium pay.
That's...
That's 110,000 a year.
Hell, I'd retire for that much.
I doubt that, sir.
I have skills
better deployed
in the field.
Ev, you have been
an inspiration to me.
I'm not afraid to admit it.
I'll look into it,
see what I can do.
Come in.
- Milt.
- Wanna grab lunch?
Not today.
- How'd it go?
- Not so good.
Director said he's going
to see what he can do.
- You all right?
- Gotta tamper down,
get it under control.
Hey, put that dictionary
on my hand.
It's that book
over there, the orange one.
It's a dictionary.
I know what
a dictionary is.
Thank you.
There are two kinds
men of action
and everyone else.
I'll see you.
Whoa whoa whoa whoa!
Stay!
Yes?
Milton?
- Yes.
This is Bob Deacon at NSA.
A while back you put in a watch
for certain chemical compounds.
This was
three years ago.
You still interested in that?
- I am.
- Good,
something's come up.
Where can I find you?
I'm coming over.
- A couple of weeks ago
- that flash drive came
into the possession
of the Romanians.
It was water-damaged...
The guy jumped off a bridge.
S.R.I. Had no luck,
so they asked us to take
a crack at it.
On it we found porn,
islamic sermons,
angry birds
and medical reports.
We ran "decitabine"
and your request came up.
Who was
abdi abdikarim?
Kenyan national.
We had some
old passport records.
Other than that,
nothing.
S.R.I. Made inquiries...
But the Kenyans weren't
all that much help.
Can I have a copy
of the full document?
- There's over 50 pages.
- That's all right.
I'll take it
electronically.
You know that the only thing
standing between
me and reassignment
is your approval.
Mr. lake, what do you wish
to do when you return?
There is
unfinished business.
Well, that's what I wish
you would talk about.
Muhammad banir
is alive.
They say he's dead...
Everybody says...
- Killed in the explosion.
- There was a body.
So what?
I didn't see any head.
I didn't see
banir's head.
If you wish to return
to work at the c.I.A...
- If I wish to return?
- I would strongly suggest
that you put the matter
of Muhammad banir behind you.
Fuck!
All the indications
pointed that direction,
but it wasn't
until the pet scan
was complete
- that we could be sure.
- No more memory tests?
- Just the opposite.
- Mental exercises are
shown to be effective...
- All right, what is it?
Eight years
and I'm dead?
Mr. ruchowski,
this is
not Alzheimer's.
For many years,
frontotemporal dementia
and Alzheimer's
were confused,
but frontotemporal dementia
is a separate disease.
It's better?
F.T.D. Is
much more aggressive.
Much more?
How much more?
Did anyone come
with you today?
- No.
- Family is very important
in a situation like this.
I don't have
any brothers or sisters.
No children.
My work is my family.
This frontal... f.T.D.,
is there anything I should
be on the lookout for?
You will be subject
to overreactions
or inappropriate reactions,
blank spells.
Perhaps you've
noticed this already.
- Mood swings, unreliable
sensory perception.
"Unreliable
sensory perception."
That's what
it's called.
There are support groups,
social services here
in Philadelphia...
In fact, wherever you go.
I've spoken
with Dr. gross,
Nathan gross,
in the special care wing.
Now after we're finished,
you'll pay him a visit.
He's expecting you.
There's no reason
to be alone in this.
So what is prescribed?
Usually serotonin inhibitors...
Zoloft, Paxil...
Or antidepressants.
- But those are drugs
- for crazy people,
manic-depressives.
That's not me.
Okay, let's get that clear.
That's not who I am.
Look, these medications
address the behavioral symptoms.
- Not the disease?
- That's correct.
Hey.
Have you seen lake?
He hasn't
been here all day.
Do you know where he is?
Did he call in?
I'm busy, sir.
Sorry.
- Yeah?
- Evan, where are you?
I've been
trying to reach you.
I left messages.
I've been busy.
-  Something's come up.
- What?
I don't wanna talk about it
over an open line.
Where are you?
I'll come meet you.
Evan, where are you?
Diamond Tuesdays.
You're at Ruby Tuesdays?
Yes, I'm at Ruby Tuesdays.
That's what I just said.
Okay, which one?
The one in...
Arlington.
- Ev.
- Yeah?
Get this man something
to eat, please,
- and a cup of coffee.
- You got it.
Can I clear that for you?
Hey.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
That wasn't
very sociable.
What's going on?
Nothing.
Do you want
to talk about it?
What is
so goddamn important?
This "something"
that has come up.
There's been
a possible hit on banir.
Over the last year,
five requests for deferiprone
- which is not too unusual...
- No, it doesn't affect
the anemia.
It's just
the iron deficiency.
Right, but the same source...
The man
requesting it was Kenyan,
but the doctor
is in Bucharest
university hospital,
a research hospital.
Decitabine
and azacitidine,
which are only used
for clinical trials...
- Mediterranean anemia.
- Thalassemia,
which is hereditary,
which we know
Muhammad banir carries,
even though he has
been dead for 20 years.
You know
his father died of it.
And abdikarim,
the man procuring the drug,
was a suspect
in a Nigerian fraud ring.
Rather than give himself up,
he jumps off a bridge.
Medical info was
on a flash drive.
He ain't no Kenyan.
- He was 100% healthy.
- He had no need
for the medication.
- What else?
- Nothing.
- I knew he didn't die.
This means his condition has
moved to an advanced stage.
Now he can lay low,
he can become invisible,
but sooner or later
the disease will
flush him out.
Banir's got it.
It's come out.
It's in his blood.
Hmm?
Mbui!
Sorry to impose
on our relationship.
- What is it?
- I've come across intelligence
which leads me to believe
Muhammad banir is alive.
Give us the room,
gentlemen.
- - Go on.
Banir was believed killed
during my extraction.
The evidence was circumstantial.
Intelligence intercepts
led the agency
to conclude
banir was dead.
He disappeared from our radar.
The c.I.A. Closed
the books on him.
Not a word about him has
been heard for 22 years...
Until now.
Banir has a hereditary
blood disease...
Thalassemia.
If not apparent
during childhood,
it can lay dormant
until midlife or later.
There have been
recent intercepts
of requests
for medicine used primarily
during clinical trials
for this anemia.
These requests have
a Kenyan source.
And what's the source
of these intercepts?
The source
is confidential.
Lake, I am the director
of the fucking agency.
Nothing is confidential.
Who's the source?
If the source were
to become known,
- the source
would be in danger.
- What do you propose?
I would like to set up
a task force,
establish
banir's whereabouts,
extract him,
and have him return
to the United States
for trial.
You'd like to set up
a task force?
- I meant the agency, sir.
- Why don't we just
let the man die?
That is assuming that
your confidential source
is correct,
and assuming that
it does in fact indicate
the presence of a man
that no one's heard of
in 22 years.
Because it is not
the policy of this agency,
nor is it the policy
of this government,
to allow the man
who's responsible
for at least 17 kidnappings,
a dozen executions
and the bombing
of a tourist bus...
Some of whom
were children,
by the way...
To go free
simply because he's sick.
Mary, sent in sanjar.
Come in.
This is Dr. sanjar.
He's with the office
of medical services.
Please, Evan, sit.
Dr. sanjar was speaking
at upenn hospital...
A conference
on service-related diseases.
Did you really think
you could travel 150 miles,
make three visits
to a neurological clinic
under a false identity,
give blood, leave fingerprints
and not have us
find out about it?
Dr. clayborne forwarded
your medical records.
You don't have to worry
about payment or privacy
or quality of care.
The c.I.A. Takes care
of its own.
- The o.M.S. Has
- a state-of-the-art facility.
In addition to which,
we coordinate our efforts
with a.F.R.H. Here
in Washington.
And we'd like
to make this as easy
as possible for you.
We've been speaking
to the d.D.O.
We'll have
a retirement dinner.
The press...
Everyone'll come
heck, even the president
will be there.
Banir.
What about banir?
Muhammad banir
is dead, lake.
-  Has been for 22 years.
We interviewed
your departmental associates.
We are concerned
about these mood swings
you've been suffering,
the unpredictability
of behavior.
Banir, damn it.
There is a concern
that you could become
a liability
to the agency.
- Fuck you.
- Calm down.
I'm a liability?
You fucked this up
just like you fucked up
everything else.
Fucked up Iran-contra,
fucked up ames,
fucked up 9/11,
fucked up w.M.D.,
Afghanistan,
Iraq, benghazi.
Not you yourself
of course, no.
No, you're just the latest
in a long line of fuck-ups
who turned this agency
into a cesspool
of politics
and special interests
on behalf of the weapons makers
and the surveillance industry,
who get richer
while we get weaker!
- Mr. lake.
- I could...
I've forgotten
more about this agency
than you'll ever know.
Who put you up
to this, huh?
Whose got their hand
in your pocket now?
I've seen
a million people like you.
A million people.
You've got your head
so far up Obama's ass,
you can't see anything
except his shit anymore.
Shame on you.
- Agent lake?
- Yes.
The director's
asked us to collect
your security badge.
Please stand, sir.
Sir, we've been instructed
to escort you
out of the facility.
- Place the items
- you would like to take
here on the desk
for inspection, sir.
You want to check
my aftershave?
- There's no need
- to be snippy, sir.
You want my life?
You want my files?
Here, take them!
Would you like awards?
Here. Here's a couple
of them for you.
This is what they give
to assholes like me
- who give their lives
for their country!
Core values!
Get someone else to give
your goddamn lecture!
I resign!
I have your stuff.
I... I hope you don't mind.
I didn't want
to leave it there.
Can I come in?
Yeah, come in.
Thanks.
You... you want
something to drink?
What are you having?
- Sake.
- Sounds good.
I screwed up
pretty bad today, huh?
No going back.
So much for
the retirement party.
- They're not gonna
do nothing about banir.
They treated me
like I was some
sort of crackpot.
- Kanpai.
Have a seat.
That's the other
reason I came.
N.S.A. Forwarded a copy
of abdi's flash drive.
The prescribing physician
is Dr. iulian cornel,
medical research.
That's why none
of the indicators went off.
- How long has
this been happening?
- Two years.
- Banir...
- Well...
Possible banir uses
abdikarim as a middleman.
Their communications,
any information about
possible banir...
Goes into the river...
Or so he thinks.
And abdi pays Dr. cornel.
Evan.
Ignorant...
Ignorant doctor in this?
Well, except for one thing.
Dr. cornel has
a Kenyan wife.
Ah.
How much does he charge?
10k euro every month.
- And doesn't report it.
- Nope.
Now we're
on the same page.
The doctor's
protecting himself.
You got the files?
-  You know what?
- What?
This is cool.
Print 'em out.
I don't like to read
off a monitor.
All right.
No answer?
Aasim.
Aasim. Aasim.
- You have a visa?
- Mm-hmm.
- Speak English?
- Yeah.
I need you to go...
Go to Bucharest.
I need you to find
this... doctor.
I need you to get
the medication, hmm?
Mmm.
Shave your beard
and get...
European ways.
Better idea.
Get this cornel
to come here.
What if...
If he give me
problems?
If he does not
want to come?
Tell him the family
of his wife
will not be spared.
Yeah, that's good.
That's good.
Here he is.
"Dr. iulian cornel,
Grant to develop novel
b-thalassemia.
Cooley's anemia foundation."
Bingo.
Muhammad banir,
you think
you can hide?
Nobody can hide
from the reaper.
Can we get in?
- Into what?
-  Into the correspondence
between banir and the doctor.
Cornel hasn't heard
from abdi...
So now he's wondering...
"Where's my payment?"
- It... it's possible, but...
- But what?
If this med
is for banir,
why hasn't anyone heard
from him in 20 years?
I can explain.
Banir thought
I had an asset
in his group, a double.
That's what he was trying
to get me to give up.
There was
no fucking asset.
I couldn't give it up
even if I wanted,
but that was the deal.
After my extraction,
I had my doubts,
so I sent some intelligence
hinting that banir himself
was the double,
a cable that
would be intercepted
at the highest levels.
If he was still alive,
i wanted him off
the playing field.
I drove him
into the ground.
Everybody figured
he was dead.
- I had my doubts.
- Why?
Because he's
a true believer.
Guys like that
don't just die.
You gotta... you gotta
rip out their hearts
with your bare hands.
You've been giving this
a lot of thought,
haven't you?
-  Just once a day.
- Every day.
- All day long.
Don't answer it.
Shit.
Uh, just stay there.
Dr. sanjar,
I'm real busy right now.
- I don't have the time.
- Evan, I don't want
to leave it the way
it was left today.
It was not right.
- It's all right.
- No, it's not.
I'm not going to let you
push this aside.
We want to help you.
Come to my office,
we'll sit down, have a talk,
prepare for the future.
It doesn't have
to be tomorrow.
Whenever you like.
- Agreed?
- Yeah. Agreed.
- I'll see you then.
You gonna tell me
what that was about?
It's nothing.
Let's get drunk.
This goes back
to when I found you
at Ruby Tuesdays,
- doesn't it?
- Can't a man have
any privacy?
All right, look,
I'm risking my job here,
but you've got
another program running,
something you won't
tell me about.
You gotta be straight.
You owe me that much.
Happy?
It's not so bad now...
Little things,
things that I can hide...
But that's a train
that only runs one way.
Everything up here?
Rotting.
Bit by bit,
it slips away.
- You've known this...
-  I suspected.
About a year ago,
something in my head just...
Fell.
By the time you start
showing symptoms,
the atrophy's
done its damage,
brain mass
has decreased.
Three years, my guess.
That's about it.
You know,
I wanna know something.
Were they asking about me?
Uh, not to me directly,
but yeah.
- You're angry?
- Not at them.
Well, actually,
maybe at them,
but this whole damn thing.
Why me?
Why the fuck me?
- I didn't do anything wrong!
- Ev, you still have time left.
Make the most of it.
Why waste it
looking for someone
who may not even exist?
He does exist.
There is a window here.
It won't be open long,
and then it will close
and banir will have
gotten away with it.
And I am gonna do something
worth remembering
with what's left of my time.
- Could you
please step out?
Mr. lake, we're going
back to the station.
Please get in the patrol car.
I will drive you there.
Place your keys
under the seat.
- - What have I done?
State law requires
physicians to report
all conditions that
might cause a loss
of consciousness, Mr. lake.
Your name is on this list.
Now if this is an error,
it will be corrected
at the station.
- Look, I work for
- the United States government,
-  just like you.
Another officer
will bring your car.
If there's someone you'd
like to pick you up, you can
call them from the station.
If you have a cellphone,
you can call now.
What made him jump,
the Kenyan?
All right, he's a conduit
for pharmaceuticals.
He's been
protecting the location
of someone presumed dead.
He's been accused
of this Nigerian
drug fraud scam.
What makes him jump?
It had to be
something else.
Something he knew.
Something he was afraid
he'd give up.
Yeah, something scary.
The money came in.
10,000 Euros,
abdi's account.
And no one to pick it up.
Shit, I gotta hurry.
The clock's running.
You're going to Romania?
How? Have you
thought about how
you're gonna do it?
Go to Bucharest,
collect the money,
track down the bad guy,
charter a jet,
set her down
at Andrew's air force base.
No, not in detail.
- I'm coming with you.
- No, you're not.
- Let me come with you.
- I'm not helpless.
I know, but do you have
multiple I.D.?
- I have old passport...
- Old passport won't cut
a deal like this,
not in today's security.
We'll need
at least three sets,
all vetted.
- How long for the I.D.S?
- Two days, three.
- What if I say no?
- No what?
- No, you can't come.
Well then,
Mr. secret agent man,
I might have
to drop a dime on you.
You know,
I half believe you would.
It's programmed
to the number I was given.
Only call
if it's an emergency.
You have cash?
Yes.
So this will be
your car.
- Do you have...
- Don't tell me anything.
I know nothing.
Do you have a gun?
In the trunk.
Have you clarified
your plan?
There's a woman
meeting us in Bucharest.
Oh. You are
full of surprises.
Michelle zubarain,
used to be a journalist,
mid-east danger junkie.
Might even have
been an agent.
She works
out of Prague now.
- She an old flame?
- Just someone I used to know.
- And?
- Just, you know,
one step at a time.
Seeing what'll
happen next.
Professor
Dr. iulian cornel.
Nothing particularly
stands out about him.
Keeps a low profile,
community service,
sits on a couple
of boards.
What about his wife?
Angena?
They met through
an aid program.
- Where?
- Mombasa.
- Sir.
- What?
This is
a nonsmoking section.
Let me just
check something.
Yup, I am in Romania.
Are you out
of your fucking mind?
This whole country
is a smoking section.
- Evan.
- Okay. Okay.
Sir, there is
a smoking area upstairs.
I'm putting it out!
Jesus!
Thank you
for bringing that
to our attention.
I know.
I'm sorry, Michelle.
I'm sorry about that.
It's the jetlag.
It's got me...
It's got me turned around.
- It's all right.
- What's the best way
to approach Dr. cornel?
In his office
during business hours,
closed door,
with colleagues nearby.
I've prepared
an official cover.
You'll be
my American colleagues.
Okay.
How did you
and Michelle meet?
If I'm not being too forward.
No, it's not
too forward. It just...
Wasn't particularly
glamorous.
How did you and Evan meet?
That's more interesting.
I was a...
Non-official
covert op in Cairo.
And I lost an asset...
The son
of a cabinet minister.
My fuck-up.
Ugly political situation.
The agency just stepped back.
Then Evan lake showed up.
Two days later,
I was on a plane
back to Washington.
They just
needed to be reminded
we take care of our own.
I was a believer then.
You still have it,
don't you?
- What?
- You know what
I'm talking about.
Show him, Evan.
Yeah, I caught a bullet
when I was extracted.
He offered once to have
that bullet put in a ring...
If I'd agree to wear it
on my finger.
I bet you didn't know
he was such a romantic.
I've gotta get back
to the room.
This flight really
took it out of me.
I'll see you later.
Did you
have to say that?
- Did I embarrass you?
- You couldn't embarrass me.
Everybody set?
That's him in the glasses.
- Dr. cornel?
-  Da.
- M-my office, please.
Decitabine is not
a prohibited drug,
- so I don't see why...
- Dr. cornel, I'm here
as a liaison.
This request has come
through official channels.
It originates
from Washington, D.C.
Washington?
- English, please.
- We have an interest
in this person,
abdi abdikarim.
What kind of a name
is that anyway?
He said
he was Kenyan.
- What's your connection to him?
- I only met him once
at a coffee shop.
- The rest was
through the mails.
- When was that?
- Two years ago.
- You've been prescribing
a rare, potent drug
to somebody you met once
in a coffee shop
two years ago?
He had medical records.
He was representing
someone else,
but the name
had been redacted.
You have no knowledge
of who's actually
using this drug?
None whatsoever,
but I did nothing wrong.
- I did everything by the book.
20,000 Euros
every two months.
Does that sound
about right?
And why should that be
a security concern?
- Cornish...
Cornish...
Cornish.
Cornel.
Dr. Julian cornel,
let us decide
what is or isn't
a security concern.
Arrest him.
Dr. cornel,
could you please stand up.
- What?
- Turn around.
No no no,
I can't be arrested.
I cannot be arrested.
- You don't understand.
- Tell it to your lawyer.
He came into my home last night.
My wife was terrified.
- Who?
He didn't
give his name.
He said abdi was dead.
He was an arab.
He wanted the decitabine
and wanted me
to go to the patient.
- Where?
- Didn't say.
Why are you still here?
- Uh...
- You asked
for more money, didn't you?
- How much?
- 30,000.
You're a successful doctor.
You're going
somewhere you don't know
to treat someone
you don't know
for a lousy 30,000 Euros.
What am I missing here?
Well...
It's my wife.
She's from Kenya.
They said
they'll kill her family
- if I didn't come.
- The arab man who
told you this,
is he planning
on traveling with you?
I assume so.
You think cornel
will contact us when
they call him?
Yeah, he'll call.
We've got him scared now.
We're his only chance.
Is there really
a Natalie negrescu
at s.R.I.?
He's not gonna contact
the Romanian authorities.
Get this cornel.
He...
He is a crook.
30,000. Who does
he think he is, eh?
I wouldn't trust him
if he wasn't.
He only wants
15,000 now, so...
He has to come.
Can we get
that much money?
I will write the details.
You... you go send it
from the Internet cafe.
It will take at least...
At least a day,
but first we'll ask
for more time.
You tell him... no.
No, I...
I don't have time.
- - Evan.
Evan.
- - 31.
44.
31.
35.
Fuck. 24.
17.
10.
Three.
Are you...
You warm enough?
I asked you to tell me
if you were going out.
I got anxious,
kept walking.
But the thing was I...
I-I... I couldn't remember
the name of the hotel.
You left your wallet.
It's just
three blocks over.
You get some sleep.
You'll be fine.
It happens towards
the end of the day.
Sundowning
it's called.
Nobody knows why.
You get anxious,
confused.
I had to get out,
go somewhere.
You take your medication?
Do you feel better?
Yeah.
Yeah, I just slipped.
Lost track.
I'm... I'm all right.
Dr. cornel called.
The money will
arrive tomorrow.
They said to be ready
to travel in a few days,
had to get him
a Kenyan visa.
Banir's arab friend?
Yeah.
Do you remember...
What he looked like?
- Who?
- Banir.
Of course.
I can see him now.
Back then
when you were...
A captive,
banir wanted a name, right?
Why didn't you
give him a name?
It didn't matter
which name, any name.
It just...
Pissed him off more,
hurt the man's pride.
If you'd have given him a name,
he probably
would've said, "good"...
And let you go.
I didn't want
to be the man
who gave up a name
under questioning.
Come on,
hotel's this way.
Let's go.
It's gonna start snowing.
I know where
the damn hotel is.
Stop trying to put
a bib on me, okay?
Okay.
It's a quarter past.
- Okay, he's got
- the money.
Shit, he's seen us.
Oof!
Hey!
The airplane ticket
and the money.
Okay.
- And the passport.
- Just give me a second.
You are out of this.
You dodged a bullet.
Nothing's gonna happen
to you or your people.
Now you can go.
Any word from aasim?
The doctor will arrive
on Wednesday.
After that...
Nothing?
Not yet.
No no. No no.
Just a few more moments.
What was
his phone number again?
254-41-834-5571.
Where is that?
- Mombasa.
- The asshole
of east Africa.
That's exactly where someone
like banir would end up.
That's where cornel
will meet with banir.
- When?
- Tuesday.
We gotta make banir
think this...
- What was his name?
- Aasim.
Is still alive.
Well, all the messages
are texts,
so we can text.
Yeah, Michelle?
Yeah, me too.
Look, milt needs
a Kenyan visa.
As soon as possible.
And there's another thing.
After the base
is down,
just tone it down
a little with a cotton ball.
Are you
taking this down?
All right,
this whole process
should take
about two hours
for the first time
and will last the better part
of a shooting day.
Serban works
on motion pictures when
he isn't helping us out.
So if you feel insecure
or need a little bit
of an ego boost,
serban is
the man for you.
The world is
not a pretty place
without makeup.
Hmm.
The eye color
is pretty different.
No. No,
I don't want contacts.
Fortunately,
our man wears glasses,
so I've added
a little tint to these.
Dr. iulian cornel.
I was able to expedite
your Kenyan visa.
Serban. What exactly
did you see?
I didn't see anything.
Thank you.
Your visa.
You might want to keep it
to yourself for a day.
- Why?
- Give Evan another day
to think about
what he's doing.
He's been thinking
about it for 20 years.
22.
Evan has retired.
It's his life,
his choice, but you...
No matter how this turns out,
it will end badly for you.
Your career will be over.
All my life,
I wanted to be
in the foreign service.
It was killing me,
being strapped to a desk.
- You should tell him.
- I tried.
He's made his choice.
- What's his name?
What is the name?
You want to...
Michelle had to run.
She was able
to get my visa.
I have it.
I was watching TV.
Something about a body
on university campus.
Let's pack up,
go to a hotel near
the airport,
stay in the room
until the flight leaves.
Just before the flight,
text banir from aasim's phone,
aasim says he's been
detained by security.
What about Michelle?
Are you gonna
tell Michelle?
What did she ask?
Did she say
anything about me?
- No.
- Don't tell her
how the story ends.
Flight 418 now boarding
at gate seven.
I am Dr. cornel.
- Dr. cornel.
- Yes.
- Julian cornel?
I am mbui.
So glad you could come.
I'll take you
to Dr. wangari's office.
Where is aasim?
He is coming.
Flight 273 now arriving.
When did Mr. Ali hariri
have his last transfusion?
Three days ago.
When is he scheduled
for another?
- Three days.
Here at the clinic?
Saeed Ali hariri
is being treated
at his own residence.
- I will see him here.
- Dr. cornel,
you were given letter
with all explained.
- We wrote this.
- I am just double checking.
Al-hariri is not able
to leave his residence.
You requested
additional payment
in the light of this.
Of course.
Let me go through
everything tonight.
These are for me,
correct?
Then tomorrow I will visit
Mr. Ali hariri
at his residence.
- Will you be coming, doctor?
- Dr. wangari will not
be able to join us.
I'll pick you up
at the hotel, 4:00 P.M.
All right, I'll give you
750 for the Jericho,
- 900 for the glock.
- No no no no no no.
- 1150 for the glock.
- 1150?
- Yeah.
- Okay, just stop.
Here's what we do.
900... 900 for the Jericho...
- No no no no no.
- 950 for the glock.
All right?
No, that's fair.
No no no no,
it's not fair,
it's not fair.
Mbui.
Come come.
Closer closer closer.
- Shh.
Aasim is missing.
Abdi is dead.
If there is
a traitor among us,
I will find him.
Is it you?
800, 900.
- No.
- No? All right, look,
this is
2,000 Euros right here.
2,000 Euros
right here, okay?
Don't underestimate me.
I have survived
much more than this.
I went shopping
at the market.
A Jericho 941...
And a glock.
- How much?
2,000 Euros.
You got took.
Well, we've got Euros
to spare.
Do you smell something?
- - Mombasa.
The other night when
we were in the park
in Bucharest,
I touched your jacket.
You were wearing this...
This blue,
like canvas jacket,
but when I touched it,
it... it felt
just like dog fur.
Isn't it strange when
you can't even trust
your own fingers?
And don't ask me
how I feel.
I wouldn't think of it.
- - Crock.
Evan.
- Crock is... gun.
No way I'll be able to bring
a gun with me tomorrow.
Mbui frisked me today.
He'll frisk me
again tomorrow.
Well, how do you
plan to do it?
It's been so long,
thought about it so long,
I'm not sure.
Maybe I'll just let
the moment guide me.
I've got a syringe
and medication.
One's quick and painless,
the other's
a strychnine derivative...
Excruciating,
takes over an hour.
Or maybe I'll just
get up close to him,
slice him
and let his blood
wash all over me.
I don't feel comfortable
letting you go in there alone.
- I'll be all right.
- Look, I... I picked
this up at the market.
They're wireless crazy
over here.
Jumped straight
from tom-Toms
to cellphones.
Just tuck that
in somewhere,
I'll be able to hear you
and I'll get g.P.S. As well.
I brought a belt blade.
I'll be able
to get that through,
but that's about it.
- So that's that then?
- Yeah.
Milt...
Thanks for coming along.
No problem,
old sport.
If I'm not out in an hour,
do whatever you want.
Please.
- Did you sleep well?
- All right.
Sometimes the heat
is a problem.
Come, doctor.
Open the briefcase.
Dr. cornel.
Salaam alaikum.
Salaam alaikum,
saeed Ali hariri.
Dr. cornel,
thank you.
Thank you
for coming.
Forgive me
for not...
Standing.
Mbui, some tea.
And those...
Those dates.
Mind if I sit?
Oh, please.
Dr. wangari has
provided me your records,
your treatment history.
Last night I was
in contact with several
of my colleagues.
Thank you.
I noticed
you were scheduled
three months ago
for a bone marrow transplant,
but I found no record
of the procedure.
Was there a problem
with the donor?
- It was too dangerous.
- Uh, no sibling donor
was possible,
no compatible cousins.
It is risky,
but an unrelated donor
can be found based on h.L.B.
And d.R. Histocompatibility.
The university hospital
can assist in finding
such a donor.
We have
a large database.
Should have
been done before.
It is more...
Dangerous now,
but we have no choice.
At present,
transplantation is
the only possible
curative therapy.
And...
It can be done here?
Yes.
Excuse me,
I am not such a young man.
Where is the toilet?
Back and to the left.
So sorry.
Oh, please. Please.
There is a problem
with the toilet.
Mmm. Mbui.
It won't flush.
- You pulled the chain?
- I pulled the chain.
There is something stuck...
In there.
I have to be honest.
Your condition is
far worse than I imagined.
Your long-term chances
for survival
are not good.
Neither are
your short-term chances.
In fact, they are
quite hopeless.
It's because I'm not a doctor.
My name isn't
Julian cornel...
And your name
isn't Ali hariri.
Your name...
Is Muhammad banir.
Mr. ruchowski.
Evan lake.
- Mbui?
- He'll be all right.
Where is your backup?
Hmm?
Your elite commandos.
Oh. You came alone.
How did you find me?
Through the request
for experimental
thalassemia medication,
decitabine.
Your family
medical history.
It was you.
Hmm?
You who sent me
into hiding.
Even so for years and years
I live in rooms
like this one.
I would have gladly
given both my ears
for my freedom.
So my health...
- Is it really hopeless?
- Yes.
You would've died of anemia
just like your father.
He was an intellectual scholar.
I... I've read
quite a bit myself.
- Yeah.
So...
How are...
How are you going
to kill me?
- I-I... I don't know.
Good.
Ah. So...
We have some time.
Perhaps we can have that...
Conversation that
I wanted to have
that time years a-ago.
Huh?
You... you only
kept giving me
your fake name. Why?
- I was making a point.
- What point?
What is it that you do now?
This company?
Intelligence analyst, yes?
Perhaps you've read
some of my writings?
- I didn't know
you were still active.
-  Oh, I-I-I, uh... I contribute.
A number of web sites
not under my name.
Of course, you are
religious man, Mr. lake?
No, I'm not religious.
I think you are.
America, yeah?
You see yourself
as a religion... America.
I've written about this,
the American way of life.
Huh?
Have you been
to greeley, Colorado?
- You know what
I'm talking about?
- Sayyid qutb...
Who went from Cairo
to Colorado
state college in 1948.
He said greeley was
like paradise on earth.
What qutb saw
was jahiliyyah, huh?
Decadence,
promiscuity, pop music.
"Baby,
it's cold outside."
Qutb was repulsed.
The-the... the flirting
and the mixing
of men and women,
the disrespect...
So no, he left.
Went back to Egypt
and the movement was born.
- - The Muslim brotherhood.
My father knew him.
No, nasser...
Nasser executed him.
It was too late.
45. 38.
Fundamentalism,
- Mr. lake,
of the prophet...
- 170.
- Was social justice!
- 38.
Better schools,
better jobs,
Mr. lake.
This doesn't just...
Just end.
Are you still
a believer?
Hmm?
Do you still believe?
I don't.
My faith, it was...
It was taken from me.
You think I'm playing games
with you, Mr. lake?
Huh?
You think
we are playing games?!
- While mullahs,
ayatollahs, they get rich.
- I'm a representative...
- They have their orgies,
imprison their opponents.
- ..For spirit systems.
- Why? Hmm? Why?!
-  I'm Charles ruchowski.
My name is
Charles ruchowski.
I'm a representative
for spirit systems.
The only hope
for islam now
is Marx, hmm?
Social justice.
We like the fear.
I like the fear.
- I like the fear.
Our believers,
not so many.
No, the truly
dangerous people
- do you think
it made any difference?
What you did! You!
Do you?
Now, what is the name
of the source,
Mr. lake?!
Ah. You are sick too. Hmm?
I see it, your face.
You have a disease
of the blood.
My disease
is in the brain.
What sort of disease?
I'm forgetting things.
Ohhh.
There is
a lot to forget.
It's the time for prayer.
Will you...
Please help me?
No, I won't do that!
So...
So what are you
going to do... to do?
I'm going to leave.
Just like that?
Just like that.
Ma'a salama.
-  Ma'a salama.
Evan.
Milt.
What happened?
- Was it worth it?
- Yeah, it was worth it.
You should've
heard him scream.
Put the car in gear.
God, I hate
this time of day.
It's the worst.
You want to have
a drink?
Outside. Let's walk.
Later on...
You wanna
talk about it?
What are
you gonna do?
- Go home, I guess.
- So should you.
What home?
- Oh come on, don't
be melodramatic.
You'll retire.
You're young, there's tons
of things you could do.
Or don't retire.
They won't put it together...
Bucharest, mombasa.
- They won't want to.
- Nah.
It was always
my dream to...
Salaam alaikum, asshole.
That boy you shot
was my friend.
What the fuck
does that mean?
- Come closer.
Come on.
- Okay.
- What the hell
- are you doing here?
Haven't you heard?
The c.I.A. Fell
from the Berlin wall
and all the president's men
can't put it back
together again!
It's broke!
Not reliable.
Not trustworthy.
Can't stand up
to the white house.
Backstabbers.
Watching porn, tapping phones.
Best and brightest
quit or retired.
What in the name of Jesus Christ
nailed to the cross
are you doing here?
Values.
The c.I.A. Has
taken some hits,
some deserved.
We've been down
on the canvas,
but we're
on our feet again,
because we've got
no choice
and because our country
needs us
and because
we've got what?
Values.