[Announcer]
And our fourth-prize winner here
in our local contest is...
BessieJune Rassmussen
of Apple Valley.
Hmph. I knew it wouldn't be me.
?? [Fanfare]
The only thing I ever won
were those free facials
down at Antoine's.
Our third-prize winner is...
HarryJerome of 16 Maple Drive.
HarryJerome. Why don't you tell
everybody he's the sponsor's nephew!
?? [Fanfare]
And for our second prize,
our second-prize winner...
is Wilma Winninger
of 477 Hesby Avenue.
Hesby Avenue?
T-That's clear across town.
Politics! Politics!
?? [Fanfare]
And our first-prize winner...
goes to a lucky person right here
in Mockingbird Heights.
It's worth $5,000.
And the first-prize winner is
Mr. Herman...
Go ahead and say it.
Mr. Herman Overholtzer.
Mr. Herman Flork.
- Mr. Herman Munster.
- Graft! Graft!
Graft! You hear me? G...
Wait a minute. It's me! It's me!
[Yelling]
It's me! I'm Herman Munster!
I'm... Hi! I'm Herman Munster!
I won a prize worth $5,000!
Lily, Grandpa!
Everybody come in quick!
What's the matter?
What's up, Herman?
What is it?
The contest on TV! I won!
I won! I won! I won! I won!
I won! I won! I won!
Where are you going, Grandpa?
Where am I going?
Down in the dungeon.
I wanna find out
what Herman's talking about.
He'll be there any minute.
Uncle Herman, you can't
keep us in suspense any longer.
Come on, Pop.
Tell us about
the neat prize you won.
All right. All right. All right.
The Munsters... mind you,
the entire family...
has won a membership to
the Mockingbird Heights Country Club.
Whoopee!
[Excited Chatter]
Oh, that club is so exclusive.
Why, you know you have to wait
for one of the members to pass away...
before you can even be
considered for membership.
I know. That's what's so wonderful.
Once we're in, we can stay forever.
As far as I can recall,
no member of my family
ever passed away for good.
You know something,
I think I'm gonna
take up golf. [Laughs]
Only I'm not sure about
being out in the sun too much.
I'd hate to lose my parlor pallor.
You know, Lily,
I'm going to love it.
[Chuckles]
It's gonna give me a chance
to mingle with some real blue bloods.
Well, Grandpa, if you do,
just don't put the bite
on them right off the bat.
I have a letter here from
the local television station.
They have a winner for
that club membership we donated.
I was against that
from the beginning.
This is an exclusive club
and awarding a membership
through a contest is very undignified.
I'm sorry, Petrie, but I'm inclined
to agree with Reggie.
A thing like this can give us
a more popular image
with the community.
I'll go along with it
because I seem to be outnumbered.
But who are these contest winners?
It's a Mr. And Mrs. Herman Munster
and family of Mockingbird Lane.
Well, we have a luncheon
and fashion show
coming up this week.
We can invite Mrs. Munster to that
and send Munster a guest card
to play golf.
That way, we can get
a close look at them... see if
they measure up to our standards.
You know, Grandpa? I bet it would
even shake up Arnold Palmer
to see me on the putting green.
[Both Laugh]
You're good all right, Herman.
You know the last time
I saw a swing like that was when
they hung my Uncle George.
Herman! Grandpa!
Uh, Lily. Lily, dear.
Please. I'm shooting.
Herman, guess what
the mailman just dropped and ran?
My new Bugs Bunny cartoon book?
It's a letter from
the Mockingbird Heights Country Club.
They're inviting me to a luncheon,
and they sent you a guest card
to play golf.
Oh. You know, Lily,
that's a very good idea.
It'll give us a chance to look over
the club and see if the people
measure up to our standards.
We'll have to dress to the occasion.
Um, I think I'll wear
my new Transylvanian original.
You know, the one with
the-the lovely shroud.
Old Hermie, the pro.
[Laughs]
Fore!
Grandpa, where did
the ball go?
What do you know about that?
A hole in one.
From the turnout today,
I think this is going to be
our most successful luncheon.
Two of the Munsters
have accepted our invitation,
so this will give us a good chance
to look them over.
I'm still not sold on this idea
of awarding a membership
through a contest.
It's the duty of this committee
to see to it that only the right sort
of people are admitted to the club.
Excuse me,
where are they having the luncheon?
- It's in the main grill.
- Thank you.
And that's another area
this committee should take up.
Every time Charley Hinshaw
gets a snootful,
he dresses up
in those ridiculous outfits.
That was
the wildest one yet.
Lily, the man said that
the luncheon is in the grill room.
Grandpa, this place
is depressingly cheerful.
But I suppose this modern decor
is what they go in for.
79.95, Sally's Togs Shop.
My the people are friendly here.
She told a perfect stranger
where she got her dress
and how much it cost.
Yes, b-but I don't care
for that style.
I wouldn't want you
to be seen dead
in a dress like that.
You're right, Grandpa.
I'll make a point not to.
Never mind, Lily.
Shall we, uh,
have a libation?
Hi, folks. A little early
for a masquerade party, isn't it?
Sure is.
[All Laugh]
Oh, you club people
are so jolly.
This is simple chiffon from
the Paris Collection, 129.95.
Now that dress is more like it.
When I used to fly around
in the Old Country,
I always found
a high neckline a challenge.
I think it's sweet the way
the women around here
confide in each other.
I think I'll float around a bit
and get acquainted.
This is simple chiffon from
the Paris Collection, 129.95.
This ensemble has a cape
made of tufted coffin lining...
in a lovely shade
of cemetery green.
This little number
was very inexpensive.
The fabric is made of
black widow's webs.
And the underslip,
pure, unborn centipede.
Now, my friend,
this is all very simple.
I'll show it to you again.
Now all you have to do
is guess under which nut
the spider is hiding.
Of course, if you don't guess
the first time...
Grandpa, I showed the ladies
my dress and...
Oh, good, you're showing
the bartender the shell game.
Don't win too much, Grandpa.
[Both Laugh]
Hey, that's not Charley Hinshaw.
Who are those people?
Those are the Munsters.
Good heavens!
He's gambling with the bartender.
She's gotten herself so stoned,
she's joining the fashion show.
You still want those contest winners
in our club?
Petrie, I'm afraid
I'll have to agree with you.
But I'll tell you something,
when that Mr. Munster
shows up to play golf,
if he doesn't turn out to be
our idea of a human being,
I'll throw them out personally.
Aunt Lily, do you mean the people
were actually rude to you
at the country club?
Yes. When we first went in,
everything was fine.
But, suddenly,
I had a feeling we weren't wanted.
That's right, Marilyn.
There I was playing my shell game with
the bartender, when all of a sudden,
some guy in a dark suit came by,
scooped up my shells
and led me outside.
He said they-they
didn't allow nuts in the club.
It must be some kind of a rule
of the department of agriculture.
I was going around showing off
my dress, when one woman
came up to me and said,
"Why don't you go home
and sleep it off, dearie."
I tell you, Marilyn.
We might just as well face it.
Those people at the country club
are just not our kind of people.
Oh, what a shame.
If Uncle Herman went down there
and got insulted...
why, he's so sensitive,
he'd go all to pieces inside.
Oh, that would never do.
The last time that happened,
he rattled for a week.
I guess we'll just have to tell Herman
that it won't work out. That we don't
want to join a club like that.
We're home from the golf store.
Yoo-hoo! We're home.
Well, how do you like it?
The man at the store said
this is what Ken Venturi wore
when he won the National Open.
We're going to play tomorrow,
and I'm going to caddy.
I bet everybody will follow us
all over the course.
Oh boy, now I know how
the Prince of Wales used to feel.
[Electricity Crackling]
That's fine, Prince.
You better start
feeling like a peasant again.
Hmm?
Grandpa.
What's he talking about?
Uh, well, Herman, um,
what would you say if we, uh...
well, if we decided
not to join the country club?
Not join?
What do you mean "not join"?
Lily, I won that membership fair
and square, and if I didn't join
the club, it would crush my spirit.
And I don't want my spirit crushed.
Oh.
But I was thinking that
I'd probably scare the boys away...
just as much at the country club
as I do here.
- So I don't care if we join or not.
- You don't?
- No.
- And I'd probably get to like...
the luncheons and the teas
and the cocktail parties,
and I'd start coming home late
and serving you TV dinners...
and neglecting my family.
You know, all those little niceties
that are part of country club living.
A-And Herman, I don't wanna
join the club because
there's no one there of my class.
After all, Herman,
you know I'm a full-blooded count.
And the closest thing
they have to royalty there
is the bartender, "Duke" Fineberg.
You know,
I've suddenly realized something.
[All]
You do?
Yes.
You know what
you've made me realize?
What?
That you don't
give a hoot what I want.
What does a man work for
all his life?
A little feeling of respectability
and-and success.
Well, that's what
joining the club would give me.
And that's what I want
and I'm gonna have it.
You hear me?
That's what I want
and I'm gonna have it!
I'm gonna have it!
[Loud Thud]
I'm gonna have it! I'm gonna have it!
I'm gonna have it!
Excuse me, Lily, while I continue
this conversation with Herman
in the dungeon.
"Dear Lily,
Eddie and I have gone
to the country club.
Will play a round of golf
before work.
Signed, Arnie Munster."
Look at the time.
It's 5:30 a.m.
Half the day is gone.
That course
will probably be jammed.
Oh, dear. I just hate the thought
of all those rude people staring
at Uncle Herman when he tees off.
"Par five, 580 yards."
Hmm. Short one.
Pop?
Hmm?
Do you wanna pick a club?
Oh. Good idea, son.
Uh, eenie-meenie-minie-mo.
What am I doing?
Eight's my lucky number.
Eight iron, caddy.
[Chuckles]
There you are.
Thank you.
Oh. Now isn't that nice of'em.
They left us two practice balls.
Now, the first thing you do, Eddie,
is to address the ball.
Hello, ball.
[Laughs]
[Stammers]
That's a joke, Eddie.
Oh. Sorry.
[Imitates Herman's Laugh]
Now, Eddie,
the hole's right down there.
Keep your eye on the ball
like a good caddy.
Hmm. You know,
those practice balls are nice and big,
but they're made very badly.
Give me one of our small ones.
Thank you, son. Now.
- Ready?
- Ready.
Hey, Dad?
Hmm?
It's in the rough.
Darn!
On the third hole,
1, 500 yards away.
[Grumbling]
I think you overclubbed yourself.
I think you're right.
But, as they say in golf, Eddie,
you gotta play 'em
where you hit 'em.
Yeah.
Come on.
We'll ride down to the ball.
Okay.
[Loud Bang]
Why do they call it
the rough, Pop?
[Groans]
That's one of the reasons.
[Blows]
[Loud Bang]
I think I made the trap.
[Laughs]
Come on, Eddie.
Hit it, Pop.!
Hit it.!
Now, Eddie,
this is a very important shot.
Getting out of the sand.
Now watch closely.
Watch the sand.
Watch the sand, Pop.
Eddie! Eddie!
[Stammering]
I made it! I made it!
I'm out and I'm pin high.
Eddie? Eddie.
Eddie, where are you, son?
Eddie?
Pop, you made the green!
How about that?
You know, Eddie?
I never knew golf
was such a fun game.
Come on, son.
Oh. Oopsy-daisy.
Oopsy-daisy.
Well, that's what you get
when you putt against the wind.
[Clicks Tongue]
Just as I thought.
I've been putting against the grain.
[Excited Laughter]
I made it! I made it!
I made it! I made it! I made it!
[Laughs]
Come on, Pop.
Let's go to the next tee.
Be right with you, Eddie.
[Grunting]
Come on, Pop.
I got your ball.
I'm coming, Eddie.
What a great game!
And to think, when I'm a member,
I'll be doing this every day.
I just hope those rude people
didn't embarrass Herman when
he tried to play golf this morning.
Lily, there's no two ways about it.
That country club is just not for us.
When Herman gets home
from work, I'm sure he'll tell us
he's decided the same thing.
And we all thought
it was so great
when he won that contest.
[Door Creaks Open and Closes]
Hi, everybody.
Hello, dear.
Sweetie,
about the country club...
Lily, please don't mention
that country club.
It's just too sad to think about.
You're right, Herman.
Grandpa!
Read the afternoon paper.
"Fiend desecrates golf course
in early morning.
"Inhuman footprints were found
this morning on putting greens
at the Mockingbird Heights Country Club.
"Enormous gouges taken from turf
and course flooded.
Greenskeeper is in a state of shock."
- Herman, what does this mean?
- What does it mean?
It means that we are not
gonna join the country club.
I will not jeopardize
the safety of my family...
at a country club where
some madman is allowed to run loose.
That's right.
That club is just no good all-around.
My letter of disapproval
is already in the mail.
I've turned down
that membership I won.
It's a shame we have to forfeit
a $5,000 prize.
Well, as far as the money's concerned,
I told the club...
that they could use that money
to repair the damage to the course
caused by that madman.
It's just lucky you didn't
run into that fiend this morning
when you were playing there.
[Gasps]
Lily, don't say
such a thing, dear.
If I ever came face-to-face with
a frightening, horrible creature like that,
it'd scare me out of
a hundred years' growth.
Now, Herman...
[Gasps]
Really, Herman.
After all the trouble we've had
with that country club,
haven't you had
enough of golf?
[Loud Crash]
Someday, I may find
a golf club worth joining.
And it won't hurt
if I keep up with my chip shots.
Grandpa? Uh, did you see
where-where the ball...
Oh, I'm... Grandpa...
Herman,
would you do me a favor?
Certainly, Grandpa.
Don't ever
take up bowling!
Oh.
[Laughs]