(Train chugging)
(squeak, steam hissing)
(whistle blowing)
(low, indistinct chatter)
(loud, excited chatter)
Men:
Oh!嗯！
Man:
Though we have Faith虽然我们有信息
And reasonable hope
for forgiveness也有希望面对宽恕
We must each face the fact我们必须承认
That our actions create我们的行为会产生
a banquet of consequences.一系列的后果
In your case you may think你也许会觉得在你的情况下
this is a mean supper这是一个残忍的晚宴
But you chose it.但是这是你的选择
If your mother were alive如果你妈妈还在世
She'd think this is best.她会认为这样做是最好的
Whatever father said to you不管爸爸跟你说什么
don't take it to heart不需要理会
Kent and I have
a little present for you肯特和我有一份小礼物送给你
For later
You'll be late
for the train你将要错过火车了
(Train whistle blowing)
(bell clanging)
Man:
Colorado springs!
All aboard for Denver.
Colorado springs here.
If you're traveling out
of town, have tickets...
Chicago what?
Hi!
Watch your
step, miss.
Thank you.
There you go.
Man:
Olivia?
Take care, buddy.
(Indistinct chatter)
I'm reverend case.
Hello.
My dear, you look
just like your mother.
I was so sorry
to hear she passed away.
Thank you.
Oh, is this it?
For now, yes.
Well, we have quite
a little drive ahead of us.
Do you need
To use the station services?
Yes, please.
Pardon me.
(Sighs)
(panting softly)
(birds singing)
Reverend case:
Out here
they grow mostly grains,
A bit of sugar beets
And vegetables.
No gasoline shortage
for farmers.
They get all
they want.
No sugar
shortage, either.
That's nice.
(Horn tooting)
You must be Olivia.
Yes, ma'am.
How do you do?
Mr. Singleton's in the parlor.
Reverend case:
Mr. Ray Singleton,
This is miss Olivia Dunne.
Livy. Everyone calls me Livy.
Ray's sister's waiting
in the church.
Well, we'll just
leave you two
To get acquainted a moment.
Raymond, why don't you pour
Some lemonade
for Livy?
Yes, ma'am.
Reverend case:
We'll be in the church
When you're ready.
Thank you.
Mr. Singleton...
Ray... Please.
Ray.
Uh...
Now that you've had a Chance
to meet me,
To see me in person,
Do you have any doubts?
N-no, ma'am.
Are you, uh...
(clears throat)
Are you having second thoughts?
No.
Do you think
you'll be able to love the baby?
Oh, I do.
Is there anything
that you'd like to ask me?
No.
You're so fine,
I can't believe no man...
I can't believe any man
would ever do this to you.
And do you, Raymond, take Olivia
to be your lawful wedded wife?
I do.
The rings?
Uh, I didn't...
I don't
have a ring.
I don't,
I don't need one...
(laughs)
Fine.
Bound by these sacred bonds,
May you vow to imitate Christ
in your new life together.
To give one another hope
when there is sorrow,
Strength when there is weakness,
Faith and understanding
When there is confusion
or doubt.
In such a love, we are sustained
on this earthly life,
Just as we hope for
eternal life through our
Savior, Jesus Christ.
Amen.
I now pronounce you
man and wife.
Martha, hank,
If you'd please sign
as witnesses.
(Organ playing "blest be
the ties that bind")
Congratulations, Ray.
Thank you.
I'm Martha.
I'm Ray's sister.
Pleased to meet you.
This is my husband, hank.
Hi. Nice
to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
Reverend case:
Congratulations, Ray.
We hesitated
to bring the children today.
Thought we'd give you a Chance
to settle in, and...
Oh, Ray, hold on.
Just a sec.
This is a little
casserole for supper.
I thought you
must be tired
From all your
traveling.
Thank you.
That's very thoughtful.
Now, Ray, you
bring Olivia over
To see us real
soon, okay?
Hank:
Well,
Welcome to
the family, huh?
Who are your neighbors?
Hmm?
Your neighbors-- who are they?
Uh, well, my sister.
(Clears throat)
She and hank live eight Miles
thataway.
(Crow cawing)
(dog barking and whining)
Here.
Thank you.
Is that garden your mother's?
Uh, yes it was.
(Dog barking and whining)
Someone sounds unhappy.
Uh, it's just the dog.
I put him in the shed
so he won't jump on you.
(Sighs)
Thank you.
Uh...
Welcome home.
Kitchen's there.
(Clears throat)
There some, uh,
coca-colas in here.
No, thank you.
Uh, this was
Martha's room,
And... Um...
This was my parents' room
where you'll be staying.
Will this be all right?
Mm-hmm.
Uh, let's see...
This is the
bunk room.
You have a brother?
Well, I do.
Well, I did.
Daniel got killed
at pearl harbor.
This is the bathroom.
Indoor plumbing.
Got your hot water,
Cold water.
I just put that in.
Where's the telephone?
Well, there's
a phone box in Wilson,
Outside the post office.
Tomorrow I'll get anything
you want to stock the kitchen.
I don't really
know how to cook.
I mean I could;
I just haven't really tried.
I can cook a fair bit.
My sister could
come over and teach you.
No, it's fine, you know,
it shouldn't be that hard.
I can get a book
from the library.
Is there a library?
Oh, yeah, in la junta.
That's an hour away.
Yeah, about that.
The reverend said
you'd had lots of schooling.
I was in
graduate school,
Studying
archeology.
My college thesis
Was Heinrich Schliemann's
excavation of Troy.
Is he German?
Yes.
Is he a Nazi?
No, he... He lived
in the 19th century.
Oh, I can...
No, sit.
Uh, Mrs. Pratt,
From church, she, uh,
She makes me a cake
nearly every week.
This one's, uh...
Chocolate, I think.
Yeah.
Can I cut you a slice?
No, thank you.
We'll save it, then.
Ray...
Um...
I was just wondering...
Why you agreed to this.
When the reverend
come out to see me
And told me about
your situation...
Well, I thought...
I thought...
Maybe it'd be God's will.
God's will.
You want anything else?
No, thank you.
Farmers get to bed early.
You have everything you need?
Yes. Thank you.
All right.
Good night.
(Distant barking)
(dog whining loudly)
(sobbing quietly)
Oh...
(ticking)
(vehicle approaching)
(distant barking)
(vehicle door slamming)
Good morning.
Morning.
I can't believe
I slept so late.
You needed
your rest.
(Barking)
Franklin!
No. Hey.
Come here.
He won't hurt you.
Good boy.
I thought I'd drive
into la junta today.
Um, maybe look
around town.
Let the family know
that I'm here.
Could I borrow the truck?
Oh, well, uh, the beet box
has a mind of its own.
The beet box.
I use that truck
to haul my beets.
Right.
It's best if
I drive you over.
Oh, I'm... I'm sure you have
things you need to do.
No bother.
I'm glad to do it.
Just, uh, get my library card,
In case you want
to check out some cookbooks.
Are those tomatoes?
Potatoes.
Some of the fields are empty.
You bet.
Why?
Well, we harvested
the first cash crop.
Winter wheat.
Next we'll harvest them
beets and those potatoes.
May I help?
I doubt it.
You're right.
I... I don't know anything
about farming.
You got the house
to take care of.
You need any change?
Uh, no, I have it.
Thank you.
I'll be
in the library.
Are you expecting a little one?
Yes, ma'am,
we are.
Well, how wonderful.
Yes, ma'am.
Do you have any books
on Henry Schliemann?
Is that s-h or s-c-h?
Well, your guess
is better than mine.
I think he was an archeologist.
Let me have
a look.
Livy:
If father wanted to punish me,
He's done a great job.
Abby:
Oh, Livy, don't cry.
Oh, hon, is he horrid?
No. No.
Livy, if he mistreats you
for even one second,
I'm coming to get you.
Abby, is there any word
from Edward?
No.
Oh, Livy,
Remember, this isn't forever.
I know.
Ray:
All right now, the clutch
tends to stick.
You gotta
ease off slow.
(Squeaking)
There you go.
Shift, shift.
Give it a pump.
That's it.
This is easy.
Ray:
Now, the gas gauge says full,
But it isn't.
You gotta hit it
just right,
It'll tell you the truth
for one split second,
Then it shoots right
back up there to full.
Where do I hit it?
Uh, right there.
Just give it a pop.
Quick like.
That's it.
We have
half a tank.
The gas can's in back,
just in case.
Wow, look at that.
(Speaking native language)
Are they Japanese?
Watch the road.
They're from camp amache.
Livy:
That's an internment camp.
Ray:
Yes, it is.
Farms are short-handed.
The government needs the food,
so they send the workers.
They work your farm?
Our farm.
Yes, they do.
(Organ playing)
Congregation:
%% for the beauty of the earth %%
%% for the glory of the skies %%
%% for the love
which from our birth %%
%% over and around us lies %%
%% Lord of all to thee we raise %%
%% this our hymn
of grateful praise %%
%% Lord of all to thee we raise %%
%% this our hymn
of grateful praise %%
%% amen. %%
Lord, we pray for the relief
of suffering
And an end to war
throughout the world.
Amen.
Congregation:
(Indistinct conversations)
Ruth's been dying
to meet you.
She's my oldest.
Hi, Ruth.
I'm Livy.
And the boy's
are running around,
But they'll come in when they
realize the foods in here.
Is your dress
store bought?
Oh, my.
Yes, it is.
I bet it was.
Well, Ray, are you
going to introduce us?
Yes, ma'am.
Miss Parker, this
is my wife, Livy.
Your wife?
Well, how
do you do?
Nice to meet you.
Your wife!
I'm miss Parker.
I've known Ray since
he was this high.
And this
is Mrs. Pratt.
Goodness me.
We never knew.
So pleased to meet you.
And Martha never
said a word.
Yes, aren't we all blessed?
Sweetheart, will you
help me at the table?
Bye.
You must not
be from here.
We've been so
worried about Ray.
The way things have
played out here.
And not a single
young women to speak of.
And Ray's such a
fine, young man.
How'd you meet?
I eloped...
Uh, we met
in Denver.
How romantic.
I never knew you
traveled to Denver.
You come sit by me
At the potluck.
We'd like stay,
but we gotta get on.
But we're really gonna
enjoy your cake,
Miss Pratt,
thank you.
You're you're most
very welcome. Welcome.
Good-bye.
Bye-bye.
I just have a letter
I need to drop
at the post office.
It's Sunday.
I could mail it
for you tomorrow.
Oh, it already has
a stamp on it.
I'm just going to drop it
in the box to my sister.
Livy:
Can you swim here?
Ray:
It's right shallow
for swimming.
There's two feet of silt
down there.
You like to swim?
I used to.
I used to love to swim.
Thank you
for lying to Mrs. Pratt.
Middle of the day is not
the best time for fishing.
Being out here
is the point.
Fishing's...
Just an excuse, I suspect.
(Distant conversation)
(women giggling)
Excuse us.
No, I'm sorry.
What, what were you studying?
Um... Butterflies.
Do you collect?
No. We log our observations
in our notebook.
I'm Livy.
I-I live in the farmhouse.
We were just
getting back to work.
No, wait, wait.
What did I cause you to miss?
What were you... What kind
of butterfly did you see?
It was a common blue.
There!
(Giggling)
Are... Are there
many species here?
Florence:
Yes, hundreds.
Like what?
Silver-spotted skippers...
Mourning cloaks,
hawkmoths...
Mm-hmm. Specklewoods.
(Laughing softly)
May I see your book?
These are beautiful.
Thank you.
Look...
There.
Oh!
What is it?
A sulphur--
some species of sulphur.
Shoo! Shoo!
I'm sorry.
Franklin, no!
He's your dog?
No. Well... Uh,
are-are you thirsty?
We should get back to work.
Come to the house
anytime you have...
We have cold colas
In the icebox.
Thank you.
Wait! What are your names?
Rose Umahara.
And Florie.
Bye. Bye.
Bye.
(Franklin whining softly)
Go away, Franklin.
Go away.
(Baby crying)
I'm almost four months pregnant.
Yes, that's
what I would have guessed.
It was a mistake.
When the baby arrives,
You won't see it
as a mistake anymore.
I'd like to believe you.
Then do so,
Mrs. Singleton.
Well, I'd say we're looking
at the third week of December.
A Christmas baby.
Mmm.
While we're in town,
I need to mail a letter.
Everything go all right?
Everything's
right on schedule.
Did he say when
the baby was coming?
December. I could have
told you that before.
(Sighing)
People will know.
People will know
the baby's early.
What will they think, then?
I don't care what people think.
I don't see
how you could be immune.
People judge, people gossip.
They won't say a thing.
And why is that?
Well...
They want the best for us.
(Engine starting)
(sizzling)
Smells good.
Livy:
A fiesta omelet.
Maybe I put too many
jalapeo peppers in it.
(Clearing throat):
No, it's real good.
Real good cooking.
The cheese--
I forgot the cheese.
It might mellow it;
hold on.
(Engine rumbling)
What is that?
That'll be hank.
What's that,
what's that sound?
It's the claw.
What are you doing
with that thing?
Thanks. You said
you like to swim.
Dig you a hole
so summertimes,
You and the children
can go swimming.
"Children"?
(Horn honking)
Aunt Livy!
Hi!
Hi.
Hey, I hope you don't
mind us coming along.
The boys couldn't miss it.
Hank.
It's not every day
somebody digs a hole.
That one that flew by
there, that's Chester,
And this is hank Jr.
Hello, hank Jr.
Hi, nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
Do you like my hair?
You look lovely.
She asked me
to do it up
just like yours.
Hank, honey,
Keep a watch on your brother.
Make sure
he doesn't get under that thing.
Here, Franklin, here, boy.
Get in there, Ray!
So, have you chosen a name
For your baby?
Ruth.
Well, you told me uncle Ray
And aunt Livy
were having a baby.
Aren't you?
I hav... I haven't
thought of a name yet.
I like the name Patricia.
My parents had to go
and name me Ruth.
Livy:
Ruth is an old
biblical name.
It's a very beautiful one,
in my opinion.
Martha:
Thank you.
Maybe now she'll keep it.
Boys, get on!
Get on!
Move it on out of here, boys!
Uncle Ray's
at the wheel.
Martha,
did you grow up in this house?
I did.
Our grandpa built it.
And before that,
he and grandma
lived in a dugout,
Which is still
over there by
the south field.
Right?
Really?
So, you never lived
anywhere else?
Nope.
Our younger brother, Danny...
Was the adventurous one.
(Loud thumping and creaking)
Drop it now!
(Thumping)
(laughing)
On the left, Ray!
Pull it way back
To the left!
What?!
What's in your locket?
Oh, I forgot I was wearing it.
Martha:
Ruth, don't pry.
It's as if your mother
didn't teach you any manners.
Hank:
Easy, easy!
It looks a little heavy, Ray!
(Rattling and groaning)
(loud thumping)
Drop her down!
Lever on the left!
On the left!
(Thumping)
Isn't there a manual
for that thing?
Well, if there were,
Do you think
they'd read it?
(Cackling)
(relieved chuckle)
Hank:
That was easy!
(Cackling)
I didn't ask him
to do that--
To dig a swimming hole.
I don't know why
he's going to the trouble.
He just wants
to please you.
I may not dance.
Well, Martha'll just
be glad we're there.
She's always been
a fool for dancing.
Slim's her favorite.
Don't you ever wonder
what else is out there,
Beyond the farm?
Sometimes.
Aren't you curious
how other people live?
I enjoy a drive, but...
I like coming
back to my place.
Sleeping on my land.
Your land.
It seems
every war in human history
Is about owning the land.
I like the Indian view--
That we're
just temporary guardians
Of the land where we live.
It's not temporary to me.
But your family's
owned this land
For less than a hundred years.
In the span of history,
that's nothing.
In the span of a life...
That's near everything.
(Lively jazzy music playing)
Hank:
Come on, girl!
You're next, you know!
And you think I'm joking.
Hank:
Come on, girl.
They're here--
uncle Ray and aunt Livy.
Oh!
Ah, there they are.
Happy birthday.
Hey, Ray.
Hey!
Happy birthday, sis.
Oh, finally.
It's not a party
till you come.
Come on, come on.
There's my guy.
(Song winds down)
(applause)
(beginning "Colohoma boogie")
Ray, you really ought to dance.
I'm fine.
All right.
You sure?
Yeah.
All right.
How about a dance
with my beautiful daughter?
Aw...
Martha:
Hank Jr?
Come here.
Good.
(Laughing)
Whoo-hoo! Whoo-hoo!
Right here.
(Song winding down)
(crowd applauding
and cheering)
It was good.
Slim:
We're here tonight
to celebrate a birthday.
I've known
this fine, young lady since...
Since I was slim.
(Laughter)
Martha, hank says
you're a fine wife.
That's the truth, slim.
The best.
Slim:
We know you're
a fine mother,
You bet.
And you're a first-
class friend.
Happy birthday.
Thank you.
Everyone:
Happy birthday!
Thank you, sweetheart.
That's my girl.
Thank you.
%% This isn't just a story %%
%% or a tale, as it may seem %%
Thank you.
%% It's all about
my brown-eyed gal... %%
Thank you, honey.
I love you, Martha.
I know.
%% If you could only see her %%
%% I am sure that
you will agree %%
%% that she will be
the only girl %%
(blowing whistle)
%% for you as well as me %%
%% she's my brown-eyed baby %%
%% she's as pretty as can be %%
%% her eyes, they shine
like starlight %%
%% and they're
just as bright to me %%
%% when I look into her eyes,
say, I really heave a sigh %%
%% yes, sir, she's
my brown-eyed baby... %%
(humming "brown-eyed baby")
Florence:
Hi, Livy.
Hi.
One...
I brought drinks.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm. Let's sit.
We skipped off
from our overseer.
Florie...
Although we shouldn't
tell you that.
This is your land.
My husband's.
He's handsome.
Who?
Your husband.
Oh.
(Giggling)
So, um, where
were you...
Before the war?
California.
Mm-hmm. Born and raised.
We were both
at USC.
What were your majors?
Mine was English.
English.
I hoped to teach literature
someday.
Rose is a long-term planner.
Everything in her life
she plans
Ten years in advance.
You didn't plan on this,
did you, Rose?
Picking potatoes?
At least I had plans.
(Sighing)
I hadn't declared
my major yet.
Too many things
interested me.
Mm-hmm. Too many boys.
(Laughs)
(vehicle approaching)
I was in
graduate school
In Denver, studying
archeology.
Someday, I wanted
to go to Turkey
To see the lost cities
of Ephesus and Troy.
Really?
Why did you leave your studies?
My mother got sick,
And Abby...
Uh, my sister, was
already married,
So I left school to be
with her until she died.
I'm sorry.
And then,
Before I knew it,
I was... Swept off my feet,
And now I'm here.
(Giggles)
That's so romantic.
When are you expecting?
Florie.
I'm sorry.
No, I didn't
realize it showed.
Forgive us
for prying...
Do you need
maternity clothes?
I hadn't really
thought about it yet.
Well, our father's
a tailor.
We all sew
In the family.
Choose the fabric,
and we'll make you
Something.
Uh-huh.
Thank you.
(Whistle blowing)
Thank you so
mu... Thank you.
You're welcome.
It's our pleasure.
Bye.
Bye. Thank you.
(Whistle blowing)
Ooh, the wind's turned.
Coming out of the north.
I made friends with two girls
from the work crew today.
They study butterflies,
and I was thinking
I could take them for a drive
in the mountains sometime.
Japanese?
Well, they're American.
Those Americans
who look Japanese.
You blame them
for pearl harbor, for Daniel?
I'm not as stupid
as you think.
I know they're not
the same people who
bombed pearl harbor.
They kept our crops
going the past
couple of years.
I never said
you were stupid.
And I never said
I disliked them.
I just said they were
Japanese, that's all.
And you keep your distance.
Look, I got a lot
to do around here.
I got to keep this place
going pretty much on my own.
I don't go into the fields to...
To socialize.
Rose and Florie
both went to USC.
Can't tell you how good it is
to talk about something
Other than crops
and the weather.
(Engine rumbling)
I bet.
Martha:
Thank you, Lord,
for your gifts,
And may we be ever mindful
of your love.
Amen.
All:
Pass the taters.
Put your napkin
on your lap first.
Would you care
for a roll, Livy?
Thanks. Ray?
I'm considering beans
in the north field.
Hank:
Mm. Are you?
Price of beans can't
go anywhere but up.
Ray:
Yeah.
Well, what do you think?
I've been thinking
about... About Troy.
Troy who?
City of. The lost one,
Over there
in Turkey.
Martha:
Turkey?
Uh, Homer wrote about it
in the Iliad.
No one knew if there really had
been such a city,
Or if Troy was merely
A myth until an archeologist
found it.
(Chuckles)
How do you lose a city?
Under the sand.
They, uh... They
had to excavate it.
Hank (chuckling):
Well, I'll be.
We could've...
We could've dug it up, Ray,
With the claw.
(Laughing)
(others laughing)
So, Ray, are you going to plant
some beans this year?
If you think we ought to.
(Sighs)
Good night.
(Franklin barking)
Abby?
Abby?!
(Squeals)
(laughing)
Abby!
Oh...
Whoo!
(barking)
hello, hello.
Franklin, it's okay, shh.
Is everything all right?
Uh, no.
What? What's happened?
Is it father?
No, he's fine. It's Kent.
They shipped him out.
He left last week.
Oh, hon, I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry.
It's worse than
I ever imagined.
You're out in the
middle of nowhere.
There are more people around
than you'd think.
We haven't heard from
you in almost a month.
I know. I've just been...
Getting a little
adjusted, I guess.
Liv, that skirt is
too small for you.
(Laughing):
Uh...
Come inside, come inside.
(Barking)
I want you to move
back to Denver
And stay with me.
Abby, how could I do that?
How could you not?
You're not having your baby
on a beet farm.
I need your help.
With Kent overseas
for who knows how long,
I'll go mad in that house alone.
You've no idea how lonely it is.
I used to feel that way...
When I was caring for mother.
I would just sit
there waiting
For those minutes a day
she was awake.
It wasn't fair
for daddy to drop
The entire burden
of caring for mother on you.
I had my hands full with Kent.
But we'd have
such a good time now, Liv,
Just the two of us...
Until Kent got home.
Ray.
Look who's here.
This is my sister, Abby.
Uh, nice to meet you.
Hello.
Welcome.
(Crickets chirping)
(Livy and Abby laughing)
(indistinct chatter)
What?
Rain.
All anyone talks
about is the weather.
(Chuckling)
Livy, when are
you coming home?
What about the baby?
I'll baby-sit.
You can go back to school.
Why not?
Father's satisfied.
You're married.
There'll be no baby born
out of wedlock.
There's more than one way
to work the rumor mill, Livy.
A few well-chosen words
among the gossips at church...
What do you mean?
The Denver ladies
will be tripping
Over themselves
to offer you sympathy.
Who knew he drank
or had that temper?
Can you image raising
a child in a home
Like that?
No, that's not Ray.
So?
Ray? No.
Ray's the most gentle
man I've ever met.
This has nothing
to do with him.
It's about doing
what's best for you.
Any word from Edward?
Mm, no.
Livy, you had
so many plans.
No one deserves to stay married
to someone they don't love,
Especially not you.
Give my love to father.
I will.
Does he ever ask about me?
Yes, often.
(Laughs)
You're a terrible liar.
Will you mail this
letter for me?
Sure, hon.
Bye.
Love you.
Mm-mm.
(Engine rumbling)
%% cheeks of Rose %%
%% tiny toes %%
%% has our little baby %%
%% eyes of blue %%
%% fingers, too %%
%% cunning all as may be... %%
Hi.
You were singing.
What was it?
It's just a song
daddy'd sing to us kids.
I was trying to remember it
so I could sing it to the baby.
My sister wants me
To go back to
Denver to deliver...
In the hospital.
Where is she?
She left already.
I'll make some lunch.
(Laughter)
Florence:
Swallowtail.
Probably a
western tiger.
Livy:
Those spots.
The spots on the wings
are beautiful.
Florence:
False eyes.
Oh, Florie, did you get it?
Got it.
False eyes confuse
its enemy.
Moths have them, too.
How can you tell
A moth from a butterfly?
Moths rest
with their wings spread,
Butterflies
with their wings together.
And more often,
moths have
Protective coloring
so they blend in.
Butterflies are bold.
Just look at some of the species
we've found. See?
Livy:
Colors.
Mm.
What is this?
That was strictly
For our observations,
Florie.
Stop fussing.
Perfect.
Florie...
(gasps):
Look! Look!
Wow, this is nice.
After your
second baby.
(Laughing)
What's your husband's
favorite color?
I don't know.
What's yours?
Blue and red.
Like the false eyes
on a swallowtail.
Yes, exactly.
How's this?
Ooh, I love that.
Rose:
Oh, good.
Florence:
Father makes
the finest suits, Livy.
Uh... It would be
wonderful if you
Could come and meet
our parents...
Would you please not
handle the fabric?
I'm going to buy this.
Are you with
these people?
Yes, I am.
Well, if they could get
on with their business,
Management would
appreciate it.
What else do
we need here?
Rose and Florence:
%% they asked me how I knew %%
%% my true love was true %%
%% I, of course, replied %%
%% something here inside %%
%% cannot be denied. %%
Germans.
Those are German POWs.
%% %%
We'll do a fitting soon.
Yes.
Bye, Livy.
Bye.
Thank you, Livy.
See you.
(Engine sputtering
intermittently)
(engine hisses to a stop)
(engine turning over
but not starting)
(starter cranking)
(groans)
(birds chirping)
(bugs chirping)
(grunting)
(door creaking)
(chittering)
Oh, my!
(Sighs)
Oh.
(Door opens and closes)
I was getting
worried.
Sorry I'm late.
I found the dugout--
The dugout that Martha
was talking about.
Look, arrowheads.
Livy, I don't mean
to disappoint you,
But my granddaddy
owned a gun.
For sure, he didn't
use a bow and arrow.
No, I know that,
but he or your grandmother
Were interested enough
to collect them.
Look. A whole jar
of flints.
Someone in your family
was a budding archeologist.
Look at this one.
(Giggling)
I so wish father could
have done this himself.
He's the expert,
But he hasn't been well
since the move.
Florence:
They took his work
And... And our house.
Still, he says,
We must prove our loyalty.
We must show them
we are good Americans.
He buys war bonds.
Florie.
Mother's no
better, Livy.
She made us
clean the house...
Stop.
We had to sell our house
for half its worth,
Yet my mother insisted
we clean it for the new owners.
We even waxed the floors.
I still don't understand
why you're so angry about that.
Of course we wanted
to present a clean house.
It was stolen from us, Rose.
You know why there are so few
young men at camp amache?
Why?
They were drafted.
The 442nd regiment
fighting in France.
Enough!
And Rose is like
our parents.
Always proper,
always good.
Florence:
Thank you, Livy.
Livy:
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Livy...
I've met someone.
Florence!
We met on one
of the farms...
He was guarding the German POWs
working there.
He gave me this.
Oh...
It belonged to his mother.
You must be very special to him.
He tells me I am.
Florie, we have to get back.
Rose is just jealous.
Um, but I want you to meet him.
Will you?
Of course I will.
Good. Thank you.
What's his name?
Walter.
Bye, Livy.
Bye.
Bye, Rose.
Bye, Livy.
Thank you. Bye.
Why on earth did you
bring him up?
No! No!
What? What-what's wrong?
My artifacts
from the dugout.
What are you doing?!
I was just cleaning
out the shed.
Where is the burlap bag?
What did you do with it!
Livy.
It was near the bottom
of the pile.
It hadn't caught fire.
Livy, this is
a working farm.
If something doesn't have a use,
I throw it out.
I thought it was trash.
It's not trash, it's history.
It's your history.
I'd do anything...
I'd do anything
to make you happy.
I know.
I know that.
Ray:
Dear Livy, if you like junk,
you'll like the cellar.
Be careful.
It's Dusty down there.
(Door creaking)
(honking)
Higher, there...
Wait, um...
I'm not sure why we're putting
an old ox yoke inside the house.
It was probably that very yoke
your grandfather used
To first break this land.
Yeah, well, it's about
to break my back.
I want to show you
the family history
That means the most to me.
I let him talk me into a deal.
If I'd stay behind
and work the farm,
He'd join the navy.
Landlocked his
whole growing up,
He was always dreaming
of the ocean.
I was the oldest.
I should have gone.
Remember, your phone
is ring-ring-ring.
Come on, daddy,
let's get to Wilson!
All right,
let's go.
If you hear only ring,
that's Miss Paulson.
Ring-ring is the Mcgregors.
Ring-ring-ring,
that's your signal.
Ring-ring-ring.
(Phone rings three times)
Hello.
We're talking
on the telephone!
Hey, everybody it's hank here!
It works!
Ruth:
Hi, aunt Livy!
(Wind whistling)
You want to come in?
All right.
Come on! Come on!
It's getting cold out here.
Come on, Franklin.
(Door opening)
Hi.
We don't have animals
in this house.
Get out! Get out!
Get out now! Get out!
Get out!
(Door slamming)
It's just for tonight.
It's terribly cold out there.
I grew up here.
I ate at this table.
For all my growing up,
My mama never let a dog
in the house,
And I won't either.
He'll freeze.
This came for you today.
To Livy Dunne.
I'm guessing he didn't
know you were married, huh?
I'm taking the night shift
at the beet factory.
It's something I sometimes
do this time of year.
Don't bother waiting up.
(Door closing)
(alarm ringing)
I didn't know what you
had for breakfast,
Because I've never
been up that early.
But I made you some
eggs and some oatmeal.
There's no need.
Just plain eggs.
There's no onions or peppers.
Ray, wait.
I'm sorry that I let
Franklin in the house.
I did not realize what
an insult that would be to you.
With all the other animals in
that barn, that dog'll be fine.
I have something
I want to tell you.
My first day here,
I looked in your dresser.
I can't even
explain why I did it.
I'm sorry.
You could've looked in there
anytime you wanted.
I got nothing to hide from you.
There was a watch.
I could
hear it ticking.
I've never seen
you carry it.
It was my father's.
Sometimes I wind it up
when I want to remember him.
I remembered how good
he was to my mama.
Kind of husband I want to be.
First day I...
Wound it up for no good reason.
Just for luck.
Ray, I made a mistake.
Which mistake
would that be, huh?
Being with him or marrying me?
Would it be easier if I left?
Is there anything
you like about me, Livy?
(Door opening)
(door slamming)
(knocking)
Hi, Chester.
Mama, it's aunt Livy!
Hi.
Oh, Ruth was just
Talking about you.
Ruth:
And here you are.
It's like you
read my mind.
See, we don't need
a telephone.
Yes, we do.
I was thinking
of you, too, Ruth.
I was wondering if you wanted
to have this dress.
As big as
I am now,
I can't imagine ever
fitting into it again.
The hat comes with it.
Can I try it?
Go on.
Did Ray tell you...
I don't know the details.
He and hank had to go over
To the beet factory.
Why don't you come in
and sit down?
For months I've...
I've written the father
of this baby.
I thought he died.
I didn't realize...
No. He... He's a
flight instructor.
He never
went overseas.
We met
on furlough.
And for months, I've...
Written him these letters.
I know it was wrong.
For the longest time,
I didn't hear from him.
And as long as I
didn't hear from him,
I could imagine
that he wanted me.
I finally
got a letter.
"Congratulations, Livy.
"You're a wonderful girl.
"And I only hope you find
the father of this baby,
Because I sincerely doubt
that I'm responsible."
I know that I've hurt Ray.
My sister wants me
To go back to Denver
to have the baby.
Might be best if I leave
after Thanksgiving.
When Ray loves a person,
it's with his whole heart.
Losing our baby brother
to the war nearly killed him.
If you're planning on leaving,
do it soon.
You know, there's one thing
I've never
heard you say.
And that's how
you feel about Ray.
Livy (crying):
Mama?
(Crying)
Livy? Livy.
(Sniffling)
It's all right.
What happened?
Calling out.
Calling out
for your mama.
After mama died,
I was so lonely.
I gave my life away,
just to be held.
By a stranger.
How could I do that?
Ray...
You are such a good...
Thank you. Thank you.
Livy:
Happy Thanksgiving.
Oh, it was so kind of you
to bake us a pie, Livy.
Happy Thanksgiving.
Livy tells me
you're from California.
Yes, we are.
Ray:
I've never been
to California.
Livy, can we talk?
Rose:
I've never been
to Colorado.
Um, do you think
you can meet my boyfriend
Two weeks
from Saturday?
Sure.
Perhaps, uh,
We could go for a drive
Just to get away from here
For the afternoon.
All right.
What time?
How's noon?
I'll pick you up here.
Oh, no. Um, not here, Livy.
Uh, on the road,
By the grain
elevators.
All right.
Thank you, Livy.
I'm grateful for
all of you, of course,
But I'd also like to pray that
this war will soon be over.
And I'm thankful for
the harvest this year.
God's been
good to us.
Ruth:
I'm thankful
that the baby's
Coming and I'm going
to have a cousin.
I'm grateful that Daniel's
seat beside me isn't empty.
I've...
I've learned more about love...
In my six months
with this family
Than I did in the 25 years
in my father's house.
I have...
I have received love here.
And I have received forbearance.
And I thank you.
I will always remember you.
Everyone of you.
Hank:
Happy Thanksgiving.
Amen.
Let's dig in.
Ray...
I, uh, have to go say
good-bye to the girls.
(Franklin whines)
Oh, that's all right.
He can stay if he wants.
It's awful cold.
When you come out here,
I know you saw this
as an agreement
Between your daddy
and reverend case.
Marrying wasn't
your idea.
I know you may have your mind
set on leaving, but...
I can't let you go without
telling you how I feel.
I've fallen in love with you.
And I love that baby.
For me, you're the best
thing that's ever happened.
Livy, you're a fine
and talented woman.
You're a pitiful cook,
But that doesn't matter.
I can do the cookin'.
I know you had your heart set
on going to faraway places,
But there's a good
bit of history
Right here
in Otero county.
If you like Indian
canyons and dugouts,
I'll help
you find them.
You can dig around
all you want.
(Sniffling)
Sound like I'm trying
to sell you something.
That day, when
the preacher married us,
I forgot the ring.
I have one now.
Ray, the truth is, I don't know
if I deserve you.
How do you know this could work?
I know, because...
Someday you're
gonna forgive yourself.
Hi.
I'm so sorry I'm late.
I knew you wouldn't
let us down.
Um, Livy,
this is Walter.
Hello. So nice
to meet you.
Um, where-where do you...
Oh, uh, we thought
we'd go south
Where we saw
the swallowtails.
That's almost to new Mexico.
Walter's on leave
And he's got a cousin
down that way.
I thought
we could
Drop him off.
You'll freeze.
It's fine.
Walter's from Idaho.
He's tough.
Um...
Well, uh, let's get going.
We have a long drive.
Are you insane?
What are you talking about?
What did he promise you?
I don't know what you're
talking about...
Florie.
I've seen him on
the work crew.
Did you make his uniform?
If you'd rather not
take me and Walter for a drive,
You should just let
us out here, Livy.
Florie, stop it!
You stop it.
You're just jealous
because he loves me.
If he loves you,
why would he leave?
As soon as this
war is over,
He'll be free.
If anyone finds out
You helped this man,
you and Rose will be
accused of treason.
You could go to prison for
the rest of your lives.
Florie, that uniform ties
him not only to you
But to your family.
To your father
and your mother.
Father and mother have
nothing to do with it.
Nor does Rose.
Listen to me--
you're going to go home,
You're going to burn
every scrap of fabric
Left from that uniform.
You're going to
take that bracelet,
You're going to throw
it into a field.
Walk away, Florie,
and never look back.
You're lonely,
And you're reaching out for
something to make it better.
But you can't do this.
You'll be paying for it
the rest of your life.
Florie?
Get out of the truck--
both of you.
Tell him that it's safer if
you don't travel with him.
It'll be safer
if you travel alone.
(Barking)
It's okay. Get down.
Come here.
Come here. Sit. Stay.
Stay.
Walter, let me
Be Frank with you.
You'll never make it across
the border dressed as an mp.
Nein.
Come with me.
This way.
My husband's room
is right up these stairs.
Open the wardrobe
and put on some clothes.
Leave the clothes that
you're wearing on the floor.
My husband will be home
any minute. Hurry.
Come on, Franklin.
(Wind whistling)
Listen...
Florie loves you.
Soon this war will be over
and you'll be free.
If you leave now,
how will you find her?
Do you have
something to drink?
Bitte?
Yes. I can make some coffee.
Come on, Franklin.
(Engine starting)
(gasping)
Wilson operator.
Operator, could you
please connect me
To the sheriff's department?
One moment, please.
(Groans)
(exhaling sharply)
Sheriff's Haynes.
Can I help you?
Sheriff, this is Livy Singleton,
Ray Singleton's wife.
Yes, ma'am.
I want you to know
that an escaped POW
Has just stolen my truck
and is now headed down route 22.
He should be running out of gas
About the time
he hits the bridge.
He's unarmed, so please
don't hurt him.
Thank you, Mrs. Singleton.
We'll put someone on it
right away.
And officer, I'm in labor.
I need some help.
(Gasps)
Oh, oh.
Livy?
What in the world
are you doing?
Getting ready
for our baby.
Our baby's coming!
Our baby...
I'll send Martha
right over!
Hurry!
(Engine turning over
but not starting)
Martha:
Thank you, doctor.
Hey there.
%% Cheeks of Rose %%
%% tiny toes %%
%% has our little baby %%
%% eyes of blue %%
%% fingers, too %%
%% gotta love this baby. %%
All:
Aw!
Thank you so much.
This is for you.
What?
Livy:
Butterflies of America.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
That's right, Danny.
This was your
granddaddy's watch.
And someday it's going
to be yours,
But in the meantime,
I'll just hold on to it for you.
(Gurgling)
We got to get going.
Your mama's set
on a treasure hunt.
It's not a treasure hunt.
It's his first
archeological dig.
For arrowheads, right?
Ready?
Come on, let's go.
Let's go.
We're going to fly there.
(Baby laughing)
(barks)
---the end---