Previously on Prison Break:
Listen, why don't I just
give you half the money
we call it a day?
All right, 60/40.
You thieving son of a bitch.
You better get down on your
knees and pray to God
that I don't find you.
Because if I do,
mark my words,
I'm gonna gut you
bow to stern.
Mr. Bellick?
Yeah?
Do you mind answering
a few more questions?
We have a lead as to where
Burroughs will be meeting up
with his brother.
It's a place he referred to
as "Bolshoi booze."
They're numbers.
Plug 'em into your GPS
they'll take you to a spot
in the New Mexico desert.
Daddy!
Hey, baby, you ready to go?
Go, go, go, go, go!
What do we do now?
(shrieks)
(electrical zapping)
She told you anything?
Not yet.
Then kill her.
Well, she knows something.
You disobey me, you are done!
Put her in the ground, Paul!
You're going to die,
and all you had to do was tell
me what your father gave you.
Go to hell.
Go!
The plane's gonna stop
at the seven-mile marker,
Route 4 at sunset.
We got to go.
I brought someone.
Dad?
We met before.
It was you.
Go easy, son.
Stay away from me.
What the hell's going on?
I know him.
What do you mean you know him?
That's impossible.
I know him.
I know this man!
Michael...
Maybe that's far enough.
This doesn't concern you.
What the hell's going on, Dad?
After Mom died...
you were in juvie.
They put me with this...
this foster father
down on Pershing Avenue.
He punished me,
locked me up.
If you leave someone alone
in the dark for that long,
their eyes start to adjust.
You start to see things,
no matter how small,
because if they exist,
they can help you.
(wood squeaks)
Help you do the only thing
you want to do...
when you're alone in the dark:
get out.
(gasps)
Get up!
ANNOUNCER (on TV):
Now everyone can fish like a pro
with Moto Lure.
MAN:
You know, I've been fishing
most of my life.
I've used just about every lure
that you could use.
Most of them, you need to be
an expert to use.
This Moto Lure's
a little different.
Everybody, I mean everybody,
can fish with it.
And you're gonna catch bigger
fish,
you're gonna catch more fish.
(knocking at door)
It even works in weedy areas
where most top-water lures
won't work.
Take a look at this baby.
This thing looks
like a real minnow.
This is one very cool bait.
I have never seen anything
quite like this.
(knocking)
Even if you've bought lures
off of TV in the past
and been disappointed--
and believe me,
I know how you feel--
Hey.
Sorry, man.
I thought you'd left.
No, still here.
Here I am.
Yeah, it's just that
a couple of guests
are complaining
about the volume
of your TV.
Oh, sorry, I fell asleep.
I must have hit the remote.
I'll take care of it.
Thanks. Sorry. Thanks.
Great. Um, so could you
do that for me now, please,
so it's taken care of?
Yeah.
Thanks.
And the Moto Lure series
makes a great gift for anyone...
(volume lowers)
Taken care of.
(water sloshing)
Is, uh, everything okay
in your bathroom?
Excuse me?
Your bathroom.
There's a noise coming from it.
Yeah, my daughter thinks
bath time is playtime.
I will clean it up.
Scout's honor. Sorry.
All right.
Have a nice day.
Yeah, you, too.
Michael, Michael,
please wait.
Michael?
He did this to you?
Michael!
Lincoln!
He did this to you?
How could you do that
to another human being
with your own hands?
(door opens)
It's okay. You're safe now.
He's not going
to hurt you anymore.
Come on.
Come with me
and don't look back.
Michael!
Michael...
(wind whistling)
It's gonna be all right.
www.1000fr.com Present
Capture:FRM@FadeOut
Sync:FRM@Navel ¾ÆÄÒ·¹´ü
Six months
Six months I was
in that place.
Where were you?
How long did you know?
I found you
as soon as I could.
The state kept moving
you around.
Then you went away again,
right?
You don't think
it killed me to
leave you like that?
To leave
in the first place?
Since the beginning,
I was the problem.
Since day one.
Your lives are what they are
because of me.
Yes, Linc told me
about the Company.
Apparently, you were some kind
of analyst.
That's the job
you chose over
your family.
I thought I was doing
the right thing.
I thought I was protecting you.
From what, Dad,
from who?
The Company had enemies!
I was important
to the Company.
I became a target.
Easiest way
to get to me
would be to get to you!
I left as soon
as I realized
how corrupt it all was.
How they were buying
the government...
You could have come back
at any time!
No, I couldn't!
Michael, turning on
the Company
put me and you
at even greater risk.
I had to stay away.
We were your sons.
And you still are, Michael.
We can fix this.
I came back
so that we could fix this.
This can never be fixed.
There's a tape.
Gives us everything
we need.
Linc will be set free
if we find it.
You're not gonna believe
who he thinks has it.
Who?
Sara.
Yes, uh, tall and slender,
brown hair, brown eyes.
She'd be pretty banged up.
WOMAN:
No one matching that description
has been brought into the ER.
Kellerman.
No report on Sara Tancredi?
She's dead.
I'm dealing with the body
right now.
You must be relieved
that it's over.
Yeah.
Yeah, I got to go.
One more thing: confirmation.
I need a photo of the body
before disposal.
Uh, take one with your phone
and send it to me and I'll...
Bill not a good time
right now, all right?
Paul, take a breath,
then take the picture.
I'm waiting.
(receiver clicks)
"The trail led
to a very dangerous place.
"Now, Arvid knew that,
"but he held tightly
onto the dragon's
leash anyway,
"as the creature ran
into the Everdark Forest,
pulling the young boy
behind him."
Why didn't he just
let go of the leash?
Well, because
he loved the dragon.
Now, when you love someone,
you'll do anything
to hold onto them.
Anything to keep them
safe and happy.
Is that why we're camping?
Yep. So we can all be together.
I'm happy.
I'm happy, too.
Here you go.
Well, it's all
working out, huh?
Don't say that.
You know, this moment,
right here, right now,
it's all worth it.
I love you.
I love you, too.
That's old.
The kids
are bigger now.
Sorry. I was just...
Getting bored
out of your wits
'cause you been
waiting so long.
Really sorry about all this.
We don't get a whole bunch
of homicides out here,
and, well, we're trying
to play catch-up.
Please, have a seat.
I'm real sorry
about your friend.
Sick world out there.
Ain't that
the truth?
So you guys out here
in Kansas together?
Yeah. That's right.
Doing what?
Well, you know,
just seeing the sights.
You left Chicago
to see the sights
in Tribune, Kansas?
Last time I checked,
a man could go where he wanted.
Mr. Bellick...
Brad.
Brad. I don't really care
what you were doing out here.
We're both in
law enforcement.
We can each sniff out a perp
like a hot fart.
Pardon my French.
(chuckles)
We both know
you're not a criminal, so...
I don't care if you
boys were out here
whoopin' it without your wives
or...
going Brokeback.
What? Hell, no.
My point is,
I don't care
what you were doing.
I just need to know
where you were doing it
and who you might
have crossed paths with
so I can find out
who carved up Mr. Geary.
Geary and I got a lead
that one of the Fox River Eight
was in town.
Which one?
Theodore Bagwell.
The man who did
all those horrible things
to those teenagers?
That's him.
We were going to bring him in
for the reward money, but we
couldn't get a handle on him.
Geary and I split up, figured
we didn't have a shot, but...
But what?
Well, after
what happened,
I'm starting to think maybe
Geary ran into ol' Bagwell
after all.
Right here in Tribune?
Now, Brad, do you think
you could answer some questions
that might help us
track down Theodore Bagwell?
I'd be indebted.
I'll do whatever I can
to help you nail
that son of a bitch.
You think Sara
has this tape?
Government does.
I just saw her yesterday.
If she does
have anything,
she doesn't know.
Well, where is she now?
I don't know.
Any way you can get
in touch with her?
We brought cell phones.
I could call her.
Please, please, please, bro,
call her
from Panama.
Please.
We got less
than two hours.
I got to make the flight.
(pebbles tumbling)
Shh! Shh! Shh!
What?
Run.
Run!
(shots firing)
Where's this car you
keep talking about?
It's over the ridge.
Give me that.
You guys head for the car!
Go!
Come on! Go!
Go back for him!
Dad!
Go!
We made it! Son of a bitch!
We made it!
linc.
Sucre, get us to a hospital.
Out here? Where the hell
am I going to find...?
Just get us
to a hospital, please!
Okay.
Don't worry.
You're going to make it.
It's bile. He got me
clean through.
You're going to be okay!
Just... hold on.
Listen to me,
both of you.
I'm sorry.
I wish I had never left.
Don't talk, don't talk.
Just breathe.
Okay, so do you want a PB & B?
Not really.
My tummy hurts.
Huh.
Where's her knapsack?
Her what?
Her knapsack.
Her medicine's in it.
I don't know, baby.
I just grabbed her and ran.
She needs that medicine.
She can't go two days
without it.
Yeah, I know.
I'm her father, all right?
Where is it?
Baby. Baby, look. Calm down.
What are you looking for?
Just tell me what it is, and
I'll go ahead and get it, okay?
Her prescription.
It's a backup.
I keep an extra,
in case.
Okay.
Um... so all we need to do
is find a pharmacy.
Don't worry.
Hey, looks like we're going
on a ride,
sweet pea.
Look, we nail Bagwell,
he might still have
some of Geary's things on him,
like his backpack, which has
his personal stuff in it.
I know his wife
would love to have it.
If we find Bagwell,
you can give it
to her personally.
Thanks.
It's the least
I can do
considering how
you're helping me out.
Though some of the guys on the
force are concerned about...
What are they concerned about?
Nothing.
But you know what?
Why don't you tell me
what you know,
we'll track down Bagwell,
we'll get Geary's effects back
to his family,
I'll make sure
that everybody involved knows
that your help was invaluable.
I'll even recommend
that you get most of,
if not all of,
that reward money.
What is it exactly
that the guys on the force
were concerned about?
Well, some of them thought
that you weren't
being totally upfront
about your head injury.
I mean, to be fair,
it does seem a little off
that you didn't see
the guy who hit you
smack-dab on the forehead.
You got me.
Geary and me
had a little dustup over how
to go about finding Bagwell.
It got physical, and he hit me.
The two of us, we
fought like brothers.
I didn't want to rat
him out to the cops.
After the fight,
we split up.
And then...
(sobbing):
Well, you know what
happened to him.
I just wish to hell
we'd never fought, you know?
Maybe then he'd still be...
Brad, you can't blame yourself.
Why don't we refocus our energy
on finding the man
who killed your friend?
That's what Roy would've wanted.
All right, baby.
Insurance card?
Uh, no, I don't have insurance.
You're paying for dexamethasone
without insurance?
You got Medicaid,
Medicare or something?
Nope.
Um, I'll just pay cash.
It's $125.
Excuse me?
Um, oh, sorry.
Sorry I don't have
anything smaller.
Um, I have to go to the back
to get change for $100.
So... I'll be right back.
Right there! Hospital!
I see it. I see it.
Just get us there.
No, you'll be caught.
Then we'll be caught.
I'm not gonna
let you die.
ALDO:
Then listen to me.
You find Sara
Tancredi.
She can end this.
It's up to you now.
Yeah, I want an alarm out
on a dark blue sedan.
License: AE9268.
40 miles southeast
of Los Cruces.
Do it now.
(cell phone ringing)
Oh, come on!
What?
what hospital?
MAN:
He came in with
a bad GSW.
Docs called us in.
He's in here.
We ran his name.
Came back with two
federal drug smuggling
warrants out on him.
Heard you wanted to talk to me.
I got some information
the Feds want...
about Michael Scofield.
Like where he's
catching a ride.
And where would that be?
It's not just the "where"
but the "when."
That "when"
is coming up soon.
But I want to cut a deal first.
Give us a minute.
Anything you want
to say?
One day.
That's all we had.
He wasn't around often.
When he was,
it mattered most.
MICHAEL:
He was... in his way.
Yep, and we never knew.
Back then, when
things were
at their worst...
there were days
I thought I'd never
see the sun again.
But he saved my life.
I just wish he could have let us
be a part of his.
Yeah.
I'll tell him. Okay.
Here's the deal.
All charges dropped
and the government
picks up medical costs
until you're fit to be deported,
all contingent upon your
information being accurate.
Where's Scofield?
No deportation.
I want citizenship.
Citizenship?
A little incentive,
and I want it in writing.
(groans softly)
I'm so tired of playing games.
Well, start typing.
No external pacemaker.
Oh, this is a good one--
no morphine drip.
Huh?
What are you doing?
FBI. Out.
Out! Out.
What the hell are you doing?
Giving you a little incentive.
Come on!
Come on,
you son of a...
SLATTERY:
And they found nothing?
Okay, thanks.
Well, your instincts
are great, Brad,
but the precinct actually
sent a unit over to
Hollander's house today.
An anonymous caller
said they saw an intruder
but no one was there.
Damn it.
If you knew about Bagwell
and Hollander,
why didn't you just
head over there yourself?
We couldn't find the house.
Really?
It's listed.
(knocking)
Excuse me.
SLATTERY:
Thank you.
Everything okay?
Yeah, yeah, everything's fine.
Brad, have you ever been
to the Fauntleroy Hotel?
It's about 15
minutes from here.
Never heard of it.
Well, that's strange,
'cause they found
this receipt in
Geary's hotel room.
It's from your credit card.
I don't know how that got there.
I think you're being evasive.
You should tell me the
truth, Mr. Bellick.
What happened to "Brad"?
About seven years
ago, I got my first
homicide case--
a woman, pretty.
She was brutally
attacked.
Animal boyfriend
left her for dead,
but she was still
breathing... barely.
But she punched
into her cell phone
the killer's number, so she
solved the crime for us.
When we found
the receipt, Brad,
it was in Geary's hand, his
finger pointing to your name.
With his last ounce of strength,
he told us you killed him.
Okay, listen.
Geary and I found Bagwell
at Hollander's house.
We roughed him up
till he told us where he'd hid
the five million bucks
we knew he dug up in Utah.
When we found the money,
Geary double-crossed me.
He hit me in the head
and took the cash.
I had nothing to do
with Geary's death.
You hear
what I'm saying?
I'm the victim here,
not that son of a bitch!
Come on, come on, come on.
Where are you at, baby?
Hey, uh, could you hurry it up?
It's just it's getting
really late-- I got to get home.
Here you go.
And, um, that's $20,
$40, $50,
and $20 is $70.
One, two, three,
four...
five... seventy-five.
???
You got to be kidding me.
Ma'am.
Afternoon, Officer.
Do you have any
ID with you?
Uh, no.
I walked over here,
so I didn't carry anything
with me.
OFFICER:
Did you?
Where'd you walk from?
Is there a problem,
Officer?
There's only a problem
if you make one, Ms. Franklin.
You want to tell us
where your husband is?
I don't know.
Place your hands behind
your back, please, ma'am.
Baby, I'm so sorry.
Oh, my God.
Where's Mommy?
Mommy, uh, Mommy is going
to meet us later.Okay?
Yes.
KIM:
Where's the photo?
Bill, there was
a tactical error.
I don't want terminology
from the Cover Your Ass
Handbook, Paul.
What happened?
There were unforeseen
circumstances,
things that could not
be predicted.
Where's Sara?
She's gone, isn't she?
Yes, she got away,
but there's no way
that she could...
Bill.
(sniffles)
(exhales forcefully)
(grunts)
I'm not going
to let you die.
I love you.
You know that, don't you?
Too many.
Too many people died
because I wanted you to be free.
You couldn't have known,
Michael.
You couldn't
have know it...
would have ended up like this.
But it did.
They wanted him.
They wanted him
in the ground,
and they got their wish.
This thing is not going
to end here, Michael.
I know.
It's going to
keep spreading.
Their hands are going
to get more and more bloody.
Well, the question is,
is the blood on their hands...
or ours?
I'm sorry, guys.
We got to go.
Get back on with Border Patrol.
Call the Navy Reserve air
station in Dallas.
They've got planes on alert.
We need an intercept of a white,
single engine A-36 Beech
heading toward the border.
Call Mexico, get clearance
for an international pursuit.
Tell them if they got to take
the plane down, just do it.
Come on, guys!
Guys, come on.
Come on, guys.
What?
We're staying.
Ay, vamonos!
Esperate, esperate,
esperate.
Michael, this is what
we've been waiting for.
Maybe we'll see you down there
somewhere.
I can't talk you
out of this one, can I?
Well, I hope so.
Be good.
Thank you, Michael.
Thank you for everything.
Take care,
all right?
I will.
Fly safe, papi.
Andele!  Andele!
Give 'em hell.
Panama would've been good.
Are you ready for this?
Been waiting years.
Good to hear it.
'Cause today is the day
we stop running.
What now?
We go back to the car.
I drive to a border town,
find a cell phone signal.
Call Sara.
Where the hell are those jets?!
(low rumbling)
You hear that?
Yeah.
Pull over.
(rumbling)
Oh, God, they're going
after Sucre.
They're gonna take him down.
How'd they find out?
I don't know.
Michael.
(engine starts)
I want to know what
the hell's going on.
If you could've arrested me,
you would've already done it.
I'm out of here.
Not really an option
for you, Mr. Bellick.
What do you got, a receipt?
He left it in his pocket.
A fight?
Big deal.
I got ten pals in Chicago
tell you Geary and I
threw down once a month.
You're right.
Any of those things
on their own,
probably not enough.
But when you add this...
What the hell's that?
You left a message
for Mr. Geary.
You thieving son of a bitch,
you better
get down on your knees and pray
to God that I don't find you.
Because if I do, mark my words:
I'm gonna gut you bow to stern.
You want to hear it again?
Now at this
juncture, Brad,
things will go a whole
lot easier for you
if you admit
to the crime.
Now you listen to me,
you manipulative little bitch.
I did not kill Roy Geary!
You understand
what I'm telling you!
Bagwell set me up!
Get your hands off of me!
Bradley Bellick,
you are under arrest
for the first-degree murder
of Roy William Geary.
You have a right
to remain silent.
Anything you say can be used
against you in a court of law.
You have a right to
talk with an attorney
and to have him present with you
when being questioned.
If you cannot hire
an attorney...
(line ringing)
WOMAN:
President Reynolds' office.
This is Agent Paul Kellerman.
I need to speak with the
president right now, please.
???
isn't familiar
with an Agent Kellerman.
June, it's me.
I need to speak
with Caroline now.
June, if you don't
put me through,
I'll make certain that
the president
knows that you were the one
who did not allow me
to provide her with some
very important information.
Now.
I'm sorry,
this administration
isn't familiar with an Agent...
(phone slams)
(mechanical voice):
Please leave a message
after the tone.
(machine beeps)
Bill, don't do this.
I've dedicated my life
to this country, to Caroline.
Everything I have, I give.
Every photo, every file.
Get rid of it all.
Make him a ghost.
I've been a perfect soldier.
I've never asked
anything of you, ever.
But I'm asking now.
Bill, don't do this.
I don't see him.
Trust me,
we haven't lost him yet.
Linc?
Hmm.
Stop the car.
What?
We got to stop the car.
That's a radio tower over there.
It must be picking up
some kind of analog signal.
We got to get closer.
Turn around.
What about your friend
back there?
If we're gonna go down,
might as well go down swinging.
Come on, come on, come on...
(beeps)
We are in business.
It's going through.
Come on, Sara, pick up.
(line ringing)
Sara.
SARA:
Hello? Hello? Michael?
Michael? Michael?
Welcome to www.1000fr.com