Previously on prison break:
Listen,why don't I just give you half
the money we call it a day?
All right,60/40.
You thieving son of a bitch.
You better get down on your knees and pray to god that I don't find you.
Because if I do,mark my words, I'm gonna gut you bow to stern.
- Mr. Bellick? - Yeah?
Do you mind answering a few more questions?
We have a lead as to where burroughs will be meeting up with his brother.
It's a place he referred to as "bolshoi booze.¡±
They're numbers.
Plug 'em into your gps they'll take you to a spot in the new mexico desert.
- Daddy! - Hey,baby,you ready to go?
Go,go,go,go,go!
What do we do now?
- she told you anything? - Not yet.
- Then kill her. - Well,she knows something.
You disobey me,you are done! Put her in the ground,paul!
You're going to die,and all you had to do was tell me what your father gave you.
Go to hell.
Go!
The plane's gonna stop at the seven-mile marker,
route 4 at sunset.
- We got to go. - I brought someone.
Dad?
We met before.
It was you.
Go easy,son.
Stay away from me.
- What the hell's going on? - I know him.
What do you mean you know him? That's impossible.
I know him. I know this man!
- Michael... - Maybe that's far enough.
This doesn't concern you.
What the hell's going on,dad?
After mom died...
you were in juvie.
They put me with this...
this foster father down on pershing avenue.
He punished me,
locked me up.
If you leave someone alone in the dark for that long,
their eyes start to adjust.
You start to see things,no matter how small,
because if they exist,they can help you.
help you do the only thing you want to do...
when you're alone in the dark:
Get out.
I've used just about every lure that you could use.
Most of them,you need to be an expert to use.
This moto lure's a little different.
Everybody,I mean everybody,can fish with it.
And you're gonna catch bigger fish, you're gonna catch more fish.
it even works in weedy areas where most top-water lures won't work.
Take a look at this baby.
This thing looks like a real minnow.
This is one very cool bait.
I have never sn anything quite like this.
even if you've bought lures off of tv in the past and been disappointed--
and believe me,I know how you feel--
- hey. - Sorry,man.I thought you'd left.
No,still here. Here I am.
Yeah,it's just that a couple of guests are complaining about the volume of your tv.
Oh,sorry,I fell asleep.
I must have hit the remote. I'll take care of it.
Thanks.Sorry. Thanks.Great.
Um,so could you do that for me now, please,so it's taken care of?
Yeah. Thanks.
taken care of .
is,uh,everything okay in your bathroom?
Excuse me?
Your bathroom. There's a noise coming from it.
Yeah,my daughter thinks bath time is playtime.
I will clean it up. Scout's honor.Sorry.
All right. Have a nice day.
Yeah,you,too.
- Michael, - Michael?
- michael,please wait. - He did this to you?
- Michael! - Lincoln!
He did this to you?
Michael!
How could you do that to another human being with your own hands?
it's okay. You're safe now.
He's not going to hurt you anymore.
Come on.
Come with me and don't look back.
Michael!
Michael...
it's gonna be all right.
Six months I was in that place.
Where were you?
How long did you know?
I found you as soon as I could. The state kept moving you around.
Then you went away again,right?
You don't think it killed me to leave you like that?
To leave in the first place?
Since the beginning,I was the problem. Since day one.
Your lives are what they are because of me.
Yes,linc told me about the company.
Apparently,you were some kind of analyst. That's the job you chose over your family.
I thought I was doing the right thing. I thought I was protecting you.
From what,dad,from who?
The company had enemies! I was important to the company.
I became a target. Easiest way to get to me would be to get to you!
I left as soon as I realized how corrupt it all was. How they were buying the government...
- you could have come back at any time! - No,I couldn't!
Michael,turning on the company put me and you at even greater risk.
I had to stay away.
We were your sons.
And you still are,michael.
We can fix this.
I came back so that we could fix this.
This can never be fixed.
There's a tape.
Gives us everything we need.
Linc will be set free if we find it.
You're not gonna believe who he thinks has it.
Who?
Sara.
Yes,uh,tall and slender, brown hair,brown eyes.
She'd be pretty banged up.
No one matching that description has been brought into the er.
Kellerman.
No report on sara tancredi?
She's dead. I'm dealing with the body right now.
You must be relieved that it's over.
Yeah. Yeah,I got to go.
One more thing: Confirmation.
I need a photo of the body before disposal.
Uh,take one with your phone and send it to me and I'll...
bill not a good time right now,all right?
Paul,take a breath,then take the picture.
I'm waiting.
"the trail led to a very dangerous place. (HARVEY.NORTH DAKOTA)
"Now,arvid knew that,"
but he held tightly onto the dragon's leash anyway,
"as the creature ran into the everdark forest, pulling the young boy behind him.¡±
Why didn't he just let go of the leash?
Well,because he loved the dragon.
Now,when you love someone,you'll do anything to hold onto them.
Anything to keep them safe and happy.
Is that why we're camping?
Yep. So we can all be together.
I'm happy.
I'm happy,too.
Here you go.
Well,it's all working out,huh?
Don't say that.
You know,this moment,right here,right now,
it's all worth it.
I love you.
I love you,too.
TRIBUNE.KANSAS
That's old.
The kids are bigger now.
Sorry. I was just...
getting bored out of your wits 'cause you been waiting so long.
Really sorry about all this.
We don't get a whole bunch of homicides out here, and,well,we're trying to play catch-up.
Please,have a seat.
I'm real sorry about your friend.
Sick world out there.
Ain't that the truth?
So you guys out here in kansas together?
Yeah. That's right.
Doing what?
Well,you know,just seeing the sights.
You left chicago to see the sights in tribune,kansas?
Last time I checked,a man could go where he wanted.
Mr. Bellick...
brad.
Brad.
I don't really care what you were doing out here.
We're both in law enforcement. We can each sniff out a perp like a hot fart.
Pardon my french.
we both know you're not a criminal,so...
I don't care if you boys were out here whoopin' it without your wives or...
going brokeback.
What?
Hell,no.
My point is,I don't care what you were doing.
I just need to know where you were doing it and who you might have crossed paths with so
I can find out who carved up Mr. Geary.
Geary and I got a lead that one of the fox river eight was in town.
Which one?
Theodore bagwell.
The man who did all those horrible things to those teenagers?
That's him.
We were going to bring him in for the reward money, but we couldn't get a handle on him.
Geary and I split up, figured we didn't have a shot,but...
but what?
Well,after what happened,I'm starting to think maybe geary ran into ol' bagwell after all.
Right here in tribune?
Now,brad,do you think you could answer some questions
that might help us track theodore bagwell?
I'd be indebted.
I'll do whatever I can to help you nail that son of a bitch.
You think sara has this tape?
Government does.
I just saw her yesterday. If she does have anything,she doesn't know.
Well,where is she now?
I don't know.
Any way you can get in touch with her?
We brought cell phones. I could call her.
Please,please,please,bro, call her from panama.
Please.
We got less than two hours. I got to make the flight.
What?
Run. Run!
where's this car you keep talking about?
- It's over the ridge. - Give me that.
You guys head for the car! Go!
Come on!
Go!
Go back for him!
Dad! Go!
Come on,dad
We made it!
Son of a bitch! We made it!
Linc.
Sucre,get us to a hospital.
Out here? Where the hell am I going to find...?
Just get us to a hospital,please!
Okay.
Don't worry. You're going to make it.
It's bile.
He got me clean through.
You're going to be okay! Just...
hold on.
Listen to me,both of you.
I'm sorry.
I wish I had never left.
Don't talk,don't talk. Just breathe.
Okay,so do you want a pb & b?
Not really. My tummy hurts.
Where's her knapsack?
Her what?
Knapsack. Her medicine's in it.
I don't know,baby. I just grabbed her and ran.
She needs that medicine. She can't go two days without it.
Yeah,I know. I'm her father,all right?
Where is it?
Baby.Baby,look. Calm down.
What are you looking for?
Just tell me what it is,and I'll go ahead and get it,okay?
Her prescription.
It's a backup. I keep an extra,in case.
Okay. Okay.
so all we need to do is find a pharmacy.
Don't worry.
Hey,looks like we're going on a ride, sweet pea.
Look,we nail bagwell,he might still have some of geary's things on him,like his backpack,
which has his personal stuff in it. I know his wife would love to have it.
If we find bagwell,you can give it to her personally.
Thanks.
It's the least I can do considering ho you're helping me out.
Though some of the guys on the force are concerned about...
what are they concerned about?
Nothing.
But you know what?
Why don't you tell me what you know, we'll track down bagwell,
we'll get geary's effects back to his family, I'll make sure that everybody involved knows that
your help was invaluable.
I'll even recommend that you get most of, if not all of,that reward money.
What is it exactly that the guys on the force were concerned about?
Well,some of them thought that you weren't being totally upfront about your head injury.
I mean,to be fair,it does seem a little off
that you didn't see the guy who hit you smack-dab on the forehead.
You got me.
Geary and me had a little dustup over how to go about finding bagwell.
It got physical,and he hit me.
The two of us,we fought like brothers. I didn't want to rat him out to the cops.
After the fight,we split up.
And then...
Well,you know what happened to him.
I just wish to hell we'd never fought, you know?
Maybe then he'd still be...
brad,you can't blame yourself.
Why don't we refocus our energy on finng the man who killed your friend?
That's what roy would've wanted.
All right,baby.
Insurance card?
Uh,no,I don't have insurance.
You're paying for dexamethasone without insurance?
You got medicaid,medicare or something?
Nope. Um,I'll just pay cash.
It's $125.
Excuse me?
Um,oh,sorry.
Sorry I don't have anything smaller.
I have to go to the back   to get change for $100.
So... I'll be right back.
- Right there! Hospital!    - I see it.
I see it. Just get us there.
No,you'll be caught.
Then we'll be caught.
I'm not gonna let you die.
Then listen to me.
You find sara tancredi.
She can end this.
It's up to you now.
yeah,I want an alarm out   on a dark blue sedan.
License: Ae9268.
40 miles southeast of los cruces.
Do it now.
oh,come on!
What?
What hospital?
CARLSBAD.NEW MEXICO    ST.DE LORENZO HOSPITAL
He came in with a bad gsw.
Docs called us in. He's in here.
We ran his name.
Came back with two federal drug   smuggling warrants out on him.
Heard you wanted to talk to me.
I got some information the feds want...
about michael scofield.
Like where he's catching a ride.
And where would that be?
It's not just the where but the when.
That when is coming up soon.
But I want to cut a deal first.
Give us a minute.
Anything you want to say?
One daY. That's all we had.
Back then,
when things were at their worst...
there were days I thought   I'd never see the sun again.
But he saved my life.
I just wish he could have   let us be a part of his.
Yeah.
I'll tell him.
Here's the deal.
All charges dropped and the government picks up   medical costs until you're fit to be deported,
all contingent upon your   information being accurate.
Where's scofield?
No deportation. I want citizenship.
Citizenship?
A little incentive,and I want it in writing.
I'm so tired of playing games.
Well,start typing.
No external pacemaker.
Oh,this is a good one--   no morphine drip.
What are you doing?
Fbi. Out. Out!
What the hell are you doing?
Giving you a little incentive.
Come on! Come on,you son of A...
And they found nothing?
Okay,thanks.
Well,your instincts are great,brad,
but the precinct actually sent a   unit over to hollander's house today.
An anonymous caller said they saw   an intruder but no one was there.
Damn it.
If you knew about bagwell and hollander,why   didn't you just head over there yourself?
We couldn't find the house.
Really? It's listed.
excuse me.
Thank you.
Everything okay?
Yeah,yeah,everything's fine.
Brad,have you ever been to the fauntleroy   hotel? It's about 15 minutes from here.
Never heard of it.
Well,that's strange,
'cause they found this   receipt in geary's hotel room.
It's from your credit card.
THANK YOU FOR SHOPPING WITH US
I don't know how that got there.
I think you're being evasive.
You should tell me   the truth,mr.Bellick.
What happened to "brad"?
About seven years ago,I   got my first homicide case
a woman,pretty.   She was brutally attacked.
Animal boyfriend left her for dead,
but she was still breathing... barely.
But she punched into her cell   phone the killer's number,
so she solved the crime for us.
When we found the receipt,brad,
it was in geary's hand,his   finger pointing to your name.
With his last ounce of strength, he told us you killed him.
Okay,listen.
Geary and I found bagwell   at hollander's house.
We roughed him up till he told us where he'd hid   the five million bucks we knew he dug up in utah.
When we found the money, geary double-crossed me.
He hit me in the   head and took the cash.
I had nothing to do   with geary's death.
You hear what I'm saying?
I'm the victim here, not that son of a bitch!
Come on,come on,come on.
Where are you at,baby?
Hey,uh,could you hurry it up?
It's just it's getting really   late-- I got to get home.
And,um,that's $20,$40,
$50,and $20 is $70.
One,two,three,four...
five...
seventy-five.
You got to be kidding me.
Ma'am.
Afternoon,officer.
Do you have any id with you?
no.I walked over here,
so i didn't carry anything with me.
Did you? Where'd you walk from?
Is there a problem,officer?
There's only a problem if   you make one,ms. Franklin.
You want to tell us   where your husband is?
I don't know.
Place your hands behind   your back,please,ma'am.
Baby,I'm so sorry.
Oh,my god.
Where's mommy?
Mommy,uh,mommy is going   to meet us later. Okay?
- Yes.    - Where's the photo?
Bill,there was a tactical error.
I don't want terminology from the   cover your ass handbook,paul.
What happened?
There were unforeseen circumstances, things that could not be predicted.
Where's sara?
She's gone,isn't she?
Yes,she got away,
but there's no way that she could...
bill.
I'm not going to let you die.
I love you.
You know that,don't you?
Too many.
Too many people died because   I wanted you to be free.
You couldn't have known,michael.
You couldn't have know it...   would have ended up like this.
But it did.
They wanted him.
They wanted him in the ground,
and they got their wish.
This thing is not going   to end here,michael.
- I know.    - It's going to keep spreading.
Their hands are going to   get more and more bloody.
Well,the question is,
is the blood on their   hands... or ours?
I'm sorry,guys.
We got to go.
Get back on with border patrol.
Call the navy reserve   air station in dallas.
They've got planes on alert.
We need an intercept of a white,single   engine a-36 beech heading toward the border.
Call mexico,get clearance   for an international pursuit.
Tell them if they got to take   the plane down,just do it.
Come on,guys!
Guys,come on.
Come on,guys.
What?
We're staying.
- Ay,vamonos!    - Esperate,esperate,esperate.
Michael,this is what   we've been waiting for.
Maybe we'll see you   down there somewhere.
I can't talk you out   of this one,can i?
Well,I hope so.
Be good.
Thank you,michael.
Thank you for everything.
- Take care,all right?     - I will.
Fly safe,papi.
Give 'em hell.
Panama would've been good.
Are you ready for this?
- Been waiting years.    - Good to hear it.
'Cause today is the   day we stop running.
- What now?     - We go back to the car.
I drive to a border town, find a cell phone signal.
Call sara.
Where the hell are those jets?
you hear that?
Yeah.
Pull over.
oh,god,they're going after sucre.
They're gonna take him down.
- How'd they find out?    - I don't know.
Michael.
I want to know what   the hell's going on.
If you could've arrested me, you would've already done it.
I'm out of here.
Not really an option   for you,mr. Bellick.
What do you got,a receipt? He left   it in his pocket. A fight? Big deal.
I got ten pals in chicago tell you   geary and i threw down once a month.
You're right.
Any of those things on their   own,probably not enough.
But when you add this...
what the hell's that?
You left a message for mr. Geary.
You thieving son of a bitch,
you better get down on your knees   and pray to god that I don't find you.
Because if I do,mark my words:
I'm gonna gut you bow to stern.
You want to hear it again?
Now at this juncture,brad,things will go a whole   lot easier for you if you admit to the crime.
Now you listen to me,
you manipulative little bitch.
I did not kill roy geary!
You understand what I'm telling you!
Bagwell set me up!
Get your hds off of me!
Bradley bellick,you are under arrest for the   first-degree murder of roy william geary.
You have a right to remain silent.
Anything you say can be used   against you in a court of law.
You have a right to talk with an attorney and to  have him present with you when being questioned.
If you cannot hire an attorney...
President reynolds' office.
This is agent paul kellerman.
I need to speak with the   president right now,please.
I'm sorry,this administration isn't   familiar with an agent kellerman.
June,it's me.
I need to speak with caroline now.
June,if you don't put me through,
I'll make certain that the  president knows that
you were the one who did not allow me to  provide her with some very important information.
Now.
I'm sorry,this administration   isn't familiar with an agent...
Please leave a message after the tone.
bill,don't do thiS.
I've dedicated my life to   this country,to caroline.
Everything I have,I give.
Every photo,every file.   Get rid of it all.
Make him a ghost.
I've been a perfect soldier.
I've never asked   anything of you,ever.
But I'm asking now.
Bill,don't do thiS.
I don't see him.
Trust me,we haven't lost him yet.
No Service..
Connecting.. No Service..
Linc?
- Stop the car.    - What?
We got to stop the car.
That's a radio tower over there.
It must be picking up some   kind of analog signal.
We got to get closer.
Turn around.
What about your  friend back there?
If we're gonna go down,
might as well go down swinging.
Come on,come on,come on...
Connecting 505-555-0162
we are in business.
it's going through.
Come on,sara,pick up.
Sara?
Hello?
Hello? Michael?
Michael?