Of course there are concerns ...
... But this is a turning point for our country.
That one coin we become part of a superpower.
And bananas law and by decree of our leader ...
... Regent 't only on Tuesdays and Thursdays.
Should I bring anything? - No. Pull your really that thing on?
Is that against the rules? - When the photographers you see ...
Wat is er? Geneer je je voor je man?
- Ja, nou en of.
They found me.
Tomorrow. I go get the newspaper.
Can not. I must give an honest answer to a question.
Christina, you're the human face. People want to trust you.
Simon?
Are you it?
So I have to stick to the agreements. - Then you win.
I'm a politician, not a representative.
Shall we talk about it at lunch?
Mrs Chance?
The judge is dead Chance. - That still does' t Barbour process?
He was constantly monitored.
An agent has him identified.
What was he doing here? - He pulled himself to the newspaper.
That he did not do the police.
Where he gets that newspaper? - What's he doing here?
Two shots to the chest. He saw the shooter so.
There is rotated one engine, ten meters from where he lies.
Witnesses?
He walks out of the way here. An engine is behind it on. He turns around.
The motorcyclist shoots twice and drives off.
No amateur so.
His wife at home, if you want to speak 'r.
You know she was party leader in the European elections?
Quickly, the CID is for us.
Cameras, alarms, police at the door, all the technological rigmarole ...
... And they leave him alone 'fetch a newspaper.
Were you too pips or so?
The lady of the house? - In the kitchen.
I'm sorry to disturb you. Superintendent Dalziel, detective.
Detective Sergeant Pascoe and Novello.
My participation.
Can I ask you a few things?
What is your husband assumed the house?
Nine o'clock. A little later maybe.
Only?
Your husband was guarded because he had threatened to 't process.
Why did not he come along or someone?
He found annoying.
It's my fault. I'm not to let go.
He did so often on Sunday morning?
He took the threats seriously?
I do not know.
He did not talk much about it.
He was found in Church Downswood.
A long way from the kiosk.
Any idea what he was doing there?
Dank u wel, Mrs Chance.
For now we know enough.
They think it's anything to do with drugs. How do we do this?
I call yet. Are you the police?
Is Mrs Chance in orde?
John Parker, haar PA. Is ze in gevaar?
How about yourself?
Has 't with' t make process? - I'm not going to speculate about.
Of course, you realize that this is a sensitive issue.
Can we discuss press statements?
Who did not come. Good day, Mr. Parker.
I came as soon as I heard it.
Look at that. Just fly in a dunghill.
I thought you escaped me. - I would never do, Rebecca.
You want me to work together with the CID. Trust me.
You're not very tactful.
Fun anyway, we clean up the mess of others.
Are you sure you do not vertilt?
Do you want to just handsome boys in Armani suits on the floor.
Morning.
It seems that this "t work of one professional.
Hoofdverdachte is Mr Kenneth Barbour...
... Which was on trial for Mr. Chance ...
... To enter one large batch of heroin.
He should be guarded 24 hours a day ...
... But that's gone wrong and now we can solve it.
Maybe you know that Mrs. Chance candidate for the elections.
Journalists find this kind of nonsense exciting ...
... So if they ask us anything, we say they can in the tree. Understood?
We go all the houses down in the vicinity of the crime scene.
Sergeant Wield pulls the tire marks and see if the motorcyclist is seen.
Novello, you do contacts with CID.
Sergeant Pascoe and I go to Barbour.
Getting started then.
I'd rather not talk about it ...
... But we will have to come up with a press statement.
What? I do not know what happened.
I think it's really to bring it up.
But it closes 48 hours before the candidates.
If you are considering to withdraw, which should for the time.
Should I decide now?
It's terrible. Terrible.
I will say that you continue. That gets in any case the news.
Are you doing still busy with your work? Do not you see how she's ready?
You better not be seen together. Can close the curtains?
Leave us alone.
Fuck off. Right now.
We have to do something that stay with you. My reputation suffers.
I've got one invitation for Mr. Dalziel and 'partner'.
That is standard nowadays. - Not at the rugby club.
Maybe you should look for somebody else. Ellie rang. I'm going tonight to talk to her.
Is she back? - You never know.
Thank Goodness. Yet the family Pascoe's more his mind.
What would you get, Ken? 18?
Customs has set me up.
But one judge to explain ... That just doing his job.
Do you have proof? - They'll be here.
But it would be easier if you know.
You're all wrong, sir.
Someone has him death threats.
Probably not his tailor. - I did not do it.
It is too much to expect cooperation from a rat like you ...
... But if you sit out ...
... Close them out so long that you fall on your beard.
We're wasting our time.
I wanted him not just dead.
The case would be canceled today. He said Friday that the customs ...
... Was to reveal the identity of their sources.
According to my lawyer, they never do and then they let me go.
Now I must again show a lot of time waiting for one retrial.
So if you discover who did it ...
... Keep him with me away.
Sorry to have bothered you.
What Barbour said, true. His lawyer is part of. The prosecution wanted to give it up.
Chance had more enemies?
So afraid he was no different.
Maybe he wanted to be as free.
Or did it feel anything else, he wanted to talk to no police?
Shall we ask the CID? They know more of his habits.
Yes, and those weasels tell us nothing of course.
We'll find out for yourself. - We can 't ask, right?
Whose side are you doing? Will you sometimes no responsibility?
Here we are again. - I want out. I feel so trapped.
We may realize the paper of your husband?
Mind if we bring anything? - No, do what you want.
What are you achieving? - In my office in Leeds. Can I leave?
Of course.
Separate bedrooms. She 's doubles and he' s single.
Maybe they found that exciting.
Back and sneak weather, creaky boards ...
Stout hassle.
The queen has one private bedroom. - I smell lavender.
That you can not say to the modern police.
Keep you at the license plates of visitors?
Who is that? - Mr. Deller. This is a family friend.
You mean? - He usually comes in the afternoon.
What? - I do not dare to guess.
I take this along.
So Christina has a boyfriend. - What did you do?
It has to be nothing.
Where's her office? - Leeds.
Looking Party headquarters? - Not really.
I am the matter to "explore t.
Do you want to drink something?
Perhaps this is not your kind of place.
Right.
Moment.
What will it be? - A beer.
Which would you prefer? - With that nice stop. That is certainly good.
Sorry. Journalists. - It saves money.
Keeping it but change.
What do you want to know?
Mrs. Chance wins the election? - I hope so.
And if not? - I do not think for a moment.
Since I do not believe it.
Wie is dat?
- David Ransom, van Ransom Telecom.
This is his building. - Certainly rich?
25 million.
Then he can just pay the prices here.
Pascoe, half acht.
I thought you were not coming. - The babysitter was late.
I have not ordered yet. Cannelloni? - I have no appetite.
We would go to dinner? - I do nothing, okay?
What the hell? You're back? - I did not say that.
If you want to say, say so. Therefore, we are on neutral ground.
Do not hang from the policeman.
It is not all up to me. - I think I'll stay very reasonable.
You're left with our daughter.
You know why I left.
You are expected to see an occasional your husband.
You have something together. Otherwise it makes no sense.
Totally agree. But you sat with your mother.
I do my work without knowing whether you back.
You act as if my feelings do not matter.
It's either me or you work.
I took one decision.
I do not want to be married to his Dalziel boy.
You have nothing to do with your brain. You are intelligent. You can be anything.
But you throwing away it and I do not want to experience.
And I do not want to wait every night or you're coming home.
And I do not want you being a stranger to our daughter.
Are you really real?
Should I look for another job because I do's late coming home?
That's life just happens.
That's what happens when you have responsibility.
I can get a research job in London.
Come with me. That is a new beginning.
Then you finally do something constructive.
It's your choice.
With Wield. Barbours lawyer called. He wants to talk.
Let Peter go. - I let him pick up tomorrow.
Goodbye, wieldy.
Peter Deller. I have an appointment with David Ransom.
Right now. David, I want to talk to you.
David, come at here. I need to talk to you.
You are here because I want to record what you say.
Where Dalziel? - Busy.
You have one good word for me.
I will see. - You're the only sergeant.
Warrant.
What did you lose?
I do not know who him killed, but I do know what.
You've checked. - No, for the process.
Little digging, getting to know the enemy.
Judge Chance liked young men.
There he liked very much.
In?
He once spent a night with one Simon Wallis. Lives in Leeds.
Who says that?
Strange, huh? He had such a beautiful woman.
As I vote on. - You can not vote.
True, Mr. Pascoe. I'm innocent.
What has Valais with murder?
The prison is dangerous.
Even for a guy like me.
I can not stick my neck too far.
Where do you want to go?
I've told you everything I know.
You as a detective but they must fit together.
What have you got him promised? - Nothing. I can really do something.
Track on which Wallis. I go to Mrs. Chance.
So we're looking for a jealous gay lover?
Who kills him during 't process to us to deceive.
How did 't with Ellie? She takes you back ...
... Or let them suffer like me?
You stand out, Andy.
Morgen, Mr Dalziel.
- Mrs Chance verwacht me.
She gets too much cash.
Tomorrow she say if she maintains her candidacy.
Terrible. - But with a murder ...
... The husband is of course important.
You want to know if they suspected? - That would be handy.
Not that we doubt her.
Frankly, I have no idea who did it.
Maybe you.
Morgen, Mrs Chance.
I see you, John.
Shall we go to my room?
You're going to wonder what I'm doing here, one day after the murder of my husband.
I don 't really yourself.
It's all very surreal.
You would do well to fix.
You must think of your supporters. - I were so noble.
Someone had latched on to your husband ...
... Or wanted him silenced.
Silenced?
What do you mean? - I do not know.
But I think he was quite complex together.
We all suffer from.
I'm sorry, Mrs. Chance, but I have to ask you this.
Whether he had homosexual relationships.
A list of names would be very welcome.
I have not.
We never really talked about it. He did not have.
You've never met them, the friends?
I know it sounds strange, but we were talking rather so.
It did not hit us.
Does the name Simon Wallis something?
A jealous lover commits such a murder is not unexpected.
Usually it gradually goes wrong.
I would have known. He had told.
This is the license plate of a car ...
... Often when you come to visit.
He is of a certain Peter Deller.
Is that a friend of yours?
A good friend?
I help Romanian children. He gave a lot of money.
We got one close.
But that was not difficult. Jerry's death was independent of Peter and me.
We were all good friends.
You tell it anyway to the press?
No way.
Mr Dalziel...
... I'd give anything to get back my husband.
Despite everything, I loved him very much.
We were good buddies.
All we know is that it was a terrain engine.
There is a footprint, but which is not usable.
No DNA encountered. - Witnesses?
A few people vaguely remember one engine, but what ...
I Simon Wallis his address. But he does not answer.
Search Novello and head him get.
Met 'n huiszoekingsbevel.
That Mrs. Chance, how important that is, politically?
According to the newspaper, they will sell us the euro. The neat face of Europe.
Why them? - She looks good.
Slim has been 'n successful lawyer. Speaks to ordinary people.
It could be. The noble widow is an unbeatable trump card.
That is far-fetched. - That's killing a bomb crater too.
Stone Cold.
Is vast al dagen dood.
Looks like an overdose.
Nowhere arrive. Call the precinct.
Take him just outside.
Z'n laptop is weg.
Look.
Lay on the mat. Posted in Wetherton.
Dear Simon, thanks for everything, but I can not go with it.
To Christina. You don 't understand it. Love, Jerry.
Van Chance.
Chance Wallis wants to leave his wife.
But Chance wants no scandal during the elections.
All or nothing, find Valais, killing Chance home and commits suicide.
He had not gotten the letter. - Phone call then?
A heroin overdose. That points out the blood test.
Suicide? - Maybe.
Otherwise, it 's really stupid mistake.
Apparently, not a user. Is there another note?
There was nothing. - Do you know the time of death?
Certainly. 36 to 48 hours ago.
So he was dead before Chance? - There goes my theory.
Wallis can 't have let do. Chance was not suicide.
Mrs. Chance may have discovered it. It could 'r her image costs.
And so did they murder them. - Such a type not she seems.
But of course one politician.
I have had many of the hundreds of messages of support.
Especially the people who pointed out to me ...
... That my husband died as a servant 's general interest.
The public interest, I would also like to serve.
With that thought in my head, I decided to continue.
My husband would have expected it.
I know I have with your support ...
... Will have more than enough power for victory.
Thank you very much.
Shoot you also so full?
Shall we take one pint?
A pint for my friend and a large vanilla latte for me.
This is still 't new Labour? Then I'll have a pint.
Excuse me. - Can I do something for you?
Probably not. - To speak to Mrs. Chance private?
Do not be. Will she have a drink with me?
Or you? A pink gin? Fits with your tie.
Modepop.
Here, you just pay it.
Brave decision. - Hopefully it 's also one good decision.
This we found this morning.
Al goed, John.
Is that the handwriting of your husband?
He's just sent to his death on Simon Wallis ...
... A 25-year-old programmer from Leeds.
Any idea where he is referring to?
Nee.
Wallis lay dead in his flat. Overdose.
Saturday deceased. We exclude nothing, as they say.
How can there be?
How are you doing? - Yeah.
Should you go after her so? She 's already so heavy.
We do our job, Mr. Deller.
Come on. I'll take you home.
However indiscreet of him. - Sitting in his nature.
Let Wield and Novello'm just tighten.
Home? - I go to someone.
Who then? - A lady.
Ha Ellie. Would I be allowed to see Sleeping Beauty?
Almost as nice as d'r mother.
Sorry for the mess. - Besides my house is a palace.
I adore your husband, but it's a slob.
He has a mother needed. - My assistant has given it.
She found socks of 'm in the oven. In order to dry.
Did he in college already.
He comes home? - I do not know.
He is turned on, if you mean.
If I have anything against him can say ...
Thank you. But you're not the right person for it.
How do you mean? - You're the problem.
His ambition keeps him home, not me.
Give him a chance, Ellie.
He loves you.
As much as he loves the police?
That brings no policeman.
Just kidding, lovey.
That's not right.
So should think police officers.
You're a good man, Andy ...
... But Peter can not be like you.
Look at.
Het complete pathologische rapport
over Chance.
Six months ago, it has been determined one nerve disease.
Chance knew he could still work a half years when he was lucky.
Therefore, he felt sure of it okay to leave without escort.
Wallis was his laptop at his last employer.
With his administration on it. He did a lot for Ransom.
There was Peter Deller still some moth along in Leeds?
Deller and Ransom put together a computer leasing company on.
That is sold. Ten million men.
Deller takes' t it. Ransom has set up one new company.
Mrs. Chance Ransom is in its building. They know each other fixed by Deller.
Good work, Peter. But what does' t all?
Ransom is in mobile telephony. He wants in Europe.
That means one hope bureaucracy. There they can do something.
I smell something, Peter.
We go Ransom but at a better look.
Toe nou, David.
I helped you.
You have created this company ...
... With money that I settled acquaintances.
10% commission is five million pounds. And we had a deal.
If you had cash, I got that money.
Where is this contract? I have not signed anything.
I find this really incredible.
They were my contacts. They trusted you because they trusted me.
You've been out there for years. Nobody cares about you.
Five million, and that you pay now.
Whether the costs are added.
You are too often went out with Charlie.
You can 't remember. I owe you nothing.
Even 's idea that one parallel world enters?
What can I do for the police?
Does the name Simon Wallis something?
Heel in de verte.
A computer consultant. Worked 't last six months especially for you.
He is dead. Yesterday found with one lethal dose of heroin in his blood.
What a tragedy.
Simon Wallis had all sorts of information about you on its hard drive.
I have more than 500 people.
Who knows, he worked on my computers. - 1 meter 80. Short hair.
Homo.
Are you married?
What the hell? You tell it's a freelancer death, he is gay ...
I am suspicious of anything?
If you know anything about Mr. Wallis, we would be very happy with that.
You are not suggesting that I was sleeping with him?
I know him disagree. - And Christina Chance?
If you have one hidden agenda? If you want to know something, ask simply.
Wallis had an affair with her husband, Judge Chance.
Wallis died twelve hours before Chance was killed.
You try to make connections.
Uw ex-compagnon Deller
is de minnaar van Christina Chance.
I barely know her. - Why do you support her?
She just has her office here.
Who pays rd phone and employees?
The party, I suppose. Which gets money from me. But political campaigns, no.
Strange that you 'r not know. A friend of yours is her lover.
Peter and I are not friends for five years.
If I have a reason needed to avoid her, he certainly is.
I notice that you have a theory. - Various.
Let me just guess. Businessman and politician together in pursuit of money.
Worker discovered 't, transmits lover in, coincidentally her husband. Two deaths.
I lead an honest business.
The Governing Board eminent names.
You can mess up 't entire company ...
... But you will not find anything.
Everything good? - What do you think?
Parker is looking for you. Something with a press conference this afternoon.
I am disgusted by John Parker. I loathe 't hassle. Was it to be over.
Hood then equally easy to get things back in line.
You will require too much of yourself.
Where I'm still doing?
I will stay here for a while?
What should I say to the press?
I'm just one good friend.
I do not know what to do.
What is that?
Something to Jerry 't was writing.
I know why he was killed.
Have you informed the police?
Read now but.
Mr Smith? Inspecteur Dalziel, recherche.
Come inside.
I pick up the books of the court.
I've seen him twelve years, since his appointment.
The last named judge in twenty years.
You have him well-known. - I have occasionally 's right to serve.
The Barbour process probably was not fun. Those threats.
That every judge. It is part of it today.
So he was worried enough.
It did nothing to him.
Did you know many of his private life?
That's not my business.
Ever heard of one young man, Simon Wallis?
According to us, he had a relationship with the judge.
These messages are spread by the tabloids.
And they were rumors, no more.
When was this?
Five years ago. When the judge was working at the court.
The national press so. - Rats. It was pure harassment.
Why do you say that?
I usually have little interest in conspiracy theories ...
... But in this case I do not know that.
I listen.
It was a case against a businessman. Trading.
According to me it was the top of one iceberg.
When he was sentenced, would follow hundred cases.
The judge was under tremendous pressure.
The case has not occurred. Because of a formality.
Does he have him run?
And I saw how nice it was not.
The judge was a very honest man.
What was that business?
Ransom. He did in computers.
To many people's surprise, David Ransom, one wealthy businessman ...
... Acquitted of three charges of insider trading.
The groom touch you, you bet on the horse. Is that right?
Then you have one unfair advantage. You play with loaded dice.
Can you gamble ethical? - Want one philosophical answer?
Ransom I want to know his role.
If he was behind the rumors, he plays' t nasty.
As. Everything in this case begins with 'if'.
If Chance Ransom suspiciously, he had it said, and his wife was not there now.
Shall we call the CID and ask if they want to follow a few people?
You want 't really like to give up, huh?
We could vertillen us this. - Do not be defeatist.
What did you do? You sit me all sewing at times.
I'm afraid for you? That you makes me?
I can not help it that you do not get recognition genius.
Is it?
I have heard no news.
There is a very good reason.
We have our theory 't formulation.
Main suspect? - The widow's got the best motive.
Reasons for arrest? - Is being worked on.
And the perpetrator of the attack?
We have expanded the investigation.
When CID they become restless.
That is mutual.
Beautiful.
What's he doing here?
I wish him speak.
There's a message in 't party office.
They want you withdraw your candidacy. Call them equally.
It is too late. - The list closes at 5 pm. About two hours.
Why? - They'll push you too much.
I pretty certainly not off. I'll do just fine, they said.
The press is behind your acquaintances.
When your application is asked whether there were potential problems.
You have not said anything about a relationship if one gay man.
It is the public interest. Since you do not answer for.
Nasty little creep.
I know what you want. Whoever takes my place?
Go home, Christina.
Those notes Jerry can you show it to anyone.
We need to talk about it. - Over three quarters at home.
Good. See u soon.
Please.
Deller is de spin in het web.
He knows everyone.
What Novello about him discovered?
Clippings about his old case and his generosity.
No spot on, apparently.
Can not, Peter. Everyone does have a spot. And sometimes more than one.
Ellie asked you one ultimatum, eh?
Since you do not have to sleuth.
Women walking to their mother when they want attention.
They want you to be home more often. Or from me.
She gets a job in London. She wants me to go.
It's a great opportunity for "r. - So.
And if you do not want to go to London? - Then they're going.
What did they do? You deserve good, nice house ...
You'll find out in a box. - I'm never home.
But you're not strange. - She just wants a job.
She has.
She adapts to me. But she thinks I'm in the house.
Your generation thinks too much. In my time was it simple.
Woman frustrated, man not at home. - We picked it.
Your wife.
Christina Chance. Can I talk to you?
Yes of course. - Under four eyes like.
De Yew Tree in Chellingwake?
- Goed. Tot over twintig minuten.
Someone saw a flash, and when he heard the bang.
What flash? - A flash, but brighter.
Where is she, at an end?
You should not have gone. I think it's so bad.
How are you with her? - Still in a coma. Blood in the brains.
Was it an accident? - Why would it not be?
I do not know. You're the policeman.
Where were you tonight, Mr. Deller?
You do not think I did it?
We will talk further on the precinct?
You can not arrest me. I did not do anything.
I can pick up for driving with one gulp. I can smell it here.
You have been before tonight Mrs. Chance.
You are both left around the same time, a little after eight.
Did she say where she was going?
To a meeting.
To say that she would keep a low profile.
She did not say she went to inspector Dalziel?
No, I do have remembered me.
Where did you go? - Home.
I called a dozen people. Trek but after.
She had something on him?
The agent at the house saw her walking with a leather briefcase.
We have not found.
I know nothing of.
Who would want to murder her?
No idea.
You and David Ransom known each other one all the time, huh?
Yes. Not that that's saying something.
I thought you were friends.
I used to. - What went wrong?
We are each "n other side passed on.
I have seen both in one bar in Leeds.
The relationship seemed "a little tense.
Why?
We had a disagreement about money.
How much money?
Surely that is our case?
Are you sure it was not Christina?
They will contrive to be grateful. - He stands apart from Christina.
They are all very thick with each other.
That's always at the top. - Are you sitting there?
No, anything but.
Does the name Simon Wallis something?
Do you'm not like a lover of justice Chance?
Jerry never said anything about that side of his life.
Ransom has acted with knowledge?
The successful businessman has not?
You're a rich man, Mr. Deller.
A player, a man with influence.
Business and politics are two peas in a pod.
You know that. That's your world.
But strangely enough powerful people want too much.
They do almost anything to keep what they have.
They try to get away even with murder.
The question is: What is it here?
And for whom?
What did Chance and Wallis?
What did Mrs. Chance tell me?
There is a secret, huh?
And you would not have told me.
He knows something.
Let him follow.
Nice car. Cost forty grand.
I can buy my apartment so for.
Sometimes you wanted to blackmail me? - The police asked for you.
You found that probably nice. - They know 't, David.
Of the briefcase.
What briefcase?
They do not know where your money comes from.
So I want ten million.
Hoop still on, Peter.
Je bent 'n stakker.
Mrs. Chance stepped down after the death of her husband.
The election committee of the party has appointed John Parker as a replacement.
What is your position on the euro?
I continue to propagate the views of Mrs. Chance to voters.
The choice is between isolation and decay ...
... And join a strong European economy.
Congratulations. The party leaves no grass grow.
I'm not elected. - That'll be fine. What a device.
Can I do anything for you?
Do you know anything of the attack on your predecessor?
It was an accident?
It was a professional attempt to make it look like it.
No idea. - If it was just her ...
... I would suspect.
But her husband and his lover are there too.
You are aware of Mr. Wallis?
U hebt vast 'n theorie.
You still have over one answer?
I thought 't was connected with his work.
All roads lead to this place.
This marble quarry hides one vicious secret.
And if you're not aware of, you hear it fixed shortly.
You are intelligent, ambitious ...
Well suited for this snake pit.
My political activities occur entirely within our rules of conduct.
What are you doing here? Why pay Ransom everything for you?
He does not. We're here six months.
The lease is paid by the party.
Of who gets the party money? - No idea.
I get to see any names of lenders. That may confirm people.
And here I thought you were smart.
Be aware, boy ...
... Associated with each banknote 's promise.
I have no bound.
Only to my constituents and the party.
They've bought your suit, son ..
Sell ​​your soul not there.
Where is he now? - Two hours was in the hospital.
And then went home. - And he had an argument with Ransom?
Deller was walking with a fierce face away.
Last Sunday Deller Ransom wanted to speak in Leeds.
This morning he had important news, because Ransom runs here.
But whatever it is, Deller is not satisfied.
Maybe he wants something and he does not get it.
Look at.
Its shares shoot up, but nobody knows why. Or they say nothing.
Who wrote this? - A woman. Cameron Stewart.
Where are you going? - To a lady.
Why such interest? - Two murders and one attempted murder.
Usually wants detectives know where it comes from capital.
Or 't is black or not. - What?
It's certainly gray here and there. That's usually the case.
Why the shares rise so fast? - So that's it feel.
It is truly confidential.
I am a journalist. I hear rumors.
But often 't just rumors.
An American company buys many shares on Ransom.
An acquisition?
That depends on the shareholders. Ransom so.
The Americans will have to provide one good price.
And how much money are you, Ransom personally?
If he gets 5 pounds per share, which ...
... More than 100 million.
Does the name Peter Deller you something?
That's a long time ago. Almost before my time.
I only know that he is completely burned.
He invested his money in the Far East.
And he has lost everything. - So bad it 's not? He is not working.
Nobody wants him to have. They know that he has won a lot of money.
But then he's screwed up. - What was he doing hanging out with Ransom?
If you had one red stripe, where did you go?
How do I withdraw after shares?
There is an office that registers owners of shares.
Find out who has Ransom shares. - That must be through the courts.
With Peter. Deller is broke. He is going to ask for money to Ransom.
And did you know that Ransom going to sell his business for hundreds of line?
Streep? What is that? - Million.
A unique deal. - Where's what it's all about?
Black money maybe. Wallis was working on one database shareholders.
He saw something, gave it on to Chance and briefed Deller.
Of course. We meet at his house Deller.
Mr Deller? Inspecteur Dalziel.
Bankruptcy Request
I thought he was it. The weapon closet is empty. He is gone.
No of course not. I'll call you back shortly.
Ransom his lawyer asks why we want to have that data.
See who benefits from this acquisition.
That's called fishing, Andy. Did you have a good reason for it?
Yes, I'm one whopper hooked.
But there is someone with a gun around. I want firearms.
I'm on your side, Andy ...
... But they want me to wear on the case.
You would like that, huh? Just one signature ...
It is more complicated than you think. - So what?
If one is dead, you get that book under the L Corpse?
You're very emotional. - I'm just doing my job.
Good then. I authorize the use of firearms ...
... But if I were you, I took the rest of the day free.
And if I were you, I was counting paperclips again ...
... Because you do not crack police work.
What do you have? - Nothing about Deller.
But when Ransom started ...
... Was one of its shareholders Northern Haul.
Owner: One Stanley Barbour.
The brother of Kenneth. Same business address.
Northern Haul stak zes miljoen
in Ransom Telecom.
Drug Money.
Deller aground ...
... And so he threatens' t hang with the big clock.
And then get his girlfriend an accident.
He is behind Ransom.
Pascoe en Dalziel, recherche.
We komen voor Mr Ransom.
What was that? Where is the door?
There was someone inside. - No idea.
I know better. Get you Ransom?
488 is fine, but I want two years of my research people.
Nee. Dat hele project kan morgen stranden.
I've one year promised. And otherwise, you get lost in the competition.
Security called: the police is coming.
Then we do it the way you want. We'll finish 't even?
We now draw by fax and in the US we arrange the final details though.
I appreciate your confidence.
Even my lawyers are happy. - You sign anything.
Disconnect. - Hands off.
Alles in orde?
This man blackmailed one right ...
... And let him and his friend murder, for this rotten deal.
David Ransom z'n grote deal.
You should not do business with him. It's a criminal.
And he's his business started with drug money.
You should not do. - You all about money? We can talk.
Sit.
Police. Drop the gun.
That gun away, then you nothing happens.
Nevertheless, gun.
Leg weg.
We know what he did.
He is to be stored for a long time. Do not worry.
But that does not happen because he buys you. He buys all.
David Ransom...
I arrest you on suspicion of 't laundering drug money.
Put that gun away now.
Then we go to the office ...
... And tell us what you know about the murder of Chance and Valais.
Well?
Up, Ransom.
Did you just saved my life, Peter?
Wie is daar?
What do you want? It's almost midnight. - I shot someone.
Professionally.
Have you been drinking?
I saved Andy. That would be gunned down. I shot the first time.
Three bullets through the heart. Could not be better.
Who was it? - An expired businessman.
What happens now? - There will be an investigation.
Praise for my courage and about one year a medal.
Then you are the wife of one man decorated. If you want.
I want? - That is the question, yes.
What kind of man do you want anyway?
I shot without thinking. Before that I trained.
Nothing academic or househusband. I'm a cop.
That's me. - You got a shock.
I feel fine. - Then you need help.
I'm for change 's honest.
I try not to protect you from what I really am.
Why we can not be honest with each other?
I want you, Ellie.
Do not walk away.
I do not want you.
Not so.
This man blackmailed one right ...
... And let him and his friend murder, for this rotten deal.
David Ransom z'n grote deal.
Mr. Deller had 't sure about' t lawsuit against you for insider trading.
I can answer questions.
I have no idea. He did so confused.
Do you judge Chance blackmailed ...
... Because of his homosexuality? - Absolutely not.
Simon Wallis may have known about the deal.
Yes, if there were leaks in 't business. But I've never met him talk.
I 's to Wallis its bills looked to you.
Other customers paid 50 pounds per hour.
Your company paid him 200. Why?
We are simply too generous.
He has earned a half years £ 100,000.
A boy of 25.
What did you pay him for?
To his knowledge. - No information about Chance?
That was a ticking time bomb.
Especially when you Wallis heard he was ill.
Other people you could buy all ...
... But a dying judge was not available, was dangerous.
He may well decide ...
... To tell you how you sabotaged the course of justice.
There I would best 's evidence to see.
The stakes were just too high.
You must eliminate the risks. Everyone silence only impose knew.
Even Mrs. Chance.
If you have one gram evidence for this madness, Mr. Dalziel?
You listened determine their telephone calls.
They used lines in your building.
I have been arrested on suspicion of money laundering?
Mr. Barbour his money was the last piece of the puzzle.
No idea what you mean.
Maybe you say something more like Mr. Barbour is heard.
Meanwhile ...
... We offer you tonight like shelter.
What do you mean you do not know where Barbour? He sat with you in jail.
When?
Since I know nothing about.
How can such a prisoner now disappear?
He is not fixed.
He sits on somewhere safe, with Narcotics.
Drugs? CID has arranged something?
He's going to testify against major traffickers.
I want to believe. Better than twenty years in prison.
What did he say about Ransom? - He will not talk to us.
Has anyone'm asked anything? - There is no evidence against Ransom.
We let him freely.
Let you run my prisoner?
Who's in charge here? - Not you and not me.
Sorry. Sometimes you just can not control.
Forgets, but now. Nobody blames you something.
Forgotten? My suspect for two murders ...
... Attempted murder and six million money laundering is released ...
... And I have to forget?
What is this? A one-two or something?
It happens fixed in general interest.
Rot still on. I know why Ransom goes free.
He knows so many bigwigs ...
... They thought: Who should we wangle.
I forget in my life days.
I should go. '
Let Mr. Dalziel to cool.
I quit, Rebecca. I'm sick of it.
Cup of tea? - Lazer still on, wieldy.
Only after Jerry's death, I noticed 't blackmail.
I looked through his papers.
He had written down everything.
Thus I came to you then ...
I thought 't was important. - He wanted to tackle Ransom.
But only after the elections.
He knew he would be fired, but of course ...
He was already dying.
I did my best, Mrs. Chance.
Had I 'tu but immediately told.
It was my fault.
I wanted to win.
I thought I 's past could disappear.
Sorry.
Trek 'tu not.
Please.
0,35 liter Euro-boerwater.
I you have a couple of guilty. - One round is already a miracle.
Ransom his deal is off. Its shares have no value whatsoever.
A couple of Germans want him for a bargain to take over.
He still holds twenty million.
Probably not, as one journalist'm tackles blackmail and money laundering.
She called me.
Someone had 'r sent a tape of that state.
Plus how it sat with its six million Barbour.
You certainly do not know how she does it.
From one old cop which nokt it?
Have you been living?
I have come to count when I rent from my pension to live.
You're not really going away?
You have to use your head.
You're not a kid anymore.
You're almost divorced.
Do not be stupid.
You wanted to show a bowls club? - Too risky.
All those horny widows.
I can still use my bammetjes at Headingley.
There's nobody else.
You can not do that.
Not now.
After all we've been through?
I beat you more than you think.
Stop your whining ...
... And get more beer.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org