I was born in Palermo, Sicily.
We came to this country when I was seven.
We immigrated to Chicago.
We were always raised to be very patriotic,
to love our country.
And we did.
When I was a little boy,
my father took me to a baseball game.
They had a martial arts demonstration
and I saw this old Japanese man...
...doing things that I thought
were magical...
...and I developed a crazy dream
to go to the Far East.
By the time I was 1 7, I was there,
studying with the masters.
In 1969 I was invited by a friend of mine
to an American Embassy party in Tokyo.
While I was there, there was a crazy,
drunk guy named Nelson Fox.
He recruited me into the CIA.
I was 22 at the time.
My eyes were about to be opened.
My friends, let me make one thing clear:
This is a nation of laws.
And as Abraham Lincoln had said:
""No one is above the law,
no one is below the law. ""
And we"re going to enforce the law!
And Americans should remember that,
if we are to have law and order!
You ever seen
chemical interrogation before?
These assholes are Agency?
We all get paid by the ClA.
But these guys are from a page
that ain't even in the book.
Don't die on me, you sucker!
What the hell's wrong?
This pussy, he just can't hold his liquor.
Doc, he's dead.
Get him the fuck out of here.
-Move it. Let's go.
-Come on!
-Get him out.
-Get him out of here.
So, my little doctor bag doesn't scare you?
l'm not scared.
You speak English.
How nice.
Where's the load, Colonel?
l'm gonna teach you never...
...never to fuck with my opium.
Oh, boy.
He's a hard one, Doc.
You took it from the French,
you took it from the Chinks.
And you'll be damned
if a Yankee's going to start you talking.
But you're gonna sing for me.
You're gonna sing like a choir!
What does this have to do
with military intelligence?
Who the fuck is this cherry?
Your orders, Toscani,
were to assist and observe.
Just back off, partner.
l'm gonna start cutting you off
at the ankles.
Then l'm gonna take your feet
and throw them right in the basket.
Cute, huh?
Shut up, Nico.
Look, l can make you disappear.
Grab his leg.
-What the hell are you doing, man?
-Nico!
You think you're soldiers?
You're fucking barbarians!
Get out!
Get back to the LZ.
lf l don't cap him now,
he's gonna do me later.
l'll call a chopper in for us. l'll cover this.
Just get the hell out of here!
Come on, move!
Bring him back here!
Nobody move! Everybody stay
on that damn porch!
Go, Nico!
Nelson, l'm through. l'm finished!
Nicola, Sara,
what name do you give your child?
Giuliano Nicola.
Giuliano...
...you have become a new creation.
With the help of your family and friends...
...we bring your Christian dignity
unstained...
...into the everlasting life of heaven.
-Come on. You always make me late.
-l'm the boss. You have to drive me!
l'll trace the sign of the Cross
upon your forehead...
...and l invite your parents to do the same.
ln the name of the Father, the Son...
...and the Holy Spirit. Amen.
Look at him. He's such a good baby.
That's beautiful.
-l know you're the boss but--
-That's right. Remember that.
Hi, guys.
Hey, how are you?
You guys look so good!
We haven't done anything.
We're clean. Some of us, anyway.
Well, Lieutenant, eight more days
and you're gonna miss me.
Parts of you, anyway.
You see this cop?
This one. This one here.
She could bust me anytime.
Look at that! Look at that!
-This is the partner?
-This is the partner.
l got dressed up because
you told me you were wearing a tux.
You look fabulous.
She goes to work looking like this?
This girl, sometimes she comes
in just lingerie.
Don't tell our secrets. She's never gonna
let you out with me again.
l told you guys to have a good time,
but take it easy, will you?
Toscani holds the record
for having more relatives...
...under federal indictment
than any other cop in the city.
Look at those stiff dicks.
A free meal and they come out like flies.
Hey, you greaseball bastards!
Didn't we buy that monkey once?
Rosa, l'm so worried. So worried.
-What's wrong?
-Nico!
lsn't today a day you should be happy?
-What's wrong?
-lt's Lucia. She's gone again.
-ls it that boy?
-SÌ, Nico.
l have to go to work right now.
You gonna be at the bakery later?
SÌ.
l'll come by the bakery and we'll talk.
Maybe l can do something.
Thank you, Nico. Thank you.
Lester, this is Unit 10, Tango-X-ray.
We're up and clear. You got that?
Delores, Toscani told me he"ll watch
over you and take care of you real good...
...your last week on the street.
Never had a friend who was a DA before.
l'm gonna take a piss and be right back.
-Here?
-Yeah.
She's fine, ain't she?
Excuse me, l just had to stop and tell you...
...you look like the sun setting
on a waterfall in the springtime.
And you got five seconds, and three are up.
You ain't got to be--
Lady cops need boyfriends, too, you dig?
But you have a nice day, just the same.
Nothing but trouble coming
in my place tonight.
l know this one.
You seen this girl?
l ain't seen shit.
You haven't seen this girl?
Hey, Schifo, how you doing?
-You seen this girl?
-You know l quit messing with that stuff.
-l ain't into this shit anymore.
-What are you into?
Why don't the fuck
you assholes leave me alone?
-l paid your boy off Monday night.
-My boys, huh?
Now take some of that fucking money
and buy your mama a condominium.
l thought this was a kosher bar, man.
No pork allowed.
Say, man, you seen this girl?
l seen the top of her head.
That's good.
Stop this motherfucker.
He's crazy. Where's my piece?
He ain't nothing. Take him out.
He's motherfucking crazy.
He's a fucking ltalian puke!
Freeze, motherfucker!
Come on, man. Please. Put the gun away.
All right. Who else wants some?
You're destroying the image of my place.
You'll never be the fucking man.
You'll never be the man.
Get over here!
Hold it, man. Don't do me ugly.
Listen. l know where the chick is.
She's upstairs.
-Yeah? She's upstairs?
-2-C. l swear, man. lt's 2-C.
This isn't what it looks like.
Listen, he's my cousin. He's a cop.
l didn't know they had all of this.
Get out of here.
You having a good time?
Pretty good time.
What is this shit? You wanna get high?
You wanna get high?
You're acting stupid, man! Stop it!
Stop. You playing the cop, l'm tired of it.
l'll show you what time is
'cause you'll do tall time.
Just take it, it's yours.
Three grand. lt's in the mattress.
You want to fucking bribe me, man?
Put your clothes on. We're going home.
Stop it.
l'm tired of you. You shut up!
Don't you understand that there are people
out there who love you.
Right. Keep talking. Keep flapping.
ln my business!
ls this your school stuff?
lt's my math homework and my history.
You gonna write me another note, Nico?
Come on. We're going home.
No, you go home. l'm tired.
l'll give you something, something big.
Oh, yeah?
This is huge, my man.
lt's a shipment coming in next Tuesday.
What the hell do you know
about a shipment?
This is square, on my mother's soul.
You gotta believe me, man.
You can't set me up.
l heard it from a hooker friend who's
banging this big coke lawyer. He told her.
-What lawyer?
-l don't know.
What do you mean you don't know?
Carlos Abandano. That's the one.
Better fucking pray to God
you ain't bullshitting me...
...or l'll come back and tear your heart out.
Let's go.
Who are you?
Get back!
l own this place!
l own this joint.
There's a guy upstairs.
l want to get him arrested!
-That's the motherfucker right there!
-These two guys are under arrest.
lt's a cesspool in there. Check it out.
Boy, you got some strange toilet habits.
l'm gonna take her home and clean her up.
l don't want to take her
to her grandmother like this.
Jax, l hate these cocaine lawyers.
And this shitty weather.
They're gonna have me serving time.
l wish you'd relax, hon.
This'll never get into court.
Except against us.
l don't care how
l have to get at these guys--
Let me reiterate.
You said you were going to protect
my butt and be my guardian angel.
Hang on, hang on.
There is an engine block
clearing customs...
...Tuesday, 10:00 pickup.
Fulton Meat Market.
An engine block?
Clever, clever, guys.
l'd like an '86 Lincoln...
...lllinois 354-DOG-67, please.
Ramone Chi Chi Testamente,
a Salvadoran national with quite a record.
Remember, you were harping on me
about having a date.
Dream on, baby.
l want to tell you, what l turned down
tonight, you could never come close to.
You should become a science-fiction
writer, instead of a cop or a DA...
...with that imagination you got.
You're right.
How you doing, Mr. Abandano?
Chi Chi, how you doing?
-l do not like this place.
-You do not like this place?
No, l don't want to go into this place.
You know l hate places like this.
-What don't you like about it?
-The element!
You know something, darling?
l really think that you should lighten up,
because...
...we're gonna party.
This is my lawyer. Say hello.
-Two for dinner?
-Just drinks.
Good work.
l don't believe it.
Sit down here. You're gonna love
this place. l promise.
Salvano, the fucking cockroach.
l don't believe this. You always do this
to me in front of people.
That is beautiful.
Excuse me.
l love it.
You'll have your engine block
on Tuesday, Boss.
lf this happened a week from Tuesday,
l could read about it in the paper.
Relax. lt'll make you famous.
Just what l need, to be famous.
Can you believe this?
Lieutenant Strozah, meet those two cops
in the back alley.
We got it down pretty good.
We got guys in the front,
we got a couple of cars out back.
Sealed off pretty good.
Three of our best guys.
l handpicked each one.
Jackson, Lukich, Nico. They're all topshelf.
They know how to do this.
They've done it before.
l can tell how much you love it here.
God! Now l know why l'm a vegetarian.
You eat meat. l know you eat meat.
-l'm gonna throw up.
-l've heard you eat meat.
Nico, keep the channel clear.
Don't embarrass us.
Right over there.
Two guys in the alley over there.
Definitely the Feds.
Frank, it"s fucking infested down here.
What are you trying to do to us?
Someone from downtown got wind of it.
Don't worry.
They're trying to make points.
Just handle the pinch.
This ain't a bust, it's a fucking convention.
l don't believe this.
Look at this, boys. Here we go.
Here we go. Jackson, stay back.
l think they made you.
You're too pretty to be a meatpacker.
lt's going down, boys. Let's go.
Keep your heads up.
Woman, let's do it.
The cars are going around the corner.
Come on, Nico. Lukich, get up there.
What do you think?
Looks good.
Let's get on with it.
-What the fuck are you assholes doing?
-Feds!
Shit! They jumped too soon!
What the fuck is this?
Freeze! Police!
Get back!
Nico, the Lincoln!
Nico!
Chi Chi!
Fucking animal!
Get rid of him!
l'm out! Do him!
He's still on the roof! Get rid of him!
Where do l go? What do l do?
Hit those hooks over there!
What do l do?
Stop the fucking car!
Hands up! Out of the car!
What the fuck is wrong with you?
You scared me to death!
Nico, you okay?
-Wait till you hear about--
-Shut the fuck up!
You make a nice hood ornament, Sarge.
-Come on!
-Gotta get this garbage out of here.
You gonna lose your license
driving around like that.
Let's go.
What do we got here?
What kind of high is this?
Sky-high.
Military explosives.
C-4, my man.
Hey, Boss...
...you can see your place
from the office of the FBl.
Ain't that something?
-Your name again?
-Agent Neeley, Chicago office.
The arresting officer, Toscani.
What does he do?
-He's a tac sergeant, CPD Vice.
-Hold on a minute--
l'll tell you what this cop is.
He's a fucking menace.
He almost strangled me!
Your problem is being
taken care of right now.
lt should've been handled 12 hours ago
when my throat was in one piece!
l don't know who's running
this outfit here...
...but l'll tell you one thing:
somebody better get his wires straight.
You don't know who you're dealing with.
This maniac should be wearing a number,
not a badge!
-The director does not want a problem.
-There won't be one.
And I don"t want any problems.
l understand.
Just listen.
They are to be released immediately.
You can count on it.
Avoid all contacts.
You'll have the Bureau's full cooperation.
You're free to go.
Thank you very much, gentlemen.
Good work. l loved the face of that
FBl guy when the call came through.
Salvano.
l don't want any more problems.
l don't enjoy babysitting.
Everything is going to be all right
from now on.
l promise you, Mr. Zagon.
Attention, please. Attention, everyone.
Please, guys.
l just want to get a few things
straightened out.
A few minutes ago, l received a call from
the First Deputy Superintendent's office.
As we all know, possession of these kinds
of explosives is a federal offense...
...and falls under the jurisdiction
of the federal agencies represented here.
What kind of bullshit is that?
The Feds come in, the doors close,
nobody hears, smells or sees anything.
And that's no answer.
lt's no answer to why
the biggest drug dealer in the city...
...is out on the street
as free as a fucking bird!
Keep it in your pants, all right. These men
have a job to do, just like we do.
lt's their game, let them play it.
What l'm about to say
does not leave this room. ls that clear?
Mr. Salvano has been working
for some time...
...in cooperation
with certain federal agencies.
l'm not at liberty to divulge the nature
or extent of Mr. Salvano's involvement.
l just learned of its existence myself
a few hours ago.
One thing l can tell you
is that Mr. Salvano's role...
...is crucial to an extremely sensitive,
ongoing investigation.
Any surveillance...
...harassment or unauthorized operations
against this individual are forbidden.
l order all of you, with due respect
for your work and your courage...
...to stand down.
Why don't you assholes
stand down on this?
You're gonna need me.
Need you. For what?
To get your ass out of jail.
You think you can afford my bail?
No.
Neither do l. Not on this pay.
You'll end up in jail for a long time,
l have the strangest feeling.
You're jealous 'cause l'm gonna stay a cop.
What the fuck is this? Go back to work.
Here we go.
What are you thinking?
lsn't this your mother's church?
Yes, but l'll bet she hasn't seen these boys
in the choir.
Hey, Nico!
l can't believe you're in church
without your family.
Hello, Father. How are you?
This must be your partner in crime.
-Delores Jackson.
-l'm Father Gennaro.
l saw you at the baptismal party.
-Nico, we gotta go!
-No, please. Wait.
God, it's good you're here.
lf you got a few minutes,
there's something l'd like to show you.
Please.
l haven't been down here since l was a kid.
What's this?
The rats are getting bigger.
-When did this happen?
-Two nights ago. l didn't call the police.
What do they want, the bingo receipts?
These are friends.
Father Tomasino, this is Nico.
-Mucho gusto, Padre.
-How do you do?
-Sister Mary.
-Hi, Nico.
-Delores.
-How do you do, Father?
-Señora, mucho gusto.
-Hello.
My friend, Father Tomasino,
is working with the sanctuary movement.
He's visiting...
...helping his people work out
some of their immigration problems.
Sorry to have troubled you.
Nico, we must go.
Gracias.
Nice meeting you, sir.
Bye-bye.
-How long have those people been here?
-Too long.
At least the children go to our school.
Who do you think broke into the room?
Kids, maybe. Maybe worse.
lt's not the first time.
Would you like us to send a car
to check on you?
No, please. Police frighten these people.
l know what you mean.
They frighten me, too.
lt's too far out of your way.
l can't ask you to go to that much trouble.
Look, l really don't mind coming by.
Promise, okay? All right?
Say, Nico, by the way,
when was your last confession?
My last confession?
l'm a married man.
l have no sins to confess.
You're a police officer.
You got a lot of sins to confess.
He's got your number!
-ls that your impression of police officers?
-l want to see you in church Sunday, okay?
l feel better when you're in church, okay?
You don't show up, l'll call your mother!
l wish you would. She loves you.
Why don't you go to church?
lt'll be good for you.
Get your soul saved.
Our leaders tell us...
...and talk to us about them and us.
But almighty God talks to us...
...about all of mankind...
...as one.
Now, we have an obligation...
...to find out what is the truth.
We need to study. We need to question.
We need to read and we need to find out...
...what they are doing in our name.
And we must support those brave souls...
...who seek...
...the truth.
God bless us. Amen.
Get down!
There's nothing else we can do.
Lord God, Heavenly Father...
...receive the soul of our dear
departed friend, Father Joseph Gennaro.
Come on.
Get a list of everybody treated here today.
Everybody.
Find those sanctuary people...
...the ones we found hiding
in the bottom of the church.
l want to know where they're from
and who might want to harm them.
Where are you gonna be?
Just stay by the radio. l'll find you.
-He didn't make it.
-Oh, Nico!
Oh, no!
Lieutenant Strozah, these are FBl agents:
Halloran, Neeley.
Sweetheart, go to the car.
l'll be right there, okay? Take Mama.
Nico, you okay? How's the family doing?
Excuse me. l'd like to have a word
with you.
Alone.
What the hell is it?
lt's you, that's what the fuck it is!
Keep your goddamn hands off me!
-You let Salvano walk.
-Salvano?
Yeah.
What are you, crazy?
What does he have to do with this?
That was no cherry bomb, that was C-4.
l've used that shit. l know what it
smells like and what it blows like.
Salvano never came near that C-4.
lt's in federal holding right now.
Besides, why would Salvano
blow up a church?
l tailed him two days ago.
He and his goon were in that church
and they weren't taking communion.
l saw the woman who planted the bomb
and she was with Salvano's lawyer.
Now, l want some fucking answers.
You tailed him after l ordered you off?
l want to know where Salvano is.
My orders were to release him,
not babysit him.
You think you're rough stuff.
Martial arts hero, chop-suey crap!
Let me tell you something.
You're not bulletproof.
You're not even a good cop.
You sneak around
playing your street-dick games...
...and all you come up with is conjecture,
wild coincidence and bullshit!
l want the name of the federal agent
who signed for those explosives.
You do your job, l'll do mine.
Bank on it, pal.
-Gentlemen.
-Hello.
Hi, how are you doing?
-How are you doing?
-Terrific.
The wallet. Let me see it.
Aide to Senator Harrison.
l hope l find you, you greasy mother!
l'm gonna kick your ass!
Who the fuck do you think you are?
l'm in front of St. Mary's church, where
seven people were killed by a bomb--
-You guys stay out of trouble.
-Okay, Nico.
-l hear you're looking for Salvano.
-You heard that?
l know where he's at.
-Where's that?
-Right here, motherfucker!
-lt's a long way from Kansas, Dorothy!
-Relax, man. Relax.
l won't shoot you.
These guys will beat you to death.
You come to our neighborhood,
fuck with our people.
Now our people are going to fuck with you.
We need a doctor!
Fuck him up!
You motherfucker!
Don't kill me! Please don't kill me!
-Who sent you?
-Nobody!
''Nobody?'' You did this for fun?
Jimmy Costanza!
lf l find out you're lying, l'll come back
and kill you in your own kitchen.
Salvano!
Bautista Salvano!
-That's my buddy, man.
-Yeah, man, l know him.
Sic him, Bulldog.
-Why are you fuckin' with my friend?
-l'm not in the mood.
Fuck your mood, man.
-What's happening?
-What it be like, homey?
-That was real good, man.
-Peace, brother.
The mayor has announced the city"s offer
of a $25,000 reward for information...
...leading to the arrest and conviction
of anyone responsible...
...for today"s tragic
St. Mary"s church bombing.
Why were we in church?
l'll tell you what.
l'm willing to break the rules and
l'm willing to tell you everything l know.
l just want some time.
lt's probably Jax.
Yeah, Jax. This better be good.
lt's bad, Nico.
Long time, Nelson.
Come on, man! You know better
than to use a name on an open line.
l'm gonna talk for 15 seconds,
and then l'm getting off.
You're in trouble, Nico.
Serious, serious trouble.
Really? That's fascinating.
Take your wife and family
and get them someplace safe, now!
l've been wanting to bring my family
to Switzerland. l just haven't had time.
You hear me? Now!
l'm risking my ass by telling you this.
Okay, don't take so long
to call me next time.
Good luck, paisà.
Why is the ClA calling you
at 2:00 in the morning?
Because Fox is a crazy asshole.
He gets drunk, he forgets he's halfway
around the world, and he calls.
He says he just wanted to know
if we got his Christmas card.
Listen, don't be that way.
-l'm just so scared.
-Don't be.
l'm gonna take care of everything,
all right?
All right?
Nico, who's there?
O'Hara, what's going on, man?
lsn't it a little early for breakfast?
Nico, how you doing?
l'm sorry. l gotta take you downtown.
The Feds want to talk. lt'll work out.
Here's the warrant, Toscani.
You fucking piece of shit.
l'll take that, thank you.
Easy guys! He's my friend. Take it easy.
lt's gonna work out. Let's go.
lt'll work out. l'm real sorry about this.
lt's not necessary! This is ridiculous!
Let him play his pussy game.
This is his setup.
Who do you think you are coming here
and treating my son like a criminal?
Who do you think you are?
-Just stop it! There's an infant here!
-Easy, easy.
-Check that coat.
-Why don't you come check it, asshole.
Take it easy!
Why don't you come
and put your hands on me!
-Get him out of here!
-Everything's gonna work out.
Come on. l'll be back in three hours!
The Police Association's
got lawyers for this!
You can't do this!
This guy, in the middle of the day,
comes in my place and starts wrecking it.
He assaults my customers.
He starts doing all this outer-space stuff,
putting my customers in orbit even.
l remember those violations
you told me he was guilty of.
Look, this is my boy, right here.
They finally got you, huh?
They finally got you, motherfucker.
l told you it was gonna go down.
Should've listened--
There he is.
You guys got one hell
of a police department around here.
l got a cousin in the department
in New Orleans.
You ever heard of Bob Bouquet?
Put your ass in that chair.
lllegal wiretaps, unauthorized surveillance.
When was this guy born?
You're quite a cop, Toscani.
You don't listen to anybody, do you?
-Where's Jax?
-She's out of this!
You're the rotten apple in this barrel.
We don't need to look any farther
than you and your family.
-You, mother--
-Nico!
Do you want to go to prison?
Unlawful entry.
-lllegal search and seizure.
-Deputy....
Who do you think is pulling their strings?
Who do you think they work for?
You were ordered to back off on Salvano.
l suppose you had too big a hard-on
for that, didn't you?
You can't be in on this, Fred.
You're officially suspended, Toscani.
l want your badge and your gun.
You gonna hold me?
You can walk for now.
Don't walk far.
Sara, l'm all right.
lt's okay, and l love you.
Tell Mama not to worry. All right?
l love you. 'Bye.
What the hell is going on?
What's happening here?
The sanctuary people, they're refugees
from El Salvador, Guatemala and Chile.
They're terrified of cops.
They're not even talking to me.
Down at the morgue, they got a guy
who was not a congregation member.
Alan Singletary.
He's an aide to Senator Harrison.
The Foreign Relations Committee Harrison.
The guy who's been crawling all over
the Central American drug connections.
You're gonna make a hell of a DA.
Harrison's staff has been compiling
some kind of heavyweight white paper.
lt implicates some of the major
intelligence agencies in drug trafficking.
They'll release it next week.
-So that's how Fox knew.
-Who?
An old Agency buddy of mine called me
last night. He said my family's in danger.
Luke, l need a favor.
l need you to go to the house, call
Uncle Branca. Mama's got the number.
Get the family ready to move out.
You got it, buddy.
They took away your pistola, right?
Yeah.
Thanks.
l don't believe this.
You come in here, with the children,
and bring all this up--
Listen.
You know me.
Please, tell these people...
...they don't have anything to worry about.
There is rubble all over the yard, Nicola.
l know, Sister.
Father Tomasino.
He came alone...
...two weeks ago. He had papers...
...papers to give to the senator.
Father Tomasino was going
to give the mass that day.
Father Gennaro talked him out of it.
He was afraid for Father Tomasino.
So it was Father Tomasino
they wanted to kill.
Where is Father Tomasino?
He go, mister. He ran away.
lf anybody knows where he is, you've got
to tell me because l know l can help him.
We don't know, mister.
Jax, l'm serious. You're out of this.
Wait a minute. l got a list.
You told me to get a list.
l'm telling you, you're finished.
l mean it. Out.
You're not talking to a rookie,
you understand?
You go home, you take care of your family,
okay, and l'll call you.
Paperwork only!
l'm gonna do what l have to do.
Thank you!
Okay, come across now.
Come on, baby, come on.
Hi, Nico!
-Call the police.
-Come on!
Freeze, motherfucker!
Anybody moves, he dies.
Drop that magazine, motherfucker, now!
Everybody's gonna ditch their weapons,
butt first.
Grab the barrel and do it, everybody. You!
Now, you.
Put your hands on your head.
All right, fall in behind the last man.
l don't think you can drop us all, badass.
You're right, but l'll get an ''A'' for effort.
All right. Let's go. Fall out!
Put your hands on your head.
Come on, you! Move!
Please don't come in here. Please, please.
Not in my store.
lt's a police emergency. l'm a cop.
On your knees. Give me the phone.
Let's go.
-This guy's gotta work, too.
-Get down, asshole.
Get the fuck down!
You wanna get down?
Get down on your fucking knees!
They tell me, ''Come to America! ''
No, not in my store!
There's the police!
No, mister!
Another police car.
Look! My store.
Come on, come on. ls it clear?
Sara, Branca will take care of us.
We'll be safe there.
Family goes in the Lincoln.
l'll ride in front.
l'll be five minutes behind you.
lt's got to be this way.
Let's go.
Where's Jax?
She thinks there's some documents
in some guy's apartment.
They killed the wrong priest.
What are you talking about?
l'll tell you what l'm talking about.
The second priest from Costa Rica...
...hiding in the church.
He was the one they meant to kill.
You know where to find this guy?
No, l do not.
Then you're gonna need help.
Yeah, l'd like you to help me.
Watch my family.
What are you gonna do?
You don't want to know.
Freeze! Put your hands up in the air.
Now go put them on the hood of the car.
Special Agent Neeley, what were you doing
with that woman up there?
Were you engaging in some kind
of unnatural sex acts with that young lady?
She must be 15!
That's illegal in some states, you know.
What are you talking about?
l thought you federal agents were straight,
honorable guys.
Does your wife know about this?
Sex is not the only thing in life.
Get in.
-So, how has your day been?
-Okay.
Listen, Toscani, l want to congratulate you.
You just made number four
on the ''most-wanted'' list.
Number four? l want to be number one.
The day is young.
What can l do for you?
There was a quantity of C-4 explosive
brought in here four days ago.
Hell, that's gone.
-When?
-Right away.
They scooped that stuff out of here
before it even got tagged.
You know who took it?
ClA.
Let me see the paperwork on it.
You got to sign.
Yeah, l remember that fellow.
Flew special out of Langley. Bomb tech.
Real nice fellow.
-l'll bet.
-Here it is.
''Fox.''
''Nelson Fox.''
-Thanks.
-Right.
Now what?
Yes, sir. The agent has been with
the Central American desk since 1984.
Thank you. That's what l wanted to know.
All right, take your shoes off.
Come on, let's go.
So you think l'm a bad cop, Neeley?
You know something? Maybe l am.
But at least l don't have my face
buried up Washington's ass.
Listen, Toscani.
Maybe l've judged you a little harshly.
l think you have.
And you know something?
What l'd like to do,
for the way you've treated me...
...is treat you in a similar fashion.
l'd like you to get up...
...run your ass over there
and jump in the fucking lake.
lf you don't hurry,
l'll empty this gun in your butt.
Move it, Agent Neeley!
Let's go!
Jump, Neeley!
Nico, what are you doing here?
-l need a favor.
-Sure.
-How late are you gonna be here today?
-l'm off at 6:00.
l'll be here.
Don't be too long, lady.
l got a crew coming in.
Thanks. We'll be done in a little while.
We don't have much time.
They're going to tear this goddamn place
down in a matter of hours.
There's no way to access
Covert Operations directly...
...but l got a guy at Princeton.
He has a database bigger than Langley.
How the hell did you get in this mess?
l thought you were finished with the ClA.
Trap door.
We'll wriggle up these two...
...operative dossiers.
Start with my friend, Nelson.
Your friend has had a hell of a career.
Give me the names of every Agency man
involved in this.
Nico, what is going on here?
Here we go.
Five agents from the Central American
desk. All of them, trained assassins.
They've all come to Chicago
in the last week and they're all still here.
They got the whole fucking
killing team here.
lt looks that way.
Thanks.
l owe you one.
-Where are you going?
-l gotta find that priest.
Be careful.
I find this totally incredulous.
You, being a station chief at the CIA,
didn"t know what was going on?
Mr. Senator,
I"d like to explain a few things.
Either you perjured yourself earlier,
or you"re lying to us now.
Take a few moments
before you answer this.
And remember that you"re under oath.
It was agreed this was a valuable asset
and that I had to work out a way...
...they had to work out a way
in which to take over.
And did that include
giving money to the enterprise?
Not insofar as I knew.
-And the colonel never told you?
-No.
Are you saying that this was going
to be a donation for the CIA...
...as far as you were concerned?
We were going to walk away from it.
Hello.
Oh, yes, Sister. Yes.
Sister Mary, right.
No, there will be no problem.
Now just calm down. Right, right.
Now where are you?
Who is it?
Father!
Get her out of here.
This way, Father.
Where did you find this guy?
The nun from the daycare called.
She's with the priest at a place on Damon.
She saw two guys sneaking
around the church and she got scared.
l got papers from that senator's aide.
Everything Harrison has been working on.
lt's unbelievable. lt's over at my place.
l need you to do me a favor.
Stay out of it. Just stay in the car.
Nico, far be it for me to complain...
...but you got Jax pulling burglaries.
You got me doing God only knows what.
When we hit the joint,
l don't want you celling with me.
Jax, we'll work out something.
Why don't you go over there
and sweet-talk him?
Sure.
lf l were you, l would listen
to what this man has to say.
He knows what's best for you.
You wouldn't lie to me would you, Father?
lt's a sin.
Look at me!
lf you spoke to anyone
about our plans to kill the senator...
...tell me now...
...and l won't have to use this.
This is from confession. l tell no one.
Let's go.
Under no circumstances
are you to come out of this car.
Just stay here, all right?
Take a nice look at it.
l got it just for you.
Do you feel that? Nice?
You like that?
Now you're gonna start feeling
something warm.
Very warm and wonderful.
Think about it.
Warm. l love it!
l enjoy this. l really enjoy the shit out
of this thing.
We'll enjoy it together.
You've always been alone.
Now you'll be with me, together!
l want to know who you told.
l told them...
...you make...
...the children see you...
...mutilating their mothers...
...and sometimes...
...you do these things...
...to the children.
Did you tell anybody?
Damn it, tell me now!
Tell me now!
Father, I have had enough of this.
Father, l want you to tell me the truth.
Can we kill him?
lf you told anyone about our plans
to kill the senator...
...we cannot kill him!
Nothing!
Phase two.
Christ!
-Move it!
-What are you doing? Get out of here.
Jax, get the hell out of here!
Nico!
Jax!
-Go!
-l got him!
Where is he?
Down there!
l got a bona fide emergency here.
What am l supposed to do?
-Shut the fuck up!
-Yes, sir.
Get inside! Come on!
l hear sirens but l don't see any cops.
lf they were cops,
they'd show me their badges, asshole.
A bona fide gunfight, asshole!
Get up front!
-Shut up! Be quiet!
-What the hell am l supposed to do?
Get the car on Track 3 out of the way.
At least, get that out of the way.
They got guns all over the place.
l got a carload of passengers.
Damn it! Call Nico's uncle
and find out if he's heard from him.
Shut up and save your strength.
l'm okay. l'm okay.
-Where are we going?
-Cubicle D.
l got on my vest.
Where is he?
What do you mean you don't know?
We don't know what happened
to him, Branca.
Yeah, she's gonna be all right.
You hear anything, you let me know.
Capisci?
lt's Nico.
Jesus Christ.
The motherfuckers got Jax.
Lukich called. She's not dead.
She's gonna make it.
She was wearing a vest.
This was picked up with your mail
this morning.
They're letting you know
if you don't back off...
...they're gonna get to your family.
-You've got to do it, Nico.
-Tell him, Sara.
You know you have to.
Listen to her, Nicola.
This is your family.
Ever notice how clean babies smell, like
nothing in the world has touched them?
Mom, take him upstairs, will you?
Come, Giuliano, we'll go upstairs.
Do you know why l love you?
What it is about you
that l've always loved?
lt's pride.
But, Nico, that pride may kill all of us.
Swallow your pride.
Choke on it, if you have to.
-Lay it down, please.
-You know something?
There's nothing in this world
that l wouldn't do for my family.
Nobody will harm us.
l don't want you to worry. Okay?
Not even you can hit him
at this range, Nico.
That wasn't the plan, Nelson.
Close range?
lt'd never work. lt's rigged.
Scanned every 35 seconds.
l was thinking of a claymore on the roof--
No!
The roof is wired, too.
Sensors every 15 feet.
Okay. Now you can move.
-lt's me. You don't have to treat me like--
-Slow!
Come on, let's get the fuck out of here.
Move! Slow.
You even look at me funny,
you're in the river, Toscani.
l figured you'd do your recon
from this building.
-You're looking fit.
-l'm getting a bit of a tire.
-ls that your own tailor?
-Hong Kong.
-You've come a long way.
-Yeah.
Just walk.
l don't believe you.
What's so hard to believe?
l want to help you, you dumb guinea.
l've been trying to talk
some sense into you.
You're still ''Fox the Fixer.''
lf l wanted to cap you,
l'd save myself all this damn chitchat.
l'd make big points for myself
if l brought your scalp in.
Shit, l'd be White House material.
ls that what Zagon is,
one of your basement boys?
Zagon's a rancher. 4,000 acres
in Costa Rica. Beautiful place.
Beautiful place, huh? Was that bought
with opium money from the triangle?
And a ton of coke a week
from other places.
Which he funnels here through Salvano.
The company getting it's cut, of course.
Legal tender.
So war is still the greatest business, huh?
These guys have started and financed
every war we've ever fought.
Nobody would believe me if l told them
the bankers were the ClA.
Come on, Toscani, don't preach to me.
So the senator couldn't be bought,
could he?
He was gonna expose your plans to invade
Nicaragua with your fucking coke money.
So the Agency clears Zagon
to cap his ass, right?
Just keep walking, asshole.
So some poor, innocent priest finds out.
He comes here.
But you can't kill the senator
until you know if the padre has talked.
So Zagon comes in, ''Tell me,'' with his
little doctor bag. Only by then, l'm in on it.
And you fucking know
l'm gonna recognize his handiwork.
lf your name would've been Joe Smith,
l never would've caught it.
But how many Nicola Toscanis are there?
Tell me something, old buddy.
Do we kill our own senators now?
Why not? The Romans did.
-Are we the fucking Romans?
-We're an empire, too.
You don't believe that shit for a minute.
Just walk. Go!
Hold it, Nico.
-Here's your key, sir.
-My buddy will drive.
You know something?
ln Europe, they're trying some 80-year-old
camp guard for Nazi war crimes.
All around our country,
they got guys on Death Row...
...for murdering one, two, three guys.
And they probably deserve
what they're gonna get.
But you and l...
...we know people
that are personally responsible...
...for the death
of 50,000 non-military personnel.
Librarians, teachers, doctors,
women, children, all dead.
We've wiped out entire cultures.
And for what?
Not one ClA agent has ever been tried,
much less accused, of any crimes.
You guys think you're above the law,
but you ain't above mine.
Nico, we don't have time for this.
Get in the goddamn car.
l've been waiting for the day
l'd catch up with this motherfucker.
Salvano and his scumbag dealer.
What a team we got here.
l told you, you'd never be the man.
Nelson, we've been looking for you.
l see that you...
...found our friend.
Thanks, Fox.
l didn't bring him. l swear it.
You two must have had a lot to talk about.
Reminiscing about the good old days?
Stay still!
Just fucking don't move.
Nelson, bring our friend in.
Come on, be a good boy.
Dive, Nico!
Get that motherfucker!
Move it!
Get him!
Stop the car, you fuck!
Stop the car, you piece of shit!
Stop it!
Fox's car!
He"s on the ramp now.
He"s coming out the Wabash entrance.
Get there, Deep Throat.
Roger, Spike Leader. We read you.
Get out of the car!
l want him alive.
He's clean.
Bring him over.
Let's go!
We're out of here.
Abandon the vehicles and get out of here.
Tommy, hurry up! Get in.
We're out of here.
Now, our honored guest,
Senator Ernest Harrison.
l hope this don't take too long
'cause l'm getting hungry.
This is bullshit. We've got work to do.
All work and no play
makes Jack a dull boy.
We've got an hour before we say good-bye
to the honorable senator.
You know, you've got to learn
to take time to...
...smell the roses.
How are you gonna do him?
Do him in the motorcade...
...or pass him through a hotel kitchen?
Put his face up.
Hold it up.
Here you go, Toscani. ''Dr. Feelgood.''
l've used these little beauties many times
to extract information.
For the first time in my life...
...l'm gonna do it just for the fun.
Get away from me with that,
you piece of shit!
That's it, fight it!
Fight it, cherry...
...so it speeds right on its way.
Fight it!
Keep fighting it!
Oh, you're a good boy, now.
That's what l've been waiting for.
Let him go.
Toscani, my sleeping beauty...
...you should've killed me
when you had the chance.
You're too fucking dumb, asshole.
Jake! Look out!
Say something. Nico?
ls there a doctor here?
Quick! Call an ambulance!
Agent Neeley, FBl. We've got a problem,
but we don't know what it is, yet.
Please, Senator Harrison, this way.
We are standing in front of the home
of Police Sergeant Nico Toscani.
Behind me, the entourage
of Senator Harrison is arriving.
Lots of security here. We have police
officers on the scene and federal agents.
Of course, there is concern
of a possible assassination attempt.
That"s why you"ve got
so many law enforcement officers here.
-This is Senator Harrison. Nico Toscani.
-How do you do?
Please, don't get up.
Detective Toscani...
...l just felt compelled to come
and thank you personally...
...and to assure you that we'll use
every resource available...
...to bring these men to justice...
...and to ensure that this type of behavior
will never be tolerated again.
That would be nice.
Let me introduce Roberta Alspaugh
of the Fifth Circuit Court.
How do you do, ma'am?
Are you sure you're well enough?
l'm ready to talk if you're ready to listen.
All right.
-Miss Jackson, l'll leave you now.
-Senator, thank you.
-We'll be leaving for Washington.
-Hey buddy, we'll be back later.
Mr. Toscani...
...can you tell us about
your military background?
ln 1973, l worked for
a special operations group...
...in Vietnam and Cambodia.
l was involved with gathering intelligence.
All of the members of this team
were doctors recruited by the ClA...
...and trained at a secret camp
in Langley, Virginia.
Gentlemen, whenever you have a group
of individuals...
...who are beyond any investigation...
...who can manipulate the press,
judges, members of our Congress...
...you"ll have within our government
those who are above the law.