{\move(10,10,190,230,100,400)\fad(0,1000)\fscx25\fscy25\t(0,6000,\fscx125\fscy125)\c&H000000&\3c&H00FFFF&}anoXmous
{\move(400,10,190,270,100,400)\fad(0,1000)\fscx25\fscy25\t(0,6000,\fscx125\fscy125)\c&H000000f&\3c&0000a6&}https://thepiratebay.se/user/anoXmous
(TV Announcer)
'Yes, folks, Moderna Designs...
'present the latest
in kitchen luxury.
'The Moderna Wonder Major
All-Automatic Convenience Centre-ette...
'gives you all the time in the world
to do the things you really want to do.
'An infrared
freezer/oven complex...
'that can make you a meal
from packet to plate...
'in 15 and a half seconds!
The Morrisons have got one that
can do that in eight seconds.
Oh?
Block of ice to beef bourguignon
in eight seconds.
Lucky things.
Dad, did you know that
the ancient Greek warriors...
had to learn 44 different
ways of unarmed Combat?
Well, at least we've got
a two-speed hedge cutter.
They were trained to kill people
26 different ways with their bare hands.
- (Watch beeping)
- Bedtime for you, Kevin. It's 9:00.
And this King Agamemnon,
he once fought...
Go on, dear. Your father said.
- Oh, all right.
- 'The man you all love, Kenny Lange!
'Well, that's today's top prize.
'Let's meet today's star guest
on Your Money Or Your Life.
'Bring them on, girls.
My, don't they look gorgeous!
'I'm sure they get lovelier
every day.'
(Father) Turn that light off!
It is off.
(Door rattling)
(Horse neighing)
(Neighing continues)
(Door opens)
What the hell
is going on up here?
I told you to put that light out
and get to bed.
- But...
- And no more noise!
It came off just like that.
The whole thermostat.
That's the toaster, the spreader
and the slicer all gone.
- She's in a terrible state.
- Should've bought German.
- Mum?
- Lt would've matched her rotissomat.
- Mum, Dad, can I...
- You're going to bed in good time tonight.
- I was thinking of going to bed now.
- Now? Certainly not.
- You must wait for your food to go down.
- I haven't eaten any food.
Well, you must eat your food.
And then wait for it to go down.
(Machine beeping)
Oh, no! Not the carvery again.
(TV audience applauding)
Oh, dear me, Beryl.
Now, all I want to know...
is what famous film star
begins with "C"?
Do you understand
the question, my darling?
(Audience laughter)
Come on, Beryl. Come on. Jumbo's
gonna end up in the soufflé, Beryl.
You've got to answer it, Beryl.
Come on. Come on, Beryl.
- It's gone down now.
- Come on, Beryl. Come on.
- What?
- My supper. It's gone down.
I can feel it.
Can I go to bed now?
Yeah, all right.
Off you go. But no noise.
- What?
- No noise!
All right. Okay.
(TV Announcer)
No, Beryl. Capetown is not a film star.
(Audience laughing)
Oh dear. Oh, well.
That's Your Money Or Your Life.
(Siren wailing)
(Yawning)
(Toy humming)
(Father) Well, it takes money.
(Mother)
With a kitchen like that?
(Father)
Our kitchen's all right, isn't it?
(Mother)
Our kitchen is light-years behind.
(Door closes)
(Clattering)
(Clattering continues)
- Where are we?
- I don't know.
- Well, look at the map.
- It's not on the map.
- Is he coming after us?
- I think we gave him the slip.
(All screaming)
It's him! Run for it!
- Which way?
- This way. Careful.
(All shouting)
(Nervous chuckle)
We can explain everything, sir.
It's not as bad as it looks.
We just borrowed the map.
Sort of got rather happy
about it, and, uh...
ran off in high spirits.
Yeah, we did.
Who are you?
That's not him.
It didn't sound
like him, did it?
It doesn't even look like him.
- It isn't him.
- Let's get him!
(All shouting)
Strutter, get his torch.
Shine it right in the face.
His face, dummy!
(Strutter) It's a kid!
Og, Fidgit, check the door.
All clear.
Strutter, the light.
Just tell us how we get out of here,
keep quiet and you won't get hurt.
Wh-Why don't you get out
the way you came?
Don't try and be smart
with me, you little creep.
Yeah.
If you want to play it smart,
I'll introduce you to Vermin.
He eats anything, you know.
I'm not trying to be smart.
I'm just trying to help.
- You know, don't you?
- I don't know anything.
You know,
and you're not going to tell us.
I'm getting angry,
and Vermin's getting hungry.
I don't kno... Ooh!
- He's found it!
- What?
- The way out.
- It's never done that before.
Come on, you lot, push!
(Men grunting)
Oh, no! Not like that!
Wait for me to give
the order, all right?
Ready? One...
(Men grunting)
Stop! Stop!
You never start on one.
Who ever heard of anybody
starting anything on one?
- What is it then, two or three?
- Three.
' (Men grunting) - And push!
- It's him!
- He's found us!
Help us! Please! Help us!
- Come on!
- Who is that?
Return what you
have stolen from me!
Return! Return the map!
It will bring you great danger!
Stop! Now!
(All screaming)
(Quacking)
(Screaming continues)
(Groaning, shouting)
- Where are we?
- I'm stuck!
Quick! The barn!
Get under here.
Hold him, Strutter.
(Kevin whimpering)
Shut up!
All clear. Wally?
Yeah.
- Strutter?
- Yeah.
- Move it. Go.
- Okay.
- Fidgit?
- Yeah.
Where are we?
What happened to my bedroom?
Who was that man?
That was no man.
That was the Supreme Being.
You mean God?
We don't know Him that well.
We only work for Him.
Shut up! Now, are we all here?
- What?
- Og, are you here?
- Yeah, he's here.
- Vermin?
(Chickens clucking)
Vermin, will you stop eating!
It's too dangerous to stay here.
He's probably still after us.
So we better keep moving.
Hey, where are you going?
- Hey, where are you going?
- Get him! He'll give us away.
(All shouting)
Help! Help!
(Horses neighing)
(Men shouting in French)
Farmers!
(Man shouts)
Look what you've done, boy.
Sorry. What town is that?
Castiglione, or what
Napoleon's left of it.
- Napoleon?
- Yes. It's his city now.
Come on, boy. You come with us.
No, thanks.
Come with us
if you know what's good for you.
You're going the wrong way.
Napoleon?
- Get down!
- You nearly got us caught!
You silly fool.
You could've ruined everything.
- Do you know where we are?
- Shut up. Of course I do.
1796. Battle of Castiglione.
See?
Are you sure we're not
in somebody's bedroom?
Look, do you want to be
leader of this gang?
- We agreed no leader.
- Right. So shut up and do as I say.
Now, we've got to get
into the city.
We can't.
The roads are too dangerous.
I've got an idea.
We can use the river.
Come on!
(Explosion)
(Man shouting)
Aaaah!
(Explosion)
(Horse neighing)
What are we going to do here?
- A robbery.
- Shhh.
- A robbery?
- Of course.
We're international
criminals. We do robberies.
(Randall) Shut up back there.
(Townspeople screaming)
Aim! Fire!
(Explosions continue)
Take aim! Fire!
(Man laughing)
(Laughing continues)
(indistinct noises)
That's him.
You're not gonna rob him?
Yeah. Every single
penny he's got.
- But that's Napoleon.
- And he's rich.
(Laughing continues)
Monsieur Commander...
I think that the mayor of
Castiglione and his Council...
would like very much
to surrender now, please.
Look at that!
Look at the little fellow!
(Napoleon laughing)
With the city, we have the whole area
of western Lombardy at our feet.
Oh, go away!
I never should've married you!
- (Whimpering)
- Oh, stop it!
(Laughing) Yes! Yes!
Mon Commander,
they are very keen to surrender.
They have been here eight hours.
Don't stand so close
to me, Neguy!
I've told you about that before.
You on one side
and him on the other...
It's like being on the bottom
of a bloody well!
Just because
you think I'm small.
No, Commander, you are
not small at all.
No, not by any means.
Five-foot-one is not small.
Yeah, five-foot-one
and Conqueror of Italy.
- Not bad, huh?
- Very, very good.
(Puppets chattering, gunshoo.
- Oh! Oh! Oh!
- What just happened?
Where'd they... l just...
(Puppeteer groaning)
(Puppeteer gasps)
Bravo!
(Napoleon) More! I want more!
- I... Thank you. Thank you very much.
- Encore!
I wonder if you would like
to see some of our other items.
We have Zuzu and Benny.
I (Fanfare)
Fun on a unicycle.
No?
How about the Great Rumbozo?
He sing and lift heavy things.
No. How about, uh...
Come on.
(Laughs)
This I think you'll like.
It's very funny.
The Three idiots...
uh, from Latvia.
It's a very funny act.
They swallow brushes.
No, no! They're all freaks!
Not one of them
under five-foot-six.
What kind of theatre
are you running, huh?
I'm sorry, sir, but...
No, no. More of the funny show,
the little puppets
hitting each other.
That's what I like!
Little things hitting each other!
(Cannon blasts)
(Whimpers, groans)
(Hushed chattering)
Come on.
Psst.
- Huh?
- Play something like this.
Tsk. Hmm.
I Like the wallpaper
sticks to the wall.
I Like the seashore
sticks to the sea.
I Like you never
get rid of your shadow.
I Boy, you didn't get rid of me.
IMe.
I And my shadow.
I Strolling down the avenue.
I Avenue, avenue, avenue.
IMe.
I And my shadow.
- I Not a soul to tell our troubles to.
- Please let go!
- I We stick together like glue.
- (Muttering)
I And when it's 12:00.
I We climb the stairs.
I We never, never knock.
I 'Cause nobody's there...
(Grunting, shouting)
I Me and my shadow.
(Shouting continues)
I Feeling blue I
(Quarrelling)
Well, what do you think?
(Quarrelling continues)
Marvellous show.
Young man, you stick with these boys,
you have a great future.
(Laughing)
You know, you are
the best thing...
to happen to me
since this whole campaign.
You know, I come
to Conquer Italy...
because I thought they
were all small, you know?
I heard they was
really tiny guys.
Sir, I really think there
are more important things...
Shut up!
Don't you dare to tell me
my business.
You are dismissed, you hear?
You, Lucien, the rest of you.
Great streaks of misery.
- But sir...
- No!
I'm going to have
some new generals for a bit.
(Napoleon)
Alexander the Great...
five feet exactly.
Isn't that incredible?
Alexander the Great, whose empire
stretched from India to Hungary...
One inch shorter than me.
(Laughs)
(Polite laughter)
(Clock chimes)
Oliver Cromwell...
the only man with any guts
in British history...
Not a big man at all.
(Dog barking)
Louis IV, 5' 21/2".
(Laughing) Charlemagne...
a dumpy little five-footer.
- (Snoring)
- Squat little chap.
Attila the Hun, 5' 11/2".
Cyrano de Bergerac, 5' 3 1/2".
Tamburlaine the Great,
four-foot-nine...
and three quarters.
(Drops glass)
Wasn't he interesting?
Strutter, wake up. Wake up.
According to this map,
there's a time hole outside.
- See if you can find it.
- Right.
The rest of you,
the hole disappears at 12:00, right?
So let's get moving.
Vermin, Fidgit, the tapestry.
Hey, that's 16th century!
It's nice, isn't it?
Get it!
Okay-
(Shouting)
We're rich! We're rich!
Ten-hut!
(Snoring)
(Laughing)
- Come on. We've got 30 seconds left.
- You found the time hole?
- Yes.
- Let's go.
(Snoring continues)
- (Laughing)
- Come on, Kevin.
(Chattering continues)
(Clock chiming)
Ten-hut!
About turn!
(Clock chiming)
' (Guam) Stop! " Go! '"
Thieves! After them!
- Follow them!
- (All shouting)
(Groaning)
Oh, Sir Vincent,
you came for me!
Oh, Good Mistress Pansy,
I could not have ridden faster.
Four horses have I exhausted
this day from Nottingham.
Oh, the way you leapt to my chamber,
so full of... manliness.
I could scarce restrain
the rushing of my feet.
These 12 long years have been
like chains that bound me.
Oh. And the personal problem?
- Much, much better.
- Ohhh.
And now we will ride full tilt to Dover,
and there embark for France.
Oh, you don't have
to wear the special...
No, no, I don't have to wear
the special... anymore.
Oh, Pansy.
No more worries now, Pansy.
- Oh.
- No. No.
- (Whistling noise)
(Shouting, muttering)
(Pansy screaming)
(Horses neighing)
(Shouting continues)
- Hey!
- (Screaming)
(Laughing)
(Laughing continues)
- Quick! Quick!
- (Randall) We did it!
- Your problem, Vincent.
- Forget the problem. Get me the money.
- We did it! We did it!
- (All laughing)
I told you. You stick with me,
and you won't go far wrong.
Sometimes I almost
believe you, Randall.
- Hey, where are we?
- Where are we?
Why, it's obvious. We're, um...
(Pansy) Vincent, don't
worry about a thing.
(Vincent) I'm not worrying.
- Exactly...
- In the Middle Ages.
Hmm... in the Middle Ages.
Five hundred years before the man
we just robbed was even born.
- Fantastic!
- Try that one in a court of law.
Vermin, that is not
meant to be eaten.
You never know
until you've eaten it.
Is it always like this
when you've done a raid?
I don't know.
We've never done one before.
But I thought you were
international criminals.
Going to be. Going to be.
Yeah, going to be.
Aren't we? Going to be?
Especially now
that we've got you, Kevin.
Hang on. He's just a kid.
He's not one of us.
He knows an awful lot.
Yeah, and he's bigger
than any of us.
- Do you really want to join us?
- Can we really go anywhere?
You name it. If it's down here.
(Laughing, cheering)
I don't understand.
What's so special about that map?
This map used to belong
to the Supreme Being.
- You stole it?
- No. Well, sort of.
He used to be our employer.
He made all the big stuff,
like good and evil,
men and women, night and day.
And when He did trees and shrubs,
we helped make all this.
Whew, that's not bad.
Yeah, and did we get
a thimbleful of credit for it?
No, all we got was the sack,
just for creating the Pink Bunkadoo.
- Pink Bunkadoo?
- Yeah. Beautiful tree that was.
- Og designed it, didn't you? Yeah.
- (Muttering)
Six-hundred feet high,
bright red and smelled terrible.
As a disciplinary measure, we were
sent down to the repairs department.
- (Chattering continues)
- What?
You see, to be quite frank, the fabric
of the universe is far from perfect.
It was a bit of a botched job.
We only had seven days to make it.
And that's where this comes in.
This is the only map of all the holes.
Well, why repair them?
Why not use them to get stinkin' rich?
Yeah, stinkin' rich!
- (Laughs)
- Lads, here's to stinkin' rich!
Stinkin' rich. Stinkin' rich.
- And to Kevin!
- Yeah, Kevin!
- Here's to Kevin!
- Stinkin' Kevin!
Hey, hold it there.
- (Chattering)
- Smile.
- Hey, the map.
- Yeah, the map. Don't forget the map.
(Kevin) Hey, come on! Smile!
(Pansy) Help! Robbers!
- Hey, that's us!
- Someone's in trouble. Come on!
(Randall) Grab the loot.
(Pansy continues screaming)
- (Robbers shouting)
- It's a bit tight.
(Robbers laughing)
- Now, those are our sort of people.
- Yeah!
(Shouting, laughing continue)
Vincent! Oh! Oh, dear!
- (Pansy) Help!
- Come on.
Oh, Vincent, someone's coming.
- (Whimpering)
- Help! Help I say!
Oh, at last. Oh, I say!
I say, my fiancé and I would appreciate
a bit of assistance.
- Oh, no! The problem, Pansy!
- Oh! Oh!
- It's started again! Oh! Oh!
- Oh, don't worry, darling.
- I say!
- I must have fruit!
(Wolf howling)
- Where are we?
- We've lost them.
Come on. Don't be so wet.
(All yelling)
- (Muttering)
- (Kevin) Hey!
What do we do now, Randall?
Just leave this to me, Wally.
We've just got to treat them right.
What do you want,
you tatty-faced old scumbag?
- What's your business, gob face?
- We're robbers!
- Villainous robbers?
- The worst.
- Stop at nothing?
- Nothing at all.
- Steal a cup outta a beggar's hands?
- Rather.
- The teeth from blind old ladies?
- Of course.
- Toys from children?
- Whenever we can.
(Both growling)
Right. Let 'em down!
They always crack in the end.
(Grunting, groaning)
Wow.
Listen, I've got a few ideas
for, uh, a linkup...
between your gang and our gang,
but I only want
to talk to the boss.
The boss?
- The boss?
- That's right.
They serious?
Ohhh.
(Men shouting, cheering)
(Bones crunching)
All right! Do it!
(Laughs) Anyone else wanna go?
Come on, you weasels.
What's this?
Lose yourself, leprechaun.
(Laughing)
(Spitballs clinking)
Move yourself, lad.
(Chattering, laughter)
(Ding)
- That's disgusting!
- Wait here! I'll get him!
(Flies buzzing)
Hello. L-I'm Hood.
- It's Robin Hood.
- Yeah.
- (Shouts)
- Say good morning, you scum.
Good morning, scum.
- Good morning. You're all robbers, then?
- The best, Mr. Hood.
Jolly good.
And you're a robber, are you?
And do you enjoy robbing, then?
Well, it helps
pay the rent, sir.
(Laughing)
Jolly good.
And you're a robber too?
How long have you been a robber?
- Four-foot-one.
- Good Lord!
- Jolly good. Four-foot-one?
- Yes.
Well, th-th-th-that is
a long time, isn't it?
Well now, I hear you've made
a pretty good haul.
Well, see for yourself, sir.
Gosh! I say!
Crikey! I mean,
I've been in robbing for years,
but I've never seen
anything like this.
Crumbs! And you acquired
all of this by yourselves?
Well, it was a good day,
Mr. Hood.
- Jolly good day!
- It's nice, isn't it?
Rather! Well, I mean,
what can I say? Thank you.
Thank you all
very, very much indeed.
Oh, don't ment... What?
Well, I mean,
it's frightfully kind of you.
The poor are going to be
absolutely thrilled.
- Have you met them?
- Who? The poor?
Oh, you must meet them.
I just know you'll like them.
Of course, they haven't
got two pennies to rub together.
- But that's because they're poor.
- (All laughing)
Uh, Marion, would you be so kind
as to ask the poor to come in, please?
- No problem.
- Thank you so much.
- Right. Come on, you lot.
- Let's just see what we've got.
This is going to be
so much help in our work.
No, you don't understand.
All this stuff is ours. We stole it.
Oh, yes, I know, and believe you me the
poor are going to be not just thrilled,
but also considerably less poor,
aren't they, Redgrave?
- (Gibberish)
- You see? What did he say?
He said, "Yeah, what with Christmas
coming up and all." - Ah, jolly good.
Yes, well, there we are.
Congratulations. Well done.
(Laughter)
There we are. Well done.
Congratulations.
(Laughing, cheering)
Is that... Is that
absolutely necessary?
- (Gibberish)
- What did he say?
- He says, yeah, he's afraid it is.
- Ah, fine. Fine.
There we are, madam.
Congratulations.
- Congratulations. Jolly good.
- Thank you.
(Laughing continues)
incidentally, would any of you like
to stay on and help us with our work?
There's still so much wealth
to redistribute.
Oh, I'd like to stay.
Jolly good. What's your name?
- Uh, Ke...
- Ke... What a jolly nice name.
- Let me go.
- Well, never mind.
- Cheerio. Thank you very much.
- (Kevin struggling)
Thank you very much.
Thank you very, very,
very, very much.
Awful people.
This can't wait! - I'll never get
a chance to meet Robin Hood again.
- Any chance of a rescue?
- Stop moaning!
He's obviously a dangerous man.
Unbalanced, if you ask me.
Giving away what isn't even his!
That's what Robin Hood
always did. Even I know that.
- Oh, of course. You know it all.
- He was one of my heroes.
Heroes! Heroes!
What do they know about a day's work?
- Leave him alone, Randall!
- Well, it makes me sick.
Anyone Who's always right
makes me sick.
- That's why you get on with yourself!
- Watch it!
Big mouth!
Horseflesh wouldn't have
got us into this.
- Horseflesh is dead.
- Then give me the map. I'm taking over!
Get off me! Get...
(Arguing continues)
(Thunderclap)
So... these are
the sort of people...
the Supreme Being
allows to steal His map?
Look at them.
Stunted little proles.
I wouldn't even trust them
to wipe their own noses.
Oh, no, sir. It's much
too difficult for them.
What sort of supreme being
created such riffraff?
Is it not the workings
of a complete incompetent?
But He created you, Evil One.
What did you say?
Well, He created you,
so He can't be totally...
Never talk to me
like that again!
No one created me! I am Evil!
Evil existed long before good.
I made myself.
I cannot be unmade.
I am all-powerful!
Yeah.
But why, if that's the case,
are you unable to escape
from this fortress?
That's a good question.
Why have I let the Supreme Being
keep me here...
in the Fortress
of Ultimate Darkness?
- Because you...
- Oh, shut up. I'm speaking rhetorically.
- Of course.
- I let Him keep me here...
in order to lull Him
into a false sense of security.
Ah, clever, clever.
When I have the map,
I will be free...
and the world will be different
because I have understanding.
- Uh, understanding of what, master?
- Of digital watches.
Soon I shall have understanding of video
cassette recorders and car telephones.
And when I have understanding of them,
I shall have understanding of computers.
And when I have understanding of
computers, I shall be the Supreme Being.
God isn't interested
in technology.
He knows nothing of the potential of the
micro-chip or the silicon revolution.
Look how He spends His time.
Forty-three species of parrots!
- Nipples for men!
- Slugs.
Slugs! He created slugs.
They can't hear. They can't speak.
They can't operate machinery.
Are we not in the hands
of a lunatic?
Sir... look!
If I were creating a world, I wouldn't mess
about with butterflies and daffodils.
I would have started
with lasers, 8:00 day one.
- (Assistant gasps)
- Sorry.
I just can't wait for a new tech...
techno... technological dawn.
Sir... look!
What is it, Benson?
The map, sir. The map!
They've brought it with them!
- What?
- I saw the map, master, just now.
- Are you sure?
- I'm sure, master.
Down there!
The little one has it.
The little one?
This is our chance.
This is what we've been waiting for!
- It will set us free.
- Shut up!
If you're wrong, Benson,
my revenge will be slow and unpleasant.
I will turn you inside out
over a very long period of time.
Oh, thank you, master.
Thank you.
Now we must bait the hook,
see if they bite...
and pull them in.
Stand by for mind control.
What about Babylon?
- Who?
- It's a city of legendary wealth.
Ahh.
(Voice echoing)
I've got a better idea.
Who said that?
I've got an idea
forming in my head.
You haven't had an idea
for thousands of years.
There is a place where we could find
the greatest thing man could want,
the goal of everybody's
hopes and dreams.
What the hell
are you talking about?
The most fabulous
object in the world.
- That sounds like a good idea.
- Yeah.
They're hooked,
the greedy little fish.
(Kevin) Why do you always
have to go after money?
Who's this?
I don't know, master.
I haven't seen him before.
He's stronger than the rest.
Who is he?
- I don't know.
- I'm losing them.
Something's going on down there.
We've lost them!
Randall, look, over there!
- We'd better move!
- (Randall) Don't rush me.
The forest! It's on fire!
It's raining, pudding head!
- Oh, no!
- What is it?
- It's Him!
Return the map.
- Make for the hole!
- Where is it?
It's over there. Quick! Come on!
- Stop! Return!
- Hurry up!
Return what you
have stolen from me.
Return the map!
There are two holes, Randall.
Which one? Which one?
Go, Kevin! Just get away!
Go! Not that one!
(Grunting, groaning)
(Growling, groaning)
(Groaning continues)
(Horse neighs)
(Growls, groaning)
(Gasping)
(Grunts)
(Growling continues)
(Kevin screaming)
(Kevin gasps, coughs)
(Shrieking)
(Kevin screams)
Where did you come from? Huh?
I'm not quite sure.
Who sent you? The gods?
Was it Zeus? Apollo?
Athena?
(Panting, sighing)
Well, you're certainly a chatty
little fellow, aren't you?
I don't believe it!
You don't believe what?
I don't believe
the way you killed him.
Yes. But it
has to be done sometimes.
No. I mean it was
such a good shot.
I bet you've killed
lots of people.
Well, the gods must
have given you a name.
Oh, yeah. Kevin.
Kevin?
Well, Kevin, here, it's yours.
- What?
- You don't want it?
Oh, yes, please.
You mean I can really have it?
Well, on condition that you
carry it back to the city for me.
Oh, great. But no,
I can't really.
I must wait. You see,
I'm with friends.
You see, if I lose them,
I may never be able to get back.
- (Horse whinnies)
- Get back? To where?
I'm not really sure.
Here, you better take this.
You'll need it. It's water.
There's enough there for your friends,
too, if they ever turn up.
(Horse whinnies)
Oh, and by the way, thank you.
No. Please.
I'd like to come, really.
No, no, please.
I'd like to come.
(Men grunting)
Better? No.
I (Whistles a tune)
(Blows horn)
(Horn)
(Horse neighs)
(Children shouting)
(Crowd cheering)
You saved my life. Remember?
The enemy of the people is dead!
(Cheering)
Hail King Agamemnon!
(Kevin) There's a man being
cut in half here.
It must have been a brilliant battle.
Choo! Choo!
All three are to receive
summary executions today.
If the queen wishes to see me,
I'll be in the courts all afternoon.
Remind the queen that
I still rule this city.
I wish I'd been
in the Trojan Wars.
Will you teach me
how to sword fight?
Come here. I'll teach you
something much more useful.
- Where is it?
- There.
That one.
Kings aren't supposed
to do things like that.
(Camera shutter clicking)
(Clicking continues)
(Crowd chattering)
You know, I never, ever
want to go back.
Don't you want to see
all your friends again?
No, thanks.
To be in your own home, to be
with your own father and mother?
No.
Very well, then.
- I can stay?
- We'll decide that tomorrow.
(Rooster crows)
(Kevin gasps)
(Horse whinnying)
(Cymbals clash)
I have decreed that this boy
shall remain here with us in our city.
Furthermore, he shall
from this day fonNard be my own son...
and heir to the throne
of Mycenae.
(Crowd murmuring)
Let the banquet begin.
(Gong chimes)
(Drum roll)
(Monkey chittering)
(Laughing, murmuring)
(Randall)
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
a masterly miracle of modern
magic before your very eyes.
Abracadee, abracadoo!
- (Laughter)
- You're doing a great job.
If we can borrow this
for a moment, sir.
(Randall) Please give generously
as my assistants pass amongst you.
Thank you very much.
That's very kind.
(Chattering continues)
Come on. Come on.
Now all we need is a volunteer. Yes,
young man, you'll do fine. - No! Please!
(Kevin) No! Leave me!
Come on! Come on!
- No way!
- May I? The crown?
Don't! Help me!
Kevin, let's get out of here!
No! Please, no!
Thank you.
- No! Please!
- Watch this!
We make a great team, don't we?
Now!
(Music stops)
(Cheering, applause)
(Steam whistle blows)
- Alone, at last.
- Isn't it glorious?
Yes. I love the ocean.
God, how I, how I love her.
- She's so, so damn...
- Wet?
Wet. Yes. Yes.
So damn... damn... wet.
Pansy. Pansy, look at me.
- Yes, Vincent?
- Do you love me?
Of course, I love you. - You don't mind
the, the thing on the end of my nose?
- Oh, you mean your... No, darling.
- Yes, my...
(Chuckling) Don't be silly.
Could you share a house
with a chap who has a thing like this
on the end of his nose?
Of course, my love.
Everyone has something odd about them.
- Why, I've got an enormous...
- Pansy!
Pansy, I'm so glad
you feel the way you do.
Because now I can ask you
what I've always wanted to ask you.
Oh, ask me.
Ask me!
Pansy, will you...
Will you...
(Yelling)
(Gulls wailing)
- Where the hell are we?
- (Yelling, chattering)
Someone hit me! Oh!
- Pansy! Pansy!
- (Screaming)
- (Screaming continues)
- Give me that!
You've ruined everything!
Pansy! Pansy, I can explain!
It's only the thing on my nose and the
hairpiece! Everything else is fine!
- (Chattering)
- I (Classical)
Fidgit, you're not supposed
to eat that.
- You're supposed to drink it.
- I like that. It's very nice.
Oh.
Six more plates
of caviar, please.
Anyone else want any?
No, none for me, thank you.
I'll stick with the quail's eyeballs.
The caviar makes me throw up,
you know.
- (Man) Waiter.
- Sorry, Randall. Sorry.
Cheer up, Kevin. Kings aren't
the only ones with money, you know.
The money wasn't important
to him.
He didn't have anything
to spend it on, did he?
Stuck out in Greece... lowest
standard of living in Europe.
- You make me sick!
- (All hooting, laughing)
(Chattering)
What?
Things are looking better all the time.
- I've got something to say to you.
- Go away!
- (Chattering continues)
- It's about the map.
The map?
I don't understand you, Randall.
You've got something
really brilliant like that,
- and you're just wasting it.
- (Scoffs)
I wouldn't call this exactly...
wasting it.
Why couldn't you leave me
where I was happy?
Because when you hear
what I've got planned,
- you're gonna be a lot happier.
- (Glass clinks, water splashes)
I was havin' a close look at the map
last night. Do you know what I found?
Og was right.
The most fabulous object in the world.
It does exist.
Look.
The time of legends... - The time of
legends! There's no such thing.
But there is.
You just gotta believe in it.
Othewvise, Horseflesh
wouldn't have put it on the map.
"In the middle of the time of legends
is a fortress of ultimate darkness,"
and inside the fortress
of ultimate darkness,
"the most fabulous object
in the world."
Give it up, Randall.
- (Chattering continues)
- Look.
- You and me... we got a lot in common.
- (Coughs)
- Not like that lot.
- (Laughing)
We like a risk.
- We like adventure.
- (Coughing continues)
Well, this is it.
This is the big one.
No namby-pamby time holes here.
We risk all. We win everything.
Waiter, more champagne.
Yes, sir.
And plenty of ice.
(Crashing)
(Yelling, screaming)
(Yelling, screaming continue)
(Wally) Hello!
I want to go home!
I can't stand it!
You'll get us all killed,
Randall!
Stop whimpering, Fidgit!
How could I know we were gonna
run slap-bang into an iceberg?
It didn't say "Get off before
the iceberg" on the ticket.
Now... Now is the time...
to star... to start our quest for the...
for the most fabulous object, Randall.
- Og's right! I've got the map.
- No!
- Let's go!
- What?
Randall, we are in the middle
of the Atlantic Ocean!
It doesn't matter where we are.
You just gotta believe in it!
Yüuure Crazy'
- We must try!
- No, don't!
- Abandon plank!
- No!
I can't swim! I can't swim!
(Fidgit) Help! Help!
- Don't worry, Fidgit! I'm coming!
- Help!
' (Laughing) - Help!
- Now we have them!
- Oh, well done. Well done, master.
(Yelling, whimpering)
Suddenly, I feel...
very, very good.
- I'm sorry, master.
- It'll pass. It'll pass.
- Shall I bring them in, master?
- Yes, Benson.
- Bring them into the time of legends.
- (Laughing)
(screaming)
(Screaming continues)
Hey! Hey, I can swim!
Look.
Look!
(Snoring)
(Grunting)
Morning, dear.
(Growling)
- (Back Cracking)
- Ooh!
- (Dwarves, Kevin screaming) Help!
- Who's that?
- What, dear?
- Thought I heard a noise.
No. It's your nerves, dear.
Here we are, darling.
(Groaning)
Come on.
- (Grunting)
- And the ointment for the leg.
I grew too fast
when I was young.
- That was the problem.
- You've been overdoing it a bit, dear.
You try being beastly and terrifying
when you... (Gasping)
you can only get one hour's sleep
a night because your back hurts,
and you daren't cough
in case you pull a muscle.
But you are horrible, dear.
You're just sayin' that.
(Giggling) And gargle.
- (Groaning)
- Come on, now. There's a good fellow.
(G rowls)
(Roaring, gargling)
- What's that?
- I don't know.
- (Gasping, panting)
- Wait for me!
Look at these bloody spots.
That's diet, that is.
- You'll outgrow them, dear.
- Look at all this bloody fish!
(Grunting) There used to be
a time when you could be sure...
of catchin' old boots, cans,
hat racks, boxes.
Now it's prawns
all the bloody time!
Anti-pollution! Wife!
What d'you want, dear?
Do you want the foot powder?
No! Come out here and help me!
- Quick!
- Dear.
- What's in there?
- I don't know, but it's not prawns.
- (Grunting, groaning)
- Here.
Here, dear.
Leave that to me, please.
- Yeah.
- (Yells)
Aren't they lovely?
We can have them for breakfast.
Ah, you mean eat their boots?
No, dear.
I mean, eat all of them.
Every little bit.
That means the big pot
and the large skewers.
- (Whimpering, grunting)
- What shall I do, dear?
Terrify them.
Oh, but what about me back?
Well, you don't have
to jump around.
Just shout horribly...
and leer at them.
You know, the way you used to.
- (Giggling)
- Right.
Right. (Laughing)
Oh, I'm so happy
'cause I'm bus-bus-bus-busy.
Right. (Clears throat)
- (Roaring)
- (Dwarves screaming)
Go away! ' (Whimpering)
(Laughing, roaring)
(Roaring, screaming continue)
Let's see. What have we here?
Some tasty little morsels, eh?
- (Laughing, roaring)
- Help! Get off!
- Hey! Put me down! Put me down!
- (Back Cracking)
(Groaning)
(Grunting) Put me down!
- (Splashing)
- (Roaring continues)
I Yes, it's wonderful
to be making a fondue again.
- (Growling)
- (Screaming)
- Be quiet!
- (Back Cracking)
(Growling, groaning continues)
D-D-Does your back hurt?
- Huh?
- I know a cure for bad backs.
Bad back? Me? An ogre?
- (Laughs, roars)
- (Cracking continues)
- W-What you need I-is stretching.
- Stretching?
I To be melting the cheese
in the southerly breeze.
I To be sharpening
the skewer again I.
- Heave!
- (Screaming)
That's better!
That's better! That's wonderful!
(Laughing) Heave again!
- (Ogre yelling)
- Are they in the pot, dear?
Yeah. Just about.
And one more for luck. Heave!
- Two, three, left, right, left, right!
- Hey, what's going on?
- Left, right!
- (Yelling)
(All yelling)
- (Laughing, cheering)
- Are you all right, dear?
- Oh! Quick! Into the pot!
- Yeah!
Winston?
Winston!
(Knife clattering)
(Door creaking)
Is this part of the Cure?
(Laughing)
- Winston.
- (Winston splashing, laughing)
What are you doing
in the water, dear?
- (Screaming)
- (Laughing continues)
(Laughing)
Oh, my back is wonderful!
- You've got to stop them, Winston!
- (Grunting)
(Coughing)
I can cough!
At last, I can really cough!
(inhales, roars)
(Roaring continues)
- Look out!
- We're going! We're saved!
- Yes! To that side! Quick!
- We're saved!
Catch all! Come on!
(Chattering continues)
- Hold on!
- Hold on tight, Wally!
How're we doing now, Randall?
Just fine.
We're on the right course.
As long as this wind keeps up,
nothing can go wrong.
- (Masts creaking)
- (Splashing)
- Keep the rudder straight, Strutter.
- Lt is straight!
All hands on the tiller!
- Quick! Drop the sail!
- All right! Leave it to me!
(Creaking continues)
Une!
(Dwarf) How about it? Eh?
- I got it.
- (Sighs)
- That's it.
- That's better. We're out of that.
(sighing)
(Creaking)
Randall! Randall?
I think there's something
that you should know.
Everybody below decks!
(Whimpers)
- Come on! Get in here!
- Quick! Get in!
(Baby crying)
(Man and woman arguing
in gibberish)
(Grumbling)
- What's going on?
- You tell me.
(Waves splashing)
(Grumbling, crying continue)
(Arguing continues)
(YellS)
Pull these boards out!
- You might sink the ship!
- Oh, shut up!
- Here's a hammer!
- That's it!
That's it! Now!
- Do it again!
- Harder! Really hard!
(Kevin) Oh, stop him!
(Chattering, grunting)
Drugs! Hey! I've got an idea!
Sleeping potion!
Strutter, take this!
Take the plug out!
Here!
Hey. Yeah!
- Hey.
- Yeah.
- Do it!
- And, heave!
(Grunts)'Squeeze! Squeeze!
(Grunting continues)
(Yelling)
(Yelling continues)
(Yawning)
(Groaning)
Hey! Oh!
(Groaning continues)
Come on! Come!
(Snoring)
(Creaking)
Hey, what's out there?
(Snoring continues)
(Snoring loudly)
Shh! Shh! Shh!
- Come on. Let's go. Run! Run!
- Quick!
The Fortress of Ultimate Darkness
is somewhere over there, I promise you!
Oh, you're joking, Randall.
There's nothing over there!
- Look! We're so close!
- (Laughing)
Y-You've been saying that
for the last 40 miles!
Let's go back!
We'll all die out here!
- Yeah!
- You can't give up now.
- When can we give up?
- Come on. It's just a bit further...
What is it?
I don't know, but it hurts.
It's some kind
of invisible barrier.
Oh! So that's what
an invisible barrier looks like.
It's what this line must be.
And just on the other side,
the Fortress
of Ultimate Darkness.
We've made it, lads! We're here!
You're mad, Randall!
Your brain's gone.
Do you know that?
I promise you, this is it!
We are here!
- We're nowhere, Randall!
- Yeah!
- Look around! There's nothing!
- Yeah.
There's only one way to go now.
- That's right. Back! Come on.
- Right!
- Come on. We're going back.
- No! Listen!
- No! Stop! Stop!
- No, you don't! Get out of the way!
- Listen to me!
- Get out of the way!
You'll never get back
without me.
Do you wanna bet?
- Wally, give that back.
- Get out of the way, Randall.
You give that back,
or I'll take your head off.
Randall! Don't do it!
We have found it!
Thank you.
Brilliant, Evil One.
- Is everything ready?
- Yes, master.
Fantastic.
Amazing.
Magnificent.
(Chattering, gasping)
(Wally) Look.
- (Chains clinking)
- (Crashing)
(Whimpering)
- Move!
- Get out of the road!
(Thunderclap)
Yes, folks. Moderno Designs present
the latest in kitchen luxury:
The Moderna Wonder Major
All-Automatic Convenience Center-ette.
And here they are... the winners of
the most fabulous object in the world.
The answer to all their
problems and yours...
is here for them tonight!
- Chattering)
- Hey!
- Don't go! Where are you going?
- We found it!
Wait! You're mad!
- (Laughing)
- Come back!
(Chattering continues)
- Let's go get it!
- Come on!
Here they come!
So let's give 'em a big welcome!
Trevor, Diane...
Oh, don't they look lovely!
' (Applause) ' Mum!
Dad!
Come on. Lead us in a big hand
for the lucky winners!
- (Applause continues)
- (Chattering continues)
(Kevin) Come back!
- It's a trap!
- Fabulous.
Fabulous.
Here they are. Congratulations.
But before they collect their prize, let's
just have a look at what made it possible...
for them to be here
with us tonight.
The map, please.
(Gasping)
- (Thunderbolt)
- (Laughing)
(All screaming)
(Shouting)
- Let us out!
- (Laughing continues)
(Wally) Let us out! Come back!
I have the map! I have the map!
And the day after tomorrow,
- the world!
- (Thunderbolt)
Oh, no!
- (Screams)
- (Shrieking)
(Squeaking)
- (Squeaking continues)
- (Crunches)
Rat, anybody?
Might be the last meal you get.
No. Leave off!
- That's it, then.
- It's all over.
We could've stayed at home
making trees.
- Oh, shut up.
- How could we have been so stupid?
I don't know.
(Gasps)
Hey! Look, look!
Quick! Come on! Look!
Look at this. Quickly!
- Look!
- Good one of Wally.
No! Look!
It's the map!
I can see it's the map.
What use is that to us now?
Look, closer.
The time of legends, see?
See the Fortress
of Ultimate Darkness?
- That's a hole?
- Exactly!
- It could lead almost anywhere.
- Everywhere!
What?
We just found
the biggest hole in the universe,
and it's practically below
our feet!
Kevin, you're a genius!
- Come on, you lot! Shift!
- We'll never get out of here!
Wanna bet?
No!
That's right, Og. Show 'em we can do
something right for a change.
That's it.
Let's have that.
Give us some more.
That's enough, Wally!
Okay, Strutter.
- Have you got the rope?
- Hold on!
(Grunting) Right.
Hold tight! Keep straight!
- Watch your feet. Watch your feet.
- Easy.
(Grunting) Hold it.
Steady. Watch it. Watch it.
Hold your fingers.
(Muttering)
He's going!
- It's coming.
- Go now.
Ready? And...
(Wally) Again! Again!
(Cheering)
- Ready, Wally!
- Okay, Strutter.
Here we go! Geronimo!
Yeah!
Okay! Go, Strutter!
(Cheering)
- (Randall) Strutter!
- Hey! We've made it!
Okay, Wally.
(Grunting)
Take up the slack.
- Quick, Wally.
- (All chattering)
" Go! ' (Whimpering)"
(Whimpering continues) Come on!
Go, Vermin!
- Go, Fidgit!
- I don't wanna go! I don't wanna go!
[' I'm 90ing] " Go!"
- (Chattering)
- Come on!
- Wally!
- Come on, Wally!
Right, lads! Watch this!
(Grunts)
(Laughing) _ (Rope creaking)
(Yelling)
Wally! ' (Crashing)
Pull the rope.
There he is! (Laughs)
- Wally!
Pull him up! That's it!
(Cheering, chattering)
- Well, we've done it.
- Yeah, we've done it.
- Now all we need is the map.
- What? (Laughing)
We don't need the map. We know where
the time hole is. Let's get out of here.
- Mm Evmlllü mm me map, IIIH.
- Ollhn, damn mht yes..
Last thing we want to do
is see him again. Come on.
But you can't leave it with him,
or he'll destroy the world!
Oh, Robert, Benson,
I feel the power of evil
coursing through my veins,
filling every corner of my being
with the desire to do wrong.
- I feel so bad, Benson.
- Good! Good!
Yes, it is good, for this is the worst
kind of badness that I'm feeling.
- Kill me, master! Kill me!
- Not now, Benson. We have work to do.
No less a work than the overthrowing
of creation itself.
We will remake man
in our image, not His.
We will turn mountains into sea,
and the skies into rivers,
and fjords into deserts.
- Come on! Come on!
- And deserts into quagmires.
The boy's insane.
We can't go in there.
Shh!
Oh!
- Let me see!
- And icebergs into fire!
And the fire into a mighty rushing wind
which will cover the face of the earth...
and wipe clean the scourge of woolly
thinking once and for all.
We can make beans into peas!
Oh, Benson.
Dear Benson, you are so mercifully free
of the ravages of intelligence.
- You say... such nice things, master.
- Yes, I know. I'm sorry.
Now, Benson, I shall have to turn you
into a dog for a while.
Thank you, master.
(Grunting)
Stay, Benson. Guard the map.
Robert, we must plan
a new world together.
This time
we'll start it properly.
Tell me about computers.
Uh, a computer
is an automatic electronic apparatus...
for making calculations.
(Robert)
Or controlling operations...
- (Creaking)
- That are expressible...
in numerical or logical terms.
(Evil)
And fast breeder reactors?
(Robert)
Ah, fast breeder reactors...
use a fast fission process...
for the generation
of fissile isotopes.
(Growling)
(Growling continues)
- Be quiet, Benson!
- (Growling, whimpering)
Show me more, Robert.
Show me...
subscriber trunk dialling.
I must know everything.
(Whimpering)
(Whimpering, barking)
Come on! Throw!
Throw it!
(Scuffling)
Stop!
Come on! Oh, no!
- (Squealing)
- Let's get out of here!
- (Grunting)
- Come on!
Stop them by every means
in my power!
- (Thunderclaps)
- (Shrieking)
(Shrieking continues)
It's coming this way!
Run for it!
I'm coming! I'm coming!
We're trapped.
- We've got to separate.
- What?
Go down the time hole.
Go wherever you can and get help.
- I'll divert them.
- But you can't do it on your own.
No. I'll take one other.
- Well done, Og.
- (Snorts)
Yes. Og and me'll stay. Ready?
- Hey! Hey! This way!
- (Shrieking continues)
- (Snorting)
- (Gasps)
(Shrieking)
You are a very troublesome
little fellow.
I think I should teach you
one of my special lessons.
What do you think, Robert?
(Evil)
Benson, what would look nice?
Half donkey?
Half warthog? Half oyster?
Half carrot?
- Or the diseased left tonsil...
- (Shrieking continues)
Call off those, those creatures,
or I'll destroy the map forever.
- Don't, don't be so stupid.
- Call them off!
Very well.
I have no need of them.
- Robert.
- Yes, master?
Your time has come.
(Gasps)
Oh, wonderful, master! Wonderful!
- Wonderful!
- Don't mention it.
Benson.
(Yelling)
I'm a reasonable man.
Give me the map,
and you might at least walk out
of here on human feet.
Og!
No!
(Squealing)
' No! ' (Laughing)
No!
(Whistle blowing)
(Snorting)
(Horses whinnying)
This way, men. Over there.
- Wally!
- (Gunshots)
(Whinnying)
(Cheering, hooting)
- Where's the trouble, sonny?
- Down there!
(Cowboy) A-ha!
So... this is the best...
the Supreme Being can do.
(Scoffs)
I guess we'll have
a lynchin', eh? Yippee!
(Gunshots, cheering)
- Wait!
- (Gunshots, hooting continue)
Got him!
- (Whinnying)
- See, sonny? No problem.
(Yelling)
(Yelling continues)
Wait a minute! Wait!
Wait a minute! Oh! Oh! Hey!
Hold on! Hey! Hey!
- Let me go!
- I don't feel so good!
I (Carnival)
(screaming)
Fire!
(Laughing)
(Hissing)
- (Grunting)
- Look out!
(screaming)
Charge!
(Tyres screeching, crashing)
(Whinnying)
Strutter! Quick!
Strutter!
Next!
Get him!
Randall, go!
Go!
- I can't control it!
- Of course you can't, you silly man.
I control them!
(Randall) Hurry! Help me!
(Yelling continues)
(Wally) Get me down!
Stay where you are!
Something's happening!
(Whimpering)
Get out of the way, Fidgit!
Get out of the way!
(screaming)
Fidgit!'Hey! Hey, Fidgit!
Fidgit!
Quick! Push it off him!
Push it off. Quick.
- He's dead.
- What?
Fidgit's dead.
(Whimpering) Oh, no. I'm sorry.
- It wasn't your fault, Wally.
- Lt was, it was his fault.
- Get down, Wally!
- Get down!
- Wally! Get down, Wally!
- Evil!
- (All shouting at once)
- Come on back!
Evil! He killed my friend!
I'll kill him! Get off me!
Get down!
- (Shouting continues)
- I'll kill him!
(Laughing)
(Whimpering)
Huh?
- Oh, no!
- He's found us!
Quick! Run for it!
Oh! I hate
having to appear like that.
Really,
it's the most tiresomely...
noisy manifestation.
Still, rather expected
of one, I suppose.
Get down! Get down!
O Great One! O Supreme Being!
O Creator of all the universe,
without whom we would be naught
but scarab beetles on the...
What a dreadful mess!
Ls the pig with you?
(Snorts)
Right.
Well, we'll sort him out first.
' (squealing) - og!
- Og, here! Quick! Out of the way!
- I was enjoying that.
One thing I can't stand,
it's mess.
I want all this stuff picked up.
(All) Yes, sir.
Anything you say.
- Anything you say, sir.
- Wally, tidy up!
But, but he's dead, Randall.
Fidgit, Fidgit's dead.
Dead?
No excuse for laying off work.
- Fidgit.
- (Whispering) Fidgit.
Fidgit? ' (Cheering)
- What happened?
- I'm sorry I killed you, Fidgit.
He's okay! He's okay!
Oh, do hurry up.
- Oh, yes, sir.
- Yes, sir.
I'd like to explain everything.
We didn't mean to steal the map.
We didn't mean to run away...
What do you mean, you didn't
mean to steal the map?
- It, it just sort of...
- Of course you didn't mean to steal it.
I gave it to you.
You silly man. And that.
- Do you really think I didn't know?
- Sir?
I had to have some way
of testing my handiwork.
I think it turned out
rather well.
' Don't you? 'Hmm?
Evil turned out rather well.
Mm-hmm.
Whose are these?
Mine, sir.
They're mine, sir.
You really are an untidy boy.
Sign... here.
Do you mean you knew
what was happening to us all the time?
Well, of course.
I am the Supreme Being.
- I'm not entirely dim.
- Oh, no, sir.
We're not suggesting that, sir.
It's just...
That I let you borrow my map.
Now I want every bit of Evil...
placed in here.
- Right away.
- Of course, sir.
Come on.
You mean you let all those people die,
just to test your creation?
Yes.
You really are a clever boy.
Why did they have to die?
You might as well say,
"Why do we have to have evil?"
Oh, we wouldn't dream of asking
a question like that, sir.
Yes. Why do we have
to have evil?
Ah.
- I think it's something to do with freewill.
- (Dwarves grunting)
Do be careful.
You weren't watching.
Don't lose any of that stuff.
That's concentrated evil.
One drop of that could turn
you all into hermit crabs.
I'm sorry, sir.
I, I was just wondering
if there's, um,
any chance we might
have our old jobs back, sir.
Oh, you certainly were
appallingly bad robbers.
Yes, sir.
I really should do something
very extrovert and vengeful with you.
Honestly, I'm too tired.
But I think I'll just transfer you
to the undergrowth department...
yes, bracken, small shrubs...
that sort of thing...
with a 19% cut in salary
backdated to the beginning of time.
- Thank you, sir.
- Oh, thank you, sir.
Well, I am the nice one.
Is it all ready? Right!
Come on, then. Back to creation.
- I mustn't waste any more time.
- Bye, Kevin.
They'll think I've lost control
again and put it all down to evolution.
- Come on.
- Sir?
Yes? - What about my friend, sir?
Can he come with us?
No, of course not.
This isn't a school outing.
But, sir, he deserves something.
- I mean, without him...
- Oh, don't go on about it.
- He's got to stay here to carry on the fight.
- Fidgit!
(Randall) Come on. Fidgit!
Hey! You can't go!
- Hey, you can't leave me!
- Fidgit!
- Fidgit, come on!
- Wait, please!
- Come on, Fidgit!
- Hey! Stop!
Hey! Hey! Don't leave me!
Hey! Help! Stop!
(Coughing)
Don't go! Help! Don't leave me!
Hey! Don't go! Stop!
- Don't leave me! Please! Wait!
- (Siren wailing)
(Coughing)
Don't leave me! Please!
(Siren stops)
(Crashing)
Come on! Come on!
(Fireman) Let's go!
- (Coughing)
- (Sirens wailing)
- Let go! I've got to save it!
- Don't be a fool, Diane!
- I'm going in for the toaster!
- No! No!
- Oh, Trevor!
- Me super deluxe steamer!
(Diane) Om.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah.
I think so. (Coughing)
You're a very lucky boy.
Honestly, Trevor.
If you'd been half a man,
you'd have gone in there
after the blender.
(Siren fading)
- This is what started it.
- Eh?
Left the Sunday joint
cookin' all night, didn't we?
Sunday joint? It's Thursday.
I never touched it!
(Diane) Well, someone put it on.
Well, there was no meat
in there last night.
Oh! Well, what do you
call this then?
Mum! Dad!
It's Evil!
Don't touch it!
(Siren wailing)
Mum?
Dad?
I (Singing)
I Midnight sunshine.
I Silence under sky
is black as day.
I Only a dream away.
I (Singing)
I Waking while you're still
deep sleeping.
I Finding you're not here.
I Watchin' a dream appear.
I Tumbling through.
I A thousand centuries.
I You don't know
where you'll land.
I It's so dark in mythology.
I Treasures of history.
I To be found.
I Within the legends of time.
I All the handiworks we made.
I Were only a dream away.
I (Singing)
I Greedy feeling.
I Wheeling, dealing.
I Losin' what you won.
I See the dream come undone.
I Stumble you may
with your mentoring.
I Lucky you got so far.
I All you owe is apologies.
I Measure the mystery.
I And the sound.
I It's like taking up time.
I it shows the handiworks
we've made.
I Only a dream away.
♪ (Singing) I
(Laughter, chattering)
(Laughter and chattering continues)
© anoXmous
@ https://thepiratebay.se/user/anoXmous