This is Chu Tu.
He's in his mid to late forties.
He's a nightclub owner, trader,
and property developer.
But we've found out all his companies
are losing money.
Hey, how are things up there?
This is Mad Wing, his bodyguard.
All of his employees
are actually hit men.
Be careful!
I'll see you at the dye factory.
Wait for me up there.
This is Danny Chu, his nephew. He's
always surrounded by bodyguards.
This is John Ko, the brains
behind Chu Tu's organisation.
This lady's name is Salina Fong.
She's only joined Chu Tu recently.
It's hard for us at this point to tell how much
she knows about Chu Tu's business.
Our mission is to arrest
all these drug dealers.
The code name is Operation Boar Hunt.
- Have you got that?
- Yes, sir!
Read your orders.
You all have specific duties.
Memorize then destroy.
It's crucial that you stay in position.
Hurry, come on!
Attention. Attention.
This is strategic headquarters.
Begin the operation at once.
I'll get you a cup of milk tea.
- Two cups of milk tea, please!
- OK!
I'll be back for them.
There is a suspicious looking guy.
Two cups of milk tea, please!
Tell the others, I'll check it out.
- Big Mouth Kam!
- You have one cup for me?
- We've been discovered.
- What?!
Follow the guy in the red top.
What is it?
Salina here! Ah Kuen said there
are two suspicious guys here...
- What are you doing?
- Police!
Police harassment!
The police are here!
Freeze!
What's happening?
- They've opened fire!
- Let's break up the crowd first.
Leave this area now!
Crime squad.
Why is this happening?!
Police!
Get back into the house.
Go on! Hurry!
Listen! Watch out for civilians and explosives.
And be especially mindful of kids!
Hurry up, kid!
Get out of here!
- Move in and help.
- But we're supposed to stay put.
The situation's changed. Move it!
- Let me go!
- It gets tighter if you move.
Let me go!
Uncle, it's dangerous here! You leave first!
Quick, cover the boss!
There's a female suspect up there.
Take her back to the station.
It's
me!
- Why did they open fire?
- Don't ask me.
Calm down!
Tak! Cover me!
Tak!
You must stay calm.
Help me.
Don't get nervous.
They mean business!
Don't forget the warning.
Mind the villagers.
But will the bad guys
give a damn about them?
Why would we be cops, then?
Come here!
Be careful, Ka Kui.
They are fearless.
Boss! This way!
Get in!
You're blocking the road!
Get out of the way!
Reverse!
Not good, not good!
- You OK?
- This way's blocked, go back.
Go back! Quick!
Go back up!
The road below is blocked!
- We're stuck, boss! Now what?!
- We fight our way down!
Let's go!
Boss!
Get out of the car!
This way!
Freeze!
Stop shooting!
Mind the civilians!
Where have you been?
Isn't this your position?
- We went up to help.
- Who gave that order? They're gone!
What do you mean by that?
Hurry, go!
Let me borrow this!
Tell them to get down.
Don't let them see my face.
Tell the driver to step on it!
Get down!
Turn here, turn!
- Keep going!
- Easy, boss, we'll make it.
- Look!
Get up there, and get rid of him.
Tell the driver to go faster!
Come down here and get him.
Come down!
Turn the bus! Go down the hill!
Are you nuts?
You're in the middle of the road!
Police. Stay back!
- Boss, the bastard's right in front!
- Run over him!
Step on it, run over him.
No need to be afraid!
Freeze!
You're under arrest,
but you have the right to...
If you let me go...
this is all yours.
A once-in-a-three-lifetimes chance,
no one will ever find out.
Smart guy!
Stop!
Well done, you guys.
Act modest when he praises you.
Don't let it go to your head.
I'm used to this kind of stuff.
You'd better tell that to Ka Kui.
I didn't do it alone. It was a
success because of careful planning.
That's a great line. Don't forget
to say it when Raymond comes.
He'll be very happy to hear that.
Operation Boar Hunt
was carefully planned.
You were told to go in
and make the arrest.
You almost let the prime suspect
get away.
What happened?
Didn't Chou give you clear orders?
Yes, but he said the operation
was very well planned.
What?!
This operation was carefully planned.
But it had a few flaws.
Why were there flaws?
The flaws must have occurred
before we got to the store.
Ka Kui couldn't handle the secretary,
and she made a mess of things.
How could Chu Tu get away?
That was your post!
What do you mean by that?
Don't point your fingers
at each other.
- What?!
- The PR lady is here.
Show her in.
The press is here,
Superintendent Li.
- Tell them no comment!
- Hold it.
- I asked them to come.
- Then tell them to wait.
- Ka Kui, you'll be our spokesman.
- Me?!
- I can't possibly.
- The speech is ready, just read it.
Learn your lines
and don't botch them.
Inspector Man,
you can go now.
The Chief is well pleased
with Ka Kui's performance.
They want to use him in PR.
After the speech, take him
to do a police recruitment poster.
And arrange for him to appear on TV.
In other words,
making him a role model?
The Chief thinks
he's a model policeman.
He'll be really good for it.
What are the charges on Salina?
Drug dealing, resisting arrest
and assaulting police officers.
- Drop all the charges.
- Really?!
You played a big part
in this operation.
The success of this operation
depended on skilful planning.
Good job.
Will you get a promotion?
As a police officer,
I don't fight crime to get promoted.
Our superiors
take care of promotions.
Did Chu Tu try to bribe you?
He sure did, with millions.
He could have bribed the whole force.
Just kidding! Don't put that down.
Can you two sit closer?
- What are you doing?
- Just saying hello.
Don't sit too close.
Let me sit here.
- He'll come this way, right?
- Yeah!
Let's start!
Straighten up your back.
Open your eyes a bit more.
Open your mouth. Wider.
Wider!
Forget it, just be yourself!
Ready?!
The handcuffs in the middle.
Try to be more energetic.
- Your plan wouldn't work.
- Why not?
She's Chu Tu's secretary.
She won't cooperate with us that easily.
Chu Tu's been arrested
and once he knows
his secretary is going to be
a witness, what will he do?
He'll do everything he can
to stop her appearing in court.
Whoever we send to protect her
will be in danger.
If you want to live to see 100,
don't become a cop.
Put that line
on one of our recruitment posters.
We don't have enough evidence to
prosecute him.
We must push him into a corner.
Then we can put him behind bars.
I'd like to suggest one person
to protect our lady witness.
I have someone in mind already.
Are we thinking of the same person?
Good luck to him.
I don't understand why you
were the only one freed on bail.
You're really lucky.
- They're here to see Superintendent Li.
- Please wait.
- Right.
You can leave after you've seen him.
- You can go in now.
- Thanks!
Please sit down!
You can leave now, Miss Fong.
Wait a second.
Please keep this subpoena,
you'll need it to appear in court.
- What's the charge?
- Nothing!
But you'll be acting
as our witness.
I'm sorry!
My client isn't going to do that.
We're not asking her.
According to law, she can't refuse it.
- Inspector Chan!
- Yes, sir.
Your job is to protect Miss Fong
until she appears in court.
- Me? Protect her?
- Why not?
- Great!
- I don't need his protection.
As long as he doesn't harass you,
you can't refuse.
Inspector Chan.
As an escort of the witness,
you must be aware
that witnesses are often faced with
threat, disturbance and assault,
or irritated
by the intentions of such.
It is your duty to see her safety
and personal rights are intact.
Yes, sir!
But can you send someone else?
You'll get expenses
for this assignment.
$32.80 per day.
It's an old tradition,
unchanged for years.
Bring your own money.
That's all.
Can we talk to you alone, Miss Fong?
My client doesn't answer questions
without the presence of her lawyer.
We won't ask her any questions.
This is not an interrogation,
just a few suggestions for her benefit.
- You have the right to refuse this.
- Let me see what they have to say.
Counsel Cheung!
Please excuse us.
You don't have to answer if they ask
you any questions about the case.
- Get out of here!
- I have to go, too?
You've got high rank?
What do you want to talk to me about?
Miss Fong, we have no further questions.
You can go now.
See you in court.
They're...
Let's go.
Ka Kui.
- Get it on tape if you can.
- OK.
- What did they say to you?
- They didn't say anything.
- I'm your lawyer, you can trust me.
- They didn't say a word to me.
- Why was it only her...
- They're coming!
- How's our boss?
- I can't bail him or the others out.
- What about Salina, then?
- She's their witness.
- What? Really?!
- They want me to do it.
You'd do that
just because they asked?
Stop bothering our witness!
- Who are you?
- I'm a cop!
My duty is to protect her.
If you don't stop your bullshit, I can charge
you with interfering with the police.
Salina...
You can only say
"see you" or "bye-bye".
One more word
and you're under arrest.
- I'll take you home.
- That's part of my job.
I'll tell them nothing!
- Now what, Counsel Cheung?
- I'll see your boss this afternoon.
All right! Let's go!
It's dangerous for you
to hang around outside.
- Let's go home, shall we?
- It's none of your business.
It's for your own safety.
I don't need your protection,
you parasite!
You know what happened to the
other four witnesses who said that?
What happened?
Were they shot? Don't try to
scare me. Tell me what happened.
You guessed right.
They're all actually okay.
- You have the right to say so.
- Scaring me?!
All the evidence
is against the defendants.
Only your situation is better.
We're depending on you,
Counsel Cheung.
I'll do my best.
You'd better be prepared for
bad news. The chances are slim.
If I walk away free,
you'll be rewarded.
There's still something
we need to worry about.
- Salina is their witness.
- Is she really?!
She's been granted bail.
The police even gave her a bodyguard,
the guy who arrested you.
Salina hasn't joined me that long.
She doesn't know much.
That doesn't concern me.
But she could say something bad
about us in court.
I don't think she would... All right.
Call Danny for me.
Tell him to take care of Salina.
All right.
- Thanks a lot!
- Keep the change!
See you later!
- It's dangerous to stay home alone.
- I like to see how dangerous it will be.
- John? I just got back.
- The phone is tapped.
All right, I'll meet you later.
I'm really scared!
You think you can scare me like that?
Help!
I'm going to kill you!
You can't escape!
You're finished!
I'm going to kill you!
I'll get you!
Don't run away!
Can't escape now, can you?
You're finished!
There's no way out. You're finished.
I'm going to kill you!
Don't worry!
I'm here to rescue you!
She's terrified. Can I go now?
You can prepare to
leave now.
Hold on to him, I'll call the police.
The phone line!
Go now!
I knocked him out!
Not yet!
He's still conscious.
He's fighting me!
Keep away from us!
Please go now.
You can't stay here any longer.
He's passed out!
No! He's still conscious. See?
Please leave here right now!
Go now! Go on!
Go! Hurry!
Leave him to me!
- He's fainted.
- Let me hit him one more time!
If you smash his face,
we'll have a problem identifying him.
- But...
- I don't want to do this any more.
I don't know him.
- They'd use a stranger to kill you.
- Why kill me?
Of course,
Chu Tu's a ruthless man.
Inspector Chou, it's Ka Kui.
I just realized this is a tough case.
Can you send a replacement? No?!
I'm not risking my life for this job.
I might as well hire myself out
as a mercenary.
She?!
Let her fend for herself!
I quit!
Enough is enough!
- Where are you going?
- Home!
- You're supposed to protect me!
- But you're not cooperating.
- How do you want me to cooperate, then?
- It's too late! I quit.
I can't believe that
you cops have no sense of duty.
But there's nothing I can do.
If I stay here, we'll just die together.
I'll cooperate.
Don't feel forced.
I'm doing it of my own free will.
You should come to my house,
it's much safer there.
- Okay, let's go.
- Like this?
- I'll get changed!
- Chu's men could be back any time.
I won't change my clothes, then.
Now what?
What is it?!
I'm checking
to see if everything's OK.
Go back!
You can come out.
- Why are you holding that?
- I'm holding the jacket for you.
I told you to put it on.
Follow me!
Use my car.
- All these cars are yours?
- No, it's that one.
- Why are you not nervous at all?
- I'm used to situations like this.
- I told you to stay quiet, didn't I?
- Now what?
- Are you all right?
- My son!
Close the car door!
It's me! Give me my gun!
It's in my jacket pocket.
Help!
I've got you!
Freeze!
Stay calm!
Give me the gun.
- Stay calm!
- Keep away!
Give me the gun!
It's me!
- Are you all right?
- Where are they?
You scared them off with that shot.
We must get you away from here,
those guys are for real.
For real?
What about before?
That was real too,
but this is more real.
- So that's why you're more nervous.
- Get in the car.
- So you are capable of crying?
- I didn't expect that Uncle Tu would treat me like this.
Don't be naive.
People like him are capable of anything.
Evil to the bone! He'll see to it that you
won't be in court.
What should I do then?
Speak out in court tomorrow.
Put him in jail,
and you'll be safe.
Speak out about what, exactly?
What business he's in,
who his contacts are,
the number of drug deals.
Why are you taping this?
It's my way of taking notes.
When did you start working for him?
Four years ago.
He's a family friend. Mom said he always
lent us money to buy milk powder.
- So now you help him sell drug powder.
- I know very little.
Then just tell what you know.
Anything else you want to add,
tell me later upstairs.
Have I said enough
to put him away?
I'm not the prosecutor,
but what you've said will be useful.
Come in.
Here.
Let me turn on the lights.
It's May.
I almost forgot today's my birthday.
Are you all right?
Let me introduce you,
this is Miss Fong.
- Are you all right?
- I'm fine. May!
They've all gone?
That was quick!
It's all my fault.
She wanted to surprise you,
but you brought a girl home.
And I'm dressed like this.
Of course she's angry.
I can be angry too!
Wouldn't even let me explain.
Left me the whole cake.
This time I won't forgive her,
even if she calls me back.
I don't think she will.
I knew she would be back!
Happy birthday!
What's so happy about it?
Why did May fly out in such a rage?
- She saw me bring home the female witness.
- I'll go and explain to her.
No need.
Have her reflect on her faults.
I have to explain to my boss.
I have to explain to the suspect.
I'm sick and tired of explaining!
Do you want some cake?
Something to drink?
- Orange juice, please!
- Help yourself!
You live by yourself?
So that the ICAC can investigate how
I can afford such a big place?
I share it with my friend,
but he's on holiday.
I'm really sorry.
Your girlfriend must be angry with me.
Never mind that.
It's all part of the job.
Come on! Come in!
You'll be all right. I'm leaving.
See you!
I'm just a cop now.
But I might become a movie star
and have to kiss ladies passionately.
She'd have to hang herself
three times a day!
She's jealous because she loves you.
I'll explain to her if I can.
What for? She's such a narrow-minded girl,
it'll only spoil her.
Aren't you going to think of
something nice to say to her?
Not a chance. If I started sweet-talking,
girls would be queuing from here to Tsim Sha Tsui.
She'd have to wait her turn.
Don't you like her?
To be honest,
I do love her a lot!
But that's no reason
for me to apologize to a girl.
I know she's going to call back
to say how sorry she is.
What a waste.
See? Can't get home fast enough,
now she's probably calling from the street.
Hello? Hello?
- Is that your girlfriend?
- Yes. She's speechless with tears.
There's no use crying.
You should have behaved yourself.
What misunderstanding?! If I was protecting
a man, you'd think I was gay.
Go and reflect on your faults.
- Let me explain to her.
- No need!
You need to promise
to control your temper.
Show me some respect in front of my friends.
Stop crying. Bye-bye!
I had to use this opportunity
to teach her a lesson.
- When did she come in?
- When you said she would hang herself three times.
So she heard everything?
The phone call.
What a dirty trick.
May! May!
Let me explain. She's our witness,
my job is to protect her.
I'm not angry about that.
I'm angry about what you just said!
You know I was only kidding.
I always call first whenever we have a fight, don't I?
You insulted me in front of another girl!
You made me lose face!
- Go away!
- Please listen to me! May!
- Are you all right?
- Go away! Happy now? It hurts.
Not happy!
My heart's hurting.
I'll get the shoes for you.
Put them on first.
Go away!
- Please listen to me!
- No, I don't want to!
- Listen to me, will you?
- Let go!
- I hate you!
- Be careful.
Where's your girlfriend?
I accepted her apology,
so she went home happy.
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
It hurts.
It's breaking! Easy!
It's breaking!
What is this ugly thing?
Get rid of it.
What? Get rid of it?
This is my precious.
You got me all wet!
I'll wipe it off for you.
It's ticklish! No, don't!
Not there, here.
- Here?!
- Yeah!
Be gentle!
You're so rough.
This sofa is so uncomfortable.
Can we go to bed?
Okay, going to bed is good.
- But where can I sleep?
- On my bed.
- And you?
- Next to you.
Using such a method to protect me.
I like it.
I'm going to sleep now.
Don't disturb me.
Women are strange!
Ka Kui? Wait a second.
Uncle Bill, it's him.
- Hurry, they're waiting at the court.
- He's out already. Maybe there's a jam.
Stop pretending! Hurry!
Bring the witness.
What was your duty on that day?
I was observing the squatter huts
behind the site.
There were about
a dozen suspects getting away.
I arrested the sixth
and seventh defendants.
Thank you!
Can I ask the witness a question?
Mr Kam, you said you saw a
dozen suspects escaping.
Did all 13 suspects
pass in front of you one by one,
or did you have a new electronic device
that let you see
all the action at once?
I object! The question twists the witness's
statement to undermine his credibility.
Overruled!
Thank you!
No more questions!
Call the next witness
for the prosecution.
- You took my spot!
- I'm in a hurry!
Stayed here any longer,
and I'd kick your ass!
Nice parking, though.
What?! She's gone?
What kind of bodyguard are you?
- Now what? I can't imagine.
- We'll lose for sure.
How could you be so sure that one of
the escaping suspects was my client?
He had the same clothes.
In other words, you didn't have a
clear view of the suspects' faces.
You could say that.
- Are you short-sighted?
- No, I'm not.
All right.
No more questions.
Next witness.
I swear to tell the truth.
I was at the squatter huts
for the operation.
The first, second, third
and fourth defendants opened fire.
I saw them jump on a bus.
So I took a short cut
and went down the hill.
A citizen helped me
to stop the bus with his car.
After the bus stopped,
I arrested the first defendant.
He tried to bribe me, but I refused.
That'll do.
That was very clear.
Thank you!
Inspector Chan,
you said you were at the squatter house.
- What time was that?
- About 6:00 am.
- What time exactly?
- 5:55 am.
Let's say 6:00 am.
In December in Hong Kong, do you know
that sunrise is at 6:23 am?
I didn't know.
- Is that true?
- How would I know?
Do you know the saying
"Darkness before dawn"?
No, I don't.
The saying means that it's dark
before the sun rises.
- I might have heard of it.
- All right.
If there wasn't much light,
should we believe
you could actually see my client?
Believe it or not, it's your business.
You shouldn't ask me.
You said you ran down the hill
to stop the bus.
- Did or did you not lose sight of the bus?
- I did not.
- Why hesitate?
- I want to be sure.
- You have doubts?!
- I object.
Sustained. The witness should be sure
of his answer.
How long did it take you
to go down the hill?
And was the bus always in sight?
For a while my view
was blocked by the hill.
Could it be that another bus
overtook the first one at that point?
- There was only one bus!
- You're lying!
I object!
Sustained!
Defense should rephrase his question.
- So are you lying?
- No!
There are four different bus routes
on that road.
On two routes,
the buses run every five minutes.
On the other two,
the buses run every six minutes.
So 88 buses run back and forth
on that road every hour.
- That's more than one bus a minute.
- I didn't know.
How long did it take you
to go down the hill?
About two minutes.
- Can you be more precise?
- Two and a half minutes.
50 two or three buses would have gone by,
maybe as many as seven or eight!
But you said there was one.
I say you're lying.
Haven't you ever waited for a bus
for half an hour?
All right. Let's give you
the benefit of the doubt.
Assume there was one bus
and you could see it all the time.
Which part was clearly visible
to you?
- The body.
- How much of the body?
- All of it!
- You're lying!
What's he doing?
You could see only one side of
this bus. At most, only half of it.
You couldn't see the other half.
- Am I right?
- Yeah.
And anything could have happened
on the side you couldn't see.
So if someone jumped off,
you couldn't see him, could you?
- No.
- Speak louder.
I could have jumped off, he couldn't.
Just answer the question.
You think just anyone
can jump off a bus?
Inspector Chan,
calm down please!
- Why did he want to bribe me, then?
- How did he bribe you?
He said I could have
the case of money if I let him go.
If it was you and someone pointed
a gun at you, what would you do?
Objection overruled!
Answer him!
- I'd give him all my money.
- That's what happened to my client.
- Am I right?
- No, I'd already identified myself.
There are many cases where
criminals pose as policemen.
I object!
Sustained!
Court will ignore that remark.
Confine yourself to this case.
I'm sorry!
Consider this, a businessman is
carrying company cash on a bus.
A policeman chasing robbers stops
the bus and points a gun at him.
So the businessman thinks
the policeman is a crook.
So he tells the policeman
to take the cash and let him go.
Inspector Chan,
isn't that right?
The witness doesn't
need to answer.
We already know the answer. He
doesn't need to say it. I conclude.
Wonderful!
- Now what?
- I know what to do.
- It's not fair to let him go free.
- Of course.
Your Honor, we request
an adjournment.
Our prime witness was delayed.
The Crown has failed
to establish a case.
There is insufficient evidence
to convict my client.
- I request a dismissal.
- Your Honor.
We have taped evidence
from our witness.
Tapes can't be accepted as evidence.
That tape is key to this case.
I will not adjourn or postpone
the hearing.
That would be unfair
to the defendant.
I will grant him bail.
But we will hear that tape first.
This case is not over yet.
Please turn up the volume.
It was taped with a small recorder.
It's an old tape, Your Honor.
Please keep listening.
It's coming up!
What are you doing?
- Nothing.
- It hurts.
It’s breaking! Easy!
It’s breaking!
- What is this ugly thing? Get rid of it.
- This is my precious.
It's only a cactus!
You got me all wet!
- I'll wipe it off for you.
- It’s ticklish! No, don't!
I spilled the orange juice!
It wasn't what you think.
This sofa is so uncomfortable.
Can we go to bed?
- Okay, going to bed is good.
- But where can I sleep?
On my bed.
- And you?
- Next to you.
Using such a method to protect me...
Come on!
Don't get too close.
No photographs!
Ka Kui!
Give me a report of the whole case.
Yes, sir.
Boss!
No pictures!
John, reserve a room
at the country club
so that we can
make a toast to justice.
- I'm leaving now.
- Thank you very much!
Next time let's hire him
as prosecutor.
This is Crime Story.
I’m so happy to see you all again.
Our guest today is
a brave police officer.
Sitting next to me is
Inspector Chan Ka Kui.
- Hello!
- Hello! Hello everyone!
After cracking a big drug case,
you’ve become very popular
among the people.
Would you share this particular
experience with us?
The success of this operation
was due to teamwork.
I was just a part of it.
We were well prepared for
the operation.
What makes your department so special
in the police force?
To be one of us, you have to be
strong, alert, smart, and...
- Boss.
- What's up?!
His photo is all over
the papers and magazines.
He's even been nominated
for some awards.
BRAVE POLICEMAN
ARRESTS DRUG TYCOON
And our Thai source is out of stock.
Why?
They've all changed jobs?
No, but all the goods
have gone to Uncle Seven.
They want cash.
Boss, Counsel Cheung is here.
Please come in.
Mr Chu, I've received your check.
Thanks a lot!
I should thank you!
How's my case now?
All evidence must remain
with the court until the case ends.
That means I can't get
my stuff back yet?
Your passport and bank account.
You can't use them now.
If you're found guilty,
your assets will be confiscated.
I won't even have
enough money to escape.
- Phone call for you, boss.
- Excuse me!
Salina.
It's boring here.
I want to go somewhere else.
Not just yet.
- Can I come and see you?
- Not now.
You should stay where you are.
The police are looking for you.
I'm planning a trip to Europe for you.
Once you're there, you'll be fine.
You just have to wait.
It’s for your own good.
Hello? Hello?
- Where were we?
- We were lucky to bail you out.
It would have been different
if they had found Salina.
I doubt they'll ever
be able to find her.
Very well. I must leave. See you.
Counsel Cheung is right.
Salina's a big problem.
You can't hide her forever.
Snake Eyes says that that stupid cop
is looking for Salina everywhere.
- We should send her abroad.
- She must never return.
Let's use that stupid cop
to kill Salina.
There are lots of other
beautiful girls, Boss.
We've got all those beauty pageants
in Hong Kong every year.
Inspector Man wants to see you.
Let him in.
We paid him, didn't we?
Paid him $100,000. But he says he wants
to retire and start a business.
- What does that mean?
- He wants more money!
This way, Inspector Man.
- Inspector Man.
- Mr. Chu.
- Sit down.
- I'm OK.
- I came to see you about...
- Yes, I know.
You want to retire
and start a business. Good idea.
- Thank you.
- I know you're a smart guy.
- But I want one more favor.
- What is it?
I want that brave cop
to disappear for good.
You want glory,
I'll give you glory.
I'll book you for that!
SUPERINTENDENT
- 1985, come on patrol with me.
- Yes, sir!
Inspector Chan!
If anything happens - usually not -
you can reach me...
By calling you on the radio?
- Call me at home.
- But you'll be on patrol.
But I can pass by my house
even though I'm on patrol.
Colleague!
I need to go to the toilet,
you stay here.
Don't break it.
Sha Tau Kok Station.
You called me,
Inspector Chan?
Of course,
any information?
On Salina? I need more time.
It's a tough job.
Tough? Tough to get paid too.
I will do it.
I'll do my best.
What? Wait a second!
Sha Tau Kok Station, wait.
- I'll give you three days, Snake Eyes.
- Three days?
That's not enough time.
What, more?
Four days, then.
If I get transferred back to Kowloon,
you'll be in trouble.
That's it for now.
That's it for now!
- Who are you looking for?
- How dare you talk to me like that, Ka Kui!
You want to speak to Inspector Chan?
Hold on.
- Your call, Inspector Chan.
- Right, thanks!
- Hello, who are you looking for?
- This is May.
- Who was that rude guy?
- Yeah, he's quite impolite. Let me scold him.
Lau, didn't I tell you to be polite
on the phone?! You're so rude!
I'm sorry,
Inspector Chan's friend.
Okay.
I've scolded him.
- What is it, May?
- What are you doing now?
Me? I'm speaking to you
on the phone.
- Have you eaten yet?
- Not yet.
I'm cooking some
instant noodles.
- Have you eaten, then?
- No.
Wait a minute.
Sha Tau Kok Station, hold on.
May?
Mom wants to have you over for dinner.
Are you free on Sunday?
Is that so? Any time.
- Sha Tau Kok Station.
- My husband beat me up!
- What? What about your husband?
- He beat me up!
- Who's beating who up?
- My husband’s beating me up!
Don't cry. I'll put you through
to a different department.
May, I'm free on Sunday.
Don't hang up.
The line's busy.
I'm still connecting you.
Sha Tau Kok Station, speak up.
I ’ve lost a cow.
I'll connect you to Missing Persons.
The line's still busy.
- Sha Tau Kok Station.
- I was raped!
What? You've been raped?
I have to write down the details.
When were you raped?
I wasn’t raped,
I was beaten up by my husband!
Oh! It's you,
I'm still connecting your call.
- It’s taking so long!
- It's a big police station. Be patient.
Who's been raped?
- Me!
- I’ve lost a cow!
The cow has to wait.
- When were you raped?
- Last year!
Last year?
Why report it now?
- Are there any morning after pills I can take?
- Pills?!
I'll find out for you.
- Hello, Missing Persons Department.
- I've lost a cow.
Bring in a photo of the cow,
and I'll help you find it.
May, I'm very busy. She wants me
to name a place for dinner?
Give me a minute first.
- Where shall we go?
- The Family Planning Clinic.
Tell her to take double portions.
It's free.
May?
Tell my mom to take pills?
Give it to your mom instead!
What?! May!
Tell my mom to take the pills?
Hello? Hello?
She isn't pregnant.
- Sha Tau Kok Station.
- This is a test by the telephone company.
Testing the phone?
- Was there a traffic jam again?
- No, not a traffic jam.
Then why?
If there was a jam,
I wouldn't be here yet.
You knew we are having
dinner today at my place.
My mom hates people
who are late.
I've been waiting several days
for Snake Eyes to phone.
You're off that case.
It's no longer your business.
Not my business?
Let me return this call first.
Hold on to the car.
The hand brake is broken.
Hold on to it.
It's me, Snake Eyes.
Chu Tu's hiding that witness you're
looking for in his villa at Rosary Village.
Where?
Hurry up, or Chu Tu will
kill her any minute now.
No kidding?
I wouldn't kid you. Hurry.
Don't tell me you're cancelling!
Chu's going to kill the witness.
I have to go and rescue her.
Don't go!
If she's dead, Chu is going to walk.
You know what Chu has done to me?
It's a matter of life and death.
- What's up?
- The car!
- What now?!
- Taxi!
Call a tow truck!
And say sorry to my future
mother-in-law for me. Bye-bye!
Be careful!
- Keep the change.
- Thanks!
- What happened?
- I don't know why they tied me up here.
- Is anyone else here?
- They all left after tying me up.
Now you know what kind
of a man Chu is.
If only you had cooperated with us,
there wouldn't be so much trouble.
Luckily, I'm well-informed.
Or else you'd be dead
without anyone knowing.
Let's get out of here.
Stop!
Freeze!
Step aside.
How did you know I was here?
Of course I knew you were here.
- Hard to believe that you...
- Hard to believe, right?
Lots of other things
are hard for you to believe.
Aren't we acting
according to the plan?
Yes, it's all according to plan.
But the boss wants to use
his own gun... to kill a cop.
To end his life
once and for all.
Then who are we
supposed to kill?
Hurry up and run!
I can't do it!
Jump!
Keep going!
Stop!
Go down
and get Salina!
Kid!
You're really something!
You dare to interfere with our business?!
That's enough!
Take care of him.
I'll clean up.
I can bet on my life
that he hasn't done it!
We're not living in a lawless society.
We've got to have proof.
How come Ka Kui and
his gun are missing,
and this bullet just happens
to be from his gun?
How do you explain that?
A cop makes a lot of enemies.
Someone may want to frame him.
If this happened to a civilian instead of
Ka Kui, what would we have done?
Sir, you can't always
go by the book!
You also have to show trust
in your men.
You think I have anything
against Ka Kui?
I just want people to know we don't
sweep our own mistakes under the rug.
I get the feeling that you want to nail him
even more than the crooks!
Enough,
Uncle Bill!
What would you do in my shoes?
Hi, May.
I know.
I'll wait for you.
THE MISSING CHAN KA KUI
IS A SUSPECT
POLICEMAN KILLED
What now?
My mom is really
worried about you.
Ka Kui, be careful!
Ka Kui's back!
- Ka Kui!
Ka Kui!
- I didn't do it.
- We believe you.
But where have you been?
I don't know.
How can you not know?! Were you drunk
and slept over at some girl's place?
I was fighting Chu Tu's men.
Inspector Man came in
and pointed his gun at me.
They took my gun
and shot Man with it.
I can't remember the rest.
Everyone knows you and Man
weren't exactly friends.
The bullet that killed him
was fired from your gun.
I didn't kill him. How would our
petty conflicts in the past make me..?
But who's going to believe you?
We're not living in a lawless society.
We need proof.
- But I'm glad you're back.
- Hand in your gun first.
Call Homicide. Tell them the prime suspect
just gave himself up.
Call in two men.
Ka Kui, don't worry.
We'll do our very best to help you.
- Take him to the holding cell.
- Yes, sir.
And charge him...
with murder.
Sir! You...
Freeze!
- Ka Kui, what are you doing?
- I didn't kill anyone!
- Why charge me with murder?
- I didn't say you killed him,
but I have to bring charges
according to the evidence.
It's so obvious that I was framed.
Can't you see that at all?!
If you were framed,
I'll investigate.
- Don't give me that!
- Ka Kui, let Superintendent Li go!
What Superintendent?!
- What you are doing is dangerous!
- Dangerous for him!
When we were risking our lives,
he was sitting there thinking
about which girl would join him for dinner.
We put the crooks under arrest
while he argued about proper procedure.
And that stupid idea of
having me protecting the witness.
That simple, right?!
One twitch from his eyebrows,
and we've got to risk our lives!
- Ka Kui!
- Shut up!
You got promoted at our expense!
Have you ever thought of us?
An officer killed only means
three bows and a full report.
We also have mothers
that gave birth to us!
If we hadn't fought for you,
would you have such a luxurious office?
- Ka Kui.
- Go away!
Come any closer
and I'll shoot him dead!
Ka Kui, don't do that!
Open the door!
Don't move!
Don't come near!
Don't!
Don't worry about me.
I know what I'm doing!
Ka Kui has taken
Superintendent Li hostage!
Don't move!
Stay cool!
Ka Kui, calm down.
Stay back!
- Ka Kui, calm down.
- Let's talk about this.
We'll sort this out.
Put your hands on the table.
On the table!
That is quite a foolish act of yours.
Give up before it's too late!
We'll help you.
Trust us!
We'll sort this out.
I trust all of you,
but I can't depend on you.
- You're making it worse!
- Don't force me!
Don't!
Don't push him!
Don't push him.
Alert all units. Send in sharpshooters.
Easy, everybody!
Ka Kui!
Get in the car.
- Ka Kui!
- Drive off!
Don't follow.
The Superintendent's life is at stake.
Where are you going?
Stop.
Get out.
Even if you didn't cooperate,
I wouldn't dare to open fire.
It's better this way.
If it wasn't like this,
I wouldn't be sure how to help you.
As soon as I get back,
I'll come after you.
I won't let you get me
before I get Chu Tu.
- I hope so.
- Thank you, sir.
But it's tough to find out
where Salina is.
Let's just get a couple of girls
and have some fun.
Inspector Chan, it wasn't my fault!
He forced me to do it!
Eat.
Can I eat, then?
I'm hungry.
Boss, that brave cop
is on the loose.
Didn't the police take him in?
- He kidnapped the superintendent.
- This guy's got some nerve!
We should have killed him too,
once and for all.
Where is Salina?
Mad Wing and Snake Eyes
are looking for her.
But we haven't heard
anything from them yet.
Would Salina be with
that brave cop?
What's up, boss?
Someone's stealing my
computer data.
- Who is it?
- It must be Salina.
Only she knows the password.
- Go and get her.
- Alert our men.
Call Counsel Cheung.
- How much longer do we need to wait?
- You're impatient?
No. I'm scared.
You two stand guard over there.
There!
Hurry and
call Uncle Bill.
Get that briefcase
or we're doomed! Quick!
This way!
Chase!
- Ka Kui!
- Why didn't you go to the police?
They might have been in league
with Inspector Man.
You are my witness.
I'm counting on you.
I've got Chu's data.
Right here!
Take her back to the office.
Hurry!
- What's going on?
- Mind your own business!
Let's go.
- Come on!
- I'm not going.
Kill him!
Catch!
It's there!
Go and get it!
- May!
- Are you all right, Ka Kui?
Don't worry about me.
Get the briefcase!
Go to hell!
Chu Tu!
Quick!
Hurry!
Ka Kui, don't do it!
- Drop the weapon!
- We'll take it from here.
- This is between him and me.
- The law will take care of him.
The law? The law takes care of
those who don't have money for a lawyer!
Doesn't work on him!
It won't favor you
to do it in public.
I have nothing to lose
if I kill him right now!
It was Danny Chu
who killed Inspector Man.
All the evidence
is in that briefcase.
Are you all right?
May is hurt, Ka Kui.
Look after her first.
Block every exit and take
all the suspects back to the station!
You cops are going too far,
threatening innocent citizens
with a weapon!
You are a police officer,
but you are not above the law.
On behalf of my client,
I am going to sue you
for assault, kidnapping,
and making threats.
This is a miscarriage of justice
and a disturbance of the peace!
- You're all witnesses!
- Ka Kui, let go of him!
- Don't fall into his trap!
- Prepare yourself for some jail time.
Yeah, how dare you
threaten the Counsel?
Counsel Cheung,
it's good you arrived that fast!
You have to help me
with this report.
- What?
- Let's write it together.
I didn't see anything.
That's enough, Ka Kui!