Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
Hey. Shh.[crying]
Hey.
You'Őre all better now.
You'Őre safe.
[coos]
[groans]
[crying]
What do you think?The black one?
Where in the fu--
heck is your daddy?
Should we go find him?
Daddy? Where are you?
[buzzing]
Now? Hello?
[buzzing stops]
You chose now
to do this?Oh, hey.
Gordita.Come to Papa.[cries]
Even thoughyou shouldn'Őt be here.
It'Ős too dusty for you.[crying]
Daddy'Ős the only one
who gets to hide away
in this man cave of his.
I know.
You going somewhere?
No, we are going somewhere.
Yeah, no. I'Őm ready.
[whistling]
You know what?I'Őm sorry, okay?
I'Őm sorryI forgot our date night.
Forget it.
[sighs]
Could you pleasejust not sigh?
[scoffs] Really? Okay.
You don'Őt honestly expect meto believe that you forgotyour own argument
about how date night was cheaperthan therapy, do you?
Right, like you forgot we agreedyour mom wasn'Őt allowedin our house anymore.
We'Őre broke. I don't see you
finding a free babysitter.
[man]
I would have. What?[scoffs]
Don'Őt start thisright now, please.
Can we just try to have fun?
We'Őre out, okay?
Let'Ős just try.
It'Ős kind of cool to be outafter dark, you know?
Childless peopledo this all the time.Gets dark and they go out.
All the neon lights.It'Ős like a fucking video game.
It'Ős like-- like Tron.
[both chuckle]
Hey. We'Őre so gladyou could make it.[woman] Thanks for having us.
[man] Wow.[woman] This place is beautiful.
Matteo and Adrienne
just bought the house
down the street.
But they--[Matteo]
Thank you. Yeah.
But they can'Őt move in
until, what, next October?
Yeah, there'Ős this co-op
living community renting it.
-It'Ős, like,eight kids in their 20s.-It'Ős, like, ten kids, actually.
Mm. I'Őm sure someone's sleepingin the laundry room.
Ew!It'Ős kind of fun.
Come on.
Shared space, you know.
Cooking, cleaning.
Life on the porch
with a ukulele.[man] Excuse me.
[Matteo] We showed upfor inspection with our baby.
She was, what, like,
seven days old.
Yeah. So little--[Matteo chuckles]
We scared them shitless.
Married people with babies.
Run!
We'Őre not married. No.
[man 1] I'Őm sorry.I didn'Őt mean to assume.
No, we just--We'Őve got the houseand the baby, and so...
Also, like, a new marriage,whatever, it'Ős like...
[man 2] Totally.We wouldn'Őt havedone it, honestly,
except my family
would'Őve killed me.
No, you mean me. They would'Ővecut my dick off with a machete.
Oh. [chuckles] Ow!
And I thought
Adrienne'Ős mom hated me.
I mean, she does,
but more in a
"I'Őm praying to God
to curse your eternal soul"
kind of way.
When she comes
to the house,
we play this game
where we pretend
we can'Őt see
or hear each other.
Very pleasant.
Okay, excuse me.
Liam?
Hey!Hey!
How are you?I'Őm good.
How are you?
[Adrienne] I'Őm good.I haven'Őt seen you herein so long.
I guess now I knowwhy you wanted to come so badly.
I had no idea thathe was going to be there, okay?
And God forbid I have friends.You certainly have friends,right?
You know,
we both deserve to be happy.
[scoffs] Liam makes you happy?
I didn'Őt say that.
Are you happy?
Yeah. Yeah, sure.
Oh, that'Ős convincing.
We agreed notto do anything crazyin the first year.
We just have to get throughthe first year.
I don'Őt want to just
get through it.
I want to enjoy it.
You want to control it.What choice do I have?
I'Őm dragging youthrough the motions of our life.
Your life.You wanted to have a baby,we had a baby.
You wanted a house,we bought the house.What now?
How about the truth?
[scoffs] Don'Őt.You can'Őt do it.
No, you want me to make upsome pretend confession
to justify your paranoia,and I won'Őt do that.
Yeah, right.
[Matteo] You'Őre not gonnabe happy till you'Őre miserable.
[Adrienne] You know, I just--I actually-- Honestly,I do not know what the point is.
Of life?
Of us. Why are we
even together anymore?
[Matteo scoffs]
We--
We have a newborn baby.We just closed escrow. What?
Now what?You want to split up?
I want to--
[gasps]
[fluid dripping]
[breathing]
[sirens wailing]
[Matteo, distorted]
All these neon lights...
It'Ős like a video game.
[EMT] Can you hear me?
Can you hear me?[machine beeping]
[Adrienne, distorted]
You know, we both deserve
to be happy.
[baby crying]
[Adrienne] Are you happy?
[breathing]
[breathing continues]
[doctor]
Time of death: 12:34 a.m.
[indistinct voices]
[homeless man]Chica! Please don'Őt!
Chica!
[gasps]
We'Őll give you a minute.
No!
Wait.
[indistinct]
[sobbing]
[inhales]
[TV host] Is there something beyond all this? Is there an afterlife?
Today on our show,
we'Őll seek answers
to those questions.
Our first guest was rushed to the hospital...
[cheerful music playing on toy]
Ellie.
Look at Mommy, baby.
-Ellie, look at Mama.-[woman on TV] I remember one minute being in this world
and the next minute
being, like, I died.
[Ellie coos]
[bell tolls]
[woman]I miss her so much.
Maggie?
I can'Őt believe
she'Ős gone.I know.
-That'Ős in my face.
-Sorry. I'Őm quitting.
[Maggie]
I just can'Őt lose you.
Come here.
[Matteo]Thank you all for being here.
[speaking Spanish]
Okay.
"To everything
there is a season...
and a time to every purpose
under the heavens...
a time to be born...
and a time to die."
I'Őm sorry.
[exhales]
This feels so unreal.
Like a mistake, you know?
Like I could reach into the
hourglass and stir the sands
and just change it all.
[sniffles]
No, I'Őm sorry. I...
I can'Őt do this. Sorry.
Sorry.
Poor thing.
I'Őm gonna go check on him.
[priest] "Love is patient,
love is kind."Shea!
"It does not envy,it does not boast."Shea!
Let'Ős let the body
cool off first, okay?
[Adrienne'Ős mom]It'Ős better this way.
My sweet girl.
See all the toys.[Ellie babbles]
Yeah! So many pretty toys.
See, this is Ellie'Ős room now,
and we'Őre gonna do
just great. Mm.
Aw.
Ellie Bellie, you'Őre gonna livewith Grandma and Grandpa now.
[sings lullaby]
Look at you.
Grandma?Hmm?
Do you really thinkshe loved my dad?
Are those my journals?
Oh, God, no. Fuck. Don'Őt--
Please don'Őt look at those.
[Adrienne'Ős mom]I think your dadwas hard to love.
[sobbing]
Stop now.
It'Ős not your faultyour father left.
Now, tears won'Őt solve anything.They won'Őt bring him back.
Bring him back
from where?
Where is your dad?
Where the shit is your dad?
[echoing] Matteo?
[Matteo]
Hey! Adrienne!
Come down.
What are you doing?
You can see me.
What?
I died.
-I died, Matteo.
-Okay.
It'Ős so wrong that that was it.It was just headlightsand a half gasp--
Stop. Stop.
You'Őre confused.
We had an accident.
Oh, my God,
you'Őre dead too.
What? No!
No, I'Őm not.
And you'Őre not.
How do you know?
Because I know.
Well, because we'Őre here.
I mean, spending eternity
on the 10 Freeway--
What did we do
to deserve that?
You weren'Őt there with Ellie.
Where do you go?
What happens to you?You just get scared and then,what, you just-- you disappear?
You concussed. That'Ős it.
No. I'Őm dead.
I could step into traffic now.It wouldn'Őt matter.Hey!
[tires screech]
Hey.
It'Ős okay.
What is this, like, purgatory?What'Ős happening to me?
Just hold on to me. Hmm?
[Ellie babbling]
[Ellie crying]
[Adrienne'Ős mom] We just wantwhat'Ős best for Ellie.
We can'Őt leave her here, Steve.
[Steve] If she had
just left instructions
for what she would'Őve wanted
in a situation like this.
[Adrienne'Ős mom]She would want usto take care of Ellie.
What about Matteo?
God forgive me,
but this is all his fault.
He couldn'Őt take care of her.He wouldn'Őt marry her.
He couldn'Őt protect her,
and now she'Ős--
[Steve] I don'Őt think
we should get ahead
of ourselves.
[Adrienne'Ős mom]We should take the baby home.
[pounding]
[screams, panting]Shit!
What? What happened?
There was somebody outside.I thought I saw some...
Outside? It was me.
I was outside.
The door was locked.I had to go around the house.
Hey.
I don'Őt know how much timeI have left here, Matteo.
Well, none of us do, right?
It'Ős part of the mystery.
I heard them talking.They'Őre gonna take Ellie.
Who said--My mother.
I just heard them.[scoffs]
I'Őm perfectly capable
of taking care of my family,
Patty.
Thank you very much.
[scoffs]
As if it was my fault.
Hey. We got
to get you better, okay?
But no one
is taking our baby.
Okay?
Hey. Come.
Come, come.
It will take a pack of wolvesmore rabid than your motherto take her away. All right?
Do we even have a baby?
What?The baby was in the car,
but the car seat was emp--
Hey. You--Maybe I just imaginedthat we have a baby.
You-- You didn'Őt wantto have a baby.
We have a baby.
Ellie is our baby.
She'Ős six months old,
kinda cute.
Remember when she was born,
that she couldn'Őt latch?
We were freaking out.
And then these researchers
from Denmark came.
Remember what he said?
"We'Őre doing a study
on the benefits of..."
Of what?
Of narrative therapyfor new mothers and newborns.
You'Őve been through
a traumatic experience,
but you'Őve been able to processby talking through it.
The birth was traumatic for you,
but you'Őve been able
to talk about it
with your husband.
Boyfriend.
Sorry?Nothing. Nothing.
Right. But the baby,
she has no idea
what has happened.
She needs to process too.
You need to tell her
her story.
Um, okay.
Hey.
We had kind ofa crazy birth, huh?
It was hard,
and it was painful...
because the cord
was wrapped around you
and you couldn'Őt breathe.
[coos]
And then all these peoplerushed in, and it was bright,and it was loud,
but those peoplewere helping you.
You weren'Őt alone.
And we were therethe whole time.
We were just not breathingwith you for those 90 seconds...
and then you did.
You breathed.
And I know you'Őre so tiredfrom all that craziness,
but you'Őre all better now.
You'Őre safe.
But, my baby, you'Őve got to eat.
[babbles]
[sniffles] She'Ős on.
[chuckles]
You see?
Remember, we have a baby.
I'Őm gonna help you make senseof everything else.
I'Őm gonna--
I'Őm gonna tell you
our story, okay?
That way you can know
that you'Őre okay.
You can know you'Őre safe.
What if you'Őre wrong?
What if it'Ős a sad story?
[knocking]No.
It'Ős not.[Patty] Sorry to wake you.
One second, Patty.
You need anything?
Tell her you'Őre fine, please.
I'Őm not even here.
So she'Ős talking to a dead girl?
To you.
Okay.
Okay, so you won'Őt talk
to anyone for a bit. Okay?
We'Őll stay here,
and we'Őll figure
this out ourselves.
[Patty]
I did some laundry,
and I was thinking
I'Őd make soup tonight.
I have to go to the store,so if you want anything...
[Matteo] Thank you, Patty.
We'Őre fine. Thank you.
Take your time.
Okay, let'Ős stay in bed.
One step at a time. Hey.
Shall we start
from the beginning?
Of time?
Of us.
Fine.
If it means you'Őll stay,then fine.
I will stay.
Close your eyes.
[Adrienne] Where are we?What is it?[Maggie] Okay, this way.
Okay, all right, stop.
Stop. Stop.I don'Őt like it.
I don'Őt want it.Okay, one, two, three.
[all] Surprise!
[man] Yeah![pop music playing]
[both laugh]
Oh, my God, you guys,this is awesome.
[chattering]
Hey!
What is this?
I was so uncomfortable
in the spotlight.
Hi!And I thought
that was so cute.
All these people are herebecause they love you so much.
Look, and there'Ősso many snacks.
[laughter, chattering]
[pop music continues]
[laughs]
I remember you blushed.
No, I didn'Őt.
Okay.What? I didn'Őt.
I lured you in
with my boyish charm.
That'Ős what I did.
[chuckles]
Oh, yeah, this one. Shia. Sean?
Come on. You remember her name.
Shea.
She was always just so much.
She never really talked to meafter we got together.
She talked to you.
I told you nothing happened
with Shea.
Yeah, you did tell me that.
[Ellie crying]
Shea got me a job
in a hotel in Palm Springs.
All the woodwork and doors.
With her?Just two months.
[footsteps departing][door unlocking]
[door closes]
[Matteo] Hey.
I haven'Őt finishedwith the night we met.
[laughter, chattering]
You remember what
we talked about?
[soft, slow music playing]
Hmm. Movies? Aliens.
My love of show tunes.
Yes, and yet,
I kept talking to you.
[chuckles]And, oh, The Bluest Eye.You love Toni Morrison.
And I wanted to give youa blow job right there.
What? No.
No way.Way.
Fuck, I wish I knew.[chuckles]
You were focused on meso intently like we werethe only ones there.
And you told meabout your stepdad.Not that night.
No, you did.About the last timethat you saw him.
Oh, yeah. I was ten.
He had his hands
around my mom'Ős neck,
so I called the cops,
and of course he denied it.
Then my mom blamed me
when he left.
I'Őm sorry.
[scoffs, chuckles]
No, I'Őm sorry.
What a downer.
[both chuckle]
My parents are a pain,but not painful enoughthat I can get rid of them.
That'Ős too bad.
I mean...No, I mean,
that'Ős good.
It'Ős good, I guess.
[laughs]
Anyway...Cheers.
You can spend the nightin my room if you promiseto, um, not molest me.
-No, wait.
That was weeks later.
-I remember.
You asked to crash on my couch.
What time'Ős your meeting
in the morning?It'Ős at 9:00.
Thank youfor letting me stay.
It'Ős just that traffic
in the morning, it'Ős crazy
heading this way, so...
I thoughtit would be easier.
Yeah, no worries.
It'Ős fine.
You know,
I lied about the meeting.
There was no meeting.
I know.
[soft music playing]
[both chuckle]
It was almost dawn.
I thought you were
never gonna kiss me.
Oh! [chuckles]I tri-- [chuckles]
I'Őm sorry.
I'Őm sorry. Come back.Come back. Come back. Please.
[both chuckling]
Mm. I'Őm sorry.
[moaning]
Make love to me.
You got a condom?
Don'Őt you?No.
[chuckles]
What? You light--Are you serious?
I mean, you lighta hundred candles,and you have no condom?
I thought you'Őd have one.
I'Őm sorry.
No. What kindof feminist are you?[both laugh]
Wait.
Bam. [chuckles]
Thank God we don'Őt usethese fucking things anymore.
Yeah, becausewe don'Őt have sex anymore.
No, I'Őm sorry. Shh, shh.
Let'Ős-- Let's not thinkabout that. Focus.
Do you smell smoke?
[speaking Spanish]
Fire!
[grunts] Fuck!
Matteo!
[coughs, panting]
You just left me there.
You just left me there to die.
[Matteo]That'Ős not what happened.
I came back.
I came back
and put it out.
I saved the day.I was fucking Supermanthat night.
We laughed about this.Yeah.
Hey. Hey.
I love you.
No, I was the onethat said it first.
Does it matter?Yes.
No. I don'Őt know.
[gasps]
[groaning]
[breathing heavily]
There you are.
Hey. You scared me.
I'Őm a good ghost.
You promised you'Őd staywith me.
I'Őve been doing
some research.
It'Ős kind of crazy what happensto people after trauma.
I mean,
what they experience,
you know?
Makes sense
that you feel off.
Off?Yeah.
What do you think happenswhen you die?
Nothing.What if it'Ős bad?
Painful, some extensionor manifestation of your fearsand your failings?
Hey.Of your last moments, againand again and again and again?
No. No, no.
Uh, wait.
It can'Őt just be an insular
emotional repetition.
I mean,
if it'Ős not nothing,
it'Ős gotta be something biggerthan that, right?
We'Őre space dust. Right?
So we just go back to that,
to be part of everything.
The water, the trees."Ashes to ashes,dust to dust."
[chuckles] If you want
to get Catholic about it,
yeah.
When you die, Adrienne...
but you'Őre not dead yet.
I think I'Őm hereto get you to step upand take care of Ellie.
We talked about this.I saw it,and you weren'Őt there.
Hey, stop it.I saw her,and you weren'Őt there.
So maybe you were lying,and that'Ős why I'm stuck here.
I wouldn'Őt lie
about that. Wait.And that'Ős why I'm still here.
No.
I know you'Őre always the fixer,always in control, but...
you gotta trust me
on this one. Hmm?
When I go,you'Őll be a good dad.
You'Őre gonna learnto braid hair...Hey, stop.
...and sing lullabies.Okay.
She'Ős gonna need you.Hey. Hey. Hey. Hey.
Let'Ős talk about
what'Ős real.
What really happened.
Okay?
Mexico. A happy memory.
[knocking]
It'Ős okay.Don'Őt.
It'Ős okay.
[boat captain speaking Spanish]
[waves lapping]
[Adrienne]
I just met your family.[Matteo] Uh-huh.
They loved you.
I'Őm so glad you made us
do this trip.
[Adrienne] Afterwards.You were always glad afterwards.
Well, how could I ever imagineit was going to be so...
Magical.It was.
I could see our whole life,just this...
beautiful adventurecarved out on the horizon.
You made me rethink
everything I thought I knew
about what I wanted.
Will they come?
[Matteo]Yeah, they'Őre coming.
Here!
[Adrienne screams]Whoa! Wow!
Yay!
[Matteo chuckles]
[Adrienne] Right here!
Right here! Right here![Matteo] Wow!
[Adrienne] There![Matteo laughs]
[Matteo] Gracias.
And then we died...
Hostel: Mexico,straight to DVD.[chuckles]
I have told this story
so many times, it'Ős almost
like it'Ős a fantasy.
This was real. This is real.
[Matteo] I could stay
in this place forever.
I so wanted you to propose.
I was going to.
What?Yeah.
I even looked at rings
and everything, but...
I thought you'Őd be mad.
I didn'Őt have a ring.
No, I wouldn'Őt have.I wouldn'Őt have been mad.
[chuckles]
Yes, you would.
[scoffs]Hey. Hey.
Okay, I didn'Őt propose,but you remember what I said?
I want to kiss you
at the end of every day
for the rest of my life.
One for yesterday...
one for today...
one for tomorrow.
[chuckles]
It'Ős so sadthat we fell apart,isn'Őt it?
Yeah.
[Matteo] What'Ős wrong?What'Ős happening?
What'Ős happening?Hey.
Adrienne. What'Ős wrong?[gasps]
What'Ős happening?
[groaning]Adrienne, take a breath.
-[groaning]
-Adrienne, take a breath.
Adrienne![gasps]
Okay. Breathe. Breathe.[groans, breathes heavily]
Breathe. Breathe.[breathes heavily]
Breathe. Adrienne, breathe.
Okay. You'Őre okay.
You'Őre okay.
You keep saying that,but clearly--
What'Ős wrong?[groaning]
The water--You didn'Őt see the water.What?
[crying]
Just breathe, please.
Breathe. You'Őre okay.
Look me in the eyes.
There you go.
That works.
[sighs]
Okay. Okay.
Let me get you a towel.
You'Őll be fine.
Okay? Don'Őt move.
[breathes heavily]
[male voice]
It'Ős over now.
Where'Ős the baby?
No. No, you can'Őt have her.
Ellie?
Ellie!
Please!
Somebody help me!
Help me!
[crying]
Adrienne!
She'Ős not breathing!What is it? Stop it. Stop it.
[Ellie crying]Let Mama have the baby.
You'Őre gonna hurt her. Steve![Matteo] What happened?
Let go. Let the baby go.
Oh...He can'Őt have her!He can'Őt have her!
[Steve] Is she okay?[Matteo] She'Ős fine.
She'Ős okay.
She'Ős okay.[Steve] It'Ős okay.
[Matteo] Adrienne,
what'Ős going on?
He'Ős coming--He'Ős coming for her.
[crying]
He'Ős coming for her.What? What'Ős coming?
What are you
talking about?Dea--
Death.
[crying]
[doctor] Your mom tells meyou'Őve been experiencing
some confusionsince the accident.
Are you in any pain?
Does that hurt?I don'Őt know.
[doctor]Adrienne, can you hear me?
Do you know what day it is?
Sorry, I'Őm not really here.
Which one is it?
[doctor]She just needs her medicine.
[indistinct]
Take two pills,
three times a day...
[indistinct]
She'Ős gonna be okay.
She'Ős a strong girl.
[Steve] Thanks for coming by.I do appreciate it.
[Ellie crying]
Ellie wanted to say hi.Why don'Őt you give her a hug?
Okay, here,
I'Őll take her.
[Patty] They'Őve got her onso many pills, I can'Őt evenkeep them straight.
[Maggie] I'Őm just gonna
sit here with you, okay?
Just so you know.
We don'Őt even have to talk.
[Patty]
She has physical therapy,
and an appointment
with a psychiatrist
on Tuesday.
[Maggie] Okay, well, you knowI'Őm here if she needs anything.She'Őll be fine.
[Patty] I'Őm gonna take Ellieto our place for a while,and Steve will stay with her.
[babbling][crashing sounds]
Children need stability,
and this just is not
a good environment for her.
[insurance agent]
So, the good news is,
the other driver was at fault,per the police report.
-Is he okay?-He isn'Őt claiming any injuries.
Will you be takingMatteo'Ős statement separately
to make surewe'Őre telling the truth?Because it was not his fault.
No matter whatmy mother may have told you.
There was a witness who said
he saw the other driver
gun through the yellow.
Do you remember that?
Adrienne?
[zombies grunting][woman screams]
Zombies?
You hate zombies.
They'Őre my people now.
I feel really connectedto them, actually.
They'Őre very misunderstood.
I-- [exhales]
I know there'Ős
something wrong with me.
Yeah.
But you'Őre gonna get better.
If I was actually a zombie,
would you tie me upand keep me in your garage?
[scoffs, chuckles]
Yeah, I guess so.
I'Őve been always afraidof losing you, so, yeah.
Because you knew you would?
Adrienne...
doesn'Őt it make sense, right...
that you'Őre alive?
That people can see you?They talk to you.
You are here.
But I feel soulless.
Hollowed out.
Do you remember when we realizedwe were having a baby?
Please don'Őt.
You keep trying to prove
that I'Őm okay,
but I can prove I'Őm not.
Can I tell you something?
Yeah.I knew I was gonna die.
What do you mean?
She told me,when we went to the houseto look at the broken window.
[chuckles]
I'Őm gonna check the window.
Hi.[young woman]
Hey, welcome.
Hey! How are you?[young woman] Hey!
What are you guys doing?A reading.
Oh, yeah?I'Őm an assistant
to Psychic Elaine.
She'Ős, like, the best in LA,
like, the real, real deal.
Like, not a storefront,
like, otherworldly,
and I'Őm studying under her.
Wow.
You want me
to do a reading on you?
Sure, why not?I can get you later.
Just don'Őt tell me I feel oldbecause I thinkthat much is obvious.
[chuckles]
Weird,your lifeline'Ős really short.
What?
I mean, it doesn'Őt
necessarily mean death.
It could be like--
like you'Őre not living,
like you'Őre not living life
to the fullest.
Um... Or I could be
doing it wrong.
No. Yes, it'Ős crazy.I'Őm-- It's true.
I'Őm dead.
I die in a car accident,two weeks after this.
Whoa. That is crazy.
We'Őll never get to
move into this house.
It sucks.
But if you knew,why did you let yourselfget into the car?
Did you want to die?
I don'Őt know. I--
This is graspingat straws, Adrienne.
It'Ős coincidence.
That'Ős what you said to her,
but then...
How old were youwhen your mother died?
What...
Did-Did-Did you tell her?No, I swear I didn'Őt.
He was 17.
She'Ős lingering for you.
There'Ős something
unresolved.
She says she wishesthat you spoke at her funeral.
[scoffs]That'Ős it.
[laughs] Uh...
Okay. That'Ős our cue
to go. Sorry.
You never told me.
Was that true?Ye-- No.
Well, yes. Yes.
Yes, it was true.
I was young.
I didn'Őt know what to say.
I was mad at her,
but that doesn'Őt prove
that she'Ős psychicor that you'Őre dead.
I kept asking myself
again and again,
what is the point of life?
Of us. You kept asking yourselfwhat'Ős the point of us.
But then when I left Gary
and Kevin'Ős that night,
I had a really bad feeling.
[Matteo] Adrienne...
Hey!I had this feeling
like everything
was falling apart.
[Matteo] Adrienne.
You were pissed at me.If we hadn'Őt bought the house,
none of this would'Őve happened.
What? It could'Őve been
a plane crash.
It'Ős my fault.Stop trying to find meaning
in something meaningless
and random.
You didn'Őt cause
the accident.
If there'Ős someone to blame,
it'Ős me. Yeah.
I wanted to go outthat night, so we did.I didn'Őt see the guy coming.
No, no, no.
I didn'Őt see the guy coming.
I wanted to stay late.
Hey, stop hijacking this.
Let me finish the story.
I don'Őt want youto finish your story.I want you to tell the truth.
You want the truth?Yes!
Fine.
It wasn'Őt all good.
Do you remember
that work event?
You had just gotten your jobdoing grunt work at the museum.
[Adrienne]
Oh, my God. Grunt work?
I'Őm managingmajor design installations.This is not grunt work.
I don'Őt know
why you took it.
Well, aside from the factthat it'Ős my dream job,
some people actually haveto work for a living,
so thatthey can support their family,so they can buy a house.
Okay, yeah?Thank you.
Have piles of shit, right?Thank you.
You don'Őt want things?
You don'Őt want tools
and tech toys
and whatever other shit it isyou get shipped directto your garage?
Okay, I'Őm just saying thatif we stay in the apartment,
we have a low rent,we keep some freedom, andwe'Őre not tied to a mortgage.
If you'Őre never tied
to anything,
then you'Őll never be free.
What musical is that from?
It'Ős from Pippin.
It doesn'Őt--[laughs]
Doesn'Őt mean that
it'Ős not true.
What about this beautifuladventure we'Őre on?
You'Őre going to be working
from 9:00 to 9:00 every day.
Gonna be laden with kids,
the house, with no time
to go anywhere.
Not everyone can
not finish school
and not get a real job...
I have a real job....and not care.
I have a real job.This is what I want.
If you don'Őt want it too,
you should just...
get out of my way.
See?
Where do you go?
[Liam] Adrienne.Hey! How are you?
I'Őm good. Champagne?
Mind reader. Thank you.
[Matteo]The look in your eyes. So alive.
He is a work colleague,
and he'Ős on the board.
I am supposed
to be nice to him.Thank you.
For what?For making this eventworth attending.
I'Őm-- Yeah. Frida Kahlo
and Maya Deren in one space?
Be still, my heart.
[chuckles]Yeah. I know I should be focusedon the art, but I just can'Őt.
Why?You'Őre distracting me.
I just-- I threw on...
like, frazzled, like,
whatever work thing.
Don'Őt underestimate
yourself.
Okay, fine. Fine.
You saw that. So what?
So what?
I'Őm sorry. Matteo is trying
to prove that I'Őm alive
by making me feel,
what, like, guilty? Thanks.
He invited meto check out his woodworking.
The same night?Yeah, I think so.
I bought a bench.
[Matteo laughs][Liam] Oh!
Here it comes.Such terror.
You told me
it was referred
by a friend.
[Liam] How did you kill me
that fast?
I didn'Őt even know
you guys knew each other.
Hmm. So you lied.
Now you know the truth.
Feel better?
I'Őm just saying,most guys would punch a guy
who was making moveson their girlfriend.
[chuckles] Okay.
You wanted me to punch him?
He'Ős got six inches on me.
No way.
Why didn'Őt you just tell meyou were jealous?
I didn'Őt thinkI could do anything about it.
I mean, probably delay it.
Did I?
I didn'Őt cheat on you.
-Did you want to?
-It doesn'Őt matter.
It matters.
It fucking matters.
[Ellie crying]
Bullshit! Bullshit!That-- That never happened.
Okay. Look me in the eyeand tell me I am making this up.
You live so in your head.
You exaggerate things.
You conflate things.Stop lying to me.
Stop ignoring--Stop disappearing on me.
On our baby.
Even me dying isn'Őt enoughto get you to step up.
It'Ős so unfair you expect me
to fail.
You can'Őt pretend to know
what'Ős going to happen,
how I would feel
if I lost you.
What fucking living hell
that would be for me.
Maybe I would never recover.
Maybe I would be no good
for Ellie.
Maybe I would break
if I lost you.
[doorbell rings]
Who is that?
I'Őm gonna check.
[priest] Hi, Steve.
How you holding up?
[Patty]
Hello, Father Richard.
Proof that I'Őm dead.
[Matteo] Your mother calls
Father Richard if the milk
is past its due date.
Adrienne,
I'Őm planning a bingo night
at the church.
What are you doing?
I'Őm trying...
I'Őm trying to work out
what to be buried in.What?
This one actuallydoesn'Őt zip up at the back,
but if you leave it unzipped,I don'Őt think anybody'sgonna notice.
Slow down.Actually,
I think I would rather bescattered somewhere beautiful.
Oh, okay.
You have a second chance,
Matteo, and you'Őve just got
to move on.
-[scoffs]
-And you gotta find somebody
that you love.
Not Shea.Please don'Őt marry Shea.
[chuckles]
Somebody-- Somebody educatedand somebody funny.
Find somebody funny
and just love them.
And let them love you.It'Ős gonna be weird
to bring a girl
with my dead girlfriend
still in my bed, right?
And I want my funeral to be fun.Not in a church, please.
Okay.No matter what my mother says.
We'Őll have a dance-pop
party funeral.
You'Őre the one
who likes pop music.
I don'Őt like pop music.
I want Missy Elliott.
Okay, we'Őll have a bunch
of geriatrics dancing
to Missy Elliott.
Man, life.
Perfect.What a tricky little minx.
Hey, stop. Stop!
Stop!
Stop. Stop. Stop. Stop.
What the fuck are you doing?
You don'Őt get
to be dead yet, okay?
Fuck. So impatient.
Adrienne.
Hey.
Look at me.
So impatient.
Shh, shh.
Even having kids.
You remember it? Last year.
D’a de Muertos.
Stay with me.
I know you remember.
[chattering]
[man 1] Yeah.[man 2] Okay.
-I'Őd be down.
-[man 1] Can we get two
of those, please?
Okay, I gotta say this quick.Uh, A wants a baby.
-What?
-Here is a cute--
She'Ős gonna break up with youif you don'Őt pull the goalieright now.
What the--
We just started talking
about this.
He shouldn'Őt
have told you that.
She said she was going topoke a hole in her diaphragm.
I was kidding.
I was kidding,
obviously.
Okay, it didn'Őt sound likeyou were kidding.
Maggie.I'Őm just being honest.
Okay, she was upset,
and I talked her down.
So impatient.
I'Őm just asking youto be patientwith me, with us.
May I finish the story?Okay, sure.
I remember
what else happened
that day.
Fucking Matteo!
Hi! You said
you were out of town.
Uh...[chuckles]
No. No. Um...[chuckles]
The-The trip got canceled.Oh...
It'Ős so funny that Shea wouldknow about a trip of yoursthat got canceled,
'Őcause you guys don't talk.This is not why I broughtthis memory up.
Hey!Shea.
Hi! Wow, you look so great.Hi. So do you, always.
How are you guys?[Adrienne] Great.
Yeah? Are you married yet?[Matteo] Uh-huh.
Oh, God, no.
No, I cannot bear the idea
of letting this oaf own me,
but it'Ős so great
that you guys still talk,
that you kept in touch.
Even though you swore to me
that you didn'Őt talk
to her anymore. Liar.
Of course.
I'Őm sorry we haven't talked.
That'Ős so--
That'Ős stupid.
It'Ős so stupid.No, totally. Right, right.
We should have lunch. Lie.
Totally.Lie.
Hey, are you still,
um, woodworking?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.Oh.
Amazing, because my dadjust bought this huge property.
So I actually, um--
I might have a job for you.
Oh, really?Yeah.
That'Ős so sweet.Yeah.
This was the beginning
of the end, wasn'Őt it?
What? No, no, no, no.Cool, so, um...
[speaking Spanish]
It was so good
to see you, girl.
[chuckles][chuckles]
Hey. Bye.
I love you.
[scoffs] What?
[chuckles]
Why don'Őt you just be
with Shea, Matteo?
Are you crazy?If I wanted to be with her,I would be.
Is that a threat?No, I'Őm just saying,
I'Őm with you.
God, I was so much, wasn'Őt I?
No. We made up, didn'Őt we?
Did we?Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. This--
This wasn'Őt the beginningof the end.
This was the moment when we...
when I told you...
Hey.
I wanna have babies
with you, okay?
I wanna have a kid.
Let'Ős have a baby.
You only agreed
because I threatened
to leave you if you didn'Őt.
Okay, yeah,
but I still agreed. Right?
Because I wanted to.
You'Őre right. Let's do it.
No, what'Ős wrong?
I'Őm so glad you said yes.
And I'Őm so glad
we had Ellie.
Hey, what'Ős wrong?I said yes, right?
Hey.
Adrienne.He'Ős here.
Who'Ős here?
Adrienne.
Hey.
Adrienne, talk to me.
Adrienne, wake up. Hey!
Hey, wake up.
Adrienne.
Adrienne, wake up.
Wake up!
Fuck. Don'Őt do that
to me, please.
I don'Őt know
how to help you.
This is bigger than me.
You saw it.
No, I didn'Őt see anything.
Let'Ős get you out
of this thing.
I give up.
I can'Őt do this anymore.
Wait.
Okay.
I guess
I'Őll go avoid your mom.
[footsteps departing]
[door opens, closes]
[sirens wailing]
[breathing heavily]
Hey.
[groans] Go away.
I can'Őt.
You can'Őt help me.
What if you'Őre wrong?
Adrienne.
You want this to be the truthEllie has to live withher whole life?
Don'Őt talk to me about truth.
You were right about Shea.
What you saw.
[Ellie crying]
Look, it'Ős a job,
a well-paid job.
We can'Őt afford
to both take time off.[mumbles]
No, you look, Matteo.
You brought this babyinto the world, a bastard.
Mom.Well, she is.You did that.
It'Ős the truth.
And now you turn your backon her?
Look, Patty,
go fuck yourself. Okay?
Matteo!What?
You'Őre gonna defend her crap?Mom. Mom.
Please--I'Őm sorry.
I'Őm sorry, Adrienne.
I can'Őt be around this.
Thank fucking God!
Are you kidding me?
That was the only help I had,the only person I had.
Please,stop being dramatic, okay?
Me?
You'Őre the one who left.
You'Őre the one
who couldn'Őt handle it.
And I stood there foreverjust hoping you would come back.
Slow down,or you'Őre going to getin an accident.
I didn'Őt.
I just needed an escape.
I was afraid of being
like my stepfather.
Of family, of all of it.
All my life tryingto avoid becoming that man,
and here I am,
just turning into him.
You'Őre not him.
You'Őre nothing like him.
And when I got back to you,I swear, nothing happened
because I was afraid
you would...
I was afraidI would lose you if I told you.
Tell me now.
[chattering]
[laughter]
[both speaking Spanish]
[romantic pop music playing]
And then...
[Adrienne]And then what?
And then, I stopped.
Because I felt like
you were there.
Like you were right there.
And I couldn'Őt be anything
but yours.
It was never clearer to me.
I was just so ashamed of lyingand of failing.
I should have been honestabout feeling overwhelmed.
I should have stayed.
I should have stood up for youwith my mom. I just--
No wonder you left.
I just made it so hard
for you to love me.No.
I was always tearing it down
and pulling you apart.
No.
Liar.
We just had so little time.
-[heart beating]
-[tires screeching]
[crashing]
I should have loved you better.
We still have time.
We just got to hold on to it.
Even if it gets messyand hard.
Take the good and the bad.
For better or worse.
Give me your hand.
Please.
Do you remember the daywe got married?
What?
Marry me.
It'Ős too late.
No. No, no, no.
Just say yes.
Marry me.
Yes.
Adrienne,
you are my best friend.
Matteo, you are my calm and my truth.
[Matteo]
My strength, my compass.
[Adrienne] I promise to have the patience that love demands.
[Matteo] I promise to be always yours.
You know I don'Őt believe
in soul mates, but...
I married youthe minute I met you.
And loving youis the closest thingto faith I'Őve ever known.
I promise to love you
and let you love me.
I promise
to always be the person
who earns your love.
I... that one.
[laughs]
[laughing]
I give you my hand.
And I give you my heart.
I give you my heart.
From this day forward...
From this day forward
for the rest of our lives.
For the rest of our lives.
I now pronounce you
husband and wife.
You may kiss the bride.
[cheering]
And one for tomorrow.
[slow romantic music playing]
You see, I'Őm dancing.I can'Őt believe it.
Will wonders never cease?
[Matteo] Look.Even the she-beast is happy.
Now I know it'Ős a dream.[chuckles]
You know how I feel?Hmm?
Alive.
Really?Yeah.
[laughs][inhales]
Oh, say it again.
Say it again.
I feel alive.
You are alive, so alive.
It makes sense.My ribs are killing me.
[laughs] I'Őm sorry.Stop pressing on them.
I'Őm sorry.[laughing]
I'Őm sorry.
I'Őm sorry.Ow.
Thank God for seat belts.
I'Őm so happy you were right.
Can you say that again?What?
The-The part
where I'Őm right.Oh. [laughs]
You were right!You'Őre right![chuckles]
I'Őm so grateful.
I'Őm so lucky.
Me too.
Hello, baby.
You'Őre so strong.
You'Őre so strong.[Patty] You gave us
quite a scare, you know.
I'Őm feeling better now.Well, you'Őre
a strong girl too.
You know,Matteo really helped me.
I know he doesn'Őt shareyour beliefs, but he'Ős apretty extraordinary person.
-I don'Őt want to speak---Can we not do this right now?
I'Őm just saying thatthere is no reason whyhe couldn'Őt take care of Ellie
on his own if he needed to.
You don'Őt have to attack me.I'Őm not attacking you.
Adrienne.[Patty] Maggie.
Maggie.Needs to get changed anyhow.
Come on, baby.Hi.
Oh, my gosh.
Think you'Őre still in shock?
You know,I actually thought I was dead.
Oh, honey.
I'Őm so sorry.Dead.
I just feel really raw.
Yeah, that'Ős totally normal.
You know what?
I'Őm here for you, okay?
Whatever you need.
Right now, we have to get
you dressed because you have
a doctor'Ős appointment.
Okay, Mom.
This is Matteo. Leave a message, and I'Őll call you back.
Hey, where'Őd you go?
We should be home by...
Sorry. Home by 2:00. Call me.
How are you feeling?
Like I don'Őt want
to be in a car.
[Patty] I heard you talking
with Maggie, and I just...
I'Őm glad that you have her
to process with.
Yeah, she'Ős amazing.
I'Őm not good at these things.
That'Ős okay. That's okay.
[Patty]
I haven'Őt known what to say.
I'Őve been trying
to find the words,
but I...
I cook and I clean,
and that'Ős what I can do.
It'Ős okay, Mom. I'm okay.
Got to take the goodwith the bad, right?That'Ős life.
For better or worse.
[Patty]I am just... I'Őm just so sorry.
As a parent, all you want to dois protect your children.
[breathing heavily]
[fluid dripping]
[Patty] And right now,I feel this for you,
the same waythat you will feel Ellie'Ős pain.
What?
Stop. Stop the car.
-[Steve] Jesus! Adrienne,
what are you doing?
-Honey! Adrienne!
[Steve] Come back here!
[horns honking]
-[chattering]
-[woman speaking Spanish]
[tires screeching]
[groans][rattling]
[banging]
[groans]
Hey. It'Ős over now. Okay?
I'Őm going to get you
out of here.
[Adrienne groans]
Is the baby in the car?Where'Ős the baby?Hey, where'Ős the baby?
Come on.
-[homeless man grunts]
-[Adrienne groans]
[horns honking]
I know you.
You'Őre the ladywhose husband diedin that accident.
What?
What did you just say?
[homeless man] Hey.[gasping]
Hey, are you okay?
I can'Őt breathe.
[groaning][homeless man]Sit down. Hey.
[EMT 1] Are you okay?Can you hear me?
Where'Ős Matteo?
[EMT 2] Breathe. Just breathe.Just breathe. Just breathe.[groaning]
You'Őre okay. Breathe. It's okay.Just breathe. Just relax. Relax.
[indistinct]
[breathing heavily, groaning]
Hey, sit down.
Sit down--
You took him!What?
You-- You took him!What? No!
You took him![grunts]
I tried to save him, okay?I'Őm sorry.
It was--He was already gone.
No. [sobbing]
[Steve] Adrienne!
Hey! Hey!
No!
Adrienne, come here.I'Őm sorry.
No, no. no.
Come here. Come on.
[Steve] It'Ős all right.
It'Ős all right.
[Adrienne sobbing][Steve] Don'Őt worry.
There you go.
Be careful.
There we go. There we go.We'Őll go home. We'll go home.
[gasps]
[Maggie]
How did it go?
Adrienne?
Adrienne.[sniffles]
Please don'Őt--
don'Őt touch me.
Slow down. Okay?Honey.
It'Ős okay.
What?
I had him.
He was right here.I had him in my bed.
He was right here.
He was in my--[Patty] Oh, honey.
I was the one that got hurt.He was fine. He was fine.
Should I call Father Richard?
Just get him to bring him back.Can he bring him back, please?[crying]
I need him to come back.
Please, Mom.
[Patty] I can'Őt.
Can I have a minute, Mom?
[Patty] Of course.
I'Őll be right here
if you need me, okay?
You just...
You just rest.
[door closes]
Come back to me.
[sighs]
[inhales]
Come back to me.
[Ellie crying]
[grunts]
[knocking]
[heart monitor beeping]
[nurse on PA]
Nurse practitioner Ramon
to the Family Birth Center,
Room 4, please.
Nurse practitioner Ramon
to the Family Birth Center,
Room 4, please.
[Ellie crying]
[Patty]She'Ős still sleeping.
Are you ready to eat?
She hasn'Őt had anything.
I mean, they gave her
some sugar water IV,
but she'Ős mostly sleeping
on and off.
Come here.
[babbling]
Shh, shh. [sniffles]
[murmurs]
[Ellie giggling]Whoosh!
Come for a walk.
[clicking tongue]
Look.
It'Ős Daddy's chair.
Should we have a rock?
[chuckles]
[humming]
What do you think?
The black one?
What are you doing,you little monkey?
Blow a kiss.
Matteo was unassuming.
He was kind and good.
If he was here now,
he would tell you that there'Ősno reason for this, no purpose.
Except what we make of it.
[whispering]Mommy, I'Őm up. I'm up.
I'Őm awake.I'Őm up. I'm up. I'Őm up.
[chuckles]
I'Őm up.I know.
Yoink.
Come here, munchkin.
Come here.[giggling, babbling]
T-bear.
[laughs][knocking]
I'Őll get it. I can do it.I can do it. I can do it.
Okay. See who it is.
[speaking Spanish]
♪ Never thought That I would grow so old
♪
♪ Of seeing the gold♪
♪ Still I never want it to go♪
♪ I would hold it up
To my cold heart♪
[Ellie]
Dolphins, where are you?
They'Őre coming.
They'Őll be here.
♪ Take, take me back to The way that I was before
♪
♪ Hungry for what was to come♪
Keep your eyes open.
♪ I'’m longing
For the way I was♪
♪ You say you will
Say you will save me♪
♪ '’Cause I can't go on If your love isn'’t strong
♪
♪ See, I wanna know♪
[Adrienne] Here they come!Here they come! Here they come!Pretty dolphins!
Hello, dolphin! Hello!Look! Hello!
♪ Don'’t save me♪
♪ No, no♪
♪ No, baby♪
♪ Don'’t save me♪
♪ No, no♪
♪ All my life I wasn'’t trying To get on a highway
♪
♪ I was wondering
Which way to go♪
Hold on tight, okay?Okay.
Goodbye.
♪ No, baby, don'’t save me♪
♪ Now♪
♪ No, baby♪
♪ Don'’t save me♪
♪ Now♪
♪ No, baby, don'’t save me♪
♪ Now♪♪ Again and again and again♪
♪ Don'’t save me now♪
♪ Take me back, give it up
Give it up to me♪
♪ '’Cause I can't go on♪
♪ If your love isn'’t strong♪
♪ See, I wanna know♪
♪ Give me all your love♪
♪ If you can'’t hold on♪
♪ Then, baby, baby♪
♪ Don'’t save me now♪
♪ No, baby♪
♪ Again and again and again♪
♪ Don'’t save me♪
♪ Don'’t save me now♪