Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
Hey, Brad! Brad.
He took our money.
We- We just wanted
a bottle of J.D.,
And he said he'd go in and get it
for us if we gave him the money.
How much money? How much? Five dollars.
He bought himself a bottle of Gin.
- Did you take their money?
- Yeah, I took five dollars.
I was gonna give this to them, but they're
smart-ass kids, and now they're not getting it.
You'll give it back now? No,
i'm not gonna give it back.
You're not gonna
give it back to them?
No, I'm not 'cause
this kid's an asshole.
Which one?
The big one.
That's my brother. Yeah.
That's your brother?
Take care of him.
He's too young to drink.
Give him the money back.
I'm not giving him the money back,
and what are you gonna do about it?
Fuck you
and fuck them.
That's what I thought.
Brad?
Do you?
Get off the car,
kid.
You wanna play?
All right.
I can play.
Come on. Get off.
All right, kid.
You asked for it.
Faster. Come on.
Whoa.
Get off,
you nutcase.
All right, kid, come on.
Get off of the car.
- What do you want?
- The five.
Now get off the car,
all right?
Now what do you want?
- The gin.
- I gave you the five.
Hey, man, you know,
we got your license plates.
Now will you
get off the car?
You're weird, kid.
You know that?
That was
fucking great, man.
I liked it. Drink your
gin, get in the truck.
Don't you want
some of this?
Come on, man.
Nice move, man.
Hi.
Hello.
Is this your friend?
Yeah, Jill.
Jill. Hi, Jill.
Hi.
You got a name?
Brad?
You don't sound so sure.
Oh, I'm Terry.
Terry. Hi.
You have
a really nice smile.
Thanks.
Terry doesn't take drugs.
What are they?
I don't really know.
They make things stronger.
What is that
supposed to mean?
Whatever you feel, it
makes you feel it stronger.
Brad!
Just get her phone number
and come on.
Just get
her phone number.
Who's that?
My brother and his partner.
I gotta drive them, I guess.
Will I see you
down here again?
I don't know.
Well, where
will I see you?
Um,
Well, I guess I could be
here, like, day after tomorrow.
All right.
Well, I'll see you then.
Okay.
Bye.
Ooh-hoo.
Bradford.
Did you tell her
your name was Bradford?
The Toyota SR-5.
The truck that feels
like a sports car.
O-O-Oh, what a feeling
To drive... Toyota
Hey, Brad.
You're always trying to go out
with those real pretty women.
All they got
is a cunt.
They're all the same.
They tell you they want you
to- To talk nice...
And act nice.
Hello!
Yeah, come on in.
All they got is
a goddamned cunt.
What you doing?
My truck's
all fucked up.
Is she home?
No. No.
Now who's that?
I wanna give her
some money.
Goddamn.
Huh?
I said,
"she could sure use it."
So, what do you think,
a hundred?
Two, three? What?
Brad.
Yeah.
Tommy?
No.
Ah.
See ya.
How old are you now,
anyway?
Old enough.
Damn.
Do you know
where he's living at?
I don't care.
He's up in Homeville.
Little Brad...
Don't even think
about it.
Is that my beer
you're drinking?
There's a Colt 45.
You can't afford it.
You know, that shit you guys are
smoking is gonna rot your brains,
But I guess in your case, that
ain't no damage done, is it?
Why don't you get a
job, boy? I tried that.
You quit as soon as you paid off that
damn truck, didn't you? That's right.
We ain't all got it so lucky
around here, you know?
You see your mom in there. She's gotta work
in the morning. Your grandma's gotta work.
But more important, I gotta work
tomorrow, and I need some sleep.
You turn that damn thing on again,
and I'll beat the Jesus out of you.
There ain't no Jesus
in me.
Go to bed, Tommy.
Look, Ernie.
This here is my house.
You lived here four years. Before that
Rising Sun, six, before that, Jennersville.
You've been five months with her.
You don't ever tell me what to do.
Ernie. Ernie!
All right, enough.
You little son of a-
Yeah, Homeville. Number for
Bradford Whitewood sr., please.
I guess you must have heard
about me or something.
I guess.
What'd you hear?
I heard you was a thief.
What do you think
about that?
Looks like you make
pretty good money at it.
Well, to some folks, I'm just
the devil in blue suede shoes.
Don't you believe it, okay?
Okay.
I never stole
nothing, hear?
Yeah. Don't you worry about
getting a speeding ticket?
Kid, you look a thousand
miles any direction...
From tennessee
to toronto,
I go back roads
just about anyplace.
Never touch the interstate.
Never see one goddamn cop.
Besides, this ain't fast.
Hello?
That's my son.
It's Brad.
He'll be staying
with us...
A couple-
A few weeks.
This is
your uncle Dickie.
- Uncle Patch.
- Hi, kid.
That's boyd.
Tony Pine.
He's epileptic.
They're sort of
part of the family.
And, uh,
my sister and mother.
That's Mary Sue.
Hi, Brad jr.
Mary Sue's about five
years older than you.
- You're own family.
- We're late.
Mary Sue, show him
that room we got.
Hell, he's cute.
See you tomorrow.
I didn't know
you had a son, Brad.
Got two.
Sort of.
Old Braddy went to prison. Julie started
dickin' some grease monkey from willerton.
Nine months later,
out popped Tommy.
What exactly
are you saying?
Nothing. Nothing.
I didn't say nothing.
Just one thing here.
You don't say nothing
against the family.
Okay.
Let's go to work.
So, uh, where'd
they go, anyway?
One's coming.
Okay, I hear it.
Patch, what's that car?
Brad.
Brad, we lost our lookout. Yo.
I think your brother's out there
pinching hubcaps or something.
I'll stay
where I can hear you.
- Hundreds?
- Twenties.
You remind me of a guy
i knew in high school.
Only he was
a real doofus.
Go for a ride?
Sure.
Gimme that foot.
Gimme those little piggies.
Mmm.
Time to do some laundry.
Kid, you like pussy?
Yeah.
Smart boy.
What's the sexiest thing you ever
thought of in your whole life?
Excuse me. Can I help you? Yeah.
You got- You got, what,
$5,500 on that car?
I'll give you five...
cash.
Do I drive her out?
What are we doing here?
Laundry.
You know that truck of mine's
gone punk dead.
I could sure use a slick
car sometime. Maybe.
- Good afternoon, sir.
- Yeah.
I just bought
this car...
For 5,500.
It's a cherry.
- Would you give me 46 for her?
- Why are you selling it?
I don't like the radio.
You're kidding.
No.
Mom said, "that's my son.
Nobody touches my son."
And she threw his suitcase
down the stairs.
I wish I'd seen that.
Brad, when are you
gonna come home?
I don't know. I'm hoping
dad might give me something.
Yeah? What?
Hey, Jill. Jill.
Hey, Terry's friend.
Hi.
You scared the hell out of me. Sorry.
Well, thanks
for coming out.
I can only stay
a minute.
Oh, well,
your friend, Jill,
Didn't know if you wanted
to come out at all.
Jill.
So, you do
remember me, huh?
- Sure.
- You were supposed to meet me, you know, that night.
I know. My mother
wouldn't let me out.
And then I tried to sneak out,
and she caught me.
Really? Yeah. She
grounded me for two weeks.
She says until I'm 17,
i can only go out-
- You're only 16?
- Yeah, so?
I thought about
your smile a lot.
I thought about you too.
Jill says
your last name's Whitewood?
Yeah.
Your father's
got kind of a rep.
Well, yeah. Don't believe
everything you hear.
- Terry.
- Oh, shit. I gotta go.
Wait a minute. Jill didn't
give me your number or anything.
555-6239.
Three-nine.
Yeah, okay. Wait. Don't go yet.
Um-
Terry?
I gotta go.
Bye.
Ha!
Hey, Patch, how come you
don't go out with them anymore?
The other guys.
'Cause your daddy's
a dickface.
Don't want me
having no money.
having no fun.
One day, I'm gonna have
my own empire.
I'm gonna steal
everything.
- Wanna help me?
- I don't know.
Sure you can. You ever
steal a police car?
No.
Me neither.
Hey, we could steal a whole
lot of stuff, you and me.
There's no sense sitting around a
dump like this, wasting our time.
I heard that. I mean, there's
a world out there waiting.
Tell you what.
Let's you and me
go in the next room...
And start sniffing
some ideas.
Let's go.
"Ideas" is
my middle name.
What do you think?
It's fuckin' beautiful.
It's a piece of shit,
but it's yours.
Is it legal?
Yes, it's legal.
There's parts on it
borrowed, but...
Registration's clean.
Don't never say
i done nothing for you.
Just don't know
if I could ever pay you back.
Try this.
Stay clear of my brother.
Which one?
You know damn well,
boy.
Okay. It's a good way for me to make some
money, you know? It's something I can do.
You two jackasses,
you'll both end up in jail.
Then, you teach me.
You show me what to do.
If I'm gonna learn, I should learn
right, from you. I got no time.
Just to show me?
Don't seem right.
Come on, dad.
I get some guys together.
I don't know.
We'll see.
You better go on home.
To your mother's.
Yeah.
I don't know why, but...
You make Mary Sue
awful skittish.
Five.
I'm going to bed.
Ten, eleven, two, three
- Wait!
Wait, wait. Julie, wait. You've got
- Mom.
Okay, she left.
Hold on. Six, seven.
Six plus five... is eleven. Is 11.
One, two, three, four...
Five, six, seven,
eight, nine, ten, eleven.
My property.
No problem.
Now we're gonna split
her property up.
I'll take boardwalk and park place. No.
You can take-
No, I want boardwalk.
No, see, grandma,
if you take this property,
You'll have a hotel on each, and
there's better odds of landing on it.
No, I want boardwalk. 'Cause there's
three of them and there's only-
Big Brad, you know,
When I married him, he had
the biggest eyes you ever saw,
And he courted me
like a regular gentleman.
With flowers
and everything.
Good night,
little Brad.
Good night.
Hey, Brad.
Are you awake?
There's a girl
on the phone.
I'd better get you home before
your mother starts to worry.
It's nice to meet you.
Likewise.
Good-bye.
What's he like?
Who?
Find one there.
Find one right there.
Back in there too.
How can you tell?
Size of the lawn,
size of the stroke.
Regular mower cuts
about a foot wide.
Good tractor
do you three or four.
See, most people
that drive through here,
They see farms,
Houses and fields
and shit.
I see money. Everywhere
i go I see money.
I see things that can move. Anything
can move, it's got my name written on it.
"Brad Whitewood, please hold
for the delivery."
- My name too.
- Yeah, little bastard.
Oh, wait, I forgot.
You's the bastard, ain't ya?
Hey.
I didn't mean
nothing by it.
I swear I didn't mean
One day, you know what?
You know what I'm gonna do?
Give you guys a present.
What do you think
of that?
Looks like
a pretty nice gun.
Fuckin' A-plus,
it's a nice gun.
It's 350, retail.
I got a good price on mine.
Real good. Wanna touch it?
Can I?
Is that all right?
- Do you like it?
- I like it a lot.
You can't have it.
It's mine.
I already
give you a car.
That don't mean nothing. I
gotta see something in you.
I gotta see you got
something... right here...
Between the legs,
Then I'll give you
a real present.
You wanna see
we got something?
We'll show you something. We'll
show you something tonight.
Yeah?
Hey, Brad.
How's it going?
- These your new recruits?
- These are my sons, lester.
Oh, well,
You boys have
a very interesting family.
Get out of my face,
lester.
For instance, remember when
we stole those muskets...
From the
revolutionary war museum?
Of course, dickie conked out
that, uh, janitor, making it...
Grand larceny,
aggravated assault.
But it was a good time,
right, Brad?
Oh, yeah, you're smart.
You don't wanna talk to me.
Come on, Brad.
I wanna work with you again.
I need some of that action.
Why, so you can tell
the cops?
Cops? Ain't so bad.
Just doing their job.
Just kidding.
Okay, I know.
I'm going.
I'm going. I'm gone.
The boy ain't got the life
expectancy of a housefly.
Like this one time, Patch goes
into this jewelry store, right?
He asks to see
this $500 watch.
So, the lady,
she shows it to him, all right,
But she don't wanna take
her paws off it.
He's tuggin' one direction,
she's tuggin' the other direction.
Finally, pulls up his sleeve, he
goes, "lady, mine's worth a thousand.
Why the hell
would I want yours?"
This makes sense to her, right? So,
she takes her hands off the thing.
He grabs the son of a bitch and
hightails it out of the store.
Shit!
Something's coming.
Oh, what a feeling
Don't stop
oh, what a feeling
Tomorrow, tomorrow
oh, oh, oh, oh, what a feeling
Toyota
Hurry up! We gotta get this
stuff to a truck stop before dawn.
Yo, Brad!
Yo!
Telephone!
All right.
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty,
kitty. You're one to talk. Hey!
Make it spicy, Rose.
Yo, what you got?
Shot.
Say again.
Shot. I got shot, man.
Birdshot in the face.
Bad?
Well, it hurts.
- Get any tractors?
- No.
- Go on home, then.
- I can't. Not with my face like this.
You can't go to my place
if that's what you're asking.
Mary Sue, me, we're here,
we're helping out... late.
Be at it all night.
Can I come
where you're at?
You got a woman...
Someplace.
I want you both downstairs with
your clothes on in five minutes.
Do you hear me, Terry?
Whoo!
Sorry.
Hey.
Wake up.
You know, I know my mom.
She's not gonna sit there.
She's gonna call the cops
after me.
I mean,
what are we gonna do?
We got $18 left.
I'm gonna have to
go home.
Listen.
If we can sometime,
You wanna go somewhere?
Get our own place
together?
Okay.
You mean it?
Sure.
I mean it.
Okay.
It might take a little while,
but I can do it.
How?
Don't worry about it.
I'll take care of it.
I worry about it.
If you're thinkin'
you're too cool to boogie
Boy, oh, boy
have I got news for you
Everybody here tonight
must boogie
And right there,
sitting on my lap...
was the most beautiful woman
you guys ever seen in your life.
Mm-hmm. Beautiful? She was a hooker.
She wasn't a hooker.
She was a... architect.
Oh, boogie
Boogie no more
some big firm in Philly.
You can't boogie no more
Boogie
boogie no more
Listen to the music except
for the assholes and the faggots,
I'm the richest son of a bitch
in this county.
Mind if I sit down?
I want you to taste something
'cause I saw you sitting there.
Yeah, see now.
Yeah.
Private stock.
There's no time to waste
Let's get this show
on the road
Were you here last week, hustling? No.
I thought I saw you last week. Wait just
a minute. I need some I.D. on the lady.
I shall return.
The sooner we begin
Get outta here.
Andy, that's my son.
Hell, Brad, I can't
- Yeah, this girl, she's 23.
Listen to the music
and let your body move
Dad, this is Terry.
Hi.
You treat my boy right.
I will.
I do.
Come on. Sit down.
Make yourself at home.
Listen, Terry? That's Patch. Yeah.
Dickie. Boyd.
Tony Pine. He's epileptic.
What you drinking?
I'm fine. Thanks.
You're overage.
She's 42.
I'll have a Rolling Rock. Hmm.
I'll have
a whiskey sour.
Whiskey sour?
They're good.
Yeah.
We're real glad to get to meet
you, Terry. What do you think...
Now that you get to see us
all in the flesh?
I don't know.
Heard a lot about you.
- Nice things?
- You ain't done nothin' nice, Brad.
I hope not.
What'd you hear?
Different things.
Dad, we wanna talk to you
for a moment.
I came here 'cause I wanted
to ask you about this.
See, Terry and I,
we wanna live together.
We wanna get a place like that.
It's gonna cost some real money.
So, I wanna join up
with you guys.
Just temporarily.
Fine. Fine.
You don't have to
let him in.
But you know,
he's better than you.
Would you excuse us?
It's all right.
That's not right.
You wanna talk to me?
You talk to me in private.
I'll tell you something.
That girl is trouble.
She's nice, she's young,
big mouth.
You stick with us. You stick by
me. You can see this is a group.
You know,
you don't violate that.
Take her home.
Don't ever do that again.
Okay? Don't worry about it.
It's okay.
And look.
Everything
will work out fine.
Yeah.
Okay.
Sorry.
Go ahead.
What else?
Well, this group of guys,
whatever you call it...
Goes all over the country, huh? Yeah.
And it's organized?
Organized?
Yeah.
Enough.
It's just guys, you know.
I know guys,
and Tony Pine knows some.
Boyd, my brothers,
everybody knows some people.
These people
know people.
Before you know it,
You know everybody you gotta
know to get the job done.
That's it.
How do you keep cops
off your ass?
I got a friend
who reads the police memos.
For instance, they
just got this report...
There's more tractors stolen in
Maryland, Delaware, Pennsylvania-
That's us
- Than all the other 47 states together.
Makes the cops around here
kinda peppy, so...
We lay off tractors
for a while.
Anything else?
Why are you letting me ask you
all this? 'Cause you gotta know.
I gotta make sure you walk
into this with your eyes wide...
And know what you're doing
and who you're with.
Especially, you know,
it's a family situation.
You go out with us
once or twice.
See how it is,
then you decide.
If you still want it
- 'Cause if you do, that's it.
It's blood.
Don't break it.
Don't want none.
Here you go, Dickie.
The caretaker's light
just went on.
Okay, don't move at all!
Don't move.
Good.
Good goin', kid.
Bye-bye.
Go, go, go!
You know what?
I've been thinking.
I oughta sign up
at the university.
Hey, that's a real good idea,
Patch. That's real swift.
No, no, no, no, no. Take
one of them art courses.
We go into a joint like that,
must be t-t-trillions-
Hundreds of trillions of dollars
hanging on the wall.
And we're too dumb
to know which ones to take.
Take the ugly ones. Uglier
they are, more they're worth.
That's right.
What? You showed me something tonight.
What?
My own blood.
Am I right?
- You're gonna make it.
- Heard that.
Lookie here.
Good ol' detective Mosker.
He's really got class.
Havin' hamburger steak.
Well, hello.
See ya later.
Oh, I know. Did you hear about that
girl that was eight before she was seven?
Oop, I hate
those short eyes jokes.
Look who waited up.
Well, I didn't want you
getting the wrong idea,
My sharin' dinner
with some fuckin' cop.
We didn't get
the wrong idea, Lester.
We got the right idea.
Yeah.
Wanna go out?
A job?
Right now.
Okay, no, I
- Don't say no. It's your chance to prove yourself.
Come on, lester.
I know you're a good man.
Catch up.
Come on, drink up, drink up.
That's more like it.
We're drunk as skunks,
And we want you to feel
just as good.
That's more like it.
Ah!
I have somethin'.
You gettin' high? Drink it,
it's for you. I don't know.
Eat this.
What is it? It's, uh,
somethin' to eat. Eat it.
What you been tellin'
the cops, lester? Nothin'!
What you talkin' to mosker
about? The weather, the phillies?
No. No, just, uh-
I know you've been talkin'
about somethin'.
I'm scared.
What?
You can't be scared.
You're a tough guy.
You used to be a member
of the Whitewood gang.
Yeah, I know, but-
What'd you say?
Speak up.
Well, I, uh, I sold him some
information. Leave him alone.
Uh-huh. Yeah, but it wasn't
true. It was about soleski.
Oh? Oh, I hate him. Yeah, I know.
I- I-I wouldn't hurt you, Brad.
You know that. He's a fat pig.
I wanna help you, I do.
Yeah?
I was pumpin' him for information,
stuff you guys can use.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, hurry up.
I found out that, uh,
they brought the F.B.I. In.
Yeah? No shit? Yeah.
Yeah, and, uh, they got
this, uh, grand jury convened.
About us?
Sure.
Mm. I'm telling you, who would
tell you this kind of stuff...
If it wasn't for me?
I don't know. Guess you're
just a real good friend.
I don't feel too good.
I drank too much.
Better pull over.
Pull over by this tree.
We're goin' down
to the river.
I'm glad
to be able to-
Ahh.
I can't walk.
Hey! Hey!
Whoa.
Feel that water, les? It's good. Yeah.
Wake you right up.
Whoo!
It's getting deeper.
Get your face wet. Water on
your face really wakes you up.
Hey, I don't need your help.
No, I can do it alone!
Hey! Whoa!
Ahh, Brad!
Shh.
We get this thing fixed up,
you'll be one cool dude,
A real rumbler.
I think I'm gonna
get myself a job...
Fixing Chevys or something.
How much you make?
You can get like ten,
twelve an hour. It depends.
That ain't that much.
Hey, it's a steady job.
Nobody gets killed.
Somebody got killed?
Brad, when you went out with dad
and them, did somebody get killed?
Forget it.
Brad. I said forget it, Tommy.
He's no good.
What?
They're no good.
What are you talking about?
They're bad people.
Hi, boys!
Hi, dad.
What you think of that? That's nice.
I just got it.
You see, the thing is-
I'm gonna tell ya-
I got some big business
over in Willerton,
And I was wondering if you guys
could help me out with some of that...
Wacky-Tobaccy.
What you say?
I got money.
Yeah.
Hurry up.
Goin' out tonight.
Be by around midnight.
What's the damage? Twenty-five? Forty.
Yeah?
Forty.
You a born thief.
You crazy.
You know, you crazy.
Lookin' good,
Julie Whitewood!
Tired old bag of shit.
You like that car?
You wanna sit in that car?
Is it all right?
Go on, sit in it.
All right.
I'm not goin' out tonight.
What?
I'm not gonna go out anymore.
You wanna live
in a dump like this?
Workin' ten hours a day
in a cannery?
I thought you were like me.
I thought you wanted something.
A car,
Nice girl sittin' in your lap,
money in your pocket.
You said I could go out
and then decide, right?
You scared?
I got somethin' else.
Somethin' or somebody?
Yeah, Terry and I
are gettin' outta here.
Where you gonna go? What are you
gonna do when you get where you go?
I got some ideas.
How you gonna pay?
Apartment, food, clothes.
All that.
I'll find something.
You'll find shit! All
you know is how to steal.
You're too fuckin' dumb
to do that by yourself.
Oh, you think so?
I know so.
You'll come back, crawlin' back to
me, "daddy, daddy, give me somethin'."
Well, we'll see. We'll
see. Yeah, we'll see, yep.
What's the matter?
Tell me about your uncle.
Your uncle. Will he
really take us?
Sure.
What's it like there?
What does it look like?
It's called
the Big Sky country,
'Cause the land goes on forever,
Lookin' out 20 miles one way,
50 in the other.
And they got jobs there too.
My cousin's husband, Rollie,
he's got a job in Billings,
And he's about as dumb
as a dog or something.
You know what else they got?
My cousin
- She's just two years older than me, and she's got a baby.
It's got little tiny feet
and little hands,
And it laughs already.
It probably talks now, but when
i was there, it was just laughing.
It was so tiny.
I guess I love you, huh?
So,
What do you think?
I don't know.
It- it seems-
It's a little big.
Who cares if it's
a fucked-up idea?
If we get away with it, we score big,
right? Look, it's not a fucked-up idea.
All we have to do is get in and
out of there as fast as possible.
Okay?
Okay.
Ahh!
Ah, come on, there's a car!
Oh, shit. Somebody's
coming. Come on, let's go.
Tommy, come on, help tim get
these ramps. Get the crowbar.
Where the fuck is it?
Aggie! Come on!
- Get a load of this, man.
- Come on, the car!
I gotta have her!
Let's go!
Come on!
Isn't she beautiful?
Let go, man! Get in!
Close the door and shut it!
Fuck it! Come on!
Now I want you to climb down
from there very slowly. Fuck!
Okay, bailed out:
Essex, Milton,
Smithson and Whitewood, t.
Go on.
You here to shut this down?
Maybe next week. What
do you want, Whitewood?
I put 500 on that gray one.
Ho, ho,
that's a shrewd bet.
What's my son sayin'?
Nothin'.
Yeah? But they haven't
really started on him yet.
What about the F.B.I.?
They really bring 'em in?
Mm-hmm, last month.
Grand jury?
Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
What they got?
Not much so far.
I'm sure they'll
find something.
Maybe a body
or two, hmm?
Can I make a donation?
A political somethin'?
No, not now.
It's too hot.
Oh, your bird lost.
So he did.
Maybe next week, hmm? If
they don't get anything more.
Yeah?
Yeah, we'll see.
If they do... get more?
Hi, is Mr. Whitewood here?
M- My name's Terry.
It's okay.
Thanks.
Um, I was planning
to go see Brad,
And, uh, his mother can't go till
the weekend 'cause she's working.
So I was wondering
if-if you're planning to go.
Maybe.
Well, if you do go,
Um, do you mind
if I go with you?
I don't see why not.
You've done a lot for my boy. I hope so.
You changed him.
Thank you.
What I don't get is why
they let everybody else out,
And they set
Brad's bail so high.
I don't get it.
They figure,
if he's in there long enough,
We'll know what he's saying. About what?
Oh.
Mm.
You want some corn flakes?
No, thanks.
You scared, kid?
Of what?
A bunch of tractor thieves?
What do you owe those guys?
What'd they ever do for you?
What'd your father
ever do for you?
I don't talk
against my family.
Hello?
Uh, look, uh,
do me a favor.
That's 12,000 cash.
Tell Brad that-
He don't want it.
Let him decide.
I said he don't want it.
- Wow, that's a really nice cake.
- Has it got a file in it?
Yeah.
I didn't-
I didn't even know you-
I didn't know you guys
knew each other really.
Lucas?
Oh, yeah.
Only one in the whole kiddie gang
knows his ass from a pitchfork.
I'm kinda takin' him
under my wing.
Yeah.
How you doin'?
Nervous, I bet.
I'm okay. Ever been
inside a jail before?
No. No way.
It's nasty, I'll tell ya. It
gives me the Jimmies every time.
Oh, yeah.
Want some? What is it? Bourbon?
It's just Rye. You're
welcome to it, if you want.
Oh, yeah. I heard that. It's good stuff.
That'll really- It's
not a bad idea, really-
Get a little juiced before you get
in there. Get some system goin'.
See, the thing is, it's
gonna be worst of all on you.
Why's that?
Bein' a girl.
Bein'- Bein' a cute girl.
Yeah, bein' real cute
and bein' a girl.
All them other convicts and the perverts
and such, be givin' you a real long look.
Oh, they be lookin' at
you all over. That's right.
Convicts stare.
Aren't you gonna protect me?
Can't.
Sure.
Not from their eyes.
Don't worry about it.
Another sip of that,
you won't feel nothin'.
Go on.
Just go on.
That's good stuff, huh?
Drink it.
Yeah.
I am okay. Come on. Just leave it there.
Whoa.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Come on. Come on. What? You touched me.
Okay.
Come on.
I wanna go-
I wanna go see Brad.
I don't wanna go in there.
Screw Brad.
No.
What are you doing?
Where's lucas?
Made a mistake. To let a woman rule his business
- That is a mistake.
What do you mean?
Where the fuck-
I wanna get out of this fucking
place. You scared yet? Hmm?
Here, drink that down. You got
that pill? What is this place?
Where is it? Where is it?
Let me see it. Right.
Drink it down.
You scared yet?
Mm.
You oughta be.
I'm not scared of you.
You scared yet? No? Look, we
gotta get something straight now.
Oh, no, you're not goin' anywhere.
We gotta get somethin' straight.
You ain't gonna see my son.
Okay?
You give me your word.
I gotta hear it.
I gotta believe it.
I love Brad.
Well, that's your mistake.
I love him! That's a
mistake. It's over. That's it.
You know too much, you think too
much, you talk too much. That's it.
Okay? Where you goin'? Where you
goin'? Where the fuck you goin'?
Come here. Let me tell you
something. Let me tell you something.
- The answer's no.
- I ain't askin'.
The answer is no.
By the time I'm through with
you, you won't wanna see him.
He won't wanna touch you. Do
you understand? Get off me!
You understand? He won't wanna
fuckin' touch you. Get off me!
You understand now?
- Well?
- Sit down.
Ma'am? Ma'am!
Yes? Is there a Thomas Whitewood here?
Are you Thomas Whitewood?
What about it?
I need you to sign this.
Please, just sign it.
What is this?
Uh-
Thank you.
Somebody gave your name
to the grand jury.
All right, you motherfucker!
Motherfucker!
Scum!
Hell, man, don't worry
about no subpoena.
They got nothing on you.
Yeah. Gee, I sure hope not.
They're just fishin'
for somethin' or other.
Now, where the hell
is this tractor, anyhow?
Patch?
Up a ways.
This is one hell of a...
Jesus H. Christ kind of a place
to go find some tractor.
We only found it,
'cause last year, Dickie,
He poached for deer
up in these woods.
A white deer.
Right over in there.
Now what's that?
Damn, I thought he was gonna
back right into his grave.
You know, aggie, I like
that ring you got.
What'd it cost?
Beats me.
Is that a real sapphire?
Wouldn't you like to know?
Yeah, I would.
Is that a real gun?
Come on, right over here!
Get your tickets right here!
Get your tickets here!
Hubba, hubba, hubba!
Come on, give me
one of those tickets!
Ever been out west, Tommy?
No.
Ever heard a coyote?
They make this sound like,
whoo, whoo, whoo.
Coyote bitch gets in heat,
First thing she does,
She'd take care
of the males.
Then she head toward town.
All the neighborhood dogs,
they smell her.
They go crazy.
They follow her.
She lures them
out onto the desert.
She get the dog
out there...
Alone.
All the other coyote
come along.
They circle round.
They kill that dog.
Eat it.
Tommy,
If you was to go up in front of
that grand jury, what would you say?
Nothin'.
- Dad.
- Liar!
That's our deal. You let me outta here
right now, or I don't say one more word.
Can't do it. Your father's
hiding three kids already.
Besides, the only thing you've talked
about so far are tractor thefts.
Why should we think you have
anything else to tell us?
Have you guys ever heard
of lester peralsky?
Ma, Terry and I are leaving'.
We're gettin' outta here.
You'd be goin' where?
I got relatives in-
Far away.
Do you have any money
we can borrow?
Not really.
Well, I-I have a little bit.
Great.
Say, Brad junior, have you
heard anything from Tommy? No.
I don't even wanna
think about Tommy.
What is that
supposed to mean?
Just itself.
Don't think about him.
How about this?
Let's tie him to a tree...
In the back of the woods...
And just stare at him
for a while.
No!
But can't you just see it?
He's tied to a tree...
naked.
And we could give him
like a lollipop or somethin'...
Or a can of Budweiser.
Shut up!
Suppose that little girl
is with him?
Then bye-bye girl.
That's too bad.
She was real cute.
Might be better, uh,
if it was at night.
Right?
I don't want no part of this. Boyd?
You got the soul
of a pig,
A stuck pig.
Sooey.
Sooey, sooey.
I don't care.
I'm not touchin' this one.
Okay.
Well?
You can hang it up where you're
going to. I mean, if you want to.
Thanks.
Gotta go.
Brad!
It's something
over 400.
Thanks a lot.
I guess
it's a rainy day.
Thanks, grandma.
Take care of Terry now.
I will.
Good-bye.
Bye.
How's it coming?
It's almost there.
It could wait till morning.
No. Your mother'll
be back in the morning.
Farther we are away,
it'll be a lot better.
You don't have to say
what I wanna do
Come on, come on, come on
and have a Pepsi day
It's the laughter of a world
at play memories of a Pepsi day
Come on, come on and have a Pepsi day
join the Pepsi generation
Have a pepsi day
Oh, I forgot
to feed the dog.
Oh, no!
Hey, dad.
Let ya outta the stir?
Yeah, I-I just told them
a pack of lies...
And now I'm just runnin'
where they can't find me.
That's good.
Where nobody can find me.
Good.
You got a beer?
Yeah, sure.
Gotta take a leak.
Dad.
It's good to see you.
Really.
You look pale.
I am pale.
Where you been tonight?
Got drunk, had a fight. Mary
Sue, you know, kicked her out.
You know, went to andy's.
Same old thing, you know?
Yeah, I know.
Know where I been?
That's nothin'. I just cut
myself on some barbed wire.
Don't move. I said,
don't fuckin' move!
Just goin' to get some-
- I said, don't fuckin' move.
Is this the gun you used?
That's a nice-looking gun.
Is this the gun you used to kill
Tommy? Tommy's dead, isn't he?
Don't talk to me about Tommy.
Is this the gun you used
to kill Terry?
I never did nothin'
to Terry.
Whoa! Whoa, wait, wait!
Wait, wait, wait, wait. Wait!
Is this the gun you used
on everybody? On me?
Is this a family gun, dad?
Jesus. Put that down.
What's eatin' you?
- You're gonna die.
- Come on-
I know one thing clearer than I've
ever known anything in my entire life,
Except that I loved Terry
before you killed her,
And that is that
you're gonna die.
You got the guts...
To kill... me?
I'm your blood!
I'm your family!
You're not my family.
Not anymore.
Yeah, you're crazy.
Crazy! Gone crazy.
Nope. Listen! Listen!
What?
I know how it is.
Cops got ya in there, get your head
all fucked-up. I know how that is.
My mind's simple, dad.
Before they got you twisted,
You must've known somethin',
you must've felt it.
I gave you money, I gave you a car, I
took you in. Don't that mean somethin'?
Means what?
It means, I got feelin' for
ya. What fuckin' feeling?
I care. What do ya-
I love you.
What?
Is that what you wanna hear?
I love you.
Yeah?
Motherfucker!
I love you too, dad.
Whoa!
Don't!
No.
No, I ain't you.
Besides,
this is too easy.
I want you to die slow.
I want you to die every day
for the rest of your life.
Go on.
- Don't fuckin' move!
- I don't move.
Your name?
Bradford Whitewood.
And what
do they call you?
Brad, little Brad,
Brad junior.
And is there a Brad senior? A big Brad?
- Yes.
- Who is he?
My father.
What did you say?
He's my father.
I have
A tale to tell
Sometimes it gets so hard
To hide it well
I was not ready for the fall
Too blind to see the writing
on the wall
A man can tell
a thousand lies
I've learned
my lesson well
Hope I live to tell the secret
i have learned
Till then
It will burn inside of me
I know
Where beauty lives
I've seen it once
I know the warm she gives
The light that you
could never see
It shines inside
You can't take that
from me
A man can tell
a thousand lies
I've learned
my lesson well
Hope I live to tell the secret
i have learned
Till then
It will burn inside of me
The truth is never
far behind
You kept it hidden well
If I live to tell the secret
i knew then
Will I
Ever have the chance again
If I ran away
I'd never have the strength
to go very far
How would they hear
The beating of my heart
Will it grow cold
will it grow cold
The secret that I hide
Will I grow old
How will they hear
when will they learn
How will they know
A man can tell
a thousand lies
I've learned my lesson well
Hope I live to tell the secret
i have learned
Till then
It will burn inside of me
The truth is never
far behind
You kept it hidden well
If I live to tell the secret
i knew then
Will I
Ever have the chance again
A man can tell
a thousand lies
I've learned my lesson well
Hope I live to tell the secre
i have learned
Till then
It will burn inside of me