How you doing   Keaton?
I can't feel my legs...
...Keyser.
Ready?
What time is it?
12:30.
It all started back in New York six weeks ago.
A truck loaded with gun parts got jacked outside of Queens.
The driver saw nobody   but someone fucked up.
He heard a voice. Sometimes that's all you need.
Mr. McManus?
Christ! Don't you fucking guys ever sleep?
- We have a warrant for your arrest. - Fuck you   pig.
Todd Hockney?
- Who wants to know? - New York Police Department.
Shit!
- Freeze! - Hold it!
You sure you brought enough guys?
It's quite simple.
A restaurant that changes with the taste without losing the esthetic.
In other words   the atmosphere will not be painted on the walls.
Let me give you an example.
This I had to see for myself.
David.
- I'm in a meeting. - Time for another one.
Everyone   this is David Kujan.
Special Agent Kujan   U.S. Customs.
These men are from the New York Police Department.
You look good   Keaton. Better than I'd have thought.
You have a problem?
A small matter of a stolen truck loaded with guns.
Mr. Keaton?
Will you excuse us for a moment?
We have some questions to ask you downtown. You'll be a while.
No   no   no   please. Please   sit down.
This is a small problem.
Enjoy the meal.
Talk to you later.
It didn't make sense that I'd be there.
These guys were hard-core hijackers.
But there I was.
At that point   I wasn't scared.
I knew I hadn't done anything they could do me for.
Besides   it was fun.
I got to make like I was notorious.
You all know the drill.
When your number is called   repeat the phrase you've been given.
Number one   step forward.
Hand me the keys   you fucking cocksucker.
Number two   step forward.
Give me the fucking keys   you cocksucker   motherfucker...
Knock it off. Get back. Number three   step forward.
- Hand me the keys   you cocksucker. - In English   please.
Excuse me?
In English.
Hand me the keys   you cocksucker. What the fuck?
Number four   step forward.
It was bullshit. The whole rap was a setup.
Hand me the keys   you fucking cocksucker.
It was the cops' fault.
You don't put guys like that into a room together.
Who knows what can happen.
Hand me the keys   you fucking cocksucker.
This has really gotta be embarrassing for you guys.
Someone was pissed about that hijacked truck. The cops had nothing.
They hoped somebody would slip and give them something.
They knew we wouldn't fight it because they knew how to lean on us.
Our rights went out the window. It was a violation. Disgraceful.
They went after McManus first. Topnotch entry man.
What truck?
- The truck with the guns   fucko. - Fucko?
He was a good guy. Crazy though.
Wanna know what Fenster told us?
- Said who? - McManus. He told us another story.
Was that the one about the hooker with the dysentery?
Fenster worked with McManus. He was a tight-ass.
But when it came to the job   he was right on. A smart man.
What are you saying?
- I said he'll flip you. - He'll what?
- Flip you for real. - I'm shaking.
Come on. Answer my question.
Can you hear me in the back?
I want my lawyer.
I'm gonna have your fucking badge   cocksucker.
Todd Hockney. Good with explosives.
Without a doubt   the guy who didn't give a fuck about anybody.
You guys don't have a leg to stand on.
I can put you in Queens on the night of the hijacking.
Really?
I live in Queens. Did you put that together yourself   Einstein?
You got a team of monkeys working on this?
You know what happens if you do another turn in the joint?
Fuck your father and then have a snack.
- You gonna charge me? - I'll charge you when I'm ready.
- With what? - You know damn well   dead man.
But Keaton? He was the real prize for them   for obvious reasons.
It was your mistake. Not mine.
Did you ever stop to ask me?
I mean   I been walking around with the same face   the same name.
I'm a businessman.
What's that? The restaurant business?
From now on   you're in the getting-fucked-by-us business.
I'm gonna make you famous   cocksucker.
Like I said...
...it was your mistake. Not mine.
Now   you charge me with this shit...
...and I'll beat it.
Let's get back to the truck   asshole.
Somebody's gotta do something. I get hauled in every five minutes.
So I did a little time. Does that mean I get railed...
...every time a truck finds its way off the planet? Fuck them.
Fenster   will you relax? These guys don't have any probable cause.
You're fucking-A right. No P.C.
You're goddamn right. You do some time   never let you go.
They treat me like a criminal   I'll end up a criminal.
You are a criminal.
Now   why you gotta go and do that? I'm trying to make a point.
Why don't you make your point? You're making me tired all over.
Fuck it   then.
- I heard you were dead. - Oh   yeah?
- You heard right. - Word I got is you hung up your spurs.
- What's that all about? - What's this?
Rumor is Keaton's gone straight.
- I hear he's tapping Edie Finneran. - Who's that?
A heavyweight criminal lawyer. I hear she's Keaton's meal ticket.
How about it   Keaton?
You a lawyer's wife?
What retainer you giving her?
Hey   Fenster   do your friend a favor.
Tell him to keep quiet.
Dean Keaton.
Gone clean   huh?
Say it ain't so.
Or did you hit that truck?
Mac   Mac. Forget him. Did you get to talk to your lawyer?
This whole thing was a shakedown.
- Why do you say that? - How many times you been in a lineup?
It's always you and four dummies.
P.D. pays homeless guys 10 bucks a head half the time.
There's no way they'd line five felons in the same row.
A voice lineup? A public defender could get you out of that.
So why was I strip-searched?
It was the feds.
A truckload of guns get snagged.
Customs comes down on NYPD for answers. They come up with us.
- They're clutching at straws. - A guy's finger was up my ass.
Is it Friday already?
Yeah   lover-boy.
You want a piece? Jump in. I'll love you.
So who are the goddamn pigs who stole our fucking truck?
- What did you say? - Who stole the fucking truck?
- I don't want to know. - Who asked you   working man?
Fuck who did it. I wanna know   who's the gimp?
- He's okay. - Says you. What about it   pretzel man?
His name is Verbal.
Verbal Kint.
Roger   really. People say I talk too much.
I was gonna tell you to shut up.
We met before once or twice.
In county. I was in for fraud.
You were in a lineup. What happened?
I walked. 90 days suspended.
So you did it.
All right   now look.
We've all been put out by this whole thing   right?
So I figure we owe it to ourselves to salvage a little dignity.
Now   me and Fenster heard about a little job.
Why don't you just calm down?
What do you care what he says?
I'm just talking here.
It seems to me like Mr. Hockney wants to hear it   and I know Fenster's down.
What about you   guy?
I'm interested. Sure.
There. See?
Now I'd like to exercise my right to free assembly.
Why don't you just shut up?
You're missing the point.
No. You're missing the point.
I don't wanna hear anything from you.
I don't care about your job.
I want nothing to do with any of you.
I beg your pardon   but you can all go to hell.
Dean Keaton...
...gone the high road.
What is the world coming to?
Fuck him.
And that was how it started.
Us five being brought in on trumped-up charges to be leaned on by half-wits.
I really can't talk about it much here.
What the cops never figured out   and what I know now...
...was that these men would never break. Never lie down.
Never bend over for anybody.
Anybody.
Who are you?
Agent Jack Baer   FBI. How many dead?
Fifteen. They're still pulling bodies out of the water.
- Any survivors? - There's two.
One guy's in County Hospital in a coma.
The D.A. has the second guy   a cripple from New York.
The chief wants this place sealed off.
If you have any questions   give him a call.
This is Dave Kujan. I'll be in Los Angeles until Tuesday.
If you need me   contact Jeff Rabin...
...of the San Pedro Police Department at extension 112. Have a nice day.
- Why can't I see him? - I told you.
The D.A. was here ready to arraign even before they moved him to county.
Kint's lawyer shows up five minutes later...
...the D.A. comes out looking like the bogeyman smacked him.
They take his statement   and they cut him a deal.
- Did they charge him with anything? - Weapons.
Misdemeanor two.
What is that?
I give the D.A. credit for getting that much. You understand?
Excuse me   sir.
This thing has turned political.
The mayor was here last night   the chief.
This morning   the governor called.
This guy is protected from up on high...
...by the Prince of Darkness. Take my word for it.
- When does he post bail? - Two hours   tops.
- I wanna see him. - No   David.
I gotta see him   Jeffrey.
You gotta do this for me. I came a long way for this.
Dave   please.
Even if I let you talk to him   he won't talk.
He's paranoid about being recorded. He knows interrogation rooms are wired.
This won't be an interrogation. Just a friendly chat.
He won't go to the interrogation room.
- Then someplace else   then. - Where?
If this was a dope deal   where is it? If it was a hit   who called it in?
I'm sure you have wild theories to answer all these questions.
- You know what I think. - That's crazy.
He's got total immunity. His story checks out.
- He doesn't know what you wanna know. - I don't think he does. Not exactly.
There's a lot more to his story   believe me.
I wanna know why 27 men died on that pier...
...for what looks to be $91 million worth of dope that wasn't there.
And above all   I wanna be sure Dean Keaton's dead.
He's dead.
Come on. Two hours. Just till he makes bail.
They're all dead. I don't care how tough a guy Keaton was.
Nobody on that boat could've come out alive.
- Is he talking? - He regained consciousness and spoke.
- Not English. Then he lapsed. - Hungarian?
- I think so. - Most of them were Hungarians.
- Put on one of these. - Burn victims are subject to infection.
And of course   there's no smoking.
Keep your mask up. Don't touch him.
Is he gonna die?
He has burns over 60% of his body.
Get a man on the door till police get here.
Is he dangerous?
Yes. Do it. Do it now.
Joel? Yeah. Baer. Down at L.A. County.
Look   the guy they pulled out of the harbor is Arkosh Kovash.
No   he's all fucked up.
I can't hear you.
Will you shut up? I'm on the phone.
Send me a Hungarian.
He's talking like a Thai hooker.
Keyser Soze!
No shit.
Joel   call Dan Metzheiser over at Justice...
...and find Dave Kujan from Customs.
Verbal   this is Agent Kujan from Customs.
Nice to meet you.
- He wants to ask you a few questions. - What about?
About Dean Keaton   mostly.
But I'd like to start at the lineup.
- Can I get some coffee? - Let's talk about the lineup.
I'm really thirsty. I used to dehydrate as a kid.
One time I got so bad my piss come out like snot.
I'll get your coffee.
Get me one too while you're at it.
That guy is tense.
Tension is a killer.
I used to be in a quartet in Skokie   Illinois.
The baritone was Kip Diskin. Big   fat guy. I mean   orca fat.
He was so stressed...
You know we're trying to help you.
Sure. And I appreciate that.
And I wanna help you   Agent Kujan. I like cops.
I would've liked to have been a fed but...
You're not telling us everything. I know you know something.
I told the D.A. everything I know.
Verbal   I know you like Keaton. I know you think he's a good man.
- I know he was good. - He was a corrupt cop.
Sure   15 years ago. But he was a good thief.
The cops wouldn't let him go legit.
Dean Keaton was a piece of shit.
Are you trying to get a rise out of me   Agent Kujan?
I just wanna hear your story.
It's all there.
May I have a cigarette?
- According to... - I need a light.
According to your statement   you're a short-con operator.
Run-of-the-mill scams.
That's been suppressed. It's inadmissible.
I know.
Sweet deal you have. Total immunity.
Well   I do have the weapons charge.
I'm looking at six whole months hard time.
You know a dealer named Ruby Deemer?
You know a religious guy named John Paul?
Ruby's in Attica.
- He didn't have my lawyer. - I know Ruby.
He's big on respect. He's a good friend of mine.
I know your testimony's sealed.
Ruby's got friends inside who do a lot of favors for him.
What would he say if he found out you dropped his name to the D.A.?
- There's nothing about Ruby. - I'll mention that to him.
First thing on the job   I learned to spot a murderer.
You arrest three guys for a killing. You put them in jail overnight.
Next day   whoever's sleeping is your man.
If you're guilty   you know you're caught. You let your guard down.
- You following me? - No.
Let me get to the point.
I'm smarter than you.
And I'll find out what I wanna know.
And I'm gonna get it from you.
I'm not a rat.
Thanks.
When I picked beans in Guatemala   we made fresh coffee.
Right off the trees   I mean.
That was good.
This is shit   but I'm at a police...
Can we get started again?
Now   what happened after the lineup?
The sergeant told me he couldn't release you.
Can you believe that? You weren't even charged.
Police!
I wanna take pictures of your face. I'll take them to the D.A.'s office.
Forget about it.
I'll have this at the grand jury by Monday.
I don't wanna talk about it   Edie.
What did Fortier and Renault say?
They asked for some more time.
They just want more time.
More time for what?
No matter how you cover me   they'll still find out about me.
Give me some credit.
I got you this far.
Let's go to the grand jury. This won't stop...
It's never gonna stop   period.
By next week   every investor is gonna be walking away from us.
It's finished.
I'm finished.
Don't give up on me now   Dean.
It's never gonna stop.
I love you.
They ruined me in there tonight.
Do you hear me?
What?
Let's just go to my place.
We'll worry about this tomorrow.
Let's go.
Fenster and McManus had a cagey proposition.
A fast jump. High risk   long money.
We all knew it could be done.
I figured to do it wrong meant killing.
To do it right took five men.
Five men meant Keaton.
Keaton took convincing.
New York's Finest Taxi Service.
Bullshit.
They don't operate anymore.
McManus has a friend in the 14th precinct. They're doing one job.
They're picking up a guy smuggling emeralds.
- McManus already has a fence set. - A fence? Who?
- Some guy in California. Redfoot. - I never heard of him.
You have to come.
- What's it to you whether I do or not? - They don't know me. You do.
They won't take me unless you go.
- Look at me. I need this. - Tough.
You're telling me you don't need this? Is this your place?
You look like you got a good little scam going with this lawyer.
Sorry.
It's okay.
You say it's the real thing. That's cool.
You okay?
I was out of line.
But they'll never stop with us. You know that.
As clean as you get   they won't let you go.
This way   we hit the cops where it hurts   and we get well in the meantime.
You're sure you're okay?
I'll be all right.
- I sometimes get... - Forget it.
I'll probably shit blood tonight.
How do they wanna do it?
McManus wants to go in shooting. I say no.
Fenster? Hockney?
They're pretty pissed off. They'll do anything.
I got a way to do it without killing anyone...
...but they won't let me in without you.
Three million?
Maybe more.
No killing?
Not if we do it my way.
New York's Finest Taxi Service wasn't a normal taxi.
It was a ring of corrupt cops that ran a high-profit racket...
...driving smugglers around the city.
For a few hundred dollars a mile   you got a police escort.
They even had business cards.
Somebody started asking questions   and the Taxi Service shut down.
Internal Affairs has been waiting to catch them in the act.
That's where we came in.
- So how was the flight? - Fucking great.
Will this get me to Staten Island?
You kidding me? This'll get you to Cape Cod.
McManus came to us with the job. Fenster got the vans.
Hockney   the hardware.
I figured out how to do it so no one died.
But Keaton   Keaton put on the finishing touch.
A little "fuck you" from the five of us to the NYPD.
All right   watch this. Watch this.
Careful   careful!
Come on   asshole.
Holy shit!
Don't move   you fuckers!
Drop it now   motherfucker.
Drop the fucking gun. Drop it.
What do you guys want?
I'm a fucking cop   you stupid asshole!
Watch the glass!
- You want a buckshot shampoo   chubby? - Shut up!
Oh   fuck.
Good afternoon   my little pork chops. Give me the shit.
Give him the shit!
Give him the fucking shit   man!
Hurry up! Come on!
- Now the money. - There's no money.
There's no fucking money.
Give him the money.
Do it! Give him the money! Give him the money!
Hurry up!
Motherfucker   you know who I am?
Do you people know who the fuck I am? Fuck!
We do now   jerkoff.
Wait a minute. What's that?
What the fuck...?
Holy shit!
Keaton made an anonymous call.
The press was there before the police.
Strausz and Rizzi were indicted 3 days later.
Within a few weeks   50 more cops went down with them.
Everybody got it right in the ass from the chief on down.
It was beautiful.
I owe you $2.50.
Dr. Keaton.
- There's more than I thought. - When's the fence coming?
Redfoot never comes to see me. I always go to see him.
In California?
Yes   Verbal   in California. Fenster and I...
Wait. Hold the fucking phone.
You and Fenster? No   no   no.
You kidding me?
Okay   so everyone's gonna go?
We all go.
What's your fucking problem   man?
My problem is that you and Fenster are off in California...
...while we're sitting here holding our dicks.
The job's over.
Cool it.
L.A.'s a good place to lay low for a while.
You wanna dance?
Ladies.
I'd like to propose a toast.
There you go.
To Mr. Verbal...
...the man with the plan.
We'll miss the flight.
Don't do this. Send her a note   something.
I said we'll make it.
We're gonna miss the plane.
She'll understand.
That's heartwarming.
Really.
I'm weepy.
Jeff   you wanna wait outside?
You wanted to know what happened after the lineup.
Come on   Verbal.
Who do you think you're talking to?
Do you expect me to believe that he retired?
For a woman?
Bullshit. Keaton was using her.
- He loved her. - Sure.
Hitting the Taxi Service wasn't his idea?
It was Fenster and McManus.
Keaton was a cop for four years. Who knew the Taxi Service better?
- That job was his. - But Edie had him turned around.
Let me tell you something.
I know Dean Keaton.
I've been investigating him for three years.
The guy I knew was a cold-blooded bastard.
I.A. indicted him on 3 counts of murder before he was kicked off the force.
He's not the hooker with the heart of gold.
You got him all wrong.
Do I?
Dean Keaton was under indictment seven times while he was on the force.
In every case   witnesses either reversed their testimony...
...or died before they could testify.
They finally nailed him for fraud.
He spent five years in Sing Sing. He killed three prisoners inside.
Of course   I can't prove this.
But I can't prove the best part either.
Dean Keaton was dead. Did you know that?
He died in a fire two years ago...
...during a murder investigation of a witness who would testify against him.
Two people saw Dean Keaton walk into a warehouse just before it blew up.
They said he went in to check a leaking gas main.
It blew up and took all of Dean Keaton with it.
Within three months of the explosion...
...the two witnesses   they were dead.
One killed himself in his car...
...the other fell down an open elevator shaft.
Let's get this show on the road.
There are far too many people...
We'll be out of here before he blows his porch light.
- I have a noon meeting. - Five minutes.
Everyone just calm down.
I want you to ask this man about the shootout in the harbor.
- He says they were buying... - Dope. We know.
He doesn't know what they were buying   but not dope. People.
What?
He needs guarantees...
- What's he talking about? - He says his life is in danger.
He saw the devil   looked him in the eye.
- I'm on my way. - No   no   wait a minute.
Ask him to tell him what he told me.
About the devil.
Who's the devil?
Keyser Soze.
Keyser Soze?
He was in the harbor killing many men.
He saw Keyser Soze?
He saw his face.
All right   look. Tell him to tell her what he looks like.
Describe him.
Six weeks ago   I get a call saying I can find Keaton...
...eating at Mondino's with his attorney. There he is.
Because he never profited from his alleged death...
...and we convicted someone else of the murder...
...we had to let him go.
He was dead long enough for the murder rap to blow over.
And then he had lunch.
I don't know about that.
I don't think you do.
But you say you saw Keaton die.
You're covering him   and he's still out there.
He's behind the circus at the harbor.
He's using your stupidity. You think he's your friend.
You tell me he's dead   so be it.
I wanna be sure he's dead.
He wasn't behind anything. It was the lawyer.
What lawyer?
When I was in that quartet in Skokie   Illinois...
I know you held out on the D.A.!
What did you leave out of that testimony? I can phone Ruby Deemer.
- The D.A. gave me immunity. - Not from me.
You get no immunity from me.
Every criminal I've put in prison or cop who owes me...
...every creep that works the street will know the name of Verbal Kint.
You talk to me or that immunity they deem so fit to grant you...
...won't be worth the paper the contract on your life is printed on.
There was a lawyer.
Kobayashi.
- Was he the one that killed Keaton? - No.
But I'm sure Keaton is dead.
Convince me.
And tell me every last detail.
We arrived in Los Angeles and met McManus' fence   Redfoot.
He had a good reputation. Seemed like a good guy.
Still   we should've known better.
How you doing?
- Good. You? - Not bad. Can't complain.
How's it going   Fenster?
No need to open it   right?
You must be Keaton.
Redfoot   Dean Keaton.
- Todd Hockney and Verbal Kint. - Verbal   the man with a plan   huh?
Interested in any more work?
- We're always looking for work. - We're on vacation.
Oh   well. That's too bad.
I got a ton of work and no good people.
- Not like you guys. - What's the job?
There's this jeweler out of Texas named Saul.
He rents a suite in a downtown hotel.
He does appraisals. Sometimes he buys   sometimes he doesn't.
The word is   he carries around a lot of cash.
So I figure I keep the merchandise   you keep the green.
- It's simple. - What about security?
A couple of bodyguards. Nothing you couldn't handle.
Give me time to check it out?
I expect nothing less from you   man.
Good to see you. We'll call you.
Enjoy L.A. Get yourself laid.
A friend of mine in New York tells me that you knew Spook Hollis.
The way I hear it   you did time with old Spook.
Good man   wasn't he?
I used to run dope for him.
Too bad he got shivved.
I shivved him.
Better you hear it from me now   than from somebody else later.
I appreciate that.
Just out of curiosity...
...was it business or personal?
A bit of both.
Like I said...
...give me a call if you're interested.
Is there a problem?
One job.
That was the deal.
One job?
One job!
That's a good one   Keaton.
Keaton fought it   but a man can't change what he is.
He can convince anyone he's someone else   but never himself.
It took one day with McManus nagging   and we went back to work.
I get out of my car and it's wrecked.
I look in the back seat of the car   and this woman is naked.
I'm laughing so hard!
Get in the car   Saul.
Freeze   motherfucker! Right there!
Here we go.
Give me the case. Give me the fucking case!
Give me the fucking case.
I'm telling you for the last time   give me the fucking case!
Come on! Hey   don't move.
Just hand over the case.
Hand over the fucking case.
Come on   let's go!
- Come on! - Bad day. Fuck it.
Let's go   let's go!
Fuck!
Looks like a lot of China to me. Shit.
Guys   come on.
- What are you doing? - I'm gonna kill him.
We're gonna do it my way.
- You gonna kill him? - I'll deal with him.
- You better deal with him. - I'll deal with him. Shut up.
What do I do with that?
I don't know. Feed it to the gimp. Ease his pain.
- You don't know? - I don't know.
- I got thrown this job by some lawyer. - Who?
I don't know. Some limey.
He's a middleman for someone. He doesn't say   I don't ask.
- You're fucking full of shit. - Fuck you.
Listen to me. We wanna meet him.
That's funny.
He called me. Says he wants to meet you guys.
- We'll meet him. - I'll call.
- Good. Do that. No problem. - I don't like it. Wait a minute.
One more thing...
...any more surprises   and I'm gonna kill you.
You're such a tough guy.
Do me a favor   all right? Get the fuck off my dick.
Better put a leash on that puppy.
You know   it's an awful shame about Saul getting whacked.
Cops will be looking for the guys who did it.
Sooner or later   they'll come asking me.
You have a sweet night   ladies.
Fuck you.
So this lawyer...
Kobayashi.
...came from Redfoot. - Right.
Why leave this out when you talked to the D.A.?
Dave   someone to see you.
Jack.
I been looking all over for you.
You still after that coke that took a walk from the bloodbath?
Well   you can stop looking. There was no coke.
I been talking to a guy they pulled out of a drainpipe after the shootout.
He came to. He started talking.
He's part of a Hungarian mob dealing with some goats from Argentina.
- He says it wasn't a dope deal. - But the 91 million...
Our man says no way on the dope.
He tells me the bunch was pulling stumps for Turkey the next day.
They had no time to negotiate   no means to move it.
- What's the money for? - He didn't know.
No one doing the deal knew   except a few people.
They were very hush about it   he says.
Whatever it was   it was very sensitive.
I don't get it.
You got the cripple in there from New York.
- Did he mention Keyser Soze? - Who?
Just bear with me here.
Who's Keyser Soze?
Fuck!
We've been going over this for an hour and a half.
What we need to do is find Redfoot and get out of here now.
What we need to do is think.
Think back.
Somebody with power...
...who was capable of tracking us from New York to L.A.
- What the hell are we doing here? - We're waiting.
Sit down.
No. It's hot   and I'm fucking bored.
Mr. Hockney   do stay.
Mr. Keaton.
Mr. Fenster   I recognize from his mug shots   as well as Mr. McManus.
I can only assume that you are Mr. Kint...
...the gentleman who disposed of Saul Berg.
My employer sends his gratitude. A most unexpected benefit.
I am Mr. Kobayashi.
I have been asked by my employer to bring a proposal to you gentlemen.
- What do you want? - My employer requires your services.
One job.
One day's work. Very dangerous.
He doesn't expect all of you to live   but those who do...
...will have $91 million to divide between you in any way you see fit.
Who's your boss?
I work for Keyser Soze.
Who's Keyser Soze?
Judging by the sudden change in mood   I'm sure your associates can tell you.
I come with an offer directly from Mr. Soze.
An order   actually.
What do you mean   "an order"?
In 1981   Mr. Keaton   you participated...
...in the hijacking of a truck in Buffalo   New York.
The cargo was raw steel. Steel which belonged to Mr. Soze...
...and which was destined for Pakistan to be used in a nuclear reactor.
A most profitable violation of UN regulations.
You had no way of knowing this.
The man shipping the steel was working for Mr. Soze...
...without his knowledge.
Earlier this year   Mr. Fenster and Mr. McManus...
...hijacked a two-prop cargo flight out of Newark airport.
The plane was carrying gold and platinum wiring   also set for Pakistan.
Two months ago...
...Mr. Hockney stole a truck carrying gun parts through Queens.
Gun parts which were set to be destroyed by the state of New York.
They were to be lost in a way station and re-routed to Belfast.
Again   Mr. Soze using pawns who had no knowledge.
Which brings us to Mr. Kint.
Nine months ago   one of Mr. Soze's less-than-intelligent couriers...
...was taken in a complicated confidence scam by a cripple.
He was relieved of $62  000.
Now   it has taken us some time to find you.
Our intention was to approach you after your apprehension in New York.
You set up the lineup.
You were not to be released until I had come to see you.
It seems Mr. Keaton's attorney   Miss Finneran...
...was a little too effective...
...in expediting his release. Holding the rest was a moot point.
- What about Redfoot? - Mr. Redfoot knew nothing.
Mr. Soze rarely works with the same people.
They never know who they work for.
One cannot be betrayed if one has no people.
So why are you telling us?
Because you have stolen from Mr. Soze   Mr. Fenster. All of you.
That you did not know you did is the only reason you're still alive.
He feels you owe him.
You will repay your debt.
Fuck the debt and fuck you. How do we know you work for Soze?
I don't think that is very relevant   Mr. Hockney.
You all are responsible for the murder of Saul Berg and his bodyguards.
Mr. Redfoot can testify to your involvement. We can see that he will.
What's your point?
The offer is this   gentlemen.
Mr. Soze's primary interest is narcotics.
He has been competing   shall we say...
...with Argentineans for years now.
Competing with Mr. Soze has taken its toll.
These Argentineans are negotiating the sale...
...of $91 million in cocaine in three days' time.
Needless to say   this purchase will revitalize...
...the diminishing strength of their organization.
Mr. Soze would like you to stop the deal.
If you choose   you may wait until after the buy.
Whatever money changes hands is yours.
Mr. Soze would like you to get to the boat and destroy the cocaine onboard.
And then you will be free of your obligations to Mr. Soze.
You give me one good reason why I shouldn't kill you right now.
A gift from Mr. Soze.
Good day   gentlemen.
They got my whole life in here. Everything I've ever done.
They know everything.
Everybody I've ever worked with or did time with.
- This isn't right. - I don't know.
Who's that guy used to talk about Soze in New York?
Bricks Marlin.
Yeah   he did jobs for him. Indirect stuff.
He made five times more money than it was worth.
This guy's a pipe dream. Kobayashi's using him for window-dressing.
I don't know. This is bad.
No   it's bullshit. This guy could be LAPD. It's a fucking setup.
The way I hear it   Soze's some kind of a butcher.
A peerless   psycho   fucked-up butcher.
There is no Keyser Soze!
Who is Keyser Soze?
He's supposed to be Turkish.
Some say his father was German.
Nobody ever believed he was real.
Nobody knew him or saw anybody that worked directly for him.
To hear Kobayashi tell it   anybody could've worked for him.
You never knew. That was his power.
The greatest trick the devil ever pulled...
...was convincing the world he didn't exist.
One story the guys told me   the story I believe...
...was from his days in Turkey.
A gang of Hungarians wanted their own mob.
They realized that to be in power...
...you didn't need guns or money or even numbers.
You just needed the will to do what the other guy wouldn't.
After a while   they come into power. They went after Soze.
He was smalltime then. Just running dope   they say.
They come to his home in the afternoon...
...looking for his business.
They find his wife and kids and decide to wait for Soze.
He comes home...
...to find his wife raped and children screaming.
The Hungarians knew Soze was tough   not to be trifled with.
So they let him know they meant business.
They tell him they want his territory   all his business.
Soze looks over the faces of his family.
Then he showed these men of will what will really was.
He tells them he would rather see his family dead...
...than live another day after this.
He lets the last Hungarian go.
He waits until his family is in the ground   then goes after the mob.
He kills their kids. He kills their wives.
He kills their parents   their parents' friends.
He burns down the houses they live in...
...the stores they work in.
He kills people that owe them money.
And like that...
...he's gone.
Underground. Nobody's ever seen him since.
He becomes a myth. A spook story that criminals tell their kids at night.
"Rat on your pop   and Keyser Soze will get you."
And no one ever really believes.
Do you believe in him   Verbal?
Keaton always said:
"I don't believe in God but I'm afraid of him."
Well   I believe in God.
And the only thing that scares me...
...is Keyser Soze.
Do you give any weight to this?
I can introduce you to Dan Metzheiser. He's got a file on Soze in D.C.
It's a hobby of his.
A lot of guys equate him to that reporter on The Incredible Hulk.
- You've heard of him? - Where? On the street?
Yeah   a few times. Outside stuff.
Somebody worked for a guy who got some money...
...from Keyser Soze. You know   shit like that.
It could be an old badge. A hex sign...
...to keep people from fucking with you.
- But you're here. - Well   shit   yeah.
A guy left a hospital on a fried drumstick because he's afraid of Soze.
I'll run it up the flagpole.
I came clean. So what if I left out how I got on the boat.
It's so full of holes   the D.A. would've told me to blow amnesty out my ass.
Big fucking deal.
That's why you never told the D.A.?
You tell me   Agent Kujan.
If I said the Loch Ness monster hired me   what would you say?
Turn state's evidence. We'll put you on the stand.
I've got immunity. What can you offer?
If there is a Soze   he's gonna come for you.
Where's your head?
Where do you think the pressure's coming from?
Soze knows where I am now.
He's got a burner under you to let me go   so he can scoop me up later.
Immunity was just a deal with you. I got a new problem when I post bail.
Why play to him? We can protect you.
Gee   thanks   Dave.
Bang-up job so far. Extortion. Coercion.
Pardon me   kiss my pucker.
The fuckers that rounded us up and sank us into this mess are bailing me out?
You think you can catch Keyser Soze?
You think he'd come this close to getting caught and stick his head out?
If he comes up   it'll be to get rid of me.
After that...
...my guess is   you'll never hear from him again.
What happened next?
The next morning Fenster was gone.
He couldn't handle the idea of slumming for Soze.
He left us a note and took a chunk of the money we'd scraped together.
Then what?
McManus was furious.
He was talking about tracking him down and ripping his heart out.
That night we got the call.
What call?
Kobayashi told us where we could find Fenster.
All right. Let's get the fuck out of here.
We gotta bury him.
With what?
With our hands.
This is nuts.
It's dry fucking sand.
When he rots   the surfers are gonna smell him a mile away.
Fuck!
What are we gonna do? This guy's gonna kill us.
I don't know about you   but I can run. I got no problem with that.
Kobayashi doesn't seem to have a problem with it either.
If you run...
...we'll be digging a hole for you. You got that?
This ain't my boy we're burying.
I don't owe anybody!
So fuck you.
He was my partner for five years.
We did more jobs and saw more money than you can count.
So fuck you!
Because now it's payback.
It's not payback!
It's precaution.
You want payback? You wanna run? I don't care.
I'm not doing this for Fenster.
I'm not doing it for you.
I'm doing this for me.
I'm gonna finish this thing.
This Kobayashi bastard isn't gonna stand on me.
After they killed Fenster   nobody ran?
I wanted to. I thought we could make it.
Why didn't you say anything?
I tried   but Keaton wouldn't have it. It was too far-fetched for him.
Keaton was a grounded guy. An ex-cop.
To a cop   the explanation is never that complicated.
There's no mystery to the street. No archcriminal behind it all.
If you got a body and think his brother did it   you're right.
Nobody argued with Keaton. They just set their minds to Kobayashi.
They're coming up.
Did you hear me? He's coming up.
He's on his way down.
Don't move.
Press 20. Do it now.
Move!
The answer is no.
- Mr. Soze will be most... - There is no Keyser Soze.
Mention him again   I'll kill you.
A strange threat. I can only assume you've come here to kill me anyway.
Now   we know that you can get to us.
But now you know that we can get to you.
I'm giving you one last chance to call this off.
Mr. S...
My employer has made up his mind. He does not change it.
Neither do we.
You got Fenster   but you won't be able to get all of us.
Not before we get to you.
I believe you   Mr. McManus.
I most sincerely do.
You wouldn't be chosen were you not so suitable.
But I cannot make this decision.
What you threaten me with is ludicrous compared to what will be done to me...
...if I do not carry out my orders in full.
I'm the guy that's gonna get you.
I just wanted you to know that.
I'm so sorry   Mr. McManus.
I implore you   Mr. Keaton   believe me...
...Mr. Soze is very real and very determined.
We'll see.
Before you do me in   Mr. McManus...
...you'll let me finish my business with Ms. Finneran   won't you?
What did you say?
Edie Finneran.
She's upstairs. In my office.
For an extradition deposition.
I requested she be put on the case personally.
She flew in yesterday.
No matter.
Kill away   Mr. McManus.
You're lying.
Am I?
Ms. Finneran's escort while she's here in Los Angeles.
Never leaves her side.
I thought you'd be glad to know she's in good hands.
Get some rest. The boat will be ready Friday.
If I see you or any of your friends before then...
...she'll find herself the victim of a gruesome violation before she dies.
As indeed   will your father   Mr. Hockney...
...and your Uncle Randall in Arizona   Mr. Kint.
I might only castrate Mr. McManus' nephew   David.
Do I make myself clear?
Take care of the bodies downstairs.
We'll add them to the cost of Mr. Fenster.
Excuse me   gentlemen.
It's a logistical nightmare.
Close quarters. Ten   maybe 20 men.
No telling how many more will be below deck.
- Can we stealth these guys? - No.
With all that coke   they're gonna be ready.
Which brings me to sunny point number two.
Even if we get through and jack the boat   we got nothing.
What if we wait for the money?
Ten more men at least.
Look   in my opinion   it can't be done.
Whoever goes there won't come out alive.
I'm gonna wait for the money.
- Me too. - Did you hear what he just said?
- If I'm going in   I want a cut. - Me too.
There's nothing that can't be done.
I can't believe we're walking into certain death.
The news said it's raining in New York.
What language is that?
I don't know.
Russian   I think.
Hungarian.
The package has arrived   gentlemen.
You kids ready?
I would be if I didn't have to stop and answer you.
I'm ready. McManus   you better be set up in 10 seconds.
I'm ready.
I want you to stay here.
I'm supposed to cover...
If we don't get out of this   take the money and go.
Find Edie. Tell her what happened. She knows people and knows what to do.
If I don't get Kobayashi my way   she'll get him her way.
Just do what I say.
Please.
Tell her that...
Tell her I tried.
McManus...
...he's on his way.
I'm there.
One   two   three   four...
...five   six   seven...
Oswald was a fag.
How you doing?
Is there... Is there a problem?
Now.
Old MacDonald had a farm
E-I-E-I-O
And on that farm he shot some guys
Bada-boom Bada-bing-bang-boom
Elvis has left the building.
Why didn't you run?
I froze up.
I thought about Fenster   how he looked when we buried him.
I thought about Keaton. It looked like he might pull it off.
A boy came across a body on the beach today. Shot twice in the head.
Two guys from the Bureau just identified him.
Arturro Marquez. A petty smuggler from Argentina.
Arrested last year in New York for trafficking.
He escapes to California. They pick him up in Long Beach.
They're setting up extradition   he escapes again.
Now   get this.
Edie Finneran's brought in to advise on the proceedings.
Kobayashi.
New York faxed me a copy of his testimony. He was a rat.
A big rat.
Arturro was very opposed to returning to prison.
So much so that he named close to 50 people.
Guess who he named in the finale?
Keyser Soze.
There's more.
I'll tell you what I know.
Stop me when this sounds familiar.
There was no dope on that boat.
You   stay quiet.
He is here.
I know he is here.
That's him. I'm telling you   that's him.
I know he is here!
- You can't understand. That's him. - Shut up!
That's him! You hear me?
I'm telling you   it's Keyser Soze!
- Where's Hockney? - I don't know.
There's no coke!
You heard me   you dumb fuck! There's no coke!
I've been up and down this ship! Every fucking room!
There is nothing!
Nothing!
Don't you fuck with me!
There is no fucking coke!
I'm out of here.
I told them nothing.
I swear.
I told them nothing. Please.
McManus.
What the fuck is going on?
The strangest thing...
You say you saw a man in a suit with a slim build.
- Wait a minute. - No.
You saw Soze? You told the D.A. you didn't know who it was.
I know there was dope there.
You know what I'm getting at!
Get out of my face.
I've got immunity. I don't have to take that shit!
You know what I'm getting at.
The truth! Try to tell me you saw someone kill Keaton.
- I did. - You're lying to me!
You've known this whole fucking time.
I don't know what you're saying. I saw Keaton get shot.
Then why didn't you help him? You had a gun.
He was your friend.
Because I was afraid.
Okay?
- Afraid. - Afraid of what?
I knew it was Keyser Soze.
It was Keyser Soze   Agent Kujan. I mean   the devil himself.
How do you shoot the devil in the back?
What if you miss?
All right. Let's get back to the pier.
Ever hear of Arturro Marquez?
What? No.
He was a stool pigeon for the Justice Department.
He swore out a statement saying that he had seen...
...and could positively identify one Keyser Soze.
It says right here:
"He had knowledge of his businesses   including but not exclusive...
...to trafficking and murder." - I never heard of him.
His own people were selling him to Hungarians.
Most likely the Hungarians that Soze all but wiped out in Turkey.
The money wasn't for dope.
The Hungarians were buying the one guy that could incriminate Keyser Soze.
I never heard of him.
Keaton did. Edie Finneran was Marquez's extradition adviser.
She knew what he knew.
- I don't... - There were no drugs on that boat.
It was a hit. A suicide mission to whack out the one guy...
...that could finger Keyser Soze.
Soze put some thieves to it.
Men he knew he could march into certain death.
You're saying Soze sent us to kill someone?
Keaton did. He left you behind for a reason.
Just do what I tell you.
If you all knew that Soze could find you anywhere...
...why did he give you the money to run? He could use you on the boat.
He wanted me to live.
A one-time dirty cop without a loyalty in the world wants to save...
...a worthless cripple?
No   sir. Why?
- Edie. - I don't buy that reform story.
Even if I did   I don't believe he would send you to protect her.
So why?
Because he was my friend.
No   Verbal. He wasn't your friend. Keaton didn't have friends.
Why are you here?
He saved you because he wanted it that way. It was his will.
Keaton was Keyser Soze!
He could wrangle the wills of men like Hockney and McManus.
He could engineer a police lineup through his contacts in NYPD.
He's a man who could've killed Edie Finneran!
She was found yesterday in a hotel in Pennsylvania   shot twice in the head.
What do you think about Keaton now?
Edie?
He used you to get on the boat. He couldn't get on alone.
He had to pull the trigger himself to make sure he got his man.
The one man that could identify him.
This is all bullshit.
You said you saw him die.
Or did you?
You hid when you heard the police.
You said you heard the shot before the fire.
But you didn't see him die.
I knew him. He'd never...
He programmed you.
He programmed you to tell us what he wanted you to. He knew we were close.
Where was the pressure coming from? Why were you protected?
It was Keaton. Immunity was your reward.
But why me?
Why not Fenster   McManus or Hockney? Why me?
I'm stupid. I'm a cripple.
Because you're a cripple.
Because you're stupid.
Because you're weaker than them.
If he's dead...
...if what you say is true   then it won't matter.
It was his idea to hit the Taxi Service   wasn't it?
- Come on   tell me the truth. - It was all Keaton.
We followed him from the beginning.
I didn't know.
I saw him die.
I believe he's dead. Oh   Christ!
You're not safe on your own.
You think he's...
Keyser Soze?
I don't know   Verbal.
Keyser Soze's a shield. Or like you said   "a spook story."
But I know Keaton. And someone is out there pulling strings for you.
- Stay here and let us protect you. - I'm not bait. I post today.
You posted 20 minutes ago.
Capt. Leo wants you out of here ASAP.
- Unless you turn state's. - I'll take my chances.
If someone wants to get you   they're gonna get you out there.
Turn state's evidence. You might never see trial.
Maybe so.
But I'm not a rat   Agent Kujan.
Fucking cops!
Excuse me. Can I use your fax machine?
You'll have to sign for these   Mr. Kint.
One watch   gold.
One cigarette lighter   gold.
One pack of cigarettes. Thank you.
We still got nothing   Dave.
I know what I wanted to know about Keaton.
Which is nothing.
No matter.
He'll have to know how close we came.
Keyser Soze or no Keyser Soze...
...if Keaton is alive   he's not coming up again.
I'll find him.
Waste of time.
A rumor's not a rumor that doesn't die.
What?
Nothing.
Man   you're a slob.
Yeah   but it all has a system   Dave.
It don't make sense when you look right at it. You gotta stand back from it.
Wanna see a real horror show? You should see my garage.
Convince me.
When I was in that quartet in Skokie...
Where's your head?
What we need to do is think. Think back.
I'm sure you've heard tall tales.
- This isn't right. - I just want your story.
It's all there. I'm telling it straight   I swear.
- guy in California named Redfoot.
A gift from Mr. Soze.
- What about Redfoot? - Mr. Redfoot knew nothing.
Big   fat guy. I mean   orca fat.
- There was a lawyer. - Kobayashi.
- never see him again.
- in Guatemala   we made fresh coffee.
...- thought he was a good man. - I know he was good.
And tell me every last detail.
How do you shoot the devil in the back?
He's protected from up on high by the Prince...
What about it   pretzel man?
- There was a lawyer. - What lawyer?
- I am Mr. Kobayashi. - Kobayashi. Kobayashi.
Tell me every last detail.
I work for Keyser Soze.
Convince me.
Every creep that walks the street will know the name of Verbal Kint.
The cripple   did you see him? Which way did he go?
He went out that way.
I know you know something.
I'm smarter than you. And I'll find out what I wanna know.
To a cop   the explanation is never that complicated.
There's no mystery to the street. No archcriminal...
Somebody with power   who was capable of tracking us from New York to L.A.
You think he'd come this close to getting caught...
...and stick his head out?
Because you're stupid. Because you're a cripple.
You've known the whole fucking time!
Keaton's dead.
I can't feel my legs   Keyser.
First thing I learned on the job was how to spot a murderer.
- the cripple from New York   he mention Keyser Soze?
Who?
And after that...
...my guess is   you'll never hear from him again.
The greatest trick the devil ever pulled...
...was convincing the world he didn't exist.
And like that...
...he's gone.
Subtitles by GELULA & CO.   INC.