[CHILDREN LAUGHlNG
AND CHATTERlNG]
[THUNDER CRASHlNG]
Can l have another?
Hey. Can l have
some more coffee, please?
Where you going?
[JINGLES]
Excuse me.
Bitch.
Hello?
Anyone here?
Lady. Lady.
Hello?
What the fuck?
[DOOR SQUEAKS]
[BLADES SCRAPlNG]
[CLANK]
[DOOR SQUEAKS]
[DEAN YELLS]
NANCY:
Dean. Dean.
I told you, if you keep falling asleep,
they're gonna kick you out of here.
Um, sorry. Won't happen again, okay?
Okay.
[BELL JlNGLES]
KRlS: Nancy.
-Hey, Kris. You can sit wherever you want.
-Actually, l'm just here to meet Dean.
-Oh, he's right over there.
Thanks.
Hey.
Wow, you look like you haven't--
Like l haven't slept in three days?
Dean, what's going on?
QUENTIN:
So, what are we doing after this?
JESSE: Let me see if we can go
to Ashley's or whatever.
Then l don't know.
Look out, here comes your girlfriend.
-Oh, hey.
-Hi. Can l get you guys anything else?
Uh.... Um....
No, I think we're good.
We'll just get the check.
JESSE: ls that the only thing
you wanna ask her, Quentin?
[JESSE CHUCKLES]
Asshole.
Hey.
JESSE:
Why is Kris with Dean?
Okay.
Come on.
QUENTIN:
That's fucked up.
[DOOR OPENS]
[BELL JlNGLES]
What was that all about?
Um, Jesse's just--
He's pissed because Kris broke up with him.
-l didn't even know they were together.
-Yeah.
I guess I can keep the change?
Yeah. Look...
[DOOR OPENS]
[BELL JlNGLES]
...l'm sorry about the mess.
-These guys are just--
-l'm used to it.
So you ever get tired
of working here every weekend?
Do you ever get tired
of coming here every weekend?
Quentin. You coming or no?
Sorry. Look, this should
take care of the rest of it.
-See you around.
-See you.
Listen, maybe you should
talk to somebody.
I did.
And he thinks all my problems
come from my past.
We began going through my childhood...
...and that's when they started.
When what started?
These nightmares.
Nightmares.
So, what, you can't sleep?
I can sleep.
I just don't want to.
Okay, Dean, listen to me.
They're just dreams.
Okay? They're not real.
These dreams...
...they're real.
They're not.
They're re-- l'm sorry, Kris.
-No, it's okay.
-Kris.
No, no. It's fine.
I'm gonna go clean myself off.
It's okay. It's okay.
[DEAN GRUNTING]
[FREDDY CHUCKLlNG]
DEAN:
You're not real.
You're not real. You're not real!
I am now.
Dean, what are you doing?
DEAN: You're not real.
-Dean, stop it. Dean.
Dean, stop it!
Dean!
MlNlSTER:
Tragedy can shake us at our core...
...and it can also unite us
in our shared grief.
Today we are gathered and united...
...for the tragic loss of a young man
with so much life ahead of him.
Let us pray.
Lord, you who can
turn the shadow of death...
...into the light of a new day...
...as we gather to commend Dean
into your hands...
...help us to wait upon thee
with penitent hearts...
...and remind us of he who died
that we might live.
MlNlSTER: --and the power and the glory
forever and ever. Amen.
CROWD: Amen.
-Come on, sweetie. lt's over.
MAN:
Yeah.
ALAN:
Let's go say hi.
-Gwen. Hi, how are you?
-Alan, hi.
-lt's been a long time.
-Yeah, yeah.
-Especially under these circumstances.
GWEN: Yeah, not a....
You know, Nance,
if you need someone to talk to....
I'm okay. Thank you.
ALAN: We're setting up a crisis center
at the school.
-You know where my office is, right, Nancy?
NANCY: Yeah.
GWEN: We're gonna head out. Take care.
-Good to see you.
GWEN:
Bye-bye, Quentin.
You knew Dean that far back?
KRlS: Jesus, that is me.
But l don't know how I'm in that picture.
I didn't meet Dean until high school.
Come on.
-Dean said something right before he died.
-Oh, please don't.
He said, "You're not real."
He kept repeating it over and over again.
Do you have any idea what that means?
No. I don't.
Think about it. What would it mean?
Dean was on a load of medication when--
Jesse.
When it happened, it was like
somebody was making him do it...
...but there was nobody there.
Jesse, you have to believe me.
Kris, it was late and you were scared.
Your mind was just playing tricks on you...
-...that's all.
-l believe you.
You do?
I've seen....
-l saw--
-You didn't see anything.
You weren't right there. Kris was.
She's already fucked up, so leave her alone.
You have no idea what I've seen.
Let's go home.
[ROARS]
[GASPS]
-Hi.
Hey, Mom, where are all the photos of me
from when I was younger?
-They're not here.
-Oh, well, who knows?
They're probably packed away
over the garage. Why?
Because today at the funeral I, um....
I saw a photo of Dean and I
when we were, like, 5.
But, you know, it's funny, l don't remember
knowing Dean before high school.
Who can remember being 5 years old?
Hey, why don't you pack those up?
Dinner's almost ready.
NORA:
Good night, honey.
[GASPS]
[FLOORBOARD CREAKS]
[KRlS SCREAMS]
[KRlS GASPING]
Remember me?
[SCREAMlNG]
Kris? You okay?
[BELL RINGlNG]
QUENTIN:
What is that?
Uh, nothing.
Just, like, a sketch.
Are you okay?
-Yeah, I'm okay.
-Yeah?
Are you okay?
Yeah, you know.
You know, like, if you ever need somebody,
if you ever wanna talk to somebody, l--
I'm sure you have like a thousand
other people you could talk to...
...but if you wanna talk to somebody....
Thanks.
Quentin. You're gonna be late to class.
Come on, buddy, let's go.
-My dad.
-l know.
Now, class, it was Pericles
who told the Athenian people...
...they should all gather
into the gates of the city...
...while his naval fleet picked off
the Spartans by sea.
Now, it was to be a slow but sure victory.
The Spartans would never make it over
the walls of the acropolis, Pericles said.
But what he didn't take into account
is that the plague would eventually strike.
Open your books to page 84.
To further complicate matters...
...the Spartans were armed
with a variety of weapons...
...some of them even improvised.
And they would not hesitate to slaughter
every Athenian they saw...
...even children.
Especially the children of soldiers.
This is where the....
Wake up.
Wake up, wake up, wake up.
You really shouldn't fall asleep in class.
[FREDDY LAUGHlNG]
[PANTlNG]
FREDDY: Hi, Kris.
-Who are you?
You look just as beautiful...
...as ever.
You have nothing to worry about.
This won't hurt...
...one...
...little...
...bit.
[SCREAMS]
Are you okay, Miss Fowles?
What happened?
I'm sorry.
What?
[BELL RINGlNG]
JESSE:
Kris!
[CAR ALARM CHlRPS]
Rufus.
Rufus, what are you doing?
Huh? What are you doing out here?
Come on.
Rufus.
[WHlSTLES]
Come on.
NORA:
Hey.
I have to fly to London on a redeye tonight.
KRlS:
Okay.
NORA:
You gonna be okay?
KRlS:
Yeah, l'm fine.
I'm gonna be all right. Have a safe flight.
I just worry about you.
-Try and get some sleep.
-Okay.
I'll call you when l land.
I love you.
KRlS:
Love you.
[FLOORBOARDS CREAKlNG]
[KRlS SlGHS]
Jesus, Jesse.
-What the hell are you doing here?
-Are you gonna let me in?
Yeah, come in.
All right, l know l've been an asshole...
...and l've been jealous and l've been fucked up.
But Dean was my friend too.
Will you please tell me what's been going on?
I'm having these dreams.
And l'm scared.
I think Dean was having them too.
Kris, listen, we've all--
I know what you're gonna say.
But now every time I dream...
...l always see this man.
And he's....
He's burned...
...and melted. And he's always trying to...
-...attack me with these knives--
-Knives on his fingers.
What?
Oh, my God.
We're having the same dream.
-Kris, it's not possible.
-lt is possible.
-lt's just a dream, all right?
-lt's not a dream.
JESSE:
Shh. Shh.
Oh, God.
I'm so afraid.
All I wanna do is go to sleep,
but if l do he's gonna kill me like Dean.
Maybe we should just
stop talking about it, all right?
We keep talking about it, we'll keep thinking
about it, then we'll keep dreaming about it.
Look at me.
You'll stay with me?
Of course I'll stay with you.
[RUFUS BARKING]
Rufus!
Rufus, get in here!
Ugh. Shit.
Rufus.
Rufus?
Rufus, come here, boy!
Come here.
[WlND CHIME TlNKLlNG]
Ru--
Ru-- Rufus.
Oh, my--
FREDDY:
I was just petting him.
[LAUGHlNG]
[BLADES SCRAPlNG]
Jess! Help!
No! No!
Help me, please! Help me!
[CHILDREN LAUGH]
GIRLS [SINGlNG]:
One, two
Freddy's coming for you
-Come on. Come on.
-Three, four, better lock your door
We have to hide.
-Five, six, grab your crucifix
FREDDY: Five...
-Seven, eight, gonna stay up late
-...four...
...three...
...two...
...one.
-Ready or not...
-Oh, my God.
[BLADES SCREECHlNG]
...here l come.
[GASPlNG]
-Jesse?
-Mm.
Jess?
[SIGHS]
Found you.
[SCREAMlNG]
Kris! All right-- Hey! Hey! Kris, stop!
Kris! Stop! Kris!
Oh, my God.
Wake up!
Kris!
[SCREAMS THEN GASPS]
Oh, shit.
Kris?
Oh, God.
Oh, shit.
[ALARM BLARING]
Fuck.
[PANTlNG]
[DOG BARKlNG]
Okay, okay.
Okay, okay, okay.
MAN:
Hey! Hey, you! l'm calling the cops!
[KNOCKS]
GWEN:
Honey?
Nancy.
-Nancy.
-Yeah?
It's the middle of the night.
You need to go to sleep, hon.
Okay, l will.
-Now.
-Okay.
JESSE:
Shh! Shh. Shh.
-Nancy, it's me. It's me.
-Jesse. What the--?
-Hey, hey.
-What are you doing here?
-Stop. Just listen to me, okay?
-What happened to you?
-Whose blood is that? ls it your blood?
-Listen, okay? Please.
-l was with Kris and--
-What'd you do to her?
I didn't do anything, I'm trying to tell you.
Listen to me, something's going on, okay?
-Tell me what happened to Kris, Jesse.
-Someone killed her in her sleep.
What?
-What are you talking about?
-Don't pretend you don't know...
...because you do.
You said it at the funeral.
He's the one who's trying
to kill us in our dreams.
-All l keep hearing is the song.
-What song?
[SINGlNG]
One, two
Freddy's coming for you
Freddy.
-That's his name and he's in all of our heads.
-No, that's impossible. No.
[KNOCKlNG]
GWEN:
Nancy.
Shit. We gotta stop this.
-How?
-l don't know.
Just don't fall asleep.
If you die in your dreams,
you die for real.
GWEN:
Nancy? Who's in there?
[SIRENS APPROACHING]
Oh, shit.
COP 1 :
Police. Don't move!
Get down! Get down!
-l didn't do anything.
COP 2: Down!
Listen to me, l didn't do anything. Please.
-Get down!
JESSE: Aah!
I loved her, man! l couldn't kill her!
COP 3 [OVER RADlO]:
What's going on down there?
JESSE:
I didn't do anything! Stop!
COP 2:
Shut up.
-Get up.
-l didn't kill her! You know!
-Shut the fuck up.
DISPATCHER: That's a roger, two-two.
[JESSE GRUNTS]
COP 2:
Get up.
COP 1 : Call it in, code four.
COP 4: Get him out of here.
COP 3 [OVER RADlO]:
Copy that, we've got a homicide.
COP 2:
Code four. Homicide suspect in custody.
Nancy! You know! You know who did it!
[SIREN WAILlNG]
COP 1 :
Coming in.
Open three.
Clear.
Clear four.
-Let him out.
COP 2: All right.
COP 1 :
Hold five open.
[INDlSTlNCT RADlO CHATTER]
COP 1 :
Open four.
[BUZZER SOUNDS]
[CELL PHONE RlNGlNG]
QUENTIN: Hello?
-Hi, it's Nancy.
Hey.
You said to call you if l needed to talk.
-Yeah.
-Kris is dead.
Stay awake.
-Stay awake.
-Quiet.
[JESSE SLAPPlNG]
Shut the fuck up.
CASHlER:
That'll be $24.97.
[CROWS CAWlNG]
[GlRLS GlGGLING]
GIRL:
Five, four, three, two....
FREDDY:
Five, six, seven....
[FREDDY WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY]
[GASPS]
Nightmares?
Yeah.
Freddy?
COP:
Open four.
[BUZZER SOUNDS]
Get up.
Folks posted your bail.
[BUZZER SOUNDS]
[STEAM HISSlNG]
KRlS:
Jesse, help me.
Help me, please.
[METAL CLANKING AND GROANlNG]
[CHILDREN GIGGLlNG]
[JESSE GASPS]
[BLADES SCRAPlNG]
JESSE:
Kris?
-Oh, God.
-No.
Just me.
What do you want from me?
FREDDY:
Hmm. l don't know, Jesse.
You think you can turn back time?
-Answer me!
-No.
Do you think you can
bring the dead back to life?
-No. No!
-No?
I didn't fucking think so.
No! No! No!
Why are you screaming?
I haven't even cut you yet.
[FREDDY CHUCKLlNG]
[SCREAMS]
I didn't do it! I'm innocent!
Get me out of here!
Let me the fuck out of here!
Did you know
that after the heart stops beating...
...the brain keeps functioning
for well over seven minutes?
[JESSE WHIMPERING]
We got six more minutes to play.
[SCREAMlNG]
-You okay?
-Yeah. I'm just really exhausted.
Here.
-What's that?
-Zoneral.
It's basically speed for kids with ADD.
I've been on it since I was, like, 1 5.
No. No. No, thanks.
Nancy, look, you're running on fumes.
Here, okay? Are you sure? It's--
Yeah, l'm fine for now.
I didn't take you for the religious type.
Yeah, well, you gotta believe
in something, you know?
What's this one doing here?
It's The Pied Piper of Hamelin.
I saw it in one of my dreams. It's about
a guy who's betrayed by a town...
...and he gets his revenge
by taking all their children.
I keep dreaming about children too.
And then there's also a school.
Well, it's gotta mean something.
Yeah, but, l mean, what? We didn't go to
school together until, like, 6th grade.
-Look, we're running out of time.
-What do you mean?
Nightmares are triggered by the belief
that the dreamer has no control...
...and this can cause insomnia.
But then it says at the 70-hour mark...
...the insomniac will begin
to experience micronaps.
"His brain will shut down its functions
for seconds in an attempt to recharge."
This basically means that you're dreaming,
but you don't know it.
Like, even if you're awake.
And then it says that after that,
your brain will shut down, inducing a coma.
Which is permanent sleep.
Nancy?
Nancy.
[KNOCKS]
Yeah?
Hey.
Where have you been?
I was at the bookstore.
Okay, well,
I didn't know where you were.
And l just feel like, with everything
that's been happening with your friends--
Hey, Mom?
Do I have some sort of connection
with Kris...
...and Dean and Jesse?
Or Quentin?
Like, maybe we went to school together
when we were little or something like that?
Not that l can recall.
Did we ever know a guy named Freddy?
I don't think so.
Okay.
Good night.
Hey, it's Gwen.
Nancy's starting to remember.
[ALARM RINGS]
[KNOCKS]
GWEN:
Honey, you okay?
Yeah, l'm fine, Mom.
-All right. I'm going to bed.
-Okay.
FREDDY:
Little Nancy.
All grown up.
You're just a nightmare.
FREDDY:
That's right.
No one can prove I was ever here.
Who are you?
FREDDY:
You don't remember?
You must.
You're my number one.
[NANCY WHIMPERS]
You're my...
...little Nancy.
[FREDDY MOANS]
I set an alarm.
Yes, you did.
In your dream.
[FREDDY CHUCKLES THEN SNlFFS]
You smell different.
[CELL PHONE RlNGlNG]
[NANCY GASPS]
Quentin?
Nancy, he got to him. Jesse's dead.
He died in his sleep.
I saw him.
-l fell asleep. l saw Freddy.
-All right, I'm coming over.
Okay.
Shit.
QUENTIN:
So Badham's a preschool.
It's on the other end of town.
It was closed years ago.
Can't find any pictures.
Wait, come here.
I drew this after my dream.
I don't know. l've never seen it before.
How is the guy in our dreams
connected to the school?
I don't know.
But l know my mom's hiding something.
QUENTIN:
There's nothing here.
Help me.
QUENTIN:
What is that?
We're all here.
Kris, Jesse, Dean.
It's me, it's you, it's--
What are you doing?
Nancy, what is going on?
-Give me the picture.
-l don't understand.
You said that....
You said that we didn't know each other.
But we're all in this picture.
We went to school together.
Give me the picture.
-lt's okay.
-Why would you lie to me?
-l didn't lie.
-lt's right here. Why would you lie to me?
-Stop lying. You're lying to me.
-l'm not lying to you.
-Stop lying to me!
-l am not lying to you!
I didn't want you to have to go
through your life with this memory!
I didn't want you to remember.
I wanted you to forget!
Remember what?
What happened at that preschool?
MAN:
Smile, everybody.
You guys look great.
GWEN:
There was a man at the preschool.
His name was Fred Krueger.
GIRLS [SINGlNG]:
One, two
Freddy's coming for you
Three, four
Better lock your door
GWEN:
He was a gardener.
He lived in the basement
of the preschool...
...and you kids were his life.
[FREDDY lMlTATlNG AIRPLANE]
[CHILDREN LAUGHlNG]
Four...
...three...
...two...
...one.
GWEN:
We didn't wanna believe it at first.
FREDDY:
Ready or not...
GWEN:
You all were so innocent.
...here l come.
GWEN:
And you, Nancy...
What are you drawing? That is so good.
...you were his favorite of all.
You know what?
I got some other drawings.
And they're, like, really bad drawings.
Maybe you can help me fix them?
And then we started to notice things.
Yeah. Uh, he has been acting
a little strange lately.
He takes us to the secret cave.
[CRYING]
It's okay. It's all right.
So, what did you do?
Did you call the police?
He left town before we ever
were able to confront him.
He's gone. He can't hurt you anymore.
So these dreams that you're having...
...they're repressed memories...
...from a terrible, terrible time.
I hope that you're right.
We have to find the other kids
in the picture.
-What are you talking about? No.
-lt doesn't make any sense.
-There's gotta be more to it. lt's not--
-This makes total sense.
You heard your mom.
These are just memories.
-What if she's wrong?
-We're experiencing them...
-...living them, but they're just memories.
-How do you know that?
Memories don't kill you.
[HORN HONKlNG]
-Whoa, whoa, whoa! Quentin, get in the car.
-lt's my dad. l gotta go.
-We have to do something.
-Look, stop.
This is crazy. Listen to yourself.
I'm sorry.
[WHlSTLE TWEETS]
COACH: l want you to do 400 warm-up.
Then do a 200-back-breast drill swim.
Quentin, I need you to focus.
I need you to wake up, get into this.
Let's go. All right, guys.
Step up. Let's go. On the blocks.
Take your mark.
[WHlSTLE TWEETS]
COACH: Make sure you're working
your underwaters...
...hit the turns, in and out really quick.
Powerful dolphins off the wall.
All right, guys, we're gonna do eight 300s,
descend one to four, hold five to eight.
All right, hop out.
On the blocks, guys. Let's go.
Let's step up.
Take your mark.
[WHlSTLE TWEETS]
[SWIMMERS GRUNT]
COACH:
Come on, pick it up. Let's go. Come on.
Come on. Come on, let's go. Attaboy.
Come on, now. Come on.
Come on, let's go.
Come on.
Come on!
[GASPlNG]
[COUGHlNG]
[TlRES SCREECHING]
QUENTIN:
Wait!
Hey!
[PANTlNG]
Okay.
ALAN: Krueger!
MAN: Come on out, you bastard!
[BANG]
Goddamn it. You open this door, Krueger!
What do you think I did?
-l didn't do anything!
-Get your ass out. Open the fucking door!
-l didn't do it!
ALAN: Norm, make sure...
-...he can't get out the back!
FREDDY: Okay.
[ALAN GRUNTlNG]
Stop!
Stop. Okay.
Okay. Okay.
What are you doing? No, no, no.
This isn't the right way.
-We gotta call the police.
-What is the right way?
Our kids get on a stand,
tell a room of people what happened?
-No, we've got to call the police.
-He's right.
-This is not the way to do this.
ALAN: This ends tonight.
[YELLS]
Okay. Okay.
This is for my son!
Come out, Krueger!
[YELLING]
[SCREAMlNG]
[WOMEN GASP]
No!
Are you okay?
[GASPlNG AND COUGHING]
Go get the nurse.
Breathe, breathe.
Come on. Come on, breathe.
-Relax and breathe. Come on. Come on.
QUENTIN: l'm okay.
I had another nightmare last night.
That burned man with the striped sweater,
he keeps trying to kill me.
I ran a different way this time.
I ended up in front of a preschool.
I woke up before l had a chance to explore,
but it has to mean something.
He chased me
into the preschool this time.
I got away,
made it down to the basement.
But it feels like that's
where he wants me to go. Like...
...he needs me to find something.
I'm starting to dream
with my eyes open.
I can't tell what's real anymore.
I haven't slept in three days.
If I sleep, l dream.
lf I dream, I'm dead.
Is there anybody else out there
that this is happening to?
Can somebody help me?
Please?
[GLASS SHATTERS]
[GASPS]
NANCY:
They're all dead.
I know what happened to Freddy.
You killed Krueger.
-Where'd you hear that name?
-You chased him...
...cornered him and burned him
to death. You hunted him!
We did not hunt him.
We were protecting you.
-From what?
-From him. From what he did to you.
-From what you kids told us he did to you.
-We were 5. We would've said anything!
-Why didn't you go to the police?
-You were so young.
No. God!
And the things we said he did....
The cave. Did you ever find it?
No.
How do you know he was guilty?
-Oh, my God.
-You killed an innocent man.
ALAN:
Mm-mm.
There's not a day that goes by that
I don't think about that night, Quentin.
Good, you deserve at least that.
Quentin. When you grow up
and you have kids...
...l hope you never know the feeling
of utterly failing to protect them.
-Don't touch-- Don't touch me.
-Son--
You listen to me.
As far as everyone around here
is concerned, Fred Krueger never existed.
Quentin.
Quentin, wait. Wait.
-What?
-Slow down.
-Stop.
-We got him killed.
Our stories, our lies.
-What if we can make him stop?
-What if we can?
The preschool. Marcus said that
Freddy wanted him to find something.
Fine.
KRlS:
Nancy.
Don't you wanna hang out, Nancy?
[FREDDY LAUGHlNG]
What are you doing?
I just saw Kris in a body bag.
All right, you've been up for too long.
You're having micronaps. We gotta go.
Let's go find the preschool.
[TlRES SCREECHING]
What are we doing here?
I need more pills.
["UN HOMME ET UNE FEMME"
PLAYlNG OVER SPEAKERS]
Come on. Come on.
[KNOCKS ON WlNDOW]
[FREDDY GROWLS]
[NANCY SCREAMING]
Hi. Um, l'm gonna need a, um,
refill on that, please.
On this, you're out of refills.
I'm gonna have to
call the doctor on this.
Look, l don't have time
to call a doctor. Look--
Oh, my God.
Look, l've been on this stuff
since I was 1 5.
Okay? lt's totally fine.
You just go back, you fill it up and--
Even just a couple.
-All l need is a couple.
-No. No, I'm sorry.
[LIGHTER CLlCKS]
[SIZZLlNG]
[GASPlNG]
[OVER SPEAKERS]
When I want you
In my arms
Quentin. Quentin.
-Just fill it up.
-No.
Dream, dream, dream
Quentin.
When I feel blue
In the night
And I need you
To hold me tight
Whenever l want you
All l have to do is dream
[SCREECHING]
NANCY:
No. No.
[FREDDY CHUCKLlNG]
[NANCY SCREAMING]
Wake up!
You're bleeding.
[SCREAMlNG]
QUENTIN:
Oh, my God. What happened?
Hang on.
His sweater.
-Okay.
-He's here.
Man, you're hurt really bad.
Let's go to the hospital. Come on.
WOMAN [OVER PA]:
Dr. Blake Mason to ICU, please.
Baby.
Oh, honey, honey, honey,
what happened?
Who did this to you?
Look at it, Mom. You know who did it.
You know who did it.
Oh, honey.
WOMAN [OVER PA]:
Dr. Zeger. Dr. William Zeger to CCU.
Dr. Zeger. Dr. Zeger to CCU.
Okay, how we doing?
It's gonna be okay.
I'm gonna give you
a little something for the pain.
-lt'll put you right out.
-lt's okay.
No, Mom, l don't want it.
I don't want it. l don't want it.
-lt's okay, it's okay.
-No, Mom, no.
-l don't want it. Don't let her do it.
-This might sting a bit.
-No! No!
GWEN: No, no.
-Okay. Okay.
-No!
-Where's Quentin?
-Can l have a word with you in the hall?
Don't leave. Don't leave, Mom. Mom.
Where's Quentin? l need Quentin.
Your daughter needs to be sedated,
but I can't do anything...
-...without your authorization.
-l just want her to be out of pain.
Good. Sign this.
She'll be fine.
Great.
Thank you.
-You okay?
-Yeah.
-Yeah?
-What is that?
-Adrenaline. Keep us awake.
-Where'd you get it?
I stole it off one of the nurse's carts.
You can't take that.
You have no idea what it's gonna do.
You know what? That is kind of the least
of my concerns right now. You want some?
No.
[QUENTIN GRUNTS]
Whoa.
Are you okay?
Yeah. l'm good.
Let's go.
NANCY: How much further?
QUENTIN: We're almost there.
Hey, will you talk to me?
I'm falling asleep.
Yeah. What do you wanna talk about?
I don't know.
What's your favorite color?
Blue.
Look, if you really wanna talk,
how come over the last couple years...
...every time I've invited you out,
you've just never shown up?
I don't know if you've noticed,
but I don't exactly fit in.
Okay, look,
if we survive the next 24 hours...
...then l'll take you out on a real date.
Well, what if I say no?
Well, why don't you sleep on it?
[TlRES SCREECHING]
QUENTIN: You okay?
-l'm fine.
Come on.
I saw him. He was right there.
We gotta go. Come on.
[FREDDY LAUGHlNG]
This is it.
This is the school.
-No!
FREDDY: Heh-heh-heh.
Are you okay?
I don't know what's real anymore.
Come on.
Follow me.
NANCY:
Hey, give me your lighter.
All right, well, now that we're here,
now what?
Because I don't remember any of this.
This must be his room.
Okay, he brought us here for a reason.
QUENTIN:
This is definitely his room.
[PAPER RUSTLlNG]
Quentin.
-What?
-There's something back there.
I've been here before.
If you can keep a secret,
I'll take you to a special place.
What are those?
What are those pictures of?
They're all of you.
-Let me see.
-No.
NANCY:
No.
[SOBBlNG]
Oh, God.
No.
We were wrong.
He's not after us because we lied.
He's after us because we told the truth.
He brought us here so we would
remember what he did to us.
God. Fuck!
Fuck.
What does he want from us?
He's never gonna stop.
I know what we need to do.
Come on.
There's gotta be another way.
If we just sit here and do nothing,
we're gonna die.
-l should do this.
-l'm the one who pulled his sweater out.
What if I'm the only one
who can bring him out?
Nancy, I can't let you go to sleep.
You're not gonna wake up.
I know you won't let that happen.
Wake me up if you see me struggle.
Gotta believe in something, right?
I'm gonna be here when you get up.
We're gonna make it.
[STEAM HISSlNG]
Aw, shit.
[SCREAMS THEN GRUNTS]
You can't save her.
Tag.
You're it.
[QUENTIN GRUNTS]
NANCY:
Krueger!
FREDDY:
Your girlfriend's here. l'll be right back.
FREDDY [SlNGING]:
One, two
Guess who's coming for you
Little Nancy.
Now that you caught me,
what game do you wanna play next?
-Fuck you.
-Ooh. Sounds like fun.
It's a little fast for me.
How about we hang first?
No. It's not real.
It's real.
I'm real.
[NANCY YELLS]
Boo.
[NANCY SCREAMS]
[GASPS]
[SCREAMS]
Now, how's this for a wet dream?
[FREDDY CHUCKLlNG]
[BLADES SCRAPlNG]
[FREDDY LAUGHlNG]
[NANCY SCREAMS]
[WOOD GROANING]
[DOOR CREAKlNG]
[TAPPlNG]
Quentin, wake me up.
[FREDDY MOANlNG]
FREDDY:
This dress...
...was always one of my favorites.
Do you remember it, Nancy?
Of course you do.
You remember everything now,
don't you?
Your memories are what fuels me.
No. Please don't.
Your mouth says no...
...but your body says yes.
Mmm.
Don't turn away.
Look at me!
Look what you did to me.
Now it's time to play.
[BOTH GRUNT]
[CHUCKLES]
Are you having fun?
[NANCY YELLS]
[FREDDY GASPS]
[CHUCKLES]
Naughty girl.
[GRUNTlNG]
You can't hurt me.
You're in my world.
And you can't ever leave.
[SCREAMlNG]
Ohh....
That's music to my ears.
I wanna wake up!
You can't wake up.
I had to keep you awake long enough
so when you finally slept...
...you'd never wake up again.
Nancy, wake up.
Wake up, Nancy, wake up!
We're gonna be in here a long time.
-Nancy, please!
-Did you really think your boyfriend...
-...could wake you up?
-Please, don't do this!
Please!
I'm your boyfriend now.
Nancy, come back! Please, wake up!
You promised!
Sweet dreams.
[NANCY GASPS]
[FREDDY YELLS]
[GASPlNG]
NANCY:
Quentin, get him.
[BOTH GRUNTlNG]
Die! Fucking bastard!
FREDDY:
Nice try, Nancy.
Now let me take a stab.
[FREDDY SCREAMS]
FREDDY:
Now, why don't you just fucking die?
[YELLS]
NANCY:
It hurts, doesn't it?
That's because you're
in my world now, bitch.
[QUENTIN COUGHING]
NANCY:
Wait.
[BOTH COUGHlNG]
FIREMAN 1 : Give me some slack.
FIREMAN 2: Yeah, aim it up a little higher.
[INDlSTlNCT RADlO CHATTER]
COP:
No sign of a body anywhere.
[SIREN WAILlNG]
Hey, Quentin.
Nightmare's over.
[CRICKETS CHlRPlNG]
I want you to go
straight up to bed, okay?
Yeah.
Hey, Mom?
I know you were just trying
to protect me. Thank you.
I'm just glad you're safe.
[SCREAMlNG]
[FREDDY GRUNTING]