Harold. You're early.
- I know.
I'm picking something up. - Where's Peggy?
Thought you two
were joined at the hip.
[Engine Starts]
[Beeping]
[Cell Phone Rings]
Yes?
[Man] How's it going, Harold?
- I'm in. I'm doing it.
- Friendly reminder-
Don't be a hero.
We hear a police siren,
Peggy's dead.
L-is she okay?
Can I talk to her? Just hurry up.
[Line Disconnects]
Please, let me talk to her- Hel- Let me- Hello?
[Beeping]
Backseat.
Let her go.
You said you would.
Pleasure doing business with you.
Thanks for the car, Harold. [Whimpering]
Come here, Peggy.
[Man] Harold.!
- Everything all right?
- Paul, I'm okay. No problem.
- Get out of the car!
- Go!
Both of you! Do it!
Okay.
Happy Halloween, man.
J-Just relax.
- Vic.! What did you do?
- No choice. Him or me.
- We could have just driven off. Get in the car.
- I didn't see anything!
- Don't move the car. I'm not done.
- Neither did Peggy.
I'm not done.
- No!
- [Gunshot]
[Barking]
## [Up-tempo Folk]
# It's a jungle out there #
# Disorder and confusion
everywhere #
# No one seems to care #
# Well, I do
Hey, who's in charge here #
# It's a jungle out there #
# Poison in the very air
we breathe #
# Do you know what's in the water
that you drink, well, I do #
# And it's amazing #
# People think I'm crazy
'cause I worry all the time #
# If you paid attention
you'd be worried too #
# You better pay attention
or this world we love so much #
# Mightjust kill you #
# I could be wrong now #
# But I don't think so #
# 'Cause it's a jungle out there #
# It's a jungle out there ##
[Chattering]
Mr. Monk, are you okay?
Everybody's waiting.
It's... over there.
What?
Dog-You know.
Dog... doo.
Did you step in it?
If I stepped in it,
I'd be in that ambulance right now...
on my way
to the emergency room, wouldn't I?
Praying for the sweet release
that only death can bring.
So, Monk, what do you think?
Who are we looking for?
Ah, I'd say it's a terrier, a Yorkie,
maybe a chihuahua.
Probably miles away by now.
We'll never catch him.
- He can't concentrate
because of the- - 'Cause of the what?
[Whispers]
The dog poo.
Lieutenant.
Clean that up for me,
would you?
Thanks.
Sergeant.
Yes, sir.
Clean that up.
No, don't.
Sir, you can't park there.
It's all right.
It's okay. I'm a detective.
I'm a detective.
One second. Here we go.
[Mutters]
Hold that?
I got it.
I usually keep it right-
Um- Oh! I got it.
Here we go.
Marty Eels.
Private Investigator.
I'm here to save your butts.
Captain!
Captain Stottlemeyer!
Oh, hell.
Who's that?
Marty Eels.
He's a private investigator.
Nickel-and-dime stuff.
Divorces, insurance fraud.
He's a professional
pain in the ass.
Hey, Captain. Captain,
you're lookin' great.
You're losin' weight
or your shirts are getting bigger.
Marty. I heard the D.A.
Pulled your license.
No, no, no. That was
just a temporary suspension.
No, no, no.
That was just a little misunderstanding.
A misunderstanding?
That's all ancient history anyway.
So I was just riding around
in the neighborhood,
and I heard a call go out
on the police scanner- Look, Marty. I'm busy.
Yeah, that's why I thought
I'd come down here and lend a hand.
So what do we got?
The jewelry store was robbed, huh? Well, that's obvious.
We got a- a dead rent-a-cop
and a missing store manager, so let me guess.
You're thinking
the store manager doing it- Yeah. Something like that.
Yeah, so let me look around, huh?
An extra pair of eyes can't hurt.
And who knows,
I could see something you guys are missing.
We're not missing anything, Mr. Eels.
We've got a C.S.I. Team here.
And, uh, see that man
over there?
It's Adrian Monk.
I think we're in pretty good hands.
Captain. Monk says I can't
just throw this away.
I gotta take it
like a mile away and bury it.
Could I see that?
Yeah.
You can't throw this away.
This-This is evidence.
[Sniffs]
[Clears Throat]
This is fresh. Mmm!
I'd say this is less than
90 minutes old.
Marty-
But isn't that when you said all this was probably going down?
The dog could've
belonged to the victim...
or to one of the perps.
I think this is important.
Monk was gonna throw this away.
Um-
You know,
he might be right.
Let's, uh, book that
into evidence.
Yes, sir.
Captain. Look.
Did that store manager
live in Oakland?
Yeah.
How'd you know that?
That's his dog.
That's from Oakland.
You can see the blue license
on its collar.
What, you can see that
from here? [Chuckles]
Little something I call
attention to detail, but- [Laughs]
Go get the dog.
Adrian Monk,
Natalie Teeger. This is Marty Eels.
He's a private investigator.
Hey, how you doing? How you doing?
I hear good things.
Good things. [Snaps Fingers]
Don't worry. I'm not competition.
I'm just here to help. Can I have one of those?
So, what do we got?
Captain, I don't think
the manager did this.
For one thing,
he didn't lock the door behind him.
Plus, I noticed
some more blood by the curb.
I think there was
a second shooting.
Yeah, he could be right.
Very good. Nicely done. Nicely done.
Captain.!
He's right.
Peggy belongs to the store manager,
Harold Gumbal,
Geary Street, Oakland.
Hmm.
You know, if the manager was robbing his own store,
he wouldn't bring
his dog along. Or leave him behind.
No, the manager is not the guy.
No, that's right. The manager is not the guy.
Here's what-
Here's what happened! Here's what happened!
This dog was a hostage.
The manager was being forced
to rob his store.
Something went wrong,
and they shot the guard.
Excuse me.
What the hell is he doing?
Captain-
Well, he did spot the dog's license from a block away.
Okay. They drove off
in Gumbal's car.
They headed south.
They're gonna dump it as soon as they can.
We're already checking
the airport. That's a waste of time.
They would never go there.
There's too much security.
- Try the train station.
- Train station.
Yeah. Try, um, San Bruno...
or Millbrae.
They probably panicked
when they shot the guard.
Maybe they dropped the gun
or some bloody clothes somewhere nearby.
[Sniffs]
What are you doing there? What-
[Sniffing]
This dog has been
sniffing around a sewer recently.
See these sewer grates
around here?
The perps might have
stuffed something down in there,
and maybe this dog
saw them do it.
You gotta be kidding.
He's kidding, right? He's joking.
The man is joking.
Just take two minutes
to check it.
[Stottlemeyer]
Officer, take a look in that sewer grate.
Captain.
From smelling a dog,
that's impossible.
Captain! There was stuff
down the drain just like he said.
[Whimpering]
No. No, Mom.
I wasn't on the news.
Because there were
no reporters there yet.
[Buzzer]
Mm-hmm. I found a lot of clues.
I found three or four big clues.
Cap- Captain was very impressed with me.
He- He just walked in.
He'll tell ya. One second.
Captain, it's my mother.
Tell her-Tell her how good I was on the crime scene.
Uh, Mrs. Eels? Hi.
Uh, yeah.
Marty did great. You'd be very proud of him.
He's a first-rate detective.
I look forward
to meeting you, too, ma'am. Okay. Bye-bye.
Uh, what were those beeps?
Oh, she was at work.
She works for Pacific Global Airlines.
She's a- She's a quality control operator.
Come in.
Come- Come on in. Sit down. Sit down.
Here, Natalie. Come sit down.
Come sit down. Make yourself at home.
- Monk, sit. Sit anywhere.
- That's okay. I'm not fine.
Did he just say he's not fine?
Yeah.
So, Captain,
am I on the case, or what?
- First I have to ask you
a couple of questions. - Yeah. Yeah.
Where were you
yesterday morning at 8:00?
You mean when the robbery
was happening? Yeah.
You guys think
I had something to do with that?
Why, because you
can't keep up with me on a crime scene?
[Stottlemeyer]
Where were you, Marty?
I was at the hospital.
St. Andrews.
- They thought I had
a concussion. - What happened?
Well-
[Chuckles] That's kind of embarrassing.
I, um- I got hit very hard
by a client.
Hit me very hard.
Yeah. Um-
I was, um, supposed to
follow his wife and take pictures.
Whoa.
She was cheating on him.
No. No. That- That's him.
That's my client.
You burst in to take a picture
of a man in bed with his own wife?
Yes, I did.
I made a mistake. I'm human.
So, the bottom line is
I was at the hospital when the jewelry thing was happening.
- You can call them.
- We will.
Why is it so hard for you guys
to believe that I'm just this good?
Because, Marty, you were
never this good before. In fact, you sort of sucked.
Well, I was-
I been teaching myself. I been- I learned how to focus.
And that's really the secret, focus.
Am I right about the focus thing?
Bay Area Center
Continuing Education.
Is that a correspondence school?
It's fully accredited.
What school
did you go to? Berkeley.
That's a good school.
I believe
they're fully accredited too.
Yeah. Yeah,
they're fully accredited.
So, Captain,
am I on the case or what?
I mean, put- put me in, Coach!
I found- I found the ski masks,
didn't I?
Look, Marty,
even if I wanted to,
I just don't have the budget
to hire two consultants.
[Stammering]
I tell you what. I tell you what.
You don't have to
pay me dime one unless I get some results.
So this costs you nothing.
Captain, could l-
You can't hire this guy.
He did find the ski masks.
By smelling a dog.
It's not possible.
Look, Monk, sometimes
when you're picking up clues,
it seems like magic to me.
I don't know
how you do it.
[Cell Phone Rings]
Maybe he's doing something that you don't understand.
I think he's cheating.
He's a cheater.
- Disher.
- This isn't the fourth grade, Monk.
He's cheating!
How?
I don't know.
We just found
the store manager's car. Guess where it was.
- Your train station?
- In San Bruno. Outstanding.
You called it, Marty.
[Stottlemeyer] Let's check it out.
Marty, come here.
You ride with me.
[Chattering]
He's cheating.
'Scuse me. 'Scuse me.
Uh, go ahead.
No, no. After you.
Please.
It's pretty weird, huh?
Maybe we should send one of them home.
Yeah, but which one?
Marty Eels.
E- E-L-S, like the fish.
He's always wanted
to be a detective.
He used to stay up late
reading Hardy Boys stories under the cover.
So your son
is helping Adrian Monk?
Who's helping who?
That's the question.
I love that.
Love the thing you do with your hands.
It's very old-school.
Thank you.
[Sighs]
[Sniffs]
Wha-What are you doing?
Mud. You can tell
where the car has been.
From tasting it?
He's tasting the mud.
Does that work?
No! It's just nuts!
Captain, how tall
was the store manager?
Uh-
Uh, 5'10", according to his driver's licence.
Hmm.
Somebody else
was driving this car,
because that chair's been adjusted
for somebody 5'11 ".
Excuse me.
It's impossible to know that.
Seat adjustments
are not that exact.
Should I write down 5'11 "?
Uh-
I don't know. Yes. In pencil.
Ah.
[Clears Throat] Here we go.
This map was used recently.
That means
that the driver was not familiar with this particular area.
L- l- I had that one.
You didn't say anything.
I was waiting my turn.
I had that one. Captain-
He's cheating.
He's a cheater.
He saw me looking.
And...
this car was driven
on Highway 47.
And... how do you
happen to know that?
It's all in the details, Captain.
See the, um- the dead bugs on the windshield?
This...
is a gray bantam-wing mosquito,
which are most common where?
Anybody? Walter Creek reservoir.
In Livingston.
Highway 47. That's fantastic.
[Laughing]
Bantam-wing mosquito.
Gentlemen, let's pop the trunk.
Monk.
This blood is still fresh.
Yes, it is.
Good for you.
Write that down.
One for Monk. [Chuckles]
All right. Gumbal was
dragged out of the car...
and into these woods.
Okeydoke. Here we go.
[Chattering]
These leaves
were recently crushed.
I'm 1%16th Cherokee.
Cool.
Thought he might be.
Now what's he doing?
I can't look.
Oh, he's using a divining rod.
The Indians used to use them.
He's 1%16th Cherokee.
Oh, that's my boy.
Can everybody see okay?
Take lots of pictures.
Film is cheap.
[Grunts]
[Murmuring]
Think I found
the store manager.
- [Clamoring]
- [Stottlemeyer] Stay back! Get outta here!
[Disher]
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Back off. Back off.
[Stottlemeyer]
He was shot in the chest.
Call the coroner's office.
Get the crime scene guys up here. And get me a 20-foot perimeter now!
Let's go! You heard the man.
Take 10 steps back! Let's go!
Get out of here!
Baker, come on! Move these guys down.
That's interesting.
What?
You don't see that?
Look at his arms.
That is an unnatural position.
Unnatural?
I think he was trying
to tell us something.
With his dying breath,
he was trying to send us a message.
[Monk]
With his dying breath.
He was trying to tell us
the name of the man who killed him. Look.
See, he's pointing to his watch.
No, he's not.
Captain, are there any perps
who'd do a job like this by the name of... Casio?
Casio?
Lefty.
Captain.
- Dial.
- Eddie Dial.
Hejust did seven years
in Folsom for kidnapping and bank robbery.
He just made parole.
Well, let's check him out.
Yes, sir.
Baker!
Johnson!
Mom, have you seen my camera?
Mm-mmm.
Did you check your jacket?
What about your pockets?
Yes, I looked everywhere.
I haven't seen it, honey.
Why don't you ask Mr. Monk to help you?
Please, Mr. Monk.
It has all my pictures in it from my school trip.
I was the official photographer
and if I lose it, I'm going to get an incomplete.
When did you see it last?
I saw it yesterday
in the living room.
That plant has been
moved recently.
That's right.
How did you know?
Well, normally,
they lean toward the sun.
This one is leaning
the other way.
Hello.
Mr. Monk, thank you so much.
You're the best. Isn't he the best?
There's no one better.
You really are amazing.
[Monk]
Oh. Wait.
When did you water this?
Oh, uh, this morning.
Well, the camera
could not have been back there this morning.
It would have gotten wet.
Thanks for trying, Julie.
My mom put me up to this.
Mr. Monk,
you really are amazing.
You're probably
the best in the world.
[Cell Phone Rings]
And you're right about
this Marty character. He's cheating.
I don't know.
He is. Hello?
Yes, sir.
Really?
Okay, okay. We're on our way.
They just caught one of the killers.
They're questioning him now.
Julie, we'll be back soon,
honey.
Natalie.
It's not Eddie Dial, is it?
Yeah.
[Stottlemeyer]
We found the manager's wallet... in your motel room, Eddie.
It's over.
We own you.
Look, man, I didn't hurt
anybody, okay?
I didn't even
have a gun.
Well, two people are dead,
Edward.
Who did the shooting?
I'm willing to bet you
it was that guy. Blanchard, Victor P.
The two of you were seen together
last weekend.
Where is he, Eddie?
I don't know!
Captain.
May I?
Where's your-
Where's your partner, Eddie?
I don't know.
Hmm. He's telling the truth.
He- He doesn't know.
- Do you have a map?
- He's like a human lie detector.
I can't believe it.
I can't believe it either.
Well, he's doing it.
Well, I still don't believe it.
What you see happening
in the next room, it's impossible. It's just-
What-What's this?
Stuff we found in Eddie's motel room,
including a pair of tickets
to Costa Rica.
[Natalie]
Did you guys find thejewels?
No, not yet.
Marty'll find them.
All righty. Now then, Eddie,
where did you hide the jewels?
Was it-Was it here?
No. Um...
Was it here?
No.
Uh, how about here?
Ah. Getting warmer.
Did you hide them here, Eddie?
Ah. Yes.
They're, uh-
They're in the state park.
Get outta here.
I know this area.
There's a water tower right here.
Oh. Oh.
Did you, uh- Did you hide them
near the water tower, Eddie?
Hmm! Bingo!
Yes!
[Marty Chuckles]
Call Dunlop in the Parks Department.
Tell him to meet us there.
And tell him
to bring some shovels. Sir.
I don't know how the hell
I'm gonna write this up.
Marty.
Oh, Mr. Monk.
Why don't you guys go ahead.
I'll meet you there.
This is District.
Give me two black-and-whites down at the state park right now.
He's cheating!
What, Monk? How is he cheating?
We've got a suspect
who just confessed.
He found the car.
He found the body.
He is solving this case
single-handedly. By cheating!
Natalie, what do you think?
I believe my boss.
[Exhales]
Anyway, we'd better go. Should we take one car or two?
Monk,
why don't you stay here?
We're gonna let Marty
take this one.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
You're firing him? No! No.
Um, it's just that Marty
seems to be in a zone.
He's got a handle
on this one.
You get the next one,
okay?
I'll call you. I gotta go.
[Dr. Kroger]
So they found thejewels.
Right where Marty
said they'd be.
Of course.
And what, then they-
They asked you to step aside?
They said Marty was on a roll.
Guess they didn't want me
to cramp his style.
Well, A-Adrian, l-I'm sure
that this is all just temporary.
Maybe he really is
better than me.
Yeah, well,
would that be so terrible?
I mean, if you
weren't number one.
An ex-cop I know...
teaches criminal justice
at Fulton College.
He offered me a job
last year.
Maybe I'll give him
a call.
All right.
So you're just giving up. Okay.
No, Adrian, I'm not suggesting
that you just give up.
I'm saying to you
that there is always someone ahead of you.
This is the human condition.
For instance,
there's a new psychiatrist
here in town, name of Lowenstern.
Now, I know that there is
no way that I will ever be as-as-well, as good as he is.
I know this.
I accept it.
He's better than you?
He's brilliant.
Nominated for a Nobel Prize.
But the point is
you think that you might enjoy teaching.
I don't know.
Tell-Tell me more about this Lowenstern.
Lowenstern.
I could introduce you. Office is right across the street.
He charges $400 an hour.
So wh-where were we?
Mmm. Okay.
Oh. Good morning, boss.
They were out of the round sponges.
Don't panic.
I'll pick some up on the way home.
Don't worry about the groceries.
You're driving me to Fulton College. I have an appointment.
You mean now?
11:00. I'm meeting the dean.
You're just gonna quit,
just like that?
I think I would make
a very good teacher.
Oh, Mr. Monk,
you'd make a terrible teacher!
It would take you four weeks
to correct one paper.
You're a detective.
You're a great detective.
- Are you gonna
drive me or not? - No. No, I'm not.
Your feelings are hurt,
and you're just not thinking straight.
Fine. Fine.
I'll take a taxi.
[Chuckles]
You're gonna take a taxi.
Do you know what people do
in taxis?
Fine! Fine.
I will drive myself.
I'll rent a car.
See? I am dialing
the number. [Beeping]
I'm not bluffing.
Do you even have
a driver's license? Yes, I have a license.
Okay, this is it.
This is the last digit.
I have dialed the number.
It is ringing.
[Recording]
Thank you for calling Cannon Rent-a-Car.
This call may be monitored
for quality purposes.
- I am on hold.
- Mr. Monk-
Fulton College
is 100 miles away.
It is up the interstate.
It's over a bridge.
You know, I have a blindfold
for going over bridges.
But you'll be driving.
Good point.
I think I can make it.
I'll just sort of peek underneath.
I'm not gonna let you drive.
You've never driven over a bridge in your life.
What choice do I have?
[Woman On Phone] Excuse me. Excuse me, sir.
Yes?
My daughter goes to Fulton College.
You don't have to take the bridge.
You can take the causeway
all the way up.
You... could hear us?
Yes, sir.
I'm a quality control operator. I'm monitoring the call.
L- I was on hold.
Yes, sir. We start listening
as soon as you're connected.
You wouldn't believe
the things I hear.
[Laughs]
People fooling around. People arguing.
I could write a book about it.
You could hear me...
while I was on hold?
That's right.
## [Pop]
[Camera Shutter Clicking]
Hey! Monk!
What a nice surprise.
This guy's from
San Francisco magazine.
I'm one of the 10 most
eligible bachelors in the city. Can you believe it?
- Marty, we need to talk.
- Not a good time, Nat.
Did you just call me Nat?
Hey, hey, get one
with me and Monk. No.
No, no, this is good.
It's like a summit of great minds.
Philip Marlowe
meets Sherlock Holmes.
It's about your mother, a little something
she might have overheard while at work.
## [Continues]
Can't-The music's too loud.
I can't hear. Take a five. Take a five.
## [Stops]
[Natalie] We know how you did it, Marty.
- We figured it out.
- How I did what?
Didn't your mother ever tell you
that cheaters never win?
Actually,
it was your mother's idea.
She works for
Pacific Global Airlines, doesn't she,
in the quality control department?
Yeah, so?
[Woman On Phone]
This call may be monitored for quality purposes.
[Monk]
Here's what happened.
After the murders,
Blanchard and Dial went back to their motel room,
counted theirjewels,
and then they called the airlines to buy plane tickets to Costa Rica.
They were put on hold.
What they didn't know
was that your mother...
was already on the line
monitoring their call.
They must have been on hold
for quite a while,
because they talked about everything-
who they killed,
where they dumped the car,
even where they hid the masks.
[Natalie]
But she didn't call the police.
She called you and told you
everything you needed to know to solve the case.
Or at least pretend
to solve it.
You're a very smart man.
Yeah.
He's the real thing.
Yep.
Course, you realize
you have no proof for any of this.
Don't airlines record
phone conversations?
Yes, Nat.
I believe they do.
Yes, they certainly do.
But those conversations...
have a way of being
accidentally erased.
So it's really
your word against mine.
And who do you think
everyone's gonna believe?
The amazing Marty Eels
or, uh...
yesterday's news?
- [Telephone Ringing]
- [Slurps]
[Scoffs]
Phone's been ringin' off the hook.
Cases, cases, cases.
[Chuckles]
- Would you mind?
- [Ringing Continues]
Ah-
[Ringing Continues]
Hey. Eels Investigations.
[Man]
Hey, Marty.
I got a proposition for you.
Who's this?
My name's Vic. We never met.
I think you know my partner, though, Eddie Dial.
In fact, you and your friends
arrested him yesterday.
How did you get this number?
This is my private line.
It's the first number
on your mother's speed dial. My mother?
Did you really think
you could screw with me and get away with it?
Where is she?
I just left her. She's fine.
For now.
If you want to see her again,
listen carefully.
- The jewels belong to me.
I want them back. - The jewels?
Bring them to the Dunn Street
bus terminal by 8:00.
Put them in locker 240
on the upper level. I got a spare key.
Wait a minute!
Wait, wait, wait! I can't get to the jewels.
They're locked up.
They're in evidence. You can do it, Marty.
I been reading all about you.
You're the flavor of the month.
Just tell them you want to
examine the evidence.
Tell them
you want to use it to set a trap. I don't care what you tell them.
Just get 'em back.
Oh, and Marty.
What?
No cops. Come alone.
Remember,
if anything happens to me,
your mother's dead
by 8:20.
- Wait!
- [Dial Tone]
Mr. Monk.!
Mr. Monk, wait!
Wait, Mr. Monk!
[Car Horn Honks]
Mr. Monk, wait!
Wait, wait.
It's Vic Blanchard.
- He just called.
He's got my mother. - I gotta call the captain.
No, no! No! No cops!
He said no cops, or he'd kill her.
Mr. Monk, please.
You gotta help me.
You were right.
I don't know what I'm doing! I don't.
Let's go.
Let's just go over this
one more time.
Can you think of anything else
he might have said on the phone? [Stammering] No cops!
[Groans]
He said ifhe even smells a cop, she's dead.
My gosh. Marty, for the 10th time,
no one's calling the cops!
She's right. Marty, look.
We know where he's gonna be at 8:00.
If we can find your mother
before that time, the cops can pick him up then.
- I know. I know. L-
- Ah! Natalie.
I got it. I'm on it!
It's all over the top.
Marty, can you just please
sit on the couch, all right?
You're making Mr. Monk
very nervous.
All right, one more time.
The kidnapper said he'd just left her, right?
So she can't be too far
from where he made that phone call.
Do you remember anything else
about the phone call?
- Like what?
- Like wh- Like anything.
Noises in the background.
- I don't know!
- He doesn't know.
This wasn't even my idea.
My mother made me do this.
She forced me into it.
She said it was the only way a loser like me...
was ever gonna be able
to solve a real crime.
She sounds delightful.
That's my mother. Where do you get off talking about somebody's mother?
Okay, Marty-
What's wrong with you?
Marty, Marty, Marty. Concentrate.
Can you please just try to think?
You must have heard something.
Yeah. Uh-
An ocean. He-
- I think he was near an ocean.
- There you go.
And there was, um...
a ringing like- like a clang.
Clang.
With a sound before it. Um-
It was like a thud...
clang.
Thud! Clang!
Okay. Give me a minute.
Thud, clang!
Yeah, Marty.
I got it. Thud, clang.
Let me think.
[Thud]
[Bell Rings]
Thud, clang.
[Monk] Okay.
Oh, my God, she's here!
She's here, she's here! Mom. Mom!
No, Marty, don't-
Don't get separated!
Mom!
Stay with the group!
Marty, I want you to focus.
Can you focus?
All right, the caller
said that she would be dead by 8:20, was it?
Why 8:20?
Why not 8:00 or 8:30?
- 8:20.
- Think!
I'm thinking.
Well, think harder!
Why don't you think?
Hey, I'm not the great big famous detective.
Well, you were two hours ago!
Natalie!
What?
- 8:20.
- What's 8:20?
High tide.
Mom.! Mom.!
That's gotta be it.
- Go, Marty. Go.!
- Come on. Run. Move!
I'll wait out here.
I got your back.!
Mom! Mom!
Mom!
Hang on, Mrs. Eels!
[Natalie]
Marty, hurry.! Hurry, Marty.! Hurry.!
[Marty Shouting, Indistinct]
- [Mrs. Eels Grunting]
- [Overlapping Shouts]
Marty, hurry.!
Marty, you gotta hurry.
[Natalie]
Hurry, Marty.!
[Coughing]
- Blanchard, hands up!
- Police officer!
Blanchard, you're under arrest
for the murder of Harold Gumbal.
- Come on! Come on.
- Go.
[Thud]
[Bell Rings]
Great. Thank you.
They got him. It's over.
That's good.
Mrs. Eels,
you're probably going to have to testify...
about that phone call
you overheard.
You told him?
I didn't tell him.
He figured it out.
He's a real detective.
Actually, he... found you.
We had no idea where you were.
He put all the clues together.
[Thud]
[Bell Rings]
He, um-
It really was
some of the most unique detective work I've ever seen.
[Natalie]
Just an incredible detective.
His detecting is like-
What?
He doesn't need
anyone's help, Mrs. Eels.
No. No one's help.
Really?
W-When the kidnapper called,
they both panicked.
L-l-I'm prone
to panicking.
A-And I had to say,
"Let's get focused, because my mother's in trouble."
And-And that got
everybody focused.
But then I had to concentrate
on the sounds from the background.
I could hear the ocean.
And I heard a clang and a thud.
Thud and a clang.
A thud and a clang.
And-And 8:20.
Why not 8:00?
Why not 8:30?
And then I remembered
high tide is at 8:20.
Once I had that piece,
then it all fell together. Oh.
Oh, Marty.
Marty, you're wonderful.
I'd like to thank
the police department,
particularly Captain Stottlemeyer...
and, uh, Adrian Monk.
This was a very difficult case
for me.
Uh, last night I made a decision.
It's the toughest decision
of my career.
But I'm going to resign my practice...
and take a teaching position
at Fulton Community College...
where I'll be teaching
modern criminal investigative techniques.
[Applause]
You were right about him,
weren't you?
[Shutters Clicking]
He was cheating.
[Reporter]
Over here, Mr. Eels.
Dropped the key.
[Chuckles]
He was cheating.
Repair and Synchronization by
Easy Subtitles Synchronizer 1.0.0.0