Man:
Car 2118. Call greenpoint hospital.
Tell them we're bringing in
a wounded cop.
Eighth precinct. Yeah.
Jesus Christ
Guess who got shot.
Serpico.
Think a cop did it?
I know six cops said they'd like to.
- Hello?
- Burnham: Sidney?
New York times. Serpico's been shot.
- Oh, my god.
Burnham: They're taking him to greenpoint.
I'll see you there.
Man: Watch it.
Commissioner: To be a police officer
means to believe in the law.
And to enforce it impartially...
Respecting
the equality of all men...
And the dignity and worth
of every individual.
Every day your life
will be on the line ..
And also your character.
You'll need integrity, courage...
Nonesty, compassion, courtesy...
Perseverance and Patience.
You men are now prepared
to join the war against crime...
And put the theory you have learned
into practice on the streets.
The same time, the same place.
Both reports.
I already made out a 424.
- You covering this, lieutenant?
- Yes, chief green.
Who was with serpico?
- Heinemann and Julio.
- I want them interrogated.
I want this conducted as an official
departmental investigation.
Transcripts by 9 A.M.
Another thing,
I want a 24-hour guard on serpico.
Man: Yes, sir.
You two over there.
Commissioner: Anthony sardo.
Ralph sidon.
Frank serpico.
Frankie!
(Set closer.
Patrolman serpico.
Upstairs. See the roll-call man.
Take a map.
Memorize your posts and sectors.
This week, 8 to 4. Next week,
4 to midnight. Grab an empty locker.
Any questions, the older guys
will fill you in. Good luck.
Yo. Eight o'clock.
Let's go. Come on,
gather round, let's go.
All right, settle down.
All right, there's a few announcements
today and two new men.
Now, on the board at my left,
you see squad one, blue sector.
Squad two, red sector.
Squad three, green sector.
Now, we want summonses,
summonses, summonses.
Charlie:
I'll help the boys, Florence.
This is frank serpico, Charlie.
- Hello, frank.
- Hello, Charlie.
- How about some creamed chicken?
- Sounds good.
Serpico:
No, I think I'll have a...
How about a roast beef on roll?
Yeah, okay. You go through the line.
I'll bring it over.
Peluce
it's all fat here.
- I saw real lean beef over there.
- Come on, take it easy. Sit down.
- What's the matter?
- Don't be so fussy. It's free.
Well, I'm not fussy. I don't know
how I'm gonna eat this.
Listen, Charlie's an okay guy.
We give him a break
on double-parking on deliveries.
Couldn't I pay for it,
get what I want?
Frank, generally you just sort of take
what Charlie gives you.
Man: Sector d, David, 1034.
Possible rape in progress.
Vicinity of p.S. 218,
grand Avenue and bq expressway.
Hey, Becker, aren't we gonna
take that?
Oh, relax, frank. It's not our sector.
Serpico: It's on the borderline.
I'm gonna take it.
Uh, d sector, 1547, 10-4.
Woman: Oh, my god.
Serpico: Hold it. Hold it. Hold it.
Woman: Ahh!
- Police officers.
Boy: Oh, shit.
Don't shoot, now. Be cool.
All right. Okay, put your guns away.
Put your guns away, man.
Come on, goddamn it. I said,
put them motherfucking guns away.
I'll cut her, goddamn fit.
Turn the motherfucking light out,
man.
I'll cut her, man. I'll cut her.
Now, you just be cool, goddamn it.
Just be cool
all right. All right.
- All right. That's it.
Woman: Unh!
The other one took his thing out.
He put it up to my mouth.
He held me down.
They said if I didn't do it...
They'd kill me.
Malone: She's gonna make
a hell of a withess
would you like a stretcher?
Muscles, he's all yours.
I'll call you from the hospital.
Okay, hard-on.
Who were your playmates?
Hey, frank, you want a piece of this?
No, I wanna fill out the arrest card.
Hey, Charlie.
Let me have five minutes with him.
Sure.
Thanks.
Thank you, Charlie.
That prick really worked you over.
How do you feel?
How come you didn't stay
for the fun?
That's not my kind of fun.
Yeah
I wanna talk to you.
I wanna take you across the street.
Get you a cup of coffee.
Without cuffs
now, look...
I didn't touch you upstairs, right”?
You take off on me,
I'll put one in your back.
Understand?
Come on.
Serpico: Goddamn shame you're gonna take
this whole rap yourself.
I don't know. Maybe you're guilty,
maybe you're not.
Maybe you just went along
for the ride.
I got a feeling you just went along.
You're the one who got caught.
You never even got your cock out.
- Put it in the report.
- It's in the report.
Look at you.
- I can't eat.
- No, you can't.
I don't understand you,
you know that?
What are you,
obligated to those guys?
Fuck it.
They left you holding the bag.
You don't owe them nothing.
They're gonna put you away,
you know that?
What can I get?
Oh, let's see. Kidnapping.
Sodomy. Rape.
Are you kidding me?
Hey.
You talk to me. Save yourself.
You're not gonna send
someone over? Look
McCoy, I get one,
I'm gonna lose the other.
Look, serpico, that's muscles' case.
He's off for a couple of days.
- I can't cut in.
- They're here now.
McCoy: It'll keep.
- No, it won't.
Police officer. Hold it. Hold.
Turn around.
Owl
- spread!
- Come on, man. Come on.
Please take that gun from my head.
Turn around slow.
We'll take it from here, kid.
You don't have to hang around.
What are you talking about?
That's my collar.
We take the collar.
A collar like this don't look good
a patrolman takes it.
Now, wait a minute. I don't care
how it looks. I did the work.
I broke my ass on this,
it's my collar.
You really want the collar, kid”?
You know, you can be
brought up on charges.
You left your post.
You left the street.
Entered the schoolyard
without permission.
That's just for openers,
right, penella?
No memo entry. Shit.
You'd be lucky to end up
with a reprimand.
We'll give you an assist
on the arrest, kid.
Jim, get out of the way.
What are you doing?
What you want me to do?
Go across the street?
- Hey, pasquale.
Pasquale: Hey, Frankie.
- How you doing?
- Okay. How you doing?
- Where's pop?
- Be back in a half-hour.
How's it going, Frankie?
Okay. I come to get my shoes.
- Yeah.
- Rev it up, rev it up.
- Oh, here they are.
- Frankie. How you doing?
Okay. Good job. Uh-huh.
Oh, you people do good work here.
So how you doing, Frankie”
you keep asking me that.
What's the matter with you? I'm okay.
Well, I thought you were coming over
to the house Saturday night.
Ah, I'm sorry, pasquale,
I couldn't make it.
Margaret invited marianne over.
Marianne was very disappointed...
Oh, now, that's... now, look...
I don't like that.
Really, don't invite people over...
If you're not sure I'm gonna come.
I mean it, now.
If I wanna see marianne, I'll call her.
What's going on
with you two anyway?
Hey, pasquale,
I'm gonna tell you something.
See, all day long
I work with cops, right?
Now, when I go out, I see marianne.
Her father's a cop.
Her brother's a cop.
Her uncle's a cop.
I got a feeling she's a cop too.
Come here.
How you doing on the job?
It's got its problems.
Mama tells me you're looking
for a new apartment. Is that true?
- Yeah.
- So where you going?
I don't know.
I'm looking around by school.
N.Y.u.? Greenwich village?
Yeah, greenwich village.
The old neighborhood's
not good enough?
Tell pop I was here.
Yeah. Frankie, Sunday?
Sunday what?
Dinner. Huh?
- Do me one favor. No marianne.
- I know. No marianne.
All right,
a couple of announcements.
"Announcing a course
in fingerprint identification...
To be given at John Jay college.
This is for those patrolmen...
Who wish to make themselves
eligible for assignment...
To the bureau
of criminal identification, b.C.I...
Which is generally considered to be
a path to a detective's gold shield.
Signed, captain mcguire.”
On the board on my left,
you see squad one.
Serpico: Hot enough for you?
Man: It's not the heat. It's the humidity.
I had a feeling
you were gonna say that.
Barto: Know how long
you're taking on that one?
Check one print category,
two, that's plenty.
I'm not gonna give a guy a "no record"
when he might have a record.
How long you been
with the b.C.L. Now, serpico?
Serpico: All my life.
Barto: That's long enough
to know how we do things.
Barto. It's not just that.
You don't like me.
Barto:
B.c.l. Never had a weirdo cop before.
Barto, stop bugging me.
Serpico: Mama.
Frankie.
Mama.
Chloe: Hey.
Wanna buy a puppy?
How about that, huh?
Where'd you get these dogs?
Oh, they're mine.
Want one for free?
Ah, no, I'll pay for it.
How much are they?
Five dollars.
You got it.
Okay, now, which one of you guys
wanna come with me?
What?
Come on.
- Listen, will you do me a favor?
Chloe: What?
Just watch the car and my stuff
over here because I'm moving in.
Chloe: Yeah. - Thank you.
Don quixote.
Senorita land?
Mr. serpico.
I got my horse here.
Maybe I can drop you someplace.
I'm going to work
at the caffe reggio.
Oh, caffe reggio.
That's fourth street and s.
- Macdougal and third.
- Yeah.
- Can I give you a lift?
Sure.
Jesus what's that?
Ah, you got your hands
on my money belt. Don't do that.
That's not a money belt.
That's a gun.
- Well, we gotta eat, don't we?
- Ha, ha.
What do you need a gun for?
I don't know.
Ever hear of barnum & Bailey?
- Yeah.
- Well, I'm their lion tamer.
- Come on.
- No, it's the truth.
I think you're full of shit.
You do?
What do you do?
Oh, me? I'm a...
I'm an actress, a singer...
- A dancer and a Buddhist.
- Oh, in that order?
I'm a cop. Would you believe that? Whoo!
No, I wouldn't believe it.
Serpico: I eslie I eslie.
Yeah
those leaps that guy made,
what do you call them again?
- Jetés.
- Jetés
yeah
you try it.
All right, how do you start it?
What's your position?
Next life come on.
What are you reading now, serpico?
My life by Isadora Duncan.
She was a ballet dancer.
A belly dancer?
No ballet dancer.
Ballet you know ballet?
- A little.
- A little bit, huh?
- Yoou ever see one”?
- Not close.
I've been to the ballet. It's terrific.
I've been taking classes. Yeah?
Yeah. That's where I go
after I leave here.
- Yeah?
- Fantastic for your body.
- It builds you up.
- I can tell
- you noticed, huh?
- I noticed.
There's five positions.
You know that?
Five... you're being short-changed.
Oh, no, it's enough, believe me.
For what? “Watch.
See? This is the first position.
From this position,
I can do anything.
You wanna see”? Sure
here we go.
Lieutenant steiger, I need a...
No. Later.
Hey, turn off the lights.
Oh, potts. I wanted to read.
Potts: Positions, positions.
Positions like that
you don't see in a pretzel factory.
Serpico: Now I gotta do my pee-pee
in the dark.
Oh, she's gotta be a nympho
with positions like that.
Hey, serpico, how can you piss
at a time like this?
Barto wants a specimen.
I'll look into this matter.
What do you got there? Here
potts: Straight ahead.
- Straight ahead where?
- Third window down.
I don't see anything over there.
Potts: I et me see.
Oh, she just pulled down her shade.
- Ah.
- You're some kind of jinx, you know that?
That's right, blame me.
Steiger: Hold it, serpico.
What were you two doing?
- What?
- In the shit house, in the dark.
Were you going down on him?
What are you talking about?
You gonna tell me
you were just doing a peeping Tom?
You were sucking his cock,
weren't you?
- What are you, crazy?
- I'll show you fucking crazy.
Last week I found a pair of shorts
with semen on them.
There.
You're actually accusing me of this?
Good morning, captain mcclain.
I'm officer serpico.
I was told I could talk to you, sir.
Certainly, son. Come in.
Lieutenant steiger
won't make a report.
He's too concerned with the image
of his department.
But it... it could affect
your future at the b.C.I.
Sir, I'll tell you, uh...
Frankly I don't see
any future there.
I mean, it's all bullshit
about it being a career path...
Toward being detective.
- I've been there two years now...
- And you want a transfer?
Yes, sir. But I don't wanna
go back to uniform.
I'll see what I can do, frank.
Francis.
You know about my weekend
retreats for catholic officers?
No
Well, you read that.
It might be of interest to you.
You are a catholic, aren't you?
Yeah. I was baptized.
(Good. Good.
Alfie, come on.
Paco. Oh, missed you, baby.
She's so crazy, that girl. I tell you.
Why "paco"?
Oh, all my friends call me paco.
Could you do me a favor?
Get my keys out of this pocket for me.
Sure.
Well, uh, what will I call you?
Frank or, uh, paco?
Paco.
Sally: Leslie
- Sally, hi. Larry. This is paco.
Larry: All right.
- Hey, man.
Leslie: Larry's a poet.
But he works
for an advertising agency.
And, uh, Sally's an actress,
but she works for a photographer.
Sally: Hello.
- Paco's a policeman.
- Oh, that's terrific.
- I work for the police department.
- Oh, hey. Wow, okay.
- That's really nice.
See you.
- How are you?
- Pat's 3 novelist.
But, uh, you're working for an insurance
company now?
- Yes, I am.
- Yeah. Paco's a policeman.
Really? How exciting.
Well, not too.
Right now, I'm filing fingerprints.
Listen, I file insurance policies.
We should get together, then.
File or something.
- Hey, that was an improvement.
- I wanna ask you something.
How come all your friends...
Are on their way to being
somebody else?
Think about that. I wanna ask you
something else too.
Will you do me a big favor?
Don't tell anybody I'm a cop.
You know, let me
just sort of do it myself.
Hey, man, are you really a cop?
Right. I am.
I eslie is a mind-fucker.
You gotta be kidding me.
I didn't know that.
What's a mind-fucker?
Well, that's a chick...
Who digs intellectual types
and super-bright guys.
Oh, yeah?
- Well, she's very perceptive.
- Ha, ha.
Pat: You know, Japanese culture
and theater and painting...
It's too rigidly stylized.
Well, you know...
Yeah, but...
I think after a while
when you get through that,
you start to appreciate the clarity.
You know, the authority.
I got a sheepdog. Yeah?
There have been sheepdogs
in my family...
Dating back for 16 generations.
Dating back to the borgias.
The family crest is a sheepdog...
- Pissing into a gondola.
- Ha. Oh, shit.
Paco, everybody loves you.
I love you.
Officer serpico reports.
That fucking thing on your lip, it goes.
And get a haircut.
- Uh, sir...
- That's an order.
You look like an asshole
with dentures.
Do I have the right of appeal, sir?
Sure.
Go see captain tolkin.
You've got one foot in shit already.
- Put the other one in.
- Where might that be? I wonder, sir.
That is one hell of a mustache.
I wish I had the guts.
Well, I have what I consider to be
good reasons for wearing it, sir.
You don't have to tell me.
- But I'd like to.
- I thought so.
I think it's time that we started, uh,
to communicate more on the street, sir.
You know, the way it is,
we're totally isolated, sir.
I mean, we're completely out of touch
with what's happening.
An undercover cop
walks around in disguise...
Wearing black shoes and white
socks. Everybody knows who he is.
You made your point.
I want you to keep your mustache.
And I'd like you to patrol
in your own car.
Wear whatever you want.
How does that strike you?
I'd like that, sir.
To be honest,
I'm bucking for detective.
No shit
- no.
- Ha, ha.
Serpico: Hold it.
Man:
What the hell are you doing?
Oh, Christ.
Hey!
I'm a police officer. Get over there.
Hey! It's me, serpico!
Hey, I'm a police officer.
Police officer.
I'm an officer. I'm a police officer.
Jesus, frank, how was I
supposed to recognize you?
- You stupid fuck.
- Frank, I didn't know you.
You didn't know me?
You fire without looking?
You fire without a warning?
Without a fucking brain in your head?
Oh, shit.
If I buy one, you motherfucker,
I'm not gonna buy it from you.
Holy shit, look at that mess.
Filling out forms till next month.
Good.
Hey, Jesus, frank...
I know it's a hell of a time
to ask you.
I'll have to go through
that ballistics bullshit.
You should.
“It'll look like hell
if I don't have anything
to show for it.
Frank, do me a favor.
Give us the collar?
You motherfucker.
You want the collar, huh?
You don't wanna
fill out forms, right?
(50 ahead.
- You're a buddy.
- Oh, I'm a buddy.
Only you tell tolkin I gave it to you.
I am passing out these marijuana
cigarettes for you to sample...
So that when you become
plainclothes men...
You'll be able to identify
the pungent aroma...
And recognize the disorienting
effect of the drug...
When you observe them
in narcotics suspects.
Among users of the drug...
A marijuana cigarette
is referred to as:
Reefer, stick, roach, joint.
The drug itself is referred to as:
- Pot, tea, boo, stuff, grass.
- Boo.
Hey, this is real good shit.
Serpico: I gotta have something to eat.
Blair: Oh, look what it is. Look what it is.
It's a potato factory, is what it is.
I have to have some because I love it.
I have to have some of that.
We have nothing to...?
- I have to have a dime?
- The dime goes in the little slot there.
That doesn't work.
It's from the civil war, this machine.
Pull on it.
Doesn't doesn't doesn't.
Go ahead. Go ahead.
Shoot it out.
Please, I beg of you.
Come out, potatoes, come out.
You're pretty fucking weird for a cop.
Me?
You. What about you, buddy? Me?
- You're a fucking hippie.
- It's beautiful, though.
The two of us.
Give me. Unh!
Where you supposed to go
from here?
Nine-three precinct, plainclothes.
Put your gun away.
You?
I'm scheduled to go
on special assignment...
With the mayor's department
of investigations, detective squad.
That's a gold shield. Yeah
no four years in plainclothes?
- Who do you know?
- It's my business to know people.
People who can help.
Unfair.
Life is unfair, man.
I mean, look, you've got
a feel for the streets, and I, uh...
- I got a feel for the politics, I guess.
- Oh, yeah?
You and me in one Batmobile,
we could clean up the city in no time.
I wonder if we can get candy
out of this machine, though.
No, thanks.
Well, this is a good place to tell you,
paco.
You know that guy in Texas
I was telling you about?
Yeah
- what about him?
- I'm gonna marry him in two months.
Unless you marry me.
What about the, uh, theater
and your dancing?
A girl has to get married sometime.
Well, you're a long way
from "sometime," Leslie.
I thought you were committed.
- I am, but...
- Mm-hm_
You are but 7?
I can go on working, studying there.
Where? Fort worth?
Amarillo
amarillo?
Well, am I invited to the wedding?
I'll ask Roy.
Yeah, it's pretty good
in this precinct.
Here you go.
Usually a 9-to-5 day is the best time
for policy and bookmaking.
But if you have to work nights,
like a liquor violation, just call in.
Don't worry about quotas right now.
A couple of hooker collars
will keep it cool.
Kirby: Serpico...
Been holding this for you.
It's from Jewish Max.
Serpico:
First day on the precinct, I get that.
This 1s great, frank.
I can open a whole
can of peas with this.
It's scary.
- I wanna protect myself.
- Okay.
You know what we do with this?
“What?
We take it to inspector kellogg.
Kellogg? Yeah
kellogg? Didn't he used to be
in plainclothes?
Second highest ranking cop in the
whole department of investigations.
So what?
I happened to be instrumental
in getting the man his job.
He owes me, you understand?
He's the most honest cop
I know, frank.
Frank.
Trust me.
Things like this were common practice
in the bad old days.
Hard to believe it's still going on.
Serpico, don't you think
it's kind of stupid...
Taking an envelope from somebody
you didn't know?
What was I supposed to do?
I mean, give me...
- How would I know what was in it?
Kellogg: You, uh...
You have two alternatives:
Force me to take you to
the commissioner of investigations.
- He'll drag you in front of a grand jury.
- I don't want that.
Oh, I can understand that.
Word will get out.
Before it's all over.
They'll find you facedown
in the east river.
What's the other alternative?
Forget it.
Well, what do I do with this?
Serpico: Hey, sarge?
Brown: Yeah?
(Got a minute?
Yeah
a colored cop gave me this.
I didn't know what to do with it
Well, I'll send it on
to the benevolent association.
Serpico: Alfie
Is that bjorling?
No it's di Stefano.
I was sure it was bjorling.
No
You can hear it better over here.
- That's an invitation, right”?
- Right.
With coffee.
I have to take a rain check.
I'm due at the hospital.
Why don't you call in sick?
Perfect place.
Not me.
You dedicated or something?
That's right, I'm dedicated.
- Most men can't stand it.
- Well, what do they know?
I like your garden.
Hey.
Love my garden.
Okay. I love your garden.
You know what they say, don't you?
No, what do they say?
If you love a man's garden,
you gotta love the man.
You like her, Alfie?
All I can tell you, sir,
is I gave it back.
I gotta get out of the 93.
Well, what happened
on your, uh, narcotics application?
It looked like it was set until I told them
I was in plainclothes, and that was it.
It was like the kiss of death. They think
everybody in clothes is on the take.
Sir, do you know anything
about the Bronx 7th division?
I mean, I can go there if I want.
But if it's the same shit, screw it.
I'd rather answer phones, uh, for Spanish
communications unit and go nuts.
Come on, Alfie.
Mcclain: Frank.
Did anyone ever tell you that you
have a tendency towards self-pity?
- No, you're the first.
- All right.
Frank, I have a friend up there.
Roy Palmer, an administrative officer.
I'll speak with him.
- Good. Thank you, sir.
- Bye, frank.
- God bless you.
- Right.
- Serpico: Yeah?
- Mcclain: Frank?
- Uh, captain mcclain here.
- Oh, captain mcclain.
- Could you hold on a minute, please?
Mcclain: Sure.
Yeah. Sorry. Mcclain: Frank
I, uh, saw inspector Palmer tonight.
And he assures me the 7th division
is as clean as a hound's tooth.
His words, frank.
"Clean as a hound's tooth"
- oh, yeah?
Mcclain: / told him he'd get a hard worker.
Wears a beard, speaks Spanish...
And would make a superb
undercover man. He was delighted.
That's good news, sir. Thank you.
- Thank you very much.
Mcclain: Goodbye, frank. God bless.
When did you start doing that?
Mcclain says that Palmer says...
That the 7th is
"as clean as a hound's tooth."
Well, if that's true,
your problems are over.
Serpico: Plainclothes division?
Upstairs.
Hey, frank. Serpico: Keough.
- How are you? Good to see you.
Serpico: All right.
We heard you were coming.
Hey, listen, say hello to Nate Smith,
frank serpico.
- Jamie morales, frank serpico.
- Serpico.
Hey, baby, you'll love it here.
It's beautiful.
I'll see youse later, right”?
Take 3 little ride with me.
- I gotta make a collar.
Serpico: I should check in first.
Keough: Fuck that come on.
Trollo: Ten on Dallas, if Minnesota.
Right.
Green bay, 12 and a half...
You dumb fuck.
We told you this location's hot.
- We told you to stay the fuck out.
- Keough...
Nobody told me. Honest.
Bullshit
- come on, let's take a walk.
Trollo: Hi, kid.
- All right, a c-note apiece.
- No way.
We got a complaint, right, frank?
Come on.
All right, make it 200, keough.
Hey, what are you, getting cheap
in your old age, bambino?
Three. Trollo: Three?
Keough: You heard me.
- All right, 3.
- I'll tell you what. I'll make it light.
Hey, frank. Serpico: Yeah
you wanna write this up?
Serpico: No, I'm gonna check in.
Take the collar. Get on the sheet.
I better check in.
Keough: Hey, frank.
We gotta have a little talk later,
right?
That dumb schmuck only came up
with 2 bills because I booked him.
Here you go, frank.
Serpico:
No, it was your collar. Keep it.
I had a hunch
you weren't gonna take it.
You know, Frankie, we got a call
about you from downtown.
Now, I ain't saying who.
They just said
you couldn't be trusted, you know.
- Because I don't take money, right?
- Hey, frank.
Face it. Who can trust a cop
who don't take money?
I mean, you are pretty weird,
you know, kid.
And with that call, the guys were
getting a little worried.
I told them you're okay,
I knew you from the old 21.
You'd never hurt another cop.
Right?
You'd never hurt another cop,
would you, frank?
- That'd depend on what he did.
- That's the wrong answer, Frankie.
Frankie.
We're not doing anything bad here.
Skimming a little gambling money.
It's clean. It's not dope.
It hurts nobody.
Frank.
A gambler is a gentleman.
They're gonna operate anyhow, right?
You don't have to explain yourself.
You do what you gotta do.
- Want some tea?
- No, I don't like that shit.
How about coffee, huh?
What's the matter, frank?
What are you worried about?
Listen, we don't go overboard here.
We're not sloppy, we're careful.
The spics, the niggers, we bust them.
They operate so dumb and sloppy.
They get your ass in hot water.
But the Italians,
now, that's a different story.
They're men of their word.
They're reliable, Frankie.
- Really got it analyzed, huh.
- You're fucking right I got it analyzed.
You know how much
the nut's running now, Frankie?
- No, I wouldn't know that.
- Eight hundred dollars a month.
That's 800 clams every time
your girlfriend gets the curse.
Tax free.
Now, here's the beauty.
You don't get it the first eight weeks.
Till the guys get to know you,
and you're okay.
But you don't lose either.
Because you get it on the other end
when you leave the division.
Frankie, it's like severance pay.
Think it over, all right? In or out.
Look at me. Shaking.
All my life I wanted to be a cop.
It's like I can remember nothing else.
I remember this one time.
There was, uh...
Something happened.
A domestic argument or something.
Somebody stabbed somebody.
And.
There was this crowd
around this tenement.
I must've been 9, 10 years old.
I was this big.
I went over to see what was going on.
I noticed a red light...
Going around and around.
All these people, and I couldn't see.
And I kept saying:
"You know what's going on?
Do you know?"
Nobody knew.
And it was, like,
the big mystery behind that...
That crowd there.
All of a sudden _.
The crowd just parted.
And there were these guys in blue.
And I said:
"They know."
What do they know?
It's amazing.
It's incredible.
But I feel like a criminal
because I don't take money.
You get so tense
when you talk about it.
- I wonder why.
- Come here.
Right there. Here?
Uh-huh.
- I'm gonna ask you a question, okay?
- Okay.
Do you like cops?
You're my first.
No, I mean,
all this shit I've been telling you.
- Do you believe it?
- Why not?
- Does it shock you?
- Not much
what's the matter with me?
Everybody knows about cops.
Did you ever hear
the story the wise king?
No. But I got the feeling
I'm gonna hear it.
Well, there was this king,
and he ruled over his kingdom.
- Yeah.
- Right in the middle of the kingdom...
There was a well.
That's where everybody drank.
- Mm-hm.
- One night...
This witch came along.
And she poisoned the well.
Ah
And the next day, everybody
drank from it except the king.
And they all went crazy.
They got together in the street
and they said:
"We gotta get rid of the king
because the king is mad."
Serpico: Uh-oh. - Ha, ha.
And then that night, he went down
and he drank from the well
and the next day
all the people rejoiced...
Because their king had regained
his reason.
You're trying to tell me something.
Me?
Yeah
keough: Frank, say hello to somebody.
Hey, grab your cocks and grab your socks.
- What the fuck is this?
Keough: Ha, ha.
Frank serpico.
Say hello to Don rubello.
He's gonna be your new partner.
Look, if you don't wanna work with
this fucking nut for some reason...
I'll buddy up with him, all right?
And go through all that crap
changing assignments? No, no.
We'll be okay. We're paisanos, eh”?
- What's with the fucking mouse?
- He's my partner.
- Partner?
Serpico: He's specially trained.
He goes to track down heroin.
Let him loose.
He goes into the hole, brings it back...
Sniffs it out, brings it to you.
Yeah, I heard of that.
- You heard of that?
Rubello: Yeah
this guy I'm looking for, Vernon.
He's a numbers collector
who ain't been meeting his obligations.
He won't be hard to spot.
He's a mover. This is prime time.
Since we're partners,
you gotta know the situation.
Straight off.
I collect for the division.
Me and two other bagmen.
That's what keough
was sort of hinting at.
Yeah, the three of us pick up
the payoff twice a month.
Hey. Look, there he is.
Son of a bitch!
Look out! Oh, my god!
Rubello: Where's the money?
You been jerking me around, you fuck. Huh?
Vernon:
I know I'm behind now, man.
Three times
you never show, right?
I'll have it for you tonight.
I swear. I'll have it for you tonight.
Don't bust me.
Rubello:
The last time, Vernon. The last time.
You fuck me and you're gone,
you hear? You hear, huh? Huh?
See you at the domino. Midnight.
And you better have $300, you fuck.
You hear? Right?
Right?
All right, frank.
Huh? Huh? Heh.
I keep this place for socializing.
Someday I'll get a couple
of broads, huh? Have a little party.
Make some ice.
Booze is right over here.
Look, Don.
If I was broke, if I had a family,
I don't know.
But I'm not broke,
and I don't have a family.
Why stick my neck out,
know what I mean?
It's already out, frank,
not taking the money.
Better the other guys
don't know that
hey, I tell you what I'll do.
I'll hold your share for you, huh?
You change your mind,
it'll be right in here.
Right in here.
Right down to the penny, huh?
I ook at that.
- What are you drinking?
- Give me a scotch.
Next thing I wanna do, get a color TV,
you know, for the games.
Heh. Hey, how about some gin,
penny a point?
Mcclain: Hello, frank. Get in.
My god, frank.
This is confidential.
He's a police officer.
- I thought maybe he could sit in.
- No, absolutely not.
All right, all right.
Frank, I notified commissioner Delaney
about everything you told me.
He wants you to stay
right where you are...
And continue to collect information.
Then you'll be his eyes and his ears.
He said he was delighted that, quote:
"A man of integrity had surfaced,”
unquote.
When do I hear from him?
Well, he said he'd reach out for you
when the time comes.
- "Reach out"?
- Mm-hm_
See, my situation's
pretty fucking sticky up there.
- What am I supposed to do? Wait?
- You must have Patience, frank.
- Yeah, but it's pretty fucking St...
- Patience and faith.
When a man like the commissioner
says he'll get in touch with you...
He'll get in touch with you.
Goodbye, son. God bless you.
Keough: All right, now.
Marinda's too hot. We gotta
lay off him for a couple of months.
And Falco's got two runners
he ain't paying for.
Check that fucking guy out, huh?
Hey, Frankie, how are you?
Listen, rubello's being transferred.
You'll have to work with a new bagman.
Al Sarno, I want you to meet frank
serpico. This will be your new man.
Sarno: Hi. Serpico: Hi
you know that operation down
by hunt's point, the new one?
What are we gonna do?
Who do we give it to?
Boy:
You the new bagman, you prick?
What happened to rubello,
you son of a bitch?
- You mother...
Sarno: Wait a minute.
You know, frank,
sometimes I ask myself:
"What the fuck am I doing?”
You know, if this ever came out...
Christ, my family...
My daughter.
She just started
with the San Francisco opera.
Chorus.
Took a lot of money.
I once tried to pull out.
Christ, they were all over me.
So you...
Just go along.
Unless you're willing
to go back to uniform duty.
Shit. How the money rolls in.
- Here. Let me give you yours now.
- No, I'm not on.
- What do you mean, you're not on?
- I'm not on, I don't take money.
- Some gag. Here.
- No, I told you straight.
I don't take money. That's the truth.
Your nut.
Where's it been going?
Ask rubello.
Serpico: All right, then, sir.
I'll go to Delaney myself, then.
That would not be advisable, frank.
You don't understand, captain.
You see, it's been weeks, not a word.
Mcclain:
I understand perfectly, frank.
- No, but... now they know I'm not on.
- I've done all I can do.
Goodbye, frank.
He's out
won't do another fucking thing.
Blair, I'm telling you, nothing's
gonna happen from the inside.
The top guys have been cops
too long.
- You haven't heard from Delaney?
- No, not a fucking word.
Are you willing to go
outside the department?
Where could we go?
Would you believe
the mayor's office?
- The mayor's office”?
- His right-hand man.
A guy named Jerry berman
from Princeton.
You knew I know somebody.
That's the somebody I know.
And he cares, frank.
He really cares.
You know what we're doing? Yeah
- we're going outside the department.
- That's right.
Dynamite. Every plainclothes man
in the division.
And one, maybe two, lieutenants?
Heh. That's... that is dynamite.
That is incredible.
That is 150...
That is $250,000 a year,
but that is just one precinct.
That is amazing.
See, what I feel is needed here is,
you know, like, a real investigation.
Berman: And I am sure that the mayor
will see this immediately.
Mcclain and Delaney,
they have done nothing?
Oh, man, that is amazing.
Another... another thing, see...
In a couple of days, they're
gonna have a meeting of the pad.
- Frank is in a very tough spot.
- I can see that.
Rumors. See, I have heard rumors.
But never touching it directly.
And for an on-the-line cop
to come forward like this is beautiful.
Really, frank, I mean,
you have my respect...
And my sympathy for what you've
been going through, man. Wow.
Hello, this is Jerry berman.
Is he there?
All right, I'll hold on.
Well?
Tell me what happened, paco.
I'd like a drink.
That guy's gonna go to the mayor.
- To the mayor.
- Ha, ha.
Come here, Alfie. We're all gonna go
to the mayor together, you know that?
I couldn't be any more embarrassed.
It's like a personal defeat.
However.
There are priorities.
What are the priorities, Jerry?
The priorities are a long,
hot summer ahead
and riots are expected.
And the mayor cannot
alienate the police force.
Now, in the fall...
Now, in the fall, it may be possible
to take another look at the situation.
All right, all right. I'm sorry.
Frank.
Serpico: All rotten
chickenshit.
The whole fucking system's corrupt.
- Who's there?
Blair: It's me, frank, I gotta talk to you.
You know, frank, you're behaving like
a goddamn child, do you hear?
Let him in.
You let him in.
Laurie: Hi. - Hello.
I'm sorry, frank, I'm sorry
I got you into the whole thing.
Bullshit. I got me
into this whole thing.
"Wow," "amazing,"
"dynamite," "beautiful."
"Dynamite." "priorities, priorities."
You and your big-deal friends.
Your contacts,
your big bullshit names.
Bob Blair, the big operator
from Princeton. Huh?
The mystery man with connections,
the line to the mayor.
Who do you think you are,
you son of a bitch?
You come looking for help, whining,
with your humble-pie act...
The Saint, the injured innocent.
Who told you the department or the
whole world was a boy scout camp?
What do you expect,
for chrissake? A magician?
A big daddy? White knight rides
in on a horse, snaps his fingers...
- You keep talking.
- The world turns white.
While the pope's choir sings
"ave Maria"? Is that it?
I tried to help you.
You're gonna blame me because those
bastards don't wanna get involved?
- I got my head handed to me.
- Where's your head?
On your shoulders, I see.
You don't look so hot.
What's all this shit over here?
Get ready to blow up again.
I got another idea.
You and your ideas
are as full of shit as you are.
Blair: Right on cue.
- Right on cue.
We could talk to foreman,
the commissioner of investigations.
Another guy.
We got another guy here.
We could even talk to a guy I know
on the the New York times.
Oh, that's terrific.
(So to the times.
Every time I talk to you, Blair, 20 more
people know about it, you know that?
Frank, it's safe. “It's safe?
- My ass on the line, it's safe?
- Your ass is already on the line.
That's my business, all right?
You don't trust me?
- I don't trust you.
- Go fuck yourself.
Fuck you.
Look, when I come home,
I want a house clean.
- Don't take it out on me, paco.
- I'm not. I don't wanna pick up shit.
Honey?
Come to bed.
- Hello, frank.
- Hey, frank.
All right, we all know
what this is about, right?
So without any bullshit,
frank, what was happening...
Between you and Don rubello?
Simple. I didn't take any money,
I don't take money.
Rubello said if I changed
my mind, he would hold my share.
Uh, he'd give it back to me.
- I didn't change my mind.
- Conniving bastard.
All right, look, I'll handle rubello.
I'll get back the money he took.
But this ain't gonna happen again.
From now on, no more three bagmen.
Starting today, every one of you fucks
makes his own collections.
- No stops, no bread. Okay?
- Okay.
- Right.
- You got it.
What about you, frank?
I'll make up what Don took from you.
Why should I start now?
Everybody would feel a lot better
about you.
You can always give it
to charity, frank.
Look, frank. What do you say,
100 a month just for expenses?
For my secretary and my
business lunches, entertainment?
All right, all right.
We split frank's share from now on.
You're a schmuck, frank.
If they would take all that energy, see,
and put it into straight police work...
We'd have the city cleaned in a week.
It'd be cleaned up, there'd be no crime.
If I could work alone,
that's the thing, see.
If I could just get... work alone.
They don't like that.
They don't want that.
- They wanna suck you in.
Laurie: You go over the same thing, paco.
They're so fucking corrupt.
Everybody, everyone.
Nobody giving a shit.
There's gotta be a way to wipe it out.
- Goddamn it, there's gotta be a way.
- Let's get out for a while, huh?
- Let's go to a movie.
- Quit handling me.
What are you doing? Go to a movie.
How am I gonna go?
You know they'd kill me
if they knew?
- You think that hasn't happened?
- Either you're exploding or catatonic.
- I can't stand it, paco.
- You don't give a shit, right?
All I care about is you.
That's all that matters to me.
That's why it hurts so much.
I can't stand to see you like this.
Scared, miserable,
dreading to go to work.
It's tearing me apart.
And then I get sick of hearing
about it, and I start hating myself.
You didn't like my being a cop,
so don't give me that. You never did.
I love you, paco.
I wanna marry you.
I wanna have children with you.
- Goddamn it! I hate it!
- If you hate it so much...
- Why don't you get out.
- Why don't you!
- It's crossed my mind.
- Well, do it.
What do you got?
- Would you bust whitey?
- Try me. Try me.
This guy's heavy.
He's Italian. Mobbed up.
- Still interested?
- Stop fucking around.
I'm not in the mood. Come on.
He's a loan shark.
Runs a big numbers operation.
This mother's so cocksure
he picks up his own slips
while he's collecting his loans.
Where's the drop?
Serpico: Hold it.
I'm a police officer.
Wait a minute.
You're under arrest.
- Hell, I thought you was some junkie.
- Yeah, I'll take that wad in your pocket.
- You're a riot, kid.
- I know, I'm a joke. What do you got?
What's that?
Put that away, or you're in more
trouble. Give me the keys to your car.
Where they been hiding you, kid?
Wouldn't you like to know?
Hold this guy for booking.
Get a rap sheet on him.
I'm gonna search his car.
Where's corsaro?
Man: Smith took him upstairs.
I swear to god I thought this guy
was some fucking junkie.
Keough: You know, listen, Rudy,
you should see some of the...
Hey, you.
Hey, who? You.
- Get over here and empty your pockets.
- I don't do that.
You're my prisoner, you do
what I tell you. Get over here.
- He's gonna get nasty about it.
- You're fucking right.
Keough: Frank, cool it, huh?
Don't play me, motherfucker.
Spread.
Frank. Hey, frank.
Rudy's on, he's good people.
Stay the fuck out of this!
What's this? What's this?
Man: Serpico.
(Got that record check on corsaro.
Wanna read something?
It's about your pal corsaro.
Here, read it. Read it.
He did 15 years. You know what for?
For killing a cop.
He's a fucking cop-killer.
Mcclain: Good to see you.
- I've had it. I'm finished
- what's wrong?
- I can't take it, I gotta get out.
If I have to go back to uniform,
I'm going back.
I can't wait for Delaney,
and I can't play their game.
- I'm right in the middle.
- The commissioner didn't get in touch?
No, he didn't get in touch with me.
No investigation, no undercover work.
I had no idea, frank.
Well, captain, I think it's only fair to
tell you I've been to outside agencies.
- I'm gonna go to more if I have to.
- What outside agencies?
Holy mother of god.
Frank, we wash
our own laundry around here.
- You could be charged for this.
- I thought so...
- But we do not wash our own laundry.
- You are in trouble, serpico.
I don't care. I don't care
who gets it, including myself.
- If I have to go to outside agencies...
- You stay away from outside agencies.
- Where am I gonna go?
- Stay away.
- Wait until you hear from me.
- Been waiting.
- I'll get back to you.
Serpico: That's not enough.
- I'll get back.
Serpico: Where am I gonna go?
It's my life, you fuck!
Strasser: Serpico.
See inspector Palmer.
Palmer: For this precinct,
cases reported of murder...
14 for August,
20 for September, 20 for...
Serpico.
Serpico: Inspector Palmer?
Deputy chief inspector daley
and inspector Gilbert...
Are waiting to see you.
You wanna come to my office.
Captain mcclain called me.
I briefed inspector daley and
inspector Gilbert on your allegations.
Now, the obvious question is this:
In all these months
why didn't you come to us?
Well
uh
I never met these gentlemen
before, sir.
Uh, you told...
I mean, you... you...
You told captain mcclain that the
division was clean as a hound's tooth
you think you're the only honest cop
on the force, serpico?
My record's clear.
Inspector Gilbert's come
from the commissioner's.
Confidential investigation unit.
Well, then you must
have heard something.
I don't understand.
Commissioner Delaney has known
about this from the beginning.
I didn't hear a thing.
But, uh, I understand your frustration,
frank, believe me. Heh.
I mean, it's, uh, sort of like trying to
punch your way out of a paper bag, right?
What outside agencies
have you been to, frank?
I don't see how that's pertinent
to my allegations.
I think we ought to ask serpico
directly if he's gonna cooperate or not.
- Come on, George.
- We've gotta know...
If there's any real basis
for an investigation.
Well, I... I'll have to think that...
I'll have to think about that.
Daley:
What is there to think about?
I don't see how the division
can investigate itself.
You got a point there.
But you would cooperate
with an impartial investigation, right?
Yeah. Up to a point.
As long as I'm not involved.
I just wanna go someplace
where I can do my job.
That's fair enough.
We'll be in touch.
Serpico: Inspector Palmer,
can I see you a minute?
Was it necessary to let everyone know
I was coming here to see these guys?
You believe that a full-scale
investigation is warranted?
Daley:
Yes, commissioner Delaney.
Goto it
but, sir...
Shouldn't headquarters
handle something like this?
No
You're all experienced men.
Chief Gallagher here will be
available for consultation.
Commissioner, uh...
Serpico claims that, uh...
Inspector mcclain talked to you
about this whole thing some time ago.
Yes
I seem to remember
something about that.
We can't set up a surveillance on
somewhere over by crotona park.
We need a location.
I've given you 36 locations
that are paying off.
Now, what do you want? The whole
thing signed, sealed, delivered?
You're conducting
this investigation, not me.
All right, frank. Lieutenant Smith.
Let's get back to him.
Lieutenant Smith.
I ieutenant Smith said to me
if I didn't want the money,
that he would stash it in his attic.
- I'll have him transferred.
- Fuck him. How about transferring me?
Burns: Serpico.
I hear you've been
vouchering pad money...
Over to a confidential
investigation squad.
Oh, yeah?
How can I voucher money
when I don't take any?
Smith:
You won't find anything on serpico.
He's clean.
Right?
- Hmm?
- You practicing your frisk?
No
I'm looking to buy
a used tape recorder.
Wear a wire?
They're feeling me up every day.
- How am I gonna wear a wire?
- Come on, frank.
Look, wearing a wire means testifying
to corroborate the tape, right? Right.
I'm not testifying.
I gotta put a dime
in the parking meter.
Daley: Franklin, put a dime in the
parking meter for serpico.
Hey, frank.
Frank, uh, you know Herman tauber,
district attorney?
Yeah, I watch television.
Frank, I wanna compliment you
for coming forward like this.
It's... it's unique.
It's uniquely unique.
You should be proud of yourself.
There's gonna be a grand jury
on these shit heels
with frank serpico
as my star witness.
Mr. tauber, you and everybody
in this room can go to hell...
Because I'm not testifying.
“Wait listen.
Wait, wait, wait. Just a second,
frank, you have nothing to fear.
- You're not gonna be singled out.
- I'm not afraid.
I don't give a fuck who knows...
If it meant something, but this
investigation is bullshit. It's bullshit.
You're not after corruption in the
department, the division, the Bronx.
A few flunky cops thrown to the wolves
to protect Delaney and those guys...
Who known about this shit and won't
do a thing. That's why I won't testify.
Hey, what's this?
Exactly what it says.
- I'm splitting.
- I never read anything so stupid.
"I'm leaving. If you wanna
discuss it, I'll be at Felix's."
I didn't feel like another
blood-and-guts scene.
I figured you wouldn't
be able to shout.
I can shout anywhere.
I won't shout.
Sit down, sit down.
It's just gonna go on and on, paco.
It isn't gonna get any better.
And if you quit,
somehow I'll be blamed.
How could you leave
the man you love?
The future father of your kids?
You never said anything like that
to me before.
And if I come back.
You won't say it again.
You wanna be free and unattached
10 go on fighting for your cause
and keep torturing yourself.
My "cause”...
Oh, paco.
I felt so safe with you...
So loving.
Stay with me, Laurie.
- Come on, stay with me.
- Oh, no.
What am I doing?
I owe you for that, huh”? Here.
Here's $2.
I aurie.
What are you doing?
Do you wanna walk away,
or should 1?
I'm not gonna walk away.
It's finished.
Who do you think you are, pulling
that "no testifying" bullshit on me?
Chief green, I know your reputation.
Look, maybe if you were borough
commander when this thing started...
Run this investigation yourself,
I'd feel different about testifying.
The truth is,
you're coming in after the fact.
Cut the crap.
You're like a quiff who says...
She won't, she will,
then she won't.
Yeah, I'm like a quiff who's been
fucked over for a year and a half...
By guys like kellogg,
mcclain, Delaney.
- I'm not kellogg, mcclain or Delaney.
- Frank, it won't be just flunky cops.
This is only the beginning.
This could be the biggest thing
since the Harry gross case.
And meanwhile where am I?
I'm out there alone.
Who gives a fuck about that?
I'm totally isolated in the department.
- I don't have a friend.
- Don't give me that.
I've been putting cops away
for 30 years.
My name's an obscenity on
every shit-house wall in every precinct.
Serpico:
I've observed that, sir.
"Friends." I fought my way up as a Jew
in the days you're supposed to have...
An uncircumcised shamrock
between your legs.
I have this nightmare: I'm on fifth ave.,
watching St. Patrick's day parade.
I have a coronary, and 9000 cops
march happily over my body. Friends.
I haven't got a friend in the force.
Serpico: I'll be your friend, chief.
- I'm not looking for any.
- I'll make an exception in your case.
Tauber: You're a good cop.
Stop being a prima Donna,
just cut out the shticklech.
I don't understand, you know.
How am I being a prima Donna?
- I wanna protect myself.
- Frank.
We're gonna get the indictments.
You're gonna have to testify.
Man: Ready on the right.
Ready on the left.
Ready on the firing line.
What are you gonna tell
the grand jury, Frankie?
Depends on what they ask me.
Suppose they ask you
who's taking money.
What I don't know, I don't know.
But you do know, frank.
Look, Frankie, I like you. I don't
wanna see anything happen to you.
But you gotta understand,
a lot of people could get hurt here.
Look, I'm not saying it's gonna happen.
I'm saying it could happen.
There's lots of ways.
Nobody has to take a shot at you.
They can just not be there
when you need them.
Somebody come at you with a gun,
they look the other way.
Or they can send you in first
enough times until one day...
You're gonna walk
in the wrong door.
- Thanks for the information.
- Fuck you, frank.
I have nothing more. Does anyone
have any further questions?
Crist: Uh, yes.
- Yes, Mrs. crist?
If I may, Mr. Knowles. Thank you.
Officer serpico came
to the 7th division
more than a year and a half ago.
All during that time, the things
he's told us were taking place. Now...
Why didn't officer serpico report
these criminal activities long before...
- When he first encountered them?
- I'd like to answer.
Mr. chairman, uh,
Mrs. crist's question...
I don't believe is, uh, material
or relevant to the present inquiry.
I'd like to answer that question, sir.
Officer serpico cannot be considered
derelict of his duty in any way...
Or guilty of any infraction
of the law. Quite the contrary.
The district attorney is not prepared
to say any more at this time.
Very well, Mr. tauber. Officer serpico,
thank you for your testimony.
This hearing is adjourned
until 10:00 tomorrow morning.
Serpico: Why didn't you tell them
about Delaney, kellogg?
Frank, this was a grand jury about
police officers engaged in corruption.
You don't implicate people
without sufficient evidence.
Now, that's crap, and you know it.
Even a dumb cop like me knows
a prosecutor can take a grand jury...
Anywhere it wants to take lit.
You never led me
anywhere near the real problems.
Nothing about the bosses,
the brass.
How corruption could exist
without anybody knowing.
Now a few flunky cops in the Bronx,
that's it. None of this shit in queens?
- Brooklyn? Manhattan?
- Why don't you mention Kansas City?
"The biggest thing since Harry gross."
That's what you said.
All right. Look, frank.
You've got guts, integrity.
There's gonna be a detective's
gold shield in this for you.
Now, that's terrific. That's good.
Maybe this is what it's about. I should
take my gold shield and forget it.
I know you've been through
an ordeal, frank.
I'm a marked man
in this department for what?
I've already arranged
a transfer for you.
To where? China”?
That takes a 14-shot clip.
You expecting an army?
No, just a division.
Tauber, did you know I've had reports
about serpico being a fag?
He used to hang out
in the b c.L washroom.
That's stupid, commissioner,
and you know it.
You know, Mr. commissioner,
a gold shield for serpico at this time...
- Would convince a lot of people.
- Not while I'm commissioner.
Commander's office?
It's down that corridor.
Hey, serpico. Do you know what
they're saying in the Bronx?
That you spilled
your guts to the grand jury.
Say it isn't so, serpico.
It isn't so.
We know how to handle
guys like you.
I ought to cut your tongue out.
Man 1: Jesus, serpico.
Man 2: What the hell are you...?
Don't move.
Officer serpico
reporting for duty, sir.
I'm inspector lombardo.
I wanna shake your hand, frank.
It's gonna be nice to have
a guy here I can trust.
Anybody in this command
you wanna work with?
Well, it's not who I wanna work with.
It's who wants to work with me.
All right. You can't find anybody
you wanna work with, frank...
I'll work with you.
That all right”?
Serpico:
How do we get past the lookouts?
How many you got? One.
There's two.
- There's the third one.
- There's three of them.
It's four buildings down. We can try
and get down the fire escape.
Get in from behind.
What'd you think?
- Good to you?
- Yeah, let's go.
- What do you think?
- Wanna try it?
Serpico: You all right?
Yeah. I feel just like
a cop again. Thank you.
Man: Close up.
Frank, come on. Come on.
Man 1: Cut it out.
Man 2: I ain't got none. I ain't...
Get in the other room.
Out of here. Get up against the wall.
What the hell's going on here?
Who the hell are you?
- Who are you?
- Police. Who do you think?
Serpico: Fuck against the wall.
Up. Up. Up.
Let's see your shield.
Wanna see a shield?
All right, there's my shield.
- Where you from?
- Borough, Manhattan, 8.
No, goddamn it.
You're not from the borough.
I paid the borough this morning.
Hey, frank.
Johnson:
The hell kind of shakedown is this?
Who'd you pay in the borough?
Nobody.
- I didn't pay nobody.
- Who'd you pay in the borough?
I didn't pay nobody.
Now let go of me.
Lombardo: We followed up...
And, uh, there's no doubt about it.
The pad
here in Manhattan is bigger...
And it's more sophisticated
than the one in the Bronx.
The pickups here are made...
You wanna get this,
the pickups are made by...
Retired policemen.
That way, no, uh, plainclothes men
are directly involved.
Now, we need investigative help
on this one, chief.
Well, inspector,
if you need investigative help...
And you don't trust
your own men...
Why don't you requisition some
recruits from the police academy?
With all due respect, sir.
Backing us up is the only hope
that the police department has got.
There are good cops
who'd come forward.
If there was any encouragement
todo so
and if they thought it would do
any good. If not, they won't do it.
I've done a whole lot more than
most people to defend and preserve...
The image of this department
and protect commissioner Delaney...
Against reckless and irresponsible
assaults from outside agencies.
That's it, huh?
I mean,
that's what's really important, isn't it?
That's what you wanna know.
What outside agencies
I've been to, right?
Blair: Hello. - Hello, prick.
- Who is this?
- Frank.
Frank, how are you? Where are you?
I'm ready to go to the times.
It's a goddamn serious step, frank.
I don't know if the timing is right.
Look, I want it to get
on the record, that's all.
In case something
should happen to me.
I want it on the record.
I don't know
if we carry enough weight.
I don't know if the times
will go out on a limb...
On the say-so of two flunky cops.
Suppose an inspector
were to come with us.
Lombardo: You know,
I got 20 years on the force.
Just bought this place.
I sighed a 500-year mortgage on it.
Will you turn that thing off
out there.
Okay, come on, everybody to bed.
Come on. Turn that damn thing down.
Lombardo: Yeah, come on, now.
Come on. Go on upstairs.
This is against department regulations.
You both know that.
If they wanna throw
the book at me, they can do it.
If I left the force
I don't know what I could do.
Okay, I made my little speech.
I'll back you up 100 percent.
Blair: Times and the news.
I got the money, fellas.
There you go, there you go,
there you go.
Newsweek, please.
Holy sh...
Blair: Oh, Christ.
You can almost predict
the numbers they're gonna do.
Delaney's gonna issue
some phony denial.
Somebody from the mayor's office
will say something noble.
Delaney will change his tune. Finally
the mayor will appoint a commission.
Serpico: "Thursday, mayor Lindsay announced
the formation of a special committee...
To review procedures
for investigating police corruption.”
Blair: How come I'm not
in the first paragraph?
Unbelievable
the times' report smells of the
familiar smear tactics of mccarthyism.
This government must
and will root out corruption...
With every means at our command.
The mayor has this day appointed
a special investigation commission...
To be headed by Whitman knapp.
Yeah, come.
Here's your reward, frank.
It's a transfer to narcotics,
Brooklyn south.
Still in clothes. You get a tin shield,
you don't get a gold one.
I miss you already, frank.
I ook...
Frank.
It's narcotics.
You be careful.
It's very easy to, uh, get hurt.
And to, uh...
To be set up.
Serpico.
Gget in.
You're not wired, are you?
Okay, you cocksucker.
You might get by in the Bronx
with that kind of shit
but down here,
800 a month is chicken feed.
Last week, one dope dealer sent out
these guys making pickups.
Forty thousand each.
We let them collect it all
and then hit them.
A hundred and twenty thousand
split four ways.
That's serious money.
And with that,
you don't fuck around.
I got the message.
Good. Now get the fuck out.
The guy's name is limbo.
He just uses this place...
His girlfriend's brother's place.
He's a pusher. Heroin.
We're gonna drive to the corner.
- Right.
- And you keep in sight out front.
When you spot somebody who's dirty,
take off your glasses and wipe them.
Right. Okay.
Serpico:
If we stay here very long...
We're gonna get spotted.
Heinemann: Well, frank...
Why don't you go up there
and check it out?
- Well, why don't you?
- I got the wrong clothes.
I'll take you shopping. Uh-huh.
Gerardo: Limbo.
(Serardo.
Heinemann: Police freeze.
- Police officer.
Man: All right.
- To the wall.
Heinemann: Against the wall.
Goddamn it, get up.
All right. Palms up on the wall
and spread them.
- Get them up. Spread them.
Man: Hands up. Come on.
Spread them. Man: Feet apart.
- I saw the buy.
Heinemann: Let's get limbo.
Man: Julio, you all right?
Julio: Yeah, yeah. I got them.
Serpico: Police officer.
What the fuck are you waiting for?
Heinemann: Police. Throw out your guns
and come out with your hands up.
Man: What do you got here?
- It's Mr. and Mrs. serpico, sir.
Man: Okay.
Woman: Yes?
- Where's our son?
- They're bringing him down from X-ray.
We want to see him.
“Just a few minutes.
Mr. and Mrs. serpico.
The news is better than we expected.
Thank god,
the bullet was a small caliber.
It didn't enter the brain.
Or strike the spinal cord.
He's on the critical list
but his condition
seems to be stable.
Thank you, doctor. Thank you.
Stay out of there.
Didn't they tell you?
What?
The word is, don't talk to him.
He's no fucking good.
- How you doing, kid?
Serpico: Hello, sid.
How are you?
Wanna read my fan mail?
Sure.
You're a big shot now, huh?
Sid.
I want you to get those fucking cops
away from my door.
The knapp commission likes you.
They want you to appear.
Well, naturally.
Frank,
heinemann and Julio are cleared.
The three of you are up
for exceptional merit awards.
That's very funny.
It's very funny.
Francesco, you love me?
I always had a thing for you, sid.
You know that
your gold shield's come through.
What's this for?
For being an honest cop”? Hmm?
Or for being stupid enough
to get shot in the face?
You tell them they can shove it.
I don't want it.
Oh, well.
Well, frank, the facts are these:
You'll have to stay on leave of absence
for a few months.
In all probability, the hearing
in your left ear won't come back.
Two bullet fragments
are still lodged in the bony portion.
One is very close
to the carotid artery...
And you'll have to be checked
from time to time.
Your left side
will feel stiff occasionally.
Once in a great while
you may experience some dizziness.
But in general you'll be okay.
Through my appearance
here today...
I hope that police officers
in the future
will not experience
the same frustration and anxiety...
That I was subjected to
for the past five years...
At the hands of my superiors...
Because of my attempt
to report corruption.
I was made to feel
that I had burdened them ..
With an unwanted task.
The problem is that the atmosphere
does not yet exist...
In which an honest police officer...
Can act without fear of ridicule
or reprisal from fellow officers.
Police corruption cannot exist...
Unless it is at least tolerated
at higher levels in the department.
Therefore, the most important result
that can come from these hearings...
Is a conviction by police officers
that the department will change.
In order to ensure this.
An independent, permanent
investigative body...
Dealing with police corruption,
like this commission, is essential.