( Buffy Saint-Marie sings Soldier Blue )
Tell you a story, and it's a true one
And I'll tell it like you'll understand
And I ain't gonna talk
like some history man
I look out and I see a land
Young and lovely,
hard and strong
For fifteen thousand years
we've danced her praises
Payed our thanks
and we've just begun
This, this is my country
Young and growin'
free and flowin', sea to sea
Yes, this is my country
Ripe and bearing
miracles in every pond and tree
I can stand upon a hill at dawn
Look all around me,
feel her surround me
Soldier Blue,
can't you see her life has just begun?
It's beating inside us,
telling us she's here to guide us
Ooh, Soldier Blue, Soldier Blue
Can't you see that there's
another way to love her?
Yes, this is my country
I sprang from her and
I'm learnin' how to count upon her
Tall trees and
the corn is high country
Yes, I love her and
I'm learnin' how to take care of her
Ooh, Soldier Blue, Soldier Blue
Can't you see that there's
another way to love her?
Soldier Blue... Soldier Blue...
Can't you see that there's
another way to love her?
Stupid frilly hat!
Honus...
Hey, Honus!
- Did you see 'em?
Did you see the
shape of them boobs?
Well? Well, where is she?
Where's the woman?
Ah... What the devil?
Who put here in there?
She's yours Captain,
you've got her
Bitch!
Detail...
Forward, ho!
Look at her, settin' in there...
Two years captive with them red bucks...
Don't it make you wonder though?
What?
How many of 'em got to her...
Don't it get you all worked up?
Wade... sometimes you
talk like a pervert...
Me?
It's not her fault the
Cheyenne grabbed her...
Well, I'm not sayin' it is, but...
by guff...
I'd sure like to get my hands
on some of that...
You can keep your hands to yourself
when we get to Fort Reunion...
- Why?
- He's waiting for her there...
- Who?
Her financée...
Spingarn!
We need flankers...
Sir?
You ought to put out some flankers.
Are you advising me Captain?
Me?
Huh?
I'm only the Pay Master...
You get no 'advice' from me soldier.
I'm telling you... put out some flankers.
(chortles) What're you afraid of Sir?
Road agents?
Cheyenne!
(chortles) Excuse me Cap'n,
but I ain't heard yet
about no Injuns comin'
after a Pay Master's detail.
- They got no use for that money chest.
- Flankers!
Yes Sir.
Get...
All right... I guess we're out far enough.
Why pick on us?
Why not?
Just getting up real close...
you can almost see her...
you could take your hand...
and you could put it right around...
one of her pretty little ankles.
You could Honus...
an' you're a snot nose...
You're a good friend...
the best friend I ever had...
but you're snot nosed and
you always will be...
Willie!
Take cover!
Spingarn...
you stupid son of a bitch...
Dismount!
Take cover and fire at will...
Oh, my God...
Lieutenant, the woman...
the woman!
Get up.
Stupid... cocking...
murdering bastards...
Imbeciles...
the American....
fire you...
now I advise you to try to control...
I told you...
Oh my God...
we're the last...
We can treat with them...
- What?
- White flag!
Talk to them...
we can make 'em listen!
Captain, those bloody butchers want
nothing more than our hides.
I'm gonna talk to them...
Captain... come back here!
- You Indians... No Kill...
No kill...
Aiii!
Iaiii!
Fire! ...Fire!
Woods are on fire...
Fire!
Won't take 'em long now...
Hey!
Hey, up here...
come on!
Come on!
Well, don't just stand there...
Get your ass up here!
Gee...
You it!
What?
You all that's coming?
- I don't know...
Well, follow me!
Wait!
Hey! Get down...
come on...
Well, there goes the wagon...
They'll be looking for us.
Nah.
Not for long.
Not him!
Not who?
Spotted Wolf!
In case you didn't know what hit you,
they're Cheyenne...
How can you tell
it's Spotted Wolf?
I saw him.
You know him by sight?
I know him.
What's your name?
Honus Gent.
Cresta Maribel Lee.
Are you wounded there?
- What? Are you wounded?
Oh? .. No...
that's not my blood
Good 'cause we've
got a long wait.
They are gonna be messin' with
those bodies down there for hours.
- Ah, what do you doing?
- I'm takin' off my pants.
Why?
'Cause it's hotter than
hell an' they're ichin'...
Oh...
Ahh... We'd better take it easy...
get comfortable...(sighs)
I sure as hell wish
I hadn't lost my hat.
Ah...
Miss?
Huh?
About Spotted Wolf?
How do you? ah...
I'm his wife...
Oh...
Hey, look here,...
come on....
Hey what're you doing there?
(sobs)
nothing...
Look, I don't want to
rush you soldier,
but it's going to be dark
in a couple of hours...
and we can't hang around here.
You're... you're robbing the dead...
My God...
You're robbing the dead!
Yep! Well I sure as
hell ain't getting much.
A little hard tack mostly,
but that'll keep...
us going for a while...
You find anything better?
My God...
- It was you...
- Me?
- He was looking for you!
- What the hell are you talking about?
Spotted Wolf...
He was out to bring you back.
- Bull shit!
- The Cheyennes would..
- What?
- You heard me. I've nothing to do with it.
- The Cheyennes would never
attack a Pay Master's detail...
Bull shit!
He was looking for you!
- Ah, he wouldn't trouble himself...
Don't flatter me, Soldier Blue...
I'm not worth any chest of gold.
They've got no use for gold.
Well, what the hell do you think
they were fighting with?
Rifles cost money, see...
and if you don't believe me...
then try and find the pay chest...
go ahead... find it!
Any more questions?
- I want to say something...
- Yea? well hang on to it, we're leaving...
For them!
Huh?
Something must be said for them.
(sighs)
You mean a kind of service, huh?
Ah, what the hell; go ahead.
Should be a prayer.
- Right! A prayer...
I bet you know a hundred prayers.
I should be here.
Huh?
I should be here,
lying with them, with my company.
Why? I mean, you've come out pretty good
it seems to me. See...
they're all lying here dead,
and you're still walking.
- Murdering savages...
- Yeh, you go right ahead.
You can howl at the
moon if you want to,
but it's not going to get
us back to Fort Reunion.
Now, you say your something,
or let's get the hell out of here.
Theirs not to make reply,
Theirs not to reason why,
Theirs but to do and die,
Into the valley of Death
Rode the six hundred,
Storm'd at with shot and shell,
Boldly they rode and well,
Into the jaws of...
of Death,
Into the mouth of Hell
Rode the six hundred.
Flash'd all their sabres bare,
Flash'd as they turn'd in air,
Charging an army, while
All the world wonder'd:
Theirs not to reason why,
Theirs but to do and die:
Into the valley of Death
Rode the six hundred.
Jesus.
(Cresta humming)
Throw them out.
What?
Your socks.
Why do you bother?
Here...
(gagging sounds)
What's the matter?
- It's mud!
- It's a little dirty...
- Where's the canteen?
- Oh, no...
You're not gonna' touch something that was
robbed from the dead, are you?
All right...
- We might be needing them later.
- That's using your head Soldier Blue.
Would you like some more mud?
Isn't it...
Can't you do something with that dress?
- Huh?
- Can't you... pull it together some way?
Couple of days, I'll lose a few pounds...
I won't be showin' through so much...
It never did fit me anyway...
one of hers...
Whose?
That woman at the Snake Flats agency...
Right off, she stripped me down naked....
stuck me in a tub, and gave me
this here dress.
Hey! Hey, did you see the hat?
Big bright yellow hat she gave me...
covered my whole face.
I did love that hat, though.
I'm sick at heart about losin' that...
- Sick at heart...
- You can say that now!
What's the matter?
What'd I say
21 men lying dead back there and you
sit here mourning a yellow hat.
- 21 men!
- A drop in the old bucket.
- A what?
- It's not the army, Soldier Blue...
They're not the ones getting killed off...
In this damn fool country...
Our country, Miss Lee,
is neither damned or foolish...
Balls!
Mrs. Lee, you have a most
profane way of speaking...
You should hear me in Cheyenne.
Do you want to?
(speaks in Cheyenne)
- No!
Good brave lads comin' out here
to kill themselves a real live injun...
puttin' up their forts in
a country they've got no claim to...
So what the hell do you expect the
indians to do? Sit back on their butts...
while the army take's
over their land
You saw for yourself what they
did, taking off scalps...
Yea, and who taught them that little trick?
The white man!
And cutting off hands
and cutting off feet and cutting off...
I know what they cut off, but at least they
don't make tobacco pouches out of them...
uhah... that's something else
you soldier boy's made up...
You're lying.
You ever seen an Indian camp
after the army's been there?
Huh? You ever see the women and what was
done to them before they where killed?
Ever see the little boys
and girls stuck on the long knifes?
Huh?
Stuck and dying?
Well, I have.
Fine.
Go to sleep.
You're lying.
(singing) My true love sleeps o'er the
hillside... Hey, ho, tiddle-um-dey...
(singing) Hey, ho, tiddle-um-dey... A few
more jumps and I'll be with him... Hey, ho...
I'll tell you about that hat... that hat
was just like the one my Daddy gave me...
on a Sunday morning a long time ago,
he knelt down and he kissed me...
then he put that hat on my head.
That's the last I ever saw of him.
- You mean he died?
- Hell no, he ran off and left me...
put me in an orphanage on Canal Street.
Eh... what the hell. Whoever asked to
get themselves born anyway... huh? Who?
- I'm going a sleep.
- You do that soldier...
and you try to keep your mind off me...
- Miss Lee, I certainly have at no...
- Oh, I know...
If you get too all-fired
horny during the night...
just, ah...
go soak your head in the stream over there.
(singing) My true love sleeps o'er the
hillside... Hey, ho, tiddle-um-dey...
Well...
That's it...
Over there...
What?
- The old Garvey wagon road.
Oh, what about it?
- We'll be sticking close to it.
Why?
Well it's a straight shoot
right into Fort Reunion...
Maybe, uh, four days at the most
There we are,
right out there in the open...
and there they come...
a-whooping it, out of nowhere.
They'll have us hanging feet high,
and let the crows pluck out our eyes.
You may not be aware, Miss Cresta Lee,
but I'm a professional
soldier, and I happen to
be well experienced in
this part of the country
How long have they kept you
private, Private...
No one's kept me, Miss Lee.
It was my father's wish...
You take that road,
Soldier Blue, and you'll
get your father coming
out here to bury you.
My father's dead.
He was killed at Little Big Horn,
last year... murdered by the Sioux...
I wonder if that General Custer
took your father's advice...
well, it's a sure thing
I ain't takin' yours...
Listen, you keep the rifle...
the jerky you can have,
just give me some of this hard tack...
There, there we are...
good luck, Soldier Blue, I'll tell
them at the Fort it wasn't my fault...
Hey, Private Gent!
Miss Lee!
- Well... get lost?
- Couldn't do it!
- Huh?
- Leaving you all alone...
I couldn't forgive myself...
if something happened to you.
Well... thank you!
Heh!
What could I say to your financée...
Oh!
You know about him, huh?
How could I face him?
How could I look him in the eye?
Yeh, I see.... A soldier's duty for
another soldier, and to hell with me.
A matter of principle, Miss Lee....
It's a matter of crap.
Have some berries...
Berries make me sick.
Well, Christ...
Naah!
(series of sighs and groans)
(coughing)
(sighs)
Look at that, another rip.
God dammit.
- Do you talk in front of him that way?
- Who?
Your fiancée?
Huh!
That's a funny thing, you know...
We don't talk.
I can't remember one
conversation we ever had...
He'd just grab hold...
and I'd hold off, and...
Thank goodness I held off long enough...
So he, uh, joined the army...
Boy, that did it....
six long months at Fort Reunion,
and no women...
I was sent for, to come out
and have a military wedding.
Here I am, still trying to get there.
You sure he's still waiting?
- He said so in the telegraph.
The way you put it, well...
Uh... A person gets the idea
you're marrying him for money.
Yeh, I am!
(gasping)
(groans)
(sighs)
Lose something?
My sock.
- Awww.
- It's gone!
- I'll tell you soldier...
It's gonna cut your washing in half.
- I'm going back a way...
- You're not! It won't take but a moment...
I promise I won't report you
for being out of uniform.
Jesus Christ...
(splashing sounds)
A hundred miles ahead of us, and
you're going back... back!
What the hell am I doing...
Twenty-one soldiers, and I get you!
Don't touch it. Don't you lay a
finger on that rifle! You hear me?
It's hidden there under the jacket...
You just let it stay like that...
- Cheyenne?
- Kiowa!
Oh! - And they want to kill
us, but not too quick...
Where'd they come from...
- From one lousy sock.
- Well, we've got to do something.
- You can watch...
What're you talking about?
They're going to rape me Soldier Blue...
and then they're gonna kill us afterwards.
Oh, my God!
(speaking in Cheyenne)
- Did I see you?
- I spit..
- Well, how could you?
- Ssshhh...
(speaking in Kiowa)
- What;s going on?
- I insulted them...
Oh no!
I told them they were five old women...
I said that they were afraid of you...
that you were tall and strong
and feared nothing...
You...
(speaking Kiowa)
Wait... don't pick it up...
take off your clothes...
Not me! Look at him, Soldier Blue.
He can move twice as fast as you can...
in those stupid army pants.
Take 'em off!
I can't fight my long johns...
Take them of too!
He can hold you with them.
Look, it's my life as well as yours...
You want to kill us both? Take them off!
- I can't!
- Take 'em off!
- No!
- You bastard!
Shut up!
(speaking Kiowa)
(laughing)
(groans)
Kill him!
You've won.
They expect you to kill him.
(speaking in Kiowa)
Hey Honus!
You did it!
Honus!
Hey, Honus... wait for me!
Honus...
Wait up!
Wha... what're you doing?
I'm freezing my ass off...
You... you can't sleep here.
Why not?
Well... I'm here...
Turn over and close your eyes,
we'll be warm in no time.
Honus what're you doing?
(sighs) I can't!
You can't what?
I can't do it.
What do you want to do, Honus?
Oh man...
Take it! You take it...
(gasps in excitement)
(goat bleating)
(panting)
I want the rifle Honus...
What for?
It's a goat..
What?
Honest to God, it is a real live goat...
Now don't argue with me...
give me the rifle
I want to see for myself...
Oh, no... Honus!
- Give me that rifle...
- Sshh, you'll scare him...
He can hear is and you're
gonna miss him by three hills...
- I'll get him...
- You'll miss him...
I'll get him...
(goat bleats)
He's gone...
(Honus sighs)
Look, you dumb gun soldier...
he's gone.
You stupid, beardless, tenderfoot!
I hope you choke on berries... Do you
hear me? I hope you throw up all night.
Owwww!
Miss Lee...
Cresta...
- Brain shot... dead on.
- Oh, oh Honus...
It's beautiful...
Oh, Honus...
(burps)
I've got to tell you the truth, Honus...
He was a tough old bastard...
- Please, I've asked you not to...
- All right, all right, I'm sorry.
- It's not that I'm a prude or anyth...
- Oh, I know you're not, Honus...
I've really gotta be more careful.
(burps)
Well, I guess it's time we turned in.
Honus...
it's stupid...
you over there,
and me over here...
Honus?
All right, I guess you're right.
Honus...
will you be all right...
I mean...
- I know what you mean...
- Will you?
I'll make it...
some how...
Listen, I'll try not to move much...
- That'll help.
- I will...
smells like rain...
Well, there isn't a cloud in the sky.
'Night, Honus.
Good night, Miss Lee.
Shut up!
It's a white man's fire...
How do you know?
It's different from a red man's fire...
Oh.
Gosh Almighty!
I hope you'll forgive the intrusion sir...
I'm Private Honus Gent,
of the Calorado 11th Cavalry...
Lord, declare...
and uh...
this young lady is Miss
Cresta Lee, from New York City...
- So 'tis, so 'tis...
- We're trying to get to Fort Reunion.
You see, uh... my troop was
wiped out by the Cheyenne...
- Devils... Devils...
- It was a Pay Master's escort...
and Miss Lee had joined us
to meet her Fiancée...
Good... hah... good for you...
yeh...
Where is your guns?
- Guns?
- Guns... you're the hunting type?
Oh no...
Uh, we lost our rifle in the flood...
Hey! That was a ripple, wasn't it?
Come near drownin' my two
beauties, there...
They been 16 years with Isaac Cumber.
Huh... Heh...
I'm pleased to meet you Mr. Cumber...
Isaac Q...
the Q part was my daddy's joke...
being as he calls me Cumber...
sayin' Q Cumber...
(both laugh)
but I kinda like it...
(laughs)...
Oh.
That's a... quite a wagon...
you... travel in style
Yeh, I do, ah, I surely do...
I got grub and tools and
blankets and, ah, bolts of calico...
- Just in case...
- In case of Indians, huh?
Take a look...
Take a look in these eyes, Soldier.
That's honesty you see there...
hard rock honesty!
I treats 'em fair,
and I treats 'em square...
and they don't fool none with Isaac Q!
What about hostiles?
Hostiles!
'Ya think I trade with hostiles?
Devils...
Hey, you look kinda' peek'd, Missy...
You don't talk much, huh?
Well, that's alright...
A man would rather look at a woman than...
talk to her, any day,
and you... uh...
I can see more of you right now...
than I seen of my wife in 27 years...
God rest her soul...
her frosty-faced soul.
- We could use some food, Mr. Cumber.
- Yea, you could, you surely could.
I'm ah... I'm partial to rabbit, myself.
That'd be fine.
If you don't mind,
I could use some of your calico.
Help yourself...
in back of the wagon
- Are we met?
- What?
- I get the feeling we met...
- No, I don't think so.
(chuckles)
In my rucksack, help
yourself, good lye soap...
you can, uh, scrub each other
off, or, uh...
whatever else you have a mind to...
(chortles)
Are you sure you haven't met him before?
- I'm sure!
- Think about it...
- Why?
- Because there's something wrong.
- What?
I don't know...
The man's a Devil, right?
- He's a pots trader, right?
- Yeh, is something wrong?
Pots traders don't go
out looking for gold...
- And especially not in Indian country...
- So he wants to get rich quick...
- Who doesn't?
- Well, uh, I still think...
Oh no! Please don't think!
Not now!
- We have got food and a nice warm fire...
- What if he... uh...
Wait a minute...
How do we know you didn't meet
through Spotted Wolf's camp?
- He doesn't trade with hostile Devils...
- That could be it...
- Trading with the Cheyenne....
- Bolts of cloth?
I mean guns...
Rifles...
Well, there's the wagon...
Go look for 'em...
Ah... eh!
- 'Ya like it?
- It's different.
Boy Honus, you sure know
how to flatter a girl...
'Must be a born gift...
They must be hidden somewhere else!
- You know the type tal...
- Here...
- What?
- Take a bath.
Listen to me... that old man is trading
off rifles for the pay cheques we had...
Honus, if I'm gonna look different,
you might as well smell different...
now take the soap...
maybe it's got a false bottom...
- I'm going to take a look...
- No!
Right now, before he get's back...
- Oh, get out of my way...
Honus, you've got no right...
(sounds of argument)
Get down!
Get off me!
Stop it!
(sighs, then sniffs and sighs again)
You've known it all along...
The rifles are inside...
and you have met him before...
Twice...
selling guns!
Yes.
- To the Cheyenne...
- Yes!
To kill American soldiers...
and you wouldn't stop him?
I couldn't then...
I wouldn't now!
What?
For your own people?
Most people I know
live in New York City...
- For your country then...
- Whose country then?
This isn't my country...
we're in Indian country.
OK...
Why?
Tell me, why did you
ever leave the Cheyenne?
All right... you really want know?
Because they tallk different...
they dress different...
and they eat different...
because I am not a Cheyenne,
Solider Blue, and I never will be...
but I can tell you right now
that I'd rather be one...
than any rump butt soldier...
of any blood thirsty
army you can name!
You're a traitor, Miss Lee.
Well... at least that's settled!
Cresta?
Got a good look, did you?
I thought you would.
Where is she?
Clunkered! Got her with my rifle butt...
over there, by the fire.
Don't worry soldier... She ain't
marked now and that won't show a bit.
(Cumber singing) I've got a heart full
of love For every star in the sky,
of love For every bird on the wing,
(Cumber singing) I've got a heart full
of love For every bird that can sing,
(Cumber singing) 'Tellin' you, I've got a heart
full of love That wants to get up and fly...
(chortles)
(singing continues)
(Cresta grunts)
(Cresta) Bite it...
(Honus) What?
(Cresta) Use your teeth...
(Honus groans)
(various groans)
(Cresta) Not there!
(Cresa) Honus?
(Cresta) What're you doing?
(various groans and sighs)
(Cresta) Oww!
(Honus) Sorry!
(Cresta) Never mind... keep at it!
(Honus) Are you all right?
(Cresta) Eww!
(Cresta) Eeww!
(loud bang)
Look at it, would ya!
Nature's wonderland. (chortles)
Out here I feel I'm close
to the great secret of life itself.
Honest to God, ah...
I get sort of choked up inside...
(chortles)
- Maggot!
- Eh... what?
I called you a Maggot!
A maggot?
(chortles)
Heh, heh!
Maggot!
Huh, the tiniest creature
in God's universe...
and which one of us is any better?
You? Me? Him?
I wouldn't count on it. There's only
one thing certain right now Missy...
pretty soon you're gonna be
back in the arms of your loved one, and...
you can bet ol' Spotted Wolf is gonna be
just a-itchin' to get his hands on you...
Are you planning to starve us for...
If I know Spotted Wolf, he's gonna want
somethin' real plump to get his hands on...
Hah, Hah, how about it Missy?
What about a juicy rump steak? Huh?
Heh, heh... ought to be a young pronghorn
around here somewheres...
heh, heh...
You got any sweet nothin's left, soldier,
you'd better say 'em now. (chortles)
- Quick! Come on, get at 'em!
- I can't!
Why not? - I haven't got any
spit left to chew with...
Chew dry!
Come on!
That's it!
It's coming, I can feel it!
A little harder...
Pull!
Good!
(grunts)
Come on Honus!
It's coming...
Pull!
A little...
I got it Honus!
(sighs)
- Give me your feet, soldier...
- What?
I'll cut your feet loose, but that's all...
Then we get right out of here.
What about the guns?
They stay where they are.
You're going to let him
bring those guns in now,
when you know what
they will be used for?
I'm giving the Cheyenne
something to keep them alive...
Nobody's going to murder them. They'll
be given land, a place to live in peace...
Bull shit!
Cut me loose!
Cut me loose.
Not your hands, just your feet.
He's got the only saddle...
we'll have to ride out bareback...
What the hell are you doing?
What do you want? A medal?
Come on!
Get up!
Get the horse!
- Ahh!
- Honus?
Honus!
Come on, get up here.
You can make it.
- Ride! Go on, get out of here...
- Get up here you son of a bitch...
Get up boy!
Get up!
Giah!
Look... ooh.
Oh, eh!
(sighs)
(loud sigh)
(groans)
(winces)
(loud sigh)
(groans)
Get up!
Honus we gotta to keep going.
(groaning)
Honus, he's following us.
Hang on, dammit...
Hang on!
Whoa, come back here, come on back...
Wait!
(grunting)
(singing to self)
(groaning)
Honus, shut up...
for God's sake...
Shut up, dammit! (groaning)
(crickets chirping)
How's your leg?
Still moves!
You're lucky...
That bullet went clean through.
- It's my, ah, head that hurts.
- Oh?
Here... I want you to eat some of these...
It'll make you feel better.
It's good... What is it?
Have some more....
I chewed up some roots
and packed them right
there, in your wound...
It kills the poison.
Big 'Injun medicine, you know...
Wouldn't think your
everyday savage would have
time for medicine, would you?
No, I guess not... Anyway, you're
lookin' um... pretty good now, Honus.
How about you?
Me?
Oh, ah...
Here, have some more of this.
Hah, you haven't told me what it is...
Hocheeka....
It's snake...
Snake?
You've got to cook it just right...
I bet you do...
(sighs)
(sighs again)
So...
You look....
better than I've ever seen you before...
you look all...
shiny and... and beautiful...
like an angel...
Cresta...
What the hell you doing?
God, what was in that snake...
No...
It's not the snake...
- You've got your fever back...
- No...
Hey! Look at me...
I'm a traitor, remember?
Uh huh... I know...
And for God's sake,
look at the way I swear all the time....
That's true...
Well...
- Well, how the hell... how can you tell...
- I'd rather not tell you anything...
Huh?
I'd rather hold you, Cresta Maribel Lee...
Damn...
Cresta...
Don't!
Please... to God, don't...
Not unless you mean it...
(sighs)
the whole shaboodle...
(humming)
(singing)
(humming with music)
Cresta!
(chuckles)
Come on! Honus!
I'm trying to be serious...
I am serious...
Naa... I've been thinking...
I should just go on...
What, alone?
I can travel a lot faster alone...
and then I'd come
back here for you...
with real food, and a horse, and...
clean socks...
We... are going back... together...
You and me... we're here Honus...
don't you see?
The two of us, right here...
That's all...
We can't be any place else...
When we go back,
it's not 'we' anymore...
(singing with music)
Excuse me... Sir,
I'm sorry to break in on you like this...
My name's Cresta Maribel Lee...
Cresta!
Johnny?
I could'ave swore...
Cresta, I can't...
I just can't believe it...
My God! I'm only asking
for two lousy troopers...
How hard is that then?
It's out of the question, Miss Lee...
I'm sorry, it can't be done.
- He'll last two weeks if he's lucky...
- Yes, well perhaps by that time...
I may be able to send some help.
Well, that's mighty big of you buster....
Cresta!
Give me a horse and supplies...
I'll go myself...
Miss Lee, this is wild country...
I'm sorry; I can't allow you
to go out there by yourself.
Well, how the hell do you think I got here?
Cresta!
(sighs)
Excuse me sir, but do you think I could
have a few moments alone with Miss Lee?
I think you should, McNair...
I suggest a long and sober talk...
Yes... well, thank you Sir.
If you'll excuse me...
Indeed!
You know, Mitchel...
Yes Sir?
When I see young people, today,
behaving like that, I just...
I can't help wondering what
this God-damned country is coming to?
When we get home we're
going to be married,
aren't we? What's so
terrible about wanting to...
get together with my bro...
Well, nothing, but, I mean, don't we...
even get to say hello first?
Oh, for Christ's sake!
You got no reason to swear...
- Swear?
Me swear?
You can send someone after Honus....
- We can't... Not for a while.
- Why not?
Cheyenne... and you, more than anyone...
ought to appreciate that.
You'll never find 'em...
Oh, we already have...
- We know exactly where they are.
- Where?
Oh just... just a little West of here... up
by the twin rock pass, the Jewels Pass...
- Are you sure of that?
- Of course.
We should be inside of their campground
by tomorrow...
(sighs)
You know... there's only
one thing wrong with me Johnny...
(sighs)... It's been so long...
so very long...
Oh yea!
- But now we're together...
Yes!
Well, it's... just that...
I haven't had anything
to eat in two days,
and I'm just so hungry...
- I don't know what I'm saying...
- Hungry?
If we could just have... a little something...
out on the tall grass, there. (chuckles)
(both laugh) Oh yea... of course...
I'll... I'll be right back.
(indistinct orders)
Excuse me Miss?
What are you doing?
Ah... Shit!
(gasps)
It's all right...
He's my fiancée...
By...
(gasps)
(sighs)
Uh!
Whoa boy...
(gasps)
Whoa...
(sounds of Indian camp)
(indistinct greetings in Cheyenne)
(happy greetings in Cheyenne)
(orders in Cheyenne)
- Cresta...
- Wantehemo...
Right, men...
put into your minds the dark
abominations...
of these Godless barbarians...
Murder...
Rape...
Torture...
And when you think of your comerades...
fallen, butchered comerades...
ask yourself...
Are we going to give them the same mercy?
You just be we are...
Major Phillips...
Take over.
Advance!
McNair?
Move out!
(indistinct orders)
Any word about your... uh...
Financée?
No sir.
I'm afraid she's...
well, I think she's hopelessly
infatuated with Private Gent...
Ah, that's too bad...
I'm going to ride in the wagon...
my back is killing me again...
(singing) Yes, we'll rally round the
flag boys, we'll rally once again...
(singing) Shouting the
battle cry of freedom...
(singing) We will rally from the hills, and
we'll gather from the plains...
(singing) Shouting the
battle cry of freedom.
(singing) The Union forever, hurrah boys, hurrah,
Down with the traitor, up with the scythe,
(singing) Yes, we'll rally round the flag,
we'll rally once again,
(singing) Shouting the battle cry of
freedom. We will rally from the hills...
(singing) and we'll gather from the plains,
shouting the battle cry of freedom.
- Well?
- It could be the two rear flankers, Sir...
- Except that there's three of them.
- Let me have those...
We found this man riding
through Lever's Pass, Sir.
It's not a cavalry mount...
No Sir.
If I may, Sir...
I'm attached to the
Colorado 11th Volunteers...
We're the Colorado
11th Volunteers...
Yes Sir!
I'm Private Honus Gent, reporting...
You?
(speaking Cheyenne)
Cannons...
Many soldiers and guns...
You must leave...
We want no war...
Your people gave me...
a flag...
and a medal of friendship...
I do not trust them...
they will kill our people...
we will fight...
I say peace...
you do not wear your necklace...
my gift of love...
you gave it to someone...
Yes...
and I must go to him.
My heart torn by all this...
(Cheyenne) Behavo...
If you'd let me talk to her
for just a few minutes she
might convince Spotted Wolf
to give up without a fight...
Without a fight?
We destroyed the rifles they were
counting on, so they can't possibly win.
- There's just no sense to it...
- Private Gent!
I don't know what sort of relationship
you and this woman have had....
but I can assure you that
my men are prepared to move...
against the enemy at daybreak.
- And move they will...
- Sir!
Twenty-one of your own comerades
murdered... cut to pieces...
- I know, Sir...
- The price will be paid, soldier.
- Is it worth it?
- Dismissed!
Yes Sir.
Prepare to fire...
There just seems to be
normal activity over there, Sir...
The cannon will commence
firing at seven thirty...
six rounds apiece until
we find the range....
(voices speaking Cheyenne)
and I know, McNair...
I know she's in there someplace...
no matter what we might think of her
she's still a white woman...
that can't be helped.
No, Sir...
Can I depend on you?
I will do my duty Sir....
Good...
All right, Lieutenant...
Give the order...
- They're coming out Sir!
- What? What's that?
- I think it's Spotted Wolf!
- My God Sir, he's got a flag of truce...
- Yes Sir, it's a white flag...
- Nonsense!
- Will you see for yourself...
- I told you Lieutenant... Give the order!
Sir?
Well, give the order!
Yes Sir.
Open Fire!
Ready...
Cover ears...
Fire!
(calls out in Cheyenne)
All pieces, increase elevation
one degree...
Fire when ready...
(screaming in Cheyenne)
(indistinct commands
and screams in Cheyenne)
They've the range now...
Stop!
Gent!
Stay away from that cannon!
No!
Arrest him!
Stop!
Arrest that man!
No!
No... There's a white woman in that...
Colonel look....
They're attacking...
Bugeler, sound Alert....
(indistinct yells)
Soldiers!
After those bastards!
Main troops... form covering party...
brace for incoming...
company ride, Forward!
(commands in Cheyenne)
Form three ranks...
Charge!
(sounds of the melee)
line up the front...
(words in Cheyenne)
(explosions)
Troops...
Rally to your Guidons....
McNair, form these troops in
two columns on the left and right...
advance at full gallop...
attacking the village on both flanks...
You take the left, I'll take the right.
Artillery pieces, cease firing.
We'll attack...
right of the village...
Troops, at the front...
March!
Troops, by the front, March...
Halt!
(challenges in Cheyenne)
Charge!
Are you OK, Colonel?
I'm all right,
McNair... Raze the village!
Burn this...
pestilence!
(shouts in Cheyenne)
Keewa!
Cresta!
Hold his legs...
Please, please... please
Please...
please...
Yah hoo!
Get that white woman out of there...
I'll put one poor devil
out of its misery....
Damn you!
What are you doing?
Why? Why? Why?
- Shut up, Honus!
He's gone mad...
Cresta...
Got a prayer, Soldier Blue?
A nice poem?
Say something pretty...
(grunting, groaning and choking)
And to each of you...
To officer and soldier alike,
I offer my most profound... admiration,
my deepest affection,
and my overwhelming gratitude...
for a job well done.
You men here today...
have succeeded... at
making another part of America...
a decent place...
for people to live.
We have given the Injun...
a lesson he will not soon forget.
But more than that...
for the rest of your lives...
You men will hold your heads proud...
when this day is mentioned...
and you will say...
Yes! I was with Iverson!
The Eleventh Colorado Volunteers...
Move out!
Cresta...
On November 29th, 1864,
a unit of Colorado cavalry,
numbering over 700 men,
attacked a peaceful Cheyenne village
at Sand Creek, Colorado.
The Indians raised the American Flag
and a white flag of surrender.
Nevertheless the cavalry attacked...
massacring 500 Indians,
more than half of whom
were women and children.
Over one hundred scalps were taken...
bodies dismembered...
plus numerous reports of rape.
General Nelson A. Miles,
Army Chief of Staff...
termed the massacre...
perhaps the foulest and
most unjust crime...
in the annals of America.
