(Crowd shouting outside)
(Angry muttering outside)
- They're going mad, sir. lt's the students.
MAN: Down with tyrants!
All right. Let them in.
(Cheering)
(Chatter and laughter)
- Swine!
- Beasts!
- lnto the valley of death...
- lnto the jaws of hell...
..rode the 600!
Hey, hey. Ease up.
You're sitting on my cloak.
- Filling up down below?
- Not a sausage.
- Ah. Here you are, Terry.
- Thank you.
(Orchestra tunes up)
l can't see him anywhere.
- Programs.
- Oh. Two, please.
One here. Thanks, pal.
Quite a turnout down below.
Old Palmer's music had better be good.
Boronskaja would hardly be dancing
the leading role if it wasn't.
- Boro who?
- Who exactly is Boronskaja?
Since you've queued for six hours, waiting to see
her dance, l should have thought...
Not to see anybody. To hear.
TERRY: Have you ever heard of
Professor Palmer?
BOTH: Never.
- You will.
The program says,
"Heart Of Fire...music by Andrew Palmer."
- Our professor at the academy.
- Boro-what's-her-name had better be good.
She's hardly likely to be anything else.
- There he is. Palmer!
- (Students call to him)
Lermontov! Lermontov!
(Bows tapping)
(Applause)
(Whistling)
Livy! Come on, Livy!
We know him.
♪ Heart Of Fire (Overture)
Do you remember my Cytherean Rhapsody?
- Forget it.
- That's it. Your rhapsody.
- lt must be an accident.
- Did you show him?
- l show him all my work.
- You think he lifted it?
Shh!
(Mouths)
She's a great patron of the arts.
Vicky.
Lermontov's coming.
- l say! That's yours, too, isn't it?
- Yes.
(Applause)
- Steady on, old boy.
- Shh!
Well, what are you waiting for?
- Be quiet.
- Please, do you mind?
- (Audience groans)
Oh, really!
Dear Professor Palmer, we're very proud of you.
l hope you're proud of yourself.
You're too kind. Monsieur Lermontov.
- We meet the great man at last.
- Enchanté, madame.
l never imagined l'd succeed
in getting you here.
l think l must be a very clever woman.
lf some fat harridan is going to sing, l must go.
- l can't bear amateurs.
- Neither can Lady Neston.
- What do you mean?
- She has a niece who dances.
Professionally.
Hello, Professor.
Now, please don't get up, Mr Lermontov.
Now, are you prepared for a surprise?
Do you mean a surprise or a shock?
Well, to take the plunge,
l've asked my niece to dance for us tonight.
- What would you call that?
- A shock.
Oh, well, you're certainly very candid.
You know, Mr Lermontov,
l wouldn't dream of boring you
with the performance of an amateur.
My niece has been dancing
leading roles for some time now.
The critics think very highly of her work.
How would you define ballet, Lady Neston?
Well...one might call it
the poetry of motion, perhaps, or...
One might. But for me, it is a great deal more.
For me, it is a religion.
And one doesn't really care
to see one's religion practised
in an atmosphere such as this.
l hope you understand.
Attractive brute.
(Gentle piano)
- Mmm...l'll have a champagne cocktail, please.
- Yes, sir.
- Champagne cocktail, please.
- Yes, madam.
Do you know, at parties
everybody is supposed to be very happy?
But perhaps you dislike them as much as l do.
Still, l think it might have been worse.
- Do you?
- lt very nearly was a great deal worse.
- Oh?
- Thank you.
We were to be treated
to a little dancing exhibition.
But now we're to be spared that horror.
Mr Lermontov, l am that horror.
Mmm...
lt's a bit late for apologies, isn't it?
Yes, a little late, l think.
l'm sorry. l'm terribly sorry.
But you're not sorry l didn't dance, are you?
- May l ask why?
- Because, my dear Miss...
Victoria Page.
My dear Miss Page,
if l accept an invitation to a party,
l do not expect to find myself at an audition.
Yes. You're quite right.
Why do you want to dance?
Why do you want to live?
Well, l don't know exactly why, but, uh...l must.
That's my answer, too.
Come with me.
- Where to?
- We are going to talk.
- But l don't want to talk to you.
- Don't worry. l'll do the talking.
(Buzzer)
MAN: Can l see Mr Lermontov now, please?
What is it, Dimitri?
A young man called Craster.
He has been here a hundred times.
l have told him you are asleep
but he will not believe me.
Either you are a bad liar
or he's a young man of good sense.
Show him in and serve breakfast.
Mr Craster.
What can l do for you, Mr Craster?
l'm sorry to bother you, Mr Lermontov,
but it's a matter of very great importance to me.
Yes?
Last night l wrote you a letter, a silly letter.
l'd like to have it back before you read it, please.
l see.
That's the one.
Unfortunately, Mr Craster,
l have already read this letter.
Oh.
- Mr Lermontov, please.
- You are Professor Palmer's pupil?
You say you've written a string quartet
and a piano concerto.
Yes.
Very interesting.
Would you care to play me something?
Something of your own, l mean.
Of course, if...if you wish it.
This is a study l wrote for the piano.
But l'm thinking of orchestrating it
and putting it into an opera l'm working on.
But are you finished already?
lt was very interesting.
Hope l haven't ruined your breakfast.
By the way...
l need a new coach for the orchestra.
Would the idea interest you?
Would it...interest?
l shouldn't be able to pay much money.
Eight pounds a week and expenses.
lt would be absolutely marvellous.
Right. Then get some breakfast
and come over to Covent Garden.
Thank you.
And your letter, Mr Craster.
lf you take my advice...
..you'll destroy it immediately
and forget all about it.
The Heart Of Fire is your work, isn't it?
- These things mostly happen unintentionally.
- l know. That's why...
That's why it is worth remembering
that it is much more disheartening
to have to steal
than to be stolen from, hmm?
Good morning.
(Man singing in distance)
♪ Cherries so red
♪ Strawberries ripe
♪ At home, of course, they'll be storming
♪ Never mind the abuse
♪ You have the excuse
♪ You went to Covent Garden in the morning
What a corker.
Course l tried to get her.
Tried to get her twice. Ta-ta.
- Here you are, son.
- Thank you.
Oi, you'll pardon me.
This is the way to the stage, isn't it?
- Name?
- Julian Craster.
- What name?
Not on the list.
- Lunch, lrina?
- Yes.
But l have an appointment...
l'm sorry, but l've got my job to look after.
- Good morning, George.
- Oh, bonjour, madame.
How is Madame George?
Oh, she's la très jalouse.
Very jalouse.
lt's that bit of a photograph
we had took together. Compris?
Oh, here you are. They've been looking
all over London for you this morning.
- Oh, flûte!
- That's what l said.
- How much longer must l wait?
- l'll send for the SM.
What is your name?
Julian Craster.
l have an appointment with Mr Lermontov.
Julian Kwis...Kweiss...
- Craster.
- Kwaster.
Well, George, if this young man
is invited by Mr Lermontov,
you can pass him, yes?
Ca va by me, madame. Ca va by me.
Follow me, young man.
- Est-ce que vous...?
- Comment?
- Are you a dancer?
- Yes...at night.
- Not very much in the morning.
- l don't know much about ballet.
- You are artiste?
- Yes. l'm a composer.
Ah! And you wish to see who?
Well, l'm afraid l'm not quite sure.
They are all there. Make your choice.
- Excuse me. Who's in charge?
- There's five or six of them that thinks they are.
- Can you tell me who's in charge?
- Don't ask me. l'm just somebody's mother.
That doesn't mean much around here,
l can tell you.
- Can you tell me who's in charge?
- ln charge of what?
- Mr Lermontov asked me to come.
- Why?
- He's engaged me.
- Not as a dancer, l hope.
No.
Allons, mes enfants! Au boulot!
And...
Well, Mr Ratov, Mr Ljubov wants it moved.
lt is on the plan, and there it stays.
Well, if you say so.
- Merci.
- Morning, madame.
Ah, here comes the great Boronskaja at last.
And today she's only 43 minutes late.
Am l supposed to congratulate myself on that?
l tell you, lrina, my patience is at an end.
l shall go to Lermontov and explain to him
how no theatre is big enough
to hold both you and me!
- l might as well start packing.
- Oh, there is no hurry.
He might choose to dispense with my services.
He is quite crazy enough.
But if we go, we go together,
Grischa, darling. Promise?
Coo, Buschka.
- Who are you?
- Victoria Page.
l expect Mr Lermontov
has spoken to you about me.
- He's invited me here...
- No, this is too much.
He invites them, l teach them.
l get rid of them, he forgets them.
And now, unhappy girl,
please go to the far corner of the stage,
where you'll meet five other young ladies
to whom Mr Lermontov
has also extended his hospitality.
Quiet, please!
l want to rehearse the first act of Heart Of Fire.
Will everybody not concerned
leave the stage, please?
Righto, boys, set act one. Hurry.
ls that so? Well, l agree.
Where are you going, my dear?
l'm going to talk to Mr Lermontov.
Wouldn't it be better to wait
until after the rehearsal?
Oh, no. You see, l know him personally.
Ah, well, that makes all the difference. Of course.
- Ratov...
- Yes, Boris?
Stay where you are. l'll come up.
(Orchestra tunes up)
- Good morning, Mr Lermontov.
- Good morning, Ratov.
We must do something about this foreground,
please.
The girls last night had hardly room to move.
Ljubov was right.
- Aha! Ljubov...
- Ljubov is always right.
- Do you really think so?
- Yes.
Well, well, well. Then take it away.
Take it away.
Well, you see, my dear,
Mr Lermontov is a very busy man.
Now, why don't you go and wait
over there with the others?
- lvan! Are you ready?
- Yes.
Yes, l will.
- Sergei Sergeyevich.
- Yes?
Are you acquainted with the works or person
of Julian Craster,
composer and conductor?
- No.
- Nor l.
Which proves how sadly
we lag behind the times,
for here he is in our midst.
Lermontov has engaged him this morning.
Rond de jambe...E.
Class dismissed.
(Wind instruments playing)
(Julian sings notes rhythmically)
(Julian sings tune)
No, gentlemen. Figure 29, sing.
- l think that will do.
Thank you, gentlemen.
The brass could do with your attention, Craster.
Tomorrow.
(Orchestra tunes up)
Gentlemen, l'm very sorry
to bring you here so early in the morning.
But l've been in front
for this particular ballet more than once
and l really must...
There are one or two things
l really must put right.
So, um, Heart Of Fire. Overture, please.
From the beginning.
Oh, by the way, trumpets...
at two bars before figure two,
have you got an E natural?
No. l've got an E flat.
Ah. Makes all the difference.
Should be E natural.
Right. From the beginning.
l know it's hard to get your lips set this early,
but we ought to be able to come in together.
Even more pianissimo. Less strings.
A oboe.
(All tune up)
From the beginning, please.
- That's nice.
- Mr Craster!
Precisely what is going on?
Have you taken leave of your senses?
Do you realise that by calling the orchestra early
we shall have to pay them?
And why are you rehearsing Heart Of Fire?
Did l ever ask you to do that?
Tell me. l'm interested.
l'm sure Mr Lermontov will be interested, too.
- Well?
- l like it.
You like it? l've no doubt you also like
the National Anthem and the Marseillaise.
l hope you won't summon
the full orchestra at dawn
to practise those noble melodies?
(Laughter)
l leave this young man to you, Lermontov.
After all, he is your discovery, not mine.
Mr Craster, l must ask you to exercise in future
a little more control over your natural ambitions.
And why you've chosen Heart Of Fire
for this early-morning escapade...
Good morning, gentlemen...
..is a mystery that l shall never hope to solve.
May l see that wrong note in the score, please?
Hmm. However,
there are passages in Heart Of Fire
which no-one need be ashamed of.
Thank you, Mr Lermontov.
- Good morning, Miss Page.
- Good morning, Edmund.
- ls Lord Oldham with you?
- Yes, miss.
Be careful, miss.
- Good morning, Peter.
- Hello, Vicky.
- What are you doing here?
- What are you?
l'm having lunch with Boris Lermontov,
the fellow who runs the ballet.
- Oh. Business or pleasure?
- A bit of both.
Are you shopping or slumming?
Don't worry, Grischa.
l'll bring her back at three o'clock.
- How are you, madame?
- How are you?
Hello, Peter.
l hope we haven't kept you waiting.
No, not at all.
- Boris, meet my friend Vicky Page.
- How do you do?
Can we give you a lift anywhere?
- No, thank you, Peter.
- Excuse me, Miss Page.
Who? Victoria Page?
Erm...yes, she may dance.
♪ Swan Lake
(Music starts)
(Needle screeches)
Good morning, my dear young ladies.
l hope l find you all very well this morning.
There are just one or two things
l would like to say.
As you know, the ballet's
leaving on Saturday for Paris.
l can't imagine anything more enchanting
than being able to invite all of you,
but l'm afraid this great pleasure
must be denied me.
To those whom we must regretfully leave behind,
l'd like to say just this -
please don't be discouraged.
The fact that we can't take you
doesn't mean that you're bad dancers.
It just means that this year
we haven't got enough room.
Please step out, Miss Faye, Miss Banes,
Miss Hardiman and Miss Laughlin.
Yes.
May l thank you four ladies
for the hard work you've done this year?
- l'm sure Mr Ljubov echoes my gratitude.
- Mmm...
Maybe next year we shall meet you again.
Good morning.
Vicky, he means us!
(Train whistle)
(Train thundering overtracks)
(Horns toot)
Si tu avais vu la Boronskaja! Un ange!
Des entrechats comme ça.
Elle touchait pas la terre.
- Sans blague!
- Ouais!
(Piano accompaniment)
Listen... Mes amis...
l am fiancée. l get married!
(Gasping and muttering)
- My dear child!
All my love and best wishes
for your happiness.
lrina, l wish you the greatest happiness
with your new partner.
- Merci. Grischa? Where is Grischa?
- l'm here, lrina!
Darling, do you hate me?
l could never hate you, lrina,
but how can l ever forgive you?
You will forgive me, that l know.
Don't quarrel with your husband
as much as with your conductor.
Where is Boris Lermontov?
He has nothing to say to me?
Boris!
He has...no heart, that man.
(Knock at door)
Entrez!
- Mr Craster, l have a job for you.
- Good!
Do l understand you have not been
altogether very happy with us so far?
- Well, l...
- Well, what?
Coaching an orchestra is not exactly
a young composer's dream, is it?
l'm afraid the job l have for you
may not be a young composer's dream, either.
All the same, l hope you do not consider it
entirely unworthy of your talent.
The ballet of The Red Shoes
is from a fairy tale by Hans Andersen...
(Orchestral music swelling)
..pair of red...shoes.
Oh, l beg your pardon?
The ballet of The Red Shoes
is from a fairy tale by Hans Andersen.
lt is the story of a girl
who is devoured by an ambition
to attend a dance in a pair of red shoes.
She gets the shoes, goes to the dance
and at first all goes well and she's very happy.
At the end of the evening,
she gets tired and wants to go home.
But the red shoes...
..are not tired.
ln fact, the red shoes are never tired.
They dance her out into the streets,
over the mountains and valleys,
through fields and forests,
through night and day.
Time rushes by. Love rushes by.
Life rushes by.
But the red shoes...dance on.
What happens in the end?
- ln the end, she dies.
- Yes. l remember.
The music was written by Felipe Beltran.
He did it for us last year
during our South American tour.
You'll find here some passages
marked with a blue pencil. They are bad.
l would like to see what you can do
in the way of a little rewriting.
- Oh.
- You can take your time.
- There's no hurry.
- Thank you.
(Knock on door)
- On vous attend sur la scène.
Oui, je viens.
Thank you.
♪ Giselle
Ah, look at our Boronskaja.
She's in wonderful form tonight.
l'm not interested in Boronskaja's form any more.
Nor in the form of any other prima ballerina
imbecile enough to get married.
- Oh, come now, Boris.
- She's out. Finished.
You cannot have it both ways.
The dancer who relies upon
the doubtful comforts of human love...
..will never be a great dancer.
Never!
That is all very pure and fine,
but you can't alter human nature.
No? l think you can do even better than that.
You can ignore it.
(Station announcements in background)
Alors c'est entendu,
vous enverrez à boire à tout le monde
avec les compliments de M. Lermontov.
Moi, je suis Ljubov.
(Station announcements in background)
Boris!
Adieu.
Well, lrina, now you'll be able to sleep
as long as you like
and eat sweets all day
and go to parties every night.
And you, now you will be calm.
The class will start on time.
No more shouting.
No more hysteria backstage. No more...
No more...lrina.
(They call out)
Oh, Monsieur Lermontov!
Quel plaisir de vous revoir.
Je m'excuse que je suis tout deshabillé,
mais j'étais en train de régler
le nouveau dispositif de lumière.
ll est au poil. Oh, Monsieur Lermontov,
cette histoire de danse...
Miss Page.
- Are you very tired?
- Yes, thank you.
l mean, l'm not very tired.
Monsieur, je vous présente Miss Victoria Page,
qui vient de nous joindre.
Monsieur Boudin,
le directeur général de l'opéra.
- Monsieur Rideaut, le régisseur.
- Enchanté, mademoiselle.
You have already visited Monte Carlo,
mademoiselle?
Yes, last season, with my aunt.
- Then you know the Hôtel de Paris.
- Yes, but l believe l'm staying...
Hôtel de Paris.
You'll be very comfortable there.
La voiture de Monsieur Lermontov
vous attend, Miss Page.
Bonsoir, mademoiselle.
Montez, mademoiselle.
- You look dressed up for a conference.
- Hello. ls there a conference on?
Yes. They're all arguing.
l've been here since seven.
There you are, Miss Page.
Will you come in here, please?
l was just going out, Mr Lermontov,
when l got your message.
Miss Page...
..l've asked you to come here tonight
because we are preparing a new ballet,
and l've decided to give you a chance
and let you dance the principal part in it.
But there's one thing l must tell you at once.
My belief in your possibilities
is not shared by my colleagues here.
However, it is hardly necessary for me to add
that whatever their personal belief may be,
they will all give you their best.
The rest, of course, is up to you.
Well, Miss Page...that's all.
We shall start work early tomorrow morning.
l suggest you now forget all about your party
and go straight home to bed.
Yes, l will.
And, Miss Page...
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
Well, what happened?
- l've got a part in a new ballet.
- A new ballet? What ballet?
(Piano plays)
- The Red Shoes!
Now, listen to this. lt's impossible.
Well, l couldn't rewrite that bit, could l?
- Why not?
- You didn't blue-pencil it.
Horrors like that speak for themselves.
As a matter of fact,
l did have some ideas about that.
Where are they, my dear fellow?
We need a score!
lf you'll allow me.
Well, it's the church scene.
Get rid of this sentimental hymn tune
and take a four-square chorale.
Something like this.
Then l thought all the way through,
we might have a church bell coming in.
All this on the strings.
(Sings tune)
Then as the priest appears, the brass.
(Sings tune with deeper voice)
Shall l play you The Dance Of The Red Shoes?
Thank you, Mr Craster. Thank you.
l want you to change everything.
l want a new score.
There you are, Mr Lermontov.
And where's the orchestration?
- When do you want it?
- Yesterday.
You said you wanted to work.
Go home and work.
l don't want to see you till it's done.
You won't!
(Band plays slow dance tune)
(Sternly) Why aren't you in bed?
- Oh, you gave me quite a fright.
- l meant to.
Why aren't you in bed?
l was ordered to but l was much too excited
to sleep, so here l am.
- Are you? l haven't seen you.
- Thank you.
By the way, you haven't seen me, either.
- Has he sent you to bed, too?
- No.
l'm just working on the score
of my new ballet - The Red Shoes.
ls that my ballet, too?
Yes, l suppose it is.
(Train whistle toots)
(Steam train chugs)
l wonder what it feels like
to wake up in the morning
and find oneself famous.
You're not likely to know
if you stay here talking much longer.
- So, good luck.
- Good luck.
(He whistles a slow tune)
(Gentle piano music)
She's putting too much into it.
Why don't you tell her, Grischa?
Mind your own business.
She has the dance with me
and the dance at the fair before this.
And the big stuff still to come.
She can't dance everything full out.
- She ought to know that.
- How do you expect her to know it,
if you never dance full out yourself
before opening night?
Here are the designs for the costumes, Boris.
One moment.
Sit down, will you, please?
l'm so sorry.
Something has to be done about the music.
She starts the pirouette a beat too early.
- The tempo's wrong. lt's too fast.
- lt's the right tempo.
Of course.
Once more.
- She'll be all right.
- l hope so.
Still unconverted, Sergei?
Well, of course she's a charming girl, but...
l know nothing about her charms.
But they won't wait till the end,
they'll applaud in the middle!
(Chuckles) Come now.
Sergei, l'll take a bet.
Oh, enough. Enough.
Miss Page, we are trying to create
something of beauty.
While you wave your arms like a scarecrow
and bend your knees like an old cart horse,
we are unlikely to succeed.
Well, well...it's a bet.
Come on, let me see your sketches.
The girl. (Chuckles)
Renée? Rendez-vous à 14 h.
N'y fais pas attention, mon petit.
Ce Ljubov est un animal.
- Un verre d'eau, s'il vous plaît.
- Bien. Vous l'aurez dans une seconde.
(Gentle piano music)
- You still think l can do it?
- (Chuckles)
Well, at the moment,
you look as if you find it difficult.
But when we open in two weeks' time
l hope it'll be supremely simple.
Don't forget, the great impression of simplicity
can only be achieved
by a great agony of body and spirit.
- Voilà.
- Uh-uh-uh!
You don't want to ruin your breathing, do you?
From today, you'll lunch in my office.
Craster.
Personne ne me dit rien, donc... Voilà...
- Will you sit over there, please?
- Je comprends pas.
Merci. Mr Craster, at the piano.
Do you usually have
a musical accompaniment to your meals?
No, Miss Page, l do not.
But l'm afraid this is your fate
for the next two weeks.
Mr Craster
is going to play The Red Shoes music for you
at every lunch, tea and dinner you take
until we open.
l see.
Yes. ln this way, you should become
quite familiar with the music.
Yes, l think l probably shall.
The music is all that matters.
Nothing but the music.
- Mr Craster?
- Certainly.
Bon appétit.
A votre service, mademoiselle.
Some composers specialise
in lunchtime music, don't they?
- Some.
- You?
ln my time.
Do you mind not playing that?
lt's the right tempo.
Let's take the ballroom scene.
That's the most digestible part of the score.
The ballroom's out. lt's been cut.
Cut as a scene, but it's still there in my score.
l wrote this dance for a ballroom.
Anyone who understands anything about music
will see a ballroom.
Even Lermontov will see a ballroom.
(Stops playing) Even you.
(Starts playing) And when you're lifted
up into the air by your partner,
my music will transform you.
lnto what?
A flower...swaying in the wind.
A cloud...drifting in the sky.
A white bird...flying.
Tell that to Ratov.
He would love your birds and flowers.
(Stops playing) You don't?
- lf you were a dancer, you'd know...
- Just a minute.
♪ Nothing matters but the music!
lt's hard enough to get off the ground, anyway,
without being a bird or a flower.
Aren't you going to imagine anything
on the first night?
Yes, a wall between me and the audience.
My music will pull you through it.
(Dramatic chord)
(Orchestra plays)
Hee-haw!
Miss Page, l am not a circus conductor
and you are not a horse.
lt's too fast.
- You would not find it too fast...
- (Grischa shouts) Both of you!
You would not find it too fast if you'd let the slow
passage end before you start your pirouette.
My downbeat marks a pause.
We understand it, don't we, gentlemen?
N'est-ce pas?
- You come in on the second beat.
- lmpossible!
One, two, tia, tia!
lt's quite simple. You see this baton?
- Yes.
- Well, follow it!
Oh!
(Orchestra tuning up)
WOMAN: Regardez comme elle est jolie.
- Ah mais ça lui fait une taille énorme, du coup.
- Laissez-moi tranquille.
(Knock at door)
- Good luck.
- Vicky. Vicky!
- (Women chatter in French)
Dance whatever tempo you like. l'll follow you.
(Women sigh)
All right?
Time to go down, Craster.
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
- Nervous?
- No.
Come on!
Do l...?
What the devil have you got to worry about?
lt's a fine score.
A magnificent score. l only wish l...
Go on.
(Applause)
(Dramatic introduction)
- Va chercher Monsieur Ljubov.
- Oui, tout de suite, mon petit.
Louis, ferme les lumières.
Moi, je baisse la main droite.
- Grischa.
- lt's chaos, chaos, chaos!
- Grischa...
- Ah, Boris.
- Mon Dieu! The red shoes.
- What?
- The red shoes are not there!
- Rideaut.
- What have you done with the red shoes?
- Mademoiselle...
Don't waste your time! Where are they?
- You haven't hidden them yourself?
- No, no, no!
Yes! Fou! Fou!
Miss Page est dans un état! Elle est si nerveuse!
Ca alors!
Boris, look here.
Elephants.
Clumsy elephants have ruined my décor.
- Calm yourself.
- The door! The door! lt won't shut.
- Somebody must hold it.
- But who?
The call boy. He will have nothing to do.
- Dimitri.
- Give it to me. Hold the door.
- Best of luck, Miss Page.
- l can't remember my entrance.
You think you can't remember it.
What about this?
(Hums tune)
Yes. That's it.
lt's all right when l hear the music.
Since you undoubtedly will hear the music,
it's undoubtedly going to be all right.
The music is all that matters.
Nothing but the music.
lf l had any doubts about you, l'd be nervous.
- Am l nervous?
- No.
You're not dancing for an audience.
You're dancing for Ljubov, Ratov, myself -
people for whom you've been dancing
many times before.
l believed in you from the very beginning.
But now everybody does.
l want you to dance tonight with the same
ecstasy l've seen in you only once before.
At the Mercury Theatre?
Yes, at the Mercury Theatre in London...
on a wet Saturday afternoon.
- 40 seconds.
- Coming.
Good luck, my dear.
You're a magician, Boris, to have produced
all this in three weeks - and from nothing.
The best magician in the world
can't produce a rabbit out of a hat
if there isn't already a rabbit in the hat.
(Music stops, applause)
lt's a pity the theatre only holds 300.
We could have filled the Albert Hall tonight!
Yes, but what we are creating tonight,
the world will talk of tomorrow.
Good boy.
Rideaut.
(Orchestra plays)
(Music stops, then starts up again)
(Music builds dramatically)
(Music slows)
(Music stops)
(Gentle music)
(Dramatic music)
(Music pauses)
(Music resumes)
(Dramatic chords, music stops)
(Applause)
(Cheering)
(Church bell tolling and music)
(Music pauses)
(Music resumes)
(Music fades and stops)
(Applause)
(Cheering)
(Applause continues)
(Whistling)
(Grischa whistles)
Ca va? Any swelling?
l mean the head.
All that clapping, bravos, roses...
Puff! All that's nothing.
But when l, who have seen Pavlova dance,
tell you that last night you were not bad -
not good, but not bad - that's something.
Now l tell you truth.
lt was...good.
Thank you, Mr Ljubov.
- My name is Grischa.
- Mine is Vicky.
How do you do?
Arm straighter. So...
Boris Lermontov wants to see you.
Why in the class time? Why?
(Lively chatter)
Silence!
E!
Hello? Hello? Yes. Who is it? Oh, it's you!
- Monsieur Lermontov...
- Une seconde.
No, it's fine. Thank you for ringing me.
You're not disturbing me at all.
- l always have time for congratulations.
- Monsieur Lermontov...
Laissez-moi parler.
Vous voyez que je téléphone.
Oh, yes. l agree.
- Monsieur Lermontov...
- A most distinguished score.
Quel est le nom du compositeur?
- Voilà, Monsieur Craster.
- Uh, Monsieur Craster?
Yes. Of course he's under contract to me.
Yes, he's going to. He's starting
with a new ballet, full of gaiety and charm.
La Belle Meunière, book by Marcel Lucien.
Go away.
Yes. Oh, yes, it's a wonderful role for her.
- Au revoir, Lermontov.
- Au revoir, madame.
No, not this season. Next season.
- Cher maître, je vous souhaite...
- Au revoir.
Merci beaucoup.
Yes. lt was very kind of you to ring me.
Thank you very much.
No more calls, not even congratulations.
Mon cher ami, je vous remercie.
N'oubliez pas ce que je vous ai dit.
Au revoir. Where are the Paris papers?
Thank you very much. Here.
Fichez-moi le camp, je vous en prie.
Excusez-moi.
Well, Mr Craster, that's all.
Thank you very much. l'm proud of you.
- Mr Lermontov, l would like to...
- Some other time, some other time.
- Ah, yes! Do you read French?
- Yes.
Well, read it.
We'll talk about it some other time.
Mademoiselle Page.
Come in, Miss Page, come in. Sit down.
l want to talk to you about your future.
When we first met,
you asked me a question
to which l gave a stupid answer.
You asked me whether
l wanted to live and l said yes.
Actually, l want more, much more!
l want to create, to make something big
out of something little.
To make a great dancer out of you.
But first, l must ask you the same question.
What do you want from life?
- To live?
- To dance.
We have two months left of the season
in Monte Carlo.
Not much time, but enough. Two months.
Then we go on tour - Rome, Vienna,
Copenhagen, Stockholm, then America.
Then next year, London again.
All the big parts for you...
Coppélia, Lac des Cygnes, Giselle,
Sleeping Princess, Les Sylphides, La Boutique.
We create them all afresh with you.
You shall dance...
and the world shall follow.
You... Sssh!
Not a word.
l will do the talking.
You...will do the dancing.
♪ La Boutique Fantasque
Quelle saison, mais c'est inouï!
Et toujours Victoria Page!
Ah, Victoria Page.
Vous avez la une, vous êtes de premier ordre,
Lermontov.
- Good night, Boris.
- Night, Grischa.
- She was not bad tonight.
- She'll be all right.
"All right"? "Not bad"? But she's a flame!
Le coryphée!
(Whistles)
- Still la-di-da? Good night, Boris.
- Good night, Sergei.
Vicky was wonderful in Boutique,
just a little Dresden shepherdess.
BOUDlN:
We should reconstruct the theatre.
- What's wrong with it?
- lt's too small!
- Good night, Lermontov.
- Good night, Livy.
- Her timing's a miracle.
- Keep her up to it.
♪ Coppélia
- Good night, Boris.
- Good night, Grischa.
- Good night, Sergei.
- Good night, Mr Lermontov.
- Good night, Vicky.
♪ Les Sylphides
- Good night, Boris.
- Good night, Sergei.
(Door closes)
Thank you, Monsieur Boudin. That's all.
- Good night, Boris.
- Good night, Grischa.
- Boudin.
- Oui?
Tell me, which is the very best restaurant
this year on the coast?
- La Réserve.
- Oui, La Réserve.
- Good night, Lermontov.
- Good night, Livy.
Book me a table.
- For...two?
- Yes.
Non, il est parti il y a cinq minutes
exactement. Au revoir.
Bonsoir!
- Julian.
- Yes?
l never said good night to Lermontov.
Monsieur Dimitri?
No, Miss Page has still not come in.
Ma clé.
Monsieur Ratov? Er...not here either.
Monsieur Ljubov? 317... No.
Tu sais bien qu'ils sont tous à Villefranche.
Ah, Monsieur Dimitri, l have just heard,
they've all gone to supper
at the Old Port with Monsieur Ljubov.
C'est son anniversaire. His birthday!
(Lively chatter and accordion music)
(Wine cork pops)
(Cheering)
(All speaking at once)
Place! Place au gâteau. Voilà.
(Cheering)
Permettez-moi, maître. Avec tous les voeux
du théâtre municipal du casino de Monte Carlo.
Ah, merci. Très touché. Regardez-moi ça.
- Quel merveilleux cake!
- (Car approaches)
Tiens!
Tiens! Boris Lermontov!
(Excited chatter)
Greetings, Grischa.
Am l permitted to join your party?
Che piacere!
What a pleasure, Boris. Che gioia!
A chair for Boris Lermontov!
Two chairs for Boris Lermontov!
Make way there. A throne.
- A throne for Boris. Take mine, Lermontov!
- No, no, take mine.
No, you sit down.
lt's your birthday. Sit down.
Prenez la mienne.
Well...seems a long time since l sat down
to supper with my entire family.
But it appears that the great Miss Page
is not with us tonight.
Don't you miss another member
of our happy little family?
No...no. l can't say l do.
Why should you? You're a busy man.
Have a drink, Lermontov!
(Laughter)
Grischa. A ta santé.
Of course we all know you're a busy man,
Boris Lermontov,
but do you mean to tell me
you have noticed nothing?
Don't exaggerate.
Boris, we have a little romance in our midst.
A great romance!
- Romeo Craster.
- And Juliet...Page.
And when...did this great romance begin?
GRlSCHA: With The Red Shoes.
Charming.
And where have they taken themselves tonight?
What does it matter where they've gone?
They are young,
they are together and they are in love.
- Darling.
- Mm-hm?
l've decided l do believe in destiny after all.
Do you, my darling?
l'm very glad.
VlCKY: Cocher.
Cocher!
- You'll wake him.
- But l want to know where we are.
Cocher? Co...
One day, when l'm old,
l want some lovely young girl to say to me...
"Tell me, where in your long life, Mr Craster,
were you most happy?"
And l shall say...
"Well, my dear, l never knew the exact place.
lt was somewhere on the Mediterranean.
l was with Victoria Page."
"What?" she will say.
"Do you mean the famous dancer?"
l will nod.
"Yes, my dear, l do.
But then, she was quite young,
comparatively unspoiled.
We were, l remember...very much in love."
♪ Swan Lake
(Music swells)
Did you see that?
She smiled at Craster.
l don't think so.
l suppose you will be sending me
to an oculist next.
Watch her dancing.
With pleasure.
Debutantes...at a charity matinée.
BORlS: Yes.
Yes!
Yes. All right. Thursday.
Good evening, Mr Lermontov.
l'm afraid the score's still a bit rough,
but l see you've had time to look at it.
Yes, Mr Craster.
l have looked at it.
However, it's not about your music
that l wish to talk at the moment.
So to come to the point...
What is all this l hear
about you and Miss Page?
Oh, l see.
- Could Dimitri...?
- Get out.
Well, Mr Craster?
(Door opens and closes)
Yes. We're in love.
l see.
Did you see Miss Page's performance
in Lac des Cygnes?
l was conducting.
Did you enjoy it?
l think it was the loveliest thing
l've ever seen in my life.
lt was impossible.
And you know why it was impossible?
Because neither her mind
nor her heart were in her work.
She was...dreaming.
And dreaming is a luxury
l've never permitted in my company.
Miss Page wants to be a great dancer.
Perhaps she has spoken to you
about her...ambitions.
- Oh, yes.
- She's not, however, a great dancer yet.
Nor is she likely to become one if she allows
herself to be sidetracked by idiotic flirtations.
Mr Lermontov, you...don't understand.
We really are in love.
And, Mr Craster, l have had time
to look at your latest effort...
Yes?
..and find it equally impossible.
That's not true. lt's good.
Childish...vulgar...
and completely insignificant.
ln that case, l'll relieve you of it.
There are so many first-class ballet companies
to which you may take it with advantage.
l don't know that it's my greatest ambition
to work for the ballet.
Some of us think
it's rather a second-rate means of expression.
- Oui, Monsieur Lermontov?
- Mr Craster is leaving the company.
Pay him two weeks' salary and get the receipt.
Spotlight sur moi.
Toujours sur moi.
Oh, hello, Boris.
- l was coming to say good night.
- Good night.
- ls anything the matter?
- No, no.
And before l forget it,
don't do any more work on the new ballet.
- l decided to scrap it.
- Scrap it? What do you mean?
l worked out half the choreography already.
That boy Julian is really gifted.
lt's one of the finest scores we've ever had.
Julian Craster is leaving the company
and l don't wish to discuss the matter any further.
Oh, you don't? Well, l do!
Do you think l don't know
a brilliant score when l hear one?
Do you think
l've been working day and night for weeks
for the pleasure of being told
l am wasting my time?
l tell you, Boris,
l've had enough of this lunatic asylum!
l am through with it!
l resign!
l think you've made a very important decision.
♪ Slowjazz
Hello, you two.
lsn't love wonderful?
Bonsoir, Julian.
Hello.
Well, what did he say?
Ah. Of course he doesn't really
want you to go, Grischa. He is very sorry.
- Well, in that case, l will think about it.
- What about Julian?
(Sighs)
l have never seen him quite as bad as this.
He talked a great deal
about ingratitude and...disloyalty.
And he said when personal relations
started to interfere...
Yes, l know that bit.
My dear children, l'm very sorry.
Boris might feel different in the morning.
The morning?
He's leaving for Paris by the 8.15 train.
Has the famous Miss Page come to see me off?
l'd like to talk to you.
Tell me why you quarrelled with Julian.
There's only three minutes.
May l suggest that such matters
are hardly your business?
However, since you've gone to all this trouble...
Mr Craster has been unwise enough
to interfere with certain plans of mine.
And that is something l do not permit.
l thought once that there would be
no room in my life for anything but dancing.
You'll think so again, my dear.
But if Julian goes, l shall go too.
And what do you intend to do?
l shall dance somewhere else.
Oh, yes.
That won't be very difficult
with the name l've given you.
Always provided l release you of your contract.
But even if l do...
..would it be quite the same?
l have never pretended to myself that it would.
l could make you one of the greatest dancers
the world has ever known.
Do you believe that?
Yes, l do.
And all that means nothing to you?
(Blast of whistle)
- You know exactly what it means to me.
En voiture! En voiture!
(Chatter from platform)
(Urgent knocking)
- The train is leaving!
Goodbye, Mr Lermontov.
Miss Page is coming!
VICKY: Julian! Julian!
l'm coming with you!
Hooray!
(Dull roar of traffic)
The fool.
Fool!
(Buzzer)
Come in. You are late.
l hope you didn't work too hard.
All finished. l have the injunction with me.
Boris, don't tell me
you've changed your mind again.
Huh.
l...l don't want to stop her doing anything.
She can dance when and where she likes...
..except The Red Shoes.
- What about the boy?
- That's different.
Everything he's written
while under contract to me is mine.
The Red Shoes and his work so far
on La Belle Meunière.
l'm not interested in anything else he may write.
But if you keep The Red Shoes in the repertoire,
you'll have to pay him royalties.
The Red Shoes is no longer in the repertoire!
Oh.
l understand Patrick Trevellyan's in Paris.
Yes.
l dined with them both last night.
Oh?
- Boronskaja was with him?
- Yes.
Anything l can do?
How's their marriage? Success?
Patrick seems to think so.
Would you like me to arrange
a meeting with lrina?
Not "arrange".
By chance.
(Dog yaps)
Oh! Boris!
♪ Les Sylphides
- Good night, Boris.
- Good night, lrina.
(Door closes)
- Good season.
- With the Ballet Lermontov, always.
(Door opens)
- Good night, Boris.
- Good night, Sergei.
- Sergei!
- Yes?
- Would you come in and wait a minute, please?
- Yes, of course, Boris.
- Good night, Boris!
- Grischa, please come in and wait.
Oh...a conference.
- Ah!
- Urgh!
Letters.
- Nobody writes to me.
- That's not true.
Yours...from Vicky.
From Vicky?
- How is that girl?
- Read it. You'll see.
And this is from Julian.
lt's all about his new opera.
lt describes the whole structure.
Enormous talent, that boy.
He says...
"She is an inspiration.
A miracle."
- Thank you, Mr Boudin. That's all.
- Merci. Bonsoir.
Well...l see it's mail day.
From our two young rebels.
Deserters. l hope they're happy.
- Read, Boris.
- Yes. Read this, too.
lt might make you sorry
to have lost that young man.
l doubt it.
By the way, that reminds me, Jacques sent me
the new score of La Belle Meunière.
l like it. l'd like you all to hear it at once.
We might open with it in London.
- With lrina?
- We can discuss that.
Lights, all gaiety, fire.
Be good enough to glance through it.
And no prejudice, please.
l hope you say that to yourself sometimes.
(Chuckles) Every day. Good night.
- Good night.
On second thoughts,
l think l would like to read those letters.
My letter was only meant to be read by me.
- See you later, Boris.
- Good night, Sergei.
l could hardly let him read it.
She calls him a monster - a gifted, cruel monster.
(Laughs) You should have told him that.
(Operatic singing)
(Julian composes on piano)
(Julian plays with left hand)
(Door bursts open)
l...l am sorry to be late, Boris Lermontov.
Lady Neston was in front tonight.
She arrived this morning.
She is staying for several weeks.
And Miss Page is joining her next week
for a short holiday.
(Knock at door)
We seem to be destined
to meet at railway stations.
WOMAN: Vite, vite!
- What are you doing in Cannes?
- Waiting for you. Won't you sit?
But you know, my dear Vicky,
how l'm always looking for great dancers.
We all have missed you.
And l was hoping that by now
you would have started to miss us...a little.
l have.
You only have to say the words.
- How is everybody?
- lncluding me?
- lncluding you.
- Never better.
- How is Grischa?
- Always fighting with Boronskaja.
- And she?
- Always fighting with Grischa.
- How is old Sergei?
- Getting younger.
- And you?
- Getting older.
And you? You are happy?
Yes. Very happy.
As a dancer, I mean.
l haven't danced very much, you know.
Oh, I know, I know.
l know every time you have danced.
- But you never stopped working?
- No.
- And you never stopped going to class?
- Never.
And why isn't he with you?
His opera's been accepted at Covent Garden.
It's in rehearsal now.
- Would he give it up if you ask him?
- l don't know.
- You do know.
- l wouldn't ask.
Then why is he asking you?
Does he know what he is asking?
We are preparing a new ballet.
We've been working at it for weeks.
The costumes and the décor
are the most beautiful Ratov has ever done.
Grischa's full of enthusiasm.
And you know what that means?
Nobody else has ever danced The Red Shoes
since you left.
Nobody else ever shall.
Put on the red shoes, Vicky...
and dance for us again.
This is the BBC Third Programme.
l am speaking from the Royal Opera House,
Covent Garden, London.
Tonight is the first night of Cupid And Psyche,
a new opera by British composer Julian Craster,
whose only well-known work has been
the score for the ballet The Red Shoes.
The Red Shoes was a great success
when produced at Monte Carlo last year
with the Ballet Lermontov,
but has not yet been seen in this country.
Oh, something must have gone wrong,
l'm afraid.
l think somebody's going to make
an announcement.
Ladies and gentlemen,
l regret to announce
that Mr Julian Craster the composer,
who was to conduct his own opera,
has been suddenly taken ill.
Sir Hartley Menzies will conduct in his place.
Here comes Sir Hartley Menzies now.
l'll announce the cast during the interval.
(Applause)
(Door closes)
ll est moins le quart, monsieur.
All the way down from London,
l wondered if l'd find you here.
And here you are.
So you left your first night?
Yes.
Oh, Julian.
Why didn't you?
- Oh, Julian.
- (He sobs)
All right, love, my sweetheart.
There's a train to Paris at 8.00.
We'll be on it together.
Better hurry up and get changed.
- But l'm dancing tonight.
- Walk out.
Good evening, Mr Craster.
Won't they be missing you
at Covent Garden tonight?
- ll est moins dix.
- Je sais.
Oh, for God's sake!
Leave me alone, both of you!
Please, Julian,
wait until after the performance.
lt'll be too late then.
You're already too late, Mr Craster.
Tell him why you've left him.
- l haven't left him!
- Oh, yes, you have.
Nobody can have two lives -
and your life is dancing.
Vicky, you can dance anywhere else
in the whole world.
Would you be satisfied with anything less
than the best?
lf you would, you'd never be a great artist.
Would you make her a great dancer as well?
Never!
Why do you think l've waited day after day
for a chance to win her back?
- Because you're jealous of her.
- Yes! I am.
But in a way that you will never understand.
- Il est moins cinq!
- Faut-il tenir le rideau?
Oui!
- Well, Vicky?
- l love you, Julian! Nobody but you!
(Vicky sobs)
But you love that more.
l don't know! l don't know.
(Julian's opera continues on wireless)
lf you go with him now,
l will never take you back. Never!
Vicky, do you want to destroy our love?
Adolescent nonsense!
All right. Go, then. Go with him.
Be a faithful housewife
with a crowd of screaming children!
Finish with dancing forever!
JULlAN: Vicky...look at me.
Goodbye, then, my darling.
Julian.
Monsieur Lermontov,
peut-on commencer l'ouverture?
- Oui. Commencez.
- Bon. Bon. Bon.
Alors, commencez toute de suite.
vite! vite!
Vicky...
Vicky. Little Vicky.
There it is, all waiting for you.
The sorrow will pass, believe me.
Life is so unimportant.
And from now onwards, you will dance...
..like nobody ever before.
(Julian's opera drowns out speech)
Qu'est-ce que tu as?
Mon petit.
Où vas-tu?
Mon petit! (Screams)
Monsieur Lermontov!
(Dramatic music)
Mademoiselle Page! Où allez-vous?
(Train horn)
No!
(Music stops)
(Silence)
Ladies...and gentlemen!
l'm sorry...to tell you...
..that Miss Page...
..is unable...
..to dance...tonight.
(Gasps from audience)
Nor indeed...
..any other nights.
(More shocked gasps)
(Murmuring)
Nevertheless...
..we've decided...
..to present...The Red Shoes!
lt...is...
..the ballet...
..that made her name...
..whose name...she made.
We...present it...
..because...
..we think...
..she would have...wished it.
(Orchestra plays)
(Murmuring)
Pas d'espoir.
(Low groans)
Julian?
Yes, my darling?
Take off the red shoes.