Ladies and gentlemen, the driving force
behind atholicism WOW!, Cardinal Glick.
Thank you
Now we all know
how the majority...
and the media in this country...
view the Catholic church.
They think of us as a passe,
archaic institution.
People find the Bible obtuse...
even hokey.
Now, in an effort to disprove
all that...
the Church has appointed this year
as a time of renewal...
both offaith and of style.
For example, the crucifix.
While it has been a time-honored symbol
of our faith...
Holy Mother Church
has decided to retire...
this highly recognizable...
yet wholly depressing image...
of our Lord, crucified.
Christ didn't come to Earth
to give us the willies.
He came to help us out.
He was a booster, and it's
with that take on our Lord in mind...
that we've come up with a new,
more inspiring Sigil.
So, it is with great pleasure
that I presentyou with the first...
of many revamps
the Catholicism Wow!. campaign...
will unveil over the nextyear,
I giveyou...
"The Buddy Christ.""
That's not the sanctioned term
we're using for the symbol.
Just something we've been
kicking around the office.
But look at it.
Doesn't it pop?.
Buddy Christ.
Well, thereyou have it.
Let me get this straight.
You don't believe in God
because of Alice in Wonderland?.
No, Through the Looking Glass.
That poem,
""The Walrus and the Carpenter""...
that's an indictment
of organized religion.
The Walrus, with his girth
and his good nature...
he obviously represents either Buddha...
orwith his tusks,
the Hindu elephant god, Lord Ganesha.
That takes care
ofyour Eastern religions.
Now, the Carpenter, which is
an obvious reference toJesus Christ...
who was raised a carpenter's son,
he represents the Western religions.
Now, in the poem,
what do they do?.
They dupe all these oysters
into following them...
and then proceed to shuck and devour
the helpless creatures en masse.
I don't know what that says toyou,
but to me it says...
that following these faiths
based on mythological figures...
ensures the destruction
of one's inner-being.
Organized religion destroys
who we are...
by inhibiting our actions,
by inhibiting our decisions...
out offear ofsome
intangible parent figure...
who shakes a finger at us
from thousands ofyears ago...
and says, "" Do it--
Do it and I'll fuckin' spankyou!""
Oh,Jesus!
The wayyou put it, I've never really
thought about it like that before.
What have I been doing
with my life?.
- What am I?.
- Yeah, I know.
Listen, my advice toyou...
you take this money thatyou've
been collecting foryour parish...
go getyourself a nice dress,
fixyourself up.
Find some man-- find some woman--you
can connect with, even for a moment...
'cause that's really all life is,
Sister-- a series of moments.
Why don'tyou seizeyours?.
That a girl.
You know, here's what
I don't get aboutyou.
You know for a fact
that there is a God.
You've been in His presence.
He's spoken toyou personally.
- Yet I heard you claim to be atheist.
- I like to fuckwith the clergy, man.
I just love it. I love to keep
those guys on their toes.
Here's what I don't get aboutyou.
Why doyou feel the need
to come to this place all the time?.
My friend, because
this is humanity at its best.
Look at them.
All that anger, all that mistrust,
all that unhappiness...
forgotten for that one perfect moment
when they get offthe plane.
See those two?.
What that guy doesn't know is that the
girl cheated on him while she was away.
- She did?.
- Twice.
- Nice.
- But it doesn't matter right now...
'cause they're just both so relieved
to be with one another.
I like that.
I wish they all could
feel that way more often.
Is this why I had to come down here
and miss my fucking cartoons?.
You call me, you tell me
it's important.
What, to share in your half-assed
obsession with Hallmark moments?.
We're going home.
Somebody sent us this in the mail.
Take it and quit leering at me. People
will think I just broke upwith you.
- You said we're going home, didn'tyou?.
- Read.
""Cardinal GlickCuts Ribbon On
Catholicism Wow! Campaign.""
And?.
You have to keep reading.
""The rededication of
St. Michael's Church...""
...is the kickoffofa new campaign
which seeks to bring...
Catholicism into the mainstream.
With a papal sanction,
the archway entrance...
ofthe century-oldJersey shore
house ofworship...
will serve as a passageway
ofplenary indulgence--
a little-known Catholic belief offering
all that passes through its arches...
a morally clean slate.
For Sunday News Brief,
I'm Grant Hicks.
Al I I gotta do, I wal k through the arch
thi ng, and then I can go back home?.
No. By walking through the archway,
all your sins are forgiven.
- Then all we have to do is die.
- Die?. I don't wanna die.
- You rather hang around here?.
- No. We don't know ifwe can die.
But what ifwe can and then
the arch thing doesn't work?.
What then, Hell?.
Fuck that.
It's impossible.
Ifwe cut off ourwings...
and transubstantiate to complete
human form, we become mortal.
Ifwe die with clean souls,
there's nowaythey can keep us out.
We won't be angels anymore,
but at least we get to go home.
- Who sent the paper?.
- Who cares who sent the paper?.
All that matters is that after
all these years, we found a loophole.
He can't keep us out anymore.
Once we're back in,
it'll be forgive and forget.
But this thing,
this is Church law.
It's not Divine Mandate.
Church laws are fallible
because they're created by man.
One ofthe last sacred promises
imparted to Peter, the first pope...
by the Son ofGod
before He left was...
- ""Whateveryou hold true on Earth--""
- "" I'll hold true in Heaven.""
It's dogmatic law. Ifthe Church
says it's so, God must adhere.
This thing has a papal sanction--
Let it never be said your
anal retentive attention to detail...
neveryielded positive results.
You can't be anal retentive
ifyou don't have an anus.
Outstanding work!
There's just one thing
I thinkwe gotta do before we leave.
This is gonna help us get back
on His good side.
What?.
Here. I've been dreaming about this
for fiveyears. Read that.
"" Mooby, the Golden Calf.
Creating an Empire
Out ofSimplicity."
I wanna hit 'em.
You really are
just a simple creature.
We finallyfind a way back
and you want to jeopardize that...
becauseyou've got a soft spot
for the good ol' days.
What betterway to repent than by
resuming the position I once denied...
thanks to you?.
I don't think a killing spree
is gonna make things better for us.
Killing spree?.
I'm talking about DivineJustice here.
I'm talking about reigning down fire
and brimstone, punishing thewicked.
He's all about that.
I know He'd want this done.
There hasn't been an Angel of Death
sinceyou quit.
Doesn't that mean anything toyou?.
And besides, what ifyou're wrong,
likeyou always are?.
IfI'm wrong-- which I'm not--
it's not gonna matter.
We're gonna pass through
your arch thing anyway.
We're gonna be forgiven.
No harm, no foul.
Well, He does hate competition.
I will say that.
And your Mooby certainly falls
under that heading.
Where is this church
we have to go to?.
NewJersey. Rededication ceremony
is in four days.
Last four days on Earth?.
Ifl had a dick,
I'd go get laid.
- We can do the next best thing.
- What's that?.
Let's kill people.
Oh, notyou.
【 Dogma 】
（Blu-ray H.264 1080P）
English DTS from Dolby-TrueHD 5.1 1536kbps
English AC3 extract Dolby-TrueHD 5.1 640kbps
The greater Illinois Chapter
ofthe Right to Life Foundation...
will be holding its
biannual softball game...
against the Cook County...
Pro-Choice League next Sunday at 2::00.
T oday's second col lection
wi I l be donated...
to the J ohn Doe J ersey Life Fund.
For those ofyou
who haven't been following the news...
an unidentified homeless man...
who was accosted and severely beaten
at the NewJersey shore last Tuesday...
Iies in critical, but stable condition
in one ofthat area's hospitals.
He lacks identification...
and police have had no luck tracking
down any possible family.
The archbishop ofthe Trenton diocese
has disputed the state's decision...
to remove the indigent man
from life-support systems...
asking that Catholics
all over the country...
join in this protest against euthanasia.
Well, now please rise
for the recession offaith.
We believe in one God,
the Father Almighty...
Maker of Heaven and Earth.
We believe inJesus Christ,
His onlySon, Our Lord--
Choose life!
You're gonna burn in Hell,
ya fuckin' baby killer!
Holy shit. It's the pope.
- Huh?.
- Where?.
What are you talking about?.
Jesus! You're a Catholic.
Can'tyou talk to them?.
They hate me more than you,
no doubt.
At leastyou have an excuse. You're
Jewish. You don't know any better.
We already used that excuse
when we killed Christ.
Where wereyou yesterday?.
We went to brunch.
I went to church.
That still kills me,
you and church.
If only they knewyourweekly tithing
came from a Planned Parenthood check.
I don't know why I still go, Liz.
I can remember going to church
when I was young and being moved.
Now I sit there every Sunday
and I feel nothing.
I don't think I have any faith left.
Remember that seminary student
I tried to setyou up with?.
The 20-year-old. The one I could
have baby-sat for in high school.
The point is,
he told me something.
He said that faith
is like a glass ofwater.
When you'reyoung, the glass is little,
so it's easyto fill.
As you get older,
the glass gets bigger.
The same amount ofliquid
doesn't fill it anymore.
But periodically
the glass has to be refilled.
You're suggesting I need
to get filled?.
In moreways than one.
You need to get laid, Bethany Sloane.
You need a man, if only for 1 0 minutes.
It's been my experience that
the average male is never a man...
not even for ten minutes
in his entire life span.
That sounds militant. Areyou thinking
ofjoining the other side?.
Couldn't do it.
Women are insane.
Then you need to go back to church
and ask God for a third option.
I think God is dead.
The sign ofa true Catholic.
Good afternoon, Mrs. Reynolds.
I'm from the EPA.
We're checking on possible
freon leaks.
Tell me,
doyou have air conditioning?.
Yes, we have central air.
In every room?.
Except the bathroom.
Why?.
Well, you do know
what that means, don'tyou?.
Move!
No pleasure, no rapture,
no exquisite sin greater...
than central air.
Pick that up.
This will be the base of operations
from here on in.
Now, ifl remember
the protocol correctly...
the powers...
will attempt to contact
the last scion.
I need you three...
to shuffle her loose
the mortal coil.
Go.
Behold the Metatron!
Herald ofthe Almighty
and voice ofthe one true God!
Behold the Metatron!
Herald ofthe Almighty
and voice ofthe one true God!
SweetJesus!
Doyou have to use the whole can?.
Who the fuck areyou and
what the fuck areyou doing in my room?.
I'm the one that's soaked and she's
the one that's surly. That's rich.
Stupid fucking--
Get the fuck out ofhere,
now!
Oryou'll do what exactly?.
Hit me with that fish?.
Now,just sit down on the bed
and shut up.
Jesus wept!
Look at my suit.
Just take whateveryou want,
but don't kill or rape me.
Give over! I couldn't rapeyou
ifl wanted to. Angels are ill-equipped.
See?.
I'm as anatomically-impaired
as a Ken doll.
Makeyourselfuseful
and give me that towel.
You bottom-feeders
and your arrogance.
You think everybody's just trying
to get in your knickers.
What areyou?.
I'm pissed offis what I am.
Doyou drench everyone who comes in your
room with flame-retardant chemicals?.
No wonderyou're single.
Stand back.
As I was sayin'...
prior toyour fire-fighting episode...
I am the Metatron.
Don't tell me the name
doesn't ring a bell?.
You people.
Ifthere isn't a movie about it,
it's not worth knowing, is it?.
I am a seraphim.
The highest choir ofangels.
You do knowwhat an angel is,
don'tyou?.
Metatron acts as the voice ofGod.
Any documented occasion when someyahoo
claims that God has spoken to them...
they're speaking to me.
Or they're talking to themselves.
Why doesn't God speak for Himself?.
Glad you decided to join
the conversation. To answer that...
human beings have neither the aural,
nor the psychological capacity...
to withstand the awesome power
ofGod's true voice.
Wereyou to hear it, your mind would
cave in and your heart would explode.
We went through five Adams
before we figured that one out.
Well, how do I know
you're an angel?.
Aside from the fiery entrance
and the expansive wingspan?.
You want more proof?.
Fine.
How about tequila?.
-Where the hell are we?.
-Only placeyou can go for good tequila.
Dos tequilas, porfavor,
and an empty glass.
We're in Mexico?.
Actually, we're in a franchised
Mexican family eatery...
down the street
from your apartment, but...
it's impressive nonetheless.
You don't mind I lost the wings, doyou?.
I'm trying to keep our profile low.
What doyou want with me?.
I am to chargeyou
with a holy crusade.
For the record,
I work in an abortion clinic.
Noah was a drunk.
Lookwhat he accomplished.
And no one's asking you to build an ark.
All you gotta do is go to NewJersey...
and visit a small church
on a very important day.
NewJersey?.
That doesn't sound like
much ofa crusade.
Aside from the fine print,
that's it.
What's the fine print?.
Stop a couple of angels from entering
and thus negating all existence.
Wait, wait, wait.
Repeat that.
Stop a couple of angels
from entering...
and thus negating all existence.
I hate it when people
need it spelled out for them.
You might want to clarify that.
Back in the old days,
God was vengeful and hot-tempered.
And His wrath was bore...
by the Angel of Death,
name of Loki.
When Sodom and Gomorrah was destroyed...
that was Loki.
When the waters wiped out everything
except Noah and his menagerie...
that was Loki--
and he was good at what he did.
But one day...
he refused to bear God's wrath
any longer.
- Why?.
- He listened to his friend...
a Grigori
by the name of Bartleby.
Grigori?.
One ofthe choirs of angels.
They're called Watchers.
Guess what they do.
So one day, Loki's wiping out
all the firstborn of Egypt--
The Tenth Plague.
Tell a person thatyou're the Metatron
and they stare atyou blankly.
Mention something out of
a Charlton Heston movie...
and suddenly everybody's
a theology scholar.
May I continue uninterrupted?.
Once he's done with the firstborn...
Loki takes his friend Bartleby out
for a post-slaughter drink.
And over many rounds...
they get into
this discussion about...
whether or not murder
in the name ofGod is okay.
And in the end...
Bartleby convinces Loki
to quit his position...
and take one which doesn't
involve slaughter.
So...
very inebriated...
Loki tells God he quits...
throws down his fiery sword...
and gives Him the finger.
Which ruins it for the rest of us
because from that day forward...
God decreed that angels
could no longer imbibe alcohol.
Hence all the spitting.
So, for their insolence...
God decreed that neither Loki
nor Bartleby...
would ever be allowed
back into Paradise.
- Were they sent to Hell?.
- Worse.
Wisconsin...
for the entire span
ofhuman history.
And when the world ends, they'll have to
sit outside the gates for all eternity.
And this has what to do with me?.
Someone has clued them in
to a loophole in Catholic dogma...
that would allow them
to reenter Heaven.
So what?. They beat the system.
Good for them.
It's not that simple.
Ifthey get in,
theywill have reversed God's decree.
Now listen closely because
this bit's very important.
Existence in all its form
and splendor...
function solely on one principle--
God is infallible.
To prove Him wrong...
would undo reality
and everything that is.
Upwould become down,
blackwould becomewhite.
Existencewould become nothingness.
In essence...
ifthey're allowed to enter
that church...
they'll unmake the world.
Ifthis is so major,
why areyou talking to me?.
- Why doesn't God do something about it?.
- He could.
But He'd rather seeyou
take care ofthis one personally.
Why me?.
Because ofwhoyou are.
And who am I?.
The girl in the pj's!
Don't ask so many questions.
Just serveyour purpose.
I'm gonna have to pass.
I beg your pardon?.
When some quiet little infection
destroyed my uterus, where was God?.
When my husband decided...
he couldn't be with a wife
who couldn't bear his children...
where was God?.
To Hell with Him.
Don't allow eons ofhistory and life
to get blinked out ofbeing...
just becauseyou've got a grudge
againstyour Creator.
Soyou lost the ability
to make life.
You're being offered the chance
to play mother to the world...
by acting like one
and protecting it--
saving it!
But I can't makeyou.
However, ifyou should decide
to stop being selfish...
and acceptyour responsibility...
you won't be alone.
You'll have support.
What?. More angels?.
Prophets.
In a manner ofspeaking.
Two of'em.
The one who speaks...
and he will, at great length,
whetheryou want him to or not...
will make mention ofhimself
as a prophet.
The other one...
well, he's the quiet type.
Look, I've gotta go.
Remember, we're working
in a time frame here.
What's He like?.
God?.
Lonely...
but funny.
He's got a great sense ofhumor.
Take sex, for example.
There's nothing funnier...
than the ridiculous faces
you people make mid-coitus.
Sex is a joke in Heaven?.
The way I understand it,
it's mostly a joke down here too.
I'll seeya.
Snootch to the motherfucking nootch!
Go back to your paper routes,
you Mighty Duck Fucks!
Snoogans.
Did you see that shit, man?.
I know theywere just kids, but we
kicked their fucking pube-less asses!
I don't know what to say
or think, except--
That you'll offer us sex
as a reward?.
That I'd like to know
who they and you are.
I'm Jay, and this is
my hetero life mate, Silent Bob.
I don't know who those kids were,
but theywould have kicked yours...
and Lunchbox's asses
ifl hadn't represented.
Thanks for being
out here so late.
Wait a minute.
Areyou protestors?.
You mean those dickheads with the signs
and pictures of dead babies?.
Shit no!
Me and Silent Bob are pro-choice.
A woman's body
is her own fucking business.
But what areyou doing
hanging around?.
We're here to pick up chicks.
Excuse me?.
We figure abortion clinics are
a good place to meet loose women.
Why else would they be here
unless they like to fuck?.
Right.
Well, I should be going.
Thanks for the rescue.
- I think.
- Wait a second.
We just saved your ass,
and you're just gonna take off.
What the shit is that?.
I had a weird night last night and
tonight's not shaping up to be better.
I think I should go home,
take some Percosets and lay down.
Now how about that shit?.
Fuck this town, man!
I'm goin' back toJersey
and startin' up the business again.
I can kick the shit out ofkids
in Red Bank and make myselfa profit.
Prophets. Two of'em.
- You know what I'm sayin', Silent Bob?.
- You gotta be kidding me.
We call this piece ""The Fecalator.""
One look at it and the target
shits him or herself.
Try it on.
It's a lot more compact than the flaming
sword, but not nearly as impressive.
It doesn't have that
""Wrath ofthe Almighty"" edge to it.
How am I supposed to strike fear into
hearts ofthe wicked with this thing?.
Look at this.
Well, then, you know, don't use a gun.
Lay the place to waste like.
Easy foryou to say.
You get offlight in a razing.
You got to stand there and read
at Sodom and Gomorrah.
I had to do all the work.
What work did you do?.
You lit a few fires.
I rained down sulfur.
There's a subtle difference.
Okay, I'm sure.
Fuckyou. Any moron with a pack
of matches can set a fire.
Raining down sulfur
is like an endurance trial.
Mass genocide is the most
exhausting activity one can engage in...
next to soccer.
I'll take this one.
So, what's up?. You have a friend for
Silent Bob, or areyou gonna do us both?.
If so, I'm first.
I hate sloppy seconds.
You're a man of principle.
Jersey's pretty far from McHenry.
May I askwhat broughtyou here?.
Some fuck named John Hughes.
Sixteen Candles John Hughes?.
You know that guy too?.
That fuckin' guy.
He made this flick Sixteen Candles.
Not bad.
There's tits in it, but no bush.
But Ebert over here don't give
a shit about that kind ofthing...
because he's like in love
with this John Hughes guy.
He goes out and rents
every one ofhis movies.
Fuckin' Breakfast Club, where stupid
kids actually show up for detention.
Fuckin' WeirdScience, where this babe
wants to undress and get down...
but, oh, no, she don't,
because it's a PG movie.
And then Prettyin Pink, which I can't
watch with this tubby bitch anymore...
because when the redhead hooks up
with her dream guy...
he starts sobbin' like a little bitch
with a skinned knee and shit.
And there's nothing worse
than watchin' a fuckin' fat man weep.
What exactly broughtyou
to Illinois?.
All these movies take place in this
small town called Shermer, Illinois...
where all the honeys are top-shelf
but all the dudes arewhiny pussies.
Except forJudd Nelson.
Hewas fuckin' harsh.
But best ofall...
there was no one dealin', man.
Then it hits me.
We could live like phat rats...
ifwe were the blunt connection
in Shermer, Illinois.
Sowe collected some money
we were owed and caught a bus.
Butyou know what the fuck
we found out when we got there?.
There is no Shermer, Illinois.
Movies are fuckin' bullshit.
- When areyou going back to NewJersey?.
- This broad asks a lot of questions.
- Tomorrow.
Yeah. Soyou do anal?.
Is it true that chicks fart
ifyou blast them in the ass?.
I didn't askyou out for sex.
I'll take head.
This is gonna sound really bad. I can't
believe I'm even thinking about this.
I think I should gowith you.
Like steady?.
You wanna be my girlfriend?.
All right, but Silent Bob gets
to live with us and you pay the rent.
No. I wanna go with you
to NewJersey.
Really?.
You're going to lead me somewhere.
Me lead you?.
Lady, look at me. I don't even know
where I am halfthe time.
Ifwe're not gonna fuck, then what
the fuck did you ask us out for?.
Someone told me I'd meetyou and you'd
take me someplace I was supposed to go.
What the hell areyou babbling about?.
We saved your ass from
some angry fuckin' dwarves...
and now we're supposed to takeyou
somewhere as ifwe know where it is?.
Doyou believe in God?.
Holy fuck! All the fine, immoral bitches
out in front ofthat place...
and we gotta get the oneJesus freak?.
- Let's get the fuck out ofhere.
- Wait.
- I'll scream rape.
- I can payyou.
Pay?.
A hundred bucks
for being my guide.
You were going toJersey anyway.
All I'm asking is to tag along.
I feel like Han Solo, you're Chewie,
and she's Ben Kenobi...
and we're in that fucked-up bar!
What about sex?.
No sex.
Let's saywe're caught in a situation
where we have five minutes left to live.
A bomb or something's gonna go off.
Would you fuck us then?.
In that highly unlikely situation?.
Yeah, sure.
She's a slut.
All right.
But I get to drive.
What gear areyou in?.
Gear?.
What do I know about shiftin'?.
Like I ever drove before.
Indiana, Ohio, Pennsylvania...
NewJersey.
Maybeyou're wrong
about this slaughter thing.
How can you be sure what incurs the
Lord's wrath these days?. Times change.
I remember eating meat on a Friday
used to be a Hell-worthy trespass.
The major sins never change.
Besides, I can spot
a commandment-breaker from a mile away.
Bet on it.
This from the guywho still owes me
ten bucks over that bet...
about which was gonna be the bigger
movie-- ET or Krush Groove.
Fuckyou, man,
'cause time's gonna tell on that one.
Are you insinuating that I don't have
what it takes anymore?.
Insinuating, no.
Flat-out telling you.
Right there.
There's one.
So?. They're kissing.
Adultery.
- Adultery?.
- Adultery.
You are just a simple creature.
- Am I right?.
- I happen to know the truth.
I'm not gonna tell you. I want to see
how boned up on the jobyou are.
- What's your proof?.
- He's wearing a wedding band.
And it never occurred to you
that maybe she's his wife?.
No married man kisses
his wife like that.
Okay. It's a good thing
you were never...
the deciding member on a jury
is all I'm saying.
"" No married man kisses
his wife like that""?. Areyou stoned?.
Excuse me.
Areyou married?.
Why?.
I'm just curious.
What doyou think?.
- What?.
- To her?.
- Areyou married to her?.
Not that it's any of
your fucking business, but no.
Why?.
Whose house
Run's house
I said, whose house
Whose house
Say what
Run's house
Martin
She's fuckin' pissed, dude.
She's never gonna fuck us now.
Maybe you,
but definitely not me.
Let me know how she is.
Nobody is fucking me!
You got that?.
I don't know what I was thinking
in that diner...
but being that I've decided to go home,
and not to NewJersey...
sorry for the inconvenience
and good-bye.
You're breaking up with us?.
Who the hell doyou think
you are, lady?.
You can't just go around
breaking people's hearts like that!
I fell in love with you!
We fell in love with you!
Guys like us just don't fall out
ofthe fuckin' sky.
Beautiful, naked, big-tittied women
just don't fall out ofthe sky.
No heartbeat.
Think someone threw him out ofa plane
with a message written on him...
Iike in ConAir?.
- Did you ever see that flick?.
- Oh, did that suck!
- ConAir?. Con Shit.
- Kill it!
- Sounds familiar.
-Jesus, areyou okay?.
Yeah, it's Rufus.
And yeah, I'm fine.
He's the fucking undead!
Cut his head off!.
What I just did gave me
a fucking migraine!
So ifyou don't pipe down, I'm gonna
yankyour sac offlike a paper towel.
Speaking ofwhich,
you're awfully nude.
- Rufus, is it?.
- Yes, Rufus it is.
It's usually Long Rufus, but it's
a little cold out here. You understand?.
Big Papa, how about lending a brother
your coat till I find my own threads?.
Dude, he fell out ofthin air.
Dude, his piece is gonna be rubbing
inside ofyour armor.
- Dude!
- Thanks a lot, baby.
I'll do my best to tuck it back.
It's been a while since physics
but I would think...
the impact with which you hit
the asphalt would have liquefied you.
Death is a worry ofthe living.
The dead, like myself, onlyworry
about decay and necrophiliacs.
- Told you he was the undead.
- Not the undead. The dead.
I died.
Christ told me the secret
to the resurrection once.
We were at this wedding in Caanan.
I got drunk and forgot it.
Wait, wait, wait.
Christ?.
You knew Christ?.
Knew him?.
Shit, nigga owes me 1 2 bucks.
Let me guess.
- You're another angel?.
- Oh, I ain't no angel.
I'm a man,just likeyou and him.
Well, maybe not him.
At least I was a man.
Been dead nearly 2,000 years.
Here, check this out.
Nowonder he sawJesus.
Homey's rockin' the ganj.
It's not a joint.
I can't read this.
It's Aramaic. It says,
"" Rufus, seeyou in twoyears.Jesus.""
Freaked me out because He basically
told me when my numberwas up.
Took all the flavor out ofthe
remaining years. We gotta get moving.
Let's saywe continue this discussion
over a two-piece and a biscuit. Come on.
I'm starvin'.
Back off, Kato.
Wait a second!
Between guys with wings,
guys falling out ofthe sky...
and guys trying like hell
to fuck me...
I think I've been a pretty good sport
about all this so far.
But I'm not going anywhere until
I find out where the hell you came from.
Me?. I came from Heaven.
Now let's start walkin'.
Walk?. Fuckyou! Doyou know
how farwe are from anywheres?.
Hey, man, back in the old days
with J.C., we used to walk everywhere.
Did you ever hear of
a fat apostle?.
What the hell's an apostle?.
Let me get this straight.
She's already met the prophets...
and the apostle's with them?.
I think that our best course
of action...
is to ensure that our parcel
is not found.
And being that I can't even
trustyou enough to kill a woman...
well, I'm left with no choice...
but to seek outside assistance
in guarding said package.
I'm gonna have to summon
the Golgothan.
I appreciate the loan, brother.
You can have that back.
Man, I rememberwhen all we used to have
for breakfast was fish and goat's milk.
- What doyou call this shit?.
- Egga Mooby Muffin.
Now, how 'boutyou start explaining
some things, like for starters...
how did you know
where to find us?.
Doyou know what the dead do
with most oftheir time?.
Watch the living.
Especially in the shower.
I can't wait to die.
And why areyou watching me?.
Becauseyou're the one who's gonna
help me get some changes made...
in that book
you put so much stock in.
- Hustler?.
- The Bible!
- What's your beefwith the Bible?.
- For starters, I'm not in it.
Neither are any of us, butyou
don't hear us bitchin' and moanin'.
But I'm supposed to be in it.
I was the 1 3th Apostle.
I've gone to church mywhole life and
never heard of Rufus, the 1 3th Apostle.
Butyou heard of
the other 1 2 Apostles.
Theywere all white boys, I might add.
But no mention of me, Rufus.
And why is that?.
'Cause I'm a black man.
Butyou know what?.
That's just my pet peeve.
I'm mainly here to correct a major error
you've been basing your faith on.
- What's that?.
-Jesus wasn't white.Jesus was black.
I don't buy it.
Ifthat's true, why did He get
written about and you were left out?.
Well, He is the Son ofGod.
Kind ofhard to have
a New Testament without him.
Soyou fudge a few facts,
you put a spin on his ethnicity.
Leaving me out is okay 'causeyou
still got 1 2 white boys to choose from.
- Areyou gonna listen to this shit?.
- That's what people of Antioch said...
right before they stoned my ass.
You were martyred?.
That's one way of puttin' it.
Anotherway is to say I was bludgeoned
to shit by big fucking rocks.
White folks onlywanna hear
the good shit--
Iife eternal,
a place in God's Heaven.
But as soon as you hear
thatyou're gettin' this good shit...
from a blackJesus, ya freak.
And that, my friends,
is called hypocrisy.
A black man can steal your stereo,
but he can't beyour savior.
You gonna eat that hash brown?.
So, you went to Heaven?.
Damn right I went to Heaven!
That's the least He could do.
In the threeyears I followed His ass
around Jerusalem, did I ever get laid?.
Hell no.
And I was in my prime.
I could have been knee-deep
in shepherds' daughters...
not to mention fine-ass
Mary Magdalene.
She had a thing for dark meat,
ifyou follow me.
Maybe this is just me talking,
but ifl were in Heaven...
I wouldn't care what the Bible said
as long as they got the message right.
The message is what counts.
But folks who build theirfaith
on that message should be colorblind.
And all my rabble-rousing
is not doing that much above.
So I'm gonna need
some help down here.
That's why I'm gonna helpyou stop those
angels from gettin' into that church...
in exchange foryou helping me
with my campaign.
How doyou know about that,
the angels?.
- Isn't much I don't know aboutyou.
- I find that hard to believe.
When you were five, you let a kid
from next door piss on your hand.
You did that shit?.
You're nasty.
I never told anybody about that.
Neither did he.
Two years later,
that kid died ofleukemia.
His name was Brian Johnson.
Your exploits,
no matter how inane...
are well documented in Heaven.
Probably Hell too.
Where areyou going?.
Tell me somethin' about me.
You masturbate more than anyone
on the planet.
Fuck. Everyone knows that.
Tell me something nobody knows.
When you do it,
you're thinking about guys.
- Dude, not all the time.
- Sorry ifl scared you.
Two-thirds of me wants to
forget about this and go home.
Yesterday, I wasn't sure
God even existed.
Now I'm up to my ass
in Christian mythology.
Let me letyou in
on a little inside info.
God hates it when
it's referred to as ""mythology.""
Oh, well, then let's ask the ""prophets""
what we should call it instead.
Where did those two assholes go?.
What areyou doing?.
Proving to this bastard
I ain't gay.
- What?.
- Long story. Forget it.
We gotta get movin'.
How can we get toJersey?.
We'll take the train.
I'll call for reservations.
I thought she looked familiar.
- Who?.
- Serendipity.
Morning, shoppers.
Good morning.
- Has anyone seen the overnights?.
- No, sir.
We creamed 'em.
Last night was a rerun,
which says to me--
Do I smell onions?.
Excuse me.
May I askwhatyou're doing
in my boardroom?.
You may proceed, mon ami.
I'm gonna have to start
by apologizing.
My friend has a bit of a penchant
for the dramatic.
Oh, come on!
Relax. I'm doing it.
Mooby, the Golden Calf.
Created by Nancy Goldruff,
a former kindergarten teacher in 1 989.
Bought by the Complex Corporation
in 1 991.
Broadcast nationally
as the "" Mooby Fun-Time Hour.""
Since its inception,
has spawned two theatrical films...
1 6 records,
8 prime-time specials...
and a library
of priced-to-own videocassettes.
Not to mention
bicoastal theme parks...
dubbed "" MoobyWorld.""
Did I miss anything?.
You forgot Mooby Magazine.
Damn it!
Is there a point to this?.
You and your board are idolaters.
I can't believe you forgot
the magazine.
That's you.
Do you know much about voodoo?.
That's a fascinating practice.
No real doctrine offaith to speak of.
More an arrangement
of superstitions...
the most well-known ofwhich...
is the voodoo doll.
You see...
a mockup of an individual
is subjected...
to various pokes and prods.
The desired result is that
the individual will feel those effects.
Call security, now!
All lines are currently down.
- I'm gonna have to apologize--
- Would you knock it off?.
You're doing it again.
Stop. What did we talk about?.
You are responsible
for raising an icon...
which draws worship
from the Lord.
You have broken
the First Commandment.
More than that,
I'm afraid not a one ofyou...
passes for a decent human being.
Your continued existence
is a mockery of morality.
Likeyou, Mr. Burton.
Lastyear, you cheated on yourwife
of 1 7 years 8 times.
You even had sex
with her best friend...
whileyou were supposed to be home
watching the kids.
In the bed thatyou
and yourwife share, no less.
Mr. Newman.
You gotyour girlfriend drunk
at lastyear's Christmas party...
and then paid a kid
from the mail room...
to have sex with her
while she was passed out...
just soyou could break up
with her guilt-free...
when she sobbingly confessed
in the morning.
She killed herself
three months later.
Mr. Brace disowned his gay son.
Very compassionate.
Mr. Ray put his mother
in a third-rate nursing home...
and used the profits
from the sale ofher home...
to buy an Oriental rug for himself.
Heavens.
Mr. Barker flew to Thailand
on the company account...
to have sex
with an eleven-year-old boy.
Mr. Holtzman okayed the production
of Mooby Dolls...
from materials he knew
to be toxic and unsafe...
because it was-- survey says--
Iess costly.
You, on the other hand...
are an innocent.
You lead a good life.
Good foryou.
But you, Mr. Whitland...
you have more skeletons
in your closet...
than this assembled party.
I cannot even mention them aloud.
You're his father,
you sick fuck!
- Good.
- Not bad, man.
That's great work.
Very good.
Well...
alone at last.
With the exception of Miss Pryce here...
there isn't a decent human being
amongstyou.
Not one.
Doyou know what makes
a human being decent?.
Fear.
And therein lies the problem.
None ofyou has anything
left to fear anymore.
You rest comfortably in seats
ofinscrutable power...
hiding behind your false idol,
far from judgment...
Iives shrouded in secrecy,
even from one another.
But not from God.
Forgot my little voodoo doll.
Man, it really looks
just likeyou, doesn't it?.
Look, ifl believed enough in this...
I wonder--
Come on.
I don't believe in voodoo.
Voodoo.
But I do believe in this.
Don't run! Don't run!
Fakes! Fakes!
All ofyou, fakes!
"" But I do believe in this.""
What does that mean?.
And one to grow on.
Gum?.
Go on. It's okay.
You've done nothing wrong.
These guys were fakes.
You're a pure soul.
Butyou didn't say ""God bless you""
when I sneezed.
Loki!
You're getting offlight.
- Loki!
- I know. I'm comin'.
You're so lucky.
I forgotyou were down here.
How long now?.
Threeyears this August.
Let me guess-- the 1 4th Apostle, left
out ofthe Bible because she's a woman?.
This girl's no woman.
Oh. Those weren't tits
I sawJay cozying up to?.
What, these?.
You should know better than anyone here
that tits don't make a woman.
Hell, the tubby, coat-wearing
motherfucker's got tits.
What traditionally defines a woman
falls between two things--
her legs.
But as you can see...
I lack definition.
Hey, they're gettin' a free show!
Let me see that shit!
Oh, God,
another angel like Metatron.
How doyou--
How does she know Metatron?.
This is the last scion.
You're kidding.
Wow.
I'm confused.
Bethany, Serendipity here
isn't technically an angel.
Nor is she, by any means,
a human being like I was and you are.
- I used to be an abstract.
- Now I'm really confused.
I'm a muse, stupid.
I can't take much more ofthis.
Soyou, what, inspire people?.
What just went down
with your friends over there--
It doesn't really take a muse to inspire
horny retards to empty theirwallets.
I used to specialize
in entertainment.
For example, I'm responsible for 1 9 of
the 20 top-grossing films ofall time.
- Nineteen?.
- Yeah.
The one about the kid
by himselfin his house...
burglars trying to come in
and he fights them off--
I had nothing to do
with that one.
Somebody sold their soul to Satan to get
the grosses up on that piece of shit.
What areyou doing stripping?.
Rememberwhy I left?.
Becauseyou were tired of getting
none ofthe credit foryour ideas.
So I opted to quit being a muse
and write for myself.
I gave my two weeks notice,
got a body, 50 bucks...
and got sent out into the world
to make my fortune.
So what happened?.
Writer's block.
Can you believe it?.
Me, a muse, for God's sake.
I can inspire anyone I meet and give out
a zillion and nine ideas a second...
but I can't keep any for myself.
Her quirky sense ofhumor.
- Whose?.
- God's.
- You're saying God's a woman?.
- Was there ever a doubt in your mind?.
He's always referred to as "" Him.""
That's not how I wrote it.
But one ofthe drawbacks
to being intangible...
is thatyou have no say
in the editorial process.
The people that held the pens
added their own perspective...
and all the penholders were men.
So She became a He.
Doesn't stop with God either.
The whole book's gender-biased.
A woman's responsible
for original sin.
A woman cuts Samson coif of power.
A woman asks for the head
ofJohn the Baptist.
Read that book again.
Women are painted as bigger antagonists
than the Egyptians and Romans combined.
It stinks.
Why is the last scion here?.
Bartleby and Loki.
They found a way back.
- Not the plenary indulgence loophole.
- You know about that?.
I always knew that thing
was a bad idea.
Leave it to the Catholics
to destroy existence.
You have issues with Catholicism,
I take it?.
I have issues with anyone who treats God
like a burden instead of a blessing...
Iike some Catholics.
You people don't celebrateyour faith,
you mourn it.
-Ifwe're wrong, what religion is right?.
-It's not about who's right orwrong.
No denomination's nailed ityet...
because they're all
too self-righteous to realize...
that it doesn't matterwhatyou have
faith in,just thatyou have faith.
Your hearts are in the right place,
butyour brains gotta wake up.
They made me and Silent Bob
part ofthe gang.
Who fuckin' farted?.
Not born.
Shit into existence.
Sweet Christ,
somebodywants you bad!
- What is that thing?.
- An excremental.
- The Golgothan.
- A what?.
A shit demon!
No man ofwoman born!
- Friend ofyours?.
- Is this smelly fuckwith us?.
It came for Bethany!
Smoke that motherfucker
like it ain't no thang!
I knew I's gonna
whack somebody today!
Getyour fuckin' hand back.
Represent!
Go! Go! Go!
Looks like we're in charge
ofthe gang now.
Over the bar!
- Where did that thing come from?.
- Ever heard ofGolgotha?.
The hill where Christ
was crucified.
It wasn't just Christ.
The Romans crucified everyone there.
Christ excluded, theywere criminals--
killers, brigands, thieves, rapists.
Whenever the crucified expired,
their bodies lost muscle control...
spilling bowel and bladder
in the process...
the result ofwhich
is that walking pile of crap--
the Golgothan shit demon,
Hell's chiefassassin.
It's here foryou, girlie.
- Bob, get down!
- Matches! Matches!
- Hey, man.
- How?.
"" Knocks strong odors out.""
- Way to go, biggie.
- Whywould you ever carry this?.
What?.
Whoever sent this might send more.
I suggest you take the princess
and get as far away as possible.
I'll try to get something
out of poopy boy here.
Ifhe tells me something,
I'll letyou know.
Hello. We'd like two tickets
to NewJersey, please.
Jersey's sold out, sir.
- What?.
- There's one at the same time tomorrow.
Don't underestimate the staggering
drawing power ofthe Garden State.
Show up two hours in advance.
Nice.
Your hard-on for smiting
has prevented us from negotiating...
what ought to be the relatively simple
matter of catching or staying on a bus.
Bus, schmuss.
Why should we fall victim to gravity
when we can just as easily rise above?.
- You mean fly?.
- We got wings, right?.
Fuck, let's use 'em!
I wouldn't suggest that.
You see, kids...
you wouldn't want to look like
a couple offairies, now, would you?.
How'd you get out of Hell?.
I told them I was coming up
on a routine possession.
I don't have much time. Ifthey figure
out my ruse, they'll come after me.
-What's with bringing us in here?.
-You two are inches from getting caught.
Going around killing people,
about to uncaseyourwings.
Don'tyou know what's going on?.
Well, we're going home.
Really. Areyou so clueless as to think
you can justwaltz back into Heaven?.
- Why not?.
- Everybody is looking foryou.
Both sides.
Above and below.
Orders are to terminateyou
on sight.
- Really?.
- Why?.
Because you're pissing people off,
that's why.
Word is that God's pissed off
at your presumption...
and I know Lucifer's pissed because
you assholes might make him look bad...
by succeeding
where he's failed so many times.
- So they're just gonna kill us?.
- They're gonna try.
That's whyyou have to travel
incognito.
Tone down your behavior.
Stay offtheir respective radars.
Quit killing people.
That's high profile.
- Oh, lighten up.
- I can't believe theywanna kill us.
Oh, believe it, boys.
They've even got the last scion
looking foryou.
- Really?.
- You're kidding.
This is huge. Your reentry
is a thorn in a lot ofsides.
They'll stop at nothing
to prevent it.
In the meantime, I suggestyou find
an alternate mode oftransportation.
Ifanything else comes up,
I'll contactyou.
Thankyou, Azrael.
You're a true friend.
I have to get back to the pit
before they get suspicious.
And remember, incognito.
Howyou coping, kid?.
It's weird.
Just when I think
I have a handle on things...
something wholly unbelievable
presents itself.
Sometimes I wish
I'd just stayed home.
You sound like the Man.
What's he like?.
He likes to listen to people talk.
Christ loved to sit around the fire,
listen to me and the other guys.
Wheneverwe were going on
about unimportant shit...
he always had a smile
on his face.
His only real beefwith mankind...
is the shit that gets carried out
in His name.
Wars, bigotry, televangelism.
The big one, though,
is the factioning ofall the religions.
He said mankind
got it all wrong...
bytaking a good idea
and building a beliefstructure on it.
You're saying having beliefs
is a bad thing?.
I just think it's better
to have ideas.
You can change an idea.
Changing a beliefis trickier.
People die for it.
People kill for it.
The whole of existence
is in jeopardy right now...
because ofthe Catholic beliefstructure
regarding this plenary indulgence shit.
Bartleby and Loki,
whether they know it or not...
are exploiting that belief...
and ifthey're successful...
you, me, all ofthis
ends in a heartbeat.
All over a belief.
I haven't seen the moron twins
in a while. How aboutyou?.
One time we were at the mall,
we tied Tubby to the ceiling...
and he went flying through the air,
fuckin' crashed through thewall.
Itwas fucked up.
You two aren't getting into
anytrouble, areyou?.
We'rejust about to smoke a fatty
with these two suave motherfuckers...
who just got on at the last stop--
Larry and Barry.
So,Jay tells us
you're gonna sleep with him.
Hit this shit, man.
It's good stuff.
Oh, fuck.
That's some bad shit, dude.
You hit that?.
Yeah, you're bad, dude.
Bad shit.
Why areyou
heading to NewJersey?.
It's just this thing I have to do.
We're going home.
Oh.
Doyou two live together?.
Unfortunately, yes.
So, how long haveyou two
been together?.
A while.
He can be pretty flaky sometimes,
but we have a lot in common.
How'd you meet?.
We were stationed together.
See, that's beautiful.
Everybody's always up in arms
about this ""out in the military"" issue.
Pardon?.
You know, there's all the macho bullshit
about it being ""this man's army.""
You two meet there, hook up--
You thinkwe're lovers?.
No, no. We're not gay.
Oh, God.
I'm sorry.
- I just assumed.
- Do I come off as gay?.
My ex-husband sort of screwed up
my relationship awareness barometer.
- You're divorced.
- That's a nice way of putting it.
I call it being dumped.
I was...
dumped once.
Don'tyou just constantly
question yourvalue?.
Like, whywas I so easy
to cast aside?.
And you wonder ifthe other party
is gonna come to their senses...
and call you back.
They always tell you
it'll hurt less with time.
When actually...
it hurts more.
You know what we need?.
What do we need?.
We need drinks.
We need a lot of drinks.
Garcon.
You still go to church?.
Every Sunday.
Does it do anything foryou?.
It gives me time to balance
my checkbook everyweek.
That's what I'm saying. People don't
go to church to feel spiritual anymore.
They go to church and feel bored...
but they keep going everyweek
just out ofhabit.
I am so buzzed.
When doyou think
you lostyour faith?.
I remember the exact moment.
I was on the phone with my mother...
and she was trying to counsel me
through this--
this thing.
And when nothing she was saying
was making me feel any better...
she said...
"" Bethany...
God has a plan."
I was-- I was so angrywith her.
I was like...
""What about my plans??"
- You know?.
- Mm-hmm.
I had planned
to have a family...
with my husband.
Wasn't that plan
good enough for God?.
Apparently not.
How aboutyou?.
How'd you loseyour faith?.
A long time ago.
One day God just stopped listening.
I kept talking, but I got the distinct
impression He wasn't listening anymore.
How did you know She was listening
in the first place?.
Well, I guess I don't.
I hate thoughts like that.
But, you know,
they come toyou with age.
'Cause when you're a kid you never
question the whole faith thing.
God's in Heaven, and He's--
She's always got her eye on you.
I'd give anything
to feel that way again.
Guess that's why
I got talked into this pilgrimage.
Where is this pilgrimage to?.
- You wouldn't believe me ifl told you.
- Try me.
All right, but I warned you.
Okay.
I'm going to this church
in NewJersey.
Really.
Kerwood Mandel to car three.
See, I'm supposed to stop
a couple of angels...
from going into the church.
They're trying--
Shit.
They're trying
to get back into Heaven.
See, they got tossed
out of Heaven...
years ago, right?.
And ifthey get back in...
it proves God wrong...
and since God is infallible...
to prove Herwrong...
would, you know, unmake existence.
May I haveyourattention, please.
The dining car will be closing
in five minutes. Thank you.
I feel so stupid...
just saying it.
The thing I don't get is...
how am I supposed to stop
an angel?.
Two, even!
I guess I'm supposed to
talk them out of it or something.
Maybeyou're supposed to kill them.
Oh, yeah, right.
Kill them.
I mean, even ifthat were the case,
which it's not...
how doyou kill an angel, Barry?.
Oh...
I don't suppose
it's much different from...
killing a human.
Where is everybody?.
I wake up and--
- The apostle.
- Holy shit!
Rufus, I wantyou to meet
my new friend Barry.
Don't be such a show-off, Barry.
Take it easy, Bartleby.
Just let her go.
- We can talk about this.
- Bartleby?.
After all this time, it comes down
to slaughter by a meat puppet?.
Get your fucking hands off me,
you dickless son of a bitch!
Save it. Five minutes ago
you were aching to top me off.
Loki!
Holy shit. The apostle.
I didn't come in you, Pete,
I swear.
What areyou doing here?.
This woman has to stop two angels
from entering a church.
- Us?.
- No, two other fucking angels.
I'd say there's a pretty good chance.
Rufus, we're to be liquidated?.
You haven't thought about
the consequences ofyour reentry.
Consequences, schmonsequences.
We're going home,
no matterwhose pride it may hurt.
- It's not a matter of pride!
- Loki, kill the girl.
What areyou, high?. I can't kill her
ifshe hasn't done anything.
Fine.
I'll kill her myself.
I fall asleep
and everyone takes off?.
- These guys are fuckin' flat-leavers.
- Shut his mouth.
Oh, shit!
Jay!
Biggie!
The door! The door!
Can't we talk about this?.
Why don't I just get off
at the next stop!
No ticket.
- The apostle is here.
- I noticed.
- Then you know who she was, don't you?.
- The scion, I imagine!
Maybe we should rethink
this whole thing.
I mean, you heard the guy.
He said there are consequences.
And Azrael tells us we're marked?.
There's more to this than we thought of.
I was close.
You know?. I was so close
to slitting that bitch's throat.
Whoa.
You know how I felt?.
Righteous.
Justified.
Eager, even.
You all right?.
Your eyes are kinda--
My eyes are open.
For the first time I get it.
When that little innocent girl
let her mission slip, I had an epiphany.
See, in the beginning it was
just us and Him-- angels and God.
Then He created humans.
Ours was designed to be
a life ofservitude and worship...
and bowing and scraping and adoration.
He gave them more than He ever gave us.
He gave them a choice.
They choose to acknowledge God
or choose to ignore Him.
All this time
we've been down here...
I've felt the absence
ofthe Divine Presence...
and it's pained me,
as I'm sure it must have pained you.
And why?.
Because ofthe way He made us.
Had we been given free will we could
choose to ignore the pain, like they do.
But no, we're servants.
Okay.
All I'm saying here is that
one of us might need a little nap.
Wake up! These humans have besmirched
everything He's bestowed upon them.
Theywere given paradise;,
they threw it away.
Theywere given this planet;
they destroyed it.
Theywere favored best
among all His endeavors...
and some ofthem
don't even believe He exists!
And in spite ofit all...
He has shown them
infinite fucking patience...
at every turn.
What about us?.
I asked you once...
to lay down the sword
because I felt sorry for them.
What was the result?.
Our expulsion from paradise.
Where was His
infinite fucking patience then?.
It's not right!
It's not fair!
We've paid our debt!
Don'tyou think it's time?.
Don'tyou think it's time
we went home?.
And to do that, I thinkwe may have to
dispatch ourwould-be dispatchers.
Wait. Wait, wait.
Kill them?.
You're talking about the last scion,
for Christ's sake.
And what aboutJay and Bob?.
Those guys were all right.
Don't.
Don't, my friend.
Don't letyour sympathies
get the best ofyou.
They did me once.
Scion or not...
she's just a human...
and by passing through that arch
our sins are forgiven.
No harm, no foul.
My God.
I've heard a rant like this before.
What did you say?.
- I've heard a rant like this before.
- Don'tyou do that to me.
- You sound like the morning star.
- You shutyour fucking face!
You sound like Lucifer, man!
You've fucking lost it!
You're not talking about
going home, Bartleby.
You're talking about
fucking war on God.
Well, fuck that.
I have seen what happens to the proud
when they take on the Throne.
I'm going back to Wisconsin.
We're going home, Loki...
and no one, notyou,
not even the Almighty Himself...
is gonna make that otherwise.
Shit.
Why couldn't we stay on the train?.
You threw those guys off.
Very basic strategy.
Ifyour enemies know whereyou are,
then don't be there.
Why are we enemies?.
Well, I know I'd perceive the person
sent to kill me as an enemy.
What does that mean?. Since when
am I supposed to kill anybody?.
I'm tired
of all this cryptic bullshit.
I'm physically and psychologically
exhausted, Rufus...
and I'm ready to kick back
and welcome the end of existence...
unless you come clean right now.
Why me?.
Out of all the people
on the goddamn planet, whywas I tapped?.
Imagineyou're a 1 2-year-old boy.
You're told you're God's only son,
but more than that, you're God.
How long doyou think it would take to
come to grips with something that huge?.
Maybe, say, 1 8 years?.
In the Bible,Jesus suddenly
goes from age 1 2 to 30. 1 2 to 30.
Now, that's some pretty bad
storytelling.
Where are the volumes oftext
dealing with the missing 1 8 years?.
I'll tell you where.
Theywere offered up as a sacrifice
to the god of ecumenical politics.
You make it sound like
there's some church conspiracy...
to cover up
""the truth about Christ.""
Oh, bullshit.
Any important material
about Christ...
would give people a better understanding
ofthe nature ofGod.
- Whywould they leave any ofit out?.
- Because it's tied in with His family.
- His mother and father.
- His brothers and sisters.
Jesus didn't have brothers and sisters.
Marywas a virgin.
Mary gave birth to Christ without having
known a man's touch. This is true.
But she did have a husband.
Doyou really think hewould've stayed
married to her for all thoseyears...
ifhe wasn't gettin' laid?.
The nature ofGod and theVirgin Birth,
those are leaps offaith.
But to believe a married couple never
got down, that's just plain gullibility.
Meaning?.
The blood that flows
through yourveins...
shares a chromosome or two
at the genetic level...
with the oneyou call Jesus.
Bethany, you are...
the great-great-great-great-great-great-
great-great-great-great-grandniece...
ofJesus Christ.
So, that would make Bethany
part black?.
I can't do this anymore.
Whereyou gonna go?.
You know what I'm saying is right.
- It's bullshit.
- Bethany.
It's bullshit!
Let her go, man.
Give her time.
Why?.
What the fuck do You want from me?.
I fucking hate You!
I hate You.
He can't hearyou, you know.
That's whywe needed you.
Why didn'tyou tell me?.
Would you--
Could you have believed me?.
It was something
you had to come to gradually.
Only after everything you've seen...
everything you've heard...
could you possibly be able
to accept the truth.
I don't want this.
It's too big.
That's whatJesus said.
I had to tell Him.
You can imagine
how that hurt the Father...
not to be able
to tell the Son Himself...
because oneword from His lips would
destroythe boy's frail human form.
So I had to deliver the news
to a scared child...
who wanted nothing more
than to playwith other children.
I had to tell this little boy
that He was God's only son...
and it meant a life of persecution
and eventual crucifixion...
at the hands ofthe very people
He'd come to enlighten and redeem.
He begged me to take it all back.
As ifl could.
He begged me to
""make it all not true.""
I'll letyou in on something, Bethany,
something I've never told anyone before.
Ifl had the power...
I would have.
It's unfair.
It's unfair to ask a child
to shoulder that responsibility...
and to askyou to do the same now.
I sympathize. I do.
I wish I could take it all back.
But I can't.
This...
is whoyou are.
Everything I am has been a lie?.
Knowing whatyou now know
doesn't mean you're not whoyou were.
You are...
Bethany Sloane.
No one can take that away from you,
not even God.
All this means is
a redefinition ofthat identity.
The incorporation ofthis new data
into whoyou are.
Be whoyou've always been.
Just...
be this as well...
from time to time.
Guess this means
no more cheating on my taxes.
To say the least.
Doyou mind ifwe adjourn
to somewhere...
a tad more habitable...
and a bit warmer?.
Fuck, I think this shit
just kicked in.
Weren't we just in the woods?.
What are we doing here now?.
Going out in style.
- The voice.
- The apostle.
Now, who's this motherfucker?.
The voice ofGod.
Show some respect.
Oh, the voice ofGod.
Where's the rest of Him?.
Funnyyou should mention that.
We're not sure.
- What?.
- Didn't it ever occur toyou...
that this Bartleby-Loki situation was
well within the sphere of His control?.
Yes, but then whywas she tapped?.
You know those constitutionals
that He likes to take?.
""Constitutionals""?.
I thinkwe're beyond euphemisms
at this point.
God's a skeeball fanatic.
The Lord has quite a fancy for the game.
He's been playing it foryears.
He assumes a human form once a month
and indulges.
Doesn't tell anyone where He's playing.
He just goes away for a couple ofhours.
And He always gives His free points away
to neighborhood children.
Isn't that sweet?.
But She hasn't come back
from one ofthese day trips?.
No, ""She"" hasn't...
and we've been unable to locate "" Her.""
He could've been killed.
Human form does have that drawback.
No, there's a different sort
offoul play afoot, children.
Whomever has set the renegade angels
on their path...
and is keeping them
quite well hidden...
is also responsible
for the Lord's whereabouts.
Were He to be killed in human form...
He'd have returned
immediately to Heaven.
Someone knew enough...
to keep Him biologically alive...
but incapacitate Him
in another fashion.
And as omnipotent as we are above...
I have to admit that we're
more or less lost without His presence.
We've looked everywhere for Him.
I tapped her because I thought we'd be
able to smoke out whoever's behind this.
But whoever he is has been clever enough
to send some lackeys afteryou...
as opposed to showing up
themselves.
Could it be Lucifer?.
Not Lucifer.
Ifhe was, he'd have made
his move by now to conquer Heaven.
And I know he's not responsible
for Bartleby and Loki...
because he's had just as much to lose
by their return as anybody else.
What do we do now?.
I saywe get drunk,
'cause I'm all out ofideas.
Why don't we just ask this guy
to close the church?.
I beg your pardon?.
The guy in charge
ofthe church thing.
Cardinal Glick?.
Maybe we can ask him
to shut down the church.
Ifit's closed that day, those guys
can't get blessed orwhatever, right?.
Good Lord.
The little stoner's got a point.
Maybe we could talk this guy Glick into
cancelling the rededication ceremony.
""We""?.
Areyou saying you're back in,
Ms. I-Don't-Think-I-Can-Do-This-Anymore?.
I wouldn't want to let the family down,
now would I?.
Well...
the prophets finally
live up to their titles.
Mass attendance is at
an all-time low in this country...
but ifwe can let 'em know the
Catholic Church has a little panache...
we can win 'em back,
even get some new ones.
Excuse me.
Fill them pews, people.
That's the key.
Grab the little ones as well.
Hook 'em while they'reyoung.
- Kinda like the tobacco industry.
- Christ, if onlywe had their numbers.
We really appreciateyou seeing us
this late in the day, Your Eminence.
My friends and I have been traveling
all night in hope oftalking toyou...
about the St. Michael's
rededication ceremony.
You looking to help out in some way?.
We'd likeyou to cancel the ceremony.
I beg your pardon.
There's gonna be a world oftrouble if
tomorrow's ceremony goes on as planned.
Areyou pro-choice?.
The trouble's not from us.
It's from these renegade angels that've
been stuck on Earth since the plagues.
These guys,
they think they're renegade angels.
See, Padre, it goes down like this.
These guys think that by passing through
that archway, they can go to Heaven.
You want me to call offthe ceremony
for that.
Who sentyou?.
We were sent
by Him who is called I Am!
Cute. Really cute.
Playtime with the cardinal is over.
- Worked for Moses.
- Stay out ofthis.
It's not a joke.
I'm telling you, man,
this ceremony's a big mistake.
The Catholic Church
does not make mistakes.
Please! What about the Church's
silent consent ofthe slave trade?.
And its platform of noninvolvement
during the Holocaust?.
All right, mistakes were made.
But one can hardly hold the current
incarnation of Holy Mother Church...
responsible for the oversights of old.
I'm a very important man with important
matters that demand my attention...
so ifyou please--
- But tomorrow--
- Tomorrow goes offwithout a hitch.
Do I make myself clear?.
Neitheryou nor any other influence
short ofthe hand ofGod Himself...
is gonna keep this thing
from going offwithout a hitch.
I can see the headlines now...
ifthere were gonna be any.
"" Existence Erased.""
Don't worry about it.
We evened the score.
Hand it over, Silent Bob.
What up.
You stole the cardinal's driver?.
That's what he gets
for messin' with our girlfriend.
Cross-dressin' fuck.
That's sort of sweet.
Thanks, guys.
What do we do now
about Bartleby and Loki?.
I guess we're gonna
have to try and kill 'em.
- You said they couldn't be killed.
- Correction.
Theywon't be killed.
And just to ensure that,
we're all gonna sit tight...
right here...
until those two idiots
pass through that arch.
There's only one idiot here,
Azrael...
and I'm looking right at him.
Muse!
Just in time tojoin us
for a drink.
Hey.
Where'd you come from?.
- Where'd you come from?.
- Me?.
Nothingness.
And that's where I'm returning to
in approximately, oh, one hour.
All right, Plato,
sounds likeyou've had enough already.
- Let's go.
- Oh, darn it!
Come on, barkeep,just one drink.
One for the road, then I'm gone?.
I was trying to find you to tell you
I figured out who was behind all this.
Is that who I think it is?.
- None other than.
- Who is he?.
All right, one drink.
Then you're gone.
Give me a...
Holy Bartender.
Never heard ofit.
He doesn't know how to make
a Holy Bartender.
You do, don'tyou, Muse?.
Don't.
Anybody?.
No?.
Well, I know how to make
a Holy Bartender.
Get it?.
Sweet Jesus, Azrael!
Why?.
Come on, Demon! Try that shit
on somebodywho's already dead!
Oh, Apostle, you maintain
that kind of an attitude...
and you and the barkeep won't be
the only corpses in the room.
The Christ bitch will join you.
Areyou really that stupid?.
You do know what's gonna happen
ifthose two jerks enter that church.
I'm actually counting on it.
And if my calculations
are correct...
the pawns are moving into checkmate
as we speak.
"" Holy Bartender."" I get it.
That's a great one!
I'd also like to acknowledge this great
state's governor, Elizabeth Dalton...
for coming this morning.
She's a Protestant, but we're
not gonna hold that against her.
Now, let me just tell you a little bit
ofhistory about this particular...
hundred-years-young house ofGod.
God's house?.
God doesn't live here anymore.
He's grown weary
ofyour superficial faith.
He's turned a deaf ear
toyour lip-service prayers.
- He has abandoned you, his favorites...
- Sorry.
to the whim ofjudgment.
Hypocrites, charlatans...
prepare to taste God's wrath.
-Maybe we should just leave.
-You wanted your body count. You got it.
This lot is rife with sin.
We'll judge them all.
Officer McGhee.
All right, mouthpiece...
Iet's leave the nice cardinal alone
and go for a ride.
Mr. McGhee, don't make me angry.
You wouldn't like me when I'm angry.
Is that so?.
Ladies and gentlemen...
you have been judged as guilty of
violations against our Almighty God...
and this very day...
I assureyou you will all
pay foryour trespasses...
in blood.
- Wings. Now.
- I'm feeling a little exposed here.
Do it!
- So he's a muse too?.
- Former muse.
He was kicked out.
Ever the fucking apple polisher.
Then what happened?.
Yes, what?.
Well, Luciferjust had to start
his little war for the throne.
Heaven became divided
into two factions--
the faithful and the renegades.
Oh, the Ethereal Plains
were chaotic with battle.
Angel against angel.
And when it was all over,
God cast the rebels into perdition.
But Azrael refused to fight.
He remained in the middle,
waiting to see who came out victorious.
What areyou,
some kind offuckin' chicken?.
No.
I was an artist...
stupid!
I was inspiration!
A muse has no place in battle.
So after the fallen
were banished to Hell...
God turned on those
that wouldn't fight...
and Azrael was sent down
with the demons...
something he considers
a great injustice.
Oh, come on.
Don't tell meyou never questioned
the judgment, Serendipity.
No.
It never bothered me.
Soyou were an artist.
Big deal!
Elvis was an artist...
but that didn't stop him from
joining the service in time ofwar.
That's why he is the king...
and you're a schmuck.
Nice.
So all this is about revenge.
You're gonna unmake existence
becauseyou have a grudge against God?.
After the first million years?.
No.
Escape from Hell
became my all-consuming reason.
So I studied the religions and waited
for my opportunity to present itself...
which it finally did...
in Catholicism.
Plenary indulgence.
But I couldn't exercise it.
Demons can't become human.
No, we can't transubstantiate.
But angels can.
Bartleby and Loki.
After that it was a simple matter
ofwaiting for a church...
to celebrate their centennial...
and when that finally happened I sent
the pair an article laced with ideas.
An incantation
I picked up in the pit...
kept them cloaked
and off Heaven's radars.
And aside from the triplets here
and the Golgothan...
no soul in Hell had a clue
as to what was going on.
But the Almighty
could still putsch the whole deal...
so I dispatched Him
in a fairly ingenious fashion.
Her. And how?.
That's the only thing
I couldn't figure out.
Oh, no, I've seen
way too many Bond movies to know...
thatyou never reveal
all the details ofyour plan...
no matter how close
you may thinkyou are to winning.
The only ""X"" factorwas the involvement
ofthe last scion here.
But fat lot of good that did, right?.
I mean, hereyou all are.
Powerless to stop the inevitable.
Look, asshole, I don't know
if anyone explained the rules toyou...
but ifyou succeed everything gets
blinked out of existence, even you.
Human, haveyou ever been to Hell?.
I think not.
I'd rather not exist
than go back to that.
And if everyone has to
go down with me, so be it.
Still thinking only aboutyourself...
you fucking child!
Now, now, now.
Things are getting
too intense in here.
Hey! What say
we watch a little TV?.
Yo, put on channel 9.
Daveyand Goliath.
Actually, I was thinking
more along the lines of current events.
Keep rolling! Keep rolling!
I repeat,
men with huge fucking wings...
have laid waste to St. Michael's!
Bullets don't seem to affect them!
The remainder ofthe crowd
have dropped to their knees...
identifying this
as the fabled apocalypse.
Now, I'm not a man offaith,
but I'm inclined to agree.
Oh, God, please, don 't come any closer!
God, no!
You see that?.
And I told them to keep a low profile.
I 'd be pissed, but in a couple minutes
it's not going to matter anyway.
Oh?.
Oh, now what was that
all about?.
What?.
Oh, nothing.
I had something in my eye.
Now who's the fucking child?.
What did you tell him,
to hit me with the golf club?.
Areyou serious?. I'm a fucking demon.
You'd have him assault mewith a putter?.
You want to play?.
Then we'll play.
One side, Red.
Go ahead, then.
Pick it up.
Call it a gift.
Come on.
That's it.
Take a shot.
Takeyour best fucking shot.
Seriously. I'm not kidding.
Take it. Come on.
Come on, bright boy.
Don'tyou know anything?.
Bethany, bless the sink!
- What?.
-Just do it!
Bless the sink, damn it!
That's whatyou get,
motherfucker.
But I'm a fucking demon.
What just happened?.
He said it himself;.
""I'm a fucking demon.""
Hit a demon with an instrument ofGod,
the pure side so it'll do some damage.
Silent Bob's an instrument ofGod?.
No, but Glick's the kind ofasshole
who'd bless his clubs for a better game.
- But the sink?.
- You've got the divine heritage.
Sanctifying is just
one ofthe fringe benefits.
Remind me to try the water-to-wine thing
at my next party.
- How far away is this church?.
- Three towns over, about ten miles.
- Rufus, grab the gun.
- Ten steps ahead ofyou.
Take the bartender's car.
He won't need it.
The whole fucking world's against us,
dude, I swear to God.
Oh, my God.
And people wonderwhy
I don't go to church anymore.
Are we too late?.
To save these poor schmucks?.
Yeah.
But we still exist.
Where are they?.
They could already be
in the church.
Which means ifthey come out,
nobody touches them.
Areyou shitting me?.
The brother here is gonna shred 'em with
his angel-be-good special. Huh, homey?.
Ifthey pass through that arch,
they come out clean.
And ifthey die,
they go straight up.
And hello!
We know what happens then, right?.
- Why don't theyjust kill themselves?.
- It's a mortal sin.
Die with a mortal sin on your soul and
you burn. They don't want to go to hell.
Then what, are we supposed to just wait
for a solution to fall from the sky?.
Friend ofyours?.
No, that was a cardinal.
You can't tell from his face,
but the rosaries are a dead giveaway.
It's one ofthem!
Kill that motherfucker!
Don'tyou listen?.
- We can't touch him!
- I wasn't. I was gonna shoot his ass.
He's been at it for a while now.
Please! Please!
We ran out of parishioners...
so he just started picking up folk
offthe road and just dropping 'em.
This is just eons of repression
getting purged.
If only they'd let us jerk off.
Whoops.
Take a step back.
Let me go!
Why?.
What areyou trying to prove?.
- All these people!
- Hey, this wasn't my idea!
Jesus Christ!
I just wanted to go home.
But him, you know...
he just lost it.
He realized whoyou were
and whatyou were gonna have to do.
He just snapped.
The funny thing is, this guy
could never even stand to see me work.
He said he felt sorry
foryou people.
Now look at him.
This guy's fuckin' drunker than hell.
Which means he's human now.
His wings have been cut off.
The muse?.
Oh, no way!
I haven't seen you--
You look terrific. Wow!
What's with the tits?.
Can I--
Haveyou walked
through the arch yet?.
Tell me. Have you gone in
and come out through the archwayyet?.
No!
He's back.
We were awaiting your arrival.
Bartleby, wait. Stop.
Listen to me.
You can't go through with this.
Azrael was just using you.
Ifyou go back--
I've become aware ofthe repercussions.
I know what I'm doing.
You sick, twisted fuck!
Bethany.
You, of all people, should understand
what I'm trying to accomplish here.
You too know what it feels like
to be cast aside.
Butyou've only dealt with the pain
a fewyears.
I've dealt with it for a millennia.
Whileyou never seeyour ex-husband or
how blissful he is with his newwife--
and he is--
seeing you people every day on this
perfect world He created foryou...
is a constant reminder...
that though my kind came first...
your kind was most revered.
And whileyou know forgiveness...
we know only regret.
The lesson must be taught.
All are accountable...
even God.
Soon a cadre of police will arrive...
just in time to kill us
as we exit the church.
Then this failed experiment
called existence...
will cease to be.
No. Hey. Hey!
I can't letyou do that,
Bartleby.
This has gone too far.
I might have to takeyou down.
It's okay. Shh.
I'll do it.
My compatriot.
Genocide takes a lot out ofhim.
He's weakened.
You're weak.
More importantly,
he's also a human being...
a condition which carries
two liabilities--
a conscience...
and...
a short life span.
I'm sorry, old friend,
butyou lost the faith.
He's lost it.
We're fucked.
- We're absolutely fucked!
- I hear that shit.
I can't believe this.
We're on the brink of nonexistence,
and God's still nowhere to be found.
- What kind of deity gets kidnapped?.
- Amen to that.
What the hell areyou doing?.
Ifthe whole world's gonna end,
you said you'd fuck me.
- You're a pig.
- Nobody's gonna beat that thing.
We can lay here all comatose like that
John DoeJersey bastard over there...
- orwe can get makin' with the love.
- What did you say?.
Make with the love.
It's a nice way of saying boning.
No, aboutJohn DoeJersey.
That guy, the one theywon't take
offlife support--John DoeJersey.
This is where he's at--
St. Michael's Hospital.
Where's the nearest boardwalk?.
I ain't got time to win you a prize.
We gotta get to the fucking.
- Where is it?.
- Asbury Park, about five miles away.
- Haveyou ever been there?.
- Once, with this chick.
We were about to fuck on the carousel
and I got sick, started puking.
- Do they have skeeball there?.
- Yeah.
That's what I'm talkin' about.
Whateveryou do, stall Bartleby
from going into that church.
Bob, come with me.
Come on!
- How am I supposed to do that?.
- Think of something!
I already did,
but it takes two of us!
I repeat, this is not a drill.
This is the apocalypse.
Please exit the hospital
in an orderly fashion.
Thank you.
Hey, Big Bi rd!
Ready for the counti ng game?.
Count the shel ls, Suck-a-Duck.
No more bullets.
Now, what the fuck
would you do that for?.
Angels have to cut theirwings off
to become human.
You just did him a favor,
stupid!
I hopeyou're the skeeball type.
Oh, Bartleby.
Was Wisconsin really that bad?.
Bow down, stupid!
I'm sorry.
Anyone who isn't dead
or from another plane of existence...
would do well to cover their ears
right about now.
What the fuck?.
Thankyou.
It never ends!
Get off of me.
I wanna see what's up.
What the fuck is this shit?.
Who the fuck areyou, lady?.
Why the fuck did you hug my head?.
Quite a little mouth on him,
isn't there?.
What the fuck is this, The Piano?.
Why ain't this broad talkin'?.
I believe the answers thatyou seek
lie within my companion's eyes.
What the fuck does that mean?.
Has everyone gone fuckin' nuts?.
What the fuck happened
to that guy's head?.
Shh.
Where was she?.
Imprisoned in a body.
Bethany figured it all out.
She's a clever girl, that one.
Hang on a minute.
You missed a bit.
Well, then, you ready
to go back, apostle?.
You ready to make some ofthose
changes I been talking about?.
We'll see.
Muse?.
Seeing as howyou
just had to get involved...
you're welcome
to return with us as well.
First I gotta say good-bye to Bethany.
Where is she?.
Oh, no.
Metatron, is she--
Afraid so.
One ofthe drawbacks to being a martyr
is that you have to die.
But no matter.
All is being taken care of.
How so?.
Wax on, wax off.
How did I--
She can rebuild you.
She has the technology.
She can make you better,
stronger, faster.
That's...
A very relieved deity.
You did well, little girl.
I knewyou'd come 'round.
Your kind always does.
You might want to
take good care ofyourself.
We're gonna need you down the road.
I know.
I'm the last scion.
Well, you're half right.
You were the last scion.
But now...
this...
is the last scion.
I'm pregnant?.
Can't put anything pastyou.
Take care ofthat parcel for us.
She has a world ofwork
ahead ofher.
Thankyou for...
I don't know...
everything.
God, there's a million things
I wish I could askyou...
most ofit questioning your great plan,
and that'd be arrogant of me, I know.
But there is one I need to ask.
I'm sureyou get it all the time, but
how many chances like this will I get?.
Why are we here?.
Didn't I tell you she was funny?.
I really enjoyed meeting you.
It was an honor.
You did so well.
I told you She was a woman.
She's not really a woman.
She's not really anything.
She's something, all right.
Crisis offaith over?.
I think I'm now burdened
with an overabundance.
When it rains, it pours.
Areyou saying you believe?.
But I have a good idea.
Yes!
The Man was right aboutyou.
Now I'm gonna go home
and tell Him so.
And ifyou clean upyour language...
I just might put in
a good word foryou too.
Thanks.
Why don'tyou name the kid
after me?.
Rufus.
Yo, we should go to Quick Stop.
Youse guys
wanna hear something sick?.
I got half a stalk
when she kissed me.
I couldn't help it.
The bitch was hot.
You can't talk to me that way anymore.
I'm gonna be somebody's mother.
You're pregnant?.
You know, when you're pregnantyou can
have sex until the third trimester.
I'll keep that in mind.
So, that wouldmake Bethany
part black?