kth presents
a GNOSIS COMPANY production
Ministry of State Security, China
They’re sending 500 Tokarevs
to North Korea.
Tokarevs?
Confirm it.
I understand.
Lock it down at once.
Yes, sir.
Do you know who I am?!
Give me my phone!
One call from me, you’ll...
Shut up!
The party knows all about it.
Those guns were to be scrapped,
what’s the big deal?
North Korea has never
requested them.
That can’t be!
Where are the guns now?
It’s being transported
to South Korea.
I didn’t know!
I thought they were
bound for the North!
Anyway,
I’ll clean it up!
Release me!
What are you doing?
I’ll take my team and
clean it up in South Korea.
You’re certain you can be covert
carrying out this mission
with your entire team there?
What if you get caught?
How should we do this then?
Send this one over alone.
But she’s just a trainee,
she’ll be up against
an arms dealer.
I know!
That’s why I’m sending her.
Sending her to die?
Chief Chao.
‘The Chinese government
did all it can,
and lost a Beijing University grad
young agent in the process.
What did the South Korean
government do in the meantime?’
We can respond as such.
Dismissed!
Sir.
What if...
she accomplishes her mission?
If she is that talented,
we’ll groom her.
But don’t expect much.
Her mission is to go and die.
MISSION: POSSIBLE
Dope Woo P.I. Agency
What are you doing
with the lights off?
Huh?
I was going to get
some shut eye.
What brings you here?
Sit down.
Want something to drink?
I stopped by for a sec.
We switched hospital.
But I got a call
from the old one.
They said someone paid the bill.
You don’t need to
give this back.
I paid it because
I’m doing well.
I’m super busy lately.
Mr. Woo!
You were in?
The lights were out earlier.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Woo, it’s getting out of hand.
The rent wasn’t deposited yesterday.
Do I always have to
come here to get the rent?
That’s not possible.
Of course it’s possible!
I know you laid off your staff
and having a tough...
Oh! I deposited a check.
You know the bank takes
a few days to get that processed.
All right.
I can check it
with the bank tomorrow.
- Take care.
- Good bye.
So many people
pay me with checks.
Su-han.
Don't worry about us.
Do you understand?
Chinatown, Incheon,
South Korea
Captain.
- Speak Korean.
- Yes, sir.
Hello?
I haven’t forgotten,
I understand.
Was that the director?
It was my wife,
she ordered cosmetics.
I see...
National ID: Yoo Da-hee
Yoo Da-hee?
All intel concerning this op
is in the tablet,
if anything comes up,
call me, don’t message.
Understood.
You will not receive any support,
this is a solo op.
Understood.
This is a really dangerous op,
you could die!
I understand.
It’s been a while,
Agent Ama.
Good to see you,
Agent Chao.
How’s NIS these days?
Not good, we’re getting
weak by the day.
So what’s up?
I have an unofficial favor to ask.
That’s quite serious.
Will you help?
You may be asking too much.
I could get on
my agency’s bad side.
We’ll cover all expenses.
That's a given.
I’ll intro you to
a Russian informant.
Okay, very well.
Kiss time!
Tell your agent to
come to our temp office.
Can I trust you?
If you don’t,
who else can you trust?
We’ve saved each other’s lives.
Wait, what’s that?
It’s an earpiece.
Are you really that jumpy?
Occupational hazard.
Kiss time!
Family men’s secret rendezvous
Could this also be
called an affair?
They’re outed by the Kiss Cam!
We’re cheering for you!
$300.
They’re rare collectibles,
so no haggling.
I came to sublet this place
for a month like before.
What?
Oh, you’re him.
$5,000 like last time?
Yes.
By the way,
after you the last sublet,
I got weird calls and
weird people came by.
Are you with an intelligence agency?
$2,000 more.
I’ll get the cash,
so wipe this place down.
There were a lot of pest.
Sure, it’ll be spick and span!
Ma’am, are you okay?
Why isn’t he coming?
I should’ve cheaped out...
Do I need to sell these?
Go to this address, a covert agent
will help you unofficially.
Don’t forget, don’t ever say
you worked on this together.
Understood, sir.
Welcome.
Sit over here.
Okay...
I can...
What brings you here?
Your boyfriend cheating on you?
Or stalking you?
You didn’t get a call?
What call?
I thought it was all arranged.
Oh, from yesterday!
Don’t you know my captain well?
I guess you could say that,
but not really,
I don’t even know his name.
Right, that makes sense.
What did you hear yesterday?
To use this space,
and to get rid of some pest.
That won’t be necessary this time.
This isn’t an assassination mission.
I just need to gather some intel
and let the police take over.
Assassination?
- Here’s the advance.
- There’s misunderstanding...
Misunderstanding?
It’s nothing.
I’m not someone who doesn’t work
without a full pay upfront...
Oh...
Then can I pay
$10,000 in halves?
No, these are heavy,
I’ll take them.
They’re not heavy at all.
No, it’s okay!
Your name is Woo Su-han?
Yes.
I need to look like I work here,
so can I call you ‘boss’?
That’s a bit much...
‘Chief’ would be more appropriate.
Okay, chief.
What’s your name?
Yoo Da-hee, sir.
You can speak freely,
I’m your employee after all.
Okay, Da-hee.
I didn’t hear about
what my role is exactly.
I see.
Where’s the briefing room?
Briefing room...
There!
You want me to brief you on that?
Why not?
Security isn’t guaranteed here.
It’s all good,
barely anyone comes by.
Can I throw these out?
What?
No!
Holy cow...
I waited a long time
to get this autograph.
Got a new one?
Give it, hold on.
You’re into that?
No, it’s a piece of evidence
I collected.
Don’t worry about it.
SI Chem Park Du-sik
This man is our target.
SI Chem imports rare-earth
elements from China.
Mr. Woo.
You didn’t deposit any checks!
Rent for 3 months.
3 months?
Okay, thank you.
Sorry about that.
- Take care, sir.
- Yeah, sure.
Continue.
This place is not secured.
He’s just a landlord,
this doesn’t make sense to him.
Who did I say this guy was?
What was it, he imports
rare items.
Rare items?
Shrimps, lobsters,
stuff like that.
It’s rare-earth elements.
You only got ‘rare’ right.
Anyway, a few days ago,
they smuggled...
Welcome, how can I help you?
My baby disappeared...
Is that right?
Please sit down.
What are you doing?
I will not steal instant coffee again
Uh, she has sticky fingers...
Ms. Kim, it’s wrong to steal.
Ms. Kim, bring us 2 cups of coffee.
Ice coffee for me.
Me too, with tons of sugar syrup.
Chief.
Where’s coffee?
Go buy some.
What is the name
of your child?
Dorothy.
Do-what?
It’s an English name,
Dorothy.
Korean-American?
No, no.
There are pet detectives
who specialize in these things...
I’ll give you this.
We are the s-pet-cialist.
Please find her.
Don’t worry about a thing.
We find dogs too?
We got retained,
we have to.
Can I continue?
Okay.
All right, so SI Chem...
how many damn times!
Park smuggled 5,000 Tokarevs here
from China a few days ago.
Tokarev? TT-33?
A pistol?
Yes.
Investigating arms smuggling
by ourselves?
What about it?
A case of this scale
should be done by cops!
But cops only get involved
when there is evidence.
So she’s not a cop...
There is no evidence,
so we’re getting involved!
NIS? DSC?
No wonder they pay so much...
What’s with him?
Will he backstab me?
If things go sour,
I’ll bail.
Is there a problem?
Nope.
Park attends a tango café
in Gangnam every night.
I’ll dance with him
and extract his phone.
I’ll hand it over to you,
and you clone it.
Okay.
Do you know how to
clone a phone?
Of course, it’s just illegal.
What we do is illegal.
That sounds right.
But do you know how to tango?
Yes, I learned the basics.
Then I’ll see you...
at the tango café tomorrow.
Don’t forget the dress.
Dress?
That’s a given.
Do I need to wear it
to a practice?
Do you not wear a swimsuit
when swimming?
Oh...
Breathe out.
One, two, three...
Can I help you?
I want to learn tango...
Oh...
We do yoga first
then tango lesson after.
And you can wear something comfy.
Dress is only for competitions.
I knew it...
Do you have anything
to change into?
- Da-hee?
- Yes?
- Don’t fart on me.
- Shut the hell up!
- Hola!
Am I late?
No, we just started.
We are incredible together.
- Sure.
- Good.
Wait...
Your dress is spectacular.
Emergency...
What the, a flip phone?
Come on...
Sent: Mr. Jeon, you’re not reachable.
If you don’t answer by today,
I’ll call the police.
My apologies.
Oh my!
Are you okay?
Are you okay, Mr. Park?
I’m fine...
Yeah, I’m at the café.
What? What do you mean?
What were you doing?!
Mr. Park!
Ms. Lee, please help!
911? Please send help,
a man collapsed.
He’s already dead,
we need to go.
Why should we?
Things will get messy
when the police arrive.
No, we’d be suspicious
if we leave now.
You sure this is okay?
We didn’t do anything,
don’t worry about it.
So... do you two
know each other?
- Yes.
- No.
So do you know
each other or not?
We didn’t know each other,
but got acquainted today,
so we do now.
Met today...
- Mr. Woo Su-han?
- Yes?
You run a private detective agency?
Yes.
Were you at the tango café
to investigate someone?
No, it’s my hobby,
to learn it.
Hobby...
And Ms. Yoo Da-hee.
Yes?
It was your first
tango session today?
Yes.
But you two are all dressed up...
Right? Awkward, no?
Why is she all dressed up
to her first session?
With gloves too!
At least take your
bow tie off!
But why are we
getting investigated?
Because people thought
you two were suspicious.
- Who?
- Everyone.
But that doesn’t mean
we’re charged with a crime.
Right, and his cause of death
was heart attack too.
- So can we leave?
- Yes.
Thank you!
Sir, aren’t they a bit suspicious?
You don’t have
the experience to feel that way,
if you become like me,
you’ll develop intuition.
Look into those two further.
Sir? Why?
They got something,
I’m getting tingly.
So our work’s done?
How so?
The target’s dead.
Park must’ve been used
and killed afterwards.
Come on, you heard him,
it was a heart attack.
High doses of potassium chloride
could induce it with no trace.
You didn’t know?
Of course I knew.
It means professionals
got involved.
So we should report this
and take a step back.
Step back from what?
If you don’t want the job,
return the advance.
I was just testing
your tenacity.
Like hell you did.
Keep those words to yourself,
I can hear them.
Oh yeah, did you clone the phone?
It... was a flip phone.
So? You couldn’t?
It had the wrong plug!
And you never said it was
going to be a flip phone!
Everyone uses smartphones now.
What about the call logs?
I saw.
He texted someone called
‘Mr. Jeon’ recently,
he was going to call the cops
if Jeon wasn’t reachable.
Did you memorize the number?
You didn’t?
They all use burner phones,
why bother memorizing it?
Arms dealer must use burners,
why’d he use his own?
So what the hell
did we do today?
By the way,
where should I drop you off?
In front of the station.
- Which station?
- Daerim.
That’s too far!
So why did you ask?
I thought you’d say
“Closest subway station”!
How could I hop on
a subway in this?
So why did you dress like that?
I dressed like this
because of someone!
It’s about the agent
I’m working with.
I don’t think he’s an agent.
That’s his talent,
no one knew he was an agent.
His codename is Ama Zing
for a reason.
I understand.
So he had no ID
or anything to identify him?
No, he had nothing,
and his phone had no records.
By the way,
I think I saw him recently.
Where?
On YouTube.
He was on a Kiss Cam
with a guy,
and outed as a gay
at the baseball game.
It went viral online.
So he attempted suicide
by running into traffic?
That sounds plausible.
That’s not right...
I’m going to save this man
no matter what.
Hang in there.
Why are you late?
Working, obviously.
Lost Puppy
We have to do this too?
We got paid, so yeah.
All right.
Why are you here?
I thought we were done.
You didn’t see the news?
Rodeo mob boss was
shot to death.
Last night.
Get him!
Then what?
Guns are already on the streets?
That’s what we have to find out.
Do you know anyone
who’s connected to that world?
“That world”?
Yeah, mobs and gangs.
How do I know that,
cops should though.
If you don’t feel like working,
cough up the advance.
I know an expert in that world.
Then let’s go!
It costs money, that’s why.
How much?
$2,000.
Here.
You sure about this?
Totally sure,
he’s like a fortune teller.
It’s been so long.
Yup.
We actually came to
a real fortune teller?
He’s famous among gangsters,
he’s an insider.
What brings you here today?
Your sexual compatibility?
- No!
You sure?
You two will create a whirlwind.
Forget that.
Did you hear anything
about Rodeo mob lately?
Why do you ask?!
That’s only $1,950.
Here it is.
He’s so good,
he knew right away.
You troublemaker.
Rodeo mob boss dropped in
out of the blue to ask me,
whether he was destined
to die with a bullet.
What did you tell him?
I told him that’d never happen.
The chance of someone
getting shot in Korea
is about the same as
getting hit by a lightning.
That’s common sense.
Oh no, no, no!
Holy shit! I’m so fucked!
Did you hear anything else?
Whether Rodeo was
trying to acquire guns?
That’d never happen!
Rodeo has a firm grasp
of Gangnam district.
Why’d they intentionally
get on the cops’ crosshair?
They can leak intel on their rivals
and use the cops
to their advantage.
Screwing your rivals legally
is the best way!
He’s right!
There’s no need for turf wars.
There aren’t any
gang wars in Korea!
Except one.
The Axe clan.
Axe clan?
They’re a vicious clan,
unlike other gangs.
They got mixed up
with a Chinese gang,
and they completely took over.
If it was them,
anything is possible, yup.
Bring it, bring it.
I’m so thirsty.
Why is this so sour?
This drink is expired!
Kiddo, the juice is expired,
throw them out, all right?
We better look into the Axe clan.
Axe clan?
The smugglers may start a gang war
in order to sell guns.
If Rodeo won’t budge,
they’ll agitate the Axe clan.
Are you nuts?!
You heard him!
He said they’re vicious!
You sure are a chicken
for a seasoned expert.
I don’t believe it.
It’s not that I’m a chicken,
I’m just not a fan of having
an amateur tagging along.
Don’t worry about me,
I can take care of myself.
Did you learn boxing diet
or something?
Boxing diet?
Should I show you?
Jeez, all right, show me.
If I hit you,
we’re going to the Axe clan.
Fine, go ahead.
The ring and the street
are completely dif...
You wanted me to hit you.
I let you hit me.
Any blood stains?
We’re from Major Crimes.
I already talked to cops earlier.
That it wasn’t us.
Did an arms dealer
come by recently?
Nope.
We’ve arrested that dealer.
Why don’t you
go ask him then?
If you’re uncooperative,
we will arrest you.
Do you have an arrest warrant?
Gang violence is a special law,
so it doesn’t need one.
Didn’t know.
I’ve had it, cuff him,
we’ll interrogate him at the station.
Cuff him?
- Yes, handcuffs.
- I don’t have one.
Where’s your head at!
How could you not bring a pair?!
What’s this?
Suspects complained that
handcuffs were hurting their wrists,
so we’re testing this new pair.
The world has improved, no?
Protecting civil rights
of criminals too.
Shouldn’t you read me
the Miranda warning first?
Miranda warning?
Isn’t that done in medical school?
That’s Hippocratic Oath.
Right, Miranda warning, I know.
You have the right
to appoint a prosecutor.
- Lawyer.
- I know.
What are you doing?
You two aren’t cops, right?
- No.
- Yes.
Hurry!
Let’s go!
- Chief?
- Yes?
- Da-hee...
You go ahead...
How could I leave you?
I’m okay, you go on...
What the heck?
Isn’t that your nosebleed smudge?
What?
Dammit!
Crap...
What took you so long!
Screw you!
Very good.
These guys really are insane.
How could they
wield guns in Korea?
I almost died back there...
Do you know any hackers?
Hackers? What for?
We have to unlock this.
No need to unlock it,
we don’t need it anymore.
What’re you talking about?
You may not have noticed,
but those guys are pros.
I noticed.
They used double tap
and Mozambique Drill
with silencers and
subsonic ammo.
They had to be
experienced mercs.
Then call in the reinforcement!
No! I have to do this alone!
Why?
We just have to do it ourselves.
If not, cough up the advance.
I’m sick of it,
I’ll cough it all up!
Minus the 50% retainer,
expenses and hazard pay,
I’ll return $2,000, happy?
So are you gonna
pay back or not?!
I did some work,
I need to get paid too.
Anyway, I’m out of this gig,
so you’re on your own.
I’ll pay $10,000 more
after the job.
So you need a hacker?
I knew it.
It costs money, that’s all.
How much?
About $3,000.
3...
And don’t skimp $50 like before.
That was so embarrassing.
That was an honest mistake.
Are you in business?
Hold on, hold on,
I can’t save here.
I saw ‘You Died’
so many times today.
Yoo Da-hee?
You two know each other?
Say what?
When did you get that?
There was a showcase recently.
Hey, could I take one?
Hell no.
I gave you a concert ticket last time.
Oh yeah...
Okay, take one.
Dope!
I’m gonna take this one too.
No, not ‘Seulgi’,
don’t be a bastard!
You’re into ‘Yeri’,
I’ll give you hers when I get it.
- You promise?
- Absolutely.
Are you serious?
Aren’t we here on business?
Could you unlock this?
Payment up front.
Of course.
Here.
No need to check
between us.
Why bother checking?
It’s short $50.
What?
That’s weird,
1 bill keeps slipping out.
So embarrassing...
It really slipped.
Any keywords to look for?
‘Tokarev’ or ‘arms dealer’
and things like that.
What about this? ‘Broker?
When was the call made?
It was... 3 days ago.
Can you check
who owns that number?
I sure can, one sec.
If the owner made
online purchases,
we can get an address too.
Give me a sec.
It’s Seoul,
I’ll text you the address.
Okay.
Let’s go.
- Go now?
- Yup.
Could I use your washroom?
Where is it?
You can’t...
It’s clogged up,
so I poured Drano...
Could you go any faster?
- Why?
- Step on it!
I can’t!
City speed limit is 60km/h.
I hate breaking laws.
What’s with you?
I drank expired juice!
I didn’t drink any.
Can’t you install a GPS?
Special Forces men memorize
the map instantly.
I memorized Korea’s highway codes,
I don’t need GPS.
Shit...
SH-1?
Highway SH-1 goes from
Jeolla to Gurye.
Jesus Christ...
JC-8?
A Jincheon interchange into
the national highway.
Go left!
Oh man...
Dammit...
Maybe no one’s home,
let’s leave.
Go where?
It’s locked again.
Anyone home?
No one’s here,
move, I’ll open it for you.
Piss off!
Red flavor!
I’m curious, honey
Wow, chief!
Is this your new car?
It sure is.
It’s like a supercar.
Don’t touch, you’ll smudge...
Already got your fingerprints on it.
What’s the situation inside?
Gunshots everywhere,
it’s a chaos.
Chief.
Did you find something?
I got something to show you.
Yeah?
This is outside the club
just before the shootout.
These two, don’t they
look like the tango couple?
I told you,
there’s something about them.
Did she clog it?
This was disguised as a suicide.
No signs of struggle,
this was done by pros.
What have you been eating?
It’s the body rotting stench.
What did you eat to make
your poop smell like a rotting body?
Like hell, it’s from
this body right here!
He didn’t die a long ago,
he can’t smell that bad.
Dammit!
Look at the blisters
by his bellybutton.
It’s been at least 3 days,
don’t you know?
I know!
Something’s blocking
on the other side.
Move aside.
See that?
Watch and learn,
this is from years of...
experience...
Kim Yeong Gu,
head of security.
Mugwang International.
It’s an arms broker.
Is there a list of execs?
Let me look.
Yes, Director Jeon Hoon.
Director Jeon Hoon?
Director Jeon!
Park threatened him with a text.
So that’s the bastard.
There’s a high chance of that.
Not just a chance,
it’s definitely him.
There’s a celebration
at Alvin Hotel tomorrow.
What celebration?
They invited overseas adoptees.
- So go there tomorrow?
- Of course.
Cloning Jeon’s phone
would be best.
No, there’s no time
to steal and return his phone.
Too dangerous, next plan.
What about luring him
with my femininity?
Too dangerous, next plan.
Why not?!
That plan only works
for real hotties.
I can’t believe what I’m hearing.
When I’m dolled up,
all the girls look like squids
in comparison.
A plate of sausage, please.
I ordered too much,
please have some.
Sure.
You see that?
Femininity plan is
used by those girls.
It’s not like I want to do it!
Got anything else?
Attaching a bug on Jeon then.
You do it.
Don’t forget to wear a dress.
Dress again?
It’s a celebration,
we gotta look the part.
Don’t wear something stupid.
Look who’s talking.
Name, Wong Iring.
She currently goes by
Yoo Da-hee,
and grew up in Korea,
so her Korean is excellent.
She studied psychology
at Beijing University,
and has been working for MSS
for about 3 years now.
Very good.
As expected, they sent a rookie.
They’ll sacrifice a young elite,
and blame us for it.
Did the agent beside her
report back?
No, not yet, sir.
I made contact
and sent him a sign,
but nothing yet.
Make contact properly,
and request a sitrep.
But I...
don’t recognize him.
He’s not one of our agents?
Um...
Doe Du-ho
You’re not as good
as last time.
That was just a warm up.
Du-ho, isn’t your mom
coming soon?
No, she’ll be late today.
Yeah? Here we go.
Why didn’t you swing?
Mom...
Du-ho! What are you doing?!
What if you get hurt?
I’m glad that I met
my husband,
and started a family because of you.
But please stay away now.
If he finds out that
you left his dad to die,
he’ll be torn apart.
I hope to never see you again.
How is he, by the way?
He’ll be fine after the surgery.
Oh...
Honey, let’s go.
Da-rong, that’s cheating!
You didn’t say it wasn’t allowed, Yuri.
Xiao-rong, go to the ER tomorrow.
This is nothing at all.
Be a pro about it.
Get it treated so it won’t
affect your performance.
Yes, boss.
How can I help you?
Salute, good day, sir!
Bud, it’s been a few days
since I got this car.
Can’t you remember?
I will absolutely do so,
take care, sir.
Chief, good afternoon.
- Afternoon.
- Sir.
Where are you off to?
We got a body.
Yeah?
Where did you rent
this high school uniform?
What do you know about fashion?
This is a designer jacket!
Hand crafted by an Italian artisan.
Designer plaid!
They got designer table cloth,
that’s incredible.
You’re embarrassing us,
take that jacket off.
Dammit, fine,
I’ll take it off.
Don’t take it off!
Why? You said to take it off.
That’s even more embarrassing,
this isn’t a fan meeting!
Use this to cover it up.
Nag, nag, nag...
Happy?
So dumb...
Chicken skewer, yum.
Did you report it?
Huh? Report what?
We found that body,
it should be reported.
Oh that, I did it in the morning.
Not with your phone,
I hope.
You take me for a fool?
I used a pay phone, duh.
No one knows we were there.
National ID: Woo Su-han
- Where did you find this?
It was on the floor
by the bedroom door.
Are they Hansel and Gretel
or something?
Bread crumbs are everywhere.
That’s him.
Using your femininity plan
would’ve bombed.
Shut up and get up.
Okay.
So where did we get
adopted to?
- I can’t speak English.
- So?
Where are you from, please?
Puerto Rico.
Puerto Rico?
My name is Jeon Hoon.
My name is Carlos Pellisiano.
And you?
Olga Pellisiano.
I'm aware there's no case of
Korean adoption to Puerto Rico so far.
Did you immigrated
after adopted to US?
Yes!
Oh, I see.
They immigrated after
adoption to the US.
Have a nice day.
Thank you, thank you.
- Bye.
What’s with them?
Buncha crazies,
so disgusting.
You got quick hands.
Puerto Rico?
I sure can think on my feet.
What an idiot...
Puerto Rico!
Boss.
The Axe clan’s here.
- I’ll see you again.
- Thank you.
Yuri.
Da-rong, Xiao-rong.
Don’t I look so dope?
Did you come here to dine?
What’s going on?
There must be a misunderstanding.
Misunderstanding?
You dying here
is a misunderstanding.
Chop them down.
Easy, let’s all calm down!
It’s a misunderstanding.
There’s no need to fight.
Think this through.
Rage crimes are rampant now.
Those not in gangs
will readily buy guns.
Why’d we intentionally
start a war?
We’ll only become
a target of investigation.
So who killed our don?
Roman scholar Cicero said once,
“To whom is it a benefit?”
If Rodeo and Axe clans go to war,
who will benefit from it?
Gangbook bastards?
Good.
You know the answer.
Sons of bitches!
How much are the guns?
Depends on how many you order.
- 100 units.
- Very well.
As a condolence to your don,
I’ll only accept 80% of price tag.
Where is it?
Guns aren’t here,
I’ll transfer them tonight.
I’ll notify you the time
and address later.
Blood-sucking bastards...
Dirty bastards...
The handoff is tonight.
Are you listening?
It’s beef!
Come on...
What’s wrong?
The guy who broke
his nose yesterday is here.
Which one?
He’s wearing the table cloth.
Oh, Puerto Rico.
We’re exposed,
we have to get out.
We gotta leave.
I didn’t have my dessert yet.
We’re exposed!
Exposed?
- Hurry up!
- I hear you!
- Come quietly.
- Okay!
- Hey!
- That bitch...
Goddamn!
You take him.
Take this!
You bastard!
Put that down!
It’s ho... cold...
Stay behind me.
I’ll take care of them.
At least walk the walk.
- Dope Woo P.I. Agency?
- Yes?
Why are you here?
If I tell you the truth,
will you let me go?
Of course.
You know head of security
Kim Yeong Gu?
Yes.
She hired me to find him.
Why?
She’s a gold digger.
She was going to scam him,
but got scammed instead.
A double scam,
can you believe it?
Her IQ must be pretty low.
So you came here to
meet Mr. Kim?
Yes, that’s right.
Then why were you at
the Axe clan HQ yesterday?
I was where yesterday?
You were at the scene
when the Axe clan don was shot.
That night club was
the Axe clan HQ?
What happened was,
we went there after seeing
Kim’s call log.
You saw his call log?
Yes.
So you hacked his phone?
Sure, that wasn’t even work.
Then you saw other stuff
in the phone?
No, not at all.
How could you not see it?
She saw everything,
she knows it all!
What do you mean,
we saw it together.
No! My eyes are bad,
I need glasses to see!
I got distorted vision.
You scheming bastard!
You paid you so much!
Like a real gold digger,
she’s got a foul temper.
I’m doing this to make money,
but it’s nonstop stress.
It’s really hard!
So, Carlos...
I mean, Mr. Woo,
you don’t know Mr. Kim at all?
That’s correct.
You can ask the gold digger
for more detail.
May I leave now?
Great.
Thank you.
Could you do me a favor though?
If you do,
I’ll let you both go.
See that police substation?
Go and kill all police officers there.
Kill police officers?
Don’t feel too bad.
They’ll die in the line of duty,
and their families will
receive special pension.
It wasn’t a simple arms smuggling?
None of your business.
If you run off,
we will kill you.
If you want to live,
do as I say.
Don’t be scared,
you got enough ammo.
Good.
Shots fired, suspect on the run,
plate number 43J-6449!
Black K5, I repeat,
43J-6449!
Can I help you?
Hands up!
Drop the gun!
Christ...
So you were investigating
an arms trafficking,
and they captured
your NIS agent partner?
Yes.
That’s huge.
Give her a call,
put it on speaker.
She certainly can’t answer,
she’s in captivity.
That’s why give it a try,
just humor me.
You really don’t get it,
she’s captured.
Just watch.
Yoo Da-hee
Huh?
Hello?
Where are you? You okay?
Of course I’m okay.
What’s up?
You’re captured!
What do you mean?
I’m on my way home.
What?
And don’t call me anymore.
How many Yangpyeong soups
did we have already?
6 times, 6!
I like Guksu noodles,
but we never had it once!
What are you talking...
Forget it, don’t call me anymore.
Yoo Da-hee, hey!
She answers just fine,
you can now relax.
NIS agent, huh?
Why’d an NIS agent
work with a private dick?!
Chief, we got a visit from NIS.
NIS?
Please excuse us.
It’s been a while, Sgt. Woo.
You headed up my rescue op
in Thailand.
Right...
I’m very regretful about
the accident that took place.
An order, you mean,
not accident.
Are you here about that?
No, not at all.
I need to confirm a few things.
Is your name Woo Su-han?
Yes.
Were you dishonorable discharged
from Special Force 707?
Yes.
Do you know this woman?
Yes, Yoo Da-hee.
How did she identify herself as?
She didn’t identify herself.
Where did you think
she belonged to?
She’s not one of yours?
She’s not our agent.
Defense Security Command?
She’s a Chinese MSS agent.
Chinese intelligence?
Why’d a Chinese agent come
to stop arms trafficking here?
So?
Over 93% chance that
he’s not lying.
I see.
Very well.
Although you’ve assisted
a foreign intelligence agent,
you have not caused any harm
to our national interest.
However, you will be
legally responsible
for your actions thus far.
I’m sorry that
I could not assist you.
You guys knew guns were
being smuggled into our country.
Why didn’t you stop it?
And Yoo Da-hee?
She was sent here
as a sacrifice.
She might not know
but her mission is to die.
And you’ll let her die?
Why should we take care
of a foreign agent?
This will be like the Thai op.
Situation is a bit different.
She’s not one of ours.
Would it make a difference...
if she was?
We only act on behalf of
national interest.
Take care.
Please follow the protocol.
What the hell...
What did you talk about?
It’s classified.
Classified?
I have to whisper it.
What for? It’s only us here.
We’re being recorded.
You’re a nobody,
we don’t record everyone.
Then I won’t tell you.
Interrogation Room
We can’t do that nowadays...
How about team dinner tonight?
- I got dinner plans.
- Me too.
- All right, I’m buying.
- Hot pot for me.
I’m in.
Mr. Woo!
What you’re doing is
a serious offense.
What the hell do you want?
Car key.
You think we’ll cooperate with you?
I’m a Korean police officer!
Please give him a key.
I don’t have a car.
Chief bought a new car.
Ow...
Oh yeah, my car...
You left it here last night,
it’s in the parking lot.
You frigging...
Hey! If you leave now,
you’re so screwed!
Buddy! Stop that car!
He knows the car’s mine.
He’ll stop it if the driver isn’t me.
Salute! Take care, sir!
Drive carefully, you mofo!
How many Yangpyeong soups
did we have already?
6 times, 6!
I like Guksu noodles,
but we never had it once!
Yeah, dude.
Look for that company’s buildings
by Yangpyeong Route 6.
They got 2 warehouses
in Yangpyeong.
1 in Guksu county,
and 1 in Geumgok.
It’s Guksu,
send me the address.
Pull out, I repeat,
pull out.
An operator has been captured.
Permission to rescue him, over.
Shoot him, I repeat,
shoot him and pull out, over.
She was sent here
as a sacrifice.
Her mission is to die.
Gunshots were fired
in front of a Jungil police station
at 3 PM today.
3 unidentified suspects
were shot and taken
- Stupid idiots...- to the hospital...
But at least he created
an aura of terror.
Your ultimate goal was
to start a gang war,
and sell guns to them?
I don’t think you’re a cop,
NIS? DSC?
Do you know what
Korea’s biggest problem is?
Raising its citizens
in a nursery.
It’s the safest country,
but government has no authority.
The rich moans,
and has hissy fits,
and the government babies them.
Is there a future
for such a country?
There’s an easy fix for that.
Removing the nursery.
“The world is dangerous,
act out and you’ll get hurt.”
To do this, firearm usage
must be allowed.
Trash those who voice rights
without any skills,
they will shoot each other
and get killed.
Kill and be killed,
kill and be killed!
This is a revolution.
A heart surgery for South Korea.
They’ve arrived.
What about the girl?
It may cause problems
if we kill her.
Let’s give her to the gangsters.
It may not be comfortable,
but try to relax.
All guns contain 8 bullets.
TT-33 models don’t have safety,
so please be careful.
What a know-it-all.
When I attended college
in Washington,
I worked as an intern
at an arms association...
I got it!
I got it...
And I got something
to test the guns.
She’s a cutie,
so kill her or take her.
Interesting, good.
Any updates from
Integrated Control Center?
No, there’s too much traffic,
so it’ll take a while.
Man...
- Hands up!
- Yes, sir.
I made 1 out of 60 payments...
Sons of bitches...
I haven’t peeled all plastic...
That looks important...
It’s from DSC.
I sent that request.
Go take a look.
What did you request?
That bastard, Woo Su-han.
I requested his service records.
And?
He’s ex-Special Forces 707.
That idiot?
He was dishonorably discharged.
What was the reason?
Disobeying an order, sir.
Bastard, he did look disobedient.
But isn’t 707 super hard
to get into?
Right, it’s really hard.
He didn’t work the mess
or the base exchange?
No, sir.
He was a close combat instructor.
That dumbass?
Xiao-rong, where you going?
I thought I heard something.
Chief!
It’s okay, no one’s here.
Sneakers over there.
What took you so long?
I got here as soon as possible.
Cops?
Don’t worry, I lost them,
I did good, right?
Why didn’t you bring them?!
How could I?
They’re after my ass!
You’re not an NIS agent, right?
Me? Why am I NIS?
I knew it.
I thought you were an NIS agent.
Then why are you here?
All by yourself?
Yoo Da-hee.
I’m still owed $10,000.
Only after the job!
That’s why I came.
I’ll take care of this,
so call it in.
You nag even after
I rescue you?
There’s no signal here.
Send a text,
it’ll work better.
Are you doing it on purpose?
What?
I don’t know what happened
in the past,
but you’re acting shallow
to avoid getting hurt.
You saw right through me,
I think so too.
I shouldn’t have said anything.
Da-hee, got anything?
What? Like what?
What do I...
Chief, what are you doing?!
My eyes!
Let’s go!
It really stings...
Is this the right way?
How should I know?
It’s my first time here.
- Da-hee.
- Yes?
Stay back.
Let’s go.
Xiao-rong!
What’s going on?
I think we have uninvited guests.
To test these guns out,
mind if we go on a hunt?
Certainly, enjoy.
Da-rong, he’s dead.
Da-rong...
I’m gonna kill him myself!
They’re looking for someone.
They’re looking for us.
What the!
Hey!
What happened?
That was not even work.
Da-hee, got a text from cops.
Cops? They’re on the way?
They found the bitch.
Which bitch?
That woman’s,
the missing dog.
That retriever? Dorothy?
I’m so glad they found her.
Who cares, we’re in danger!
Don’t worry.
Toss your gun.
If you do, we’re both dead.
Then let’s begin
with a bullet in her.
One in the chamber, asshole!
Toss your gun!
I’m Yuri.
Yeri?
Me, Seulgi.
What do you mean?
He must be a Red Velvet fan too.
What?!
Let’s duel it out.
Seulgi.
What about Seulgi?
I’ll lend you mine.
Holy crap, he almost got me.
No, I think he tossed you one
to have a duel with you.
What a weirdo,
why’d anyone do a duel?
Hey! Think this through.
With someone of your caliber,
we can start a revolution.
And I’ll pay you whatever.
Revolution? What revolution?
He wants to flood Korea with guns.
For what?
We can clean up trash
who’re polluting this country.
That’s what I’m doing.
No, not us!
We are revolutionists,
the real trash!
Unskilled, dormant criminals!
We can clean up those trash!
Elaborate.
Those who pollute Korea
for their right to vote!
We must eradicate those trash!
Hey!
You sure like to talk.
No, it’s not that...
I don’t know why I’m here...
Dump him in the toilet.
I’m really sorry.
Couldn’t I just get
a beating here?
I’ll gladly get a beating!
Please no!
Although it wasn’t intentional,
my bosses are happy
about wrapping up this case
as a joint op with China.
Then get me out of here.
You stir up way too much
trouble for us to do that.
There is one way though.
What?
Become our covert agent.
You want me to
become an NIS agent?
We received another request
for a joint op with China.
We believe you are perfect for it.
Are you nuts?
Do that again?
No way, I’m not doing it.
You’ll be stuck here for a while...
Wait, I stopped guns from
flooding our country...
- It should be an extenuating...
- Assault, bodily harm, murder,
impersonating an officer, break-in,
obstruction of justice, damage to...
So damn much...
Even with an extenuating circumstance,
you’ll get 10 years minimum.
I’d rather stay here for 10 years.
I almost died so many times!
I’m not doing it.
Never, ever.
$100,000 retainer.
Another $100,000
upon completion of the op.
Deal!
Pediatric Cancer Ward
Ma’am?
Yes?
Sorry to bother you.
I need to get your signature.
For what?
Before we fix the surgery date,
the guardian needs to sign off.
Surgery date?
You decided to have it.
Surgery was already paid for.
I’m so thankful that
you resolved the incident.
No, we’re the one in your debt.
Eh?
It’s been a while.
As you may already know,
he’s your partner agent
for this joint op.
Good to meet you,
I’m Agent Chao.
Woo Su-han.
“Agent”?
It worked out that way.
What happened to Agent Ama?
I can’t reach him.
We are actively searching for him.
Could it be related
to the missing Dorothy case?
We must approach it
from that angle.
Dorothy?
Who exactly is Dorothy?
A codename for
a former KGB informant.
She was to hand over
a North Korea intel to Agent Ama,
but both are unreachable.
How was she supposed to
hand it over?
Dorothy loves gold,
so she normally imbeds
micro SD card inside a gold bar.
Where’s the gold pig?
- I sold it.
- What?
Pardon?
- It’s nothing.
- Nothing, sir.
You are to disguise
as a couple and infiltrate
the place where we think
they’re in captivity.
- A couple?
You two are in sync.
- Of course not!
Didn’t you coordinate
your clothes today?
- No way!
Totally in sync.
Do we have to dress like this?
It’s Vladivostok!
Russia is so cold!
Look around, no one’s
dressed like us.
They just don’t know!
They might get off on route.
Oh yeah.
What was that text you got
from cops about finding the dog?
It wasn’t Dorothy.
How could you sell the gold pig?
If you hadn’t sold it,
we’d be done by now.
Did you know?
That it had an SD card?
Was I the only one?
Then why not get it back?!
They melted it down...
You can’t do anything right...
When’s the informant coming?
The meeting point is
the cruise’s bow.
Hello? Where are you?
Behind me?
There’s an ocean.
What?
Why are you dressed like that?
We’re taking this boat?
We have to go in stealthily.
I knew it.
Can we really get there
on this boat?
We’ll find out soon.
What? What the hell?!
KIM YOUNG-GWANG
LEE SUN-BIN
WRITTEN AND DIRECTED BY
KIM HYUNG-JOO
So you don’t remember anything?
No.
Any images that pop up?
Nothing like that?
I see a man,
naked and tied to a chair.
He was into BDSM...
And a gun, knife and a needle,
I keep seeing those.
He had constant suicidal thoughts.
If it’s okay,
I know someone who
may be able to help you.
Would you like to meet him?
I’m sure it’s been tough.
Perception’s gotten so much better.
So don’t do anything regrettable.
Here you were.
We found your family member.
Yeah?
Honey! Honey! Honey!
I looked everywhere for you!
Are you all right?
“Honey”?
Because I’m his wife.
Not his aunt?
You’re risking your life
with those words!
It’s obvious this is
very peculiar.
Why’d this handsome man
marry someone like you?
What’d you even know
about women’s attraction?
I really don’t get it.
Honey, let’s go somewhere else.
You had women trouble in the past,
but now men too?
Where are you going?
Our home, of course,
none of your business!
How could we trust him
with a suspicious woman?
Suspicious? We’re married!
You’re at least 20 years older!
I get Botox regularly!
Honey! Where are you going?!
Careful!