Keep away from me.
Do not be afraid.
Don't!
Close your eyes and I will see
for both of us.
Alright, mister,
we'll take her now.
It's time to
go home, Gwyneth.
It's time to go.
Your tread must
be light and sure...
...as though your path
were upon rice paper.
It is said a Shaolin priest
can walk through walls.
Looked for, he cannot be seen.
Listened for,
he cannot be heard.
Touched, he cannot be felt.
This rice paper is the test.
Fragile as the wings
of the dragonfly.
Clinging as the cocoon
of the silkworm.
When you can walk its length
and leave no trace...
...you will have learned.
It's time to go now.
Get her! We can't afford
to lose her again.
-She was in chains.
-Of course she's in chains.
She's a patient
from a mental asylum...
...she has
to be restrained.
Devil! Devil! What have you
done with the priests?
You think I don't know.
I heard the scratching
in the wall.
You sealed the priests in
the wall behind my room.
Now they listen to me.
They listen to me.
I can't sleep,
thinking about it.
I can't sleep.
I will help you to sleep.
No! Poison!
When you have rested,
we can talk.
Master...
...what besets that man?
He has been marked
to wander inward...
...through and beyond the dark
and terrifying land...
...where no road exists
and no signpost points the way.
But why?
Who can say?
Should he not be locked
in his room?
And prevented from his journey?
If he can pass through
the trackless land...
...he will find peace,
his answer, his cure.
As far as we are able,
we must travel with him...
...help him along his way.
But how, when there are
no roads and no signposts?
There are steps, his and ours.
We take them together.
This is our duty to all
who are marked, as he is.
I should hope then never
to meet another like him.
Very often, a wanderer
in the trackless land...
...finds that which he sought
and more...
...something of rare value for
the one who shared his journey.
Could you risk the loss
of such a benefit?
Parker!
Fight's all run out of her.
Get the horses.
You will lock her up
in your asylum?
Well, look at her, down on
all fours like an animal.
She has a journey to complete.
I cannot let you take her.
Stand aside.
Get her.
Leave him alone.
He's crazier than she is.
You want her that bad,
you can keep her. Let's go.
They are gone.
Where have you
seen these signs?
In my dreams,
and awake sometimes.
What do they mean to you?
They're the mark of a devil
that makes me see things...
...that aren't there.
You see things
that other people do not?
Yes.
Didn't you hear Dr. Tracer
say I'm crazy?
These are herbs, medicine.
They will make your wrists heal
without scarring.
Once I met a stone carver who
had been blind from birth.
His carvings were of beautiful,
fierce beasts.
No one with eyes had ever
seen such beasts.
Yet he who could
not see saw them.
He must have been crazy too.
He was gifted.
Why are you afraid of me?
Have I hurt you?
No, but you will.
You'll destroy me.
Why?
I don't know.
Have I not just treated you
as a friend?
Shall I tell you
why I will help you?
Why?
I will, in time,
ask you a question...
...which you may
be able to answer.
What question?
You are not ready
to answer yet.
-What's your name?
-I am Caine.
And you?
Gwyneth.
It's a Welsh name.
Supposed to mean
someone who's blessed.
It doesn't suit me very well.
You have a home?
An aunt and uncle.
They have a farm north of here.
I wouldn't call it home.
We should go.
No, not there.
They will wish
to know you are safe.
Can I just stay with you?
Caine, please don't
take me home.
We are close then?
You're gonna take me there
and leave me, aren't you?
I have told you, I have
a question to ask you.
In time, I will ask it.
Until then, I will
stay with you.
Alright.
There.
Isn't it beautiful?
By Saint Asaph, she's taken up
with a Chinaman.
That's my aunt and uncle.
What are we gonna
do, Mr. Jenkins?
She looks so thin.
Never mind how she looks.
I will not have her
in my house again.
I understand
your feelings, Mr. Jenkins...
...but since your accident...
...we could use an extra pair
of hands around the place.
He probably thinks
you're crazy too.
Did they let you
out of that place?
I ran away.
Why did you come back here?
-You are her family.
-Both look so hungry.
And the girl could do
with a clean dress.
A Chinaman, eating supper
at my table?
The Bible says we must practice
Christian charity.
Just a bite to eat and a place
to sleep for a night.
We rebuilt the house
down the road there.
You come along,
and we'll have a talk.
They hate me.
No.
They fear you.
Do all your countrymen
abstain from...
...the eating
of meat, Mr. Caine?
No. It is a personal choice.
How come you don't wear
a long pigtail down your back?
Uncle.
That too is a personal choice.
You are a choosing man,
aren't you?
-I'll help you, Aunt Mary.
-Sit down.
You're not right in
the head yet, are you?
I don't know how
to answer that.
Your aunt and I have
been thinking...
...maybe you could stay.
We'd try it again.
Stay?
Tell her to stop staring at me.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean anything.
You were staring at me
with that evil eye.
If you don't keep
her away from me...
...you can get
yourself another man.
Now look what you've done.
I won't have any
of your funny business, now.
I'll send you back, you hear?
-What did you see?
-Nothing.
Trust me.
I didn't see anything.
I swear it!
Aunt Mary, I didn't.
You frighten me, child.
As God is my witness,
you frighten me.
Frank!
-Where is she?
-Resting.
She can't stay here, Caine.
That's out.
You see, we don't even know
if she's really our niece.
She came to our doorstep
one morning, 20-years-old...
...looking more Injun
than white.
She claimed that her father
was my brother.
And she told me his name,
and that the family was dead.
I don't know how she found us.
She cost Mr. Jenkins
lotta of money.
He had to buy her from
those Indians she was with.
Well, I felt it was my duty.
But she wasn't
right in the head...
from the day we got her.
And then, finally,
she burned the house down.
You are certain
Gwyneth did this?
-I am. And that's not all.
-There are other things.
Like, she tells you things
before they come to pass.
She sees things,
and then she makes them happen.
You can both stay
here tonight...
...but you'll have to
be gone by morning.
Watch out for her.
See she doesn't start anything.
-What is it?
-Frank. He's coming back.
-Which way?
-Leave me alone.
You've seen something.
-Look at it.
-No.
Look at it.
I saw him falling
from his horse.
Please stop me before I make
this happen again.
Seeing something does not
cause it to happen.
Where is Frank now?
You're she-wolf.
Who'll you murder next?
It was an accident.
We'll see what
the sheriff calls it.
Some food and my jar of money.
Take her away before my husband
comes back with the law.
I cannot accept money.
It's for her.
A woman has needs.
How can you look at me?
Something evil inside me,
turning me into a monster.
We must go.
Mr. Caine.
There's peacefulness in you.
Help her if you can.
Caine.
What are you doing?
Thinking.
What will you do now?
Where do you wish to go?
I don't know.
There's no place,
no one...but you.
No. No.
You. You tricked me.
I thought you were good,
but you're evil.
Evil. Evil! Evil!
Master, why do such
fearsome statues stand...
...at the entrance
to our peaceful place?
These are the threshold
guardians, grasshopper...
...set here
to keep away those...
...not ready for
the silence within.
Must they be so horrible?
Those incapable
of understanding...
...the way see things
divine as monsters.
Better for them never
to enter here.
Yet, if a man
is unafraid of stone...
...he may pass unhampered.
He may physically pass
the guardian.
But if his mind is
in the outer world...
...he will leave us,
in time, to rejoin it.
Why did you follow me?
Are you ready
to ask your question now?
Not yet.
It's an evil thing you'll ask,
because you're evil.
Gwyneth.
You must stop running away from
everything...
...you do not understand.
You must give in to your dreams.
Listen to what they tell you.
I'm so tired.
Soon, you will come to
the end of your journey.
You will go beyond your fears
and find peace.
You saw these signs
before we met?
That was your deeper self
giving you a message.
-Can you take the dreams away?
-No.
I can help you
to understand them.
Breathe slowly, deeply,
as if you were floating.
I'm afraid.
Don't make me see this.
What do you see?
It's an awful place.
It's dark and still.
It looks like people lying
on tree branches.
Death is everywhere.
We shouldn't be here.
It's changing.
A place called Blue Ridge Pass,
I think.
Mountains.
Caine, don't make me see
any more of this.
I feel cold all over.
What is beyond the pass?
I'm numb. I can't feel
my body. Caine!
Beyond the pass, go there.
A wagon...
...with settlers.
A big family.
Do you know them?
No.
Someone's attacking
with fire arrows.
Speak English.
This is my friend.
-You know each other?
-He's my brother.
Black Horse is dead.
-When?
-In the Moon of the Snowblind.
By his last words,
he wished this for you.
You always wanted it,
you keep it.
Only those who have had thunder
visions may act as heyokas.
There is sickness among us.
Meat is scarce.
The Grandfather punishes us for
selling you back to your people.
I'm only woman, Tall Fire.
What can I do?
Come back with us now.
We know of the life you had
with the  wasicus.
We offer you a life with honor.
I'd rather die first.
Who is Black Horse?
Their heyoka,
the sacred fool.
He was my father
while I lived with them.
He adopted me when he heard
of my dreams.
I'm sorry he's dead.
-Where is the Blue Ridge Pass?
-I don't know. It's only words.
You know.
That way, three days.
Perhaps we should go there.
There's something horrible
there, Caine...
...something dark and terrible.
If I see it,
I'll die, I know it.
I feel it, like a chill all
the way to my soul.
When a fear
becomes strong enough...
...it is like another
being within you...
...who fights to stay alive.
It is not you who will die,
Gwyneth, it is your fear.
Where'd you come from?
Outside.
I know that.
The stage ain't due for a week.
I didn't hear
any horses or a wagon.
We walked.
It's not possible.
Don't mind that.
It ain't real.
I got that done by
a professional, back East.
Scares Indians. Big medicine.
Keeps me safe.
What can I do for you?
Can you tell us the way
to Blue Ridge Pass, please?
Day's ride, straight
into the sunset.
Mountains rise blue
on either side of the pass.
Lots of spruce up
that way too.
But that's hostile
territory, mister.
No one goes up there. No one.
Thank you.
This was our winter campground.
I've never seen it
this time of year.
A friend?
My sister.
We lived as captives
of the Sioux.
For a while, at least,
we had each other.
When they learned
about my dreams...
...Black Horse took me
to the lodge...
...and made me his daughter.
Emily was treated like a slave,
while I was privileged.
After a year...
...she died from the hardship.
What of your mother and father?
I don't know.
I remember being
with them in Wales.
They must have died.
I kept her dress.
Nobody knew.
One night, I thought...
...if I burned the dress...
...I'd burn the memory.
The fire in your uncle's house?
Yeah.
We're getting close.
I don't want to go any farther.
Caine.
-I want to stop.
-No.
I can't breathe.
It's like a weight pressing down
on me. I'm suffocating.
Caine, I'm suffocating.
I'm suffocating.
Your heart beats too fast.
You must quiet it.
What frightened you?
I heard the silence, master.
I felt my whole being diffuse,
like a cloud.
Then rain fell from
the sky through me.
I was part of everything,
yet I was myself.
You have experienced oneness.
Yes, master.
But in this great joy...
...I felt as if I was dying.
That is what frightened me.
You know the lesson
of the silkworm?
The silkworm dies,
the moth lives...
...yet they are not two separate
beings, but one and the same.
It is the same with man.
His false beliefs must die...
...so that he may know
the joy of the way.
What you felt in
the silence was real.
Something in you is dying.
It is called ignorance.
This is sacred ground.
No one may enter but a holy man.
We can't go any farther.
After we have gone through...
...perhaps you will be able
to tell me what I must know.
No.
Oh!
Oh, no.
My mother and father died here.
They tried to protect us
with their bodies.
I could feel the weight
of her body on top of me.
I couldn't breathe.
I knew she was dead.
I wanted her to be alive again.
The wagon...
...in my vision,
it wasn't in this train.
No wagon in this train
had that many children.
Are you certain?
Yes. No wagon had
that many children.
You cannot go through this way.
It's free open land, I'll go
where I please.
Stop!
Peace.
These people will not violate
the sacred ground.
The daughter of Black Horse
bids you let them be.
Alright. Kids.
Mister, I owe you an apology.
How did you know, and I didn't?
Without fear,
one sees more clearly.
Your vision is not a curse.
It is a gift.
It saved those people's lives.
I'm not afraid anymore.
You have come to the end
of your journey.
You've walked
with me step by step.
And now I've left my fears
behind me.
I must go back and serve my
people now.
You have found
what you were seeking.
Peace for yourself.
It was once said to me...
...that if I shared
a journey such as yours...
...at the end, I might find
something of value for myself.
-Your question?
-Yes, it is time.
Since coming to this land,
I have searched for my brother.
Now I wonder
if my search is idle.
Tell me if he still lives.
Oh, Caine, after all
you've done for me...
...I can't answer
your question.
Please try.
-How?
-Think.
Look.
I need to know.
Oh, please, just this once.
Oh, Caine. You've done so much
for me. If I could--
Nothing.
Oh, poor Danny, if I could
just help you in some way.
I have not told you his name.
Yes, he lives.
And you'll find him.
Oh, Caine.