[male announcer] Now, to open
our MusiCares tribute to Dolly Parton,
Miley Cyrus, Shawn Mendes,
and Mark Ronson.
[applause, cheering]
[Shawn]Sing with us.
[band plays]
♪ Baby, when I met you ♪
♪ There was peace unknown ♪
♪ I set out to get you ♪
♪ With a fine-tooth comb ♪
♪ I was soft inside ♪
♪ There was something going on ♪
I'd like to join you.
♪ You do something to me ♪
♪ That I can't explain ♪
♪ Hold me closer and I feel no pain ♪
♪ Every beat of my heart ♪
♪ We've got something going on ♪
♪ 'Cause tender love is blind ♪
♪ It requires a dedication ♪
♪ All this love we feel ♪
♪ Needs no conversation ♪
♪ We ride it together, uh-huh ♪
♪ Making love with each other, uh-huh ♪
♪ Islands in the stream ♪
♪ That is what we are ♪
♪ No one in-between ♪
♪ How can we be wrong? ♪
♪ Sail away with me to another world ♪
♪ And we rely on each other, uh-huh ♪
♪ From one lover to another, uh-huh ♪
I love you, Dolly.
[cheering]
♪ I can't live without you ♪
♪ If the love was gone ♪
♪ Everything is nothing ♪
♪ If you got no one ♪
♪ And you did walk in tonight ♪
♪ Slowly losing sight of the real thing ♪
♪ But that won't happen to us ♪
♪ And we've got no doubt ♪
♪ Too deep in love ♪
♪ And we've got no way out ♪
♪ And the message is clear ♪
♪ This could be the year ♪
♪ For the real thing ♪
♪ No more will you cry ♪
♪ Baby, I will never hurt you ♪
♪ We start and end ♪
♪ As one in love forever ♪
♪ We can ride it together, uh-huh ♪
♪ Making love with each other, uh-huh ♪
♪ Islands in the stream ♪
♪ That is what we are ♪
♪ No one in-between ♪
♪ How can we be wrong? ♪
♪ Sail away with me, Dolly ♪
♪ To another world ♪
♪ And we rely on each other, uh-huh ♪
♪ From one lover to another, uh-huh ♪
♪ Yeah yeah yeah ♪
♪ Islands in the stream ♪
♪ That is what we are ♪
♪ No one in-between ♪
♪ How can we be wrong? ♪
♪ Sail away with me ♪
♪ To another world ♪
♪ And we rely on each other, uh-huh ♪
♪ From one lover to another, uh-huh ♪
All right, y'all.
♪ Islands in the stream ♪
[Miley] Hey, my dress is short.
♪ That is what we are ♪
♪ No one in-between ♪
[Miley] Sorry, Dad.
♪ How can we be wrong? ♪
♪ Sail away with me ♪
♪ To another world ♪
♪ And we rely on each other… ♪
Hey!
♪ From one lover to another, uh-huh ♪
[applause, cheering]
- [Shawn] Miley Cyrus, everybody.
- Shawn Mendes, Mark Ronson.
Thank you, everybody.
Thank you.
- [whistling]
- [band plays]
[announcer] She's the queen of country,
a global icon, and one of the most beloved
entertainers in America
and all around the world.
Now, Dolly Parton
is celebrated by an all-star lineup
as she receives one of music's
most prestigious honors:
MusiCares Person of the Year.
Each year, the Recording Academy
bestows the MusiCares honor
on a deserving musical legend.
Past winners include
the biggest names in music,
like Paul McCartney, Bruce Springsteen,
Stevie Wonder, Barbra Streisand,
Elton John, Fleetwood Mac, Lionel Richie,
among others.
For 30 years,
MusiCares has been raising
millions of dollars,
providing a much-needed lifeline
for people in the music business
in times when they need a helping hand.
No one exemplifies this spirit
of giving back more than Dolly Parton.
In addition to her towering place
in music, television, and film,
it is her philanthropy and generous spirit
that defines who Dolly Parton is.
Now, we all have a front row seat
to one of music's biggest nights
as Dolly Parton becomes
the MusiCares Person of the Year.
With special performances
by Willie Nelson,
Brandi Carlile, Katy Perry,
Kacey Musgraves,
Norah Jones with Puss n Boots,
Chris Stapleton, Mavis Staples,
Leon Bridges, Jennifer Nettles,
Margo Price, Cam, Lauren Daigle,
Yolanda Adams,
Linda Perry, and Dolly Parton herself.
[drums roll]
[band music crescendos]
[applause, cheering]
[announcer] Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome our hosts
a Grammy-winning group of Dolly fans,
Little Big Town.
[crowd cheering]
Good evening and welcome to
the MusiCares Person of the Year tribute
to the incomparable Dolly Parton.
[cheering, applause]
We are so honored to be here tonight
to celebrate the life and legacy
of this remarkable woman, Dolly Parton.
Dolly has been one of the biggest stars
in entertainment
for as long as any of us can remember.
And her influence and impact on us
and millions of her fans around the world
remains as powerful as ever.
And out of everyone in the band,
I have to say
I'm the biggest fan of Dolly.
- [laughing]
- [man 1] By far.
You got to be freakin' kidding me.
You're not. I worship her.
- They're married, by the way.
- What?
- [man 2] Come on.
- [man 1] No.
I dressed up as Dolly Parton
for Halloween one year. I mean…
[laughing]
Y'all,
I named my baby after Dolly Parton!
[men laughing]
- [man 2] Okay.
- [woman] Look…
- That's hard to compete with.
- You win.
- I win.
- Okay. You win. Yeah.
We have an incredible lineup
for you tonight
featuring some of
the biggest names in music.
[cheering, whistling, applause]
And few are more celebrated
than this next performer.
He's one of the most original voices.
One of my heroes,
and he's one of the best voices
in music history.
And she has more Grammy nominations
this year than any other female artist.
Here to perform a wonderful duet
that Dolly and Willie
turned into a top ten hit
back in the early '80s,
please welcome Willie Nelson
and Brandi Carlile.
[cheering, applause]
We love you, Doll.
[band plays]
[harmonica wails]
♪ When I look out over
A green field of clover ♪
♪ Or watch the sunset ♪
♪ At the end of the day ♪
♪ Yeah, well, I get kind of moody ♪
♪ To see such a beauty ♪
'♪ Cause everything's beautiful ♪
♪ In its own way ♪
♪ I see a fountain ♪
♪ Flow from a mountain ♪
♪ Or see April showers ♪
♪ Bring flowers to May ♪
♪ I can't help but ponder ♪
♪ Life is such a wonder ♪
♪ And everything's beautiful ♪
♪ In its own way ♪
[cheering, applause]
♪ And words can't describe ♪
♪ What I feel inside ♪
♪ When I see the beauty ♪
♪ In each coming day ♪
♪ And what my eyes behold ♪
♪ Can't be bought or sold ♪
♪ Everything's beautiful ♪
♪ In its own way ♪
♪ When I see the clouds form ♪
♪ A black summer wind storm ♪
♪ That uproots the harvest ♪
♪ And hurls it away ♪
♪ In the midst of such anger ♪
♪ Destruction and danger ♪
♪ The storm's even beautiful ♪
♪ In its own way ♪
♪ When I see the leaves drop ♪
♪ From off of the treetops ♪
♪ Or see the snow fall ♪
♪ On a cold winter's day ♪
♪ My thoughts seem to wander ♪
♪ Into the blue yonder ♪
♪ For God made all things beautiful ♪
♪ In their own way ♪
♪ And words can't describe ♪
♪ What I feel inside ♪
♪ When I see the beauty ♪
♪ In each coming day ♪
♪ What my eyes behold ♪
♪ Can't be bought or sold ♪
♪ Everything's beautiful ♪
♪ In its own way ♪
[cheering, applause]
[Willie] Thank you.
[whistling]
Willie Nelson!
[announcer] Here they come
together for Dolly,
Katy Perry and Kacey Musgraves.
[band plays]
♪ Here you come again ♪
♪ Just when I begun
To get myself together ♪
♪ You waltz right in the door ♪
♪ Just like you done before ♪
♪ And you wrap my heart ♪
♪ 'Round your little finger ♪
♪ Here you come again ♪
♪ Oh, just when I'm about ♪
♪ To make it work without you ♪
♪ You look into my eyes ♪
♪ And lie those pretty lies ♪
♪ And pretty soon I'm wondering ♪
♪ How I came to doubt you ♪
♪ All you gotta do is smile that smile ♪
♪ And there go all my defenses ♪
♪ Oh, just leave it up to you ♪
♪ And in a little while ♪
♪ You're messing up my mind ♪
♪ And filling up my senses ♪
♪ Here you come again ♪
♪ Looking better than a body ♪
♪ Has the right to ♪
♪ And shaking me up so ♪
♪ So that all I really know ♪
♪ Is here you come again ♪
♪ And here I go, yeah ♪
♪ Oh, all you gotta do
Is smile and smile ♪
♪ And there go all my defenses ♪
♪ Just leave it up to you ♪
♪ And in a little while ♪
♪ You're messing with my mind ♪
♪ And filling up my senses ♪
♪ Oh, here you come again, yeah ♪
♪ Looking better than a body ♪
♪ Has a right to ♪
♪ And shaking me up so ♪
♪ That all I really know ♪
♪ Is here you come again ♪
♪ And here I go, yeah ♪
♪ Here I go, yeah ♪
♪ Here you come again ♪
♪ Oh, here you come again, all right ♪
♪ Here you come again
Here I go again ♪
♪ Here I go ♪
♪ Oh ♪
We love you, Dolly!
We wanna be just like you when we grow up.
- We love ya!
- [music crescendos]
I love you.
[cheering, applause]
[piano plays]
[announcer] Here to perform the track
from Dolly's Grammy award-winning
bluegrass album
is nine-time Grammy winner Norah Jones
with Puss n Boots.
♪ I've had to think of ♪
♪ A way to survive ♪
♪ Since you said it's over ♪
♪ Told me good-bye ♪
♪ I just can't make it ♪
♪ One day without you ♪
♪ Unless I pretend ♪
♪ That the opposite's true ♪
♪ Rivers flow backwards ♪
♪ Valleys are high ♪
♪ Mountains are level ♪
♪ The truth is a lie ♪
♪ I'm perfectly fine ♪
♪ And I don't miss you ♪
♪ And the sky is green ♪
♪ And the grass is blue ♪
[band plays]
♪ How much can a heart ♪
♪ And a troubled mind take ♪
♪ Where is that fine line ♪
♪ Before it all breaks ♪
♪ Can one end their sorrow? ♪
♪ Just cross over it ♪
♪ And into that realm ♪
♪ Of insanity's bliss ♪
♪ There's snow in the tropics ♪
♪ There's ice on the sun ♪
♪ It's hot in the arctic ♪
♪ And crying is fun ♪
♪ And I'm happy now ♪
♪ And I'm glad we're through ♪
♪ And the sky is green ♪
♪ And the grass is blue ♪
♪ And the rivers flow backwards ♪
♪ And my tears are dry ♪
♪ Swans hate the water ♪
♪ And eagles can't fly ♪
♪ And I'm all right now ♪
♪ Now that I'm over you ♪
♪ And the sky is green ♪
♪ And the grass is blue ♪
♪ And I don't love you ♪
♪ And the grass is ♪
♪ Blue ♪
[cheering, whistling, applause]
[man] Amazing.
Okay, a few years ago, we had the pleasure
of joining this next artist for a cover
of the classic Oak Ridge Boys hit
"Elvira," and we had so much fun.
To this day, it remains
one of our favorite collaborations,
because he is such a perfect example
of why country music is alive and well.
This next song
was not only the title track
to one of Dolly's greatest hits,
film roles,
but it also earned her
an Oscar nomination.
[cheers]
Here to perform the title song
from the American classic 9 to 5,
please welcome five-time Grammy winner
and our friend…
Chris Stapleton!
[applause, cheering]
[piano plays]
[band plays]
♪ Tumble outta bed
And stumble to the kitchen ♪
♪ Pour myself a cup of ambition ♪
♪ And yawn and stretch
And try to come to life ♪
♪ Jump in the shower
And the blood starts pumping ♪
♪ Out on the street
The traffic starts jumping ♪
♪ With folks like me on the job
From 9 to 5 ♪
♪ Working 9 to 5 ♪
♪ What a way to make a living ♪
♪ Barely getting by ♪
♪ It's all taking and no giving ♪
♪ They just use your mind ♪
♪ And they never give you credit ♪
♪ It's enough to drive you ♪
♪ Crazy if you let it ♪
♪ 9 to 5 ♪
♪ For service and devotion ♪
♪ You would think that I ♪
♪ Would deserve a fair promotion ♪
♪ Want to move ahead ♪
♪ But the boss won't seem to let me ♪
♪ I swear sometimes that man is ♪
♪ Out to get me ♪
[crowd cheering]
♪ They let you dream
Just to watch them shatter ♪
♪ You're just a step
On the boss man's ladder ♪
♪ But you got dreams
He'll never take away ♪
♪ You're in the same boat
With a lot of your friends ♪
♪ Waiting for the day
Your ship'll come in ♪
♪ And the tide's gonna turn
And it's all gonna roll away ♪
♪ Working 9 to 5 ♪
♪ What a way to make a living ♪
♪ Barely getting by ♪
♪ It's all taking and no giving ♪
♪ They just use your mind ♪
♪ And you never get the credit ♪
♪ It's enough to drive you ♪
♪ Crazy if you let it ♪
♪ 9 to 5 ♪
♪ Yeah, they got you where they want you ♪
♪ There's a better life ♪
♪ And you think about it, don't you? ♪
♪ It's a rich man's game ♪
♪ No matter what they call it ♪
♪ And you spend your life ♪
♪ Putting money in his wallet ♪
♪ 9 to 5 ♪
♪ Oh, what a way to make a living ♪
♪ Barely getting by ♪
♪ It's all taking and no giving ♪
♪ They just use your mind ♪
♪ And they never give you credit ♪
♪ It's enough to drive you ♪
♪ Crazy if you let it ♪
♪ 9 to 5 ♪
♪ Yeah, they got you where they want you ♪
♪ There's a better life ♪
♪ And you dream about it, don't you? ♪
♪ It's a rich man's game ♪
♪ Don't matter what they call it ♪
♪ And you spend your life ♪
♪ Putting money in his wallet ♪
♪ 9 to 5 ♪
[music crescendos]
[cheering, applause]
Thank you, Dolly. We love you so much.
[announcer] Here to make a joyful noise
for Dolly,
accompanied by Jon Batiste,
are Grammy winners Mavis Staples
and Leon Bridges.
♪ Not enough, not enough ♪
♪ Not enough love ♪
♪ There's no room for hate ♪
♪ And a heart is for kindness ♪
♪ How long will it take then ♪
♪ For that to ring true? ♪
♪ Our chances are fading ♪
♪ To stop all this blindness ♪
♪ A new world is waiting ♪
♪ For us if we do ♪
♪ But there's not enough love
In our heart ♪
[band plays]
♪ They write songs about it ♪
♪ They put it in movies ♪
♪ Our life would be better ♪
♪ With just enough love ♪
♪ Still we tend to doubt it ♪
♪ Though sometimes it moves us ♪
♪ They settle for little ♪
♪ When we could have much ♪
♪ 'Cause there's not enough love ♪
♪ In our hearts ♪
♪ Not enough love, not enough love ♪
♪ Not enough love in our hearts ♪
♪ There's not enough love ♪
♪ There's not enough trust ♪
♪ And it tends to keep us apart
Keep us apart ♪
♪ There's not enough caring
Caring ♪
♪ There's not enough sharing
Sharing ♪
♪ Too much me me
Me, yeah ♪
♪ Too much double daring
Double daring ♪
♪ There's too much delaying
Delaying ♪
♪ Oh, not enough praying
Praying ♪
♪ Saying that it's not enough
Oh, it's not enough ♪
♪ I'm just saying it's not enough
No, it's not enough ♪
[singer] Woo!
♪ I often wonder ♪
♪ What God must be thinking ♪
♪ Looking down on us ♪
♪ It must be sad ♪
♪ We better wise up now ♪
♪ Before we start sinking ♪
♪ He gave us free choice ♪
♪ But we messed it up bad ♪
♪ But there's not enough love ♪
♪ In our heart ♪
♪ There's not enough love in our heart ♪
♪ There's not enough love ♪
♪ Not enough love
Sing it, baby ♪
♪ There's not enough love in our heart ♪
♪ There's not enough love ♪
♪ There's not enough trust ♪
♪ It's never too late to start ♪
♪ Too late to start ♪
♪ There's not enough heart
Heart ♪
♪ Father ♪
♪ Why can't we do better?
Better ♪
♪ Love's a good starter
Good starter ♪
♪ Too much naysaying
Naysaying ♪
♪ And not enough praying
Praying ♪
♪ I'm just saying ♪
♪ It's not enough
Oh, it's not enough ♪
♪ I'm just saying it's not enough
No, it's not enough ♪
♪ Oh, it's only love that matters
Not enough, not enough ♪
♪ Not enough love ♪
♪ Not enough, not enough ♪
♪ Too much crying
Crying ♪
♪ Too much dying
Dying ♪
♪ Too much hating
Hating ♪
♪ And not enough trying
Trying ♪
♪ Not enough staying
Staying ♪
♪ Too much good-bye-ing
Good-bye-ing ♪
♪ It's not enough, no, no
Oh, it's not enough ♪
♪ Sing it, it's not enough
No, it's not enough ♪
♪ Not enough, not enough ♪
♪ Not enough love ♪
♪ Between us ♪
♪ Let's build a foundation
Foundation ♪
♪ Create a situation
Situation ♪
♪ Start the salvation
Salvation ♪
♪ Heed the revelation
Revelation ♪
♪ Fall on your knees
Your knees ♪
♪ Burn your temptation ♪
♪ I'm just saying, it's not enough
Oh, it's not enough ♪
♪ No, I'm just saying, it's not enough
No, it's not enough ♪
[Mavis humming]
♪ Not enough, not enough ♪
♪ Not enough love ♪
♪ Not enough trust
Trust ♪
♪ Not enough love ♪
♪ When love is good and righteous ♪
♪ Let your soul love, you'll feel better ♪
♪ Love is enough, now ♪
♪ Down in our hearts ♪
♪ It's not enough ♪
♪ Not enough love ♪
♪ Oh, down in our hearts ♪
♪ Gotta show love so it never leaves you ♪
♪ Down in our hearts ♪
♪ Not enough love, no
Down in our heart ♪
♪ Not enough love ♪
♪ In our hearts ♪
♪ In our hearts
Oh, yeah, oh God, oh Lord ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
[music crescendos]
- [Mavis] Woo!
- [cheering, applause]
[Mavis] Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you.
- [whistling]
- [band plays]
[announcer] Here to honor Dolly,
Jennifer Nettles, Margo Price, and Cam.
- [crowd cheering]
- [guitar music plays]
♪ Oh, sometimes I go walking ♪
♪ Through fields where we walked ♪
♪ Long ago in the sweet used to be ♪
♪ And the flowers still grow ♪
♪ But they don't smell as sweet ♪
♪ As they did ♪
♪ When you picked them for me ♪
♪ And when I think of you ♪
♪ And the love we once knew ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ How I wish we could go back in time ♪
♪ Do you ever think back ♪
♪ On old memories like that ♪
♪ Or do I ever cross your mind? ♪
♪ Do you ever wake up lonely ♪
♪ In the middle of the night ♪
♪ 'Cause you miss me? ♪
♪ Do you, darlin'? ♪
♪ Oh, and do your memories ♪
♪ Ever take you back ♪
♪ To another place and time? ♪
♪ Do you ever miss the feelings ♪
♪ And the love we shared ♪
♪ When you were with me? ♪
♪ Tell me darlin' ♪
♪ Or do I ever cross your mind? ♪
♪ Oh, how often I wish ♪
♪ That again I could kiss ♪
♪ Your sweet lips ♪
♪ Like I did long ago ♪
♪ And how often I long ♪
♪ For those two lovin' arms ♪
♪ That once held me so gentle and close ♪
♪ And when I think of you ♪
♪ And the love we once knew ♪
♪ How ♪
♪ I wish we could go back in time ♪
♪ Go back in time ♪
♪ Do you ever recall ♪
♪ These old memories at all ♪
♪ Or do I ever cross your mind? ♪
♪ Do I ever cross your mind? ♪
♪ Tell me darlin' ♪
[applause, cheering, whistling]
[announcer] Please welcome
two-time Grammy award winner
Lauren Daigle.
- [band playing]
- [cheering]
♪ I am a seeker ♪
♪ A poor sinful creature ♪
♪ There is no weaker than I am ♪
♪ I am a seeker ♪
♪ And you are a teacher ♪
♪ You are a reacher ♪
♪ So reach out ♪
♪ Reach out and lead me ♪
♪ Guide me and keep me ♪
♪ In the shelter of your care each day ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ 'Cause I am a seeker ♪
♪ And you are a keeper ♪
♪ You are a leader ♪
♪ Won't you show me the way? ♪
♪ I am a vessel ♪
♪ That's empty and useless ♪
♪ I am a bad seed ♪
♪ That fell by the way ♪
♪ Oh I am a loser ♪
♪ That wants to be a winner ♪
♪ And you are my last hope ♪
♪ Don't turn me away ♪
♪ Oh I am a seeker ♪
♪ A poor sinful creature ♪
♪ There is no weaker than I am ♪
♪ I am a seeker ♪
♪ And you are a teacher ♪
♪ You are the reacher ♪
♪ So reach down ♪
♪ Reach out and lead me ♪
♪ Oh guide me and keep me ♪
♪ In the shelter of your care each day ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Oh I am a seeker ♪
♪ And you are the keeper ♪
♪ You are the leader ♪
♪ Won't you show me the way? ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ You are the mountain ♪
♪ Hey yeah ♪
♪ From which there flows a fountain
Oh ♪
♪ So let that water wash my sins away ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Oh I am a seeker ♪
♪ And you are the keeper ♪
♪ You are the teacher ♪
♪ Won't you teach me the way? ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Reach out and lead me ♪
♪ Oh guide me and keep me ♪
♪ In the shelter of your care each day ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ 'Cause I am a seeker ♪
♪ And you are a keeper ♪
♪ You are a leader ♪
♪ Won't you show me ♪
♪ The way? ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
Hah! Yeah!
[cheering, whistling, applause]
All right!
[announcer] Here to perform
a Dolly classic we will always love,
the four-time Grammy award-winning
first lady of gospel,
Yolanda Adams.
[cheering, applause]
We love you, Dolly.
♪ If I ♪
♪ Should stay ♪
♪ I would only be in ♪
♪ Your way ♪
♪ But I'll go ♪
♪ And I'll know ♪
♪ I'll think of you every step of ♪
♪ The way ♪
♪ And I ♪
[band plays]
♪ Will always love you ♪
♪ I will always ♪
♪ Love you ♪
♪ You, my darling you ♪
♪ You ♪
♪ Bitter sweet memories ♪
♪ That is all I'm taking ♪
♪ With me ♪
♪ So goodbye ♪
♪ Please don't cry ♪
♪ We both know I'm not what you
♪ You need ♪
♪ And I ♪
♪ Will always love you ♪
♪ I will always ♪
♪ Love you ♪
♪ You ♪
♪ I hope life treats you kind ♪
♪ And I hope you have all you ♪
♪ Dreamed of ♪
♪ And I wish you joy and happiness ♪
♪ But above all this ♪
♪ I wish you ♪
♪ Love ♪
♪ And I ♪
♪ Will always love you ♪
♪ I will always love you ♪
♪ I will always ♪
♪ Love you ♪
♪ I will always love you ♪
♪ You you you you ♪
♪ I will always ♪
♪ Love ♪
♪ Love love love love love ♪
♪ You ♪
[cheering, applause]
♪ I will always ♪
♪ I will always love ♪
♪ You ♪
[cheering, whistling]
[announcer] Along with Dolly Parton,
these legendary artists
made quite the trio.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Linda Ronstadt and Emmylou Harris.
[applause, cheering]
Hi, everybody.
When Linda and I met in 1973,
the first thing we found out
about each other
was how much we both loved
and admired Dolly Parton.
So when Emmy called me
two years later saying,
"Dolly Parton is on her way to my house,"
I got in my car and went to Emmy's as fast
as I legally could, except I went faster.
[Emmylou chuckles]
Together at last,
we did what all singers do
when gathered in a living room.
We sat on the floor and sang a song.
And when we heard the blend
of our three voices,
well, we were pretty stunned.
We knew we had something special
and immediately decided we had to capture
that sound on a record.
Twelve years later, we did,
and we loved it so much,
we did another one.
The making of those albums
was just absolute pure joy.
Pure joy.
And that's why it's such a sweet thing
for me and Linda to be here tonight
celebrating our very dear
and great friend.
Such an extraordinary woman
who has touched so many lives
with her remarkable talent.
But not just with her talent.
Her grace, her humor.
She's one of the funniest people I know.
She cracks me up.
And her generosity.
Ladies and gentlemen, this is Dolly.
[country music plays]
[female announcer] She's as close
as a figur e of American entertainment
gets to royalty.
A queen of country
whose voice, songs, and influence
have reached virtually all fans
of popular music.
Over the course of her remarkable career,
Dolly Parton has transcended celebrityhood
to become a beloved icon,
instantly recognized around the world.
And behind the rhinestones,
the dazzling smile,
the larger than life image,
and the easygoing showmanship
is an even more remarkable wealth
of sheer talent.
On the strength of that talent,
Dolly rose from the humblest
of family beginnings
as the fourth of 12 children
growing up in rural Tennessee
to become a convention-smashing,
expectation-defying,
record-setting artist.
♪ Jolene ♪
♪ I'm begging of you please ♪
♪ Don't take my man ♪
[announcer] Songs in a suitcase
and nothing else to guarantee survival,
Dolly Parton moved to Nashville in 1964,
the day after her high school graduation.
Putting her dues in,
she quickly found success penning hits
for other artists of the time.
While she's collaborated
with other writers through the years,
most of her writing has been done alone.
Parton estimates she's penned
more than 3,000 songs,
including some of the 20th century's
most popular.
♪ Blessed it with a kiss ♪
♪ My coat of many colors ♪
♪ That my mama made for me ♪
[announcer] From "Coat of Many Colors"
to "Jolene" to "9 to 5,"
the themes of poverty, heartbreak,
and the workforce allow her audiences
to universally connect
with her storytelling.
♪ I will always ♪
♪ Love you ♪
[announcer] "I Will Always Love You"
is to date the biggest hit
of Parton's songwriting career
and one of the longest-running
number-one hits of the modern pop era
thanks to Whitney Houston's 1992
powerhouse delivery
for The Bodyguard film and soundtrack.
Parton made country music history
with the song
by becoming the first artist
to see the same song
ascend to number one twice
in different decades by the same artist.
With an illustrious catalog,
it's no surprise that Dolly Parton is the
most-awarded female artist
in the history of country music.
Dolly's music has lifted spirits
for decades,
and as the entrepreneur behind the wildly
successful Dollywood theme park,
she's brought joy to fans
in countless other ways.
But she's also embraced some more direct
approaches for improving the lives
of those in need.
Dolly has long been an advocate
for literacy,
and since 1996,
her Dollywood Foundation's
Imagination Library
has provided more than
a hundred million books
to young children around the globe.
Audiences of all ages continue
to be introduced to Dolly's music
via numerous younger artists
who have been both impacted
and encouraged by this musical icon.
From befriending Katy Perry
and performing with her on
the 2017 Academy of Country Music Awards
to being Miley Cyrus' godmother
and appearing on Disney Channel's hit
Hannah Montana,
the superstar loves to bring people
under her wings.
Dolly Parton is proud to be an influence
for all in the business today.
- [cheering, applause]
- [band plays]
[male announcer] Ladies and gentlemen,
our honoree tonight,
the MusiCares Person of the Year,
Dolly Parton.
Oh, thank you so much. Hello, everybody.
[cheering]
I have been in music for a long time.
But it has been in me a lot longer.
I used to stand out on the porch
back at my old Tennessee mountain home.
I used to put a tobacco stick
down in a crack in the floor,
put a tin can on top of it,
and pretend like I was singing
on the Grand Ole Opry.
'Course I'd sing to the chickens
and the ducks and the pigs
and the little kids
that were too young to crawl off.
[Dolly laughing]
But it was my dream.
And it's a long way
from the hills of East Tennessee
to the Hollywood Hills,
but it has been a wonderful journey.
Now, people say to me,
"Well, wasn't it a man's world
back when you got in the business?"
I said, "It sure was, and, buddy,
I had a ball."
[crowd laughing]
Because I have actually worked with
so many wonderful men,
and I've never met a man
that I didn't like
whose ass I couldn't kick
if he didn't treat me
with the right respect.
- [Dolly laughing]
- [cheering]
'Cause you got to remember,
I also still have that pistol in my purse,
and I can still change 'em
to a rooster to a hen with one shot.
- [Dolly chuckling]
- [cheering]
'Cause these nine-inch nails
and five-inch stilettos
are lethal weapons.
But seriously.
- [crowd laughing]
- It's been such a thrill for me tonight
to see all these great artists
that are singing songs that I've written
or been a part of.
'Course…
It's sort of like…
Watching them is sort of
like watching porn.
[crowd laughing]
You're not personally involved,
but you still get off on it.
So I...
- [Dolly laughing]
- [laughing, cheering]
I really got off on this show tonight.
- [crowd laughing, whistling]
- [Dolly] Hey, now, don't blame me.
At my age,
you'll take anything you can get.
[laughing]
- But seriously…
- [Dolly chuckling]
And I'm still hoping
that I live long enough
to get the Betty White longevity award.
- [crowd laughing]
- And I'm working on it.
Anyway, I feel so honored and proud
to be part of all of this
'cause I know that MusiCares
really is such a wonderful cause.
And so I'm happy
that we raised a lot of money.
And I want to commend this wonderful band,
Greg and all the musicians.
Didn't they do a great job?
- And the singers.
- [applause]
In addition to all of the artists,
I'm so proud of that.
And I know it's late.
- And I know you wanna pee, I know I do.
- [crowd laughing]
So I'm gonna kinda do one more song
if you don't mind.
I'm gonna walk over, though
and meet up with a friend of mine,
Linda Perry,
who's worked with me on a few things.
I had my nails too long to pick tonight
'cause I'm getting ready for the Grammys.
So thank you again, and God bless you.
- Okay? All right.
- [crowd cheering]
[Miley] Hello, everybody.
Two blondes in sparkly black dresses.
I stole this from her.
What an honor to be in this room
celebrating the fabulous life and career
of my fairy godmother, Dolly Parton.
[cheering, applause]
[Miley chuckling]
Everyone always asks me what it's like
to have Dolly as a godmother,
and I say she isn't just mine,
but she's everyone's fairy godmother.
And I share her joyfully
with the entire world.
Teaching us all what it means
to be truly kind,
to be individual, to never give up,
and to never judge a book by its cover
or its huge boobs and big hair.
- [Dolly laughing]
- [Miley] I got jokes too.
But seriously, tonight is a family affair,
and it has been such a privilege
to be a part of this night
that is beyond well deserved.
Nights like this were made for icons
like Dolly Parton
who is joined tonight
by one of the greatest,
Linda Perry.
[Miley] Linda, this is about you too.
You have inspired me
to wake in the morning
and step outside,
to take a deep breath and,
my favorite part,
get real high,
and scream at the top of my lungs,
"What's going on?"
I love you both so much.
Linda and Dolly Parton, everybody.
- [Dolly] Oh, thank you so much.
- [applause]
Miley, I love you,
and we did not coordinate our outfits.
We were laughing backstage
when we saw we were both wearing black.
But I'm honored to be here with Linda.
We've been doing some really good work,
and I asked her if she'd play tonight.
Thank you again.
- Linda, are you ready?
- I'm ready.
This is the story of my little coat
of many colors.
'Cause it's kind of the song
that got me here.
♪ Back through the years ♪
♪ I go wandrin' once again ♪
♪ Back to the seasons of my youth ♪
♪ And I recall a box of rags ♪
♪ Someone gave us ♪
♪ And how my mama put those rags to use ♪
♪ Now there were rags of many colors ♪
♪ But every piece was small ♪
♪ I didn't have a coat ♪
♪ And it was way down in the fall ♪
♪ Mama sewed the rags together ♪
♪ Sewing every piece with love ♪
♪ She made my coat of many colors ♪
♪ That I was so proud of ♪
♪ While Mama sewed she told a story ♪
♪ From the Bible she had read ♪
♪ About a coat of many colors ♪
♪ Joseph wore and then she said ♪
♪ I hope this coat will bring you ♪
♪ Good luck and happiness ♪
♪ And I just couldn't wait to wear it ♪
♪ And Mama blessed it with a kiss ♪
♪ My coat of many colors ♪
♪ That my mama made for me ♪
♪ Was made only from rags ♪
♪ But I wore it so proudly ♪
♪ And although we had no money ♪
♪ I was rich as I could be ♪
♪ In my coat of many colors ♪
♪ Mama made for me ♪
♪ And so with patches on my britches ♪
♪ And holes in both my shoes ♪
♪ In my coat of many colors ♪
♪ I hurried off to school ♪
♪ Just to find the others laughing ♪
♪ And making fun of me ♪
♪ In my coat of many colors ♪
♪ That Mom had made for me ♪
♪ And oh I couldn't understand that ♪
♪ 'Cause I felt I was rich ♪
♪ And I told 'em of the love ♪
♪ Mama sewed in every stitch ♪
♪ I even told 'em all that story ♪
♪ That Mama told me while she sewed ♪
♪ And why my coat of many colors ♪
♪ Was worth more than all their clothes ♪
♪ But they didn't understand it ♪
♪ And I tried to make 'em see ♪
♪ That one is only poor ♪
♪ Only if they choose to be ♪
♪ Aw it's true we had no money ♪
♪ But I was rich as I could be ♪
♪ In my coat of many colors ♪
♪ Mama made for me ♪
♪ 'Cause she made it just for me ♪
Thank you.
Goodnight and God bless you.
[crowd cheering]
Thank you so much.
And I will see you
down the road somewhere.
So long, guys.
How about it for Linda Perry?
My new friend.
Bye-bye!
[drums roll]
[band plays instrumental "9 to 5"]
[band plays "Here You Come Again"]
[applauding, cheering]