[Script Info]
;本字幕文件用 SrtEdit MPC播放版 Version 5.2 编辑制作
;Unicode SrtEdit Copyright(C) 2005-2009 袁卫国

Title: 
Original Script: 
Original Translation: 
Original Timing: 
Original Editing: 
Script Updated By: 
Update Details: 
ScriptType: v4.00+
Collisions: Normal
PlayResX: 0
PlayResY: 0
Timer: 100.0000
Synch Point: 
WrapStyle: 0
ScaledBorderAndShadow: no

[V4+ Styles]
Format: Name, Fontname, Fontsize, PrimaryColour, SecondaryColour, OutlineColour, BackColour, Bold, Italic, Underline, StrikeOut, ScaleX, ScaleY, Spacing, Angle, BorderStyle, Outline, Shadow, Alignment, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Encoding
Style: Default,方正兰亭纤黑_GBK,20,&H00FFFFFF,&H00000000,&H00000000,&H00000000,-1,0,0,0,100,100,0,0,1,2,1,2,5,5,6,134

[Events]
Format: Layer, Start, End, Style, Name, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Effect, Text
Dialogue: 0,0:01:00.23,0:01:04.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\fs72\an5\1c&HFFE9D2&}灵异第六感
Dialogue: 0,0:04:09.28,0:04:11.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,天气转凉了\N{\fs14}It's gettin' cold.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:04:15.58,0:04:18.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个框真不错\N{\fs14}That is one fine frame.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:04:18.92,0:04:21.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真是个不错的框\N{\fs14}One fine frame that is.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:04:21.15,0:04:24.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你觉得...\N{\fs14}How much...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:04:26.39,0:04:30.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这么高级的框值多少钱\N{\fs14}Does a fine frame like that cost, do you think?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:04:32.70,0:04:36.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我没跟你说过 你喝醉时真像苏斯博士\N{\fs14}I never told you, but you sound a little like Dr. Seuss when you're drunk.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:04:36.87,0:04:40.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,安娜 我是说真的\N{\fs14}I know. I'm serious.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:04:40.27,0:04:42.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我很认真哦\N{\fs14}Serious, I am.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:04:44.58,0:04:47.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我猜最少也要几百块钱\N{\fs14}I'd say it cost at least a couple hundred.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:04:47.11,0:04:51.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 我要宣读一下 - 我真的像苏斯博士?\N{\fs14}- I'm gonna read it for you. - Do I really sound like Dr. Seuss?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:04:51.72,0:04:54.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,兹表扬他在儿童心理学界\N{\fs14}"In recognition of his outstanding achievement...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:04:54.92,0:04:57.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 不凡的成就 - 嗯嗯\N{\fs14}- "in the field of child psychology, - Mm-hmm.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:04:57.59,0:05:02.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,与热忱的工作态度以及他持续努力地帮助...\N{\fs14}His dedication to his work and his continuing efforts to improve the quality of life..."{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:05:02.60,0:05:06.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,专心一点 好吗?\N{\fs14}Will you concentrate?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:05:06.13,0:05:08.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他持续努力地帮助...\N{\fs14}"...his continuing efforts to improve the quality of life...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:05:08.52,0:05:12.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,无数儿童及其家人\N{\fs14}"for countless children and their families,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:05:12.44,0:05:16.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,市府很荣幸颁予费城之子\N{\fs14}"the city of Philadelphia proudly bestows upon its son...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:05:16.54,0:05:19.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,马尔科姆·克劳医生 就是你\N{\fs14}Dr. Malcolm Crowe..." That's you...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:05:19.35,0:05:22.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,特等专业优良奖状\N{\fs14}"...the Mayor's Citation for professional excellence."{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:05:24.22,0:05:27.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他们称你费城之子呢\N{\fs14}They called you their son.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:05:27.19,0:05:29.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,天呐\N{\fs14}Wow.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:05:29.99,0:05:32.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我们该把这挂到厕所去\N{\fs14}We should hang it in the bathroom.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:05:35.60,0:05:38.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,今晚对我们很重要\N{\fs14}This is an important night for us.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:05:39.67,0:05:44.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,终于有人了解你所做的牺牲\N{\fs14}Finally, someone is recognizing the sacrifices you've made...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:05:44.00,0:05:48.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你将一切置于其次 包括我\N{\fs14}that you have put everything second, including me,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:05:48.64,0:05:51.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,只为了这些儿童的福祉\N{\fs14}for those families that they're talking about.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:05:55.72,0:05:58.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这也证明我丈夫很有天份\N{\fs14}They're also saying that my husband has a gift.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:06:00.15,0:06:02.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你教孩子如何坚强面对...\N{\fs14}You have a gift that teaches children...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:06:02.16,0:06:08.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,连大人都受不了的处境\N{\fs14}how to be strong in situations... Where most adults would piss on themselves.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:06:08.73,0:06:11.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我相信这些话是真的\N{\fs14}I believe what they wrote is real.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:06:15.74,0:06:17.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,谢谢你\N{\fs14}Thank you.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:06:21.27,0:06:24.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想用酒杯喝酒\N{\fs14}I would like some wine in a glass.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:06:24.04,0:06:26.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不想用马克杯\N{\fs14}I would not like it in a mug.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:06:26.08,0:06:30.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也不想用啤酒杯\N{\fs14}I would not like it in a jug.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:06:52.77,0:06:54.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,马尔科姆\N{\fs14}Look.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:07:37.88,0:07:40.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,安娜 别动 别出声\N{\fs14}Anna, don't move. Don't make a sound.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:07:45.19,0:07:48.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这里是洛克斯街47号\N{\fs14}This is 47 Locus Street.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:07:49.86,0:07:51.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你闯入了私人住宅\N{\fs14}You've broken a window and entered a private residence.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:07:51.97,0:07:55.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你什么也不知道\N{\fs14}You don't know so many things.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:07:55.77,0:08:01.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这里没有毒品或药物\N{\fs14}There are no needles or prescription drugs of any kind in this house.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:08:09.98,0:08:12.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,人独处时为什么会害怕?\N{\fs14}Do you know why you're afraid when you're alone?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:08:15.99,0:08:18.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我知道\N{\fs14}I do. I do.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:08:18.66,0:08:20.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你要干嘛?\N{\fs14}What do you want?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:08:20.99,0:08:24.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他答应过我 我要他做到\N{\fs14}What he promised me! I want what he promised me.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:08:24.86,0:08:27.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 我的天 - 我认识你吗?\N{\fs14}- Oh, my God. - Do I know you?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:08:27.33,0:08:31.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,神医 你不认得我了?\N{\fs14}Don't you know me, hero?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:08:31.04,0:08:33.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你不记得自己的病人?\N{\fs14}Don't you even remember your own patients?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:08:37.18,0:08:39.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,市区诊所\N{\fs14}Downtown clinic.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:08:39.64,0:08:42.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,单亲家庭\N{\fs14}Single-parent family.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:08:44.28,0:08:46.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可能患有情绪失调症\N{\fs14}Possible mood disorder.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:08:48.52,0:08:50.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我那时好害怕\N{\fs14}I was afraid!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:08:50.86,0:08:55.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你说我无法面对我父母离婚\N{\fs14}You told me I was having trouble coping with my parents'divorce.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:08:55.53,0:08:58.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你错了 你错了\N{\fs14}You were wrong. You were wrong.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:09:00.90,0:09:03.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,现在看看我\N{\fs14}Now look at me!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:09:03.54,0:09:07.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 我不想再感到害怕 - 等我想一下\N{\fs14}- I don't want to be afraid no more. - Just give me a minute to think.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:09:08.07,0:09:10.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我等你十年了\N{\fs14}I waited ten years for you!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:09:10.31,0:09:11.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不会再等了\N{\fs14}I'm not giving you nothin'!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:09:12.31,0:09:15.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,班·费肯?\N{\fs14}Ben Friedkin?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:09:15.15,0:09:19.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有些人叫我怪胎\N{\fs14}Some people, they call me "freak."{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:09:19.59,0:09:21.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,朗诺·桑尼?\N{\fs14}Ryan Sumner?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:09:21.82,0:09:24.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我的确是个怪胎 看看我\N{\fs14}I am. I am a freak. Look at...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:09:26.99,0:09:29.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,文森\N{\fs14}Vincent.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:09:29.20,0:09:31.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,文森·格瑞\N{\fs14}Vincent Gray.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:09:33.47,0:09:36.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不 你没有\N{\fs14}No, you don't.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:09:36.17,0:09:38.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我当然记得你\N{\fs14}I do remember you.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:09:38.67,0:09:42.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,安静 聪明\N{\fs14}Quiet, very smart.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:09:42.34,0:09:44.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有同情心\N{\fs14}Compassionate.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:09:46.05,0:09:48.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,非常有同情心\N{\fs14}Unusually compassionate.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:09:50.68,0:09:52.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你忘了我也受到诅咒\N{\fs14}You forgot cursed.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:09:56.09,0:09:58.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你放弃我\N{\fs14}You failed me.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:09:58.79,0:10:00.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你放弃了我!\N{\fs14}You failed me!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:10:04.33,0:10:07.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,文森 很抱歉我... 没帮到你\N{\fs14}Vincent, I'm sorry if I wasn't... if I didn't help you.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:10:08.20,0:10:11.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,让我再试一下\N{\fs14}But if you just let me try,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:10:11.10,0:10:15.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,如果你能再给我一次机会\N{\fs14}if you just give me a chance...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:10:21.28,0:10:24.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,上帝啊\N{\fs14}Oh, God! Oh, God!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:10:24.18,0:10:27.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 文森 - 别说话\N{\fs14}- Did Vincent... - Don't talk. Shh.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:10:40.62,0:10:44.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,"次年秋天"
Dialogue: 0,0:10:46.17,0:10:48.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,"南费城"
Dialogue: 0,0:10:54.43,0:10:56.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,"文森·格瑞:十岁"
Dialogue: 0,0:11:12.35,0:11:15.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,"科尔·希尔:九岁"
Dialogue: 0,0:11:15.42,0:11:17.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,"父母离异"
Dialogue: 0,0:11:17.95,0:11:20.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,"极度焦虑 个性孤僻"
Dialogue: 0,0:11:20.79,0:11:23.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,"可能患有情绪失调症"
Dialogue: 0,0:12:57.70,0:12:59.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,科尔 别怕\N{\fs14}It's okay, Cole.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:12:59.74,0:13:02.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我是马尔科姆·克劳医生\N{\fs14}My name is Dr. Malcolm Crowe.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:13:03.81,0:13:07.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我们今天本来要见面的 但是... 我没赶到\N{\fs14}We were supposed to meet today, but I missed our appointment.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:13:07.95,0:13:09.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,对不起\N{\fs14}I'm sorry.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:13:18.52,0:13:23.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在很久以前的欧洲 人们会躲进教堂\N{\fs14}You know, in the olden days in Europe, people used to hide out in churches.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:13:23.16,0:13:25.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,寻求庇护\N{\fs14}They would claim sanctuary.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:13:30.60,0:13:32.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他们在躲什么?\N{\fs14}What were they hiding from?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:13:36.21,0:13:38.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,大多是在躲坏人\N{\fs14}Bad people, mostly.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:13:38.51,0:13:43.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那些想把他们关进监狱 伤害他们的坏人\N{\fs14}People that wanted to put them in jail, hurt them.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:13:45.52,0:13:49.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我注意到你的眼镜 上面并没有镜片\N{\fs14}I noticed your eyeglasses. They don't have any lenses in them.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:13:49.39,0:13:51.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这是我爸的\N{\fs14}They're my dad's.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:13:51.69,0:13:54.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有镜片不舒服\N{\fs14}The lenses hurt my eyes.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:13:55.80,0:14:00.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你刚才跟玩具兵说什么?\N{\fs14}What were you talking about with your soldiers when I came in? Day...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:14:00.13,0:14:03.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,De profundus clamo adite domine
Dialogue: 0,0:14:04.10,0:14:06.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那是拉丁文\N{\fs14}It's called "Latin."{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:14:10.58,0:14:14.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 它们都说拉丁文吗? - 没有\N{\fs14}- All your soldiers speak Latin? - No.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:14:14.81,0:14:16.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,只有一个\N{\fs14}Just one.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:14:18.82,0:14:21.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你是好医生吗?\N{\fs14}Are you a good doctor?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:14:21.62,0:14:24.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是的\N{\fs14}Well,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:14:24.16,0:14:26.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,以前是\N{\fs14}I used to be.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:14:27.46,0:14:30.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我得过一张奖状 市长颁给我的\N{\fs14}I won an award once from the mayor.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:14:31.70,0:14:33.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,它的框很贵\N{\fs14}It had an expensive frame.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:14:48.15,0:14:50.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我会再见到你 对吧?\N{\fs14}I'm gonna see you again, right?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:14:50.18,0:14:52.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,若你不介意的话\N{\fs14}If that's okay with you.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:15:26.25,0:15:28.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我回来了\N{\fs14}It's me.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:16:12.06,0:16:14.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,"拉丁文字典"
Dialogue: 0,0:16:45.42,0:16:50.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,"神啊 我自深渊向你哭喊"
Dialogue: 0,0:17:26.04,0:17:28.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,早安\N{\fs14}Hey, good morning.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:17:35.48,0:17:37.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,科尔\N{\fs14}Cole.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:17:40.82,0:17:43.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,科尔\N{\fs14}Cole!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:17:43.82,0:17:46.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你的巧克力脆片都软掉了\N{\fs14}Hey, your Cocoa Puffs are gettin' soggy.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:17:48.90,0:17:54.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,让我看看 宝贝 这儿有污点\N{\fs14}Let me see you. Oh, honey, you got a spot. Head up.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:17:59.94,0:18:02.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可以了 终于好了\N{\fs14}Okay, here we go.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:18:16.76,0:18:18.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你在找什么吗?\N{\fs14}Something you were looking for, baby?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:18:21.83,0:18:23.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,夹心馅饼\N{\fs14}Pop Tarts?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:18:25.80,0:18:27.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就在这儿\N{\fs14}They're right here.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:18:37.28,0:18:39.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,妈咪 你在想什么?\N{\fs14}Well, what are you thinking, Mama?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:18:41.35,0:18:44.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,很多事\N{\fs14}Lots of things.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:18:44.68,0:18:46.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你觉得我很坏吗?\N{\fs14}Anything bad about me?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:18:46.95,0:18:49.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嗨 看着我\N{\fs14}Hey, look at my face.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:18:49.99,0:18:52.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我绝对不会觉得你很坏\N{\fs14}I was not thinking something bad about you.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:18:53.93,0:18:55.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,明白吗?\N{\fs14}Got it?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:18:58.06,0:19:00.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,明白\N{\fs14}Got it.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:19:01.53,0:19:03.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,抬起头\N{\fs14}Here, head up.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:19:03.54,0:19:05.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 汤米来了 - 好了 领带塞进去 科尔\N{\fs14}- That's Tommy. - That's okay. You tuck it in.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:19:05.77,0:19:08.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你要这个吗?\N{\fs14}Cole, you want this?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:19:38.64,0:19:42.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怪胎 搭肩膀那招如何?\N{\fs14}Hey, freak, how'd you like that "arm around the shoulder" bit?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:19:42.21,0:19:44.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我临时想的 我真有天份\N{\fs14}I just made that up. I went with it.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:19:44.88,0:19:47.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一流的演员都会 这叫即兴表演\N{\fs14}It's what great actors do. It's called "improv."{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:20:26.35,0:20:28.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,宝贝\N{\fs14}Hey, baby.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:20:28.75,0:20:30.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,今天过得好吗?\N{\fs14}How was your day?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:20:32.79,0:20:35.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,恩\N{\fs14}Hmm?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:20:38.13,0:20:40.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你想说什么就说\N{\fs14}You know, you can tell me things if you need to.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:20:46.01,0:20:49.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你知道我今天做什么了吗?\N{\fs14}Well, you know what I did today?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:20:49.21,0:20:54.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我...一早就赢了宾州彩券\N{\fs14}I, uh, I won the Pennsylvania Lottery in the morning,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:20:54.38,0:20:56.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我辞掉了工作\N{\fs14}I quit my jobs,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:20:56.38,0:21:01.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,接着到公园去 吃了好多巧克力慕斯派\N{\fs14}and I ate a big picnic in the park with lots of chocolate mousse pie.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:21:01.39,0:21:04.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,下午还在喷泉里游泳\N{\fs14}And then I swam in the fountain all afternoon.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:21:04.82,0:21:06.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你做了什么?\N{\fs14}What'd you do?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:21:12.13,0:21:15.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,下课后我被选为棒球队的第一选手\N{\fs14}I was picked first for kick ball teams at recess.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:21:15.74,0:21:17.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我打了支满垒全垒打\N{\fs14}I hit a grand slam to win the game.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:21:17.74,0:21:21.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,同学把我抬起来大声欢呼\N{\fs14}Everybody lifted me up on their shoulders and carried me around, cheering.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:21:26.71,0:21:29.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真不错 我替你煎三角形松饼\N{\fs14}Well, in that case, I am gonna make you some triangle pancakes.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:21:30.85,0:21:32.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一个钟头就好\N{\fs14}You got an hour.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:21:38.79,0:21:40.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嗨\N{\fs14}Hi.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:21:44.83,0:21:47.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,想坐吗?\N{\fs14}Wanna sit?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:21:51.77,0:21:54.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,今天不想谈吗?\N{\fs14}Don't feel like talking today?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:21:57.84,0:21:59.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,想玩游戏吗?\N{\fs14}Wanna play a game?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:22:01.41,0:22:03.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这是个猜谜游戏\N{\fs14}It's a mind-reading game.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:22:03.75,0:22:05.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是这样玩的\N{\fs14}Here's how it works.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:22:05.85,0:22:08.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我猜你在想什么\N{\fs14}I read your mind.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:22:08.35,0:22:11.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我说对了 你就往前走一步\N{\fs14}If what I say is right, you take one step towards the chair.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:22:11.72,0:22:17.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,如果我说错 你就往后一步退到门口\N{\fs14}If what I say is wrong, you take one step back... towards the doorway.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:22:17.83,0:22:21.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,若你走到椅子旁就得坐下\N{\fs14}If you reach the chair, you sit down.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:22:21.50,0:22:25.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,若你退到门口就可以走\N{\fs14}If you reach the door, you can go.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:22:26.87,0:22:28.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,想玩吗?\N{\fs14}Wanna play?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:22:36.12,0:22:38.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好\N{\fs14}Okay.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:22:53.77,0:22:57.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你父母刚离婚时\N{\fs14}When your mother and father were first divorced,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:22:57.24,0:23:01.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你妈妈找过我这种医生 他帮不了她\N{\fs14}your mom went to see a doctor like me, and he didn't help her.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:23:01.57,0:23:05.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以你觉得我也帮不了你\N{\fs14}So you think I'm not going to be able to help you.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:23:20.76,0:23:25.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你很担心 她说她跟医生说了一些事\N{\fs14}You're worried that she said she told him things...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:23:25.50,0:23:27.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一些她没跟别人说的事\N{\fs14}things she couldn't tell anyone else.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:23:29.17,0:23:31.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一些秘密\N{\fs14}Secrets.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:23:38.38,0:23:40.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你也有不想告诉我的秘密\N{\fs14}You have a secret, but you don't want to tell me.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:23:53.93,0:23:58.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你父亲走之前把那只表留给你\N{\fs14}Your dad gave you that watch as a present just before he went away.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:24:08.91,0:24:11.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他把它忘在抽屉里了\N{\fs14}He forgot it in a drawer.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:24:11.41,0:24:13.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,它坏了\N{\fs14}Doesn't work.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:24:25.39,0:24:28.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你在学校很安静 但...\N{\fs14}You keep pretty quiet in school, but...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:24:28.89,0:24:33.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你是好学生 从不闯祸\N{\fs14}you're a good student, you've never really been in any serious trouble.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:24:41.07,0:24:43.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有一次上美术课\N{\fs14}We were supposed to draw a picture.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:24:43.08,0:24:45.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,随便我们画什么\N{\fs14}Anything we wanted.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:24:48.18,0:24:51.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我画了一个人\N{\fs14}I drew a man.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:24:51.28,0:24:54.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,另一人拿螺丝起子刺他脖子\N{\fs14}He got hurt in the neck by another man with a screwdriver.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:24:57.89,0:25:00.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你在电视看到的吗?\N{\fs14}You saw that on TV, Cole?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:25:04.06,0:25:06.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,老师很生气\N{\fs14}Everyone got upset.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:25:07.57,0:25:10.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他们找妈妈开会\N{\fs14}They had a meeting.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:25:10.44,0:25:12.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,妈妈开始哭\N{\fs14}Mom started crying.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:25:12.44,0:25:15.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,后来我就不画这些了\N{\fs14}I don't draw like that anymore.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:25:17.08,0:25:19.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你现在画什么?\N{\fs14}How do you draw now?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:25:21.45,0:25:24.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,微笑的人们\N{\fs14}I draw... people smiling,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:25:24.92,0:25:26.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,奔跑的狗儿\N{\fs14}dogs running,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:25:28.35,0:25:30.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,还有彩虹\N{\fs14}rainbows.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:25:31.52,0:25:34.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,画彩虹不会惹上麻烦\N{\fs14}They don't have meetings about rainbows.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:25:35.73,0:25:39.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,没错 我想是不会\N{\fs14}No. I guess they don't.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:25:47.87,0:25:50.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我现在在想什么?\N{\fs14}What am I thinking now?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:25:51.04,0:25:54.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不知道你在想什么\N{\fs14}I don't know what you're thinking now.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:26:00.69,0:26:02.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我在想...\N{\fs14}I was thinking...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:26:02.62,0:26:04.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你人很好\N{\fs14}you're nice,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:26:06.73,0:26:08.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但是你帮不了我\N{\fs14}but you can't help me.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:26:25.44,0:26:29.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我以为你说的是另一家餐厅\N{\fs14}I thought you meant the other Italian restaurant I asked you to marry me in.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:26:36.19,0:26:38.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,安娜 对不起\N{\fs14}I'm so sorry, Anna.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:26:39.56,0:26:42.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我最近老是忘了时间\N{\fs14}I just can't seem to keep track of time.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:26:44.90,0:26:47.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,今天的访谈也不太顺利\N{\fs14}And I didn't have a very good session today.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:26:52.30,0:26:55.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他们俩非常相似\N{\fs14}They're both so similar.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:26:55.24,0:27:00.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,相同的动作和表情 也有同样的心理问题\N{\fs14}The same mannerisms, same expressions, same things hanging over their head.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:27:02.98,0:27:05.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他可能有受到虐待\N{\fs14}I think it might be some kind of abuse.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:27:06.55,0:27:10.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,科尔的手上有抓痕\N{\fs14}Cole has... scratches on his arm.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:27:10.06,0:27:12.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好像是被指甲抓伤\N{\fs14}I think they might be fingernail cuts.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:27:12.76,0:27:15.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也许是抗拒时抓伤的 我不知道\N{\fs14}Defensive cuts, maybe. I don't know.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:27:16.66,0:27:20.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可能是老师或邻居\N{\fs14}Maybe a teacher or a neighbor.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:27:20.17,0:27:25.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,应该不是他母亲 我看过他们相处 看起来不像是她\N{\fs14}I don't think it's the mother. I've seen her with him, and it doesn't seem to fit.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:27:28.37,0:27:30.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我也可能看错\N{\fs14}Or I could just be wrong.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:27:30.38,0:27:33.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也许他只是很喜欢爬树\N{\fs14}Maybe he's just a kid who likes to climb trees a lot.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:27:41.89,0:27:44.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,安娜\N{\fs14}Anna.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:27:45.49,0:27:48.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我知道我疏远了你\N{\fs14}I know that I've been a little distant, all right?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:27:48.60,0:27:51.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我知道你很生气\N{\fs14}I know that it makes you mad. I just...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:27:51.83,0:27:55.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但我觉得这是我弥补的机会 我不想错失它\N{\fs14}feel like I'm being given a second chance, and I don't want it to slip away.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:27:57.37,0:27:59.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,安娜\N{\fs14}Anna.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:28:01.11,0:28:03.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,结婚纪念日快乐\N{\fs14}Happy anniversary.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:28:12.82,0:28:14.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,别一直看我\N{\fs14}Stop looking at me.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:28:14.82,0:28:17.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不喜欢被人这样看\N{\fs14}I don't like when people look at me like that.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:28:20.46,0:28:24.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我都跟汤米·唐一起上学\N{\fs14}I walk this way to school with Tommy Tammisimo.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:28:24.53,0:28:26.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他是你的好朋友?\N{\fs14}Is he your best buddy?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:28:26.53,0:28:28.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他讨厌我\N{\fs14}He hates me.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:28:28.53,0:28:31.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你也讨厌他?\N{\fs14}Do you hate him?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:28:31.04,0:28:33.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不\N{\fs14}No.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:28:34.57,0:28:36.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这是你妈妈安排的?\N{\fs14}Did your mom set that up?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:28:36.91,0:28:38.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,对\N{\fs14}Yes.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:28:40.61,0:28:43.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你跟她说过汤米的事吗?\N{\fs14}Did you ever talk to your mom about how things are with Tommy?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:28:43.25,0:28:46.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 我什么都不跟她说 - 为什么?\N{\fs14}- I don't tell her things. - Why not?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:28:46.45,0:28:49.21,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不希望她像别人那样看我\N{\fs14}'Cause she doesn't look at me like everybody else, and I don't want her to.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:28:49.22,0:28:52.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 我不想让她知道 - 知道什么?\N{\fs14}- I don't want her to know. - Know what?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:28:52.02,0:28:54.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我是个怪胎\N{\fs14}That I'm a freak.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:28:54.56,0:28:56.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嘿\N{\fs14}Hey.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:28:56.76,0:29:00.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你不是怪胎 好吗?\N{\fs14}You are not a freak. Okay?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:29:00.73,0:29:05.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,别相信别人说的话 那全是屁话\N{\fs14}Don't you believe anybody that tries to convince you of that. That's bullshit.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:29:05.60,0:29:08.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你不必相信这种话\N{\fs14}You don't have to go through your life believing that.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:29:09.71,0:29:11.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好吗?\N{\fs14}Okay?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:29:14.08,0:29:16.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,走吧\N{\fs14}Come on.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:29:19.28,0:29:25.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 你说了脏话 - 我知道 对不起\N{\fs14}- You said the "S" word. - Yeah, I know. Sorry.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:30:32.86,0:30:35.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你爸跟收费站小姐\N{\fs14}So your dad lives in Pittsburgh with a lady...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:30:35.09,0:30:37.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,住在一起?\N{\fs14}that works in a toll booth?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:30:39.53,0:30:42.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她工作时尿急怎么办?\N{\fs14}I wonder if she has to pee when she's working.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:30:42.94,0:30:45.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她会忍住吗?\N{\fs14}Think she just holds it?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:30:45.07,0:30:48.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不知道 我也在想这问题\N{\fs14}I don't know. I was just thinking about that myself.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:30:50.11,0:30:52.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,今天你一直问起我爸\N{\fs14}You asked a lot of questions about Dad today.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:30:52.24,0:30:54.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,为什么?\N{\fs14}How come?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:30:54.55,0:30:58.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有时我们会做些事引人注意\N{\fs14}Well, sometimes we do things to draw attention,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:30:58.32,0:31:03.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,以表达我们对某些事的感觉\N{\fs14}to express our feelings about certain issues...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:31:03.56,0:31:06.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,像离婚之类的事\N{\fs14}divorce, whatever.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:31:07.03,0:31:10.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就像有些人会故意丢东西 让人找到\N{\fs14}For example, a person might leave something on the desk for someone else to find.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:31:15.30,0:31:17.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你知道自由联想书写法吗?\N{\fs14}Do you know what free association writing is, Cole?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:31:19.14,0:31:21.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不知道\N{\fs14}No.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:31:21.27,0:31:25.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,自由联想书写法就是拿支笔\N{\fs14}Free association writing is when you take a pencil in your hand,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:31:25.61,0:31:31.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在一张纸上开始写字\N{\fs14}and you put the pencil to a piece of paper and you start writing.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:31:31.08,0:31:33.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不去看或是想你在写什么\N{\fs14}And you don't look at what you're writing or think about what you're writing.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:31:33.85,0:31:37.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,只是不停地写\N{\fs14}You just keep your hand moving.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:31:37.29,0:31:41.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你的手只要不停下来 过一阵子...\N{\fs14}And after a while, if you keep your hand moving long enough,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:31:41.39,0:31:44.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那些你从不知道的思路会浮现出来\N{\fs14}words and thoughts start coming out that you didn't even know you had in you.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:31:44.86,0:31:50.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也许是... 你在别处听到的事\N{\fs14}It could be something you heard somewhere else,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:31:50.44,0:31:53.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,或是藏在你内心深处的事\N{\fs14}or feelings you had deep inside of you.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:31:57.41,0:32:00.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你写过吗? "不让婴儿安静我就宰了你"\N{\fs14}Have you ever done any free association writing, Cole?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:32:03.75,0:32:05.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,写过\N{\fs14}Yes.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:32:05.75,0:32:07.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你都写些什么?\N{\fs14}What did you write?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:32:09.35,0:32:11.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,令人不安的事\N{\fs14}Upset words.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:32:13.13,0:32:16.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在你爸离开前 你写过那些事吗?\N{\fs14}Did you ever write any upset words before your father left?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:32:17.96,0:32:19.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不记得了\N{\fs14}I don't remember.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:32:21.90,0:32:24.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,帮我个忙 好吗?\N{\fs14}Can you do something for me?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:32:26.27,0:32:30.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,想想对于我们的访谈 你要什么结果\N{\fs14}I want you to think about what you wanna get out of our time together...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:32:30.28,0:32:32.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,订个目标\N{\fs14}what our goal should be.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:32:33.38,0:32:35.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我要什么?\N{\fs14}Something I want?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:32:37.15,0:32:39.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,如果你能改变你的人生\N{\fs14}If you could change something in your life, anything at all,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:32:39.42,0:32:41.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你要改变什么?\N{\fs14}what would it be?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:32:41.95,0:32:45.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我能不能不要什么?\N{\fs14}Instead of something I want, can it be something I don't want?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:32:46.96,0:32:48.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可以\N{\fs14}Okay.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:32:50.00,0:32:52.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不要再感到害怕\N{\fs14}I don't want to be scared anymore.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:32:58.31,0:33:04.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,"伤痕可能是自残的结果"
Dialogue: 0,0:33:04.84,0:33:06.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你去开门好吗?\N{\fs14}You gonna get that?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:33:13.65,0:33:15.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你去开门好不好?\N{\fs14}Are you gonna get that?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:33:20.43,0:33:22.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 你好-你好\N{\fs14}- Hi. - Hi.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:33:22.73,0:33:24.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 你在店里没看够我吗? - 我正要去...\N{\fs14}- Don't you see enough of me at the store? - Yeah, I'm on my way out...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:33:24.43,0:33:27.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,亚美希人的跳蚤市场\N{\fs14}to the flea market in the Amish country.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:33:27.40,0:33:29.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想请你一起去\N{\fs14}I thought maybe you'd wanna come along...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:33:29.40,0:33:32.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,顺便教我挑货\N{\fs14}and show me how to buy at one of these things.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:33:32.24,0:33:35.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我今天不想跟亚美希人打交道\N{\fs14}I don't know if I can deal with the Amish today.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:33:35.11,0:33:38.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他们不准别人骂脏话吐口水\N{\fs14}You can't curse or spit or anything around them.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:33:38.78,0:33:41.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我以为你想出去走走\N{\fs14}I just figured maybe you'd just want to get out and get some air,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:33:41.71,0:33:44.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,最近你有点沮丧\N{\fs14}because you've seemed kind of down lately.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:33:45.48,0:33:48.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我没事\N{\fs14}Um, I'm okay.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:33:49.96,0:33:52.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我回来时可以过来把东西带给你看\N{\fs14}Do you think that maybe I should stop by on the way back, show you what I got?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:33:52.92,0:33:55.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不会很麻烦的\N{\fs14}Because that wouldn't be a problem.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:33:55.29,0:33:58.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不用了 礼拜一再说\N{\fs14}No, l... You know, I can see on Monday.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:33:58.73,0:34:01.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好吧 没关系\N{\fs14}Sure, yeah, that's fiine. I'm just...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:34:01.83,0:34:05.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那我走了 回头再谈\N{\fs14}Okay, so I guess I'm gonna get going then. I'll speak to you later.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:34:05.54,0:34:08.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 别踩到马粪了 - 多谢关心\N{\fs14}- Don't step in the horse manure. - Thank you very much.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:34:18.48,0:34:21.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,臭小子 快走吧\N{\fs14}Keep moving, cheese dick.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:34:28.39,0:34:32.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,"我不会再打人"
Dialogue: 0,0:34:44.74,0:34:50.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有没有人能告诉我 1790到1800年间\N{\fs14}Can anybody guess what city was capital of the United States of America...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:34:50.34,0:34:54.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,美国首都在哪里?\N{\fs14}from 1790 to 1800?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:34:56.92,0:35:00.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,给你们一个提示 是你们住的城市\N{\fs14}I'll give you a hint: It's the city you live in.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:35:00.49,0:35:03.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 费城 - 没错\N{\fs14}Philadelphia! - Right, right.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:35:03.53,0:35:06.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,费城是美国最古老的城市之一\N{\fs14}Philadelphia's one of the oldest cities in this country.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:35:06.13,0:35:08.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,很多人终其一生待在这\N{\fs14}A lot of generations have lived here and died here.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:35:08.67,0:35:13.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这里的每个地方几乎都有悠久历史\N{\fs14}Almost anyplace you go in this city has a history and a story behind it.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:35:13.34,0:35:16.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,包括这所学校和校园\N{\fs14}Even this school and the grounds it sits on.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:35:16.51,0:35:21.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有没有人能告诉我 一百年前这所学校是什么?\N{\fs14}Can anyone guess what this building was used for a hundred years ago...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:35:21.18,0:35:25.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在你来上学之前 甚至在我来这儿上学之前\N{\fs14}before you went to school here, before I went to this school even?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:35:32.56,0:35:34.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,科尔 你说\N{\fs14}Yes, Cole.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:35:36.86,0:35:38.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他们以前在这儿吊死人\N{\fs14}They used to hang people here.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:35:43.77,0:35:47.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不对 你从哪儿听来的?\N{\fs14}No, uh, that... Mm-mm. That's not correct. Where'd you hear that?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:35:47.37,0:35:52.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他们把哭喊的犯人拉开\N{\fs14}They pulled the people in, crying and kissing their families bye.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:35:52.58,0:35:56.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,旁观者向他们吐口水\N{\fs14}People watching... spit at them.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:35:58.18,0:36:02.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,科尔 这里以前是法院\N{\fs14}Uh, Cole, this building was a legal courthouse.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:36:02.62,0:36:06.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,很多法律在这里制定通过\N{\fs14}Laws were passed here... some of the very first laws of this country.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:36:06.12,0:36:08.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,当时这儿都是律师 议员\N{\fs14}This whole building was full of, uh, lawyers,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:36:08.39,0:36:11.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 立法者 - 他们也吊死犯人\N{\fs14}- lawmakers. - They were the ones that hanged everybody.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:36:13.83,0:36:15.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,呃\N{\fs14}Uh...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:36:15.87,0:36:18.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不知道是谁跟你说的 但是...\N{\fs14}I don't know which one of these guys told you that,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:36:18.67,0:36:21.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他们不过是想吓唬你\N{\fs14}but, uh, they were just trying to scare you.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:36:31.72,0:36:34.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不喜欢别人这样看我\N{\fs14}I don't like people looking at me like that.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:36:36.87,0:36:37.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎样看你?\N{\fs14}Like what?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:36:38.14,0:36:39.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,别看了\N{\fs14}Stop it!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:36:40.23,0:36:43.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不知道该怎么看\N{\fs14}I, uh, l-l-I don't know how else to look.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:36:45.10,0:36:47.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你是结巴史丹利\N{\fs14}You're Stuttering Stanley!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:36:50.17,0:36:53.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 什么? - 你在上学时讲话都会结巴\N{\fs14}- Excuse me? - You talked funny when you went to school here.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:36:53.91,0:36:55.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一直到高中都还这样\N{\fs14}You talked funny all the way to high school.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:36:55.74,0:36:59.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 什么? - 别这样看人 这样对方会很难受\N{\fs14}- What? - You shouldn't look at people. It makes them feel bad.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:36:59.84,0:37:01.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 你怎么... - 别再看着我了\N{\fs14}- How did you... - Stop looking at me!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:37:02.10,0:37:05.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是...是谁告诉你的?\N{\fs14}Who have you... Been speaking to?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:37:05.43,0:37:08.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,结巴史丹利 结巴史丹利...\N{\fs14}Stuttering Stanley! Stuttering Stanley!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:37:08.59,0:37:10.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 别说了 - 结巴史丹利\N{\fs14}- Stop it. St-St-St... - Stuttering Stanley!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:37:10.92,0:37:14.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 别说了 - 结巴史丹利\N{\fs14}- Stop that! - Stuttering Stanley! Stuttering Stanley!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:37:14.69,0:37:18.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,结巴史丹利...\N{\fs14}Stuttering Stanley! Stuttering Stanley!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:37:18.86,0:37:22.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,住嘴 你... 你这怪胎\N{\fs14}Shut up, you f-f-freak!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:37:37.32,0:37:39.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嗨 大人物\N{\fs14}Hey, big guy.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:37:43.92,0:37:45.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你好吗?\N{\fs14}How's it goin'?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:37:45.92,0:37:48.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我现在什么都不想谈\N{\fs14}I don't wanna talk about anything right now.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:37:48.39,0:37:50.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好吧\N{\fs14}Okay.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:38:05.08,0:38:07.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你喜欢魔术吗?\N{\fs14}You like magic?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:38:07.75,0:38:09.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,恩\N{\fs14}Hmm?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:38:13.32,0:38:16.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,仔细看 神奇的铜板\N{\fs14}Observe: The magic penny.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:38:16.92,0:38:20.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,看起来很普通\N{\fs14}Looks like an ordinary penny.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:38:20.23,0:38:22.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但我只要摇一下\N{\fs14}But I do my little magic shake, and...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:38:24.26,0:38:26.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,它就会跑到右手里\N{\fs14}now it's in my right hand.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:38:26.33,0:38:28.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不过把戏还没有完\N{\fs14}But that's not the end of the magic trick.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:38:29.83,0:38:32.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我只要再摇一下\N{\fs14}I do another little shake, and...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:38:35.01,0:38:36.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,它就会跑到口袋里\N{\fs14}right there in the vest pocket.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:38:38.38,0:38:40.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不过这也还没有完\N{\fs14}But that's not the end of the magic trick.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:38:40.85,0:38:43.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我再摇一下\N{\fs14}I do another little shake...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:38:43.45,0:38:45.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,然后\N{\fs14}and...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:38:46.95,0:38:50.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,它又回到左手来了\N{\fs14}right back in the left hand where it started.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:38:51.66,0:38:53.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这不是魔术\N{\fs14}That isn't magic.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:38:53.66,0:38:57.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,什么意思?当然是魔术\N{\fs14}What are you talking about? Of course it's magic.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:38:57.56,0:39:00.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,铜板一直都在你的左手\N{\fs14}You just kept the penny in that hand the whole time.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:39:04.87,0:39:06.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是吗?\N{\fs14}Think so?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:39:08.34,0:39:11.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不知道你也会搞笑\N{\fs14}I didn't know you were funny.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:39:24.96,0:39:28.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,马尔科姆 给我坐下来听好\N{\fs14}Malcolm, sit your cute butt down and listen up.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:39:29.83,0:39:33.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,实际上 安娜就像我的姐妹\N{\fs14}No doubt about it. Anna is like my sister.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:39:33.36,0:39:35.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你最好让她快乐\N{\fs14}And you better make her happy. I'm not talkin'about no...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:39:35.73,0:39:39.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不只是表面上的快乐而已\N{\fs14}"Mmm, this taste like real butter"kind of happy.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:39:40.04,0:39:43.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我说的是...\N{\fs14}I'm talkin' about... What's up, girl?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:39:43.11,0:39:45.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,像"真善美"的茱丽安德鲁丝\N{\fs14}"Julie Andrews twirling around like...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:39:45.78,0:39:48.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在山顶上跳舞一样那么快乐\N{\fs14}a mental patient on a mountaintop" kind of happy.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:39:48.28,0:39:51.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我说的是这种快乐\N{\fs14}That's the kind of happy I'm talkin'about.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:39:51.55,0:39:53.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,过来\N{\fs14}Shh. Come here.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:39:53.59,0:39:56.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,别跟她说是我说的\N{\fs14}Don't tell her I told you,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:39:56.19,0:39:59.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她说她第一次在街上见到你\N{\fs14}but she said she knew she love you...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:39:59.66,0:40:02.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她就知道她爱你\N{\fs14}from the first time she met you on the street.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:40:03.83,0:40:08.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她愿意为你付出一切\N{\fs14}She'd do anything for you.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:40:08.20,0:40:10.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我爱你们\N{\fs14}I love you guys.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:40:13.10,0:40:15.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我哭惨了...\N{\fs14}My nose is running. Turn it...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:40:57.38,0:41:02.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,"抗忧郁剂 日服二次"
Dialogue: 0,0:41:34.45,0:41:36.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,只要轻轻摇一下\N{\fs14}And then you do the magic shake.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:41:37.72,0:41:40.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,铜板就会从我口袋...\N{\fs14}The penny has moved from my pocket...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:41:40.22,0:41:42.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,跑到原来的手里\N{\fs14}all the way back to the hand it started in.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:41:45.23,0:41:47.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真无聊\N{\fs14}That's stupid.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:41:49.30,0:41:51.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这应该很好笑的\N{\fs14}It's supposed to be funny.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:41:51.87,0:41:55.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,蠢毙了 把铜板还我\N{\fs14}It's stupid. I want my penny back.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:41:57.91,0:42:00.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他很少被人邀请 这是我们的荣幸\N{\fs14}He doesn't get invited places, so it's our pleasure.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:42:01.28,0:42:04.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他上次参加聚会已是一年前的事\N{\fs14}Last time was a Chuck E. Cheese party a year ago.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:42:04.85,0:42:09.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他躲在玩具隧道里不肯出来\N{\fs14}He hid in one of those purple plastic tunnels and didn't come out.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:42:09.12,0:42:12.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 在什么地方? - 是一间儿童餐厅 小孩去的地方\N{\fs14}- Chucky who? - Cheese. It's a kids place.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:42:12.22,0:42:15.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 借过 - 抱歉\N{\fs14}- Excuse me. - Sorry.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:42:49.73,0:42:52.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,外面有人吗?\N{\fs14}Is someone out there?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:42:53.00,0:42:55.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,请开这扇门\N{\fs14}Open this door, please. Come on.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:42:55.43,0:43:00.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我没法呼吸 你听见了就开门吧\N{\fs14}I can't breathe. If you can hear me, open this door.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:43:00.34,0:43:04.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我发誓我没偷主人的马匹\N{\fs14}I swear on my life I didn't take the master's horse.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:43:04.58,0:43:08.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,快开门 否则我破门而出把你扼毙\N{\fs14}Open this door, or I'll break through it and grab you!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:43:08.35,0:43:12.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 广告明星都有自己的休息室 - 用来干嘛?\N{\fs14}- The star of the commercial always gets his own trailer. - For what?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:43:12.92,0:43:16.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,用来单独思考角色与对白\N{\fs14}He needs a place to think about his character, alone.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:43:16.12,0:43:18.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你只有一句台词\N{\fs14}You only had one line.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:43:21.06,0:43:22.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,达伦 快看\N{\fs14}Derrick, check it out.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:43:23.26,0:43:28.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我爸逼我邀请他的\N{\fs14}Oh, yeah. My dad made me invite him.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:43:46.15,0:43:48.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,生日快乐 达伦\N{\fs14}Happy birthday, Derrick.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:43:48.89,0:43:51.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你想进去吗?\N{\fs14}Is there somethin' you want to see in there?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:43:51.19,0:43:53.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不\N{\fs14}No.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:43:55.73,0:43:57.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我们要演一部戏\N{\fs14}We're gonna put on a pretend play.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:43:57.80,0:44:01.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 你想加入吗? - 好\N{\fs14}- Wanna be in it? - Okay.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:44:01.97,0:44:05.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,剧名是"地窖里有谁"?\N{\fs14}It's called "Locked in the Dungeon."{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:44:05.57,0:44:08.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你就演被关在地窖里的角色\N{\fs14}Yes, Cole, and, uh, you get to be the one locked in the dungeon.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:44:12.98,0:44:15.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不\N{\fs14}Don't! Don't! Don't! Don't!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:44:15.95,0:44:18.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不要...\N{\fs14}Don't!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:44:18.58,0:44:20.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不要...\N{\fs14}Let me out! No! No!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:44:20.62,0:44:22.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不!不!\N{\fs14}No! No!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:44:45.91,0:44:48.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,科尔?\N{\fs14}- Cole?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:44:51.15,0:44:54.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,科尔?\N{\fs14}Cole!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:44:54.15,0:44:57.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这门的钥匙在哪?\N{\fs14}Is there a key for this door?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:44:57.12,0:44:59.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,科尔?听得见我吗?\N{\fs14}Cole? Honey? Honey, can you hear me?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:45:03.49,0:45:06.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,科尔...天啊!\N{\fs14}Oh, my God! Cole!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:45:06.30,0:45:10.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,救救我!救命啊!\N{\fs14}Help me! Help! Help! Help!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:45:22.65,0:45:25.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他没有心脏病\N{\fs14}The tests would indicate he did not have a seizure.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:45:25.42,0:45:27.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他很好\N{\fs14}He's doing fiine.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:45:27.95,0:45:30.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,休息一下就可以回家了\N{\fs14}After some rest, he can go home tonight.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:45:35.96,0:45:40.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你儿子身上有些瘀青和伤痕\N{\fs14}There's some cuts and bruises on your son...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:45:40.23,0:45:43.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 我很担心 - 糟了\N{\fs14}- that are concerning me. - Oh, man.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:45:45.37,0:45:47.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那是运动造成的\N{\fs14}Yeah, those are from sports.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:45:53.38,0:45:55.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你以为是我弄的?\N{\fs14}You think I hurt my child?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:45:59.08,0:46:01.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你想我是个坏母亲?\N{\fs14}You think I'm a bad mother?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:46:01.12,0:46:06.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,史隆太太就在那里 她是医院社工人员\N{\fs14}Mrs. Sloan over there, she's a social worker with the hospital.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:46:06.89,0:46:09.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她会问你一些手续上的问题\N{\fs14}She's gonna ask you a couple procedural questions.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:46:10.76,0:46:13.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我孩子今天怎么了?\N{\fs14}What happened to my child today?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:46:13.43,0:46:18.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他出事了 出事了 事情很不对劲\N{\fs14}Something was happening to him, physically happening. Something was very wrong!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:46:23.14,0:46:25.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嗨\N{\fs14}Hey.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:46:35.05,0:46:38.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你父亲睡前会说故事吗?\N{\fs14}Did your father used to tell you bedtime stories?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:46:49.43,0:46:52.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,很久以前 有一个王子\N{\fs14}Once upon a time there was this young prince,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:46:52.64,0:46:57.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他决定要开车兜风\N{\fs14}and he decided that he wanted to go for a drive.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:46:57.38,0:47:02.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他找来他的司机 他们就开始出发\N{\fs14}He got his driver, and they started driving.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:47:02.48,0:47:05.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,开着 开着\N{\fs14}Driving, driving.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:47:05.62,0:47:10.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,开了很久的车\N{\fs14}Driving a lot.And, uh,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:47:10.82,0:47:14.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他们开太久 他睡着了...\N{\fs14}they drove so much that he fell asleep.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:47:14.56,0:47:16.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,当他醒来...\N{\fs14}And...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:47:19.70,0:47:23.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他发现他们还在开车\N{\fs14}Then he woke up, and he realized they were still driving.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:47:23.73,0:47:26.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 这旅程真长 - 克劳医生?\N{\fs14}- This was a very long trip. - Dr. Crowe?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:47:27.67,0:47:30.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你以前根本没说过睡前故事\N{\fs14}You haven't told bedtime stories before.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:47:30.64,0:47:32.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我是没说过\N{\fs14}Uh, not too many, no.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:47:32.94,0:47:35.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你得加点剧情进去\N{\fs14}You have to add some twists and stuff.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:47:37.18,0:47:39.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好 加点剧情\N{\fs14}Okay. Some twists.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:47:40.99,0:47:44.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,哪种剧情?给我点提示吧\N{\fs14}Like what kind of twists? Give me an example.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:47:46.09,0:47:47.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 也许他们没油了 - 他们没油?\N{\fs14}- Maybe they run out of gas. - They run out of gas?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:47:48.38,0:47:52.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,没油 很好 他们在开车嘛\N{\fs14}That's good, 'cause they're driving, right? Okay, so...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:47:52.90,0:47:55.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,告诉我你为何忧伤?\N{\fs14}Tell me the story about why you're sad.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:47:58.20,0:48:00.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你觉得我很忧伤?\N{\fs14}You think I'm sad?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:48:03.11,0:48:05.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你怎会这么想?\N{\fs14}What makes you think that?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:48:07.21,0:48:09.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你的眼神告诉我的\N{\fs14}Your eyes told me.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:48:11.02,0:48:13.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不该谈这个的\N{\fs14}Not supposed to talk about stuff like that.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:48:25.13,0:48:28.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,以前有个叫马尔科姆·克劳的人\N{\fs14}Once upon a time, there was this person named Malcolm.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:48:28.23,0:48:30.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他帮小孩解决问题\N{\fs14}He worked with children.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:48:32.34,0:48:34.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他喜欢这份工作\N{\fs14}He loved it.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:48:34.97,0:48:38.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他爱这工作甚于一切\N{\fs14}He loved it more than anything else.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:48:40.48,0:48:41.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有一天...\N{\fs14}And then one night, he found out that...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:48:41.87,0:48:45.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他发现他错待了一个孩子\N{\fs14}he made a mistake with one of them.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:48:45.72,0:48:48.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他帮不了那个孩子\N{\fs14}He couldn't help that one.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:48:49.92,0:48:52.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他自责不已\N{\fs14}And he can't stop thinking about it.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:48:52.59,0:48:54.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,无法忘怀\N{\fs14}He can't forget.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:48:58.00,0:49:00.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,从那时起 一切都改变了\N{\fs14}Ever since then, things have been different.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:49:02.10,0:49:05.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他不再是以前的他了\N{\fs14}He's not the same person that he used to be.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:49:06.84,0:49:09.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他太太\N{\fs14}And his wife...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:49:09.24,0:49:13.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不喜欢现在的他\N{\fs14}doesn't like the person that he's become.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:49:13.01,0:49:15.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他们不再交谈 像陌生人一样\N{\fs14}They barely speak anymore. They're like strangers.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:49:19.08,0:49:22.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有一天 马尔科姆遇见了一个小孩\N{\fs14}And then one day, Malcolm meets this wonderful little boy.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:49:22.82,0:49:26.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一个很棒的小孩\N{\fs14}A really cool little boy.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:49:26.59,0:49:29.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这小孩跟那孩子很像\N{\fs14}Reminds him a lot of the other one.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:49:31.86,0:49:35.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,马尔科姆决定要帮助这小孩\N{\fs14}And Malcolm decides to try and help this new boy...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:49:37.13,0:49:41.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,因为他觉得如果能帮得了这个小孩\N{\fs14}'cause he feels that if he can help this new boy,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:49:41.71,0:49:46.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那就等于是... 救了先前的那个小孩\N{\fs14}it will be like... helping that other one too.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:49:48.91,0:49:51.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这故事有什么结局?\N{\fs14}How does the story end?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:49:53.45,0:49:55.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不知道\N{\fs14}I don't know.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:50:12.64,0:50:15.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,现在我要跟你说我的秘密\N{\fs14}I wanna tell you my secret now.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:50:20.58,0:50:22.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好\N{\fs14}Okay.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:50:29.55,0:50:32.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我可以看见死人\N{\fs14}I see dead people.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:50:34.73,0:50:36.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在梦里吗?\N{\fs14}In your dreams?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:50:38.86,0:50:40.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在你醒着的时候?\N{\fs14}While you're awake?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:50:46.94,0:50:50.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在棺材里的死人吗?\N{\fs14}Dead people, like, in graves, in coffins?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:50:50.41,0:50:53.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他们像我们一样走来走去\N{\fs14}Walking around like regular people.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:50:54.75,0:50:57.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,互相看不见对方\N{\fs14}They don't see each other.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:50:57.35,0:51:00.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他们只看得到他们想看到的\N{\fs14}They only see what they wanna see.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:51:01.29,0:51:04.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他们不知道自己已经死了\N{\fs14}They don't know they're dead.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:51:05.82,0:51:08.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你多常见到他们?\N{\fs14}How often do you see them?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:51:11.53,0:51:14.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,每时每刻\N{\fs14}All the time.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:51:16.50,0:51:18.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,到处都有他们\N{\fs14}They're everywhere.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:51:21.41,0:51:24.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你不会跟别人说吧?\N{\fs14}You won't tell anyone my secret, right?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:51:24.58,0:51:27.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不会 我保证\N{\fs14}No. I promise.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:51:29.18,0:51:32.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,等我睡着再走 好吗?\N{\fs14}Will you stay here until I fall asleep?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:51:34.25,0:51:36.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,当然好\N{\fs14}Of course.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:51:46.80,0:51:52.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,科尔...他的病情比我想的严重\N{\fs14}Cole has pathologies more severe than initially assessed.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:51:53.37,0:51:56.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他会产生幻觉\N{\fs14}He's suffering from visual hallucinations,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:51:56.27,0:51:59.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有妄想症\N{\fs14}paranoia,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:51:59.04,0:52:03.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,还有某种学龄儿童的精神分裂症\N{\fs14}Some kind of... school-age schizophrenia.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:52:05.25,0:52:08.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也许必须住院服药\N{\fs14}Medication, hospitalization may be required.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:52:15.16,0:52:17.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我也帮不了他\N{\fs14}And I'm not helping him.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:53:44.75,0:53:47.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我是席琳恩 科尔的妈妈\N{\fs14}Hi, this is Lynn Sear, Cole's mom.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:53:49.05,0:53:51.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想跟你谈谈你儿子和他的朋友\N{\fs14}Yeah, uh, l... I'd like to talk to you...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:53:51.79,0:53:56.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,叫他们别再碰我的儿子...\N{\fs14}about your boy and his friends keeping their goddamn hands off my son.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:55:33.66,0:55:35.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,妈妈?\N{\fs14}Mama?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:55:36.83,0:55:40.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不行 晚饭还没煮好\N{\fs14}No, dinner is not ready!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:55:40.23,0:55:42.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你想怎样?\N{\fs14}What are you gonna do?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:55:43.00,0:55:46.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你不能再伤害我了\N{\fs14}You can't hurt me anymore!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:55:46.54,0:55:49.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,兰尼 你是个坏老公\N{\fs14}Neddy! You're a terrible husband, Neddy!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:55:49.91,0:55:52.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我是被你逼死的 兰尼\N{\fs14}Look what you made me do! Neddy!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:56:12.30,0:56:14.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,从前有个男孩\N{\fs14}Once there was a boy,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:56:14.67,0:56:17.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一个与众不同的男孩\N{\fs14}very different from all the other boys.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:56:17.27,0:56:21.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他住在丛林里\N{\fs14}He lived in the jungle,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:56:21.27,0:56:24.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他能跟动物交谈\N{\fs14}and he could speak to the animals.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:56:39.28,0:56:41.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你觉得这出戏很逊吗?\N{\fs14}Did you think the play sucked big time?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:56:41.98,0:56:45.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,什么?\N{\fs14}What?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:56:45.25,0:56:48.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,汤米·唐演过咳嗽药广告\N{\fs14}Tommy Tammisimo acted in a cough syrup commercial.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:56:48.76,0:56:51.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他说大家都演得很不自然\N{\fs14}He said everyone was self-conscious and unrealistic.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:56:51.63,0:56:53.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,还说这出戏逊毙了\N{\fs14}He said the play sucked big time.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:56:53.76,0:56:56.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个汤米好像很讨人厌\N{\fs14}This Tommy kid sounds like a real punk.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:56:58.50,0:57:02.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我觉得这出戏很好看 比"猫"还棒\N{\fs14}I thought the play was excellent. Better than "Cats."{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:57:02.27,0:57:04.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- "猫"? - 算了\N{\fs14}- "Cats"? - Never mind.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:57:07.54,0:57:10.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你在医院里说的话很有意思\N{\fs14}Cole, I was really interested in what you told me at the hospital.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:57:10.74,0:57:13.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想再多听一些\N{\fs14}I'd like to hear more about it.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:57:23.46,0:57:25.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,科尔\N{\fs14}Cole?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:57:28.83,0:57:30.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎么了?\N{\fs14}What?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:57:43.14,0:57:46.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那里有什么吗?\N{\fs14}Is something up there?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:57:49.72,0:57:52.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,科尔\N{\fs14}Cole,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:57:55.29,0:57:58.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我什么也没看见\N{\fs14}I don't see anything.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:58:01.76,0:58:05.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不要动\N{\fs14}Be real still.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:58:08.40,0:58:10.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有时你会有种感觉\N{\fs14}Sometimes you feel it inside,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:58:10.74,0:58:13.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好像坠入万丈深渊\N{\fs14}like you're falling down real fast,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:58:13.64,0:58:16.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但你其实根本没动\N{\fs14}but you're really just standing still.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:58:21.21,0:58:25.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你会不会突然觉得颈背寒毛直竖?\N{\fs14}You ever feel the prickly things on the back of your neck?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:58:25.55,0:58:28.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,会\N{\fs14}Yes.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:58:28.52,0:58:32.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,全身上下都起鸡皮疙瘩?\N{\fs14}And the tiny hairs on your arm, you know, when they stand up?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:58:32.49,0:58:35.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,会\N{\fs14}Yes.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:58:36.76,0:58:39.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那就是他们\N{\fs14}That's them.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:58:42.14,0:58:44.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,当他们生气\N{\fs14}When they get mad,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:58:48.24,0:58:50.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就会变得很冷\N{\fs14}it gets cold.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:59:07.46,0:59:11.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我没看到 你确定他们真的在吗?\N{\fs14}I don't see anything. Are you sure they're there?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:59:12.87,0:59:15.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,科尔\N{\fs14}Cole?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:59:17.10,0:59:19.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,请你叫他们走开\N{\fs14}Please make them leave.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:59:19.94,0:59:22.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我正在努力\N{\fs14}I'm workin' on it.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,0:59:24.34,0:59:26.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,走吧\N{\fs14}Come on.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:00:11.32,1:00:14.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,爸 妈\N{\fs14}Mommy, Daddy?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:00:16.96,1:00:19.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我的喉咙好疼\N{\fs14}My throat hurts.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:00:27.91,1:00:29.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,跑!快跑!\N{\fs14}Run! Run!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:00:31.34,1:00:33.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,小儿止咳糖浆\N{\fs14}Pedia Ease cough suppressant.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:00:33.35,1:00:37.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 药力温和 有效... - 科尔\N{\fs14}- Gentle, fast, effect... - Cole.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:00:38.51,1:00:41.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不管他们怎么说 暖气坏了\N{\fs14}I don't care what they say, this thing is broken.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:00:49.80,1:00:52.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,把手套脱掉\N{\fs14}Take 'em off.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:00:55.74,1:00:58.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,别放在餐桌上\N{\fs14}I don't want them on my table.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:01:02.88,1:01:05.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我在打扫时看了你的抽屉\N{\fs14}I saw what was in your bureau drawer when I was cleaning.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:01:05.98,1:01:07.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你要不要坦白一下?\N{\fs14}Got something you want to confess?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:01:11.02,1:01:17.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你为何老是拿走那只坠子?\N{\fs14}Hmm? The bumblebee pendant? Why do you keep taking it?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:01:20.99,1:01:23.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那是外婆的\N{\fs14}It was Grandma's.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:01:23.26,1:01:26.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,要是摔坏了你知道我会怎样\N{\fs14}You know, what if it broke? You know how sad I'd be.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:01:28.74,1:01:31.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你会哭 因为你很想念外婆\N{\fs14}You'd cry 'cause you miss Grandma so much.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:01:32.81,1:01:35.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,没错\N{\fs14}That's right.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:01:39.05,1:01:42.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,人们有时以为失去了什么\N{\fs14}Sometimes people think they lose things,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:01:44.55,1:01:48.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,其实没有 只是被换了个地方\N{\fs14}and they really didn't lose them... it just gets moved.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:01:48.39,1:01:50.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是你把那坠子换了个地方的吗?\N{\fs14}So, did you move the bumblebee pendant?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:01:59.10,1:02:01.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不要生气\N{\fs14}Don't get mad.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:02:01.27,1:02:03.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这次是谁拿走的?\N{\fs14}So, who moved it this time?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:02:03.37,1:02:07.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也许有人跑进来 把坠子从我抽屉拿走\N{\fs14}Maybe someone came in our house, took the bumblebee pendant out of my closet...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:02:07.11,1:02:09.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,再放进你的抽屉\N{\fs14}and placed it nicely in your drawer.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:02:10.68,1:02:14.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 也许是 - 我很累了 科尔\N{\fs14}- Maybe. - God, I am so tired, Cole.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:02:14.11,1:02:16.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我的身心都很疲倦 我的心灵也累了\N{\fs14}I'm tired in my body, I'm tired in my mind,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:02:16.68,1:02:19.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我的心灵也累了\N{\fs14}I'm... tired in my heart.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:02:19.75,1:02:21.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我需要帮忙\N{\fs14}I need some help.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:02:21.92,1:02:26.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我们家的状况不是很好\N{\fs14}You know, I don't know if you noticed, but our little family isn't doing so good.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:02:26.23,1:02:28.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我一直在祷告\N{\fs14}I mean, I've been praying,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:02:28.26,1:02:31.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也许是我祷告的方法不对\N{\fs14}but I must not be praying right.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:02:31.43,1:02:34.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,现在我们只能自求多福\N{\fs14}Looks like we're just gonna have to answer each other's prayers.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:02:37.90,1:02:40.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我们无法坦白就无法撑下去\N{\fs14}If we can't talk to each other, we're not gonna make it.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:02:44.58,1:02:48.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,老实告诉我 宝贝 我不会生气的\N{\fs14}Now, tell me, baby. I won't get mad, honey.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:02:48.31,1:02:50.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,坠子是不是你拿的?\N{\fs14}Did you take the bumblebee pendant?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:02:59.36,1:03:01.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不是\N{\fs14}No.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:03:03.53,1:03:06.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你吃够了 马上离开餐桌\N{\fs14}You've had enough roast beef. You need to leave the table.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:03:08.90,1:03:11.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,快点\N{\fs14}Go!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:03:34.06,1:03:39.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,快来 我带你看我爸藏的枪\N{\fs14}Hey, come on. I'll show you where my dad keeps his gun. Come on.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:03:44.27,1:03:47.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,狗狗 来吧\N{\fs14}Sebastian, come on!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:03:47.94,1:03:52.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,妈妈\N{\fs14}- Mama?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:03:56.48,1:03:59.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,如果你的气消了\N{\fs14}If you're not very mad,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:03:59.19,1:04:01.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我今晚能不能跟你一起睡?\N{\fs14}can I sleep in your bed tonight?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:04:03.62,1:04:06.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,看着我\N{\fs14}Look at my face.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:04:06.26,1:04:09.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我没有生气\N{\fs14}I'm not very mad.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:04:12.10,1:04:15.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,宝贝 你为什么发抖?\N{\fs14}- Baby, why are you shaking?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:04:17.10,1:04:19.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,科尔 怎么了?\N{\fs14}Cole, what's wrong?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:04:19.41,1:04:23.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,神啊 求求你告诉我\N{\fs14}Oh, God, please tell me!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:04:23.31,1:04:26.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,求求你\N{\fs14}Oh, please.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:04:39.69,1:04:42.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这是爱德华时期的 镶工细致 镶满了细钻...\N{\fs14}It's Edwardian, beautifully worked...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:04:42.66,1:04:47.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,和一颗缅甸蓝宝石\N{\fs14}with mine-cut diamonds and an actual color Burmese sapphire.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:04:47.80,1:04:50.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,经典之作\N{\fs14}It's timeless.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:04:53.01,1:04:55.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你...\N{\fs14}You, uh...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:04:55.58,1:04:58.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有没有普通一点的钻戒?\N{\fs14}Got anything a little plainer?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:04:58.38,1:05:03.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,普通一点? 你想用个普通的钻戒 来配你那普通的老婆 对吧?\N{\fs14}Plainer? You want a plain ring to go with your plain fiance? Is that how it is?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:05:03.15,1:05:07.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不是啦 宝贝 别生气\N{\fs14}No! Baby, don't get in a tissy.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:05:09.22,1:05:13.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你太美了\N{\fs14}Uh... You're so beautiful.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:05:13.99,1:05:17.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你就像缅甸蓝宝石一样美\N{\fs14}You're like a Burmese sapphire all by yourself.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:05:17.80,1:05:20.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 你根本不需要这些 - 嗯嗯\N{\fs14}- You don't need all that. - Uh-huh.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:05:20.70,1:05:23.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,为什么不先试戴一下\N{\fs14}Why don't you try it on...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:05:23.27,1:05:25.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,看看你们觉得怎样?\N{\fs14}and see how you both feel about it.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:05:30.81,1:05:34.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎么样?\N{\fs14}There. How does that feel?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:05:34.41,1:05:38.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这枚钻戒代表一种渴望\N{\fs14}I think this piece, um, communicates a longing.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:05:38.79,1:05:41.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,曾经拥有这枚钻戒的女主人\N{\fs14}I imagine that the woman who owned it...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:05:41.89,1:05:45.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有过一段刻骨铭心的恋情\N{\fs14}Ioved a man that she couldn't be with.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:05:46.46,1:05:49.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她是卷发和棕色眼睛吗?\N{\fs14}Did he have wavy hair and chestnut eyes?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:05:49.70,1:05:53.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 呃 - 我不知道\N{\fs14}- Huh? - Um, I don't know, but...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:05:53.87,1:05:55.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这里有许多首饰都能和主人沟通\N{\fs14}a lot of the pieces in this store communicate,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:05:55.91,1:06:00.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你们应该挑个合适的\N{\fs14}and I think you should choose a piece that speaks to you.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:06:01.77,1:06:06.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,当人们死后 他们所拥有过的东西\N{\fs14}I think maybe when people own things and then they pass away,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:06:06.65,1:06:10.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,上面都会留下他们的痕迹\N{\fs14}a part of themselves gets printed on those things,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:06:10.18,1:06:13.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就像...是指纹\N{\fs14}like... like fingerprints.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:06:15.99,1:06:18.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我帮你们包起来\N{\fs14}I'll just wrap it up.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:06:24.96,1:06:27.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你不需要一个硕士\N{\fs14}You don't need a guy with a Master's.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:06:27.33,1:06:30.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你需要个虎臂熊腰的壮汉\N{\fs14}You need a wrestler with a neck larger than his head.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:06:30.17,1:06:33.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不 我需要有硕士学位的壮汉\N{\fs14}No, I need a wrestler with a Master's.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:06:34.51,1:06:37.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这是什么? 生日快乐\N{\fs14}- What's this? - Happy birthday.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:06:37.14,1:06:39.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 你送的? - 嗯\N{\fs14}- For me? - Mm-hmm.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:06:46.89,1:06:51.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这是... 初版书\N{\fs14}It's a... first edition.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:06:51.22,1:06:53.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,哇哦\N{\fs14}Wow.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:06:53.76,1:06:58.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 你一定花了不少钱 - 不 我从你的年终奖金上扣下来\N{\fs14}- You know, this is too much. - No. Took it out of your Christmas bonus.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:06:58.67,1:07:03.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,太棒了 安娜\N{\fs14}It's perfect, Anna.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:07:03.00,1:07:06.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,谢谢\N{\fs14}- Thanks.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:07:11.08,1:07:14.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你最想要什么?\N{\fs14}What do you want more than anything?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:07:14.01,1:07:16.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不知道\N{\fs14}I don't know.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:07:16.32,1:07:19.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我说过我想要什么\N{\fs14}I've told you what I want.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:07:21.85,1:07:23.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我知道我想要什么\N{\fs14}I know what I want.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:07:25.99,1:07:28.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,跟我老婆再度交谈\N{\fs14}I want to be able to talk to my wife again.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:07:31.03,1:07:34.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就跟以前一样\N{\fs14}The way we used to talk to each other.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:07:34.43,1:07:37.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,回到两人世界\N{\fs14}Like there was no one else in the world except us.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:07:39.24,1:07:40.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你要怎么做?\N{\fs14}How are you gonna do that?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:07:46.78,1:07:48.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不能再当你的医生了\N{\fs14}Can't be your doctor anymore.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:07:48.78,1:07:53.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我没有关怀自己的家人\N{\fs14}I haven't paid enough attention to my family.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:07:53.42,1:07:55.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这样是不对的\N{\fs14}Bad things happen when you do that.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:07:57.32,1:07:59.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你懂吗?\N{\fs14}Do you understand?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:07:59.73,1:08:03.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 我会帮你介绍... - 别放弃我\N{\fs14}- I'm going to transfer you. I know two psychologists. - Don't fail me.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:08:06.20,1:08:08.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,别放弃我 你是唯一能帮助我的人\N{\fs14}Don't give up. You're the only one who can help me, I know it.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:08:10.50,1:08:13.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我帮不了你\N{\fs14}I can't help you.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:08:14.47,1:08:16.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你说过...\N{\fs14}You...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:08:16.48,1:08:19.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,会有别人来帮你的\N{\fs14}Someone else can help you.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:08:22.82,1:08:26.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你相信我 对吧?\N{\fs14}You believe me, right?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:08:29.76,1:08:32.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,克劳医生 你相信我的秘密吧?\N{\fs14}Dr. Crowe, you believe my secret, right?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:08:34.56,1:08:37.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不知道该怎么回答\N{\fs14}I don't know how to answer that, Cole.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:08:47.61,1:08:50.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你如果不相信我的话\N{\fs14}How can you help me...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:08:50.61,1:08:53.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你怎么能够帮我?\N{\fs14}if you don't believe me?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:08:56.98,1:09:01.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有些魔术是真的\N{\fs14}Some magic's real.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:09:16.34,1:09:20.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,人独处时为什么会害怕?\N{\fs14}Do you know why you're afraid when you're alone?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:09:20.41,1:09:24.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我知道 我知道\N{\fs14}I do. I do.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:09:31.62,1:09:35.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,抱歉让你等这么久 文森\N{\fs14}I'm sorry, Vincent. I hope I didn't leave you alone too long.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:09:35.79,1:09:39.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这里好冷\N{\fs14}Whew. It's cold in here.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:09:41.69,1:09:45.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,文森 你怎么哭了?\N{\fs14}Vincent, why are you crying?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:09:49.17,1:09:52.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你不会相信我的\N{\fs14}You won't believe.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:09:57.91,1:10:02.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,抱歉让你等这么久 文森\N{\fs14}Sorry, Vincent. I hope I didn't leave you alone too long.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:10:02.08,1:10:05.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这里好冷\N{\fs14}Whew. It's cold in here.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:10:08.05,1:10:11.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,文森...\N{\fs14}Vincent...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:10:11.09,1:10:15.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这里好冷\N{\fs14}Whew. It's cold in here.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:10:20.83,1:10:24.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,知道吗 我也不喜欢针筒\N{\fs14}Nah, you know what? I never liked him either.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:10:24.44,1:10:27.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我小时候有一次验血\N{\fs14}When I was a kid, I had this blood test done,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:10:27.04,1:10:31.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我吐了护士一身\N{\fs14}and I threw up chili cheese fries all over this male nurse.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:10:32.78,1:10:35.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,抱歉 李医生在 2 线\N{\fs14}Excuse me. Dr. Reed is on line two.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:10:35.65,1:10:38.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我得听这个电话\N{\fs14}Vincent, will you excuse me? I have to take this.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:10:38.45,1:10:40.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,等我一下\N{\fs14}Just give me a minute, okay?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:11:58.33,1:12:00.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不想死\N{\fs14}Yo no quiero morir.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:12:08.04,1:12:09.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不想死\N{\fs14}Yo no quiero morir.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:12:09.43,1:12:13.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 我的天啊 - 我不想死\N{\fs14}- Oh, my God. - Yo no quiero morir!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:12:18.92,1:12:22.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你最近很忙?\N{\fs14}You been running around?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:12:25.02,1:12:27.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这样比较好过?\N{\fs14}Make you feel better?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:12:28.66,1:12:31.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我喜欢忙碌 那样很好\N{\fs14}I like to run around. It's good exercise.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:12:34.69,1:12:37.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,想问我问题?\N{\fs14}Do you want to ask me questions now?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:12:39.27,1:12:43.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,想加入陆战队第七师吗?\N{\fs14}Want to be a lance corporal in Company "M, " Third Battalion, Seventh Marines?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:12:43.01,1:12:46.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我们刚被派往越南打仗\N{\fs14}We're being dispatched into the Quang Nam province.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:12:46.11,1:12:48.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,待会吧\N{\fs14}Maybe later.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:12:50.85,1:12:52.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有事发生了 对吗?\N{\fs14}Something happened, didn't it?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:12:56.06,1:12:58.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你吓坏了?\N{\fs14}You wigging out?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:13:00.09,1:13:03.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是的 我想是吧\N{\fs14}Yes. I think I am.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:13:05.90,1:13:09.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,知道这话什么意思吗?\N{\fs14}Do you know what "Yo no quiero morir" means?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:13:09.27,1:13:12.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,西班牙文 意思是"我不想死"\N{\fs14}It's Spanish. It means "I don't want to die."{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:13:15.31,1:13:17.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你觉得那些鬼魂为什么找上你?\N{\fs14}What do you think these ghosts want when they talk to you?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:13:26.02,1:13:28.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你想一想\N{\fs14}I want you to think about it, Cole.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:13:29.76,1:13:33.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,仔细地想一想\N{\fs14}I want you to think about it really carefully.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:13:33.36,1:13:36.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你想他们想干嘛?\N{\fs14}What do you think they want?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:13:39.77,1:13:44.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,要我帮忙 对 我也这么想\N{\fs14}- Just help. - That's right. That's what I think too.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:13:44.24,1:13:46.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他们想要你帮忙\N{\fs14}They just want help, even the scary ones.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:13:46.74,1:13:50.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想我知道该怎么让他们走开\N{\fs14}I think I might know a way to make them go away.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:13:50.01,1:13:52.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎么做?\N{\fs14}How?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:13:52.46,1:13:55.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,倾听他们\N{\fs14}Listen to them.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:13:56.82,1:13:59.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,如果他们不想要我帮忙呢?\N{\fs14}What if they don't want help?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:13:59.15,1:14:02.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,万一他们只是想伤害别人呢?\N{\fs14}What if they're just angry and they just want to hurt somebody?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:14:02.66,1:14:05.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想应该不会\N{\fs14}I don't think that's the way it works.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:14:05.06,1:14:07.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你怎能确定?\N{\fs14}How do you know for sure?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:14:09.10,1:14:11.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我并不确定\N{\fs14}I don't.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:14:31.12,1:14:34.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嗨\N{\fs14}Hey!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:14:34.39,1:14:37.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嗨\N{\fs14}Hey! Hey!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:14:53.77,1:14:58.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎么回事?\N{\fs14}What's happening?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:14:58.01,1:15:02.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎么回事?\N{\fs14}What's happening?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:15:03.58,1:15:06.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,科尔\N{\fs14}Go!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:15:18.66,1:15:21.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你怎么了?\N{\fs14}What's happening to you?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:15:21.50,1:15:24.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有人伤害你? 我去揍扁他们\N{\fs14}Is someone hurting you? I'll kick their ass.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:15:24.80,1:15:28.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,科尔 要是他们伤害你...\N{\fs14}Cole, if they're hurting you...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:15:40.45,1:15:43.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,妈妈 你睡吧\N{\fs14}Mama, you sleep now.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:17:50.15,1:17:53.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我觉得好多了\N{\fs14}I'm feeling much better now.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:17:57.42,1:18:00.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你是不是想告诉我什么?\N{\fs14}Do you want to tell me something?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:18:36.26,1:18:39.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她跑了大老远才找到我 对吧?\N{\fs14}She came a long way to visit me, didn't she?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:18:40.57,1:18:43.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想是的\N{\fs14}I guess she did.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:19:29.21,1:19:31.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,去拿杯水吧\N{\fs14}Can you get some water?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:19:35.22,1:19:37.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那是她妹妹\N{\fs14}That's her sister.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:19:55.01,1:19:59.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我父亲癌症过世时我就经历过了\N{\fs14}You know, when I went through this with my father's cancer...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:19:59.48,1:20:02.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但这孩子卧病在床两年\N{\fs14}I just can't imagine a child being in bed for two years.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:20:02.85,1:20:05.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,看过多少医生?\N{\fs14}How many... How many doctors?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:20:05.45,1:20:08.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 我想有六个了 - 六个不同的医生都...\N{\fs14}- I think it was six. - Six different doctors?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:20:08.45,1:20:10.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想是的\N{\fs14}I think so, yes.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:20:16.73,1:20:21.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我刚听说... 小的那个现在也病了\N{\fs14}I just heard the, uh, little one is falling ill now.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:20:21.27,1:20:23.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,愿上帝帮助他们\N{\fs14}God help them.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:20:43.09,1:20:45.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,别离开 好吗?\N{\fs14}Don't go home, okay?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:20:45.69,1:20:48.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不会的\N{\fs14}I definitely won't.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:21:43.38,1:21:46.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,恩\N{\fs14}Aah!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:22:46.58,1:22:49.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,先生?\N{\fs14}Mister?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:22:52.02,1:22:54.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,抱歉 先生\N{\fs14}Excuse me, mister.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:22:58.62,1:23:01.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你是琪拉的爸爸吗?\N{\fs14}Are you Kyra's daddy?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:23:14.61,1:23:18.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这是给你的\N{\fs14}It's for you.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:23:18.28,1:23:21.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她有事想告诉你\N{\fs14}Sh-She wanted to tell you something.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:23:59.35,1:24:02.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不 他来了 正朝我走过来呢\N{\fs14}Oh, no, here he comes. He's coming my way. Psst!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:24:06.59,1:24:09.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,想跳舞吗?\N{\fs14}Would you like to dance?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:24:09.59,1:24:13.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我跟朋友一起来的\N{\fs14}Well, actually, I just came with my friends.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:24:13.67,1:24:16.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎么样?\N{\fs14}Oh, well, how about this?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:24:16.20,1:24:16.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我们先跳一下\N{\fs14}We can dance for a little bit,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:24:17.39,1:24:21.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我要是跳不好 你可以踢我\N{\fs14}and if you don't like the way I dance, you can kick me.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:24:21.77,1:24:24.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好吧\N{\fs14}Oh, okay then.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:25:33.91,1:25:37.21,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,该吃午餐了\N{\fs14}It's time for lunch, Kyra.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:25:41.25,1:25:43.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我觉得好多了-很好啊\N{\fs14}I'm feeling much better now. - That's so great, honey.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:25:44.06,1:25:46.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你该吃饭了\N{\fs14}It's time for your food.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:25:48.36,1:25:50.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我吃完以后可以出去玩吗?\N{\fs14}Can I go outside if I eat this?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:25:50.70,1:25:53.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你下午的情况一向都不好\N{\fs14}I don't know. You know how you get sick in the afternoons.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:25:53.17,1:25:56.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,再说吧\N{\fs14}We'll see.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:25:57.57,1:26:01.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,别说吃起来很奇怪 我不想听你那么说\N{\fs14}Don't say that it tastes funny. You know I don't like to hear that.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:26:04.11,1:26:08.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,山姆他妈妈打电话来了\N{\fs14}Tami's mom called.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:26:23.80,1:26:26.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是你害她一直都病着\N{\fs14}You were keeping her sick.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:26:43.05,1:26:45.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她说你喜欢它\N{\fs14}You liked it, she said.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:26:48.79,1:26:51.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她会保护你的\N{\fs14}She looked out for you.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:26:51.96,1:26:54.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,琪拉会回来吗?\N{\fs14}Is Kyra coming back?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:26:57.40,1:27:00.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,再也不会了\N{\fs14}Not anymore.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:27:07.31,1:27:09.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好 化好了\N{\fs14}I think that's enough. That's enough makeup.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:27:09.67,1:27:12.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好的\N{\fs14}Okay. {\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:27:12.38,1:27:16.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 该你上场了 - 我们得快点\N{\fs14}- They're calling for the stable boy. - We have to hurry!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:27:19.55,1:27:21.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你刚刚跟谁说话?\N{\fs14}Who, uh... Who were you talking to?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:27:28.73,1:27:31.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我是在练习台词\N{\fs14}Just practicing my lines.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:27:34.93,1:27:37.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,谢谢你给我这个机会\N{\fs14}Thanks for giving me this part, Mr. Cunningham.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:27:37.80,1:27:41.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,很久以前 这剧院发生过一次大火\N{\fs14}You know, when I went to school here, there was a terrible fire in this section of the theater.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:27:41.64,1:27:43.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他们重建了这里\N{\fs14}They rebuilt the whole thing.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:27:43.74,1:27:46.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我知道\N{\fs14}Yeah, I know.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:27:56.86,1:28:01.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,只有心无邪念的人 才能拔出石中剑\N{\fs14}Only he who is pure of heart can take the sword from the stone.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:28:01.79,1:28:04.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,让那孩子试试\N{\fs14}Let the boy try.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:28:11.60,1:28:14.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但他只是个清扫马厩的男孩\N{\fs14}He is a stable boy. He cleans up after the horses.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:28:14.71,1:28:17.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,安静 无知的村民\N{\fs14}- Silence, village idiot.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:28:17.54,1:28:20.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,让那孩子走向前\N{\fs14}Let the boy step forward.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:28:47.81,1:28:50.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,亚瑟王万岁\N{\fs14}Hail, King Arthur!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:28:55.38,1:28:57.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,耶\N{\fs14}Yea!{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:29:22.71,1:29:25.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你演得很棒\N{\fs14}I thought you were really great in the play, Cole.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:29:25.71,1:29:27.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 真的? - 是的\N{\fs14}- Really? - Yeah.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:29:27.95,1:29:30.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 知道吗... - 什么?\N{\fs14}- You know what else? - What?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:29:30.45,1:29:34.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我觉得汤米·唐很逊\N{\fs14}I thought Tommy Tammisimo sucked big time.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:29:42.13,1:29:45.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我有办法让你妻子听你说话\N{\fs14}I got an idea how you can talk to your wife.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:29:45.56,1:29:48.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,趁她熟睡时跟她说话\N{\fs14}Wait till she's asleep.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:29:48.90,1:29:52.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她会不知不觉的把你的话听进去\N{\fs14}Then she'll listen to you and she won't even know it.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:29:59.78,1:30:03.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不会再见到你了吧?\N{\fs14}I'm not gonna see you anymore, am I?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:30:05.08,1:30:08.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想我们该谈的都已经谈过了\N{\fs14}I think we said everything we needed to say.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:30:09.45,1:30:12.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也许该跟你的亲人谈一谈了\N{\fs14}Maybe it's time to say things to someone closer to you.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:30:14.46,1:30:17.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也许我们可以假装明天还要见面\N{\fs14}Maybe we can pretend like we're gonna see each other tomorrow.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:30:19.93,1:30:22.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,只是假装\N{\fs14}Just for pretend.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:30:27.95,1:30:30.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好的\N{\fs14}Okay.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:30:35.08,1:30:37.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我要走了\N{\fs14}I'm gonna go now.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:30:43.66,1:30:46.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,明天见 科尔\N{\fs14}I'll see you tomorrow, Cole.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:31:13.22,1:31:16.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我没事 警察先生\N{\fs14}I'm okay, Officer.I-I'm okay.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:31:16.86,1:31:19.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不知道是怎么回事\N{\fs14}I don't know what happened.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:31:27.47,1:31:30.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,天啊 希望没有人受伤\N{\fs14}Geez, I hope nobody got hurt.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:31:33.81,1:31:37.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你很安静\N{\fs14}You're very quiet.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:31:37.04,1:31:40.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你在气我没赶上你的演出\N{\fs14}You're mad I missed the play, aren't you?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:31:40.41,1:31:42.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我得做两份工作\N{\fs14}I have two jobs, baby.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:31:42.88,1:31:45.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这对我们非常重要\N{\fs14}You know how important they are for us.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:31:47.92,1:31:50.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我真的很想到场\N{\fs14}I'd give anything to have been there.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:32:02.20,1:32:04.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我现在可以跟你沟通了\N{\fs14}I'm ready to communicate with you now.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:32:09.77,1:32:11.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,沟通?\N{\fs14}Communicate?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:32:13.38,1:32:15.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,告诉你我的秘密\N{\fs14}Tell you my secrets.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:32:17.32,1:32:19.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是什么?\N{\fs14}What is it?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:32:23.56,1:32:26.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不知道前面发生了什么事故?\N{\fs14}You know the accident up there?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:32:26.42,1:32:29.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,什么\N{\fs14}Yeah.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:32:29.53,1:32:31.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有人受伤了\N{\fs14}Someone got hurt.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:32:31.70,1:32:33.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真的?\N{\fs14}They did?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:32:33.97,1:32:37.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是一位女士\N{\fs14}A lady.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:32:37.57,1:32:39.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她死了\N{\fs14}She died.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:32:39.94,1:32:42.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,天啊 你看得到她?\N{\fs14}Oh, my God. What, you can see her?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:32:43.88,1:32:46.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,对 她在哪里?\N{\fs14}- Yes. - Where is she?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:32:50.52,1:32:54.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就站在我的车窗旁边\N{\fs14}Standing next to my window.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:33:00.46,1:33:03.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你吓坏我了\N{\fs14}Cole, you're scaring me.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:33:03.49,1:33:05.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他们有时也吓坏我了\N{\fs14}They scare me too sometimes.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:33:08.43,1:33:10.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他们?\N{\fs14}They?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:33:13.57,1:33:15.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,鬼魂\N{\fs14}Ghosts.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:33:19.91,1:33:22.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你看得见鬼魂?\N{\fs14}You see ghosts, Cole?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:33:24.58,1:33:27.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他们要我帮忙\N{\fs14}They want me to do things for them.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:33:30.19,1:33:32.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他们跟你说话?\N{\fs14}They... They talk to you?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:33:32.46,1:33:35.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他们要你做事?\N{\fs14}They tell you to do things?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:33:36.66,1:33:39.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,以前就是他们吓坏了我\N{\fs14}They're the ones that used to hurt me.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:33:41.10,1:33:43.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,妈妈 你在想什么?\N{\fs14}What are you thinking, Mama?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:33:43.94,1:33:48.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你以为我是怪胎? 看着我\N{\fs14}- You think I'm a freak? - Look at my face.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:33:48.64,1:33:51.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我绝不会认为你是怪胎 永远不会\N{\fs14}I would never think that about you. Ever.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:33:52.94,1:33:55.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 懂了吗? - 懂了\N{\fs14}- Got it? - Got it.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:34:02.65,1:34:04.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,让我想一下\N{\fs14}Just let me think for a minute.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:34:08.59,1:34:10.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,外婆跟你问好\N{\fs14}Grandma says hi.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:34:14.17,1:34:17.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她说她很抱歉拿走坠子\N{\fs14}She says she's sorry for taking the bumblebee pendant.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:34:17.40,1:34:20.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她太喜欢它了\N{\fs14}She just likes it a lot.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:34:22.51,1:34:26.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,什么? 外婆有时会来看我\N{\fs14}- What? - Grandma comes to visit me sometimes.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:34:28.88,1:34:31.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,科尔 这样是不对的\N{\fs14}Cole, that's very wrong.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:34:31.68,1:34:32.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 你知道外婆已经过世了 - 我知道\N{\fs14}- Grandma's gone, you know that. - I know.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:34:33.21,1:34:36.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 她要我... - 别说了\N{\fs14}- She wanted me to tell you... - Cole, please stop.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:34:36.42,1:34:40.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她要我告诉你 她去看你跳舞\N{\fs14}She wanted me to tell you she saw you dance.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:34:42.13,1:34:45.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她说你小的时候...\N{\fs14}She said when you were little,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:34:45.83,1:34:47.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,跟她吵过一次架\N{\fs14}you and her had a fight...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:34:47.83,1:34:50.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就在你舞蹈表演之前\N{\fs14}right before your dance recital.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:34:53.94,1:34:57.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你以为她不想看你跳舞\N{\fs14}You thought she didn't come to see you dance.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:35:01.38,1:35:03.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她去看了\N{\fs14}She did.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:35:09.09,1:35:12.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她躲在后面 你没看到她\N{\fs14}She hid in the back so you wouldn't see.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:35:12.99,1:35:15.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她说你像个天使\N{\fs14}Sh-She said you were like an angel.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:35:20.43,1:35:22.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她说...\N{\fs14}She said...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:35:22.63,1:35:26.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你曾经到她的墓地去\N{\fs14}you came to the place where they buried her,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:35:28.34,1:35:30.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,问了她一个问题\N{\fs14}asked her a question.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:35:33.41,1:35:37.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她说答案是...\N{\fs14}She said the answer is...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:35:37.78,1:35:39.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,每一天\N{\fs14}every day.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:35:42.32,1:35:44.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你问了她什么?\N{\fs14}What did you ask?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:35:52.76,1:35:56.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我...\N{\fs14}Do...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:35:56.07,1:35:59.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有没有让她感到骄傲?\N{\fs14}Do I make her proud?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:36:02.17,1:36:04.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,妈妈\N{\fs14}Mama.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:36:34.11,1:36:36.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,大家好 你们都知道 我...\N{\fs14}Hi, everybody. As most of you know,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:36:36.71,1:36:39.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我并不习惯这样\N{\fs14}I'm not used to doing this,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:36:39.41,1:36:43.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我也答应安娜不会令她困窘\N{\fs14}and I promised Anna that I'd try not to embarrass her.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:36:43.15,1:36:47.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这任务就交给她母亲吧\N{\fs14}I'll leave that to her mother.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:36:47.39,1:36:49.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我们想谢谢大家的出席\N{\fs14}But we do want to thank all of you for coming...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:36:49.69,1:36:52.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,并与我们分享这美妙的日子\N{\fs14}and for sharing this wonderful day with us.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:36:52.59,1:36:55.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我心中既苦又乐\N{\fs14}It's bittersweet almost, for me,{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:36:55.49,1:36:57.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,因为我并不想把她交出去\N{\fs14}'cause I hate giving her up.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:36:57.76,1:36:59.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,安娜\N{\fs14}Anna?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:37:09.71,1:37:11.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我好想你\N{\fs14}I miss you.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:37:17.55,1:37:20.21,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我也想你\N{\fs14}I miss you too.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:37:20.22,1:37:23.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,为什么 马尔科姆?\N{\fs14}Why, Malcolm?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:37:23.12,1:37:25.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,什么?\N{\fs14}What?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:37:27.66,1:37:31.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 什么... - 你为何离我而去?\N{\fs14}- What is it? - Why did you leave me?{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:37:31.36,1:37:34.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我并未离你而去\N{\fs14}I didn't leave you.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:37:55.32,1:37:59.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我看得见死人\N{\fs14}I see people.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:37:59.12,1:38:01.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他们不知道自己已经死了\N{\fs14}They don't know they're dead.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:38:05.76,1:38:10.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 你多常见到他们? - 每时每刻\N{\fs14}- How often do you see them? - All the time.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:38:13.20,1:38:15.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,到处都有他们\N{\fs14}They're everywhere.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:38:25.77,1:38:29.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他们只看得到他们想看的\N{\fs14}They only see what they want to see.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:38:34.39,1:38:37.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好了 麦克\N{\fs14}Okay, Mikey.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:38:38.00,1:38:41.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,等等 让我想一下\N{\fs14}Come on. Give me a minute.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:39:19.30,1:39:21.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,天啊\N{\fs14}Oh, God.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:39:21.71,1:39:25.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 不是很痛 - 让我看看\N{\fs14}- It doesn't even hurt. - Let me see.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:39:27.95,1:39:31.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,让我看看 把手拿开\N{\fs14}Let me see. Put your hand...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:39:31.25,1:39:33.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,天啊\N{\fs14}Oh, God.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:39:38.92,1:39:41.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好的\N{\fs14}Okay.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:39:59.94,1:40:01.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想我没事 真的\N{\fs14}I think I'm okay. Really, I think it just went...{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:40:01.73,1:40:06.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想子弹并没有留在里面\N{\fs14}went in and out.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:40:09.25,1:40:12.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,根本不会痛\N{\fs14}It doesn't even hurt anymore.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:40:41.85,1:40:44.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想我现在可以走了\N{\fs14}I think I can go now.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:40:48.09,1:40:50.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我只是需要做几件事\N{\fs14}I just needed to do a couple things.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:40:55.63,1:40:58.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我得帮助一个人\N{\fs14}I needed to help someone.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:41:00.77,1:41:03.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想我做到了\N{\fs14}I think I did.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:41:09.11,1:41:11.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我也要告诉你一些事\N{\fs14}And I needed to tell you something.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:41:16.65,1:41:19.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你对我一直都是最重要的\N{\fs14}You were never second.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:41:19.89,1:41:22.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,永远都是\N{\fs14}Ever.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:41:24.70,1:41:27.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我爱你\N{\fs14}I love you.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:41:32.94,1:41:35.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好好睡吧\N{\fs14}You sleep now.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:41:37.04,1:41:39.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,明早开始一切都会改观的\N{\fs14}Everything will be different in the morning.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:41:45.78,1:41:48.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,晚安 马尔科姆\N{\fs14}Good night, Malcolm.{\r}
Dialogue: 0,1:41:53.59,1:41:56.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,晚安 亲爱的\N{\fs14}Good night, sweetheart.{\r}

