E
good
well
on
in
up
free fine frame
how much cost
sues sick
first we've
decide scenes recognition
his outstanding chief infield his
dedication to his
discontinue efforts to improve the
quality
action his continuing
efforts to improve quality of life
countless children
city of Philadelphia
how the Pistons some took
ski citation for perfection
X the cold
shit
this is an important night for us
finally someone is recognizing the
sacrifices
me that you've put everything second
including me
least
same has been gift
Ste situations most
pistons I
thanks like
top
X
this is 47 Locust Street broken a window
and
those me needles
prescription drugs many kinds
your free manual
do
what do you want what he promised okay
you know me
0 patients
and
clinic stink fam
possible mood disorder
you tell me
hits okay
disc
you not kill you
that freak them
economy of some
the its
its qua
to %um smart compassion sheik
you for
cursed of
you be if you
so just
me try just committee chair
which
its okay cool
name is doctor Malcolm Crowe you're
supposed to meet
missed our point sorry
olden days your people use to churches
claim sanctuary
from
people mostly people they want to put
them in jail
them
noticed your eyeglasses anyone's is in
he talking about your soldiers
Nick the prefer
disclaimer come back
you're so to speak plan just
green
tapped
used to be
won awards from the mayor and expense
frame
see again that's okay with you
me
up
it
call the you cook
you
ok
who
think was not think it
to get it
up
3 like caramel
Smith go limp
i'd today yeah
the Pennsylvania Lottery matchups
8 take
pack nice women
speak first keep 36 green sleep
company shooters
he said
said
feel like talking
monthly gain to mind reading
works i read your mind price is right
you take one step towards chair when I
say is wrong
take one step back was doorway
you reach here you sit down
you reach the door you can go
play
okay
when your mother and father were first
divorced your mom want to see a doctor
like me
he didn't happen so you think I'm not
going to be
help you
you're worried then she said she told
them things
think she can tell anyone else
secrets
you have secretly tell me
decade watches present just before
can children ok
Yuki pretty quiet in school Kidston
you never really been a serious trouble
response to rocket ship when
for me
different
screwdriver it
something on TV Co
having its
me
streak controlling
redrawn
trial
people smiling talks
remarks
don't me us
yes
week
know what you think
stinky
us
UK
the other time restaurant
sorry
skins contract
sessions
us same
terrorism same expression same things
hanging over their head
maybe some
abuse Cole
as scratches on his own you might be
thinking
cuts defensive cuts may be a teacher
neighbor I don't think some other singer
with them
doesn't seem to fit I could just be
maybe he's just a kid who likes to climb
trees
an old
just makes
just he likened been given a second
chance want to slip away
happy anniversary
stop
look
school Thomas
best buddy
to him on Sat yes
you're talking about how things all the
time thanks
she doesn't look everybody else want you
one know what freak
you are not a freak K should leave
anybody tries to convince you
bullshit to go if you like
okay
he said
sorry
see in Pittsburgh with the lady that
works in a toll booth first
he's working just
just thinking about that myself
questions sometimes we do things to draw
attention
to express our feelings about certain
issues
divorce whatever for example a person
might leave something on a desk for
someone else to find
you know it free association writing is
cool
Association writing is when you take a
pencil in your hand
you put a pencil to a piece of paper and
start writing look at what you're
writing
think about what you're writing just
keep your hand moving
after a while keep you moving on
words and thoughts are coming out there
you didn't even know you
in you could be something you heard
somewhere else or feelings deep inside
you
to be written any free association
yes
with you upset its
uranium said words before your father
left
can you do something for me what you
wanna get
time
should
teaching something you know step
scared
you gonna get in
to get in
just
down
okay
do you think stop
problem
keep moving cheese dick
anybody's guess what
City was capital the United States of
America
seventy ninety to 1800 give you the city
you live in
his when the all the cities in this
country
generations tear here see
she going to see history in a story
school
the ground it's can anyone guess this
building was used for a hundred years
ago before you went to school
before i'd school
yes call
East keeper no that
that's not correct which people
crime people watch
speed
call this this building was legal
courthouse
laws were passed your some very first
loss in this country
so building this fall warriors lawmakers
everyone I don't know
which when these guys that they're just
trying to scare you
don't like people looking
likewise
snappy I don't know
how else to look
yes keep
excuse me toxic went to school you
only high school should
lucky people next few how did you its
you
been speaking
stuff
in
big
years ago talk
magic
serve magic pay second
my little magic
which
I'd she can
spur
I'd
she back
its his
to course expect
just kept playing
thanks
I D
6 like
you its
she said
I'm
him
all the way
skip
space
stupid
doesn't places our pleasure last techies
party your
purple plastic come out
Jackie she's place
us
opens
pic
if you're school
life school
with this right drive
stock commercial skits
tree peace police thing
scare him
care
happy birthday cake
shop you wanna seen
were confirmed for 10 play
the unique okay
Scott locked in the dungeon yeah
to be locked in a tense
test for indicating
seizure is doing fine
have to stress you go home tonight
this cuts and bruises news-sun
concerning
you this from spot
much
become a Batman Sloan
she's a social worker with the hospital
she's gonna ask you a couple procedural
questions
what happened two months
today thing was happening to you
was very K
if I these stores
once upon a time there was this young
prince and he decided he wanted to go
for
try he his
driver in starter tribal
petrosa my city fell asleep
he woke up
realize they were still dry very
trip to crow told
Street for too many
first twist
I cook twists comix
again
Craddick yes it's good because are
driving right sorry
said said
makes things
stop Spurs
top
support who is this person ok worked
with children
him thing else
he made stake
conduct can't stop thinking can't forget
since things different same person East
p his wife
doesn't like personalities because
papers
speak exchanges missus wonderful
boy really cool
could decide to try help just
she feels
snoop oi peak
helping to
story
post
stick
dreams
week
the people in graves coffins
its sick
this
pic
C
truck first first
parks
cars
cool
songs usually assessed suffering from
visuals nations
in
schoolies schizophrenia
education schools ish maybe
each
this is Lindsey calls mmm I
like to talk to you about your boy his
friends keeping
him
it
dinner is not
his what you could do
you of
here
once there was a boy every
different boys he leaves jump
and he could speak to the animals
did you fall into place sect
kerosene
academic officer commercial said
everyone self-conscious
realistic said the place Sep stomach it
sounds like a real punk
the play was excellent
cats mine
cause really interested hospital like to
hear more
call
you
Co
I don't see anything
house
funny
through your chest
seeks few
years here weakest
thank you
schools
sure
Co
ok
me hurts
his cough suppressant
fast call to see
ECM of I want my table
I so euro joy when I was cleaning its ok
and bumble bee pendant Mikey taken
was gramm
us how little broke asset me
crack screen each
right
keep
richest
did you move the BB
so moved at this time
maybe someone can I haz took the bumble
bee pendant
out my closet placed nicely usual
himself time call entire my body
entire in my mind I'm tiny my somehow
family doing so good
having crane must not be praying right
looks like risk have to answer each
other's crackers
if we can talk to each other can make it
tell me
I I won't get mad honey did you take
the bumblebee can
if
as beef you need to the table go
me
pic X Scott
St on
free
me
shaky
Co
its edwardian beautifully worked with
mine cut diamond
actual copper me safire time
you plane joint pain ring to complain
fiance
on see
so beautiful
your like burmese of
why don't you
list
I think this piece communicate some
I imagine that the woman who owned after
man
cheek be to see have Wi Fi
test I don't know
that another pieces in the store
communique
I think you should choose piece that
speaks to you
I think maybe when people
things in pass away part of themselves
it's pretty damn things
see just wrap it up
missed
rest neck
rest masters assess
for me
first
to mass
to get Christmas poems
is perfect
took you
p.m. talk tomorrow pic
we've used used
week
cake campaign
tension things happen
to a chance for you
exc Inc
newly take
some risk me
free ok really believe secret free
ok
checks
your
when you're alone
eight
sup school
soap
school
sick
through chili cheese fries
his physically excuse
this
up
in
them
youth
running around
you
like to exercise
asking questions when you reach corporal
company in 3rd battalion 7th Marines
means-testing non-profits
yes
think I am
you know what Nokia means Spanish
side you think these goes for
to
when you think back you think
we think
Ste
that's right that's what I think too
just one help even the scary parts
way to Macon co said
from one who
what did you think we need just one
hurts so it works
crash
good
much
teehee two minutes
did
dish
someone
first
I just can't
engines
6 thanks
her
good
up
mister
schemes
step
sprint
heat
X
actually
just friends well
yes week little if you'd
ants you can me
good
step
much
up
sick
safeties
smoke
UPPP sick and
in
each
me
here
there
calling for a stable boy who were
who were you talking to
is see my rights
streaking Spartans took you know when
I'm
school it was a terrible section you we
don't
thing
only he who is pure
take from still let
boy try
he's a stable boy cleans up after horses
silence ability
let the boy step forward
you really great plea
no one else
time seems
picked
I
pic
talk to you
we tell she's Angeles
your chic
silly
think we said everything its
is to say thanks because maybe we can
protect
just perfect
see it
of
GE's nobody got hurt
Creek
you minimized plan
have two jobs baby downplay anything too
the key
communicate
secrets
when is it
walks
said
store
you can see
yes
where she
still next
scaring me just
us
today
ghosts
seacoast school
sport
C
the talk to you to do things
once Easter
what do you think
you think freak face I would never think
that
cue ever got it
crimes
she says she's sorry for keep she just
likes it
ok Ste sometimes who
its sky should
you want she saw you she said of
forced
first
sheik CT
shit
he Ste
she's you keep place
week mister
question
she said space
freak
to
to Inc
everybody
few
to
he said
house
pic
see and
sick this in
okay
the ok
C
of
fixmo
sprint
sick
just need
to a couple X
it helps some
did
needed to tell you something
you never sec
F
use
to be /c different morning
Wed
screen
in
in good
good
it
in
the good
and
good
in