This is the night
It's a beautiful night
And they call it bella notte
Look at the skies
They have stars
in their eyes
On this lovely bella notte
So take the love
Of your loved one
You'll need it
about this time
To keep from falling
like a star
When you make
that dizzy climb
For this is the night
And the heavens
are right
On this lovely
Bella notte
Silent as the snowflake
in the night
Holy is the spirit
Of this night
All the world is calm
And peaceful
All the world
is bright and joyful
Spirit of love
And child of peace
Love unending
That shall not cease
Peace, my children
Of good will
Peace, best all
It's for you, darling.
Merry Christmas.
Oh, Jim dear!
It's the one I was admiring, isn't it?
Trimmed with ribbons?
Uh, well, it has a ribbon.
Oh, how sweet!
- You like her, darling?
- Oh, I love her.
What a perfectly beautiful little lady.
Come on, Lady.
Over here.
That's a girl.
There now.
A nice little bed for you.
But, Jim dear, are you sure
she'll be warm enough?
Why, of course, darling.
She'll be snug as a bug in a... Uh-oh.
Almost forgot something.
There.
Good night, Lady.
Now, now.
Don't worry, darling.
She'll go right to sleep.
No, no, Lady.
This is where you belong.
Right here.
Ah, look. She's lonesome.
Don't you think maybe
just for tonight?
Now, darling, if we're going
to show her who's master...
we must be firm
from the very beginning.
Lady! Stop that now!
Stop it!
Lady, quiet now!
Do ya hear me?
Back to bed.
Quick now.
Not one more sound.
- Aw, Jim.
- Hmm? What? What?
Oh.
Oh, all right.
But remember, just for tonight.
All right, Lady. All right.
I'm up. I'm up, Lady. I...
Oh, no!
What's wrong, Jim?
What is it?
Can't you explain to Lady
about Sundays?
Have you noticed, darling,
since we've had Lady...
we see less and less
of those disturbing headlines?
Yes, I just don't know
how we ever got along without her.
Say, she must be about six months old.
We'd better be getting her a license.
Hope it fits.
My, but it does look nice.
So grown up.
Won't Jock and Trusty be surprised?
Four steps ahead
Then to the left
And right to the place
where I marked it
With a bonny, bonny bone
that I'll bury for me own
In my bonny, bonny bank
in the backyard
- Ah, that's a grand sight!
- Jock!
Oh, Jock!
- Hello, Jock.
- Oh, oh, i-it's you, lassie.
Notice anything different?
- Eh, uh, y-you've had a bath?
- No, not that.
You've had your nails clipped?
Uh-uh. Guess again.
Well, I-I wouldn't a-be a-knowin' then.
Why-o, lassie,
a bonny new collar.
- Do you like it?
- Aye.
Mmm, it must be very expensive.
- Have you shown it to Trusty yet?
- No.
Ah, we'd best go at once.
You know how sensitive he is
about these things.
He's dreaming.
Aye. Dreaming of those
bonny bygone days when...
he and his grandfather were
trackin' criminals through the swamps.
They were?
But that was before...
Before what?
This time you knew the truth, lassie.
It shouldn't have happened to a dog.
But, well...
Trusty has lost his sense of smell.
- No!
- Aye.
But we must never let on
that we know, lassie.
'T would break his poor heart.
Uh, uh, uh, which way'd he go?
Which way did he go?
- Go?
- Yeah! Big fella.
'Bout, uh, six foot two.
No, uh, three.
Wore a stripped suit. No collar.
Why, Miss Lady!
You have a collar.
Mm-hmm. And a license.
My, my, how time does fly.
Aye. It seems only yesterday
she was cuttin' her teeth...
on Jim Dear's slippers.
And now, there she is,
a full-grown lady.
Wearin' the greatest honor
man can bestow.
The badge of faith and respectability.
That's right, Miss Lady.
A-As my grand pappy,
Old Reliable, used to say...
Don't recollect if I've ever mentioned
Old Reliable before.
Aye, you have, laddie.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, it's Jim Dear.
Please excuse me.
Hello there, Lady.
Come on. Beat ya home.
Ah, you win again.
Steady now. Steady.
Well, what have we here?
Oh, big girl now, huh?
All right.
Oh, ladies first.
You know, darling, with Lady here
I'd say life is quite complete.
Yes, dear. I don't imagine anything
could ever take her place in our hearts.
What a day!
Well, now to dig up some breakfast.
Cute little rascals.
Coochie, coochie, coochie, coochie, coo.
Now, that breakfast.
Let's see. Bernie's?
No. Francois?
Oh, no, no. Nope. Too much starch.
Ah, Tony's!
Oh, that's it.
Haven't been there in a week.
A beautiful day
to make pizza to taste
And they call it bella notte
Well, buongiorno, Butch!
You wanna your breakfast, eh?
Okay. The boss-a, he's-a save-a
some-a nice-a bones-a for you.
Breakfast a-comin' up
from-a left field.
Good-a catch!
Whoa, boy. Whoa.
Hey. Psst. Psst.
- Blimey! Look, Peg. It's the Tramp.
- Shh.
Hiya, handsome.
Come to join the party?
All right, all right. No time
for wisecracks. I've gotta get you out.
I'm tellin' ya, the pressure's
really hot. Signs all over town.
- Gee, thanks.
- You're a bit of all right, chum.
- Okay, okay, get going.
- Hey, what's goin' on over there?
Scram! And be careful.
What? You mangy mutt.
Hey, let go. Let go of me!
Well, Snob Hill. Ha.
Hi, gals.
How's pickin's?
Pretty slim, eh?
Yeah, I'll bet they've got a lid
on every trash can.
Uh-oh. And a fence around every tree.
I wonder what the leash and collar set
does for excitement.
Lassie! Lassie!
Oh, Miss Lady, ma'am!
Miss Lady!
Ah, good mornin', lassie.
'Tis a bonny, braw, bright day,
uh, today.
Why, Miss Lady,
is, uh, somethin' wrong?
Aye, tell us, lassie.
If somebody's been mistreatin' ya...
Oh, no, Jock.
It's something I've done, I guess.
You?
It must be.
Jim Dear and Darling...
are acting so...
- Jim Dear and Darling?
- Hush, man!
- Now, lassie, get on with the details.
- Well.
I first noticed it the other day
when Jim Dear came home.
Down, Lady. Down!
Darling? Darling, are you all right?
Of course I am.
Why shouldn't I be?
Well, I just can't help worrying.
After all...
in your condition,
alone here all day, walking that dog.
- "That dog"?
He's never called me that before.
Well, now, lassie, I wouldn't
a-worry my wee head about that.
Remember, they're only humans after all.
That's right, Miss Lady.
Uh, as my grand pappy, Old Reliable,
used to say, um...
Don't recollect if I've ever mentioned
Old Reliable before.
Aye, you have, laddie,
uh, frequently.
Oh, yeah.
But now Darling is...
Well, we've always enjoyed
our afternoon romp together.
But yesterday...
No, Lady. No walk today.
No, Lady. Not now.
Lady! Drop that, Lady!
Drop it, I say!
It didn't hurt really.
But Darling has never struck me before.
Now, lassie, do not take it
too seriously.
After all, at a time like this...
Why, yes.
You see, Miss Lady...
there comes a time in the life
of all humans when, uh...
Well, as they put it, uh,
the birds and the bees.
Or, well, uh, the stork.
You know? Uh, no?
Well, then, uh...
What he's trying to say, lassie, is...
Darling is expecting
a wee bairn.
- Bairn?
- He means a baby, Miss Lady.
Oh. What's a baby?
Well, they, they resemble humans.
- But I'd say a mite smaller.
- Aye. And they walk on all fours.
And if I remember correctly,
they "beller" a lot.
Aye. And they're very expensive.
You'll not be permitted to play with it.
But they're mighty sweet.
And very, very soft.
Just a cute little bundle...
of trouble.
Yeah. They scratch, pinch,
pull ears.
Aw, but, shucks,
any dog can take that.
It's what they do to your happy home.
Move it over, will ya, friend?
Home wreckers, that's what they are.
Look here, laddie!
Who are you to barge in?
The voice of experience, buster.
Why, just wait till junior gets here.
You get the urge for
a nice, comfortable scratch and...
"Put that dog out!
He'll get fleas all over the baby."
You start barking
at some strange mutt.
"Stop that racket!
You'll wake the baby."
And then, then they hit you
in the room and board department.
Remember those nice, juicy cuts of beef?
Forget 'em.
Leftover baby food.
And that nice, warm bed by the fire?
A leaky doghouse.
- Oh, dear!
- Do not listen, lassie.
- No human is that cruel.
- Of course not, Miss Lady.
Why, everybody knows
a dog's best friend...
is his human.
Oh, come on now, fellas.
Oh, you haven't fallen
for that old line now, have ya?
Aye, and we've no need for mongrels
and their radical ideas.
- Off with ya, now!
Off with ya! Off with ya!
- Okay, Sandy.
- The name's Jock.
- Okay, Jock.
- Heather Lad O' Glencairn to you!
- Okay, okay, okay!
But remember this, pigeon.
A human heart...
has only so much room
for love and affection.
When a baby moves in...
the dog moves out.
Now, let's see.
That'll be about...
Oh, well.
Darling?
There isn't any way we can tell...
for sure what it's going to be,
is there?
I'm afraid not.
Nobody ever knows for certain.
All we can do is hope.
Darling, are you sure
you want watermelon?
Mm-hmm. Oh, and some chop suey, too.
Chop suey?
Oh, all right, darling.
That darling booty.
- And that bonnet!
- Isn't it just too adorable!
- Don't you just love showers?
- Darling, I've never seen you
look more beautiful.
- Isn't she absolutely radiant?
- Radiant?
Why, that's just what I told Bill
yesterday. "Bill," I said...
Darling looks radiant.
Positively radiant."
"Why, in all my days," I said,
"I've never seen anyone
as radiant as Darling."
- Oh, Jim, you look terrible.
- Jim, absolutely horrible.
I never saw you look worse.
Cheer up, Jim. Old Doc Jones
has never lost a father yet.
Yes, Aunt Sarah, it's boy!
Uh-huh, a boy! And he...
What's that? Eyes?
Oh, what color are they? Wh...
Oh, gosh! I-I-I forgot to look.
A boy! It's a boy!
It's a... Doctor!
- Doctor, it's a boy.
- Yes. Yes, I know.
Uh-huh, a boy.
Oh, boy! Oh, boy!
It's a boy! It's a boy! It's a boy!
Hello? Hello, Jim?
Are, are you there, Jim?
Central? Central, we've been cut off.
Hello.
Hello? Hello? Hello?
What is a baby?
I just can't understand.
It must be something wonderful
It must be something grand
'Cause everybody's smiling
In a kind and wistful way
And they haven't even noticed
That I'm around today
What is a baby, anyway?
Oh, what is a baby
I must find out today
What makes Jim Dear and Darling
Act this way
Oh, my little star sweeper
I'll sweep the stardust
For you
Little soft fluffy sleeper
Here comes a pink cloud
For you
Little wandering angel
Fold up your wings
Close your eyes
And may love be your keeper
There now, little star sweeper,
dream on.
Well, that should do it.
There's enough here
to take us halfway to China.
Darling? Darling?
We haven't much time.
Jim, I just can't leave him.
- He's still so small and helpless.
- He'll be all right.
Now, come on.
If he wakes up, we'll never get away.
But, Jim, I feel so guilty
deserting him like this.
Oh, nonsense.
Hey! What's the matter with Lady?
Oh, she thinks we're running out on him.
Aw, don't worry, old girl.
We'll be back in a few days.
- And Aunt Sarah will be here.
- And with you here to help her...
Well, there's the old girl now.
Coming, Aunt Sarah! Coming!
Sorry I'm late, dears.
Hope I haven't kept you waiting.
- Here, let me take your things.
- Now, now, now, now, no fussing.
I know my way around.
On your way, now.
Mustn't miss your train.
Have a good time,
and don't worry about a thing.
Goodbye, dears.
Goodbye, goodbye.
Goodbye.
Now to see that big nephew of mine.
Coochie, coochie, coochie.
Oh, you adorable lit...
Good gracious! What are you doing here?
Go on, now. Shoo, shoo! Scat!
Get out of here.
Oh, there, there.
Aunt Sarah won't let that dog
frighten you anymore.
No, no, no, no, no.
Rock-a-bye, baby
On the treetop
When the wind blows
We are Siamese
if you please
if you don't please
Now we looking over
our new domicile
If we like we stay
for may be quite a while
Do you seeing that thing
swimming round and round?
Yes.
Maybe we could reaching in
and make it drown.
If we sneaking up
upon it carefully...
there will be a head for you,
a tail for me.
Do you hear what I hear?
A baby cry.
Where we finding baby
there are milk nearby.
If we lookin baby buggy
there could be
Plenty milk for you
and also some for me
What's going on down there?
Oh, merciful heavens!
My darlings!
My precious pets!
Oh. Oh, that wicked animal.
Attacking my poor, innocent
little angels.
Good afternoon, ma'am.
What can I do for you?
I want a muzzle.
A good, strong muzzle.
Uh, yes, ma'am.
Now, here's our latest.
Combination leash and muzzle. Now,
we'll just slip it on like this, and...
No. No, no, no, no.
Nice doggy. No, no, don't wiggle.
Uh, steady now.
Now, now, now.
- Careful, you little...
- Watch out!
- Doggy! Careful, doggy!
- Come back.
Come back here, I say!
Come back here.
Hey, Pige, what are you doing
on this side of the tracks?
I thought you... Wha...
Ah, you poor kid.
Oh, we've gotta get this off.
I think I know the very place.
Come on.
Well, here we are.
- The zoo?
- Sure!
No, no. This way.
Follow me.
- Oh!
- What's the matter, Pige?
- We can't go in?
- Why not?
- Well, the sign says...
- Yeah, well, well that's...
- That's the angle.
- Angle?
Look, we'll just wait for the right...
Uh-oh. Here we are now.
Just lay low.
Hey, you!
Uh, I beg your pardon.
Were you addressing me?
- What's the matter? Can't you read?
- Why, yes. Several languages.
Oh, a wise guy, eh?
All right, now,
what's this creature doin' here?
- He's not my dog.
- Oh, he's not, eh?
Go away. Go on.
Why, certainly not, Officer.
Aye, I suppose you'll be tellin' me next
it was the dog that was whistlin', eh?
- I-I'm certain I don't know.
- Oh, I'm a liar now, am I?
Well, you listen to me!
Aha! Resistin' an officer of the law.
You're gonna pay! Oh!
Pull a knife on me, will ya?
Tryin' to assassinate me, are ya?
Carryin' a concealed weapon!
Come on, Pige.
The place is ours.
We'd better go through this place
from A to Z.
Apes.
No, no, no. No use even asking them.
They wouldn't understand.
- They wouldn't?
- Uh-uh.
Too closely related to humans.
Uh-oh!
Alligators! Now, there's an idea!
Say, Al, do you suppose your could nip
this contraption off for us?
Glad to oblige.
Whoa! Whoa!
Hmph. If anybody ever needed
a muzzle, it's him.
Timber!
Hey, Pigeon, look out!
What harebrained idiot would...
Hey, look. A beaver!
Here's the answer to our problem.
Let me see here.
Six foot six
and seven-sixteenth inches.
Pardon me, friend.
I wonder if you'd do us a little...
Busy, sonny, busy.
Can't stop to gossip now.
Gotta slide this sycamore
to the swamp.
This will only take a second
of your time.
Only a second?
L-Listen, listen, sonny.
Do you realize every second...
70 centimeters of water
is wasted over that spillway?
- Yeah, but...
- Gotta get this log movin', sonny.
Gotta get it movin'.
'T ain't the cuttin' takes the time.
It's the doggone haulin'!
The haulin'. Exactly!
- Now, what you need is...
- Better bisect this section here.
What you need is a log puller.
I said, a log puller!
I ain't "deaf", sonny.
There's no need to...
Did you say, "log puller"?
And, by a lucky coincidence,
you see before you...
modeled by the lovely little lady...
the new, improved, patented,
handy-dandy...
never-fail, little-giant log puller!
The busy beaver's friend.
You don't say!
Guaranteed not to wear, tear,
rip or ravel.
Turn around, sister,
and show the customer the merchandise.
And it cuts log hauling time
66 percent!
Sixty-six percent, eh?
Think of that!
Well, how's it work?
Why, it's no work at all.
You merely slip this ring over
the limb like this, and haul it off.
Say, you mind
if I slip it on for size?
Help yourself, friend.
Help yourself.
Okay, don't mind if I do.
How do you get
the "consarned" thing off, sonny?
Glad you brought that up, friend.
Glad you brought that up.
To remove it, simply place the strap
between your teeth.
Like this?
Correct, friend.
Now, bite hard!
You see?
It's off!
Say, that is simple.
Well, friend,
we'll be on our way now, so...
Not so fast now, sonny.
I'll have to make certain
it's satisfactory...
before we settle on a price.
Oh, no, it's all yours, friend.
You can keep it!
Uh, I can, huh? I can?
Uh-huh. It's a free sample.
Well, thanks a lot!
Thanks ever so...
Say, it works swell!
But when she put
that horrible muzzle on me...
Oh, say no more. I get the
whole picture. Aunts, cats, muzzles.
Well, that's what comes
of tying yourself down to one family.
- Haven't you a family?
- One for every day of the week.
The point is,
none of them have me.
I'm afraid I don't understand.
It's simple. You see...
Hey!
Something tells me it's supper-time.
Come on. I'll show you what I mean.
Now take the Schultzes here.
Little Fritzie...
That's me, Pige.
Makes this his Monday home.
Monday home?
Ach, ja! Mondays is Mama Schultz
cooking der wiener schnitzel.
Delicious!
Now, O'Briens here
is where little Mike...
Sure and that's me again, Pige.
Comes of a Tuesday.
Of a Tuesday?
Begorra and that's when they're after
havin' that darlin' corn beef.
You see, Pige, when you're
footloose and collar-free...
ah, you take nothing but the best.
Hey, Tony's!
Of course. The very place
for a very special occasion.
No, this way, Pige.
I have my own private entrance.
Wait here.
Just-a one-a minute.
I'm a-comin'. I'm a...
What's-a matter? Somebody's a-makin'
the April fool with...
Oh, hello, Butch!
Where you been-a so long?
Hey, Joe, look who's here.
Well, what do ya know?
It's-a Butch-a.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, Joe.
Joe, bring-a some bones for Butch-a
before he eat-a me up.
Okay, Tony. Okay.
Bones a-comin' up-a.
What's this?
Hey, Joe! Look-a.
Butch, he's got a new girlfriend.
Well, a-son of a gun!
He's-a got a cocker Spanish a-girl.
Hey, she's pretty sweet kiddo, Butch.
You take-a Tony's advice
and a-settle down with this-a one, eh?
- "This-a one"?
- This-a one. This-a one. Oh!
Tony, you know, he's-a not-a
speak-a English a-pretty good.
Now, first-a we fix-a the table.
Here's your bones, a-Tony.
Okay, bones... Bones!
What's the matter for you, Joe?
I break-a your face-a.
Tonight, Butch-a,
he's a-get a-best in-a house!
Okay, Tony. You the boss.
Now, tell me,
what's your pleasure?
A la carte? Dinner?
Aha! Okay. Hey, Joe.
Butch-a, he says he wants-a
two spaghetti especialle.
Heavy on-a meats-a-ball-a.
Tony, dogs a-don't a-talk.
- He's a-talkin' to me!
- Okay, he's a-talkin' to you.
You the boss! Mamma mia!
Now, here you are-a,
the best-a spaghetti in-a town.
For this is the night
It's a beautiful night
And we call it bella notte
Look at the skies
They have stars in their eyes
On this lovely bella notte
Side by side
With your loved one
You'll find enchantment here
The night will weave its magic spell
When the one you love is near
For this is the night
And the heavens are right
On this lovely
Bella notte
This is the night
It's a beautiful night
And we call it
Bella notte
Look at the skies
They have stars in their eyes
On this lovely
Bella notte
Side by side
with your loved one
You'll find enchantment here
The night will weave its magic spell
When the one you love is near
For this is the night
And the heavens are right
On this lovely
Bella notte
Oh! Oh, dear.
- Is something wrong, Pige?
- It's morning.
Yeah. So it is.
I should've been home hours ago.
Why? Because you still believe in that
"ever faithful old dog trey" routine?
- Ah, come on, Pige. Open up your eyes.
- Open my eyes?
To what a dog's life can really be.
Show ya what I mean.
Look down there.
Tell me what you see.
Well, I see nice homes
with yards and fences...
Exactly. Life on a leash.
Look again, Pige.
Look, there's a great big hunk of world
down there with no fence around it...
where two dogs can find
adventure and excitement...
and beyond those distant hills...
who knows what wonderful experiences.
And it's all ours for the taking, Pige.
It's all ours.
It sounds wonderful.
But?
But who'd watch over the baby?
You win.
Come on. I'll take ya home.
It's a beautiful night
And they call it bella...
Not to change the subject,
but, uh, ever chase chickens?
- I should say not.
- Oh, ho. Then you've never lived!
- But we shouldn't.
- I know. That's what makes it fun.
Aw, come on, kid.
Start building some memories.
But we, we won't hurt the chickens?
Hurt 'em? No.
We'll just stir 'em up a bit.
Just look at those fat, lazy biddies.
They should have been up hours ago.
Some fun, eh, kid?
Hey, what's goin' on in there?
- What's that?
- That's the signal to get going.
Come on!
- This is living, eh, kid?
- Is it?
Come on, Pige, follow me.
You know, there's a little bit of bird
dog in all of us, eh, Pige? Pige? Pige?
Pige? Where are ya, Pige?
Pige?
Pigeon?
Oh, Pige!
Hey, hey, Dachsie, how we comin'?
Just one more chorus and we're out.
Okay, on a downbeat.
One, two...
Put her in number four, Bill,
while I check her license number.
Okay.
All right, baby, in here.
Well, well, look youse guys,
Miss Park Avenue herself.
Blimey, a regular
bloomin' "debutante".
Yeah, and pipe the crown jewel
she's wearin'.
Yeah. What ya in for, sweetheart?
Puttin' fleas on the butler?
All right, all right, you guys.
Lay off, will ya?
Ah, what's the matter, Peg?
We was only havin' a bit of sport,
we was.
Well, can't you see the poor kid's
scared enough already?
Pay no attention,
my little "orchechornya".
That's right, dearie.
They don't mean no real harm.
Is like Gorky says in lower Dapts.
Quote: "Miserable being must find
more miserable being.
Then is happy." Unquote.
Boris is a philosopher.
Besides, little "bublichki,"
wearing license here...
that is like waving,
you should excuse the expression...
red flag in front of bull.
My license?
But what's wrong with it?
There ain't nothin' wrong with it,
dearie.
Confidential. Is not one dog here
would not give left hind leg
for such a knick-knack.
That's your passport to freedom,
honey. Without it...
Hey. Hey, hey, youse guys, look.
Poor Nutsy is takin' the long walk.
- Where is he taking him?
- Through the one-way door, sister.
You, you mean he's...
Oh, oh, well, a short life
and a merry one.
Yep, that's what the Tramp always says.
- The Tramp?
- There now, there's a bloke
what never gets caught.
He's given the slip
to every dog catcher in this burg.
You won't believe this, dearie,
but no matter how tight a jam he's in...
that Tramp always finds some way out.
I can quite easily believe that.
Ah, but remember, my friends,
even Tramp has his Achilles heel.
Pardon me, amigo,
what is this "chili heel"?
Achilles heel, Pedro.
This is meaning his, uh, weaknesses.
Oh, oh, the dames! Yeah!
He has an eye
for a well-turned paw, he has.
Let's see. There's been Lulu.
Yeah, and Trixie.
Und Fifi.
And my sister, Rosita Chiquita
Juanita Chihuahua, I think.
What a dog!
Yeah! Tell us about it, Peg.
Peg used to be
in the Dog and Pony Follies.
He's a tramp
but they love him
Breaks a new heart everyday
He's a tramp
They adore him
And I only hope
he'll stay that way
He's a tramp
He's a scoundrel
He's a rounder
He's a cad
He's a tramp
But I love him
Yes, even I have got it pretty bad
You can never tell when he'll show up
He gives you plenty of trouble
I guess he's just a no-count pup
But I wish that he were double
- He's a tramp
- Boom ba-boom, ruff
- He's a rover
- And there's nothing more to say
- Boom ba-boom, ruff
If he's a tramp
He's a good one
And I wish that I could travel his way
Wish that I could travel his way
Yeah, but he never takes 'em serious.
Ah, but some day
he is meeting someone different...
some delicate, fragile creature...
who is giving him a wish
to shelter and protect.
Like Miss Park Avenue here,
eh, matey?
Mmm, could be.
But when he does...
Yeah, I'm way ahead of ya.
Under the spell of true love...
The poor chump grows careless.
The Cossacks are picking him up.
And it's curtains for the Tramp.
It's the little cocker, Bill,
in number four.
Okay.
All right, baby,
they've come to take you home.
You're too nice a girl
to be in this place.
Courage, man. Courage.
But I-I've never
even considered matrimony.
Nor I, but no matter
which of us she accepts...
we'll always be the best of friends.
Now remember, not a word
about her unfortunate experience.
- You don't want to hurt her feelings.
- Ah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Lassie.
Miss Lady, ma'am.
Please, I don't want to see anybody.
Now, now, lassie,
Do not feel that way about it.
Of course not, Miss Lady.
Why, some of the finest people
I ever tracked down were jail birds.
Quiet, you great loony!
Uh, please, lassie, uh, we've come...
with a-a proposition for helping' ya.
Help me?
What do you mean?
Well, now, you see, lassie...
neither of us is as young
as we used to be.
But we're still in the prime of life.
Aye, and we've both got
very comfortable homes.
That's right.
Where we know you'll be welcome
and appreciated, Miss Lady.
So, s-so to come directly
to the point...
If you could, uh, find it possible...
to, uh, to, uh, to, uh...
You're both very kind,
and I do appreciate it, but...
Oh, Pigeon! Oh, Pige...
Oh! Hi, boys.
Anything new in the kennel club set?
Little something I picked up
for ya, Pige.
Looks like I'm the one
that's in the doghouse.
If this person is annoyin' you,
Miss Lady...
We'll gladly throw the rascal out!
That won't be necessary.
Thank you.
Very well, ma'am.
You, you mongrel!
Ah, come on, Pige.
I-It wasn't my fault.
I thought you were right behind me.
Honest!
- When I heard they'd taken you
to the pound...
- Oh!
Don't even mention
that horrible place.
I was so embarrassed
and, and frightened.
Oh, now, now, now.
Who could ever harm
a cute little trick like you?
Trick? Trick!
- That reminds me. Who is Trixie?
- Trixie?
And Lulu? And Fifi? And Rosita Chiquita
w-w-whatever her name is?
Chiquita ch-ch... Oh!
Oh, yes, well, I, I can explain...
- As far as I'm concerned,
you needn't worry about your old heel.
- M-M-My heel?
- I don't need you to shelter
and protect me.
- Yes, but, but, but...
If you grow careless, don't blame me.
And I don't care if the Cossacks
do pick up you.
Goodbye!
And take this with you!
Stop that!
Hush now! Hush!
Stop that racket!
What's wrong, Pige?
- A rat!
- Where?
Upstairs, in the baby's room.
- How do I get in?
- The little door on the porch.
Merciful heavens!
Oh, you poor little darling.
Now, now, now, now, now.
Thank goodness you're not hurt.
You, you vicious brutes!
Back! Get back!
Go, go on! Get back!
Now, the pound! The pound!
That's it. I'll call the pound.
Come here! Come here!
Come on, come on. Come along!
I'll call them this minute.
Couldn't sleep a wink
with that brute in the house.
Hello! Hello!
I don't care if you are alone there,
young man.
I insist you pick him up immediately.
Darling, look!
And if you want my advice,
you'll destroy that animal at once.
Don't worry, ma'am.
We've been after this one for months.
We'll take care of him.
- Well, what do you suppose...
- Say, what's going on here?
Just pickin' up a stray, mister.
Come on, get up!
- Caught him attackin' a baby.
- Good heavens!
- My baby!
- Aunt Sarah!
Aunt Sarah! Aunt Sarah!
I was certain he was no good
the moment I first laid eyes on him.
Yeah, but, uh...
I never thought
he'd do a thing like that.
Thank goodness I got there in time.
There they were, crib overturned...
Oh, I'm sure there must be some mistake.
I know Lady wouldn't...
Watch out! That dog's loose!
Keep her away!
Nonsense! She's trying
to tell us something.
What is it, old girl?
What are you trying...
Darling, Aunt Sarah, come here.
- What is it, Jim?
- Ah! A rat!
A rat?
We should've known.
I misjudged him badly.
Come on.
We got to stop that wagon.
But, man, we do not know
which way they've gone.
We'll track 'em down.
- A-A-And then?
- We'll hold 'em, hold 'em at bay.
- Now what?
- The scent. Follow the scent.
Ach, let's face it, man.
We both know you've lost
your sense of smell.
Go on! Get outtalk here!
Go on, you, get away!
Watch it now. Watch it! Watch it!
Hi, Pige.
All right, everybody,
watch the birdie.
Steady now.
Hold it.
I guess I used a little too much.
Uh-oh. Darling.
- Visitors.
- Visitors?
Why, it's Jock.
And good old Trusty.
Careful now, man. Careful.
- It's a wee bit slippery.
- Yes, yes.
All right, boy, we'll let 'em in.
Oh, no, not you, young man.
You're going to take a nap.
Well, Merry Christmas!
Come in! Come in!
If you'll just step into the parlor,
I'll see about refreshments.
Oh, darling, where did you put
the dog biscuits?
You know, the box Aunt Sarah
sent for Christmas.
In the kitchen, Jim dear.
Oh, no doubt about it.
They've got their mother's eyes.
Aye.
But there is a bit of their father
in 'em, too.
Well, and I see
you finally acquired a collar.
Oh, yes, complete with license.
Oh, yeah, a new collar.
Caught the scent the moment
I came in the house.
"Trusty," I says, "Trusty,
somebody's wearin' a new collar."
Of course, now...
my sense of smell
is very highly developed.
Runs in the family, you know.
There'll be no livin' with him
from now on.
As my grand pappy, Old Reliable,
used to say...
I don't recollect if I've ever
mentioned Old Reliable before.
No, you haven't, Uncle Trusty.
Huh? I haven't?
Well, uh, as Old Reliable
used to say...
He'd say, uh, uh...
Dog gone.
You know, I-I clean forgot
what it was he used to say.
Peace, my children
Of good will
Peace
Be still