You're looking
good, Dutch.
It's been a long time,
General.
Come on inside.
188 hours ago,
we lost a chopper
carrying a cabinet minister
and his aide
from this charming
little country.
We've got a transponder fixed
on their position about here.
This cabinet minister,
does he always travel
on the wrong side
of the border?
Apparently,
they strayed off course.
And we're fairly certain
they're in guerrilla hands.
Why don't you use
the regular army? Why us?
Because some damned fool
accused you of being the best.
Dillon!
You son of a bitch!
What's the matter?
The CIA got you pushing
too many pencils?
Huh?
Had enough?
Make it easy
on yourself, Dutch.
Ok! Ok!
You never did know
when to quit.
Damn good to see you.
What is this
fucking tie business?
I heard about that job
you pulled off in Berlin.
Very nice, Dutch.
Good old days.
How come you passed
on Libya?
That wasn't my style.
You got no style.
You know that.
Come on.
Why did you pass?
We're a rescue team,
not assassins.
Now, what do we
got to do?
That cabinet minister is
important to our operations
in this part of the world.
Our friends are about
to get squeezed.
We can't let that happen.
We need the best... you.
Go on.
Simple setup.
One-day operation.
We pick up their trail
at the chopper, run them down,
grab those hostages,
and bounce back.
What do you mean, "we"?
I'm going in
with you, Dutch.
General, my team
always works alone.
You know that.
Once you reach
your objective,
Dillon will evaluate
the situation and take charge.
? Gonna tell Aunt Mary
about UncleJohn?
? He claims he has the misery,
but he has a lot of fun?
? Oh, baby?
? Yeah, baby?
? Whoo, baby?
? Havin'me some fun tonight?
? Yeah?
? Well, Long Tall Sally,
she's built sweet, she got?
Yeah, ok.
? Everything that UncleJohn need?
? Oh, baby?
? Yeah, baby?
? Whoo, baby?
? Havin'me some fun tonight?
? Yeah?
? Well, I saw UncleJohn
with bald-head Sally?
? He saw Aunt Mary comin; and
he ducked back in the alley?
? Oh, baby?
? Yeah, baby?
? Whoo, baby?
? Havin'me
some fun tonight?
? Yeah, aaah?
Delta one-zero.
Yeah.
Rendezvous points and radio freqs
are indicated and fixed.
AWACS contact
on four-hour intervals.
Who's our backup?
No such thing.
This is a one-way ticket.
Once we cross that border,
we're on our own.
This is getting better
by the minute.
? She's built sweet,
she got?
? Everything
that UncleJohn need?
? Oh, baby?
? Yeah, baby?
? Whoo, baby?
? Havin'me
some fun tonight?
? Yeah?
? Well, Long Tall Sally,
she's built sweet, she got?
Hey, Billy.
? Everything?
Billy, the other day
I went up to my girlfriend.
I said,
"I'd like
a little pussy."
She said, " Me, too.
Mine's as big as a house!"
She wanted
a littler one
'cause hers was...
? And he ducked
back in the alley?
Big as a house.
? Yeah, baby?
? Whoo, baby?
? Havin'me
some fun tonight?
Get that stinking shit
out of my face.
Bunch of slack-jawed
faggots around here!
This stuff will make you
a goddamn sexual tyrannosaurus
just like me.
Strap this
on your sore ass, Blain.
Ha ha ha!
That was in '72.
Me and Dutch both got one.
? Well, Long Tall Sally,
she's built sweet, she got?
? Everything
that UncleJohn need?
? Oh, baby?
? Yeah, baby?
? Whoo, baby?
? Havin'me
some fun tonight?
? Yeah?
? Well, I saw UncleJohn
with bald-head Sally?
? He saw Aunt Mary comin'?
That's a real nasty habit
you got there.
? Yeah, baby?
? Whoo, baby?
[Beep]
? Havin'me
some fun tonight?
Right.
? Gonna have
some fun tonight?
[Beep]
? Gonna have
some fun tonight, whoo?
[Beep]
? Have some fun tonight...??
[Beeping]
Ok.
You got it, leader.
[Beeping]
Never knew how much
I missed this, Dutch.
You never were
that smart.
Hawkins, you're up.
Lines away.
The pilots have each
got one round in the head.
Whoever hit it
stripped the shit out of it.
Took him out
with a heat-seeker.
This is no ordinary
army taxi.
It looks more like
a surveillance bird to me.
Pick up the trail yet?
Billy's on it.
Heat-seeker, Dillon.
Pretty sophisticated for
half-assed mountain boys.
They're getting
better-equipped every day.
There were
182 guerrillas.
They took the two men from
the helicopter,
but there's
something else.
What?
Six men wearing
U.S. Issued army boots.
They came in
from the north,
and then followed
the guerrillas.
Mean anything to you?
Probably just
another rebel patrol.
They operate in here
all the time.
Get ahead and see
what you can find.
Yes, sir.
[Birds Screech]
What's he got?
Same business. Guerrillas hauling
two guys from the chopper,
followed by men
with American equipment.
Do you remember
Afghanistan?
Trying to forget it.
Come on. Let's go.
[Wings Flapping]
Holy mother of God.
Jim Hopper.
Mac, cut them down.
I knew these men...
Green Berets
out of Fort Bragg.
What the hell were
they doing here?
I don't know, Dutch.
This is inhuman.
Nobody told me there was
an operation in this area.
They shouldn't
have been here.
Somebody sent them.
The guerrillas
skinned them?
Why did they
skin them?
Ain't no way for
no soldier to die.
What happened here, Billy?
Strange, Major.
There was a fire fight.
They were shooting
in all directions.
I can't believe thatJim Hopper
walked into an ambush.
I don't believe he did.
I can't find
a single track.
Just doesn't
make sense.
There's no sign, sir.
They never left here.
Hell, it's like
they just disappeared.
Stick with
the guerrilla trail.
Let's get the hostages.
We move, five-minute spread.
No sound.
It's time to let Old Painless
out of the bag.
Pay-back time.
[Birds Screeching]
You're ghostin' us,
motherfucker.
I don't care who you are
back in the world.
You give our position
one more time,
I'll bleed you
and leave you here.
Got that?
[Sound Of Motor]
[Speaking Spanish]
Aah!
Fuck you.
[Speaking Russian]
[Speaking Spanish]
He killed one of the hostages.
We move.
Mac, Blain...
the nest.
Billy, Poncho...
the guard.
Hawkins, Dillon...
backup.
As soon as they're set,
I hit the fuel dump.
[Deep Breath]
One down.
[Whistles]
[Beep Beep]
What the hell's
he doing?
What the fuck?
Aaaah!
Showtime, kid.
[Shouting In Russian]
Target's the center,
upper level!
Aaaiiy!
Dutch, on your nine!
[Engine Accelerating]
[Speaking Russian]
Aah! Aah!
[Speaking Spanish]
Get that mother!
Go!
Stick around.
Hostages inside!
Knock knock.
[Whistles]
I got 'em!
Hawkins, call in position
and situation.
Get Connor
for the hook!
You got it, Major.
[Click]
Shit.
Mac, any sign
of the other hostage?
Found the other guy.
He's dead, too,
and the kid from the chopper.
But if they're
Central American,
I'm a goddamn Chinaman.
It looks like
our cabinet minister was CIA.
We were lucky.
Other guys we waxed...
Russian military advisers.
Something pretty big
was going to happen here.
Good work, Mac.
Clear the area.
No traces.
Get the men
ready to move.
Son of a bitch is dug in
like an Alabama tick.
You're hit.
You're bleeding, man.
I ain't got time
to bleed.
Oh... ok.
You got time to duck?
This is goddamn beautiful.
Goddamn jackpot.
This is more than
we ever thought we'd get.
We got those bastards.
We got 'em.
I think this is
what you're looking for.
You set us up!
It's all bullshit... the cabinet
minister, the whole business.
Got us in here
to do your dirty work.
We just stopped
a major invasion.
In three days, they'd have been
across the border.
Why us?
Nobody else
could've done it.
You wouldn't have gone
without the cover story.
What story did
you hand Hopper?
We've spent months
hunting this place.
My men were in that chopper
when it got hit!
Hopper was supposed to
get my men, and he disappeared.
Disappear?
He was skinned alive!
My orders were
to get someone
who could crack
these bastards!
So you cooked up a story
and dropped us in a meat grinder.
What happened to you, Dillon?
You used to be somebody
I could trust.
I woke up.
Why don't you?
You're an asset,
an expendable asset,
and I used you
to get the job done.
Got it?
My men are
not expendable.
And I don't do
this kind of work.
Major! Major, we stepped
into some bullshit here!
Air surveillance
says we got
guerrillas
all over the place.
Can't be more than
18, 2 miles away.
How much time?
Half-hour or less.
We move in five.
She goes, too.
She's valuable.
She'll give away our position.
No deal.
You're still
under orders, Major.
Want to make that call,
or should I?
She's your baggage.
You fall behind,
and you're on your own.
It's too hot
for a pickup.
They won't touch us
till we get over the border.
Billy, give me a way out.
The only way out is
that valley that leads east.
I wouldn't waste that
on a broke-dick dog.
Not much choice.
Poncho, take lead.
Double-time it.
[Muffled Voices]
[Speaking Spanish]
Dillon!
Over here.
Turn around.
Why?
Thanks.
Anytime.
Billy! Billy!
The other day, I was
going down on my girlfriend,
and I said to her,
"Jeez, you got
a big pussy."
Jeez, you got
a big pussy.
She said, " Why did you
say that twice?"
And I said,
"I didn't."
See, it was
because of the echo.
Ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha!
Over here. Over here.
Over here.
Turn around.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Turn around. Over here.
Ha ha ha ha!
Anytime.
Goddamn!
Buddy, buddy,
buddy, buddy!
I've seen some
bad-ass bush before, man,
but nothing
like this.
I hear you.
This shit's something.
Makes Cambodia
look like Kansas.
Hey, que pasa, amigo?
Little taste of home.
You lose it here,
you're in a world
of hurt.
Come on, sweetheart.
Stop sandbaggin' it.
Now, get up.
Come on, get up.
Would you get up?
Mierda!
Ni lo intentes.
Maybe you better
put her on a leash.
Try it again...
please.
Callate.
What's got Billy
so spooked?
Can't say, Major.
Been acting squirrely
all morning.
That damn nose of his...
it's weird.
What is it?
Billy.
What the hell
is wrong with you?
There's something
in those trees.
Do you see anything?
Up there.
Nothing.
What do you think?
I guess
it's nothing, Major.
[Whistles]
[Screaming Voices]
Please!
[Crackling]
Aah!
[Rustling]
Billy, break back.
Back right.
What the...
This isn't her blood.
What the hell
did you do to him?
Major, look at this.
Did you find Hawkins?
L... I can't tell.
What in God's name?
I think it's Hawkins.
Where the hell
is his body?
There's no sign of it.
Ask her what happened.
Que paso, mujer?
Mujer, que paso?
Que fue lo que viste?
Quien fue?
Yo no se.
Dime, mujer!
Quien fue? I Dime!
La selva se lo llevo.
No estoy segura.
No se.
She says the jungle,
it just came alive
and took him.
Bullshit! That's not
what she said!
What she said
doesn't make sense.
Those sappers
have followed us...
they've been
in front of us!
This woman...
Hold it!
Why didn't they take
his radio or his weapon?
Why didn't she escape?
Hopper.
What?
They did the same thing
toJim Hopper.
I want Hawkins' body found.
Sweep pattern. Double back.
50 meters. Let's go.
Come on in,
you fuckers.
Come on in.
Old Painless is waiting.
Sergeant!
Motherfucker!
Aaaah!
What happened?
I saw it.
You saw what?
Blain.
No powder burns,
no shrapnel.
The wound's all
fused, cauterized.
What the hell could have
done this to a man?
Mac.
Mac, look at me!
Who did this?
I don't know, goddamn it.
I saw something.
Not a thing,
not a fucking trace.
No blood, no bodies.
We hit nothing.
Dillon, better
get on the radio.
Mac.
Sergeant! I want a defensive position
above that ridge
mined with everything
we've got.
Put him in his poncho.
Take him with us.
I got him.
Vamonos.
Major, I set up flares,
frags, and claymores.
Nothing's coming
near this place
without tripping
on something.
Thank you, Sergeant.
Mac.
He was a good soldier.
He was, um...
my friend.
Goodbye, bro.
Aah!
Blazer 18, I repeat,
extraction necessary.
Say again, Blazer 18.
Say again.
Request for extraction denied.
Area is still compromised.
Proceed to sector 3,000
for prisoner extraction.
Priority, out.
Next contact 0930.
Roger, Blazer 18.
18030 hours.
Bastards say
we're still in too far,
and they can't
risk coming in.
We're assets, Dillon.
Expendable assets.
Comes with the job.
I can accept it.
Bullshit.
You're just like us.
Shitload of good a chopper's
going to do anyhow.
Sergeant?
Sergeant!
Who hit us today?
I don't know.
I only saw one of them
camouflaged.
He was there.
Those eyes disappeared.
What was that?
Those eyes, they...
they disappeared.
I know one thing.
I drew and
fired straight at it.
Capped off 200 rounds
in the minigun,
full pack.
Nothing on this earth
could have lived,
not at that range.
Mac, you take
first watch,
then you
get some rest.
Ask her what she saw.
Ask her what happened
to Hawkins.
Go ahead, ask her.
Que paso hoy?
Que fue lo que viste?
Te dijo lo que se.
Fue la selva
que se lo llevo.
She says the same
fucking thing.
The jungle came alive
and took him.
Billy...
you know something.
What is it?
I'm scared, Poncho.
Bullshit. You ain't
afraid of no man.
There's something out there
waiting for us,
and it ain't no man.
We're all going to die.
The man's losing it.
He's losing his cool.
There's nothing but
a couple guys running around.
You still
don't understand.
Whatever it is
out there,
it killed Hopper,
and now it wants us.
Here we are again, bro,
just you and me.
Same kind of moon
and same kind of jungle.
Real number 180 night, remember?
Whole platoon,
32 men chopped into meat,
and we walk out,
just you and me.
Nobody else.
Right on top.
Not a scratch.
Not a fucking scratch.
You know,
whoever got you,
he'll come back again,
and when he does,
I'm going to cut your
name right into him.
I'm going to cut
your name into him.
[Clink]
- What the hell?
- Mac!
- Where are you?
- This way!
- Mac, where are you?
- Over here!
Mac!
Aah!
Fuck!
Mac, where are you?
[Rarr]
Jesus.
I got you, motherfuck.
I killed you, you fuck.
Jesus, you killed a pig.
You think you could have
found something bigger?
Fuck you, Poncho.
Fuck you!
Where's the girl?
Ahh, shit!
Why the hell wasn't
anybody watching her?
Why didn't she
try to get away?
Look at her.
She's scared out of her mind.
Major, you better
take a look at this.
Blain's body, it's gone.
It came in through
the trip wires.
Took it right out
from under our noses.
That boar had to set off
a trip flare
because there
ain't no other tracks.
How could anyone
get through this
and carry out Blain
without us knowing it?
Why didn't he try
and kill one of us?
He came
to get the body.
He's killing us
one at a time.
Like a hunter.
He's using the trees.
Yesterday,
what did you see?
You're wasting
your time.
No more games.
I don't know
what it was.
It...
Go on.
It changed colors
like the chameleon.
It uses the jungle.
Blain and Hawkins
were killed
by a fucking lizard?
That's a bullshit
psych job.
There's two
or three men.
Fucking lizard!
What's your name?
Anna.
Anna, this thing
is hunting us.
All of us.
You know that.
What the hell
are you doing?
We'll need everyone.
I'm taking her back.
We're leaving in five minutes.
We're not going yet.
The rendezvous
is 180 miles away.
You think the chopper's
going to wait?
We make a stand now
or nobody will be left.
There is
something else.
When the big man
was killed,
you must have
wounded it.
Its blood was
on the leaves.
If it bleeds,
we can kill it.
Look out.
You really think
this boy scout bullshit's
going to work?
It can see trip wires.
Maybe it can't see this.
Instead of complaining,
maybe you should help.
What makes you think
he'll come through here?
The trees
have trip wires.
This is the only way in.
When I was little,
we found a man.
He looked like...
like butchered.
The old women
in the village
crossed themselves and
whispered crazy things,
said strange things.
El Diablo,
cazador de hombres.
Only in the hottest
years, this happens.
And this year,
it grows hot.
We begin
finding our men.
We found them sometimes
without their skin,
and sometimes
much, much worse.
El que hace trofeos
de los hombres
means the demon
who makes trophies of man.
[Wings Flapping]
[Bird Squawks]
What you going to
try next, cheese?
Hey, Dutch.
Dutch!
Shit!
Aah!
[Gunshots]
I got you, you mother!
I got you!
I'm coming!
Mac. Mac!
Get to the chopper.
Hold it.
I'm going after Mac.
That's not
your style, Dillon.
I picked up
bad habits from you.
You can't
win this, Dillon.
Maybe I can get even.
Dillon.
Just hold onto
that damn chopper.
Ohh!
He's busted up
pretty bad, Major.
I can make it.
Get the radio.
Forget the rest.
Ohh!
Come on, Poncho.
Ahh! Ahh!
Long Tall Sally,
she's built sweet!
She's got everything
that UncleJohn need.
Oh, baby.
I'm going to have
me some fun.
Turn around.
Over here.
Mac?
Shh.
Out there.
Past them trees.
You see it?
I see you.
I see it.
Yeah...
You know, we can
get this thing, Mac.
You work your way
down there toward him.
I'll get in back of him,
flush him toward you.
When I flush that
son of a bitch, you nail him.
I got a score to settle.
We've both got
scores to settle.
Vamos!
Vamos.
Come on! Quickly!
Hurry up!
Don't. Leave it.
It didn't kill you
because you weren't armed.
No sport.
Mac.
Anytime.
Aaaah!
Aaaaah!
Let's go.
Ahh.
Billy!
Billy, let's go!
Uh! Oh!
Dame I'arma!
Give me the weapon!
Dame la mano!
Aaaaaah!
Aah!
No!
Run!
Go!
Get to the chopper!
Yaaah!
Oh, shit!
[Crackling]
[Squeak]
[Sighs]
He couldn't see me.
Arrrr!
Ahhhhhhh.
Aaaaaaaaaaaaah!
[Chattering]
Eeeee!
Arrrr!
Rrrrr.
[Footsteps]
Arrrr!
Bleed, bastard.
[Splash]
You're one ugly
motherfucker.
Arrrr!
Bad idea.
Come on.
Come on! Do it!
Do it!
Come on. Come on!
Kill me! I'm here!
Kill me!
I'm here! Kill me!
Come on, kill me!
I'm here!
Come on, do it now!
Kill me!
[Sighs]
What the hell are you?
[Guttural Voice]
[Beeping]
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Ok!
Did you get it?
What the...
My God!
[Helicopter Approaches]