THE WEEK OF THE KILLER
- The minister secretary general
of the movement
and vice president of the council,
Mr. Fernandez Miranda--
- Ernie says, in this weather,
it's much better to have consommeé.
But this soup will fill you up good, huh.
It's real chicken and no preservatives.
Not like they use where
you work at, Marcos.
- Listen, Rosa, the soups we make
in the factory aren't that bad.
- "Soup from Flory
has all the right ingredients."
Yes.
It tastes like mother used to make.
- But it's nowhere near
as good as yours, Rosa.
It's really getting hot.
- What spree do you have prepared for later?
- Well, the same as every Sunday.
I'll take the girl to the movies,
we'll have a spin,
and then, you know.
- When are you going to look for
a woman to marry?
It's about time.
- Come on Rosa, don't get caught up.
There is much to do.
Can't you hear me or what?
- I'm going, I'm going.
And then he says
to be nice to customers.
- I always give my family
the best food that I can find.
That's why I give them Flory Soup,
because Flory soups have...
Mmm... the flavor of good, rich meat.
- Hello.
- It's about time, right?
- We finished eating very late.
- If I went looking for you at your house,
I wouldn't have to wait like a fool.
- I've told you a thousand times,
they think I go out with guys my age,
you don't know how he'd get if he knew
that I was dating a man like you.
- Come on, speak, what do you think?
If you're getting bored,
say so, but speak up.
- Sometimes I think that
we will never get married.
Men your age
date a younger girl
to get married right away,
but you don't talk about that,
you only talk about the factory, your work,
not about earning more
so that we can get married.
- If you want to break up, say so.
Paula, I--
- But I love you, Marcos.
- We will get married.
They will give me a better
position in the factory,
trust me.
- Yes, Marcos, yes.
- We're very far from the metro,
what should we do? It's very late.
- Don't worry, we'll take a taxi.
Look, here comes one.
Taxi, taxi.
- Taxi.
- Hello.
- Good evening.
- Pinchado is in, scoring
the third goal for his team.
He got the ball in from the right side--
- Madrid's third goal. They are crazy.
- Nicho was defending the goal
when he threw himself
to the left to stop it.
This almost always happens--
- Well, look at that, very good.
- Three to zero, Real Madrid wins.
And now we see how Miguel Munoz
will deliver for his team, for the fans,
because it seems Merengue is
going to let Fleitas in,
a beloved player and expected by all
the followers of the Merengue team.
Mr. Santana tells him to retire,
we'll see. Fleitas, however,
says he is going to indicate--
- This is as far as we go.
- What's going on?
- What do you mean, what's going on?
What do you think my taxi is?
You have the whole field to do that.
- Hey, nobody messed with you.
- It would be good for
you to mess with me.
- Have you never had a girlfriend or what?
What did you do back then?
Play Parcheesi? Okay.
- And why do you care?
- What we do is none
of your business either.
- It so happens that you are in my taxi.
- Please, Marcos, let's go, don't argue.
- Yes, leave, you can still seize the night.
If you were my daughter,
I would give you a--
If at least you were with a boy your age.
- Okay, that's enough.
Okay?
Come on, and shove your taxi
up your you know what.
- Just a moment,
don't run, the meter here shows 23 pesetas.
Surely, you don't expect me
to give you the ride for free, right?
- Well, you should have
taken us where we said.
- Hey, sir, or you... I don't
even know how to treat you.
What are you saying? That you won't pay me?
- Not a penny.
And treat me as a sir, sir,
we don't know each other well yet.
- Pay him, Marcos, don't look for trouble.
- Come on.
- It's good advice, you know?
This night could turn into
a bad memory for you.
- Your father will pay you,
understand? Your father.
- You beast.
- Now you'll see, I'm
going to give you the
slap your father didn't
give you on time.
- Marcos.
Marcos.
- Let's go, quickly.
- You think so?
- Sure, that was
a minor blow.
- Don't walk with me anymore,
someone from my family could see us.
- Relax.
People are only killed
that easily in movies.
- Is there anything on my face?
- No.
- They're going to be so
angry at me for being late.
- I'll pick you up at the
supermarket tomorrow.
- No, wait for me at the bus stop.
- Okay, I'll wait for you at the stop.
- I won't be able to sleep.
I'm so nervous.
- Don't be silly.
- Goodbye.
- Come on.
- Hello.
Hey, walking the dog?
- Yes, like every night.
- I didn't think you'd be here.
Yesterday, your girl told me
you were going on vacation.
- Yes, my parents have left.
Tosca and I stayed by ourselves.
- Why did you stay here in this heat?
- I didn't feel like going.
Hey, you always address me formally, why?
- I'm just used to it.
- We've seen each other every time
I walk my dog, I don't know,
you can almost say that we're friends.
Do you smoke?
- Thank you.
- You seem pretty tired. Are you?
- No. I'm a little bit nervous.
I'm going to sleep, good night.
- See you tomorrow.
- Marcos, leave that wheelbarrow,
the chief of staff wants to speak with you.
- With me? What for?
- I don't know.
Go upstairs and find out.
TAXI DRIVER FOUND DEAD
- Marcos, what's up? Was there
something in the news about it?
- No, nothing.
- Don't lie to me.
- Yes, there was something about it.
I've killed him,
you were going to find out anyway.
Had he hit me with his knee,
maybe I would be the one dead.
Plus, when I saw him hitting you,
I couldn't contain myself.
Come on, don't cry.
Come on, let's go.
- Where are you taking me?
- To my house,
the only place
where we can talk quietly.
- And your brother?
Out with the truck.
He won't be back until
the day after tomorrow.
We have come to talk,
stop spinning that pack.
What is that?
- Plastic bags for the garbage can.
My mother asked me to get them.
- Okay.
- I'm scared, Marcos.
- Scared of what?
Nobody knows we took that taxi,
nobody saw us.
- They will find out.
- Not from me,
but if you keep making that face,
the whole world will find out.
Don't be silly,
trust me.
- Are you sure that
nothing will happen to us?
- Nothing.
- Do you want to smoke?
Are you still thinking about that?
Are you crying for that?
Are you crying for this?
See, you're just a little girl.
- Why don't we tell the police everything?
About what? What we just did?
- Don't try to be funny.
Really, Marcos, let's
go to the police station.
- We agreed that you were
going to let me handle everything.
- Yes, but after doing what we did,
we must do everything together.
- No one's going to the police.
- We can tell them how it happened,
that he hit us both.
- They won't believe anything.
And your family?
They don't even know you go out
with a man my age.
- We have to tell them,
because you want to marry me, right?
- Of course, silly.
- Let's go to the police.
- Don't be a moron.
If we go to the police,
we're going to spoil everything.
Do you know what time it is?
Around 10:00 PM,
it's getting pretty late.
You'll see, you'll think
differently tomorrow.
- I'll keep thinking the same.
- Me too, I don't want to be locked up.
- If you don't want to go, I'll go alone.
- Why would you go?
You behave more like a child every day.
- You just got me to
stop behaving like a child.
- Look, Paula, even if it's very late,
let's go back home,
we have to keep talking, come on.
- We can talk all you want,
but you won't get me to change my mind.
- At least listen to me, all right?
I'm not a kid your age, do you understand?
And when I say no, it's no.
- That's the bad thing,
if you were younger, you'd be braver.
- Well, you should have chosen better,
there are plenty of kids out there.
- You're hurting me, stop.
- Don't you see, Paula?
If we go to the police station,
if they take me to jail,
I'll be an old man when they let me out.
- How afraid are you of going to jail?
- You seem like you're
looking forward to it.
- No, but I don't want to
waste my life being afraid.
- You don't have to be afraid,
trust me.
- Trust you?
Sure, the mature, strong man, sure.
Do you know what you are?
A loser full of fear.
I don't know why you're so afraid of jail.
After all, you just want
to live in this shack
and continue being
a worker all your life.
- Is that what you think?
- Yes.
- Then go to the police or
wherever you want.
- Marcos.
- No, don't start with that now,
that you love me despite everything.
It wouldn't be true.
- Hello, Esteban.
- Hi, Marcos.
They have screwed me well, bro.
In the end, the trip to Burgos got ruined,
that's why I came a day earlier.
- Have you eaten yet?
- No, is there anything cold to drink?
- Nothing left, not even wine.
- Let's go to Rosa's tavern.
I've been in the truck
for six hours straight.
And as she persisted
in having a goodbye gift,
I bought her a wristwatch
that cost me 2,000 calas.
So, between that and the wedding expenses,
I haven't been able to afford much.
- Sure, from now on
the revelry is over.
- You must say that because of
all the fun you have being single.
From the factory to the house,
and from the house to the factory.
- Man, one takes what one can get.
- Hush, you're a weird guy.
It's unbelievable that I'm your brother.
- Here, a six for you to fold.
- Wow, there it goes. I fold.
- Come on, I thought I was winning this one.
- Have you been here long, Esteban?
- A few days.
I'm getting married next week.
I'll have to go to Levante for her.
- It's true, Carmen told
me something about that.
Treat her well, she's a good girl.
Don't scare her.
- She's not scared of anything.
- Wow. Let's see if you're
the one getting scared.
- Hey, could I leave the truck in the shed?
- Aren't you taking it?
- Yes, sure, to spend
the wedding night in the cabin?
Well, look, that way,
Carmen wouldn't take off running.
- Hey, Rosa, what do you give my brother
for him to be so dull?
- What do I give him? Nothing.
- I mean to eat, of course.
- Okay.
- Is something the matter?
- Yes.
- Come on.
Let it out, man. We're brothers, right?
- It's about my girlfriend.
- Girlfriend?
You're too old to be so stupid.
- No, it's not that.
It's somewhat more complicated.
- Come on, man. Tell me.
- Let's go home.
We can talk better there.
- Hey, Rosa.
- Coming.
- I'll come back later.
Is Agustin dealing tonight?
- Agustin starts snoring
as soon as the food is served.
Come if you want.
We can play, you and 1.
- To the Mus or the goose?
And I'll deal, because it's my turn.
- Are you crazy?
What happened? Did
she not allow you or what?
You could have put up with it.
- No, it's not that. It wasn't like that.
- Yeah, you wanted to scare her,
and it got out of hand.
If you had chosen Rosa,
nothing would have happened,
and you would have
eaten for free all your life.
- I'll tell you everything later,
but something has to be done.
You have to help me.
- We'll go to the police together.
We'll make something up.
- No. I don't want to go to the police.
We can put her in the truck and then--
- Don't act funny, we'll do none of that.
I don't want to see the
grays hanging around here.
What do you think?
That they won't look for the girl?
- But you don't want me to go to jail.
You--
- Yes. And you don't even care
that I've thrown away my money
on the flat I've already paid for,
the wedding and everything else.
- But Esteban, if you
don't help me, who will?
- Marcos,
you're entangled in a big mess,
and, in these cases,
there's no choice but to turn yourself in.
- I won't go.
- Look, it has never crossed my mind
to lay a finger on you,
but I'll take you to the police station,
even if I have to drag you by force.
- If you want me to go, I'll go.
No need for us to fight.
- Come on, Marcos.
The longer we wait, the worse.
- They're Paula's,
they got caught up here
when I carried her corpse.
- Don't think about that anymore,
what matters is that you confess
everything as soon as possible.
Yes.
- Look Marcos, it would be silly
of you to start crying now.
- Are you done working for the day?
- Yes, I'm leaving the factory now.
- He must be smelling a bitch,
do you know anyone
with a female boxer?
- No, all there is around here
is stray dogs.
- They're useless,
it must be another boxer.
- This one is not very handsome.
- You're right.
I think that tonight I'm going to let
him loose, so he can do what he can.
- Be careful, he could get eaten.
The dogs around here
are starving.
- I'm not afraid of that, a
well-fed animal is always stronger.
- You never know, nothing gives
you more strength than hunger.
- Don't be a demagogue.
- Don't be a what?
- Nothing man, nothing.
Don't get angry, it's not an insult.
So long, bye.
- I've been sitting here for an hour.
Where's your brother?
- He hasn't returned yet.
- Returned from where?
Yesterday he phoned me saying
that he was about to arrive.
- He's back from the trip already,
but he went out to run errands.
- This is the last straw.
He hasn't called me all day.
The wedding is in less than a week,
and we still have
to make many arrangements.
- Come on, Carmen, don't get nervous.
Do you want to come in?
- If you prefer, I'll wait here.
I suppose he'll be here soon.
It's almost 10:00 PM.
Where has this idiot gone?
I'm not leaving until he gets back
and listens to me.
Hey, your house is super filthy.
It smells awful.
The thing is my father
is waiting for me to have dinner.
- He should get used to dining alone,
as soon as you get married--
- You don't know him well.
He still hasn't warmed up to the idea
that I'm going to get married,
he doesn't want to give me up.
Of course, he'll be so alone.
- If you're running late, go home.
As soon as Esteban
arrives, I'll tell him to call you.
- That hooligan.
What a bachelor party
he must be having.
The truth is, if I weren't so in love--
At least I'll get some jewelry.
Hey, Marcos, do you know if he brought
the gift he promised me?
- No, what was it?
- A wristwatch.
I'm sure he has it in his room, I'll check.
- No, don't go into the room.
- Man, what's up with you?
Well, he wants to surprise me.
He's so stupid, even when
he seems to be such a brute.
Come on, let me see.
- I told you not to go in.
- Okay, don't be like that.
You're so faithful
to your little brother and his secrets.
- I'm sorry, Carmen, but you see,
he told me he wants to surprise you.
Why would we spoil the surprise?
- Okay, okay, okay.
I'm starting to get a headache.
Do you have any aspirin lying around?
- I don't know,
maybe there's some in the kitchen.
- Go on, Marcos, be nice,
bring me a glass of water
and see if you can find an aspirin. Huh?
- Do you really want
me to go get an aspirin?
- Yes, my head hurts a lot.
- As you wish.
- Here's the glass of water.
I'm sorry, Carmen,
but I couldn't find an aspirin.
I'm really sorry.
Take the water.
- What's up? Getting some fresh air?
- Yes.
Did you finish with that girl yet?
Come on kid,
I saw that a girl was waiting for you
while you were coming home,
and she looked pretty good,
you could introduce her to me.
- No, it's not what you think,
plus, she just left.
- Is that why you're so tired?
- Yes, it must be, I don't know, the heat.
- Yes. It's a horrible night.
You know what? I've released the dog,
I'm going to let it walk
around for two hours.
Do you want to go for a spin?
- No, it's very late.
- Come on, man,
don't make me wait for
Trosqui to come back.
- It's curious,
we've seen each other
every night for a long time,
and I don't even know your name.
My name is Nestor.
And you are?
- Marcos.
- We know each other a little more now.
- What interest can you have
in knowing someone like me?
You must have friends your age,
important people.
- Important people are very boring,
they always have a solution for everything.
- That must be great,
to have solutions for everything.
- You know what?
You'll think that I'm a fool,
but in the middle of so much darkness
I'm starting to get scared.
- Scared?
Why?
- I don't know, it's easy to
be afraid, especially at night.
I told you, you'll think that I'm a fool.
Look, there's a refreshment stand
behind the esplanade.
Let's go there, my mouth is dry.
I'm thinking we're two weird guys.
- Yes? Why?
- It's obvious.
I should be, like you said,
with people my age,
dancing at a discotheque,
spending the summer in Torremolinos,
and racing down the highways
at 140 per hour,
and you should be married
to a woman beginning to get plump,
have a couple of kids,
with a washing machine bill pending
and the illusion that one day
you can buy a 600.
- It's curious.
Without knowing why, suddenly,
I get the impression
that all my worries,
I don't know,
that they've disappeared, like--
when you wake up from a dream
and you're happy because
all that horrible stuff is a lie
and nothing has happened. And
then you eat your breakfast very calmly.
You're right,
we're two pretty weird guys.
- I have a friend with a long beard
and very thick glasses,
who would say that you
and I are two outcasts.
- What? Two what?
- Nothing, intellectual quarrels.
- Police. Documentation, please.
- Yes, yes, right away.
- You, where's your ID?
- Sorry, I don't have it with me.
- No identification?
- I left it at the house.
- What are you doing
here at this time of night?
- Passing the time, and having a drink.
Don't you know it's the law that you
have to carry some kind of identity card?
- I'm sorry.
Excuse me, Inspector, I know the young man,
he lives in this new building over there.
- Oh, he lives over there, in
one of those high-rise apartments.
Well, in that case, just don't forget
you should always carry
your identity card with you.
We have to be careful. You never
know what we might find out here.
Good evening.
- So long, Inspector.
Always good to see you.
- I like your house.
There are few like that left.
- I don't.
- Why do you live there?
I've been told that almost everyone
who lived in these houses
have gone to those colonies
that they've built back there.
- Someday they'll build them here too,
and I'll have to go.
- It's a pity.
By the way, you have to show me
the inside of your home.
- There's very little to see, old junk,
damp and dirty walls.
If I don't leave, it's
because it's full of memories.
- Bury them.
- How?
- Bury the memories.
Here he comes.
Hello, Trosqui. Did you have fun?
- I'm going, it's very late.
- Trosqui and I are leaving
too. See you tomorrow.
- Goodbye.
- Hey, thanks for the company.
- You're welcome, man, you too.
- How? You at this hour, Mr. Ambrosio?
- Where's your brother?
- You know, he's with the truck.
He hasn't come back yet.
- Yesterday, Carmen came to see him.
She told me he was here already.
- Want some?
- No.
- That's weird.
Carmen must have been confused.
- Look, let's see if we
understand each other.
Yesterday my daughter left home at 5:00 PM,
it's 6:00 AM and she hasn't come back yet.
- How could you think
they're here?
Listen, Mr. Ambrosio.
- Get away from the door, let me in.
- No.
- Carmen knows that when she gets married,
I'm going to be lonely.
But she doesn't seem to care much
when she couldn't even stay
for the remaining days, that--
- Man, it's not so bad.
- If my deceased wife was here--
If I was 10 years younger,
you would not prevent me
from entering that room.
You and Esteban would know who I am.
But be careful,
this isn't going to stay like this.
- Mr. Ambrosio.
- What?
- Okay.
Go into the room, if you want.
Let's see if that calms you down.
- What?
Are you ashamed to look me in the face?
- We start our program in the morning with
joy, good vibes, and upbeat music.
- There's not much today, people
have chosen not to eat meat this week.
- It's not like the dog eats like a tiger.
- Good morning. A coffee with milk.
- I'm going, Marcos.
- What? To work?
- You're right. Hey, I didn't know you
got up so early, too.
- No, I'm not getting up
early. I'm staying up late.
I haven't gone to bed yet.
- Partying?
- No, I've been writing all night.
- To whom? To your parents?
- No, I write scripts for movies.
It's fun.
- Do you make movies?
- Well, maybe someday I'll make one.
I don't know.
Maybe when I get my inheritance.
- I have to go.
Rosa, here you go.
- Okay.
You should come around more often.
- Do you play sports?
- Yes, I go to the gym.
- It weighs a lot, doesn't it?
Do you dedicate yourself to lifting stones?
- No, it's just that I've
put my work stuff in.
See you later.
- I can come with you to play sports any day.
That hardens the bones.
Trosqui, don't get bothersome.
- I'm leaving, I'm late.
- We'll see you later, right?
- Maybe. See you later.
- Thank you.
And, you?
- I want something to make
my house smell good.
What they spray in movie theaters.
- An environment purifier.
- That. Give me six.
- They come in different kinds and sizes,
but we have this at a very discounted
price, and it smells of pine. Glorious.
Anything else?
- Cologne.
- What kind?
- One with a strong scent.
- There are many types of cologne.
But I have one that's very fresh, very
perfumed and with a strong graduation.
- I'll take 10.
- What? 107
Jesus, how much cologne can one need?
No, not like that.
Smell it, do you like it?
It's called Aromas of the Harem. Okay?
- Yes.
- Anything else?
- No, nothing else.
- Your wife will be very happy
because she'll have cologne
for a long time.
- I'm not married.
- Oh, you're not?
You do very well.
Also, I warn you that this cologne
can also be used by a gentleman
without the slightest qualm.
- What do I owe you?
- 500 pesetas.
Thank you.
Don't you want to take the coupons?
- Come on. Get out. Out of here.
Come on, out, out. Out of here.
- Do you want dinner?
- Yes, but I'll have a snack somewhere.
- Wait, I haven't had dinner either.
Come on.
Are you okay?
- Yes. And Agustin?
- Snoring like always.
Your brother, where is he?
- He went to town, had to get
some papers for the wedding.
- I was very surprised not to see him,
and it's funny, it's been a while since
I've seen Carmen and her father.
- Of course. You know,
Carmen and her father live alone,
they have to do it all by themselves.
- Do you want anything else to eat?
- No, I'm not hungry anymore.
- I'll make you a glass of milk
with a couple of yolks.
- Really, don't. I'm not hungry.
- You won't even feel it in your stomach.
Come on, take it.
Finish it off, you look really sad
these days.
God knows what you're up to.
Wow, sorry, man.
We'll fix it right away.
- It's okay,
these are my work clothes.
- Done. As soon as they dry,
you'll be ready.
- Thank you for serving me even
though it's closed. What do I owe you?
- Nothing, it's on the house.
- Rosa--
- Don't be silly.
I told you it's on me, and that's it.
- Thank you, Rosa.
- Hi, did I scare you?
- Honestly, you did.
- Sorry, it was a joke.
What are you doing here?
- I just had dinner and was going home.
- Would you like to go for a swim?
- A swim? Where?
- I know a pool that's open
until dawn, are you coming?
- Come on, we're here.
- I fell asleep completely.
- It's common, you get up very early.
- I think it's weird.
I should be wide awake,
and I've slept like a child.
- If I were a curious person,
I'd ask what's going on with you,
but I'm not a curious person.
- I'm going.
I really liked that site.
- Have a nice rest.
Take advantage of the
hours of sleep you have left.
- See you tomorrow.
- Look, here he comes.
Do you play sports now, bro?
- Yes, boxing.
- Look at him, Hurtain,
he's smashing the bag.
Are you wearing gloves?
Shut up, what a sight
the veteran has become.
- We're not going to spoil it.
Come on, take off the gloves
and warm up a little, man.
- Stop joking, it's time.
Don't be kids.
- Pass it to me.
- There it goes. Come on.
- Get it.
- Here, here. Manolo, here.
- Here, come on.
- Me, me, me. Mine.
- Me, me, me.
- It's so heavy. Come on, it weighs a lot.
Here.
- Hey, man, what's going on here?
- Don't you see how much this weighs?
It smells like cologne and rotten stuff.
Take the bag, rich man, and put it away,
make sure they don't take it away from you.
This veteran gets on your nerves
since they made him a
specialized worker. Go now.
All objects not used at work
must be left in the locker room.
- Marcos,
the soup is on the table.
- Don't let it cool, this soup
isn't like the others.
As soon as it cools down, it gets thick
and no one wants to eat it.
You don't like it very much, do you?
- What's wrong with this one?
It's not as bad as it seems, man.
- What happened?
Are you feeling okay?
- I'm going.
I'm going to work.
- Take some of the battered cow brains
that we have as a second course,
even the ill eat that.
- Tomorrow I'll feel better.
- Come on, go home and lie down.
- Is something wrong, Marcos?
- Something I ate, I feel bad.
- Can I get you something? An aspirin?
- No, thanks, I'm okay.
I'll be all right.
- As you wish.
- See you later.
- Where are you going?
- Don't you hear? To mass.
- To mass? But you haven't gone to church
since Faustino died.
- Look, I'm going today, Corcho.
My mother died eight years ago
today. Goodbye.
- Hey, what about the veil?
- Oh, come on. No one wears a veil anymore.
- As soon as the blessing is done, return,
because I'm not going to paint
the labels and cook tapas alone, be--
- Who is it?
- Open up, Marcos. It's me, Rosa.
Marcos, how are you feeling?
- Good, I'm better now.
- I'm glad.
I was just passing by,
I thought that if you were worse,
someone would have to bring you food.
- No, I'm fine now.
- I'm glad, man. Won't you invite me in?
- If you want to.
- I have to see how the house of
a man living alone is kept.
Have you had breakfast?
- No, I just woke up.
- Man, come on, lie down again
while I make you breakfast.
I brought you an ensaimada.
Hey, what does it smell like in here?
- Smells? Yes, of course it smells.
A pipe has burst.
- Do you have milk at home?
- There must be some around there.
- Go lay down at once.
- No need, I feel better now.
- Don't be silly. 1
prepare more than 100
breakfasts every day,
one more is no bother.
The smell is coming from there.
Who knows how much crap
you have in that room.
Your breakfast is ready.
- Thank you, Rosa.
You're very kind.
- No. Don't get up, it's better to lay down.
You aren't eating the ensaimada.
- Later, I don't feel like it now.
- Now, you'll let me come from
time to time to fix all this mess for you.
A woman is needed in a house.
Right now, I'm going
to fix that room for you.
A foul smell is coming from inside.
- No, no. Don't do anything,
it's just that we don't use it much,
and it doesn't have good ventilation.
Also, I already told you
that the smell is from a pipe.
- No, no. It's not the smell
of a broken pipe.
You'll see.
Right now, I'll fix your room,
clean it, and let the air in.
Otherwise, you'll catch an infection.
- Don't you understand?
I don't want you to go in there.
- Well, sweetie, really?
- Sorry, Rosa, but I wouldn't
want you to suspect--
- Suspect?
Suspect what?
Sorry, Marcos, but I have to go.
Gee, I've been here over an hour.
I don't know what I'm
going to tell Agustin.
Because today we have a lot
of work at the bar, it's Sunday.
Of course you know that already.
- Don't leave me alone, Rosa.
Yes, I know it doesn't smell good in here.
But look, we'll remove the bad smell.
Only you can clean that room for me.
Do you understand?
I've been so happy since you
brought that ensaimada for me.
I never eat breakfast at home, you know.
I was so happy when you said that you
were going to help me clean everything.
- Tomorrow.
Yes, tomorrow I'll come
and fix the whole house.
It's just that I'm wearing my Sunday
clothes and I might stain them.
I'll be back tomorrow.
- You see? There, it no longer smells.
Well, it still smells
a bit, but very little.
Tomorrow I'll buy more jars.
They're very cheap, you know?
And they smell like pine.
Don't you smell pine?
The other smell still remains,
very little, but still, right?
It's very weird, you know?
Sometimes, I don't
notice that it smells bad.
It's like when you work a lot and sweat.
Sweat smells, but you don't notice it
because you're the one who smells,
you know?
The same happens with
this, suddenly it smells.
- Yes, I understand.
So long, Marcos.
You'll come to eat, right?
Today we have a delicious paella.
- Why did you have to
come this morning, Rosa?
- Marcos.
Marcos.
- What happened?
- His paw is broken.
- I could tell someone.
- Yes, it's best to call a vet, right?
- You'll see, they won't want to come.
- Come on, get out of here. Come on.
- What are you doing?
- I don't know.
- I see you're very lonely.
- I almost always am.
- Today more than ever.
Why don't you go into your house?
- I don't feel like going in.
- Then come to mine.
- To yours?
- Why not?
We can have a drink, chat,
be bored together.
I locked the dog out so we could talk.
Sometimes it's too much,
you know what I mean?
We need ice,
come with me to the kitchen.
My mother didn't want
to leave me alone here.
She was afraid I'd have parties
and get into trouble,
but she doesn't know.
- What happened?
- I cut myself, it's not the first time
with these damn things.
- Don't do it that way.
It's better with cold water.
It'll soon be okay.
- I know a lot of people who get ill
when they see blood.
You're not the same way about blood.
- No, it doesn't bother me in the least.
- I've locked up the dog,
So we can be more relaxed.
Do you want sparkling water?
- Okay.
- Do you like soccer?
- A bit.
- A nice view, you know?
They're good binoculars,
they have a lot of magnification.
Look. Now I'm looking at your house,
the small window with flower curtains,
the window of the
living room, the skylight.
By the way, you've left the light on.
Look.
Turn the little wheel sideways
SO you can see it well.
- Have you noticed? You
can see everything clearly.
- Do you look much through these binoculars?
- Yes.
It is very exciting.
Bury them.
Is something wrong with you, Marcos?
What are you doing?
- Take this,
you need it.
Don't break it.
- Have I scared you much?
- Man, they don't try to
cut my throat open every day.
- You weren't afraid.
Fear shows,
it feels like something thick,
and you were not afraid.
- Yes, it's funny.
I wasn't afraid.
Maybe, I told you, it's
because I'm a strange guy.
Or, maybe because I
think you're not a murderer.
Although most likely,
it's that I don't mind dying.
- This whiskey is good.
Not that I know much
about it, but I like it.
What have you seen
through those binoculars?
What do you know about me?
- Not much.
You're alone,
you're sad, you need help,
and I want to help you.
- Why?
I don't know.
Does there have to be a reason?
- There always is.
No one has ever helped me for free.
- Never?
- Never.
- I would like to help you
for free.
You don't believe me?
- Yes,
I believe you.
I'm leaving.
- Why are you leaving?
- Yes, Nestor, I'm leaving.
You don't have to walk me
to the door,
I remember the way.
Thanks for the whiskey,
and thank you
for everything.
Police,
I've killed six people.
I'm waiting for you outside my home.
Write down
my address.