Previously on Yellowstone...
Fished a radio collar out
of the Yellowstone River.
Seen any wolves around lately?
Sounds like poachers.
- Sure does.
- Care to ride with us?
Monica wants
to have a funeral.
She wants him here
where she can visit.
Whatever she wants, you...
You give it, son.
I can't serve both.
I choose her
and I choose my son.
You promised and you took
millions in lease payments!
You have no case.
And you know it.
You're better than I expected.
I am here just to find
a soft landing.
How busy are you tomorrow night?
New York would like
to drop the suit.
Find a way to ruin
this family, Ellis.
Hey, let's go
to a bar in Bozeman.
Yeah, that's a bad
idea every time.
Aren't you a tall
drink of water?
I'm married. Go on.
I'm taking your husband home.
What day is it?
Thursday, I think.
What happened to you?
Fucking men.
Worked you over
pretty good, huh?
I'm talking about the
cop that arrested me.
Prick is in the club
three nights a week.
He can't cut me a break?
They get you for D.U.I.?
Aggravated assault.
Some bitch from California
tried to fuck my husband
so I beat her with
a beer bottle.
So, you're like
a fucking criminal.
I am the wrath
of a woman scorned.
Call it what you will.
It's always some
bitch from California.
Every fucking time.
Bethany Dutton.
Let's go.
You don't look like a Bethany.
I'm not a Bethany.
I'm a Beth.
My hero.
Knock when you're done.
Boy, you have really
fucking done it this time.
What's the big deal, Jamie?
I got into
a bar fight in Bozeman.
I mean, Montana Board of Tourism
should put that on
fucking t-shirts.
I don't think the Montana
Board of Tourism
is too fond of locals
beating the shit
out of tourists on vacation.
Well, that's why I called you.
You can find the rug to
sweep this under, right?
There is no rug
for this one, Beth.
It's a County Attorney issue.
So your best bet is to hope this
woman has a plane to catch
or she's too hungover
to come down here
and file formal charges.
This is your legal advice?
Sit here and hope?
It's not advice.
It's your only option.
If she doesn't file charges,
and that's a big fucking "if"
considering the photo
I saw of the grapefruit
on her forehead,
then I will ask the
County Attorney
to show some mercy based on
your diminished capacity
to control your
fucking emotions.
So, yeah, you just sit
here and hope.
But no matter what,
if this reaches the press,
it's a big embarrassment
for our father.
You mean my father.
Your father's out of chances to
be embarrassed, isn't he, Jamie?
I'm going to go back to my cell.
I'm going to take a nap.
And you're going to sit on
the fucking steps of this place
and you're going to wait
for Miss California
to walk up, and when she does,
you are going to stop her.
How the hell am
I going to do that?
It's not my problem, Jamie.
Hey. You got this Dutton
assault case?
Uh, yes, sir.
Why no charges against
the complainant?
It was a bar fight, wasn't it?
It was one hell of
a bar fight from the report.
There is no self defense
in a bar fight,
which is to say the victim
is a defendant as well.
Is she coming in?
- I'm waiting for her now.
- I'll wait with you.
You have the Montana
Educators Luncheon at noon.
Cancel it.
Governor, I think that
sends the wrong message.
All right, who exactly attends
the Montana Educators Luncheon?
Everyone.
Senator Perry will be there.
Legislators,
School Superintendents,
the President of Montana State.
Why do they call it
the Educators Euncheon
if there's no educators there?
It's Thursday, Clara, all
the educators are in school.
Tell you what, when the
Educators' Luncheon
is about teachers, I'll go.
Who are they?
It's the policy
advisors' meeting.
Policy advisors for who?
For you.
How can my policy advisors
have a meeting
about policies without me?
Um...
You're in my seat.
So what policies are
we discussing today?
Nobody?
Let's see...
"In accordance with the
U.S. Green initiative,
"Montana is leasing 7,000 acres
in Powder River County
to Sun Energies."
What is Sun Energies?
It's a solar farm company.
Mm. And you are?
Stanley... Roberts.
And you are?
Your chief policy advisor,
Mr. Governor.
Well, nice to fucking meet you.
I tried to schedule
a lunch but you're...
She said you aren't
taking lunches.
Where's your office, Stanley?
Just... Right down the hall.
Know what?
So is mine.
Ever dawn on you just
to come by and say howdy?
My mistake.
I'd say.
Let's see what other
policies I'm proposing.
Suspend natural gas leases
on state land
in Powder River County
to support
the Sage Grouse
Restoration Project.
Um, there's been a precipitous
drop in sage grouse numbers
and there is empirical evidence
that gas exploration
and extraction
have a negative impact on
the sage grouse environment.
And what effect do you
think seven thousand acres
of solar panels are going to
have on their environment?
There's... no evidence that
solar panels
would have any impact on
the sage grouse environment.
What do they do
with the sage brush
when they put
in the solar panels?
They, they...
They would clear it before
putting in the solar panels.
They remove the sage brush.
Yes, sir.
Sage grouse live
in the sage brush.
They do.
And you don't think
removing the sage brush
is going to have an effect
on the population?
I just said there's
no evidence...
Know what scares me about
you, Stanley? You're serious.
You're looking at me
and you're not joking.
I think tops on my agenda today
is going to be budget
discipline. You're all fired.
I'm very mindful of
our tax payers' money,
and you are all wasting it.
I'll advise myself
on policy, Clara.
How much money did we just save?
I would say...
Roughly 1.6 Million dollars
in salary and benefits
if you're serious.
Oh, I'm pretty serious.
Look at that.
What a great day
for the State of Montana.
Where to next?
We have an emergency meeting
with park officials
and U.S. Fish and Wildlife.
Emergency meeting about what?
Doesn't say.
Usually means someone
died in the park.
They're in your office.
What's the emergency?
Governor, we'd like for you
to take a look at this map.
The red lines indicate the
path of a radio-collared wolf
associated with the
Rescue Creek pack.
All right.
As you can see...
Wherever we see these clusters,
we associate with a kill site.
They'll feed on a carcass for a
few days, then they'll move on.
They left the park here
roughly three weeks ago,
they traveled the tree
line to here,
then they dropped down in
this valley to here.
Mm hm.
That's my ranch.
We're aware.
The wolves clustered here
for three days,
around what appears
to be a kill,
then they move straight south
for thirty miles to here.
Now, that's the
Yellowstone River...
They jump into the river,
according to this data
and they swim downstream
for five miles.
Wasn't aware wolves
swam down rivers.
They don't.
We recovered one of the radio
collars from the river.
What are you getting at?
We think the wolves were
killed on your ranch
and the collars transported
back to the park.
You think my cowboys
killed those wolves.
We think your cowboys
Yes sir?
We had any wolves
messing with the cattle?
Wolves? No sir.
Fish and Wildlife came
by asking the same thing.
All right.
There you have it.
Look, if they get
into your cattle
you gotta do what you gotta do.
they shot them
from a distance
didn't notice the collar,
got spooked and tried
to cover their tracks.
These radio collars
aren't monitored by us.
An NGO pays for this research,
and they have
the same data we have
and they are going to draw
the same conclusion.
When they do,
they will come after you
with both barrels, Governor.
Look forward to it.
Anything else?
Thank you, gentlemen.
Governor, we have the...
Yep.
Environmental groups
can be a real problem.
Yeah, you don't say.
This is Clara.
It's Jamie, let me speak to him.
Attorney general.
Yeah?
All right, there is a good
chance I can make this go away.
But, in case I can't,
I need you to know
that I'm in police station
in Bozeman
hoping to convince
a young woman to drop
the aggravated assault
charges she plans
to file against your daughter.
This fucking day.
Can I, uh...
Can I have a little
more context, Jamie?
Yeah, she mouthed
off to Beth in a bar
and it went about
how you'd expect.
All right.
Just, uh, keep me posted.
Is there a crisis manager
on my team, by any chance?
Well, that would be your press
secretary who you never hired,
so I guess your crisis
manager is me.
Can I have a minute?
Having fun yet?
No chance you'd
want to change jobs?
You'd hate this one more.
Any chance you're in Helena?
A good chance.
- Lunch plans?
- Not anymore.
You know Benny's Bistro?
Sure.
- Noon?
- You made my day.
Yeah, maybe you can make mine.
See you in a bit.
Yes, sir.
Miss Brewer.
I understand you'd
like to press.
Very much.
I feel I must point
out that by doing so,
you are exposing
yourself to prosecution.
How am I doing that?
There is no self defense
claim in a bar fight.
I assume you had been drinking,
and I understand you
approached Miss Dutton
and instigated the incident.
I didn't instigate anything.
Oh, um...
Let me see.
Yeah, you approached
Miss Dutton and stated,
"I'm taking your husband home.
"You can come with us and watch
or he can tell you
about it tomorrow."
Are those not your words?
I mean...
I was kidding.
Mm.
She didn't find it very funny.
No shit.
Making statements or actions
that threaten harm to another
or make them feel
they are in danger is assault.
You don't have to hit
somebody to commit assault,
you just have to
present a threat.
You presented the threat.
So if you press charges
the state must
press charges against you.
And since you are not
a resident of Montana,
you present a flight risk
and you bail will be withheld.
Do you understand
what that means?
So she just...
She just gets away with it?
She didn't get away
with anything.
She spent the night in jail
and she's going to be charged
with disorderly conduct.
The choice is yours.
I can't wait to get
out of this state.
Those fucking hillbillies.
Well, the feeling is mutual.
May I leave?
Please.
Saved me a ton of paperwork.
Thanks.
Happy to help.
What're they doing?
For Kayce's boy is my guess.
They told us this spot.
If I would've known I would
have dug that hole for you.
We don't mind.
It's part of the ceremony.
There's a dead horse over there.
When did he die?
He died Monday.
I got an excavator coming
out tomorrow to bury him.
We'll bury him now.
We'll put him in the ground
beside the boy.
Can I ask you why?
You can ask,
but I ain't gonna answer.
Kayce's all right
with this, then?
He knows.
Well, you're gonna
need a big hole.
Jake, Ethan,
run back to the barn
and grab us a bunch of shovels.
I'll help you, Mo.
Thank you.
Don't wish for
what you don't want.
You're in it now, John.
You might as well accept it.
All right.
Explain this job to me,
because it makes no sense.
All I do is go to middle
schools and ribbon cuttings.
Well, when the legislature's
in session
you'll be praying
for ribbon cuttings.
At the end of the day,
Montana is a business...
12,000 employees,
600,000 customers,
and you're the CEO,
and that's all there is.
And you really need to change
your perspective
about these
school meetings, too.
You know, these kids are gonna
remember meeting the governor
for the rest of their lives.
And who knows, you might
even inspire one of them
to become the governor one day.
I mean, that's how
I was inspired.
All right, point taken.
I stepped on a few
land mines it appears.
Already?
Others stepped on them for me.
Seems my daughter
got herself into a bar fight
and has been arrested.
I'm sorry.
It's not funny.
I can see how that's funny
to anybody but me.
All right, well, if it doesn't
go away, just ignore it.
You don't comment
on your personal family.
You love your daughter and hope
she learns from her mistakes.
If she's convicted,
what are my...
what are my options?
You have none.
Well, I take that back,
you could pardon her,
but that's officially the end
of your political career, so...
I don't have to wait
until the end of my term
to pardon someone?
I would strongly advise it
but no, you have the
authority to pardon,
to commute sentence,
grant clemency,
whenever you want.
But once you open that
Pandora's Box,
it does not close, so...
Next land mine?
Environmental groups
relating to...
wolves.
- Avoid them at all costs.
- Yeah.
Buffalo and wolves were
the bane of my two terms.
They are kryptonite.
You need to stay away
and try like hell
to avoid taking a position.
And you need to get
an environmental advisor.
Not one of your rancher buddies,
an environmentalist.
Someone who understands
the way that they think
so they can explain to you what
the hell it is they're thinking.
Here's my best
advice about this job.
Good governors initiate action,
and bad governors spend
all their time reacting.
There are plenty of things
to clean up besides an airport.
You're the only man I know
who would actually pout
over winning
the election that he entered.
I'm not pouting.
Skulking, maybe,
but... not pouting.
You know, this is as much
your legacy as that ranch.
You're a smart woman, Lynelle.
Oh, you're just
figuring that out?
Just enjoy your lunch, John.
It's on me.
Disorderly conduct?
Way to go.
You're welcome.
Now I gotta pick up trash
on the highway
with all my fucking free time.
Which car is yours?
I can't take you back.
I have to go to Helena.
- Which one?
- I'm serious.
Well, how do you want me
to get home, Jamie?
Huh? Want me to hike
my skirt up on the on-ramp?
I doubt it'd be the first time.
What the fuck is that?
What's what?
The baby seat.
What the fuck is that for?
You have a child?
Do you have a child, Jamie?
A boy.
God gave you a boy?
You have my womb
cut out of me...
and God gave you a boy?
Fuck you!
Beth?
Let me guess, is it
that brood mare
of a fucking campaign manager?
- Yes.
- I saw her coming.
Beth.
Come on, Beth.
Beth, stop, stop, stop!
Taking you to that clinic is
the greatest regret of my life.
Of all the awful shit
that you have done
in your 45 years on this planet,
Jamie, that is... that is
really saying something.
What...
What did you name him?
He's named after me.
Of course he is!
That's what the world
fucking needs.
Another fucking you.
Beth.
Dad doesn't know about this.
Nobody knows about this.
Don't worry
about me telling him.
I'm gonna take him from you.
I'm going to rob you
of fatherhood, Jamie.
You don't deserve it.
And he deserves better than you.
Next time you see him,
you can kiss him goodbye,
because he's as good as gone.
Car trouble?
Actually, I just
got out of jail.
And when they let you out,
they just let you out,
there's no, uh,
no phone call to a friend
or a bus ticket.
Just, you know, let you
out on the street.
Seems an unfair policy
toward one who is clearly
having trouble coping
in society, don't you think?
Definitely creates, uh...
Additional challenges for sure.
Right?
- Do you need a...
- Ride?
I'd love one.
Thank you.
What are the odds
that you have a cigarette?
Not good.
Well, aren't you cute?
Mom's gonna kill you, Dad.
Is Mom the jealous type?
Mom wears the pants,
if you know what I mean.
Sister, I know exactly
what you mean.
Stop the car.
Nobody told me.
He didn't tell anybody.
Just pulled up and saw
all the cars.
Should we, uh, get closer?
I think this is as close
as they want us, Dad.
So how was jail?
Loud-mouthed pussy.
You and I are going to
have a long talk later.
Yeah, well, I'm going
to sleep later.
We'll have a short one now then.
Impulse control.
Find some.
I don't think they want us here.
Even if they don't want us,
they need to know
we care enough to stay.
Make me a promise.
Don't ever let them
do that to me.
Turn me to ashes
and throw me to the wind.
That's all the care I want.
John.
I'm not sure the protocol.
There's no protocol now.
Ceremony's over.
I wish I'd known.
Grief isn't meant to be shared.
But comfort is.
They could use some now.
John...
This isn't the place
but we do need to talk.
About what?
About the three hundred jobs
you eliminated
when you canceled
the airport project.
A lot of very unhappy
people on the Reservation.
Can you meet me at
the Capitol tomorrow?
I think you should
meet me on the Reservation.
Show the people
you care enough to visit.
I can do that.
I know how you feel.
I wished I didn't, but I do.
I buried a son right over there.
I remember.
Blaming yourself, aren't you?
Yeah, I did that, too.
Still do some days.
I'll tell you something
I've never told anybody.
I had a brother
for about eighteen hours.
His name was Peter.
He was born early,
and his little heart
wasn't strong enough.
Not much they
could do back in those days.
Not a lot they can do now.
So, they just gave him
back to my mother.
The doctors hoped
and we prayed and...
neither worked.
And it changed my mother.
It hardened her.
She never... she never tried
to have children again.
Years later, I was grown
and Lee had just been born.
Both my parents are looking at
him, taking turns holding him.
And my father got white
as a ghost,
looked at my mother and said,
"Peter lived a perfect life.
"All he saw of this planet
was you
and all he knew
was you loved him."
That boy lived
a perfect life, Monica.
We're the only ones
who know it was brief.
All he knew was you
and that you loved him.
Thank you.
Named him after me.
I did.
Means more than
you'll ever know, son.
I know what it means.
Yeah.
Hang on to this.
Even if you don't use it,
now is not the time
to stop drawing a paycheck.
I'll find someone
to take your place
if that's what you want.
It's what I want.
Looks like you
got tossed off one.
Just been digging graves.
Horses go in the field,
you know that.
Yeah, I know but they wanted
it beside the boy.
Didn't figure you'd say no.
They say why?
My guess is the boy has
something to ride into Heaven.
Uh, the Poison Creek outfit,
they reached out,
they're short handed to brand.
They wanted our help so,
if you're all right with it,
go over there tomorrow.
When are we starting?
Well, next week.
You plan on being
here, don't you?
I mean, it's not my place to...
- I'll be here.
- All right.
Park Rangers came and asked me
some question about wolves
that held up here.
You know anything about that?
Mm. They pulled down a cow,
and I asked Ryan to
go out and shoot 'em.
He shot the ones with
the damn collars on 'em.
I was worried that it was going
to cause you a problem
so I tried to outsmart 'em
and I guess I didn't.
So, I'm sorry, sir.
Where are the wolves now?
In a place that nobody
will ever find them.
Horses in heaven.
Mm-hm. That's the best
I could figure it.
Wouldn't that be something?
♪ Well, in you ♪
♪ The good I'll do
Good I'll do, oh ♪
♪ The good I'll do ♪
♪ The way the grass smells
At night ♪
♪ And you've got flames
All in your eyes ♪
♪ As they reflect the sparkler ♪
♪ And you say
we'll never die ♪
♪ Grab me by the hands
Just as callused as I am ♪
♪ Say your proud ♪
♪ Well, there's blue jeans
in the driveway ♪
♪ And you're walking
Inside sideways ♪
♪ The wine always affects you
In beautiful kind ways ♪
♪ Ask me if I'm staying
And I say that I'm ♪
♪ Sleeping on the floor ♪
♪ Won't you tell me
that you need me ♪
♪ 'Cause lately I've been
Needing someone to remind me ♪
♪ I'm worth more than
Just an evening ♪
♪ I awoke to kitchen smoke,
You dancin' ♪
♪ Like God's moved
In you before ♪
♪ Well, in you ♪
♪ The good I'll do
Good I'll do, oh ♪
♪ Good I'll do ♪
♪ Well, in you ♪
♪ I'm new, I'm new
Oh, how I'm new ♪
♪ Look in my eyes ♪
♪ I don't wanna to hide ♪
♪ I've been waiting for you
All damn night ♪
I know but he's
gotta go somewhere.
♪ Sundress, I'll undress
With nails on your skin ♪
♪ Turning white ♪
♪ Getting high out in Austin
Drunk in Tennessee ♪
♪ I don't care where I am
As long as you're with me ♪
♪ Those boys downtown talk
So much shit when I leave ♪
Good job, Reese.
♪ Well, in you ♪
♪ The good I'll do
Good I'll do, oh ♪
♪ The good I'll do ♪
♪ 'Cause in you ♪
♪ I'm new, I'm new
Oh, how I'm new ♪
♪ The way the grass smells
At night ♪
♪ And you've got flames
All in your eyes ♪
♪ As they reflect the sparkler ♪
Whoo!
♪ And you say
we'll never die ♪
♪ Grab me by the hands
Just as callused as I am ♪
♪ Say your proud ♪
So how many are
y'all running this year?
Bout the same as last year.
But we won't add any
yearlings this year though.
Not with diesel prices and corn.
- No.
- Shit.
When this finally
makes it to the butcher shop,
it's gonna sting.
It's good to see your boy back.
It's just for the summer.
He graduated,
got a job in Boise.
But my daughter wants to stay.
We'll see if I can
make a cowboy out of her
shit-for-brains husband.
Only thing he seems
to like making is babies.
Is that right?
World sure is shrinking
where you are.
It's good to see that
airport squashed.
That ain't gonna
change nothing, Delbert.
I mean, shit, it might
slow it down a bit.
At least the world hasn't found
out about this place yet.
It breaks my heart to think
of the world we're leaving them.
Breaks my heart, too.
Hell, I don't even have
any kids.
Higgins.
What took you so long?
I've only been Governor a week.
I see you survived.
- Thank you.
- Well, there's a catch.
A catch?
Yeah, it's a supervised
release for six months.
Supervised by who?
You're looking at him.
So, you release me from
prison just to kidnap me?
More or less.
Need your help.
With what?
Help me understand you.
Help me understand
the way you think.
What do I get in return?
You just got it.
Get in.
- Where am I staying?
- With me.
I'm no political strategist
but granting clemency to a woman
you're shacking up with
in the Governor's mansion lends
itself to some negative press.
At the ranch.
Oh, great. With your bi-polar
sociopathic daughter?
She's hardly ever there.
So you know, I just
went a year without sex,
which is the longest I've gone
since the first time I had it,
and I'm still not fucking you.
Oh, God.
Our relationship will
be purely professional.
Let her in.
Miss Atwood.
Oh, come on. It's Sarah.
Have a seat.
I took the liberty of
ordering us a bottle of Rosé.
I hope you don't mind.
Well, can't say
I've ever had it.
Oh. Well the French,
they drink it
like water in the summer.
Try it.
It's refreshing.
It's nice.
What?
Oh, I'm just trying to decide
the best path forward.
How do we manage this?
How do we as a company, recover?
How do we save face?
But most importantly, how
do we reverse his decision?
Either reverse his decision
or get our money back.
I mean, the state is facing
a multi-billion dollar lawsuit
and you know it.
You won't win.
With some of the most
vital elements
of your development now in
a Conservation Easement,
the argument is moot.
We don't have to win.
We just need to keep it in
the news long enough
to assassinate your
father's reputation
and choose a politician
to support as the next governor.
Hm.
I'm getting ahead of myself.
The purpose of this dinner
was to seek a soft landing.
Not to threaten positions.
Let's figure out if we can
even get along first.
Are you hungry?
Not really.
Mm-mm. Me neither.
I've had enough of
this fruity shit.
Do you want to go to the bar?
Sure.
Oh, that's not funny.
Then why are you laughing?
I'm laughing because
I'm uncomfortable.
You're uncomfortable
because you find it funny.
I'm dreading arguing
with you in court.
You should.
Yeah?
How the hell are
you still single?
Well...
when you live on
a ranch an hour from town...
an hour from anything...
You don't live
on a ranch anymore.
Hm. No, I don't.
I'm feeling
a little irresponsible.
Hm.
I'm starting to
feel that way myself, too.
Oh.
Take me somewhere and prove it.
♪ But you know
I've always been ♪
Follow me.
Okay.
I don't hear anybody.
Wow.
This way.
- You...
- No.
This is what I call
a fucking bathroom.
Wait. Wait...
Who cares?
Let him listen.
What are you doing?
Nothing, baby.
Just thinking.
Maybe you should think
about something different.
I'd love to.
But... it ain't gonna happen.
Go back to sleep.
Who is this bitch?
Yeah, not her real name.
What a surprise.
Our Justice system is in a
state of utter collapse, huh?
And to think of all the hard
work I did to put you in prison.
And think of all the hard work
I'm doing to stay out.
And I do mean hard.
I'll pick you up some
Doxycycline when I'm in town
to kill whatever funk your
snatch caught in the clink.
Mm. Thanks. Could you also
get me a toothbrush?
I hate to keep using yours.
Oh, well.
Back to work.
I am not starting
this day sober.
Next time on Yellowstone...
John: First Duttons
to settle this valley...
fighting was all they knew.
She is not gonna help you, Dad.
You have invited your worst
enemy to sleep in your bed.
Market Equities or its partners.
We can do whatever we want.
They want the land, Dad.
That is all that you need
to understand.
Cowards rule the world
these days, Rip.
I think it's time we showed them
what we do and how we do it.