My name is Eliza Scarlet.
I'm a private detective.
And, please, don't say,
"You're a what?"
I'm running
this London office now,
and I can assure you,
things will pick up.
We have exactly no clients.
Desperate times call
for desperate measures.
No sniffing around or digging.
I'm not a dog, William.
What have you done?!
You look tired.
You look beautiful.
Here at Nash and Sons,
we offer the most professional
of services.
And I do not boast when I say
that these past few months
under my leadership
have seen even greater success.
A woman, no less, at the helm
of London's most esteemed
private detective agency.
Eliza Scarlet,
chief investigator.
One T in Scarlet,
Mr. Godfrey.
Ah.
As you can see, my success here
speaks for itself.
Sorry to disturb you,
Miss Scarlet,
but I need your sign-off
on the Whitlock case
investigation.
Of course.
Another successful conclusion
to one of our many cases.
And if you could ensure
that our address is placed
somewhere prominent
in the article, Mr. Godfrey.
How many times?
It's the Whitlock case
or the Whitlock investigation,
not both.
I was not hired by Mr. Nash
to pretend to be
a private detective.
So you said, three times.
Thank you, everyone.
You know the drill by now.
Miss Scarlet,
may I speak my mind?
No.
I know it's not ideal
that Mr. Nash's entire
staff of men have
left you.
Thank you...
Deserted is more
an appropriate term.
But whilst he's in Paris,
it is my number-one
responsibility
to make sure his business
is financially viable.
As it is mine--
thank you.
So, so, as his accountant,
I must advise you
in the strongest
possible terms
that this, this financial
practice is not prudent.
Thank you.
Thank you, Miss Scarlet.
I know what I'm doing,
Clarence.
Really?
Really? Because,
because hiring actors
to pretend to be detectives
tells me otherwise!
So, I've done some sums.
And our financial situation
is not as bad
as we first thought.
It is worse.
Hence my reservations
at hiring actors
who purport to be employees.
It's a waste of money.
It's not.
"The Illustrated Police News"
will publish an article
declaring our success
since Mr. Nash
left me in charge.
This, in turn,
will attract more clients.
The term "more" implies
we already have a full roster.
But the last time I checked,
we have exactly
no clients.
I do not wish to lay blame
squarely at your door...
Good, because the fact
they didn't want a woman
running their accounts is a
question of biology, not fault.
And the same goes for
Mr. Nash's staff of men.
My recollection is that
Mr. Nash's men left
because of the manner
in which you dealt with them.
Half of them never returned
after their lunch
and the other half strolled
into work when it suited.
I was trying to run
a tighter ship.
Well, Mr. Nash's way
was a little more respectful.
Clarence, need I remind you
that he's not here anymore?
I'm running
this London office now,
and I can assure you,
things will pick up.
If you say so.
I do.
Get me the files on the
local talent from Felton Street
to Bridge Lane,
anyone handy with a knife.
Yes, sir.
You track down the dead man's
relatives,
inform them of the stabbing.
Straightaway, sir.
Hey, Duke...
Not now.
Sir!
Not now!
All right, let's get started.
I said, quiet!
Now, I know this last month
has been difficult...
Diabolical, more like.
But it has just been
confirmed that,
as well as the additional areas
in Essex and Kent,
we'll now be policing
further districts
in Surrey and Middlesex, too.
Bloody hell, skipper,
we're flat-out as it is.
To cope with demand,
all leave will be canceled
and double shifts
implemented.
I said not now!
It's urgent, sir.
What's this?
Get to it, then.
Fitzroy, Phelps.
Listen, if I want your opinion,
Charlie, I will ask for it.
I'm not telling you
to do anything
that I'm not
already doing myself.
I haven't been home for days.
I know, skipper-- sorry.
Right, there's been a shooting
in Mayfair.
Sounds like an armed robbery.
It's that place at the end
of Turner Street.
The Temple of Elysium.
Elysium?
Is it a theater?
No, son.
It ain't no theater.
Hello, handsome.
I've already given
my statement to the officer
that was here earlier,
as did my girls.
I really must insist
that they be allowed home.
They've been working all night.
Well, that is as may be,
but I need you and them
to tell me
the chain of events.
So, an armed gunman
entered the brothel...
It's not a brothel.
It is an elite gentlemen's club.
An armed gunman entered
the elite gentlemen's club,
robbed it, then shot
one of your punters.
A gunman came
through the entrance.
He held our watchman
at gunpoint and demanded
that he tie himself up.
Then he went from bedroom
to bedroom robbing my clients.
My watchman managed
to untie himself.
And then he went outside
calling for help,
instead of tackling the gunman
and protecting me and my girls,
which is what
he's paid to do.
You'll need to come
to the station
to make a statement, sir.
I need a description
of the gunman.
A black scarf
covering his face,
shabby cloth cap
and overcoat,
average height,
fair hair, and blue eyes.
We'll need to talk
to your punters, too.
Well, they've all left.
This is a private club,
Detective.
Gentlemen come
to the Temple of Elysium
to enjoy some discreet time
with one of my goddesses.
Not to be part of
some police investigation.
On that, were you aware
that Greek goddesses
actually lived on Mount Olympus,
not Elysium?
Elysium was a paradise
for warriors
favored by the gods.
I mean, there may have been
some women there...
Yes, thank you for the lesson,
Detective Fitzroy.
Fascinating, I'm sure.
What about the punter
who was shot?
They are not punters!
They are gentleman callers.
So, this gentleman caller
was sleeping off
some overindulgence
and the intruder
tried to rob him,
and a fight ensued.
Which I assume is why
the fella got shot.
So...
Who tended to him?
One of my girls happened
to be with a doctor.
He examined him and
took him off to hospital.
And what did this doctor say
about his injuries?
I never asked.
Which hospital was he taken to?
What was the name of the man
who was shot?
They never say.
And let me guess.
You never asked.
Discretion is what this place
is built on, Detective.
Gentlemen come here
for good reason.
There is never
a good reason
to be unfaithful to your wife,
madam.
Let's talk again
when you're married, son.
I'm in a vicious circle.
No clients means no money.
No money means
no hiring of new staff.
I'm just hoping that when
this article is published,
it will attract new business.
Ivy, are you even
listening to me?
Sorry.
I've just got to a really
good bit in the story.
The detective has just found
another dead body.
Blood everywhere.
All you ever do these days
is have your nose in a book.
You're the one who told me
to read novels
like a normal person, instead of
your father's old law books.
Yes, but not all the time.
What about some
freshly baked biscuits?
Will that help?
Always.
And what about Moses?
He brings in a case or two--
when's he back?
Not any time soon.
Paris seems to suit him.
Well...
What about the inspector?
I can't ask him.
Why?
Things aren't quite the same
since Arabella.
But I thought that ended.
Well, yes, but we haven't
seen each other in a while.
Why not?
Because I've been busy.
No, you haven't.
Go and see him, Lizzie.
Ah! Back!
The rest are for Barnabus.
Excuse me.
Jim.
Hey.
Watch out, sir.
Here we go--
thank you very much.
William, there you are.
I thought perhaps
you'd left for the evening.
You look tired.
You look beautiful.
Oh...
Thank you.
So, to what do I owe
this unexpected visit?
Well, I was just passing
and thought I'd pop in
to visit my oldest friend.
Passing?
To where at this time
of night?
Dinner.
With whom?
Well, you wouldn't know them.
Because they don't exist?
What's that
supposed to mean?
I know you, Eliza.
You neither pass
nor pop,
you premeditate.
Now, I'm afraid,
is not a good time.
We are experiencing an
unprecedented level of cases.
I cannot go into why...
Well, because of the
further expansion
of Scotland Yard's
jurisdiction.
That's classified information
at the moment.
How do you know that?
I read it in the report
that's on your desk.
Well, it seems you could do
with more manpower.
So, how fortuitous
that I should drop by.
Since I'm now in charge
at Nash and Sons,
I have a large team of men
at my disposal.
Ah, there it is.
The real reason
that you're here.
You were the one who brought up
being understaffed.
All I'm saying...
Yes, Eliza, I know exactly
what you're saying.
I always know exactly what
you're saying,
even when
you're not saying it.
Good night.
Thank you.
I can confirm
he is the only patient
that was brought in today
with a gunshot wound to the leg.
I need the gentleman's name.
He refused to share it
when he was admitted.
And since then,
he's been administered laudanum
for the pain.
It'll be some time
before he's able to talk.
Thank you, Nurse.
Matron.
Oh, straighten that cap,
Sister!
Yes, Matron.
And see to the patient
in room five!
Reminds me of my missus.
Well...
There's not much more
we can do here tonight.
We'll come back
in the morning
when he's compos mentis,
find out who he is then.
I know exactly who he is.
I've seen him at meetings
with my father.
He's a government minister,
Charlie.
I have all the files here,
Inspector.
And once we've gone
through these,
I'll take you through
to the adjoining room
where there are even more
cadavers for your attention.
I can hardly wait.
I do not exaggerate when I say
we are bursting at the seams.
Our coroner, Mr. Wormsley's,
agitated indeed.
He is a precise man
who, who prides himself
on his meticulous
examinations.
Yet since this expansion,
he has felt--
and I hope I betray
no confidence here--
disgruntled,
to say the least.
Yes, well, I share Mr.
Wormsley's concern, Mr. Potts.
Mm.
Thank you.
Wellington.
Sir.
Commissioner Fitzroy.
May I say what a,
what a pleasure it is
to have you here in person.
Leave us.
I have a delicate matter
to discuss with you.
The brothel, in Mayfair.
The man who was shot
comes from the Home Office,
and he was not the only
gentleman of influence there.
Most of the possessions
that were stolen
have personal messages
and family crests
engraved on them,
so you can imagine
it would not be ideal
if it became public knowledge
where they were lost.
Yes, I can see that, sir.
Which is why we are going
to make it our absolute priority
to find out who did this and
to get those possessions back.
Yes.
And I want you to lead
the case yourself.
Well, sir, you, uh,
told me to specifically oversee
all active investigations.
Oh, forget what I told you.
Many of these men
have a say in my budgets.
They could make my life...
...difficult.
So, you will lead this case
and you will resolve it
with speed and discretion.
And, if you do not,
I will hold you
directly responsible.
Is that understood,
Wellington?
Yes, sir.
I won't tell you again,
I want no part in this.
Any association with that place
would be catastrophic for me.
I'm not just
a government minister,
I'm a married man
with children.
Yes.
Nevertheless, sir,
there are some questions
that I have to ask.
So, the gunman
came into the bedroom,
demanded your possessions...
I need some pain relief!
And I will send
for the nurse
when you have answered
my questions.
Am I under arrest?
No.
Then here is my statement.
I received this gunshot
in a hunting accident.
This is what I have told
my wife
and this is what I
will tell anyone who asks.
I do hope that answers any
further questions, Inspector.
"Illustrated Police News."
Fresh off the press!
"Illustrated Police..."
Excuse me.
There you go.
Thank you.
"Illustrated Police News."
Morning, Clarence.
I have decided
today is the day
our fortunes change.
Do not bother,
Miss Scarlet.
I've already checked
and there is no article.
But Mr. Godfrey
specifically said
it would be in today's edition.
Oh, well, journalists
will promise the moon and stars
until a bigger and better
story comes along.
If, as I had advised,
you had kept our
advertising account with them,
they would have prioritized us,
as they did when Mr. Nash
was here.
Instead, you saw fit
to cancel said account
and spend the money
elsewhere.
For instance, on actors.
I'm curious, Clarence.
If you're so dissatisfied
with how I run things,
why do you not leave
like the rest?
Because...
I am not a quitter,
Miss Scarlet.
And I believe you could be
a little more grateful for that.
I understand
that a police investigation
might not be good
for business.
Well, that's an
understatement.
None of my clients
will come within a mile
while there's
a police presence.
And I can't afford
to have this place
shut down
for much longer.
Then help me
with my inquiries.
Don't you want to catch
whoever did this?
Oh, he'll be caught,
all right.
It's not just the great
and the good that come here.
I have clients from
all walks of life.
They'll catch
that toe-rag for me,
and when they do,
he'll wish he'd never
been born.
I must insist
that you don't take the law
into your own hands, madam--
we will find whoever did this.
I'm privy to many
conversations, Inspector.
Judges, politicians.
And when they've had their fill
of whiskey and women,
they like a nice little chat,
and I'm a very good listener.
Word is they're not very happy
with the great Scotland Yard.
From what I gather,
it's a shambles over there.
So, forgive me if I don't
share your confidence.
Sir, I've gathered files on all
those with previous conviction
for armed robbery
for the past three years,
but there's over
2,000 of them.
Better get on with it, then.
But, sir,
it's just such a huge task
and we just don't
have the manpower...
Then tell your father
what a mess we're in,
because he sure as hell
won't listen to me!
That was, uh,
that was uncalled for.
I apologize.
Permission to speak, sir?
Oliver, you don't
have to ask permission.
It's just you haven't
been home for days.
You, you need to rest.
Sleep is a luxury
that I don't have at the moment.
Right now, we need to find
a way to go through those files
and compare them to the
description of the gunman.
Well, we're gonna need
more men.
William, how nice to see you.
I received your telegram.
Although I must admit
I was unsure
whether I'd have time
to fit you in.
As you can see, things are
extremely busy at present.
Sorry to disturb you,
Miss Scarlet,
but I need your sign-off on the
Whitlock investigation.
Mm.
Shall we?
So, this brothel
in Mayfair...
All I can tell you is that
it was an armed robbery
where one of the punters was
injured with a gunshot wound.
So, I assume the fact that
you're keeping his identity
confidential means
that he's a man of influence.
Eliza, please don't
assume anything.
It never ends well.
Well, it's an
awful lot of files
you wish my men to go through.
Not to mention how vague the
description of the gunman is.
Perhaps you might be willing
to negotiate a higher fee?
Do you want the job or not?
Yes.
I'll take the case.
Good.
Then I'll have the files
delivered this afternoon.
And no sniffing around,
Eliza, or digging.
I'm not a dog, William.
No, but you are
relentless.
Do only what I ask of you,
nothing more.
My word is my bond.
If only that were true.
Yes!
I should not be doing
this donkey work.
Lest we forget,
Miss Scarlet,
I am a fully
qualified accountant.
How could I forget, Clarence,
when you remind me so often?
And with just the two of us,
this task will take
days to complete.
You're right, perhaps we do
need to get some help.
We do not have the money
to pay for extra help.
Who said anything
about paying?
I couldn't believe it
when I got your note, Lizzie.
Me, helping with
a real investigation!
It's just like in my novel.
The detective asks
his uncle for assistance.
Yes, he's an ex-policeman,
but still.
Right.
This little lot is done--
I'll go and get some more.
Are we brought so low that
we have to turn to your maid
for assistance?
She's more efficient
than you.
For every one file
you've checked, she's done five.
Mr. Nash...
I don't care what he
did or didn't do.
I'm in charge now.
And if you're so enamored
with Mr. Nash,
why didn't you go to Paris
with him?
What?
Go easy, hey?
I don't need advice on
how to manage my employees.
Employee, singular.
When you were a girl...
Oh, please, God, no.
Fine, I'll talk to him.
In my determination
to keep this agency afloat,
I may come across
as a little terse sometimes.
I apologize.
All I was going to say
about Mr. Nash
is that he has an army
of paid informants,
including girls who work
at many different brothels
across London.
Where would I find information
on these informants?
Why wasn't I told
this was in here?
Well, Mr. Nash likes to
keep the identity
of his informants
confidential.
I'm the chief investigator!
You're the only
investigator.
Right, um...
Police informants.
Legal informants.
Government informants.
Here we are.
Ladies of the night.
I adore Mr. Nash.
Always so good to me.
A very fair man--
everyone loves him.
Perhaps we could talk about
something other than Mr. Nash.
So, you work at
the Temple of Elysium.
For my sins.
I've heard of it.
I always thought it very clever.
A brothel themed
as a mythological paradise.
Hm, well, according to
the copper that came by,
women weren't even
allowed in Elysium.
Well, he's right.
It was one of the three realms
of the underworld
in Greek mythology.
Tartarus,
the Asphodel Meadows,
and then there was Elysium,
an Eden for heroes
favored by the gods.
Well, I can tell you, darling,
the men that visit me
ain't no heroes.
So, this shooting.
The description
of the gunman--
average height,
fair hair, blue eyes--
it's a little generic.
It's a pack of lies, too.
He was tall, brown hair,
brown eyes.
Me and the other girls
were told to lie
to the coppers by her.
Her?
Madam Hera.
That's not her real name,
of course,
just like Athena ain't mine.
Why would she tell you to lie?
Word is, she called in a favor
to find the gunman herself.
You cross the madam
at your own peril.
Poor old Dimitrie
found that out.
Dimitrie?
The watchman that was on
when the robbery took place.
She sacked the poor sod.
Welcome to Solomon's.
How can I help?
Is Solomon here?
I'm afraid my uncle's gone back
to Jamaica to visit family.
Well, perhaps you could
help me.
I'm an acquaintance of his,
Miss Scarlet.
I'm looking for man,
a watchman.
He was dismissed
from a, a brothel in Mayfair.
I need to find his address--
I wish to speak with him.
I'm afraid I have no idea
what you're talking about.
This is a shop to
buy things in, Miss Scarlet.
And speaking of which,
we've just had a new delivery
this very morning.
The golden vamp butterfly
from the Himalayan mountains.
Very rare.
There are
no golden vamp butterflies
in the Northern Hemisphere.
Ah, my mistake, yeah.
This is the golden vamp
from Madagascar.
And nor are they
completely golden,
just the tips of their wings.
This is very pretty.
What if I bought one?
I'll wrap it up for you.
What if I bought two?
Then I'll wrap them both.
How about three?
A watchman, you say?
Let me get my pen.
Miss Scarlet.
Mr. Sinclaire.
How are you, Miss Scarlet?
Busy.
Always such
a busy, busy bee.
I suppose, since
you've taken over
at Nash and Sons,
not that he has any sons,
time is precious.
What do you want,
Mr. Sinclaire?
Why, just to tell you
how hurt I am.
When I learned that you'd gone
to my underling, Mr. Godfrey,
instead of directly to me,
the chief correspondent of
our esteemed publication,
it was like a dagger
to my heart.
You have a heart,
Mr. Sinclaire.
That is welcome news.
"Basil," I said to myself,
"You and Miss Scarlet are
old acquaintances, are you not?
Why on Earth would she
do such a thing?"
The last time
we worked together,
you printed a pack of lies--
does that help?
Ooh, lies, you say?
Like the ones you fed
young Mr. Godfrey?
It seems that in your eagerness
to laud your success,
it has led you down the
slippery slope of dishonesty.
Oh, dear, dear me.
You see, I happen
to know for a fact
that Mr. Nash's entire staff
have deserted you,
and so, too,
his book of clients.
And so, in my capacity
as chief correspondent,
I have decided that I will be
the one to write the article,
and it shall be one
based on the truth:
that the once
most successful
private investigation
agency in London
is now on the verge of collapse.
And it is all thanks
to the lady detective.
Ah.
Whoa.
Good day, Miss Scarlet.
Ride on!
Sir-- hup!
Let him go.
Sir.
Any luck?
He's got an alibi,
just like all the others.
So, we round up some more?
We'll make a detective
of you yet, Charlie.
William.
Inspector Wellington.
Inspector Wellington,
Detective Phelps.
Miss Scarlet.
Get the wagons ready.
I'll meet you
out front.
I have something I need
to tell you, William,
but will you promise
to remain calm?
You hired actors to pose
as your staff of detectives?
I knew you'd react
like this.
You fooled me into hiring you!
How would you like me to react?
Well, at least I did the decent
thing to tell you myself,
rather than you reading it
in Sinclaire's rag.
The decent thing was not
to lie to me in the first place.
There's nothing you can say
that I haven't already said
to myself.
Oh, I'm quite sure
that there is.
It's all very well
for you in your
comfortable job.
I haven't slept for weeks
worrying about mine.
My God, Eliza, there is nothing
comfortable about my job,
and if you had
any shred of concern
for anyone
other than yourself,
then you would know this!
Good day, Miss Scarlet.
Is, is all well?
Not remotely.
But never mind that.
You're on the
brothel robbery?
I am.
Good.
Because I have some information
I'd like to share with you.
So, the madam lied about
the description of the gunman.
Apparently so.
I've also put the feelers out
to find this dismissed watchman.
Thank you,
this is most helpful.
Oliver.
Inspector Wellington,
how have you found him
recently?
I cannot lie, um,
I'm concerned about him.
He hasn't been home
for days.
He's putting all his attention
on this robbery,
to the detriment
of other cases,
of which there are many.
Well, then, let me help you.
Share your findings with me.
Uh, this is a highly
confidential investigation.
I'm afraid I cannot.
However,
if I were to leave
the file here,
and if I were to just
pop out for a moment,
then if someone were to read
the file without my knowledge,
well...
The man who was shot.
Any identity yet?
Page four.
What are you doing?
Why are you not
in your uniform?
I don't understand.
You are Nurse James,
due to start today?
Well, this room
is a disgrace!
These soiled clothes should
have been disposed of yesterday!
And when you have done that,
his bed needs remaking,
his temperature recorded,
and bandage changed.
So get these clothes
down to the basement
ready to be
incinerated,
get into your uniform,
and report back immediately!
Is that clear?
If you would
just let me speak.
I'm not a nurse.
My name is Eliza Scarlet.
I'm a private detective--
and, please,
don't say,
"You're a what?"
Come on, come on!
Come on, we haven't got all day.
Go, go, go!
Get this lot inside, Charlie.
All right, you ugly lot,
hurry up!
Or you'll feel my boot
where the sun don't shine!
There you are, sir.
I have new information
on the Elysium case.
Go on.
The madam of
the brothel lied.
The gunman wasn't fair,
blue eyes, or medium height.
He was the opposite: tall,
brown hair, brown eyes.
According to whom?
Miss Scarlet.
She seemed quite certain
of it, too.
I think I'll pay Madam Hera
a little visit.
Where's Ivy?
Gone to make dinner
for someone called Barnabus.
She did take a box of files
with her
to work through--
oh, this came for you.
It's a court summons
for rent arrears.
I really could do with
some good news, Clarence.
Well, the watchman
you've been looking for...
He's in your office.
So, the madam dismissed you
after the robbery.
Because I ran outside for help
instead of tackling the gunman.
I came here 20 years ago
in search for better life.
But, as a watchman,
I have spent those years
getting beaten up
and shot at.
And when I was young,
I did not mind, but...
I'm getting old.
I have children
I want to see grow up.
And because of that woman,
I will not be able
to put some food
on my family's table
tonight.
I have no loyalty to her,
so I will tell you
something.
I'm listening.
She told me to lie
to the police.
When I was calling for help, I
saw no gunman leave the brothel.
But if you didn't see the gunman
leave, then how did he get away?
A back entrance?
There is no back entrance.
I was forbidden
to ever go upstairs,
but I've heard
there is a secret way
in and out.
The building
that adjoins the brothel
was once
an exclusive gentlemen's club.
It shut down years ago,
but it was once frequented
by the rich and powerful,
by politicians and even princes.
Legend has it that the clients
would use a connecting door
into the brothel
as a discreet way in.
If the door exists,
I believe that's how
the gunman escaped.
Three sons of Titan.
Zeus, god of the sky.
Poseidon, god of the sea.
And Hades, god of the three
realms of the underworld:
Tartarus, the Asphodel Meadows,
and Elysium.
A bullet hole.
Well, that's news to me.
What do you mean
they've been returned?
Exactly that.
Everything stolen
is in this box.
It was outside the entrance
this morning.
I've got no idea who left it.
So, I will return these
to their rightful owners,
and case is closed.
The case is closed
when I say it is.
I'll be taking the contents
of that box
back to Scotland Yard,
where it will be logged
as evidence.
As for you,
you'll come with me
and make a statement
explaining how you came
to be in possession
of these stolen goods.
I'm quite sure, Inspector,
that your superiors
have instructed you
to close this case
with speed and discretion.
Taking these valuables
to Scotland Yard,
and, indeed, me,
I would argue that is the
very opposite of discretion.
So, we're agreed.
I will return these
to my clients,
and you will leave
my premises
and bother me no more.
See, you're forgetting
something, madam.
There is a man lying in hospital
who was shot on these premises.
Last I heard, the poor minister,
he was adamant that he was
wounded in a hunting accident.
No more days out shooting
for him.
Not if his wife
has anything to do with it.
I do not have the appetite
nor the inclination
for another argument, Eliza.
My day has been vexing enough.
I do not come
to argue.
I come to tell you
I've made
a discovery
on the brothel case.
No, Eliza...
I know who the gunman is.
There's a hidden door
that leads from the bedroom
where the minister was shot
into a room
of an abandoned building,
and it's there
that I found a bullet.
I believe it was discharged
by the gunman as he escaped.
Trousers belonging
to the minister.
They were due to be
incinerated at the hospital.
So, what does this
have to do with the bullet?
This was attached
to the bullet.
I recognized the pattern
on the cloth.
I knew I'd seen it before
at hospital.
So, why, why
would the minister lie
and say that the gunman
shot him in the bedroom?
Because he is the gunman,
William.
Why on Earth would I want
to stage a robbery?
I'm a government minister,
for heaven's sake!
Well, I've done some
digging on you, sir,
and it would appear that you're
also in grave financial straits.
I would say
that that is motive enough.
Being a junior minister
must be a costly business
if you hope
for a promotion.
Dinners, theater trips, hosting
parties with the right wine.
It must be a strain
on one's resources.
Anyone who tells you,
"It's not who you know,
but what you know," is a liar.
I needed the money
to rise up the ranks,
to impress those with the power
to help me advance.
So, you staged a robbery
in a place where no one
would want to admit to being.
It is the favored brothel
by those at the Home Office.
It seemed like the perfect place
to do it.
So, while everyone thought
you were in bed intoxicated,
you disguised yourself
as the gunman.
And when it came
to robbing yourself,
you staged a fight
to make it look like
there'd been a struggle.
I planned to leave
the gunman's attire
and what I'd stolen
in the room next door.
I would then get back into bed
as the drunk minister,
and no one would be
any the wiser.
But then I heard the watchman on
duty yelling for help outside,
and I...
I flew into a panic.
As I squeezed through the door
to the disused room,
I stumbled and fell.
And the handgun went off.
I've never used a handgun
before.
Bought it from some rough type
in a pub in Whitechapel.
But you had to cover the fact
you'd been shot,
so you put a bullet
in the bedroom floor, too.
I told the madam everything.
I had to.
I needed her help.
She was livid I'd done such a
thing in her place of business,
so she instructed
that I keep my mouth shut.
And she would get rid
of the evidence.
Which is why she
pretended to track down
the stolen possessions,
when, in fact, she had them
all the time.
They would be returned
to their owners,
and the case would be closed
quickly and discreetly.
Minister Delaware will resign
and go away quietly.
And this Madam Hera,
she's up to her eyes
in all this, too.
Oh, no, no.
She's to be left alone.
She knows too much
about too many.
Sir, um,
this expansion is crippling us.
We lack the manpower
and the resources to cope.
My biggest fear is
that I am sending my men
into situations
that they are ill prepared for.
Someone is going to get hurt.
What would you have me do?
I cannot pluck money
out of thin air.
No, sir, but, um...
But perhaps this,
this case can,
can give you some more sway
with the Home Office.
After all, it's for their sake
that we're staying quiet.
You are asking me
to blackmail them,
a government department.
No, of course not, sir,
not blackmail, more, um...
More leverage to negotiate.
If I had my way, I would dismiss
you with immediate effect
for the mere suggestion
of such a thing.
But given the flux we are in,
that would benefit no one.
You are to keep your mouth shut
about this case.
Is that clear,
Wellington?
Perfectly, sir.
You were simply
thinking of your men.
The police commissioner didn't
quite see it like that.
Would you like me
to have a word with him?
It's nice to see you
smile.
Well, I haven't had much
to smile about recently.
I'm sorry I lied to you.
I did try to lead Nash's men.
But they just saw me
as some bossy woman.
You're not bossy, Eliza.
You are determined.
Things haven't quite
turned out how I'd hoped.
Sometimes I do wonder...
If it's all worth it?
You are a good detective,
Eliza, very good.
And whatever happens from here,
you'll find a way
to make it work.
You always do.
Are you just saying that
so that I pay
for dinner tomorrow evening?
I wasn't aware
that we were due to dine.
Well, the last Wednesday
of every month, we dine,
and that just happens
to be tomorrow.
It's been a while
since we enjoyed an evening out.
It has.
Well, no more burning
the midnight oil.
You must go home tonight
and rest-- I will not
have you falling asleep
at the table.
I take back what I said.
You are bossy.
Good night, Eliza.
Good night, William.
Night, Inspector.
Night, Ivy.
I've found something
in these files
you asked me
to look through.
The case is closed, Ivy.
It's not about the gunman.
It's about someone else
entirely.
Now I understand why you
haven't sought another position
like the others.
Or gone to Paris
with Mr. Nash.
The small issue
of a criminal record
would have put paid
to that!
You are mentioned
as an associate to not one,
but three criminal gangs
as their accountant.
And not a very successful one,
given you've served time
for taxation fraud.
Mr. Nash hired me
when no one else would.
And I shall be forever grateful
for that.
I shall fetch my coat and hat.
No, don't.
Neither of us is perfect,
Clarence.
And if I promise to be
more accommodating,
I would like you to promise to
stop comparing me to Mr. Nash.
So, we are stuck
with each other.
It seems so.
Together, Clarence,
we shall once more
make this agency
successful.
And those that underestimate us
should do so at their own peril.
Oh, um, on that, our informant
from the brothel, Athena,
came by for her fee.
She likes to chat, that one.
She told me something
that may be of interest to you.
Mr. Sinclaire.
Ah, Miss Scarlet.
How serendipitous.
I was intending to pay you
a visit this very afternoon.
It appears you have
saved me a journey.
Here is the story I have
just penned
about you and your...
...lamentable fall from grace.
Would you care
to read it now?
Or perhaps you would rather
wait until it's published,
which I believe it will be,
in tomorrow morning's edition.
No, it will not,
Mr. Sinclaire.
In fact, you will return
immediately to the office
and retract the article.
And why on Earth
would I do that?
You've no doubt heard about
the robbery that took place
at the brothel in Mayfair,
the Temple of Elysium.
The madam has
asked her girls
to reunite
their regular clients
with their stolen
possessions.
And one of those girls
just happens to be
an associate of mine.
Athena?
She kindly allowed me
to return this to you.
Very nice inscription
of your name.
No mention of you being
chief correspondent, though.
Perhaps the next time
your wife
inscribes a gift, she'll
remember to include it.
Oh, and just to reassure you,
Inspector Wellington has
logged it as evidence.
So, should the need
ever arise to prove
your presence at the brothel,
it will not be hard to do so.
Good day, Mr. Sinclaire.
Thank you.
Miss Scarlet.
If you will excuse me,
I'm taking tea
with my good friend.
Theobald!
You wish to hire me?
Desperate times call
for desperate measures.
I'm sure I'll be fine
to visit such a dangerous,
violent criminal.
Alone.
Visit our website for videos,
newsletters, podcasts, and more.
And join us on social media.
To order this program,
visit ShopPBS.
"Masterpiece" is available
with PBS Passport
and on Amazon Prime Video.