That won't do
You need to warm up
What's going on, Ms. JUNG Soon-jung.
I couldn't reach you
That's not nice
Long time no see
The suspect has
killed five people
The modus operandi is
extremely violent
and she uses the
most unusual weapons
Cosmetic plaster,
(a) plastic bag, duct tape
And she even used scissors
- She uses them in the oddest ways.
- What is her motive?
Her 6-year-old daughter was
kidnapped by a lunatic
She was deserted after
being raped and killed
That must have ticked her off
But her killer was caught
What does she have
against those 5 people?
I don't know that yet
I'm sorry
You must find out so that
we can prevent the next murder
I'm sorry
Her ex-husband, who was that?
Yeah, Detective Oh.
Where is he now?
Sir, I thought you quit your job
Why are you here?
I'm here to look into every
lead I can track down
Why are you here?
I thought you knew everything
about that case
Shit. Why does it seem like
someone else's story?
Let me take a look
The victims do not surface on
any of the official records
I don't know who else is left
Nothing
Defendant's attorney,
KIM Woo-taek
Good luck!
Where are you going?
The chief wants me
to bring you in.
Are you going to arrest me?
You must be busy,
having your phone turned off
If you want to meet me,
you must look for me
I'm sure you can find me
if you put your mind to it
Hurry up. I'll be waiting
This was just practice
I heard you sold your Porsche.
It looked like a new car
It's not like I'm in my 20's
I don't want to be in the
public eye anymore
Why do you think
I still drive a BMW?
What happened to the person
that you told me to defend?
Indicted?
Not yet
- What do you mean not yet?
- It's not over yet.
What isn't over?
The crime
What crime?
Murder
Murder?
Murder...
You know, the thing is...
There's no such thing as crime
It's a matter of whether you can
be protected by the law or not
Murder, burglary, rape...
It happens every day since the
beginning of human history
When we call it a crime,
it becomes one
And it's just as easy
to turn it over
What we call law is
something very funny
Thank you for calling Kim
and Park Law Firm
Let me talk to
Attorney KIM Wu-taek
Can you give me
his cell number?
I'm sorry. I can't give out
his number to anyone
I'm Detective OH of
Kangnam Police Department
It's an emergency
Please, call back tomorrow
I told you it's
an emergency bitch
Huh?
Hello. This is Mr.
KIM's phone.
He's unable to come
to the phone now
Who is this answering?
It's me. Don't you
recognize my voice?
What are you doing there?
Me? I'm having a date with Mr. KIM
Where are you?
No, you won't dare do it
Guess where I'm at right now
Do you know why I like you (so)?
You never try to use
your body to seduce me
That's cool
You carrying a lot of money?
No, it's my phone...
Now for the real action!
Okay?
Okay...
Bitch!
You're totally crazy
You crazy bitch.
Who the hell are you?
What the...
Mister!
I want to go home
My mom's waiting
Crazy bitch
The suspect,
I mean your ex-wife's
number has appeared
You were right.
KIM Wu-taek is the next target.
I'm on my way
Both of their phones
have been turned off
No one's answering?
I just got through on his phone
- I'm sure he's there.
- Hello.
Ninth floor.
Hurry up!
Take the next one
- Why?
- I'm busy. Sorry.
Door closing
Let's go up together.
You said the car's here
I'll be there in a second.
One minute?
So many of them
Sir
What happened?
Did she get away?
I'm sorry.
I barely missed her
It's a total mess
Where are you now?
I'm in my car.
Don't you ask me where I'm going?
Where are you headed?
? Well, where shall I go?
Try to guess
Ask her if the victim
is still alive
What happened to the lawyer?
Is he still alive?
He's alive
Guess why I let him live
It's been too easy so far.
It's been quite a bore
So, I want to give him a chance
and make a decision later.
Whether to let him live or die.
So you'll have to find me soon
How can we be sure he's alive?
Can we talk to him?
Of course
Here, talk
Hello?
This is the police
Save me. I'm at...
Hello? Where are you?
Use your head. Or try praying
A stolen BMW.
License number 01 Jo 6743.
A murder suspect has kidnapped a victim
They fled
"Top Palace" around 21:14
The suspect is 33 years old
The woman's name is
JUNG Soon-jung
Appearance?
Her appearance...
- She's 160 centimeters in height.
- 160 centimeters in height.
. - Big eyes.
- Big eyes...
And she looks kind
and?
Do you think the Jung Soon-jung
you know is the real JUNG Soon-jung?
Don't you remember
me from somewhere?
Of course you don't remember
Do you remember who OH Min-ah is?
I'm giving you a chance to live.
You won't get a second chance
If you don't remember Min-ah,
you must die.
You have a good memory
That's how you became a lawyer
I know how dad feels now
When he said that life is lonely
I heard his sad voice as
he whispered in my sleep
Look at that. Look at that.
I can't get it off
I told you not to do it
You're tickling me
Are you ticklish? Here?
Where?
I'm going to punish you for
not listening to me
Start singing
I know how dad feels now
When he said that
life is lonely
What is it?
I know who OH Min-ah
is A year ago,
the HONG Gi-beom case
A six-year-old girl was
kidnapped and raped
She was killed and abandoned
She's OH Min-ah, isn't she?
Took you long enough, bastard
Do you know what the
dead leave behind?
Nothing, really
The dead are remembered
by those alive
Memories are all you have
But
how many people
do you think will
remember a six-year-old girl?
Not many
But you of all people should
have remembered her
You accepted bribes
from the criminal(s)
Who did terrible
things to my girl
And you let him off
by pleading that
he was mentally ill
You let him have it easy at
the mental institution
instead of prison
You should have remembered her name
when you eat and when you sleep
and everytime you take a breath!
How could you forget?
But a promise is a promise, right?
Congratulations.
You passed the first test.
But the second one awaits
How are you sir?
Do you have a hunch?
Actually,
today's is my little
girl's birthday
It's also the day she died
She died on her birthday...
Where is her grave?
Don't people usually
go to the cemetery?
- We cremated her.
- Wait. Wait. Wait.
A hostage? Where?
Okay, wait (for me)
A woman claiming to be Soon-jung
called up the TV station
telling them she was holding a hostage
at the sanitary landfill center
The landfill center
That's where our girl was found
That's it. Let's go
Move it guys
Move it, move it!
Princess Aurora was
her nickname
She used to love that cartoon
The day she disappeared,
Soon-jung called me
We were divorced.
But since I was her father.
And a policeman,
she thought I'd take care of it
But I was no help at all
I told her to make a
police report
I was too busy to help out
Stop it would you?
You'll get ill if you
keep recalling the past
Look at that crowd out there...
But why would the suspect,
I mean your ex-wife...
Why would she call
the TV station?
I heard his sad voice as he
whispered in my sleep.
- What is that?
- Get rid of the cameras.
- Shit, off with the cameras
- Shit, be quiet!
Hello
I'm Princess Aurora
Thank you for coming here
Today is my birthday.
But no one is coming to see me
This is a lonely place
It's quite lonely here
Where is she?
I think it's coming from
the crane operating room
That's why I'm having
a birthday party
That's why I invited the police.
My daddy is also a policeman.
I'm sure my daddy is here too.
Daddy!
Daddy, where are you?
- Is that your wife?
- Yes.
- I'm here, daddy.
- Shall we go and arrest her?
Shit
Teams 1 and 2, move to the
back of the crane
Team 3, position under the crane
to go after the hostage
He's not here...
The camera's good
The lighting's great.
Let's not make it a show.
Should use your discretion
when you're filming
Do you even know why
she's doing this? Shit!
Do you know what
she's going through?
It's me. Do you see me?
Let's talk
I'm going to go over there.
Talk to me
I don't want to talk to you
Oh Sung-ho, what gives you
the right to talk to me?
Because you're her father?
You don't have a rightto
claim to be her father
You're a cop,
but you couldn't even
protect your own daughter
Did you know that it's
Min-ah's birthday today?
But in this very spot,
my daughter was killed
and was found dead
(She was) naked!
A six-year-old girl
My little angel
She was killed by an animal
and left here to die
In the middle of
all this waste
My girl was left to die
in this place where
all the waste in Seoul lies
And where is that
son of a bitch now?
He's being treated in a hospital
What were you doing?
You didn't even know it was
Min-ah's birthday that day
I'll be going over there.
Let's talk face to face
No, dad! Don't come here, dad
Ms. JUNG Soon-jung,
can you hear me?
This is the Chief Officer,
BYUN Sang-ho.
Mister, my mom doesn't
want to talk to you now
She must be really mad (now)
My mom gets really scary
when she's mad
What is this? I can't talk to
her like this
Keep talking to her so that
we can launch the operation
Try to divert her attention
Make sure you move carefully
so she doesn't notice
In any case, Soon-jung,
please release the hostage
- No.
- Why not?
That lawyer is a bad person
Princess Aurora will punish him
What was your daughter's name?
Min-ah. OH Min-ah
You're a good girl, Min-ah.
Aren't you?
Min-ah's a good girl. Right?
Daddy, I'm scared
Daddy, I'm so scared
Don't cry, Min-ah. Don't cry
I'm sorry
I really wanted to see you
Make sure to get the suspect
completely immobilized
I'm so scared, daddy
It's okay. It's going to be okay
Daddy is sorry to
Min-ah and Mommy...
Don't cry Daddy.
If you cry, it will make me feel sad.
Mommy will be sad, too.
It's okay. It's okay.
Don't worry.
Be sure to act calm,
to prepare for the worst
Min-ah
I love you. I love you
Cleared to go
Daddy
Daddy, I don't want to go
Daddy! Daddy! Daddy,
I don't want to go
look this way
I'm Sorry
- Mom.
- Be careful. Don't run
Did you have fun?
What did you learn today,
Princess Aurora?
Look here.
Make it disappear. Poof!
Did you make me disappear?
Min-ah. This is your present.
Happy birthday.
Thank you
What are you doing?
Hurry up. Run!
Bye
You're always making me late.
Get on, quick.
- You must feel great
- Mom,
I feel sorry for Do-yeon
Why do you say that?
She's her step-mom
When her father's not around,
she always hit Do-yeon
That's why she prays
every night
That her step-mom would die
Min-ah, your birthday is coming up.
What shall we do?
- Let's see what this is.
- Wow, it's my favorite
You must be so happy.
Will you give me one?
I'm on my way Min-ah.
Wait for me.
Oh
Oh, shit.
Look where you going,
will you?
Oh, you little bitch
Why didn't you stay home
if your kid is waiting?
Why did you have to take your
car out and bump into mine?
This is a one-way street
You look like a real fox
Hit me if you want.
Take a punch.
- Oh, Shin-ok. I got into an accident.
- You're really funny, you know that?
- No, I'm almost there.
- Let's hurry up and settle.
I'm nearby
Man, she got into an accident.
I told you we shouldn't
hire someone with a kid!
I have a reservation
at the spa. Oh, no!
- You can just go.
- What about the shop?
You can just lock up.
No one's going to take the girl
Yes, I can just lock up, right?
Hey, what do you want to do?
Come on out
Shouldn't divorce when
you have a kid!
Hey, have a piece of gum
Mister, I'm short of
the taxi fare
I can't believe you're
trying to hitch a ride
Damn it!
Mommy...
Hey kid
What are you doing here?
Do you want a ride?
No, Min-ah!
Don't Min-ah! No, no, no!
- No, Min-ah. No! No, Min-ah!
- Relax. Just relax
estate policy will be effective
The middle class people
dreaming of their
own houses are
feeling the crunch
This was KIM Ok-kyeom
of YTN News
A regular housewife turned into
a killer after her only
child was killed
We have the latest on the case
dubbed the Princess Aurora murders
This is where the hearing
of a serial killer
JUNG Soon-jung is taking place
After 4 months of
intense deliberation,
she was sentenced
to a life sentence
However, the court has decided
that because she has been
tormented mentally,
she will undergo 6 months of medical
treatment under prison custody
The institution
where she will be
treated is a place where
the criminals with
severe mental...
You still don't want to talk?
Say something
I quit my job
If I'd quit long ago, we wouldn't
have had to go through this
I quit studying to
become a pastor too
Did you meet him?
I've put in my bible.
Try to read it.
It'll help you out
I'm going
Thanks
You're good at...
pretending to be a patient
Don't you remember me?
Huh?
HONG Gi-beum,
you didn't think you could
escape from me, did you?
I'm Min-ah's mother
Mr HONG, get up!
Nurse! Nurse! Nurse!