Brrr.
Ah, hello dear!
Oh it's a nasty night isn't it?
Here.
Here, you are, go
and get yourself a little nip.
Thank you Miss, thank you.
Same to you, really!
Mary Clark.
Yes Mary we know all about that.
But I still want to know why you
hit him with the bottle?
Like I said, he insulted me!
Come Nelly you've been insulted before.
That's hardly the point officer.
Anyway he wouldn't pay me what he owed me!
Ah that's better, now we're
getting nearer the facts.
He insulted me.
- Oh good evening sir!
- Is Inspector O'Neill in?
Yes sir, should I tell him you're...
Ooh, a Mr. Tuff.
That Nelly was the
Assistant Commissioner
from Scotland Yard, not that
it's any of your business!
It's his if he's come to put a rocket
under you fat backside!
Another of them Ripper jobs last night!
Or haven't you read about it?
You've had all the extra
men you've asked for!
The rest of London is
practically naked of policemen,
and still you're no nearer
to making an arrest!
I've made plenty of
arrests here, dozens of them.
Every lunatic and
sensation seeker in London
has given himself up as Jack the Ripper.
Stop using that stupid name!
I didn't Christen him sir,
but the one who did knew
what he was talking about.
Have you ever seen any of his victims?
No, a body's a body isn't it?
What's the point of
romanticizing these crimes?
Do you know that they've asked another
question in the house today?
- So I heard.
- Home secretary's
practically out of his mind!
"What's been done," they keep asking him!
He's run out of replies!
- He has my deepest sympathy.
- There's no cause
to be flippant O'Neill!
I am not being flippant sir,
and I'm going to tell you something else.
Do you know how long it
is since I've been home?
Four days.
Do you know how much sleep
I've had in the past 48 hours?
Six hours, all here on this chair!
I've got every man working in this station
every hour God created, most
of them are ready to drop
but they go on just like I
do because it's their job!
Despite the fact that
every ignorant layabout
from here to Westminster and back thinks
they're lazy and incompetent
and they ought to be dismissed!
You must pardon me if
I don't feel sympathy
for the home secretary just because
he's embarrassed in the house!
Yes.
Yes, of course.
Well, what's the next move?
Every line of investigation
will be followed
to its logical conclusion.
That's what you said last time.
And I shall very likely
way it next time too.
Come in!
What is it?
- Sorry sir,
but that's a man in the
bar at The Red Goose
asking questions about the Ripper.
The governor thinks the crowd
might start getting ideas.
The crowd at the Red Goose always
have ideas of some sort or another.
Well I suppose I better go down and see
what it's all about, all right Sergeant.
You'll excuse me sir.
But remember inspector, the police force
are in particularly bad
order at the moment.
We're all relying on you
to do something about it.
I shall continue to do my best sir.
I'm sure you will,
there's a good fellow!
No off you go.
This man might be the Ripper himself, eh?
He might sir, he might.
We know what you're about mister!
Don't give us that stuff!
- All I asked was
if anyone had actually seen the Ripper.
We heard what you said, we're not deaf.
We want to know why you
asked it, that's what.
- I'm interested, that's why.
- We know you're interested,
mister, how interested?
- Oh I'm sorry...
- It wouldn't be that
you're interested to see if anyone's seen
your face, are you?
Now you don't think that...
Come now gentlemen, I just arrived
from America this morning.
That's what you say.
Can you prove it?
Why should I have to prove it?
- Let's give it to him.
- Hold on a minute boys,
this gent ain't done no harm!
You keep out of this!
Well come on what you waiting for?
Well come on, they said
the Ripper was a foreigner!
Now Mr. Jack the Ripper,
what have you got to say for yourself?
We'll soon make him talk won't we boys?
All right my friend, let's see how
you like your belly slit open!
Stop that!
Let him go Charlie!
You too Tom!
Well he's been asking all sorts of
questions Mr. O'Neill,
questions about the Ripper!
Since when did you take
the law into your own hands?
With all due respect to you Mr. O'Neill,
but the police haven't
been much help have they?
That's still no excuse!
Now get out of here all of you, come on,
take him with you!
Come on, move!
Your listening to him
makes you a bad as he is!
Now get a move on.
Come on, hurry it up!
Nice piece of work mister,
the way you handled 'em I mean.
Nasty rough men they are.
There, that's right, better now sir?
Yes, thank you.
Give it back Snaky.
- Give what back?
- He's a friend of mine.
Oh on my life Mr. O'Neill I never knew
he was a mate of yours...
- Give it back!
Here you are governor.
I never knew you was a
mate of Mr. O'Neill's,
I swear I never.
I, I wouldn't have done it.
- Oh!
- Drink?
- Whisky.
- Two whiskies please.
- Well?
- Well what?
It never quits, I visit
America, you drag me out of
a fight in New York,
you've come to London,
and favor returned.
- All part of the
metropolitan police service?
- When did you arrive?
- This morning.
Well why didn't you come and see me?
I thought I'd have a look around at
the scene of the crime,
get a little local color.
You nearly became
part of the local color!
Bright red.
- Thanks.
Oh and uh, thanks for
your help, young lady.
Oh that's all right sir.
Hello Helen, how's your mother?
Oh she's much better
thank you, Mr. O'Neill.
Good
Nice kid.
You know I'm almost glad I came.
You'll excuse me asking,
but why did you come?
Your letter just said you were writing.
Believe it or not the
New York Police Department
have given me a vacation.
Oh you've chose a good
time to come to London.
So it seems.
You want any help?
What about your vacation?
Well, a change is as good as a rest.
Anyway in New York we don't have a Ripper.
Are you serious?
Yeah, do you mind if I tag along?
By all means, you can't do any harm.
Why that settles that.
Where do we start?
First I suggest you come home and have
some supper with me.
After supper you can go
around to the station,
start reading up what we know to date.
Get some of that local color
you were talking about.
Since when can a
policeman afford to travel
3000 miles on a vacation?
Something I didn't tell you Ned.
The department are paying.
- Oh.
- They're interested in
this Ripper business
in so far as it effects
the local populace, general reactions,
attitude towards the police,
mob violence, stuff like that.
Well see for yourself,
look up the street.
Before this Ripper business started you
could hardly move along here.
Stalls, barrel organs, people
spilling out of the pubs,
it was a happy place.
Not particularly moral but happy.
Take these men that attacked you in there.
One of 'em is a blacksmith,
another a shop assistant,
I know them well.
Apart from the one with the knife
they're just ordinary people.
Yeah, they didn't seem much
like ordinary people to me!
That's what the Ripper has done to them.
- Now you mean to tell me...
- And no jokes, please!
You'll learn, come on.
Leave me alone,
leave me alone!
The next time you come
in here and can't pay,
I'll have you fixed proper!
Ah none of that, none
of that, off with you.
Hey, you!
You're late.
I'm sorry sir, I lost my way.
First day, late.
I don't know what some of you
girls think this place is!
Go on, get inside!
Good evening Mr. O'Neill, and you too sir!
- Who was that?
- Just a drunkard sir,
we get 'em all the time.
- The girl, the girl!
- Oh, the girl,
oh oh, she's new, started today.
Just make sure nothing happens to her
like happened to the Turner girl.
Look Mr. O'Neill, I
should be responsible
for what happens to my
employees in their spare time?
It's no good pleading innocence with me
about the Turner girl.
She came to me the day before
she jumped into the river.
I told her to go back to
her family in the country,
but she thought she knew better.
I'm gonna keep an eye on this new girl,
so help me if anything happens to her
I'll come back here
and break every bottle,
glass mirror and chair
over your filthy head!
Come on Sam.
Thank you Miss.
Good night.
- Good evening Hodges.
Good evening Miss.
Do you know where my guardian is?
Well Dr. Chambers is
supposed to be operating
about now Miss, would you like
me to tell him you're here?
Oh don't bother, I don't
want to interrupt him.
I'll wait for him in the almoner's office.
Very well Miss, if I see
him I'll tell him you're here.
Hodges have you seen Dr. Tranter?
Good evening Dr. Urquhart!
I thought he was operating right now?
Well he's supposed to be but
we can't find him anywhere.
Perhaps he went on an outside case?
Must be a very important
one to take him away
when he should be in the theater.
What are you doing here?
- I came to meet him.
And I want to see Mrs. Bolton.
Maybe I'll see you later.
Well, if you find him, will you tell him
I'm waiting in the almoner's office?
Of course.
Hello my dear, you shouldn't
be about as late as this!
Nonsense Mrs. Bolton.
If I'm to take over your duties
I shall be a great deal later.
If you take over my duties.
I still don't think Dr.
Tranter will allow it.
I'm of age now, I can
make up my own mind.
Indeed you can my dear, indeed you can!
How about a nice cup of tea?
Thank you.
- May I go Master?
- Yes.
You'll be all right
walking home by yourself?
Oh of course, it's only a little way!
All right dear,
goodnight, see you tomorrow!
Goodnight sir!
It's you!
What do you want?
You hit me on the head
with a bottle tonight!
Well it was no more
than what you deserved!
Now get out of me way or
I'll call the governor,
he's in the bar room!
Mary Clark.
No that's not me name, I'm sorry.
Where can if find her?
Any sign of Dr. Tranter yet?
No sir.
Cover those instruments
in front of a patient.
Nothing to be frightened of Kitty.
Dr. Tranter is a very good surgeon.
You won't feel a thing.
Sorry I'm late.
Outside case.
All ready here?
- Yes sir.
Let me see that.
Knowles isn't it?
- Yes sir.
Right now let's see what
we can do for you, shall we?
Thank you nurse.
Now breathe deeply, deeply.
That's right, breathe deeply.
Now don't fight, relax, relax.
That's right, now breathe deeply.
Now count with me.
One.
- One.
- Two.
- Three.
- Four.
- Five.
- Five...
Six.
Scalpel.
Cut deeply John, that's the
secret of surgery these days.
Cut deeply.
♪ When underneath
♪ Isn't it a pity that the likes of her
Eh...
Hello, what have we got here then?
You'll catch cold
sleeping out here old boy.
Oh, or is it old girl?
Yes it is a girly.
Not old girl neither.
Hey daxxy, what you doing
sleeping in the?
Now why don't you go home eh?
Easing the load on her,
I'll give you a hand, eh!
Oh!
My god, the
Ripper, he's done her in!
The Ripper, he's done another of 'em!
Help, help, the Ripper!
He's done it again,
help, help please help!
He's done it again!
- Well shut the window!
- Help!
How many times do I have to
repeat I must have the windows
- Help!
- Shut when I'm operating?
The Ripper!
- Shut it this instant!
- He's done it again!
Help, help, men, help!
Ghost,
ain't she?
It was me what found her!
- Was it?
- Yes, just laying there!
I thought she was sleeping!
Run along now you!
Bloody marvelous, I was
right half an hour after.
It's crazy!
Yeah, why don't we have protection?
There's Mr. O'Neill now.
What'll you do about that O'Neill?
Keep back!
Always like this?
Always.
Do you know her?
- And very much sir.
The barmaid at the Red Goose.
- Poor kid.
- They're all poor kids.
What's the verdict Inspector,
natural causes?
Pity Jack didn't rip
off a copper, eh O'Neill?
You call the wagon?
Hey, you
can't come through here.
That's all right constable.
Evening Sir David.
O'Neill have you no control over
these kind of jobs?
Mutilation.
Admirable diagnosis.
And who might this be?
Uh, Mr. Lowry sir, he's from America.
That would account for it.
Have the body taken to the hospital,
I'll do a post mortem right away.
I've already sent for the wagon.
Heavens man, let's get this
thing out of the gutters!
Carry her, it's only a few hundred yards,
and be quick about it!
- That told 'em!
- It's about time somebody
started giving a few orders around here!
Go home, break
it up, break it up!
Who was the distinguished gentleman?
Sir David Rogers, Governor of the
Mercy Hospital for Women,
it's just around the corner.
Sociable is he?
He's all right, his bark
is worse than his bite.
He's performed the majority of
post mortems on these girls.
It's easy to understand
why he's short tempered.
I'll get Sir David to look at her
next time he comes in,
she'll be all right.
Oh incidentally, Anne
called for you earlier.
She's downstairs in the almoner's office.
Huh.
Oh Louis,
if you're taking those
things away to clean,
clean and hone this for me will you?
I'll pick it up tomorrow.
A boil lancing, rather nasty.
- With that?
- It was the only one
I had with me.
A little like cutting a fingernail with
a pair of garden shears.
These are the patient's records.
We keep them for a year,
then if they haven't been...
Ah Mrs. Bolton, there's a
body coming into the morgue.
I'm going to do a post mortem,
let them know will you?
Yes Sir David.
Well good evening, who are you?
Anne Ford, sir.
I'm doctor...
- Of course, you're
Tranter's ward, aren't you?
How silly of me.
Well what you doing messing
about with this stuff?
Well Mrs. Bolton's going
on holiday shortly sir,
and I'm taking over her duties as Almoner
while she's away.
- That's right,
I'd forgotten.
Admirable, admirable.
Evening Tranter, I've just
been talking to your ward.
Delighted she's going
to be the new almoner.
Pretty face is just what this place needs.
I was going to tell you as soon as
everything was arranged.
We'll talk about that later, come along.
Sir David's here sir, he
wants you in the morgue.
- What on earth for?
- They're bringing in a body.
- What sort of body?
- A dead one.
I know that, but why should Sir David
want to see it tonight?
It's a Ripper job sir.
Oh, I see.
Oh, Sir David's doing a post mortem.
So I understand.
Come along my dear.
- Here they come now sir!
Well open them up, I want to
get away before they arrive.
Well, do you think that very wise sir?
I mean, they get a little nasty
when something like this happens.
I'm perfectly capable of
looking after myself Urquhart.
I wish you goodnight.
Goodnight sir.
- Good evening Dr. Tranter.
- Oh good evening Inspector.
Who is it this time, another
little drab from the streets?
Even if it was, what
difference would it make?
Ah the police force
are recruiting colonials now Inspector?
Ah, this is Mr. Lowry sir.
Sam, Dr. Tranter.
Mr. Lowry's an American.
I fail to see the distinction.
We had a war a way back, remember?
A revolution Mr. Lowry, not a war.
Now if you'll excuse me please?
You're not going to try and
get through that crowd sir?
- Well of course I am.
- I wouldn't,
especially with the young lady.
Come along.
Get out of the way.
You heard what I said, get out of the way!
I'll teach you to respect betters!
Let's get him out of there!
Grab the girl Sam!
Thank you mister...
Lowry, Sam Lowry.
I'm indebted, Anne Ford.
Pleased to meet you.
I'm most grateful to you sir.
Come along my dear,
we'll go out by the back.
Sir David is doing the post mortem,
we'd like to be present,
is that all right?
Of course you can, will
you come this way please?
Hey Ned!
We're gonna fix you!
Don't worry, they'll
quiet them down, come on.
There he is!
He's the Ripper!
I'll smack you!
I'm sorry Anne, but you saw
what happened here tonight.
That sort of job's not for you.
Don't you understand,
this is the sort of work I want to do!
It's no place for a woman.
Mrs. Bolton's a woman.
Mrs. Bolton's different.
She's only different
because she's not your ward.
I'm of age now, I feel I have
certain responsibilities.
The emancipation of womanhood
that I've heard so much about.
So you've been bitten by this disease too.
Call it what you like,
but this is the work I want to do.
I'd sooner have done
it with your blessing.
I've always tried to act in
the best way possible for you.
But as you've said, you've of age
and a determined young woman.
Go ahead Anne, take the job,
do the work if it pleases you.
But not with my blessing.
Well so much for that.
Get rid of those Urquhart.
- Yes sir.
You interested in the findings
of the post mortem, gentlemen?
No, not unless they're different.
They're not, bruises on the neck,
deep seated multiple abdominal incisions,
and as before inflicted by someone who
knew what he was doing.
Excuse me Sir David, how do you mean,
knew what he was doing?
Hasn't the inspector told you young man?
These wounds are not the
savage slashings of a maniac,
they're careful, well
defined abdominal incisions
that show a good knowledge
of anatomy and surgery.
- You mean a doctor?
- Doctor, nurse, student,
any one of a number of professions.
What's the trouble Louis?
All right Louis I'll look after her now.
Under the circumstances,
there is no verdict I can give other than
murder by a person, or persons unknown.
However, before I adjourn this court,
I would like to say this.
And it is not my opinion alone.
Public confidence in the
police has never been
as low as it is today!
In their complete inability to apprehend
the perpetrator of these ghastly crimes,
they are showing themselves
to be incompetent,
inadequate, and inept!
Court is adjourned!
Incompetent, inadequate and inept.
Oh the papers are gonna love this!
- Shoeshine miser, shoeshine?
- No sonny, go away!
What do you think about
the coroners report?
- What about a statement sir?
- Gentlemen you heard
what the coroner said, didn't you?
Anne.
- Oh Mr. Lowry.
- Miss Ford.
How nice.
May I share your carriage?
Certainly, when I get one.
Maybe we'll stand a better
chance up the street a little.
All right then.
You've uh, been to the inquest?
Of course, why do you ask?
I thought, uh, oh it doesn't matter.
You thought what does a girl like me
doing being interested in such things.
You're as bad as my uncle.
It's a social problem as well
as a criminal one you know.
- Oh how come?
- It's a matter of
class difference.
If it happened to some
old duchess in Mayfair,
there'd be such an outcry something
would have to be done
about it, and done quickly.
Because these are poor people,
and not particularly respectable,
the general reaction from the...
The right side of the fence?
That's it.
General reaction is they're probably
not getting much more than they deserve.
Oh yes ma'am.
You're making fun of me.
Believe me I'm not.
And how are your
investigations going Mr. Lowry?
Has the well trained American mind
brought new light to bear on the subject?
Now you're making fun of me.
Seriously though the most
difficult thing I've found
is getting to know the
people and the place.
London isn't just one city, a hundred,
and each section is completely different.
What I need is a competent
guide to show me around.
One who knows both sides of the tracks,
and is accepted.
You think this may help?
Oh indeed I do.
Uh, you wouldn't know anyone, would you?
Well I suppose I could...
I'll take you around Mr.
Lowry, how would that be?
That would be just fine.
When can we start?
- When would you
like to start?
- This evening.
Come for me at my house at eight.
27 Brooklyn Square.
That'll be just fine.
Are you just going to sit,
or are you going somewhere?
No, I'm not going anywhere.
How 'bout you?
Oh, will you ask him to
take me to the hospital?
Certainly, oh and, thanks
for the ride Miss Ford.
Until this evening.
Mercy Hospital for Women,
Whitechapel please.
Mr. Lowry?
I would have been extremely disappointed
if you hadn't managed
to fabricate a reason
for wanting to see me again.
Tell him I'll be right down
will you?
- Tell who?
Oh Uncle.
I thought it was Perkins
announcing my escort.
Who's the lucky man this evening?
That American policeman, Mr. Lowry.
Remember we met him that
awful night at the hospital?
You're going out with him?
- Yes.
- I wish you wouldn't.
- Why on earth not?
- But he seems so,
so brash.
Uncle, just because he has an accent and
didn't go to Eaton?
- I still wish you wouldn't
go out with him.
I'm perfectly capable of taking care
of myself you know.
- Yes I know that but it's,
it's just the idea I don't like
the idea of you going
about with a policeman.
What is it?
There's a Mr. Lowry downstairs Miss.
Oh tell him
I'll be down in a moment.
Where is he taking you?
To where, to a concert.
Chamber music, very dull.
Goodnight darling.
Goodnight.
Waiter, waiter!
Table please!
Ah, Mr.!
Good of you sir, good evening!
Oh no, no, this will do just fine.
- Waiter!
- Yes sir?
Champagne!
Well, side of
the tracks you finally see.
Do you see something?
That lean girl.
The one on the end.
O'Neill warned.
Glad somebody does.
See we're not the only ones that
crossed the tracks this way.
Good evening My Lord!
Wait a minute, who's that?
That one on the end?
Send her up.
Say, you two!
Upstairs, 10 minutes.
All right who is it?
Sopwith, he's got a friend with him.
Show her what to do.
- Oh not her!
- Why not?
She's only been here a week!
Well it's time she
started earning her living!
You don't mind having a
drink with a couple of
special customers do you my dear?
- I don't think so.
- No of course not!
10 minutes.
- Come on luv.
Yeah come on, you're on!
♪ And I'll not ask for wine
It can't be long now old boy.
Just give them time to change,
into something appropriate.
- Got any gin luv?
- Why?
To paint my toenails
with, what do you think?
- Yes I have.
- Well?
I'm gonna keep it, you
don't know what it cost me.
I've a very good idea darling.
What have you got over there?
- Mentholated spirits.
- Oh you are a mean
lot of cows this evening!
Why don't you buy some of your own?
Watch out Maggie she's after you booze.
- Am I all right?
- Don't worry yourself dear,
you look lovely!
- Do you mind deary?
- There we are.
- My my, don't we look lovely.
Now if they make a joke laugh,
even if you don't understand it.
Keep smiling like you're
having a wonderful time.
I can't imagine why a
lord should want to meet me.
I don't know what to say!
- You don't have to say
anything deary, just watch Maggie,
she'll show you what to do.
Play your cards right and
you might end up a duchess!
Why don't you button your mouth?
Oh listen to the lady!
Don't take any notice of her.
Since when have you
become so high and mighty?
Since his lordship
gave up sluts like you!
Why you cow!
Very nice, very nice indeed!
Now take these with you, room four.
Have you been at the bottle again?
Oh go to hell!
Come on you lot, you're
all on in five minutes!
Go away, we know!
Buddy, we brought some extra ammunition!
Maggie, you're looking enchanting!
I'm Margaret and this
is Hazel, she's new!
Oh, fascinating,
now come over here my dear!
Come on luv he's not gonna bite you!
I wouldn't bank on that my dear!
Go on dear, do like the gentlemen!
Sit down!
A glass of champagne?
No thank you sir, I don't drink!
- She is new!
- Of course she drinks!
If the young lady doesn't want to drink
she doesn't have to!
I like a girl that, knows her own mind!
Thank you sir.
You don't have to call me sir my dear.
Tom's the name.
- But I don't know you.
Oh she's a card this one, always joking!
Call him Tom!
All right, Tom.
Are you quite sure you
won't have one my dear?
All right then, perhaps just this once.
Oh are you sure my dear?
I don't want you to do anything
that you don't want to do.
Oh I'd like too.
We'll take ours in the other room!
Have fun children!
Where have they gone?
They thought we'd like to be alone.
What for I thought
we were having a party?
And we are, a private,
intimate party, just you and I!
Oh well, I don't even...
Now come on, finish up
your bubbly.
Won't do any harm, you like it don't you?
Drink it up lass, right to the bottom,
come on now, that's it.
There it wasn't so bad was it?
Yeah yeah, you like me don't you?
You seem very kind.
Seeings how you like me...
What about giving me a
little kiss?
I shall do nothing!
Just one little mmm...
Oh champagne, he poured
champagne all over!
Oh, look at me!
Come come darling this way!
I think I better be going!
- Come here!
- Oh I must go!
Not what about the kiss
you're gonna give me!
Leave me alone!
Let me go!
I like a girl with a little spirit!
Look what you've done!
You've ruined my dress!
- Take it off then!
Ah!
You little...
What are you doing here?
That man, he tore my dress!
Well, don't be so stupid girl!
What do you think you went up there for?
Hey come back here you little fool!
Well don't just stand there, go after her!
We don't want no trouble with the police!
Miss, come back!
That man,
is he after you?
Down here!
Miss, come back!
Thank you, thank you so much!
Are you Mary Clark?
Help!
Do you like
policeman for one evening?
Fine.
The Ripper!
The Ripper's done it again!
Lowry!
I thought you'd have an explanation for
bringing my ward to an
establishment like this?
- I brought him.
- I find that hard to believe,
however luckily I happened to see you!
Come along my dear, I'll take you home.
- You'd better go.
- Well if you say so.
I assume you're off to join the morbid
and the sensation seekers
at the scene of the crime.
I've had a most pleasant evening,
thank you very much, goodnight.
- Goodnight.
- Sir.
I don't approve of Mr. Lowry any more
than I approve of places like this.
- Well why are you here?
- Since you must know
I didn't believe your story of the concert
and I followed you, now, shall we go home?
Has anyone sent for a doctor?
- Undertaker more like it!
- A wagon's been sent for.
- Inspector O'Neill?
- Yeah he's been
sent for too sir.
Why ain't O'Neill here,
then it might never have happened!
He's never here when he's wanted!
- Ain't safe no more!
- Come on why don't you
go home, huh?
- Yeah get rid of them all!
- It's him!
- He's the Ripper!
- Hold on to him!
- Look at that knife!
That's what he did her with!
You're the Ripper aren't ya!
He's dumb, can't talk!
You're right!
Let's get him!
Come on!
Grab him!
Now, let's see how you like it!
Now...
Oh, me arm!
You broke it!
- It'll be your head
next time, now get out of here before
I forget that I'm a policeman!
Move, go on, home all of you!
Come on men!
I went to see the home
secretary personally!
He was delighted, delighted!
There'll be a promotion
in this for you O'Neill!
I'm not making any promises though,
but there's every chance!
What do you think of that eh?
- Oh, very gratifying sir.
- I thought you'd feel
that way, now, I think we'll
keep the fiend here tonight.
Have to organize well
of course the crowd will
probably try to rob us of our prey.
And then tomorrow morning
we'll move him, and...
Can't move him sir.
Can't?
Why not?
- He hasn't been charged
with anything.
You're joking of course.
I put Benz into protective
custody sir, nothing more.
Well go down to his cell
and charge him, right away!
- With what?
- Murder, multiple murder!
He is Jack the Ripper!
- Is he?
What do you mean is he, of course he is,
you locked him up didn't you?
Protective custody I said sir.
I'm sorry sir these
reporters are
breaking the door down!
- Get rid of them Sergeant!
- Well they want
a statement sir!
- Do as I say, this instant!
Come on, get out!
What's going to happen to him?
- Has he been charged?
- What does Inspector O'Neill
think his charges are?
Can O'Neill make a statement?
Gentlemen please, you've all
heard the official statement,
I'm afraid I can't add to it!
Louis Benz an employee at the
Mercy Hospital for Women
has been taken into custody.
Now what sort of a statement is that?
- That's right!
- The official sort,
and that's all you're gonna get!
- Where's O'Neill?
- Aren't you
Sir David Roberts?
- Benz works at your hospital,
what do you think about this affair?
- Do you think Benz did it?
- Is O'Neill in here?
Yes sir but
you can't go in there!
Ah!
O'Neill what's this I hear about
Louis Benz being locked up?
- That's right sir.
- What do you
mean that's right?
Release him immediately!
- For what may I ask?
- Who are you?
This is Assistant Commissioner Hodges
of Scotland Yard, Sir David.
Ah good, I bet you
can talk some sense into
this mutton-headed policeman.
Tell him to release Benz at once!
I shall do no such thing!
Who do you think you are,
barging in here like this,
giving me instructions?
- Never mind who I am,
do as I tell you!
You realize of course that this Benz
is Jack the Ripper!
Balderdash!
Whose idea is that, yours O'Neill?
- Eh, no sir.
- Yours then I suppose?
Really Mr. Assistant Commissioner I think
the Metropolitan Police Force is staffed
by a bunch of half-wits!
And none so half-witted
as those at the top!
What put that damn fool
idea into your head anyway?
Benz was carrying a bag
full of surgical instruments!
Oh was he now, well of
course that makes a difference.
What do you suppose these are, toothpicks?
Go on arrest me!
While you're at it try locking
up the rest of my staff,
Tranter, Urquhart all of us,
there's not one Jack the Ripper,
there's half a dozen of us!
We take it in turns!
Louis Benz is in protective custody.
He hasn't yet been charged.
I, we thought it was
the only safe place for him.
Then why didn't you say
so in the first place?
I'm still not saying
he isn't the Ripper!
Then you're still being asinine!
And I'm going to see the home
secretary and tell him so!
Goodnight sir!
Shall I go downstairs
now sir and charge Benz?
Nnn, no, no O'Neill,
we'll leave it for a while.
Well if you'll pardon
me sir, I have work to do.
What's that?
I'm going to try and
find Jack the Ripper.
Come on Sam.
My life Mr. O'Neill, how was I to know
the poor little thing was going to
get herself carved up by the Ripper?
You can't blame me for that, can you?
What was it that sent her running out
into the night on her own?
I can't blame you for
that either I suppose?
- Well I...
- Well?
I've got to make a living Mr. O'Neill!
The legitimate side of the
business don't pay nothing!
People come in here, they buy half a beer
and they sit all the evening!
I've got to make a living!
The suit, now mind the suit Mr. O'Neill!
Listen you, it so happens that I've got
something else that's
taking up all of my time,
but as soon as I clear
it up you better start
looking for a new way of making a living,
because I'm gonna close
this place up so tight
it won't see daylight for 20 years!
Flaming busy body,
I hope the Ripper carves him up!
I came long here sir,
and just there was where
I saw the courting couple,
and then I went on to...
Courting couple in this door?
Yes that's right sir,
and then I went on...
That's where you discovered the body.
Oh no sir, down here...
Hey wait a minute,
you're right Mr. O'Neill!
You're dead right!
So he wasn't caught in after all!
The Ripper Harry, you saw the Ripper!
Oh god!
Harry what did this man look like?
Well I don't know sir,
I didn't really look at him actually.
Hey wait a minute, if he was the Ripper,
I heard him talk!
- Talk?
- What was he saying?
Well I just passed by still
looking for the young lady,
and him say, is your name,
is your name something or other.
Well what Harry, is your name what?
Mary, Mary it was, Mary something.
- Think man think!
- I am thinking sir.
Mary, Mary, Mary Clark!
That was it, is your name Mary Clark!
Mary Clark.
Ring any bells then?
Not right off.
All right Harry you can go now,
not a word of this to
anyone, do you understand?
Yes sir, if you say so sir!
- I say so!
- That's so you
don't forget huh?
Oh thanks Mr. Lowry,
goodnight, goodnight sir!
Goodnight.
Mary Clark, I wonder who she is?
Wherever she is the
Ripper's looking for her
but he hasn't found her yet.
That doesn't explain why
these other young girls
have been butchered.
Why, they could identify
him couldn't they?
Yeah, let's hope for her
sake we find her first.
Kitty you're not well enough yet.
Anne you speak to her.
Won't do any good.
Just a few more days,
until you're really strong.
No thank you it's all the same.
I want to go home.
All right Kitty, but I want
you to promise me something.
- What?
- That you'll let me
come and visit you.
Morning.
- Morning sir.
- Urquhart you'll have
to get someone else to
assist in the theater.
Those idiots have still
got Benz locked up.
- Yes.
- Hello dear, you one of mine?
Oh, Dr. Tranter's case sir.
She's asking to be discharged.
I told her I do not
consider her fit enough.
Hmm, what does Dr. Tranter say?
He says we can't hold
her against her will.
Afraid he's right.
If she insists on leaving
we can't stop her.
But I must say I think you're
being very foolish young lady.
The doctor here knows what's best for you.
I still want to go home sir.
All right Urquhart, sign the discharge.
- Yes sir.
- Don't forget about
the theater assistant will you?
No sir.
I think this is him.
Your name's Clark, isn't it?
- Yeah.
- I'm Inspector O'Neill
Good luck!
Lord help me governor, I'm!
This fellow said to me
did I want to make me self
a couple of quid and I said
no, not if it ain't honest!
Anyway I wasn't there!
Records show that you have
a daughter Mary, Mary Clark.
Even if I had'a been there I wouldn't...
What Mary?
What's my
poor little baby daughter
got to do with all this?
If you have a daughter Mary...
Yeah and a sweeter,
kinder girl never lived!
She depends on my you know, I'm her only
means of support, if you locks
me up she'll starve to death!
We're not gonna lock you up Clark,
we just want to find
out about your daughter.
- Honest?
- That's all.
It's not about the
Houston Road job then,
the one where I wasn't there?
No we just want to find your daughter.
Ooh, I can't help you I'm afraid.
What's that supposed to mean?
Why I aint seen the
little snot for 10 years!
- You just said...
- Ah that's flannel guv,
just flannel!
- You have no idea
where she is?
- And I forgot I had
a daughter till that other
fellow come looking for her!
- What other fellow?
- I don't know who he was,
about four months ago,
posh feller he was too!
What'd he look like?
I didn't see him properly
because it was dark,
but he was a posh fella, here,
he was carrying a little black bag.
Well, so much for that fool idea
of Louis Benz being the Ripper.
I've already released him.
About time too.
Take that Urquhart.
- Right sir.
The whole idea was a
lot of nonsense anyway.
- Pawn ticket.
- No name.
Here, here we are.
Grace Merchant.
- Hello Kitty.
- Hello Miss.
- May I come in?
- If you want to.
Well of course I want to.
You said I could come and visit you.
What'd you come out for?
To see how you were.
Oh I'm all right thank you.
Well then, do you need anything?
No thank you.
Oh, lovely flowers.
Is this your young man?
- Leave it alone.
- I'm sorry, I,
I didn't mean to upset you.
I shouldn't have behaved like that
it was very rude of me, I'm sorry.
That's all right.
It was my young man.
We were gonna be married.
He found out about, well
my life before I met him.
The men I've been with.
Don't think you'd understand
like for a girl like me.
I'm not much good, never was.
Then I met him.
He was very kind.
He said he loved me.
I wanted to tell him all about myself,
and what I was.
But somehow each time I
was going to I put it off.
And then one day, he found out,
and the next day they found
his body in the river.
Kitty!
Oh how dreadful!
I-I'm so sorry!
- I'll be all right
in a moment.
I'm sorry, can I get you
something, a cup of tea...
You stay there, I'll get it.
Kitty, when was the last time
you had something to eat?
Yesterday evening,
but I'll be all right.
I'm going out later to see
a woman I know about a job.
But you won't get paid
for at least a week,
in the meantime you've got to eat.
Look I'll put you down
on the parish register.
That way you can get
food from the hospital.
I don't want any charity.
Now don't be so silly.
You've been ill, if you don't eat
you'll find yourself back in the hospital.
It's cheaper for us to keep you out.
Oh have you got a birth certificate?
Yes, what you want it for?
Well I have to have it
for the parish register.
Oh.
Fine.
I'll call around later this evening,
bring you a hamper.
Oh I don't want you to
go to any trouble Miss.
Oh it's no trouble.
Good.
Thank you Miss, you're very kind.
See you later this evening.
Oh!
I thought it was you.
I've been following you, you
shouldn't have tried to hide!
Now then, what's going on here?
How did you two get in?
- The gate was open.
- Oh was it now?
We'll have to see about that.
And I'll ask you both to leave!
- Of course.
- But...
We'll leave at once.
Anne!
What's the matter?
I, I saw you come from
Kitty Knowles' place
and I tried to catch up with you,
but you were going so fast.
I, I was frightened.
Frightened?
What on earth...
Oh no, wait a minute,
you didn't think that I,
that I... !
Oh Anne!
Oh come on, I'll walk back to the
hospital with you!
Give me the clips.
You put that one there.
Not there idiot, there, and hurry!
It's no good Benz, leave her alone.
Let her die in peace.
Just looking in to see
if everything's all right.
What's the matter Louis?
What's that, let me have a look!
It's no good sir, she's going to die.
Nonsense, no one dies while
their heart's still beating!
We must hurry, get that clip out,
it's tangling the blood vessel!
Louis, I want swabs, clips,
sterilizing pan, quickly!
Hello dear.
What's the matter?
I feel a bit tired, I'm going home.
Are you ready?
Oh, I have some work to do first.
Anyway Mr. Lowry's calling for me later.
Kitty Knowles, isn't that
the girl I operated on?
- Yes.
- Mary Clark.
It's on her birth certificate.
Well if you're not
coming home I'll get along.
Well, she'll be all right, eh Tranter?
Yes sir I think she will.
Of course she will.
- Sir David?
- What is it?
I, I'd like you to
accept my resignation.
Uncle!
Resignation?
What are you talking about?
Well you saw what happened here.
If you hadn't arrived when you did,
that girl would have died.
Even Louis Benz knew when
I was making a mistake.
Good heavens man, that's
no reason to resign!
I think it is.
I feel I've come to the
end of my work here.
Nonsense!
You've been over working, that's all.
You need a rest.
Look, why not take a couple of weeks off?
Then if you still want to resign,
we can talk about it again.
- Very well sir.
- I'll walk to the
gates with you.
And Tranter, you'll never come
to the end of your work
here, remember that.
Thank you sir, goodnight.
- Goodnight.
- Excuse me.
But Uncle, because of one small error?
I've told you why.
I feel I've accomplished everything
that I set out to do
in this part of London.
There's no more for me.
Sir David's suggestion was right.
Take two weeks rest.
Goodnight my dear.
And don't be too late home.
I'll be all right.
Hello Hodges.
Miss Anne still here?
She had to go out sir,
took a hamper of food
to that Kitty Knowles.
She said would you wait sir.
Thanks.
Kitty?
Mary Clark.
Here!
Why you're...
- No matter who I am.
And you knew my son rather well.
Your son?
Oh you're Paul's father!
I was.
- What do you want?
- I want my son.
But he'd dead isn't he?
You killed him.
- I killed him?
- As surely as if
you'd plant a knife into his heart.
He was gonna be a surgeon you know,
a brilliant surgeon, a genius.
But you turned his mind,
even drove my boy to suicide!
No I loved him!
How dare you speak of love!
You defile the word!
Like some foul, malignant
virus you and your kind
contaminate the gutter you inhabit!
The very air you breathe!
No one is safe!
I've been sweeping the
streets looking for you
Mary Clark, scouring the pavements,
so young men may be safe!
Young men like, like, Paul.
Paul, Paul!
You're ill!
Yes I know.
A virus, I must kill the virus,
I must kill it before it's too late!
Destroy it, now Mary!
Anne!
Did you see, did you see who it was?
No!
Mary!
All right, all right, all right
all right, what's all this noise about?
Come on you idiot open up!
Of course!
Why what's happened?
You're covered in blood!
Are you all right?
O'Neill will be here in a minute.
You know what to do.
Yes I think so.
Good evening Sir David.
Yeah, what do you want?
- Working late aren't you?
- Obviously.
What are you doing here?
Oh I have reason to believe the Ripper
is somewhere in this hospital.
Nonsense.
The porter's just been attacked.
Why should that lead you to believe
the Ripper's in the building?
I was under the impression he confined
his attacks to women.
Well there has been another killing,
only this time he was
forced to leave in a hurry.
He left this behind.
Well, just like my bag, eh Mr. Lowry?
Now if you don't mind I have work to do!
Good evening Sir David.
Look here Inspector, this is a mortuary,
not a public art gallery!
I'm sorry sir but I came
to see you about the porter.
Mr. Lowry's already informed me!
The porter was murdered by some ruffian.
I didn't say he'd
been murdered Sir David.
I said he'd been attacked.
Well you uh, you implied it then.
He's been taken to
the operating theater.
Dr. Urquhart thinks he can be saved,
he'd like you to operate.
Well that's, that's quite impossible!
Well can't you see I'm busy,
I've got to finish this post mortem!
I think you'd better
come to the theater sir.
Are you telling me what to do Inspector?
Yes sir I am.
It is impertinence, gross impertinence!
Possibly, but we want
to save this man's life.
You're a doctor, surely
that's your wish too.
Very well, I'll see what I can do.
Thank you sir.
Sir David please!
This hospital's becoming
like Piccadilly Circus!
If I see this man I must see him alone.
Is that clear?
- Perfectly clear Sir David.
How is he Dr. Urquhart?
He's regaining consciousness slowly.
It's all right Hodges,
Sir David's here to look after you now.
, ground floor!
Around the front!
Why we didn't take him to the morgue
in the first place beats me!
Poor Alfred, even I
could see he was dead.
Turn it off!
But you don't know, not for sure.
Oh we know, we can't prove it.
And we'll never be able to prove it.
The most infamous
murderer since Bluebeard,
and the files will always
be marked, unsolved.
Well goodnight.
Goodnight you two.