IT WAS THE SUMMER
EVERYONE THOUGHT THE RUSSIANS
WERE GOING TO INVADE
LONG ISLAND ANY MINUTE,
AND PRESIDENT KENNEDY
WAS GOING TO BERLIN
TO HEAD THEM OFF.
SPUTNIK HAD BEEN
AROUND THE WORLD 10 TIMES,
AND MR. ROSSI,
OUR NEIGHBOR,
SWORE HE SAW IT FLY
RIGHT OVER HIS BACKYARD.
BUT I HAD OTHER THINGS
ON MY MIND THAT SUMMER,
AND SO DID EVERYONE ELSE
ON MY BLOCK.
MINE IS DEFINITELY BIG.
IS NOT!
IS SO. 'CAUSE
I WAS BORN FIRST.
BULL! MINE IS
10 TIMES BIGGER.
DROP DEAD!
O.K., THEN PROVE IT.
THE MEYER TWINS WERE ALWAYS
FIGHTING ABOUT SOMETHING.
THEY'D DO ALMOST ANYTHING
TO GET KATHRYN'S AND
BARBARA'S ATTENTION.
WHAT'D I TELL YOU?
GROSS!
YOU'RE
STRETCHING IT!
THAT'S A CHEAT.
I AM NOT!
LOOK. THEY'RE EVEN.
EXACTLY EVEN, MICKEY.
WHAT ARE YOU
STARING AT...TOAD?
NOTHING.
STILL CAN'T CATCH
A FIREFLY?
HEY! GIVE IT BACK!
THEY WERE ALWAYS
TEASING ME.
MICKEY WAS THE WORST.
ONCE, BEHIND
THE ROSSI HOUSE,
HE SAID HE WANTED
TO KISS ME...
THEN HE SPIT IN MY EAR.
BOOGER BALLS!
YEAH. HE REALLY
IS A CREEP.
TOO BAD HE'S SUCH
A GREAT KISSER.
HE KISSED YOU? WHEN?
LAST NIGHT,
DURING
FATHER KNOWS BEST.
AND...MAX KISSED
BARBARA.
COME ON, KATHRYN!
HURRY UP.
WELL, DID HE LEAN
WAY BACK
AND MAKE A SOUND
LIKE THIS?
[KISSING SOUND]
THEN IT WASN'T
A LOVE KISS.
THAT'S A FACT, KATHRYN.
DON'T EMBARRASS
YOURSELF, ALICE.
BESIDES,
WHAT WOULD YOU KNOW
ABOUT L-O-V-E?
HEY, YOU GUYS! WAIT!
WAIT FOR ME!
KATHRYN WAS RIGHT.
I GUESS I DIDN'T KNOW
MUCH ABOUT IT.
BUT I READ
EVERYTHING I COULD,
LIKEMODERN ROMANCE,
ENCYCLOPEDIAS,
EVEN STUFF THAT
TOOK A WHOLE MONTH
TO GET IN THE MAIL.
BUT STILL, I FELT LIKE
IT WAS SOME BIG SECRET
EVERYONE WAS
IN ON BUT ME--
EXCEPT SOMETIMES,
LATE AT NIGHT,
WHEN SHERYL CAME HOME.
RIGHT AFTER SHE MOVED IN
LAST WINTER,
THE BOYS STARTED
COMING AROUND.
THEY WANTED HER
TO GO STEADY
AND BE THEIR GIRL,
BUT SHE WASN'T INTERESTED.
OH, WHAT A NIGHT!
MR. O'CONNER.
HI, DAD.
WHO'S, UH,
WHO'S THIS?
IS THIS BRAD?
JIMMY.
YEAH! JIMMY.
SHE TALKS ABOUT YOU
ALL THE TIME.
GOOD NIGHT.
HOPE YOU HAD FUN.
IF I COULD JUST BE HER
FOR ONE NIGHT,
EVEN FOR JUST ONE MINUTE.
I FOUND OUT EVERYTHING
ABOUT HER--
THAT SHE PLAYED
THE SAME SONG EVERY NIGHT--
RULER OF MY HEART.
♪ OOH
♪ MY HEART CRIES OUT
♪ PAIN INSIDE
♪ WHERE CAN YOU BE?
I KNEW THAT EVERY FRIDAY
AFTER SCHOOL,
SHE BOUGHT A BRAND-NEW SCARF
AT WOOLWORTH'S.
♪ WHERE'S YOUR LOVE?
♪ THE BOAT GETS ROUGH ♪
THAT SHE PUT HER FAVORITE
PERFUME ON EVERY NIGHT
BEFORE SHE WENT TO SLEEP.
IT WAS AMBUSH.
THAT SHE THOUGHT
BRENDA LEE WAS ALL RIGHT
BECAUSE SHE TURNED DOWN
A DATE WITH RICKY NELSON,
THAT J.F.K. WAS THE COOLEST
CATHOLIC SHE KNEW...
OUTSIDE OF HER DAD,
AND THAT A NUN
AT MOUNT SAINT MARY'S
SLAPPED HER IN THE FACE
WITH ALL HER MIGHT
AND SHE DIDN'T EVEN CRY.
THAT SHE NEVER SLEPT
IN ANYTHING AT ALL,
EVEN IN THE MIDDLE
OF WINTER.
SHE DIDN'T KNOW ME
OR MY NAME,
BUT I WANTED
TO LAUGH HER LAUGH
AND DREAM HER DREAMS.
YOUR ATTENTION, PLEASE.
THE 8:03 FROM MANHATTAN
WILL BE ARRIVING
IN FIVE MINUTES.
I'VE TRIED
JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING.
I'M ABOUT TO GIVE UP!
I'M TELLING YOU,
CAROL. THE ANSWER
IS HEADSTANDS.
WHAT?
HEADSTANDS.
BIBS SWEARS IT.
SHE'S EIGHT WEEKS.
BIBS GINSBURG?
THE RABBIT DIED?
SHE'S EIGHT WEEKS.
I HAVE TO STAND
ON MY HEAD?
DO YOU WANT TO
HAVE ANOTHER BABY?
[TIRES SCREECHING]
♪ I WANNA KNOW-OH-OH
♪ IF YOU'LL BE MY GIRL
♪ HEY
♪ HEY, BABY
SOMEBODY OUGHT TO PUT
A NET ON THAT ONE.
THEY SHOULD TAKE
AWAY HER LICENSE
BUT--BUT SHE ALWAYS
DRIVES LIKE THAT.
SHE DROVE
TO CARVEL'S AND BACK
IN FOUR MINUTES
JUST FOR
AN EGG CREAM.
HOW WOULD YOU KNOW THAT?
AMY LUCHESI'S SISTER
SAID THAT SHE RAN
THE FASTEST
AT MOUNT
SAINT MARY'S.
SHE DIDN'T
EVEN SWEAT.
OH, ALICE.
ROLL UP YOUR WINDOW.
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
♪ I WANNA KNOW-OH-OH
♪ IF YOU'LL BE MY GIRL ♪
HI, DAD.
HI, HONEY.
THANKS FOR
PICKING ME UP.
I BARELY MADE IT HERE.
SO WHAT ELSE
IS NEW?
HOW WAS YOUR DAY?
HEY, FUNNY FACE.
HOW'S MY GIRL?
HMM?
HI, DAD.
LOOK WHAT I GOT
YOUR MOM.
THEY'RE BEAUTIFUL.
HI, HONEY!
YOU'LL LOVE
THE BEACH.
I DO MY DAVID NIVEN.
CAROL, YOU KNOW HOW
I GET LIKE DAVID NIVEN?
I LOOK HIM IN THE EYE
AND SAY THE WORD...
BALLPLAYERS.
THE OLD MAN'S
DUMBFOUNDED.
HE WAS?
YEAH. SO I SAY,
WHAT METROPOLITAN LIFE
NEEDS ISN'T
A BETTER POLICY.
METROPOLITAN NEEDS
A BETTER SPOKESMAN--
SOMEBODY EVERYONE
CAN IDENTIFY WITH.
THAT'S GREAT.
IT MEANS I MIGHT PAL
AROUND WITH ROGER
MARIS THIS FALL.
DID YOU HEAR
BIBS GINSBURG'S
PREGNANT?
HANK WAS
ON THE TRAIN.
NO, I DIDN'T.
HOW MANY
IS THAT FOR THEM?
A LOT.
DAD?
WHERE THEY
GOING TO PUT THEM?
AT LEAST
WE DON'T HAVE TO
WORRY ABOUT IT.
AND TO SAY IT
IN FRONT OF ALICE!
YOU KNOW IT UPSETS HER.
ALICE DOESN'T
KNOW WHAT WE'RE
TALKING ABOUT.
OF COURSE SHE DOES!
IT MAKES HER
UNCOMFORTABLE.
YOU'RE SO OBLIVIOUS
SOMETIMES!
I'M OBLIVIOUS?
LARRY,
THAT'S NOT FAIR!
WELL, IT'S TRUE,
ISN'T IT?
[DOOR SLAMS]
[MICKEY]
UNBELIEVABLE!
THE WRONG LANE!
I DIDN'T KNOW THERE
WAS ANYTHING WORSE
THAN A GUTTER BALL.
I SWEAR, MISTER.
I NEVER SAW HER
BEFORE IN MY LIFE!
HOW SHOULD WE
SCORE THAT?
MINUS ZERO!
WHAT A DUFUS!
[WHISTLING]
YOU GOT MY HEART
A-BEATING WILDLY.
YOU AND ME,
SATURDAY NIGHT.
THERE'LL BE MAGIC
IN THE AIR!
COME ON, SWEETHEART.
YOUR ROMEO'S ARRIVED.
GIVE ME A LITTLE
SMILE--SOMETHING!
GIVE ME
AN INDICATION.
COME ON.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
SAINT MARY'S GIRLS
DON'T DRINK BEER?
WE'RE AFRAID YOU
WOULDN'T KNOW WHICH END
OF THE BOTTLE TO SUCK.
IF I WANTED
IT BUSTED,
I'D DO IT MYSELF.
WHO ARE YOU?
I WORK HERE.
I'M RICK.
WANT TO LET GO
OF MY HAND?
THINK YOU CAN
CONTROL YOURSELF?
I'LL STOP SHAKING
WHEN YOU DO.
MY SHOE SIZE IS 7.
I WANT THE GREEN LACES.
THEY'RE GONE.
THEY'RE NOT GONE!
JEFF HOLDS THEM
FOR ME EVERY SATURDAY.
JEFF'S GONE.
YOU WANT A TIGHT FIT
OR LOOSE FIT?
WHAT DO YOU THINK,
GENIUS?
I THINK YOU'RE
A CATHOLIC GIRL.
JUST GIVE ME
MY SHOES, ALL RIGHT?
DO YOU BELIEVE IN
LOVE AT FIRST SIGHT?
NO.
ME NEITHER.
YES!
BEAT THAT ONE,
MICKEY!
SEE, I ALWAYS
SCORE HIGHER.
YOU DO NOT.
[KATHRYN]
SHE STUFFS.
SHE DEFINITELY STUFFS.
[BARBARA]
LOOK. THEY'RE
NOT EVEN MOVING.
YEAH, THEY'RE
DEFINITELY CHEATERS.
NO. THEY'RE REAL.
OH, RIGHT!
LIKE YOU
MIGHT KNOW.
WE'RE FRIENDS.
I SEE HER
ALL THE TIME.
YOU'RE A LIAR!
SHE WOULDN'T BE
CAUGHT DEAD WITH YOU.
SHE WOULD SO.
OH, YEAH?
THEN PROVE IT.
GET HER
TO SIP THIS.
COME ON.
SHE'S YOUR
BOSOM BUDDY.
GO AHEAD.
YEAH, ALICE.
I'M NOT
ASKING HER!
ARE YOU SCARED?
JUST GO!
GO!GO!
KEEP GOING!
GO ON!
[RICK]
SHERYL O'CONNER.
SHERYL O'CONNER, PLEASE
COME TO THE CASHIER.
SHERYL O'CONNER.
I THOUGHT THAT IF EITHER
OF MY PARENTS DIED,
I'D DIE, TOO.
THAT IF
THEY STOPPED BREATHING,
THEY'D DRAW ME
BACK INSIDE.
LIKE THEY ONCE TOLD ME,
THEY KISSED EACH OTHER
AND BREATHED ME INTO LIFE.
THAT SHERYL STILL LIVED,
THAT SHE PUT ON HER SHOES
AND COMBED HER HAIR,
ALL WITH HER FATHER DEAD,
SEEMED MORE
SURPRISING TO ME
THAN ANYTHING ELSE
IN THE WHOLE WORLD.
SHERRY, MY CONDOLENCES.
SHERYL?
I--I APOLOGIZE!
WHAT?
I APOLOGIZE
ABOUT YOUR DAD.
I MEAN, I'M SORRY...
A-ABOUT YOUR HEART.
I MEAN, HIS HEART.
YOUR DAD'S?
I CAN'T RIGHT NOW, O.K.?
LEAVE ME ALONE, PLEASE.
I DIDN'T KNOW
YOU COULD BOWL
THIS LATE.
HEY, NOW.
SO YOU ARE...
ALICE. ALICE BLOOM.
FROM ACROSS THE STREET.
SOME PEOPLE
CALL ME ALLEY,
BUT NOT MY DAD
OR MY TEACHERS,
ONLY PEOPLE
WHO I LIKE,
WHO LIKE ME BACK.
BUT THERE AREN'T
A LOT OF PEOPLE
LIKE THAT.
ANYONE SEEN SHERYL?
LISTEN, ALLEY.
COULD YOU KEEP A SECRET
IF I ASKED YOU?
ME?
YOU NEVER SAW ME
TONIGHT, O.K.?
IT'S REALLY IMPORTANT.
SURE.
HA HA.
THANKS.
HEY, SHERYL!
WHAT'S YOUR
FAVORITE COLOR?
I GUESS IT'S BLUE.
HEY, NOW.
WE'RE CLOSED.
I JUST WANTED
TO BRING THESE BACK.
SURE.
NO CHARGE.
THANKS.
HEY, YOU WANT TO TALK?
ABOUT WHAT?
THOSE AREN'T EXACTLY
PARTY CLOTHES
YOU'RE WEARING.
WHAT'D THEY SAY?
TIME HEALS ALL WOUNDS?
GOD HAS HIS REASONS?
TRUTH IS...MAYBE HE DOES.
DOESN'T MAKE
A GOD DAMN BIT OF SENSE.
IT'S A MORTAL SIN
TO SAY THAT.
IT'S A SIN TO BELIEVE
ANYTHING ELSE.
YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
THEN WHY DID
YOU COME HERE?
I TOLD YOU...
I JUST--I WALKED OUT
IN YOUR SHOES.
YEAH, YOU DID.
I HAD NOWHERE ELSE
TO GO.
THEN DON'T GO ANYWHERE.
YOU SAID
YOU WERE CLOSED.
I LIED.
HI. THIS IS SHERYL--
SHERYL O'CONNER.
MY DAD DIED.
THIS IS STUPID.
I DON'T WANT
TO DO THIS.
O.K.
HERE'S SOMETHING.
TONIGHT THIS OLD GUY--
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHO HE WAS,
BUT HE WAS TELLING ME
THAT WHEN MY DAD
WAS YOUNG,
HE WAS THIS
REALLY GREAT DANCER,
AND ALL THE GIRLS
AT THE COPA
USED TO
HANG ALL OVER HIM.
I WOULD HAVE LOVED
TO SEE THAT.
I NEVER EVEN SAW
MY DADDY DANCE BEFORE.
I MEAN...NOT REALLY.
WHAT AM I SUPPOSED
TO DO WITH THIS?
BURY IT.
FOR WHAT?
YOU KNOW, FOR LIKE
A TIME CAPSULE.
THEN
WE'LL PICK A DAY
AND GET TOGETHER
AND DIG THEM UP,
LIKE JULY 4, 1999.
YOU MADE ONE OF THESE?
A LONG TIME AGO,
AFTER MY OLD MAN
SPLIT.
DOESN'T SEEM
LIKE A BIG DEAL.
JUST BECAUSE
THEY'RE YOUR PARENTS
DOESN'T MEAN
YOU GOT TO LOVE THEM.
I LOVE--
I LOVED MY DAD.
THEN YOU'RE ONE
OF THE LUCKY ONES.
YOU BETTER GET IN THERE
BEFORE
YOU GET IN TROUBLE.
YEAH.
WELL, LISTEN,
I'LL SEE YOU
ON THE 4th OF JULY,
1999.
O.K.
I'LL BRING
THE POTATO SALAD.
AND I'LL BRING
THE FIREWORKS.
HEY.
HEY, NOW.
THANK YOU.
I MEAN, THANKS
FOR TONIGHT.
IT'S MY PLEASURE.
SHERRY? WHERE
HAVE YOU BEEN?
OH, HONEY.
"YES, GIRLS,
CAN YOU BELIEVE IT?
"TWO YEARS AGO,
I WAS TURNED DOWN
"FOR MODELING JOBS
IN HOLLYWOOD.
"THEY SAID I WAS
TOO FLAT-CHESTED.
"I TRIED BARBELLS,
SWIMMING. NOTHING HELPED.
THEN I DISCOVERED
NEW LADY MAGIC CREAM."
THESE WILL GROW,
TOO, RIGHT?
YOUR NIPPLES?
NO. THEY
STAY THE SAME--
EXACTLY THE SAME.
"RESULTS IN JUST 30 DAYS
OR YOUR MONEY BACK."
THAT'S PERFECT.
THEY'LL BE JUST RIGHT
FOR MICKEY'S PARTY.
WE'LL HAVE
TO WEAR A BRA.
PROBABLY.
THEY WON'T GET...
TOO BIG.
I WOULDN'T WORRY
ABOUT IT, ALICE.
[CARS DRIVING BY]
HEY!
WOO!
WOW.
OW! HEY!
SHIT!
OZZIE AND HARRIET
LIVE HERE?
I THINK I SAW
DORIS DAY.
OH, MY GOD.
IT'S THE LUBE HEAD
FROM THE
STRIKE AND SPARE.
HE'S KIND OF CUTE...
FOR A GREASER.
HER FATHER
DIED.
MY CONDOLENCES, MA'AM.
COULD YOU JUST
TELL HER IT'S RICK?
HEY, NOW.
WANT TO GO GET
A COKE OR SOMETHING?
YEAH. DEFINITELY.
NOW HOLD ON
A MINUTE.
IS HE
YOUR FRIEND?
YEAH, MOM, HE'S A FRIEND.
WHAT ARE YOU,
AFRAID TO COME ALONE?
WELL, YOU KNOW, WE WERE
IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
I DON'T WANT YOU
LEAVING THIS HOUSE.
MOM, I'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
I CAN'T BREATHE IN THERE.
THAT IS SO TRAMPY.
COME ON, BARBARA.
LET'S GO.
ALICE.
DON'T GET ALL EXCITED.
THEY'RE NOT
GOING TO ASK YOU
TO COME ALONG.
SHERRY, WHO ARE
THESE BOYS?
I DON'T KNOW.
DOO-WOPPERS, PUNKS,
COMMUNISTS, MOM.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE OUT OF HERE.
BYE, MOM. DON'T WORRY.
I'LL BE O.K.
♪ SWEET DREAM BABY
♪ HOW LONG
MUST I DREAM? ♪
♪ DREAM BABY, GOT ME
DREAMIN' SWEET DREAMS ♪
♪ THE WHOLE DAY THROUGH
♪ DREAM BABY, GOT ME
DREAMIN' SWEET DREAMS ♪
♪ NIGHTTIME, TOO
♪ I LOVE YOU,
AND I'M DREAMING OF YOU ♪
♪ BUT THAT WON'T DO
♪ DREAM BABY, MAKE ME
STOP MY DREAMIN' ♪
♪ YOU CAN MAKE MY DREAMS
COME TRUE ♪
COME ON. A LITTLE MORE.
♪ SWEET DREAM BABY
A LITTLE MORE.
COME ON.
♪ SHA NA NA NA
♪ SWEET DREAM BABY
♪ HOW LONG MUST I DREAM?
O.K., SWEETHEART.
YOU'RE ON.
♪ DREAM BABY
♪ GOT ME DREAMIN'
SWEET DREAMS ♪
♪ THE WHOLE DAY THROUGH
♪ DREAM BABY, GOT ME
DREAMIN' SWEET DREAMS ♪
♪ NIGHTTIME, TOO
♪ I LOVE YOU,
AND I'M DREAMING OF YOU ♪
♪ BUT THAT WON'T DO
♪ DREAM BABY, MAKE ME
STOP MY DREAMIN' ♪
♪ YOU CAN MAKE MY DREAMS
COME TRUE ♪
♪ OH, SWEET DREAM ♪
I THOUGHT
YOU SAID YOU WENT
TO CATHOLIC SCHOOL.
YEAH.
BUT THEY'VE
BEEN TELLING US
ABOUT GUYS LIKE YOU
SINCE I WAS
IN THE FIRST GRADE.
I DON'T WANT
TO SAY ANYTHING,
BUT DO THE GIRLS
IN QUEENS
ACTUALLY FALL
FOR THIS KIND
OF ROUTINE?
WHAT ROUTINE?
YOU KNOW,
STUFFING ME WITH
OYSTERS AND TEQUILA.
YOU GOT YOUR HAIR
TRIMMED.
YOU'VE GOT ON
AQUA VELVA.
IT'S NOT AQUA VELVA.
WELL, IT'S TOO BAD.
IT'S
MY FAVORITE SCENT.
I WAS WAITING
FOR YOU TO CALL.
THOUGHT I SHOULD
GIVE YOU A LITTLE TIME.
THAT'S FUNNY.
ALL I GOT IS TIME.
IT'S LIKE
IT ALL JUST STOPPED,
BEING IN THAT HOUSE
WITH MY MOM
ALL ALONE.
IT'S SO HORRIBLE
THAT PEOPLE YOU LOVE
CAN DIE LIKE THAT,
THAT THEY CAN JUST
DISAPPEAR.
JUST
BECAUSE THEY'RE GONE
DOESN'T MEAN YOU GOT
TO STOP LOVING THEM.
I MEAN,
YOU DON'T KNOW.
YOU MIGHT
SEE HIM AGAIN.
WHERE?
ON THE OTHER SIDE,
THAT'S WHERE.
YOU GOT TO KEEP YOUR
OPTIONS OPEN, RIGHT?
I LIKE THAT.
YOUR TURN.
I COULDN'T SAY
VENUS WAS
IN THE SKY THAT NIGHT,
BUT IT COULD HAVE BEEN.
AFTER THAT NIGHT,
THEY WERE INSEPARABLE.
I SAW THEM EVERYWHERE.
LIKE AT THE
STRIKE AND SPARE,
SHE'D HANG AROUND
ALL AFTERNOON
WAITING FOR HIS BREAK.
SOMETIMES THEY'D EVEN
HANG OUT ON HER LAWN
WHEN HER MOTHER
WASN'T AROUND.
NO ONE WAS HAPPY
ABOUT IT.
MR. BELL SAID
IF HE'D WANTED THEM
IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD,
HE WOULD HAVE
NEVER LEFT QUEENS.
AND MR. ROSSI, HE HEARD
THEY ALL HAD RECORDS,
AND HE'D CALL THE COPS
IF IT KEPT UP.
BUT ME, I DIDN'T CARE
IF THEY'D ALL
BEEN IN SING-SING.
I WANTED THEM
TO STAY AROUND FOREVER.
♪ RULER OF MY HEART
♪ FATHER OF MY SOUL
♪ WHERE CAN YOU BE?
♪ I WAIT PATIENTLY
♪ MY HEART CRIES OUT
BEST OF ALL IS WHEN HE'D
BRING HER BACK LATE
AND PARK DOWN THE BLOCK,
NOT TO WAKE HER MOM,
AND IT WOULD JUST BE US
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT
IN THE DARKNESS.
♪ RULER OF MY HEART
♪ FATHER OF MY SOUL
♪ HEAR MY CRY
♪ OO-EE-EE-MM ♪
DID YOU TRY
THE HEADSTANDS?
YEAH, I TRIED IT.
FELT LIKE A JACKASS.
I BET.
AND 11.
THANK YOU.
LOOK, ENOUGH
OF THE HEADSTANDS
ALREADY.
DID YOU TRY
A VINEGAR DOUCHE?
MAYBE I'M NOT READY
TO HAVE ANOTHER BABY.
MAYBE
IT'S HIS PLUMBING.
[SHERYL]
AAH! AH...
JESUS.
IF HER SHORTS
GET ANY TIGHTER,
SHE'LL
HAVE TO HAVE THEM
SURGICALLY REMOVED.
WHY DON'T THEY
LIE DOWN ON THE GRASS
AND GET IT OVER WITH?
HA HA! HEE!
AAH!
OH...
IT'S PROBABLY
JUST A PHASE.
MY PRINCESS BETTER NOT
GO THROUGH THAT PHASE.
MY INNOCENT LITTLE ONE.
OH, GOD.
THE FRONT SEAT
OF GENE'S BUICK.
TEX WILLIAMS
PLAYING ON THE RADIO.
♪ SMOKE, SMOKE,
SMOKE THAT CIGARETTE ♪♪
MUST HAVE BEEN 1948.
THAT WAS
YOUR FIRST KISS?
YOU'RE CLOSE.
DO YOU REMEMBER
WHEN LARRY KISSED YOU
LIKE THAT?
YEAH.
DON'T, DON'T, DON'T.
HEY, WHAT IS THAT?
IT WAS SUPPOSED
TO BE A SURPRISE.
WHAT IS THAT?
YOU GOT A TATTOO?
THAT'S BEAUTIFUL.
THAT'S GOING TO BE
THERE FOREVER, YOU KNOW.
AAH!
THEY'RE DEFINITELY
DOING IT.
DEFINITELY.
DOING WHAT?
YOU KNOW,
DOING IT--
BANGING,
BOFFING,
BALLING.
THE SEX
THING.
FORGET IT.
SHE'S TOO YOUNG
TO UNDERSTAND.
I AM NOT. I KNOW
AS MUCH AS YOU.
MY PARENTS DO IT
ON THEIR HEADS.
OH, ALICE.
YOU'RE
SUCH A WEENIE.
DUMMY, THE GUY GETS
ON TOP OF THE GIRL.
WHAM, WHAM, WHAM.
THEN YOU
HAVE A BABY.
ONLY IF THE GUY SWEATS.
THE GUY'S GOTTA
SWEAT AND THE LADY'S
GOTTA DRINK IT.
WHO TOLD YOU THAT?
DAD.
MAYBE IT'S NOT
THE SWEAT SHE DRINKS.
MAYBE IT HAS TO
DO WITH WHERE YOU
GO TO THE BATHROOM.
OH, OOH!OH, OOH!
HEY, SHE'LL KNOW.
YEAH.
YOU GO ASK HER.
WE'LL WAIT HERE.
SHE'S YOUR
BEST FRIEND, RIGHT?
I'M NOT ASKING HER.
HEY!
LET GO!
STOP IT! NO!
OW! YOU'RE
HURTING ME!
STOP IT!
I'M NOT
ASKING HER!
LET GO!
DON'T!
STOP!
NO!
AAH!
OHH!
ALICE
CASTRATED MICKEY!
OHH!
ALICE, I'M NOT GOING
TO ASK YOU AGAIN.
SHE SAID IT
WAS AN ACCIDENT.
I THINK THE BEST
THING TO DO
IS TO APOLOGIZE
TO THE MEYER BOY.
LET'S GO.
LISTEN TO HER
FOR ONCE.
STOP TAKING
HER SIDE.
MICKEY'S A LIAR.
HE SAID SHERYL AND
RICK WERE DOING IT.
DOING WHAT?
BANGING.
BANGING?
BANGING, BOFFING,
BALLING.
O.K., NOW,
THAT'S ENOUGH.
MOM, WHY DO BOYS
HAVE TO BE SUCH BABIES
ALL THE TIME?
WELL, THEY
NEED THE PRACTICE
SO THEY CAN
BECOME HUSBANDS.
NOW, GOOD NIGHT.
MOM, YOU LOVE DAD,
DON'T YOU?
YEAH.
AND HE
LOVES YOU, TOO.
NOW GO TO SLEEP.
HOW COME YOU AND DAD
NEVER KISS LIKE
SHERYL AND RICK?
WELL, WE DID.
IT'S JUST, UM...
WE USED TO, BUT
IT'S DIFFERENT NOW.
IT CHANGES.
WHY?
WELL, YOU JUST
GET OLDER, THAT'S ALL.
YOU JUST GET OLDER.
NO, THE PROBLEM
IS WITH YOUR DAUGHTER.
DAD SAID IT WAS OVER,
LIKE POLIO
AND THE IRON LUNG.
SHERYL'S MOM
PUT HER FOOT DOWN.
[HORN HONKING]
RICK WASN'T ALLOWED
TO COME AROUND ANYMORE.
AND I HAD TO APOLOGIZE
TO MICKEY MEYER
AND GO TO
HIS BIRTHDAY PARTY.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
HONEY, LOOK
WHO'S HERE.
SORRY WE'RE LATE.
NO PROBLEM. HI.
THE TWINS ARE
REALLY LOOKING
FORWARD TO THIS.
THE WHOLE GANG'S
DOWNSTAIRS.
IT'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
MOM!
HAVE A GOOD TIME.
WE HAVE
CHIPS AND DIP,
M&Ms.
I'LL TAKE THIS.
SHE'LL BE FINE.
HAVE A GOOD TIME
AT THE PLAY.
HI, ALICE!HI, ALICE!
DO YOU NEED
MORE CANDY?
NO, THANKS, MOM!NO, THANKS!
HOW'S THE GAME?
GREAT!GREAT.
CAN I GET ANYTHING?
NO, THANKS.NO, THANKS.
O.K., I'LL
SEE YOU ALL LATER.
4.
1, 2, 3, 4.
[BARBARA]
SHE'S GONE.
GET THE BOOK.
"THIS IS THE FIRST TIME
"THE INEXPERIENCED BRIDE
HAS EVER SEEN A FULL-BLOWN
ERECT PENIS.
"SHE WILL SOMETIMES
BECOME SO EXCITED
"THAT SHE'LL
SQUEEZE TOO HARD
AND UNWILLINGLY
HURT HER PARTNER."
OOH!OOH!OOH!
NO WAY!
THAT'S IT! I'M
NEVER DOING IT!
NOBODY'S
TOUCHING MINE!
DON'T YOU WANT
TO HAVE A BABY?
I'LL BUY ONE.
♪ OH, YES, WAIT A MINUTE,
MR. POSTMAN ♪
WHOO!WHOO!WHOO!
GO, BARBARA!
♪ PLEASE, MR. POSTMAN,
LOOK AND SEE ♪
♪ OH, YEAH
OH, GOD!
SHE FRENCHED HIM!
FRENCH!FRENCH!
♪ OH, YEAH
♪ IF THERE'S A LETTER FROM
THIS BOYFRIEND OF MINE ♪
WHOO!WHOO!WHOO!
GO ON, ALICE.
KISS AND MAKE UP.
OPEN YOUR MOUTH SO
HE CAN TONGUE YOU.
AND CLOSE
YOUR EYES.
♪ LOOK AND SEE
♪ IS THERE A LETTER,
A LETTER FOR ME? ♪
♪ I WAS STANDIN'
HERE WAITIN', MR. POSTMAN ♪
♪ SOOOO, SO PATIENTLY
WIDER!
♪ FOR JUST A CARD
♪ FOR JUST A LETTER
♪ SAYIN' HE'S
RETURNIN' HOME TO ME ♪♪
HA HA HA!HA HA HA!
HER MOTHER SHOULD
TAKE HER INTO HER ROOM
AND EXPLAIN
THE FACTS OF LIFE,
THE BIRDS AND THE BEES,
AND ALL THAT.
THEN HER FATHER SHOULD
TAKE HER INTO A ROOM
AND EXPLAIN TRASH--
HOW ABOUT I GO
TO CARVEL'S AND
GET SOME SHAKES?
THAT'S A GREAT IDEA.
I'LL COME WITH YOU.
MOM, YOU CAN'T
JUST GROUND ME
LIKE THIS.
YES, I CAN.
[RETCHING]
WHAT IS IT?
IT'S THE GIRL FROM
ACROSS THE STREET.
I THINK
SHE'S PUKING.
HEY! HEY, NOW!
[VOMITING]
GOD, WHAT'S THE MATTER?
WHAT HAPPENED?
I WANT...
TO KILL HIM.
OH, ONE OF THOSE, HUH?
WELL, O.K., COME ON.
BOYS. OH, I SWEAR.
SOME GUYS JUST
FUNCTION THAT WAY.
THIS GUY LARRY WINANT PUT
A RAT DOWN MY BACK ONCE.
DID YOU GET BIT?
NO. IT WAS DEAD.
SEE, WHEN THEY LIKE YOU,
THEY GOT TO DO SOMETHING
TO DRIVE YOU CRAZY.
THEN SIX MONTHS LATER,
HE GAVE ME MY FIRST KISS.
HOW MANY GLASSES
IS THAT NOW?
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
IT'S THEM!
IT'S THE MEYERS.
I'M NOT GOING BACK.
I'LL DROWN MYSELF.
ALLEY, CALM DOWN.
GOD. RELAX,
O.K.?
LEAVE IT TO ME.
HELLO?
NO, THIS IS SHERYL
FROM ACROSS THE STREET.
YEAH, SHE'S FINE.
EVERYTHING'S O.K.
HOLD ON. SHE
WANTS TO TALK TO YOU.
CAN'T YOU
STAY WITH ME UNTIL
MY PARENTS GET HOME?
ALLEY, I'M NOT STAYING
HERE ALL NIGHT. I'M SORRY.
BUT WE DON'T
HAVE TO STAY HERE.
NO ONE WOULD
HAVE TO KNOW.
ONLY RICK.
WHAT?
YOU COULD TELL
YOUR MOTHER YOU
WERE BABYSITTING.
THAT'S PERFECT.
SHE SAID IF WE
WERE GOING TO CHASE
THE NIGHT TOGETHER,
I'D HAVE TO
CHANGE MY LOOKS.
I DIDN'T MIND.
I DIDN'T MIND AT ALL.
♪ LITTLE SISTER
♪ DON'T YOU KISS
ME ONCE OR TWICE ♪
♪ AND SAY
IT'S VERY NICE ♪
♪ AND THEN YOU RUN
♪ LITTLE SISTER
♪ DON'T YOU DO WHAT
YOUR BIG SISTER DONE ♪
♪ WELL, I DATED YOUR--
WHAT IF WE GET CAUGHT?
♪ AND I TOOK
HER TO A SHOW ♪
[HORN HONKS]
♪ I WENT
FOR SOME CANDY ♪
♪ ALONG CAME
JIM DANDY ♪
♪ AND THEY SNUCK
RIGHT OUT THE DOOR ♪
♪ LITTLE SISTER,
DON'T YOU-- ♪
♪ LITTLE SISTER, DON'T YOU
KISS ME ONCE OR TWICE ♪
♪ AND SAY
IT'S VERY NICE-- ♪
HE SAID HE'D BEEN
WITH LOTS OF GIRLS
BEFORE ME.
NO BIG DEAL, RIGHT?
I SET HIM STRAIGHT.
YOU CAN SEE IT
IN HIS EYES NOW.
I CAN TELL NOBODY
EVER REALLY LOVED HIM
BEFORE ME.
I KNEW THE MOMENT
WE MET WE'D BE
TOGETHER FOREVER.
W-WELL, WHO TOLD YOU?
NOBODY TELLS YOU.
YOU JUST FEEL IT.
IT'S LIKE
BEING ON FIRE.
YOUR BODY'S GLOWING,
LIKE YOU'RE BURNING UP.
YOUR HEART
BEATS SO FAST,
IT FEELS LIKE
IT'S GOING TO BURST.
I KNEW IT.
I WISH I'D BEEN IN LOVE
10,000 TIMES ALREADY.
♪ LITTLE SISTER
♪ DON'T YOU DO WHAT
YOUR BIG SISTER DONE ♪♪
CHECKMATE.
OH, NOT POSSIBLE.
NOT AGAIN.
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE
EXPOSED YOUR QUEEN.
TWO MOVES AGO,
YOU COULD HAVE
HAD A DRAW.
WHAT IS IT WITH YOU?
YOU DRESS LIKE SHIT
AND CLIP PEOPLE?
I JUST DRESS LIKE SHIT.
HEY, NOW.
HI.HEY!
WHAT ARE
YOU DOING HERE?
I HAD TO SEE YOU.
I WAS READY TO
BUST IN YOUR DOOR.
I COULDN'T GET OUT.
SHERRY,
THAT AIN'T RIGHT.
YOU CAN'T HAVE HER
DOING THAT TO YOU.
SHE'S REALLY SCARED,
MY DAD GONE AND ALL.
SHE'D DO SOMETHING
CRAZY, I KNOW HER.
HOW'D YOU GET OUT TONIGHT?
WELL, I'M BABYSITTING.
SOMEBODY PUT A FROG
DOWN HER THROAT,
AND SHE GOT SICK.
HI, ALICE BLOOM.
I ATE THE FROG.
NO, RICK, YOU
HAVE IT ALL WRONG.
IT'S NOT THAT
THEY DON'T LIKE YOU.
MRS. CARPENTER THINKS
YOU LOOK EXACTLY LIKE
FRANK SINATRA
OR LITTLE JOE.
THEY JUST THINK THAT
SHERYL'S TOO YOUNG
FOR YOU, THAT'S ALL.
WELL, TELL THEM THAT
ROMEO AND JULIET,
THEY WERE 13.
TELL THEM TO MIND
THEIR OWN BUSINESS,
STARTING WITH
YOUR OLD MAN.
WHAT?
NOTHING, ALLEY,
IT'S NOTHING.
DON'T
WORRY ABOUT IT.
MY DAD?
WHAT DID HE DO?
HE SAID SOMETHING
TO MY MOM.
IT'S NO BIG DEAL.
WHO HASN'T?
WHO CARES, RIGHT?
SO COME ON.
LET'S GO HAVE
SOME FUN.
THEY TOOK ME
UNDER THE BOARDWALK.
HE SAID THERE WAS
NOTHING TO BE AFRAID OF,
BUT I WAS SCARED.
HOW YOU DOING?
HERE YOU GO,
SWEETIE,
HAVE A SIP.
ALLEY, DON'T.
♪ WELL, SEE
♪ SEE SEE RIDER
♪ JUST A SEE
♪ WHAT YOU HAVE
A DONE ♪
♪ LORD, LORD,
LORD, LORD ♪
♪ SEE SEE RIDER
♪ SEE WHAT YOU
♪ HAVE A DONE
♪ HUH HUH
♪ WELL, YOU MADE A ME
A LOVE YOU ♪
♪ NOW YOUR GIRL
HAS COME ♪
♪ WHAT I SAY?
♪ I SAID SEE
♪ SEE SEE RIDER
♪ OH, SEE
♪ WHOA,
YEAH YEAH YEAH ♪♪
YOU WANT TO
DANCE WITH ME?
ME? NO, I--I--
ME, I CAN'T.
COME ON.
♪ I MAY GET WEARY
♪ WOMEN DO GET WEARY
♪ WEARIN' THE SAME
♪ SHABBY DRESS
♪ BUT TO ONE
WHO'S WEARY ♪
♪ TRY A LITTLE
TENDERNESS ♪
♪ OHHHH
♪ I MAY BE WAITING
♪ JUST ANTICIPATING
♪ ALL OF THE THINGS
♪ I MAY NEVER POSSESS
♪ MMM, BUT
WHILE I'M WAITIN' ♪
♪ TRY A LITTLE
TENDERNESS ♪
♪ I MAY BE
SENTIMENTAL ♪
I WONDERED IF ANYONE
WOULD EVER FEEL ABOUT ME
THE WAY RICK
FELT ABOUT SHERYL.
♪ ...THAT I'VE
HAD MY GRIEFS ♪
♪ OH, AND I'VE
HAD MY CARES ♪
SHE SAID I
SHOULD MAKE A RECORD
ABOUT ALL THE STUFF
THAT HAPPENED THAT NIGHT,
BOTH THE GOOD
AND THE BAD.
THEN WE'D BURY IT
WITH HERS
AND PLAY IT AGAIN
IN 50 YEARS.
♪ MAKES IT
♪ MAKES IT EASIER
♪ EASIER TO BEAR ♪
I COULDN'T STOP TALKING.
BUT SHERYL WAS WORRIED
ABOUT GETTING ME HOME,
AND THAT WAS THAT.
I'VE GOT IT
ALL FIGURED OUT.
YOU SHOULD RUN
AWAY TOGETHER.
HOW ABOUT HAWAII
OR TAHITI?
LOOK, I HAVE
ALL THESE MAPS.
GET IN BED ALREADY,
WOULD YOU?
HA HA HA HA.
OH, YOU
WEAR AMBUSH, TOO?
IT'S MY MOM'S.
WELL, MR. BELL--
IT'S BARBARA'S DAD--
HE SAID RICK
WAS IN PRISON.
IS THAT TRUE OR FALSE?
NO. HE'S JUST MADE
A COUPLE OF WRONG
TURNS, THAT'S ALL.
I GUESS YOU'RE
A RIGHT TURN.
I'M ALL
HE'S GOT, REALLY.
HE DOESN'T
HAVE ANY FAMILY.
SEE, IF HE HAD DIED
BEFORE MEETING ME,
HE WOULD HAVE NEVER
BEEN LOVED BY ANYONE.
YOU NEED SOMEONE
TO LOVE YOU TO KEEP
YOUR SPIRIT ALIVE
AFTER YOU DIE.
IT'S LIKE MY
BABY BROTHER,
I GUESS.
WHAT?
YOU HAVE A BROTHER?
I DID.
HE HAD TROUBLE BREATHING
OR SOMETHING.
THEY SAY HE NEVER
CRIED OR ANYTHING.
I DIDN'T KNOW THAT,
ALLEY. I'M SORRY.
MY DAD, HE--HE BOUGHT HIM
THIS YANKEES' CAP.
IT'S STILL OUTSIDE
IN THE GARAGE
WITH SOME OF
HIS OTHER STUFF.
I WISH--I WISH
I WERE ROGER MARIS
OR SOMEONE.
HA HA HA HA.
NO, YOU DON'T.
YOU'D BE IN THE DUGOUT
ALL THE TIME.
YOU AND I WOULDN'T
BE TIGHT LIKE WE ARE.
WE'RE TIGHT?
YEAH.
O.K., GOOD NIGHT.
GOOD NIGHT.
ALLEY! YOU LISTEN
TO THIS RECORD, TOO?
WELL...
YEAH, I JUST BOUGHT IT.
THAT'S SOME VIEW, ALLEY.
[CAR APPROACHING]
THEY'RE HERE.
O.K., NOT A WORD
ABOUT TONIGHT.
WHEN DO WE
BURY OUR RECORDS?
UH, MAYBE TOMORROW.
LOSE THE SCARF, BLUE.
SHERYL!
HEY, BLUE.
I GOT MY RECORD.
I CAN'T TODAY,
ALLEY.
I MUST HAVE A HANGOVER
OR SOMETHING.
YOU SURE?
YEAH. I JUST
DON'T FEEL RIGHT.
YEAH, I THINK I
HAVE A HANGOVER, TOO.
YEAH, RIGHT.
SEE YOU SOON.
WAIT, ALLEY.
LISTEN, CAN--
COULD YOU HELP ME?
SURE.
TELL RICK THAT, UM,
THAT I'M SICK,
AND TOMORROW NIGHT,
MIDNIGHT, I PROMISE.
UH, I'LL GO.
NO, I'LL RUN.
I'LL GET MY DAD
TO TAKE ME.
DRINK LOTS
OF GINGER ALE.
I THOUGHT YOU SAID
YOU NEVER WANTED
TO GO BOWLING AGAIN.
I'VE BEEN PRACTICING...
IN MY ROOM.
WHY DON'T
I GET THE SHOES,
AND YOU CAN
GRAB A COUPLE OF
COKES AND SOME PIZZA.
I CAN'T. I MEAN,
I'LL STAY WITH YOU.
HEY, NOW.
SIZE 11 AND A 5.
LANE 13. YOU ALL
HAVE A GOOD TIME.
I'M TELLING YOU
THESE AREN'T RIGHT.
THEY'RE SIZE 5,
SWEETIE.
THEY'RE
THE WRONG COLOR.
COME ON, ALICE.
RED ALWAYS
MAKES ME FEEL SICK.
REMEMBER, I USED
TO GET BLOODY NOSES
ALL THE TIME?
THAT WAS RED.
O.K.! O.K.,
CHANGE 'EM.
SHE CAN'T MAKE IT.
SHE'S GOT A BUG.
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
SHE'S GOT A BAD
STOMACHACHE.
SHE'S SICK.
SHE CAN'T MAKE IT.
GET OUT OF HERE.
HEY, GUYS.
HOW DO YOU
KNOW HIM SO WELL?
FROM GETTING SHOES.
I DON'T WANT YOU
ANYWHERE NEAR HIM.
HE'S A PUNK.
HE IS NOT.
HE'S AN ELECTRICIAN.
SHERYL TOLD ME.
THEY'RE
STILL IN LOVE.
SWEETHEART, YOU
DON'T KNOW ABOUT LOVE.
SHERYL IS 17, O.K.?
WELL, JULIET WAS 13.
THAT'S A MADE-UP STORY,
ALICE.
THE MEYERS
MET IN HIGH SCHOOL.
THEY'RE STILL MARRIED.
AND WHAT
ABOUT CINDERELLA?
WHAT ABOUT CINDERELLA?
SHE WAS
THE YOUNGEST SISTER.
SHE COULDN'T EVEN DRIVE
WHEN SHE MET THE PRINCE.
I WANT YOU TO BE MORE
CAREFUL WHO YOU TALK TO.
YOU SHOULD BE CAREFUL.
IT'S ALL YOUR FAULT.
WHY DID YOU
HAVE TO STOP THEM?
WHY DO YOU HAVE
TO MAKE EVERYONE'S
LIFE MISERABLE?
WHAT'D THEY
EVER DO TO YOU?
ALICE--
JESUS, ALICE!
YOU DON'T KNOW
ANYTHING ABOUT LOVE.
JUST HOW TO
MAKE IT GO AWAY.
ALICE!
HI, GANG.
HAVE A GOOD TIME?
WHAT HAPPENED?
SO, I EXPLAINED
TO ALICE
THAT I'D SPOKEN
TO SHERYL'S MOM
BECAUSE I KNEW
HER HUSBAND
WOULD'VE WANTED TO DO
THE SAME THING.
YOU KNOW WHAT
SHE SAID TO ME?
"DID HE WRITE YOU
A LETTER FROM HEAVEN?"
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
WE'LL DO WITH HER.
SHE'S A LITTLE GIRL.
HEY, CAROL,
SHE'S OUT OF CONTROL.
IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE BOWLING ALLEY,
SHE'S YELLING THAT
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT LOVE.
WELL, MAYBE YOU DON'T.
WHAT DO YOU
MEAN BY THAT?
I ASKED YOU
A QUESTION, CAROL.
IT MIGHT BE
A HEADACHE ON ITS WAY,
A STOMACHACHE
ON ITS WAY--
[TURNS TV OFF]
I ASKED YOU A QUESTION.
MAYBE I DON'T WANT
TO HAVE ANOTHER BABY.
MAYBE IT'S NOT TIME.
IT'S ONLY BEEN A YEAR.
I MEAN, LARRY,
MAYBE I JUST CAN'T,
O.K.?
CAROL.
[CAROL SNIFFLING]
[SOBBING]
THEY ALL THOUGHT
IT WAS OVER,
THAT SHERYL
HAD COME TO HER SENSES
AND FORGOTTEN HIM.
I WAS THE ONLY ONE
WHO KNEW
THAT SHE WOULD SNEAK OUT
NIGHT AFTER NIGHT
AND GO TO HIM.
"S-H-E-R."
I COULD BE ANYONE.
SHERWOOD.
SHERMAN.
SHERBET.
WE COULD HAVE BEEN BORN
THOUSANDS OF MILES APART,
SPOKEN DIFFERENT LANGUAGES
AND EVERYTHING.
NEVER EVEN MET.
NOTHING ELSE MATTERS,
DOES IT, RICK?
I MEAN, NOT OUR FAMILY,
OUR FRIENDS, NOTHING, RIGHT?
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
YOU'RE ABOUT TO DUMP ME?
NO.
HEY,
WHY DO I ALWAYS WANT
TO BE INSIDE YOU?
I DON'T KNOW. IT'S JUST
SOMETHING ABOUT BEING...
BEING THIS CLOSE
ALL THE TIME.
AND I CAN'T STAND NOT
BEING WITH YOU, SHERRY.
YOU GOT TO TELL
YOUR MOM WE'RE GOING
TO SEE EACH OTHER.
I CAN'T.
I CAN'T DO THAT.
WELL, WHY NOT?
WHAT'S THE BIG DEAL?
WE'RE NOT KIDS ANYMORE.
RICK, I KNOW.
WE HAVE A PRIEST
OVER AT MY HOUSE
EVERY FIVE MINUTES.
SHE'S ALREADY
THREATENING TO SEND
ME TO SOME RETREAT.
SO, I'LL COME
AND RESCUE YOU.
I CAN'T
TELL HER NOW.
WHEN ARE YOU
GOING TO TELL HER--
WHEN I'M
DRIVING A BUICK?
AFTER I'VE GOT
SOME FANCY DEGREE?
THAT'S JUST A BUNCH
OF BULLSHIT, SHERRY.
I KNOW.
I KNOW IT IS.
WELL, LISTEN,
FRIDAY NIGHT,
I GOT TICKETS TO
ROY ORBISON, O.K.?
NOW, IT'S REAL SIMPLE.
YOU TALK TO HER
AND YOU TELL HER
WHAT'S GOING ON.
THEN WE'LL GO
OVER TO VACRA'S FIRST.
WE'LL CELEBRATE.
WE'LL HAVE A GREAT NIGHT.
IT'S JUST SO HARD.
I MEAN, WHAT IF
STUFF GOES WRONG,
YOU KNOW?
WHAT, LIKE YOUR MOM?
NO, IT'S NOT
JUST ABOUT MY MOM.
I MEAN, PEOPLE STOP
LIKING EACH OTHER
ALL THE TIME,
YOU KNOW?
AND, LIKE,
WHAT IF YOU DECIDED
TO GO TO SCHOOL?
OR WHAT IF
I GOT PREGNANT?
HEY, NOW WAIT A SECOND.
SCHOOL WAS YOUR IDEA.
O.K., YOU'RE NOT
GOING TO GET PREGNANT.
WE'RE CAREFUL.
YEAH, BUT WHAT IF?
LOOK, I DON'T KNOW,
YOU KNOW?
WE GO TO MEXICO.
YOU KNOW,
WE FIND SOME GUY,
WE DRINK A BUNCH OF
MARGARITAS. I DON'T KNOW.
RICK.
SEE YOU FRIDAY NIGHT.
DON'T WORRY
ABOUT YOUR MOM.
BET YOU CAN'T
CATCH ME.
FATHER JOHN SAYS
IT'S THE BEST UNWED
MOTHER'S HOME
IN THE STATE.
HE'S TAKING CARE
OF EVERYTHING.
I HAVE TO TALK TO HIM.
THAT'S NOT
A GOOD IDEA, SHERRY.
DON'T.
I CAN'T JUST
DISAPPEAR
LIKE THAT!
THAT'S NOT FAIR,
MOM!
WHAT HAS FAIR
GOT TO DO WITH IT?
I CAN'T DISAPPEAR!
DO YOU THINK IT'S FAIR
THAT YOUR DADDY DIED?
NO!
I'LL LOSE YOU, SHERRY.
I WON'T HAVE ANYONE.
I HAVE TO SEE HIM.
FOR GOD'S SAKE, SHERRY,
YOU'RE 17 YEARS OLD.
THEN I'LL HAVE
AN ABORTION.
BITE YOUR TONGUE.
DON'T MAKE ME
CALL THE POLICE.
SHERRY!
YOU DON'T LOVE HIM.
HOW DO YOU KNOW
THAT?
WHAT ARE YOU
GOING TO DO?
YOU WANT HIM
TO GO TO SCHOOL
AND SUPPORT
A WIFE AND BABY?
WE WILL MAKE IT.
HONEY, HE'S
GOING TO END UP
WORKING IN SOME
DAMN BOWLING ALLEY
AND HATING YOU
FOR THE REST
OF HIS LIFE.
SHERRY, HONEY,
IF YOU REALLY
DO LOVE HIM,
YOU'LL LET HIM GO.
THAT'S WHAT
YOUR DADDY
WOULD HAVE SAID.
I KNOW THAT, MOM.
I KNOW IT.
OH, BABY.
BABY.
SHERYL SAID HER MOM
HAD FOUND OUT
SHE'D BEEN SNEAKING OUT
TO SEE HIM,
AND SHE WAS GOING TO
SEND SHERYL AWAY.
I HAD TO GET TO RICK.
DON'T PUNK OUT
ON ME, ALLEY.
O.K. I PROMISE.
I IMAGINED HIM
COMING FOR HER
IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE NIGHT.
HER SUITCASE
WOULD BE PACKED.
HE'D THROW PEBBLES
AGAINST HER WINDOW,
AND THEY'D ESCAPE
TO SOME ISLAND
NO ONE HAD EVER HEARD OF.
MAYBE THEY'D
TAKE ME, TOO.
MOM, I'VE GOT TO
GO OUT.
I GOT TO GET
MY BIKE FIXED.
IT NEEDS A NEW CHAIN...
RICK TOOK US
DOWN BY THE WATER.
THE OCEAN'S
DIFFERENT AT NIGHT,
DARK.
NO, STOP!
YOU CAN'T
LISTEN TO IT.
LEAVE IT ALONE.
IT'S MINE!
I HAVE TO GO
TAKE MY BIKE!
HEY, WHOA!
YOU'RE NOT GOING
ANYWHERE.
LEAVE ME ALONE!
I HAVE TO GO!
HEY!
THEY SAID SHE WAS GOING
TO HER AUNT'S IN CALIFORNIA.
I COULDN'T GET TO RICK.
I COULDN'T GET
TO ANYONE.
THE NEXT DAY WAS
THE HOTTEST DAY OF THE YEAR.
THE TV SAID THERE WAS
A STORM FRONT
OVER THE ATLANTIC,
AND IT WOULD RAIN ANY DAY.
THERE WAS NO WIND,
NO RAIN,
NOTHING.
YOU COULD HEAR
YOURSELF BREATHE.
YOU COULD
HEAR YOUR HEART BEAT
IF YOU LISTENED.
LISTEN,
MRS. O'CONNER,
IF SHERYL
DOESN'T WANT
TO TALK TO ME,
LET HER TELL ME
HERSELF.
OH!
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
DID YOU GUYS
HAVE A FIGHT
OR SOMETHING?
I DON'T KNOW.
COME ON, MAN.
COOL OUT.
YOU'RE GOING TO
SEE THIS CHICK AGAIN.
I DON'T WANT TO
JUST SEE HER
AGAIN, MAN.
I NEED TO
TALK TO HER.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
YOU FALLING
FOR THIS CHICK?
I GOT TO
TALK TO HER, MAN.
[GLASS SHATTERS]
WATCH OUT!
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
I CAME TO TALK
TO SHERYL, MRS. O'CONNER.
I GOT A RIGHT
TO TALK TO HER.
SHERRY'S NOT HERE.
PLEASE LEAVE
US ALONE.
SHERRY?
SHERYL?
SHERYL!
LISTEN, I DON'T WANT
TO CAUSE ANY TROUBLE
HERE, O.K.?
I JUST WANT TO
TALK TO YOUR DAUGHTER.
SHERYL!
SHERRY.
SHERRY!
SHERYL!
I WANT YOU OFF
MY PROPERTY.
I NEED TO TALK
TO SHERRY. SHERRY!
I'M CALLING
THE POLICE.
NO! SHERYL!
HEY!
SHERRY?
SOMEBODY HELP ME OUT HERE!
DAD!
COME ON, GUYS.
HELP ME OUT HERE.
STOP! LARRY?
OH, GOD.
STAY OUT OF
THE NEIGHBORHOOD!
SHERYL!
NO!
RICK IS GOING TO
BE O.K., HONEY.
PLEASE COME OUT.
ALICE, HE WAS GOING TO
HURT MRS. O'CONNER.
SHE'S NOT
VISITING HER AUNT
IN CALIFORNIA...
IS SHE?
NO, HONEY.
NO, SHE'S NOT.
WHERE IS SHE?
TELL ME THE TRUTH.
SWEETIE,
SHERYL GOT PREGNANT
BY THAT BOY.
SHE HAD TO GO AWAY
TO A PLACE
WHERE YOUNG GIRLS GO
TO HAVE BABIES.
THAT'S WHAT HAPPENS
WHEN YOU'RE NOT MARRIED.
F-FOR HOW LONG?
A LONG TIME,
SWEETHEART.
A LONG, LONG TIME.
THAT'S WHAT HAPPENS.
MOM SAID RICK WAS IN JAIL
FOR A WHOLE WEEK
AND THAT THEY SHOULD HAVE
CHARGED HIM WITH MELODRAMA.
DAD SAID IF HE EVER
CAME AROUND AGAIN,
HE'D KILL HIM.
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
RICK.
YOU SHOULD BE
AT HOME.
IT'S FOR YOU.
SHE STILL LOVES YOU.
WHERE THE HELL
IS SHE?
WHERE'S THE REST
OF THE NOTE?
I ATE IT.
I MEMORIZED IT,
AND THEN I ATE IT.
ALLEY, I'M NOT
GOING TO TAKE YOU.
NOW, THAT'S THAT.
SO JUST TELL ME
WHERE SHE'S AT.
WHERE IS SHE?
THEY'LL NEVER
LET YOU SEE HER,
AND I CAN HELP.
IF I GET
CAUGHT WITH YOU,
THAT'LL BE KIDNAPPING.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND
THAT?
WELL...
I DREW A LINE.
IT'S 325 MILES
ONE WAY.
I CAN BE BACK
TOMORROW NIGHT.
I'LL TELL THEM
THAT I HID BEHIND
THE LIBRARY.
LET ME SEE THAT.
I HAVE TO
SEE HER, TOO.
THEN I--I'LL
COME RIGHT BACK.
I PROMISE!
HE TOLD ME SOME THINGS,
THINGS I DIDN'T KNOW,
LIKE HOW HIS DAD
WALKED OUT ONE DAY
AND NEVER CAME BACK
AND HOW HIS MOM
WENT CRAZY
AND LANDED
IN SOME BUG HOUSE.
HE COULDN'T STOP TALKING
ABOUT ALL THE TROUBLE
HE'D BEEN IN AFTER THAT
BECAUSE HE DIDN'T CARE
ABOUT ANYONE OR ANYTHING
AND HOW SHERYL
HAD CHANGED ALL THAT.
I TOLD HIM
SOME STUFF, TOO,
LIKE ABOUT SHERYL'S BABY.
ONE THING WAS FOR SURE--
MY PARENTS WOULD BE
GLAD TO TAKE IT
IF IT WAS A PROBLEM.
VISITING HOURS
ARE SUNDAY
FROM 1:00 TO 5:00.
YOU'LL HAVE TO
COME BACK WITH
A PARENT, DEAR.
BUT I JUST
WANT TO DROP OFF
SOME STUFF--
HER HAND CREAM
AND HER FAVORITE
PERFUME.
TELL HER
IT'S COUSIN ALICE.
I'M SORRY. THERE'S
NO EXCEPTIONS, DEAR.
BUT I HAVE TO SEE HER.
PLEASE!
BUT I'M HER
COUSIN ALICE.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING?
WHERE ARE THEY?
WHAT DID THEY SAY?
I'LL BE BACK.
EXCUSE ME.
HAVE YOU SEEN
SHERYL O'CONNER?
ALICE?
ALLEY,
THIS IS INSANE.
HOW'D YOU GET HERE?
WE DROVE ALL NIGHT.
WAIT--RICK'S HERE?
YEAH, IN THE CAR
OUTSIDE.
HE WANTS TO
SEE YOU TONIGHT
AT THE DINER
DOWN THE ROAD.
CAN YOU GET THERE?
BUT HE CAME
TO GET YOU.
HURRY UP. SHE'S COMING!
MIDNIGHT.
I'LL TELL HIM
THAT YOU'LL BE THERE.
I DON'T KNOW
IF I CAN, ALLEY.
COME ON. COME ON. COME ON.
YOU GOT TO GO.
O.K. HURRY.
GO DOWN THE STAIRS
ON THE LEFT.
IT'S YOUR FAVORITE.
I'LL SEE YOU TONIGHT.
SO WHAT'S THE DEAL?
I SAW HER!
SHE'S FINE.
SHE WANTS TO
MEET YOU TONIGHT.
WHAT DID SHE SAY?
SHE WAS SO SURPRISED.
IS THAT IT?
DID SHE SAY
SOMETHING ELSE?
WELL, SHE SAID THAT--
THAT SHE MISSED YOU...
AND SHE COULDN'T
WAIT TO SEE YOU.
GOOD GIRL.
HE SAT...AND HE WAITED.
HE SAID HE KNEW
SHE WAS COMING,
BUT I COULD TELL
HE WAS SCARED.
I WAS SCARED, TOO.
HEY, NOW.
[DOOR CLOSES]
WANT SOME COFFEE
OR SOMETHING?
I'M SORRY.
I MEAN...
EVERYTHING HAPPENED
REALLY FAST.
UM...
I TRIED TO GET
TO YOU, RICK.
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
I TRIED...
TO CALL.
HEY.
I WANT YOU
TO COME WITH ME...
TONIGHT, RIGHT NOW.
AREN'T YOU EVEN
GOING TO MENTION
THE BABY?
YEAH.
UM...I'M GOING
TO PUT IT UP
FOR ADOPTION.
UM...THEY SAID
THAT THERE'S
A CATHOLIC HOSPITAL,
AND THEY'LL
GIVE THE BABY
A REALLY GOOD HOME.
THEYSAY?
WHAT DO YOU
EXPECT ME TO DO,
RICK,
GO TO MEXICO
AND GET DRUNK
ON MARGARITAS?
I CAN'T DO THAT.
HEY, I'M NOT
ASKING YOU TO DO THAT.
WE DON'T HAVE
ANY MONEY.
AND WE DON'T
HAVE INSURANCE.
BABIES GET SICK
ALL THE TIME,
AND
YOU NEED MONEY
FOR INSURANCE
AND FOOD AND...
A HOUSE.
I'LL SELL SHOES.
I'LL WASH WINDOWS.
I'LL CLEAN TOILETS
IF THAT'S WHAT
I GOT TO DO.
AND WE'D END UP
SPLITTING UP
AFTER A COUPLE
OF YEARS.
I DRIVE ALL THE WAY
UP HERE,
AT LEAST YOU CAN
LOOK AT ME.
COME ON.
IT'S MY WHOLE LIFE,
RICK.
THAT'S WHAT
YOU'RE ASKING FOR.
YEAH.
I NEVER SAID
I WAS THIS TOUGH.
YOU CAN PAWN IT
FOR THE INSURANCE
OR SOMETHING.
YOU SAID NOTHING
COULD CHANGE IT.
ALICE?
THAT ONCE YOU LOVE
SOMEONE LIKE THAT,
NOTHING ELSE
MATTERS.
NO. YOU DON'T
UNDERSTAND, ALLEY.
WE COULD
RUN AWAY TOGETHER,
TAKE A FREIGHTER
TO BALI
OR DRIVE ALL THE WAY
TO SOUTH AMERICA
ON THE PAN AMERICAN
HIGHWAY.
IT'LL BE JUST
THE THREE OF US,
LIKE THAT NIGHT--
STOP. STOP.
STOP IT, ALLEY.
YOU'VE GOT IT
SO TWISTED UP,
FOLLOWING ME AROUND
LIKE I'M SOME
GOD DAMN PRINCESS,
WEARING MY PERFUME
AND LISTENING
TO MY RECORDS.
I'M JUST THIS GIRL
THAT LIVED ACROSS
THE STREET FROM YOU,
AND I DON'T NOW.
YOU HAVE TO GO HOME.
BUT I DON'T
BELONG THERE.
YOU HAVE A FAMILY.
YOU CAN'T JUST
LEAVE THEM
LIKE THAT,
'CAUSE IF YOU DO,
IT'D JUST KILL THEM.
IT WOULD JUST
KILL THEM, ALLEY,
THAT'S ALL.
[DOOR CLOSES]
ALICE, COME ON.
YOU HAVE A BUS
TO CATCH.
GO ON, ALLEY.
HEY, NOW.
I'M GOING TO BE
TRAVELING ON,
SO SOON AS
I LAND SOMEPLACE,
I'LL DROP YOU
A LINE.
COME ON.
WE GAVE IT
OUR BEST SHOT.
COME ON.
YOU'D BETTER
GET ON THE BUS.
ALLEY OOP!
YOU BE GOOD.
I WANTED TO CALL OUT
TO THEM, TO SAY GOODBYE
OR JUST A HEY, NOW.
BUT IT WAS ENOUGH
JUST TO SEE THEM TOGETHER
ONE LAST TIME.
ALICE?
OH, SWEETIE!
LARRY!
LARRY, SHE'S HOME.
I THOUGHT I WAS
A DEAD MAN.
BUT HE SAID THINGS
ABOUT LOVE AND FORGIVENESS,
THINGS I WAS ONLY
BEGINNING TO UNDERSTAND.
SOMEONE HEARD
THAT SHERYL HAD RUN AWAY.
MRS. CARPENTER
SWORE SHE SAW HER IN MANHATTAN
WITH AN OLDER MAN.
MRS. ROSSI SAID SHE HAD
AN ABORTION IN MEXICO
AND WAS LIVING
IN EL PASO.
BUT I GOT A POSTCARD
FROM SALT LAKE CITY.
SHERYL SAID THAT
THEY WERE HEADING WEST,
AND SO FAR,
THINGS WERE GOING FINE.
AND BY THE WAY,
SHE HOPED I HAD
BURIED MY RECORD
AND I SHOULDN'T DIG IT UP
FOR 50 YEARS.
HEY, ALICE.
HEY, MAX.
IT'S MICKEY.
OH.
HEY, I HEARD
YOU RAN AWAY.
YEAH.
FOR TWO WHOLE DAYS?
MM-HMM.
THAT'S COOL.
YOU KNOW,
I'M NOT COUPLED UP
WITH KATHRYN ANYMORE.
I DIDN'T KNOW
YOU WERE STEADIES.
WELL, WE WEREN'T.
I MEAN...NOT REALLY.
I LIKE HER AND ALL,
BUT HER FEET
WERE KIND OF BIG.
YOU KNOW...
I'M GETTING
A CHEVY COUPE
WHEN I GET OLDER.
A V-8. IN RED.
A CHEVY?
THAT'S NICE.
TAKE YOU OUT
FOR A SPIN SOMETIME.
I MEAN...
IF YOU WANT.
MAYBE.
HEY, NOW.
THE RUSSIANS NEVER DID
INVADE LONG ISLAND,
AND MR. ROSSI TURNED OUT
TO BE ALL WRONG
ABOUT SEEING SPUTNIK
FLYING OVER HIS BACKYARD.
BUT I LEARNED SOME THINGS
THAT SUMMER,
THINGS I'D NEVER FORGET.
♪ SWEET DREAM BABY
♪ HOW LONG MUST I DREAM?
♪ OOH
♪ DREAM BABY,
GOT ME DREAMIN' SWEET DREAMS ♪
♪ THE WHOLE DAY THROUGH
♪ OOH
♪ DREAM BABY,
GOT ME DREAMIN' SWEET DREAMS ♪
♪ NIGHTTIME, TOO
♪ AHH
♪ I LOVE YOU,
AND I'M DREAMING OF YOU ♪
♪ THAT WON'T DO
♪ DREAM BABY,
MAKE MY SUMMER DREAMIN' ♪
♪ YOU CAN MAKE
MY DREAMS COME TRUE ♪
♪♪ SWEET ♪ SHA DA DA DA
♪ DREAM ♪ SHA DA DA DA
♪ BABY ♪ SHA DA DA DA
♪ SHA DA DA DA
♪ SWEET ♪ SHA DA DA DA
♪ DREAM ♪ SHA DA DA DA
♪ BABY ♪ SHA DA DA DA
♪ SHA DA DA DA
♪ SWEET ♪ SHA DA DA DA
♪ DREAM ♪ SHA DA DA DA
♪ BABY ♪ SHA DA DA DA
♪ SHA DA DA DA
♪ HOW LONG ♪ SHA DA DA DA
♪ MUST I DREAM? ♪ OOH
♪ DREAM BABY, GOT ME
DREAMIN' SWEET DREAMS ♪
♪ THE WHOLE DAY THROUGH
♪ DREAM BABY
♪ DREAM BABY, GOT ME
DREAMIN' SWEET DREAMS ♪
♪ NIGHTTIME, TOO
♪ DREAM BABY
♪ I LOVE YOU,
AND I'M DREAMING OF YOU ♪
♪ THAT WON'T DO
♪ DREAM BABY ♪ DREAM BABY
♪ MAKE MY SUMMER DREAMIN'
♪ YOU CAN MAKE
MY DREAMS COME TRUE ♪
♪ HOW SWEET ♪ AHH
♪ DREAM BABY
♪ UH-HUH
♪ YEAH, SWEET DREAM
♪ AHH
♪ BABY
♪ DREAM BABY
♪ UH-HUH
♪ SWEET DREAM ♪ AHH
♪ BABY ♪ DREAM BABY
♪ UH-HUH
♪ HOW LONG ♪ AHH
♪ MUST I DREAM?
♪ SWEET ♪ AHH
♪ DREAM BABY
♪ DREAM BABY,
UH-HUH ♪
♪ YEAH, SWEET DREAM
♪ AHH
♪ BABY
♪ DREAM BABY
♪ UH-HUH
♪ SWEET DREAM
♪ AHH
♪ BABY
♪ DREAM BABY
♪ UH-HUH
♪ HOW LONG
♪ AHH
♪ MUST I DREAM?
♪ SWEET DREAM
♪ AHH
♪ BABY
♪ DREAM BABY
♪ UH-HUH
♪ SWEET DREAM
♪ AHH
♪ BABY
♪ DREAM BABY
♪ UH-HUH ♪
♪ RULER OF MY HEART
♪ FATHER OF MY SOUL
♪ WHERE CAN YOU BE?
♪ I WAIT PATIENTLY
♪ MY HEART CRIES OUT
♪ PAIN INSIDE
♪ WHERE CAN YOU BE?
♪ I WAIT PATIENTLY
♪ WHEN YOU'RE ALONE
♪ THE GOING GETS ROUGH
♪ COME BACK, COME BACK
♪ COME BACK
♪ I'VE HEARD ENOUGH
♪ MAKE ME YOUR QUEEN
♪ HAPPY AGAIN
♪ HEAR MY CRY
♪ HE'S MY KING
♪ FATHER OF MY SOUL
♪ HEAR MY CRY
♪ PLEASE
♪ OH, PLEASE ♪
CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
WARNER BROS.
CAPTIONING PERFORMED BY
THE NATIONAL CAPTIONING
INSTITUTE, INC.
CAPTIONS COPYRIGHT 1993
REGENCY ENTERPRISES V.O.F. AND
LESTUDIO CANAL +
PUBLIC PERFORMANCE OF CAPTIONS
PROHIBITED WITHOUT PERMISSION OF
NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE