- Oh God
- Hurry!
Step on it
I can`t go any faster
Why not? I `ll kill y ou if you don`t
That`s the speed limit
You`re only going 60
You can go up to 160
That`s the radio
Radio?
Sorry, I `m short-sighted
- Just hurry!
- That way... by the bridge
- Go right?
- Yes, turn here
Hurry!
- What are you doing? Over there!
- Hurry!
You`re too slow! How many in your family?
- 8
- That many?
- Then they can do without you
- Hurry!
That way!
Big brother!
You too?
Boss!
You can join us if y ou do well
Over here!
Slowly...
Stop the car
That way!
That`s my big brother
- Good!
- Don`t forget your bag!
Better notify his family
before it`s too late
He has no family
Any relatives?
Can`t you save him?
Are you a doctor?
All I can do is reduce his pain
That`s all
Thank you
Good!
Wait!
That needle is too much!
I don`t have needles for humans
I `m a vet
Sorry!
There`s a hospital sign...
It says Pet Hospital
Moron!
- Sakuma
- Yes!
- Masa
- Aki
- Yes!
- Hiko
About the successor, I have to tell you
Yes?
Let my nephew take over
Where is he?
His name is...
Koizumi
No classes today?
Today is your father`s funeral
We plan to payour respects
Thank you
You`re alone?
I have no relatives
I`m like an orphan
What about your father`s colleagues?
I didn`t tell any one
He probably wants me to see him off
He must love y ou
Since my mother died
I`m not just his daughter
I took care of him
Like his wife or mother
So I`ll be there to see him off
Clasp your hands
"Sailor Suit and Machine Gun"
Brace yourself!
Work hard!
Come back to school soon
Thank s! You should be getting back
- Bye
I`m all alone now
But...
That`s alright
Who are you?
Are you Koizumi?
Yes, I`am
My name is Mayumi
What do y ou want from me?
Can we go inside?
My father said
I`m not to let strangers in
I`m not a stranger
Takashi taIks about you all the time
Takashi?
Hoshi Takashi is your father
Nice place
Don`t touch that!
I don`t want strangers to touch it
Here...
What is it?
Read it
My father wrote this?
Dear Mayumi,
because I`m a traveling salesman
It`s highly likely I`ll get into
an accident
If anything happens to me, go to my house
and live with my daughter
Koizumi is strong
but she`s also very naive
With her you can share your views in life
Thank you for taking care of her
Bless you- Takashi
Excuse me
What is your relationship with my father?
Is it...
a male-female relationship?
To put it bluntly
Are you...
my father`s mistress?
Stop!
- Tomoo
- Yes!
- Leave quietly if you`re done
- Sorry
Make the nose higher
No, it doesn`t look like it
I can`t do it
You better go home
Look over there
Who are those men?
It`s dangerous!
Bullets may come flying...
Move away... back off
Please leave, it`s dangerous
Move away!
- Back off
-It`s scary!
Back off!
Hurry!
What are they doing?
Nobody knows! That`s what worries me
- Let me go in
- Stay back...
We`ll escort Izumi home
Use the back door
Alright...too crowded up front
No! I want to see...
- Stay back
- Don`t push!
- Where?
- Let me see!
This is the first time
I see the Yakuza at the school
We can`t take the back door
Hurry!
Koizumi
Koizumi come back!
Don`t go! Come back!
Koizumi
Hoshi
- Come back!
Hurry! Come back!
Hoshi
- Come back!
Hoshi Izumi?
We`re here to pick you up
Go!
- Move aside
- Open the door
Please go upstairs
Gang of Medaka?
That`s the Yakuza
Gang of Medaka existed before the war
Nothing like the so-called gangs
these days
4th generation
Successor...
Hoshi Izumi
Excuse me...
My name is also Hoshi Izumi
Yes, that`s you
Please let me explain
My father is a blood relation?
Your father was named successor
We went through great trouble to find him
But he died in a car accident
We went to the crematory
and you were the only one there
That`s why...
- You chose me?
- Right!
If his nephew can`t take over
We were supposed to find his
lineal relative
Please accept...
Wait a minute!
You are...
You`re being reckless!
Listen to me
I`m an ordinary high school girl
Don`t worry!
Age and gender is not an issue
But...
It`s impossible!
I can`t do it!
I`m not capable...
There`s a first time for everything
You can earn your experience
What experience?
Fighting, gambling...
Murder? That kind of experience?
No way
I refuse
You must be kidding
You leave us no choice
We give up
This has turned into a farewell party
- Hiko, pass the wine
- Yes
Aki, get ready
We`ll settle our score with the
Matsunoki Gang
Before we disband, we must put on
a good show
- Prepare to die
- Yes!
Will you come to the farewell party?
But...
If you`re dismissed
Why do you still have to fight?
It`s the 4 of us against 40
There were a lot of you outside
the school
Big Brother found them
They`re on loan from other gangs
There`s only 4 of us left
It`s time to disband
Dismissed!
- Let`s go
- Yes!
Let`s do it!
- Wait!
- Let`s go!
Hold on!
Please wait!
I forbid you to fight
You can`t go!
This does not concern you,
you`re not the Boss
I...
I accept
Miss...
That`s why...
I forbid you to fight
Miss...
Shall appreciate
if you address me as Boss
Boss!
Pass the wine cups
- Hurry!
- Yes!
That`s a hang over
Please, not so loud!
My head is pounding
I called in sick for you
Thank you
You made such a scene at the school
that day
Every one thought you have been kidnapped
You must eat!
Or your breasts won`t grow
They`re big enough!
You`re in a bad mood?
No!
I just don`t know
what my father saw in you
I`m curious
You`re not very pretty
and not particularly smart
In that case...
It must be your body
That must be it
I`m sure of it
You`re silly
How much did you drink?
Wine cups of this size
I had 5
I`m the Boss, I had to drink
You`re in trouble!
Gang of Medaka is a real gang
Yes!
You know about them?
I heard of them in my degenerate days
I`m so worried
I`m sorry you had to do this
We have to say hello! Where are we going?
What?
Where are we going?
To meet with the Boss of
Gang of Hamaguchi
That`s the biggest gang in this
neighborhood
What a pain!
I don`t know any gang etiquette
I must not offend any one
All gangs have a front these day s
The boss is alway s a chairman of
some company
What`s on the roof?
Graves
Do we alway s have to wait this long?
Be patient!
We can`t survive if we offend them
Is the Boss in?
Please wait!
Who is that?
That`s Sekine of Gang of Matsunoki
Gang of Matsunoki?
Were you supposed to fight them?
They`re affiliated with the
Gang of Hamaguchi
That`s why they moved in on our turf
Is that Sakuma?
Long time no see
How are you?
Fine!
I see
This is our Boss
You must be kidding!
I `m the new Boss of Gang of Medaka!
Nice to meet you
Nice to meet you, listen to that
Are you running an amusement park,
Sakuma?
You expect this littIe girl
to run the gang?
Can`t even sell her to the bath houses
Go home and change diapers
Say that again!
You`re dead if you make fun of her again
Don`t get mad, Sakuma
I`m just kidding
Hey, look again
You`re quite cute!
How sweet!
- What the hell...!
- You little bitch!
- What the hell...
- Wait!
Sekine
Come see me. Also invite our guests
from Gang of Medaka
Yes!
I like you
You have guts and you`re cute
You deserve to be the Boss
I really Iike you
Boss!
Stop it!
Gang of Matsunoki has taken over
our turf, I want it back
Is this for real?
This is a gift from boss of
Gang of Hamaguchi
This is great!
A toast to the Boss!
Dodge!
Here it comes again!
Are y ou alright?
We haven`t had so much fun
in a long time
I`m so happy
It must be hard on you
Don`t say that! This is a new beginning
- Exactly! Don`t cry!
- Boss!
Yes, this is a new beginning!
Attention!
Brace yourselves! Gangsters don`t cry!
Understand?
Yes!
Cheers!
What happened?
Machine guns
- Hiko, get the stuff
- What stuff?
Weapons!
Aki, get the weapons!
- Get it
- Sure!
Withdraw from school?
Koizumi
We`ll sign a petition for you
Don`t be discouraged!
Hoshi Izumi?
Yes, I`am
I`m Detective Kuroki from Shinjuku
- Police?
- Yes
- You`re here about y esterday?
- Yesterday?
No?
I`m here about your father
My father?
He was killed by a car at the airport
when he came back from a business trip
Is that right?
He was dead when the Police called me
Actually, I think he Iost control
of the car
and crashed into a tow truck
You`re saying...
My father is murdered?
- He work s for a trading company?
- Yes
- Does he travel much?
- All the time
Did he bring home any gifts?
Something about this big?
Like that? Did he have it?
No!
What are you trying to find out?
Most murder cases at the airport
involve smuggling
Smuggling?
You think my father is a smuggler?
That`s impossible! You must be joking
I apologize
We must check out every one
It`s not a popular job
Please believe me
- I don`t think your father is involved
- Goodbye!
I was at your house, there was a woman
Who is she?
You mean Mayumi?
She`s a relative,
I`m afraid to live alone
Is something wrong?
I have seen her picture.
She`s wanted by the police
Her real name is Tsuchida Koumi
She`s wanted for theft, prostitution
Maybe I`m mistaken! Goodbye!
You gave me a scare!
I just arrived at the station
and I heard you called 110
Sorry!
My goodness!
This is the work of a professional
I don`t suppose you`ll find finger prints
What`s the name of that woman?
She`s gone
This is what I found when I came home
Strange! Is she really a relative?
She has a letter from my father
He wanted me to live with her
That`s weird!
Look at this mess!
They didn`t take anything,
isn`t that weird?
They`re not after money
CouId she have done this?
She must be looking for something
But she didn`t find it
If she did, she didn`t have to do this
Right?
You`re very sharp!
That`s what I think too
What are they looking for?
Perhaps...drugs
Drugs?
He`s just kidding
You`re scaring us
Sorry! I `m telling the truth
He`s probably jealous
and he lied! He wanted to kill that guy
He didn`t expect him to be a cop
- She`s so cute!
- Are you in love now?
Of course not!
- You`re blushing!
- Come here!
You`re serious?
- Who do you think you are?
- Come back!
What a fool!
Listen...cheer up
It`s frustrating to see you like this
- Have a drink!
- Come on!
No, they`re underage
You must drink!
Drink up!
Hurry!
Hurry...
Alright...
Good!
I`ll drink it
Excellent...
What did I tell you...
That hurts... I`m going to die
Like hell you are!
I`m still a virgin, I don`t want to die
Virgin?
I`m too far from that
- Over here!
- Aki
At the bath house when I was in
junior high
You`re weird! A fool
- Yeah!
- What about you?
You were a rapist
Shut up! How dare you make fun of me!
Don`t lose your heads
You ruined my mood! Really!
We`ll be careful
We have to go, Koizumi
We have to go!
Sure!
You can stay with me, I have extra rooms
No, thanks
Why?
No reason! I want some fun
I don`t want to be alone
If I`m alone, I `ll be bored to death
I`ll be like this...
For a girl
I don`t want people to see me like this
I see...
I don`t want you to know me
That`s the difference between the sexes
You won`t understand
Koizumi
Thanks! Good night
Good night!
Go home and get to bed, kid
You`re crazy!
- Hiko
- What?
Could you give me a ride on a motor bike?
Motor bike?
Let the wind blow away my troubles
Sure, no problem
Aki, the Boss thinks she`ll go crazy
tonight
What does that mean?
I don`t know!
Stop! It`s me!
You`ll get yourself killed!
Look! It`s me!
- How are you?
- Get down...
I need that
- Give me the bike
- Sure
Please get on, Boss
- Get her a helmet!
- Come on...
Here...try this!
Perfect!
Hold on! Here we go!
Move it!
- Let`s go!
- Move it!
I`m cold
Boss
What is it?
The rain on my back
My shirt is wet. I`ll catch a cold
It`s alright
It stopped raining
What? It stopped?
Yes!
It feels good
I`ll speed up
- Hiko
- Yes?
Why did you join the gang?
No reason!
You must answer me... in 100 words
I can`t find anything I want to do
I hate school... I hate work even more
It`s a natural move from the
motorbike gang
It`s the only way out
Here...
Is there any order to this?
Yes, red one in the middle
Red... red in the middle
Good morning!
- Good morning!
- Morning!
Morning!
What are you doing?
Redecorating for you
- Coffee?
- Yes
Here!
Aki did this, Boss! He has good taste
Excellent...
I used to be a painter
We have money to renovate?
Thanks to you, we`re making money
Your coffee, Boss
You want it here or at your desk?
Enjoy your coffee, Boss
Come!
Milk, Boss?
Please!
Where is Hiko?
You don`t know where he is?
I haven`t seen him
since he took me home last night
He`s like a bullet
He doesn`t come back
I`ll get it
Hello?
Who was it?
Some man
- He said the goods are on the stairs
- What goods?
- I`ll check
- Alright!
Here you go, Boss!
I don`t suppose it`s a bomb
- After the machine gun?
- I don`t think so
Aki
Hiko
Gang of Matsunoki did this!
The shootout was a warning.
Now he killed us one by one
Hiko, we`ll avenge you
Shooting at us on our turf
and now they killed one of us!
I`ll handle this
I can`t just stand by and watch!
This is not a joke
Boss...
Why are you acting like this?
Stop yelling! Don`t you ever listen?
Boss...
Damn! This is messed up!
- Wait!
- What are you doing?
Let me go!
- Boss...
- Let go of me
Boss!
You have a lot of nerve
I hope to talk to you as one boss
to another
One of my men was killed
You know about this?
Yes
That`s why I`m here
I believe you`re behind this
Cut this nonsense!
Listen to me, littIe girl
I ordered the shooting
But...
since the chief gave his order
We laid off you and your men
The cops are watching
Giving me a lot of trouble
Do you understand?
Yes!
I just want to make sure
Goodbye!
Wait!
Teach this naive little girl
a good lesson
Yes, sir!
Come on!
Come here!
- Come here!
- Quiet!
Move it!
Your clothes are dirty
Up to her head!
How`s the water temperature?
I `d like to take a bath too!
Hello? Sekine speaking!
What? You have Akira?
Help me, Father!
If there`s even a scratch on my Boss
your idiotic son is history
Tell him again!
Father!
Don`t die on me! I need you
Say it...
Help!
Stop!
The Boss says to stop
Stop it!
Hold it!
Let her down!
Hurry!
Put her down!
Have you heard of Fatso?
Fatso?
His real name is Sandaiji Ichi,
another Yakuza boss
What about him?
Only he`s capable of such brutality
But why?
For drugs
Fatso is alway s into big drug deals
I think he`s after your father`s drugs
He turned your flat upside down
and couldn`t find it
So he tortured Hiko
But I don`t have any drugs
It should be there
Or else Fatso won`t be involved
Boss
You must be careful
Don`t do anything reckless
Reckless?
For example going to
Gang of Matsunoki alone
I did it for Hiko
Someone killed him
- Aren`t you upset?
- Of course I`am
But that`s different for me
No one can replace y ou
You`re heartless!
I can`t believe you`re Iike this
Hello?
Hoshi residence
Who is this?
Koizumi?
Speaking
It`s me, Mayumi
Long time no see! I don`t know
what to say
How are you?
I`m fine
Good!
Did you want something?
I ran into a bit of trouble
You must wonder why I disappeared
That`s why I`m calling
You seem to be doing alright
Not really
Nothing is going the way I want
Really?
You sound depressed