#What shall l do today
(What shall we do today)#
What shall l do#
#l could start a new adventure#
#By jumping on my bed#
#l could wahe up Mr. Nilsson#
#Carry horse above my head#
#l could dance the schottische#
#Spread magic everywhere#
#l could skate around the k_' chen#
#Flip pancakes in the air#
#We'll do handsprings in the classroom
We'll do anything l want#
#Villa Villehulla is waiting for us#
#What shall l do today
(What shall we do today)#
What shall l do#
#What shall l do today#
#What shall we do today#
#What shall l do today
What shall l do#
What was that?
Well, Fridolf, we made it.
This is where l get off.
When you find father
be sure to tell him
l'll be waiting
at Villa Villekulla.
Ta ta, eveyone!
Bye.
You'll have to wave for me
Mr. Nilsson.
l haven't got enough hands.
The wind's died.
Can you give us a start, Pippi?
She... she... she...horse... blew...
There.
Now it's my turn to ride.
Here l come, Mr. Nilsson.
l know. Let's go home, Horse.
They certainly know how to sleep around
here, don't they, Mr. Nilsson?
Now, let's see.
l think this is the way.
ARer all, we were only here once
and that was a long, long time ago.
Now that's not a snore.
Maybe there is someone up.
Look out!
Oh, dear.
You really should be more careful.
You never know when you
might bump into a horse.
- What? l might...
- Or a hippopotamus.
What if l'd been riding a hippo
instead of a horse?
- Just think about that.
- Will you be quiet!
l've never heard such
nonsense in my life!
l hope you're not one ofthose girls
who talks back to grown-ups.
We can always hope.
Disgraceful.
Where are you going
at this hour, an_ay?
To Villa Villekulla.
Is this the right way?
There's a sign right there!
Or are you too busy
bumping into people to read?
Does that say Ville Villekulla?
l thought it started with a ''Q''.
Ridiculous!
Oh, go away!
Out of my sight!
l have to finish
my morning exercise.
Come on, Horse.
l think she's angy about something.
Heavens, what a dreadful creature.
Now where's my hat?
What? How?
That animal!
That animal ate my new hat!
Wait! Stop!
Stop that horse!
You haven't heard
the last ofthis, my little
well, whatever you are!
lf l remember correctly
we should be there
Just about now.
l guess Mr. Nilsson remembers,
wouldn't you say, Horse?
Now you have a nice game
of croquet.
lt's really a lot of fun.
lt is not! It's...
Boring!
lt's the most boring game
in the histoy ofthe world!
And this is the most
boring place to live!
Nothing interesting
ever happens here!
Nothing.
We should have refused to
move all the way out here.
Right.
We should go on
strike right now!
Right!
A sit down strike.
You know what?
This is boring, too.
l know.
Four-three-mo-one!
Huh?
Who was that?
She must have moved
into that old house.
Come on!
Four-three-mo-one!
Why are you walking backwards?
lt's a free county, isn't it?
Huh?
Who says l can't walk
backwards if l want to?
An_ay, in Egypt eveyone
walks backwards,
and nobody even notices.
They think it's hysterically funny
when somebody walks forwards.
You've been to Egypt?
l've been almost eveywhere.
Sometimes mice.
Speaking ofwalking,
did you know that in India
they all walk on their hands?
Even when they're
playing hopscotch?
No way. That's not true!
No, it isn't.
You shouldn't tell stories.
No, l shouldn't.
But what else can you expect from
a girl who has no mother
and whose father is a sea captain
who was lost in a storm at sea?
Was he really?
He certainly was.
But l know he'll
come back one day.
That's why he bought
Villa Villekulla for me
to wait for him
ifwe ever got separated.
By the way, my name is
Pippilotta Delicatessa Windowshade
Mackrelmint Efraims
Daughter Longstocking?
but you can call me Pippi
Pippi Longstocking.
and this is Mr. Nilsson.
l'm Tommy, and this is Annika.
We live right over there.
Delighted to meet you.
Would you like to
come for a visit?
Yes!
Stop!
You can't come for a visit
ifyou're already here.
You have to go away first.
But don't wory.
l'll be here when you get back.
Goodbye for now.
Four-three-mo-one!
Look!
That's a horse!
Why does she keep
horse on the verandah?
Well, he doesn't like the parlour.
And he'd be in the way
in the kitchen.
But never mind Horse
come on in.
Breakfast is almost ready.
Pippi, you're all white!
l am?
Oh, that's not me.
That's flour. See!
Now, let's have breakfast.
l think they're done
so here they come!
Look out!
Pancakes, anyone?
l always have one pancake
for the road.
There's nothing like pancakes
on horseback,
don't you find?
Um, l guess.
l hope you won't be sory
you came to live here.
Why should l be?
It looks vey nice so far.
Because it's so boring
that's why.
Nothing exciting ever happens here.
Never?
Never.
Until now, that is!
Hury!
Can't he go any faster?
He can go like lightning
when he wants to.
When's that?
Not vey oRen, l'm afraid.
lt would be quicker ifwe got off.
Were going on ahead, Horse.
See you later.
l said l'll take that ball.
You don't mind, do you, kid?
No, he doesn't mind.
Yeah, he likes getting beat up.
Guys, come on.
lt's my ball!
lt's that bully Bengt.
Why doesn't he pick on
someone his own size.
lt's mine!
Not anymore, it ain't.
lf he wants a ball
he should buy his own.
Pippi, wait! Don't get near him!
Yes, he's really mean!
Excuse me,
but do you think
you're being fair?
Well, well, what have we here?
Look, you guys,
the circus must be
selling off its old clothes.
Or else she's one ofthe clowns.
You are a girl, aren't you?
Look at that hair!
That's the dumbest looking hair
l ever saw.
Sure it's not red straw?
Hey! Hey!
Put me down!
Do something! Help!
Put me down! Help!
l... l don't... see ya later!
He won't take your ball again.
Will you?
And don't forget it, Bengt
Look who finally caught up.
Come on, eveyone
Iet's finish our ride.
Get me outta here!
Did you hear something?
lt was probably the wind.
Quiet, please! One at a time.
What exactly happened?
First of all, this wild child
bumped right into me
and almost knocked me down.
Right.
That would mean an illegal bumping
into people complaint form.
l saw her liR up a whole horse.
With one hand.
Right. illegal liRing of horses form.
She liRed me up, too!
And people.
And threw me up a tree!
lllegal tree throwing form.
No, wait...
lllegal throwing people
into trees form.
And she keeps a monkey!
lllegal possession of monkey form.
Where is that one?
Use mine.
Thank you.
No, wait a second
this is for cheetahs.
lsn't that what you said?
No, monkeys!
No, monkeys?
So what do we need a form for?
And she filled the sails
with one breath.
lllegal sail filling form.
And the branch where
she hung me broke
and l fell down and really got hurt!
lllegal branch breaking form.
Anything else?
Yes! Her horse ate my new hat!
Horse hat eating form.
That's enough forms!
Just do something! Immediately!
All in good time.
Now, let's get this straight.
As l see it ...
We're looking for a strangely dressed
little girl with gigantic pigtails...
Who's so strong
she can liR horses.
And blow ships on their way.
And so tall she can
hang teenagers on trees.
And lives in the jungle
with wild animals.
And eats plants for breakfast.
ls that right, now?
ldiots.
She's nothing like that!
She's just sort of like a...
Like a little girl in funny clothes
that's all.
Just a little girl?
All this fuss over a little girl?
l think we can handle
a little girl, don't you, Klang?
l'd say we can have this case
wrapped up before lunch, Kling .
Wait here.
This is police business.
Right.
Children!
Bye, Pippi
See you aRer lunch.
l will look forward to it.
Unless l decide to take a six month
caravan to Afghanistan, of course.
No, you're right, Horse.
We still have unpacking to do.
Phew.
You do it for a while.
My head hurts.
So does mine.
An_ay, that's
Villa Villekulla up there.
There's a horse on the verandah?
We have to put away father's
gold coins, Mr. Nilsson.
Now let's see...
There. Right in the middle.
That way we'll always
be able to see it.
There's someone at the door!
Our first surprise caller!
l'm so glad to see you.
How nice ofyou to call.
Are you the little girl
who just moved in here?
Why, yes, l am and you are
my vey first guests.
Um, we'd like to
speak to your parents.
Oh, l'm afraid l don't have any...
not at the moment, an_ay.
But that's illegal.
Children without parents must
live in the children's home.
That's all right then.
l already do.
ARer all, l'm a child
and this is my home,
so this must be a children's home.
But, uh...
Never mind, Klang.
We'll explain to
the little girl when we...
Take her in!
Missed me that time.
But don't give up! Keep tying!
Hey!
You come down here!
You come up here.