前门‎
字幕制作：葫芦        Q群：491019388
你的名字是罗伊·费里曼
住在曼森大道东213号‎
生于1964年3月23日‎
不要喝酒
周三记得丢垃圾
接电话没关系‎
长官特别嘉许 警员罗伊·费里曼‎
厨房 浴室‎
社会安全号码165839170
鞋码11号‎
冷冻肉品放这‎
饥饿人无骨炸鸡‎
从纸盒取出 把托盘放进微波炉‎
微波4分半 撕开包装 小心烫 ‎
Fuck‎
卧 槽
你罹患了阿兹海默症
你的医生是梅塔医生‎
<i>Name three objects in this room.</i>‎
说出房间内的三个东西‎
Chair, lamp, clock‎
椅子 灯 时钟‎
Three objects not in this room‎
说出房间内没有的三个东西‎
Whisky bottle airplane, racehorse‎
威士忌酒瓶 飞机 赛马‎
Fuck‎
该死‎
Today's date - Thursday‎
今天的日期？‎
星期四‎
The date not the day of the week‎
我问日期 不是星期几‎
Um..‎
呃…‎
September. Sep..‎
九月‎
How about the year?‎
年份呢？‎
<i>What's your city of birth?</i>‎
你出生的城市是？‎
<i>Do you remember your mother's name?</i>‎
还记得你母亲的名字吗？‎
<i>How about your father?</i>‎
父亲呢？‎
『 沉 睡 猎 犬 』
<i>This is an experimental procedure.</i>‎
这只是试验程序‎
<i>Electrodes will send impulses</i>‎
电极会将脉冲‎
<i>to the target areas in your brain.</i>‎
传送到您大脑的目标区域‎
<i>New neural pathways should develop,</i>‎
刺激新的神经通路生长‎
but the results can be a little less predictable‎
但结果可能较难预测‎
especially given your history of substance abuse‎
尤其你的药物滥用史‎
a common trigger for Alzheimer's‎
是阿兹海默症的常见诱因‎
未知来电‎
Hello‎
喂？‎
<i>Is this Roy Freeman?</i>‎
是罗伊·费里曼吗？‎
你的名字是罗伊·费里曼‎
<i>Hello?</i>‎
喂？‎
Yeah <i>Um, my name is Emily Dietz.</i>‎
我是‎
我叫艾蜜莉·狄耶兹‎
<i>I work with the Clean Hands Project.</i>‎
我是净手专案的人员‎
Clean Hands Project?‎
净手专案？‎
<i>Yes!</i>‎
是的‎
<i>We are a legal action nonprofit</i>‎
我们是法律诉讼的非营利组织‎
<i>and we advocate for inmates</i>‎
专门为被体制剥夺权利的囚犯‎
<i>who have been disenfranchised by the system.</i>‎
提供辩护服务‎
Okay‎
好‎
方便见个面吗？‎
<i>Would you have a few minutes to speak?</i>‎
Yeah‎
可以‎
What's this about?‎
有什么事吗？‎
<i>It's... regarding an old case of yours.</i>‎
是关于您的一桩旧案‎
3:30
艾蜜莉·狄耶兹‎
“净手专案”
Emily Dietz‎
艾蜜莉·狄耶兹‎
Mr. Freeman? - Ms. Dietz‎
费里曼先生？‎
狄耶兹小姐‎
Oh. Hi‎
你好 叫我艾蜜莉‎
- Emily - Emily‎
I really appreciate you meeting with me‎
-艾蜜莉 -谢谢你愿意见我‎
No problem‎
别客气‎
You said it was about uh, an old case, huh?‎
你说这和我的一桩旧案有关？‎
Yes, sir. Isaac Samuel‎
是的 艾萨克·山谬‎
Isaac Samuel?‎
艾萨克·山谬？‎
Um... I... I'm sorry I-I don't, uh..‎
抱歉 我不太…‎
Oh. Of course‎
没关系‎
I'm sure you've seen more cases‎
你经手的案子肯定很多‎
than you care to remember‎
记不得也很正常‎
Yeah. Something like that‎
算是吧‎
He was convicted in the Joseph Wieder murder‎
他因十年前沃特福大学的‎
将对杀人凶手执行注射死刑
乔瑟夫·维德谋杀案被定罪
at Waterford College ten years ago‎
and is scheduled to be executed‎
预计于下个月底执行死刑‎
end of next month‎
我们曾请愿州长暂缓执行‎
We've tried to get a stay from the governor‎
但成效不佳‎
but it's not looking good‎
Okay‎
嗯‎
I don't recognize him‎
我不认得他了‎
What's he got to do with me?‎
所以他跟我有什么关系？‎
Mr. Samuel requested to speak with the detectives‎
山谬先生想和他认罪当晚‎
who had interrogated him the night of his confession‎
讯问他的警探谈一谈‎
I interrogated him?‎
我曾讯问过他？‎
And I have yet to locate your former partner‎
但我找不到你的前搭档‎
What does he want to talk about?‎
他想谈什么？‎
I'm afraid he didn't say‎
很遗憾 他并未透露‎
That's something that you will have to ask him yourself‎
恐怕你得亲自问他了‎
华盛顿县警局‎
受害者头部大量出血‎
遭受钝器重击‎
多次击打‎
未寻获凶器‎
Isaac Samuel?‎
艾萨克·山谬？‎
Yeah‎
对‎
I'm Roy Freeman I used to be a detective‎
我是罗伊·费里曼 一名退休警探‎
I've been told you wanted to see me‎
听说你想见我‎
- Yeah? - Yeah‎
-是吗？ -是‎
Okay‎
好‎
Well, here I am‎
所以我来了‎
How are you doing?‎
你好吗？‎
Oh, you know I'm blessed, Roy‎
罗伊 我过得可幸福了‎
Ten years three hots and a cot‎
十年光阴 三顿热餐和一张窄床‎
member of the death row book club‎
还是死囚读书俱乐部的会员‎
Prison got my body but Allah got my spirit‎
监狱能囚禁我的身体 但阿拉会解放我的灵魂‎
Like you give a fuck how I'm doing‎
少一副假惺惺的模样了‎
I see‎
好吧‎
So, this lady uh... Emily Dietz‎
那位女士…‎
净手专案的艾蜜莉·狄耶兹‎
from the Clean Hands Project‎
she told me you wanted to talk to me‎
她说你想和我谈谈‎
Is that what you wanted to say?‎
你想说的就是这些？‎
No, you're here 'cause I want to know how it feels‎
不 我要你来 是因为我想知道‎
to know an innocent man is gonna be put to death‎
看着无辜的人冤死 你会有什么感觉‎
Right‎
好哦‎
And, uh... you are the innocent man?‎
所以你是无辜的？‎
Yeah‎
对‎
Don't get me wrong, Roy‎
罗伊 别误会我的意思‎
I'd done some bad shit made some bad decisions‎
我干了很多坏事 也做过不少傻事‎
but killing Joe Wieder ain't one of them‎
但我绝对没杀乔瑟夫·维德‎
Isaac..‎
艾萨克…‎
you confessed‎
你认罪了‎
You were brought in for questioning‎
你接受了讯问 并且认罪了‎
and you confessed‎
So now you're telling me all this time later‎
所以你是说 经过了这么久‎
suddenly you remember things different?‎
你突然想起了不同的真相？‎
Ain't nothing sudden about it‎
并不是突然‎
I've been in here ten years Ten fucking years‎
他妈的 我在这里蹲十年了‎
Nothing to do but replay that shit in my head‎
什么也做不了 只能想着那段凄惨回忆‎
- How it really went down - Right‎
-回想事发经过 -好吧‎
That's why I'm here‎
所以我来了‎
So you can tell me how it really went down‎
告诉我究竟发生了什么事‎
Look, I know you ain't no cop no more‎
听着 我知道你已经退休了‎
the way they shit-canned you‎
因为那起酒驾事故‎
over that drunk-driving accident‎
他们就把你开除了‎
but maybe you want to clear your conscience‎
但也许你会想告慰自己的良心‎
At least hear me out.. this time‎
至少 听我一次吧‎
就一次‎
I'm listening‎
说吧 我在听‎
Night of the murder‎
谋杀案当晚‎
I was so strung out I ain't remember shit‎
我嗑多了 什么也不记得了‎
<i>You guys hammered me all night.</i>‎
你们整晚不停质问我‎
<i>By the time I saw those photos, I was so fucked up</i>‎
看到那些照片 想说我完蛋了‎
<i>I thought I must have done it.</i>‎
我心想 这一定是我干的好事‎
You broke in you beat him to death‎
你闯了进去 把人给打死了‎
We found your fingerprints all over the house‎
屋内到处都是你的指纹‎
Come on‎
好了‎
Just admit it, son. Admit it‎
乖乖认罪吧 小子‎
就是你干的 你就是凶手‎
This was you. This was you You did this! This is you‎
This is all fucking you‎
全是你干的‎
Admit it‎
给我认罪‎
好吧‎
Yeah‎
Why did you go to his house?‎
你为什么要去他家？‎
The year before Wieder got killed‎
在维德被杀害的前一年‎
I got rung up for theft‎
我因为窃盗被举报‎
Formula for my little man‎
对我这种人来说只是日常‎
And Wieder testified as an expert witness for the DA‎
维德以地方检察官的 专家证人身分出庭作证‎
I told the judge I was so high that night‎
我告诉法官我嗑嗨了 脑子不清楚‎
I wasn't thinking straight‎
但维德说 我很清楚自己的作为‎
but Wieder said I knew exactly what I was doing‎
于是他们以成人身分将我定罪‎
So they tried me as an adult‎
You know what it's like to be 18 years old‎
你能想像18岁的孩子‎
and some skinhead's bitch?‎
和一群光头恶棍关在一起 会有多惨吗？‎
Let's just go back over this‎
言归正传吧‎
Wieder testifies against you and gets you prison time‎
维德作证指控 害你入狱‎
You go to his house, it's late at night. You're angry‎
所以当天深夜你潜入他家 挟怨报复‎
You don't like this--I ain't no killer‎
-你不喜欢这家伙 -我没杀人‎
I just wanted my son back‎
我只想要回我儿子‎
想说维德或许能帮上忙‎
and I thought maybe Wieder could help‎
<i>Yeah, I went to his house.</i>‎
所以我去了他家‎
<i>I waited for his caretaker to leave</i>‎
等他家的管理员离开后‎
<i>and I went round the back.</i>‎
我便绕到了屋后‎
<i>I even made it all the way inside.</i>‎
我好不容易才进到屋内‎
Hello, Shadow‎
哈罗 小影子‎
接着有另一个人进来了‎
<i>But then someone else came in.</i>‎
Oh! Back so soon?‎
哦 这么快就回来了？‎
<i>And then shit just went bad.</i>‎
然后情况开始失控‎
I'm sorry‎
对不起‎
<i>I panicked and I left before I could see who it was.</i>‎
我吓得惊慌失措 赶紧逃跑‎
根本没看到是谁‎
[Wieder] No‎
不‎
Okay. So you never touched him‎
所以你根本没碰到他？‎
Uh, but you don't... I'm telling you the truth‎
-但是你… -我说的是真的‎
Okay, Isaac‎
艾萨克 别激动‎
You think I'm lying‎
你觉得我在说谎？‎
Well, ask Richard Finn He'd tell you‎
你去问理查·弗林‎
他会告诉你‎
You're gonna have to remind me‎
你能提醒我一下吗？‎
Um... who-who is Richard Finn?‎
谁是理查·弗林？‎
他在几个月前来见过我‎
He came to see me a few months back‎
He's writing some book about the murder‎
他写了一本关于凶手的书‎
- A book? - Yeah‎
-书？ -对‎
Look, uh Isaac, I just don't see‎
听着 艾萨克‎
我只是不明白这件事和我有什么关系‎
that I'm gonna be in a position to get involved‎
You already involved, Roy This is on you‎
当然有关系 罗伊 全是你的责任‎
You were there when I signed that fucking confession‎
我签下认罪协议时 你也在场‎
Make it right‎
导正这一切‎
I paid for what I did when I was 18‎
18岁犯的错 我已经付出了代价‎
Make this shit right or I'm dead‎
替我平反 否则我就死定了‎
把土司放进这里 按下按钮开始烤‎
热水 冷水‎
<i>The medication can aid synaptic regeneration,</i>‎
这种药物能帮助突触再生‎
但你必须保持头脑运作‎
<i>but you must keep your mind active--</i>‎
<i>books, puzzles, anything to stimulate your brain.</i>‎
书籍 拼图或任何能刺激大脑的东西‎
It was you It was you! Admit it‎
就是你干的 认罪吧‎
You did this! This is you‎
是你干的‎
Well, ask Richard Finn‎
去问理查·弗林吧‎
理查·弗林‎
逮捕记录 艾萨克·山谬‎
调查笔录 理查·弗林‎
警官签字：吉米·雷米斯‎
吉米·雷米斯‎
Hey‎
嗨‎
Roy?‎
罗伊？‎
Yeah‎
是我‎
What the fuck are you doing here?‎
你来这里干什么？‎
I was just in the neighborhood‎
我刚好在附近‎
Come in‎
请进‎
Hey‎
嗨‎
Come in come in, come in‎
快进来‎
Come in, come in‎
请进‎
You know, I can't remember the last time I saw your face‎
上次见面都多久以前的事了‎
There you go, Roy‎
罗伊 给你‎
You know when it was?‎
你还记得是几年前吗？‎
Ahh, it must have been ten years ago‎
肯定有十年了‎
when those fucking sons of bitches took your badge‎
就是那些王八蛋夺走你的警徽时‎
Yeah, I suppose so‎
应该有吧‎
Listen, I hope you're not still carrying around all that shit‎
罗伊 希望你没把那些破事放在心上‎
I mean, we all drank on the job back then‎
谁在值勤时不喝一点呢‎
That accident‎
那起意外…‎
that could have been any one of us‎
谁碰上都不奇怪‎
Cheers‎
干杯‎
What's up? You on the wagon or something?‎
怎么？你戒酒了是吧？‎
Uh... well, yeah‎
算是吧‎
My-my doctor says it'll mess with my medication, so..‎
医生说会影响我的药物 所以…‎
You're sick, Roy?‎
罗伊 你生病了？‎
不是 比较像是临床试验‎
No. I'm doing, uh like a clinical trial‎
I've got Alzheimer's‎
我得了阿兹海默症‎
so they put these little pulses into my fucking head‎
所以他们把这些该死的小脉冲‎
放进我的脑袋里‎
It's supposed to stimulate memory‎
能帮忙刺激记忆‎
Jesus Christ, Roy‎
天啊 罗伊‎
If you hadn't have said my name at the front door‎
要不是你在前门喊出我的名字‎
I wouldn't have known it was you‎
我根本不记得是你‎
So you..‎
那你…‎
you have no memory of you and me on the job?‎
不记得以前一起工作的事情了吗？‎
- No - Fuck‎
-不记得了 -靠‎
我看了以前的案件资料‎
No, I-I read old case files‎
and it's all fresh information for me‎
对我来说就像新的案件‎
Yeah, but it's not just my time on the job‎
而且不只是工作‎
感觉我的人生一片空白 我…‎
My whole fucking life is a black hole. I..‎
Fuck, man‎
太惨了‎
Remember Cat?‎
还记得凯特吗？‎
My wife‎
我太太‎
Anyway, she, uh..‎
总之 她…‎
she passed last year‎
去年过世了‎
Cancer‎
因为癌症‎
- I'm sorry - Yeah‎
-节哀 -嗯‎
Fucking cancer‎
该死的癌症‎
Department health fund‎
警察健康基金‎
wouldn't pay her hospital bills‎
不愿意负担她的住院费用‎
I had to sort it out‎
我只好另寻他法‎
Anyway, you didn't come here for that shit‎
算了 你来也不是为了听这些‎
What brings you by, Roy?‎
罗伊 是什么风把你吹来？‎
Okay. Uh... you remember a guy called Isaac Samuel?‎
你还记得那个艾萨克·山谬吗？‎
He got convicted for murder‎
他被指控谋杀‎
that thing that happened at Waterford College‎
沃特福大学教授的那起案件？‎
with a professor?‎
Ahh. You've been talking to the lady‎
哦 那名倡议团体的女士也找上你了‎
from the advocacy group‎
I didn't call her back‎
我没有回电给她‎
Oh, well, I took the call‎
我接了电话‎
and, uh, she said that Isaac wanted to talk to me, so..‎
她说艾萨克想和我谈谈 于是…‎
You spoke to Isaac Samuel?‎
你跟艾萨克·山谬谈过了？‎
Yeah. I went down to the state prison‎
对 我去了州立监狱‎
and we talked and, uh..‎
跟他谈了一下…‎
he tells me he didn't do it‎
他说不是他干的‎
Come on, Roy. That's what they all say on death row‎
拜托 罗伊‎
死刑犯都是这样说的‎
Yeah, I know, I know‎
我知道‎
But I gotta say, Jimmy he was... convincing‎
但是吉米 他的话很有说服力‎
He mentioned another guy that came to see him. Uh..‎
他提到有另一个人也来找过他 叫…‎
Finn‎
弗林‎
Richard Finn‎
理查·弗林‎
Does that name ring any kind of bell with you?‎
你听过这个名字吗？‎
It was so long ago I-I-I don't remember..‎
那么久的事 我…‎
我不记得了‎
Well, I read the file‎
我读过资料‎
and when we dusted that house‎
我们调查那间房子时‎
Finn's prints are all over the place inside‎
屋内到处都是弗林的指纹‎
All through the house‎
整间屋子都是‎
So?‎
那又怎样？‎
They were there. Who cares?‎
就算有指纹又怎样？‎
Richard Finn said he wasn't at the house‎
理查·弗林说谋杀案当晚他人不在屋里‎
the night of the murder‎
That's in his statement, okay?‎
那是他的供词内容‎
But we never followed it up‎
但我们从没追查过‎
We never corroborated his whereabouts‎
也从未证实过他的行踪‎
and I just kinda found that a bit strange‎
我只是觉得这很奇怪‎
Is that not strange?‎
难道不是吗？‎
What's your point?‎
你想说什么？‎
I don't know‎
我不知道‎
I was just thinking that you and me‎
我只是在想‎
we'd maybe go and talk to him‎
也许你能和我一起去找他‎
see what he has to say for himself‎
看看他怎么解释‎
- Why? - I don't know‎
为什么？‎
我不知道 只是直觉‎
It's just a feeling‎
我这几天一直在调查这件事‎
That's all I got to go on these days‎
Besides, my doctor says I gotta keep my mind active‎
而且 医生叫我多动脑‎
so what the fuck, huh?‎
有利无弊 是吧？‎
Sure, Roy‎
当然‎
I'll look into it‎
我会去调查这件事‎
I still got a few friends on the job‎
我还有一些朋友还没退休‎
Okay‎
好‎
I'll be in touch, Roy‎
罗伊 保持联络‎
地方警察因疑似酒驾性命垂危‎
<i>♪ You ♪</i>‎
<i>♪ What do you see? ♪</i>‎
你看见了什么？‎
Ah‎
吉米·雷米斯‎
Yeah <i>I found your boy.</i>‎
什么事？‎
找到人了‎
<i>I found Richard Finn.</i>‎
我找到理查·弗林了‎
The landlady found him when she let the gas man in‎
女房东让瓦斯工进屋时发现了他‎
How did he die?‎
他怎么死的？‎
Overdose. Fentanyl‎
芬太尼 用药过量‎
Only one needle hole‎
只有一个针孔‎
What?‎
什么？‎
He's not much of a junkie‎
他不是毒虫‎
There's no track marks‎
身上也没有抓痕‎
那他就是个菜鸟毒虫‎
So he's a newbie Didn't know what he was doing‎
不知道自己惹了祸‎
- You alright there, Roy? - He was there‎
罗伊 你还好吗？‎
他在‎
At the crime scene‎
他曾到过犯罪现场‎
- Yeah. You said that - No‎
我知道 你说过了‎
不对 不只是他的指纹‎
No, not just his prints‎
He was there the next morning when we were there‎
我们隔天早上到场时 他还待在那里‎
Is this what you're remembering‎
你还记得？‎
seeing him at the crime scene?‎
你在犯罪现场见过他？‎
This guy's prints are at the house. All over it‎
屋内到处都是他的指纹 到处都是‎
He turns up to the crime scene the next morning‎
隔天早上还出现在犯罪现场‎
We talk to him‎
我们询问过他‎
His alibi for the time of the murder‎
谋杀案发生时 他的不在场证明‎
is that he was home alone‎
就是他独自在家‎
And we don't follow it up‎
但我们却没深究‎
We don't talk to his friends‎
我们没去问他的朋友‎
we don't talk to his neighbors‎
没去问他的邻居‎
Isaac Samuel's prints were all over the house‎
屋内到处都是艾萨克·山谬的指纹‎
He had motive and he confessed‎
他有明确动机 也认罪了‎
It doesn't make sense‎
这不合理‎
Well, it doesn't matter now The dead don't talk‎
反正也不重要了‎
死人是不会说话的‎
Yeah, maybe‎
也许吧‎
But they do leave shit behind‎
但他们留下了一堆鸟事‎
From ashes to ashes from dust to the dust‎
尘归尘 土归土‎
so it must be‎
再无挂碍‎
Oh, God the spirit of all our joys‎
上帝啊 我们喜乐的精魂‎
the cause of our delights‎
我们雀跃的源泉‎
the glory of our darkest nights‎
至黑之夜的荣耀‎
Uh, Mrs. Finn?‎
弗林太太？‎
My name's Roy Freeman‎
我是罗伊·费里曼 我…‎
I, uh..‎
I understand this is a very bad time‎
我知道现在不是个好时机‎
but can I just ask a couple of questions‎
但是不知道你方不方便回答我‎
about your husband?‎
几个关于你丈夫的问题？‎
Uh... I'm her husband, Eddie‎
呃 我就是她丈夫艾迪‎
Oh, I'm so sorry, Eddie‎
非常抱歉 艾迪‎
Hi. Uh... is the other Mrs. Finn around here somewhere?‎
你好 呃…‎
这里还有其他的弗林太太吗？‎
Uh, no‎
没有了‎
她和理查其实处得不太好‎
She and Richard weren't exactly on the best of terms‎
Now, is there something I can help you with?‎
请问有什么需要帮忙的吗？‎
He was my brother‎
他是我哥哥‎
I'm looking into a case‎
我正在调查一件‎
that your brother was particularly interested in‎
你哥哥之前很感兴趣的案子‎
Recently he went to visit a death row inmate‎
不久前 他曾探望过一名死囚‎
and he mentioned he was actually writing a book‎
并提到他在写一本关于这起事件的书‎
on the subject‎
不知道你是否有听说‎
I wondered if you knew anything about this‎
I'm gonna get a ride home with Aunt Jude‎
那我和裘蒂阿姨一起搭车回家‎
- Yeah - Okay?‎
-好 -可以吗？‎
Okay - Okay‎
-好 -好‎
I'm, uh... just over here‎
我…‎
这边请‎
Here‎
给你‎
I found it in his apartment‎
我在他公寓找到的‎
He called it <i>The Book of Mirrors.</i>‎
他说这是“镜之书”‎
The title doesn't make any sense to me‎
我不懂这个书名的意思‎
<i>Book of Mirrors...</i>‎
“镜之书”…‎
Isaac Samuel that, uh, death row inmate‎
艾萨克·山谬 那名死囚…‎
he said this is about the Wieder murder?‎
他说这和维德有关？‎
Yeah, well if Richard were here‎
对 要是理查还活着‎
he'd probably call it a crime memoir or some shit‎
他可能会称之为犯罪回忆录什么的‎
You read it?‎
你读过了吗？‎
Much as I could stomach‎
勉强读了‎
It's a bunch of self-aggrandizing garbage‎
要我说的话‎
都是些自吹自擂的废话‎
you ask me‎
和他大学时迷恋的女孩有关‎
About some girl he was obsessed with in college‎
So, uh, you guys weren't close?‎
你们的关系不好吗？‎
Look, I don't mean to speak ill of the dead‎
听着 我并不想说死者的坏话‎
but Richard wasn't exactly someone‎
但理查绝对不是那种‎
that you wanted to get close to‎
你会想深交的对象‎
How long had he been using?‎
他用多久了？‎
Drugs?‎
你说毒品？‎
No. No‎
我根本不知道他有吸毒‎
I never knew him to be into drugs‎
It just didn't seem his thing Then again, with Richard‎
很不像他会做的事‎
但是话说回来 理查一直都是难以捉摸的人‎
nothing was ever really how it seemed‎
I mean, he'd always been a little bit off‎
从我们小时候开始‎
even when we were kids‎
他就有点不对劲‎
but this last year last couple of years, even‎
但是这几年 尤其过去几年‎
something just didn't seem right‎
情况变本加厉‎
What was different?‎
有什么变化吗？‎
I don't know. He was..‎
我也不知道 他…‎
agitated, paranoid‎
变得既激动又偏执‎
Just like he comes across in that book‎
正如他在书中的描述‎
Now, listen, if I were you‎
说真的 如果我是你‎
I wouldn't waste too much time on it‎
我不会浪费时间在这玩意上‎
Okay. I can keep this?‎
我能拿走吗？‎
Be my guest‎
请便‎
《镜之书》
作者：理查·弗林
<i>"Memory is a fickle thing.</i>‎
记忆是一种善变的东西‎
<i>What we can recall what we can't.</i>‎
有时能忆起 有时会忘却‎
<i>Rare moments that forever imprint,</i>‎
只有少数时刻能被永远铭记‎
理查·弗林
平庸之事则无法‎
<i>banalities that don't.</i>‎
<i>Sufferings so painful,</i>‎
受难如此痛苦‎
<i>they're buried deep in our mind's recesses,</i>‎
深深埋藏在我们心灵的深处‎
<i>forgotten till time digs it back up.</i>‎
彻底遗忘 直到时间将其发掘‎
<i>Whatever the memory, though-- good, bad, unremarkable--</i>‎
无论是好是坏 抑或是平凡的记忆‎
<i>it never comes back all at once.</i>‎
全都无法一次忆起‎
<i>They're always doled out in fragments</i>‎
总像碎片一样片片飘来‎
<i>like pieces of a puzzle you have to wait to complete."</i>‎
如同拼图般 你只能静候拼图完成‎
<i>"When you'll get another puzzle piece...</i>‎
何时能得到下一片拼图‎
<i>that's anyone's guess.</i>‎
谁也说不准‎
欢迎光临 艺术硕士同学们‎
<i>Months, years could be a decade."</i>‎
几个月 几年 甚至十年‎
理查·弗林‎
Richard Finn‎
正如乔瑟夫·维德的谋杀案‎
<i>"Like it was with the murder of Joseph Wieder.</i>‎
<i>Ten years of never understanding it."</i>‎
十年过去 我仍不明白‎
<i>"Or as I now know misunderstanding it."</i>‎
或者据我现在所知 全搞错了‎
No‎
<i>"And all because of her.</i>‎
全是因为她‎
<i>Laura Baines.</i>‎
萝拉·贝恩斯‎
<i>She was one of those rare unicorns</i>‎
她就是珍稀的独角兽‎
<i>who knew everything about everything."</i>‎
无所不知 无所不晓‎
Nobody made better use of chromatic counterpoint‎
没人比拉赫曼尼诺夫‎
更擅长半音对位法‎
than Rachmaninoff‎
<i>"Double bachelor's in</i>‎
艺术史和神经科学 双学士学位‎
<i>art history and neuroscience."</i>‎
...between lower cortisol levels and their predisposition..‎
较低的皮质醇水平及其倾向之间…‎
<i>"A master's in math."</i>‎
数学硕士‎
The beauty of what Odlyzko showed‎
奥德里兹科所展示的美妙之处‎
is that the distribution..‎
在于分布…‎
<i>"Spoke five languages."</i>‎
会说五种语言‎
俄语‎……
法语‎‎……
日语‎‎……
<i>"She knew exactly who she was.</i>‎
她很清楚自己的本事‎
<i>If only I did back then."</i>‎
如果我当时知道就好了‎
How's the punch?‎
潘趣酒怎么样？‎
The way you've been skulking around‎
你一直在鬼鬼祟祟地‎
waiting for your moment to come and talk to me‎
等待跟我说话的时机到来‎
I figured you'd at least come up with something better than‎
还以为你能想出更好的搭讪台词‎
"How's the punch?"‎
“潘趣酒怎么样？”‎
I wasn't skulking‎
我才没有鬼鬼祟祟‎
Not just skulking Leering too‎
不只鬼鬼祟祟 还色眯眯看着我‎
Oh! Skulking <i>and</i> leering‎
鬼鬼祟祟又色眯眯‎
你把我形容成连环杀手了‎
You're making me sound like I'm a serial killer‎
Well, I can say I knew you when‎
到时候我会说我早就知道了‎
- I'm, uh, Richard - I know‎
我叫理查‎
我知道‎
It's on your chest‎
你胸前有名字‎
Oh. Right‎
也对‎
And yet, uh, here you are‎
但你是…神秘的无名氏‎
nameless and shrouded in mystery. Seems unfair‎
似乎有点不公平‎
"Oh, what's in a name, really?‎
名字有什么重要的？‎
That which we call a rose by any other name."‎
玫瑰如果不叫玫瑰…‎
Oh, great‎
说得好‎
Another bardolater‎
又一个莎士比亚专家‎
So, uh, what's your thesis about?‎
所以你的论文主题是什么？‎
Um... No! Don't tell me‎
-呃… -不‎
-别告诉我 让我猜猜看 -好吧‎
- Let me guess. Okay - Okay‎
Uh... it's probably something controversial‎
应该是某个很有争议的主题‎
- Probably - Yeah‎
-或许吧 -好‎
Okay, "Cross Gender Interference‎
《仲夏夜之梦》中的跨性别干扰‎
in <i>A Midsummer Night's Dream."</i>‎
Boom‎
猜对了？‎
Close‎
差一点‎
"Memory Reconsolidation‎
“透过加速解析疗法进行记忆巩固”‎
Through Accelerated Resolution Therapy."‎
Oh. One of the Bard's lesser known works‎
吟游诗人鲜为人知的作品之一‎
Um..‎
嗯…‎
Psychology department I'm Laura‎
我是心理学系的萝拉‎
What, you just like to crash other departments' mixers?‎
所以 你喜欢乱入其他系的舞会？‎
Oh, uh, no I came with a friend‎
不 我是和朋友一起来的‎
Well, a colleague, really Professor Wieder‎
其实是同事 维德教授‎
I'm helping him with some research‎
我正在帮他做一些研究‎
and he's administering my thesis‎
他负责盯我的论文‎
Right‎
好吧‎
On memory reconstruction‎
你是说透过加速解析疗法 进行记忆重建？‎
through the accelerated reconciliation?‎
是记忆巩固…‎
"Memory Reconsolidation Through..."‎
Yeah, okay‎
好吧 算了‎
抱歉 我可能对你要求太高了‎
No. Sorry. I'm just being hard on you now‎
确实是有点拗口‎
It is a bit of a mouthful‎
How many wishes do you get?‎
你有多少愿望？‎
Oh‎
哦‎
It, uh... It belonged to my grandmother‎
呃 这其实是我奶奶的‎
I read somewhere‎
我曾经读过‎
that, uh, when a woman plays with her jewelry‎
当女人摆弄她的珠宝时‎
it means she's flirting with you‎
代表她在和你调情‎
Oh! Really? Hmm‎
是这样吗？‎
Well, you shouldn't believe everything you read‎
你不该相信你读到的所有内容‎
Okay‎
好吧‎
Choke me‎
掐住我‎
What?‎
什么？‎
Do it‎
掐我‎
Harder‎
用力一点‎
Oh! Oh‎
<i>"From that moment on,</i>‎
从那之后‎
<i>it was like we were inseparable."</i>‎
我们变得形影不离‎
<i>"For the next few months,</i>‎
接下来几个月‎
我们做什么都黏在一起‎
<i>we did everything together.</i>‎
<i>She made me feel like the best version of myself."</i>‎
她让我感觉‎
这是我人生最美好的时刻‎
So... what do you think?‎
所以 你觉得如何？‎
What do I think?‎
我觉得如何？‎
I think you're fucking brilliant, Richard‎
理查 你真是太天才了‎
I mean, other people need to read your work‎
真该让其他人看看你的作品‎
You should send it to.. to <i>Harper's, The Atlantic,</i>‎
你应该把作品寄到 《哈泼杂志》或《大西洋》‎
all the big fiction rags‎
那些大型小说杂志‎
<i>"It was like I was experiencing the world</i>‎
感觉就像是透过她的眼睛‎
<i>for the first time through her eyes."</i>‎
第一次体验这个世界‎
- You're so talented - Thanks‎
-你真有才 -谢谢‎
Just, uh, one second. Sorry‎
抱歉 等我一下‎
妈‎
Hey, Mom‎
嗨 老妈‎
但是 并非一切都称心如意‎
<i>"But not everything was looking rosy."</i>‎
Uh-huh‎
嗯哼‎
和她认识几个月后‎
<i>"A few months after we met,</i>‎
<i>my father died of a heart attack.</i>‎
我父亲就因心脏病去世了‎
<i>My mother couldn't afford my room and board.</i>‎
我妈付不起我的食宿费用‎
<i>Laura wanted to help</i>‎
萝拉想帮我‎
<i>and that's how I first met Professor Joseph Wieder."</i>‎
那也是我第一次遇见乔瑟夫·维德教授‎
Laura. Welcome‎
萝拉？欢迎‎
Uh, sorry we're late‎
抱歉 我们迟到了‎
- Not a problem - Hi‎
-没关系 -你好‎
Hello‎
你好‎
Had to finish a call with our friend in DC, anyway‎
我也刚和华盛顿的朋友讲完电话‎
- Ah! Mm-hm - Mm-mm‎
You must be Richard‎
你一定就是理查‎
Laura's told me a lot about you‎
萝拉经常提到你‎
All lies, I'm sure‎
肯定没一句真话‎
Exaggerations and half-truths‎
夸饰了点 然后半真半假‎
Those I can live with‎
那还可以接受‎
Do we feel like martinis?‎
要来点马丁尼吗？‎
- Sure - Yes‎
-当然 -好‎
So, Richard, Laura tells me you want to be a novelist‎
理查 萝拉说你想当小说家‎
Literary memoir, actually‎
其实是文学回忆录‎
- Mmm - Oh?‎
哦？‎
I'm not familiar‎
这我比较少听到‎
Well, you see‎
是这样的‎
传统的回忆录是描述某人的人生故事‎
a traditional memoir is someone's life story‎
The genre's not concerned with questions of truth‎
这种类型的回忆录不在乎真相‎
imagination, memory, style‎
想像 记忆或风格的问题‎
Literary memoir has a fictional element, then?‎
那么文学回忆录有虚构的成分吗？‎
No, no, I wouldn't call it fictional, really‎
不 我不会称之为虚构‎
- No - Oh. Sorry‎
抱歉‎
No, you see, uh, the author's‎
别在意‎
作者所讲述的是故事的真相‎
telling the truth of the story‎
as he believes it to be true‎
因为他相信这是真的‎
They. As <i>they</i> believe it to be true‎
是他们 他们相信这是真的‎
Self-perception and personal experience‎
其中参杂了自我认知和个人经验‎
have a part in it‎
Okay‎
是啦‎
More wine?‎
再来点酒？‎
- Please - Yes‎
-麻烦了 -好‎
You know something?‎
你知道吗？‎
-抱歉 -我爱你
距今10年后…‎
Ten years from now..‎
we'll look back to this dinner‎
当我们回顾这顿晚餐‎
and all we'll remember is‎
我们只会记得‎
the Chateau Leoville Barton‎
这瓶李维巴顿堡‎
Oh, I doubt that‎
我不这么认为‎
The mind replaces memories all the time‎
大脑会持续取代旧的记忆‎
It's innate to its wiring‎
这就是大脑的机制‎
Especially if you drink too much‎
尤其是当你喝多了的时候‎
Do the thing‎
秀一手吧‎
Hmm?[Laura] Come on‎
-嗯？ -快嘛‎
It's not a party trick‎
那可不是派对把戏‎
Wait. What is she talking about?‎
等等 她在说什么？‎
It helps explain what we're working on‎
那能帮助你了解我们的研究内容‎
Okay, then. Pick a memory. Hmm?‎
好吧 回想某件事‎
From your childhood. Anything‎
你的童年往事 什么都好‎
Objects, moments, people‎
物体 回忆或人们‎
Anything you can easily recall?‎
任何容易想起的事物‎
Uh..‎
呃…‎
Okay Uh..‎
好吧‎
I remember we had this green shag rug‎
我记得我们有张绿色长毛地毯‎
and, uh..‎
还有…‎
...four goldfish‎
四条金鱼‎
named after the guys in KISS‎
以“接吻合唱团”成员命名‎
That's a good memory‎
真是美妙的回忆‎
How about something that you wish you could forget?‎
你有想忘掉的回忆吗？‎
Um..‎
呃…‎
Did your parents ever hit you?‎
你的父母有打过你吗？‎
No‎
没有‎
Did you ever get lost‎
你是否曾在…‎
in a shopping mall or a big supermarket?‎
购物商场或大型超市走丢？‎
I mean... come to think of it there was this one time‎
这么说来 倒是有一次‎
we went to a toy store and, uh..‎
我们去了玩具店 然后…‎
I... I couldn't find my mom‎
我找不到我妈妈‎
Were you scared?‎
你当时很害怕吗？‎
I mean, I haven't thought about it‎
在走丢之后‎
我其实没想过害不害怕 但是…‎
since it happened, but..‎
Yeah‎
对‎
I looked for her everywhere‎
我到处找她‎
And you eventually found her?‎
你最后有找到她吗？‎
Uh... outside smoking‎
在外面抽烟‎
Huh. It's... crazy‎
呃‎
这太扯了‎
I'd forgotten all that‎
连我自己都忘记了‎
没错‎
At the, uh... the heart of our research, uh..‎
这就是我们的研究核心…‎
Joe's research‎
乔瑟夫的研究核心‎
is the thesis that most people experience trauma‎
大多数人都经历过创伤‎
but the mind blocks those memories‎
但大脑封锁了这些记忆‎
from ever actually presenting‎
不让这些记忆浮现‎
那天你经历的创伤‎
The trauma you experienced that day‎
was your mother abandoning you‎
是被母亲抛弃‎
You were a child. Vulnerable‎
你年纪还小 心灵脆弱‎
And that fact that your mother might actually harm you‎
你的母亲可能会伤害你‎
is too traumatic to process‎
这项事实对你来说太痛苦了 难以接受‎
So you suppressed it from memory‎
所以你从记忆中将其抹除‎
But the effects of that trauma‎
但这种创伤的影响‎
still linger in your subconscious‎
仍然潜藏于你的潜意识中‎
and become part of the fabric of who you are‎
并成为你的一部分‎
Wow. Okay‎
哇 这实在…‎
That's..‎
Therapy with dinner‎
治疗要在晚餐时‎
Cheers‎
干杯‎
Richard‎
理查‎
Would you come with me?‎
你能跟我来吗？‎
I've got something I'd like to show you. Hmm?‎
我有一些东西想让你看看‎
Okay‎
好‎
Okay That's a lot of books‎
这里的书可真多‎
I can offer you $500 a week to organize it‎
我每周给你五百元 请你帮忙整理‎
To classify them electronically‎
在你有空的时间‎
when you can, until you're done‎
以电子方式分类直到完成‎
要我说的话 这得花上一点时间‎
which, if I had to guess won't be anytime soon‎
I... I mean, I don't really know what to say. Uh..‎
我不知道该说什么了…‎
Laura told me about what happened to your father‎
萝拉把你父亲的遭遇‎
and the situation that you're in‎
和你的处境都告诉我了‎
你只要回答好就行了‎
So you might want to just say you'll do it‎
Thank you‎
谢谢你‎
<i>"Working for Wieder was a dream.</i>‎
替维德工作简直是梦想成真‎
<i>New worlds opened up.</i>‎
新世界的大门为之敞开‎
<i>A curated collection of the world's greatest thinkers.</i>‎
这些都是世界最伟大思想家的精选集‎
艺术‎
哲学‎
宗教‎
<i>For every two I'd catalog...</i>‎
每编好两本书‎
<i>I'd find myself reading another.</i>‎
我就会读一本‎
<i>Eventually, though, all the time I spent at Wieder's</i>‎
结果 在维德家度过的时光‎
让我接触到了一些意想不到的事情‎
<i>exposed me to something I wasn't expecting."</i>‎
- More books? - Yeah‎
-你带了书来？ -对‎
The professor wants me to donate them‎
教授要我把这些书捐给慈善机构‎
但里面有一些好东西‎
but there's some good shit in here‎
是说 这些球棒是什么？‎
Say, uh, what's with the bats?‎
His dad's‎
他老爸的‎
Collected them, I guess‎
可能是他的收藏‎
Signed too‎
还有签名呢‎
Willie McCovey. Al Kaline‎
威利·麦考维‎
艾尔卡·莱恩‎
Ted Williams‎
泰德·威廉斯‎
You wanna finish this? I gotta work‎
你收拾一下吧 我还得去工作‎
Yeah. Sure‎
没问题‎
Thanks‎
谢谢你‎
<i>"A laugh."</i> Yeah‎
笑声‎
<i>"A hand grazing an arm."</i>‎
一只手擦过一只手臂‎
<i>"One thing's clear."</i>‎
至少有一点是明白的‎
来自萝拉·贝恩斯的新讯息‎
<i>Hey, it's me.</i>‎
喂 是我‎
抱歉 我今晚不能吃晚餐了‎
<i>I'm sorry, but I have to bag on dinner tonight.</i>‎
<i>I'm stuck at the office helping Joe,</i>‎
我在办公室帮忙乔瑟夫‎
<i>but I'll, uh... I'll see you when I get home.</i>‎
等我回家再说吧‎
<i>"Laura Baines was more than</i>‎
萝拉·贝恩斯‎
不只是乔瑟夫·维德的研究员‎
<i>just Joseph Wieder's research fellow."</i>‎
I'm supposed to be working‎
你应该在工作才对‎
你明天没有研究论文要交吗？‎
Don't you have a research paper due tomorrow?‎
Yeah‎
有‎
I have so many patient notes to transcribe‎
我还有很多病例要抄‎
我会做不完的‎
Stop‎
别这样‎
Oh, God Do you like that?‎
天啊‎
你喜欢这样吗？‎
You know I like that‎
你明知道我喜欢‎
[Laura] You know I do‎
你清楚得很‎
<i>"Despite our time together,</i>‎
虽然相处了一段时间‎
但我根本不了解萝拉·贝恩斯‎
<i>I didn't know Laura Baines at all."</i>‎
<i>"And when I found that manuscript...</i>‎
当我发现那份手稿时‎
《镜像效应》
作者：乔瑟夫·维德
我才意识到我不是唯一一个‎
<i>I realized I wasn't the only one."</i>‎
Are you hungry?‎
你饿了吗？‎
Oh, hey. I didn't know you were home‎
嗨 我不知道你在家‎
- What have you got there? - I don't know‎
你发现了什么？‎
我不知道‎
I found it in, uh..‎
我发现它…呃…‎
被藏在一些书的后面‎
It was lodged in the back there behind some books‎
Oh. Huh‎
哦 这样啊‎
Laura. So eager‎
合著作者：萝拉·贝恩斯
萝拉 她真心急‎
Oh‎
Come on Before lunch gets cold‎
来吧 不然午餐要冷了‎
Do you like to cook, Richard?‎
理查 你喜欢做菜吗？‎
I don't really know how‎
我不会做菜‎
Well, you should learn‎
你应该学学‎
Maybe you're good at it maybe you're not, hmm?‎
谁知道你擅不擅长呢？‎
Experiment‎
试试才知道‎
Mm-hm‎
嗯‎
Laura likes a man who can cook‎
萝拉喜欢会做菜的男人‎
How are things going between you two?‎
你们两个还顺利吗？‎
We're just friends‎
我们只是朋友‎
Oh, come on‎
少来了‎
I got the impression you were more than that‎
你们绝对不只是朋友‎
Is that what she told you?‎
她是这么跟你说的？‎
不需要萝拉说 我也看得出来‎
I don't need Laura to tell me something to know it‎
I can sense things‎
我感觉得出来‎
I've known her for some time now‎
我认识她一段时间了‎
Right. I mean I-I would never presume..‎
那太好了 我从不会假设…‎
But, Richard, she brought you into my life to help‎
但是 理查‎
她介绍你给我认识是在帮你‎
not to complicate things‎
别把事情搞得太复杂‎
And that's what I'm here for to help‎
所以我才来这里帮你‎
Well, good‎
很好‎
To that end, then‎
那就这样吧‎
I think-- and these are just my thoughts--‎
我想…‎
虽然只是我个人的想法…‎
I think it would be better if you stopped seeing each other‎
如果你们不再见面会更好‎
Wait, what?‎
等等 你说什么？‎
Nobody likes it when things‎
大家都不希望把事情搞得太复杂‎
become overly complicated‎
I'm going out of town to meet some people about my book‎
我要出城去 和一些人讨论我的书‎
I imagine when I get back‎
希望等我回来‎
you will have sorted out some new arrangement‎
你已经替自己做了新的安排‎
Bon appétit‎
请慢用‎
<i>"He'd crossed a line,</i>‎
他非常过份‎
<i>but I never sorted anything out.</i>‎
但我其实没做过任何安排‎
<i>She sorted it out for me."</i>‎
一切都是她的主意‎
Babe?‎
宝贝？‎
You home?‎
你在家吗？‎
Hey, uh..‎
呃…‎
I got you some stuff from Bamboo House‎
我在翠竹居买了一些吃的‎
You know those dumplings you like‎
有你喜欢的饺子‎
Babe?‎
宝贝？‎
<i>"She was gone.</i>‎
她离开了‎
<i>And then the next day it happened."</i>‎
隔天 就发生了那起事件‎
<i>"Professor Joseph Wieder was found dead.</i>‎
乔瑟夫·维德教授被发现身亡‎
<i>Beaten to death.</i>‎
遭到殴打致死‎
<i>Some junkie confessed to the crime."</i>‎
某个毒虫坦承犯罪‎
<i>"The Waterford College community digested the tragedy</i>‎
这桩悲剧在沃特福大学逐渐平息‎
<i>and I went on to become a novelist of no repute,</i>‎
而我成为了一名默默无闻的小说家‎
<i>toiling in obscurity."</i>‎
低调地写作‎
情绪导向：苦难深埋在我们心灵的深处‎
遗忘……
<i>"And Laura Baines?</i>‎
至于萝拉·贝恩斯呢？‎
<i>I later found out that a week before the murder</i>‎
后来发现 在谋杀案发生前一周‎
<i>she went to see Susan Avery,</i>‎
她去找了苏珊·艾弗里‎
<i>Wieder's contact at the Department of Defense,</i>‎
也就是维德在国防部的联络人‎
<i>claiming ownership over Wieder's work."</i>‎
她声称维德的研究全归自己所有‎
No, it doesn't work like that‎
不 事情不是这样的‎
The US Government commissioned the study‎
这项研究由美国政府委托进行‎
The grant is for Professor Wieder‎
补助金是授予维德教授的‎
But I wrote it‎
但我才是作者‎
Look, Ms. Baines‎
贝恩斯小姐 听我说‎
I don't know what arrangement you made with Dr. Wieder‎
我不知道你和维德博士‎
怎么分配工作‎
but I recommend you take it up with the university‎
但我建议你直接去找大学‎
or directly with him‎
或是直接去找他‎
拜托 这是我的作品‎
Oh, come on! This is my work‎
and he just put his name on it‎
他只是把名字写在上面‎
- I'm sorry - Is that all you can say?‎
-我很抱歉 -你就只会说这种话？‎
This is bullshit‎
太离谱了‎
You can't just get away with this‎
你们不能就这样坐享其成‎
<i>"After the murder she disappeared.</i>‎
萝拉·贝恩斯
谋杀案发生后 她便消失无踪‎
<i>It was like she'd fallen right off the face of the Earth."</i>‎
感觉就像从人间蒸发‎
<i>"Until the day I saw her again."</i>‎
直到我再次见到她‎
"Until.. I saw her again."‎
“直到我再次见到她”‎
Until you saw her again where?‎
你在哪见到她的？‎
Ah, you motherfucker‎
王八蛋‎
萝拉·贝恩斯‎
You know what? She's probably dead‎
你知道吗？她可能已经死了‎
她的社会安全号码仍然有效‎
Her social security number is still active‎
She's got no address no social media presence‎
找不到住址 没有社交媒体‎
no place of business, nothing‎
也没有营业地点 什么也没有‎
Just one old pic from high school‎
只有一张高中时的老照片‎
So what? She's a private person‎
那又怎样？这代表她很注重隐私‎
It's the same with Wayne Devereaux‎
韦恩·德弗罗也是这样‎
Wieder's caretaker‎
他是维德家的管理员‎
No phone number no job history‎
没有手机 没有工作记录
I did a reverse address search, nothing‎
反向搜寻地址也一无所获‎
It's like everyone from Wieder's life at that time‎
仿佛当初维德周遭的人们‎
is now a fucking ghost‎
都成了幽灵‎
You know what?‎
你知道吗？‎
别擅自把我当成幽灵好吗？‎
You're making me feel like I want to be a fucking ghost‎
The only one I've been able to track down is Finn's ex-wife‎
唯一能找到的只有弗林的前妻‎
I'm gonna go and talk to her‎
我要去找她谈谈‎
And what the fuck's she gonna say to you?‎
她又能告诉你什么？‎
I don't know‎
我不知道‎
She might know something‎
她或许知道些什么‎
You know? Finn might have been onto something‎
说不定弗林真的发现了什么‎
太多的假设 太多的如果了‎
That's a lot of somethings and maybes and ifs and buts‎
Look, man if Isaac Samuel is innocent‎
听着 假如艾萨克·山谬是无辜的‎
and we've put away the wrong guy‎
我们抓错人了‎
come on‎
拜托‎
That's a chance for us to make that right‎
这是我们拨乱反正的机会‎
- The guy confessed - I know he confessed, okay?‎
-是他自己认罪的 -我知道‎
He admits he was in the house on that night. He says that‎
他坦承那晚他就在屋内 他亲口说的‎
But he also says before he could do anything‎
但他也说 在他动作前‎
someone else came in to the house‎
就有人进了屋内‎
Who?‎
是谁？‎
Who came in, Roy?‎
罗伊 是谁进了屋内？‎
I don't know‎
我不知道‎
Well, if you don't fucking know‎
妈的 如果你不知道‎
then I don't fucking know either‎
那我怎么可能知道‎
I'm gonna take a piss‎
我要去尿尿‎
又进一球‎
<i>And he drops in another one!</i>‎
这孩子手感火烫‎
<i>This kid's on fire!</i>‎
Hey‎
嘿‎
What the fuck, man?‎
有事吗？‎
I'm sorry‎
抱歉‎
<i>Hallucinations are often a common byproduct</i>‎
幻觉是治疗过程中 常见的副作用‎
<i>of the procedure.</i>‎
But I've only ever seen pictures of her‎
但我只看过她的照片‎
Yeah, well it indicates recall‎
没错 那就是回忆能力‎
even if it wasn't really her‎
即使那不是真正的她‎
Same with the snippets of memory you've reported‎
只要和你记忆中的片段相同‎
It means your neural pathways are starting to reactivate‎
这代表你的神经通路‎
开始重新活化了‎
So I'm not just going completely crazy, then?‎
我不会彻底疯掉吧？‎
Far from it‎
你想太多了‎
You're actually what we'd call a good result‎
你的情况 我们会称之为好结果‎
Treatment's working‎
治疗是有效的‎
衣服-西装
裤子 外套
鞋子‎
你叫罗伊·费里曼‎
衣服-西装
裤子 外套
鞋子‎
[man] Put that down‎
把东西放下‎
驾照
黛娜·欧森‎
Ms. Finn?‎
弗林太太？‎
I'm sorry to disturb you. I..‎
不好意思打扰你 我…‎
You the cop?‎
你是那个警察？‎
Roy Freeman, yeah. I called‎
对 罗伊·费里曼‎ 我过打电话
Yeah, I'm actually you know, uh..‎
其实我已经…‎
...retired‎
退休了‎
And so I'm not with the police anymore‎
所以我已经不算警察了‎
Good. Never liked cops‎
好极了 我从来就不喜欢警察‎
<i>Doesn't make sense.</i>‎
这不可能‎
Richard was a lot of things--‎
理查有很多问题‎
paranoid, deluded‎
偏执 好骗…‎
real misanthrope‎
而且很厌世‎
But he wasn't a druggie‎
但他绝非毒虫‎
So you think his death was an accident, maybe?‎
所以你觉得他的死可能是一场意外？‎
I bet that cunt Elizabeth Westlake‎
那个婊子 伊莉莎白·韦斯特莱克‎
had something to do with it‎
这件事肯定和她有关‎
I'm sorry I-I don't know who that is‎
抱歉 我没听过这个人‎
Yeah. Neither did I until recently‎
我也是最近才知道‎
Crazy-ass bitch‎
那个疯婆子‎
They had some big argument‎
在理查搬出去的几周前‎
a few weeks before Richard moved out‎
他们才刚大吵过‎
Elizabeth... Westlake?‎
伊莉莎白…韦斯特莱克…？‎
Yeah.[Roy] Yeah. Okay‎
-对 -好‎
伊莉莎白·韦斯特莱克‎
Richard started drinking again‎
理查又开始酗酒了‎
And one night he comes home screaming on the phone‎
某天晚上他回到家‎
对着电话大吼大叫 非常生气‎
all pissed‎
Huh. No, no, no‎
不是‎
No, no, no‎
才不是‎
No, no, no you listen to me, okay?‎
不 你听我说好吗？‎
Don't you fucking lie to me‎
妈的 你别骗我‎
<i>He must have thought I was asleep.</i>‎
他肯定以为我睡了‎
Okay, I-I know what you did Yeah‎
我知道你干了什么‎
And you're not gonna get away with it‎
你可别想脱身‎
You ever ask him what the argument was about?‎
你有问过他在吵什么吗？‎
I tried not to talk to Richard when he was like that‎
理查发怒时 我一向不会去搭话‎
Right‎
好吧‎
<i>So I waited until he was asleep.</i>‎
于是我等到他入睡‎
近期通话记录
隔天 我拨了那通电话‎
<i>Next day, I called the number,</i>‎
and got her voicemail‎
进到了语音信箱‎
你还知道关于她的什么事吗？‎
What else do you know about her?‎
Know what she does? Do you know how they connect?‎
你知道她做了什么吗？‎
他们怎么搭上线的？‎
- No - Nothing?‎
不知道‎
都不知道‎
You just called her a crazy-ass bitch‎
但你刚刚叫她疯婆子‎
Look, all I know is I never heard him talk‎
听着 我只知道他从没用那种语气‎
to anybody like that before‎
跟任何人讲过话‎
Not even me‎
即使是我‎
You ask me..‎
如果你问我…‎
she killed him‎
我会说是她杀了他‎
伊莉莎白·韦斯特莱克‎
萝拉·贝恩斯‎
伊莉莎白·韦斯特莱克博士‎
Ms. Westlake‎
韦斯特莱克小姐‎
Oh. Mr. Freeman‎
费里曼先生‎
Have we met?‎
我们见过吗？‎
I'm sorry. I have a condition‎
抱歉 我身体出了点问题‎
I forget a lot of stuff‎
忘了很多事情‎
Well, I'm sorry‎
该抱歉的是我‎
We met in passing a long time ago‎
我们在很久以前见过面‎
And I'd read about your accident in the newspaper‎
我有在报纸上看到你的意外‎
Would you mind if I asked you where?‎
介意我问一下是在哪吗？‎
- Where did we meet? - I wish I could talk‎
-我们在哪见过？ -我很想继续聊‎
But I need to get to the office‎
但我得去办公室了‎
That's okay‎
那没关系‎
其实我来找你是想问‎
I actually just wanted to talk to you‎
about Richard Finn‎
理查·弗林的事‎
Now, there's someone I'd like to forget‎
我真想把那人的事给忘了‎
Why is that?‎
为什么？‎
I guess you've never been stalked‎
你肯定没被人跟踪过吧‎
made to feel like you always‎
那会让人觉得 无时无刻都必须警惕身后‎
need to be looking over your shoulder‎
Oh. Yeah, well you know, uh..‎
是的 其实…‎
he had it in his mind‎
他在怀疑‎
that you had something to do with Joseph Wieder's murder‎
你和乔瑟夫·维德的谋杀案有关‎
So you've spoken to him?‎
你和他谈过了？‎
No, I haven't. Uh..‎
没有 呃…‎
I tried to but he passed away‎
我是想过 但他已经过世了‎
- I see - Yeah‎
-原来如此 -对‎
He left something behind, though‎
不过他留下了一些东西‎
A memoir‎
一本回忆录‎
And I was wondering if you'd like to have a look at it‎
我猜你可能会有兴趣看看‎
You could just tell me what you think‎
然后告诉我你的看法‎
I've worked very hard to forget that time in my life‎
为了忘掉那段人生‎
我一直在努力工作‎
Professor Wieder's death and I'd rather not relive it‎
维德教授死了 我也不愿再想起‎
Totally understand. Yeah‎
我明白‎
You know, though, uh..‎
不过…‎
there is a man who is on death row‎
有一名男子因为乔瑟夫·维德的谋杀案‎
for Joseph Wieder's murder‎
即将被处死‎
and his date's coming up pretty soon‎
执行的时间就快到了‎
So maybe you could just you know, take a look‎
或许你能帮忙稍微看一下‎
If I have a free moment‎
如果我有空的话‎
Great. Thank you Thank you very much‎
太好了 太感谢你了‎
- Alright - Alright‎
-好的 -好‎
You have a great day‎
祝你顺心‎
You take care of yourself now, Roy‎
罗伊 多保重‎
搜索结果‎送达
韦恩·德弗罗
地址：退伍军人林荫大道1916号‎
韦恩·德弗罗‎
This is it, man‎
就是这里了‎
Mr. Devereaux?‎
德弗罗先生？‎
It's been a while‎
好久不见了‎
Took me a second there to place you‎
我一时之间没认出你‎
but my story's the same as it was then‎
但我的证词和以前没两样‎
I just never got to tell it to you 'cause..‎
我也没必要再告诉你了 因为…‎
you already had your man‎
你已经逮到凶手了‎
Well, if it's okay with you I'd like to hear it now‎
如果可以的话 我想听你再说一次‎
Yeah? Why is that?‎
是吗？为什么？‎
我正在调查以前的案件‎
I'm just going back through things‎
Making sure all the right boxes got checked‎
我必须厘清所有疑点 懂吗？‎
you know?‎
Okay‎
好吧‎
Well..‎
嗯…‎
Professor Wieder found me‎
维德教授找到了我‎
当时的我就像是行尸走肉‎
<i>when I was a shell of who I was.</i>‎
<i>He helped me get back on my feet.</i>‎
他帮助我重新振作‎
<i>He got me a job working maintenance.</i>‎
还帮我找了份维修工的工作‎
<i>I mean, I remember it crystal clear, man.</i>‎
我记得一清二楚‎
<i>He was like a celebrity.</i>‎
他当时相当有名望‎
<i>Everyone loved him.</i>‎
所有人都爱戴他‎
<i>He did all sorts of work.</i>‎
他几乎什么样的工作都接‎
<i>I don't know what exactly,</i>‎
虽然不确定具体是什么‎
但常常有人来他家‎
<i>but there was always people visiting.</i>‎
Thank you so much‎
感激不尽‎
<i>Important people.</i>‎
各种大人物‎
<i>People from the government,</i>‎
有政界人士‎
Department of Defense‎
国防部官员‎
He was running a trial for them‎
他也在大学的系所内‎
out of his department at the college‎
替他们进行实验‎
Trauma patients‎
像是找创伤患者‎
Testing a medication he developed‎
来测试他开发的药物‎
I guess I was a perfect candidate‎
我想我是完美的人选‎
我是第一批抵达伊拉克的军人‎
<i>I was first on the ground in Iraq.</i>‎
<i>Saw my share of it before taking a bullet.</i>‎
在中枪前 我看尽了战场的丑恶‎
I didn't know the real damage till I got home‎
回到家之后 才发现我受了严重的心理创伤‎
Just couldn't get right‎
一直无法康复‎
Wieder found me at the VA‎
维德在退伍军人事务部找到了我‎
said I fit his research profile‎
说我符合他的研究背景‎
What kind of research?‎
什么样的研究？‎
Wayne, what if I told you‎
韦恩 如果我告诉你‎
that through medicine and suggestion‎
透过药物和建议‎
you could replace the memory of your trauma of Iraq‎
你就能用美好的记忆‎
取代你在伊拉克的创伤‎
with better memories‎
or perhaps erase the memory of your trauma altogether?‎
又或许‎
能够完全消除你的心灵创伤呢？‎
Man, I'd say sign me up‎
那我会立刻加入‎
By activating opposite sides of the brain‎
透过启动大脑的另一侧‎
we can release the emotional experiences‎
我们可以解放受困于‎
trapped in our nervous system‎
神经系统中的情绪体验‎
But before we make that bad memory go away‎
但是在消除丑恶的记忆前‎
we have to fully confront it‎
我们必须正视它‎
Breathe‎
深呼吸‎
He said it was effective for dealing with PTSD‎
他说这对治疗创伤后压力症候群很有效‎
but that was only part of the treatment‎
但那不过是治疗的一部分‎
200毫克锭剂
切勿突然停药‎
Take one in the morning‎
早上吃一颗‎
And one before bed‎
睡前吃一颗‎
<i>The rest was that medication he developed.</i>‎
然后就是他开发的药物‎
<i>He said it could wipe the slate clean.</i>‎
他说这能抹去那些记忆‎
<i>But you just told me about Iraq.</i>‎
但你刚才提到了伊拉克‎
Does that mean the treatment didn't work?‎
代表治疗没效罗？‎
Oh, it did for a time‎
曾经一度有效‎
Details faded No more panic attacks‎
细节变得模糊 恐慌不再发作‎
但是那些药 老天…‎
But those pills, man I mean..‎
有一些极其骇人的副作用‎
<i>...they had some fucking mean side effects.</i>‎
我连自己都认不得了‎
<i>I didn't recognize myself anymore.</i>‎
<i>I'd black out.</i>‎
我会晕过去‎
No idea where I was how I got there‎
不知道自己在哪 也不知道怎么到的‎
So you stopped taking the medication?‎
所以你就停药了？‎
Mm-hm‎
嗯‎
Yeah, against the professor's wishes‎
是的 我违背了教授的期许‎
Where's your car?‎
你的车停在哪？‎
I came here by taxi‎
我搭计程车来的‎
You want a ride?‎
要搭便车吗？‎
市里的美国爱护动物协会 为狗狗们买了我的边料‎
ASPCA in the city buys my offcuts for dogs‎
- You sure? - Yeah, man. Seat's free‎
你确定吗？‎
确定 不收钱的‎
Do you know anything about Laura Baines?‎
你认识萝拉·贝恩斯吗？‎
拜托‎
Oh, man. I don't think anybody ever really knew Laura Baines‎
从来就没人真正认识萝拉·贝恩斯‎
Her and Wieder were a thing, yeah?‎
她和维德之间不单纯 对吧？‎
I don't know nothin' about that‎
我什么都不知道‎
据他所说 她就只是个实验室助理‎
From what he said, she's just a lab assistant, nothing more‎
I mean, maybe she'd like to be‎
也许她有那个意思‎
But if they were I never saw it‎
但就算真有什么 我也没亲眼看过‎
<i>Not that I didn't see others.</i>‎
不过我也不是没看到其他人‎
<i>I'd come over the house every now and then,</i>‎
我偶尔会进那间屋子‎
<i>to fix this and that.</i>‎
修东修西的‎
<i>There were a lot of women.</i>‎
进出的女人很多‎
He kept a record of them too‎
他把她们全都记录了下来‎
What kind of record?‎
怎么记录？‎
他有一台老式摄影机‎
<i>He had one of those old-school camcorders.</i>‎
黛安
他有一台老式摄影机‎
<i>I guess he liked to revisit his past exploits.</i>‎
我猜他喜欢重温自己过去的战绩
<i>Did Laura Baines ever call him out on it?</i>‎
萝拉·贝恩斯有和他大吵过吗？‎
No, man. Only time I heard them exchange words‎
没有 我只听他们吵过一次‎
was over some research paper they were writing‎
是关于他们研究论文的事情‎
But the night he was killed her and Finn‎
但是他被杀害的那晚‎
她和弗林来到屋内‎
<i>they came over to the house</i>‎
<i>and there was some kind of argument.</i>‎
似乎起了口角‎
We need to have a rational conversation‎
有话好好讲…‎
-好好讲？ -别影射或指控‎
without all this accusation‎
You're fucking lying![Laura] He's not lying‎
-你这个骗子 -他没有说谎‎
-哦 你还帮她说话？ -我不需要别人帮我说话‎
- Oh! You wanna defend him now? - I don't need defending‎
What were they fighting about?‎
他们在吵什么？‎
我怎么知道 只知道弗林非常生气‎
Fuck if I know Finn got real pissed off‎
Know what? Fuck the both of you‎
听好了 去你们的 一对贱人
- You deserve each other - Are you fucking kidding me?‎
-你在说什么鬼话？ -他离开了‎
<i>He left and I went to go out front,</i>‎
我也跟着从前门离开‎
<i>talk to him maybe see what's what.</i>‎
想跟他聊一聊 问问情况‎
But he was just... gone‎
但他就直接走了‎
Or he never left‎
又或者他根本没走‎
In Finn's statement he says he was home alone‎
根据弗林的说法 谋杀案发生时‎
at the time of the murder‎
他一个人待在家中‎
Well, I mean, I can only tell you what I saw‎
我能说的就只有自己的见闻‎
What about Laura? You see her leave?‎
萝拉呢？‎
有看见她离开吗？‎
Yeah, later in a taxi‎
有 她后来搭计程车走了‎
So where'd you go?‎
那你去了哪里？‎
My usual. Old Warren‎
我经常去的 “旧城区”‎
<i>The bartender there, Diane,</i>‎
那里的酒保黛安‎
也曾经是教授的女人‎
<i>even she was one of the professor's girls.</i>‎
He was a good man‎
他是个好人‎
He lost his way that's all‎
只是有点迷失罢了‎
It can happen to any one of us‎
谁都有可能行差踏错‎
But it's like the Bible says‎
但就像圣经上写的‎
"Do not judge lest you too be judged."‎
“你们不要论断人 免得你们被论断”‎
Thanks for the lift‎
谢谢你送我‎
Yeah. It's me‎
对 是我‎
He's home‎
他到家了‎
过去罪行：窃盗 持有毒品‎……
调查笔录
韦恩·德弗罗‎
黛安·琳区‎
我记得韦恩·德弗罗
9点过后没多久来到酒吧‎
黛安·琳区‎
Diane Lynch‎
警官签字：吉米·雷米斯‎
警官签字：罗伊·费里曼 和 吉米·雷米斯‎
A very, very interesting read‎
这本书非常有意思‎
Aren't you gonna invite me in?‎
我能进去坐坐吗？‎
Can I get you a water?‎
要喝杯水吗？‎
Maybe some whiskey‎
来点威士忌吧‎
I, uh... I don't have any in the house‎
呃 我家里没有威士忌‎
Doctors. [chuckles]‎
医生的嘱咐‎
I can't even remember the last time I had a drink‎
我已经不记得上次喝酒 是什么时候的事了‎
One of the few benefits of your condition, I suppose‎
我想这是失忆症少数的优点‎
You can't remember the bad times‎
把坏事都给忘了‎
Can't remember the good times, either‎
好事我也记不得了‎
那太惨了‎
That's too bad‎
Must be hard--‎
肯定很辛苦‎
想不起朋友 家人或过去的经验‎
no memory of friends, family past experience‎
No context for who you are Your place in the world‎
不知道自己是谁 或是在世界上的定位‎
萝拉·贝恩斯
真难想像那是什么感觉‎
I can't imagine what that's like‎
to feel so lost‎
肯定很迷茫
So alone‎
又孤独‎
So what did you think of Finn's book?‎
弗林的书你有什么看法？‎
It was..‎
那是…‎
a bunch of bullshit‎
胡说八道‎
So, you two were uh... never lovers?‎
所以你们两个从没…‎
爱过彼此？‎
No. That was just his little fantasy‎
是的 那只是他的小小妄想‎
People make things up all the time‎
人们总爱编造事实‎
Lie to protect themselves‎
用谎言来保护自己‎
Manufacture histories to appear more than they are‎
捏造历史 让回忆对自己更有利‎
因为现实太过痛苦了‎
'cause the reality is too painful‎
- I spoke with Wayne Devereaux - Hmm‎
-我跟韦恩·德弗罗谈过了 -嗯‎
He seemed to confirm a lot of what's in there‎
他认同里面的许多内容‎
Wow. Another reliable witness Makes sense, though‎
哇 又一个可靠的证人‎
不过这也说得通‎
Lots of vets who suffer from trauma‎
许多受过创伤的退伍军人‎
turn to escapist invention-- video games‎
会转向逃避现实的发明 像是电子游戏‎
pornography‎
或是色情作品‎
So, did he invent the research study‎
所以维德的研究‎
也是他虚构的吗？‎
Wieder was working on too?‎
No. Wayne was a participant in that‎
不 韦恩曾参与过研究‎
But if I remember correctly‎
但如果我没记错的话‎
he didn't respond favorably to the protocol‎
他对疗程似乎不太满意‎
He resented what it did to him‎
他埋怨实验对他造成的影响‎
他变得易怒 而且有攻击性‎
He was prone to bouts of anger, aggression‎
You seem to know a whole lot about him‎
看来你对他很了解‎
Well, I transcribed Wieder's patient notes. All of them‎
对 我抄录了维德所有的患者病历‎
Sometimes you learn things you'd prefer you didn't‎
有时候 会知道一些不想知道的事‎
He said that Wieder was intending‎
他说维德原本打算 发表他的成果 所以…‎
on publishing his findings, so..‎
That's what you do You work for years‎
这是理所当然的‎
你努力多年 当然要发表自己的成果‎
and then you publish your findings‎
But he died before it was complete‎
但他在发表前就过世了‎
Do you feel he was giving you the credit you deserved?‎
他有放上你的名字吗？‎
He died before we could work that out as well‎
在解决这个问题前 他就死了‎
A drug that can help people forget past trauma‎
一种能帮助人们忘记过去创伤的药物‎
Seems to me someone could make‎
在我看来肯定有人能靠这种药发财‎
a whole lot of money out of that‎
Now you think someone killed him for money‎
所以你觉得有人为了钱杀了他‎
You may not have memory Mr. Freeman‎
费里曼先生 你记性不好‎
but you do have quite the imagination‎
但倒是挺有想像力的‎
People kill for a whole lot of different reasons‎
人会因为各式各样的原因杀人‎
I reached out to Susan Avery‎
我曾连络过苏珊·艾弗里‎
Wieder's DOD contact‎
维德在国防部的联络人‎
I know who Susan Avery is‎
我知道谁是苏珊·艾弗里‎
She collaborated with Wieder for decades‎
她和维德合作十几年了‎
So then you also know‎
那你应该也知道‎
that she's taken over his department at Waterford‎
她已经接手了他在沃特福的系所‎
Hmm‎
嗯‎
其实这场会谈‎
You know, this conversation would have been a lot better‎
更适合配一杯威士忌‎
with whiskey‎
You used to love a good drink, Roy‎
罗伊 你曾经很爱美酒的‎
<i>Now call the play.</i>‎
那就开始吧‎
I'll give you five seconds to unbuckle your guns‎
我给你五秒把枪解下‎
One‎
一‎
Two‎
二‎
<i>Three.</i>‎
三 玩够了 孩子们 把枪解下吧‎
<i>Enough fun Unbuckle them.</i>‎
哈瑞 杰克森 去拿装备‎
<i>Harry Jackson, get the hardware.</i>‎
<i>Doc!</i>‎
博士‎
<i>Anybody else want to try their luck?</i>‎
还有谁想试试自己的运气？‎
<i>Get moving!</i>‎
快走‎
快走 所有人快走‎
<i>Come on, keep moving all of ya!</i>‎
Oh, fuck‎
<i>911. What's your emergency?</i>‎
这里是911 是什么紧急状况？‎
Yeah, uh, I wanna report a shooting‎
是的 我想通报一起枪击案‎
Mr. Freeman, I'm going to read you your rights‎
费里曼先生 我将宣读你的权利‎
You have the right to remain silent‎
你有权保持沉默‎
If you refuse this right‎
如果你拒绝保持沉默‎
那么你所说的一切都能够用作为你的呈堂证供
anything you say can be used against you in a court of law‎
You have the right to an attorney‎
你有权聘请律师‎
If you cannot afford an attorney‎
如果你请不起律师‎
one will be appointed to you by the court‎
法庭将为你指定一名律师‎
We all done?‎
都结束了？‎
Case closed‎
结案了‎
Another one off the books‎
又是一桩没有记录的案件‎
Let's go celebrate I'm buying‎
我们去庆祝吧 我买单‎
Yeah. Let me catch you up‎
我待会去找你‎
I'll wait for you in the car‎
我会在车里等你‎
If you cannot afford an attorney‎
如果你请不起律师‎
one will be appointed to you by the court‎
法庭将为你指定一名律师‎
Do you understand the rights I just read to you, sir?‎
先生 清楚我刚刚宣读的权利吗？‎
You know you're one lucky sonofabitch‎
你真是幸运的混球‎
Those security cameras caught him trying to run you down‎
那些监视器有拍到他打算辗过你‎
There's gonna be a lot of red tape‎
这下文书工作有得忙了‎
but, uh, it'll prove it's self-defense‎
但这样就能证明你是出于自卫‎
Thanks for coming down‎
谢谢你跑一趟‎
Yeah, course‎
不客气‎
You'd have done exactly the same thing for me‎
是我的话 你也会这么做的‎
CSI found two vials of fentanyl‎
CSI发现两瓶芬太尼
in Devereaux's truck--‎
就在德弗罗的卡车内‎
the same shit that killed Finn‎
就是害死弗林的那种毒品‎
They're calling it a homicide‎
他们判定那是一起凶杀案‎
What?‎
你说什么？‎
Devereaux killed Finn?‎
德弗罗杀了弗林？‎
For what?‎
为什么？‎
Stop him IDing him for Wieder's murder?‎
阻止他查出 他就是杀害维德的凶手？‎
Sure. Makes sense‎
那样就说得通了‎
No. No, it doesn't make fuckin' sense‎
不 这一点也说不通‎
In his own goddamn book‎
在他那本该死的书中 弗林百分之百肯定‎
Finn is pointing 100% to Elizabeth Westlake‎
凶手是伊莉莎白·韦斯特莱克 不是德弗罗‎
not to Devereaux‎
Something's not right‎
事情不对劲‎
Yeah, something's not right‎
没错 是不对劲‎
Something's not right with you, Roy‎
不对劲的是你 罗伊‎
Isaac Samuel committed this act‎
凶手是艾萨克·山谬‎
Isaac Samuel confessed to it‎
艾萨克·山谬已经认罪了‎
In one month‎
不到一个月后‎
there will be justice and he will be dead‎
正义将会伸张 他将会被处刑‎
And you can move on and forget about all this‎
你可以放下这件事 忘了这一切‎
Was I a good cop?‎
我是个好警察吗？‎
Were you a good cop? What?‎
你是个好警察吗？什么意思？‎
What the fuck are you talking about?‎
你到底在说什么？‎
Was I good at my job?‎
我有尽自己的职责吗？‎
Or was I a bad cop? Was I a shit cop?‎
还是我是个坏警察？是个糟糕的警察？‎
Was I a lazy sonofabitch‎
我是不是个懒惰的烂人‎
who just marked his card and showed up?‎
随便做个记录 然后草草结案？‎
Roy, you were one of the best‎
罗伊 你绝对是最出色的‎
You were a great cop‎
你是个优秀的警察‎
My name's not on any of the sign-offs‎
我没看到任何我的签名‎
What?‎
什么？‎
In the Wieder file‎
在维德的档案中‎
My name is not on any of the officials‎
官方资料中全都没有我的名字‎
Not the incident report..‎
事件报告没有…‎
not the witness sheet‎
证人资料没有…‎
forensic findings Samuel's confession‎
法医调查结果和山谬的自白都没有‎
None of it‎
一次也没看到‎
It's just your name..‎
所有文件上面…‎
on all of it‎
都只有你的名字‎
What are you trying to say, Roy?‎
你想说什么 罗伊？‎
I've been going back through 30 years of case files‎
我翻阅了30年来的案件档案‎
Thirty years‎
整整30年‎
Every one, every document every single one..‎
所有档案 每一份文件我都看了‎
we co-signed‎
我们都是共同签署的‎
My name right next to yours‎
我的名字就在你的旁边‎
Except for this one‎
除了这起案件‎
Why is that?‎
为什么？‎
I see what you're doing here Roy‎
罗伊 我知道你在搞什么了‎
You've interviewed everyone else‎
你找所有人问过话之后‎
Now you're gonna accuse me‎
现在要来指控我了？‎
Jesus Christ, Roy‎
老天啊 罗伊‎
you're some fuckin' piece of work‎
你真是个混蛋‎
You come to my house out of nowhere‎
你无缘无故跑来我家‎
asking for my help‎
寻求我的协助‎
and now you accuse me?‎
现在你还指控我？‎
Fuck you, Roy‎
去你的 罗伊‎
Fuck you‎
去你的‎
I ain't no killer‎
我没杀人‎
You're in rare form tonight‎
你今晚真反常‎
Where is she?‎
她人在哪？‎
She won't be coming in for a while, Roy‎
她有一阵子不会来了 罗伊‎
黛安·琳区
“旧城区”‎
- Okay - Uh-huh‎
-好吧 -啊？‎
I'm out‎
我完事了‎
Oh, don't take my car, Roy‎
别开我的车 罗伊‎
Hey I will bring it back tomorrow‎
我明天就还给你‎
What you did I will never forget‎
你所做的一切 我永远不会忘记‎
Tomorrow‎
明天见‎
We're not open yet‎
我们还没开店‎
这里以前的老板‎
Was there an old gray-haired guy‎
是不是一个白发苍苍的老人？‎
used to run this place?‎
Eric? Eric O'Toole?‎
艾瑞克？艾瑞克·奥图尔？‎
Yeah, he's retired. Is there anything I can help you with?‎
对 他退休了 有什么事情吗？‎
It's my pop's place now‎
这里现在是我爸的店了‎
Yeah, I'm looking for a woman who used to work here too‎
我在找一位以前在这里工作的女士‎
- Her name's Diane - Oh, you mean Diane Lynch?‎
她叫黛安‎
哦 你是说黛安·琳区？‎
Yeah, right. Any idea where I could find her?‎
是的 我能在哪找到她呢？‎
Yeah, just over at Calvary Catholic‎
就在加略山天主教堂‎
She died about five years ago‎
她五年前就去世了‎
Oh, you don't say?‎
不会吧？‎
Fuck‎
可恶‎
Was she a friend or something?‎
她是你的朋友吗？‎
Eh, she gave a deposition in a case I was working on‎
她曾为我调查的案件作证‎
我只是想了解后续情况‎
- I was just following up - So, you a cop?‎
所以你是警察？‎
Used to be‎
曾经是‎
Well..‎
那…‎
On me‎
这杯我请‎
My grandfather was a cop‎
我爷爷也是警察‎
I just recently remembered I actually, uh..‎
我直到最近才想起来 其实我…‎
I like to do this‎
挺爱喝的‎
Don't we all?‎
大家不都是吗？‎
To Diane‎
敬黛安‎
Hey You mind if I use your bathroom?‎
那个…‎
能借一下厕所吗？‎
Just around the corner other side of the jukebox‎
当然 就在点唱机另一边的转角处‎
Thanks‎
谢了‎
Hello? <i>Mr. Freeman?</i>‎
喂？‎
费里曼先生？我是苏珊·艾弗里‎
<i>It's Susan Avery returning your call.</i>‎
Blunt object to the head‎
钝器敲击头部‎
Um, Susan? <i>From Waterford College.</i>‎
呃 苏珊？‎
我是沃特福大学的人‎
<i>I have something for you.</i>‎
我有东西想给你看‎
You sure I can't get you a glass of water?‎
你确定不要水吗？‎
No, no, I'm fine‎
没关系‎
You said you had something for me?‎
你说有东西想给我看？‎
I don't know where the original is‎
我不知道原稿在哪‎
Probably in storage at the DOD, if I had to guess‎
要我猜的话 可能是收藏在国防部‎
but that's the only copy I had from my time there‎
但这是我在那边拿到的唯一副本‎
“镜像效应”‎
<i>The Mirror Effect.</i>‎
Wieder was quite proud of this work‎
维德对这份研究非常自豪‎
He thought it would help people‎
他认为这能帮助那些遭受创伤的人‎
who were suffering with their trauma‎
这是值得获奖的研究‎
- It's award-worthy research - It was never published?‎
但却从未发表？‎
At least not under his name‎
至少不是以他的名义‎
I don't understand‎
我不明白‎
I gather you haven't read her book‎
我懂了 你还没读过她的书‎
She updated Wieder's research with additional findings‎
《过往非序幕》
在攻读博士学位期间‎
作者：伊莉莎白·韦斯特莱克博士
她搜集了更多资料‎
she culled together over the years‎
she was getting her doctorate‎
更新了维德的研究‎
So, she stole his work?‎
所以她剽窃了他的作品？‎
It happens all the time in academic research‎
这种情况在学术界常发生‎
Besides, who would protest?‎
再说 还有谁会抗议呢？‎
- Wieder's dead - But you contracted it?‎
维德已经死了‎
是你授意的？‎
It's not as simple as that‎
没那么简单‎
Before Wieder died‎
在维德死前‎
萝拉·贝恩斯带着那份手稿来找我‎
Laura Baines came to me with that manuscript‎
Yeah, I heard she wasn't happy‎
是的 听说她很不高兴‎
<i>She claimed the work was hers.</i>‎
她声称那份研究是属于她的‎
Wieder wasn't giving her the credit she deserved‎
维德没有给她应有的名分‎
This is bullshit! He can't just get away with this‎
太离谱了‎
你们不能就这样坐享其成‎
那她是怎么发表的？‎
So, how did she publish it?‎
We'd been circulating it‎
我们在退伍军人事务部的多间医院 流传这份研究‎
in a number of the VA hospitals‎
but the department's priorities changed‎
但国防部的优先事项改变了‎
A few years later after I started working here‎
几年后 我开始在这里工作后‎
I found her book review‎
我找到了她的书评‎
So... why didn't you go after her?‎
那么…‎
你为什么不去找她呢？‎
There was nothing to go after her for‎
没什么好追究的‎
过往非序幕：记忆 创伤 和代换角色 疗法
这项计划已经终止了‎
The project was shuttered‎
Wieder used to live around here, right?‎
维德以前住在这附近 对吗？‎
Over on Chestnut. Apparently the house is still empty‎
就在雀斯特纳斯 屋子还是空的‎
Blunt object to the head‎
钝器敲击头部‎
Any sign of it?‎
有任何线索吗？‎
No. Couple of bats in the garage, though‎
没有 不过车库有几支球棒‎
One's missing, right?‎
少了一支 对吧？‎
Caretaker there said they were all signed by Hall of Famers‎
那里的管理员说‎
这些都是名人堂成员的签名球棒‎
so probably worth a lot of money‎
说不定很值钱‎
You wanna go talk to him?‎
你要跟他谈谈吗？‎
- I will. Come on - Sir‎
我会的 来吧‎
是 长官‎
What you got there, Roy?‎
罗伊 你有什么发现？‎
Never did find the murder weapon‎
你一直没找到 维德案件中的凶器是吗？‎
from the Wieder case, did you?‎
You put this here?‎
这是你放的？‎
Put it back in the hole, Roy‎
罗伊 把东西放回去吧‎
Both of youse, get inside‎
你们都进来吧‎
Why couldn't you just listen to me?‎
你为什么就是不听我的话呢？‎
You just couldn't let it go could you?‎
你就是不肯放手 是吗？‎
What did you do, Jim?‎
你做了什么 吉米？‎
What did I do?‎
我做了什么？‎
I cleaned this fucking mess up‎
我在收拾残局‎
Ten years ago. Don't you remember any of this?‎
十年了 你什么都不记得了吗？‎
- What Diane did? - Diane?‎
黛安做了什么？‎
黛安？‎
She told me what you knew‎
她把你知道的事告诉了我‎
Diane Lynch?‎
黛安·琳区？‎
Get away from me‎
别靠近我‎
From your favorite bar‎
就在你最爱的酒吧‎
She was one of Wieder's patients‎
她曾是维德的病患‎
Enough, Laura‎
够了 萝拉‎
I told you I would take care of this‎
我说过我会把事情处理妥当的‎
Oh‎
哦？‎
You know each other?‎
你们认识？‎
I see‎
我懂了‎
So, you're in this together?‎
所以你们两个都有份？‎
Fuck me.[Roy] No, I get it‎
-操 -我懂了‎
I get it, Jimmy‎
我终于懂了 吉米‎
Your wife got really sick‎
你的妻子生了重病‎
You got deep in debt‎
你深受债务所苦‎
She comes along pays to you kill Wieder‎
萝拉来找你 付钱要你杀了维德‎
so she can publish her book‎
好让她能出版自己的书‎
and you you railroad Isaac Samuel‎
然后你逼艾萨克·山谬认罪‎
cover it all up‎
掩盖这一切‎
No, no, no, no, no. I did not pay him to kill Wieder‎
不 我没有雇他去杀维德‎
We didn't meet until after your accident‎
自从你发生意外后 我们就没见过面‎
<i>My life was destroyed.</i>‎
我的生活全毁了‎
<i>I was facing losing years of clinical research.</i>‎
我失去了多年的临床研究资料‎
The name "Laura Baines"‎
发生的一切始终离不开‎
would always be associated with what happened‎
“萝拉·贝恩斯”这个名字‎
<i>Then your partner showed up asking all kinds of questions.</i>‎
然后你的伙伴出现了‎
问了我各种问题‎
我不知道他想做什么‎
<i>I didn't know what he wanted but he wouldn't let up</i>‎
但他就是不肯放手 所以我非常害怕‎
<i>and I was so scared.</i>‎
去你的 萝拉‎
Oh, fuck you, Laura‎
So, I... left‎
于是我离开了‎
I moved, changed my name started over‎
我搬了家 改名换姓重新来过‎
completed the research and published <i>my</i> book‎
完成研究并出版了我的书‎
hoping I would never see him again‎
祈祷我再也不会见到他‎
<i>But then, a few years ago,</i>‎
但过了几年‎
<i>Richard Finn started poking around.</i>‎
理查·弗林开始四处调查‎
She's an author Elizabeth Westlake‎
她就是作者 伊莉莎白·韦斯特莱克‎
But she changed it It used to be Laura Baines‎
但她改了名 她以前叫萝拉·贝恩斯‎
<i>She must have taken Wieder's work after he died.</i>‎
她一定是在维德死后偷走了他的研究‎
<i>You ask me she's the one who killed him.</i>‎
我觉得她就是杀他的凶手‎
乔瑟夫·维德案证据‎
<i>Then somehow your partner found me</i>‎
然后 你的伙伴不知怎么找上了门‎
<i>and he turned up with his hand out,</i>‎
镜像效应
作者：乔瑟夫·维德 和 萝拉·贝恩斯
他出现在我面前 伸出了手‎
and this time, it's for money‎
这一次 他要的是钱‎
All this, all this is just fucking bullshit, Roy‎
罗伊 这全都是胡说八道‎
I'm not lying He blackmailed me‎
我没说谎 是他勒索我‎
He said he'd go public with proof my book wasn't my work‎
他说他要公开证明我的书 不是我的作品‎
除非我付钱给他‎
unless I paid him‎
So, you killed Richard Finn too‎
所以你把理查·弗林也杀了‎
in case he got the same idea?‎
防止他兴起同样的念头？‎
I didn't kill anyone‎
我没杀任何人‎
She killed Finn the same way she killed Wieder‎
是她杀了弗林 维德也是她杀的‎
Finn's writing a book about the murder‎
弗林正在写一本关于那起谋杀案的书‎
and he thinks you killed Wieder‎
他认为是你杀了维德‎
You need to talk to him‎
你得和他谈谈‎
<i>With other people's hands.</i>‎
借他人之手‎
Okay‎
好吧‎
I'm telling you, Laura‎
我告诉你 萝拉‎
you can fuck around all you want, but I'm not..‎
你想怎么乱搞随便你 但我不会…‎
<i>Devereaux was already a trained killer.</i>‎
德弗罗是一名训练有素的杀手‎
<i>With Finn out of the way she got him to come after you.</i>‎
杀了弗林之后 她便派他来杀你‎
He's home‎
他到家了‎
Wait until he leaves and then take care of it‎
等他走了再动手‎
She's a manipulator, Roy‎
罗伊 她就是幕后黑手‎
She's manipulating you right now‎
她正玩弄你于股掌间‎
She gets people to come in and do her dirty work‎
她让其他人来干脏活‎
and then she just skates away‎
好让自己全身而退‎
她必须负起责任‎
She has to be held accountable‎
Hm, it's such a funny thing the mind‎
人的心智真是十分有意思‎
the things it can live with‎
有能够忍受的事情‎
and the things it just can't bear‎
和无法忍受的事情‎
To get to die ignorant of both‎
就这样 在一无所知下死去‎
now that..‎
Oh, that is a special kind of bliss‎
就此刻而言…‎
可真是无比的幸福‎
What I did..‎
我做的一切…‎
I did for you‎
全都是为了你‎
罗伊·费里曼‎
<i>Breaking news in a decades-old murder</i>‎
沃特福大学十年前的谋杀案‎
<i>out at Waterford College</i>‎
有了最新的发展‎
<i>as fresh evidence in the brutal killing</i>‎
心理学家乔瑟夫·维德惨遭杀害的案件‎
<i>of psychology professor Joseph Wieder</i>‎
发现了全新的证据 被关押的死囚获判无罪‎
<i>exonerates a man incarcerated on death row.</i>‎
<i>29-year-old Isaac Samuel was convicted of revenge killing</i>‎
29岁的艾萨克·山谬被以报复杀人定罪‎
<i>and was scheduled to die by lethal injection</i>‎
原订在一个月内 接受注射死刑‎
<i>in just one month's time.</i>‎
<i>But information uncovered in the wake of a double homicide</i>‎
但经过上周二在维德废弃宅邸中‎
<i>this past Tuesday at Wieder's abandoned home</i>‎
发生的双重谋杀案后‎
<i>tells a different kind of story.</i>‎
新的证据颠覆了案件的全貌‎
<i>Name three objects in this room.</i>‎
说出房间内的三个东西‎
Chair, lamp... clock‎
椅子 灯 时钟‎
And three objects not in this room‎
说出房间内没有的三个东西‎
Wine glass, newspaper, gun‎
酒杯 报纸 枪‎
Today's date?‎
今天的日期？‎
October 21st‎
10月21日‎
Your place of birth?‎
你的出生地？‎
Larksville, Pennsylvania‎
宾州拉克斯维尔‎
Your mother's name?‎
你母亲的名字？‎
Florence‎
佛罗伦斯‎
Your father's name?‎
你父亲的名字？‎
George‎
乔治‎
Your middle school?‎
你就读的中学？‎
South Side‎
南边中学‎
患者姓名：罗伊·费里曼‎
Very good‎
很好‎
看来治疗的效果非常好‎
It seems the treatment's been very effective‎
It must be gratifying to be able to remember again‎
能够重拾记忆 你一定很开心‎
Yeah‎
是啊‎
<i>The former detective</i>‎
十年前调查此案的警探‎
<i>who investigated the case ten years ago,</i>‎
<i>Roy Freeman,</i>‎
罗伊·费里曼‎
协助将真凶绳之以法‎
<i>was instrumental in bringing the responsible parties</i>‎
<i>to justice.</i>‎
他揭露了一起华盛顿县警局‎
<i>He uncovered a twisted murder-for-hire plot</i>‎
<i>with roots in the Washington County Police</i>‎
和沃特福学术界扭曲的买凶谋杀阴谋‎
<i>and the Waterford academic community.</i>‎
<i>Mr. Freeman a highly decorated detective,</i>‎
费里曼先生是一位功勋卓著的警探‎
几年前因车祸离开了警察行列…‎
<i>left the police force some years ago</i>‎
<i>following a car accident...</i>‎
<i>Professor Wieder is a doctor. He took an oath.</i>‎
维德教授是一名医生‎
他曾发过誓‎
Keep them from harm and injustice‎
使病人免于伤害与不公平‎
Uh-huh Well, she took an oath too‎
呃 她也有发过誓‎
We both did‎
我们都发过誓‎
To have and to hold in sickness and in health‎
“我愿对你承诺 无论疾病或健康‎”
She came to see him six months ago‎
六个月前她去找他‎
about some, uh unresolved trauma‎
为了一些无法解决的创伤‎
You know I just don't believe you‎
我不会相信你的‎
Her alcoholic father she was..‎
她的父亲酗酒 她…‎
She was concerned she was repeating patterns‎
她担心自己 会在你们的婚姻中重蹈覆辙‎
in your marriage‎
She was vulnerable and he just took advantage‎
她很脆弱 而他利用了这一点‎
I'm sorry to have to be the one to tell you this‎
对不起 必须由我来告诉你真相‎
Well, why are you? Huh? Just for the fuck of it?‎
为什么是你？啊？凭什么？‎
You want me to believe you're some kind of good Samaritan‎
你要我相信 你是出于善意才告诉我‎
who just thought I should know my wife is fucking her shrink?‎
我的太太搞上了她的精神科医生？‎
Is that it?‎
是这样吗？‎
In case you want proof‎
如果你需要证据的话‎
黛安‎
And what's on that?‎
里面是什么？‎
Your wife‎
你的妻子‎
<i>♪ Oh, ah the miseries I've had... ♪</i>‎
唉 我所经历的苦难…‎
Just let me go‎
让我走吧‎
Get the fuck away from me‎
别再靠近我‎
Open the door, Diane Open the door‎
开门 黛安 快开门‎
别管我‎
<i>Leave me alone!</i>‎
Just let me go‎
让我走吧‎
Oh! Back so soon?‎
哦‎
这么快就回来了？‎
I'm... I'm sorry‎
我很抱歉…‎
No‎
不‎
等等‎
Jesus fucking Christ‎
我的天啊‎
Roy‎
罗伊‎
Let's get it done‎
结束这一切吧‎
字幕制作：葫芦        Q群：491019388
<i>♪ Well, it's moon rise in the daytime ♪</i>‎
月亮于白昼升起‎
<i>♪ Yeah, it's darkness crystal clear ♪</i>‎
黑暗无比清澈‎
<i>♪ In the desert and down hallways ♪</i>‎
在沙漠与走廊里‎
<i>♪ Somehow you always pull me near ♪</i>‎
你总是将我拉近‎
一袭金色装扮‎
<i>♪ All dressed up in golden ♪</i>‎
我是个傻瓜‎
<i>♪ I was a fool ♪</i>‎
<i>♪ I did what you told me ♪</i>‎
你说的 我都做了‎
<i>♪ But there's no rest for the lonely ♪</i>‎
但孤独却永无宁日‎
<i>♪ Are the wicked truly broken? ♪</i>‎
邪恶是否早已粉身碎骨？‎
<i>♪ Yeah ♪</i>‎
是啊‎
<i>♪ Hey, hey, sweet darlin' ♪</i>‎
嘿 亲爱的‎
<i>♪ Hey, hey I hate to see you fallin' ♪</i>‎
嘿 我不愿看着你堕落‎
<i>♪ Like a cannonball ♪</i>‎
宛如炮弹奋不顾身‎
<i>♪ Maybe you're no angel after all ♪</i>‎
也许你从来就不是天使‎
<i>♪ Now you say that you don't know me ♪</i>‎
你却说你从不认识我‎
但是 你成就了现在的我‎
<i>♪ But you made me who I am ♪</i>‎
<i>♪ And it's not about the feeling ♪</i>‎
我的感受并不重要‎
你是否能接受自己的所作所为？‎
<i>♪ Can you live with what you've done? ♪</i>‎
<i>♪ What you've done ♪</i>‎
你的所作所为‎
<i>♪ Yeah ♪</i>‎
是啊‎
<i>♪ Hey, hey, sweet darlin' ♪</i>‎
嘿 亲爱的‎
<i>♪ Hey, hey I hate to see you fallin' ♪</i>‎
嘿 我不愿看着你堕落‎
<i>♪ Like a cannonball ♪</i>‎
宛如炮弹奋不顾身‎
<i>♪ Maybe you're no angel ♪</i>‎
也许你不是天使‎
<i>♪ Hey, hey, sweet darlin' ♪</i>‎
嘿 亲爱的‎
<i>♪ Hey, hey I hate to see you crawlin' ♪</i>‎
我不愿看着你匍匐挣扎‎
<i>♪ Like a cannonball ♪</i>‎
宛如炮弹奋不顾身‎
<i>♪ Maybe you're no angel ♪</i>‎
也许你不是天使‎
<i>♪ Maybe you're no angel after all ♪</i>‎
也许你从来就不是天使‎