When Communism fell
in Eastern Europe,
law and order broke down.
Organized crime rose in its place--
not that it wasn't there before.
But after that,
it became open season,
everyone looking for a fistful of Euros,
myself included.
When one mob family has a problem
with another, they call me.
For the right price, I solve it.
I'm a fixer.
That's what I do.
But that's not the only reason
I'm here.
Hey, man.
It's been a while, Demyan.
What's up, brother?
- Liev, good to see you. I'm fine.
- Vlad is waiting for you upstairs.
- Hello?
- Yes, Nicholi. Yes.
We're ready on our end.
Everything is in place
and ready for the shipment.
Perfect. We'll be ready to deliver it
within the next 48 hours.
What can I say, Vlad?
It's been a pleasure.
I'll call you after it's arrived.
Welcome back, my friend.
It's good to be back, Vlad.
You were away too goddamn long,
you know that?
I had to drink alone.
I am sure
this was no problem for you.
Eh?
- Let's drink together.
- Come on.
Thank you, Nadia.
So, tell me about Grozny.
This deal, it went well. Because
they're looking after our interest.
I figured as much,
but I meant tell me about the city.
I have heard they almost rebuilt it now
brick for brick.
It's still Grozny.
Remember Sergei?
He shot that bitch
just for scuffing his boot.
He was a crazy bastard.
So many of our brothers
died in Chechnya.
To Sergei.
You know, someone
should go back there
and knock it down again
for old times' sake.
Vlad,
the war is long over, hmm?
Not in here it isn't.
Not for me.
- Vlad?
- I'm busy.
It's Mikhail Suverov.
Mikhail, good to hear from you.
We drew lines in the sand,
you and I.
You've wiped them clean.
What are you talking about?
You're doing business with
Nicholi Dvorak without my green light.
Bullshit.
Who the hell told you this?
Someone who knew.
Look, I don't know
who this man is,
but whoever it is,
he's lying to you.
He's trying to turn us
against each other.
The problem I have with that
is that his is not the only mouth
I've heard this from.
You know how it goes--
you hear things so many times,
there's maybe probably
some truth to it.
It's not what you think.
Nicholi, he came to us.
Of course he did, my friend.
You're trying to take my business
from beneath me.
You're undercutting me
by five points.
You killed three years
of peace between us
for a handful of silver, Vlad.
And I have just killed you.
No, wait--
Vlad? Demyan?
Talk to me.
We are pinned down.
He's got a gunman with .50 cal
across the street,
shooting through a window.
When you find him,
you murder the son of a bitch.
Across the street.
Go, go.
Ah!
- Come on!
- Ah!
- No, no!
Shit.
Is he done?
Get rid of that.
What are you waiting for?
Get rid of it.
And make sure he disappears.
We don't want any combat.
Hey, you, stop!
I said stop!
Turn the fuck around.
I said turn around!
There are those who say
it's a blessing to know who you are,
what you've been destined
to do in life.
But to me
it's more like a curse.
How did I end up here?
A series of random events, fate.
It's hard to tell anymore.
But here I am.
The money's good,
but you still pay a price.
Isaiah 43:18--
"Forget the former things;
do not dwell in the past."
If there's one thing in life
I know that's true,
it's that the past is the devil.
You can't run from it.
It's always behind you.
- Hey.
- Ciao.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, Janice.
Yes, it arrives tomorrow.
Me as well, my friend.
I'll call you with an update
as soon as I know more.
Speak then.
Bobby.
- How'd it go?
- Good.
He's chomping at the bit
to get the cargo.
- Hmm. Has it left Damascus yet?
- No.
it only left Astrakhan
an hour ago.
it should be there
about three and a half hours.
And the turnaround?
it should hit Colombia
by late tomorrow evening.
Say two hours
for offload, reload, refuel,
and then another 23 hours
back again.
We should be good to go
by the end of the week.
Is good.
Go and get the car.
Da?
I am calling
to negotiate terms.
Who the fuck is this?
Mikhail, my father always told me,
never ask a question
you already know the answer.
You waste my fucking time.
You thought I was dead,
didn't you?
Demyan.
Look, Mikhail,
I hold the reins now.
And fortunately for both you and I,
we are at the reset point.
So I figure it's best
we negotiate terms swiftly
while there's still blood
in the water.
Da. I'm listening.
You crawl into Vlad's grave
and bury yourself alive,
or I will find you
and I'll kill you
and I'll bury you myself.
Those are my terms.
What now?
We hit them harder
than they hit us.
I am going to unleash hell.
Go.
We need to think this through.
We need to be smart.
I'm going to destroy him.
Yeah, but we go to war with Demyan
and we can't go through Leo.
His cleaner screwing up and
not eliminating Demyan as well as Vlad
is the reason we have the problem
in the first place.
But he's the only independent
in town.
So what do you suggest?
Did you ever hear of the Wolf?
He's a fairy tale.
Tsk-tsk-tsk. The stories I hear,
they're no fairy tale.
Ari Perovsky has his number.
Shut it.
- What?
- Is this the man they call the Wolf?
I prefer Aleksey,
but yes, they're one and the same.
Can you be in Prague
by tomorrow?
That's a bit
short notice there, mate.
We'll double your rate.
Okay, text me an address.
And until then, fuck off.
Sorry about that.
Now about that money
you be owin' Slim Jimmy...
So, they sent a dog
to collect their scraps.
Actually they sent a wolf.
Go!
Can you pay?
Ahhh!
- Will you pay?
- Yes!
Ahh!
- When?
- Ah! Stop, God damn it!
It's in the other room.
Ah! Okay, okay!
It's in the vault behind the bar!
Ah-hh!
One for the client...
and the rest for me.
Good dog.
I've been watching her
for a long time now.
We're like two trains on the same track
headed for a collision course.
I've been reluctant
to deal with it.
But sooner or later,
if I don't,
it will deal with me.
The time is near.
Is that you, Leo?
Usual place, tomorrow,
half past 8:00.
Hey, listen, it's my--
Excuse me.
Well, hello, Ray.
One unaccounted for.
Yeah, so I was told.
Hey, man, Mikhail is the one
who asked to make a show of it.
If you didn't agree to the terms, you
shouldn't have accepted the job, Ray.
Fair enough.
He shouldn't have
pulled a woman in front of him.
She was a whore.
We work on results, Ray,
not excuses. You know that.
I will finish with Demyan.
I can promise you that.
You're a day late and a dollar short
for that, my friend.
They've already hired in
another shooter for the job.
So where does that leave me?
I strongly doubt
that Mr. Mikhail Suverov
will be requiring my services
anytime soon due to this little fiasco.
They're angry, Ray.
And who can blame them?
There's a million like Suverov,
just like him.
Why do you think I rang?
Another gig in my own back yard
doesn't exactly sit well with me, Leo.
Besides, this looKs like
we're biting the hand that feeds us.
Not if the hand isn't
feeding you anymore, it isn't.
Demyan wants to retaliate.
And he's willing to pay
a lot more than the Suverovs.
And hitting both brothers, well...
he'll pay extra for that.
Hey, Ray?
We started a war here.
Wars are good for business.
So you can cash in
or you can cash out.
The choice is yours.
♪ How lovely life, it gets ♪
♪ When you're in love ♪
♪ How soft the breeze, it blows ♪
♪ How quick the hour grows ♪
♪ When spring is in the air ♪
♪ And you're in love. ♪
What do you want?
I'm looking for Bobby Suverov.
And who the hell are you?
Aleksey Andreev.
Who?
Fuck you, that's who.
Much obliged.
♪ Hold on just a minute ♪
♪ Stop ♪
♪ Go ♪
♪ Hold on just a minute ♪
♪ Stop ♪
♪ Go. ♪
And you are?
Hungry, tired, thirsty.
Aleksey.
Come. Come!
What do you want?
Ahem.
Well, I don't know.
What would you recommend
to be sipping on
in a wet fucking heat
like the here and now?
A tall glass of ice water
coupled with shots, sir.
Are you all right with shots?
I prefer it, in fact.
Appleton Estate, 30-year-old rum
from Jamaica, sir.
I think it would be
perfect in here, sir.
I'm digging
the sales pitch there, boyo.
I'll give it a go.
So, my friend,
how do we begin?
Introductions would be nice.
Mikhail Suverov.
Bobby Suverov.
Aleksey.
As for my unfortunate moniker,
I'd rather you not use it.
It's so goddamn cliché.
Yeah, whatever.
Aleksey, tell me,
what do you know
about the current state of play
here in the Golden City?
Same old, same old,
I'd assume.
Two parties of different opinions
gnawing at each other's throats
over trivialities.
- I like the way you think.
- I don't...
think, that is.
I simply do.
What exactly is it
that you do?
I play chess with the old Boromets
in the park
every Tuesday,
Thursday afternoon.
I restore cars from the '70s,
pinball machines from the '90s,
and if you pay me enough,
I'll probably kill
anything that breathes.
Probably?
As in no innocent party, mate.
Kids are off the table regardless,
but I have no problem with women.
Although I only shoot them.
Using your hands
or a blade on a lady
just comes across as rather weak
and rather tacky, you know?
That's fair enough.
So what is it
that you want me to do?
Wreak havoc.
This is Demyan Ivanov,
his underboss Grigori Rikoniev,
and his number two.
And Nicholi Dvorak,
local Czech scum.
Nicholi is the one that started this,
so he's up first.
Hello, Nicholi.
Who are you?
A trained monkey.
But well enough paid
to do the little touch.
What are you doing, Ray?
Seriously, it's time to go.
I haven't finished my drink.
Just finish the one you've got
and pay.
Ha.
Bring me another drink now.
Sorry, we're closed.
You've had enough. Go.
Oh, yeah, bitch?
Then I'm taking this with me.
- You're not taking anything--
- Get your fucking--
- Ah!
- Let go of him.
Okay, okay, I'll go.
It's okay. Let go, please.
It's okay. Um...
- Everything okay, Janice?
- Yeah, it's fine. It's okay.
- I'm sorry about that.
- No, no, no, no.
No use crying over spilt milk.
Huh. You're American.
Yeah.
- Give me a sec, okay?
- No, that's okay.
No, I'll take care of this.
It'll just be a second.
Club soda and salt,
works every time.
First they killed Vlad,
and then Demyan becomes boss.
But is he happy
about his accidental promotion?
No.
The bastard appreciates nothing.
Hey, they served together
in Chechnya.
Vlad took a bullet for Demyan.
- They were brothers in blood.
- So what?
Does that make me
less of a man
because I didn't kill bitches
with them in Grozny?
I mean, what about me?
First I'm the underboss's underboss,
and then the boss dies
and what does that make me?
I'm still a fucking underboss.
Life is shit.
You always see the glass half empty
when you drink, Grigori.
Oh, by the way,
my glass is empty, Liev.
Tell me, if I always
get to refill your fucking drinks,
then what does that make me?
An underboss.
Two at table two,
one at table three,
four at table six,
three at table eight.
Two clips, 17 rounds apiece,
makes 34.
10 men, three rounds apiece,
four slated to miss.
Oi!
Which one of you poor fools
is Grigori?
Who the fuck are you?
So the left's
only three in the clip,
and the right...
one in the chamber.
It was a thing of beauty, no?
You know that shit
that killed Elvis, right?
This shit here
definitely would.
Well, if it killed Elvis, it could kill
me and maybe I don't want to do it.
Baby, relax.
It's just an expression. Come on.
Well, it doesn't sound good. You should
think of a different expression.
Just fucking do it.
Shut up.
I told you, right?
Baby?
What really did kill Elvis?
That? Pills, something.
I don't know. Fuck.
- You.
- Out.
You-- you worked for us.
Not anymore.
Look, whatever it is
they're paying you,
Mikhail will double it.
Okay?
He'll triple it.
No, wait. I mean...
I'm his only brother.
He should have had another.
It's Bobby! It's Bobby!
- What do you mean? What do you mean?
- There's someone out there!
He's got a gun!
No!
Yeah?
What the fuck is going on,
Andrei?
What's happened
to my goddamn update?
Yeah, Leo--
Leo's man took care
of Bobby last night.
And Mikhail?
From what I understand, he walked in
only seconds after the job was done.
Hmm.
This is fucking beautiful.
Yeah, I hear it's really
fucked Mikhail up.
Of course it did.
This was his brother.
He's been looking out for this kid
his whole life.
Maybe this time he should try
looking out a little harder.
I, uh...
I got bits of bad news.
What exactly is bad news, Andrei?
They hit Nicholi Dvorak.
What?
The police found him
floating in the pool, 9mm to the head.
It's not the end of the world.
We'll find somebody else
to do the business with.
Andrei, is this it?
This is the bad news?
Nicholi isn't the only one
who got hit.
What are you talking about?
Who else?
Somebody hit
the booking house.
Killed everybody--
killed all the boys.
Grigori?
Grigori, Liev--
everybody there dead.
What about my money?
I'm not sure.
What the fuck do you mean
you're not sure?!
I-- I just got bits and pieces.
The cops were crawling
out of the place.
- I couldn't stay for long, but--
- But nothing!
- Find my goddamn money, Andrei!
- Yes, boss. I understand, yes.
Just give me some time
to make some calls.
Give me 20 minutes
and I'll call you right back.
You've only got 10.
- Hey.
There you are.
You left yourjacket.
Oh, right.
How'd you find me?
Oh.
I found this in your pocket.
Address. Nice.
It's clean, by the way.
Oh. How much do I owe you?
No, no, no. I did it myself.
It's good.
Lucky for me, the right address
was in the envelope,
because it didn't have your name.
- I'm Ray.
- Oh.
- Just Ray?
- Ray Carver.
I'm Janice.
Look, I'm sorry forjust stopping by.
I just wanted to say thank you.
You know, you took off so fast, I--
No, I'm glad you did. I--
I guess I owe you one.
Oh, yeah?
Okay.
Well, in that case, um...
Mmm.
Fair enough.
Well, hopefully I'll--
I'll talk to you soon.
Hopefully.
Bye.
Shit.
Did you lock yourself out?
Nope, I'm good.
See ya.
Okay.
So...
am I still on the payroll?
Hmm.
What would you have me do?
If it were my way,
I would have you raze this city
to the ground
and salt every inch of it.
But I made a promise
to my brother
to be smart,
to think things through.
Come with me.
Mikhail.
Leo.
Hey, Aleksey.
I heard you were in town.
He's very expensive,
but he's worth it.
You two have met?
Let's just say that we both run
in similar circles.
Why am I here, Mikhail?
Your boy, whoever he is,
he didn't finish the job
with Demyan,
but he sure hit a home run
when he killed my brother.
Now exactly which boy
are we talking about?
Bobby's girl
saw the black bastard.
Come on, Leo, be honest.
How many monkeys
are there in this city?
Playing both sides
is a very dangerous game, my friend.
I want to know his name
and I want to know
where he sleeps.
Come on, Mikhail,
you're taking a piss.
What sort of handler
would I be
if I kept tossing out the names
of my assets, eh?
You disrespect me.
You are Iucky to be alive!
You accepted the contract
for my brother.
That makes you
directly involved in his death.
You should be counting your
fucking blessings that I am asking you.
My black bastard
isn't mine anymore.
Not since he cost me
my livelihood with you.
Come on, Mikhail!
You're my best client.
Do I look that stupid?
If you're lying to me,
I'll cut your fucking head off.
I don't doubt you, Mikhail.
I've known you for a long time.
You tell me everything you know
about this boy.
I will tell you one thing--
if you go looking for him,
he'll find you first.
I promise you.
That's not him.
This is longer than 10 minutes.
I'm sorry. I had to reach out
to a friend of mine at the department.
It wasn't easy.
And?
The cops took the money.
They have it in evidence
downtown.
I did find out, though,
that there was a survivor
at the betting room,
one of the bookies.
He saw the whole thing.
According to him,
this huge guy
came right to the front door,
called out Grigori,
whipped out two 9mms
and started blazing.
One guy?
This is bullshit, Andrei.
What the bookie said he looked like
is even crazier.
What do you mean?
Seven-foot tall,
wearing a tacky Hawaiian shirt
with a white fedora.
He said he looked like
a Frank Sinatra on steroids.
The Wolf.
What?
Mikhail--
he hired an out-of-towner.
He hired the Wolf.
But the Wolf is just
a bullshit ghost story.
No.
No, he's as real as it gets.
He must have been the same one
who took out Vlad as well.
What are we going to do?
What the fuck
do you think we're going to do?
We're going to go Wolf hunting.
Everyone bleeds, Andrei.
Put the word out-- I will pay top dollar
to find this guy, okay?
- Okay, I understand.
- Good.
Meet me tomorrow
at the betting room at 5:00.
Don't be late,
and fuckin' bring me something.
- Something good.
- Okay.
Leo, this is my third message.
What the hell is going on?
How'd they know
I was going to be there?
Call me back!
Wow.
Not bad.
Can I get you a drink?
No, I'm good. Thanks.
Look, it's just your accent,
you being from the States and all...
Mmm.
I guess you remind me
of home.
Mmm, ah.
You miss it?
Yeah.
But I had to leave.
Why?
Too many bad memories.
And now sometimes I think
I'm just in this city to hide, you know?
Too scared to go back.
Right. Scared of what?
My dad was murdered.
The guy that did it--
they never found him.
He had this mask on.
I saw him, though.
I saw the whole thing.
I was just a little girl,
but, hmm,
I'll never forget.
I'm sorry.
I mean, that's tough.
I don't know why
I'm telling you this.
I'm sorry.
I have to get this.
Leo?
I'm sorry, mate,
but I did you wrong.
What's up?
Things are going to get
pretty tough for us, Ray.
What are you telling me, Leo?
I'm gonna get out of Dodge.
You gotta get out too.
Get outta Prague.
Mikhail clamped the vise.
And I gave you up--
your name,
where you're gonna be,
where you live.
All of it. I'm sorry, mate.
If I didn't, I was history.
Sorry.
Hey.
This belonged to my dad.
He took it everywhere.
Why is it here?
Tell me!
There's pictures of me in here.
This is my life.
What-- why?
Did you have something to do
with his death?
Huh?
Tell me.
Tell me. Tell me!
Yes.
Why?
Because it was
what I was hired to do.
And now you're here
to kill me?
No.
I'm trying to protect you.
Am I supposed to
believe that, really?
Catch you at a bad time?
I threw you out the window.
I bounce real good.
And the grenades?
I thought it was a nice touch.
Just who the hell
do you think you are?
The bad guy.
That's funny.
I thought I was.
We just got back
from the black guy's place.
Is it over?
Is he dead?
No, I don't think so.
What happened?
The place was a mess.
But no bodies.
We thought this might be
interesting to you.
The same girl--
she's in every picture.
And Aleksey?
I called him.
He told me to tell you
goodbye.
Shit.
Guess what?
Thrill me.
We got an anonymous tip
about Mikhail's new man.
You're right--
it is the Wolf.
He's staying at some
high-end hotel downtown.
We end this.
We end this now.
Hi, this is Janice.
Please leave a message
and I'll get back to you
as soon as I can. ThanKs.
Hey, Janice, it's me again.
Can you please call me back?
It's just I, uh...
Just call me back.
- You ready?
- Shit.
I mean yeah.
Shh.
Everyone bleeds.
♪ The light shines from her eyes ♪
♪ Such a pretty sweet surprise ♪
♪ When the moon is in the sky... ♪
♪ When spring is in the air ♪
♪ Love is foolish... ♪
Come on.
You know,
some call it a sixth sense,
others intuition
or a gut instinct.
But in reality,
it's the little things
like terrible ventilation...
Sorry about this.
♪ Spring is in the air ♪
♪ And you're in love... ♪
Yah!
♪ When spring is in the air ♪
♪ And you're in love. ♪
Amateurs.
Yeah?
Ray, how the hell are you, mate?
Leo?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, it's me.
Why are you calling me
from Janice's phone, Leo?
I got down here as soon as I could
just like you asked.
How many waiting for me?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
She's here right now.
Lovely girl, Ray.
Hey, you should have told me
about her before.
We are actually
getting rat-assed together.
Can you get out?
No, no, no, no can do.
She's a bit tied up at the moment,
taking someone's order.
The place
is absolutely jumping, Ray.
I'm on my way.
Hey, we'll tie one off before we get
out of this dump for good, shall we?
Right.
Did I overdo it?
Depends on whether or not
he shows.
He'll show, trust me.
You won't be disappointed.
You've never looked better, Leo.
It's the one-armed push-ups, Ray.
Where is she?
She's with Mikhail.
Said he was going back to the club.
Sorry, Ray.
Looks like I four-letter-worded you
again, mate.
They say after the second time,
you should give flowers
or a box of candy.
Let's go.
I wish I had something
to give you.
Maybe you still can.
Thank you, Ray.
Jeremiah 8:20--
"The summer has passed,
the harvest has ended,
and we are not saved."
We all have to pay
for our sins eventually.
That I know.
We all have it coming.
♪ First name, Trouble ♪
♪ Middle name, Drama ♪
♪ One is the air ♪
♪ And one is in the chamber ♪
♪ I suggest you gun it, boy,
I think that you in danger... ♪
Hey, boss,
I can't reach any of the guys.
What do you mean?
None of them?
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ What, what... ♪
♪ First name, Trouble ♪
♪ Middle name, Drama ♪
♪ One is in the air ♪
♪ And one is in the chamber... ♪
♪ I suggest you gun it, boy,
I think that you in danger... ♪
Stay quiet!
Who's fucking next?!
Enough!
Back off!
Drop it or she's dead.
Put it down.
You're gonna die tonight.
The question is--
does she die with you?
Catch you fellas at a bad time?
Ray?
Go. Go.
You gotta go.
You gotta get out of Prague.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry for everything.
You gotta go.
I spent a lot of time
and came a long way
to ask you
one extremely short question.
Why didn't I kill you?
Nobody paid me to kill you.
But the next logical question is...
what the fuck
are you doing in my house?
I never really enjoyed being manipulated
by those underworld assholes,
so then I thought to myself--
"Aleksey, there are a lot of assholes
out there with lots of money.
Instead of earning it from them...
why don't we
just take it from them?"
Why not?
Maybe I'll give you
a call sometime.
That, my friend, you may.
Lamentations 3:26--
"It is good that a man
should both hope and quietly wait
for the salvation of the Lord."
No matter where you run,
you always end up
right back where it all started,
back with yourself.
Maybe I'll never know
how I ended up where I have.
I do know that the price
I have to pay
is that I'll never be saved,
but at least she can be.