(WALKERS SNARLING)
(THUNDERCLAP)
(GROWLING)
(WALKER GRUNTING)
(SNARLING)
(DOOR CREAKS)
Thomas, that's enough.
Okay, man. No problem, man.
(CHUCKLES)
(CARNIVAL MUSIC PLAYING)
You did great in there, buddy.
You were very brave.
(CHUCKLES) Hey!
Don't worry, little dude.
You're home, see? Safe and sound.
Apples?
Come on. Let's go take a look.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(CARNIVAL MUSIC PLAYING)
Thank you.
JUDITH: I'll take a witch hat.
-Good choice.
-Thank you.
Hey, you're one
of the new people, right?
I heard you all lived out
on the wasteland, killing rotters.
Yeah, I guess.
Cool. So there's probably
nothing you're afraid of, huh?
Come on, I'll show you
where all the good candy's at.
And I'm Mei.
Jude.
Cool name.
So, what do you think?
Takes a minute
to get used to all this, you know?
CAROL: You know,
this place was up and running
long before we ever got here.
Maybe we don't have
to do anything to make it work.
No, there's always something
you gotta do to make it work.
-(CROWD CHEERING)
-Want another one?
Oh, hello!
Happy Halloween.
And here's one for you,
and one for you.
PAMELA: And first place goes to,
dressed as our
very own Mercer, Celeste!
And this year's grand prize is
ten lottery tickets!
(CROWD CHEERING)
Let's take some pictures.
Thank you all for coming out today.
You all look fantastic,
and I'm so happy
you're out here for Halloween.
I always thought she was so classy.
I never knew anything about her.
Mmm.
I used to read a lot of tabloids.
Hey, you two look busy.
Connie's a reporter for the paper,
and we've got a full day, so...
How's work?
It's nice to be reporting again,
but Commonwealth news isn't exactly...
hard-hitting.
Have you met Pamela yet?
I've interviewed her once
before the world fell.
Yeah, and you also got her uncle
kicked out of Congress, so...
CAROL: That was you?
We got to go.
We have a lot to do
before the masquerade ball, so...
See you later.
You should ask her to dance.
I gotta get to work.
Okay. Catch up later?
Yeah. See you later.
(SNORTING)
(EXCLAIMS, LAUGHS)
ROSITA: Thanks for watching Coco.
I'll come by tonight to pick her up?
You know, why don't I just
keep her overnight?
You're sure to be exhausted
after the late shift.
You sure?
Yeah, of course.
Okay, cool. Thank you.
I'll get her before your Bible studies.
-Okay.
-(BABY CRYING)
-(ROSITA SHUSHES)
Thank you. Bye.
-Hey!
How's your place, get any better?
Hell no. No, I think this place
is literally made out of paper.
You sleeping?
Nah, not at all.
Can't wait till basic's over
and we get new apartments.
Worrying about money again
is so weird.
It's not forever.
JERRY: Ready, set, go!
(JERRY AND KIDS LAUGHING)
Tide's turning
and Ezra's back in the game,
just when we thought it was over.
There is no telling how this ends.
Ezekiel, come play.
Nothing I'd love more, but I've got
to take care of these little guys.
Us, too.
Okay, okay,
let's thank Ezekiel
for letting us use Shiva's collar.
It's the cherry on top
of that sweet costume, right?
I'm sorry, bud.
We've got to give it back.
You know, Ezra,
your dad saved this
from Hilltop when it burned,
because he knew
how precious it was to me.
But there's something actually more
precious, and that is your family.
So this leash is yours,
on two conditions.
One, that it always makes you
as happy as it made me,
and two,
that you honor Shiva's memory,
and always think of her
when you play with it.
(CHUCKLES)
Go have fun, buddy.
Ezekiel, are you sure?
Yeah, just be careful. It's a chain.
(LAUGHS)
JERRY: Who's hungry?
Yeah...
It looks like they had fun today.
-Well, I think it was good for everybody.
-Yeah.
How are you feeling?
Also good.
Excuse me.
How was your doctor's appointment?
Fine.
No changes.
Have you heard from Maggie or Lydia?
I'm sure they're okay.
You?
On a beautiful day like today?
Never better.
(WOMAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY OVER PA)
Oh, God! I'm so sorry.
I'm such a klutz.
Carol.
What are you doing here?
(SIGHS)
Sorry.
I'm snooping.
Well, I was worried about Ezekiel.
What do you want to know?
Well, I know that he needs surgery,
and I know that he's in line.
How long before
you get to number 147?
Too long.
Patients aren't aware
of their place in line,
so can you do me a favor?
Keep that to yourself.
Mmm-hmm. Of course.
Does Ezekiel know
how bad his chances are?
(EXHALES)
He knows the odds aren't good,
but he doesn't know
that there's likely no chance
he'll get the surgery unless,
by some miracle,
he moves up the line.
I'm sorry,
and I wish I could do more.
MERCER: Welcome to the kill house.
In this exercise,
killing is not your primary goal.
I'm looking for speed and teamwork.
Two teams of two will start
the course simultaneously.
One team goes through
the house on the right,
the other team
takes the house on the left.
There's one weapon,
per team, that must be shared.
Your objective,
get through the house,
and all the rotters inside.
There will be a rotter marked in red
at the end of each house.
First team to take out their red
gets one step closer
to earning their stripes.
But fail to work as a unit,
see what you get.
Hart, you're with Thomas.
Espinosa, Green.
Quintana, Johnson.
Dixon, Daniels.
Team up.
You mind if I go with Espinosa?
We make a good team.
Did I ask for your opinion?
Espinosa, Green,
Dixon, Daniels,
you're up first.
We got this. I know you're
the fastest and I'm the baddest,
-so we're good.
-Let's do this.
Hey, I'm Jake.
What's up, Jake? (CLEARS THROAT)
(BLOWS WHISTLE)
(GROWLING)
I got it!
(GRUNTS)
Clear.
(SNARLING)
Move.
Take it.
Keep going!
-(GRUNTING)
-(SNARLING)
MAN: Help!
Dixon!
Man, what was that?
He was good. I was right there.
I said speed and teamwork.
Green, Espinosa, nicely done.
Dixon...
You're with me.
(UPBEAT SONG PLAYING)
Looking up I see a new light...
You have to get this, it's so good.
I don't have any money.
Oh. Don't you get an allowance?
Hey, who's your friend, Jude?
Hi, Princess. This is Mei.
Oh, I see Mei got the memo.
I dig her already.
You girls need any help?
Um, I think I'm ready to check out.
Oh! Rock on. Good taste.
Well, pleasure doing business,
and come back any time, ladies.
You didn't have to.
It's a gift, for a friend.
Can I have the receipt?
Oh, don't worry about paying me back.
I'd like it as a reminder.
Of a good day.
MAX: None of these
are going to work.
-MAN: Are you serious? None of these?
-None of these.
MAN: This is ridiculous.
MAX: Aren't you gonna...
MAN: I'm not.
I'm not angry. I'm just frustrated.
I just don't know what she wants.
She wants something worthy
of tonight's guests. That isn't it.
We did the best we could
with the time we had.
She knows you'll come through.
(MAN SIGHS)
(GLASS BREAKING)
(GROWLING)
(SNARLING)
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
-(WALKERS SNARLING)
-(BANGING ON METAL CAGE)
Hi.
Espinosa,
we don't need you for this.
I volunteer.
Give her a bag.
I love volunteers.
Especially ones that look like that.
Right here.
All right. Let's see
what Santa brought me.
This supposed to be funny?
He gets the newest ones for his drills.
Advanced military training, Mercer.
-Advanced military training.
-It's fine.
DARYL: Hey! Careful with that one.
This toothpick?
(SIGHS)
It's not worth my time.
(CHUCKLES)
-You got to swing all the way through.
-That thing is pathetic.
Belongs on a wall.
All right, release the rotters.
With me.
Two at a time, on my count.
Three, two, one.
(SNARLING)
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
Why did you do that?
Are you serious?
This is the future soldier
of the Commonwealth?
MERCER: You shouldn't have intervened.
He would've been fine.
Did I fail another team-building exercise?
You're used to handling things
on your own, I get that.
But that's not
how it works around here.
Sometimes we have to
set each other up to win.
What does that have to do
with that little prick's ego?
This place
is as good as anything I've seen.
It'll give you a decent life
if you can cut it,
and I want you to succeed.
But you gotta get out
of your own damn way.
-(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING IN DISTANCE)
-(DOOR OPENS)
Did you get lost out there?
Sorry. There was
a long line at the kitchen.
(BABY CRYING NEXT DOOR)
There you go.
How was your day?
-What?
-How was your day?
It was great.
I made a new friend.
She got me a record.
You ever heard of Motorhead?
That's good stuff. Come here, boy.
No, hey!
-Daryl?
-Yeah?
Can I get an allowance?
Can we wait a little while
until my job settles,
then we can talk about it again?
So we can stay?
Do you want to stay, even after
Alexandria is all cleaned up?
I do.
DARYL: Yeah?
It's nice.
I think as long as my mom knows
where to find us, I want to stay.
(COUGHS) Yeah, no. It's way too tight.
(SIGHS)
All right, tell Max
we'll have something by tonight.
(EXHALES)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
How did you know?
My mother always
taught me to be observant.
So you found a way
to get outside the walls, huh?
Mmm...
What do you want from me?
I have a friend who's waiting for surgery,
and I need you to get him
to the front of the line.
That's a big ask.
It's difficult stuff.
Not for you.
First things first, I need to make sure
this wine goes over well.
Oh, it will.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
Mmm. I can almost taste it.
It's a shame. My kids
don't even know what mango is.
Well, maybe they'll have some one day.
(CHUCKLES)
My kids?
Not anytime soon.
Thank you.
Want some wine?
I hear it's really good.
Thank you.
Cheers.
(TOMI CLEARS THROAT)
What's wrong?
(CLEARS THROAT)
Not really my scene.
You know, I was cool being
on the other side of this.
This is your world, not mine.
Okay, just take it easy.
If this is how the other half lives,
might as well enjoy it, right?
-(SOFT JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
-(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
WOMAN: Good to see you, sir.
Wow. He hates you. That was a hate smile.
(CHEERING)
(CHANTING) Mercer! Mercer! Mercer!
Hey, Mercer?
(SPEAKS FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
I'm gonna need a translation.
I just wanted to say hi.
You look very handsome tonight.
(SPEAKS FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
It's not my thing.
Oh, it is, trust me.
You know, I...
I hate these work events.
They're kind of boring.
You want to make it more interesting?
Join me?
I would be honored.
MAN: Name?
She's with me.
There's a dress code.
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
YUMIKO: Princess!
Pamela. How do you like the wine?
It's fine.
If you'll excuse me, Lance,
I'm due for an interview.
Oh.
And we need to get a meeting on the
books about this Alexandria thing.
I have questions.
I have a pitch.
(CHUCKLES) I'm sure you do.
Connie, so lovely to see you again.
-Kelly, nice to meet you.
-Nice to meet you.
I hope you're enjoying the festivities.
It's such an eventful day.
But speaking on the record,
do you celebrate every holiday
with such grandeur here?
Traditions provide comfort
and structure in uncertain times,
so, yes, we treasure our holidays here.
But Halloween is extra special.
You may remember from
my father's time in the White House
that it was his favorite.
He always loved
a good masquerade ball.
What would your father say about
the class divide on display here?
Well, we're lucky you found us.
We appreciate and celebrate
every single person
who contributes to our vibrant community.
In fact, I wanna introduce you to someone.
Carrie is last year's lottery winner.
This is her first masquerade ball.
If you'll excuse me.
Excuse me, Pamela. I'm...
Excuse me, I'm sorry, Miss Milton
has a very strict itinerary tonight.
Thank you.
That guy looks so familiar.
Yeah, I kicked his ass in the train car.
-Is that true?
-Uh-huh.
YUMIKO: Why is he serving food?
HORNSBY: (OVER MIC) Testing.
Ladies and gentlemen, may I have
your attention for a moment, please?
It is my honor tonight to introduce
someone who needs no introduction,
our esteemed leader,
the Governor of the Commonwealth,
Miss Pamela Milton.
Thank you all
for coming out this evening.
Tonight, I have the great pleasure
of giving you a sneak peek
at something truly special.
(CROWD CLAPPING)
This is the work of the brilliant
Alexa Park, who is here tonight.
Don't be shy, Alexa.
It took Miss Park nine months
to lovingly create this painting.
Like many of our citizens,
she sustained serious injuries
out in the world before she found
sanctuary at the Commonwealth.
Thanks to my father's sacrifices,
we are all here.
Brick by brick and block by block,
we are putting the world
back together the way it was.
(APPLAUDING)
My father would be so proud to see
what the Commonwealth is today,
how much this place protects
and cares for all its citizens.
Bullshit!
This is bullshit.
-Sir, that's enough...
-Does anyone here really believe
the Commonwealth cares
for all its citizens?
Do you know who I am?
MAX: Sir, this isn't the time.
Please, you need to stop.
-Don't come any closer.
-(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
I just want to talk.
Will you please just talk to me?
I would have died for this place.
What's my name?
I don't know, but I'd like to.
Tyler Davis. I was a trooper.
I tried and I tried to reach you.
One mistake and I lost everything.
I came here to talk to you,
to make you listen.
Tyler, I want to listen.
-Let's talk, just the two of us.
-Don't lie!
This is what you care about.
Fancy parties and paintings.
(PEOPLE GASP, SCREAM)
-(GASPING)
-Not people like me.
We're nothing to you, disposable.
You're wrong, Tyler.
I see you. I see you're hurting,
and I want to fix that,
but first you have to promise
not to hurt anyone else.
Please put down the knife
and let my assistant go.
Her name is Max.
I'm like you.
I'm sorry.
(MAX GASPING)
I'm so sorry.
(MAX WHIMPERING)
-(CROWD GASPING)
-MERCER: Max.
-Did he hurt you?
-MAX: I'm okay. I'm okay.
SEBASTIAN:
You're just going to stand there?
Go after him!
Get him.
WOMAN ON RADIO:
South wing and roof, all clear.
MERCER: I need a status on Dixon.
(DOOR CREAKS)
(TYLER GRUNTS)
(TYLER BREATHING HEAVILY)
You got nowhere to go.
Are you taking me in?
You gonna give me a choice?
(SNIFFLING)
Shit, I didn't mean to...
I just wanted to talk to her,
to get her to understand.
Now it's never gonna happen.
Don't! Don't do that.
I screwed up protocols,
with a prisoner. I got beat up,
lost my apartment, my spending card.
I have no way to help
my sister or her kids.
You got a sister?
That means you got family.
A lot of us don't get
to have that anymore.
Don't take that away from her.
That's not fair.
(SOBS)
Turn around.
(HANDCUFFS CLICKING)
Let's go.
You caught the bastard.
Finally did something right.
No. No, you caught him.
Go ahead, take him to your mom.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(ALL APPLAUDING)
Well done, Sebastian.
Remove him.
You think getting rid of me
solves anything?
There are thousands more like me.
Resist the Commonwealth!
Visibility for workers, equality for all.
Are there thousands more?
No.
Make sure.
Inside please, miss. Let's go.
So how'd the wine go over?
Great. It was a good first step.
What's next?
I'm glad you asked.
Murphy, you're on the door.
Cass, Lewis, split the wait staff.
Figure out how he gained access.
Did he have help?
I want answers.
Espinosa.
-Your friend on the wait staff...
-Yeah?
See if she knows anything.
Yes, sir.
So did you work with him long?
No, we never even met.
Really? It's such a small crew in here.
You think I'm lying?
I'm just trying to figure out
what happened.
I think it's pretty clear.
Didn't you hear what he said?
Yeah, that there were others.
What do you think he meant by that?
No idea.
But for what it's worth,
I believe him.
This place is like a city from before.
You remember.
Yeah, I do.
But you're doing this?
So you don't know how he got in?
Nope.
Great.
I wasn't expecting you.
Well, it's nice to see you, too.
Come in.
Thanks.
Oh.
Vintage.
Yes, I am a lady of high caliber.
The highest.
Wasn't that something today?
Oh. (CHUCKLES)
They really know how to throw
a party around here, don't they?
Kids had a blast.
Yeah.
He would've loved it.
Yep.
I know that this was
too painful before,
but this belongs to you.
-You should keep it.
-No, no, no.
I want you to have it.
This place can be a fresh start,
if you want it to be.
How are you, really?
Just great.
Still finding reasons to smile.
Well, then...
To fresh starts.
(CHUCKLES)
-It's not bad.
-No.
It's not bad at all.
You always took the big glass.
(CAROL CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(EXHALES)
You look awesome.
Thanks.
And you look official.
Yeah? You think so?
Hmm.
I don't feel official.
(SNICKERS)
Hey, I got you something.
Yes!
Hmm.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Sittin' down in a restaurant
Tell the waiter just what you want
Is that the meat you wanted to eat?
Clear!
Hash browns and bacon strips
I love the way
that you lick your lips
No fooling, I can see you drooling
Feel the hunger grow
Come on baby, eat the rich
Put the bite on the son of a bitch
Don't mess up,
don't you give me no switch
Come on baby, and eat the rich
Come on honey, here's your supper
Come on baby, bite that sucker
Come on baby, eat the rich
Eat it baby, eat the rich
Eat the rich
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)