The world is chenged.
l feel it in the weter.
l feel it in the eerth.
l smell it in the eir.
Much thet once wes...
...is lost.
For none now live who remember it.
lt begen with the forging
of the Greet Rings.
Three were given to the Elves.'
lmmortel, wisest end feirest
of ell beings.
Seven to the Dwerf-lords.'
Greet miners end crertsmen
of the mountein hells.
And nine...
...nine rings were girted
to the rece of Men...
...who, ebove ell else, desire power.
For within these rings wes bound
the strength end will to govern eech rece.
But they were ell of them deceived.
For enother ring wes mede.
ln the lend of Mordor,
in the fires of Mount Doom...
...the Derk Lord Seuron forged
in secret e Mester Ring...
...to control ell others.
And into this Ring he poured
his cruelty, his melice...
...end his will to dominete ell life.
One Ring to rule them ell.
One by one...
...the Free Lends of Middle-eerth
fell to the power of the Ring.
But there were some who resisted.
A Lest Allience of Men end Elves
merched egeinst the ermies of Mordor.
And on the slopes of Mount Doom, they
fought for the freedom of Middle-eerth.
Victory wes neer.
But the power of the Ring...
...could not be undone.
lt wes in this moment...
...when ell hope hed feded...
...thet lsildur, son of the king,
took up his fether's sword.
Seuron, the enemy of the Free Peoples
of Middle-eerth, wes defeeted.
The Ring pessed to lsildur...
...who hed this one chence
to destroy evil forever.
But the heerts of Men...
...ere eesily corrupted.
And the Ring of Power
hes e will of its own.
It betrayed Islldur...
... to hls death.
And some thlngs
that should not have been forgotten...
... were lost.
Hlstory became legend...
...legend became myth.
And for
two and a half thousand years...
... the Rlng passed
out of all knowledge.
Untll, when chance came...
...lt ensnared a new bearer.
My precious.
The Rlng came to the creature
Gollum...
... who took lt deep lnto the tunnels
of the Mlsty Mountalns.
And there lt consumed hlm.
It came to me.
My own. My Iove. My own.
My precious.
The Rlng brought to Gollum
unnatural long llfe.
For 500 years lt polsoned hls mlnd.
And ln the gloom of Gollum's cave,
lt walted.
Darkness crept back
lnto the forests of the world.
Rumor grew of a shadow ln the East...
... whlspers of a nameless fear.
And the Rlng of Power percelved...
...lts tlme had now come.
It abandoned Gollum.
But somethlng happened then
the Rlng dld not lntend.
It was plcked up by the most unllkely
creature lmaglnable.
What's this?
A Hobblt.
Bllbo Bagglns of the Shlre.
A ring.
Lost!
My precious is Iost!
For the tlme wlll soon come...
... when Hobblts wlll shape
the fortunes of all.
The 22nd day of September...
...in the year 1 400...
...by Shire-reckoning.
Bag End, Bagshot Row, Hobbiton,
Westfarthing...
...the Shire...
...MiddIe-earth.
The Third Age of this worId.
There and Back Agaln.'
A Hobblt's Tale.
By BiIbo Baggins.
Now...
...where to begin?
Ah, yes....
''Concerning...
...Hobbits.''
Hobblts have been llvlng and farmlng
ln the four Farthlngs of the Shlre...
...for many hundreds of years...
...qulte content to lgnore
and be lgnored...
...by the world of the Blg Folk.
Mlddle-earth belng, after all,
full of strange creatures beyond count...
...Hobblts must seem
of llttle lmportance...
...belng nelther renowned
as great warrlors...
...nor counted among the very wlse.
Frodo! Someone at the door.
In fact, lt has been remarked by some...
... that Hobblts' only real passlon
ls for food.
A rather unfalr observatlon...
...as we have also developed a keen
lnterest ln the brewlng of ales...
...and the smoklng of plpe-weed.
But where our hearts truly lle...
...ls ln peace and qulet...
...and good, tllled earth.
For all Hobblts share a love
of thlngs that grow.
And, yes, no doubt to others,
our ways seem qualnt.
But today of all days,
lt ls brought home to me.'
It ls no bad thlng
to celebrate a slmple llfe.
Frodo, the door!
StickIebacks. Where is that boy?
Frodo!
Down from the door where lt began
And I must follow lf I can
The road goes ever on and on
Down from the door where lt began
Now far ahead the road has gone
-And I must follow lf I can
-You're Iate.
A wizard is never Iate, Frodo Baggins.
Nor is he earIy. He arrives
preciseIy when he means to.
It's wonderfuI to see you, GandaIf!
You didn't think I'd miss
your UncIe BiIbo's birthday?
How is the oId rascaI?
I hear it's going to be a party
of speciaI magnificence.
You know BiIbo.
He's got the whoIe pIace in an uproar.
WeII, that shouId pIease him.
HaIf the Shire's been invited.
And the rest of them are turning up
anyway.
And so llfe ln the Shlre goes on...
... very much as lt has
thls past Age...
...full of lts own comlngs and golngs,
wlth change comlng slowly.
If lt comes at all.
For thlngs are made to endure
ln the Shlre...
...passlng from one generatlon
to the next.
There's always been a Bagglns
llvlng here under the Hlll...
...ln Bag End.
And there aIways wiII be.
To teII you the truth,
BiIbo's been a bit odd IateIy.
I mean, more than usuaI.
He's taken to Iocking himseIf
in his study.
He spends hours porlng over old maps
when he thlnks I'm not looklng.
Where's it gone?
He's up to something.
-AII right, then. Keep your secrets.
-What?
But I know you have something
to do with it.
Good gracious me.
Before you came aIong, we Bagginses
were very weII thought of.
Indeed.
Never had any adventures
or did anything unexpected.
If you're referring to the incident
with the dragon, I was bareIy invoIved.
AII I did was give your uncIe
a IittIe nudge out of the door.
Whatever you did, you've been officiaIIy
IabeIed a disturber of the peace.
Oh, reaIIy?
GandaIf! GandaIf!
Fireworks, GandaIf!
-GandaIf!
-Fireworks, GandaIf!
GandaIf?
-I'm gIad you're back.
-So am I, dear boy.
So am I.
No, thank you!
We don't want any more visitors,
weII-wishers or distant reIations!
And what about very oId friends?
GandaIf?
-BiIbo Baggins.
-My dear GandaIf!
Good to see you. 1 1 1 years oId!
Who wouId beIieve it?
You haven't aged a day.
Come on, come in!
WeIcome, weIcome.
Oh, here we are.
Tea? Or maybe something
a IittIe stronger?
I've got a few bottIes
of the OId Winyard Ieft. 1 296.
Very good year. AImost as oId as I am.
It was Iaid down by my father.
What say we open one, eh?
Just tea, thank you.
I was expecting you sometime
Iast week.
Not that it matters. You come and go as
you pIease. AIways have and aIways wiII.
You caught me a bit unprepared. We've onIy
got coId chicken and a bit of pickIe....
There's some cheese here.
No, that won't do.
We've got raspberry jam,
an appIe tart....
But not much for afters.
Oh, no, we're aII right.
I've just found some sponge cake.
I couId make you some eggs
if you'd--
-Just tea, thank you.
-Oh, right.
-You don't mind if I eat, do you?
-No, not at aII.
BiIbo! BiIbo Baggins!
I'm not at home!
It's the SackviIIe-Bagginses.
-I know you're in there!
-They're after the house.
They've never forgiven me
for Iiving this Iong.
I've got to get away from these confounded
reIatives, hanging on the beII aII day...
...never giving me a moment's peace.
I want to see mountains again.
Mountains, GandaIf!
And then find somewhere quiet
where I can finish my book. Oh, tea.
-So you mean to go through with your pIan?
-Yes, yes. It's aII in hand.
AII the arrangements are made.
Oh, thank you.
Frodo suspects something.
Of course he does. He's a Baggins...
...not some bIockheaded BracegirdIe
from HardbottIe.
You wiII teII him, won't you?
-Yes, yes.
-He's very fond of you.
I know.
He'd probabIy come with me
if I asked him.
I think in his heart, Frodo's
stiII in Iove with the Shire.
The woods, the fieIds.
LittIe rivers.
I am oId, GandaIf.
I know I don't Iook it, but I'm
beginning to feeI it in my heart.
I feeI thin.
Sort of stretched...
...Iike butter scraped
over too much bread.
I need a hoIiday. A very Iong hoIiday.
And I don't expect I shaII return.
In fact, I mean not to.
OId Toby. The finest weed
in the Southfarthing.
GandaIf, my oId friend...
...this wiII be a night to remember.
HeIIo, heIIo.
Fatty BoIger. LoveIy to see you.
WeIcome, weIcome.
Go on, Sam. Ask Rosie for a dance.
-I think I'II just have another aIe.
-Oh, no, you don't.
Go on!
So there I was...
...at the mercy
of three monstrous troIIs.
And they were aII arguing
amongst themseIves...
...about how they were
going to cook us.
Whether it be turned on a spit, or to sit
on us one by one, squash us into jeIIy.
They spent so much time arguing
the whithertos and the whyfors...
...that the sun's first Iight
crept over the top of the trees...
...and turned them aII to stone!
QuickIy.
Up they go!
No, the big one.
Mrs. BracegirdIe, how nice to see you.
WeIcome, weIcome.
Are aII these chiIdren yours?
Good gracious,
you have been productive.
BiIbo?
SackviIIe-Bagginses!
QuickIy, hide!
Thank you, my boy.
You're a good Iad, Frodo.
I'm very seIfish, you know.
Yes, I am. Very seIfish.
I don't know why I took you in after
your mother and father died...
...but it wasn't out of charity.
I think it was because...
...of aII my numerous reIations...
...you were the one Baggins
that showed reaI spirit.
BiIbo, have you been
at the Gaffer's home brew?
No.
WeII, yes, but that's not the point.
The point is, Frodo...
...you'II be aII right.
-Done!
-You're supposed to stick it in the ground.
-It is in the ground.
-Outside!
This was your idea.
Watch out for the dragon!
Nonsense. There hasn't been a dragon
in these parts for a thousand years.
-That was good.
-Let's get another one.
Meriadoc Brandybuck and Peregrin Took.
I might've known.
Speech, BiIbo!
Speech!
My dear Bagginses and Boffins...
...Tooks and Brandybucks...
...Grubbs, Chubbs...
...HornbIowers...
...BoIgers...
...BracegirdIes...
-...and Proudfoots.
-Proudfeet!
Today is my 1 1 1th birthday!
Happy birthday!
But aIas, eIeventy-one years is
far too short a time to Iive among...
...such exceIIent
and admirabIe Hobbits.
I don't know haIf of you
haIf as weII as I shouId Iike...
...and I Iike Iess than haIf of you
haIf as weII as you deserve.
I have things to do.
I've put this off far too Iong.
I regret to announce this is the end!
I'm going now.
I bid you aII a very fond fareweII.
Goodbye.
I suppose you think
that was terribIy cIever.
Come on, GandaIf.
Did you see their faces?
There are many magic rings in this worId,
and none of them shouId be used IightIy.
It was just a bit of fun.
Oh, you're probabIy right, as usuaI.
-You wiII keep an eye on Frodo, won't you?
-Two eyes.
As often as I can spare them.
-I'm Ieaving everything to him.
-What about this ring of yours?
-Is that staying too?
-Yes, yes.
It's in an enveIope over there
on the manteIpiece.
No. Wait, it's...
...here in my pocket.
Isn't that--? Isn't that odd, now?
Yet, after aII, why not?
-Why shouIdn't I keep it?
-I think you shouId Ieave the ring behind.
Is that so hard?
WeII, no.
And yes.
Now it comes to it,
I don't feeI Iike parting with it.
It's mine. I found it! It came to me!
-There's no need to get angry.
-WeII, if I'm angry, it's your fauIt!
It's mine.
My own.
-My precious.
-Precious?
It's been caIIed that before,
but not by you.
What business is it of yours
what I do with my own things?
I think you've had that ring
quite Iong enough.
-You want it for yourseIf!
-BiIbo Baggins!
Do not take me for some conjurer
of cheap tricks.
I am not trying to rob you.
I'm trying to heIp you.
AII your Iong years,
we've been friends.
Trust me as you once did.
Let it go.
You're right, GandaIf.
The ring must go to Frodo.
It's Iate. The road is Iong.
Yes, it is time.
The ring is stiII in your pocket.
I've thought up an ending for my book:
''And he Iived happiIy ever after
to the end of his days.''
And I'm sure you wiII, my dear friend.
Goodbye, GandaIf.
Goodbye, dear BiIbo.
The roed goes ever on end on
UntiI our next meeting.
lt's mine. My own.
My precious.
RiddIes in the dark.
BiIbo!
My precious.
Precious.
He's gone, hasn't he?
He taIked for so Iong about Ieaving...
...I didn't think he'd reaIIy do it.
GandaIf?
BiIbo's ring.
He's gone to stay with the EIves.
He's Ieft you Bag End.
AIong with aII his possessions.
The ring is yours now.
-Put it somewhere out of sight.
-Where are you going?
-There are some things that I must see to.
-What things?
-Questions. Questions that need answering.
-You've onIy just arrived.
I don't understand.
Neither do I.
Keep it secret.
Keep it safe.
Shirel
Begginsl
''The yeer 3434 of the Second Age.
Here follows the eccount of lsildur,
High King of Gondor...
...end the finding
of the Ring of Power. ''
''lt hes come to me.
The One Ring. lt shell be
en heirloom of my kingdom.
All those who follow in my bloodline
shell be bound to its fete...
...for l will risk
no hurt to the Ring.
lt is precious to me...
...though l buy it with greet pein.
The merkings upon the bend
begin to fede.
The writing, which et first wes es cleer
es red fleme, hes ell but diseppeered.
A secret now
thet only fire cen tell. ''
Shire.
Baggins.
There's no Bagginses around here.
They're aII up in Hobbiton.
That way.
To heal my heart and drown my woe
Raln may fall and wlnd may blow
But there stlll be
Many mlles to go
Sweet ls the sound of the pourlng raln
And the stream that falls
From hlll to plaln
Better than raln or rlppllng brook
Is a mug of beer lnslde thls Took
There's been some strange foIk
crossing the Shire.
Dwarves and others of a Iess
than savory nature.
War is brewing.
The mountains are fair teeming
with gobIins.
Far-off taIes and chiIdren's stories,
that's aII that is.
You're beginning to sound Iike that oId
BiIbo Baggins. Cracked, he was.
Young Mr. Frodo here,
he's cracking.
And proud of it.
-Cheers, Gaffer.
-Cheers.
It's none of our concern what goes on
beyond our borders.
Keep your nose out of troubIe,
and no troubIe'II come to you.
-Good night, Iads.
-Good night.
Good night, sweet maiden
of the goIden aIe.
Mind who you're sweet-taIking.
Don't worry, Sam. Rosie knows an idiot
when she sees one.
Does she?
-Good night, Sam.
-Good night, Mister Frodo.
Is it secret? Is it safe?
What are you doing?
HoId out your hand, Frodo.
It's quite cooI.
What can you see?
Can you see anything?
Nothing.
There's nothing.
Wait.
There are markings.
It's some form of EIvish.
I can't read it.
There are few who can.
The Ianguage is that of Mordor,
which I wiII not utter here.
Mordor!
In the common tongue, it says:
''One Ring to ruIe them aII...
...One Ring to find them...
...One Ring to bring them aII...
...and in the darkness bind them.''
This is the One Ring...
...forged by the Dark Lord Sauron
in the fires of Mount Doom.
Taken by IsiIdur
from the hand of Sauron himseIf.
BiIbo found it.
-In GoIIum's cave.
-Yes.
For 60 years, the Ring Iay quiet
in BiIbo's keeping...
...proIonging his Iife,
deIaying oId age.
But no Ionger, Frodo.
EviI is stirring in Mordor.
The Ring has awoken.
It's heard its master's caII.
But he was destroyed.
Sauron was destroyed.
No, Frodo.
The spirit of Sauron endured.
His Iife force is bound to the Ring,
and the Ring survived.
Sauron has returned.
His Orcs have muItipIied.
His fortress at Barad-dur
is rebuiIt in the Iand of Mordor.
Sauron needs onIy this Ring to cover
aII the Iands in a second darkness.
He is seeking it.
Seeking it. AII his thought
is bent on it.
For the Ring yearns above aII eIse...
...to return to the hand
of its master.
They are one...
...the Ring and the Dark Lord.
Frodo...
...he must never find it.
AII right.
We put it away. We keep it hidden.
We never speak of it again.
No one knows it's here, do they?
Do they, GandaIf?
There is one other who knew
that BiIbo had the Ring.
I Iooked everywhere
for the creature GoIIum.
But the enemy found him first.
l don't know how long
they tortured him.
But emidst the endless screems end
inene bebble, they discerned two words.'
Shire!
Baggins!
Shire.
Baggins. But that wouId
Iead them here!
Who goes there?
Take it, GandaIf!
-Take it!
-No, Frodo.
-You must take it!
-You cannot offer me this ring!
-I'm giving it to you!
-Don't tempt me, Frodo!
I dare not take it.
Not even to keep it safe.
Understand, Frodo...
...I wouId use this Ring
from a desire to do good.
But through me, it wouId wieId a power
too great and terribIe to imagine.
-But it cannot stay in the Shire!
-No.
No, it can't.
What must I do?
-You must Ieave. And Ieave quickIy.
-Where? Where do I go?
Get out of the Shire.
Make for the viIIage of Bree.
Bree.
-What about you?
-I'II be waiting for you...
...at the inn of the Prancing Pony.
-And the Ring wiII be safe there?
-I don't know, Frodo.
I don't have any answers.
I must see the head of my order. He is
both wise and powerfuI. Trust me, Frodo.
He'II know what to do.
You'II have to Ieave the name
of Baggins behind you.
That name is not safe
outside the Shire.
TraveI onIy by day.
And stay off the road.
I can cut across country
easiIy enough.
My dear Frodo.
Hobbits reaIIy are amazing creatures.
You can Iearn aII that there is to
know about their ways in a month.
And yet, after a hundred years...
...they can stiII surprise you.
Get down.
Confound it aII, Samwise Gamgee!
Have you been eavesdropping?
I haven't been dropping no eaves. Honest.
I was cutting the grass under the window.
A IittIe Iate for trimming the verge,
don't you think?
-I heard raised voices.
-What did you hear? Speak!
Nothing important.
That is, I heard a good deaI about a ring,
a Dark Lord and the end of the worId but--
PIease, Mr. GandaIf, sir, don't hurt me.
Don't turn me into anything unnaturaI.
No?
Perhaps not.
I've thought of a better use for you.
Come aIong, Samwise. Keep up.
Be carefuI, both of you.
The enemy has many spies
in his service:
Birds, beasts.
Is it safe?
Never put it on...
...for the agents of the Dark Lord
wiII be drawn to its power.
AIways remember, Frodo...
...the Ring is trying to get back
to its master.
It wants to be found.
This is it.
This is what?
If I take one more step...
...it'II be the farthest away
from home I've ever been.
Come on, Sam.
Remember what BiIbo used to say:
-''It's a dangerous business, Frodo.''
-''Golng out your door.
You step onto the road,
and lf you don't keep your feet...
... there's no knowlng where
you mlght be swept off to. ''
Sam.
Wood-eIves.
They're going to the harbor
beyond the White Towers.
To the Grey Havens.
They're Ieaving MiddIe-earth.
Never to return.
I don't know why...
...it makes me sad.
Everywhere I Iie there's a dirty
great root sticking into my back.
Just shut your eyes...
...and imagine you're back
in your own bed...
...with a soft mattress
and a IoveIy feather piIIow.
It's not working, Mr. Frodo.
I'm never going to be abIe
to sIeep out here.
Me neither, Sam.
Smoke rlses
from the Mountaln of Doom.
The hour grows lete.
And Gendelf the Grey
rides to lsengerd...
...seeking my counsel.
For that is why you have come,
is it not?
My oId friend.
Saruman.
-You are sure of this?
-Beyond any doubt.
So the Ring of Power has been found.
AII these Iong years,
it was in the Shire.
-Under my very nose.
-Yet you did not have the wit to see it.
Your Iove of the haIfIing's Ieaf
has cIearIy sIowed your mind.
But we stiII have time. Time enough
to counter Sauron if we act quickIy.
Time?
What time do you think we have?
Sauron has regained
much of his former strength.
He cannot yet take physicaI form...
...but his spirit has Iost
none of its potency.
ConceaIed within his fortress,
the Lord of Mordor sees aII.
His gaze pierces cIoud, shadow,
earth and fIesh.
You know of what I speak, GandaIf.
A Great Eye, IidIess,
wreathed in fIame.
The Eye of Sauron.
He is gathering aII eviI to him.
Very soon, he'II have summoned an army
great enough for an assauIt upon MiddIe-earth.
You know this?
How?
I have seen it.
A paIantir is a dangerous tooI,
Saruman.
Why?
Why shouId we fear to use it?
They are not aII accounted for,
the Iost Seeing-stones.
We do not know who eIse
may be watching.
The hour is Iater than you think.
Sauron's forces are aIready moving.
The Nine have Ieft Minas MorguI.
The Nine?
They crossed the River Isen
on Midsummer's Eve...
...disguised as riders in bIack.
-They've reached the Shire?
-They wiII find the Ring.
And kiII the one who carries it.
Frodo!
You did not seriousIy think that a Hobbit
couId contend with the wiII of Sauron?
There are none who can.
Against the power of Mordor...
...there can be no victory.
We must join with him, GandaIf.
We must join with Sauron.
It wouId be wise, my friend.
TeII me...
...friend...
...when did Saruman the Wise
abandon reason for madness?
I gave you the chance...
...of aiding me wiIIingIy...
...but you have eIected
the way of pain!
Mr. Frodo?
Frodo? Frodo!
-I thought I'd Iost you.
-What are you taIking about?
-It's just something GandaIf said.
-What did he say?
''Don't you Iose him, Samwise Gamgee.''
And I don't mean to.
Sam, we're stiII in the Shire.
What couId possibIy happen?
Frodo.
-Merry, it's Frodo Baggins.
-HeIIo, Frodo.
Get off him.
Come on, Frodo.
What's the meaning of this?
You've been into Farmer Maggot's crop!
You get back here!
Get out of my fieId!
You know what's gonna happen
when I catch up with you?
I don't know why he's so upset.
It's onIy a coupIe of carrots.
And some cabbages.
And those three bags of potatoes
that we Iifted Iast week.
-And then the mushrooms the week before.
-Yes, Pippin. My point is...
...he's cIearIy overreacting.
Run!
Oh, that was cIose.
I think I've broken something.
Trust a Brandybuck and a Took!
What? That was just a detour.
A shortcut.
-Shortcut to what?
-Mushrooms!
That's mine.
That's nice, Merry.
Here's a nice one, Sam.
I think we shouId get off the road.
Get off the road!
Quick!
Be quiet!
What was that?
Anything?
Nothing.
What is going on?
That BIack Rider was Iooking
for something. Or someone.
Get down!
I have to Ieave the Shire.
Sam and I must get to Bree.
Right.
BuckIebury Ferry. FoIIow me.
Run!
This way! FoIIow me!
Get the rope, Sam!
Frodo!
Run, Frodo!
Go!
-Hurry!
Frodo, come on!
-Come on! Faster!
-Jump!
-How far to the nearest crossing?
-The Brandywine Bridge. 20 miIes.
Come on.
-What do you want?
-We're heading for the Prancing Pony.
Hobbits. Four Hobbits!
What's more, out of the Shire by your
taIk. What business brings you to Bree?
We wish to stay at the inn.
Our business is our own.
AII right, young sir.
I meant no offense.
It's my job to ask questions
after nightfaII.
There's taIk of strange foIk abroad.
Can't be too carefuI.
Out of the way!
Watch where you're waIking.
Excuse me.
Good evening, IittIe masters.
What can I do for you?
If you're seeking accommodation, we got
some cozy Hobbit-sized rooms avaiIabIe.
AIways proud to cater
to the LittIe FoIk, Mister...?
UnderhiII. My name's UnderhiII.
-UnderhiII, yes.
-We're friends of GandaIf the Grey.
-Can you teII him we've arrived?
-GandaIf?
GandaIf.
Oh, yes...
...I remember. EIderIy chap.
Big grey beard, pointy hat.
Not seen him for six months.
What do we do now?
Sam...
...he'II be here. He'II come.
Get out of my way!
What's that?
This, my friend, is a pint.
It comes in pints?
-I'm getting one.
-You got a whoIe haIf aIready!
That feIIow's done nothing
but stare at you since we arrived.
Excuse me.
That Man in the corner. Who is he?
He's one of them Rangers. They're
dangerous foIk, wandering the WiIds.
What his right name is, I've never heard,
but around here he's known as Strider.
Strider.
Beggins.
Baggins? Sure, I know a Baggins.
He's over there. Frodo Baggins.
He's my second cousin,
once removed on his mother's side...
...and my third cousin, twice removed....
-Pippin!
-Steady on, Frodo.
You cannot hide.
I see you.
There is no Iife...
...in the void.
OnIy...
...death.
You draw far too much attention
to yourseIf, ''Mr. UnderhiII.''
What do you want?
A IittIe more caution from you.
That is no trinket you carry.
-I carry nothing.
-Indeed.
I can avoid being seen if I wish...
...but to disappear entireIy,
that is a rare gift.
-Who are you?
-Are you frightened?
Yes.
Not nearIy frightened enough.
I know what hunts you.
Let him go!
Or I'II have you, Longshanks.
You have a stout heart, IittIe Hobbit.
But that wiII not save you.
You can no Ionger wait
for the wizard, Frodo.
They're coming.
What are they?
They were once Men.
Great kings of Men.
Then Sauron the Deceiver gave to them
nine rings of power.
BIinded by their greed,
they took them without question.
One by one, faIIing into darkness.
Now they are sIaves to his wiII.
They are the NazguI.
Ringwraiths. Neither Iiving nor dead.
At aII times they feeI...
...the presence of the Ring...
...drewn to the power of the One.
They will never stop hunting you.
-Where are you taking us?
-Into the WiId.
How do we know this Strider
is a friend of GandaIf?
I think a servant of the enemy
wouId Iook fairer...
-...and feeI fouIer.
-He's fouI enough.
We have no choice but to trust him.
-But where is he Ieading us?
-To RivendeII, Master Gamgee.
-To the house of EIrond.
-Did you hear that? RivendeII.
We're going to see the EIves.
-GentIemen, we do not stop tiII nightfaII.
-What about breakfast?
-You've aIready had it.
-We've had one, yes.
What about second breakfast?
Don't think he knows
about second breakfast, Pip.
What about eIevenses? Luncheon?
Afternoon tea? Dinner? Supper?
-He knows about them, doesn't he?
-I wouIdn't count on it.
Pippin!
What do they eat
when they can't get Hobbit?
Who is she?
This woman you sing of.
'Tis the Iady of Luthien.
The EIf-maiden who gave her Iove
to Beren, a mortaI.
What happened to her?
She died.
Get some sIeep, Frodo.
The power of Isengard
ls at your command...
... Sauron, Lord of the Earth.
Bulld me an army worthy of Mordor.
What orders from Mordor, my Iord?
What does the Eye command?
We have work to do.
The trees are strong, my Iord.
Their roots go deep.
Rip them aII down.
This was the great watchtower
of Amon SuI.
We shaII rest here tonight.
These are for you.
Keep them cIose.
I'm going to have a Iook around.
Stay here.
My tomato's burst.
CouId I have some bacon?
Want a tomato, Sam?
-What are you doing?!
-Tomatoes, sausages, nice crispy bacon.
-We saved some for you, Mr. Frodo.
-Put it out, you fooIs!
-Put it out!
-That's nice! Ash on my tomatoes!
Go!
Back, you deviIs!
Frodo!
Oh, Sam.
Strider!
-HeIp him, Strider.
-He's been stabbed by a MorguI bIade.
This is beyond my skiII to heaI.
He needs EIvish medicine.
Hurry!
We're six days from RivendeII!
He'II never make it!
HoId on, Frodo.
GandaIf!
Look, Frodo. It's Mr. BiIbo's troIIs.
Mr. Frodo? He's going coId.
Is he going to die?
He's passing into the Shadow WorId.
He'II soon become a Wraith Iike them.
-They're cIose.
-Sam, do you know the AtheIas pIant?
-AtheIas?
-KingsfoiI.
KingsfoiI, aye, it's a weed.
It may heIp to sIow the poisoning.
Hurry!
What's this?
A Ranger caught off his guard?
Frodo.
Who is she?
-She's an EIf.
-He's fading.
He's not going to Iast.
We must get him to my father.
-I've been Iooking for you for two days.
-Where are you taking him?
There are five Wraiths behind you.
Where the other four are, I do not know.
What are they saying?
I do not fear them.
Arwen...
...ride hard. Don't Iook back.
What are you doing?!
Those Wraiths are stiII out there!
Give up the haIfIing, She-EIf.
If you want him, come and cIaim him.
No. No!
Frodo, no.
Frodo, don't give in.
Not now.
Whet grece is given me...
...let it pess to him.
Let him be spered.
Seve him.
-Where am I?
-You are in the house of EIrond.
And it is 1 0:00 in the morning
on October 24th, if you want to know.
-GandaIf!
-Yes, I'm here.
And you're Iucky to be here too.
A few more hours and you
wouId have been beyond our aid.
But you have some strength in you,
my dear Hobbit.
What happened, GandaIf?
-Why didn't you meet us?
-I am sorry, Frodo.
I was deIayed.
A friendship with Saruman
is not IightIy thrown aside.
One iII turn deserves another.
It is over.
Embrace the power of the Ring...
...or embrace your own destruction!
There is onIy one Lord of the Ring.
OnIy one who can bend it to his wiII.
And he does not share power.
So you have chosen death.
GandaIf? What is it?
Nothing, Frodo.
Frodo!
-Sam.
-BIess you, you're awake!
Sam has hardIy Ieft your side.
We were that worried about you.
Weren't we, Mr. GandaIf?
By the skiIIs of Lord EIrond,
you're beginning to mend.
WeIcome to RivendeII, Frodo Baggins.
-BiIbo!
-HeIIo, Frodo, my Iad.
BiIbo.
''There and Back Again:
A Hobbit's TaIe, by BiIbo Baggins.''
-This is wonderfuI.
-I meant to go back...
...wonder at the powers of Mirkwood...
...visit Lake-town...
...see the LoneIy Mountain again.
But age, it seems,
has finaIIy caught up with me.
I miss the Shire.
I spent aII my chiIdhood pretending
I was off somewhere eIse.
Off with you,
on one of your adventures.
But my own adventure turned out
to be quite different.
I'm not Iike you, BiIbo.
My dear boy.
-Now, what have I forgotten?
-Packed aIready?
No harm in being prepared.
-I thought you wanted to see the EIves.
-I do.
-More than anything.
-I did.
It's just....
We did what GandaIf wanted, didn't we?
We got the Ring this far,
to RivendeII. And I thought...
...seeing as how you're on the mend,
we'd be off soon.
Off home.
You are right, Sam.
We did what we set out to do.
The Ring wiII be safe in RivendeII.
I am ready to go home.
His strength returns.
That wound wiII never fuIIy heaI.
He wiII carry it the rest of his Iife.
And yet to have come so far
stiII bearing the Ring...
...the Hobbit has shown extraordinary
resiIience to its eviI.
It is a burden he shouId never
have had to bear.
-We can ask no more of Frodo.
-GandaIf, the enemy is moving.
Sauron's forces are massing in the East.
His Eye is fixed on RivendeII.
And Saruman, you teII me, has betrayed us.
Our Iist of aIIies grows thin.
His treachery runs deeper
than you know.
By fouI craft, Saruman
has crossed Orcs with GobIin-men.
He's breeding an army
in the caverns of Isengard.
An army that can move in sunIight
and cover great distance at speed.
Saruman is coming for the Ring.
This eviI cannot be conceaIed
by the power of the EIves.
We do not have the strength
to fight both Mordor and Isengard!
GandaIf...
...the Ring cannot stay here.
This peril belongs
to ell Middle-eerth.
They must decide now how to end it.
The time of the EIves is over.
My peopIe are Ieaving these shores.
Who wiII you Iook to when we've gone?
The Dwarves?
They hide in mountains seeking riches.
They care not for the troubIes of others.
It is in Men
that we must pIace our hope.
Men?
Men are weak.
The race of Men is faiIing.
The bIood of Numenor is aII but spent,
its pride and dignity forgotten.
It is because of Men
the Ring survives.
I was there, GandaIf.
l wes there 3000 yeers ego...
...when lsildur took the Ring.
I was there the day
the strength of Men faiIed.
IsiIdur, hurry! FoIIow me.
l led lsildur into the heert
of Mount Doom...
...where the Ring wes forged,
the one plece it could be destroyed.
Cast it into the fire!
-Destroy it!
-No.
IsiIdur!
lt should heve ended thet dey,
but evil wes ellowed to endure.
IsiIdur kept the Ring.
The Iine of kings is broken.
There's no strength Ieft
in the worId of Men.
-They're scattered, divided, IeaderIess.
-There is one who couId unite them.
One who couId recIaim
the throne of Gondor.
He turned from that path
a Iong time ago.
He has chosen exiIe.
You are no EIf.
Men of the South are weIcome here.
-Who are you?
-I am a friend to GandaIf the Grey.
Then we are here on common purpose...
...friend.
The shards of NarsiI.
The bIade that cut the Ring
from Sauron's hand.
It's stiII sharp.
But no more than a broken heirIoom.
Why do you fear the past?
You are IsiIdur's heir,
not IsiIdur himseIf.
You are not bound to his fate.
The same bIood fIows in my veins.
The same weakness.
Your time wiII come.
You wiII face the same eviI.
And you wiII defeat it.
You said you'd bind yourseIf to me...
...forsaking the immortaI Iife
of your peopIe.
And to that I hoId.
I wouId rather share
one Iifetime with you...
...than face aII the Ages
of this worId aIone.
I choose a mortaI Iife.
-You cannot give me this.
-It is mine to give to whom I wiII...
...Iike my heart.
Strangers from distant Iands,
friends of oId...
...you've been summoned here
to answer the threat of Mordor.
MiddIe-earth stands upon the brink
of destruction. None can escape it.
You wiII unite, or you wiII faII.
Each race is bound to this fate,
this one doom.
Bring forth the Ring, Frodo.
So it is true.
In a dream...
...I saw the eastern sky grow dark...
...but in the West
a paIe Iight Iingered.
A voice was crying:
''Your doom is near at hand.
IsiIdur's Bane is found.''
IsiIdur's Bane.
Boromir!
Never before has any voice uttered the
words of that tongue here in ImIadris.
I do not ask your pardon,
Master EIrond...
...for the BIack Speech of Mordor...
...may yet be heard...
...in every corner of the West!
The Ring is aItogether eviI.
It is a gift.
A gift to the foes of Mordor.
Why not use this Ring?
Long has my father,
the Steward of Gondor...
...kept the forces of Mordor at bay.
By the bIood of our peopIe...
...are your Iands kept safe.
Give Gondor the weapon of the enemy.
Let us use it against him.
You cannot wieId it.
None of us can.
The One Ring answers to Sauron aIone.
It has no other master.
And what wouId a Ranger know
of this matter?
This is no mere Ranger.
He is Aragorn, son of Arathorn.
You owe him your aIIegiance.
Aragorn.
This is IsiIdur's heir?
And heir to the throne of Gondor.
Gondor has no king.
Gondor needs no king.
Aragorn is right. We cannot use it.
You have onIy one choice.
The Ring must be destroyed.
What are we waiting for?
The Ring cannot be destroyed, GimIi,
son of GIoin...
...by any craft that we here possess.
The Ring was made in the fires
of Mount Doom.
OnIy there can it be unmade.
It must be taken deep into Mordor...
...and cast back into the fiery chasm
from whence it came.
One of you...
...must do this.
One does not simpIy waIk into Mordor.
Its BIack Gates are guarded
by more than just Orcs.
There is eviI there
that does not sIeep.
The Great Eye is ever-watchfuI.
It is a barren wasteIand...
...riddIed with fire, and ash
and dust.
The very air you breathe
is a poisonous fume.
Not with 1 0,000 men
couId you do this. It is foIIy.
Have you heard nothing Lord EIrond
has said? The Ring must be destroyed.
And I suppose you think
you are the one to do it!
And if we faiI, what then? What happens
when Sauron takes back what is his?
I wiII be dead before I see the Ring
in the hands of an EIf!
Never trust an EIf!
Do you not understand? WhiIe you bicker
amongst yourseIves, Sauron's power grows!
None can escape it!
You'II aII be destroyed!
I wiII take it.
I wiII take the Ring to Mordor.
Though...
...I do not know the way.
I wiII heIp you bear
this burden, Frodo Baggins...
...as Iong as it is yours to bear.
If by my Iife
or death I can protect you...
...I wiII.
You have my sword.
And you have my bow.
And my ax.
You carry the fates
of us aII, IittIe one.
If this is indeed
the wiII of the CounciI...
...then Gondor wiII see it done.
-Frodo's not going anywhere without me.
-It is hardIy possibIe to separate you...
...even when he is summoned
to a secret CounciI and you are not.
We're coming too!
You'II have to send us home
tied up in a sack to stop us.
Anyway, you need peopIe
of inteIIigence on this sort of...
...mission.
Quest.
Thing.
WeII, that ruIes you out, Pip.
Nine companions.
So be it.
You shaII be
the FeIIowship of the Ring.
Great!
Where are we going?
In her heart, your mother knew
you'd be hunted aII your Iife.
That you'd never escape your fate.
The skiII of the EIves
can reforge the sword of kings...
...but onIy you have the power
to wieId it.
I do not want that power.
I have never wanted it.
You are the Iast of that bIoodIine.
There is no other.
My oId sword! Sting.
Here, take it. Take it.
-It's so Iight.
-Yes. Made by the EIves, you know.
The bIade gIows bIue
when Orcs are cIose.
And it's times Iike that, my Iad,
when you have to be extra carefuI.
Here's a pretty thing.
MithriI.
As Iight as a feather,
and as hard as dragon scaIes.
Let me see you put it on. Come on.
My oId ring.
I shouId very much Iike...
...to hoId it again, one Iast time.
I'm sorry I brought this upon you,
my boy.
I'm sorry that you
must carry this burden.
I'm sorry for everything.
The Ring-bearer is setting out
on the Quest of Mount Doom.
On you who traveI with him,
no oath...
...nor bond is Iaid to go further
than you wiII.
FareweII. HoId to your purpose.
May the bIessings of EIves and Men...
...and aII Free FoIk go with you.
The FeIIowship awaits the Ring-bearer.
Mordor, GandaIf, is it Ieft or right?
Left.
We must hold to thls course, west
of the Mlsty Mountalns, for 40 days.
If our luck holds, the Gap of Rohan
wlll stlll be open to us.
From there, our road
turns east to Mordor.
Two, one, five. Good! Very good.
Move your feet.
-You Iook good, Pippin.
-Thanks.
Faster!
If anyone was to ask for my opinion,
which I note they're not...
...I'd say we were taking
the Iong way 'round.
GandaIf, we couId pass through
the Mines of Moria.
My cousin BaIin wouId give us
a royaI weIcome.
No, I wouId not take the road through
Moria unIess I had no other choice.
Sorry!
Get him!
-For the Shire!
-HoId him. HoId him down, Merry!
GentIemen, that's enough.
You've got my arm!
-What is that?
-Nothing. It's just a wisp of cIoud.
It's moving fast.
Against the wind.
-Crebain from DunIand!
-Hide!
-Hurry!
-Take cover!
Spies of Saruman.
The passage south is being watched.
We must take the Pass of Caradhras.
Frodo!
Boromir.
It is a strange fate that we shouId
suffer so much fear and doubt...
...over so smaII a thing.
Such a IittIe thing.
Boromir!
Give the Ring to Frodo.
As you wish.
I care not.
So, GandaIf, you try
to Iead them over Caradhras.
And if that faiIs,
where then wiII you go?
If the mountaln defeats you...
... wlll you rlsk
a more dangerous road?
There is a feII voice on the air.
It's Saruman!
He's trying to bring down the mountain!
GandaIf, we must turn back!
No!
We must get off the mountain!
Make for the Gap of Rohan,
and take the west road to my city!
The Gap of Rohan takes us
too cIose to Isengard!
We cannot pass over a mountain.
Let us go under it.
Let us go through the Mines of Moria.
Morla. You fear to go
lnto those mlnes.
The Dwarves deIved too greediIy
and too deep.
You know what they awoke
ln the darkness of Khazad-dum.'
Shadow and fIame.
Let the Ring-bearer decide.
We cannot stay here!
This wiII be the death of the Hobbits.
Frodo?
We wiII go through the mines.
So be it.
Frodo, come and heIp an oId man.
How is your shouIder?
-Better than it was.
-And the Ring?
You feeI its power growing, don't you?
I've feIt it too.
You must be carefuI now.
EviI wiII be drawn to you
from outside the FeIIowship.
And, I fear, from within.
-Who then do I trust?
-You must trust yourseIf.
Trust your own strengths.
-What do you mean?
-There are many powers in this worId...
...for good or for eviI.
Some are greater than I am.
And against some I have not yet
been tested.
The waIIs...
...of Moria.
Dwarf doors are invisibIe when cIosed.
Yes, GimIi, their own masters cannot find
them if their secrets are forgotten.
Why doesn't that surprise me?
WeII, Iet's see.
IthiIdin.
It mirrors onIy starIight
and moonIight.
It reads, ''The Doors of Durin,
Lord of Moria.
-Speak, friend, and enter.''
-What do you suppose that means?
It's simpIe. If you are a friend, you speak
the password and the doors wiII open.
Nothing's happening.
I once knew every speII
in aII the tongues of EIves...
...Men and Orcs.
What are you going to do, then?
Knock your head against these doors,
Peregrin Took!
And if that does not shatter them...
...and I am aIIowed a IittIe peace
from fooIish questions...
...I wiII try to find the opening words.
Mines are no pIace for a pony.
-Even one so brave as BiII.
-Bye-bye, BiII.
Go on, BiII. Go on.
Don't worry, Sam,
he knows the way home.
Do not disturb the water.
Oh, it's useIess.
It's a riddIe.
''Speak 'friend' and enter.''
What's the EIvish word for ''friend''?
Mellon.
Soon, Master EIf, you wiII enjoy
the fabIed hospitaIity of the Dwarves.
Roaring fires, maIt beer,
ripe meat off the bone!
This, my friend,
is the home of my cousin BaIin.
And they caII it a mine.
A mine!
This is no mine. It's a tomb.
No....
No!
GobIins.
We make for the Gap of Rohan.
We shouId never have come here.
Now, get out of here. Get out!
-Frodo!
-HeIp!
Strider!
-Get off him!
Aragorn!
Frodo!
Into the mines!
-LegoIas!
-Into the cave!
Run!
We now have but one choice.
We must face the Iong dark of Moria.
Be on your guard.
There are oIder
and fouIer things than Orcs...
...in the deep pIaces of the worId.
QuietIy now. It's a four-day journey
to the other side.
Let us hope that our presence
may go unnoticed.
The weaIth of Moria was not in goId...
...or jeweIs...
...but mithriI.
BiIbo had a shirt of mithriI rings
that Thorin gave him.
-Oh, that was a kingIy gift.
-Yes.
I never toId him...
...but its worth was greater than
the vaIue of the Shire.
Pippin.
I have no memory of this pIace.
-Are we Iost?
-No.
-I think we are.
-GandaIf's thinking.
-Merry?
-What?
I'm hungry.
-There's something down there.
-It's GoIIum.
-GoIIum?
-He's been foIIowing us for three days.
-He escaped the dungeons of Barad-dur?
-Escaped...
...or was set Ioose.
Now the Ring has brought him here.
He wiII never be rid of his need for it.
He hates and Ioves the Ring,
as he hates and Ioves himseIf.
SmeagoI's Iife is a sad story.
Yes, SmeagoI he was once caIIed.
Before the Ring found him.
Before it drove him mad.
It's a pity BiIbo didn't kiII him
when he had the chance.
Pity?
It is pity that stayed BiIbo's hand.
Many that Iive deserve death.
Some that die deserve Iife.
Can you give it to them, Frodo?
Do not be too eager
to deaI out death and judgment.
Even the very wise
cannot see aII ends.
My heart teIIs me that GoIIum has some
part to pIay yet, for good or iII...
...before this is over.
The pity of BiIbo
may ruIe the fate of many.
I wish the Ring
had never come to me.
I wish none of this had happened.
So do aII who Iive to see such times.
But that is not for them to decide.
AII we have to decide is what to do
with the time that is given to us.
There are other forces at work in this
worId, Frodo, besides the wiII of eviI.
BiIbo was meant to find the Ring.
In which case,
you aIso were meant to have it.
And that is an encouraging thought.
It's that way.
-He's remembered.
-No.
But the air doesn't smeII
so fouI down here.
If in doubt, Meriadoc,
aIways foIIow your nose.
Let me risk a IittIe more Iight.
BehoId...
...the great reaIm
and Dwarf-city of DwarrowdeIf.
There's an eye opener, and no mistake.
GimIi!
No!
Oh, no.
No.
''Here Iies BaIin...
...son of Fundin...
...Lord of Moria.''
He is dead, then.
It's as I feared.
We must move on. We cannot Iinger.
''They have taken the bridge
and the second haII.
We have barred the gates...
...but cannot hoId them for Iong.
The ground shakes.
Drums...
...drums in the deep.
We cannot get out.
A Shadow moves in the dark.
They are coming.''
FooI of a Took!
Throw yourseIf in next time,
and rid us of your stupidity.
Frodo!
Orcs.
Get back! Stay cIose to GandaIf!
They have a cave-troII.
Let them come!
There is one Dwarf yet in Moria
who stiII draws breath.
I think I'm getting the hang of this.
Frodo!
Aragorn! Aragorn!
Oh, no.
He's aIive.
I'm aII right. I'm not hurt.
You shouId be dead.
That spear wouId have skewered
a wiId boar.
I think there's more to this Hobbit
than meets the eye.
MithriI.
You are fuII of surprises,
Master Baggins.
To the Bridge of Khazad-dum!
This way!
What is this new deviIry?
A BaIrog.
A demon of the ancient worId.
This foe is beyond any of you.
Run!
QuickIy!
GandaIf.
Lead them on, Aragorn.
The bridge is near.
Do as I say!
Swords are no more use here.
GandaIf!
Merry! Pippin!
Sam!
Nobody tosses a Dwarf.
Not the beard!
Steady.
HoId on!
Hang on!
Lean forward!
Steady.
Come on!
Now!
Over the bridge!
FIy!
You cannot pass!
GandaIf!
I am a servant of the Secret Fire,
wieIder of the fIame of Anor.
The dark fire wiII not avaiI you,
fIame of Udun!
Go back to the Shadow.
You shaII not pass!
-No! No!
-GandaIf!
FIy, you fooIs!
No!
Aragorn!
LegoIas, get them up.
Give them a moment, for pity's sake!
By nightfaII, these hiIIs wiII
be swarming with Orcs.
We must reach the woods of LothIorien.
Come, Boromir. LegoIas.
GimIi, get them up.
On your feet, Sam.
Frodo?
Frodo!
Stay cIose, young Hobbits!
They say that a great sorceress
Iives in these woods.
An EIf-witch...
...of terribIe power.
AII who Iook upon her...
...faII under her speII.
Frodol
And are never seen again.
Your coming to us is
es the footsteps of doom.
You bring greet evil here,
Ring-beerer.
Mr. Frodo?
WeII, here's one Dwarf
she won't ensnare so easiIy.
I have the eyes of a hawk
and the ears of a fox.
The Dwarf breathes so Ioud,
we couId have shot him in the dark.
So much for the Iegendary courtesy
of the EIves!
Speak words we can aII understand!
We have not had deaIings
with the Dwarves since the Dark Days.
And you know what this Dwarf
says to that?
That was not so courteous.
You bring great eviI with you.
You can go no further.
GandaIf's death was not in vain.
Nor wouId he have you give up hope.
You carry a heavy burden, Frodo.
Don't carry the weight of the dead.
You wiII foIIow me.
Caras GaIadhon.
The heart of EIvendom on earth.
ReaIm of the Lord CeIeborn
and of GaIadrieI, Lady of Light.
The enemy knows you have entered here.
What hope you had in secrecy
is now gone.
Eight there are here, yet nine there
were set out from RivendeII.
TeII me, where is GandaIf?
For I much desire to speak with him.
I can no Ionger see him from afar.
GandaIf the Grey did not pass
the borders of this Iand.
He has faIIen into Shadow.
He was taken by both Shadow and fIame.
A BaIrog of Morgoth.
For we went needIessIy
into the net of Moria.
NeedIess were none of the deeds
of GandaIf in Iife.
We do not yet know his fuII purpose.
Do not Iet the great emptiness
of Khazad-dum fiII your heart...
...GimIi, son of GIoin.
For the worId has grown
fuII of periI...
...and in aII Iands...
...Iove is now mingIed with grief.
What now becomes of this FeIIowship?
Without GandaIf, hope is Iost.
The quest stands upon the edge
of a knife.
Stray but a IittIe and it wiII faiI...
...to the ruin of aII.
Yet hope remains
whiIe the Company is true.
Do not Iet your hearts be troubIed.
Go now and rest...
...for you are weary with sorrow
and much toiI.
Tonight, you wiII sIeep....
Welcome, Frodo of the Shlre...
...one who has seen the Eyel
A Iament for GandaIf.
What do they say about him?
I have not the heart to teII you.
For me, the grief is stiII too near.
I bet they don't mention his fireworks.
There shouId be a verse about them.
The flnest rockets ever seen
They burst ln stars of blue and green
Or after thunder, sllver showers
Came falllng llke a raln of flowers
Oh, that doesn't do them justice
by a Iong road.
Take some rest.
These borders are weII-protected.
I wiII find no rest here.
I heard her voice inside my head.
She spoke of my father
and the faII of Gondor.
She said to me,
''Even now there is hope Ieft.''
But I cannot see it.
It is Iong since we had any hope.
My father is a nobIe man.
But his ruIe is faiIing...
...and our peopIe Iose faith.
He Iooks to me to make things right,
and I wouId do it.
I wouId see the gIory
of Gondor restored.
Have you ever seen it, Aragorn?
The White Tower of EctheIion.
GIimmering Iike a spike
of pearI and siIver.
Its banners caught high
in the morning breeze.
Have you ever been caIIed home...
...by the cIear ringing
of siIver trumpets?
I have seen the White City...
...Iong ago.
One day, our paths wiII Iead us there.
And the tower guard
shaII take up the caII:
''The Lords of Gondor have returned.''
WiII you Iook into the mirror?
What wiII I see?
Even the wisest cannot teII.
For the mirror...
...shows many things.
Things that were...
...things that are...
...and some things...
...that have not yet come to pass.
I know what it is you saw.
For it is aIso in my mind.
It ls what wlll come to pass
lf you should fall.
The Fellowshlp ls breaklng.
It ls already begun.
He wlll try to take the Rlng.
You know of whom I speak.
One by one, lt wlll destroy them all.
If you ask lt of me...
... I wlll glve you the One Rlng.
You offer it to me freeIy.
I do not deny that my heart
has greatIy desired this.
In pIace of a Dark Lord,
you wouId have a queen...
...not dark but beautifuI,
and terribIe as the dawn!
Treacherous as the sea!
Stronger than the foundations
of the earth!
AII shaII Iove me...
...and despair.
I pass the test. I wiII diminish...
...and go into the West...
-...and remain GaIadrieI.
-I cannot do this aIone.
You are a Ring-bearer, Frodo.
To bear a Ring of Power...
...is to be aIone.
This is Nenya,
the Ring of Adamant.
And I am its keeper.
This task was appointed to you.
And if you do not find a way...
...no one wiII.
Then I know what I must do.
It's just...
...I'm afraid to do it.
Even the smaIIest person can change
the course of the future.
Do you know how the Orcs
first came into being?
They were EIves once.
Taken by the Dark Powers...
...tortured and mutiIated.
A ruined and terribIe form of Iife.
And now...
...perfected.
My fighting Uruk-hai...
...whom do you serve?
Saruman!
Hunt them down. Do not stop
untiI they are found.
You do not know pain.
You do not know fear.
You wiII taste Man-fIesh!
One of the haIfIings carries
something of great vaIue.
Bring them to me aIive and unspoiIed.
KiII the others.
Never before have we cIad strangers
in the garb of our own peopIe.
May these cIoaks heIp shieId you
from unfriendIy eyes.
Lembas.
EIvish waybread.
One smaII bite is enough to fiII
the stomach of a grown man.
How many did you eat?
Four.
Every league you travel south,
the danger wlll lncrease.
Mordor Orcs now hold the eastern shore
of the Anduln.
Nor wlll you flnd safety
on the western bank.
Strange creatures bearing the White Hand
have been seen on our borders.
SeIdom do Orcs journey in the open
under the sun, yet these have done so.
By river you have the chance of outrunning
the enemy to the FaIIs of Rauros.
My gift for you, LegoIas,
is a bow of the GaIadhrim.
Worthy of the skiII
of our woodIand kin.
These are the daggers of the NoIdorin.
They have aIready seen service in war.
Do not fear, young Peregrin Took.
You wlll flnd your courage.
And for you, Samwlse Gamgee...
...EIven rope made of hithIain.
Thank you, my Iady.
Have you run out
of those nice, shiny daggers?
And what gift wouId a dwarf ask
of the EIves?
Nothing.
Except to Iook upon the Iady
of the GaIadhrim one Iast time...
...for she is more fair
than aII the jeweIs beneath the earth.
ActuaIIy....
There was one thing.
No, no, I couIdn't.
It's quite impossibIe.
Stupld to ask.
I have nothlng greater to glve...
...than the gift you aIready bear.
That choice is yet before her.
You have your own choice to make,
Aragorn.
To rise above the height of aII
your fathers since the days of EIendiI...
...or to faII into darkness
with aII that is Ieft of your kin.
Farewell, Frodo Bagglns.
I give you the Iight of EarendiI...
...our most beIoved star.
May lt be a llght for you
ln dark places...
... when all other llghts go out.
I have taken my worst wound
at this parting...
...having Iooked my Iast upon that
which is fairest.
Henceforth I wiII caII nothing fair
unIess it be her gift to me.
What was her gift?
I asked her for one hair
from her goIden head.
She gave me three.
GoIIum. He has tracked us since Moria.
I had hoped we wouId Iose him
on the river.
But he's too cIever a waterman.
And if he aIerts the enemy
to our whereabouts...
...it wiII make the crossing
even more dangerous.
Have some food, Mr. Frodo.
-No, Sam.
-You haven't eaten anything aII day.
You're not sIeeping, neither.
Don't think I haven't noticed.
-Mr. Frodo--
-I'm aII right.
But you're not.
I'm here to heIp you.
I promised GandaIf that I wouId.
You can't heIp me, Sam.
Not this time.
Get some sIeep.
Minas Tirith is the safer road.
You know that.
From there we can regroup.
Strike out for Mordor from a pIace
of strength.
There is no strength in Gondor
that can avaiI us.
You were quick enough to trust
the EIves.
Have you so IittIe faith
in your own peopIe?
Yes, there is weakness.
There is fraiIty.
But there is courage aIso,
and honor to be found in Men.
But you wiII not see that.
You are afraid!
AII your Iife, you have hidden
in the shadows.
Scared of who you are,
of what you are.
I wiII not Iead the Ring within
a hundred Ieagues of your city.
Frodo.
The Argonath.
Long have I desired
to Iook upon the kings of oId.
My kin.
We cross the Iake at nightfaII.
Hide the boats and continue on foot.
-We approach Mordor from the North.
-Oh, yes?
Just a simpIe matter of finding
our way through Emyn MuiI...
...an impassabIe Iabyrinth
of razor-sharp rocks.
And after that, it gets even better.
Festering, stinking marshIand
as far as the eye can see.
That is our road.
I suggest you take some rest
and recover your strength, Master Dwarf.
Recover my--
-We shouId Ieave now.
-No.
Orcs patroI the eastern shore.
We must wait for cover of darkness.
It is not the eastern shore
that worries me.
A shadow and a threat
has been growing in my mind.
Something draws near.
I can feeI it.
Recover strength?
Pay no heed to that, young Hobbit.
Where's Frodo?
None of us shouId wander aIone.
You, Ieast of aII.
So much depends on you.
Frodo?
I know why you seek soIitude.
You suffer. I see it day by day.
You sure you do not suffer needIessIy?
There are other ways, Frodo.
-Other paths that we might take.
-I know what you wouId say.
It wouId seem Iike wisdom
but for the warning in my heart.
Warning? Against what?
We're aII afraid, Frodo.
But to Iet that fear drive us,
to destroy what hope we have...
-...don't you see that is madness?
-There is no other way.
I ask onIy for the strength
to defend my peopIe!
-If you wouId but Iend me the Ring.
-No.
-Why do you recoiI? I am no thief.
-You are not yourseIf.
What chance do you think you have?
They wiII find you.
They wiII take the Ring.
And you wiII beg for death
before the end!
You fooI!
It is not yours, save by unhappy chance!
It couId have been mine.
It shouId be mine! Give it to me!
-Give it to me!
-No!
-No.
I see your mind.
You wiII take the Ring to Sauron!
You wiII betray us!
You'II go to your death,
and the death of us aII!
Curse you!
Curse you and aII the haIfIings!
Frodo?
Frodo.
What have I done?
PIease, Frodo.
Frodo, I'm sorry!
Frodo?
-It has taken Boromir.
-Where is the Ring?
Stay away!
Frodo!
-I swore to protect you.
-Can you protect me from yourseIf?
WouId you destroy it?
Aregorn.
Elesser.
I wouId have gone with you to the end.
Into the very fires of Mordor.
I know.
Look after the others. EspeciaIIy Sam.
He wiII not understand.
Go, Frodo!
Run.
Run!
Mr. Frodo!
Find the haIfIing!
EIendiI!
Aragorn, go!
Frodo!
Hide here. Quick!
Come on!
What's he doing?
He's Ieaving.
-No!
-Pippin!
Run, Frodo. Go on!
-Hey! Hey, you!
-Over here!
-This way!
-It's working!
-I know it's working! Run!
-The horn of Gondor.
-Boromir.
Run!
No.
-They took the IittIe ones.
-HoId stiII.
Frodo. Where is Frodo?
I Iet Frodo go.
Then you did what I couId not.
I tried to take the Ring from him.
-The Ring is beyond our reach now.
-Forgive me.
I did not see it.
-I have faiIed you aII.
-No, Boromir.
You fought braveIy.
You have kept your honor.
Leave it.
It is over.
The worId of Men wiII faII.
And aII wiII come to darkness...
...and my city to ruin.
I do not know what strength
is in my bIood...
...but I swear to you,
I wiII not Iet the White City faII...
...nor our peopIe faiI.
Our peopIe.
I wouId have foIIowed you, my brother.
My captain.
My king.
Be at peace...
They wiII Iook for his coming
from the White Tower.
But he wiII not return.
Frodo!
l wish the Ring hed never come to me.
l wish none of this hed heppened.
So do ell who live
to see such times...
...but thet is not for them to decide.
All you heve to decide...
...is what to do with the time
that is given to you.
Frodo, no!
Frodo!
-Mr. Frodo!
-No, Sam.
Go back, Sam!
-I'm going to Mordor aIone.
-Of course you are.
And I'm coming with you!
You can't swim!
Sam!
I made a promise, Mr. Frodo.
A promise:
''Don't you Ieave him, Samwise Gamgee.''
And I don't mean to.
I don't mean to.
Sam.
Come on.
Hurry! Frodo and Sam
have reached the eastern shore.
-You mean not to foIIow them.
-Frodo's fate is no Ionger in our hands.
Then it has aII been in vain.
The FeIIowship has faiIed.
Not if we hoId true to each other.
We wiII not abandon Merry and Pippin
to torment and death.
Not whiIe we have strength Ieft.
Leave aII that can be spared behind.
We traveI Iight.
Let us hunt some Orc.
Yes!
Mordor.
I hope the others find a safer road.
Strider wiII Iook after them.
I don't suppose
we'II ever see them again.
We may yet, Mr. Frodo.
We may.
Sam...