www.Team-NCIS.com
Okay, we're set.
Later this week, Congress will be voting
on a $14 billion appropriation
for construction
of a new class aircraft carrier.
Many watchdog groups feel that the money
would be better spent at home,
on schools and infrastructure.
Your opinion?
That's a difficult question
for me to answer.
I don't really know
what the military needs.
That's a husband question.
I'd have to talk to him to see
how I feel about it.
Thank you.
Your honesty is refreshing.
Okay, we're good.
Chad,
the guy with the camera over there.
Excuse me, sir, ZNN.
Can we interview you
for the evening news?
- It'll only take a second.
- Please, don't point that at me.
Please, sir, if you could just...
Someone call 911!
NCIS Season 9 Episode 04
Enemy on the Hill 1.0 LOL
Synchro: Gaillots,
Keller & Kujathemas.
Rereading: Bruno & Magic Turtle.
www.Team-NCIS.com
Abby, what, what?
Unbelievable.
I was chosen.
I'm a match.
They want me down at the hospital
for an interview right away.
You donating bone marrow again?
No. A kidney.
- Who do you know that needs a kidney?
- I don't know him. I just volunteered.
Slow down. Back up.
What are you talking about?
I heard about it at church.
There's this 18-year-old kid,
he's on dialysis, and he needs a kidney,
but nobody in his family was
a match, so I had to do something.
I went there, got tested,
and they called me.
You're going to give a perfectly
good kidney to a total stranger?
- Are you out of your mind?
- That is very noble.
Abby, that's major surgery.
What's the recovery time on that?
It's gotta be weeks.
I don't know, but I'll find out.
I have an interview with the transplant
coordinator in, like, an hour.
Hey, Detective Sportelli,
what are you doing here?
- Long time.
- I gotta go.
Abby, don't you commit to anything.
It's gonna be great.
- Sportelli, what's up?
- I arrested The Cooler.
Come on, FBI's most-wanted list.
It's a career-making bust.
- The Cooler?
- He puts people on ice.
He's suspected in at least a half-dozen
high-profile contract assassinations.
The only thing tying the cases together
is the slugs taken from the victims.
Yeah, he's been like a ghost,
blending into the background.
FBI has no idea what he looks like,
let alone have a name.
They got one now.
Paul Arliss.
He's been living
the good life in suburbia.
On a cul-de-sac in Woodley Park.
- How'd you catch him?
- News doing on-the-street interviews.
He tried to avoid the camera
and ran into traffic.
Got hit by a van.
He's in critical condition.
I saw footage of that
on the news last night.
They did not mention anything
about him being a fugitive.
We kept it quiet
till we figured out who he was.
You gotta keep that quiet.
You wouldn't want anyone to know.
Great work, Detective Sportelli.
You arrested the unconscious man.
Did you have to cuff him
when he was down on the sidewalk there?
How'd you I.D. him?
Ballistics tied the weapon
he was carrying to four unsolved hits.
- You here to gloat?
- No, I'm here to help you.
We found surveillance photos
and handwritten notes in his car,
parked about a block away.
Looks like his next target
is going to be a Navy Lieutenant
Commander named Geoffrey Brett.
You got any leads
on who hired Arliss?
We need to interview him.
Where is he?
Washington General Hospital
prison ward.
I'll call you
when he's able to speak.
Great detective work, Sportelli.
I think we're all very proud of you.
Always a pleasure, DiNozzo.
Boss, Commander Brett's
an Academy grad.
Top Gun pilot.
Flew F-18 Hornets
in Iraq and Afghanistan.
Got shot down over Kunar Province.
Wait a second.
I know him.
That's the guy that survived
by eating mud, bark
and bugs while evading the Taliban.
Took the Marines
two weeks to find and rescue him.
One tough S.O.B.
He's divorced, has one daughter.
Currently assigned
as a legislative fellow
to the House Armed
Services Committee.
Good afternoon.
Lieutenant Commander Brett's office.
You say
this guy was trying to kill me.
Got a good reason to believe so.
He's a wanted contract killer.
This is crazy.
I can't think of anyone
who would want me dead.
It's got to be a joke.
Captain Thornton put you up to this,
didn't he?
I don't know Captain Thornton.
Clearly this must be
some sort of mistake.
Metro police came to us
with solid evidence.
You said the guy's been caught,
so there's nothing to worry about.
Whoever hired him to kill you,
wants you dead.
They'll find someone else
to do the job.
We would like to put you in protective
custody until we know more.
You're serious?
I can take care of myself.
My job is to advise the members
of the Armed Services Committee.
There's a critical vote about
to take place on the Hill regarding
a substantial military expenditure.
I'm going to be
in sensitive meetings all week.
Let an agent shadow you at work.
We'll set you up tonight at
the officers' quarters at the Navy Yard.
Yeah, I don't know, I've...
And who will be
the agent shadowing me?
Hi, Ducky.
Just a second, Abby.
I'm just finishing cleaning
and lubricating
the Hornby model of my namesake...
"The Mallard",
magnificent locomotive.
It set the world speed record
for a steam engine back in 1938.
126 miles per hour.
It was on a slight downgrade between
Bytham and Essendine.
Remained in service until 1960...
What's the matter?
Do you have a minute?
Certainly.
- I just came from the hospital.
- I heard.
Donating a kidney
is not a decision
to be taken lightly.
The transplant coordinator said that
I'm not the only one that's a match.
- There's also a guy.
- Really?
Well, usually it's hard
to find one donor that's a match.
Yeah, exactly.
That's why she was amazed
that she found a brother
and a sister both willing to donate.
Your brother also volunteered?
No. I spoke to Luca.
- He doesn't know anything about it.
- I'm confused.
Why does the transplant coordinator
think that you and this man are...
siblings?
As part of the screening process, we had
to give a mitochondrial DNA sample.
Ours was a dead-on match, Ducky.
More than 99.9%.
We have to be full-on
brother and sister, right?
I pressed the coordinator for details...
like his name and address, but
she clammed up,
saying she'd said too much already.
It's pro forma
for all donors' medical
and personal records
to be kept confidential.
Could my parents
have had another child
they gave up for adoption?
I mean, it doesn't make any sense.
I don't believe it.
And neither does my little brother Luca.
He's as blown away as I am.
With your parents deceased,
isn't there anyone else you can ask?
Thanks for listening.
I think
we should have waited for Gibbs.
No time.
Sportelli said he was conscious.
We don't know for how long.
When we get into the room,
you let me do the talking.
Why?
The Cooler's evaded
the FBI for years.
Getting him to tell us who took out
the hit on Commander Brett is going
- to take a deft hand.
- And that's you?
You didn't even know
who The Cooler was until I told you.
Neither did Ziva.
I need to talk to him alone, so you've
got to get Sportelli out of the room.
And how am I supposed to do that?
I don't know...
you distract him.
Talk about your stupid obsession with
jet packs... men strapped to rockets.
- I am not obsessed.
- Special agents.
You're not going to get
to talk to Arliss, boys.
- You said we could.
- He flatlined.
He's dead?
Over and out.
Hard to believe this guy
was an infamous killer.
Up until yesterday,
his only claim to fame was
salesman of the year as a manufacturer's
rep for a furniture company.
He's got a wife, two kids,
no criminal record.
Not even a parking ticket.
He evaded the FBI for years
by hiding in plain sight.
In a weird way,
you got to admire the guy...
He's a mass murderer.
Despicable.
Nothing to admire.
You connect him to anyone
who knows the commander?
No. Metro's got a team going
through his house.
If only I could have interrogated him,
I tell ya.
Five minutes in my magic hands
and I would have had him coughing up
the name of that hit man.
5 minutes?
5 minutes,
because I learned from the best.
- We need to find out who hired him.
- I've been looking for enemies.
But Commander Brett
is a decorated hero.
He's well-liked.
Spoke to his former C.O.
He climbed over people while angling
for his plum assignment on the Hill,
but no one denies he deserved it.
While angling for his plum assignment
on the Hill? Who talks like that?
I'm already five minutes late.
Is your day always this busy?
Some are worse.
Especially when there's a big vote.
It's the first time I've ever been
accompanied by a woman who's packing.
Packing?
Carrying a gun.
Why does someone who looks like you
become an NCIS agent?
What are agents
supposed to look like?
Stern, surly, humorless.
The problem with you guys
is you're too uptight.
Try lightening up a little.
Agent Ziva, relax.
I know him.
- Sorry, Nick. You okay?
- Yeah. No!
What the hell is going on?
They mistakenly believe
I need protection. It's nothing really.
You just roughed up
one of the barons of K Street.
He avoids using the pejorative.
I'm a lobbyist.
Are you going to be in your office later
this afternoon? I need to talk to you.
- Yeah, I'll be back around 4:00.
- Great. Nice meeting you, I think.
Thanks for being so discreet.
What the hell's DiNozzo doing?
I don't know.
Are you sure about Arliss' wife?
She thought he was on the road,
selling furniture.
Be my guest. Talk to her.
Look around.
Better move fast.
FBI's on their way.
They're taking over.
Hate those guys.
Glory hounds.
I'd rather deal with you
than the Bureau.
I don't blame you.
Something's wrong here.
I paced off the inside
and outside of the garage.
There's a couple feet missing.
Looks like there's some electrical power
going behind this wall.
Sounds hollow.
There's something back here.
There's a seam.
That's interesting.
Eureka.
- The FBI'S gonna have a field day.
- Oh, yeah, they will.
Do you want to let us take
the computer?
Our people are real good.
You'll tell me what you find.
No, this doesn't have anything
to do with a sweepstakes.
No, no, I'm Abigail,
your niece...
Gloria's daughter?
- What're you doing?
- I found something on Arliss' computer.
I need to clone his hard drive.
Do you have your USB-3 cable?
No, no,
I'm not a cheerleader anymore.
I graduated high school
a long time ago.
I'm sorry.
I can't bring you bonbons now.
I live in Washington DC, now.
I'll visit soon, yeah, I promise.
No, this is, this is Abby.
Okay, Aunt Gert,
go have your dinner.
Love you. Bye.
Abby, you okay?
I just thought if anyone
would know about my parents
giving up a child, it'd be my Aunt Gert,
but she can't even remember
her own name, poor thing.
Her dementia's gotten so bad.
- That your aunt?
- No, it's my mom.
She was beautiful.
What'd you find?
Well, the day before
Arliss was hit by the truck,
he received a $25,000 wire transfer
from the brokerage account
of a "George Kaplan".
$25,000.
That's how much it costs to get
somebody whacked these days?
Mr. Kaplan lives at 1313 Branchport
Avenue, Northwest,
apartment 3C.
I wish you could spend the night,
honey
but something has come up
and Daddy has to stay in the city, okay?
I'll talk to your mother.
We'll see if we can work out
something for the weekend.
Yes, I promise.
Okay, I love you, sweetheart.
Bye.
How old is she?
Eight.
She has special needs,
but she doesn't let it stop her.
She's a great kid.
She's adorable.
What's her name?
Matilda.
I call her Tilly.
She's my life.
- You found something.
- You know a man named George Kaplan?
- Should I?
- We believe he put out the hit on you.
Well, has he been arrested?
Not yet. We got a lead on an address.
We're still looking for him.
This is getting crazier.
Why would someone I don't know
want to have me killed?
And about my daughter?
My ex wanted to take Tilly
to her parent's house in Hilton Head.
I'm gonna tell her to do it.
What do you expect to see?
I don't know. You'd think a guy
who popped 25 grand for a hit
would live in better digs than this.
I've been meaning
on getting that fixed.
Boss, this is the landlady,
Mrs. Roach.
Understand you don't have
a warrant, Boss.
I can get one if you want.
Let's get this over with.
I'm missing Judge Judy.
Kaplan's got terrible taste.
The apartment comes furnished.
- I picked everything out.
- How long's Kaplan been living here?
- Over a year. Maybe a year and a half.
- No clothes in the closet.
- No food.
- When's the last time you saw Kaplan?
- When I rented him the apartment.
- You haven't seen him since?
Don't think so.
You don't find it strange someone rents
an apartment then doesn't use it?
He's my best tenant.
Doesn't make any noise.
His business manager sends a check,
every month, on time.
Guy who lives in this dump like this
has a business manager?
No offense.
- What's the business manager's name?
- I don't know.
I mean,
I got the name in my apartment.
I suppose you want me to go down
and get it.
You wanna come with me, Boss?
I'll wait here.
It's what they call a turkey vulture.
20 years past a cougar.
Still likes to hunt,
but too old to take down the prey.
I wouldn't bet on that.
Dust for prints, Boss?
It's late.
- I'm not that hungry.
- Let's just get to the Navy Yard.
- I don't want to spend the night there.
- Hopefully, it won't be for long.
Let's take the stairs.
It's quicker.
After you.
Sorry.
Open it.
Goodbye.
Any response to the BOLO?
I felt, all day,
he wanted to shake me.
Hard to protect someone
who doesn't want to be.
- His cell's still off.
- What was his schedule this morning?
Has to be in his office
by 11:00 a.m.
for a conference call
with Admiral Mosley in Pearl Harbor.
I doubt he'll miss that.
You got anything?
There's no DC driver's license
or passport issued
to a George Kaplan
at 1313 Branchport Avenue, Northwest.
We're trying surrounding states,
but it's common name.
- There's gonna be a lot of hits.
- Military or criminal record?
I got something.
The Social Security number of the George
Kaplan on Branchport Avenue.
- Why does it sound so familiar?
- Where'd you get the number?
Kaplan's stockbroker.
Turns out he's got $1.1 mil in
the account that paid for the hit man.
- Broker give you a description?
- He ever met him.
Dealt with the business manager,
a Drew Turner.
It's the same name
we got from the landlady.
The broker says it's not unusual.
Deals with managers all the time.
Turns out that Turner
had power of attorney.
All the documentation you need
to open an account.
Which means he's got Kaplan's
Social Security number and
address which has to be a residence.
Can't be a P.O. box.
Kaplan files State
and federal tax returns.
Prepared by...
Drew Turner.
Time to talk to him.
Subpoena the records
of Kaplan's account. Now.
You're a woman.
What gave it away?
Agents McGee and DiNozzo.
We need to speak with you.
Navy investigators.
I am running really late
to a meeting with the IRS.
Come on in.
I just got back into town
this morning.
Listen, they are only auditing
your entertainment expenses
and I'm bringing copies
of all your receipts.
So relax,
you have nothing to worry about, Harry.
I can meet you in ten...
15 minutes at the most.
Okay, bye.
Nervous client.
First time being audited. Sorry.
Must be nice...
working out of your home.
Never late to work.
I bet.
CPA. So you do personal tax returns?
It's impressive.
We're looking for a client of yours,
George Kaplan.
- Do you know where we can find him?
- You check his apartment?
Maybe he's out of town.
He seems to move around a lot.
I haven't seen him
since last tax season.
Can you describe him?
On the shorter side,
five-eight maybe.
Dark hair.
I don't know him that well.
I just helped him set up an investment
account and do his taxes once a year.
What is this about?
Do you know a Lieutenant Commander
named Geoffrey Brett?
No. Sorry.
And I gotta get going.
I mean, my client is at the IRS office
and he is hyperventilating.
We need you to come by the Navy Yard
and help us with a sketch of Kaplan.
- Are you gonna be there?
- Definitely.
You'll be working
with our forensic scientist Abby Sciuto.
Whatever.
I'll be there as soon as I'm done.
Let's say an hour, two at the most?
Sounds good.
Thanks.
- How much trouble am I in?
- You're not taking
- the threat on your life seriously.
- You're right, I'm not. It's bogus.
Fact: a professional hit man
is targeting you.
You have no basis. I can't,
for the life of me, think of anyone
- I've pissed off.
- Why'd you ditch me?
Okay, this is awkward.
- The truth?
- That would be nice.
I was uncomfortable having you
with me in meetings all day,
but there was no way I could
let you accompany me last night.
I was with a woman.
- She married?
- No
and no jealous ex-boyfriends.
Trust me, I thought of that.
You two don't get it.
I've got a life to live.
And if anyone's trying to kill me
I can take care of myself.
I'm glad this is your detail
and not mine.
Go on.
- What do you got, Abs?
- Gibbs, you scared me.
What are you doing?
I'm searching male birth records
from Jefferson Parish, Louisiana.
You find anything?
How'd you make out with the prints found
in Kaplan's apartment?
I haven't gotten to them yet.
What about the computer sketch?
- His business manager never showed up.
- Did you tell Tony, McGee?
I've been a little distracted.
I need you.
I appreciate it.
Broker said he got a call from
Drew Turner, the hot, sexy accountant,
last week, authorizing
the money transfer to Costa Rica
from Kaplan's account.
She told us she hadn't spoken to Kaplan
since last tax season.
- She lied.
- I guess she won't be doing your taxes.
- I'm going to call Gibbs.
- Hold it, probie.
I'm the one who subpoenaed
the brokerage papers.
Yeah, but I'm the one that traced
the transfer to the gambling Web site.
- Boss, that's me.
- Actually, that was me.
I got Kaplan's brokerage statement.
Week before the 25 grand
was wired to the hit man
there was a $500,000 withdrawal.
I tracked it to an online gambling
Web site in Costa Rica.
Transaction was initiated by Kaplan's
business manager, Drew Turner.
We told you Drew is a woman, right?
Of course we did.
She is authorized
to sign on the account.
You knew that, too.
She told us she hadn't talked
to Kaplan in months.
We think that little kitty cat
is up to something.
Clearly, she and George Kaplan
were in this together.
Turner did not show
to do the sketch with Abby.
Bring her in.
She's not home.
Car's here.
I'm gonna have Abby track her cell.
What do you expect to see, Tony?
You don't have to track her cell.
She's home.
What's she doing?
Not much.
We better call Gibbs.
She's a civilian.
- I want the body.
- No. We found her.
She's our lead to who may have put out
the hit out on the commander.
A lot of good
she's gonna do you dead.
She leave a suicide note?
The late Ms. Turner
did not commit suicide.
What are you talking about?
She hung herself.
Meet Metro Detective Sportelli.
Good morning.
I'd shake hands, but...
I'm cool.
- What are you thinking, Duck?
- The hanging was staged.
- How can you tell?
- Well, to begin with,
suicide by hanging is very unusual
uncharacteristic for a female.
So I was suspicious.
Human flesh reacts differently
after death.
When a person hangs themselves
they are suspended by the neck with the
weight of the body pulling downwards.
The ligature creates a furrow
with a pattern that runs from the front
to the back.
But when the ligature
is applied after death
as in this case,
you can see it's fairly even.
The tissue, not being infused
with blood, reacts differently.
It's drier and more yellowish.
Then how did she die?
I opened up the neck,
and I found bruising
on her organs consistent
with manual strangulation.
Ms. Turner was choked to death,
and then hanged to make it look
as if the manner of death
was indeed suicide.
A cover-up?
Fake suicide?
- Think she was killed by George Kaplan?
- What if there isn't a Kaplan?
The only person other than Drew Turner
who says that they met Kaplan
is his landlady,
and she's got a real fuzzy memory.
We've got no photo I.D. of him.
Maybe Drew Turner was Kaplan.
I don't know.
She doesn't look like a George to me.
Besides...
they did sign the authorization card
for the brokerage account.
She could've disguised her handwriting,
signed both.
Faked suicide, fake names
women pretending to be men.
This is getting messy.
I tell you what...
I'm out of here.
I'll let you duke it out
with the FBI.
So long, Gibbs.
How does this all tie
into Commander Brett?
We still don't know
why someone wants him dead.
It's like Deep Throat said
in All the President's Men:
"Follow the money".
There's over a million bucks
in Kaplan's account still.
We know what he spent some of it on.
Paying off gambling debts
ordering a hit.
Where'd the money come from?
I'm going to try and get Abby
to compare both signatures, see
if they were made by the same person.
Try, McGee?
Abby's been real distracted
by this brother thing.
I noticed.
She had no luck finding the guy.
Do your thing.
See what you can find out
about the brother.
Nope, never heard the name.
- Who is he?
- She.
Kaplan's business manager.
She was found dead yesterday.
How did she die?
Murdered.
There's a connection
to the hit on you.
That is why you need to stay
in protective custody, Commander.
All right.
You convinced me.
I won't fight you anymore.
Look at the spacing between
the letters and the names.
I compared the relative height,
width, size and slant of the letters
that are common to both names...
"E", "N" and "R".
The baseline habits
are totally different,
these signatures were definitely made
by two separate people.
You sure?
McGee.
Now, look at Kaplan's signature.
The counter of the "A"s
and the cramped loop of the "E"...
it's a very masculine trait.
There's a difference between male
and female handwriting?
Of course.
I was wrong.
There is a George Kaplan,
and he's out there somewhere.
I'm going to dust
the original signature card.
Maybe Kaplan left a print
when he signed it.
My dynamic duo.
Does anyone know
where I can find Gibbs?
Think he's still in the conference room.
What do you got?
"I know where Kaplan got the money."
Can you just try telling us
like a normal human being?
All the funds were wired
from the Broussard Banque
- in Geneva, Switzerland.
- Whose account?
I don't know yet.
But I'm going to find out.
See ya!
We got to keep him away
from that new coffee machine.
You got a sec?
We need to talk.
I think we're losing
Kenneally's vote.
Hello.
Hi.
I'll let you two talk.
She's still here.
You going to tell me what's going on?
NCIS says there's been
a threat on my life.
Don't worry.
It's got to be a mistake.
This will all go away
in a couple days.
In the last year and a half,
there have been four deposits
into George Kaplan's account,
totaling $1.5 million.
They all came from the Broussard
Banque in Switzerland.
Special Agent Survoy in Marseilles
is currently trying to find out
who authorized
the transfer of funds to Kaplan.
Abby looks
like she's in a better mood.
You got something?
I pulled the prints of three people off
the brokerage account signature card.
One was a clerk
that works in the file room.
And Drew Turner,
the business manager.
And... ta-da...
Lieutenant Commander Geoffrey Brett.
- His fingerprints are on the card?
- There's more.
Look at the uppercase "G"s,
and then the lowercase,
"O"s, "E"s and "R"s.
Those signatures came
from the same person.
Lieutenant Commander Geoffrey Brett
is George Kaplan.
It doesn't make sense.
What did Brett put
a hit out on himself?
Did he kill Drew Turner?
We need proof that Brett
and Drew Turner knew each other.
George Kaplan!
Of course.
I'm slipping.
What took me so long?
Spit it out, DiNozzo.
The Hitchcock classic,
North by Northwest...
George Kaplan is the name of the guy
who never existed.
Brett created Kaplan
to hide the money,
he was getting from the Broussard
Banque in Switzerland.
Drew Turner had to be in on it.
She helped Brett set the whole thing up.
She opened up a brokerage
account under the fake name,
filed all the tax returns
and rented an apartment
so they'd have
a valid mailing address.
DiNozzo, fill Ziva in.
- Can Brett hear you?
- Yes, of course.
- You sitting down?
- What is it?
Put on your most Mossad/ninja face.
No big reaction.
Commander Brett is George Kaplan.
They are one and the same person.
Really?
What's the plan?
Gibbs wants you to hang in there
until we know more.
Don't let him out of your sight
like you did last time.
Nice.
I'll wait for you
to call me back, sweetheart.
Good luck.
Bye.
Boyfriend?
DiNozzo, get me Special
Agent Survoy in Marseilles.
I want to know
who this money's coming from.
Boss.
- What is that?
- That call was from a friend,
at Health and Human Services.
This is the name and address
of the man whose DNA matches Abby's.
What should I do with it?
I'll take care of it.
You bring me a Caf-POW as my reward?
No. I've got something else for you.
Is that what I think it is?
His name's Kyle Davis?
That's a lot of responsibility.
What are you gonna do with it?
I want to meet him.
Okay.
You sure you want to open that door?
You want me to go with you?
I think this is something
I have to do alone.
You've always known
what's best for Abby.
Yeah, it's Gibbs.
I've been in contact with Broussard
Banque in Geneva.
Under the 2009 information-sharing
agreement with the United States,
they gave me the name of the company
who wired the funds to "George Kaplan".
It's a foreign subsidiary
to Stembridge Marine.
It's one of the largest naval
shipbuilders in the U.S.
And Brett's the liaison for the House
Armed Services Committee.
For the past year, he's been running up
and down the halls of Congress,
pushing Stembridge Marine's
$14 billion aircraft carrier.
It's like having their own lobbyist.
- Can you say "kickback"?
- Thank you, Special Agent Survoy.
I heard there's an opening
in Contingency Response.
Could you put in a good...
Boss, I ran a matrix
comparing Brett's
and Drew Turner's credit card
statements.
Almost every Thursday night
over the last two years,
they've both hung at the 1812 Pub.
Bartender thought they were an item.
Brett couldn't explain
his massive income.
Not on a Navy salary.
He had to launder it,
so he got a little help from his
bar honey/accountant, Drew Turner.
They created the fictitious
George Kaplan,
then they ran the money
through the brokerage account,
- so they could make it legal.
- It was brilliant.
Until it went sideways.
Hi.
Cute?
He has a great personality.
You want to hold him?
Do I know you from somewhere?
I don't think so.
The dog park on 11th, right?
I've never been there.
You sure look familiar.
Are you looking
to rescue a pet today?
I was just window-shopping.
But I really admire
what you do here.
I love your dog collar.
We have a pit bull terrier
that has one just like it.
Come take a look.
You'll get a kick out of her.
Come on.
The vote's in a couple days.
I have better things to do
than be dragged back to NCIS.
We had a break in the case.
Why don't you just tell me
what it is?
"Interrogation Room"?
That doesn't sound good.
Oh. Sorry.
Did not know this room was used.
Not a problem.
Just finishing up here.
You know Nick Sandlock.
We were just talking about Stembridge,
kickbacks and Swiss banks.
We can talk in here.
Bye-bye.
Special Agent McGee.
You look like you may need to sit down,
Commander.
Sounded like a pretty sweet plan
till Drew Turner got in trouble.
What was it, Costa Rica?
Her gambling?
She was addicted to it.
When did you realize she was using
your money to pay off her bets?
When you said "George Kaplan"
took out a hit on me.
Drew was the only other person
who knew that name.
With you dead, she'd have access
to everything in the account.
The greedy bitch used
the money to have me killed.
That why you ditched Ziva?
So you could go after her?
I was putting that money away
for my daughter.
For her future needs.
I think this is where I tell you
I need to talk to a lawyer.
Door's unlocked, Abs.
Hi, Gibbs.
So?
- You see the guy?
- Kyle?
My brother?
Yeah.
How'd it go?
It was fine.
I didn't tell him who I was.
He seems really, really nice.
He doesn't need the added stress.
He just got chosen to donate a kidney,
and the operation's tomorrow.
I have things I have to work out,
you know?
Are you drinking tea?
Yeah.
Don't tell Ducky.
He'll give me a lecture on brewing.
What do you need to work out?
This whole brother-sister thing.
It didn't make any sense to me.
Kyle and me...
our DNA is a total match.
So, we have to have
the same biological parents.
So then I was like,
what did they give him up
for adoption?
And I can't imagine,
the wonderful, loving parents
that raised me and Luca
ever giving up a child.
But they would have adopted a child.
And they did.
Me.
I'm adopted, Gibbs.
How do you know that?
This is my mom's hair.
And I ran a DNA test on it
and I compared it to mine.
It wasn't a biological match, Gibbs.
So I...
I don't know who I am anymore.
I don't know who my parents were.
I'm just like...
like Little Orphan Abby.
You're still the same person.
Your parents...
they're still your parents,
as you remember them.
Family's more than just... DNA.
It's about...
people who care
and take care of each other.
I know.
But why didn't they tell me
I was adopted?
I mean, there's got to be a reason.
And I need to find out before,
I completely turn Luca
and Kyle's lives upside down.
You don't have to do this alone,
Abby.
You've got a family.
And we'll help you through it.
www.Team-NCIS.com
www.tvsubtitles.net