The worst of the Eight Hells
is called Continuous Hell.
It has the meaning of Continuous
Suffering. Thus the name
5 years ago
we started valet parking in Tuen Mun.
We were full of ambition.
But 2 weeks had hardly gone by
and the cops started busting us every day.
Within one year
6 of our brothers died.
Thanks to the Buddha, my life was spared.
What thousands must die
so that Caesar may become great.
But I don't believe in destiny.
The rule of this game
is to take fate in our own hands.
You are the newest in my gang.
Your records are the cleanest.
You can choose your own future.
OK.
I wish you guys
every success in the police force.
Bottoms up, officers
27149, you were here 10 minutes ago.
How many files were on my desk?
Six, sir. Four beige ones on the left
one red and one white on the right.
What do you think of me?
Sorry, I'm not sure, sir.
But I know you're in a hurry today
'coz your socks don't match
27149, you can go now.
Yes, sir.
You owe me $500.
OK, but wait till pay day next month
I told you he would make the best
undercover cop.
Now that you're in the cadet school
you should follow the rules.
Those who break the rules will be
like him.
They will be expelled.
Who wants to trade place with him?
I do.
this is a long-term undercover mission.
Your records in the cadet school
will be erased.
Only Superintendent Wong and
I know of your identity.
This mission is highly dangerous
is that clear?
Yes, sir.
Sir, I can't stand it any longer
I'm either harassed by cops
or beaten up by gangsters.
4927, you are still a rookie.
Give me a good reason
why I should promote you.
Hang on?
Why don't you go hang yourself instead?
I won the Silver Whistle Award
at the cadet
and have received numerous kudos as
an officer.
I am confident I can lead the police force
sir.
Boss.
OK, I got it.
Move forward.
Hurry up.
Please go over there to take your mugshot.
Excuse me.
Can I try this stereo?
What speakers are you using?
Nothing special, any recommendations?
Try this tube amplifier
made in Hong Kong, 10,000 only.
And use this cable, also locally made
about 1000.
The sound is as good as expensive
European amps.
Sweet high notes, crisp middle
strong bass.
In a word, transparent.
Come and listen.
Human voices are drifting towards you.
See that?
Voices are indeed drifting towards you.
Try this one.
This is ideal for listening to oldies.
What do you think?
Much better indeed.
Any discount if I buy the whole set?
Buy the tube amp here
but not the speakers.
Go to Cheung Wai; It's cheaper there.
Whom should I ask for?
Just tell them Yan sent you.
Which one is mine?
The one in the middle.
Okay, thanks.
You're welcome.
Is Cheung Wai open yet?
Sure.
You bastard.
I told you to watch the store
not to send my customers away.
But your speakers are over-priced
if I don't sell them at this price how can
I afford to pay "protection money"?
You can try not paying for a change.
Hey, the cable
I'll return it in a few days
$4,000 for a few days?
Where are you rushing to?
A funeral.
Tell me.
How many times have you been busted
for assault?
I am trying to convince
the Department of Justice
that you need to see a shrink.
But you keep on beating people up.
Are you really going nuts?
Have you forgotten you're a cop?
You told me it's only for 3 years.
But after 3 years come another 3 years
and another
it's almost 10 years already, boss.
Can't you be a bit more courteous to me?
I'm the only one in Hong Kong
who knows your real identity now.
Maybe I'll just erase your file
so you can stick with the Triads for good.
What do you want me to do?
Remind myself I'm a cop every day?
Shouting "Drop your gun, I'm a cop"
even in my dreams?
When will Sam place his order?
No idea.
Sometime this week.
What?
The Thais are here.
Once the goods arrive
Sam will resell them.
Where is the warehouse?
How the hell do I know?
I started working for him only 3 years ago.
OK, I'll let you retire after this.
Bullshit
I heard this a zillion times already.
Shit. These mikes again?
The Police is loaded with cash
Tell them to get more advanced models.
How about implanting it into your body?
Into which part of my body?
A pinhole camera?
Where's the lens?
Your birthday is on the 25th, right?
I never wear watches.
If we got nothing for the Interpol by 5pm
the counterfeit passport case is off
3:15. Tea time.
What would you like, boss?
Tea with milk, please.
They won't talk without their attorney.
Has paged their lawyers
but he hasn't called back yet.
I won't talk without my attorney.
I am Mr. Lau, your attorney.
Did you call home?
Why should I call home?
It's good then.
Where were you last Friday
from 3:45 to 5:00 pm?
Brother Mo told me to ask you
if your family needs any help.
No need to look around.
They won't record anything
when a lawyer is present
it's not admissible in court anyway.
Brother Mo sent you?
Those 2 kids next door
have squealed on the workshop already.
Cops are heading there now.
Brother Mo told you not to say anything
if your brother is there
tell him to leave right away.
Here.
What?
Scram.
I ask you to scram, do you hear?
Scram right away.
All right. I'll leave you
if you don't trust me, so be it.
Take care.
Remember don't talk without your attorney.
I don't need you to tell me that.
Fanny.
Yes?
Take this.
Check this number.
Sure.
Send this message for me.
Cheung Fai Industrial Building, 2nd Floor.
Cheung Fai Industrial Building, 2nd Floor
OK.
Boss.
All set.
A Triad member.
Where's my tea?
Here.
Thanks.
You're great.
How did you know it's Mo's hideout?
Thanks.
Hello, yes.
No problem. OK.
Sorry guys, over time tonight.
Our target tonight is a drug trafficking
cartel.
In an hour's time
they will be trading with a Thai seller.
Cash will be handed over in the building
across the street
in a unit on the 3rd floor.
Where the goods will be delivered is
still unknown.
CIB shall tag the target
and tap the phone lines.
Our unit will not take action till our
mole has pinned down the delivery location.
Let's take a look at our principal stars.
Here are our principal stars tonight:
Hon Sam, Chen Wing-yan, Del Piero.
We've been watching them for a long time.
We'd better nail them tonight.
OK? No more questions?
Let's get to work.
Sorry for paging you so urgently.
But our mission is kept confidential till
the last moment.
No problem.
Do you have confidence?
Yes, it should be OK.
Hello, Dad.
Pass the phone to Dad.
I can't come home for dinner.
Too bad
Dinner has been prepared already.
Call me when you're back
I'll heat it up for you.
You look so relaxed
it's only work
We can always work on it next time.
Sorry.
All cell phone signals in this area
are under surveillance.
SP Wong.
SP Wong, which channel?
Channel 454870.
Attention. Our prey is in sight.
Big Brother.
Boss.
Take out all your cell phones.
You two, go get the car.
Wait.
Yan
escort the Thais here.
You two, follow me.
Lau.
Yes.
Did Sam and his gang make any calls?
No. They probably changed their phones.
Let's search randomly for calls
made from this area.
Searching.
Some 6,500 cell phones
are being connected in this area right now.
267 cell phones are making calls
on this street alone.
Give me 10 minutes.
Good.
Thank you.
Did they spot us?
Are those two over there watching us?
Which two?
Those two.
No one is watching you.
Those two making out over there.
They are just making out
Why would they be watching you?
You think you're a movie star?
Our prey is back.
Yip, watch our prey closely.
Boss. The Thais are here.
Hey man.
What's up?
How are you?
Cigar?
Is that any good?
Excellent.
Is it cold in Hong Kong?
Very cold.
You even know how to speak Cantonese.
How fantastic.
Marvelous indeed.
AA+
Deal.
Automobile license plate number HN397
is taking off.
Repeat, Helen, Nelson
HN397 is taking off.
Attention. HN397 is taking off.
Repeat, Helen, Nelson, 397.
Should we send a car to tail them?
Elephant
Kwai Chung Container Terminus
Roger.
Piero. You're being tailed.
Lead them in circles.
They know which channel we are on.
Switch to channel 456855.
Boss, where are those two going?
Don't worry, take it easy.
Take care of the Thais for me.
Sorry, sir.
Hello?
Why don't you use the walkie talkie?
We've switched channels?
Are you done yet?
Beat it.
Piero, are you being tailed?
Keep driving around.
Cheung.
Use the current channel to tell Elephant
that action has been canceled.
Yes, sir.
Elephant, no hunting tonight.
Come back to the station
it's done.
What the hell is going on?
Our guys are freezing to death out there.
What's so funny?
I speak Thai. I know what they're saying.
Really?
Yes. They are bitching at the boss.
What are they bitching about?
Those Thais at Lung Koo Bay
are freezing to death.
You know they can't stand the cold.
That's right.
You're sharp.
Cheung, call Elephant.
Goods to be delivered at Lung Koo Bay.
Boss, I found it.
Tell Keung to check the goods
And make sure no one is around.
Not a soul.
A boat is approaching
Probably for checking the goods.
The cocaine is all here.
Keung, are you an idiot or what?
Boss.
I heard it.
Tell Keung to shout a loud
that the cocaine is his.
Keung, the Boss
asks you to shout aloud that the cocaine
is yours.
The cocaine is yours.
Take delivery.
They are taking delivery
Get ready for action.
Thanks. Thanks.
Thank you.
Double Eight.
As soon as the Thais step out, arrest them.
There's a stooge. Stop the deal.
Wait.
Hello?
Cast all the goods into the sea. Now.
Keung. Cast all the goods into the sea.
Police. Freeze.
We got the men but lost the goods.
They have cast everything into the sea.
Double Eight, hold it.
All of you, follow me.
What are you looking at?
Boss. Let's...
Police, don't move
Sam.
Your food looks good.
Not bad.
We've straightened it out.
Your boys are only strolling on the beach.
So they can go now?
Sure, any time.
We don't want to waste any more of
your precious time.
We've known each other for so long.
Don't give me that.
I haven't had my dinner here
for quite a while
if you like it, you're always welcome here.
How about tomorrow?
I'll take a rain check.
I feel bad coming here empty-handed.
Don't stand on ceremonies.
I' should feel bad
for making you drop several grand
tonight.
You think planting a mole in us will do
us in?
Same here.
I remember a story.
Two fools are waiting for their
kidney transplants
but only one kidney is available.
The two guys thus play a game.
They each put a playing card
into the other's pocket.
Whoever guesses the card in his own
pocket wins.
You know I can see your card.
I think so too.
I will beat you.
Let's see.
We should be more careful.
I will.
By the way
whoever loses the game will die.
Let's see when you're gonna die.
Ever seen someone shakes
a corpse's hand?
Let's go.
Put it next to the couch.
OK
Thanks
Mary.
What's interior designer's number?
The interior designer... 90255047.
How many boxes have I counted?
24? Are you sure?
Positive.
Pass me the phone.
Coming.
Hello?
Hold on please.
Who is it?
I don't know.
Hello
it's me.
Yes, I'm moving in.
Don't eavesdrop. It's confidential
I lost all of my goods.
There's a mole.
Dig him out for me.
Hold on, too many people around here.
Hold on.
I have no access to those undercover files.
I can't dig him out.
I don't care how difficult it is.
I only know he uses Morse codes.
Give me all the information on the people
around you last night.
Their real names, ID card no.
Account no., etc.
See you tonight, at the cinema.
OK.
What's the matter?
I'm talking about my novel
I know what I'm going to write about
Come here
I can write about a man with 28 different
personalities.
Are you talking about me?
Be more serious.
Think about it.
A man with 28 personalities.
That means he starts role playing
the minute he wakes up.
He is no longer certain
which personality is the real him
isn't it scary?
Very much.
Good?
Yeah. Will be a bestseller for sure.
Wait...
What is it?
Why is the ottoman so big?
Which one?
I must have gotten the measurements
wrong.
Take it easy.
You women...
Let me see. Get up slowly.
Don't be mad.
Meet up?
You want me dead?
There's a mole in the police station.
Dig him out first.
So who is he?
I can't talk anymore.
What?
Just now?
I was at a Chinese chiropractor.
I'm seeing the shrink now.
I'm going psycho. That's it.
This chair is really... incredible.
You should get one for yourself?
So you don't need to come here
and sleep every time
it's more comfortable here.
Don't be so peevish.
During these 4 months, if it weren't for me
you wouldn't have the time to play
it's 5 months computer games.
In one more month
your mandatory therapy will be over.
You can sleep peacefully at home then.
So soon?
I don't seem to have improved at all.
Why don't you just prolong my treatment.
Besides, my head is splitting these days.
Could it be schizophrenia?
This is called "headache"
I'll prescribe some Panadol for you.
Actually
there's something I want to ask you
but...
it's kind of embarrassing.
What do you think of me?
Do you think I'm a good guy or a bad guy?
I hardly know who you are.
Tell you a secret, but don't tell anyone.
I'm actually a cop.
So am I.
Let's continue next week.
Try to remember your dreams.
Of course.
I will dream about you.
See you next week.
Just Panadol?
Bye.
Your promotion should be OK.
You will be transferred to Internal Affairs
but you will work at OCTB.
I don't understand.
I suspect Sam has a mole
in the department.
I want you to investigate.
Why me?
We have scrutinized all possible
candidates.
You have an immaculate record.
You have solved many cases in CIB.
Working in LA, you will get in touch
with senior officials.
That's a good opportunity.
I've arranged for you to appear on TV.
Remember to spruce up a bit.
When will I meet the Board?
You just did.
Come, take a stab.
Thanks.
By the way
how's the wedding?
Everything's on schedule.
That's good.
You'll be more stable after marriage.
Your image will improve too.
You have chance of further promotion.
Yes, broaden your horizon.
Fill in your real name.
This is my real name.
You don't know Del Piero is my real name?
Is that so?
Yes.
What are you guys writing?
The Boss told us to fill in these forms.
Must be setting up mandatory
provident funds for us.
You know, MPF.
Are you serious?
You don't know to spell BODYGUARD?
Isn't it supposed to look like this?
Of course not.
Should be B-O-D-Y-G-A-R-D.
That's it.
A shipment will come in next week.
They are watching closely.
You do what you need to do.
I'll handle the rest.
The file is open. I'm
afraid I can't handle it.
So you're not worried about me.
You are worried about yourself
Inspector Lau.
Those girls are so ugly.
I'll take care of it as soon as I can.
Hello?
I'm on my way back.
Yan.
How long have you worked for me?
3 or 4 years already.
That long?
Doesn't seem that long to me.
I have another shipment next week.
But this time
I'm using some tough, new faces.
So you guys can rest.
Even Keung and the others?
Keung?
Don't you know he's nuts?
There's a mole within us. You know that?
What do you think we should do?
I'll take care of it.
How?
I'll find out who he is in a couple of days
Get ready for action.
Yan.
Of all the brothers, I trust you the most.
Lau.
No, thanks.
These folks.
You know most of them
no need for introduction, right?
No, but...
they are so...
Who doesn't know you're sent here
to find the mole?
What do you want them to do?
Pour you a cup of coffee?
Only an idiot will not be envied, right?
They all want to know who the mole is.
Just tell me whom you want to investigate.
OK
Any clues?
Two days ago, my informer
nearly found out who he was.
Too bad he lost him.
But if Sam is getting a new shipment
he must contact the mole again.
Just follow Sam and we'll get
what we want.
That's right. I've much to learn from you.
Don't say that.
Our seniors sent you here
because they think you can do it.
Not everyone can handle LA tasks
it's stuffy here.
Let's get out of here.
The coffee here is the best
in the headquarters.
I'll pour you a cup.
My informer nearly found out
who the mole was.
But if Sam is getting a new shipment
he must contact the mole again.
Yes?
Hey.
The bed has arrived.
Is that so? Comfortable?
You want to try it?
Don't be silly. I have work to do.
Think about it.
No, I can't.
Come on.
Saturday.
I'll be free next Saturday
We can try it then.
OK.
OK, next Saturday then.
Bye.
Up already?
Yes.
We just tested the bed
and you are working again?
I'm very hardworking.
What are you writing now?
Here.
The more I think of it, the more
pathetic the main character appears.
Pathetic indeed.
Perhaps I should make him a happier guy.
Good.
Should I turn him into a good guy?
Even though he is good
he has done bad things.
So how should it end?
That's a good question.
I'll leave this to you writers.
You're not going to sleep?
Help me, please.
Help me, please?
I can't.
Go to sleep. You are tired.
From now on
follow SP Wong around the clock.
Piero, I know how to spot a plainclothes.
How?
If he seems to be doing something
but is paying attention to us instead
then he is a cop.
Is that so?
Then the whole place is filled with cops.
They're everywhere.
Yan.
Boss.
Watching something?
You are a cop.
We are guessing who a cop is.
How trivial.
I'm going for a massage, wanna come?
I hate it.
Don't tell.
Tell on him.
I won't.
What a coincidence.
Yes, I was shopping in the hood.
Haven't seen you for ages
6 or 7 years already.
How are you?
I'm married. How about you?
Still working in...?
Mommy.
Your daughter?
Yes.
How old is she?
5 years old.
I'm waiting for my husband's car, so...
I'm also in a hurry.
Bye.
Mommy, I'm 6 already.
Sorry, I always get it wrong.
Where are you now?
On my way.
Hello?
Boss, he is taking the subway.
Keep following him.
Boss, he has gone to the 24th floor.
Stay put. Don't do anything rash.
Boss, we've got him.
I don't know yet.
But I know where he is now.
Keep watch over here.
So? Any good news?
A shipment will come in next week.
Time and location yet to be confirmed.
I still don't know who Sam's mole is
but he seems confident he can blow
my cover.
In that case
we'd better stop it
We're gonna lose for sure.
You are kidding, right?
What else can we do? It's deadly business.
Hello?
Boss said he had found the mole.
He told us to take care of him.
I'll be right there.
Hello?
Keep an eye on SP Wong.
You two, take the stairs.
Keung, take the elevator.
Anyone knows you're seeing me today?
No.
They are downstairs now.
What are you doing?
Put it away.
Take the window-washing scaffolding.
How about you?
I'll take the elevator.
Be careful.
- Hey.
- What?
Nothing.
Darling, the apartment is superb.
A 180-degree window facing
the golf course
plus club membership costs less than
a million.
Superintendent Wong?
Turn around to the main entrance.
What do you think of me?
Your birthday is on the 25th, right?
Let's go.
Police. Let's go.
Bad news, Boss.
Something happened to SP Wong.
There's a gunfight in Sheung Wan
this afternoon.
Three suspects were dead;
Several suspects and pedestrians
were injured.
The police confirmed that
one of the victims
was superintendent in OCTB
Mr. Wong Chi-shing.
The motive is unknown.
Possibility of gang feud is not ruled out.
They are now after several triad members
active in the Southern Kowloon area.
The Police Commissioner
expressed condolence
and pledged to solve the case
as soon as possible
It was a close shave
10 minutes after you went to your massage.
Boss told us to get ready.
I was scared stiff.
You know
I hide under the car in every fight.
And there were guns up there.
I wanted to sneak out of there.
Two days ago
Boss told me to go to his room.
He asked me how long I'd worked for him.
How the hell could I remember?
He then said: Keung
it's been 5 years already.
You've performed well all these years.
I have a question for you
if one of your brothers is a mole
will you dare to take him out?
Of course I said yes to his face.
You think I'm an idiot?
What's the result?
Of course they couldn't find the mole.
The cop was tough.
They dragged him upstairs
and beat him up for a good 10 minutes
10 minutes...
He didn't say a word.
Keung.
Boss said...
the cop was hot on his trail.
Who didn't show up today is the mole.
I didn't...
tell him you went for a massage
if Boss knew, you're dead meat.
Yan, I want to ask you something.
How was the masseuse today?
Because...
if she's ugly, it's not worth it.
Leave right away.
There will be lots of
cops after a car crash.
Anyway, remember this:
If you see someone
doing something
but at the same time watching you...
then he is a cop.
According to the closed-circuit TV.
SP Wong entered that building at 4:15 pm.
The suspects entered 20 minutes later.
At 4:38 pm
we received Inspector Lau's report
8 minutes before we arrived
someone fell off the building.
That was SP Wong.
All the suspects killed or
injured belong to Sam's gang.
Many suspects escaped.
The actual numbers are unknown.
Do you know why SP Wong went to
that building?
It was me.
I told CIB to follow him.
Why was CIB following him?
That's IA's business.
Now that SP Wong is dead
it is OCTB's business.
What kind of attitude is that?
SP Wong was dedicated to the police force
and you investigated him?
What kind of attitude is that?
So we senior officers have to ask
for your approval, huh?
Your people have made a mistake now.
Or SP Wong wouldn't have died.
I am talking business here.
I am talking personal matters.
Nobody wanted this, OK?
Sorry, sir
it's my negligence.
I will give everybody an answer.
Sorry.
SP Wong has a file
with information on our undercover
in Sam's gang
it is locked by a password.
The technical staff can't decipher it.
Inspector Lau.
Yes.
Work with CIB
to unlock it.
Find our man and get him out of there.
By the way.
SP Wong was a good cop.
We should give him a grand funeral.
Okay?
Yes, sir.
Hello?
Boss. Why made such a scene?
He was following me all the time.
One of us would have to die.
I'm now in charge of everything here
if you're having any transactions
just let me know
it's done.
We got the goods when they killed
the cop today.
I won't bother you now.
What did you call me for?
So you're the one?
Who are you?
Inspector Lau of OCTB.
SP Wong is gone. We're all upset.
I still have unfinished business.
SP Wong wouldn't want you to
take law in your own hands.
What do you want?
Co-operation.
The police has discovered
the body of a fugitive suspect
He was involved in
the Sheung Wan shooting earlier today.
The police has confirmed
the body to be an undercover cop
Tsui Wai-keung.
The police has expressed their condolence
and promised a thorough investigation.
Boss, Yan is back.
Three vehicles collided in Yuen Long
today.
The driver of the private car was trapped
until firefighters came and rescued him.
Boss.
What is it, Yan?
I have taken care of Keung already.
Did you ever send him to the warehouse?
It will be disastrous
if he knows where it is.
Boss. It's me.
You don't have to go yourself.
I don't want anyone to know the password.
I understand.
I'll send everyone away.
Inspector Cheung.
Tell those boys to stop
following Sam's gang.
I got information that Sam is
heading towards the warehouse.
He won't go if he's being tailed.
Just call them back.
Let's do something for SP Wong.
Please help me, OK?
Say something.
This is not my case.
Officer Chan told me not to get involved
if they're willing to stop
then it's up to them.
I know I'm responsible for
SP Wong's death.
I am also a cop, like you.
I want to solve the case too.
I thought you only want promotion.
It's SP Wong's mole who tipped me off.
Do you believe it or not?
This is our last chance
Are you ready to take the risk?
Attention: Target vehicle
on Highway no.3.
U-turn at Pier 3
to Lung Cheung Road.
They have been here for 20 minutes
they are going to the 4th floor of
the car park.
Officer Chan won't let me touch this case
if anything goes wrong
you'll take the blame.
They are loading the goods at 4P.
Elephant, stand by at the exit at 3P.
Double Eight, watch the entrance at 2P.
Fishball and Cheung, stand by here.
All of you, wait for my signal.
Oh, I forgot Boss told me to stay behind.
Drop me off here.
Run him over.
My Master always said that about my life:
What thousands must die so that
Caesar may become great.
You choose your own future.
That's what you have chosen.
Coffee for you.
He's waited a long time for you.
So it's you?
Was the stereo OK?
Pretty good.
Those tube amps have to be warmed up.
Wait 10 minutes and it sounds great.
Should I salute you?
Not, don't.
How long have you been an undercover?
I've followed Sam for 3 years.
I had several other bosses before.
All together it's been 10 years
10 years?
I should salute you instead.
I just want an identity.
I want to be a normal man.
Getting tired?
You've never been a mole
you won't understand.
Too bad I still can't find the stooge
I'll take him down if I find him.
Don't worry
Let me give you back your identity
I'll open your file but...
I don't have the password.
What's the Morse code for
"undercover"?
That's it?
Are you serious?
You don't even know to
spell BODYGUARD?
Isn't it supposed to look like this?
Of course not.
Dr. Lee.
I thought you wouldn't come.
You're wanted by the police.
Can I sleep in your chair again?
Let's talk upstairs.
Last time you said you're a cop.
Is it true?
It was true.
But I'm not so sure now.
So what's your plan?
I don't know. Still thinking.
There's one thing I've been trying to
tell you for a while.
But it's too embarrassing.
I told you I dreamt about you all the time
it's true.
Me too.
Remember my secret. Goodbye
Mary.
What is it? Has it broken down?
This morning
the guys from the stereo shop came.
They have tuned it up already.
They also left a CD sampler for you.
I've listened to it.
Have you had breakfast yet?
I'll get you some.
Iced tea?
Chinese buns?
Sure.
I can't finish my novel.
I don't know whether he's good or bad.
I think only he knows.
A shipment will come in next week.
They are watching closely.
You do what you need to do.
I will handle the rest.
The file is open. I can't handle it.
So you're not worried about me.
You are worried about yourself
Inspector Lau.
Are the voices crisp enough?
The precious recording
was taken from Sam's office
it's not your lucky day.
Don't threaten me. What do you want?
I want my identity back
3 pm, Central Ferry Pier.
Keep your cell on.
The number you have dialed cannot be
connected.
Please leave a message after the beep.
Mary, I'm sorry.
I've chosen to be the good guy.
I'm going to meet Yan now.
No matter what
I'll give him back his identity.
The file is in my computer.
The password is your birthday.
You sure know what you're doing.
I also went to the cadet school.
Do all undercover cops like rooftops?
Unlike you, I'm not afraid of light.
So where's the stuff I want?
I don't think you've brought
what I want either.
So what does this mean?
We came up here to sunbathe?
Give me a chance.
How?
I have no choice before
but now I want to turn over a new leaf.
Good.
Try telling that to the judge.
See what he has to say.
You want me dead?
Sorry, I'm a cop.
Who knows that?
Don't move. Police.
Drop your weapon and let Inspector Lau
go first.
Your boss is Sam's mole.
I got evidence.
Let's clear this up at the station.
Drop your weapon now.
I've called the police.
Why should I trust you?
You don't have to.
You'd better watch out.
Look who's talking.
I wish you every success in
the police force.
Bottoms up, officers.
No sweat. We are brothers.
Sam is dead now.
You have to look after me.
I joined the cadet school in 1994.
But my career never really takes off.
Sam looked down on me.
I've taken care of Sam's tape.
Don't worry. I'll follow you from now on.
Our folks will be here any minute
Let's give them a good show
I'm actually quite smart.
Too bad Sam never knew that.
I'm a cop.
Six months later, Dr. Lee Sum Yee
was looking through the personal
properties left by Officer Yip
Headmaster of the Cadet.
She found Chen Wing-yan's file that
proved his police identity.
Chen Wing-yan is now buried
next to SP Wong Chi-shing.
How are you, Mr. Policeman?
Those who break the rules will be like him.
They will be expelled.
Anybody wants to trade place with him?
I do.
Says the Buddha:
"He who is in Continuous Hell never dies.
Longevity is a big hardship
in Continuous Hell"