Previously on "the rookie"
I can't just go back
to the way things were.
- Are you breaking up with me?
- I'm sorry.
Blair London, rookie police psychiatrist.
She had leverage on mad dog.
She's blackmailed one
cop, there may be more.
Someone is trying to kill
me, and I need to know who.
I want you to help
me break out of prison.
Jason.
- Who are you?
- Her boyfriend.
- And you are?
- Her husband.
Nolan!
What's wrong?
Oscar and Jason just
escaped from prison.
SWAT says ten-minute warning.
We should get down there.
Unless you want to sit this one out.
No, I'm good.
With all due respect, sir,
nobody would fault you.
You're one day back from
being wounded in the line.
Got to get right back on
that horse, officer juarez.
Especially a man of a certain age.
I would guess getting
shot in your hindquarters
might make horse riding problematic, sir.
You making fun, officer juarez?
- Not at all, sir.
- Good.
Still got three months
left in your training.
It's imperative you stay on my good side.
You really think Jason
is in the target house?
Damn sure hope so.
Ci says that he's been
hanging with the occupants.
Bailey's deployment with
the national guard ends soon.
It's all I could do to get her to extend
so she stays safe outside the country.
All right, let's get this done.
Overwatch counts four occupants,
but there could be more.
Three male, one female.
Photos are being sent to your devices.
These are violent criminals
all looking at three strikes,
so they're not gonna go down easy.
We won't have air support
given our proximity to the airport
and overwatch's field
of view is imperfect,
so let's make sure we
communicate out there.
Any questions?
Yeah, sergeant. Sorry. Lieutenant.
All good.
I'm still getting used to it myself.
Why don't we have a fixed perimeter?
Our targets have known
associates in the neighborhood.
We don't want them raising the alarm,
so our perimeter will
roll in at the last minute.
We good? Now let's get ready.
Hey.
You up for this?
No shame being in the second wave.
No, I'm good to go, sir.
Ok. Mount up.
Is our boy up yet?
Haven't seen him.
He was hitting it pretty hard last night.
Cops!
Go, go, go.
Officers taking fire in
the primary entrance.
One officer down.
We are evacuating through the a side.
Everyone else hold.
Do not advance through
the primary doorway.
Over here!
Get in.
Runner! I'm going in. Cover me.
Gotcha.
Control, Bradford and chen making entry
bathroom window, east side.
Be advised. Potential blue-on-blue.
Repeat. Blue-on-blue.
- Ready?
- Yep.
7-Adam-15. Foot pursuit.
Female raid suspect heading
south towards bellanca.
No, no, no, no, no!
I need you to back up! Back up!
Ma'am, police.
I need to commandeer your ride. Thanks.
Sir! Damn it.
I lost sight of her.
Control, this is chen.
We have one suspect in
custody, east bathroom.
We're advancing through the house.
Outside officers be advised,
we are still downrange of fire.
Blue-on-blue. Will
advise when we're clear.
Yeah.
Police! Show me your hands!
On your 6:00.
Cuff him.
I give up.
Get down! On the floor!
Any sign of Jason?
Negative... we haven't
finished clearing the house yet.
Police! Hands!
Show me your hands!
- Where's Jason?
- I don't know.
You got one shot at
telling us the truth here.
I swear, I-I don't know. I never met him.
Stay down, stay down.
Hey.
Gimme that arm.
Hands.
- You ok?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
- I'm good.
How the hell did you get here before me?
Work smarter, not harder.
Come on, get up.
Are you sure you're all right?
Yeah, yeah. Like I said, code-4.
7-Adam-15. Fourth suspect in custody.
Code-4.
Copy. House is secure.
All suspects in custody.
No sign of Jason.
Damn it.
I'm just saying it's not a great idea
to show up your to at a workout.
A, I did no such thing.
B, it's my first day in short sleeves.
I got to make sure the
gun show is popping.
I see.
So you're planning on
flaunting your superiority
over the new incoming rookies?
Not at all.
I plan to be a welcoming presence
as a veteran member of the fto program.
What?
A veteran member of the fto program.
You are still a rookie.
You still got to sit in the front row
with the other newbies.
Why you got to be such a hater?
It's in the job description.
I'm so nervous.
You nervous?
That's stupid. You don't get
you don't get nervous.
Not getting and not showing
are two different things.
Can't let them smell fear, dude.
They'll eat you alive,
so you got to walk the
walk no matter what.
Why aren't you ready yet, boot?
Roll call starts in ten.
I... we... I am getting ready, sir.
Sergeant, sir... sergeant, sir!
Let me make this easy for you, boot.
Don't bother lacing up.
You don't belong here.
Better to quit now than be
embarrassed out on the street.
- Something funny?
- No, sir.
I got mad respect for
a real-life drill sergeant.
Many aspire, but few
live it, as you so clearly do.
Morning!
Are these the academy's finest?
Negative.
These two are scraped
from the bottom of the barrel.
A fainting goat and a peacock.
Well, welcome to the
crucible, gentlemen.
I look forward to learning your
names if you survive the week.
Hey.
- This doesn't look fun.
- It's not.
The only downside
about making lieutenant
is now I'm in charge of the patrol budget.
And I have two new
rookies starting today
and only one available training officer.
Well, what about smitty?
Anyway, this is why you're here.
I used my new rank, pull some strings,
and got you an interim promotion to p3.
Wow, I... that's very kind, but,
but your goal is to work undercover.
I know.
This is short-term.
Helping me out of a jam.
Hey, I'd owe you.
And this will only
strengthen your position
when a detective slot opens up.
Understood.
I-I'm honored you asked.
I won't let you down.
I know you won't.
Hey.
Sorry to interrupt.
You wanted to see me before roll call?
Officer chen is stepping up
to train one of our new rookies.
Good choice. She had
an excellent teacher.
Well, was it the teacher or the student?
Ok, I don't know what this is,
but I need to finish up the
paperwork before roll call.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, sir.
Seriously, if you need any pointers,
- don't hesitate to ask.
- Thank you.
But I'm very familiar
with your bag of tricks.
I'll be using a more modern
approach to train my rookie.
Cut the crust off his sandwiches,
making them feel supported?
My job is to set him up for success,
not push him to failure.
Care to put money on it?
On what? Who trains a better rookie?
No, thank you.
That's so
what exactly would
the terms of the bet be?
Whose rookie's
best-trained after a month.
Most successes, fewest infractions,
each day's reports
independently verified.
But I understand if you want no part of it.
I mean, I'm a veteran, you're a rookie to.
It's not really a fair contest.
Bring it on.
Hey, over here.
Celina juarez.
Rookies sit in the front row
and only speak when spoken to.
I've been here ten months
and I'm happy to show you the ropes.
Ok. That's awesome. Thank you.
Appreciate it, but I'm good.
I'm only technically a rookie.
Got two years of policing
under my belt back in Texas.
Well, that's... that's... that's amazing.
Good morning and congratulations.
- Welcome to the to team.
- Thank you.
So which one of you gets the ringer?
What? Ringer?
Yeah, the tall guy is from Texas pd.
Tim and I met him in the locker room.
Wow, what kind of
hustle are you running?
There's no hustle and he's no ringer.
Cops who transfer from other
states have to be untrained
and retrained from all their bad habits.
Honestly, I'm praying
grey gives me the virgin.
All right.
Good morning. Let's get started.
Detective.
Following up on yesterday's raid,
despite our winning personalities
and fearsome interrogation methods,
detective Lopez and I were unsuccessful
in gaining any further
insight into the whereabouts
of Jason wyler and Oscar hut chin son,
which means two of
the most dangerous men
we have ever arrested are still at large.
Now, luckily, the FBI
and the U.S. marshals
are both fully engaged in the hunt.
Given our continued fallout
from the mess Monica
and Blair London created,
Ada Wesley evers has been
assigned here temporarily
to make sure we're flying right.
Good morning.
I understand your
reactions, but it is vital
that law enforcement show the public
that we are taking this
corruption scandal seriously.
So while I'm not here to judge you,
I do have a mandate from the da's office
to review arrest reports and
ensure their completeness
and viability.
- Is that it?
- That's it.
Thank you, Wesley.
And if that wasn't enough,
we have two new rookies starting today.
Stand, state your name
and your badge numbers.
Hi, I'm... I'm Seth Ridley.
Badge number 6514... 651407.
Howdy.
Miles penn, badge number 653013.
Two-year veteran of
the sugar land, Texas
police department.
I've known I was destined
for greatness my whole life.
But I wasn't gonna find it in a small town,
so I came to Hollywood.
Officer penn.
Did I ask for an editorial comment?
No, sir. That was free of charge.
Well, thank you.
Keep your comments to yourself, son.
Or you'll be finding greatness elsewhere.
Am I clear?
Yes, sir.
Now, you both earned
the right to be here,
but you have to prove yourself to stay.
- Understood?
- Yes, sir.
Good. Officer penn, you're
assigned to sergeant Bradford.
Officer Ridley, you'll be
riding with officer chen.
That's it. Be safe out there.
Just as I expected. You got the ringer.
- Hi.
- Hey.
Hi. This is gonna be a
pleasure, officer chen.
Nice to meet you. Let's save all that
until you get the war bags and
we set up our shop, all right?
- All right. Yes, ma'am.
- All right.
Is it too late to ask for a to swap?
Get your eyes off officer chen, Texas.
You're not fit to breathe the same air.
Go get us set up.
After all the peacocking you've displayed,
I'm expecting perfection.
I'll be grading you on a serious curve.
- What?
- Nothing.
I'm just liking my chances right now.
I heard you got booed in roll call.
Who am I hurting?
That's fine. I can take it.
And having my wife beat up the people
that are mean to me isn't
gonna win me any fans.
I'm just saying, I'll cut a bitch.
Nice of Metro to let
you use the liaison office.
Yeah, I need the privacy.
I still need to finish
reviewing the final recordings
of Blair London's therapy sessions.
So creepy.
Yeah, tell me about it.
All I feel is dirty listening
to everybody's secrets.
Especially when most are only guilty
of being humans in emotional distress.
Hey.
Any news on Monica?
Not since she evaded Interpol in Bolivia.
Why did you make me wait
so long to wear short sleeves?
Aaron got his way
earlier in his rookie year.
You had to earn 'em.
How is Aaron doing over
in north Hollywood, anyway?
He's settling in.
Happy that no one at the station
knows he was a patient of Blair's.
God, this is so freeing.
And clearly distracting.
Perhaps I need to reverse the privilege.
No, no. I-I've celebrated enough.
Whoa. On the right.
7-Adam-15.
Possible disturbance
at El adobe pharmacy.
Code-6 to investigate.
Come on, come on! Hurry!
I-I'm going as fast as I can.
7-Adam-15. We have a 211 armed.
Send backup.
Ready?
What are these back here? These oxys?
The big one, the big ones.
Powerful stuff, come on, powerful stuff.
Hurry!
Go, go, go, go!
You want to get shot today?
Nolan?
I'm good! Go!
- Get out of the car!
- My god!
Control, suspect just shot a victim
and fled north on
Kingsley in a gray vehicle.
Partial plate, Edward 2-3-9.
I need an ra for a
30-year-old male victim,
single GSW to the chest.
I got it. Just breathe.
It's very simple.
You know, my job is to
set you up for success.
But things move way
too fast out on the street
for me to coddle you. Yeah?
Yeah. I understand.
Just consider me like your sponge.
I'm eager to absorb all your knowledge.
All units, be on the
lookout for a gray vehicle.
Partial license plate, Edward 2-3-9.
Suspect is white male,
black shirt, brown shirt,
armed and dangerous.
Shots were fired, at least one victim.
Unknown condition.
Ok.
Officer Ridley, what's our follow-up?
Don't you want to
know distance of travel?
The time element.
- Right.
- Yeah?
Control, what is our
dot and time element?
- - Six minutes ago.
- South on garmond.
Which means he's
headed away from us.
No, garmond is north of us,
which means he's
coming in our direction.
Good. And he's probably
headed towards the freeway.
But the traffic's heavy
this time of morning,
so if we hustle... We
might just catch up to him.
You want to hit the lights?
Do y'all have license plate readers?
I assume you do, big city like this.
Yeah, we do. Where you going with this?
I'm plugging in the partial.
Request a real-time
search of this neighborhood.
It's ok, baby. You're gonna be ok.
My god, our daughter. She's at school.
Westside charter.
It's ok, it's ok.
Officer juarez and I will go pick her up
- and bring her to you, ok?
- Thank you.
- Her name is Nikki.
- Nikki. Ok.
- How bad?
- Bad.
Shot in the chest, pulse is spotty.
Something bothering you?
I just... there was a
moment inside the pharmacy
where I might have had
the shot, but I didn't take it.
You think this citizen
catching a bullet outside
is your fault?
No, I just couldn't tell if
if my background was clear,
and then it turns out it wasn't.
You didn't have confidence
you could make the shot?
No, sir.
I'm saying I wasn't
confident I had a clean shot,
and it turned out I was right.
Look, Nolan, we're in the
split-second decision business.
It's no use second-guessing
until we review the body cam footage.
Yes, sir.
You ready to go?
Yeah.
We need to pick up
their daughter on the way.
Thanks, Dr. London.
It feels good to finally be
able to unburden myself.
I'll see you next week.
Ok. No incriminating information.
Cleared.
I had that dream again, doc.
It was even hotter this time.
The things she did to me.
Seriously, this is becoming a problem.
I mean, how am I supposed
to work next to Angela Lopez
when all I can think about
is how much I want to...
Well, I think it's best if
we let your mom explain.
But what kind of accident?
Is my dad gonna be ok?
We hope so.
He has the very best doctors,
and we're going to be at the
hospital in just a few minutes.
All right?
Ok.
All units, 211 suspect plates recorded
heading west, 2100 block
of Lincoln ten minutes ago,
but the vehicle did not pass
through the next intersection.
That's just around the corner.
There's an alley on Lincoln.
Maybe he ditched the car down there.
My god. There it is.
Ok, focus, officer Ridley.
Do I park here or pull in closer?
We, we park here.
Why?
Because we can't see if the suspect
is in the vehicle or not,
so it's safer to approach on foot.
Correct.
7-Adam-19, I have eyes
on the suspect vehicle.
West Side of the alley,
2100 block of Lincoln.
Show us code-6 to
investigate. Send backup.
- Copy that, 7-Adam-19.
- Be careful.
All right. Tell me how we approach.
We have our weapons drawn,
we approach with caution,
we try to call out the driver.
If he does not respond,
then we can get a little bit closer.
Always make sure we
have an exit route available.
And we'll check the trunk on the way up.
It's an SUV. There is no trunk.
Don't just parrot
academy training, all right?
This is the real world.
Right. Yes, ma'am.
All right.
Control, can we make sure
that nobody comes northbound
to this alley in case there's fire?
Copy that, 7-Adam-19.
That's a good call.
Driver! This is the police!
Roll down your window
and show me your hands!
Show me your hands!
Do it now!
Watch your... watch your muzzle.
Sorry, sorry.
- Go this way.
- Ok.
I see the suspect.
Show me your hands!
He looks dead.
We can't know for sure.
Come this side.
I'm gonna open the door.
You grab his shoulders,
pull them out on three.
- Ok?
- Ok.
One, two.
Hey, do not get sick.
Ok.
Don't puke on him.
No.
Damn it.
Ridley, you just
contaminated the crime scene.
Sorry.
7-Adam-19, 211 suspect in custody.
We need ra for possible od.
Must have been jonesing for a fix
when he robbed the pharmacy.
Pulled over to dope up as
soon as he thought it was safe.
On the bright side, taxpayers
save millions if he kicks it.
We never root for a
suspect to die, officer penn.
Yeah, totally.
I-I'm just saying
finally, a little action of our own.
Reported stolen early this morning.
Pull up close and I'll shoot out the tires.
I'm kidding, man.
Ooh, that hurt.
Ok, what... police! Show me your hands!
Show me your damn hands!
He's running!
Get down! Show me your hands!
You should have waited.
That was all bad, Texas.
Strike one, you jumped out the car
while I was trying to communicate.
What if I was trying to tell you
I saw a gun or a second suspect?
Strike two, you ran out
in front of my field of fire,
so I couldn't engage even if I had to.
And strike three, by going
to that driver's side alone,
you left an escape route
out the passenger side.
And don't even get me started
on your little "shoot
out the tires" comment.
It is now a permanent part of this case.
That may not sound like much now,
but wait till a civil Liberty
attorney hears about it.
Might be writing this
kid checks for years.
All right, as punishment
for being a cowboy,
you're checking every
vin on that stolen vehicle
to make sure it matches.
That'll take hours, sarge.
It's sergeant Bradford, not sarge.
You're way too eager to get in trouble,
so I'm slowing you down.
Back out.
Wait. Why? What is that alarm for?
Back out!
Every department garage
has a geiger counter.
This car we brought in is radioactive.
12 hours ago, a suitcase nuke
arrived on a naval cargo ship
from Eastern Europe.
It's a cold war relic from Ukraine
that got turned over for demolition.
A secure convoy was
meant to take it to Oklahoma
to be decommissioned,
but the nuke went missing
at the port sometime before dawn.
How the hell does that happen?
That's what we've
been desperately trying
to figure out, along with who took it
and what the hell they're
planning on doing with it.
And you didn't think to inform the LAPD?
There's been a lot of
pressure to keep this quiet,
not to panic people.
I argued against it,
but the decision was
made up the food chain.
You're with us.
Go study your rook book.
Close that.
A battlefield nuke was stolen
from the port this morning.
And the og backpack
runs about 80 pounds,
making it highly mobile.
What do you know about
the stolen car's owner?
Paul scoville, 31, rent-a-cop at the port.
Recently divorced.
I assume money problems,
but I can't confirm
till I pull his financials.
Any idea where he is now?
No. Called his house, his
cell, haven't heard back.
But I just found out
he's a person of interest
five seconds ago.
I'll have the office work on the warrants.
- Known associates, too?
- Absolutely.
We are gonna piggyback
the whole menu on this.
Home, phone, storage lockers, po boxes,
and the same for all known associates.
Anyone we can establish
a clear nexus with.
I'll mobilize hrt.
Can you get Metro
and SWAT up to speed?
- Of course.
- Good.
We're gonna need to
get ready and gear up,
because when it is time to move,
we are gonna need to move fast.
Copy.
Hey.
They officially called
time of death at 1329.
Right.
Write that down.
And they still have to do an autopsy,
but it seems pretty clear
it was an overdose, so
listen, about earlier.
No, look, I get it.
It's your first dead body.
All those fluids, it got to you.
But we have to protect the scene.
Yeah, no, I... I
yes, we got to protect the scene,
but it's not that simple.
I... this is not my first od.
I had this girlfriend back
in junior year of high school,
and I found her after prom
in a bathroom at Rory hatcher's house.
And... She had her eyes
rolled back, you know,
and
she wasn't breathing,
so I tried to give her cpr,
but
I couldn't get the taste of
her sick out of her mouth
for like two days.
And I can still taste it if I...
I
I wasn't being a delicate
flower out there today, ok?
It all just came rushing back.
And I promise it's not
gonna happen again.
Seth, that's awful.
I'm sorry that happened to you.
But in this job, we have to
separate from the personal.
It's the hardest thing we have to do.
Because if we lose control,
bad things happen, right?
Understood.
Right over here.
Any news?
Husband died on the
table a few minutes ago.
She doesn't know yet.
Man, that's rough. Why
haven't they told her?
We asked them to wait a beat.
We need to take a statement,
and she'll be in no condition
to give us one when she knows.
I mean, it just seems wrong, you know,
to keep the news from her.
Yeah, and waiting another ten minutes
isn't gonna make it any worse.
It's grey. Yes, sir.
I'm here with special agent garza.
We have a situation
that's not for broadcast.
A battlefield nuke is at large.
Small yield, but high dispersal.
We need you and officer juarez
to go put eyes on a suspect's house
while FBI and SWAT mobilize.
Address to your box.
Yes, sirs. On it.
- What's happening?
- Nothing good.
Detective Graham, right?
Yes, sir.
You're the hall monitor
from the da's office.
I'm actually thrilled you're here.
Anything you can do to
improve on patrol's paperwork
is a lifesaver.
You work with my wife, Angela Lopez.
Yeah.
She's amazing.
Sure you already know that.
Yeah, I do.
I have to admit I didn't
think you guys would last.
I always thought she'd end up with a cop.
And yet here we are,
happily married, two kids.
Well, you must be doing something right.
A little more.
Right there. Perfect.
How you doing?
I'm fine.
If you want to talk
about anything... I don't.
I'm just saying if it was me,
I'd be beating myself
up, wondering if there was
anything I could have done differently
inside the pharmacy.
And I said I'm good.
Right, no. Yeah, you did.
But if I was going
through that self-doubt,
what would you say to
me as my training officer?
Well, I would say that the
whole benefit of experience
is to learn from each incident,
both victories and mistakes.
So if the situation ever happens again,
it'll be a win.
It's a brutal job to
have to learn as you go.
Contact.
It appears there's
been a little falling out
between nuclear thieves.
We have to intervene, right?
Even though we're
just meant to observe?
Well, it depends.
As harsh as it may sound,
if that man is dead,
he's just evidence now.
Ok, well, what if he's alive
and needs help and
we don't do anything?
What's the plan?
Well, we can't go in there guns blazing.
We need those guys alive
in case the nuke isn't here.
So stealth and surprise.
What are you wearing
under that uniform?
Hello? I need your help.
Please.
- What?
- I lost my dog.
We were jogging.
He pulled the leash out of my hand.
It's a brown labradoodle.
Have you seen him?
No.
Can I... can I check your backyard
just to make sure he
didn't get back there?
No. I'm sorry.
Police! Show me your hands.
We got two in custody.
Scoville's in the tub.
He's still breathing, but he
needs an ambulance asap.
Nothing, boss.
There are no traces of
radiation in this house,
so the nuke isn't here.
It never was.
So we are gonna have ourselves
a long, hard conversation.
You're wasting your breath.
I ain't talking.
That's fine.
Better you listen for the moment anyway,
because what you choose to do next
will decide the rest of your life.
Paul scoville is clinging to
his life at Saint Stephens.
So as of this moment,
there's still a path to immunity for you.
We can hang the charges on your crew,
give you a golden ticket to a new life.
But we need names and
a location for the device.
I told you... shut up!
You have literally five minutes to decide
if you are gonna be part of the solution
or go to prison as a domestic terrorist.
You think he'll flip on his guys?
He has to. There's no other option.
How's it going with your cowboy?
Great. How's the virgin?
Great.
Celina's doing great,
too. Thank you for asking.
Is it always this intense?
No.
Well, kind of.
That's the point, though, right?
If you prove yourself here,
you know that you're the best.
I... it's not really like that.
For me, I... I... I just
want to help people.
Aries, pisces?
- Yeah.
- How did... how'd you know?
Well, it's a... it's a gift.
Everything ok?
What?
No, just you have a
pained look on your face.
Just checking to make sure
you're not having a heart attack.
No, no, no. No, I'm fine.
I'm fine.
It's just I'm an officer of the court.
I can't violate the confidentiality
that I've been entrusted with.
And that's the
the cornerstone of the
legal profession, really.
No matter how much you
want to unknow what you know,
you can't, it's just there, always.
Every time you close your eyes.
Hey, they need you in interrogation.
Nuclear guy's ready to talk,
but they need you to sign off on the deal.
Right.
Crew leader's Marcus Leonard.
He's holed up in a rental in west la
with Evan ardle and leshawn wilkes.
That's where the nuke is.
We're waiting to rendezvous
with a buyer in the desert.
Outside of Vegas.
But you better hurry.
They're on the move
in less than an hour.
Eyes are in the sky. Radio
on scrambled channel.
Be advised, license
plate camera captured
suspect vehicle heading east
on Wilshire boulevard one minute ago.
That's east on Wilshire boulevard.
How come I got to sit next to nuke?
It doesn't matter who sits closest.
Radiation is the same for all of us.
Minor.
I still don't like it.
$10 million payday's gonna
get you past that real quick.
Can I get mine in crypto?
Heads up.
Suspect vehicle spotted
west on Wilshire boulevard
heading for the freeway.
7-Adam-100 two blocks away,
heading northwest on olive.
What are our rules of engagement?
Don't shoot the nuke.
7-Adam-19, five blocks away,
heading south on figueroa.
This seems unreal. Was
your first day like this?
No, I saved my tos life
after he got shot during a firefight.
This is a walk in the park.
All right, 7-Adam-15
on an intercept course.
- There he is.
We're busted. Get
us the hell out of here.
Hey, secure that thing!
FBI unit 1, joining the pursuit.
Watch out for that car.
I see it.
Ok, we're turning here on hope street.
Go, e, come on!
7-Adam-15, two more units
attaching to pursuit three blocks out.
Suspect vehicle heading
east, entering lower grand.
I know we're not supposed
to shoot the device,
but how do you feel
about us crashing into it?
And I'm the cowboy?
Well, in theory, it's stable
enough for an outside impact,
but the thing's 60 years old, so
yeah, that... that sounds like a no.
Hang on.
Bail out!
Bring the nuke.
No way.
Three shooters.
Cover us.
Go!
Two shooters running off.
- Get up!
- Got him, got him.
Shooter down.
Penn, slow down!
Clear the truck.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Get down, get down.
Go.
Stay down.
Ridley, pull her in.
I got you cover fire.
Reload.
Why ain't they shooting at us?
It's a nuke.
They don't want to hit the nuke.
Officer down.
Hey, here. Hold on.
7-Adam-15, shots fired.
We have an officer down,
requesting ra at my location.
Get up.
Get up!
The hell you doing?
Shut up.
Back off!
Back off or I'll blow us all up!
You want to be a cowboy?
I will level this place!
On your knees now!
Nice shot, officer Nolan.
Thank you, sir.
Code-4, all suspects in custody.
Man, that
you think tomorrow's
gonna be any quieter?
Not now that you jinxed it.
Looks like you survived the day, boot.
Yeah, sir. Sergeant, sir.
Any blemishes? Don't lie to me.
I will find out.
No, just a small incident
when officer chen and I
found the carjacker od'ed,
I just puked in the vehicle.
Dude.
I wouldn't be so quick
to judge, officer penn.
You almost got a blue page
for your reckless behavior this morning.
Yes, sir.
I truly appreciate your leniency.
Don't mistake it for kindness.
You remain on very thin ice.
Yes, sir. See you tomorrow.
Unfortunately. Try to suck less.
Will do.
How's lieutenant life treating you?
I love the pay bump.
Just wish it came under
better circumstances.
What do you mean?
I just can't help but to feel guilty
because I got rewarded
for exposing the corruption scandal.
Lot of cops got fired.
Yeah, well, they deserved it.
So you deserve this promotion
no matter how it came about, ok?
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
Just doesn't seem right.
We saved the city,
and our reward is
sitting in rush hour traffic.
Got to love la.
Hey.
Heard your guy puked
all over a crime scene.
Well, at least he didn't
light his duty manual on fire
and throw it out the window.
Shoot out the tires?
He's a little rough around
the edges, but it's day one.
I'll get him under control.
Likewise.
So wait, since they both screwed up
yeah, I guess it's a draw.
Tomorrow's a new day.
Yes, it is.
Well, I will see you tomorrow.
Look forward to it.
Good night.
What?
It's nothing.
If you want to fool around, just ask.
No.
I mean, of course I do.
It's just... it's just what?
You're happy, right?
In this moment, I'm sleepy
and a little concerned about
whatever this conversation is.
But in general, yes, I'm very happy.
Ok, good.
So do you want to fool around or not?
I mean, if you're offering.
Hey, it's me.
It's like 5:00 in the
morning where you are,
so I'm glad you didn't pick up.
Miss you.
Hard day.
Would have been nice to snuggle up,
have you tell me I did a good job.
Anyway, just got home.
Hope you're having a
good time being a soldier.
I love you.
You did a good job today.
Yeah, that was weird.
Damn it.