And, good morning, Dallas.
Ron Chapman on KVIL.
We've got a gorgeous morning
working outside.
Temperatures at 8:OO A.M.
Standing already at 68 degrees.
We expect them to go up
to 75 degrees this afternoon.
[Crash]
Ow.
Ugh.
oh!
ohh!
Get his ass out
of there,Jo Bob!
l ain't touching
no faggot.
Faggot! Give me five.
Get out of there.
Let's go hunting.
l ain't going
hunting.
What? Come on!
Get up!
No! Get out of here!
We just want to kill
a little something.
Yee-haw!
Hot damn.
See that old cow
out there?
Want to see her run?
Oh, Christ,
they're shooting at cows.
They're too drunk
to hit anything.
Don't worry
about it.
Man, they're just crazy.
Oh, my God!
Do you know something?
Hmm?
l can't figure out
how l dropped that turn-in.
lt happens.
No, not to me
it doesn't.
Jesus Christ, you caught
the game-winning pass.
Relax.
Enjoy yourself.
lt's a pretty day.
Man, l had that ball
right in my hands.
l just couldn't
hang on to the damn thing.
John Heny, the man
is just like you--
He's never
satisfied.
Hey, l'm gonna dump
these suckers up here.
Gee whiz.
Goddamn, the marines
have landed.
[Bugle Blares]
Come on out!
Surrender, you suckers!
Ha!
Come on, O.W.
Don't want to wake
them fuckers up.
Elliott, where's
your gun, man?
Freud says guns are an extension
of your dick,Jo Bob.
That son of a bitch.
Ha ha ha.
He's a regular wise ass,
you know that?
Hold up, O.W.
B.A. wants me
in his office tomorrow.
Must mean l'm
going to start, huh?
l doubt that.
What the hell
you mean?
l made some
great catches.
They can't keep me
on the bench forever.
You'll never get
off that bench
till you stop
fighting them suckers.
You gotta learn
how to fool them, man.
Give them what
they want. l know.
l've been fooling
them bastards for years.
If you start pretending
to be somebody else,
that's what you're gonna end up,
bein_ somebody else.
Damn it, if l didn't
like you, boy,
if you didn't have
such great hands,
l'd keep
my mouth shut
and watch you go
right down the tubes.
l'm gonna
tell you something
for your own good.
You better learn how
to play the game.
And l don'tjust mean
the game of football.
Hell, we're all
whores, anyway.
We might as well
be the best.
There's one!
Goddamn it,Jo Bob,
you crazy son of a bitch!
What happened?
Jesus Christ!
We damn near
got the bird.
Didn't you see?
[Loud Disco Music Playing]
Go! Go! Go! Go!
[Cheers And Applause]
All right, let me
have that TV.
1 3. Look for 1 3.
Yep, l'd rather face
Pittsburgh's
defensive line
than one of
Peter's parties.
Somebody's got to
do it, though.
Hey, it's all yours.
Go for it.
Hey, big guy.
Good game, baby.
Tony, good game,
my man.
Howdy, howdy.
Hey, Seth,
great game, boy.
Hey, mama.
Hey, Maxwell!
Hey, Seth!
Man: Hey, Phil.
Hey, Peter.
Where's that dolly
you promised me?
He's ripped tonight,
ain't he?
Hey,Jo Bob,
what will you do
against Alcie Weeks
in Chicago?
Know what l mean?
Crazy guy!
Hit me.
Hey,Jo Bob,
l got a great
dolly for you.
She's last year's
Miss Farm Implements.
Come on this way.
She's from S.M.U.
and she's almost a virgin.
Help him
to relax, honey.
He needs, uh,
understanding.
Show 'em your
finesse,Jo Bob.
Hey, Billy Joe!
l've never seen
titties like yours.
l swear to God,
l never have.
They're beautiful.
Hey,Jo Bob,
how you doing?
How you doing,
Elliott?
Can l show your titties
to my buddy O.W.?
Can l? Would you?
All right! O.W.!
O.W.! Come here!
Ooh,John Heny,
don't get so excited.
We got all night.
Who's John Heny?
Ha ha ha.
He's an old friend
of mine.
Did you girls ever ty
a quarterback sandwich?
Sounds good
to me.
Seth, l need
to talk to you
about that condo deal
down at Padre Island.
Not now, Steve.
Hey, you ever drink
a pink poontang?
lt'll get you high.
Say, Phil!
Phil!
Great catch, boy.
Great catch.
l've got some
ostrich boots
and some lizard.
l'll get them for you
after l change my shirt.
Alan, l'll be with
you in a minute.
Got to go change
my shirt.
Hey, Phil.
Oh, man, we were
just leaving.
Hey, Eric.
Hi, Susie.
Hi.
Susie wants to get home
and put Audrey to bed.
And it's almost time
50I The Osmonds.
Why don't you come over
Wednesday night for dinner?
Look, guy, come on over.
Fitch and his wife
are coming.
Afterward, Susie's gonna
read some scripture.
uh, I...
Oh, man.
Maybe we'll all
take turns or something.
Hmm.
All right,
l'll ty hard.
Yeah.
See what you
can do.
All right, Sue.
We got plenty.
All right?
Hey, how you doing?
Hey, Billy.
See you later.
Being a little
hard on yourself, Andy.
Yeah, l know.
See that stewardess
over there?
Which one?
That one, there.
Goddamn, does she
get off on football.
Alan got some tit from
her the other night
just by showing her
that little bruise
on his calf.
l figure if she
gives up some tit
just by showing her
a bruise,
once she sees
this blood here,
she might give up
the whole thing.
Know what l mean?
Uh-huh.
l'd love to sit here
and talk, but l can't.
l got to test Balford's
theory of erotica.
Check you later, baby.
He's real intelligent,
ain't he?
Baby.
You like that?
Come on, Andy,
l'm with her.
Andy, l'm with her,
l said.
lt's nice to see
there's a little romance
Ieft in the world.
lt's an old story--
boy meets boy.
Well, l love
happy endings.
Oh, really? Good.
Now we can sit back
and wait for the
real obscenities.
You mean it gets worse?
lt definitely
gets different.
See, alcohol
and fear
makes for a good
combination.
fear?
Mm-hmm.
What are they
afraid of?
Falling on their
asses in Chicago.
Who are you,
and what are you
doing here?
Charlotte Calder,
and l'm asking myself
the same question.
l'm Phil Elliott.
l'm supposed to be here
to take you away
from all this.
Oh, yeah. See,
l'm a very funny guy.
The newspapers call me
the team funnyman.
Obviously you can't
believe evey thing you read.
l'm sorry.
l'm not very good
at this
small talk stuff.
ln fact, l learned
all my social graces
from football coaches,
so just give me
another ty, huh?
OK, team funnyman.
You've got
fantastic eyes.
Hilarious.
[Scream]
Hey, quit pushing
On me, man.
Put me down!
Why can't somebody
stop him?
What, are you crazy?
Look at him.
No!
Please put me down!
Jo Bob's here
to remind everybody
that the meanest
and the biggest
get to make
all the rules.
l don't agree with that.
Agreement doesn't
enter into it.
O.W .
Aah!
How can you
tolerate that?
l make allowances,
then l get ready,
and l run like hell.
That's what l like--
A man of courage.
Miss?
My name's Jo Bob.
Charlotte:
Please let me pass.
l love your hair and
your nose and your legs.
Put me down.
You know l love
your legs.
Please put me down.
l want to fuck you.
l really do.
Will you put me down?
Will you let me go?
Aw, no.
Jo Bob: l'll be nice
to you, understand?
l won't let anybody
take you away from me.
What are you so fussy
about, lady?
Piss off, Elliott.
Hey, Seth!
Seth!
Find something for Jo Bob
to do with his hands.
Hey,Jo Bob.
l told you to
piss off, Elliott.
Let her go.
Shit!
Aah!
Jo Bob, goddamn it.
Who the fuck are you
giving orders to?
Hey,Jo Bob.
l'm going to
kill you.
He's just tying to keep
that dolly from raping you.
Jo Bob, it's me, Seth.
Come on, man. Relax.
lt's a party.
Come on,Jo Bob.
Calm down, baby.
Why's he always
making fun of me?
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Yaa!
Hey, l know you.
You had your chance.
What the hell are you
tying to prove,
taking on Jo Bob
over some chick?
For Christ's sake,
Seth, shit.
Seemed like a good idea
at the time.
A good idea?
l need Jo Bob, son.
l want him up.
l want him feeling
like he can climb
the Empire State
Building.
You may keep me
on the sports page,
but he keeps me off
the obituaries.
Where the hell
would l be
with Jo Bob's confidence
destroyed?
Goddamn it, son,
what did she expect?
These girls know
what happens
at these parties.
That's why they
come here.
She didn't seem
like that to me.
Just lay off
Jo Bob, all right?
l want you both at your
best Monday night.
Oh, for Christ's sake,
l didn't hurt Jo Bob.
Damn it, quit
aggravating him.
Let him have
what he wants.
What he wants?
What about
what l want?
He's a baby,
for Christ's sake.
Don't put yourself
on his level.
Rise above it.
Come on, let's go
get in a pile.
mw,
it's the same
old pile, Seth.
Shit, l'm going to get
knee deep in it, son.
Go ahead, partner.
See you tomorrow.
Yep.
[Doorbell Rings]
Hi.
Hello.
l'm glad to see that
you're still alive.
Thanks for letting me
run like hell.
lt's too bad l don't
take my own advice.
Yeah.
Can I come in?
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Can l get you
a drink?
Yeah, you got
any whiskey?
l only have milk.
Yeah, l love milk.
Good.
Nice place
you got here.
Oh, thanks.
Are you married?
Was.
Mmm, yeah,
so was l.
Do you work?
No.
What's this--alimony?
Oh.
You talk a lot,
don't you?
No.
Hmm.
You look terrible.
Thanks. That really
builds up my confidence.
Why did you go to
that party, anyhow?
l don't know.
l thought it
would be fun.
Obviously
l made a mistake.
Hmm.
l'm tired.
l'm really
tired.
l'm sorry.
l was lonely.
l just needed
someone to talk to.
Well, you can't
sleep here.
Thanks for letting
me sleep here.
No, l--l said
you c_n't sleep here.
Hello?
Oh, shit.
Yeech!
[Snoring]
Hi, Peggy.
Hi, Phil.
l've got a meeting
with B.A.
Yeah, just a minute.
Phil Elliott's here.
[Elevator Bell Rings]
You know, Phil.
There's not one damn
corporation l own
that means as much to me
right here
as my football team.
Come on.
Made a hell of a catch
on Sunday.
That's just,
uh, luck.
You know, Phil,
there's one thing
l learned early on in life.
The most important thing
a man can have.
What's that? Money?
Luck.
Luck tells me
something about a man.
lf my people are lucky,
they tap into a big field.
lf not, they can have evey
geology degree in the world
and drill one dy duster
right after another.
Take me.
l'm the luckiest man
in the world.
Sure as hell
ain't brains, is it?
Phil, there's always
a place in our little family
for the right
kind of man.
Mm-hmm.
Now Phil...
people who confuse
brains and luck
can get in a whole
Iot of trouble.
Seeing through
the game
is not the same
as winning the game.
lt's gotten to the point
where's Phil's
almost predictable.
l can know what
he's going to do--
[Door Opens]
Hey, Phil,
how are you doing?
Hey, Emmett. B.A.,
l'm sorry l'm late.
Why don't you all
stay in my office?
l got to see Connie
for a minute.
Thank you very much,
Emmett.
See you later, Phil.
Sit down.
That's it, Phil.
What it all boils down
to is your attitude.
And another thing,
l know you don't like
sitting on the bench.
You're a team member.
You have to adjust.
Actually,
l have know players
that got used
to sitting on the bench,
if that's possible.
lt's not.
You're too proud?
l want you
to listen to something.
The apostle Paul
in one of his letters
to the Corinthians said,
''When l was a child,
l thought as a child.
l spake as a child.
l understood
as a child,
but when
l came to be a man,
l put away
childish things.''
Hmm.
And there's a theme
that runs through
all this data.
lt's immaturity,
your immaturity.
You lack
seriousness.
l scored five TDs
coming off the bench.
That's pretty serious.
You scored five TDs?
Don't you know that
we worked for those?
We planned for them.
We let you
score those touchdowns.
B.A., l've always
given you 1 OOOx.
1 OOOx!
You're talking about
individual effort.
Yes, you give that.
l don't deny it.
That's not what
l'm talking about.
l'm talking
about a team.
about a winning team.
A winning team is
45 finely meshed gears
working together
in perfect
synchronization.
If one of those gears
flies off on its own,
l'll pull it.
And if that's
not straight enough,
l'll say it
a different way.
If you want
to play football for me,
you have to change,
starting right now.
Ahem.
B.A., l'm sorry if my
immaturity has offended you,
and l'll honestly
ty to change...
but l've been a starter
for six years,
and it's hard
to sit on the bench, but...
l'll wait my chance.
And when
you do start me,
l'll make you
glad you did.
l appreciate that,
Phil...
and we'll see.
Hey, Phil, how
are you doing?
You know
Joanne Rodney.
Phil Elliott.
Oh, my gosh.
Wait a minute.
Ruth, you got
that contract?
l want you to see this.
lt's a contract for our
number-one draft choice,
wide receiver
out of Lubbock,
a real good one here.
So, l, uh...
Gosh, l guess
next year you'll be...
Do you speak
Canadian at all?
Emmett, you've been running
these guys at me for years.
[Doorbell Chimes]
Come on.
Now, goddamn it,
Joanne--
Oh, wait. Ow!
God! That's my--
That's my
sore shoulder.
Which one?
That one, the one
you always hurt.
Oh,Jesus! My knee. Ohh.
Your left knee?
No. What do you mean,
my left knee?
Ahh! Phil!
What do you mean, Phil?
Come on.
Ow. Ow.
Ow. You always
hurt me,Jo.
B.A. wants me to adjust
to sitting on the bench.
Hell, l'll die
on the bench.
What's the sense
of the team winning
if l don't survive, huh?
You'll survive.
Really?
You know what l do?
l pull for the other team,
so we'll get behind
and B.A. will have
to put me in.
That's weird.
Why don't you
just quit?
Well, what would l do
that wouldn't be
the same or worse?
lt's the only thing
l know how to do good.
Best hands in the league,
you know.
Phil,
do you love me?
Sort of.
What kind of
an answer is that?
Well...
it's the only kind of answer
l know how to give
when somebody l really like
needs to know the truth.
Hey, how long
you been awake?
Couldn't sleep.
You know, you don't
Iook too good.
Maybe you ought
to take some vitamins.
l don't need
a healthy body.
l do it all
with my mind.
Yeah?
l've been ignoring the fact
that l'm falling apart.
Say,Joanne...
Mm-hmm.
Where's the pictures
of yourself you cut out?
Hmm?
Well, that girl just
doesn't exist anymore.
Oh, so Joanne Rodney
Well
in that case,
it kind of
Iooks like you.
Uh, what do you
want for breakfast?
l'll have whatever
you're having.
Well, l'm having
chocolate pudding.
Uh, wait a minute,
Joanne.
Uh, wait a minute.
How about
some bacon and eggs?
Don't have any bacon.
How about some eggs?
Mmm, nope.
Toast?
No butter.
Dy toast
or chocolate pudding.
l'll have
chocolate pudding, then.
l only have one,
but l'll share it
with you.
Really? It's
a great meal then.
Let's go.
Come on, feed me.
Well, l'm going
to do it.
Good.
Give me some more.
No, seriously.
l'm really
going to do it.
Do what?
Mary Emmett Hunter.
Come on, what do you want
to mary Emmett for?
He's nothing. It's just
gonna screw up your life.
When l told him l wanted
to keep the apartment,
and he said l could.
You'll come by
and see me, won't you?
lf l can.
l got to get through.
Hey, cheer up.
Everybody gets married
now and then.
Yeah, but l thought
you'd draw the line
at joining the family.
Yeah. Me, too.
Mm-hmm.
But look at it
like this--
With me
in the Hunter family,
you won't have to learn
to speak Canadian.
We boring you,
Douglas?
Fall asleep again,
it's $ 1 OO fine.
OK, 3rd and 8.
All right!
The things l do for love.
No. You should never
have thrown to Elliott
with that kind
of coverage.
Look at Delma there.
He's wide open.
l don't like
this buddy-buddy stuff
interfering
with my judgment.
Shit. You can't win
for losing around here.
[Laughter]
Run it back, run it back.
That's it, Stallings.
Real good.
Stallings, what were you
thinking of here?
l'm...l'm
not sure, sir.
You're not sure.
No, sir.
The entire game riding
on this one series of downs,
and we have a player
who's not sure.
There's no room in this
business for uncertainty.
No room.
Shit. Here it comes.
Here's where
you screwed up.
l didn't screw up.
You changed the play.
l didn't
change the play.
You brought it in.
l did not.
Just cover for me.
l'd like all of you
to watch this
next play carefully.
Especially you.
Especially you, Elliott.
Great catch.
Yeah!
All right!
Whoo!
Now, Elliott,
how would you
describe this play?
Well...
l'd say we
scored a touchdown.
Oh, you think it's funny!
Well, l fail to see
any humor at all.
Maxwell changed the play
that l sent in,
Elliott broke his pattern,
and the catch
was a fluke.
There's no room for flukes
in winning game plans.
Why do you think that
we go over and over
the printouts
of a game plan?
Because deviating
from that plan
can cost us
a championship.
lf there's some of you
who aren't interested
in being champions,
well, then you laugh.
Relax. Have a good time,
but you'll do it
on somebody else's
football team, not mine.
The key to being
a professional
is consistency,
and the computer
measures that quality.
No one of you is as good
as that computer.
l hope l'm understood.
Now, everybody on the bus
in 1 O minutes,
except you, Stallings.
l'd like a word with you
in private, please.
Hey, let me have
those shoes.
That's cold, man.
Hey, baby.
Do you believe
they cut Stallings?
Who's Stallings?
Runner's
run-pass-49-right.
Sounds
real important.
Look at it.
On two.
Ready?
Break!
4-3, number 2-zone.
Ready? Break!
Stunt left!
Watch
the running back sweep.
l got it.
Hut! Hut!
Coming in, coming in!
Coming in!
Whoo!
Douglas!
The reason
we drafted you
was because they said
you were fast and smart.
At this point
l'd be delighted
if you'd be at
Ieast one of those.
Yes, sir.
Carney, get in here
for Douglas!
Back in the huddle!
Hey, Douglas.
lsn't this
the kind of day
you'd rather be by a fire
with a good book?
Fuck you, faggot.
Promises, promises.
Set!
Hut!
How's an old fart like me
supposed to keep up
with a dedicated, young
Christian stud like Hartman?
lt's discouraging.
lt's like you told me.
You got to cheat.
l wrote the book
on that, hoss.
l believe it.
Elliott!
Get your ass
in here!
Coming, boss.
Red-right-74.
You're going to get
yourself a fine,Jo Bob.
lt's worth it.
You got it?
Yes, sir.
On three.
Ready? Break!
Hut!
2-49!
Check!
2-76!
Hut!
Ow!
Ahh! Goddamn it!
Goddamn it!
Ahh!
Hold it.
Oh, goddamn it!
Pull them out.
Don't move,
don't move.
Pull it!
Pull!
You all right?
Which one?
Christ,
which do you think?
Elliott!
That's what comes
from not concentrating.
Yes, sir.
Amazed at how these
young fellows
can take the punishment
of their profession.
Hello, Monsignor.
Oh, hello, Phil.
You're a very brave
young man.
That's real devotion.
You remind me of the
magnificent missionaries
of history.
Never thought
of that, Monsignor.
Come on, Elliott,
stop dogging it!
That's fine.
Run this here
Chicago pass pattern.
Red-right-74.
Look at it.
Here we go.
On 2.
Ready? Break!
Come on, snap it up!
Elliott,
get in there!
Brown-left.
Set!
Hold it!
Carney, get in there!
No!
Douglas in, please.
Carney, get the hell
out of there!
Let's go.
Here we go.
Set!
2-75!
Check!
2-72!
Hartman! Hartman!
Let's just get
the ball snapped!
You're giving me
a fucking headache!
Rookies.
High schoolers.
Let's go.
A bunch
of high schoolers.
Set!
Hut!
Are you all right, man?
Hey, Phil,
you all right?
You OK?
Yeah, l'm all right.
Wait--wait--wait--
wait a minute.
Help me up.
There's your hat, man.
Nice catch.
Yeah.
Now, that's
concentration, Elliott.
Feels pretty swollen.
Let's work that knee.
Goddamn it, Eddie,
it's not the knee.
l hit my shoulder
when l hit the floor.
lt feels like
it's full of gravel.
lt's always felt like
it was full of gravel.
Give me a B-1 2 shot.
That's what l want.
Always messing
with my knee.
How you doing, baby?
Fine. You going
to get a shot?
No shots for me, turkey.
l can't stand needles.
You got to master
the game's technology.
How do you do that?
Take those pills
and shots, man.
Does terrible things
to your body.
If you last long enough,
you'll realize
the only way to survive
is the pills and shots.
Not me, turkey.
l got respect
for my body.
You'll get past that.
You're crazy, too.
l'd appreciate it
if you could finish up
with butter fingers
and give me my
B-1 2 shot.
l got an important
business meeting.
l found two boys
from Oklahoma
that want to invest
in my restaurant business.
Oklahoma?
That's right.
That figures.
Once the first one
starts making money,
then you sell franchises.
That's where
the big money is.
What are you gonna
call the restaurants?
Jo Bob's Fine Foods.
Do you like it?
That's right.
Jo Bob's Fine Foods.
Eat here
or l'll kill you.
Ha ha ha!
You son of a bitch!
We're not going
to have trouble here!
Come on,Jo Bob!
Jo Bob!
Go on to your
meeting now.
You goddamn bird turd!
Get out or l'll
report you to B.A.
You would?
You bet your ass.
You're chicken shit.
Get out of my face,
Monroe.
lt always did take
two of you
to hold one of me.
Excuse me.
Too damn much B-1 2.
[Door Opens]
[Rummaging Noises]
Back off, asshole!
Back off!
I ain't moving!
Jo Bob loves you.
God almighty!
Damn, shit!
God.
lt's the tooth fairy.
Fuck you, tooth fairy.
Ha ha ha!
Oh, shit.
l hope l don't look
as bad as you look.
You make me look like
Cinderella, asshole.
lf l had a dog
like you,
l'd shave his butt and
make him walk backwards.
Old Doc Elliott's
gonna take care of us.
lt's time to break into
the old medicine cabinet.
How's your elbow?
Goddamn it,
Elliott!
Eddie's going to get
your ass for this.
Yeah, but they won't
do nothing to you.
l ain't the one
that's doing it.
You're going
to take some.
They turn me in,
they got to turn you in.
They won't do that.
That's 'cause
l'm a star.
Genuine
sports personality.
A legendary folk hero.
Folk hero,
have some Dexedrine.
Don't mind if l do.
A little Compazine.
Would you like Codeine?
Does a shark shit
in the sea?
Give me
some of this.
One for me.
That's the breakfast
of champions there.
Nectar of the gods.
Yes.
You know something?
You're
the only guy l know
that's got an uglier
body than mine.
Bullshit.
Ha ha ha!
John Heny,
why do we abuse
ourselves this way?
Hey, Seth.
Have you ever
Ioved anybody?
You know,
Ioved somebody.
Aw, last night.
All-time show stopper,
SOn.
l don't want
to hear this.
All-time show stopper.
You know Jery Drake?
Drake?
Big Tex
Automotive Supply?
l know that asshole.
lt was his YMCA team
that me and Hartman had
to talk to last night.
l gave them my usual
bullshit.
Football, character
development, all that crap.
Hartman comes up
with this story
about Jesus being captain
of a football team.
And the apostles each played
different positions, right?
Whoo!
And Judas
was the coach.
Nope,Judas
sold the playbook
to the devil's team.
Oh, God.
Wait'll you hear
this part.
Drake invites me
and Hartman
to his house
for a drink.
Now,
l got the wheels,
so Hartman's stuck
with me, right?
Anyway,
here's the point.
lt turns out Drake
wants to watch
while me and Hartman
do nasty things
to his bouncy-bottomed
little wife.
Aw,Jesus, Maxwell.
Really.
Hey, l know.
lt's not your
type of thing.
But l'm more
of a philosopher.
l like to mingle
with the little people.
What about Hartman?
You know Hartman.
Goody two-shoes
is fidgeting around
like a one-legged cat
tying to buy shit
on a frozen pond.
Until Seth fixes him
a couple of pink
poontang specials.
The crazy tourist drink
that l fix
for stewardesses.
Two shots out of that,
and Hartman
is shot to shit.
Freaked out.
l never saw a guy
having so much fun
and crying
at the same time.
l don't believe it,
but l'm getting horny.
Aha!
Wait'll you get
to this part.
Drake takes out some
of them fake dicks.
Aw, Max, that's gross.
That's not gross.
Gross is when you kiss
your grandpa good night,
and he sticks his tongue
down your throat.
Anyway, he's got one
that's about
8 inches long.
lt's pink and it's got
crinkledees in it.
lt's got a grinder
that you turn like this.
lt goes in and out--
l don't want to hear
any of this.
l'm getting
to the weird part.
The weird part?
Yeah, it gets weird.
OK, who did it?
He did it.
ls that right, Seth?
Did what?
The medicine cabinet!
lf B.A. finds out,
it'll be somebody's ass.
Your water's too hot.
Calm down.
The man
was desperate.
Think of it
as an emergency.
l suppose you stood there
and watched.
No, he held me down
and made me swallow them.
This shit
has got to stop.
And leave my goddamn
beer alone!
Elliott,
don't you piss in there.
Ahh.
Bastard.
Did l call my wife
Iast night?
l don't
think so, son.
What do l tell her?
Tell her you escaped,
and you don't have
to pay the ransom.
l can't tell her that.
Ha ha ha!
Dream up the wildest
thing you can think of,
and lay it on her.
She'll go for it,
coming from you.
Yeah?
l'm right.
Why do l smell
like strawberries?
What'd you do
Iast night, Poot?
Grrr!
Come on,
what'd you do?
Well, l'll tell you.
l had a date
with Charlotte.
Oh, shit.
l hope you're not
getting hooked
on that chick.
Breaks
your concentration.
l'll tell you something.
The only thing l haven't
broken is my concentration.
Why do we do it,
partner?
Well, the only way
to find that out, man,
is to quit.
You're not thinking
about quitting.
l'm thinking l'm tired
of beating myself up.
Don't worry.
You'll get tired
of thinking.
Coca-Cola, Poot.
Throw me an RC,
Seth.
She believed me.
Of course
she believed you.
Who wouldn't
believe you?
But l'm--
You did the right thing.
Lying can be really good
for a relationship.
Hey, Art.
Welcome
to the big leagues.
You know, l'm getting
to like the pain.
Huh?
Remember when
l busted my elbow?
Oh, yeah.
l knew it was
dislocated
the second
it happened, man.
When l was
Iaying there,
yelling, flopping
all over the field
in front
of all those people,
you know
what l felt?
Ohh.
Satisfaction.
Yeah. l mean,
it made me feel
like l was doing
something important,
you know?
Yeah.
When the pain
got the worst,
that's when l felt
the most...
SeCUre.
Yeah, l hear you.
l hear you.
The answer is no.
No, what?
l ain't never
Ioved nobody.
[Phil Grunting]
[Joints Popping
And Cracking]
[Crowd Roars]
Good morning.
Did you sleep well?
Yeah, l slept great.
Settle down
and listen up.
l want some asses
kicked this week.
Douglas, that's a $ 1 OO
fine for being late.
l want you guys to study
Chicago's tendencies.
If you ain't ready
by Monday night,
they're gonna run
down your throats
and out your assholes.
Whoo!
Ooh!
And there'll be
a written test on Friday
on these tendencies.
Coach.
Those of you
whose names appeared
on the bulletin board
are invited to
Mr. Hunter's home tomorrow
to help Conrad Jr.
celebrate his birthday.
Be there at 1 2:OO sharp,
appropriately dressed.
Now, before we break
into our separate groups,
there are a few
general comments
which l am obliged
to make, gentlemen.
We won a game Sunday
against an opponent,
measurably and on paper,
inferior to ours.
ln doing so,
we managed to play
far below our potential.
Our punting team gave them
4.5 yards per kick--
More than
our reasonable goal
and 9.9 yards more
than outstanding.
That's not the kind
of football
conference champions play.
Offense--four turnovers.
Five scoring
opportunities blown.
3rd down conversions
we failed six times more
than our seasonal average.
Pass completions were 490x.
That's 6.30x less
than reasonable
and it's 1 90x less
than our outstanding.
That is a negative 1 90x
against Seattle!
Now, clearly,
it's time for us
to take a long,
hard look at ourselves,
and in this connection,
Coach Johnson has
prepared some material
which l trust will be
beneficial to you.
Johnson.
Thank you, Coach.
Now, listen, you guys.
If we can take
an extra moment here,
l'd like to read something
that B.A. thinks
is pretty important.
When l was playing
college ball at Maryland,
l found this
taped to a locker.
l think you'll understand
what it means.
Means he's out
of his fucking mind.
lt means that the difference
between good and great
is that much.
That's the same size
as his pecker.
lt comes
from right up here.
[Coughing]
Something wrong,
Elliott?
No, sir. l had something
caught in my throat.
l can't think of anyone
who can use this advice
better than you can.
Yes, sir.
Excuse me,
Coach Johnson.
Thank you.
''If you think
you can't win, you won't.''
Right.
''If you think
you're losing...
you've lost.''
All right!
''If you refuse to strive
to the limit,
the limit's as far
as you'll go.''
Right, sir.
''Give in
to the fear and pain--''
Talk about
the pain.
Shut up, Delma.
This ain't exactly
no revival meeting.
You want something
with me, Monroe?
Hey, cut it out,
you guys!
l'm sorry, Coach.
l couldn't--
Go ahead, sir.
''If you give in
to the fear and pain,
there are thrills
you'll never know.''
That's right.
''We have all been
put here by God
as a test of
our courage and faith.
The rewards
to his warriors are many.
The rewards to
the losers--disgrace.''
''Some say winning's
not evey thing,
that competition
has a limited place.
But if that cowardly
slogan is true,
why did God name this...
the human race?''
Good question.
Coach,
would it be OK
if Jo Bob and l
had a couple copies
of that poem?
Jo Bob: Yeah,
we'd appreciate that.
That has to be
one of the most
inspiring poems
I ever heard,sir.
Yeah. l'd like one,
too, Coach.
Yeah.
Me, too, Coach.
Brown noser.
Yeah. Pussy.
1, 2, 3, 4,
5, 6, 7, 8,
9, 1 O.
Hold it!
We count during
this drill, Elliott,
and you didn't count.
We're going to do it
over again,
and you can thank Elliott
for the extra work.
Team:
Phil, Phil, Phil,
Phil, Phil, Phil!
All right.
Knock that shit off!
Let's go!
Let's finish up
with 1 O jumping jacks.
Ready? Exercise.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5,
6, 7, 8, 9, 1 O.
Let's break up
into your groups.
l wasn't really counting,
l was just moving
my lips.
You son of a bitch!
Let's see if you
can catch one.
Look at Phil.
About time
you caught one.
How are you?
Hey, Emmett,
how are you?
Thanks for
inviting me.
Yeah.
Sorry to hear
about your daddy.
Thank you.
That's the only fight
he ever lost.
When a man
of your daddy's wealth
dies of cancer,
you know they haven't
found a cure.
Let's go!
Come on.
Come on, Delma.
Coach: l'll tell you
if you got hurt.
Easy, easy.
What is it?
lt's my hamstring.
Did you feel it tear?
No. l heard it pop.
Take him inside.
Give me a hand.
Coach: l seen better
hands on a clock.
Oh, shit.
Back to the tub
again, huh, Delma?
Let's go
to team drill--
Chicago defense.
Elliott, get back
with the first unit.
If you moved slower,
you'd be going
backwards.
Very funny, Elliott.
Very funny.
One more game and we
take our division.
That's what makes it
all worthwhile.
Christ, Con.
You make more
in your manufacturing
division in one week
than this damned football
team makes in one year,
even if they do win.
That's true,
but my manufacturing
division never got
the cover
of Time magazine.
l'm going all
the way this year.
The big one.
The Super Bowl.
No question
about it.
The money isn't
evey thing.
You ought to be
ashamed of yourself.
lt's either pulled
or torn.
We'll know more
tomorrow.
Can you get him
ready for Monday?
Set!
Hut!
Next play. Next play.
Break it up.
Come on.
Shit!
Give Jo Bob
some work in there.
3-22.
Hut! Hut!
[Whistle Blows]
You son of a bitch.
Jo Bob, is that how
you're going to hit
in Chicago.
Goddamn it,Coach!
We're supposed to be
doing this half speed.
l don't want excuses,
just results.
If you ain't ready,
Weeks will tear off your head
and crap in your neck.
All right.
Same play, let's go.
3-22.
Asshole.
Hut!
Jo Bob, get your head
out of your ass.
Son of a bitch!
Bring it up
to full speed.
All your teammates would love
a live scrimmage.
Let's do it again,
and do it right.
Get your fucking ass
back on the line.
Fuck you, asshole.
Huddle up.
You cocksucker.
Your mama was
the best teacher.
They're
fired up now.
Oh, yeah. They're
going to ream Chicago.
That's enough.
OK. Break it up.
Break it up.
OK, OK.
All right, gentlemen.
All right.
Everyone at the airport
at 1 O:OO A.M. tomorrow.
Elliott, l'd like
to see you, please.
Walk with me, Phil.
How's the knee?
Great. Feels
real good.
You're limping.
That's just habit,
but, uh, feels good.
Phil, l'm going to
need you in Chicago.
Delma's pulled
his hamstring again,
and you know Delma.
He can't stand pain.
He'll say
it hurts too much,
but he doesn't like
to use the needles.
So...
can l count on you,
Phil, and your knee
for the entire game?
B.A., you can always
count on me
to do whatever
it takes to play.
Hell, l love needles.
l guess that's what
we call maturity.
Huh?
Yeow!
lt's beautiful.
Yeah, really...
really beautiful.
Come on. Let's
go into the house.
OK.
lnto the living room.
Ah, through the wall.
Yeah.
All right.
Now...
uh...um...
uh, this is
as far as l've got.
How long did it take you
to get this far?
Oh, about uh...
three years.
Anyway, l got 20 acres,
and it runs
along that gully,
and it goes
back in that valley.
Oh, God,
it's magnificent.
Yeah. That's where l'm
going to have the horses.
l think you should
finish it though.
l am going to finish it.
Ta-da!
Made with
my own fair hands.
Oh, great.
l'll get the wine.
Get the salad.
OK. Excuse me.
Well, excuse me.
l need all the room here.
You've got
all the room.
What are we going
to do about napkins?
Use the toilet paper.
Oh, Chic.
Chic.
Listen, uh...
do you think
this raising horses
is just a dream of mine?
l don't know. Maybe.
lt doesn't
seem very real.
Yeah?
Come on.
Hey!
You like burned steak?
Hey,
you know something?
When l'm with you,
my mind's
a million miles
away from football.
l feel free.
Sounds like you're
tired of football.
Well, if l was,
l wouldn't admit it.
That would scare
the hell out of me.
Here, you
want some wi ne?
Yeah.
l'm scared to death
most of the time anyhow.
Scared of what?
Of injury,
of playing badly,
anything that can knock
me out of the game.
You don't act like it.
Yeah. l don't dare.
You know, someday
you will be out of it.
Then what?
Oh, come on, Charlotte,
that's serious.
l don't want
to get into that.
For Christ's sake!
Let's don't
talk about football.
l'm starting Monday.
Everything in my life's
just great.
We got any butter?
Well, l don't think
it's great.
You know, l saw you
the other night.
You were in so much pain
you couldn't sleep.
Your body's
twisted and scarred.
You're
drugging yourself.
Hey, listen, that's just part
of the game, Charlotte.
Game?
You call men smashing
each other a game?
For Christ's sake!
You can't judge!
You live in a little house
secure with your Texas money,
what the hell
do you know about it?
You live
in an unreal world!
lf football's
the real world,
l don't want
any part of it!
lt scares me.
Well, good.
It's not your life.
lt's mine.
Come on, let's eat.
Why don't you
build your ranch
instead of
dreaming about it?
Maybe l like it better
as a fantasy.
The payments are lower.
And you accuse me
of living in a dream world.
Look, l got to keep
my mind in the game.
l don't want
to get confused now,
so drop it!
Why don't you
watch the game?
l'll do something
special for you
in Chicago.
Hey, Eddie, give me
a match, will you?
Hey, Phil,
what's happening?
What are you doing
here early, man?
l got butter_ies.
l couldn't sit
around the hotel.
Where in the hell
is Jo Bob and O.W.?
They were in a cab
right behind me.
l told you boys
when you got special
taping to do,
get to the stadium early.
Maybe l ought to
start getting here
the night before.
Come on, Frank!
What are you doing?
We got an important
ball game.
You tape
my left ankle first.
You tying to
put the hex on me?
You old fart.
l'll tape that knee
after the doctor checks it.
You don't look
healthy at all.
Yeah. l hurt myself.
l'll catch you later.
Have a good ball game.
Yeah. You, too.
Oh, yeah.
Jo Bob,
this is it, babe.
This is what
we want.
What are we
going to do?
We're going
to kick their butts.
We know how
We'll do it very roughly,
with no respect.
We're going
to do it.
to get them!
We're going
Yes.
l mean Weeks now.
Where's my locker?
Get your jock on, babe.
Phil, what is it?
The knee.
The knee, huh?
Let's have a look.
Tell me when.
oh!
Ah ah ah ah.
X marks the spot.
Hey, baby, you going
to make it tonight?
l don't think so.
We need you, man.
Yeah. Frank, can l
get this hot packed?
You got it, babe.
Hey, is this it?
Here?
Yeah, that's it.
Hold on.
Come on, Delma,
lift it up.
No? Tell him.
OK.
OK, here we go.
Ooh,Jesus.
No, wait a second.
Just wait a second.
Say when.
All right. Not yet.
Goddamn it!
Jesus, it burns.
Goddamn!
Christ, how often
do you put this shit
in the coaches' hearts?
There.
Whew.
Now that wasn't
bad, was it?
Oh, no.
l loved it.
There.
Now ty it.
How does
it feel?
lt's numb.
Good, good.
lt's a brand-new
knee, Doc.
Better football
through chemistry, huh?
Hey, Delma,
using the heat, huh?
You must
be feeling better.
No, Coach,
it feels real bad.
l don't think
l can make it.
Come on,
you saw Elliott.
He was hurting, too,
but he has the guts to do
what it takes when we need him.
lf l shoot up
l could hurt myself
real bad.
l don't mess
with needles.
You don't feel
anything.
l could tear my
hamstring to bits.
lsn't it time you thought
about the team?
Now you listen, Delma.
You can't make it
in this league
if you don't know
the difference
between pain and injury.
Hey...
l'm just tying to help.
Fuck it.
Come on, you guys.
Stop playing grab ass
and get ready.
l want to hit somebody!
Use some of that.
Hit somebody!
l want to hit...
hit...
Give me some,
too, man.
That's good.
When Weeks starts
Iooping over the middle,
what are you gonna do?
l'll stay at home.
OK, no problem
there.
That's right.
You know who that is?
That's Alcie Weeks, baby.
He's ugly.
He's the ugliest man
l ever seen,
and l don't want
none of his ugly
rubbing off
on my pretty face.
All right.
Knock his cock in
his watch pocket,Jo Bob.
All right.
l want him walking
on his elbows
in the morning,Jo Bob.
He will.
What you going
to do to him,Jo Bob?
He'll be eating him up
all night long.
My man.
You'll be eating
his ass up.
Just like white
on rice,
you'll be sticking
to him,Jo Bob.
l'm going to get him.
We're going
to do it.
All night long,
Jo Bob.
They say
he's the best.
He ain't the best.
He's nothing.
You can be the best.
You are the best.
lt's time
to get down.
Let's pad up, man.
Get down.
Let's get ready now.
All right.
You ready?
Let's pad up.
Where's my locker?
Right behind you.
Hey, Hartman,
while you're at it,
why don't you ask the man
about the point spread?
Pussy.
Well, all right.
No wonder they call it
The Windy City.
Hey, baby. Cook.
Save some for the party.
You've got a face
like a baby's butt.
Thank you, Seth.
Beautiful.
OK. Wait a minute.
l'm going to get
the bastard for this.
All right.
Mother clotheslined
me last time.
l'm going
to tear his ass up.
l lost 4 fucking teeth.
l'm going
to tear his ass up.
1 O minutes!
You ready, baby?
Alan,
l can't fumble.
You saw what they
did to Stallings.
Hey.
You'll be all right.
OK?
Give me a hit.
Ready?
Yeah.
Thank you.
Can't fumble.
Can't fumble
the football.
All right.
Have
a good game.
All right.
Let's go,Jo Bob.
Let's get them.
How's that,
Mark?
Little
more air, Keith.
Why don't you pump up his ass
and blow his brains out?
Up yours, asshole.
Fuck you.
five minutes!
How long, Coach?
Five--fuck you!
All right, settle down.
Listen up.
Out with the cigarettes.
Coach.
Just one reminder,
gentlemen.
Please remember
to take off your helmets
when they play
the national anthem.
Also remember you're
on national TV,
so don't pick your noses
or scratch your nuts.
Excuse me,
Coach Johnson.
Mr. Hunter would like to say
a few words to you now.
Thank you, B.A.
Men...
l want you
to win this game
for our fans,
for Dallas,
for me and
my little brother.
Not necessarily
in that order.
If we win
this game,
you're all invited
to spend a weekend
with your wives
and families
at my private island
in the Caribbean.
Bullshit.
And remember,
the eyes of Texas
are on you.
[Whistling]
Knock that
shit off.
Monsignor.
Dear Lord,
l ask your blessing
on these brave boys
as they venture
out to battle.
Take off your
fucking hats.
Sorry, Monsignor.
We ask not for victory,
not for glory,
not for fame.
We ask only
for the preservation
of our bodies
and of our minds.
Bless also
the entire Hunter family
who have so
unselfishly given us
evey thing
we need for victory,
except our efforts
in the spirit
of sportsmanship,
with Thy guidance,
Thy kingdom,
power, and glory
for evermore.
Amen.
- Amen.
- Amen
let's go kill
those cocksuckers!
Elliott?
Yeah?
l'm starting Delma,
but you stay up.
Be ready when l need you.
He said he's
starting Delma.
l heard.
But l thought--
l can't worry
about that now.
You
just be ready.
Sportscaster: With less
than two minutes left
this might be it
for North Dallas.
Chicago
Ieading 1 4-7.
North Dallas is
on the Chicago 25.
1 st and 1 O.
Second Sportscaster:
Nail-biting time for the fans.
But it it suck-it-up
time for the players
because they have
to score on this drive.
Seth Maxwell fakes.
Hands off
to Andy Melbourne
and he's down for
a three-yard loss
by Alcie Weeks.
They haven't kept
Weeks out all night.
He has been in that
backfield all day.
They should
give him a uniform
they way he plays in
the North Dallas backfield.
lt'll be a 3-yard loss.
The clock is running.
l wonder what
they're saying
as far as strategy
is concerned
in the North Dallas
huddle?
Jo Bob, when you get through
titty blocking Weeks,
why don't you
hit the fucker?
Why don't you
go fuck yourself?
Just hang on to the ball.
We'll take care of up front.
Fuck you, psycho!
Just get
the fucking ball
across the line
of scrimmage.
You're a pain
in the ass!
Shut the fuck up!
Nobody talks in this
fucking huddle except me.
Jo Bob, O.W.,
goddamn it,
l cannot
throw the football
with these guys
hanging all over my ass.
Fitch, l want
a wing-quick-burst.
All right.
Red-right-76 on two.
Ready?
Break!
Weeks, this time l'm fucking
going to kill you.
Hey,Jo Bob.
You're looking lousy.
You're getting old.
l hate to do it,
but l'm going to put
your dick all in the dirt.
Maxwell: Set!
4-48.
Hut!
Sportscaster: Maxwell's
in a shotgun formation.
He fades to pass...
what a rush by Weeks,
who dumps him.
The pass is off,
though.
Fitch, streaking down
the middle, is in the open.
Drop it.
The pass is no good.
Come on, Fitch!
Concentrate!
Are you OK, baby?
Hey, Weeks!
Sportscaster:
The clock is stopped.
And now an altercation
breaks out
on the field.
Sportscaster 2: l can understand
why tempers are a little hot,
because
the game's winding down.
Maxwell's asking
for a time out
although the clock
is stopped.
We've got less than
a minute to play.
Maxwell coming to
talk to his coach.
You have to think
now that Chicago
will drop back
on defense
and be in
a prevent defense
because North Dallas
to win this game
will have to keep
it in the air.
This is the last time out
that North Dallas has.
They're probably
figuring out strategy
that will allow them to run
3 or 4 plays in a row.
They have very little time left
if they're going to score.
Maxwell is signaling
to Phil Elliott
to come
into the ball game.
l'll go with Elliott
and Huddle as wide receivers.
And we're going to look
for some pass plays.
Having fun, boys?
Blow it
out your ass.
How's the leg,
Del?
Like your knee.
l can't
feel anything.
All right, huddle up!
Jo Bob, l ain't
Iosing this game.
l'm tired of Weeks sitting
on my face all night.
But
l hurt, Seth.
l hurt bad.
l don't give a shit.
We all hurt.
Let's trap
the son of a bitch.
O.W.,Jo Bob, break his
fucking leg if you have to.
l want him out of there.
All right?
Green-right-C-motion.
41 -trap-delay on three.
Ready?
Break!
Sportscaster: Maxwell brings
them out of the huddle.
You know Chicago's gonna
be coming on this play.
Let's see if they've
come up with a good play.
l wonder if Maxwell
called it or the coach.
Huddle lines up
on their left
and Maxwell
down under center.
The clock won't start
till the snap of the ball.
Huddle's in motion
to the right.
Back to pass
is Maxwell.
lt's a draw play
ball fake.
[Whistles Blow]
Jo Bob: Suck
on that, Weeks.
Sportscaster 2: Weeks,
the big defensive tackle
for Chicago is down.
This could be a serious blow
to the Marauders chances
if he is
out of the game.
North Dallas not only
gets a first down,
the clock
is stopped.
lt looks like he got
hurt in a trap block
by Jo Bob Priddy
and O.W. Shaddock.
Weeks had been beating
those two all night
and they finally
got back at him.
And a big first down
for North Dallas.
Jesus,Jo Bob, we
hurt him bad, man.
Fuck him.
Huddle up.
Huddle up!
Aah!
Let's tie it up
and take it into overtime.
Can you get the outside
linebacker, Phil?
Del, it's your chance
to be a star.
Red-lax-92.
First sound,
all right?
Ready?
Break!
Sportscaster 2:
North Dallas has the ball
1 8 yards away
from a touchdown
but they have only 24 seconds
Ieft in the game.
They have to score
if they're going to tie
this championship contest up
and send it into overtime.
Maxwell sends Huddle
and Elliott to the left
so they overload
Chicago's right side
on 1 st and 1 O.
Back to pass,
Maxwell.
And the pass is to
Huddle on the sidelines.
There's a flag down
and Huddle is hurt.
Oh, what a hit
from the secondary!
Let's check
the penalty marker.
The indication
from the official
is offensive holding
against the Bulls.
So instead of a gain
for Huddle,
it will be
a 1 O-yard penalty
against
North Dallas.
The play is erased.
Goddamn it.
Look at his face.
Fix his face!
Elliott!
Get up, Delma!
Get back
in the huddle!
The doctor
will look after him!
You get back in that huddle now
or off the field!
Ah! Ah! Ah!
Sportscaster: Let's look
at that play again.
Sportscaster 2:
This play was well set up.
Huddle takes a swing pass
from Maxwell.
He is wide open
when he starts down field.
But then he grabs his leg,
obviously in pain,
and Francis Chapman
Iays a massive blow on him.
There is no way Huddle will
make it back in this contest.
You should see
Delma's face.
Not now, Poot.
OK, let's get mean.
Let's stick it
up their ass.
Two plays,
back to back.
Red-right-76
and come back
with red-right-79.
Phil.
You throw it,
partner,
l'll catch it.
Both plays on 2.
Ready...
break!
Sportscaster 2: The Bulls
have got only 1 6 seconds left,
but they are 28 yards
away from the score.
Sportscaster: 1 st and 20,
as Maxwell sets them up.
The clock will start
when the snap is made.
Elliott is in motion
to the right.
Maxwell's back to pass.
He's going to Elliott.
lt's complete
at the 1 5-yard line,
but the clock
is running.
Good catch by Elliott,
but he didn't
get out of bounds.
They've got to hurry to get
another chance to score
before this game
is over.
5...
4...
3...
2...
they got
the play off.
Yeow!
Yeah!
Yeah! Yeah!
Great catch!
Yeah!
You're my
ace in the hole.
Nice pass.
Sportscaster: North Dallas
has a chance to tie it.
And Prejza, the outstanding
kicker, is in there.
Sportscaster 2: North Dallas
couldn't have the ball
in any better hands
in this case--or feet
because Prejza has kicked
43 straight extra points.
That's a new
North Dallas record.
They're calling him
'' Mr. Automatic.''
There's the snap.
The ball gets away
from Hartman.
lt's on the ground.
Chicago recovers.
The game is over.
The Chicago Marauders
have held off
the North Dallas rally
to win 1 4-1 3,
and what a finish.
That snap seemed
right on the money.
Hartman just
couldn't control it.
What a shame
for North Dallas
after making such
a dramatic comeback
in the last few seconds.
An agonizing defeat
for North Dallas.
They thought they had
the ballgame tied.
They felt overtime
was upcoming.
And the Chicago
Marauders
have won
the championship
by 1 point.
How's Delma?
He needs surgery.
Hey, Elliott.
You looked pretty good
out there tonight.
You played good.
l wish we could say the same
thing for you,Jo Bob.
You should've studied
Weeks' tendencies.
l thought l did.
You don't listen.
We would've won if we'd
studied those tendencies.
Aw, shit!
You never
give us anything
to bring in the game
except your fucking
facts and tendencies!
To you, it's
just a business.
But to us,
it's still a sport.
You're supposed
to be professional--
We work harder
than anybody to win.
When we're dead tired
in the fourth quarter,
winning's got to mean
more than just money.
You were hired
to do a job!
l don't want
no fucking job!
l want to play
football, asshole!
l want some feeling!
l want some fucking
team spirit!
This ain't no high school.
You don't have to love
each other to play.
That's what l mean,
you bastard.
Evey time l call it a game,
you call it a business.
And evey time l call it
a business, you call it a game.
You and B.A. and all
you other coaches
are chicken-shit
cocksuckers.
No feeling
for the game at all.
You'll win,
but it'll just be
numbers on a scoreboard.
Numbers, that's all
you care about.
That's not enough
for me.
l don't have
to listen--
Oh, yes, you fucking do!
You got to listen
to me for once!
All you coaches are
chicken-shit cocksuckers!
Goddamn you!
Far out.
Hartman: For...
[Grunts]
Hey, Del,
how you doing?
Hey, come on, man.
You'll be back.
Um, um...
[Sobbing]
Come on. Hey, Del.
Come on.
You're going to be back.
Come on, huh?
Come on.
Whoa.
Good boy.
Hi.
Are you all right?
Yeah.
Just slightly damaged.
Look, um, l'm sorry
about the other night.
l had no right,
no right at all.
You had a right.
You see the game?
Yeah.
See the catch l made?
It was terrific.
l'm sorry you lost.
l thought l was going
to start that game.
Hell, l even
shot up my knee,
but they weren't going
to let me start.
They were using me
to get another ball player
to deaden his leg.
God, that's awful.
Yeah. Well
that's the way 'it is.
But what's important
is my performing...
the moment of the catch,
that feeling, that high.
Hell
l can take th' e crap.
l can take
the manipulation.
l can take the pain.
As long as l get
that chance evey Sunday.
l think that this game
is twisting your mind.
The game's not twisting
my mind, Charlotte.
l know the game.
lt's the rules
they make up.
l'm going to play,
so l'm going
by their rules.
You can't separate
one from the other.
Yeah, but l can't buck
their system or fight them
any more than
you can drop out.
lf you've made up
your mind,
why did you
come to me?
'Cause l care
about you...
and l want
to see you again.
l've got a meeting
with Conrad Hunter.
Hell, l can't let him see
that the merchandise
is damaged.
Here. Let me help you.
Yeah.
You know,
when you think about it,
they're not worse
than anybody else, really.
Come in, Phil.
Come on in.
Hello, B.A.
Sit there,
Phil.
All right, Ray.
Mr. Elliott,
where were you last Monday
until approximately
8 A.M. Tuesday?
Uh, who wants
to know that?
l'm Ray March.
l'm with the league's
lnternal Investigations
Division.
On Tuesday of last week,
where were you?
uh...
now that, um...
l don't know.
You know that.
Why don't you tell me
where l was, huh?
No, no, no.
W-wait a minute.
Let me give you
a little hint,
'cause that wise-ass
attitude of yours
isn't going to get you
out of this one,
you understand that?
l think you'd best
answer, Phil, old boy.
All right.
Ruth, would, um...
would you send in
Mr. Rindquist, please?
Go ahead,
Mr. Rindquist.
l am Joseph Rindquist,
and l am a vice-officer
with the Dallas Police.
Off-duty, l work
for Mr. Ray March
investigating reports
of league misconduct.
One week ago,
l was instructed to
take up the surveillance
of Philip Elliott,
an employee
of the Dallas franchise.
l followed the suspect
from then
until he boarded the plane
for Chicago this last weekend.
And all this time l thought
l was just paranoid.
Rindquist: ''On Monday of this week,
at a party in a private
North Dallas residence,
the suspect was observed
near the swimming pool
in the company
of an unidentified
caucasian adult male.''
What do you mean,
''an unidentified
white caucasian male,''
for Christ's sake?
Didn't you recognize him?
Who was it
that was with me?
Didn't you
recognize him, huh?
Some investigator.
Continue, Mr. Rindquist.
''At this time,
the suspect
was photographed
smoking
a marijuana cigarette.''
Photo exhibit ''F.''
''Now, picking up the suspect
again on Tuesday,
l followed him
from these offices
to 261 2 Houston Drive,
where he remained
until morning.
This address
is the residence
of a woman named
Joanne Rodney--''
We don't need to bring
others into this mess.
Continue.
''A search of the suspect's
premises was effected,
uncovering a bag
of marijuana...
and assorted pills.''
You got this
from Mr. Elliott's house?
Yes, sir.
lllegal drugs
are forbidden
by the league rules, Phil.
You know that.
For Christ's sake--
Jesus, smoking grass?
Are you kidding me?
If you nailed
all the ballplayers
that smoked grass,
you couldn't field
a punt return team.
You give me harder stuff
in Chicago
just to get out of the
goddamn locker room,
hard drugs.
What's...
Continue.
Uh, photo exhibit ''H''
shows Mr. Elliott
in the company of a woman
named Charlotte Calder
as they leave
a county and western--
Jesus Christ!
You sleazy bastard!
Sit down
in that chair!
What do you think
you're doing here?
Who the hell
you think you are?
We treated you
pretty well.
We paid you
damn well!
Ty to earn
that much out there.
You're in
for a surprise!
l'll take care of this.
You're nothing but a
two-bit football player.
Calm down!
Let him talk.
You got anything
to say, Phil?
Nah.
Are you part of this,
B.A.?
Phil, you have the best
hands in football.
There's a lot more
to this business
than ability.
You're wrong,
because it is ability.
lt is what l can do
with these hands,
and that's why
l play the game.
lt's dedication.
lt's discipline.
lt's sacrifice.
You can't
take all the time.
You have to give something
back to the game.
For Christ's sake,
my nose is busted.
l can't even
breathe through it.
l can hardly stand up.
l haven't slept
more than three hours
at a stretch in two years.
lsn't that giving
something back?
There's pieces of me scattered
from here to Pittsburgh
on these football fields.
lsn't that giving something
back to the game?
Isn't it?
B.A...
how can you
take this away from me?
How can you do this?
OK, Phil.
Only now l
speak for myself.
And it's your
childish attitude.
You hurt the team.
Team?
They're the team!
These guys right here,
B.A.
They're the team.
We're the equipment.
We're the jockstraps,
the helmets.
They just depreciate us
and take us off their
goddamn tax returns!
That's what that is.
Yeah. Well...
l was good
when l played.
Because the only thing
that's real
in that game...
is me.
And that's enough.
Well, l feel
for you, Phil,
but you confused
Iuck and brain.
You betrayed me.
You betrayed my family.
l tried to warn you.
You violated
the morals clause
of your contract.
lt's that simple,
so, pending
a league hearing,
you're hereby suspended
without pay.
Yeah?
ls that what it is, Emmett?
ls that what this whole
charade has been about,
so you don't have
to pay my contract?
l don't need your money
that bad. l quit!
You are right, B.A.
Thank you.
lt's time to put away
childish things.
Things get ugly up there?
Pretty ugly.
My name come up?
Uh...
ahem.
There's no reason
to bring you into this.
They suspend you?
l quit.
l can't take it.
They want too much.
Too much ain't enough.
Not for them.
What you gonna do?
l don't know.
l'm going to go home.
l'm going to get
in bed with Charlotte.
l'm going to spend
a week with her.
l'm going to heal up.
l'll spend time with her
and take it easy.
Hoss.
Hmm?
l appreciate you keeping
my name out of it.
Uh, no sweat.
You knew about it.
You know evey thing,
don't you, Max?
That l do, Poot.
That l do.
Hey, Poot.
Yeah?
Got any of them
old pain killers?
You keep them, cowboy.
You're going
to need them.
Ahh.
Hey, Seth.
We really had them worried
in Chicago, didn't we?
Best catch
l ever seen, Poot.
Not a bad pass either.
Good luck on Sunday.
Hey, Poot.
Yeah?