1
00:00:40,000 --> 00:00:45,750
<font color=#EBE8D4>==果然电影小分队 荣誉出品==</font>

2
00:00:47,800 --> 00:00:55,800
<b><font color=#FFFFFF>☆☆☆</font><font color=#2A394F>果然字幕组出品 www.grimmfan.com</font><font color=#FFFFFF>☆☆☆</font>
<font color=#2A394F>白雪公主与猎人</font> <font color=#FFFFFF>Snow White and the Huntsman</font>
<font color=#2A394F>翻译</font> <font color=#FFFFFF>Sandy 歪子 Emily</font>  <font color=#2A394F>校对</font> <font color=#FFFFFF>小嗷 蘑里个菇 money 池塘</font>
<font color=#2A394F>时间</font> <font color=#FFFFFF>Sherly   </font><font color=#2A394F>后期</font> <font color=#FFFFFF>弥   </font><font color=#2A394F>压制</font> <font color=#FFFFFF>掠影 Eos   </font><font color=#2A394F>统筹</font> <font color=#FFFFFF>Sherly  </font></b>
字幕片源来自网络 仅供学习交流 版权归原公司所有

3
00:01:02,350 --> 00:01:06,700
很久很久以前 在一个严冬
Once upon a time, in deep winter,

4
00:01:06,850 --> 00:01:09,780
有一位皇后在欣赏飘落的雪花
a queen was admiring the falling snow

5
00:01:09,940 --> 00:01:13,410
她看到一朵玫瑰对抗严寒兀自绽放
when she saw a rose blooming in defiance of the cold.

6
00:01:14,650 --> 00:01:20,000
她伸手触摸它 却刺伤了手指 三滴血坠落
Reaching for it, she pricked her finger and three drops of blood fell.

7
00:01:24,370 --> 00:01:27,250
因为红色在白雪的衬托下显得如此绚烂
And because the red seemed so alive against the white

8
00:01:27,330 --> 00:01:30,930
她心想 要是我的孩子肌肤像雪一样白皙
she thought, "If only I had a child as white as snow,

9
00:01:31,000 --> 00:01:35,430
嘴唇像血一样红艳 头发像乌鸦的翅膀一样乌黑
"lips as red as blood hair as black as a raven's wings

10
00:01:35,510 --> 00:01:39,060
性格像这朵玫瑰一样坚强就好了
"and all with the strength of that rose. "

11
00:01:42,600 --> 00:01:49,400
不久之后皇后生了一个女儿 取名为白雪公主
Soon after, a daughter was born to the Queen and was named, "Snow White."

12
00:01:52,270 --> 00:01:54,400
整个国家都非常喜爱她
And she was adored throughout the kingdom

13
00:01:54,530 --> 00:01:58,950
无论是她的美貌 还是她敢于反抗的精神
as much for her defiant spirit as for her beauty.

14
00:02:30,150 --> 00:02:34,320
我们在树林里找到的 它受伤了 妈妈
We found it in the woods. It's injured, Mother.

15
00:02:34,980 --> 00:02:36,410
它肯定是折了翅膀
It must have broken its wing.

16
00:02:37,650 --> 00:02:41,580
- 别担心 它慢慢就会好的  - 我会照顾它的
- Don't worry, it will heal in time. -  I'll look after it.

17
00:02:42,410 --> 00:02:44,410
亲爱的 你的美非常珍贵
You possess a rare beauty, my love.

18
00:02:46,240 --> 00:02:49,500
它源自内心 永远不要失去它
In here. Never lose it.

19
00:02:50,330 --> 00:02:52,260
当你成为一个王后时 它会对你很有用
It will serve you well when you become queen.

20
00:03:01,590 --> 00:03:05,710
- 小心点别摔下来  - 我摘了个苹果 给你
- Be careful you don't fall.  - I'm just getting you an apple. Here you go.

21
00:03:06,050 --> 00:03:08,190
谢谢你 威廉
Thank you. William!

22
00:03:09,430 --> 00:03:10,940
威廉
William!

23
00:03:15,770 --> 00:03:18,570
下一个冬天是记忆里最难熬的
The next winter was the harshest in memory

24
00:03:18,740 --> 00:03:21,990
白雪的妈妈过世了
and Snow White's mother passed away.

25
00:03:23,280 --> 00:03:25,780
国王极其悲痛
The King was inconsolable.

26
00:03:26,240 --> 00:03:28,000
趁着他陷入悲痛
Taking advantage of his grief,

27
00:03:28,080 --> 00:03:32,250
一支黑暗神秘的军队出现了 诱使他打响了战争
a dark and mysterious army appeared and lured him into battle.

28
00:03:59,360 --> 00:04:02,410
- 这是什么恶魔组成的军队  - 把他们送回地狱
- What devil spawned this army? -  Send them back to hell!

29
00:04:02,820 --> 00:04:03,910
不留活口
No prisoners!

30
00:05:07,470 --> 00:05:12,930
黑暗军队被打败了 但接踵而至的将比之更加黑暗
The dark army was defeated, but what would soon come to pass was far darker.

31
00:05:13,100 --> 00:05:14,100
陛下
Sire!

32
00:05:20,440 --> 00:05:21,660
俘虏
A prisoner.

33
00:05:25,110 --> 00:05:28,580
不用害怕 我和我的人不会伤害你
Fear not, you will come to no harm from me or my men.

34
00:05:30,280 --> 00:05:32,290
夫人 您的名字是
What is your name, my lady?

35
00:05:35,290 --> 00:05:37,130
瑞雯娜 陛下
Ravenna, sire.

36
00:05:40,960 --> 00:05:43,560
国王被她的美貌征服
So enchanted by her beauty was the King

37
00:05:44,170 --> 00:05:47,350
使得他第一次忘记了心碎
that he forgot, for the first time, his broken heart

38
00:05:47,510 --> 00:05:51,890
就在第二天 她成为了他的妻子
and the very next day, she would become his wife.

39
00:05:53,270 --> 00:05:57,610
- 你真美  - 多谢你 孩子
- You're so beautiful.   - That's kind, Child.

40
00:05:59,350 --> 00:06:03,580
特别是当人们说你的容貌才是这个国家最美的
Especially when it is said that yours is the face of true beauty in this kingdom.

41
00:06:04,280 --> 00:06:05,320
过来
Come.

42
00:06:08,910 --> 00:06:10,410
这些对你来说一定很艰难
This all must be difficult for you.

43
00:06:11,280 --> 00:06:15,080
我也在小时候失去了我的母亲
I, too, lost my mother when I was a young girl.

44
00:06:15,250 --> 00:06:19,870
我永远不能取代你母亲的位置 永远不能
I can never take your mother's place. Never

45
00:06:20,080 --> 00:06:22,930
但是我感到你我心意相通
But I feel that you and I are bound.

46
00:06:26,090 --> 00:06:30,260
在这儿 我感受到了 你的内心
I feel it there. Your heart.

47
00:07:19,850 --> 00:07:22,150
你将会成为我的灭亡
You will be the ruin of me.

48
00:07:22,310 --> 00:07:24,910
是的 吾王
Indeed, my lord.

49
00:07:29,070 --> 00:07:32,740
我曾经也被一个如你般的皇帝摧残
I was ruined by a king like you once.

50
00:07:36,200 --> 00:07:41,880
我取代了她的王后 一个老女人
I replaced his queen, an old woman.

51
00:07:43,750 --> 00:07:47,880
不久后我也被取代
And, in time, I, too, would have been replaced.

52
00:07:49,760 --> 00:07:52,050
男人利用女人
Men use women.

53
00:07:53,800 --> 00:07:58,810
在玩够我们之后 他们便毁了我们
They ruin us and when they are finished with us

54
00:07:59,930 --> 00:08:04,060
将我们弃如敝履
they toss us to the dogs like scraps.

55
00:08:05,940 --> 00:08:07,070
你对我做了什么
What have you given me?

56
00:08:07,400 --> 00:08:12,540
当一个女人青春和美貌永驻 世界便由她掌控
When a woman stays young and beautiful forever, the world is hers.

57
00:08:15,410 --> 00:08:20,040
首先 我会要了你的命 吾王
First, I will take your life, my lord.

58
00:08:23,460 --> 00:08:25,960
然后 我将夺走你的皇位
And then I'll take your throne.

59
00:09:00,990 --> 00:09:05,130
- 欢迎 哥哥  - 我的王后
- Welcome, brother.  - My queen.

60
00:09:06,960 --> 00:09:10,630
她用诡计让她的幽灵军队将她带进王国
She had tricked her way into the kingdom with a phantom army.

61
00:09:10,800 --> 00:09:14,470
现在 她带来了一支真正的军队
She now welcomed a very real one.

62
00:09:51,840 --> 00:09:54,590
- 威廉  - 白雪 快出来 白雪
- William!  - Snow, get out! Snow!

63
00:09:55,170 --> 00:09:56,850
我不能离开
I can't leave!

64
00:09:58,220 --> 00:10:00,350
公主 不
The Princess! No!

65
00:10:00,890 --> 00:10:02,260
快出来 快走
Get out of here! Go!

66
00:10:13,070 --> 00:10:15,440
威廉 别离开我
William! Don't leave me!

67
00:10:15,610 --> 00:10:17,860
父亲 我们必须回去
Father, we must go back! We must!

68
00:10:18,200 --> 00:10:19,870
- 不  - 我们已经失去她了
- No!  -We've lost her!

69
00:10:20,030 --> 00:10:22,200
不 不 不
No! No! No!

70
00:10:23,700 --> 00:10:26,800
别丢下我 威廉
Don't leave me! William!

71
00:11:31,230 --> 00:11:32,400
出去
Out.

72
00:11:34,770 --> 00:11:36,450
出去
Out!

73
00:11:52,000 --> 00:11:56,840
魔镜 魔镜 告诉我
Mirror, mirror on the wall,

74
00:12:01,720 --> 00:12:04,470
谁是世界上最美丽的人
who is the fairest of them all?

75
00:12:42,670 --> 00:12:44,970
是您 王后
It is you, my queen.

76
00:12:45,510 --> 00:12:48,860
又一个王国败倒在您的荣光之下
Yet another kingdom falls to your glory.

77
00:12:50,520 --> 00:12:55,490
您的力量和美貌永无止境
Is there no end to your power and beauty?

78
00:13:07,620 --> 00:13:11,120
剩余的人 我的王后 你要怎么处置他们
The remnants, my queen. What do we do with them?

79
00:13:14,210 --> 00:13:16,000
都杀了
To the sword.

80
00:13:19,460 --> 00:13:20,840
芬恩
Finn.

81
00:13:24,550 --> 00:13:26,520
把她关起来
Lock her up.

82
00:13:26,590 --> 00:13:31,390
没有人知道什么时候会变得有价值
One never knows when royal blood may be of value.

83
00:13:46,860 --> 00:13:50,040
瑞雯娜的统治如此狠毒
So poisonous was the reign of Ravenna,

84
00:13:50,200 --> 00:13:54,000
世风日下 人心不古
that nature turned on itself and people turned on each other.

85
00:13:54,160 --> 00:13:59,420
生灵涂炭 民不聊生
The land died and with if, hope

86
00:14:00,500 --> 00:14:04,430
一直以来 她将白雪公主囚禁
And all that time, she kept Snow White imprisoned

87
00:14:04,590 --> 00:14:07,140
囚禁在北边的高塔中
high up in the north tower.

88
00:15:10,240 --> 00:15:12,580
天主啊 以您之圣名
Our Father who art in heaven, hallowed be thy name.

89
00:15:12,740 --> 00:15:15,740
愿天国降临 愿您的旨意行在地上 如同天堂
Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done on Earth as it is in heaven,

90
00:15:15,910 --> 00:15:18,210
愿您赐福今日之饮食 宽恕往日之罪恶
Give us this day our daily bread, and forgive us our sins,

91
00:15:18,370 --> 00:15:20,540
如吾辈宽恕他人之罪责
as we forgive those who sin against us.

92
00:15:20,710 --> 00:15:25,470
带领吾辈避开诱惑远离邪恶 阿门
Lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil. Amen.

93
00:15:47,070 --> 00:15:48,110
你好
Hello'?

94
00:15:50,450 --> 00:15:52,070
你好
Hello'?

95
00:15:58,740 --> 00:16:00,790
- 你叫什么名字  - 我叫格蕾塔
- What is your name?  - I am Greta.

96
00:16:00,960 --> 00:16:03,920
- 你怎么了  - 我们村子里所有的姑娘都被抓起来了
- What happened to you'?   -All the girls in our village were taken.

97
00:16:04,080 --> 00:16:06,800
我被抓时正打算去哈蒙德公爵的城堡
I was trying to reach Duke Hammond's castle when I was caught.

98
00:16:06,960 --> 00:16:10,300
哈蒙德公爵 他还活着么
Duke Hammond? Is he alive'?

99
00:16:11,300 --> 00:16:15,180
- 他是否仍以我父亲的名字奋战  - 你是国王的女儿
- Does he still fight in my father's name?  - You're the King's daughter.

100
00:16:15,800 --> 00:16:19,430
国王死的那晚上 我们被告知城堡里的人都被杀了
The night the King died, we were told all in the castle were slain.

101
00:16:20,480 --> 00:16:23,640
那么威廉呢 公爵的儿子还活着么
And William? Is the Duke's son still alive?

102
00:16:23,810 --> 00:16:26,190
我不知道 公主
I don't know, Princess.

103
00:16:27,020 --> 00:16:28,990
他们要把我怎么样
What will they do to me?

104
00:17:01,270 --> 00:17:07,520
你还记得我们小时候乞讨剩饭么 就像那些贱民一样
Do you remember when we were children begging for scraps like those wretches?

105
00:17:07,730 --> 00:17:11,950
- 记得 妹妹  - 我是不是不再仁慈了
- Yes, sister.  - Am I not kinder?

106
00:17:14,240 --> 00:17:15,710
是的
YES.

107
00:18:02,910 --> 00:18:06,750
这两个人埋伏在我们的供给火车上 被我们抓捕了
These two were captured leading an ambush on one of our supply trains.

108
00:18:15,970 --> 00:18:19,850
你儿子 很英俊
Your son'? Handsome.

109
00:18:22,220 --> 00:18:24,900
明显是遗传了你母亲的美貌
Obviously, a debt owed to your mother.

110
00:18:25,730 --> 00:18:30,570
曾经我也会为你这样的面容芳心大乱
There was a time I would have lost my heart to a face like yours.

111
00:18:30,940 --> 00:18:35,490
而你 无疑 会伤了我的心
And you, no doubt, would have broken it.

112
00:18:36,360 --> 00:18:37,360
连恩 不要
lain, no!

113
00:18:56,050 --> 00:18:59,020
你想杀你的王后
You would kill your queen'?

114
00:19:00,800 --> 00:19:04,270
如此勇气 如此美好
Such courage. Such beauty.

115
00:19:04,470 --> 00:19:08,480
你的心又有多强大呢
But how strong is your heart?

116
00:19:15,900 --> 00:19:26,290
不 我的儿子 我的儿子
No. My son. My son!

117
00:19:31,120 --> 00:19:32,970
放开他
Leave him.

118
00:19:34,500 --> 00:19:37,180
让他回到公爵身边
Let him return to the Duke

119
00:19:37,760 --> 00:19:41,230
诉说他的皇后有多慷慨
and speak of the generosity of his queen.

120
00:19:41,930 --> 00:19:42,930
退下
Out.

121
00:19:43,220 --> 00:19:44,440
退下
Out!

122
00:20:24,760 --> 00:20:29,720
- 魔法都要付出昂贵的代价  - 代价会越来越高
- Magic comes at a lofty price.  - And the expense grows.

123
00:20:29,970 --> 00:20:33,520
- 你看上去...  - 老了  - 是累了
- You look...  - Old.   - Tired.

124
00:20:37,900 --> 00:20:42,910
我的力量在消失
My Dower fades.

125
00:20:47,830 --> 00:20:50,750
我带来了些可以缓解你苦恼的东西
I have something for what ails you.

126
00:21:00,960 --> 00:21:02,180
噢
Oh.

127
00:21:55,640 --> 00:21:56,940
格蕾塔
Greta?

128
00:21:59,480 --> 00:22:00,650
格蕾塔
Greta?

129
00:22:06,990 --> 00:22:08,610
魔镜 魔镜 告诉我
Mirror, mirror,on the wall,

130
00:22:09,070 --> 00:22:13,290
谁是世界上最美丽的人
who is fairest of them all?

131
00:22:13,910 --> 00:22:15,290
我的王后
My queen,

132
00:22:15,870 --> 00:22:19,550
现在 有一个人已经长大
on this day, one has come of age

133
00:22:19,710 --> 00:22:22,760
她比您更美
fairer even than you.

134
00:22:22,920 --> 00:22:26,390
她是您的能力衰竭的原因
She is the reason your powers wane.

135
00:22:26,920 --> 00:22:28,050
是谁
Who is it'?

136
00:22:28,590 --> 00:22:30,970
白雪公主
Snow White.

137
00:22:32,010 --> 00:22:33,510
白雪公主
Snow White?

138
00:22:34,350 --> 00:22:36,690
她是我的祸根
She is my undoing?

139
00:22:38,940 --> 00:22:41,610
我应该在她还是个孩子的时候就杀了她
I should have killed her when she was a child.

140
00:22:41,770 --> 00:22:43,270
小心
Be warned.

141
00:22:43,440 --> 00:22:48,410
她的纯真纯洁足以毁灭您
Her innocence and purity is all that can destroy you.

142
00:22:49,200 --> 00:22:53,330
但她也是您的救赎 王后
But she is also your salvation, Queen.

143
00:22:54,450 --> 00:22:56,620
只要得到她的心脏
Take her heart in your hand

144
00:22:56,790 --> 00:23:00,290
您的青春将永不衰竭
and you shall never again need to consume youth.

145
00:23:00,460 --> 00:23:04,380
您将再也不会虚弱衰老
You shall never again weaken or age.

146
00:23:04,550 --> 00:23:06,720
不死之身
Immortality.

147
00:23:07,420 --> 00:23:12,050
永生不灭
Immortality forever.

148
00:23:13,970 --> 00:23:15,810
芬恩
Finn!

149
00:23:18,060 --> 00:23:19,400
哥哥
Brother,

150
00:23:19,560 --> 00:23:21,650
把国王的女儿带来
bring me the King's daughter.

151
00:24:31,800 --> 00:24:33,640
我吵醒你了么
Did I wake you?

152
00:24:44,980 --> 00:24:47,650
我看到你的时候你总是醒着
Are you always awake when I watch you'?

153
00:24:52,650 --> 00:24:54,120
你以前从来没进来过
You've never come in before.

154
00:24:54,280 --> 00:24:56,120
我的妹妹不允许
My sister won't allow it.

155
00:24:59,160 --> 00:25:01,380
她想要见你
She wants you all to herself.

156
00:25:01,620 --> 00:25:03,340
我不怕她
I'm afraid of her.

157
00:25:05,620 --> 00:25:07,340
也不怕我
And not of me?

158
00:25:08,500 --> 00:25:09,500
不
No.

159
00:25:11,840 --> 00:25:13,310
别害怕 公主
Fear not, Princess.

160
00:25:16,340 --> 00:25:20,190
你不会再被关在这牢房里
You will never again be locked in this cell.

161
00:25:20,350 --> 00:25:22,820
她想从我这得到什么
What does she want from me'?

162
00:25:24,230 --> 00:25:27,200
你跳动的心脏
Your beating heart.

163
00:25:45,040 --> 00:25:46,590
让我出去
Get me out of here!

164
00:25:47,580 --> 00:25:48,580
不
No!

165
00:25:49,040 --> 00:25:50,170
格蕾塔
Greta?

166
00:25:52,550 --> 00:25:54,720
- 快走  - 放我出去
- Go.  - Get me out of here!

167
00:25:54,880 --> 00:25:56,680
- 不  - 快走
- No!  - Go.

168
00:25:56,840 --> 00:25:57,890
不
No!

169
00:26:28,370 --> 00:26:29,470
拦下她
Stop her!

170
00:26:33,590 --> 00:26:34,590
抓住她
Catch her!

171
00:26:43,060 --> 00:26:44,310
抓住她
Seize her!

172
00:27:04,120 --> 00:27:05,460
到大门那去
Get to the gate!

173
00:27:34,730 --> 00:27:36,480
把她给我带回来
Bring her back to me!

174
00:32:41,370 --> 00:32:45,050
试问 一个天真的小女孩
How is it thatan innocent young girl

175
00:32:45,130 --> 00:32:48,130
怎么会耍得了我的哥哥
makes a fool of my brother?

176
00:32:50,460 --> 00:32:53,220
仅以一个钉子做武器
Armed only with a nail.

177
00:32:55,340 --> 00:32:57,810
她要是有把剑
If she'd had a sword,

178
00:32:57,970 --> 00:33:00,220
岂不夺了我的国家
she would have taken my kingdom.

179
00:33:01,180 --> 00:33:04,150
我让你 把国王的女儿给我带来
"Bring me the King's daughter,"

180
00:33:04,310 --> 00:33:10,910
你却让她从你小小的指缝中溜走
and you let her slip right through your tiny little fingers.

181
00:33:11,820 --> 00:33:12,820
为何
How'?

182
00:33:13,240 --> 00:33:16,830
你发过誓要保护我
You swore that you would protect me!

183
00:33:16,990 --> 00:33:18,990
你发过誓的
You swore!

184
00:33:22,040 --> 00:33:24,380
已经没人能让我信任了
Now there's no one I can trust.

185
00:33:24,540 --> 00:33:27,880
没有人 毫无忠诚可言 毫无忠诚
No one. There's no loyalty, no loyalty.

186
00:33:28,040 --> 00:33:30,550
没有忠诚 甚至是你
None, not even from you!

187
00:33:31,000 --> 00:33:34,050
她在哪
Where is she?

188
00:33:35,880 --> 00:33:39,350
我们的人追着她进入黑森林
She was chased into the Dark Forest,

189
00:33:39,510 --> 00:33:40,860
之后追丢了
where the men lost her.

190
00:33:41,010 --> 00:33:44,770
她在黑森林里失踪对我一点用都没有
She's no good to me in the Dark Forest, lost!

191
00:33:44,940 --> 00:33:49,030
我要她的心脏 你让我失望了 芬恩
I need her heart! You failed me, Finn!

192
00:33:49,190 --> 00:33:51,860
我不是把一切都给了你了么
Have I not given all to you!

193
00:33:59,070 --> 00:34:04,200
我没有把我的一切给你么
Have l not given you all?

194
00:34:06,920 --> 00:34:08,260
有的 妹妹
Yes, sister.

195
00:34:17,590 --> 00:34:19,220
安静
Quiet.

196
00:34:21,050 --> 00:34:24,060
我在黑森林里没有魔力
I have no powers in the Dark Forest.

197
00:34:25,730 --> 00:34:28,900
你要为我找到一个人
You have to find me someone.

198
00:34:30,110 --> 00:34:32,450
一个熟悉森林的人
Someone who knows it.

199
00:34:34,440 --> 00:34:36,740
一个能抓住她的人
Someone who can hunt her.

200
00:34:41,740 --> 00:34:43,840
你欠我的钱
You owe me money from my pocket

201
00:34:43,990 --> 00:34:45,090
还有那女孩的钱
and money for the girl.

202
00:34:45,250 --> 00:34:47,920
嗯 你知道的 我好像都给喝掉了
Well, you know, I seem to have drunk it all,

203
00:34:48,080 --> 00:34:50,000
不过你想要的话我可以吐出来给你
but you're welcome to it when it comes out again.

204
00:34:56,800 --> 00:34:59,930
你太过分了 把钱还给我
You've gone too far. I want my money!

205
00:35:00,590 --> 00:35:01,970
给你
Here it is!

206
00:35:41,970 --> 00:35:43,640
王后要召见你
The Queen demands your presence.

207
00:35:43,800 --> 00:35:46,060
没看见我正在洗澡
Can't you see I'm having a bath?

208
00:35:48,770 --> 00:35:51,070
相信我这一点 妹妹
Trust me on this, sister.

209
00:35:53,060 --> 00:35:55,280
好吧 好吧
All right! All right!

210
00:35:56,270 --> 00:35:57,280
嘿
Hey!

211
00:36:04,950 --> 00:36:08,950
我的哥哥说你是个鳏夫 一个酒鬼
My brother tells me you are a widower. A drunkard.

212
00:36:09,500 --> 00:36:12,840
还是少数进过黑森林的人
And one of few who has ventured into the Dark Forest.

213
00:36:13,000 --> 00:36:14,050
是的
Aye.

214
00:36:14,170 --> 00:36:16,170
我的一个囚犯逃到那去了
One of my prisoners has escaped there.

215
00:36:16,340 --> 00:36:17,800
- 那他死定了  - 是她
- Then he's dead.  - She.

216
00:36:17,960 --> 00:36:19,260
那她绝对死定了
She is certainly dead.

217
00:36:22,840 --> 00:36:24,010
找到她
Find her.

218
00:36:25,350 --> 00:36:26,350
把她带给我
Bring her to me.

219
00:36:26,430 --> 00:36:28,520
我去过那个森林 我再也不要进去了
No, I've been to that forest. I'm not going back.

220
00:36:28,680 --> 00:36:31,860
我会给你数目可观的赏金
You will be rewarded handsomely.

221
00:36:32,020 --> 00:36:33,190
要是我横尸荒野
What good is gold to me

222
00:36:33,270 --> 00:36:35,190
被乌鸦啄着眼珠 金子对我来说还有什么用呢
if I'm lying dead with the crows picking at my eyes?

223
00:36:38,610 --> 00:36:40,200
她为什么这么重要
Why is she of such value?

224
00:36:40,440 --> 00:36:42,370
这与你无关
That is none of your concern.

225
00:36:42,820 --> 00:36:44,540
谢谢 我知道什么和我有关
I'll determine what concerns me, thank you.

226
00:36:44,700 --> 00:36:48,080
你必须得去 猎人
You will do this for me, huntsman!

227
00:36:50,160 --> 00:36:51,710
我要是拒绝呢
And if I refuse?

228
00:36:55,500 --> 00:36:57,470
饶了我吧 我请求您
Do me the favor, I beg of you.

229
00:36:57,670 --> 00:36:59,510
让他跪下
To his knees.

230
00:37:05,720 --> 00:37:08,470
你是不是想和你的挚爱团聚了
So you wish to be reunited with your beloved?

231
00:37:10,600 --> 00:37:12,600
不许提我的妻子
You do not speak of my wife.

232
00:37:15,810 --> 00:37:18,030
你很想她
You miss her.

233
00:37:26,410 --> 00:37:30,630
要是你能再见到她 你愿意付出什么代价
What would you give to see her again?

234
00:37:33,250 --> 00:37:35,210
你知道我的能力
You know of my powers.

235
00:37:35,790 --> 00:37:38,760
把女孩带给我
Bring me the girl

236
00:37:39,590 --> 00:37:42,210
我就把妻子带还给你
and I will bring back your wife.

237
00:37:43,380 --> 00:37:44,720
没什么能让她起死回生
Nothing can bring her back.

238
00:37:45,010 --> 00:37:46,260
我可以
I can.

239
00:37:52,850 --> 00:37:57,280
一命 换一命
A life for a life.

240
00:38:13,370 --> 00:38:15,090
她走不了多远
She can't have gone far.

241
00:38:17,460 --> 00:38:19,630
照我的做
All right, do exactly as I do.

242
00:38:21,960 --> 00:38:23,680
这可是个坏主意
It's a bad idea.

243
00:38:49,740 --> 00:38:50,960
待着别动
Stay here.

244
00:39:51,550 --> 00:39:53,350
- 过来  - 不
- Come here'  - No!

245
00:39:57,560 --> 00:39:58,600
请你帮帮我好吗
Will you help me?

246
00:39:59,100 --> 00:40:01,320
求你了 王后要杀我
Please, the Queen is going to kill me.

247
00:40:01,480 --> 00:40:02,480
她当然会
Sure she is.

248
00:40:02,560 --> 00:40:04,440
她会挖我的心出来
She's going to rip out my heart.

249
00:40:05,610 --> 00:40:06,650
手脚挺快的
Quick work.

250
00:40:07,440 --> 00:40:08,530
嘿
Hey.

251
00:40:08,690 --> 00:40:10,070
猎人 干得好
Well done, huntsman.

252
00:40:11,530 --> 00:40:12,580
把她交过来
Hand her over.

253
00:40:15,070 --> 00:40:17,040
你们打算怎么处置她
What do you intend to do with her?

254
00:40:17,950 --> 00:40:18,950
为什么你这么在意
Why do you care'?

255
00:40:19,540 --> 00:40:21,080
你想要她.. 嘿
You want her... Hey!

256
00:40:21,250 --> 00:40:23,300
你得先兑现你们的承诺
Give me what I was promised.

257
00:40:23,460 --> 00:40:25,210
你干得非常好
You did your job well.

258
00:40:25,840 --> 00:40:28,050
请你先信守诺言
Now, keep your word.

259
00:40:28,380 --> 00:40:30,350
- 他会杀了我们俩的  - 闭嘴
- He'll kill us both  - Shut up.

260
00:40:30,510 --> 00:40:32,470
- 他肯定会的 - 我说闭嘴
- He will.  - I said, shut up.

261
00:40:32,630 --> 00:40:34,180
不 不
No, no.

262
00:40:34,340 --> 00:40:36,600
如果王后遵守诺言 我也会说到做到
I'll keep my word when the Queen keeps hers.

263
00:40:36,760 --> 00:40:37,890
我的妻子到底在哪里
Where's my wife?

264
00:40:39,430 --> 00:40:41,650
他会背叛你的
He's going to betray you.

265
00:40:42,560 --> 00:40:46,160
我妹妹拥有很多能力
My sister has many powers.

266
00:40:47,150 --> 00:40:50,990
她可以决定人的生死
She can take life away, or sustain it,

267
00:40:51,990 --> 00:40:56,910
但她可不能让你的妻子起死回生 你真是愚蠢
but she can't bring your wife back from the dead, you fool!

268
00:40:58,200 --> 00:40:59,420
我想让她回来
I want her back!

269
00:42:01,600 --> 00:42:05,190
我会找到你的
I will find you!

270
00:42:13,440 --> 00:42:15,540
安静 没事吧
Quiet. All right?

271
00:42:20,740 --> 00:42:22,920
他妈的到底发生什么事
Hey, what the hell's going on'?

272
00:42:23,080 --> 00:42:24,880
你是谁  王后为什么要杀你
Who are you? Why does the Queen want you dead?

273
00:42:25,040 --> 00:42:26,210
她希望所有人都死 所有人
She wants everyone dead, all of us.

274
00:42:26,370 --> 00:42:27,620
什么使得你如此有价值
What makes you so damn valuable?

275
00:42:27,710 --> 00:42:30,430
你该知道的 你是来追杀我的
You should know, you're the one hunting me.

276
00:42:35,420 --> 00:42:36,600
算了吧
Forget it.

277
00:42:39,390 --> 00:42:42,390
我就不应该跟王后的事扯上关系
I should have never got involved in the Queen's business.

278
00:42:42,560 --> 00:42:44,400
我到底是卷入了什么 蠢死了
What did I get in? Stupid...

279
00:42:44,560 --> 00:42:46,230
你要去哪里
Where are you going'?

280
00:42:47,850 --> 00:42:50,570
远离你 你就是个麻烦的源头
Getting away from you. You're trouble, is what you are.

281
00:42:52,110 --> 00:42:54,860
我需要去公爵的城堡 那里有只军队
I need to get to the Duke's castle. There's an army there.

282
00:42:55,070 --> 00:42:57,570
哦 公爵的军队
Oh, the Duke's army?

283
00:42:58,400 --> 00:43:01,410
一群农夫 还有拿着干草叉的挤奶女工
Bunch of farmers and milkmaids with pitchforks.

284
00:43:03,870 --> 00:43:05,750
绵羊打架的次数都比他们多
I know sheep that have more fight in them.

285
00:43:05,910 --> 00:43:07,040
我很值钱
I'm valuable.

286
00:43:07,580 --> 00:43:09,250
你跟着我就是因为我是有价值的 不是吗
That's why you're here, isn't it?

287
00:43:11,580 --> 00:43:13,800
如果你抛下我就这样回去 你会死的
If you return without me, you're dead.

288
00:43:14,380 --> 00:43:16,720
如果你离开我 我也会死
If you leave me, I'm dead.

289
00:43:20,640 --> 00:43:23,760
姑且以这为基础 有多少报酬
Just for argument's sake, how much reward?

290
00:43:24,140 --> 00:43:25,140
多少才足够
However much is enough.

291
00:43:25,260 --> 00:43:28,270
- 至少30金币..  - 一百
- At least thirty gold pieces...  - A hundred.

292
00:43:31,100 --> 00:43:32,570
帮帮我
Help me.

293
00:43:34,940 --> 00:43:35,940
你到底是谁
Who are you?

294
00:43:36,110 --> 00:43:38,450
你应该问王后
Maybe you should have asked the Queen that.

295
00:43:38,610 --> 00:43:39,950
我不相信你
I don't trust you.

296
00:43:40,320 --> 00:43:43,620
- 我已经给了你我的承诺  - 我还是不相信你
- I've given you my word.  - I still don't trust you.

297
00:43:45,740 --> 00:43:47,250
但我们的有协议
But you have a deal.

298
00:43:57,300 --> 00:44:00,430
在你失去手指前 把那个给我
Give me that, before you lose a finger.

299
00:44:06,560 --> 00:44:09,810
她轻而易举的就杀了我勇敢的连恩
She killed my brave lain with just the palm of her hand

300
00:44:09,980 --> 00:44:12,070
然后她从身体里把匕首拔出来
and then she drew a dagger from her side with no blood.

301
00:44:12,150 --> 00:44:13,990
她不会被杀死
She cannot be killed.

302
00:44:16,230 --> 00:44:17,480
但事情还没完
But there is more.

303
00:44:19,150 --> 00:44:21,370
公主还活着
The Princess is alive.

304
00:44:24,490 --> 00:44:25,710
我的儿子呢
Where is my son'?

305
00:45:22,010 --> 00:45:23,850
我们收到了公主的消息
We have word of the Princess.

306
00:45:24,720 --> 00:45:27,390
这些年里瑞雯娜一直不让你们知道
Ravenna has kept her, all these years.

307
00:45:29,760 --> 00:45:30,890
她还活着
She lives?

308
00:45:31,890 --> 00:45:34,860
她从城堡逃了出来 躲进了暗黑森林
She escaped the castle, into the Dark Forest.

309
00:45:36,900 --> 00:45:38,400
我要去找她
I'm going after her.

310
00:45:38,560 --> 00:45:40,190
我们不知道她是否还活着 威廉
We don't know if she survived.

311
00:45:40,270 --> 00:45:41,280
威廉
William!

312
00:45:42,690 --> 00:45:43,690
什么
What?

313
00:45:43,860 --> 00:45:47,080
你又要冒险地越过城堡之墙 无视我的命令
You ventured beyond the castle walls again, disobeying my orders.

314
00:45:47,530 --> 00:45:49,080
我们是这里仅剩的人了 你还不明白么
We're all that's left, don't you understand?

315
00:45:50,410 --> 00:45:52,250
我不能让任何人出事
I cannot afford to lose any more of my men.

316
00:45:52,410 --> 00:45:53,410
我一个人去
I'm going alone.

317
00:45:54,120 --> 00:45:56,540
我不能失去我唯一的儿子
I will not lose my only son.

318
00:45:58,420 --> 00:45:59,960
你根本不了解暗黑森林
You don't know the Dark Forest.

319
00:46:00,130 --> 00:46:02,130
那我就去找了解的人
Then I'll find somebody who does.

320
00:46:02,300 --> 00:46:04,420
我不会再次抛下她的
I will not abandon her a second time.

321
00:46:40,840 --> 00:46:43,680
这个森林会从以你恐惧为食
The forest gains its strength from your weakness.

322
00:46:55,470 --> 00:46:56,980
你喝酒是为了让你忘却悲伤
Do you drink to drown your sorrows?

323
00:46:57,440 --> 00:46:58,980
还是你的良心
Or your conscience?

324
00:46:59,150 --> 00:47:01,520
你为什么要关心我喝酒的原因
What concern is it of yours, why I drink?

325
00:47:02,020 --> 00:47:03,650
我认为男人的悲伤只属于他自己
I suppose a man's sorrows are his own.

326
00:47:04,110 --> 00:47:07,330
像你这样的小女孩懂什么悲伤呢
What does a young girl like you know about sorrow?

327
00:47:19,290 --> 00:47:21,380
别太得意忘形
Don't flatter yourself.

328
00:47:21,710 --> 00:47:23,090
现在跟进了
Now stay close.

329
00:47:30,430 --> 00:47:32,770
你们熟悉黑森林么
You men know the dark forest?

330
00:47:40,270 --> 00:47:41,740
准备出发
Load and prepare.

331
00:47:42,610 --> 00:47:44,820
给你们50金币
You ride for 50 gold pieces.

332
00:47:45,650 --> 00:47:49,750
服侍她会不会让你苦恼
Does it not trouble you to serve her'?

333
00:47:50,780 --> 00:47:52,330
谁 王后
Who the Queen?

334
00:47:54,530 --> 00:47:56,160
我不服侍任何人
I serve no one.

335
00:47:58,000 --> 00:48:02,420
尤其是那种老巫婆 还有其他皇室 他们都该死
Especially that old hag, and any other royalty. They're all damned.

336
00:48:04,880 --> 00:48:07,220
国王和他真正的皇后并不该死
The King and his true queen are not damned.

337
00:48:07,300 --> 00:48:08,390
国王
The King?

338
00:48:08,800 --> 00:48:11,050
他是将恶魔引入门中的
He's the one that let the devil in the door.

339
00:48:11,130 --> 00:48:14,390
将王国陷入黑暗都是他的错
It's his fault the kingdom's plunged into darkness.

340
00:48:16,640 --> 00:48:17,640
你认为
From you?

341
00:48:18,060 --> 00:48:19,060
你什么都不知道
You know nothing.

342
00:48:19,140 --> 00:48:20,310
什么 那你就知道了
What? And you do?

343
00:48:21,140 --> 00:48:23,740
你这么个小家伙这么关心国王
What's a wee scrod like you care about the King anyway?

344
00:48:23,810 --> 00:48:25,610
照你的年龄几乎都不会记得他
You're barely old enough to remember him.

345
00:48:25,690 --> 00:48:27,740
病态的土地
The land is diseased.

346
00:48:27,820 --> 00:48:29,410
颠覆的自然
Nature is upturned.

347
00:48:29,490 --> 00:48:32,530
这 这就是你心爱的国王的遗赠
This, this is the legacy of your precious king.

348
00:48:57,220 --> 00:48:58,720
你需要弓箭手吗
Do you need a bowman?

349
00:49:01,560 --> 00:49:03,230
我有弓箭手
I have a bowman.

350
00:49:05,310 --> 00:49:06,690
杀了他
Kill him.

351
00:49:12,190 --> 00:49:15,200
我说了 你是否需要弓箭手
I said, do you need a bowman?

352
00:49:30,000 --> 00:49:32,050
过来 我给你看一些东西
Here, I want to show you something.

353
00:49:35,890 --> 00:49:37,810
这是你的控制范围
Which is your lead foot?

354
00:49:40,680 --> 00:49:43,180
如果有人接近你 你举起这只手臂
If someone comes at you, you raise this arm up

355
00:49:43,310 --> 00:49:46,150
你挡住他们 然后反借他们的力量来防御
and you block, and use their strength against them.

356
00:49:47,230 --> 00:49:49,230
你个子太小了 所以要等到他们靠过来
You're small, so wait until they're close

357
00:49:49,400 --> 00:49:52,700
然后你抓住刀柄朝最大限度的朝他们心脏猛刺过去
and you drive it through their heart to the hilt.

358
00:49:52,860 --> 00:49:55,700
明白吗 不要犹豫
You understand'? Do not hesitate.

359
00:49:56,030 --> 00:49:57,160
你要直视他们的眼睛
You look in their eyes

360
00:49:57,320 --> 00:49:59,870
在确定他们死之前都不能拔出小刀
and do not pull it out until you see their soul.

361
00:50:10,790 --> 00:50:12,640
我做不到
I couldn't do that.

362
00:50:14,420 --> 00:50:16,640
你别无选择
Well, you might not have a choice.

363
00:50:35,610 --> 00:50:37,450
我们找到了他们的踪迹
We have their trail.

364
00:50:42,330 --> 00:50:44,040
前进 前进
Move on. Move on!

365
00:51:14,440 --> 00:51:15,780
等等
Wait.

366
00:51:18,030 --> 00:51:19,620
这里是暗黑森林的边缘吗
Is this the edge of the Dark Forest?

367
00:51:19,780 --> 00:51:20,830
是的
Aye.

368
00:51:23,160 --> 00:51:24,330
这是什么
What is it?

369
00:51:38,840 --> 00:51:40,060
是巨魔
Troll!

370
00:51:51,810 --> 00:51:52,810
快走
Go!

371
00:52:01,360 --> 00:52:02,360
跑啊
Run!

372
00:53:31,790 --> 00:53:33,080
我叫你跑
I told you to run.

373
00:53:33,660 --> 00:53:35,130
如果我走了你会死的
If I had, you would be dead.

374
00:54:04,450 --> 00:54:07,670
只有恶魔或妖精才能穿过暗黑森林 你们是哪一类
Only demons or spirits pass through the Dark Forest. Which are you?

375
00:54:07,990 --> 00:54:10,710
我们是逃亡者 王后在追杀我们
We're fugitives from the Queen.

376
00:54:10,990 --> 00:54:13,000
我们对你们并无恶意
We mean you no harm.

377
00:54:52,740 --> 00:54:54,840
男人都去了哪里
Where are all the men?

378
00:54:56,370 --> 00:54:57,500
离开了
Gone.

379
00:55:19,940 --> 00:55:21,410
你们没有酒吗
Have you got nothing to drink?

380
00:55:25,360 --> 00:55:26,910
你长途跋涉
You have traveled far

381
00:55:28,450 --> 00:55:30,740
而且有着沉重的负担
and carried a great burden.

382
00:55:31,910 --> 00:55:33,250
我经历过更糟糕的
I've had worse jobs.

383
00:55:35,410 --> 00:55:38,540
不过 她这个负担并不算重
Anyway, she's not that heavy.

384
00:55:42,080 --> 00:55:44,050
你不知道她的真正身份
You don't know who she is.

385
00:55:45,550 --> 00:55:46,550
什么意思
What do you mean?

386
00:55:51,390 --> 00:55:53,100
为什么 她是谁
Why? Who is she?

387
00:55:53,890 --> 00:55:56,940
也许它需要一条裙子 或者衣服什么的
Maybe it needs a skirt, or a dress or something?

388
00:55:57,520 --> 00:55:58,810
这很棒
That's nice.

389
00:55:59,270 --> 00:56:00,740
给它添张脸怎么样
How about a face?

390
00:56:01,270 --> 00:56:02,570
你母亲想见你
Your mother wants to see you.

391
00:56:14,240 --> 00:56:15,960
为什么你不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?

392
00:56:17,620 --> 00:56:20,790
因为我会认为这是一个太过艰难的任务吗
Because I'd think it was too difficult a task?

393
00:56:21,420 --> 00:56:22,460
你是对的
You would be right.

394
00:56:27,460 --> 00:56:29,140
我不相信你
I didn't trust you.

395
00:56:32,800 --> 00:56:35,050
- 对不起  - 是啊
- I'm sorry.  - Yeah.

396
00:57:06,540 --> 00:57:08,720
我们的伤疤保护着我们
Our scars protect us.

397
00:57:09,210 --> 00:57:12,140
失去美貌的我们对王后而言一文不值
Without beauty, we are worthless to the Queen.

398
00:57:12,630 --> 00:57:14,890
这是我们做出的牺牲
It's a sacrifice we made

399
00:57:15,840 --> 00:57:18,310
所以我们在他们的父亲在战场上时
so we could raise our children in peace

400
00:57:19,600 --> 00:57:21,850
可以安宁地抚养孩子
while their fathers are at war.

401
00:57:22,310 --> 00:57:23,940
而你
And you,

402
00:57:24,850 --> 00:57:26,360
你也将要做出牺牲
your sacrifice will come.

403
00:57:31,690 --> 00:57:32,690
你该休息了
You must rest.

404
00:57:55,180 --> 00:57:58,020
你知道真相后怎么可以遗弃她
How can you desert her when you know the truth?

405
00:57:58,180 --> 00:57:59,930
是啊 我知道真相
Aye, I know the truth.

406
00:58:00,100 --> 00:58:03,190
那就是她要尽可能远离我的原因
That's why she should be as far away from me as possible.

407
00:58:03,350 --> 00:58:05,480
我在乎的任何东西最后都会被夺走
Anything I ever cared about was taken away from me.

408
00:58:06,850 --> 00:58:08,110
不仅仅这次
Not this time.

409
00:58:08,270 --> 00:58:09,570
她留在这里会更安全
She's safer here with you.

410
00:58:38,470 --> 00:58:40,140
莉莉 莉莉 快点
Lily! Lily, come On!

411
00:58:40,300 --> 00:58:41,680
快点
Come on!

412
00:58:47,020 --> 00:58:49,820
跑啊你们这群卑贱的人 跑啊
Run, rats, run!

413
00:58:54,110 --> 00:58:55,280
快去找她
Find her!

414
00:58:57,110 --> 00:58:58,710
找到她
Find her!

415
00:58:59,280 --> 00:59:00,450
过来
Come on!

416
00:59:02,200 --> 00:59:04,290
上船 快上船
Get in the boats! Get in the boats!

417
00:59:04,450 --> 00:59:05,630
莉莉
Lily!

418
01:00:35,210 --> 01:00:36,550
到这来 宝贝
In there, baby. There you go.

419
01:00:39,550 --> 01:00:40,640
过来
Come on!

420
01:00:42,130 --> 01:00:43,890
不 不
NO! No!

421
01:00:48,890 --> 01:00:49,890
过来 快走
Come on! Let's go!

422
01:00:50,060 --> 01:00:51,440
不 我们要帮他们
No! We have to help them!

423
01:00:51,600 --> 01:00:52,730
你会的 快走
You will. Go'

424
01:00:52,890 --> 01:00:54,820
- 快点  - 快走
- Come on!  - Go!

425
01:01:24,760 --> 01:01:28,060
瑞雯娜 你的美貌是你唯一的救赎
Your beauty is all that can save you, Ravenna.

426
01:01:29,220 --> 01:01:33,480
这咒语可以令你的美貌成为你的力量和守护
This spell will make your beauty your power and protection.

427
01:01:36,900 --> 01:01:39,900
你需要最鲜红的血液来完成这咒语
By fairest blood it is done.

428
01:01:39,980 --> 01:01:41,580
这儿 快喝 快喝
Here. Drink, drink!

429
01:01:46,570 --> 01:01:47,830
但是要警告你
But, be warned.

430
01:01:47,990 --> 01:01:51,460
最鲜红的血液也会解除咒语
By fairest blood, this spell can be undone.

431
01:01:57,630 --> 01:01:59,920
为我们报仇
Avenge us!

432
01:02:34,000 --> 01:02:35,000
对不起
I'm sorry.

433
01:02:39,460 --> 01:02:40,840
- 对不起  - 你没有
- I'm sorry.  - You're not.

434
01:02:41,000 --> 01:02:42,170
- 真的 - 你抛下了我们
- I am.  - You left us.

435
01:02:45,300 --> 01:02:47,640
我们根本就不该去那儿
We should never have been there.

436
01:02:50,680 --> 01:02:52,730
嘿 看着我
Hey, look at me.

437
01:02:53,680 --> 01:02:55,730
我会把你带去公爵哈蒙德那里
I'll take you to Duke Hammond's, okay?

438
01:02:55,890 --> 01:02:57,310
好吧
All right'?

439
01:02:59,350 --> 01:03:01,070
我对你许诺
You have my word.

440
01:03:04,070 --> 01:03:05,320
等等
Wait!

441
01:03:16,500 --> 01:03:17,710
真是我们幸运日啊
This is our lucky day.

442
01:03:17,870 --> 01:03:20,000
噢 不 矮人
Oh, no. Dwarves.

443
01:03:20,170 --> 01:03:23,050
世界上我最讨厌的豪猪 真是天上掉馅饼了
The hedge-pig I loathe most in the world lands right in our lap.

444
01:03:23,210 --> 01:03:24,430
嘿 贝斯
Come on, Beith.

445
01:03:24,880 --> 01:03:25,880
你就是这样招待朋友的吗
Is this how you treat a friend?

446
01:03:26,050 --> 01:03:28,770
噢 不 帕塔克
Oh! No, no, no, you puttock.

447
01:03:28,930 --> 01:03:30,550
这才是我招待朋友的方法
This is how I treat a friend.

448
01:03:33,050 --> 01:03:34,270
她可真漂亮
She's pretty.

449
01:03:35,430 --> 01:03:36,560
但这男的是谁
And who's this?

450
01:03:36,730 --> 01:03:39,400
是跑路的学徒 还是被你迷住的
Is this an errant apprentice or captive?

451
01:03:39,560 --> 01:03:40,560
他是来帮我的
This man is helping me.

452
01:03:40,730 --> 01:03:41,860
我们该把他们都杀了
We should kill them both.

453
01:03:42,020 --> 01:03:43,400
除了麻烦他不能带来我们任何好处
He's caused us nothing but trouble.

454
01:03:43,570 --> 01:03:47,200
刺穿他 然后扔下任其腐烂吧 我不喜欢杀女人
Skewer him and leave her to rot. I don't like killing girls.

455
01:03:47,360 --> 01:03:49,200
- 我喜欢  - 太好了
- I do.  - Good.

456
01:03:49,360 --> 01:03:50,610
把她留在这儿吧 杜尔
Leave her alone, Duir.

457
01:03:52,570 --> 01:03:55,750
什么都没有 只有一枚银币和一个空的兜袋
He's got nothing. One silver coin and an empty codpiece.

458
01:03:56,370 --> 01:03:58,710
我们在这里坐了两天得到什么了
Two days we sat here. What for?

459
01:03:58,870 --> 01:04:00,250
一根毛都没有
Nothing.

460
01:04:00,620 --> 01:04:02,630
我们应该留在河边的 真是浪费时间
We should have stayed by the river. What a waste of time!

461
01:04:02,790 --> 01:04:05,760
贝斯 把我们放下来 我有金币可以付给你
Cut us down, Beith. I have gold I can pay you.

462
01:04:05,920 --> 01:04:08,920
但不在这儿 它藏在树林后面
It's not here, it's hidden back in the woods.

463
01:04:09,090 --> 01:04:10,760
别让我看到你恶心的脸 猎人
Shut your ugly mug, huntsman.

464
01:04:10,930 --> 01:04:14,300
如果你有钱 你现在就会喝蜂蜜酒喝到酩酊大醉了
If you had any pennies, you would have pissed it away on mead by now.

465
01:04:14,470 --> 01:04:15,640
放我下来 我会证明给你看
Cut us down, then I'll show you.

466
01:04:15,810 --> 01:04:17,310
把另一个拉起来 你个满嘴谎言的混蛋
Pull the other one, you lying dangler.

467
01:04:17,470 --> 01:04:20,480
把真相告诉他们吧 猎人 时间不够了
Tell them the truth, huntsman. There's no time!

468
01:04:20,640 --> 01:04:23,990
我要把这女孩带到哈蒙德那里 她在这里不安全
I have to take this girl to Hammond's. She's not safe here.

469
01:04:24,400 --> 01:04:26,820
我的小心脏都为你难过啊
Well, my little heart bleeds for you.

470
01:04:26,980 --> 01:04:28,610
我们应该把他们剁碎了喂狼的
We should chop them up and feed them to the wolves.

471
01:04:28,780 --> 01:04:29,990
是啊 是的
Yeah. Yes!

472
01:04:30,450 --> 01:04:31,540
她是谁
Who is she?

473
01:04:31,610 --> 01:04:33,460
对我而言她值许多金币
She's worth a lot of gold to me.

474
01:04:33,740 --> 01:04:35,990
我兴致来了才会告诉你们这群愚蠢的矮人
Which I am happy to share with you stupid little dwarves.

475
01:04:36,580 --> 01:04:37,580
住手
Stop that!

476
01:04:37,660 --> 01:04:40,290
如果我们死了 金币对你们而言将毫无价值
Gold is worth nothing to any of you if you're all dead!

477
01:04:40,460 --> 01:04:41,800
王后的人在追杀我们
The Queen's men hunt us!

478
01:04:42,080 --> 01:04:44,130
- 他们马上就到了  - 闭嘴
- They're very close!  - Shut up!

479
01:04:45,250 --> 01:04:46,300
你们是拥护皇后的
You have love for the Queen?

480
01:04:46,460 --> 01:04:48,760
我们才不拥护她
We have no love for the Queen.

481
01:04:48,920 --> 01:04:50,050
那你们是反对她的吗
Then you fight against her?

482
01:04:50,130 --> 01:04:51,600
不 没人会跟王后做对
No one fights against the Queen.

483
01:04:51,760 --> 01:04:53,980
国王死的时候 我们失去了所有
We lost everything when the King died.

484
01:04:54,140 --> 01:04:55,430
我们只为自己而战
We fight only for ourselves!

485
01:04:55,600 --> 01:04:56,600
没错
Yes

486
01:04:56,850 --> 01:04:59,320
我的父亲就是马格纳斯国王
My father was King Magnus.

487
01:05:07,520 --> 01:05:08,650
缪尔
Muir,

488
01:05:09,650 --> 01:05:11,780
她说的是真的吗
does she speak the truth?

489
01:05:12,530 --> 01:05:15,830
是的 她是王族的人
Yes. She is of the blood.

490
01:05:17,950 --> 01:05:20,300
贝斯 她是注定的那个人
She is destined, Beith.

491
01:05:22,660 --> 01:05:25,340
我可以看见黑暗的终结了
I see an end to the darkness.

492
01:05:29,800 --> 01:05:30,890
骑兵
Riders!

493
01:05:31,050 --> 01:05:32,170
他们发现我们了
They found us!

494
01:05:32,340 --> 01:05:33,890
如果你还不放我们下来 我们都会被杀的
If you don't cut us down, we'll all be killed!

495
01:05:34,050 --> 01:05:36,180
我并不喜欢这样 贝斯 听起来真麻烦
I don't like this, Beith. It smells like trouble.

496
01:05:36,340 --> 01:05:38,720
如果你放我们下来 你会得到你体重那么多的金币
You'll find your weight in gold if you out us down, now!

497
01:05:38,890 --> 01:05:39,890
公主你闭嘴
Shut up, Princess.

498
01:05:40,350 --> 01:05:41,850
王后的骑兵
Queen's riders!

499
01:05:42,520 --> 01:05:43,890
他们沿这条路过来了
And they're coming this way!

500
01:05:44,810 --> 01:05:46,030
我们带走她 但不带猎人
We'll take her, but not him!

501
01:05:46,190 --> 01:05:47,560
什么
What?

502
01:05:47,730 --> 01:05:49,030
把我们都带走
No, both of us!

503
01:05:49,190 --> 01:05:50,690
把他们都放下来 高特
Cut them both down, Gort!

504
01:05:50,860 --> 01:05:52,360
他妈的我们快离开这里
Let's get the hell out of here!

505
01:05:52,690 --> 01:05:54,240
快点 再快点
Move it! Move it!

506
01:06:32,400 --> 01:06:33,530
他们就在附近
They're close.

507
01:07:44,810 --> 01:07:46,230
要命的精灵之歌
Blasted fairy music.

508
01:07:46,430 --> 01:07:48,810
同意
Yeah.

509
01:07:48,980 --> 01:07:51,360
幸好这里长满了苔藓
Good thing there's plenty of moss about.

510
01:07:57,360 --> 01:07:58,990
我们在哪里
Where are we?

511
01:08:00,240 --> 01:08:02,490
夫人 他们称这里是圣地
They call it Sanctuary, my lady.

512
01:08:02,660 --> 01:08:04,530
是精灵之家
It's the home of the fairies.

513
01:08:08,500 --> 01:08:10,040
精灵
Fairies.

514
01:08:27,600 --> 01:08:29,020
安全
Clear!

515
01:08:29,520 --> 01:08:30,860
科尔
Coll'?

516
01:08:34,060 --> 01:08:35,410
安全
Clear!

517
01:08:38,940 --> 01:08:40,240
扎营
Set up camp!

518
01:08:40,400 --> 01:08:42,530
格斯 奎特 你们俩生火
Gus. Quert. Make the fire.

519
01:08:43,360 --> 01:08:45,410
高特 你的杯子
Gort, your mug.

520
01:09:06,430 --> 01:09:08,150
声音大点儿 你们这些面无血色的人
Play louder, you whey-face,

521
01:09:08,220 --> 01:09:10,730
我仍然能听见鸟身女妖的叫声
I can still hear them harpy fairies.

522
01:09:15,230 --> 01:09:18,900
杜尔 你真的想杀了她吗
Duir, would you really have killed her?

523
01:09:19,570 --> 01:09:20,570
是的
Yeah.

524
01:09:20,740 --> 01:09:22,240
当然了
Of course.

525
01:09:42,420 --> 01:09:46,140
请坐吧 边上没人
That seat's not taken, if that's what you were about to ask.

526
01:09:51,140 --> 01:09:52,770
我想跟你道谢
I want to thank you.

527
01:09:52,930 --> 01:09:54,280
举手之劳
It's only a log.

528
01:09:55,230 --> 01:09:56,980
没有必要感谢我
There's no need to thank me.

529
01:09:57,110 --> 01:09:58,400
不 是为了之前的事
No, for before.

530
01:09:59,440 --> 01:10:00,610
你保护了我
For defending me.

531
01:10:01,780 --> 01:10:03,950
你父亲是个好人
Ah. Your father was a good man.

532
01:10:04,110 --> 01:10:06,110
王国繁荣
The kingdom prospered.

533
01:10:06,280 --> 01:10:07,950
我们百姓也过得舒适
Our people prospered.

534
01:10:10,740 --> 01:10:11,790
还有更多的矮人
There were more of you.

535
01:10:11,950 --> 01:10:13,380
- 是啊  - 是的
- Aye.  - Yeah.

536
01:10:14,500 --> 01:10:16,800
眼前你看到的这些
The men you see before you

537
01:10:16,960 --> 01:10:20,760
并且还有更多的矮人 他们在深深的地洞里
and many, many more, went deep into the caves.

538
01:10:21,960 --> 01:10:25,310
我们曾是优秀的金矿挖掘者
We were noble gold miners

539
01:10:25,630 --> 01:10:28,310
因为我们可以在黑暗中看到细微的光亮
because we could see the light in the darkness.

540
01:10:31,140 --> 01:10:32,480
格斯 格斯
Gus. Gus?

541
01:10:33,930 --> 01:10:36,980
当时你还是个小男孩 但你该记得
You were just a boy, but you remember.

542
01:10:37,480 --> 01:10:40,150
当我们回到地面
When we returned to the surface,

543
01:10:42,360 --> 01:10:44,160
什么都没了
there was nothing.

544
01:10:44,780 --> 01:10:45,820
土地被烧焦
The land was blackened.

545
01:10:46,990 --> 01:10:48,960
所有东西 所有人都不见了
Everything, everyone was gone.

546
01:10:52,370 --> 01:10:53,490
都死了
Was dead.

547
01:10:54,830 --> 01:10:57,500
那是你父亲死后的一个月
That was the month your father died.

548
01:10:59,040 --> 01:11:00,090
我很抱歉
I'm very sorry.

549
01:11:00,170 --> 01:11:03,510
公主 我和你一样的难过
As am I, Princess. As am I.

550
01:11:04,630 --> 01:11:07,350
孩子 弹首欢快的歌儿吧
Son, play a happy song.

551
01:11:08,130 --> 01:11:11,680
为什么要浪费你的闲暇时间 失去快乐
Why spend your leisure Bereft of pleasure

552
01:11:11,850 --> 01:11:15,020
积累财富 为什么要挖掘节省
Amassing treasure why scrape and save?

553
01:11:15,390 --> 01:11:18,740
为什么要看紧一分一毫
Why look so canny at ev'ry penny?

554
01:11:18,900 --> 01:11:21,690
你将不会带着钱财进入坟墓
You'll take no money within the grave

555
01:11:22,980 --> 01:11:25,700
我知道我有点讨人厌
I know I'm a bit gicky,

556
01:11:27,030 --> 01:11:28,200
但是我可以请你跳舞吗
but would you care for a dance'?

557
01:11:29,030 --> 01:11:30,530
我很荣幸 格斯
I'd be honored, Gus.

558
01:11:31,700 --> 01:11:34,540
我们杯盏叮当碰 美酒一杯接一杯
Our glasses clinking and round and round

559
01:11:40,750 --> 01:11:43,720
所以 男孩 女孩们 因为岁月流逝
So, lads and lasses Because life passes

560
01:11:43,880 --> 01:11:47,880
来添满酒杯 再喝一轮
Come fill your glasses for another round

561
01:11:52,140 --> 01:11:57,900
不管缪尔说什么 我都不信任她 不相信她
I don't trust her, and I don't believe her. No matter what Muir says.

562
01:11:58,060 --> 01:11:59,980
我感觉很奇怪
I feel peculiar.

563
01:12:00,390 --> 01:12:01,570
可以说是很诡异
Queer almost.

564
01:12:01,730 --> 01:12:02,900
什么 什么时候开始的
What'? Since when?

565
01:12:03,060 --> 01:12:06,410
我不但浑身没有刺痛感了 还觉得很欢脱
I'm tingling all over, but I feel lovely.

566
01:12:06,570 --> 01:12:08,070
我感觉很愉悦
I feel lovely.

567
01:12:09,070 --> 01:12:10,490
你痛风怎么样了
How's your gout'?

568
01:12:10,660 --> 01:12:11,910
痛风吗
Gout?

569
01:12:14,870 --> 01:12:16,210
好些了
It's a bit better.

570
01:12:16,370 --> 01:12:17,420
我的咳嗽也好些了
And my cough.

571
01:12:18,080 --> 01:12:19,420
你懂的
You know,

572
01:12:20,250 --> 01:12:21,920
这都是受她所赐
this is her doing.

573
01:12:23,000 --> 01:12:24,250
你喝了多少酒啊
How much have you had to drink?

574
01:12:24,420 --> 01:12:26,170
不 是那些蘑菇
No, it was the mushrooms.

575
01:12:28,420 --> 01:12:30,930
得去上个厕所啊
Send a log downstream.

576
01:12:33,340 --> 01:12:36,100
旅途中的烦闷 经文中的骆驼
With hump for tramel the scripture's camel

577
01:12:36,260 --> 01:12:39,190
还在剥削我们的酒啊 猎人
Still fleecing us out of our bevvy, huntsman?

578
01:12:41,770 --> 01:12:43,690
我觉得你说过你会既往不咎的
What do you say we let bygones be bygones?

579
01:12:43,860 --> 01:12:45,610
还没
Not yet, nut-hook.

580
01:12:50,400 --> 01:12:51,780
抱一个
Hug.

581
01:12:51,950 --> 01:12:54,570
来添满酒杯 再喝一轮
Come fill your glasses for another round

582
01:12:57,950 --> 01:12:59,450
你是为了什么
So what's in it for you?

583
01:13:00,580 --> 01:13:02,080
你在说什么
What are you talking about?

584
01:13:02,580 --> 01:13:04,050
我在说那女孩
I'm talking about the girl.

585
01:13:05,790 --> 01:13:10,590
来填满酒杯 再喝一轮
Come fill your glasses for another round

586
01:13:10,760 --> 01:13:13,310
真的只是为了金币吗
Is it really just the gold?

587
01:13:14,590 --> 01:13:16,140
我说不清  贝斯
I'm not sure, Beith.

588
01:13:17,930 --> 01:13:20,180
如果我有一丝理智的话 早就弃她而去了
If I had any sense, I'd have abandoned her long ago.

589
01:13:20,270 --> 01:13:22,640
缪尔说她是注定的那个人
Muir says she's destined.

590
01:13:23,810 --> 01:13:27,950
问题是 猎人 注定为何
Question is, huntsman, for what?

591
01:13:28,610 --> 01:13:29,660
唔
Hmm?

592
01:15:00,370 --> 01:15:01,370
起来
Get up.

593
01:15:18,880 --> 01:15:21,810
父亲 那是什么 父亲
Father? What was that? Father?

594
01:15:21,970 --> 01:15:23,940
我知道了儿子 我知道了
I know, son, I know.

595
01:15:24,680 --> 01:15:25,770
是他
It's him.

596
01:16:26,660 --> 01:16:28,630
别动 猎人
No, no, no, huntsman.

597
01:16:29,120 --> 01:16:31,170
从没有见过如此这般场景
No one's ever seen this before.

598
01:17:03,610 --> 01:17:06,710
白色之心屈膝于公主前 父亲
The white hart bows before the Princess, Father.

599
01:17:08,540 --> 01:17:10,210
他在赐福于她
He's blessing her.

600
01:17:10,700 --> 01:17:12,330
你们在说什么
What are you talking about?

601
01:17:13,210 --> 01:17:15,880
有眼无珠的猎人 你和她在一起的时间最长
You have eyes, huntsman, but you do not see.

602
01:17:16,340 --> 01:17:18,840
却视而不见
You, who have been with her the longest.

603
01:17:19,550 --> 01:17:21,680
她就是万物生命之源
She is life itself.

604
01:17:22,630 --> 01:17:24,480
她将会治愈这片枯寂的大地
She will heal the land.

605
01:17:24,680 --> 01:17:27,060
她就是那个救世之人
She is the one.

606
01:17:32,270 --> 01:17:35,900
难道你们没有感觉到吗 难道你们的疾病还在吗
Can't you feel it? Are your ailments not gone?

607
01:17:36,690 --> 01:17:38,490
不论有没有黄金的赏赐
Gold or no gold,

608
01:17:38,650 --> 01:17:41,490
我都追随着她
where she leads, I follow.

609
01:17:41,650 --> 01:17:42,900
- 我也是  - 我同你一起
- Aye.  - I'm with you'

610
01:17:43,070 --> 01:17:44,070
是的 父亲
Yes, Father.

611
01:17:49,910 --> 01:17:51,000
有埋伏
Ambush!

612
01:17:51,080 --> 01:17:53,210
瞄准低处 瞄准低处
Aim low! Aim low!

613
01:18:04,470 --> 01:18:06,470
科尔 缪尔 捉住他
Coll, Duir, take him.

614
01:18:08,260 --> 01:18:09,760
格斯 你跟随公主
Gus, go with her.

615
01:18:19,520 --> 01:18:21,400
- 跟上我  - 你等等我
- Stay with me.  - Don't you wait for me.

616
01:18:29,740 --> 01:18:31,040
你先上
You first.

617
01:18:31,910 --> 01:18:33,080
我知道
I know.

618
01:18:51,100 --> 01:18:52,600
走 那边
Go. That way.

619
01:18:52,770 --> 01:18:54,190
快走
Go, go!

620
01:19:50,530 --> 01:19:52,370
不要 是我 威廉
No, no, it's me! It's William.

621
01:19:52,870 --> 01:19:53,910
我是威廉
It's William.

622
01:20:08,720 --> 01:20:11,220
我钦佩你的奋勇抵抗 猎人
I admire your fight, huntsman.

623
01:20:13,390 --> 01:20:15,060
你的妻子也一样
Your wife was the same.

624
01:20:15,220 --> 01:20:16,570
你什么意思 我妻子
What do you know of my wife?

625
01:20:16,720 --> 01:20:18,070
那些逝者 我全都记得
I remember them all.

626
01:20:21,020 --> 01:20:26,070
尤其是那些誓死抵抗的
But especially the ones with fight.

627
01:20:30,240 --> 01:20:31,580
她当时惊叫着你的名字
She screamed your name,

628
01:20:32,700 --> 01:20:35,000
可你不在
but you weren't there.

629
01:20:45,090 --> 01:20:48,340
现在 你可以在另一世界里乞求她的原谅了
Now, you can beg her forgiveness in the otherworld.

630
01:21:06,940 --> 01:21:07,990
妹妹
Sister,

631
01:21:08,940 --> 01:21:10,910
治愈我
heal me.

632
01:21:24,290 --> 01:21:26,040
原谅我 哥哥
Forgive me, brother.

633
01:21:30,960 --> 01:21:32,640
我感觉..
I feel...

634
01:22:01,700 --> 01:22:02,700
小心箭
Arrow!

635
01:22:20,350 --> 01:22:22,520
格斯 格斯
Gus. Gus!

636
01:22:27,940 --> 01:22:29,860
- 呼吸  - 呼吸就好
- Gus, breathe.  - Gus, breathe.

637
01:22:47,500 --> 01:22:49,380
我不会弃你而去 小姐
I won't leave you, miss.

638
01:23:34,000 --> 01:23:35,720
我们过去常常倍感自豪
We used to have pride.

639
01:23:36,380 --> 01:23:38,880
而如今我们偷窃 酗酒
And now we just pilfer and drink

640
01:23:40,390 --> 01:23:42,260
梦想着回到过去
and dream about when we didn't.

641
01:23:43,060 --> 01:23:47,940
在这的每个人都要誓死拼搏 成为像他这样的勇士
Every man here would die for the chance of becoming that man again.

642
01:23:49,560 --> 01:23:51,610
所以无论生死
So, we follow you, Princess,

643
01:23:51,770 --> 01:23:54,070
我们都要追随着你 公主
in life and in death.

644
01:23:54,230 --> 01:23:56,240
我将会再次赢回昔日的自豪感
And we shall have our pride again.

645
01:23:57,490 --> 01:24:01,040
以格斯之剑的名义 我起誓
On Gus's soul, this I swear.

646
01:24:17,380 --> 01:24:23,060
星辰暗淡 月光微暗
Dark the stars And dark the moon

647
01:24:25,850 --> 01:24:31,320
安静的夜晚 黎明潜在
Hush the night and the morning loon

648
01:24:32,560 --> 01:24:38,740
告诉马儿 敲响鼓声
Tell the horses and beat on your drum

649
01:24:40,150 --> 01:24:45,500
主人离去 太阳消失
Gone their master gone their sun

650
01:24:47,870 --> 01:24:53,340
大海黑暗 天空漆黑
Dark the oceans dark the sky

651
01:24:54,080 --> 01:25:00,060
安静的鱼群 还有潮汐
Hush the whales and the ocean tide

652
01:25:02,300 --> 01:25:08,270
告诉盐沼 敲响鼓声
Tell the salt marsh and beat on your drum

653
01:25:10,060 --> 01:25:12,730
主人离去
Gone their master

654
01:25:12,940 --> 01:25:16,940
太阳消失
Gone their sun

655
01:25:20,110 --> 01:25:25,790
黑夜白天 白天黑夜
Dark to light and light to dark

656
01:25:28,080 --> 01:25:33,250
三辆黑色马车 三辆白色推车
Three black carriages three white carts

657
01:25:36,590 --> 01:25:43,560
是什么将我们聚在一起 又是什么将我们分开
What brings us together's what pulls us apart

658
01:25:47,680 --> 01:25:54,650
失去兄弟 失去勇气
Gone our brother gone our heart

659
01:25:57,230 --> 01:25:59,110
对不起我离弃了你
I'm sorry I left you.

660
01:26:00,900 --> 01:26:02,320
你没有
You didn't.

661
01:26:03,740 --> 01:26:06,370
若我知道你还尚在...
If I'd have thought you were alive,

662
01:26:06,530 --> 01:26:08,530
我早就会去找你
I would have come for you.

663
01:26:09,580 --> 01:26:11,120
我们那时还是孩子 威廉
We were children, William.

664
01:26:12,830 --> 01:26:14,750
你现在找到我了
You're here now.

665
01:26:31,810 --> 01:26:37,230
安静的鱼群 还有潮汐
Hush the whales and the ocean tide

666
01:26:40,320 --> 01:26:46,700
告诉盐沼 敲响鼓声
Tell the salt marsh and beat on your drum

667
01:26:50,620 --> 01:26:56,970
主人离去 太阳消失
Gone their master gone their sun

668
01:27:31,950 --> 01:27:33,200
给你
Here.

669
01:27:51,510 --> 01:27:53,060
她一点都没变
She hasn't changed.

670
01:27:55,140 --> 01:27:57,730
她的内心依旧明朗
She has that same light inside her.

671
01:28:02,860 --> 01:28:04,530
你一定见识到了
You must see it.

672
01:28:05,780 --> 01:28:07,950
要是没有肯定是瞎了
You'd be blind if you didn't.

673
01:28:14,330 --> 01:28:16,550
自从失去她之后我每天都在思念她
Thought about her every day since I lost her.

674
01:28:20,120 --> 01:28:22,590
简直不能相信我找到了她
I can hardly believe I found her.

675
01:28:25,500 --> 01:28:27,350
你应该告诉她你的感觉
You should tell her how you feel.

676
01:28:27,420 --> 01:28:28,470
这样是对她好
It'd be good for her.

677
01:28:28,550 --> 01:28:29,550
不
No.

678
01:28:30,680 --> 01:28:31,930
我不知道怎样表达
I wouldn't know how.

679
01:28:33,550 --> 01:28:36,650
你不对一些人表达些这样的感觉
Your not telling someone something like that

680
01:28:37,520 --> 01:28:39,740
然后带着后悔过日
and living with the regret

681
01:28:40,560 --> 01:28:42,230
则是更糟糕
is a lot worse.

682
01:29:06,550 --> 01:29:07,720
威廉
William.

683
01:29:11,300 --> 01:29:13,470
好像这里的一切从未改变
It's as if nothing's changed here.

684
01:29:16,470 --> 01:29:19,690
世界似乎又美好了
The world seems beautiful again.

685
01:29:19,850 --> 01:29:20,940
会变得美好的
It Will be,

686
01:29:22,100 --> 01:29:23,570
当你成为王后的时候
when you are queen.

687
01:29:25,360 --> 01:29:28,610
这个国度的子民都对瑞雯娜痛恨至极
The people of this kingdom hate Ravenna with every fiber.

688
01:29:30,780 --> 01:29:32,450
我以前也恨她
I used to hate her.

689
01:29:34,450 --> 01:29:36,200
但现在我只感到悲伤
But now I feel only sorrow.

690
01:29:37,370 --> 01:29:38,710
一旦人们发现你还活着
Once people find out you're alive,

691
01:29:38,790 --> 01:29:40,040
他们会以你之名起义
they will rise up in your name.

692
01:29:42,460 --> 01:29:44,210
这不仅仅是名号的问题
It takes more than a name.

693
01:29:45,540 --> 01:29:47,670
你是你父亲的女儿
You are your father's daughter.

694
01:29:47,960 --> 01:29:49,840
合法继承人
The rightful heir.

695
01:29:51,630 --> 01:29:53,880
若我可以选择 我会带你远走高飞
If I had a choice, I'd take you far away.

696
01:29:56,890 --> 01:29:59,480
在我身边 保护你的安全
Keep you safe by my side.

697
01:30:00,310 --> 01:30:03,730
但我有职责 你也是
But I have a duty. And so do you.

698
01:30:04,730 --> 01:30:06,320
我该怎么鼓舞士气
How do I inspire?

699
01:30:08,230 --> 01:30:09,820
怎么统帅全军
How will I lead men?

700
01:30:11,570 --> 01:30:14,070
像我们儿时你带领我一样
The way you led me when we were children.

701
01:30:15,950 --> 01:30:17,820
无论哪里我都跟随你
I followed you everywhere.

702
01:30:19,450 --> 01:30:21,950
你叫我跑就跑
I ran when you called.

703
01:30:23,620 --> 01:30:26,170
我会为你做任何事情
I would have done anything for you.

704
01:30:28,080 --> 01:30:29,550
我记得可不是这样的
That's not how I remember it.

705
01:30:29,710 --> 01:30:32,010
- 不是吗  - 不是啊
- No?  -No.

706
01:30:33,470 --> 01:30:35,890
我们以前老是打架
And we used to fight all the time.

707
01:30:37,090 --> 01:30:38,560
还有争吵
And argue.

708
01:31:06,870 --> 01:31:08,420
还记得那个小把戏吗
Do you remember that trick?

709
01:31:08,630 --> 01:31:10,170
什么小把戏
What trick?

710
01:31:37,900 --> 01:31:39,500
你看孩提时代
You see, child,

711
01:31:41,280 --> 01:31:43,960
爱总是背叛我们
love always betrays us.

712
01:32:01,930 --> 01:32:03,310
醒醒
Wake up.

713
01:32:36,800 --> 01:32:40,220
只有最美的血液才能让我永葆青春 长生不老
By fairest blood it was done,

714
01:32:42,090 --> 01:32:48,600
也只有最美鲜红的血液会解除咒语
and only by fairest blood can it be undone.

715
01:32:50,020 --> 01:32:53,740
你是唯一一个能解除魔咒
You were the only one

716
01:32:53,900 --> 01:32:57,400
和摧毁我的人
who could break the spell and destroy me.

717
01:33:07,370 --> 01:33:09,370
也是唯一一个
And the only one

718
01:33:09,540 --> 01:33:11,510
纯净无暇
pure enough

719
01:33:12,830 --> 01:33:15,130
能够拯救我的人
to save me.

720
01:33:17,500 --> 01:33:21,810
你甚至不明白自己有多幸运
You don't even realize how lucky you are

721
01:33:21,970 --> 01:33:25,350
因为你从不知道什么是变老
never to know what it is to grow old.

722
01:33:25,510 --> 01:33:26,640
住手
NO!

723
01:33:52,120 --> 01:33:53,170
住手
No.

724
01:34:09,560 --> 01:34:12,230
快住手
No. No.

725
01:34:16,560 --> 01:34:18,690
你们在看什么 做点什么啊
What are you looking at'? Do something!

726
01:34:18,860 --> 01:34:20,400
你不是矮人治愈师吗
You're dwarves, healers.

727
01:34:20,570 --> 01:34:22,660
救救她 帮帮她
Save her. Help her.

728
01:34:27,530 --> 01:34:30,910
不 怎么会这样
No. This cannot be.

729
01:34:36,580 --> 01:34:39,590
别放弃 活下来
Please, please.

730
01:35:21,590 --> 01:35:22,630
别离开我
Please.

731
01:35:25,260 --> 01:35:27,480
贝斯 接下来我们怎么办
What do we do, Beith?

732
01:35:28,470 --> 01:35:30,190
履行我们的承诺
What we promised.

733
01:37:36,720 --> 01:37:38,560
如今你在此
Well, here you are.

734
01:37:39,890 --> 01:37:42,440
梳妆得体 就如你将要醒来
All dressed up, like you're about to

735
01:37:42,600 --> 01:37:44,600
带给我更多的悲伤 我说的对吗
wake up and give me more grief. Am I right'?

736
01:37:55,740 --> 01:37:57,960
你本该有更好的结局
You deserved better.

737
01:38:02,370 --> 01:38:04,880
我曾经有位妻子 公主
I once had a wife, Princess.

738
01:38:07,880 --> 01:38:10,300
她叫莎拉
Sara was her name.

739
01:38:11,550 --> 01:38:13,140
我离开战场回来时
When I came back from the wars,

740
01:38:13,220 --> 01:38:15,180
尸体的恶臭 死亡的气息
I carried with me the stench of death

741
01:38:15,340 --> 01:38:17,470
丧失战友的愤怒时刻萦绕着我
and the anger of the lost.

742
01:38:18,260 --> 01:38:22,390
我不值得被挽救 的确是 但不管怎样她还是这么做了
I wasn't worth saving, that's for sure. But she did so anyway.

743
01:38:24,350 --> 01:38:26,450
我太爱她了
And I loved her so much.

744
01:38:27,980 --> 01:38:29,780
我爱她超越了任何人 任何事
I loved her more than anyone or anything.

745
01:38:29,940 --> 01:38:33,820
可我.. 让她离开了我的视线 她便一去不复返
And then I let her out of my sight and she was gone.

746
01:38:37,740 --> 01:38:40,290
我再次回到以前的状态
And I became myself again.

747
01:38:40,450 --> 01:38:42,750
仿佛我从不介意自己这样
A self I never cared for.

748
01:38:47,750 --> 01:38:49,130
直到遇见你
Until you.

749
01:38:52,880 --> 01:38:55,100
因为你让我想起了她
See, you remind me of her.

750
01:38:57,340 --> 01:38:59,940
她的善心 她的志气
Her heart. Her spirit.

751
01:39:03,640 --> 01:39:06,360
可如今你也离开了人世
But now you, too, have gone'

752
01:39:07,020 --> 01:39:10,570
你俩都应得到更好的结局 实在对不起我让你失望了
You both deserved better, and I'm so sorry I failed you.

753
01:39:11,400 --> 01:39:13,030
实在对不起
I'm so sorry.

754
01:39:21,030 --> 01:39:23,540
但如今你会是天堂里的王后
But you'll be a queen in heaven now

755
01:39:24,410 --> 01:39:26,340
围坐在天使之中
and sit among the angels.

756
01:40:14,550 --> 01:40:16,170
她因我们而死
She died for us!

757
01:40:16,800 --> 01:40:18,390
为了我们
For our cause!

758
01:40:18,550 --> 01:40:20,430
我们不能就这样躲在城墙之下
We cannot just hide behind these walls

759
01:40:20,590 --> 01:40:22,470
看着她随这片土地消失殆尽
and watch this land die with her!

760
01:40:23,390 --> 01:40:25,640
我儿 你的悲伤混淆了你的判断力
Your grief clouds your judgment, my son.

761
01:40:27,680 --> 01:40:30,730
我的悲伤使我看的更清楚 父亲
My grief makes me see clearer, Father.

762
01:40:33,560 --> 01:40:36,940
我的职责是保护这些前来向我寻求帮助的人们
My duty is to protect those people who come to me for help.

763
01:40:37,990 --> 01:40:40,700
我会保护他们直到我剩下最后一滴血
I will defend them to the last drop of my blood,

764
01:40:41,780 --> 01:40:44,030
我不会放弃这些城墙
but I will not abandon these walls.

765
01:41:05,180 --> 01:41:07,060
咒语解除了
The spell is lifted.

766
01:41:38,460 --> 01:41:40,060
死亡曾青睐于你
Death has favored you.

767
01:41:40,210 --> 01:41:41,930
死亡不青睐于任何人
Death favors no man.

768
01:41:42,930 --> 01:41:43,970
我们必须出兵
We must ride

769
01:41:44,140 --> 01:41:47,510
在我父亲的战旗之下 像雷鸣闪电下的海浪般异军突起
like thundering waves under the tattered battle flag of my father.

770
01:41:47,850 --> 01:41:49,100
你必须休息
You must rest.

771
01:41:50,520 --> 01:41:52,110
我们已经休息了够久的了
We have rested long enough.

772
01:42:01,110 --> 01:42:03,700
霜冻燃烧 烈火结霜
Frost to fire and fire to frost.

773
01:42:08,740 --> 01:42:10,710
铁会融化
Iron will melt.

774
01:42:14,250 --> 01:42:17,380
但它的内心会痛苦
But it will writhe inside of itself!

775
01:42:20,380 --> 01:42:21,470
这些年来
All these years

776
01:42:22,800 --> 01:42:24,640
我所知的只有黑暗
all I've known is darkness.

777
01:42:26,890 --> 01:42:30,560
但我刚刚睁开双眼时 从未见过如此明亮之光
But I have never seen a brighter light than when my eyes just opened.

778
01:42:32,430 --> 01:42:35,560
我知道那束光芒燃烧在你们所有人心中
And I know that light burns in all of you!

779
01:42:37,810 --> 01:42:41,910
这些星星之火必须燃烧成火焰
Those embers must turn to flame.

780
01:42:43,990 --> 01:42:46,460
铁锻造成剑
Iron into sword!

781
01:42:46,570 --> 01:42:48,570
我会成为你们的武器
I will become your weapon!

782
01:42:49,580 --> 01:42:51,000
由熊熊烈火铸造而成
Forged by the fierce fire

783
01:42:51,160 --> 01:42:53,290
我知道这已是你们内心所向 心中所想
that I know is in your hearts!

784
01:42:55,410 --> 01:42:57,790
只因我已看到她所看到的
For I have seen what she sees.

785
01:42:59,590 --> 01:43:01,630
我知道她所知道的
I know what she knows.

786
01:43:04,010 --> 01:43:05,930
我能够杀了她
I can kill her.

787
01:43:09,930 --> 01:43:11,770
而且我宁愿今天死去
And I'd rather die today

788
01:43:13,020 --> 01:43:16,140
也不愿行尸走肉般的多活一天
than live another day of this death!

789
01:43:18,850 --> 01:43:20,950
谁会随我出征
And who will ride with me'?

790
01:43:21,860 --> 01:43:23,030
谁愿成为我的战友
Who will be my brother?

791
01:43:23,650 --> 01:43:25,120
我们
Aye!

792
01:44:11,740 --> 01:44:13,490
再见 公主
Farewell, Princess.

793
01:44:37,680 --> 01:44:39,030
他们到哪了
Where are they?

794
01:44:39,190 --> 01:44:40,900
大批人马聚集在悬崖边
Amassed on the cliffs.

795
01:44:41,060 --> 01:44:43,030
数目仍在增长
Their numbers have swollen.

796
01:44:43,360 --> 01:44:46,110
他们说国王的圣灵已再次升起
They say the King's standard flies again.

797
01:44:47,070 --> 01:44:48,610
那就让他们放马过来
Then let them come.

798
01:44:49,360 --> 01:44:53,580
让他们的头颅粉碎在这石墙之上吧
And let them break their skulls on these stone walls

799
01:44:53,950 --> 01:44:56,200
顺便带来我的战利品
and bring me my prize.

800
01:45:12,720 --> 01:45:13,770
殿下
My lord,

801
01:45:13,890 --> 01:45:16,060
在潮汐来临之前我们只剩下几个小时
we only have a few hours before the tide comes in.

802
01:45:16,220 --> 01:45:18,400
时间紧迫 不足以攻破城墙
Not long enough to breach the castle walls.

803
01:45:18,560 --> 01:45:19,980
没有其他入口吗
Is there no other way in?

804
01:45:20,140 --> 01:45:21,440
有一个
There is another way.

805
01:45:25,310 --> 01:45:27,490
我去 伙计们 这可不是我们的活
Hi-ho, lads, it's off to work.

806
01:45:27,650 --> 01:45:30,530
要是他开始吹口哨 我打烂他的脸
If he starts whistling, I'll smash his face in.

807
01:45:35,570 --> 01:45:36,580
没错
YES.

808
01:45:36,830 --> 01:45:38,830
承诺给我们的金币呢 看看现在我们得到些啥
We're promised gold and what do we get'?

809
01:45:38,990 --> 01:45:40,090
屎
POO!

810
01:45:40,250 --> 01:45:42,040
矮人族要多矮会被淹没
How low has the dwarf race sunk?

811
01:45:45,080 --> 01:45:46,630
那个洞看起来合我的身材
That looks like one of mine.

812
01:45:46,960 --> 01:45:47,960
拿着这个
Hold this!

813
01:46:09,820 --> 01:46:11,240
行了
All right.

814
01:46:11,320 --> 01:46:13,070
警卫室在右边50米处
The gatehouse is 50 yards to the right.

815
01:46:13,240 --> 01:46:14,960
但那里有一只军队
And there's a whole army out there.

816
01:46:15,280 --> 01:46:17,330
六个小矮人对付一只军队
Six dwarves against an army?

817
01:46:18,120 --> 01:46:19,990
我喜欢这胜算
I like them odds.

818
01:46:22,120 --> 01:46:24,590
我们必须现在出发 掉闸会被打开
We must ride now. The portcullis will be open.

819
01:46:30,920 --> 01:46:33,930
所以说 你起死回生 并且煽动群众
So, you're back from the dead and instigating the masses.

820
01:46:37,800 --> 01:46:40,020
你的盔甲看起来很合身
You look very fetching in mail.

821
01:46:44,520 --> 01:46:45,940
我们出发
We ride!

822
01:46:50,150 --> 01:46:53,780
我们紧跟对方 整体行动
All right. We move as one.

823
01:46:58,280 --> 01:46:59,500
你先走
After you.

824
01:47:14,630 --> 01:47:17,480
嘿 走 走 走
Hey, go, go,go

825
01:48:35,550 --> 01:48:36,760
不好意思
Sorry.

826
01:48:40,880 --> 01:48:41,890
什么情况 科尔
What's happening, Coll'?

827
01:48:42,140 --> 01:48:43,310
他们到海边了
They're on the beach!

828
01:48:50,060 --> 01:48:51,280
发射
Release!

829
01:49:32,140 --> 01:49:34,150
预备 放箭
Ready! Release!

830
01:49:39,150 --> 01:49:40,320
放箭
Release!

831
01:49:54,830 --> 01:49:57,180
赶快 赶快
Go, go, go!

832
01:50:00,710 --> 01:50:02,590
被破坏了
The summit's breached!

833
01:50:09,680 --> 01:50:11,020
退后你 加油
Back here, lads! Come on!

834
01:50:11,180 --> 01:50:12,690
快回去拉
Get back to it!

835
01:50:25,700 --> 01:50:27,670
用力 拉 奈恩 去拉那条绳子
Pull! Nion, get on that rope!

836
01:50:27,830 --> 01:50:29,580
用力 继续
Come on! Go on!

837
01:50:30,700 --> 01:50:31,750
奎特
Quert!

838
01:50:34,250 --> 01:50:35,300
外面简直就是屠杀
It's a massacre down there!

839
01:50:35,370 --> 01:50:37,170
高特 那根绳
Gort, on that rope!

840
01:50:39,040 --> 01:50:40,390
我们必须掉头回去
We must turn back!

841
01:50:40,670 --> 01:50:43,170
不 我向他们承诺过
No! I gave them my word!

842
01:50:43,340 --> 01:50:44,680
搞定了 到那去
It's over! Get on now!

843
01:50:49,890 --> 01:50:50,890
动了
She's moving.

844
01:50:52,390 --> 01:50:53,610
你们做到了 伙计
You done it, lads!

845
01:50:59,020 --> 01:51:00,700
冲
Charge!

846
01:51:01,320 --> 01:51:02,320
驾
Ya!

847
01:51:12,200 --> 01:51:14,830
队列 队列
Form! Form!

848
01:53:01,270 --> 01:53:02,690
威廉
William!

849
01:55:27,210 --> 01:55:30,510
来 替父报仇吧
Come and avenge your father

850
01:55:31,170 --> 01:55:34,590
他太懦弱 不敢举起他的剑
who was too weak to raise his sword.

851
01:55:39,590 --> 01:55:40,810
哈
Ah.

852
01:55:53,860 --> 01:55:54,860
继续
Go on.

853
01:55:56,190 --> 01:55:58,450
看着他们死吧
Watch them die.

854
01:56:14,550 --> 01:56:16,220
感觉如何
How does it feel,

855
01:56:16,380 --> 01:56:19,230
当你知道你才是那个带领他们走向死亡的人
knowing you were the one who led them to their deaths?

856
01:56:19,630 --> 01:56:20,640
你瞧
You see?

857
01:56:20,720 --> 01:56:23,440
咱俩并不是毫不相同 不是吗
We're not that different, are we?

858
01:56:26,100 --> 01:56:27,730
我是你所没有的一切
I'm everything you're not.

859
01:56:50,920 --> 01:56:53,800
你们不能战胜我
You cannot defeat me!

860
01:56:54,920 --> 01:56:58,050
我活了太久
I've lived too many lives.

861
01:56:58,470 --> 01:57:00,930
掠夺了整个王国
Ravaged entire kingdoms.

862
01:57:01,340 --> 01:57:05,470
我被授予的法力 你们甚至无法理解
I have been given powers that you could not even fathom!

863
01:57:08,270 --> 01:57:09,690
我永远不会停止
I will never stop.

864
01:57:11,100 --> 01:57:12,520
永远不会
Never

865
01:57:14,650 --> 01:57:21,870
我将会给予可悲世界应有的王后
I will give this wretched world the queen it deserves.

866
01:57:26,620 --> 01:57:29,670
最鲜红的血液来完成这咒语
By fairest blood, it is done!

867
01:57:46,720 --> 01:57:49,470
也只有最美的血液才能摧毁你
And only by fairest blood is it undone.

868
01:58:46,160 --> 01:58:48,530
我不能拥有我的心
You can't have my heart.

869
02:00:00,400 --> 02:00:04,320
以这土地上所有圣洁美好之名
In the name of all that is good and just in this land

870
02:00:04,480 --> 02:00:06,450
我加冕你为王后
I crown you queen.

871
02:00:49,070 --> 02:00:50,620
向王后致敬
Hail to the Queen!

872
02:00:51,410 --> 02:00:53,280
向王后致敬
Hail to the Queen!

873
02:00:53,660 --> 02:00:55,330
向王后致敬
Hail to the Queen!

874
02:00:55,660 --> 02:00:57,330
向王后致敬
Hail to the Queen!

875
02:00:57,660 --> 02:00:59,660
向王后致敬
Hail to the Queen!

