--==麦克风博客 http://brucettt.info/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
Guardian of the Universe ...
Protection against the superpowers
of this man?
He can catch a ball.
Look at the sky. Is it a bird?
They are protected by an extraordinary
group of men and women ...
who have dedicated themselves
to fighting crime.
The forces of them go beyond the
competence of earthlings.
I was always wonder why
nobody ever did for me.
I mean, all those comic books,
movies and TV shows ...
You'd think a costume n eccentric
loner had made.
Is everyday life really
so exciting?
Are the schools and offices so exciting
that I just fantasize about?
Be honest with yourself.
At one point in our lives ...
we all want a super hero.
I am not.
This is a Armenir with mental
health problems.
Who am I? I Kick Ass.
I am. Before the madness began.
I'm not saying that something
was wrong with me.
But there is not
anything special.
I did not really sports.
I was not 'mateleet.
Whether a hardcore gamer.
I had no piercings.
Or an eating disorder.
Or 3000 friends on MySpace.
My only superpower was invisible
to the girls.
And my friends, I was
not the funniest.
Like most people my age,
I just existed.
Good morning, class.
Turn your book open.
It seems you do.
If you're pushing at my bedroom
door, I think watching TV.
Or I talk to my friend
Todd on Skype.
Do you watch Family Guy
- No.
Neither do I.
Go to nippleslip.com,
that's good.
Or subtraction.
Mostly because of my
English teacher.
Dave Lizewski do not you think
I see you looking at my tits?
I want you to touch me. Please.
What I mean by the
school helped ...
was a contribution to make in the 'relief
department store for later.
To be honest, there was not much
need for me to get excited.
If my hormones are balanced, the
plunging shares of Kleenex.
You would not now be
looking to Hamlet?
Yes, Mrs. Zane.
Sorry.
I also like girls my own age.
Sure Katie Deauxma.
- Hello, beautiful.
No, you referred to Erika.
I knew that.
I was just kidding.
Look, I'm Todd's mother.
This is funny. This is your father.
- No, that's still my mother.
I was just an ordinary boy.
... No radioactive spiders
No refugee status of a doomed
world of extraterrestrials.
Todd says she still "Count
Chocula" make.
They sell not only
in the stores.
My mother is deceased to an
aneurisme in the kitchen.
Not by a hitman in an alley.
So if you're hoping for some ...
- I will avenge you, mother.
Then you have no luck.
In the 18 months since my
mother is deceased ...
is the only revelation I had,
I realized that life goes on.
Have they changed
the face of who?
No.
Why has nobody ever tried
to be a superhero?
I do not know.
Perhaps because it
is impossible.
A mask, and help people,
why is that impossible?
That's not a superhero.
Super if you're stronger
than anyone.
And so fly, that's a hero.
No, that's not a hero.
This is psychologically
disturbed.
Bruce Wayne had no powers?
Yes, but he had all the expensive
junk that does not exist.
I thought you meant, why does
nobody in real life.
Yes, I meant that.
- If someone does that
in real life ...
they get a kick in the ass, then
they are dead within one day.
I'm not saying they should do it, I just
do not understand why nobody does.
Of all the millions of people
who love superheroes ...
one that would still endeavor.
Are not you cross?
Thousands like Paris Hilton,
why nobody Spiderman.
Yes, it really has no tits.
Maybe it's the porn tape.
He has no porn tape.
Have you ever "One Night
in Spiderman've seen?
Who do you think?
Do you also feel sorry
for Chris D'Amico?
It must be terrible to have a rich father
and everything you want to have.
Did you not say that,
later I still cry.
He was always alone.
Go talk to him.
See if he wants to
come sit with us.
Well, talk to him ...
Great if he wanted to be our friend.
Then motherfuckers never
someone with us.
Come on, Todd. I can ...
- No.
Should I talk to him
- to go Dave.
What?
- You really gotta go.
You're a dick.
- Do not be afraid, Dave.
You're a sissy.
Fuck you.
Have you leaked
- I got into my pants.
I had caught him.
If you ever have someone
kick his ass dungeon
I would go for his knees.
You chattering nonsense.
- The power of Batman ...
went through the force
field of the Joker ...
Patrol sissies.
Telephones, money ...
Come on.
Tel.
- This last week
has been stolen.
Sissy.
Give me the bag then.
- These are just comic books.
Would you be stabbed?
That bastard just looks.
Be honest with yourself.
Would you do differently?
We see someone in trouble,
we would like to help ...
but we do not.
The world in which I lived, there
are only heroes in comic books.
That would not be bad if the bad
guys were or even fantasies.
But they are not.
Frankie, I am really
not making this up.
This guy comes from nowhere, and gives us a
lot of our thunder, and steals the coke.
The guy in 'Batman' looks?
I said no.
That you have said.
He had a mask and so on.
- And a cape?
Like Batman.
- I never said, like Batman.
So I have a problem with it.
Our mole says that the Russians
make things different.
According to him, you have sold them
my coke, and have usurped the money.
That is a lie.
That you believe that nonsense
from a Russian.
What's more likely ...
that you're a greedy
little dick ...
or that all my coke stolen
from Superman?
Batman.
- I never said that.
Enough!
My son is waiting in the
car to go to the movie.
I do not disappoint him.
Joe, you're in charge.
That's the worst excuse
I ever heard, Tre.
Sorry you had to wait.
- The movie starts
in ten minutes.
'll Be fine.
We lack only the trailers.
But I want popcorn.
- That I buy it for you.
You want a Pepsi?
- Good.
He is a Pepsi and I icee.
Mixed.
Just as they mix the
red and blue.
And a suit Twist Handlers.
The comic books were wrong.
There was no trauma required,
or cosmic rays, a super hero.
Only the perfect combination of optimism
and navigational capacity.
You're awesome!
Come on. Go ahead.
I'm scared, Dad.
- Come on, Mindy, you're
a big girl.
You have nothing to be afraid.
Does it really hurt
- but a moment.
A shot up by more than 1100
kilometers per hour.
Up close, you will surely be
thrown down by the force ...
but it is really no more painful
than a slap on your chest.
I hate when I get a
slap on my chest.
Everything will be fine.
That was not so bad?
But nice anyway?
Now you know how it feels.
Now you no longer fear as
a junkie pulls a Glock.
I would not have been afraid.
- That's the spirit. Get up.
Twice, then go home.
- Again?
Only if we go bowling on the way.
- Bowling?
Yes, and then ice.
More than twice.
Not cringe, not whining,
you have a deal.
I want a hot fudge sundae.
- Good choice.
What more could you want
for your birthday?
Can I have a puppy?
You want a dog
- a fluffy stuffed animal.
And a movie star makeover
Bratz Sasha doll.
I'll take you but a fool.
I want a handmade model 42 butterfly.
- Child, you always
take me a fool.
You get two.
Two
- And two, that you get.
I'll be honest.
In the first weeks there
was not much crime.
Yet I loved my new
job pretty busy.
I called it "preparation".
But if you 'fantasy', is nothing
against this situation.
I only knew that I had
never felt so good.
Maybe I was still in the Beta testing
phase, but it was a start.
What are you looking at?
Nothing.
- Thurs then.
As if each knew the serial killer, ultimately
does not fantasize for you.
It was time to get involved.
What is that?
What you looking at?
I said, 'Where are
you looking at?
Two losers cheap balls with a car where
someone has worked for destroyed.
What?
- Let go, man.
He is clearly high.
- I am not.
You only think you can
do whatever you want.
Go away from the vehicle,
and we forget this.
You're crazy.
Get out.
I was just conscious enough to beg the
doctor to say nothing about the suit.
That he promised.
I just knew my dad
would murder me.
Why do I get a gun? I'm a guard.
You are now a door, you
will get no more gun.
I look like an idiot.
- You look good with
all those buttons.
Do your work and make
that door open.
Happy days.
Tomorrow, Frank.
- How are you, Joe?
Fine.
- Want some coffee?
Maybe later. Tomorrow, Nance.
Chris.
- Morning, Joe.
There is a problem.
A big problem.
Sorry, honey.
- Do what you gotta do.
Where are you going?
- I need to talk to Dad.
Frank, honey.
Where are you going?
- I do not mind you talking
about things.
I'm going to sit there quietly.
I must still learn things.
Eat your oatmeal on.
- I am 18 about eight months.
Sit down.
What is the problem?
Our Russian says Tre just sold another 5 kg.
At half the price.
What Tre
- Tre Dead.
Now I get so screwed by a ghost
- or Tre told the truth.
Is this my choice?
Do I believe in ghosts,
or superheroes?
No super hero, but I think someone
has taken him to graze.
Let our Rus invite
a friendly chat.
Let's see what's
really going on.
Early bird, you have me.
I wanted this morning for
breakfast you get.
Congratulations, honey.
Look.
Thank you.
Daddy.
Cool, Dad.
- Ask.
What is the correct name for this?
- Easy, Filipino.
Still n.
- Excellent. Good.
The AR 15 was a smaller lighter
version of what caliber?
Eugene Stoner's AR 10.
Come and work hard.
The name of the first film by John Woo.
- Tie Han Rou Qing.
The young dragon.
Daddy, look. You're not looking.
And those bastards killing
our boys so.
Until we know who it is, I want no
more of you on your ass down.
Yes, that is training.
Moment. Dad, phone!
There is phone for you.
- Who is it?
What is the problem
- we have the vice here anymore.
Really?
We do have a brand new industrial microwave
which they use for woodworking.
That is beautiful.
You confuse me with someone who
apparently something to wood.
All right, I'm sorry.
- I want information.
Go ahead.
- The boys, Tre Fernandez.
What do I know?
Now you say that Fernandez is dead.
- Shut up.
He lied.
This works as a real wave?
What I know of.
I do not eat. Turn it on.
I want to know who
our coke sold.
And say this time, someone
who is dead.
I said, 'Who was our
cocaine you sold.
Who told you we sell coke?
Some time later.
This is great.
I have been Wolverine.
Did they have metal detectors
in school?
Yes, they will collapse.
I must ask you something.
According to the police report, you were found naked.
You do not remember why.
The robbers do not you ...
What?
No, I was not even ...
They took my clothes thrown
away in the ambulance.
By the blood.
- Right.
In no time I was better again.
What is Dave?
Outside some damaged
nerve endings ...
the doctors have me
pretty botched.
Did you know?
- No.
You look like Jason Bourne is.
And then
- No.
Let it sit.
I'm only half a day back, and through
you I miss the hospital now al
He's right. I do very childish.
- Stop it.
How are you? You look better.
Much better.
You fond of cartoons?
Erica and I sometimes go after
school that nice shop ...
Atomic Comics, who make
the best mocha.
Yes?
I would sometimes go with you, if
you need someone to talk to.
Please, thank you.
- Well, see you later.
Did you know?
Katie Deauxma invites
me for coffee.
I do not think that looks like.
- What are you talking about?
Katie Deauxma is only quitters.
What has that to do with me
- I've been thinking
how to tell.
There is a rumor ...
that you're a gay
- a gay?
What rumor is that
- and if you are robbed ...
You were robbed
- I know, but ...
We are not beaten up, and our
clothes are not taken away.
That's not true.
The doctors have thrown
away my clothes.
Rumors mean nothing.
We know the truth.
Maybe you helped to fuck.
Not if she thinks
that he is gay.
Backward.
- Help me better.
I'm just honest.
I became my old self again.
I had of course it must stop.
But you can not reprogram
yourself ...
what you want, who you are
and your purpose in life.
I'm here just some.
It is what it is.
Who never saw you, h?
You better run away.
Maybe you should not do.
What?
Are you looking at me?
This is my business.
I am a masked mi
daadbestrijdiger.
My hardware was now made.
I was back, and work under
Kick Ass Version 2.0.
Has anyone seen Mr. Bitey?
Have you seen this cat?
- No.
Great.
Come here, kitty.
Come here, Mr. Bitey.
No, Mr. Bitey, come on.
Come here, I'll bring you home.
Get the pip, Mr. Bitey.
I am so sorry.
- Fucking bastard.
Thank you, freak.
Leave them alone.
- Let me go.
It's your business.
True.
Call 112.
A boy dressed as a superhero
saves a few others together.
It's great.
Leave him alone.
Give it up, man. Just walk away.
No, never.
- What happened to you?
Rather you die for a piece of
crap you do not even know?
And then three assholes who take one
tackle while everyone watches?
Want to know what's
wrong with me?
Yes, I would rather die then.
But come on.
You're crazy.
What?
- Thank you.
That was great. Who are you?
I Kick-Ass.
Look at this.
- What is that?
A costumed vigilante has become the
latest internet phenomenon ...
after someone in the Hamilton Park filmed
him during an intervention ...
in an attack by a gang.
- This is great.
Welcome to this special broadcast
of Eye on New York.
How far would you go to
your neighbor to help?
This colorful person has this
week made headlines.
A video of his involvement in the
violence of a street gang ...
was the most common clip
on the Internet.
38 my MySpace friends.
MySpace Kick Ass 16,000
and rising.
This went beyond all.
And I thought it was awesome.
We want to know who this man is.
Does anyone know who the father
cross-suit that is?
He must be someone's
son or brother ...
one's neighbor.
- Crikey mina.
What happened
- what happened? This boy.
Everyone now feels a superhero.
Kick-Ass.
I like kick-ass awesome.
- He has a terrible suit.
Kick-Ass is all great.
His clip was good.
He had a suit on
his ass can get.
Then he had himself "Kick
Ass," to call.
That makes no sense.
This is the guy his death.
I would email him when
I have a problem.
I have 100 guys who can solve a problem.
N so I do not need.
I do not want to interfere in your
affairs, if I'm not wanted.
You think I'm Kick-Ass,
but that's not me.
I'm very busy now.
Sorry. Later. Kick-Ass
Hi, Dave. How about that coffee?
You do not read comics.
I am just started.
That boy had given me a few recommended
Scott Pilgrim, Sjoho Beat.
I'm not as familiar with
all the superhero stuff.
Then you're not in line for
the new comic Kick-Ass?
I do not think so.
I was really thinking about his site email.
I can help to good use.
Help? What then?
You know I am a volunteer
at the drug clinic?
I did not.
There is a boy, Rasul.
I had such a pity for him.
The more I heard about
his childhood ...
That's weird.
I'm usually the one who
plays therapist.
Can I confess something?
Since I was little, I always want
to have a friend like you.
May I say that?
That is not homophobic?
I do not think you're
quite the same.
Of course not.
Thank you.
I do not know if I was what Cathy had dreamed
as a "gay best friend forever."
But I did my best.
And more importantly, I persuaded
her to Kick Ass-mail.
A long story short.
This special weakling of her ...
showed a more stupid cobra.
She wanted the money back
that they had given him.
Or an apology for the blue
eye that he had given her.
She just wanted it understood
that it was over.
And he left her alone.
Let's be realistic ...
no other request would have
done me more pleasure.
What do you suggest?
The green condom?
Halloween is only a few months.
I came to Rasul.
Who are you?
- A friend of Katie.
Kids today ...
Who of you is Rasul?
I am Rasul.
Can not you see my big tits?
Is it candy or I'll
shoot or something?
Now I am dead.
- I have a message for Rasul ...
Katie Deauxma.
Rasul are you?
Now you have to stay
away from Katie.
It's over.
Leave her alone, everything
is in order.
Who should you, then?
And what is this?
- I Kick-Ass.
Find it.
And I give you this by ...
Leave Katie alone.
And otherwise?
Otherwise I will return
and break your legs.
Come on.
Hold him.
You go there really.
Ok, dicks.
Let's see what you can do now.
Alpine, meeny, moe ...
So I have one too.
Come on
- You want to play?
This is a mieterige tazer.
Relax. We are on the same team.
Stand up.
Hit-Girl, we always stand
with their backs to ...
Against the wall, Daddy. I know.
It will not happen again.
Nice shot.
- Thank you.
Come on.
Asshole, not by the front door.
Wait.
Who are you?
- I?
I am Hit-Girl.
And that is Big Daddy.
Come on.
Big Daddy and Hit-Girl.
They were the real thing.
And I was just an
idiot in a suit.
What am I here now?
Sal's phone.
This is found in his hand.
That he must have caught
just before he died.
This sounds crazy, but the
guy in the picture ...
that's crazy that
the TV superhero.
Who, Kick-Ass? And man?
If a man killed eight
of our people?
Eight of Sal, in which
four children Rasul.
There is nothing on
the street so?
And man.
- I think they are.
If you have similar, we seem
to have a bunch of sissies.
What do you want me to do?
Kick-Ass I want his head on a stick.
Now.
I have not told anything.
I swear.
Good, Ass-Kick.
Let's keep it that way.
You know what this is?
That shit from your
mieterige tazertje.
The police here so you
can detect them.
Fortunately I've picked up.
Thank you.
- Say for security.
Now it's easier for
you to believe.
We can see, but we trust you.
Nothing personal.
We trust nobody.
I've checked your IP address.
It was too simple to find you.
Not considered.
I am your anything.
I wanted my site is already shut.
This is crazy.
I'm up to my neck in.
- Unfortunately, you
have potential.
Your choice.
We are nearby if you need us.
How can I reach
- but to call the mayor.
He has a sign in the sky shines
in the form of a dick.
Put on your website that you are on vacation.
We believe you.
Hit-Girl, back to headquarters.
Dreams.
You must remove Kick-Ass.
- What is it?
What is?
He makes my people off, Gigante.
Condolences, but this is
beyond my jurisdiction.
Your jurisdiction?
You sit in the police and
he is breaking the law.
He sits down to his ass
in your jurisdiction.
I grab criminals, you pay
me for not doing so.
The other is a gray area.
- Just do it simply.
Unbelievable.
Where's Cody? It is too late.
Thank you, Cody.
We appreciate your cooperation.
Can I look now?
I've told all the names
and addresses.
I say nothing.
Take it from who you want.
I know a lot of bad characters.
Very nasty individuals.
Do not. Come on.
Please, no.
What a dick.
Have you ever used self tanner?
- Yes, I always do.
Murder, superheroes who hack
into my bedroom ...
my life was a dream where
I was not awake.
Even the beautiful pieces
were unreal.
Those old Spider-Man comics
of yours were pretty good.
That they are.
I have one week of Rasul
heard nothing.
That's great.
There were two super agents once
called Daddy and Marcus.
They were good at picking
up bad guys.
Frank D'Amico was the worst.
And he devised a plan
to get rid of Daddy.
Search for it here.
Expose him as a drug dealer was the
worst that could happen to Daddy.
The prison was not his
natural environment.
He was very upset.
Police Held in jail.
Now Daddy was imprisoned,
his pregnant wife alone.
She could not.
But every cloud has a silver
lining, and her death ...
Mindy was born.
Mark was her guardian.
Daddy and devised a plan itself.
Five years later he
Fri he was ready.
Now there's Mindy was ready.
How did you find me, Marcus?
- And one of us is still a cop.
Mindy so brainwashed you
- you say that. I say a game.
A game, Damon?
Own right play, mass murder?
Where is she
- she is safe.
Can I see her? I miss her.
I miss you both.
- I do appreciate your concern.
But you have to go now.
I must warn you that Gigante
to Kick-Ass is looking for.
Does that have anything to do with you?
A cut superhero club
or something?
Never heard of.
- You've been warned.
If you go you will
find him soon.
He has worked for D'Amico
you that since declined.
You know I do not lose.
Not until D'Amico and his whole
operation have become ashes.
And buried.
As you get her back.
This is Mindy's life.
You owe her a childhood.
I'll tell you who it
is owed a youth?
Frank D'Amico.
I do not believe this.
Follow him around the corner.
Not so fast.
Why the hands? I will give him.
What nonsense.
Continue to follow him.
Not too close.
He goes into the alley.
Stop when I tell you. Ready?
How are you?
My men finish? Steal my coke?
What are you doing? We gotta go.
Frank, he is not worth it.
Come on.
Where do you look to now?
Step.
He was so young.
He did not deserve to die so.
I can not believe he's dead.
I know.
Katie, like Rasul men caught
up in things ...
If it was my fault?
To Kick-Ass it's done?
Should I call the police?
- You talk nonsense.
He has your e-mail may
never have read.
Do not worry.
I'm glad you're here.
I'm a wreck.
It's okay. No problem.
- You're amazing.
Hopefully I can say this, it's
so fucking gay that you are.
Kick-Ass impersonator killed
- Unbelievable.
What the hell is that
for comedian.
A Spider-Man party for children,
good, but a kick-ass party?
They even sell paper plates
and napkins in the store?
Frank, you're scaring me.
When you make your
hands dirty again?
You had to deliver kick-ass, so ...
- We have been working one week.
We have emailed him.
Half the team is bait.
We work us out of the seam.
What are you doing?
Use your stuff back?
"Mommy, I want a kick-ass party.
Stupid children.
I know how you can catch him.
How long are you there?
On Thurs.
Want to hear
- hear what?
You're a superhero and lonely,
you can not trust anyone ...
He reads comic books all day.
A super hero but in a
strange way n trust.
I can be that strange.
Give me a chance.
I just have a few things.
- What?
This is what I need.
Is this a joke? What's this?
Everything I need.
Maybe someone there rags.
Louie or something.
Or someone else.
- Tony.
I hate Tony.
- Tony is an asshole.
I swear this will work.
Tony Romeda, one of America's
wanted criminals ...
is arrested today in Queens.
After a call from someone ...
who claimed to be
a superhero ...
How's Katie?
Great. I sleep ...
and we have all night to
look Ugly Betty ...
other's nails done.
The longer you wait,
the worse it gets.
I would tell her, but
she is so happy.
This is your chance.
Did she see it?
Have you watched TV,
the new super hero?
Look. Can something harder?
But this individual, who
called Red Mist ...
Crime is at a new level ...
as he showed last night.
What did you say?
They do not want to
live in fear ...
Kick-Ass and proves that n individuals
can change anything.
If someone need help, I am
every week usable ...
with just one click
on redmist.org.
Will it matter?
What is so special about him?
He has a big drug
dealer arrested.
And a lot of drugs found.
- That's pretty cool.
And he has a better costume.
- And a cape. Those are cool.
Cape that allows him well.
Better than Kick Ass
- They are both good ...
but Red Mist has a better body.
Do not you?
Yes, Dave. Nothing for you, all that leather?
- He's not really my type.
Say what Red Mist.
Kick-Ass.
- Red Mist.
That hurt.
All right
- all right.
You are here. You're my hero.
You have inspired me.
No Kick-Ass Red Mist no.
Really?
- Sure.
If you want me ... get your assistant
- my assistant?
You and I can handle everything.
Want to fight crime
- now?
I want to show you something.
I normally work only between
two and nine.
I should be back.
Great.
Is this yours?
- See Mist Mobile.
GPS, iPhone for the site's
emergency move ...
what mood lighting.
Rear view cameras,
nothing special.
And you'll love this.
The fog.
Therefore we are superheroes.
They love us.
Smoking?
Cannabis extracts the
stress a little.
That gang is a bit scary, right?
Is there anything
- you're different
than I thought.
I have received an email from a girl.
She says that someone follows
her from her work.
I have her address. Would you look
- why not.
We're naked, they sit on my lap,
I ask what was in her mind.
He is on the way.
- Very well.
Do not call him before
I get there.
Comics still have something
delivered.
Your boy has done well.
He resembles his father.
Almost forgot.
What is that?
Do you:
- There are people in there.
Should we fire ...
Red Mist.
Can you hear me?
Where are you?
We have to leave. Hurry.
Did you see that look?
- Yes.
Why you saved the bear
- What?
No idea, come on.
And?
What are you doing?
You know I can not be.
What is it?
- Kick-Ass burned down
my warehouse.
Calm. Kick-Ass
- You gotta help me.
My son was there.
He is still missing.
They're all dead!
Everybody from the
warehouse, dead!
Weapon away. It's Chris.
Chris Red Mist?
Make you more worried
about Kick-Ass.
No, he's just a nerd.
Do not worry about him.
Look at this.
What does it do?
- Really now?
Put you down.
What are you doing?
What is that?
You bought it to spy on
the nanny, remember?
You placed in the warehouse?
Yeah, I thought it was cool to the
unmasking of Kick-Ass online.
Look.
Who is that guy?
- No idea, Dad.
Kick-Ass said we were
not the only heroes.
Maybe he knows who this guy is.
Close this place down.
Nobody comes in or out.
Until somebody shoots
asshole mess.
They sit on your heels.
You hear me?
I thought she looked
Kick-Ass ...
Not anymore.
Gigante wants us to
find another hero.
He has a warehouse in a lot
of D'Amico's people killed.
That was you sure?
I had the cameras turned off.
- Apparently not.
You must hide as soon
as possible.
I appreciate it.
Mindy ...
No more homework ...
it is time to go bye
bye Frank D'Amico.
X-Men, Fantastic Four ...
now I save them rotten.
Nothing was still under control.
What should I do?
Is it? You look tired.
Early to bed tonight
- I could talk with anyone.
Hi
- Yeah, sure.
I never felt more alone.
I always wanted to show a super hero.
But this was a nightmare.
It was time to let that
ridiculous costume.
But there remains
for me one thing.
What is the difference between
Spider-Man and Peter Parker?
Spider-Man gets the girl.
Hi!
I Kick Ass, You had emailed me?
What do you do, go
from my house!
I'm going to hurt you, I am!
I just wanted to surprise you.
Dave? What are you doing?
Why are you dressed like Kick-Ass
- Kick-Ass I bn.
What are you talking about
- I'm not gay.
I'm an idiot who lied to you.
I know.
If you feel better through it,
you can not hate me ...
than I hate myself.
Please ...
I'm so sorry.
I've met anyone so lovely ...
than you.
Dave.
- Yeah?
The alarm is probably on,
so bring the window.
Or ...
you can just continue.
Continue?
Sleep would be great.
Sorry, I didn 't mean
to scare you.
We have to, do it and what
it is established.
I have something, I think.
He is perfect, they can
deliver in three days.
They need $ 1000.
- Can you spend on
anything else?
That's cool!
- Yes.
Add to shopping card.
- Okay.
Kick-Ass and battle between
Red Mist, who would win?
Why fight it?
That just seems stupid.
What do you think?
- Kick-Ass was cuter.
Really?
I would sew his brains out
if I had the chance.
Really?
- Absolutely.
Want to see the new Kate Hudson movie?
The following display.
Absolutely.
We're apparently not invited.
Come here, I can now convert
to a strip reader.
I finally understood why superhero
comics only existed.
I understood why people gave
their lives to strangers.
Since I first in my life I
had something to live for.
Something to lose.
Katie was worried about me.
I promised her that my Kick-Ass
days were over.
And actually I barely missed.
I had the website up
to show week view.
I'm off then.
Katie does not pass
- Tomorrow, Wednesday Volunteer.
You look like a different person.
Your mother would
have been proud.
Dude.
What are you doing? I must meet you!
Red Mist
Hi, sweetheart.
- What's happening?
I need a kick-ass thing.
- What?
Thus, you were stopped?
- Last, I promise.
I'm worried about you.
Do not it.
- That is impossible,
because ...
I like very much to you.
I also like about you.
Hopefully this seriously, because I promised
my friend that this was done.
We are both dead.
Is that serious enough?
Dead? How?
Who killed the store have friends
who see us as a perpetrator.
There is a price on our heads.
- Is this the Wild
West or something?
I do not laugh, they know where I
live, and I'm fucking screwed.
All right.
Damn.
What do we do?
Remember when there were other heroes
- Yes.
You think they can help us?
Hot chocolate, extra
marshmallows.
It looks even better
than the picture.
These photo were not
machine guns.
Nice work. I take mine to bed.
Okay, baby. Sleep well.
- Thank you.
Kick-Ass?
Get dressed, we met
him at address B.
We drink our hot chocolate
when we get back.
Look.
- Do you know where that is?
No, I put it in the GPS.
- Go ahead.
Damn.
Well, here you are.
And Red Mist too.
Pleasant.
- Nice, sir.
Come in, please.
- After you.
Hit-Girl, your manners.
Hi, I'm Hit-Girl.
He's with me.
- Shut up, your father
is the boss.
He's with me. Let him go.
So one I always wanted to have.
- Do you do it?
If you love to be like a superhero ...
- That's funny ...
Get him outta here.
Kick-Ass sorry.
Why not absolve you
this motherfucker?
Ignore him ...
a Bazooka?
We had a deal pap ...
I would care for the man who did it,
if you let go now Kick-Ass ...
He has done nothing wrong.
Check this out from my side ...
I need people to send a message.
Which superhero are bad
for your health ...
and that big bastard
who nobody knows.
That is not fair.
- Life is not fair, forget it.
What do you do to them?
Do you really know?
Yes.
- Sit down, shut up and watch.
Frank we are ready. Enjoy.
Did you see the control.
- Indeed, look and learn.
Welcome back to the worldwide web
broadcast with shocking news ...
about the superhero from New
York, known as Kick-Ass ...
will appear as live.
According to rumors, this will
be his last performance ...
and that he will stop
fighting evil.
As the news spreads,
thinking ISPs ...
that this might be the most watched moment
in the history of the Internet can be.
Where is Dave really?
- There is no i
dication that ...
Have you also heard that ...
By Katie, probably.
Why should I be different.
Nobody knows yet who is behind the
broadcast of this show is ...
it is heard in many
server crashes ...
Dave, why did you not say.
You're on the news.
Call me.
- The next to the clock
that counts down.
Showtime.
Hello, boys and girls ...
you know who this is ...
This man here is Big Daddy.
These are all my friends.
Come say hello guys.
There they are al Hello.
Big Daddy and Kick-Ass
will help us ...
to show you why a hero
is a bad idea.
Do you know what a silent K? That's when the word starts with a K.
..
but you do not pronounce.
As to the Knock-out word.
And you get a box with handle.
That was certainly painful.
We look at it from
a different angle.
That was really painful.
In French they say so "Baton".
We have stakes of Kick-Ass, we
will show you what they can.
Go your way guys.
In America we say this to
a stick, 'Baseball Bat'.
Good for hitting on
knees or head ...
also good to use someone
in the balls to hit.
But we do not individually,
but all at once.
Gentlemen, get your swing.
This looks very painful out.
Given the shocking images ...
we can no longer broadcast
live internet images.
Despite speculation that this would
be a publicity stunt ...
it is now clear that the
hostages indeed at risk.
With the intention to show a live
broadcast of an execution.
Even with my metal plates
and broken my nervous ...
I can say that pretty painful.
Kerosene, the silent killer.
But not half as painful as the thought that
I should leave everything behind ...
Katie, my father, Todd
and Marty ...
and all these things
I've done ...
like driving a car, or know how
our children will be ...
Lost or how it ends.
And if you think I get it because
I'm talking to you ...
Do not be such a smartass.
You've never seen Sin City,
or Sunset Boulevard?
American Beauty?
This, beyond all t
oglodytes, is fire.
Fire. Fire is good.
Fire is our friend.
Gentlemen ...
time to die right there.
What the hell ...
Pick up the lighter.
Take cover.
Use kryptonite.
This show is over, assholes.
I think I love her.
She looks like she was
only eleven years ...
I wait on her.
That will be very
difficult for you.
Is everything okay?
- Yes.
Well done.
I'm so proud of you.
Is everything okay?
Shot down was less painful
than when you did.
I used ball with less speed.
You are the sweetest dad in the world.
- No, I'm ...
I love you.
Love you, Dad.
Sleep tight.
What's your name?
Your real name?
A superhero never reveals
his true identity.
But you can not ...
How you do this also
have lived ...
it's over.
Is there anyone else?
Family or something ...
I can take care of myself ...
I've also saved you anyway.
And money?
You also need long-term
thinking.
I have about 3 million
in this case ...
is that enough for
the long term?
It is not just about
the money ...
I stand with you in debt.
If you had not been there,
I was now dead.
If you had not been there ...
My father would be alive.
Take note what you need and
then we go to my house.
I'm just fine.
- Go ahead.
I meant your pajamas
and your clothes ...
you can not take it to my house.
You know what my dad really
would have wanted?
That I finished what we started.
I will do that.
Is this the home of
Frank D'Amico?
All that security,
are you crazy?
My mother has already
died for nothing ...
So I'll leave that to
my father not happen.
You can not succeed alone.
Exactly.
Want to blame my father's honor?
Keep your mouth shut
and choose a weapon.
Is that what I think it is?
- Yes, certainly.
Read the manual but ...
who do you need so much.
Look, you have 5 minutes and then
I want you back to your post ...
and let this tidy.
Everything
- everything is fine.
I got my gun back. ... It is not
Let her inside.
It was a small child.
What do you think?
Is it, dear?
I lost my mom and dad.
She lost her mom and dad.
Want my phone?
You know the song?
If I were a super hero, it was for me
the world is no more to offer ...
than good intentions
and a good stamina.
Without power, there is
no responsibility.
Except that it was not true.
Kenny, help me.
Everyone is dead.
She sits behind the counter,
and she has no more bullets.
Do you think they
have her address?
If they failed, then
it will succeed.
Go to it.
- Now?
What's going on here?
She is trapped, and
she is unarmed.
What are you waiting for?
Go get her.
- I have no weapon.
Now.
I get the bazooka.
Bazooka?
Only me.
Everything is under control.
Under control, why
pick up a bazooka?
Go ahead.
This is what I always
wanted to say.
Say hello to my little friend.
Die, motherfuckers.
That was a weird sound
for a bazooka.
Catch them.
The playtime is over.
I never play.
Really?
Runeren my case?
Everyone on my payroll finish.
I had a son like you.
Time for a family Renie.
Pick someone your own size from.
Will it work
- Yes.
Time to go home.
Thanks, Kick-Ass.
My dad ...
would have been proud of us.
Dave Lizewski.
I know, loser.
Mindy ...
Mindy Macready.
Goodbye.
Mindy went to live with Mark,
who came to my school ...
its first school ever.
And so I could watch her ...
not necessary.
Hey, rookie.
Your lunch money now.
Kick-Ass was gone but
not forgotten.
And my world was much safer with
all the new superheroes ...
They said I was their
inspiration ...
I have only the door of
my dream world open ...
a world with only superhero.
As a great man once said ...
wait until they charge me see.