1
00:04:28,851 --> 00:04:32,020
现在是华氏四十七度，七点十七分
It's 47 degrees right now at 7:17.

2
00:04:32,188 --> 00:04:35,023
体育新闻在七点二十五分播出
Sports news coming up
at twenty-five after the hour.

3
00:04:35,191 --> 00:04:38,735
杰克·沃尔特将采访比利·马丁
Jack Walters will be having that
exclusive interview with Billy Martin,

4
00:04:38,903 --> 00:04:41,196
你知道那将令人激动
and you know that could be fireworks.

5
00:04:41,364 --> 00:04:43,365
从泽西岛过来…
The best bet for you folks
coming in from Jersey,

6
00:04:43,533 --> 00:04:46,118
无论如何都要走哈林大坝
do whatever you got to do
to use the Holland

7
00:04:46,286 --> 00:04:47,869
而不是林肯隧道
rather than the Lincoln Tunnel.

8
00:04:48,037 --> 00:04:50,789
林肯隧道已经成为噩梦了
The backup there, at the Lincoln,
is already a nightmare.

9
00:04:50,957 --> 00:04:55,002
希望今天一整天天气都晴朗
阳光明媚，
Looking forward to some bright blue
skies all day today, with sunshine

10
00:04:55,169 --> 00:04:57,713
可能会达到五十多度
and the highs this afternoon
somewhere in the upper 50s.

11
00:04:57,880 --> 00:05:00,424
城市里可能会高达六十度
Especially in the city,
it could get up near 60.

12
00:05:00,591 --> 00:05:02,009
趁机享受吧，我的朋友
Enjoy it while you can, my friend.

13
00:05:02,176 --> 00:05:05,053
冬季随时都会降临
Old Man Winter is going to be blowing
on your neck any day now.

14
00:05:05,596 --> 00:05:07,347
今晚最低温度三十多度
Lows tonight in the upper 30s

15
00:05:07,515 --> 00:05:10,684
北部有些地方有霜降
with frost in some of the usually
colder regions upstate.

16
00:05:10,852 --> 00:05:14,187
你们在收听PRM-FM93波段的
威利·克雷格
You're listening to Willie Craig
on PRM-FM 93.

17
00:05:14,355 --> 00:05:17,024
如果你的收音机时间定在七点十八分
And if your clock radio
is set to go off at 7:18,

18
00:05:17,191 --> 00:05:20,777
就是现在了
it should be doing that right about now.

19
00:05:20,945 --> 00:05:23,613
每天PRM这里以音乐开始
Start every day with music on PRM.

20
00:05:23,781 --> 00:05:27,659
这段儿选自万魔殿，由斯蒂维小姐演唱
This is a cut from the new Pandemonium
album, "Lady Stevie."

21
00:05:32,123 --> 00:05:36,251
彼得，你该在半小时之内准备好
Peter, you're supposed to be ready
in half an hour.

22
00:05:36,419 --> 00:05:37,544
准备好干什么？
Ready for what?

23
00:05:37,712 --> 00:05:40,088
我们今天要去博物馆，你跟迈克和我…
We're going to the museum today,
and then you and Mike and I...

24
00:05:40,256 --> 00:05:43,425
妈，我要利用假期剩余的时间
把这个做完
Mom, I can't go. I need the rest
of the vacation to finish this thing.

25
00:05:43,593 --> 00:05:45,635
一周前就计划好了
We made these plans
a week ago, remember?

26
00:05:45,803 --> 00:05:49,014
我知道，但我落后了许多，对不起
I know. But I'm way behind my schedule.
I'm sorry.

27
00:05:49,682 --> 00:05:52,267
彼得，你又一晚上没睡？
Peter, have you been up all night again?

28
00:05:52,435 --> 00:05:55,479
妈，市科学竞赛下周就要举行了
Mom, the City Science Championships
are next week.

29
00:05:56,856 --> 00:05:58,982
把它关掉，
Turn that thing off.

30
00:05:59,150 --> 00:06:00,942
把它放下，看着我
Put that down and look at me.

31
00:06:07,658 --> 00:06:09,785
我们达成了个小小的协议，是不是？
We made a little deal, didn't we?

32
00:06:12,246 --> 00:06:14,790
我对你的研究感到非常骄傲和兴奋
You know I'm very proud and excited
about your project,

33
00:06:14,957 --> 00:06:17,417
但我不能让你整夜都忙着干这个
but I don't want
you working all night on it.

34
00:06:17,585 --> 00:06:19,878
我知道，我知道，对不起
I know. I'm sorry.

35
00:06:20,046 --> 00:06:22,881
妈，这是我最好的创作
Mom, this is the most incredible thing
that I've ever built.

36
00:06:23,049 --> 00:06:24,424
我是指这个运载体
I mean, this carries.

37
00:06:24,592 --> 00:06:27,010
这是运载体？运载什么？
It carries? Carries what?

38
00:06:27,178 --> 00:06:30,889
二进制数字
它能储存高达二十位的数字
Binary numbers.
It can hold up to a 20-digit figure.

39
00:06:31,057 --> 00:06:35,060
等等，你说它可以运载也能储存？
Now wait a second. You said
it can carry, and it holds, too?

40
00:06:35,228 --> 00:06:36,978
两样都行，这就是要点
Both. It does both.
That's the whole point.

41
00:06:37,146 --> 00:06:40,023
我书中没有任何这样的电路
I mean, there isn't a circuit like this
in any of my books.

42
00:06:40,191 --> 00:06:41,858
我自己发明的
I've invented it.

43
00:06:42,610 --> 00:06:44,111
太好了
Well, that's great.

44
00:06:45,488 --> 00:06:46,822
太好了，彼得，
That's great, Peter.

45
00:06:46,989 --> 00:06:49,324
你给它起个什么名字？
What are you going to call it?

46
00:06:49,492 --> 00:06:50,492
我不知道
I don't know.

47
00:06:50,660 --> 00:06:52,077
想想吧
Well, come on.

48
00:06:52,245 --> 00:06:55,831
大家都知道
当创造出或发明出什么东西时
Everybody knows that when you invent
or discover something,

49
00:06:55,998 --> 00:06:59,918
你得给它起个名字，比如拿破仑
you get to name it, like... a napoleon.

50
00:07:01,212 --> 00:07:02,838
什么？
法国糕点
A what?
You know, the French pastry.

51
00:07:03,005 --> 00:07:04,589
有种饼就叫拿破仑
It was named after Napoleon.

52
00:07:05,133 --> 00:07:07,259
拿破仑发明了糕点？他是将军
Napoleon invented pastry?
I thought he was a general.

53
00:07:07,885 --> 00:07:10,011
人总不能一天到晚打仗吧
Well, you can't fight battles
all the time.

54
00:07:10,179 --> 00:07:13,014
他有空烤点饼当做休闲
He baked as a kind of relaxation.

55
00:07:15,268 --> 00:07:16,977
你没事吧，妈妈？
Are you OK, Mom?

56
00:07:17,520 --> 00:07:21,106
听我说，别再熬通宵了，好吗？
Listen. No more all-nighters, OK?

57
00:07:22,358 --> 00:07:23,984
好吧
OK.

58
00:07:27,780 --> 00:07:30,198
这玩意到底叫什么名字？
What is this called, anyway?

59
00:07:30,825 --> 00:07:32,409
噢，当然叫它彼得
It's a peter, of course.

60
00:07:33,369 --> 00:07:35,120
当然要等到发明出来了才算数
That is, if I ever get it finished.

61
00:07:35,288 --> 00:07:37,914
好吧，这回饶了你
OK, I'll let you skip it this time,

62
00:07:38,082 --> 00:07:40,625
不过你要答应我不要再熬夜了
but only if you promise
not to work all night.

63
00:07:43,212 --> 00:07:45,255
我保证
OK, I promise.

64
00:07:47,383 --> 00:07:49,759
我保证，行吗？
I promise. All right?

65
00:07:51,387 --> 00:07:53,597
奶奶会非常失望，
Grandma's going to be very disappointed.

66
00:07:53,764 --> 00:07:58,268
不过没什么
我向她解释一下你在做你的彼得
But it's all right. I'll explain
that you're working on your peter.

67
00:08:42,396 --> 00:08:45,440
有人在敲门，对
There's someone at the front door. Yes.

68
00:08:45,608 --> 00:08:48,068
星期四十一点至十二点之间，对吧？
Between 11:00 and 12:00,
Thursday, right?

69
00:08:48,236 --> 00:08:50,111
行，好，再见
OK, fine. Bye.

70
00:08:52,573 --> 00:08:54,449
凯特！见到你很高兴
Kate, good to see you.

71
00:08:55,368 --> 00:08:58,537
玛丽正在度假
我得自己当接待员，
Mary is on vacation,
so I have to be my own receptionist.

72
00:08:59,539 --> 00:09:00,664
我当得怎么样？
How am I doing?

73
00:09:00,831 --> 00:09:04,584
别让我久等，我想早点儿去博物馆
I hope you won't keep me waiting today.
I want to get to the museum early.

74
00:09:04,752 --> 00:09:07,504
我十二点半跟麦克和他妈妈吃饭
I have to be at lunch by 12:30
with Mike and his mother.

75
00:09:07,672 --> 00:09:09,089
不用等，现在就进来
No waiting, go right in.

76
00:09:09,257 --> 00:09:11,258
大夫马上来了
The doctor will be with you shortly.

77
00:09:20,017 --> 00:09:22,644
那么，出了什么事？
So, what's happening?

78
00:09:26,816 --> 00:09:29,317
我妈妈像往常一样让我发疯
My mother's driving me crazy as usual.

79
00:09:29,485 --> 00:09:30,610
你跟她谈过没有？
Did you talk to her?

80
00:09:30,778 --> 00:09:32,988
嗯
Mm-hm.

81
00:09:33,155 --> 00:09:36,992
她露口风说要给我的生日一个惊喜
She's hinting around
about surprising me for my birthday.

82
00:09:38,327 --> 00:09:40,620
她打算从佛罗里达来看你吗
She's going to come up from Florida,
is she?

83
00:09:40,788 --> 00:09:42,539
那就是她的惊喜
That's her surprise.

84
00:09:44,584 --> 00:09:46,626
你想不想见到她
How do you feel about seeing her?

85
00:09:48,004 --> 00:09:49,212
我是觉得，
Well, I feel...

86
00:09:50,506 --> 00:09:51,923
我应该想见她
...I should want to see her.

87
00:09:52,091 --> 00:09:54,384
我们已经有六个月没见面了
It's been six months
since we've been down there,

88
00:09:54,552 --> 00:09:57,679
她要搞砸我的生日
but... she'll just ruin my birthday.

89
00:09:57,847 --> 00:09:59,806
那是我的生日，不是她的
And it's my day, not hers.

90
00:10:01,267 --> 00:10:04,477
嗯，现在，想想，你还有别的选择吗？
Well, now, think.
What are our options?

91
00:10:06,939 --> 00:10:09,691
我可以找个藉口不让她来
I could make up an excuse
and tell her not to come.

92
00:10:09,859 --> 00:10:11,943
嗯
Mm-hm.

93
00:10:13,738 --> 00:10:15,196
不，我不能这样
No, I can't do that.

94
00:10:16,616 --> 00:10:18,908
况且她还要给我一个惊喜
And let's not forget,
it's supposed to be a surprise.

95
00:10:19,076 --> 00:10:20,368
总之…不是她的原因
Anyway, it's not her.

96
00:10:20,536 --> 00:10:21,870
只是…
It's just...

97
00:10:23,331 --> 00:10:26,124
而是我做什么事都不起劲
I don't feel up to it,
or her or anything.

98
00:10:27,752 --> 00:10:29,377
跟麦克怎么样了？
How are things going with Mike?

99
00:10:29,545 --> 00:10:31,463
还好
那很好
Fine.
Good.

100
00:10:33,424 --> 00:10:36,760
不，才不好，我不喜欢那个字眼
No, they're not fine.
What a dumb word that is.

101
00:10:38,679 --> 00:10:42,724
今天早上他给了我一个
他所谓的特别重击
He gave me one of his wham-bang
specials this morning,

102
00:10:42,892 --> 00:10:44,601
我很生他的气
and I'm mad at him.

103
00:10:44,769 --> 00:10:46,686
这样做对吗？我应该生气吗？
Isn't that right? Shouldn't I be mad?

104
00:10:47,730 --> 00:10:50,440
你告诉他了没有？
Yeah. Did you tell him?

105
00:10:51,692 --> 00:10:54,361
什么？
说你生他的气
What?
That you were mad at him.

106
00:10:55,780 --> 00:10:57,155
当然没有
Of course not.

107
00:10:59,742 --> 00:11:01,826
他碰我时我高兴得呻吟
I moaned with pleasure at his touch.

108
00:11:01,994 --> 00:11:04,162
男人不是都希望这样吗？
Isn’t that what every man wants?

109
00:11:04,580 --> 00:11:06,289
我不知道是吗？
I don't know. Is it?

110
00:11:07,041 --> 00:11:08,583
别跟我装糊涂
Don't start that stuff with me.

111
00:11:09,418 --> 00:11:12,420
你不认为如果你对麦克发火
要比对我发火有用吧
Don't you think you'd feel better
if you snapped at Mike instead of me?

112
00:11:14,340 --> 00:11:17,258
想想看
你的脾气应该要向谁发
Think about where your anger is going.

113
00:11:22,264 --> 00:11:23,264
对不起
I'm sorry.

114
00:11:23,432 --> 00:11:27,143
别道歉了，告诉麦克他让你生气
Stop apologizing
and tell Mike he makes you mad.

115
00:11:29,230 --> 00:11:30,897
告诉他他床上的功夫真差？
Tell him he stinks in bed?

116
00:11:31,065 --> 00:11:32,524
他差吗？
Does he?

117
00:11:35,152 --> 00:11:37,487
是的
那就告诉他
Yes.
Then tell him.

118
00:11:42,785 --> 00:11:44,744
说不定有问题的是我
Maybe there's something wrong with me.

119
00:11:45,371 --> 00:11:47,163
你没有任何问题
There's nothing wrong with you.

120
00:11:47,998 --> 00:11:49,624
你觉得我吸引人吗？
Do you find me attractive?

121
00:11:50,292 --> 00:11:51,292
当然
Of course.

122
00:11:52,503 --> 00:11:54,045
你想跟我睡觉吗？
Would you want to sleep with me?

123
00:11:55,131 --> 00:11:56,297
想啊
Yes.

124
00:11:58,008 --> 00:11:59,342
那你为什么不？
Then why don't you?

125
00:12:04,223 --> 00:12:06,224
因么我爱我的妻子
Because I love my wife,

126
00:12:06,392 --> 00:12:09,018
和你上床会破坏我的婚姻
and sleeping with you isn't worth
jeopardizing my marriage.

127
00:12:10,146 --> 00:12:13,022
你也不想破坏你的婚姻吧？
Is it worth it to you
to jeopardize yours?

128
00:12:13,190 --> 00:12:14,649
我不知道
I don't know.

129
00:12:35,004 --> 00:12:37,172
来吧，看看图片
Come on, look at the pictures.

130
00:13:03,532 --> 00:13:06,201
这么无聊。得了吧。
This is so boring. Come on.

131
00:13:06,368 --> 00:13:10,747
看看图片
这就是我们来到这里的。
Look at the pictures.
That's what we came here for.

132
00:13:15,920 --> 00:13:17,212
嗨
Hi.

133
00:13:20,007 --> 00:13:21,841
第一次来这里吗？
First time here?

134
00:13:27,389 --> 00:13:28,640
别摸了
Stop it.

135
00:13:33,020 --> 00:13:34,687
停
Cut it out.

136
00:14:06,846 --> 00:14:08,012
妈咪！
Mommy.

137
00:14:10,766 --> 00:14:11,641
妈咪！
Mommy.

138
00:14:11,809 --> 00:14:16,187
别这样，站着不要动…
Now you stop that. I told you
to stand and be still and I meant it.

139
00:14:32,726 --> 00:14:34,320
疯子
Nuts

140
00:14:54,652 --> 00:14:58,355
挑选了个劣货！
Pick up Teukey!

141
00:22:14,958 --> 00:22:18,753
对不起，我很不懂礼貌
谢谢你帮我捡起…
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have been
so rude. Thank you for picking up...

142
00:27:08,084 --> 00:27:09,376
喂？
Hello?

143
00:27:12,797 --> 00:27:14,089
你是谁？
Who is this?

144
00:29:06,749 --> 00:29:10,237
华尔街体育田径俱乐部，483号会员
WALL STREET ATHLETIC CLUB
MEMBER 483

145
00:29:31,568 --> 00:29:35,766
我爱今天下午，也许我们会再见面
I loved the afternoon.
Maybe well meet again.

146
00:29:51,427 --> 00:29:54,015
我爱我们的下午
I loved our afternoon.

147
00:30:13,547 --> 00:30:16,019
纽约市卫生局
曼哈顿分局
City of New York DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH
LOWER MANHATTAN HEALTH DISTRICT

148
00:30:18,020 --> 00:30:20,392
华伦·洛克曼
WARREN LOCKMAN

149
00:30:20,392 --> 00:30:23,932
你必须马上
到福特·格林地区卫生中心登记
It is urgent that you report to:
Ft. Greene District Health Center

150
00:30:31,256 --> 00:30:37,014
你感染了性病
YOU HAVE CONTRACTED A VENEREAL DISEASE!

151
00:32:42,377 --> 00:32:44,294
盯着看人不礼貌
It's not polite to stare.

152
00:33:58,661 --> 00:33:59,703
不要…
No.

153
00:34:00,788 --> 00:34:01,997
不要…
No.

154
00:34:02,957 --> 00:34:04,875
不要…不要…
No. No.

155
00:34:10,798 --> 00:34:13,383
你真的认为奥蒂朗股票会上涨吗？
So you really think Auditron's going up?

156
00:34:13,551 --> 00:34:15,594
嗯，我的消息来源很可靠
Well, I got it from a very good source.

157
00:34:25,563 --> 00:34:27,898
涨一倍，真的？
你不是从我这里听到的
Double, huh?
You didn't hear it from me.

158
00:34:42,830 --> 00:34:46,416
你知道吗？
我要给我的经纪人打个电话
You know what? I'm going to give
my broker a little call.

159
00:34:46,584 --> 00:34:49,169
天啊！
嗯，这样…？
Jesus.
Well, what about...?

160
00:34:59,055 --> 00:35:01,056
天！
Oh, my...

161
00:35:52,608 --> 00:35:54,651
不，等等！
No, wait! Help!

162
00:35:54,819 --> 00:35:57,779
求你了，你还不明白！
叫警察啊，还等！
Please, you don't understand!
Please, call the police! Wait!

163
00:36:00,616 --> 00:36:02,659
叫警察！
Please, call the police!

164
00:36:23,848 --> 00:36:26,933
叫警察，谁去叫一下警察！
Call the police!
Somebody call the police!

165
00:36:58,466 --> 00:37:01,718
艾略特医生，我是罗·费里曼
我人还在芝加哥
Dr. Elliott, this is Lou Freeman.
I'm still in Chicago.

166
00:37:01,886 --> 00:37:05,055
星期五的约会我赶不回来了
I won't be back in time
for our appointment on Friday.

167
00:37:05,223 --> 00:37:07,515
我星期一再打电话给你，行吗？
I'll give you a call on Monday, OK?

168
00:37:12,647 --> 00:37:15,649
罗伯特，给乔治打电话，我周末回家
Robert, call George.
I'll be home over the weekend.

169
00:37:22,406 --> 00:37:23,990
我是芭比
This is Bobbi.

170
00:37:26,661 --> 00:37:28,036
你这阵子见不到我了
You won't see me anymore,

171
00:37:28,204 --> 00:37:30,872
我只能对着你的答录机说话
so I'm going to have a little session
with your machine.

172
00:37:33,042 --> 00:37:35,418
医生，我非常不愉快
Doctor, I'm so unhappy.

173
00:37:35,586 --> 00:37:38,505
我是男儿身女儿心啊
I'm a girl inside this man's body,

174
00:37:38,673 --> 00:37:41,132
而你又不帮我
and you're not helping me to get out.

175
00:37:41,801 --> 00:37:43,468
我只好另请高明
So I got a new shrink.

176
00:37:43,636 --> 00:37:45,512
他叫利维
他要帮我签署文件
Levy's his name,
and he's going to sign the papers

177
00:37:45,680 --> 00:37:47,847
好让我动手术
so I can get my operation.

178
00:37:49,684 --> 00:37:52,519
我借了你的剃刀
I borrowed your razor and...

179
00:37:54,188 --> 00:37:57,023
反正你会在报上看到
Well, you'll read all about it.

180
00:37:58,192 --> 00:38:00,860
有个金发的婊子看到了
不过我会找到她的
Some blonde bitch saw me,
but I'll get her.

181
00:38:05,408 --> 00:38:08,243
记住，如果利维给你打电话
Remember, if he calls you...

182
00:38:09,412 --> 00:38:11,621
你最好告诉他我很好
...you better tell Levy I'm OK.

183
00:38:13,374 --> 00:38:16,876
别再逼我变成一个坏姑娘
Don't make me be a bad girl again.

184
00:38:22,133 --> 00:38:24,718
艾洛特医生？我是彼得夫人
Yes, Dr. Elliott,
this is Mrs. Peters.

185
00:38:24,885 --> 00:38:29,973
我要确定明天下午两点的会诊时间…
I just wanted to confirm our appointment
for tomorrow. Two o'clock, right?

186
00:38:38,691 --> 00:38:41,609
我是十三辖区的马利诺侦探
This is Detective Marino
from the 13th Precinct.

187
00:38:42,945 --> 00:38:46,406
你的一个病人，凯特·米勒今晚被杀了
One of your patients, Kate Miller,
was killed tonight.

188
00:38:47,158 --> 00:38:49,868
我不知道你是否能来分局一下
I wonder if you'd stop down
at the precinct and ask for me.

189
00:38:50,036 --> 00:38:52,412
我有一些问题，我想你能帮助我澄清
I got some questions
I think you can help me with.

190
00:39:10,348 --> 00:39:11,890
你确定吗？
Are you sure?

191
00:39:12,350 --> 00:39:13,266
嗯
Mm-hm.

192
00:39:13,434 --> 00:39:14,684
是的
OK.

193
00:39:21,442 --> 00:39:22,859
身份确定
Positive ID.

194
00:39:28,991 --> 00:39:32,243
嘿，艾迪！把这个送到实验室，
Hey, Eddie. Listen, I want
you to take this over to the lab

195
00:39:32,411 --> 00:39:34,579
翻拍几张照片
好
and get some pictures made of it.
Yeah.

196
00:39:34,747 --> 00:39:36,414
注意她一下
好
Keep an eye on her.
Right.

197
00:39:37,583 --> 00:39:38,917
马利诺侦探？
我就是
Detective Marino?
OK.

198
00:39:39,085 --> 00:39:40,877
是的
我是艾略特医生
Yeah.
I'm Dr. Elliott.

199
00:39:41,045 --> 00:39:42,087
医生
Oh, Doctor.

200
00:39:43,130 --> 00:39:46,466
你在我办公室外面那边坐会儿好吗？
Listen, would you have a seat outside
my office in the corner over there.

201
00:39:46,634 --> 00:39:48,551
我马上就好
好的
I'll be right with you.
All right.

202
00:39:48,719 --> 00:39:50,512
帮我复印三张…
So give me three copies...

203
00:39:52,306 --> 00:39:54,808
你为什么不让我走？放我走吧
Why don't you let go of me, will you?

204
00:40:14,870 --> 00:40:16,996
你是凯特·米勒的儿子？
Are you Kate Miller's son?

205
00:40:20,876 --> 00:40:23,962
我是艾略特医生，你母亲的医生
I'm Dr. Elliott, your mother's doctor.

206
00:40:31,137 --> 00:40:33,221
你为什么在这里？
Why do you have to be here?

207
00:40:34,515 --> 00:40:36,474
我让麦克带我来的
I made Mike bring me.

208
00:40:36,642 --> 00:40:38,768
他在辨认…
He's identifying the...

209
00:40:41,188 --> 00:40:43,481
如果我跟我妈妈一起去
她就不会死的
My mom wouldn't be dead
if I had gone with her.

210
00:40:44,733 --> 00:40:47,193
你不该为你妈妈的死而责怪自己
You shouldn't feel responsible
for your mother's death.

211
00:40:48,737 --> 00:40:51,156
如果你想说什么
或许我可以帮得上忙
If you talk about it,
I might be able to help.

212
00:40:51,323 --> 00:40:52,699
你知道是谁杀死她的吗？
Do you know who killed her?

213
00:40:53,451 --> 00:40:54,868
不知道
那就帮不了她，是不是？
No.
Then you can't help, can you?

214
00:40:55,035 --> 00:40:56,578
现在或许帮不上，
Not now maybe.

215
00:40:57,830 --> 00:41:01,624
也许，以后如果你想跟谁谈谈此事
But later, if you want someone
to talk to about all this.

216
00:41:02,710 --> 00:41:04,711
让你爸爸打电话…
不…他才不是我父亲
Ask your father to call...
No, he's not my father.

217
00:41:04,879 --> 00:41:06,880
我父亲在越南阵亡了
My father was killed in Vietnam.

218
00:41:15,681 --> 00:41:17,223
拿着
Take this.

219
00:41:18,267 --> 00:41:19,934
你随时都可以给我打电话
You can call me any time.

220
00:41:20,603 --> 00:41:22,479
我通常都在…
I'm always there all day long.
I'm usually there...

221
00:41:22,646 --> 00:41:24,355
医生，我们谈谈
OK, Doctor, let's talk in here.

222
00:41:26,901 --> 00:41:28,109
打电话给我
Call me.

223
00:42:22,039 --> 00:42:24,457
洛克曼在博物馆钓上她
She was picked up by Lockman
at the museum.

224
00:42:24,625 --> 00:42:26,084
她在他的公寓度了一个下午
She spent the afternoon at his place

225
00:42:26,252 --> 00:42:28,294
下电梯时遭人刺死
and was chopped up in the elevator
on the way out.

226
00:42:28,462 --> 00:42:29,901
那边儿的那个姑娘看到了凶手
That girl out there saw the murderer.

227
00:42:29,901 --> 00:42:31,370
这真可怕
That's terrible.

228
00:42:34,385 --> 00:42:36,469
你知道是谁干的吗？
是个金发女孩
Do you know who it is?
Some broad.

229
00:42:36,637 --> 00:42:38,555
一个女人？
对
A woman?
Yeah.

230
00:42:38,722 --> 00:42:40,974
布雷克小姐没看见她的脸
Miss Blake didn't get
a great look at her face

231
00:42:41,141 --> 00:42:43,268
因为她戴着个大太阳眼镜
because she had on these big sunglasses.

232
00:42:43,435 --> 00:42:44,769
我能帮得上忙吗？
Is there anything I can do to help?

233
00:42:46,188 --> 00:42:48,523
可以，你见米勒太太
Yeah. When you spoke with Mrs. Miller...

234
00:42:49,316 --> 00:42:51,401
她有没有说要去见谁
...did she say
she was going to meet anybody?

235
00:42:51,569 --> 00:42:52,819
没有
No.

236
00:42:52,987 --> 00:42:54,988
有人跟她一起离开你的办公室吗？
Did she leave your office
with anybody?

237
00:42:55,155 --> 00:42:56,322
没有
No.

238
00:42:56,657 --> 00:42:58,157
她去看什么病？
What was she seeing you for?

239
00:42:58,325 --> 00:43:00,827
小毛病，
她的婚姻出了点儿问题
Nothing too serious. She had
some problems with her marriage,

240
00:43:00,995 --> 00:43:02,787
我正在帮她解决
and I was helping her work them out.

241
00:43:02,955 --> 00:43:04,289
什么样的问题？
What kind of problems?

242
00:43:04,456 --> 00:43:06,833
你结婚了吗，马利诺侦探？
Are you married, Detective Marino?

243
00:43:08,669 --> 00:43:11,045
是的
有孩子吗？
Yeah.
Children?

244
00:43:11,213 --> 00:43:12,171
两个儿子
Two sons.

245
00:43:12,339 --> 00:43:14,841
你多久没有和你太太做爱了
When was the last time
you had intercourse with your wife?

246
00:43:17,720 --> 00:43:19,846
那跟你有他妈的什么关系？
Now what the fuck is it to you?

247
00:43:20,014 --> 00:43:23,433
那就是你问米勒太太那些问题时我的感觉
That's exactly how I feel about
your questions concerning Mrs. Miller.

248
00:43:27,771 --> 00:43:30,607
嘿，你听好，医生
Hey, look, Doctor,

249
00:43:30,774 --> 00:43:33,860
这里有个被残酷杀死的妇女
we got a brutally murdered woman here,

250
00:43:34,028 --> 00:43:37,071
她已经不会再不好意思了
who passed the point
of being embarrassed

251
00:43:37,239 --> 00:43:39,324
你可以告诉我任何事
by anything you might tell me.

252
00:43:43,287 --> 00:43:44,996
你说的对
对不起，
I guess you're right.
I'm sorry,

253
00:43:45,164 --> 00:43:47,790
只是我不常和外人谈病人的情形
but I'm not used to discussing
a patient's case with outsiders.

254
00:43:47,958 --> 00:43:50,376
我不是外人，我是个警察！
I'm not an outsider. I'm a cop.

255
00:43:51,462 --> 00:43:53,713
我们直说吧，
Now, let's make it easy for you.

256
00:43:53,881 --> 00:43:55,632
她有没有寻短见的迹象
Was she looking to get killed?

257
00:43:55,799 --> 00:43:57,383
你是说自杀？
对
You mean, was she suicidal?
Yeah.

258
00:43:57,551 --> 00:43:58,551
没有
没有
No.
No.

259
00:43:58,719 --> 00:44:01,220
那她干嘛搭上洛克曼？
So why did she pick up
this Lockman character?

260
00:44:01,388 --> 00:44:02,972
他可能是个杀手
可他不是
He could've been a killer.
But he wasn't.

261
00:44:03,140 --> 00:44:06,684
没错，可是她再挑的男人可能是杀手
如果你一开始不成功的话
Yeah, but the next guy might have been.
You know, if at first you don't succeed.

262
00:44:06,852 --> 00:44:08,186
你认为她想死？
Do you think she wanted to get killed?

263
00:44:08,354 --> 00:44:09,896
你不这样认为？
Don't you? Look.

264
00:44:10,064 --> 00:44:13,691
我们有个激情洋溢的女人
到处勾搭陌生男子
We got some hot-pants broad
cruising around for some action.

265
00:44:13,859 --> 00:44:17,737
那个小子在计程车内
就动手动脚了，他妈的
The guy she picked up went down on her
in a cab, for Christ's sake.

266
00:44:17,905 --> 00:44:21,991
我这里有司机详细的描述
I got a blow-by-blow description
from the cabby.

267
00:44:22,743 --> 00:44:24,077
她和他办完事后
After she finishes with him,

268
00:44:24,244 --> 00:44:26,954
她又跟一个怪癖在电梯里干上了？
she comes on to some weirdo
in the elevator?

269
00:44:27,122 --> 00:44:30,249
在这个城里想死的话
方法可多着呢
Hey. There's all kinds of ways
to get killed in this city,

270
00:44:30,417 --> 00:44:32,168
如果你真的想要
if you're looking for it.

271
00:44:34,421 --> 00:44:38,341
她的性生活的确存在着问题
Well... Yes, she did have a problem
about her sexual worth.

272
00:44:39,677 --> 00:44:43,596
今天早上
她还问我对她有没兴趣
And this morning she asked me
if I was attracted to her.

273
00:44:43,764 --> 00:44:45,682
对，可是你又不是心理医生
Yeah, but you're not a psycho.

274
00:44:47,226 --> 00:44:49,519
你有些这方面的知识，对吧，医生？
You do know something, though,
don't you, Doc?

275
00:44:50,104 --> 00:44:52,647
当然，我在精神院做过事
Yes, of course.
I do some work at Bellevue.

276
00:44:54,358 --> 00:44:57,026
她会不会在你办公室里遇见了一个疯子
Could she have met one of these nuts
at your office?

277
00:44:57,194 --> 00:45:00,446
而那个怪癖可能跟踪她呢？
I mean, some kind of weirdo she could've
turned on that might have followed her?

278
00:45:01,740 --> 00:45:05,702
马利诺侦探，我们使用的术语不是怪癖
The term we use, Detective Marino,
is not "weirdo,"

279
00:45:05,869 --> 00:45:08,621
而是患有精神机能失调
but a person
suffering from emotional dysfunction

280
00:45:08,789 --> 00:45:11,290
和适应不良问题的人
and a problem of maladaption.

281
00:45:11,458 --> 00:45:13,042
他们从不会到我办公室来
And they never come to my office.

282
00:45:16,130 --> 00:45:17,380
你敢肯定？
Are you sure?

283
00:45:20,884 --> 00:45:22,093
如果是一个新病人会怎么样？
How about a new patient?

284
00:45:23,262 --> 00:45:26,639
见面之前你怎么知道他们有没有疯？
I mean, how do you know
how nuts they are until you see them?

285
00:45:26,807 --> 00:45:28,808
是有可能，可是可能性不大
That's possible,
but it's hardly likely...

286
00:45:28,976 --> 00:45:30,143
医生！
Doctor.

287
00:45:31,729 --> 00:45:34,397
你不会是想保护某个病人吗？
You're not protecting
one of your patients now, are you?

288
00:45:34,565 --> 00:45:36,190
绝对不是
Absolutely not.

289
00:45:39,361 --> 00:45:42,155
嗯，医生，你得从我的立场看问题
Well, Doc,
you've got to look at it my way.

290
00:45:43,323 --> 00:45:46,701
我现在一点线索也没有
只有一个目击证人
See, we got no leads,
except a witness out there

291
00:45:46,869 --> 00:45:49,579
她也许应该看看病人的照片
who maybe should take a look
at all your patients

292
00:45:49,747 --> 00:45:51,164
你那天上午的
that were around that morning.

293
00:45:51,331 --> 00:45:54,125
这样我才能确定
And that way, I can be absolutely sure

294
00:45:54,293 --> 00:45:57,837
我的疯子不是你的
that my weirdo isn't your

295
00:45:58,005 --> 00:46:01,007
遭受精神机能失调
"person suffering
from emotional dysfunctions

296
00:46:01,175 --> 00:46:04,385
和适应不良问题的人
and problems of maladaption."

297
00:46:06,173 --> 00:46:09,842
彼得，走吧，我们回家
Peter. well, we're going home.

298
00:46:10,142 --> 00:46:11,267
对不起
Excuse me.

299
00:46:23,923 --> 00:46:27,227
伊丽莎白·布雷克
Elisabeth H.Blake

300
00:46:39,046 --> 00:46:41,005
好，医生，
OK, Doctor.

301
00:46:41,173 --> 00:46:44,884
很遗憾你不能配合我们
I'm sorry you're not more cooperative,
which means that

302
00:46:45,052 --> 00:46:48,429
我只好浪费时间去要求法院
I'm just going to have to waste some
time in getting a court order

303
00:46:48,597 --> 00:46:50,264
允许我我查你病人的纪录
to check out your appointment book.

304
00:46:50,432 --> 00:46:51,432
对不起，
I'm sorry, too.

305
00:46:51,600 --> 00:46:54,685
但我觉得
我必须保护我病人的机密
But I feel I must protect
the confidentiality of my patients.

306
00:46:54,853 --> 00:46:59,732
当然，我们只是职业不同，
都在尽职工作
Of course, we're just two professionals
doing our job.

307
00:47:00,400 --> 00:47:03,319
我们不能一起工作真是太糟了
走吧
It's too bad we can't work together.
Come on.

308
00:47:05,072 --> 00:47:08,115
谢谢你的帮助，我会与你保持联系的
Thank you very much for your help.
I'll be in touch.

309
00:47:13,580 --> 00:47:16,165
我是电话秘书，请稍等，
Yes, thank you for waiting.
This is the answering service.

310
00:47:16,333 --> 00:47:17,185
你要留话吗？
是的，我愿意，
Would you care to leave a message?
Yes, I would.

311
00:47:17,185 --> 00:47:18,836
艾略特
E-L-L-I-O-T-T

312
00:47:18,836 --> 00:47:21,003
我是艾略特医生
怎么拼？
This is Dr. Elliott.
How do you spell that?

313
00:47:21,171 --> 00:47:23,798
一个E，两个L，IO，两个T
E-L-L-I-O-T-T.

314
00:47:23,966 --> 00:47:25,424
要留什么话？
What is the message?

315
00:47:25,592 --> 00:47:28,344
请告诉她，我想见她
Would you please say
that I would very much like to see her,

316
00:47:28,512 --> 00:47:30,179
请她打电话到我的办公室来
and could she call me at my office.

317
00:47:32,891 --> 00:47:34,267
那么，布雷克小姐
So, Miss Blake.

318
00:47:35,644 --> 00:47:38,396
你仍住在纳索街九十三号吗？
Are you still living
at 93 Nassau Street?

319
00:47:38,564 --> 00:47:39,981
是的
That's right.

320
00:47:40,148 --> 00:47:42,775
告诉我，你当时为什么会在
Tell me, how did you happen to be
in that building

321
00:47:42,943 --> 00:47:44,777
米勒太太被害的楼里？
that Mrs. Miller was killed in?

322
00:47:45,404 --> 00:47:47,238
我去看一位朋友
I was visiting a friend.

323
00:47:47,406 --> 00:47:49,282
你朋友是谁？
And who was that?

324
00:47:49,992 --> 00:47:53,202
有点儿难为情，
Well... it's sort of embarrassing.

325
00:47:53,370 --> 00:47:55,663
我不想谈论这个
I'd really rather not say.

326
00:47:55,831 --> 00:47:56,998
为什么？
Why?

327
00:47:59,126 --> 00:48:00,626
他已经结婚了
He's married.

328
00:48:02,087 --> 00:48:05,840
这是幢什么样的楼房？
大家午饭后都干一次？
What kind of building is this?
Everybody's getting laid after lunch.

329
00:48:08,260 --> 00:48:12,763
我没有说我被干了
用你的话来说
I didn't say I was "getting laid,"
to use your expression.

330
00:48:14,725 --> 00:48:16,392
怎么啦？
What's the matter?

331
00:48:16,560 --> 00:48:19,937
我对你有点儿粗鲁啦？
是的
I'm a little crude for you?
That's right.

332
00:48:23,317 --> 00:48:27,820
瞧，布雷克小姐，我们直说吧
我有你的纪录
Look, Miss Blake, let's cut this shit.
I got all the dope on you right here.

333
00:48:28,697 --> 00:48:31,073
这个人很眼熟吧，你看，
Does this look familiar? Let me see.

334
00:48:31,241 --> 00:48:33,743
三月五号，被控行为不检…
March 5th. Charge: disorderly conduct,

335
00:48:33,911 --> 00:48:36,537
为卖淫而拉客
solicitation
for the purpose of prostitution.

336
00:48:36,705 --> 00:48:40,791
引起达拉谟警官的注意
在公园大道饭店被捕
Arresting Officer: Duram.
Apprehended at the Park Avenue Hotel.

337
00:48:41,335 --> 00:48:43,210
高级的哦
Classy arrest.

338
00:48:43,378 --> 00:48:45,880
谢谢
我们来面对这些吧，你是个妓女
Thank you.
Let's face it, you're a whore.

339
00:48:46,048 --> 00:48:48,674
一个公园大道的妓女，但你仍是妓女
A Park Avenue whore,
but you're still a whore.

340
00:48:48,842 --> 00:48:51,427
你当时和谁在搞？
Now, who were you fucking?

341
00:48:54,973 --> 00:48:56,140
去你的
Fuck you.

342
00:48:56,308 --> 00:48:58,225
不对，去你的
No, fuck you.

343
00:48:58,393 --> 00:49:00,645
你可是嫌犯而不是证人
You're no witness.
You're a suspect.

344
00:49:00,812 --> 00:49:02,271
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?

345
00:49:02,439 --> 00:49:04,690
凶器上有你的手印
We got a murder weapon
with your prints on it.

346
00:49:04,858 --> 00:49:06,817
简直是放屁，我为什么要杀她？
That's bullshit.
Why would I want to kill her?

347
00:49:06,985 --> 00:49:08,527
那个剃刀在你那里，你说过
You were there with the razor.
You tell me.

348
00:49:08,695 --> 00:49:10,863
我说过了
电梯里有个金发女郎…
I told you. There was a blonde woman
in the elevator...

349
00:49:11,031 --> 00:49:12,698
没有其他人看见那个金发女郎
Yeah, except nobody else saw
this blonde woman

350
00:49:12,866 --> 00:49:14,450
进入或离开这幢大楼
enter or leave the building.

351
00:49:14,618 --> 00:49:16,661
你没有注意到她有没有翅膀，是不是？
You didn't notice
if she had wings, did you?

352
00:49:17,704 --> 00:49:20,206
她就在电梯里，我看到她了
She was in the elevator. I saw her.

353
00:49:20,374 --> 00:49:22,333
你在那里干什么？
So, what were you doing there?

354
00:49:22,501 --> 00:49:24,210
我在工作
谁？
I had a job.
Who?

355
00:49:24,378 --> 00:49:25,711
你想让我惹麻烦吗？
You want me to get in trouble,
don't you?

356
00:49:25,879 --> 00:49:28,047
你已经有麻烦了
我没有杀她
You are in trouble.
Hey, I didn't kill her.

357
00:49:28,215 --> 00:49:30,049
那你在跟谁搞？
So who were you fucking?

358
00:49:30,217 --> 00:49:33,052
泰德，我不知道他姓什么，他是外地人
Ted, I didn't get his last name.
He's from out of town.

359
00:49:33,762 --> 00:49:35,888
太好了，来自外地的泰德
Well, that's great.
Yeah, Ted from out of town.

360
00:49:36,056 --> 00:49:38,724
这就跟电梯里的金发女郎差不多
That's almost as good
as the blonde from the elevator.

361
00:49:39,393 --> 00:49:41,560
真的
他就站在我的身后
It's true.
He was standing right behind me.

362
00:49:41,728 --> 00:49:44,063
他看到电梯门打开了
He saw the elevator doors open
and that...

363
00:49:45,273 --> 00:49:47,233
里面的女人被割伤了，流着血
...woman inside all cut up and bleeding.

364
00:49:47,401 --> 00:49:49,902
我知道米勒太太的一切
我们把她搬下了楼
I know all about Mrs. Miller.
We got her downstairs.

365
00:49:50,070 --> 00:49:52,029
他也看见了那个金发女郎吗？
But what about this blonde?
Did he see her, too?

366
00:49:52,572 --> 00:49:54,573
我不知道
I don't know.

367
00:49:57,411 --> 00:50:00,246
嗯，听着，布雷克小姐
Well, look, Miss... Miss Blake.

368
00:50:00,414 --> 00:50:05,209
找到泰德会减少你许多的麻烦
You're going to save me a lot of trouble
by finding this Ted from out of town

369
00:50:05,377 --> 00:50:08,004
把他从城外带到这里
and getting him in town
and downtown and in here

370
00:50:08,171 --> 00:50:11,799
签署一张声明说出他所看到的一切及时间
to sign this statement as to exactly
what he saw and when he saw it.

371
00:50:11,967 --> 00:50:14,260
我怎么知道他的下落？
How the hell am I supposed to know
where he is?

372
00:50:14,428 --> 00:50:16,595
如果你找不到他，我也一定找不到的
Well, if you can't find him,
I sure can't.

373
00:50:16,763 --> 00:50:20,975
不管怎样，你比我更有动机
你是个混蛋
And anyway, you got a lot better
motivation than I do. your ass.

374
00:50:23,186 --> 00:50:24,895
现在快滚
Now, get the hell out of here.

375
00:50:25,063 --> 00:50:27,314
我给你48小时的时间
I'm giving you 48 hours.

376
00:50:27,482 --> 00:50:30,776
别想离开城市，我会盯你的梢的
And don't try to blow town.
I'll be keeping tabs on you.

377
00:50:32,112 --> 00:50:33,904
诺玛？莉兹
Norma? Liz.

378
00:50:34,072 --> 00:50:36,907
你去哪里了？我一整天都在找你
Where the hell have you been?
I've been trying to get you all day.

379
00:50:42,039 --> 00:50:43,330
泰德太棒了
Ted was terrific.

380
00:50:43,498 --> 00:50:46,208
我打电话因为我想再见见他
That's why I'm calling.
I'd like to see him again.

381
00:50:46,376 --> 00:50:48,252
他什么时候回来？
When's he coming back?

382
00:50:50,630 --> 00:50:52,548
两个星期？
Two weeks?

383
00:50:52,716 --> 00:50:53,883
这不行
That's no good.

384
00:50:54,551 --> 00:50:57,928
你有他的电话号码吗？
我想跟他联络
Do you have a number for him?
I'd like to give him a call.

385
00:51:00,432 --> 00:51:02,725
这是什么意思？
伴游中心不提供电话？
What do you mean, your escort service
doesn't give out numbers?

386
00:51:02,893 --> 00:51:04,351
我想跟他联络
I want to talk to him.

387
00:51:06,313 --> 00:51:09,982
什么麻烦事，才没有
我只想找他聊聊
Trouble? No, I'm not in any trouble.
I just want to talk to the guy.

388
00:51:12,194 --> 00:51:13,652
好吧，好吧，真谢谢你啦
OK.

389
00:51:13,820 --> 00:51:15,362
好吧，真谢谢你啦
OK, thanks!

390
00:51:15,530 --> 00:51:16,947
谢什么呀
Thanks for nothing.

391
00:55:45,592 --> 00:55:46,884
你总是不在
You're just never in.

392
00:55:49,387 --> 00:55:52,139
我自己出去了
追捕那个多嘴的婊子
I've been out myself,
running down that nosy bitch.

393
00:55:56,561 --> 00:55:58,771
我发现了她的住处
I found out where she lives,

394
00:55:58,938 --> 00:56:02,775
所以我要在这里等她
等待她的面孔出现
so I'm just going to wait right here
until she shows her face.

395
00:56:05,153 --> 00:56:08,280
然后我就把她的贼眼挖出来
And then I'm going to cut
those spying eyes out.

396
00:56:11,284 --> 00:56:13,285
你打电话给我干什么？
What were you calling me about, anyway?

397
00:56:13,912 --> 00:56:17,456
不是关于我从报上看到的谋杀吧？
It wouldn't be about that murder
I read about in the papers.

398
00:56:17,624 --> 00:56:21,293
失去病人很不好受吧
你当初就不该跟她们有染！
Hell of a way to lose a patient.
But you shouldn't try to fuck them, Doc.

399
00:56:21,461 --> 00:56:23,003
嗨，马克斯，是莉兹
Hi, Max. It's Liz.

400
00:56:23,171 --> 00:56:27,091
我想买六十股奥迪庄股票
卖价是多少？
Look, I want to buy 60 shares
of Auditron. What does it sell for?

401
00:56:27,258 --> 00:56:29,301
真高兴我修理了那个爱戏弄人的傢伙
I'm glad I took care
of that cock-teaser.

402
00:56:31,137 --> 00:56:32,638
十五块六一股？
$15.60 a share?

403
00:56:32,806 --> 00:56:34,640
要是你，你也会这么做
You would've done
the same thing yourself.

404
00:56:34,808 --> 00:56:38,602
那就是九百三十六元…等等，马克斯
That's $936... Hold it a minute, Max.

405
00:56:39,896 --> 00:56:41,980
我想这就是我用你剃刀的原因
I guess that's why I used your razor.

406
00:56:42,148 --> 00:56:44,358
哈啰
不过你不用担心
Hello.
But don't worry about it, Doc.

407
00:56:44,526 --> 00:56:46,318
嗨，诺玛
打电话给警察
Hi, Norma.
Just call the police...

408
00:56:46,486 --> 00:56:48,987
昨天的事我很抱歉
失物招领中心
I'm sorry about yesterday.
...lost-and-found department.

409
00:56:49,155 --> 00:56:51,448
我知道，我是个坏姑娘
Yes, I know, I was a bad girl.

410
00:56:51,616 --> 00:56:53,575
记住，如果利维打电话…
Remember, if Levy calls...

411
00:56:53,743 --> 00:56:54,660
今晚？
Tonight?

412
00:56:54,828 --> 00:56:57,454
…告诉他我很好
不，我真的不能
...tell him I'm OK.
No, I really can't.

413
00:56:57,831 --> 00:57:00,833
诺玛，等一会儿，我在跟我妈通话
Norma, hold on just a minute.
I'm talking to my mother.

414
00:57:01,668 --> 00:57:04,002
马克斯，你什么时候需要钱？
真好玩…
Max, when do you need money?
That's funny.

415
00:57:04,170 --> 00:57:06,713
不，我不卖，
可以吗？
No, I don't want to sell anything.
Isn’t it?

416
00:57:06,881 --> 00:57:08,006
等等，马克斯
Hold it, Max.

417
00:57:09,551 --> 00:57:13,178
诺玛，你看这傢伙愿意出个五百美金吗？
Norma, do you think this guy
might go for $500?

418
00:57:15,265 --> 00:57:16,306
太好了，
Great.

419
00:57:16,474 --> 00:57:18,851
等一下儿
我跟我妈妈说声再见
Hold on just a minute.
I'm going to say goodbye to my mother.

420
00:57:19,853 --> 00:57:22,855
好，马克斯，钱到手了，
明天就交给你
OK, Max, I got the money.
I'll have it for you tomorrow.

421
00:57:23,022 --> 00:57:24,523
好，好
OK. OK.

422
00:57:26,443 --> 00:57:27,693
嗨，诺玛
Hi, Norma.

423
00:57:27,861 --> 00:57:31,947
可不可以喝个咖啡，再顺便吃个午饭
Do you think you could put together
a coffee break and a hot lunch,

424
00:57:32,115 --> 00:57:34,032
明天？
for tomorrow?

425
00:57:34,200 --> 00:57:37,411
我需要一千美元给我妈妈做手术
Yeah, I need $1, 000
for my mother's operation.

426
00:57:38,997 --> 00:57:41,748
不，没什么，我敢保证她不会有事的
No, it's nothing serious.
I'm sure she'll be fine.

427
00:57:43,543 --> 00:57:45,878
太好了，今晚几点？
这是三...
Great. Now, what time tonight?
It's been three

428
00:57:46,045 --> 00:57:47,713
到四年前动过的手术
to four years since your surgery.

429
00:57:47,881 --> 00:57:51,049
八点半，在哪里？
这是你以前的照片…
8:30. Where?
I want to show a picture, prior to...

430
00:57:51,217 --> 00:57:53,552
好，有什么特别的吗？
OK, anything special?
Where'd you find that?

431
00:57:53,720 --> 00:57:57,014
我们从人物杂志那里偷来的
Actually we stole it from
People magazine, which has an article.

432
00:57:57,182 --> 00:57:59,349
感谢上帝，异性恋还是主流
Thank God straight fucks
are still in style.

433
00:57:59,517 --> 00:58:01,310
这是南茜哈特，变性人
This is Nancy Hart, the transsexual.

434
00:58:01,478 --> 00:58:04,104
刚从克利夫兰来
这是不是非常与众不同？
Just in from Cleveland.
Isn’t that something?

435
00:58:04,272 --> 00:58:06,273
我一会儿就来
你当过战地记者？
I'll be there.
You were a war correspondent?

436
00:58:06,441 --> 00:58:07,608
还干过其他的，
Among other things.

437
00:58:07,775 --> 00:58:11,737
我还当过派驻中东的记者
And a foreign correspondent
in the Middle East. And...

438
00:58:11,905 --> 00:58:16,867
我还报导过警政新闻
我潜入过西班牙的宝藏沉船…
...I did a lot of police reporting,
and I dove on Spanish treasure wrecks.

439
00:58:17,035 --> 00:58:18,494
那个时候你很有男子气概
You did a lot
of macho things, then?

440
00:58:18,661 --> 00:58:21,705
这种变性人很多
你发现…
This is very common among transsexuals.
You find...

441
00:58:23,249 --> 00:58:26,418
我指的是由男人
变成女人的变性人
When I speak of transsexuals,
I tend to speak of male to female

442
00:58:26,586 --> 00:58:29,421
因为这种变法比从女人变成男人的多得多
because there are a whole lot of more
of them than going the other way.

443
00:58:29,589 --> 00:58:33,592
他们中间许多人有真正强壮的背景
And an awful lot of them
have real macho backgrounds.

444
00:58:33,760 --> 00:58:38,764
我认识一个警官，一个西点军校毕业生
两个战斗机驾驶员
I know a police captain, a West Pointer,
a couple of fighter pilots.

445
00:58:40,266 --> 00:58:42,935
他们都，你知道
他们都经历过痛苦的一刻
They all, you know,
most of them tried real hard.

446
00:58:43,102 --> 00:58:44,561
你结过两次婚是不是
You were married twice?

447
00:58:44,729 --> 00:58:46,939
你也是三个孩子的父亲
You are also the father
of three children.

448
00:58:48,441 --> 00:58:50,859
那你喜欢…正常…
So, you enjoyed a...

449
00:58:52,529 --> 00:58:54,863
我不应该这么说
用“正常”来表示是带有偏见的
I don't want to say normal, I guess
that's a prejudicial way to put it,

450
00:58:55,031 --> 00:58:58,784
你喜爱传统父亲的角色
but you enjoyed the traditional role
of father.

451
00:58:58,952 --> 00:59:00,244
你是三个孩子的父亲
You fathered three children,

452
00:59:00,411 --> 00:59:05,499
可你至少有两个异性性关系
and you have engaged in
at least two heterosexual relationships.

453
00:59:06,501 --> 00:59:09,294
我一直是个虔诚的异性恋者
More than that.
I've always been a devout heterosexual.

454
00:59:22,475 --> 00:59:24,017
克利夫兰？
Cleveland?

455
00:59:24,185 --> 00:59:25,227
对不起？
Excuse me?

456
00:59:25,395 --> 00:59:28,021
331号房，
请问你是从克利夫兰来的吗？
Room 331,
you're the guy from Cleveland, right?

457
00:59:29,023 --> 00:59:30,649
这是331，我是来自克利夫兰
Three-thirty-one. I'm from Cleveland.

458
00:59:31,442 --> 00:59:34,444
我是伴游服务公司的莉兹
Well, hi.
I'm Liz from the escort service.

459
00:59:36,239 --> 00:59:37,698
你没开玩笑吧
You're kidding?

460
00:59:39,158 --> 00:59:41,326
是我
是我没错
It's me.
Well, hi.

461
00:59:41,494 --> 00:59:43,120
你好？见到你很高兴
Yeah, I'm glad to meet you.

462
00:59:44,247 --> 00:59:47,291
你要我在这里干站着还是请我进去？
Well, are you going to pump me dry here
or invite me in?

463
00:59:47,458 --> 00:59:50,085
对不起，请进，要不要喝点什么
I'm sorry, come in.
You know, could I get you anything...?

464
00:59:55,117 --> 00:59:57,361
希尔顿中心
Sheraton Centre

465
01:00:16,362 --> 01:00:18,405
纳索街93号
93 Nassau Street.

466
01:00:21,117 --> 01:00:22,826
快，我们走！
Well, come on, let's go.

467
01:00:37,175 --> 01:00:39,801
别去我刚才给你的地址
Look, forget that address
I just gave you.

468
01:00:39,969 --> 01:00:42,095
把我放在哥伦布圆场
Drop me at Columbus Circle.

469
01:00:43,348 --> 01:00:46,516
你能帮帮我吗？有人在跟踪我
Could you help me out?
Someone's following me.

470
01:00:48,645 --> 01:00:52,022
我是艾略特医生
芭比听到了我的留言了吗？
This is Dr. Elliott again.
Did Bobbi pick up my messages yet?

471
01:00:52,774 --> 01:00:54,816
她知道了
真的吗？
Yes, she has.
She did?

472
01:00:54,984 --> 01:00:56,943
对，她听到了
何时？什么时候？
Yes, she did.
When?

473
01:00:57,111 --> 01:00:58,945
对不起，我不知道
I'm sorry. I wouldn't know.

474
01:01:02,784 --> 01:01:04,910
能再留个口信给她吗？
Could you give her
another message, please?

475
01:01:05,078 --> 01:01:06,912
行，说吧
哎
Yes. Go ahead.
Yeah.

476
01:01:07,080 --> 01:01:09,581
我有急事要见她
It is urgent that I see her.

477
01:01:10,249 --> 01:01:12,959
我今晚一直都会在我的办公室里
I will be in my office all tonight

478
01:01:13,127 --> 01:01:14,836
明天五点以后也会在
and after 5:00 tomorrow.

479
01:01:24,847 --> 01:01:27,808
闯红灯现在罚多少钱？
What's the going rate on running lights?

480
01:01:38,528 --> 01:01:40,028
我甩掉她了吗？
Did I lose her?

481
01:01:41,572 --> 01:01:43,615
你真行，真的很行
You're doing swell, just swell.

482
01:01:47,954 --> 01:01:49,830
但她又跟上来了
But she's still coming.

483
01:01:58,047 --> 01:02:01,967
听着，我下班后
请你吃顿晚餐怎么样
Look, I didn't deliver, so why don't you
let me take you to dinner instead?

484
01:02:03,344 --> 01:02:05,595
好，一言为定
好
All right, you got a date.
OK.

485
01:02:05,763 --> 01:02:08,265
好，我得走了
好，我会打电话给你
Look, I gotta go.
OK. Listen, I'll give you a call.

486
01:02:08,433 --> 01:02:10,100
好，要打给我就打吧
Yeah, call me.

487
01:02:27,285 --> 01:02:29,035
对不起！
Excuse me.

488
01:02:45,428 --> 01:02:47,804
让开
Get out of the way!

489
01:02:49,599 --> 01:02:52,434
这里是没人管的！
他差点夹伤我！
It's a free country!
He nearly clipped me!

490
01:04:11,180 --> 01:04:14,099
她在这里干嘛，你认识她吗？
Keeps pushing me.
Do you know her?

491
01:04:19,313 --> 01:04:21,606
女士，你在等什么？
Hey, lady, what you looking for?

492
01:04:21,774 --> 01:04:24,359
火车，这儿有站吧？
A train.
They still stop here, don't they?

493
01:04:24,527 --> 01:04:27,946
有啊，这儿有站，那里也有站
Yeah, they stop here.
They stop down there, too.

494
01:04:30,324 --> 01:04:32,284
我没有碍到你吧？
Am I bothering you?

495
01:04:32,451 --> 01:04:35,912
没有，不碍事的
那就好
No, you ain't bothering me.
Good.

496
01:04:36,080 --> 01:04:37,873
可是你碍到我了
But you're bothering me.

497
01:04:38,040 --> 01:04:39,082
桑尼，她碍到你了吗
She's bothering you, Sonny?

498
01:04:39,250 --> 01:04:41,835
对，这个贱人碍到我了
Yeah, that's right,
this bitch is bothering me.

499
01:04:42,003 --> 01:04:45,297
你打算怎么办？
揍烂她的屁股
What are you going to do about it?
I'm going to break her fucking ass.

500
01:04:45,464 --> 01:04:47,883
为什么要揍烂它？我们可以先搞她
Hey, why break it
when we can fuck it first?

501
01:04:48,050 --> 01:04:49,134
宝贝，你要上哪儿去
Hey, lady, where you going?

502
01:04:49,302 --> 01:04:50,719
我不想跟你们这些傢伙挤在一起
I don't want to crowd you guys.

503
01:04:50,887 --> 01:04:52,888
不想挤，来这里做什么
Why are you down here
if you didn't want to crowd us?

504
01:04:53,055 --> 01:04:54,306
放开我，呃？
Give me a break.

505
01:04:54,473 --> 01:04:57,142
别让她跑掉
Hey, man, don't let her get away!
Get after her!

506
01:04:57,310 --> 01:05:00,478
快，伙计！
快，捉住她！
Come on, man.
Come on, catch her, man.

507
01:05:01,063 --> 01:05:02,731
该死！滚开！
Shit! Get out of the way!

508
01:05:08,487 --> 01:05:10,614
慢点儿，女士，这不是交通尖峰期！
Take it easy, lady,
this ain't the rush hour.

509
01:05:10,781 --> 01:05:12,824
需要你们的时候
你们他妈的在哪里？
Where the fuck are you guys
when somebody needs you?

510
01:05:12,992 --> 01:05:14,075
我遭到攻击了
I was almost attacked.

511
01:05:14,243 --> 01:05:17,412
什么时候？
刚才，那些混蛋干的
When?
Right here, now, by those punks.

512
01:05:30,092 --> 01:05:31,509
我们什么也没看到
I don't see nothing.

513
01:05:31,677 --> 01:05:33,219
他们刚刚就在这里
Well, they were right here.

514
01:05:33,387 --> 01:05:35,305
你说你遭到了袭击
I thought you said you were attacked...

515
01:05:42,188 --> 01:05:45,023
刚刚有人追我
还有一个金发女郎
There are, but there's this blonde
that's been following...

516
01:05:46,525 --> 01:05:48,193
算了吧
Oh, forget it.

517
01:08:10,836 --> 01:08:12,462
我们他妈的快离开这里
Let's get the fuck out of here!

518
01:08:33,067 --> 01:08:35,068
那个金发女郎
一定是艾略特的病人
The blonde must be
one of Elliott's patients.

519
01:08:35,236 --> 01:08:37,570
我装摄影机时看到她出了诊所
I was unloading my camera
when I saw her come out of his office

520
01:08:37,738 --> 01:08:38,822
我跟踪她到你那里
and I followed her to you.

521
01:08:38,989 --> 01:08:40,615
你喷的是什么东西
What was that stuff you sprayed on her?

522
01:08:40,783 --> 01:08:42,117
我自己做的一种喷剂，
It's a kind of Mace I made at home.

523
01:08:42,284 --> 01:08:44,244
成份很简单…一种钠化合物
It's a pretty simple compound
of sodium...

524
01:08:44,411 --> 01:08:48,123
别给我上巫术课了，钠和亚当我分不清
Save the Mr. Wizard lecture,
I wouldn't know sodium from Adam.

525
01:08:49,166 --> 01:08:50,416
确实很管用
It sure worked.

526
01:08:51,502 --> 01:08:54,003
会造成暂时性的失明
只有10秒的功效
It's temporary blindness.
It only lasts about ten seconds.

527
01:08:58,008 --> 01:08:59,926
这救了我的命
Saved my life.

528
01:09:00,094 --> 01:09:01,386
我知道
I know.

529
01:09:02,221 --> 01:09:03,888
我真希望它也能救我妈一命
I wish I had saved Mom's.

530
01:09:07,393 --> 01:09:09,102
你很爱你的妈妈，是不是？
You liked your mom a lot, didn't you?

531
01:09:11,856 --> 01:09:13,398
对
Yeah.

532
01:09:15,192 --> 01:09:16,776
我想念她
I miss her.

533
01:09:22,658 --> 01:09:24,367
你还要可乐吗？
You want some more Coke?

534
01:09:25,411 --> 01:09:27,495
哦，谢谢
Yeah. Yeah, thank you.

535
01:09:28,581 --> 01:09:29,747
你看我的画儿怎么样？
How do you like my painting?

536
01:09:35,588 --> 01:09:37,088
很不错
It's... very nice.

537
01:09:37,256 --> 01:09:40,425
我几年前花五百美元买的
I bought it a couple of years ago
for $500.

538
01:09:41,343 --> 01:09:43,595
确实是个很大的投资
It's really a great investment.

539
01:09:43,762 --> 01:09:47,974
十年后可能有百万的价值
I mean, ten years from now,
it could be worth... a million dollars.

540
01:09:50,644 --> 01:09:52,395
当然，如果画家死了会更值钱
More if the artist dies, of course.

541
01:09:56,567 --> 01:09:58,526
祝你好运
谢谢
Good luck with it.
Thanks.

542
01:09:59,820 --> 01:10:01,779
你父亲不会纳闷你在哪里吗？
Doesn't your father wonder
where you are?

543
01:10:01,947 --> 01:10:04,115
他不是我父亲，是我继父
He's not my father. He's my stepfather.

544
01:10:04,283 --> 01:10:07,452
我告诉他，我住在朋友保罗家
保罗会掩护我
I told him I am staying at my friend
Paul's, and he'll cover for me.

545
01:10:07,620 --> 01:10:09,329
那我明天送你回家
I'll take you home tomorrow.

546
01:10:09,496 --> 01:10:12,123
不，我不想回家
瞧，布雷克小姐，我有张照片…
I don't want to go home.
Miss Blake, I've got some pictures...

547
01:10:12,291 --> 01:10:13,249
叫我莉兹，好吗？
Call me Liz, OK?

548
01:10:13,417 --> 01:10:15,460
莉兹，我拍了张金发女郎的照片
Liz, I've got some pictures
of that blonde

549
01:10:15,628 --> 01:10:17,462
我在艾略特办公室外藏了个照相机
from a camera I hid
outside Elliott's office.

550
01:10:17,630 --> 01:10:21,299
我们得进去，找到艾略特的记录薄
找出她的姓名
Now, we gotta get in, get Elliott's
appointment book, and get her name.

551
01:10:21,467 --> 01:10:24,719
警察就是干这个的
我们去跟马利诺谈谈
That's what the police are for.
Come on, let's talk to Marino.

552
01:10:24,887 --> 01:10:27,388
好，你去找马利诺谈吧，
我去找出金发女郎的姓名
Fine, you talk to Marino.
I'm going to find out the blonde's name.

553
01:10:28,140 --> 01:10:31,935
你以为你是谁，超人？
天啊，你只是个孩子
Who do you think you are, Superman?
You're just a kid, for God's sake.

554
01:10:32,102 --> 01:10:34,479
我是救了你一命的孩子
Yeah, I'm the kid that saved your life.

555
01:10:39,151 --> 01:10:43,821
这样好了，我去跟马利诺谈谈
All right, look,
let me talk to Marino.

556
01:10:45,491 --> 01:10:47,408
如果他不管，我再帮你的忙
If he cops out, then I'll help you.

557
01:10:50,829 --> 01:10:54,290
好吧，但你不能提我的名字
OK, but you can't mention my name.

558
01:10:54,458 --> 01:10:55,875
麦克会杀死我的
Mike would kill me.

559
01:10:56,043 --> 01:10:59,879
我应该在准备法语考试
I'm supposed to be...
studying for a French exam.

560
01:11:01,840 --> 01:11:04,842
你朋友今晚掩护你，是不是？
Well, your friend's covering
for you tonight, right?

561
01:11:06,095 --> 01:11:09,764
嗯，我也是你的朋友
我将是你最大的掩护
Well, I'm your friend, too,
and I'll be the best cover you ever had.

562
01:11:11,475 --> 01:11:12,558
好吧
OK.

563
01:11:13,769 --> 01:11:15,645
你在这里不会有事吧？
You sure you going to be OK here?

564
01:11:15,813 --> 01:11:16,854
没事
Fine.

565
01:11:17,815 --> 01:11:20,483
嗯，给你
Well... Here you go.

566
01:11:21,527 --> 01:11:23,278
晚安
晚安
Good night.
Good night.

567
01:11:27,658 --> 01:11:29,617
马利诺，我得跟你谈谈
Hey, Marino, I gotta talk to you.

568
01:11:29,785 --> 01:11:31,119
你的外地客户出现了吗？
没有
Mr. Out-of-Town turn up?
No.

569
01:11:31,287 --> 01:11:32,996
那你最好带睡袋过来
Then you better send
for your overnight bags.

570
01:11:33,163 --> 01:11:35,540
算了吧
你知道我没杀那个女人
Hey, come on,
you know I didn't kill that woman.

571
01:11:35,708 --> 01:11:36,958
你仍是我最佳的赌注
You're still my best bet.

572
01:11:38,210 --> 01:11:41,462
你听好，她昨晚差点杀了我
For your information,
she tried to kill me last night.

573
01:11:42,214 --> 01:11:43,798
真的吗？
Really?

574
01:11:43,966 --> 01:11:46,175
这是你关心的声音吗？
Is that supposed to be concern
in your voice?

575
01:11:46,343 --> 01:11:49,971
我从职业的角度来关心公民间的彼此残杀
I take a professional interest
in our citizens knocking each other off.

576
01:11:50,139 --> 01:11:52,223
这是在哪里发生的？
Where did this happen?

577
01:11:52,391 --> 01:11:54,225
她一路从希尔顿饭店跟着我
跟到地下铁
She followed me from the Sheraton
into the subway.

578
01:11:54,393 --> 01:11:56,686
我以为我甩了她
结果我回家时她在等我
I thought I lost her,
but she was waiting when I got home.

579
01:11:56,854 --> 01:11:58,813
她企图用剃刀杀我
有没有目击者
She tried to slash me.
Any witnesses to this one?

580
01:11:58,981 --> 01:12:00,023
有
谁？
Yes.
Who?

581
01:12:03,736 --> 01:12:06,696
我不能告诉你
又出城了吗？
I can't tell you.
Out of town again?

582
01:12:07,448 --> 01:12:09,324
没有，我只是答应什么都不说
No, I just promised
I wouldn't say anything.

583
01:12:10,492 --> 01:12:12,493
这一套我听多了
You know, this has
a familiar ring to it.

584
01:12:12,661 --> 01:12:15,246
听着，马利诺
我对你自认聪明的混帐话不感兴趣
Look, Marino, I'm not interested
in your wiseass remarks.

585
01:12:15,414 --> 01:12:16,998
有人想杀我，我需要帮助
Someone's trying to kill me,
and I need help.

586
01:12:17,166 --> 01:12:19,959
我会帮助你的，我有个好牢房
你在那里会安全的
I'll help you. I got a nice cell.
You'll be very safe in it.

587
01:12:20,127 --> 01:12:21,252
嘿，艾迪！
Hey, Eddie.

588
01:12:21,420 --> 01:12:22,670
等一等
Hey, wait a minute. Look.

589
01:12:22,838 --> 01:12:25,256
我知道杀人犯是艾略特的一个病人
I know the murderer is
one of Elliott's patients.

590
01:12:25,424 --> 01:12:27,592
你怎么知道的？
她从他的办公室出来！
How do you know that?
Because she came out of his office.

591
01:12:27,760 --> 01:12:29,385
你看见的吗？
Did you see her?

592
01:12:30,929 --> 01:12:33,806
不是，但我知道她从那里出来
Well, no, not exactly.
But I know she came out.

593
01:12:33,974 --> 01:12:36,017
你要得到他的纪录簿
You got to get in there,
get his appointment book.

594
01:12:36,185 --> 01:12:37,310
上面一定有她的名字
Her name's got to be in it.

595
01:12:38,020 --> 01:12:40,271
希望你当妓女比当侦探更加出色
I hope you make a better hooker
than you do a detective.

596
01:12:41,065 --> 01:12:43,775
我很久以前就想到了艾略特的记录簿
I thought about Elliott's appointment
book a long time ago.

597
01:12:43,942 --> 01:12:45,068
那么？
结果呢
So?
So...

598
01:12:45,235 --> 01:12:48,946
你不能走进一个医生的诊所
没头没脑的去查
You can’t just walk into some shrink's
joint and start going through his books.

599
01:12:49,114 --> 01:12:51,741
你得有搜索证
而法官需要很长时间
You need a search warrant.
And judges take a long time

600
01:12:51,909 --> 01:12:54,702
才会让你开始四处探索
before they let you start snooping
around some shrink's office.

601
01:12:56,789 --> 01:13:01,459
当然，这不能阻止
一个偏执的杀人嫌疑犯
Of course, that wouldn't prevent
a paranoid murder suspect

602
01:13:01,627 --> 01:13:03,795
偷偷进去
from breaking in.

603
01:13:04,380 --> 01:13:08,508
寻找某些证据来为她的案子辩护
You know, searching for some evidence
to defend her case.

604
01:13:08,675 --> 01:13:11,302
我懂了，你要我替你当小偷
Oh, I get it.
You want me to break in for you.

605
01:13:11,470 --> 01:13:15,139
我没想让你做任何非法的事
你可以引用我的话
I don't want you to do anything illegal.
You can quote me on that.

606
01:13:15,974 --> 01:13:20,228
但我明天会抓你进来，明白吗？明天
But I'm booking you tomorrow.
You got it? Tomorrow.

607
01:13:42,668 --> 01:13:43,709
我是利维医生
I'm Dr. Levy.

608
01:13:43,877 --> 01:13:45,878
你好？我是艾略特医生
How do you do? I'm Dr. Elliott.

609
01:13:48,173 --> 01:13:50,508
我能为你做点儿什么，艾略特医生？
What can I do for you, Dr. Elliott?

610
01:13:51,510 --> 01:13:53,469
你还诊断过我的病人呢
You're seeing a patient of mine.

611
01:13:53,637 --> 01:13:54,929
没错
That's right.

612
01:13:55,097 --> 01:13:56,556
我认为她很危险
I believe she's dangerous.

613
01:13:56,723 --> 01:13:58,641
真的？怎么个危险法？
Really? In what way?

614
01:13:58,809 --> 01:14:00,685
她在给我惹麻烦
因为我不同意
She's causing me trouble
because I wouldn't approve

615
01:14:00,853 --> 01:14:02,061
她动变性手术
her sex-change operation.

616
01:14:02,896 --> 01:14:04,772
什么样的麻烦？
What kind of trouble has she caused you?

617
01:14:04,940 --> 01:14:07,567
她几次打电话威胁我
She's threatened me several times
over the phone.

618
01:14:07,734 --> 01:14:11,529
她还偷了我的剃刀
她为什么要那么做？
She also stole my razor.
Why would she do that?

619
01:14:11,697 --> 01:14:15,366
医生，你知道有位妇女
在电梯里被杀的报道吗？
Doctor, did you read about the woman
who was slashed to death in an elevator?

620
01:14:15,534 --> 01:14:17,326
那是头条新闻
It was on the front page,
I could hardly miss...

621
01:14:17,494 --> 01:14:19,871
凯特·米勒，遇害者，我的病人！
Kate Miller, the victim, was my patient.

622
01:14:21,081 --> 01:14:23,541
你想芭比与此有关
You don't think that Bobbi
had anything to do with that?

623
01:14:23,709 --> 01:14:27,044
我的剃刀不见了
凯特·米勒是被剃刀杀死的
My razor's gone.
Kate Miller was killed with a razor.

624
01:14:28,213 --> 01:14:29,672
会不会是别人拿走的？
Nobody else could have taken it?

625
01:14:29,840 --> 01:14:33,468
医生，我不是紧张过度
芭比用电话威胁我
Doctor, I am not paranoid.
Bobbi has threatened me over the phone.

626
01:14:33,635 --> 01:14:35,219
她说要伤害我
She said she was going to hurt me.

627
01:14:35,387 --> 01:14:38,055
我的病人被杀了，我的剃刀不见了！
My patient was slashed to death,
and my razor's gone.

628
01:14:38,223 --> 01:14:41,559
现在你不必是个侦探就可以推算出
是不是？
Now you don't have to be a detective
to figure it out, do you?

629
01:14:42,644 --> 01:14:46,147
跟我来，我们去跟警察谈谈
Come with me, and...
we'll talk to the police.

630
01:14:46,315 --> 01:14:47,773
我已经去过警察局了
I've already been to the police.

631
01:14:48,567 --> 01:14:51,777
我没有提到芭比，我想先跟她谈谈
But I didn't tell them about Bobbi.
I wanted to talk to her first.

632
01:14:51,945 --> 01:14:54,572
我要确定是她干的
I wanted to be absolutely sure
that it was her.

633
01:14:54,740 --> 01:14:57,074
但她不给我回电话
But she wouldn't return my calls.

634
01:14:57,242 --> 01:14:59,243
我希望你能够帮我
I was hoping you'd be able to help.

635
01:15:00,287 --> 01:15:01,704
好，我来帮你
Yes, I'll help.

636
01:15:02,289 --> 01:15:03,998
我跟她谈谈
I'll talk to her.

637
01:15:04,166 --> 01:15:07,084
如果我同意你的诊断，我们就去警察局
If I agree with your diagnosis,
we'll go to the police.

638
01:15:07,252 --> 01:15:08,336
谢谢
Thank you.

639
01:15:08,962 --> 01:15:10,796
请告诉我进展的情况
Please let me know what happens.

640
01:15:10,964 --> 01:15:13,257
你知道为什么芭比到我这里来吗？
Do you know why Bobbi came to see me
in the first place?

641
01:15:13,759 --> 01:15:15,092
不知道
No.

642
01:15:19,640 --> 01:15:23,392
何不到我办公室去，我来联络她
Why don't we go to my office,
and we'll try to get in touch with her.

643
01:15:23,560 --> 01:15:26,020
我约会要晚了
I am late for an appointment now.

644
01:15:26,188 --> 01:15:29,023
联络上她之后打个电话到我办公室，好吗？
Why don't you call me at my office
when you've reached her.

645
01:15:29,191 --> 01:15:30,274
好
All right.

646
01:15:30,984 --> 01:15:32,652
那你一定会在办公室里吗？
You sure you'll be at your office?

647
01:15:32,819 --> 01:15:34,237
对，我一定会在的
Yes, I'm sure.

648
01:15:35,113 --> 01:15:36,614
到时，我再给你打电话
I'll call you there.

649
01:15:47,209 --> 01:15:50,127
彼得·米勒，我冲洗了些八厘米胶卷
Peter Miller, I left some Super-8 film.

650
01:15:50,295 --> 01:15:52,088
这是四美元
There's four dollars there.

651
01:16:04,935 --> 01:16:07,144
我计算了艾略特病人离开的时间
I timed Elliott's patients
coming out of his office,

652
01:16:07,312 --> 01:16:08,646
最快是八秒
and the fastest was eight seconds.

653
01:16:08,814 --> 01:16:10,606
我的相机每四秒闪一次，
So I set my camera to go off
every four seconds

654
01:16:10,774 --> 01:16:13,276
没有人逃得掉
so I'd be sure to get a good shot
of everybody.

655
01:16:27,833 --> 01:16:31,085
那就是她
她一定是最后的一位
That's her.
She must be his last appointment.

656
01:16:31,628 --> 01:16:33,170
我们得看一下那个本子
We got to get a look in that book.

657
01:16:34,006 --> 01:16:37,675
我知道，马利诺也想看
只是我能让他早点儿看到
Yeah, I know. Marino wants it, too.
Only, I can get it for him faster.

658
01:16:38,552 --> 01:16:41,178
他威胁我，一定要我去拿
No legal red tape, just my ass.

659
01:16:41,346 --> 01:16:45,057
我去拿好了，没人敢威胁我吧
我只是个悲伤的孩子
Look, I'll get it, nobody cares about
my ass. I'm just a grief-struck kid.

660
01:16:46,018 --> 01:16:47,560
多好的孩子
Yeah, but what a kid.

661
01:16:50,439 --> 01:16:52,940
我有个主意
Okay, I got an idea.

662
01:16:56,069 --> 01:16:57,862
你能见我真是太好了
It was very nice of you to see...

663
01:17:02,034 --> 01:17:04,201
能这么快见我真是太好了
It was nice of you to see me so soon.

664
01:17:05,329 --> 01:17:07,913
我晚上都空着回电话
I try to keep my nights open
for returning phone calls

665
01:17:08,081 --> 01:17:10,625
或以防病人有些额外的需要
or in case a patient
needs some extra help.

666
01:17:12,544 --> 01:17:13,919
我很为你担心
I was worried about you.

667
01:17:15,380 --> 01:17:17,506
你一定有痛苦的经历吧
You've had a terrible experience.

668
01:17:19,259 --> 01:17:20,843
我知道
I know.

669
01:17:21,011 --> 01:17:23,095
我没有意识到这点儿
I didn't realize...

670
01:17:23,263 --> 01:17:26,182
但我一直在做噩梦
But I've been having
these terrible nightmares.

671
01:17:31,063 --> 01:17:32,855
是关于什么的？
What were they about?

672
01:17:34,232 --> 01:17:35,483
唔
Well...

673
01:17:37,235 --> 01:17:39,028
我得抽支烟
I have to get a cigarette.

674
01:17:41,156 --> 01:17:44,659
我在一个屋子里，会见朋友
I'm in this house that I've never
been to before, visiting a friend.

675
01:17:49,539 --> 01:17:50,623
他不在那里
He's not there.

676
01:17:53,043 --> 01:17:57,171
我在看电视，门铃响了
I'm watching TV...
and the doorbell rings.

677
01:17:59,091 --> 01:18:00,383
是个男人
It's a man.

678
01:18:01,593 --> 01:18:04,261
长的又高又黑
He's big, dark.

679
01:18:07,182 --> 01:18:10,267
他说他的车子抛锚了
需要借用电话
He says his car broke down,
and he needs to use the phone.

680
01:18:12,104 --> 01:18:14,105
我相信了，就让他进来了
I believe him and let him in...

681
01:18:16,108 --> 01:18:18,526
但我觉得有点不对劲
...although I know something's wrong.

682
01:18:22,072 --> 01:18:26,784
他关上了门，上了锁
拿出了剃刀
He closes the door, locks it,
and takes out a razor.

683
01:18:29,037 --> 01:18:31,247
他说他不想伤害我
He says he's not going to hurt me.

684
01:18:36,294 --> 01:18:40,506
然后他告诉我他将怎么对待我
Then he tells me...
what he's going to do to me...

685
01:18:42,926 --> 01:18:45,219
他还说我一定会喜欢
...and how much I'm going to like it.

686
01:18:45,929 --> 01:18:48,889
他说话的时候
All the time he's talking,

687
01:18:49,057 --> 01:18:51,809
我看到他的裤裆一直鼓着
I can see the bulge in his pants.

688
01:18:54,104 --> 01:18:55,938
他让我脱光衣服
He orders me to strip.

689
01:18:57,149 --> 01:19:00,484
我照着做了，眼睛看着剃刀
I do it,
keeping one eye on the razor.

690
01:19:02,988 --> 01:19:05,364
他脱下了裤子
He drops his pants...

691
01:19:06,491 --> 01:19:10,286
他强迫我趴下
...forces me down, on my stomach.

692
01:19:11,496 --> 01:19:15,374
他摊开我的腿，跪在我后面
He spreads my legs,
kneels down behind me...

693
01:19:17,085 --> 01:19:19,170
将冰凉的刀片…
...and rests the cold blade.

694
01:19:33,477 --> 01:19:34,727
…强行将其…
Forcing it.

695
01:19:38,023 --> 01:19:39,273
对不起
I'm sorry.

696
01:19:41,359 --> 01:19:42,777
怎么啦？
What's the matter?

697
01:19:42,944 --> 01:19:44,695
太恶心了
It's just so dirty.

698
01:19:45,697 --> 01:19:47,198
你为什么要这么说？
Why do you say that?

699
01:19:48,200 --> 01:19:50,659
我知道什么是恶心的事
这件事是叫人恶心
Look, I know what dirty is,
and this is dirty.

700
01:19:55,457 --> 01:19:58,083
你为什么不讲出来？
Well, why don't you just talk about it?

701
01:19:58,251 --> 01:20:00,377
我保证不会跟你想得一样坏
I'm sure it's not as bad as you think.

702
01:20:01,713 --> 01:20:03,047
很坏
It's very bad.

703
01:20:04,257 --> 01:20:06,509
我是个坏事专家
And you're talking to an expert on bad.

704
01:20:06,676 --> 01:20:07,718
真的吗
Oh, really?

705
01:20:08,762 --> 01:20:10,888
为何你认为你是专家？
Now what makes you such an expert?

706
01:20:11,890 --> 01:20:13,432
因为我是个妓女
Because I'm a hooker.

707
01:20:13,934 --> 01:20:15,017
呵
Ah.

708
01:20:15,811 --> 01:20:20,272
你刚才说到的坏事我都差不多干过
And I have done most of the bad things
you just read about.

709
01:20:21,066 --> 01:20:23,067
你喜欢干这些事吗？
Do you like doing these things?

710
01:20:23,610 --> 01:20:25,861
有时候会喜欢
你喜欢其中的什么？
Sometimes.
What do you like about it?

711
01:20:27,405 --> 01:20:28,823
我喜欢挑逗男人
I like to turn men on.

712
01:20:30,784 --> 01:20:33,410
我必须好好干，他们付给我的钱很多
I must do a pretty good job
because they pay me a lot.

713
01:20:34,246 --> 01:20:35,913
你从来没有免费性交过？
Do you ever have any sex
that's not paid for?

714
01:20:38,917 --> 01:20:40,626
这是个建议吗？
Is that a proposal?

715
01:20:41,920 --> 01:20:43,337
没有
No. It...

716
01:20:44,256 --> 01:20:47,591
我们心理医生称之为问题
It's what we psychiatrists call
a question.

717
01:20:48,677 --> 01:20:50,469
有啊
Yes.

718
01:20:50,637 --> 01:20:51,804
有什么
"Yes" what?

719
01:20:51,972 --> 01:20:55,015
是的，有过，如果一个男人能挑起我情欲
Yes, I do. For men that turn me on.

720
01:20:56,768 --> 01:20:58,227
什么样的男人能挑起你情欲？
What sort of men turn you on?

721
01:21:01,606 --> 01:21:03,983
成熟、医生型的
Mature, doctorly type.

722
01:21:04,943 --> 01:21:06,569
就像你
Like you.

723
01:21:09,573 --> 01:21:11,365
你被我的性感吸引住了吗？
Are you sexually attracted to me?

724
01:21:12,409 --> 01:21:14,451
是的，你呢？
Yes. Are you?

725
01:21:14,619 --> 01:21:16,579
被你吸引住了？
嗯
Attracted to you?
Mm-hm.

726
01:21:18,206 --> 01:21:19,790
是的
Yes.

727
01:21:21,751 --> 01:21:24,169
可是这又不是一般的拜访
But then,
this isn't a social visit, is it?

728
01:21:24,337 --> 01:21:27,965
你需要帮助
而我的责任是要帮助你调整情绪
You've come here for help and my job
is to offer you emotional assistance.

729
01:21:28,967 --> 01:21:31,176
来点儿性帮助怎么样？
How about some sexual assistance?

730
01:21:33,346 --> 01:21:34,889
你想搞我吗？
Do you want to fuck me?

731
01:21:35,932 --> 01:21:38,225
想啊
那为何不上？
Oh, yes.
Well, why don't you?

732
01:21:38,393 --> 01:21:40,978
我是个医生…而且…
我搞过医生…
Because I'm a doctor and...
Fucked a lot of doctors.

733
01:21:41,146 --> 01:21:43,105
我结婚了
我也搞过结婚的
And I'm married.
Fucked a lot of them, too.

734
01:21:43,273 --> 01:21:44,732
我们是不是离题了？
Don't you think
we're getting off the point?

735
01:21:46,735 --> 01:21:48,360
你不介意我脱掉外衣吧？
Do you mind if I take off my coat?

736
01:21:49,738 --> 01:21:50,905
不会
No.

737
01:22:02,792 --> 01:22:05,618
还有其他的？
And the rest, too?

738
01:22:07,005 --> 01:22:09,673
你为什么想做这样的事？
Now, why would you want to do
a thing like that?

739
01:22:10,508 --> 01:22:14,887
因为你内裤凸起的尺寸
Well, because of the size of that cock
in your pants.

740
01:22:16,222 --> 01:22:18,682
我看你不那么像个已婚者
I don't think you're so married.

741
01:22:30,820 --> 01:22:32,154
嗯？
Well?

742
01:22:33,406 --> 01:22:35,199
你看怎么样？
What do you think?

743
01:22:39,329 --> 01:22:41,205
我看你是个很吸引人的女人
I think you're a very attractive woman.

744
01:22:44,084 --> 01:22:45,501
你想摸摸我吗？
Would you like to touch me?

745
01:22:49,255 --> 01:22:50,714
想也不想，想是因为我是…
Yes and no. Yes, because I'm...

746
01:22:50,882 --> 01:22:52,174
嗯，那你为什么不摸？
Well, why don't you?

747
01:22:53,051 --> 01:22:54,343
我已经告诉你原因了
I told you why.

748
01:22:58,181 --> 01:23:02,226
对，你是位结了婚的医生，我想起来了
That's right. You're a married doctor.
I remember now.

749
01:23:02,936 --> 01:23:05,729
我看你是胡说八道
是吗？
I think you're full of shit.
You do?

750
01:23:06,731 --> 01:23:09,525
仅仅是因为我有个人和职业道德？
Just because I happen to have
personal and professional ethics?

751
01:23:11,403 --> 01:23:14,446
瞧，医生，你看你有点害羞
Look, Doc, I think you're kind of shy.

752
01:23:15,198 --> 01:23:20,244
我去给鼻子上点粉
So... I'm going to go powder my nose

753
01:23:20,412 --> 01:23:22,663
我回来时
and when I come back,

754
01:23:22,831 --> 01:23:26,542
希望看到你的衣服就在我的旁边
I hope to find your clothes
right next to mine.

755
01:23:27,043 --> 01:23:30,921
否则我们只好继续意淫下去
And if not, we can just get back
to the mind-fuck.

756
01:25:05,558 --> 01:25:08,099
十一月二十号
NOVEMBER 20

757
01:25:10,192 --> 01:25:12,195
克里斯·克莱门
Chris Clemens

758
01:26:14,586 --> 01:26:16,170
艾略特医生？
Dr. Elliott?

759
01:26:25,305 --> 01:26:26,972
艾略特医生？
Dr. Elliott?

760
01:26:30,226 --> 01:26:31,560
艾略特医生？
Dr. Elliott?

761
01:26:35,732 --> 01:26:37,566
你真得很害羞，是不是？
You really are shy, aren't you?

762
01:26:37,734 --> 01:26:39,109
莉兹！
Liz!

763
01:26:49,120 --> 01:26:50,454
在你身后，莉兹！
Behind you, Liz!

764
01:28:13,037 --> 01:28:14,246
那你在跟踪我？
So you had me followed?

765
01:28:14,414 --> 01:28:15,956
对
That's right.

766
01:28:16,124 --> 01:28:19,543
你碰到了贝蒂·露丝
我们最好的年轻警察之一
You've met Betty Luce, one of our best
young police... persons.

767
01:28:19,711 --> 01:28:22,879
当我告诉你我被攻击时
你以为我是个疯子
When I told you I was attacked
on the subway, you thought I was nuts.

768
01:28:23,047 --> 01:28:26,133
露丝侦探告诉我
她在哥伦布圆环跟丢了你
Well, Detective Luce told me
she lost you at Columbus Circle.

769
01:28:26,301 --> 01:28:30,220
我没有意识到
还有个金发女郎跟踪你，谁会想到呢？
I didn't figure there was another blonde
following you. I mean, who would?

770
01:28:30,388 --> 01:28:33,974
对啊，你还认为我在胡思乱想
Yeah, and you wrote me off as a girl
with an overactive imagination.

771
01:28:34,142 --> 01:28:35,309
的确如此
Yeah, something like that.

772
01:28:35,476 --> 01:28:38,270
她就跟踪我到艾略特这里
对
And she followed me to Elliott's.
That's right.

773
01:28:39,063 --> 01:28:42,232
谢天谢地，那个傢伙到底有什么毛病？
Thank God.
What's wrong with that guy, anyway?

774
01:28:42,525 --> 01:28:44,192
他是个变性人
什么？
He was a transsexual.
What?

775
01:28:44,360 --> 01:28:46,069
变性人
A transsexual.

776
01:28:46,779 --> 01:28:50,157
他男性的一面使他不能跨出最后的一步
About to make the final step, but his
male side couldn't let him do it.

777
01:28:50,325 --> 01:28:51,533
男性的一面？
Male side?

778
01:28:52,702 --> 01:28:54,286
有个艾略特医生，
There was Dr. Elliott,

779
01:28:54,454 --> 01:28:56,079
有个芭比
and there was Bobbi.

780
01:28:56,247 --> 01:28:58,707
芭比来找我批准
Bobbi came to me
to get psychiatric approval

781
01:28:58,875 --> 01:29:00,417
做变性手术
for a sex-reassignment operation.

782
01:29:00,585 --> 01:29:04,338
我想他不稳定
艾略特后来证实了我的诊断
I thought he was unstable,
and Elliott confirmed my diagnosis.

783
01:29:04,505 --> 01:29:07,507
对立的性别存在于同一个躯体
Opposite sexes inhabiting the same body.

784
01:29:07,675 --> 01:29:10,218
变性手术是要解决这个冲突
The sex-change operation
was to resolve the conflict.

785
01:29:10,386 --> 01:29:14,222
但芭比努力争取手术
But as much as Bobbi tried to get it,

786
01:29:14,390 --> 01:29:15,849
艾略特却封杀了道路
Elliott blocked it.

787
01:29:17,268 --> 01:29:18,643
所以芭比报复了
So Bobbi got even.

788
01:29:18,811 --> 01:29:20,604
杀死了米勒太太
By killing Mrs. Miller.

789
01:29:20,772 --> 01:29:24,858
对，她刺激了艾略特
就像你刚才那样，布雷克小姐
Yes, she aroused Elliott,
just as you did, Miss Blake.

790
01:29:25,526 --> 01:29:28,278
你是说，当艾略特“性”奋时
就变成芭比？
You mean, when Elliott got turned on,
Bobbi took over?

791
01:29:28,446 --> 01:29:32,115
对，这就像是芭比的红色警报
Yes. It was like Bobbi's red alert.

792
01:29:32,533 --> 01:29:35,660
艾略特勃起了，芭比就掌控情势
Elliott's penis became erect
and Bobbi took control,

793
01:29:35,828 --> 01:29:38,997
试图杀害任何使艾略特男性崛起的人
trying to kill anyone
that made Elliott masculinely sexual.

794
01:29:39,165 --> 01:29:41,917
我遇见艾略特时
那是我首次...
When Elliott came to my office,
it was the first time

795
01:29:42,085 --> 01:29:44,252
见到芭比男性的一面
I saw Bobbi's masculine self.

796
01:29:44,420 --> 01:29:48,215
当他告诉我
他认为芭比杀害了米勒太太时
When he told me that he thought
Bobbi had killed Mrs. Miller,

797
01:29:48,383 --> 01:29:49,966
他在自首
he was confessing himself.

798
01:29:51,636 --> 01:29:53,929
我马上通知了马利诺侦探
I immediately called Detective Marino.

799
01:29:55,473 --> 01:29:58,225
那你为什么不阻止我到这里来？
So why the hell didn't you stop me
from going to Elliott's?

800
01:29:58,393 --> 01:30:02,646
为什么？因为我跟我孩子在看足球比赛
Why? Because I was at a football game
with my kids, that's why.

801
01:30:02,814 --> 01:30:05,607
我跟利维医生联系上时
你已经来这里了
By the time I spoke with Dr. Levy,
you were already over there.

802
01:30:06,275 --> 01:30:08,610
那你从来也没认为是我杀了米勒太太
So you never really thought
I killed Mrs. Miller?

803
01:30:09,821 --> 01:30:13,990
没有，但我得去艾略特的办公室
找出那个怪癖是谁
No. But I had to get into Elliott's
office to find out which weirdo did,

804
01:30:14,158 --> 01:30:16,868
因此我逼你帮忙
so I pressed you into service.

805
01:30:17,036 --> 01:30:18,120
你开玩笑吧？
Are you kidding?

806
01:30:19,372 --> 01:30:21,248
我让露丝小姐跟踪你
So I had Miss Luce there tailing you

807
01:30:21,416 --> 01:30:23,792
确保你不会遇到太大麻烦
to make sure
you didn't get into too much trouble.

808
01:30:25,878 --> 01:30:26,962
谢谢
Thanks.

809
01:30:28,464 --> 01:30:33,009
帮助警察总令人开心
Well, it's always wonderful
to be of some assistance to the police.

810
01:30:33,177 --> 01:30:34,553
你在开玩笑？
Are you kidding?

811
01:30:36,556 --> 01:30:38,557
艾略特会怎么样？
So what's going to happen to Elliott?

812
01:30:51,612 --> 01:30:52,529
嗯？
Well?

813
01:30:52,697 --> 01:30:56,032
有些男人和女人认为他们生错了身体
There's some men and women who think
they're born in the wrong body.

814
01:30:56,200 --> 01:30:57,701
他们叫做有异性转化欲者
They're called transsexuals.

815
01:30:57,869 --> 01:31:00,704
他们唯一想要做的是改变性别
And all they want to do
is have their sex changed.

816
01:31:05,042 --> 01:31:06,418
你怎么改啊？
How do you do that?

817
01:31:07,211 --> 01:31:09,045
如果你是个男人想变成女人
Well, if you're a man
that wants to become a woman,

818
01:31:09,213 --> 01:31:11,214
你吃雌性荷尔蒙
you take female hormones.

819
01:31:11,382 --> 01:31:12,591
它们有什么用呢？
What do they do?

820
01:31:13,509 --> 01:31:17,929
你皮肤变软
乳房增大，你再也不会变硬了
Well, your skin softens, you grow
breasts, and you don't get hard anymore.

821
01:31:21,726 --> 01:31:22,767
很好
Great.

822
01:31:24,145 --> 01:31:26,438
你真地想了解这些吗？
You sure you want to know about this?

823
01:31:26,606 --> 01:31:31,234
这为我的科学计划
提供了一些很好的新主意
Yeah. It's giving me some wonderful
new ideas for a science project.

824
01:31:31,819 --> 01:31:35,822
我不造电脑了
我要造一个女人--从我体内
Instead of building a computer,
I could build a woman... out of me.

825
01:31:35,990 --> 01:31:40,202
好主意，那样的话
我详情地讲给你听
Great idea. In that case,
I'll give you all the details.

826
01:31:40,369 --> 01:31:42,245
下一步是动手术
The next step is surgery.

827
01:31:42,914 --> 01:31:46,166
让我想想我是否记住了利维用的词
Let me see if I can remember
the exact word that Levy told me.

828
01:31:46,334 --> 01:31:48,084
阴茎解剖
Oh, yeah, a penectomy.

829
01:31:49,170 --> 01:31:50,337
那是什么？
What's that?

830
01:31:50,755 --> 01:31:55,175
你知道，他们抓住你的阴茎，从中间剖开
You know, when they take your penis
and slice it down the middle.

831
01:31:56,469 --> 01:31:59,054
我想就是这个意思
Yeah, that's what I thought it was.

832
01:31:59,222 --> 01:32:00,972
然后…
Then...

833
01:32:02,183 --> 01:32:03,767
去势
...castration...

834
01:32:05,436 --> 01:32:09,564
塑胶整形，形成一个人工阴道
...plastic reconstruction and
the formation of an artificial vagina.

835
01:32:09,732 --> 01:32:13,026
行话称之为“塑胶阴道”
A vaginoplasty, to those in the know.

836
01:32:15,613 --> 01:32:17,781
我以为艾略特只是穿上了裙子
And I thought Elliott
just put on a dress.

837
01:32:17,949 --> 01:32:20,033
他穿了，还戴了假发
He did. And a wig, too.

838
01:32:20,201 --> 01:32:23,203
但在床上这还不够，你得脱掉一切
But you see, that's no good in bed,
when you gotta take everything off.

839
01:32:23,955 --> 01:32:25,413
他现在会怎么样？
What's going to happen to him now?

840
01:32:26,249 --> 01:32:28,625
首先他得先治好枪伤
Well, first he has to recover
from the gun wound,

841
01:32:28,793 --> 01:32:32,796
如果他疯病好了能走出疯人院
他们就会审判他
and then if he's ever sane enough
to get out of Bellevue, they'll try him.

842
01:32:33,464 --> 01:32:36,466
你猜谁是明星证人？
And guess who's the star witness.

843
01:32:36,634 --> 01:32:37,551
你
You.

844
01:32:37,718 --> 01:32:40,428
好，这是我真正想见到的事
Right. Something
I'm really looking forward to.

845
01:32:42,932 --> 01:32:46,518
嗯，我想我继续从事我的电脑
Well, I think I'm going to stick
to my computer.

846
01:32:48,062 --> 01:32:50,313
这听起来是个好主意
That sounds like a very good idea.

847
01:32:55,987 --> 01:32:59,990
瞧，莉兹，我得回家工作了
Look, Liz...
I gotta get home and get to work.

848
01:33:01,826 --> 01:33:04,202
少了你这个跟班，我会想念你的
I'm going to miss having you on my tail.

849
01:33:05,162 --> 01:33:07,038
你让我有种安全感
It made me feel kind of safe.

850
01:33:08,499 --> 01:33:11,710
你想跟我一块儿回家吗？
我喜欢你作伴
Look, you want to come home with me?
I'd love the company.

851
01:33:13,087 --> 01:33:14,337
麦克不会介意吧？
Wouldn't Mike mind?

852
01:33:17,049 --> 01:33:19,926
麦克出城做生意了
Well, Mike's out of town
on a business trip.

853
01:33:21,429 --> 01:33:23,096
我们地方很大
We got plenty of room.

854
01:33:23,264 --> 01:33:26,016
太好了，我可以利用这个假期
Great. I could sure use the vacation.

855
01:33:28,227 --> 01:33:30,854
好，好，我去买单
Good. I'll get the check.

856
01:41:57,239 --> 01:41:59,730
莉兹，是我，我是彼得
It's me, Liz. I'm Peter.

857
01:42:09,670 --> 01:42:13,908
不要…
No...

