I thought weapons were forbidden
on this planet.
Besides...
...I can't believe you'd kill me
for a field of empty holes.
It's all I have.
- Your pain runs deep.
- What do you know of my pain?
Let us explore it... together.
Each man hides a secret pain.
It must be exposed and reckoned with.
It must be dragged
from the darkness into the light.
Share your pain.
Share your pain with me.
And gain strength from the sharing.
Where did you get this power?
The power was within you.
It is as if a weight
has been lifted from my heart.
- How can I repay you?
- Join my quest.
- What is it you seek?
- What you seek.
What all men have sought
since time began.
The ultimate knowledge.
To find it we need a starship.
A starship? There are
no starships on Nimbus III.
- I have a way to bring one here.
- But how?
Have faith, my friend.
There are more of us than you know.
You're a Vulcan.
"You'll have a great time
on shore leave, Bones."
"You'll be able to relax."
You call this relaxing?
I'm a nervous wreck.
If I'm not careful,
I'll end up talking to myself.
Greetings, Captain.
- Spock, what are you doing here?
- I'm monitoring your progress.
I'm flattered, but of all the
points of interest here why pick me?
The record for climbing El Capitan
is in no danger of being broken.
I'm doing this because I enjoy it.
Not to mention the most important
reason for climbing a mountain...
Because it's there.
I do not think you realize
the gravity of your situation.
On the contrary,
gravity is foremost on my mind.
I'm trying to make an ascent.
Go pester Dr. McCoy.
Dr. McCoy is not in the best of moods.
Goddamn irresponsible!
Playing games with life.
Concentration is vital.
You must be one with the rock.
If you don't stop distracting me...
Perhaps "because it is there" is not
sufficient reason to climb a mountain.
I am hardly in a position to disagree.
Hi, Bones.
Mind if we drop in for dinner?
- I am Caithlin Dar.
- Yes! Our new Romulan representative.
Welcome to Paradise City, capital
of the Planet of Galactic Peace.
I'm St John Talbot, the Federation
Representative here on Nimbus III.
My charming companion
is the Klingon Consul, Korrd.
- I expect that's Klingon for hello.
- Come in, my dear.
20 years ago, our three governments
agreed to develop this planet.
- A new age was born.
- It died a quick death.
The settlers we conned into
coming here took to fighting.
We forbad them weapons,
but they fashioned their own.
It appears I've arrived just in time.
Get away from that transmitter.
Romulan.
Terran.
Klingon.
- Consider yourselves my prisoners.
- Prisoners?
We're already prisoners here
on this worthless lump of rock.
- What value could we be to you?
- Nimbus III is a worthless lump of rock.
But it is the only place in the galaxy
that has the three of you.
Our governments will stop at nothing
to ensure our safety.
That's exactly what I'm counting on.
USS Enterprise,
shakedown cruise report.
I think this new ship
was put together by monkeys.
Half the doors won't open, and guess
whose job it is to make it right?
Borgus frat!
"Let's see what she's got, Scotty."
We found out, didn't we?
- I know you'll whip her into shape.
- Uhura, I thought you were on leave.
- I thought we were going together.
- I can't leave her when she needs me.
I had a feeling you would
say something like that.
So I brought us dinner.
You're the most understanding woman
I know.
Red alert.
I just fixed that damn thing!
Turn it off, will you?
Red alert.
This is a red alert.
Enterprise, acknowledge.
This is Enterprise. Identify yourself.
This is Starfleet. We have a Priority 7
situation in the Neutral Zone.
- Scotty, this is for real.
- They can't be serious!
The ship's in pieces and
we've got less than a skeleton crew.
Starfleet, are you aware
of our current status?
Yes. Stand by to copy operational
orders and recall key personnel.
- Admit it, we're lost.
- Yes, but we're making good time.
- Commander Sulu, come in.
- I don't believe this.
Shore leave is cancelled.
- Rescued at last.
- Return to prearranged coordinates.
- You can't say we're lost.
- Is there a problem?
Yes. We've been caught in... a blizzard.
We can't see a thing.
Direct us to the coordinates.
My visual says
sunny skies and 70 degrees.
Look, the sun has come out.
It's a miracle.
Don't worry, your secret is safe
with me. I'll send the shuttle for you.
Uhura, I owe you one.
Come and get it!
Bones, knock it off.
We're right here and we're starving.
- Bipodal seeds, Doctor?
- Beans, Spock, but no ordinary beans.
These are from an old recipe
handed down to me by my father.
If you stick your Vulcan nose
up at these, -
- you're insulting
generations of McCoys.
In that case I have little choice
but to sample your beans.
Surprisingly good. It does have
a flavoring I'm not familiar with.
- That's the secret ingredient.
- Any more secret ingredient, Bones?
Be my guest.
- Your secret ingredient is alcohol?
- Tennessee whiskey.
Bourbon and beans, an explosive
combination. Can Spock handle it?
With that Vulcan metabolism,
he could eat a bowl of termites.
- Doctor, I am half human.
- It certainly doesn't show.
- Thank you.
- This guy never changes.
I insult him
and he takes it as a compliment.
- You two could drive a man to drink.
- What did I do?
Human life is far too precious
to risk on crazy stunts.
You should have been killed
when you fell off that mountain.
It did cross my mind.
But even as I fell
I knew I wouldn't die.
- Isn't he the only one who's immortal?
- No, it isn't that.
I knew I wouldn't die
because the two of you were with me.
- I do not understand.
- I've always known...
...I'll die alone.
I'll call Valhalla and
reserve a room for you.
All that time in space,
getting on each other's nerves...
So what do we do on shore leave?
We spend it together.
- Other people have families.
- Other people, not us.
What are you doing?
I'm preparing to toast a "marsh melon".
I'll be damned! A marsh melon.
Where did you learn to do that?
I have familiarized myself with the
customs associated with camping out.
What do we do
after we toast the marsh melon?
- We consume them.
- No, I mean after that.
We are required to engage in a ritual
known as the sing-along.
I haven't sung around the campfire
since I was a boy in Iowa.
What are we going to sing?
- "Camptown Races".
- "Pack up your troubles".
- Are we leaving?
- It's a song title.
- "Moon over Rigel 7".
- "Row, row, row your boat".
- Do you know "Row your boat"?
- It didn't come up in my research.
The lyrics are very simple...
"Row, row, row your boat
gently down the stream."
"Merrily, merrily, merrily, merrily,
life is but a dream."
The Doctor and I will start off
and you jump in.
- Doctor, if you please.
- Don't say I didn't warn you.
- Spock, why didn't you jump in?
- I cannot comprehend the words.
It's a song, you green-blooded Vulcan.
The words aren't important.
- You just have a good time singing.
- I am sorry, Doctor.
- Were we having a good time?
- I liked him better before he died.
Let's just get some sleep.
- Captain...
- We're on leave. Call me Jim.
- Jim...
- Yes, Spock?
Life is not a dream.
- Go to sleep, Spock.
- Yes, Captain.
- Good night, Bones.
- Good night, Jim.
- Good night, Spock.
- Good night, Doctor.
- Good night, Jim.
I don't know. I just don't know.
Get the damn light out of my face.
We had to send the shuttlecraft.
The transporter is non-operational.
- We have received new orders.
- I had my communicator.
- You forgot to take it with you.
- I wonder why I did that.
It appears shore leave has been
cancelled. Pack out your trash.
"All I ask is a tall ship
and a star to steer her by."
- Melville.
- John Masefield.
- Are you sure about that?
- I'm well-versed in the classics.
Then how come you don't know
"Row, row, row your boat"?
- Enterprise, you have control.
- We're doing just fine.
All I can say is, they don't make them
like they used to.
You told me you could have this ship
operational in two weeks.
I think you gave me too much time.
How many times do I have to tell you?
The right tool for the right job.
I've never seen him happier.
Bridge... I hope.
I could use a shower.
Yes.
- Doesn't anything work on this ship?
- They can't send us out like this.
- Starfleet transmission on line.
- Put it on the view screen.
Can we have a little quiet, please?
Can you clear that up?
Can we have a little quiet?
- Bob!
- Jim!
- We are dressing informally.
- I'm on my way to the shower.
I apologize for cancelling shore leave.
We have a dangerous situation
out on Nimbus III.
On the Planet of Galactic Peace?
A terrorist force
has captured the only settlement.
They've taken hostages. The Klingon,
the Romulan, the Federation Consuls.
- The Enterprise is not up to specs...
- The Enterprise is a disaster.
- We have ships in the quadrant.
- But no experienced commanders.
- I need Jim Kirk.
- Please!
Proceed to Nimbus III
and assess the situation.
Avoid a confrontation.
Above all, however,
get those hostages back safely.
- Have the Klingons responded?
- No, but you can bet they will.
- Plot a course for Nimbus III, Mr. Sulu.
- Course plotted.
I'm afraid the ship's problems
will have to be solved en route.
I'm counting on each one of you
to give his best. Let's go to work.
Jim, if you ask me, and you haven't...
I think this is a terrible idea.
We're bound to bump into the Klingons.
- And they don't exactly like you.
- The feeling's mutual.
Engine room, we'll need all the power
you can muster, mister.
We'll beat those Klingon devils
even if I have to get out and push.
I hope it won't come to that.
- All possible speed, Mr. Sulu.
- Aye, sir.
- What's the matter?
- I miss my old chair.
Captain's log: Stardate 84...
- Good morning, Captain.
- Forget it.
- We have the hostage information.
- Put it on the screen.
This is an authorized transmission
from the Starfleet memory bank.
- Not General Korrd!
- He's apparently fallen from favor.
Korrd's military strategies were
required learning at the Academy.
When they put me out to pasture,
I hope I fair better than Korrd.
This must be the hostage tape.
A short time ago, we surrendered
to the Galactic Army of Light.
We are now in the protective custody
of their leader.
We will be treated humanely
as long as we cooperate.
He requests that you send a starship
to parley for our release at once.
We are in good health and would
appreciate your immediate response.
I regret this desperate act,
but these are desperate times.
I mean no harm to these innocents,
but do not put me to the test.
I implore you to respond immediately.
What is it?
- You look like you've seen a ghost.
- Perhaps I have, Captain.
Spock, what is it?
Do you know this Vulcan?
- I cannot be certain.
- But he does seem familiar?
He reminds me of someone
I knew in my youth.
- I didn't know you had one.
- I do not often think of the past.
- Who does he remind you of?
- A gifted young student.
He possessed a great intelligence.
It was assumed that he would
join the great scholars of Vulcan.
- But he was a revolutionary.
- What do you mean?
The knowledge he sought
was forbidden by Vulcan belief.
- Forbidden?
- He rejected his logical upbringing.
He embraced the animal passions
of our ancestors.
He believed the key to self-knowledge
was emotion... not logic.
Imagine that, a passionate Vulcan.
When he encouraged others to follow
him, he was banished from Vulcan.
Fascinating.
- Captain to the bridge.
- On my way.
- Spock?
- Coming, Captain.
- Approaching Nimbus III.
- Standard orbit, Mr. Sulu.
Paradise City is demanding
to know our intentions.
Respond with static.
Let them think we're having difficulty.
Paradise City, we are barely
receiving your transmission.
- Transporter room, status.
- Transporter is still inoperative.
If we could lock on to the hostages,
we couldn't beam them up.
- We'll have to get them out ourselves.
- Klingon vessel approaching.
Bird of Prey.
1.9 hours till her weapons are in range.
Damn! Let's go.
Their scanning equipment
is primitive, but effective.
- Land at coordinate 856.3.
- That's far from the city.
- We cannot risk detection.
- Mr. Sulu, execute.
- This is the starship Enterprise.
- A Federation starship.
This is Captain Pavel Chekov.
You are in violation of our treaty.
Release your hostages at once
or suffer the consequences.
Your threats amuse me.
What consequences?
A Klingon warship
will arrive within the hour.
- The Klingons will be quite angry.
- They are likely to destroy the planet.
Then it is fortunate I have you
and your starship to protect me.
You and your first officer
are to beam down to my coordinates.
We will be happy to beam down,
but we must have certain assurances.
At foot speed the journey
to the city will take 1.2 hours.
We don't have 1.2 hours.
Wait a minute... Perfect!
We'll have to get their attention.
What's that?
Is she naked?
Hello, boys.
I've always wanted to play
to a captive audience.
- Spock, be one with the horse.
- Yes, Captain.
Open the gate.
It's our lookout party.
Federation soldiers are right behind us.
Close the gate.
Where are they going?
- Spock...
- Hold your horse, I'm scanning.
The hostages are being held
in that structure.
Galileo, start your run.
Phasers on stun.
Sulu, take out that light.
- What's going on?
- Surrender, you are under attack.
- It wasn't bloodshed I wanted.
- Wait! Come back.
- Uhura, come on down.
- Roger, coming in.
Nimbus III is famous for its wildlife,
and the fishing is terrific!
Easy financing through
Federation Federal can take you there.
- Thank God.
- Please cooperate.
Hand over your weapons.
Well done, my friends.
Qual se tu?
Spock!
Spock, it's me.
It's Sybok.
You've finally caught up with me.
Don't you have anything to say to me?
You are under arrest for 17 violations
of the Neutral Zone Treaty.
- You've developed a sense of humor.
- I did not intend to amuse you.
These are serious charges.
However, if you surrender now...
I'm sorry, Spock, I'm not through
violating the Neutral Zone Treaty.
In fact, I'm just getting started.
For my next violation, -
- I intend to steal something.
Something very big.
Your starship.
You staged all this
to get your hands on my ship?
- Who are you?
- Captain James T Kirk.
I thought Captain Chekov...
I see... very clever, Captain.
Spock, you have been given
a second chance to join me.
- I am a Starfleet officer.
- Of course.
Of course. Then I'll take the ship
without your help.
- Shuttle en route.
- Position of Bird of Prey?
Closing!
- The Bird of Prey must have cloaked.
- Raise shields.
- The shuttle?
- Do it. Go to red alert.
Once we control your vessel,
we'll bring up our followers.
The Klingons are out there.
We'll be lucky to make it to the ship.
This is Enterprise, red alert.
Bird of Prey approaching.
Raising shields.
Find a safe harbor.
No!
No reply. Remain on course.
Listen to me. In order for this
craft to enter the landing bay, -
- Enterprise must lower the shields
and activate the tractor beam.
- To re-raise the shields will take...
- 15.5 seconds.
An eternity, during which
we'll be vulnerable to attack.
He speaks the truth. If my people
are cloaked, then they intend to strike.
- We cannot turn back.
- Let me do something.
Very well, do what you must,
but no more.
Enterprise, this is Kirk.
Understand your situation.
Are unable to return to planet.
Stand by to execute
emergency landing plan... B.
- Emergency landing plan B?
- B as in barricade.
What are you doing?
In order to lower and raise the shields
quickly, we'll forego the tractor beam.
We'll fly her in manually.
- How often have you done this?
- Actually, it's my first attempt.
He's good... really.
Scotty, open bay doors.
Scotty, lower shields.
Lowering shields.
- Bird of Prey bearing 105.2.
- Go, Sulu.
They're in.
Warp speed now!
We must change course at once.
I'll take you to the bridge.
Pick it up.
Sybok...
You must surrender.
No!
- You must kill me.
- Shoot him!
For a moment...
I thought you might actually do it.
Put him in the brig with Captain Kirk.
Spock, you will accompany me
to the bridge?
No... I will not.
You know I'm right.
Then you must join them.
- These two will be useful.
- Give us a moment alone.
Don't be afraid.
Goddamn it, Spock.
You betrayed us all.
I do not expect you to forgive me.
- I ought to knock you on your ass.
- If you think it would help.
- You want me to hold him?
- Stay out of this... Why?
- All you had to do was pull the trigger.
- Then Sybok would be dead.
- I ordered you to defend your ship.
- And kill my brother.
- A fellow Vulcan is not a...
- Sybok also is a son of Sarek.
He's your brother brother?
You made that up.
- I did not.
- You don't have a brother.
- Technically I don't have a brother.
- See?
- I have a half-brother.
- I've got to sit down.
You and Sybok have the same father
but different mothers?
Sybok's mother was a Vulcan princess,
but we were raised as brothers.
- Why didn't you tell us this before?
- It is a personal matter.
- For that I am sorry.
- That makes everything all right. Sorry!
Spock could no more kill
his own brother than he could kill you.
He's already in the brig. Besides,
we've got bigger problems to deal with.
Like how do we get out of here.
I'll say one thing,
you never cease to amaze me.
Nor I myself.
- I was beginning to worry.
- It's all right. Sybok will explain.
- What are you doing?
- Plotting our new course.
You have no authority.
- What's going on here?
- Pavel, listen to this man.
- I don't understand.
- Each of us hides a secret pain.
Share yours with me
and gain strength from the sharing.
Useless.
Unwise.
You could have warned me.
He did, Jim.