That's your solution for everything.
The guy's homeless, right?
Let him be. Set your anger free.
Look at you, Lou. You've really calmed
down since working with Dr. B.
-We all have.
-Hey, fellas.
Could you bring it down a little bit?
We're trying to have dinner.
The walls are really thin.
-This is a free country!
-What's going on with you?!
-Are you crazy?!
-Go in! Just go in.
Goosfraba! Goosfraba!
Goosfraba.
Very good.
What are you guys doing here?
I need to see Dr. B. I'm in crisis.
He's not here.
Why don't you go look for him?
Davey, your girlfriend stopped by
and she dropped these off for you.
Those are her keys to my apartment.
I think your girlfriend's cheating
on you.
-Why?
-I heard her on her cell phone...
...talking to a guy...
-...making a date.
-I'm so sorry, Dave.
Andrew.
I'll kill that guy.
She ain't cheating on me by the way.
We agreed to take a break.
She's not taking a break
from the old sausage, huh?
Sorry.
She's meeting the Andrew at Mort's
on 86th Street now...
...if you want to go watch.
No. No, I can't do that.
We're here.
-Both of you showed up?
-You like Stacy better or something?
It's just that I want to go on a fake
date to get my girlfriend jealous...
...so I really only needed
one of you guys.
Well, now she'll be twice as jealous.
-So do you know the guy she's with?
-I think I might.
Let me ask you something.
Because of your profession
you probably have seen a lot of them.
Does size count at all, or is that just
some weird thing guys think about?
This is where Gina and I
always get into a heated debate.
I like them when they're really big.
And I think it's better
when they're enormous.
Good evening.
Table for three?
-May we take your coats?
-No. We're okay.
The girls are gonna
take their coats off.
Would you like a boobs--? Booth?
Actually, could you give us a table
overlooking that table right there?
-Sure. Right this way.
-Thank you.
Oh, my God. It's Stacy and Gina.
Who?
Nobody.
I'm so hungry I could eat you, Dave.
Yummy. Yummy.
-Let's get wasted tonight.
-Definitely.
Have fun.
Lucky son of a bitch.
What?
I can't believe this.
Excuse me.
Linda. I'm a little embarrassed. I
didn't know you were going to be here.
I guess not. Are those your friends?
I'm supposed to date other people
so I figured I'd give it a try.
Gina, can you stop sucking
on Stacy's finger for one second?
I want to introduce you to somebody.
-Stacy, Gina, this is Linda.
-Nice to meet you.
And I'd like you to meet my date.
Ladies, this is Buddy Rydell.
-Look, Dave, it's Buddy.
-I see.
-You know Stacy and Gina?
-Yes, yes, I do.
We're in Dave's anger group.
Fury Fighters!
Well, gee whiz.
Here's your Rémy, Linda.
This is a bit awkward.
I mean, group members...
...are not supposed to get
romantically involved.
-Yeah! I agree with that.
-You know that.
I'd like to talk to you alone
for a second.
There's a rage control technique I'd
like to go over with you right now.
Of course. Excuse me--
What?
-Two of the usual, Duke.
-Coming right up, Dr. B.
You're the biggest backstabbing
piece of crap I ever met.
What are you saying?
I'm trying to give you a hand.
It's my job.
Bullshit!
Your job is to steal my girlfriend?!
My job is trying to prevent
Mr. Andrew...
...from unleashing the Whopper
with Cheese.
That's right. Since you've
been out of the picture...
...Andrew's been burning up the wires
night and day...
...trying to rekindle those
hotsie-totsie nights up at Brown U.
-How would you know?
-You think I only tapped your phone?
What was she saying?
The good news is, I already launched
a preemptive strike.
Now the situation is contained.
You and I control the game.
How?
I will be uncharacteristically
aggressively boring.
I keep talking about myself,
acting arrogant and obnoxious.
When Linda sees what
the dating world is really like...
...then guess who comes out
smelling like a white mushroom?
-You swear to me this will work?
-The ball's already up in the air.
Incidentally, nice move
bringing the girls.
Very strong. Come on.
I'll see you at home
in a half-hour, keed.
That's 25 dollars, pal.
We don't....
Where were you? It's 1:00.
When you hear what happened, you'll
bow down and worship me like a god.
-Better be good. Give it to me.
-Okay.
After dinner, she insisted we go home.
So we hop on the bus--
The bus? You took the bus?
What happened to your car?
I was way too smashed to drive.
I told her I didn't want to waste money
on a cab. That did not go down well.
Okay. I like that.
So we get to her house...
...we have some kind of a weird
argument...
...about the number of syllables
in a haiku.
Poetry garbage.
She said it was getting late,
we kissed and I headed on home.
Now, you say you kissed?
It was nothing. Little five-second kiss.
That's all.
Wait. Wait. Wait. Wait.
You're having this horrible evening.
-How do you end up kissing, again?
-I wish I knew, keed.
We were both pretty geezed up.
One second we're fighting,
and the next second we're laughing...
...and then just a quick
10-second kiss.
I thought that you said five seconds.
First it was a five-second one...
...and then a little break because
my beard gave her a tickle.
She's cute.
And then a 10-second Frencher.
You had your crazy, corroded tongue
in my girlfriend's mouth?
Just a second. Just one second, Dave.
Dr. B, let it bip.
Well, hello.
I shouldn't really talk right now.
Well, I suppose you're right.
It's got to be done.
Who was that? Linda?
I've got some good news for you
and some potentially upsetting news.
First, the good news.
I'm going to sign your papers.
You're a free man.
Let me hear
the potentially upsetting news.
Linda and I have fallen
for one another.
Pretty hard too.
David, I hope you believe me
when I say this:
I didn't intend for this to happen.
It was no one's fault, I guess.
It was just--
Wait a minute.
I figured this out.
You're messing with me.
I wish I were, Dave.
However, I did insist that we not
go forward without your blessing...
...because we're best friends.
So, what do you say, Dave?
Is it all right if I date your ex?
Welcome back, Mr. Buznik.
I am appalled by your assault
on Dr. Rydell.
Obviously, anger management
has been a complete failure for you.
I'm setting a trial date for 3 weeks
from today for attempted murder.
As for Dr. Rydell's safety,
I'm issuing a restraining order.
Which means that at no time can you
come within 500 feet of him...
...or his lovely new girlfriend, Linda.
Court is adjourned.
Coming, Peaches.
Are you kidding me?
Numb-nuts, where's the catalog
for my Fat Cat clothing line?
I said I'd have it by 3.
-Okay.
-Get in gear.
I'm so sorry I'm late.
I hope you have it.
My presentation's in two hours.
What's this? Your fat-shit cat's
been sitting there all day.
Don't worry about him.
Here you go.
I think you're gonna like it.
It's good stuff.
That's a good picture, I think.
What the hell is this?!
You keep telling everybody you
created the Husky Cat line.
I thought you'd want your picture
in there. No?
Question: Can I get two couches
in my office?
If friends come over, I want them
to feel comfortable.
What office?
Frank was nice enough to give me
some creative executive position.
-You gave him the job that I wanted?
-He earned it.
Why can't you be happy for me?
Linda's gonna be.
Know something?
I'm sick of you hanging out with Linda.
She dumped you 15 years ago.
Get over it.
I wouldn't worry about me.
It's your pal Buddy who's taking her
to the Yankee game tonight.
Yankee game.
Did he steal my proposal idea?
Buznik, your behavior
is unacceptable.
Unacceptable?
I've been getting your coffee and
doing your work for five years now.
When a good position
actually opens up...
...you give it to the biggest dick
in the world?
I don't know about the world, but it's
definitely the biggest one in the room.
Now, when I started here...
...I was promised advancement
opportunities.
And breaking that promise, to me,
is unacceptable.
You see? I golf also.
You should bring me sometime.
So when I get out of jail, sometime
in the next two to five years...
...I expect you to give me the position
that Andrew just resigned from.
-Okay.
-Great.
Have fun looking like Colonel Klink.
By the way, his name is not
Fat-shit Cat, it's Meatball...
...and he's eating your crab cakes
right now.
-You starting to get excited?
-Are you kidding? I'm out of my mind.
This is going to be some night.
Come on. Come on.
-Dr. B, how's it going?
-Very well, thank you.
Always a thrill. Right this way.
Where the hell's a spot?
Where's a spot?
Whoa! Watch it, man!
Your attention, please.
Before tonight's National Anthem...
...Metropolitan Opera star Robert
Merrill...
...will present a special moment
for two special people.
I love when they do this.
-Good.
-Ladies and gentlemen, Robert Merrill.
Linda?! Linda!
What the hell do you think
you're doing?
Wait, don't I know you?
-Come on.
-Where's your German accent?
You have me confused
with somebody--
I wanna get on the field.
I'm a fan of Mr. Merrill's.
-There's no fans allowed on that field.
-Galaxia.
It's Gary.
Whatever. Someone else will marry
my woman if you don't let me go.
-Hebrew Melvin's in love.
-Very much.
I can't stop love.
-Go.
-Thank you.
Don't think I don't owe you
a couple smacks by the way.
Good evening. Tonight, romance
comes to Yankee Stadium.
Oh, my God, it's Dave.
What the heck are you doing here?
-I wanna borrow this for a second.
-That's my mike!
Linda? Where are you?
Don't move.
Linda? Are you out there, honey?
Linda, I'm not mad at you.
Oh, shit.
I know that crazy man
brought you here.
Davey's going crazy!
I've done crazier stuff than that
to win back a chick.
Once I ran naked
through a subway station.
How was that supposed to work?
I guess I never really
thought it through.
I gotta tell you something personal!
This kid lost his marbles.
I'm over here!
Linda, think about
what you're doing to us.
Sweet tackle. Wow!
Dave just got leveled!
-Nobody messes with my microphone.
-I'm sorry.
Bob?
-Everything all right, Buddy?
-Oh, yeah.
I've never seen you so excited.
It's not every day a man
gets to propose marriage...
...to the woman he loves.
Now, here's what I want you to write
on the scoreboard.
Linda! Linda, I've loved you
since the day I met you!
I won't let you do this to us!
Don't marry him!
Wait!
Let this man finish
what he came here to say.
Let the man back in.
-Who was that guy?
-I think it's Regis Philbin.
Thank you, Mayor Giuliani.
You're the man, by the way.
This clown better hurry up.
My arm's starting to ice over.
Chill, Rocket. Goosfraba.
Goosfraba.
I can understand why you wanted
to see other people. I really can.
Buddy Rydell is a psycho!
But he was right about one thing.
I was an angry guy.
Mainly angry at myself...
...for letting people treat me like crap
all the time.
But I don't want to be that angry guy
anymore.
I wanna change.
If you give me a chance...
...I can show you that I got the guts
to stand up for what I believe in.
And I believe in us, Linda.
I love you with all my heart,
and I know you love me back.
I should be your husband...
...not that weirdo.
I want to have a family with you.
I want to have kids with you.
Kids who have your eyes...
...and your lips...
...and my...
...last name.
That's all I wish on them.
Please marry me, Linda.
Before I make my decision,
you have to do something for me.
You have to kiss me
in front of all these people!
You can do it, David!
Give her a five-second Frencher!
Kiss her, David.
Kiss her, David!
Go Yankees!
Dave's a dirty boy.
That wasn't so bad, was it?
I can't believe you actually
started to fall for that crazy man.
Buddy's not such a bad guy.
Congratulations! You just graduated
from anger management!
I'm glad your car died.
The train's romantic.
Don't change the subject.
You're telling me the past two weeks
of my life was just therapy?
Well....
Yeah.
I met with Buddy
after reading his book...
...and I told him about some
of the things going on in your life...
...and how upset it was making you
and how nuts it was making me.
He said that he thought he could help,
but it would be tough.
So how much of this thing was a
setup?
Well, the guy in your seat on the
plane, the flight attendant, the judge...
...they're all friends of Buddy's.
What about the air marshal
who tasered me? Was he in on it?
No, he was just having a bad day.
Son of a bitch.
Skipper, how you doing?
Buddy Rydell, you're a great man.