女士們先生們
機長通知我
我們預計抵達墨西哥哈帕拉的時間
估計是 是1點15分左右
你剛剛是不是跟我說了什麼？
我沒
那是空姐
我們快到了
不錯
你知道 這是一門丟失的藝術
她的技術已經多年沒有使用過了
結果非常棒
嗯哼
這個給蘇西·貝克
她的地址是...
沒關係 親愛的
我這裡有所有地址
好的
我不知道她有這麼多朋友
她大多都寫了兩次
看這個 甜心
這個娃娃就是
你爸爸要在墨西哥做的娃娃
你確定嗎
這是我們要給她做衣服
所使用的工廠
她很漂亮 對吧？
而且你會擁有世界上只有一個
會為你製作漂亮娃娃的父親
是不是很有趣
我們會非常成功的
那我們可以回洛杉磯嗎？
韋德先生
見到你真是太高興了
歡迎來到墨西哥
你好
韋德先生，這是您所有的文件和
許可證
您的第三方托管在上午9點就結束了
這是一封來自哈帕拉市的信
正式歡迎你
並祝你在多莉最親愛的製造公司
開業時事業蒸蒸日上
快點提箱子
哦
韋德太太 我們付出了很多努力
為了讓你住的更舒適
我希望你會滿意
我相信我們會很滿意的
卡米拉！
卡米拉
準備青辣椒
好的
請帶上手提箱
是的 女士
這是卡米拉
她會好好照顧你的
你好 韋德先生
歡迎你
歡迎你 韋德先生
謝謝你
你好 小韋德的孩子
你的東西已經安全到達了
我現在要幫你打開包裝
請進
很棒的房子
我沒想到會這麼好
你喜歡讀書嗎
這些書里有很多我們國家的歷史
真的嗎
傑西？
韋德先生
你想去工廠看看嗎？
我們走
爸爸？
我可以和你一起去嗎？
當然可以
親愛的 來吧
來吧
讓我們看看我們的新業務
沒關係 繼續
我們到了
惡心
德魯加夫人做的娃娃
是世界上最好的
她贏得了許多獎項
當我還是個小孩子的時候
我會來這裡只是為了看他們畫小臉
以及她臨死前創造的一個
如此美麗的娃娃
能幫你處理這件事
是我的榮幸 韋德先生
這是我第一次賣東西
埃斯特雷拉先生
評估文件顯示
在德盧加死後
工廠還在繼續運作
是的 先生
我們會非常小心地
讓一切保持原樣
這就是為什麼從來都沒有人
來看這個工廠的原因
是的
我知道了
Come, let me show you over here
where all the molding
equipment's been stored.
Mr. Estrella,
what's this big,
round mixing thing?
Oh, that is where
they combine all the ingredients
to make the deluga dolls.
The future
heartthrob of millions
of little girls.
Once in a lifetime opportunity.
Si, of course, seiior,
I understand that.
We need a little
cleaning, perhaps.
The market projections.
The assessments.
Who prepared that material?
1, 1 did that, sir.
I copy from American
business book.
Nice work.
Jessica, are you in here?
I'm up here, daddy.
Look what I found.
May I have one, daddy?
Oh, look at that.
Fabulous.
Every little girl in the world
is going to want one of those.
I want
that one.
Well, you've got it.
My first sale.
Thank you, daddy.
I'm going to love her so much.
Jimmy!
Uh, Mr. Estrella, what is that?
What's going on over there?
That is Mayan ruins.
They uncover much history
of Mayan civilization.
Very important find.
Mayan, huh?
We studied about
them last semester.
They were pretty cool dudes.
Cool or not,
I don't want you
going over there.
Yeah, last week they had
an unfortunate accident.
A man was crushed
by a stone underneath the earth.
Work's been suspended
until the archeologist
from the university arrives.
I'm going to
brush your hair.
So the end of a long day.
Tomorrow we'll all
start unpacking.
Now, won't that be fun?
Probably not.
Good night, sweetheart.
Don't forget
to say good night to Dolly.
Sweet dreams, Dolly.
Good night, Dolly.
You're going to be
my new playmate.
my only playmate.
Mmm, these
vegetables smell good.
These all come from
my brother's garden.
I get you good price, of course.
He uses fresh Turkey manure.
Turkey manure is the very best.
It gives you the best crop.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
I didn't know that.
Now, my sister,
she makes us all very proud.
She gave her life to the church.
She belongs to the nuns of the
carmelitas, the carmelites.
Really?
Uh-huh.
Mommy!
Just leave it on the table
with the other letters, honey.
I wanted to tell
you I'll be in the back yard.
You and I can go play
in the Dollhouse.
Jessie, is that you?
We're almost ready to go, honey.
Is anyone out there?
What is it?
Mom, what is it?
Jessica!
Tell me what's wrong.
What's wrong with her?
No!
I want Dolly!
Jimmy.
Camilla.
Camilla?
What is the priest doing here?
I called the priest
to bless the house.
It is custom.
Professor resnick.
What?
The photos from
hapalla have arrived.
Ah, at last.
What do you think?
Could this be the tomb?
I'm not sure.
Have you ever seen
this symbol before?
No, sir.
I'm certain it's not Mayan.
They haven't disturbed
the sarcophagus, have they?
No, no one has touched a thing
since larabe's body was removed.
When are you leaving?
Bob larabe and I
were friends for over 30 years.
Did you know that?
No, sir.
I'm leaving right now.
How is she?
She seems all right.
We had a long talk about her
old playmates at school mostly.
I wish you would
have seen her, Elliot.
She scared me,
really scared me.
There's no reason for it.
None.
I'm gonna take Jimmy with
me to the factory tomorrow
and give you two
some time together.
Good.
That, that would help.
The sewing machines arrive
next week. Did I tell you?
Oh, yes.
You told me.
It's a secret.
That's funny.
Why are you doing that?
Jessica, what are you doing?
Dolly says we're
going to like it here.
Oh, we are going to
like it here, honey.
Now, come on.
Let's go to bed.
Well, it looks like
you're enjoying your lunch.
What is that, honey?
I don't know.
Well, did you see it somewhere?
Dolly told me.
She says she's been
waiting for a little girl
just like me.
Sweetheart.
Jessica!
Jessica, I saw that!
Camilla, I am so sorry.
She, I, I don't know
what's gotten into her.
Kinta kintero.
What?
Jessica!
Jessica, come back here!
Camilla, I am terribly sorry.
She's never had outbursts
like this before.
It is the sanzia.
She spoke the ancient
language of the sanzia.
Wait a minute, wait a minute,
what are you talking about?
I know of their language.
I know of these people.
Their spirits fly
with the evil one.
No.
I know that you wouldn't lie.
I won't tell.
I can keep a secret.
What do you want?
Don't talk to me in
that tone, young lady.
Why did you push Camilla?
I saw you do it.
Why?
Camilla prays to the spirits,
and her spirits hate Dolly.
Jessie,
whatever it was you
said to Camilla,
did you hear it from her?
Dolly told me.
Stop saying that!
Now, where did you hear it?
Okay come on.
I want you to
apologize to Camilla.
Leave Dolly here.
I'm sorry I pushed your plate.
Camilla, I don't
want to interfere
with your religious
practices, but...
Sefora, there is evil here.
I can feel it.
I pray to protect us
from the evil spirit.
Right, right, right.
That's my point.
In the future, I
would appreciate it
if you could just, uh,
make your observances
more private.
If you could just...
I understand.
Today I spoke to my
sister in the convent.
I think it's best that
you find someone else
for your house.
Where are you going?
We're just going out
for a quick dinner.
Did you have a good
time with mommy today?
It was okay.
She's been acting
very funny lately.
Maybe you should
have a talk with her.
I don't think she likes it here.
Do you know what?
I think you're right,
and we're going to have to
be very patient with mommy.
Good night, honey.
Good night, daddy.
Good night, Dolly.
Dolly?
Dolly, where are you?
Dolly, don't hide
from me, please.
Dolly?
Dolly, where are you?
Jessie, follow me.
Jessica.
Jessica!
What are you doing?
Come back in the house.
Jessica!
Why aren't you listening to
me qirl?
I'm talking to you.
Jessica, you come
back in the house.
You sit down.
I'll go around the front.
Jimmy!
Open the door!
Ay! This kid.
Jessica, is that you?
Jessie, now we can play.
No lights.
Camilla said there was a problem
with the fuse box.
I'll check.
Jimmy?
Huh?
You scared me.
What's with the candle?
The electricity is out.
Is your sister in here?
No.
Maybe she's with Camilla.
I'll go.
Camilla's not there.
Well, then they
must be together.
I bet they're in your room.
Oh.
Damn it.
Maybe they're downstairs.
She's so afraid
of the lightning.
Jessie?
She's not in there.
Oh, my god.
She's in the Dollhouse.
I'll get you all tucked in
and cozy and I'll read
you a bedtime story.
Would you like that?
I just spoke with her family.
They're making all
the arrangements.
Are you okay?
Jessica,
would you lock the door?
Lock the door now.
That's a good girl.
Ah, she's listening.
If she comes, don't open it.
No, no.
Jessica, don't open it.
Jessie, open up the door.
Jessica?
What did you do to your hair?
We cut it.
Don't I look like Dolly now?
Jessica, you were
holding the door.
Dolly locked the door.
She doesn't like
people coming in here.
This is our house.
Jessie, I want you
to leave Dolly here
and I want you to come with me.
No, thank you.
We'd rather stay here.
I'm sorry, mommy.
It's just that Dolly's
the only friend I have,
and I don't want to lose her.
Can I stay for just
a little while?
I'll leave the door open.
I love you, mommy.
I love you, too.
I love you so much.
Are you okay?
I'm okay, mommy.
I am.
Okay.
God!
Sorry.
Come on! Get
the hell out of there!
Hi.
Uh, you're the archeologist
from the university?
Hi.
I'm Jimmy Wade. My dad owns
the factory over there.
Son, the sign up
there says "no pase."
That means this entire
area is off limits,
so please, take a hike.
Okay, but you're
going to need my help
when you get down in there.
Further down, you'll
see the top is caved in,
the opening's too small.
You won't be able
to squeeze through.
I'll take my chances.
I'll wait.
How far back have
you been in there?
Uh, only about halfway,
but I can squeeze
through to the end.
I can do it.
I can be like your
eyes and ears for you.
What do you think?
Does your father
know you're down here?
Sure, he does.
My father's always
looking for ways
to further my education,
so let me crawl on top
and take a look for you.
I've done it before,
but it's getting
kinda dark in there,
if you know what I mean.
Look, I appreciate your
fondness for exploration,
but we'll both just have to wait
to see what's inside the crypt.
A crypt.
I knew it was a crypt!
Hey!
Come back here.
Hey.
Oh.
Neat hat.
What do you see?
Uh,
I don't know.
It's real small.
It's a coffin, I guess.
But it's made out
of stone maybe?
All right, that's enough.
Come out of there now!
Wow.
What a rush.
Now what?
Ow!
Don't you ever do that again.
I won't.
You hear?
You know, I've been reading
up you know, on the Mayans
because I wanted to be prepared
for when you got here.
I mean, you being
from the university
and me only being
in seventh grade.
I just didn't want you to think
that I couldn't handle the job,
because I can.
I can handle the job.
What job?
Your assistant.
Does your dad's
factory have a phone?
Oh, sure.
Come on.
He'll let you use it.
So, uh, who's buried in there?
A Maya king?
He must be a short guy.
This is like king tut, right?
Are you coming?
I'll go get my dad.
Put the boxes over here.
This is my father, Elliot Wade.
Karl resnick.
I hope this isn't an imposition.
You can use my phone anytime.
These creatures are beautiful.
Very haunting.
Yes, they are.
The more I'm with them,
the more they take on
a life of their own.
I'm sorry about the
accident at your excavation.
Thank you.
Bob larabe was a
very dedicated man.
If his theory is correct,
this excavation will
answer many questions
about a bizarre tribe of people
called the sanzia.
What do you mean, it's not Maya?
Oh, no.
Not Maya.
The sanzias occupied this
area about 900 years ago.
Sanzia means Satan on earth.
Sounds fascinating.
When do you start?
I'll start tonight.
My men will arrive tomorrow.
The pipe! The pipe!
There's water all over!
Okay water main.
Excuse me.
The phone is in the corner.
Help yourself.
Give me a hand.
Tonight, huh?
When the sun disappears,
I expect your face
to go with it.
Understood?
Sanzia.
"Cult of the dead."
Wow.
It's may the third.
1900 hours.
I'm in the tunnel.
I have already observed
these inscriptions
on the photographs
sent to me by larabe.
They appear to be sanzia.
I'm going to remove
the earth by hand.
No, we already finished.
When will you be home?
In about an hour.
The fridge again?
No, it's not that.
It's, uh,
it's Jessica.
What's wrong with her?
I don't know what's wrong.
I'm worried about her.
I don't know, uh,
I don't know what to do
about this fixation
she has on the doll.
Let me finish
here, and I'll be home soon.
All right.
Okay sure.
We'll talk about it
when you get back.
Okay
I love you.
I love you, too.
Mr. Wade, you join
me in a burrito?
Sounds good, Luis,
but no, thanks.
I'm going to be getting
out of here soon.
Well, I think I
better go to bed.
So early?
Good night!
That's it.
I've had it.
Luis, it's all yours.
Lock up for me.
Good night.
Good night, Mr. Wade.
I can now see
additional inscriptions
on the left side of the crypt.
Larabe was right.
They're sanzia.
They are warnings,
warnings not to cross the
threshold of the tomb.
Senorita.
I say you join me
for dinner, eh?
You look very
lovely tonight, huh?
Heh heh heh heh!
Of course
you look lovely every night.
You want to lambada, no?
Whoo-hoo!
You come up to my
room later, eh?
No?
You women, you're
all alike, you know?
Well, let me tell you something.
You're ugly,
and your nose is shiny, too.
Heh heh heh heh!
You got a big head.
All women have big heads.
You wait here.
I'll be right back.
Hey, hey, give me a hand.
Surprise.
We got you.
The interior of the crypt
is three meters
by three by 2.5 in height.
It doesn't appear that
it's been entered.
It's beautiful.
It's at least 900 years old.
The detail is amazing.
It is the story of creation.
It is the story
of the birth of evil on earth.
Oh, god, larabe.
It is the crypt.
This is where the sanzia
have entombed the devil child.
Oh, man.
What a screw up.
Now we'll have some fun.
Is anybody here?
Who are you?
Are you crazy?
What are you doing?
You must stop this.
Everybody will be killed
if you do not stop this.
What are you talking
about? Who are you?
You brought their evil back,
with your picks
and your shovels.
Close the tomb now and leave.
The sanzias are dead.
All of them are dead.
He opened up the gate to hell,
and the killings began.
There will be others.
The soul of the
sanzia child is alive.
It has returned.
All of the children
are in danger.
Close the tomb now
and maybe god will spare us.
Wait.
Wait!
Wait for me!
What was that about?
Superstition.
There's frequent opposition
to dredging up the past,
a past descendants
of the sanzias
would prefer we left in secrecy.
I'm looking for my son.
He snuck out of the house.
I thought he might
be here with you.
Jimmy, my assistant,
the explorer?
No, I haven't seen him, ha, yet.
What's going on here?
That's it.
I'm getting out of here.
Dad, there's a man in there.
He's dead!
I saw him!
Jimmy, stop it.
Calm down.
Stay here.
Luis!
Luis?
Hello?
It's an emergency.
We need an ambulance...
At camino El Rey
Looks like it was
a heart attack.
Under the circumstances
with Luis,
I'm not going to punish you,
but what you did was
totally irresponsible.
Just what did you think you
were gonna do out there?
I don't know.
Mr. resnick mentioned
that old tribe,
and I read all about them,
how they were like
really weird dudes.
They tried to make, like,
an evil kid or something,
you know, a devil
child, they called it.
Sanzias were into
really scary stuff.
It just got me going, I guess.
What did you say the
name of that tribe was?
Sanzia.
From now on, you
can forget about
some of the more exotic
goings-on around here,
such as Mr. resnick and
the archeological digs.
What?
Dad, come on.
The digs are a cool place.
What does that have
to do with anything?
It has to do with your ability
to separate what's
real and what's not.
What are you doing?
I thought that you'd
be more comfortable
if Dolly slept over
there in the chair.
Don't touch her.
Jessica, I'm taking the doll
out of the bed
and I don't want hear
another word about it.
I'll kill you!
I'll kill you if you
try to separate us!
I'll kill you!
She's mine!
Whoa!
Neat trick with your voice.
Daddy, mommy's trying to
take Dolly away from me.
Don't take her, daddy!
Calm down.
I want my Dolly.
It's okay.
We keep each other company.
Come on.
Get under the covers now.
Jimmy, go to your room.
She said she'd kill me.
If you'd heard
her voice, Elliot.
Elliot, she's changing.
She's, she's changing.
It's,
it's the doll.
It's controlling her somehow.
It's doing something to her.
Don't you see it?
No, I don't see it.
I see that you've changed.
What you're saying is
completely irrational.
I want to get her out of here.
I'm afraid for her.
I want to take her back to la.
Marilyn, we've
invested everything
into this factory.
We can't just pack up
because our seven-year-old
is having a tantrum.
Honey,
we'll work with her, okay?
She'll be all right.
Just let her go
through some changes.
You're not hearing
a word I'm saying.
That man, that man Karl resnick,
what do you know about the crypt
in the field?
Why is he so interested in it?
He's interested because
he's an archeologist.
What are you suggesting?
I don't know.
I'm trying to make sense of it.
Camilla was frightened
of the sanzia.
She said that Jessica
spoke to her in their language.
You told me yourself
Camilla spent half the day
mumbling over burning candles.
If Jessica said anything,
she heard it from her.
No, she didn't, Elliot.
She heard it from someone,
but it wasn't her.
Okay I'm sorry.
I'm tired, I'm hungry,
it's the middle of the night,
and I don't want to
hear this right now.
Mr. resnick, I'm Marilyn Wade.
Oh, happy to meet
you, sefora Wade.
I see your beauty
in your son's face.
How is he?
He had a rough night.
It was an unfortunate
experience.
Yes, it was.
I wonder if I could talk to you
about these carvings down here.
Oh, please.
These.
These were removed
from the tomb?
Yes.
Well, actually, they're
portions of the damaged door.
See, the details are exquisite.
These are very old.
Sanzia, right?
Correct.
Our son tells us
these people have
a grisly history.
What is it that
you're looking for?
We're looking for the remains
of the sanzia devil child.
The legends say
the sanzia prepared a place
for the birth of Satan's child.
They suckled a child
that was neither man nor beast.
It had the body of an infant
and the head of a goat.
They fed it with the warm blood
of slaughtered children.
A child so evil that
its reign of terror
almost caused their extinction
before they put the creature
to its howling death.
And you knew this before
you opened the crypt?
Sefora, whatever
made the sanzia afraid,
this child was not supernatural.
- How do you know it wasn't?
- Because I'm a man of reason.
It's not possible.
Mr. resnick, my daughter
has been drawing these symbols
since we arrived here.
Our housekeeper Camilla
told me that Jessica
spoke sanzia to her.
She tried to warn me,
and now she's dead
and so is the night watchman,
and so is your archeologist,
and my daughter is being
touched by something,
by some outside force.
Sefior resnick!
We need help with the machine!
How much time?
Sefiora, where are you going?
Camilla said she has a sister
in the convent.
I want to speak with her.
Uh, mom said you
should take a nap.
Um, but that's okay,
you don't have to if
you don't want to.
Do you speak english?
Yes, I do.
I'm looking for sister alva.
Sister alva is ill.
A member of her family
has passed away.
Yes, I know.
Please, it's very
important that I see her.
She's in seclusion.
Please.
My daughter's life is in danger.
I'm Marilyn Wade.
I know who you are.
I'm very sorry
about your sister.
Did Camilla tell you
about my daughter?
You of the modern world.
You put your faith
in your machines,
your science.
You ignore the powers
of heaven and hell.
My sister tried to warn you.
Yes, I know she did.
But, please, tell me now.
What is happening
to my daughter?
How can I stop it?
It's too late.
The spirit of the
sanzia devil child
has been set free.
It's too late.
Listen to me, I'm
not losing my daughter
to a goddamn
900-year-old goat head!
Tell me what you know.
How does this thing,
this spirit work?
Could it, could it
go into something
other than a human?
Could it go into a doll?
The devil takes
any form it desires.
It can be one,
or it can be many.
The sanzia devil
child wants children.
It will do anything
to spread its word
to the children.
Through the dolls?
I don't know what
course Satan will travel.
All I can do is pray
for their salvation.
You see?
It has begun.
There will be no end
to its reign of fear.
It's fear that
keeps them ignorant.
To believe that
malarkey is insanity.
Maybe it is, maybe it is.
I have a husband who
thinks it's insanity,
and I'm inclined
to agree with him,
but I have a daughter at home
who's being controlled
by a fucking doll.
Now, you tell me what
the hell that is.
Jessica?
Are you in there?
Shh.
What are you doing in there?
I'm hiding.
Where's Jessica?
They're in their room.
Ma, ya gotta go look.
The doll talks.
I saw it.
It moves and everything.
The door's locked.
I need a...
Jessica?
Jessie?
Where is she?
What have you done with her?
She's in here with me.
She belongs to me.
You'll never get her back now.
We're together forever!
Ha ha hal
she'll always be mine!
Mommy, mommy, help me!
Help me!
No!
I want my daughter!
Call your father at the factory.
I'm going to get
her out of there.
Mom, it's busy.
I can't get through.
Keep trying.
Jimmy, I want you
to stay downstairs.
Suppose you need me?
Do as I say for once!
Jessica?
Operator?
Uh, emergencia.
Interruption.
No.
What?
Never, nevermind.
Oh, sweetheart.
Jimmy, get in the car!
Jimmy, where are you?
Oh, goody.
We're going for a ride.
Get out of my way.
Jessica, let's play with mommy.
Hold her down!
Don't let her go!
We'll fix mommy!
Get her!
Let's kill her!
I hate you!
Kill her!
Play with this, bitch.
Uhh, uhh.
Mommy.
It's time to play.
Oh, my god.
It's true.
What have I done?
Pull it!
We've got you now!
This is fun!
You!
Ready to go in the mixer?
Help!
Oh!
You!
Help!
Ready?
No!
Help!
You want to be next?
Where do you kill the power?
On the wall!
Are you all right?
I got to get home.
There's another
one at the house.
Thank god you're all right.
Elliot,
it was alive.
It was alive.
I know.
They're all alive.
How is this happening?
I don't know.
Wow.
Oh, my god. What
are you going to do?
We're going back inside.
Take the kids down the hill.
Elliot, no.
Let's just get out
of here, please.
I don't know how this happened,
but we're going to destroy them.
All of them.
Elliot, we can get
help from someone.
Don't go in there,
please, Elliot!
We don't have
time to run a wire.
The longest fuse is a minute.
Place it and move
on to the next.
We'll line the inside perimeter.
Take the right.
I'll go to the left,
we'll come down the
center to the door.
Perfect.
Can I go?
Can I set one?
No. Jimmy, I want
you down the hill
with your mother.
I don't want you anywhere
near this factory.
Here.
Get down.
Jimmy.
Jimmy!
I'm going to blow up the pit.
Hey, come here!
Bastards!
Mom, get back!
The pit's going to blow!
Huh?
Honey, it's over.