We should've talked
at the boatyard.
You don't wanna
talk about it here.
l'm not falling all over
myself to talk about
it much of anywhere, Jack.
How much do you know?
Not much.
The Birmingham one
was in the papers
over a month ago.
The second one in Atlanta
was all over TV.
Did you ever think
about giving me a call?
No.
Why not?
l quit. Remember?
You look all right now.
l am all right.
lf you can't
look anymore,
l understand.
Don't try to run
a game down on me, Jack.
lf l really didn't need you
to come back, l wouldn't ask.
This guy's on a lunar cycle.
l have three weeks
and a few days until
the next full moon.
We have a better chance
to get him fast if you help.
l'll think about it.
Stay and eat.
Hi, Molly.
Think it'll keep
them out, Dad?
Yep.
How many turtle eggs
do you think are in here?
ln this hatchery?
l'll bet there's
40 or 50 of them.
Crabs get most
of the newborns, huh?
Yeah, but not now.
These are all gonna
make it, guaranteed.
What about the dogs?
Are they gonna get in here?
They can't dig under.
That's why we bury
the wire down in the sand.
We need more staples, pal.
You're supposed
to be his friend, Jack.
Why didn't you
leave him alone?
lf he decides
to do it, Molly,
l'll keep him
as far away
from it as l can.
We got it pretty good,
don't we?
We have it more than good.
All that happened to you
before lets you know that.
lf l went back,
l'd only look at evidence.
l wouldn't get
deeply involved.
He'd never even
see me or know my name.
lf they find him,
they'll have to take
him down, not me.
What do you think?
l think you've already decided
and you're not really asking.
lf l were asking?
Stay here with me,
me and Kevin.
But it's selfish,
and l know it.
Come here.
OFFlCER: l'll come inside
with you, if you want,
to show you around.
Mr. Crawford said maybe
you'd want to be alone, but. . .
That's right.
There's a VCR hooked up
in your hotel room.
They transferred
some home movies of both
families onto half-inch VHS.
Thanks.
lntruder entered through
kitchen sliding door.
Used a glass cutter
anchored to a suction cup.
His entry was skillful.
All the prints
are smooth gloves.
Blond hair, strong,
size 1 2 shoe imprint.
Blood AB positive,
typed from saliva on glass
from licking the suction cup.
Why didn't he care that
he left saliva on the glass?
lt was hot out that night,
so inside the house
must have felt cool to him.
lntruder cut Charles Leeds'
throat as he was rising,
then shot Mrs. Leeds.
Bullet entered right
of her navel and lodged
in her lumbar spine,
but she died
of strangulation.
Moderate elevation
of serotonin
and marked increase
of free histamine level
in gunshot wound
indicates she lived
at least five minutes
after she was shot.
All her other injuries
were post-mortem.
Direction and velocity
of bloodstains on east wall
indicate arterial spray.
Even with his throat cut,
Leeds tried to fight
because the intruder
was moving
to the children's room.
Bloodstains on west wall
of master bedroom
and matted sliding
marks on hall carpet
remain unexplained,
as does superficial ligature
mark around Mr. Leeds' chest,
also believed
to be post-mortem.
What did the killer
do with them
after they were dead?
(PHONE RlNGlNG)
VALERIE ON ANSWERING MACHINE:
Hi, this is VaIerie Leeds.
Sorry, I can't come
to the phone right now,
but if you'd like
to Ieave a message
please do so after the beep,
and l'll call you back
as soon as I can.
(ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS)
(DlAL TONE SOUNDlNG)
ELECTRONlC VOlCE:
Twenty-ninth floor.
Going up.
When they were dead,
he smashed the mirrors
and began selecting pieces
that he would use
later on Mrs. Leeds.
(SlGHS)
Killing Mr. Leeds
and the children would
take less than a minute.
Mrs. Leeds'
injuries were post-mortem,
four or five minutes later.
What did he do
in the interval?
(SlGHS)
The smeared bloodstains
on the west wall. . .
(SlGHS)
(PHONE RlNGlNG)
Hello?
WlLL: Molly?
MOLLY: Will, is that you?
Yeah, it's me, honey.
Look, l'll call you tomorrow.
Go back to sleep.
l love you.
l love you too, baby.
What are you dreaming?
That's something you can't
afford for me to know about,
isn't it?
God, she's lovely,
isn't she?
lt was maddening to have
to touch her with rubber
gloves on, wasn't it?
They found talcum
powder on her leg,
but there wasn't
any talcum powder
in the bathroom.
The talcum powder came
out of a rubber glove
as you pulled
it off to touch her.
You took off your gloves
to touch her, didn't you?
Didn't you,
you son of a bitch?
You touched her
with your bare hands,
and then you put
your gloves back on.
But while your
gloves were off,
did you open all their eyes
so that they could see you?
JACK: Hello?
Jack, this is Graham.
ls Price still
in Latent Prints?
Yeah, he's in charge
of the Single Print lndex now.
What do you got, Will?
Get him to Atlanta.
Atlanta PD swears
they dusted everything,
and their guy is pretty good.
He is good.
He's not as good as Price.
l'll get him on a plane
in the morning.
What do you want him to do?
Dust Mrs. Leeds'
finger and toenails
and the corneas
of all their eyes.
l think he took
off his gloves.
Our people swear
he wore surgeon's gloves
the whole time.
They dusted everything.
Your report
didn't mention eyes.
Why do you think
he took his gloves off?
WlLL: Because Mrs. Leeds
was a beautiful woman.
This is what the subject's
teeth looked like.
The Smithsonian in Washington
reconstructed these
from the impressions that
we took of the bite marks
on the Leeds woman here
and the Jacobi woman
in Birmingham last month.
As you can see, he has
pegged lateral incisors,
that's these teeth
here and here.
SPRlNGFlELD:
Vice and Narcotics,
you take the K-Y cowboys
and leather bars.
Marcus, Whitman,
heads up at the funeral.
The rest of your assignments
are on the sheet. Let's go.
One more thing.
l've heard officers
referring to this killer
as the Tooth Fairy.
ALL LAUGHlNG)
Well, l don't want
to hear that in public,
and l don't want to see
it in internal memoranda.
That's it.
(OFFlCERS CHATTERlNG)
l know a burglar's
gonna fence what he stole
'cause his motive
is cash money.
l know his motive,
so l go to work on fences.
This guy, we don't
even have motive.
None of us have shit,
and we know it.
WlLL: lt's in his dreams.
His motive?
WlLL: Yeah.
His act fuels his fantasy.
Which is?
l don't know.
The commissioner was saying
that you're the one
who got Garrett Jacob Hobbs,
and then Dr. Lecktor
three years ago.
Lecktor killed nine
people, didn't he?
Nine that we know of.
Two didn't die.
What happened to them?
One's on a respirator
at a hospital in Baltimore,
the other's in a private
mental hospital in Denver.
What did the psychologists
say was wrong with Lecktor?
(SNlCKERS)
The psychologists
call him a psychopath.
They don't know
what else to call him.
l understand
he cut you
pretty good.
What about the dog?
lt's at the vet's. The kids
brought it in with a puncture
wound in the abdomen.
The Jacobis in Birmingham
had a cat, didn't they?
That's right.
We found
a litter box downstairs,
but we didn't find a cat.
Why don't you get
Birmingham PD a methane
probe out of Washington,
have them cover
the back yard.
Maybe the cat's dead
and the kids buried it.
(PHONE RlNGlNG)
SPRlNGFlELD: Yeah?
OVER PHONE:
This is Jimmy Price, FBl.
Let me put you
on speakerphone.
Who am l talking to?
Jimmy, it's Jack Crawford.
You got Will Graham here, too.
l got a partial print
with a tented arch,
it's probably a thumb.
And the fragment
of a palm off the nail
of Mrs. Leeds' left big toe.
Thumbprint came off
the oldest kid's left eye.
lt stood out against
an eight-ball hemorrhage
from the gunshot wound.
Can we make
an identification
off of it?
Maybe,
if he's ever been printed
and he's in my index.
l want to work these up
in my own darkroom.
l'll fax the prints
down to you this afternoon.
Thanks, Jimmy.
(REPORTERS CHATTERlNG)
No comment.
JACK: lf we get lucky
with that print, we're in,
if Jimmy can find
him in the index
and if he's ever been printed.
lf not, l don't know.
Hey, Will Graham !
What do you say?
You remember me?
Freddie Lounds,
covered the Lecktor case
for the Tattler,
did the paperback.
So, Will, when did
they call you in?
What do you got?
Hey, look, l'm buying lunch.
Lounds, why don't
you give it a rest?
Hey, he's news.
l'm doing my job.
So, how does this guy
compare with Lecktor?
How does he do them?
How's he do them, Will?
(GROANS)
Keep the fuck away from me.
JACK: Will, Will.
Son of a bitch snuck
into the hospital while
l was sedated after Lecktor.
He pulled back the sheets,
and he took pictures.
Yeah, l know.
Look, don't expect
too much from me,
all right?
We only got
three weeks left,
and you're our best shot.
You think l'm gonna see
him standing in the street
and say, "There he is"?
That's Houdini
you're thinking about.
The Tooth Fairy's
gonna go on until
we get smart or get lucky.
He won't stop.
Why?
He's got a genuine
taste for it.
You do know
something about him.
Not enough.
l think l'll go see
Lecktor tomorrow.
Why?
Recover the mindset.
That's the same atrocious
aftershave you wore
in court three years ago.
Yeah, l keep
getting it for Christmas.
Did you get my card?
l got it. Thank you.
How is Officer Stewart?
The one who was first
to see my basement.
Stewart's fine.
Emotional problems, l hear.
Do you have
any problems, Will?
No.
No, of course you don't.
(SNlCKERS)
l'm glad you came.
My callers are mostly
clinical psychologists
from cornfield
universities somewhere.
Second-raters, the lot.
Dr. Bloom
showed me your article
on surgical addiction
in the Journal
of Clinical Psychiatry.
And?
Very interesting.
Even to a layman.
l want you to help me,
Dr. Lecktor.
Yes, l thought so.
lt's about Atlanta
and Birmingham.
Yes?
You read about it?
ln the papers.
l don't tear out
the articles.
l wouldn't want them
to think l was dwelling
on anything morbid.
You want to know
how he's choosing
them, don't you?
l thought you might
have some ideas.
Why should l tell you?
You'd get to see
the file on this case.
And there's another reason.
Pray tell.
Thought you might
be curious to see
if you're smarter
than the person
l'm looking for.
Then by implication you think
you're smarter than me,
since you caught me.
No. l know that
l'm not smarter than you.
Then how did you catch me?
You had disadvantages.
What disadvantages?
You're insane.
You are very tan, Will.
Your hands are rough.
They don't look like
cop's hands anymore.
And that shaving lotion
is something
a child would select.
lt has a ship
on the bottle,
doesn't it?
Don't think you can
persuade me with appeals
to my intellectual vanity.
l don't think
l'll persuade you at all.
You'll either
do it or you won't.
Besides, we have
Dr. Bloom working on it,
and he's the best.
Do you have
the file with you?
Yes.
Pictures?
Let me have them,
and l might consider it.
No.
Dream much, Will?
Goodbye, Dr. Lecktor.
You haven't threatened
to take away my books yet.
Let me have the file,
and l'll tell
you what l think.
(KNOCKlNG ON DOOR)
(PAGES FLlPPlNG)
This is a very shy boy, Will.
What were their yards like?
Big back yards.
Fences, hedges.
Why?
Because, my dear Will,
if this pilgrim
imagines he has a relationship
with the moon,
he might go outside
to look at it.
Have you ever seen
blood in the moonlight?
lt appears quite black.
lf one were nude, it would
be better to have privacy
for this sort of thing.
That's interesting.
No, it's not.
You thought of it before.
l considered it.
You came here to look at me,
to get the old scent
back again, didn't you?
l want your opinion.
l don't have one right now.
Well, when you have one,
l'd like to hear it.
Can l keep this?
l haven't decided yet.
l'll study them.
When you get more files,
l'd like to see them, too.
You can call me.
When l have to call my lawyer,
they bring me a telephone.
Would you like to leave me
your home phone number?
No.
Do you know
how you caught me?
Goodbye, Dr. Lecktor.
You can leave
messages for me.
LECKTOR: Do you know
how you caught me?
The reason you caught me,
Will, is we're just alike.
Do you understand?
Smell yourself.
(PANTlNG)
(CLlCKlNG)
Gotcha.
WOMAN ON PA: ...217
now boarding at Gate 1 2.
Eastern Airlines
Flight 217 is now ready
for boarding at Gate 1 2.
Get up against the bunk
and face the wall.
Don't turn around,
or l'll Mace you
in the face.
Thank you so much.
l'll call you
when l'm finished.
FEMALE OPERATOR:
Are you ready for your call?
Yes, thank you.
(PHONE RlNGlNG)
WOMAN 1 : PaItrow,
Christiansen & GoIub,
Law Offices.
Excuse me.
l must have misdialed.
(PHONE RlNGlNG)
MALE OPERATOR:
Thank you for using AT&T.
This is Operator 24.
Operator, l don't
have the use of my arms.
Would you be so kind
as to dial a number
for me, please?
Certainly. What's the number?
Area code 301 ,
555-6624.
(PHONE DlALlNG)
WOMAN 2:
The University of Chicago,
Department of Psychiatry.
Dr. Sidney Bloom, please.
He's not in,
but l'll connect you
to his office.
What's his
secretary's
name again?
Martha King.
Just a moment, please.
WOMAN 3: Martha King's desk.
Hi, Martha.
Martha doesn't
come in nights.
Maybe you can help me.
This is Bob Greer
of Blaine & Edwards
publishing company,
Dr. Bloom asked me
to send a copy
of The Psychiatrist
and the Law to someone.
Martha never sent me
the address and phone number.
She'll be in in the morning.
Well, l've got to catch
Federal Express in about
five minutes.
l'd be immensely appreciative
if you could pull it out
of her Rolodex for me.
l don't see a Rolodex.
l'll bet she has a call caddy
right next to her phone.
Yeah...
Well, zip that
little pointer
right on down
to the letter G.
All right.
The name we're looking for,
last name Graham,
the man the book
is supposed
to be sent to,
a Mr. Will Graham.
Federal Bureau
of lnvestigation,
1 0th and Pennsylvania,
Washington, D.C.
Now, l'll bet it has his
home address there, too.
3680 DeSoto Highway,
Captiva, Florida.
Thank you so very much.
(TAPPlNG)
l've finished.
(PASSENGERS CHATTERlNG)
(BREATHlNG HEAVlLY)
Mom !
Oh, my gosh.
lt's all right. Stewardess!
CAPTAlN ON PA SYSTEM:
Ladies and gentlemen,
we are beginning our descent
into Birmingham.
WlLL: You used a cutting
tool on the branch
so that you could see.
Then you passed
the time whittling
and dreaming.
When night came,
you saw them pass by
their bright windows.
Then you watched
the shades go down,
then you saw the lights
go out, one by one.
Then after a while,
you climbed down
and you went in to them,
didn't you?
Didn't you,
you son of a bitch?
You watched them
all goddamned day long !
That's why houses
with big yards.
WlLL: l need Firearms
and Tool Marks section
out here on a severed branch.
l need to know what kind
of cutting tool he used.
And then l need
Bowman in Documents
to fall on this carving.
JACK: ls it weird?
The mark? Yeah.
lf Documents
can't do the carving,
l'll send it up to Langley.
WlLL: Did Price
get an identification
off the Leeds print?
No, Price hasn't found
him in the index yet.
lt's a hand search.
He's got half
his department on it.
Listen, have you seen
this week's Tattler?
(SCOFFS) lt's not on my
preferred reading list.
WeII,
your picture's
all over the front page.
Who the hell was it? Lounds?
Of course. Who else?
God damn it, Jack!
l promised Molly!
l promised her!
Come in.
GUARD: Dr. Chilton?
Yes?
When we were cleaning
out Dr. Lecktor's cell,
he heard us coming
and hid something
in a book.
We got him
out of there
and dug around.
ls that it?
Yes.
Put it down
on my desk, Bonner.
Has anyone else
seen this except you?
No.
SECRETARY: Special Agent
Crawford's office.
This is Dr. Chilton.
l need to speak
to Mr. Graham right away.
He's not here,
he's in Birmingham.
Special Agent Crawford
is on the line with him now.
Please tell them
this is very, very urgent.
l'll hold on.
Dr. Chilton,
it's Jack Crawford.
You have Will Graham
on the line, too.
CHlLTON: l have a note,
or two pieces of a note
that appears to be
from that man who killed
those people in Atlanta.
Where did you get it?
ln Hannibal Lecktor's cell.
lt was hidden in a book.
WlLL: Don't touch the note.
Can you read it to us?
lt's written
on toilet tissue.
"My dear Dr. Lecktor,
"l wanted to tell you
l'm delighted that you've
taken an interest in me.
"l know that you alone
can understand
what l am becoming.
"You alone know
the people l use
to help me in these things
"are only elements
undergoing change
"to fuel the radiance
of what l am becoming,
"just as the source
of light is burning.
"l have a collection
of your press clippings.
"l think they are absurd,
as are mine.
"'The Tooth Fairy,'
what could be
more inappropriate?
"lnvestigator Graham
interests me,
"very purposeful-looking.
"l hope we can correspond."
There's a piece missing here.
Now l'll read
the bottom part.
"After l hear back from you,
"l might send
you something wet."
Signed "Avid Fan."
lt has teeth marks
pressed into it
at the bottom.
Order a chopper,
next thing smoking.
l don't care whose it is.
Two, call Alabama
Air National Guard,
get Graham back
here right now.
Then call Documents
and tell them
to scramble a team.
l want everybody moving
five minutes ago.
You understand?
JACK: l have a Documents
team on its way to you
by helicopter
to pick up the note.
Listen, after we've
worked the note,
l want to replace
it in Lecktor's cell.
l don't want Lecktor to know
that we've found it,
he might try to warn
the killer somehow.
Where's Lecktor now?
CHlLTON: Holding cell.
How long can you keep
him in there without
him getting suspicious?
CHILTON: Three, four hours.
Brian, we have a note
coming in on the flight,
possibly from the Tooth Fairy,
number one priority.
lt has to go
to Hair and Fiber,
Latent Prints,
and then Documents.
Will Graham and l
will be walking it through.
One hair, Graham.
Maybe half an inch.
And a couple of blue grains.
Work the hair.
What do we have
for negative comparison?
Hair from Lecktor's comb,
whiskers from Lecktor's
razor they let him use.
This is hair from
the security guard.
MAN: How many guys
handled this without gloves?
The guard,
cleanup man, Lecktor.
The cleanup man
scrubbing sinks
probably had the oil
washed off his fingers.
But the others. . .
One smudge.
Those aren't ridges.
lt's just the texture
of the paper.
l can fume for a print,
but can't guarantee
the iodine stains
would fade out.
Ninhydrin?
Boost it with heat?
No.
We couldn't wash it after.
l can't get a print off this
in the time you've got
to get it back, Will.
BOWMAN: How long do l have?
JACK: Twenty minutes, max.
BOWMAN: The main thing
to find out is,
how was Lecktor supposed
to reply to him?
Which is probably
the missing section,
because at the top it says,
"l hope we can correspond,"
then comes the gap.
This note was written
in ballpoint,
but it looks like Lecktor
went over this area
with a felt-tip pen,
then tore it away.
You're so sly,
but so am l.
The aniline dyes used
in the ink of the felt-tip
pens like Lecktor used
are transparent to infrared.
The Tooth Fairy's
ballpoint isn't.
This looks like the tip
of a T here, here, and here.
At the end is what
could be the top of an R.
There's three Ts
and an R in "Tattler."
We know our boy reads it.
The article about me
and Lecktor.
l don't know anybody else
that's carried that.
Personal ads.
We believe the Tooth Fairy
told Lecktor to reply to him
through the personal
ad section of
the National Tattler.
The Chicago office
is down there right now
running through their ads.
We have cut into
a line of communication
between the Tooth Fairy
and Lecktor.
lf we find Lecktor's
reply we plan to pull it,
substitute it
with one of our own.
And this is what
the Tooth Fairy
will read. Bill?
"Dear Avid Fan,
inherit my mantle and surpass
my achievements.
"Mementoes for you
at Baltimore Central
Left Luggage.
"Ticket number 72683."
lt's a Secret Service
letter drop.
We plan to stake it out.
When he shows,
we'll grab him.
Anything from Chicago?
SARAH: Not yet.
When do they go to press?
JACK: Thirty-five minutes.
Christ.
Let's get to the physical.
There was no print.
Scale counts
and core size of the hair
match the blond hair
found in the Jacobis'.
That note was written
by your man.
Aside from the hair,
three blue grains,
dark flecks,
went to Brian's end.
The grains are commercial
granulated cleanser
with chlorine,
from the cleaning man.
Several particles
of dried blood,
but not enough to type.
(PHONE RlNGlNG)
OVER PHONE: This is Chester.
Who am l talking to?
Will Graham, Jack Crawford.
Got a personal ad with
"Avid Fan" in it being
telexed to you right now.
Read it.
"Dear Avid Fan,
"You honor me.
You're very beautiful."
JACK: Oh, Christ.
"l offer 1 00 prayers
for your safety.
"Find help in Galatians
6: 1 1 , 1 5:2,
"Acts 3:3, ReveIations 1 8:7,
"Jonah 6:8, John 6:22,
"Luke 1 :7."
JACK: Thanks.
Jimmy.
Did you get anywhere
at all identifying him
off the Leeds' prints?
Not yet.
Photography at Langley?
They got shot a telex.
They're on it now.
No. And our ad has to go
out in the same book
code Lecktor used,
or he'll know
it wasn't Lecktor
talking to him.
Book code?
"1 00 prayers" could
be the page number,
the paired numbers
could be line and letter.
But what book?
JACK: Not the Bible?
No.
Galatians 1 5:2.
Galatians only
has six chapters.
The same with Jonah 6:8.
Jonah only has
four chapters.
Lecktor was not
using the Bible.
Then the Tooth Fairy
probably named the book
in the part Lecktor tore out.
Right.
What about sweating Lecktor?
They tried sodium amytal
on him three years ago
to find where
he buried a Princeton student.
He gave them a recipe
for potato chip dip.
JACK: Wonderful.
The Tooth Fairy would have
named a book he knew
Lecktor has access to.
He'd know it from articles
he'd read about Lecktor.
JACK: Willingham,
when he tossed his cell,
took Polaroids so they can
get everything back in place.
Have him meet me
with pictures
of Lecktor's books.
JACK: Where?
BOWMAN: Library of Congress.
Twenty-five minutes.
He won't make it in time.
Lecktor's ad runs as is,
we decode it later.
Or we pull it,
figure out the code
and run our own ad next week.
And lose a week?
We got 1 7 days till
the next full moon.
And l don't like
Lecktor's ad running
without knowing what it says.
lt's your call, Will.
Run it.
And what if it encourages
the Tooth Fairy to do
something else beside write?
We'll all feel sick
for a very long time.
JACK: And if Bowman
still can't figure it out?
Then we'll bait him
with something else
in next week's Tattler.
JACK: What, for instance?
Me.
l don't think
that's a very good idea.
Why not?
Don't you think
we can provoke him?
Maybe.
Maybe he can be provoked.
What l was thinking
about is you.
You're getting deeper
and deeper into this.
Good night.
Sidney.
l'll talk to you.
Last time you did that
you did a real good job
of pushing yourself
all out of shape.
You try it on again
or you go through
some big trauma,
you could relapse,
my friend.
Sidney,
don't worry about me.
l'm working the evidence,
making moves. That's all.
l'm fine.
Bowman just struck out.
lt is not books
in Lecktor's cell.
Price?
He just heard.
lt's a bust-out.
As evidence, the Leeds print
will get us a conviction
if we could ever
find the guy.
But he must never
have been printed because
he is not in our index.
We are not gonna
identify him off the print.
l'll use Lounds.
What for?
Our boy doesn't
read the New York Times
literary supplement.
He reads Lounds
in the Tattler.
What else should we cover?
He put the shorts
on Charles Leeds
after he was dead.
l believe
he did this to make sure
we wouldn't think he was gay.
He's molested
all of his male victims.
He may be impotent
with members
of the opposite sex.
Our forensic
psychologists
have projected,
though l'm not sure,
that he may have had sexual
relations with his mother.
(LAUGHS)
So, how long do you plan
to stay in Washington?
Till we've taken
out the Tooth Fairy.
LOUNDS: Can the Tattler rely
on getting the straight stuff
from you?
Absolutely.
How does working on this case
affect your sex life?
Mine? lt doesn't affect mine,
it affects yours.
Go fuck yourself.
Look, pal of mine,
you're news.
Shoot the pictures.
All right, Symie,
let's shoot them.
l'm in the shots
with Graham.
What?
l'm in the shots with you.
Come on, you want this
to look real or not?
Make sure the theater sign
across the street is just
slightly out of focus.
We want him to be able
to read it so he can find it,
but we don't want
to look too obvious.
You make sure that
l look excellent.
All right, shoot it.
One more.
That's enough.
Okay, Graham.
Hey, always nice, huh?
Let's have lunch,
call my service.
Crawford, always a thrill.
Dr. Bloom. l need them
on my desk in two hours.
Did Bowman break
the code yet?
No.
Tools and Firearms
say the cutting tool
used on the severed branch
was a common bolt cutter.
l got a call from
Asian Studies at Langley.
The mark you found
on the tree?
Yeah?
lt's a Chinese character
considered a lucky sign
in gambling.
That same character appears
on a Mah Jongg piece.
lt means "Red Dragon."
Mean anything to you?
No.
lf he shows,
and he's smart,
he'll approach you
from the front, pass, turn,
try and take you
from behind.
How's your hearing?
lt's good.
You'll wear a wire,
one-way.
We'll hear you,
you won't hear us.
You checked out
a Charter Arms
.44 Special Bulldog?
Yeah.
Load these in it.
You ever fire them?
Glaser Safety Slugs.
Yeah. Number 1 2 shots.
Suspended in liquid Teflon
in a copper casing.
On impact it all
opens up in the target.
Guaranteed one-shot stop.
You got body armor?
Yeah, Kevlar Second Chance.
l hope you get one.
'Cause he's gone
for the head shot
eight of eleven times?
Let's walk the route.
WOMAN ON PA:
United Flight 849 to Newark
now boarding at Gate 7...
now boarding at Gate 7.
Someone's coming.
(GRUNTS)
Go!
Don't! Don't move!
Take the money!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
Clear!
What you moving
in slow motion for, man?
l'm being mugged !
For real.
Can you believe that?
Pay up.
RADlO ANNOUNCER:
...in sports,
the Cubs lost again.
Hey!
(MUFFLED SCREAM)
(BREAKlNG)
You know who l am?
l don't want
to know who you are.
According to you,
l'm a sexual pervert.
"An animal," you said.
You know who l am now?
Yes.
Do you feel privileged?
l'm very scared.
Open your eyes.
Mr. Lounds,
you're a reporter.
Your job is to report.
That's why you're here.
And if you don't
open your eyes,
l'll staple your eyelids
to your forehead.
Well, here l am.
(PROJECTOR WHlRRlNG)
Look at the screen.
William Blake's
The Great Red Dragon
and the Woman Clothed
ln The Rays Of The Sun.
Do you see?
Yes.
Mrs. Leeds. Do you see?
Mrs. Jacobi. Do you see?
Yes.
The next family
as they will look
when l go to visit them.
Do you see?
Yes.
Mrs. Leeds, later.
Her husband beside her.
Yes.
Mrs. Jacobi
after her changing.
The Dragon rampant.
Freddie Lounds,
your photograph.
No.
No what?
Not me, please.
Please.
Are you a man?
Yes.
Do you imply that l'm queer?
God, no.
Before me,
you are a slug in the sun.
You are privy
to a great becoming,
and you recognize nothing.
You are an ant
in the afterbirth.
lt is your nature
to do one thing correctly,
tremble.
But fear is not
what you owe me.
No, Lounds,
you and the others,
you owe me awe.
We have one more
piece of work to do.
lf he takes off the mask,
l am a dead man.
Open your eyes.
Open your eyes!
You will read this
into the tape recorder.
Go.
"l have had
a great privilege.
"l have seen with wonder
and awe the strength
of the Red Dragon.
"All l wrote
about him were lies.
"Will Graham
made me write them
"to pull him into
a trap in Washington,
District of Columbia.
"Will Graham,
you will learn
from my own lips
"how much you have to dread
because l was forced to lie.
"He will be more merciful
to me than to you.
"You will lie awake
in fear of what
the Red Dragon will do.
"l will be a testament
to the truth of this."
(SHUDDERlNG)
You did very well.
Will you let me go now?
Please?
You will tell the truth?
l promise.
Good.
We'll seal your
promise with. . .
We'll seal your promise
with a kiss.
(LOUNDS SCREAMlNG)
MAN ON RADlO: We'll be showing
five possible answers
to the questions
l'll be asking.
Any member of a team
may buzz in an answer,
but if incorrect,
then the other team
will have the opportunity...
(SQUEAKlNG)
(FlRE ROARlNG)
(WHEELCHAlR SQUEAKlNG)
(SCREAMlNG)
Bowman, just skip
the cryptography and tell me
what the hell it says, okay?
Did he try to say
anything at all?
No, he sure didn't.
He never regained
consciousness.
Did you hear the tape?
Yeah.
Listen, Bowman just broke
the code that Lecktor used
in the Tattler personal ad.
lt was the State
of Maryland statutes.
You need to know
what it said right now.
What?
Listen to me.
Everything is okay.
l've taken care of it.
What is it, Jack?
The bastard gave him
your home address.
lt said, "Graham home,
3860 DeSoto Highway,
"Captiva, Florida.
"Save yourself.
Kill them all."
Get me a plane.
Will !
Mom.
Huh?
What time. . . What?
Someone's outside.
There are noises.
Where?
Outside.
(WHlSPERlNG) Mom. . .
Go back to your room
and close the door.
Mom. . .
Do it now.
Ma'am, are you all right?
What? What is it?
What is it?
What's going on?
OFFlCER: Ma'am, l think
you should come back inside.
What's going on?
Come back inside.
Please. l think
you should come back inside.
l'm sorry, Molly.
l'm sorry about all of this.
This place is fine.
We'll be fine.
He's after you now,
isn't he?
This is just a precaution.
Kevin, why don't you
run down to the water,
check out the dock?
l want to hang around here.
l'm in the kitchen, Mom.
Okay.
What is that about?
What, he's afraid
to leave you alone
with me now?
He saw the article
in the Tattler, right?
l wanted to talk
with him about it,
but he said he wanted
to bring it up to you,
face to face.
Good for him.
Kevin, help me
unpack, will you?
Then we'll go
get some groceries.
You and Mom are very
well-protected, you know.
No one's gonna find
out where you are.
KEVlN: ls there
anything l need
to know to see about Mom?
No.
KEVlN: This guy
is trying to kill us?
We don't know that.
When are you
going to kill him?
l'm not.
lt's only my job
to find him.
Barry's mom had
this newspaper.
lt said you were
in a special hospital.
Well, it was
a regular hospital,
then l was transferred
into the psychiatric wing.
That bothers you,
doesn't it?
l don't know.
Was it because
in the papers it said
it was this man Lecktor?
Mmm-hmm.
What happened?
Well, Lecktor was attacking
college girls,
then he killed them.
How?
ln bad ways.
He was a psychiatrist.
One of the girls
was his patient,
and l went to talk
to him about her.
l tried to build feelings
in my imagination
like the killer had
so that l would know
why he did what he did,
because that would
help me find him.
When l was sitting
in Lecktor's office
and l looked up,
l saw a book on his shelf.
lt had pictures of
war wounds in it.
And l knew it was him.
So l went to a pay phone
down the hall
to call the police
and that's when
he attacked me.
You and Mom
came to see me
in the hospital,
and that helped a lot.
But after my body got okay,
l still had his thoughts
going around in my head.
And l stopped
talking to people.
And a doctor friend of mine,
a Dr. Bloom,
asked me to get some help.
And l did.
Then after a while
l felt better,
and l was okay again.
And the way
he thought felt that bad?
Kevin,
they're the ugliest
thoughts in the world.
So, what kind of
coffee do you like?
You like that
Folgers stuff, right?
Yeah.
Mom likes that, too.
When can we go home, Dad?
l don't know, Kevin.
So, where are things?
Nowhere.
Everything we've tried
is either a dead end
or it's backfired.
Crawford's already planning
the next crime scene
so they can get it fresh.
We've got about six more days
till the next full moon.
Can you quit?
No.
What's next?
l go to Atlanta.
Crawford?
No.
l have to be alone.
You're talking about doing
exactly what you said you. . .
This killing,
it's gotta stop.
William, you're
gonna make yourself sick.
Or get yourself killed.
You and Kevin
should go to Montana.
See your dad.
He hasn't seen
Kevin for a long time.
And l'll come up
and get you afterwards.
(WOMAN CHATTERlNG
ON PA SYSTEM)
VALERlE ON ANSWERlNG MACHlNE:
Hi, this is VaIerie Leeds.
Sorry l can't come
to the phone right now.
l'm sorry, too.
WAlTRESS: Excuse me.
Coffee.
lt's just you
and me now, sport.
l'm gonna find you,
God damn it.
Mr. Dollarhyde?
Eileen.
Bill told me to tell you
there was a variation
in the gamma
of number three.
But he caught it in time.
Eileen,
good. Good.
(KNOCKlNG ON DOOR)
REBA: Who's there?
Mr. Dollarhyde.
l came about
the low-light
infrared emulsion.
REBA: Oh, yeah.
Come on in, it's safe.
Put your back
against the door.
There's a stool
just to your right.
You're the production
controller from Admin, right?
Can you give me an idea
of the conditions?
Shooting from
maybe eight feet.
l can't use any lights.
Okay, what's being
photographed?
The activities
of nocturnal animals.
When do you need it?
Four days.
Okay, let me stick
this in the black hole.
1 000-C infrared sensitive
has to be handled
in total darkness.
Remember to be
very careful with it.
But still,
it's easier to handle
than the 1 200 series.
lt'll be fine.
ln case you're wondering,
l keep the samples
straight by touch code.
No, l wasn't wondering.
Reba, l gotta fly.
Maybe Mr. Dollarhyde
can drive you home tonight.
No, that's okay.
l'll take care of myself.
RALPH: l can
change things around.
No, thanks, go on.
Okay.
l'll take you.
No, thanks.
l'll order you 1 200 feet
of 1 000-C in the morning.
Ride with me.
Thanks,
but l'll take the bus.
l do it all the time.
Ride with me.
lt would be because
l would like you to.
Okay, sure.
Let me get my stuff on.
How did you come to Gateway?
Oh, they had to hire
the handicapped
to shape up their
employment practices
to get this defense contract.
You worked out well.
Everybody they hired did.
You know,
you speak very well.
Although you avoid
fricatives and sibilants.
At the Riker lnstitute
for the Blind,
l trained in therapy
for speech- and
hearing-impaired children.
l'll probably
go back to it someday.
Mmm-hmm.
You know, if you don't
want to talk, that's okay.
But l hope you will,
because you're very direct,
and l like that,
and l like what
you have to say.
May l touch your face?
l want to know whether
you're smiling or frowning.
l guess l want to know whether
l should be quiet or not.
Take my word for it.
l'm smiling.
l didn't mean to offend you.
On the way,
can l take you somewhere?
Where?
lt would be my surprise.
Okay, sure.
Are you apprehensive?
No.
The very protective
Mr. Dollarhyde
over there is watching us.
No, no, l want to.
ln about two hours
we're going to cap his tooth.
REBA: Yeah.
DOCTOR: lt's warm.
(HEART BEATlNG)
Back a little bit. There.
You hear it?
Yeah.
You
rearrange the dead families
into an audience
to see what you do.
You think that what you do
will make you into something
different.
You are becoming.
What is it you think
you're becoming?
The answer is in the way
you use the mirrors.
What do the mirrors
make you dream
you're becoming?
(PROJECTOR WHlRRlNG)
A little to your left.
Francis, that was
a great dinner.
Thank you.
l made you
a gin and tonic.
lt's right in
front of you.
What are you watching?
lt's just
a little homework.
(THlS BlG HUSH PLAYING)
(lNHALES DEEPLY)
You're a sweet,
thoughtful man, D.
ls there a fire in the sky?
Your heart's loud.
ls there a moon up there?
lf you'll hold me. . .
ls anything alive now?
This darkness is what l hear
This is a breathless silence
A moment out of time
l see your face in the shadows
The tell-tale signs
are in your eyes
Aching with a passion inside
Deep as the river
All desire
The ashes and the fire
Turning this night inside
And the light from you
ls there a flame in the dark?
ls there a bright heart star?
These creatures
look the same now
We freeze wherever we are
We wake alone in the blackness
We sleep wherever we fall
One dream all around us
This big hush infects us all
Forever in this half-light
All desire
The ashes and the fire
Turning this night inside
(CRYlNG)
And the light from you
All desire
The ashes and the fire
Turning this night inside
And the light from you
REBA: ls that you, D?
DOLLARHYDE: Are you okay?
Yeah, l'm fine.
Hi.
(DOLLARHYDE CHUCKLES)
Good morning.
Morning.
You know, if you show me
where things are,
l'll make us some coffee.
No, no. . .
Don't go back
inside the house.
Why? l left
my purse inside.
l'll get it. lt's okay.
l mean, you should stay
outside, it's. . . lt's. . .
lt's 'cause you look
so good in the sun.
(LAUGHlNG) Okay.
(SlGHS)
When. . .
Reba, when can
l see you again?
Oh ! Um. . .
We could meet
at my house.
JACK OVER PHONE: You got
the message Lecktor called?
Yeah. l arranged
for him to have a phone.
l gotta call him
in a few minutes.
Good.
Listen, we identified
the tire tracks left
when Lounds was delivered
back to the Tattler.
G-781 6 Goodyear truck tires.
Looks like our
boy drives a van.
l'm setting up
our base in Chicago.
When are you coming back?
When l'm done, Jack.
(PHONE RlNGlNG)
Yeah, this is Will
Graham of the FBl.
Dr. Chilton arranged for me
to talk to Dr. Lecktor.
Hello?
LECKTOR: HeIIo, WiII.
l wanted to congratulate
you for the job
you did on Mr. Lounds.
l admire that enormously.
Oh, what a cunning
boy you are.
l'm sick of you
crazy sons of bitches.
You got something
to say, say it.
l want to help you.
You'd be more comfortable
if you relax with yourself.
We don't invent our natures,
they're issued to us,
along with our lungs
and pancreas
and everything else.
Why fight it?
Fight what?
Did you really
feel so depressed
after you shot
Mr. Garrett Jacob Hobbs
to death?
l didn't know you then,
but l think you probably did.
But it wasn't the act
that got you down, was it?
Didn't you really feel
so bad because killing
him felt so good?
And why shouldn't
it feel good?
lt must feel good to God.
He does it all the time.
God's terrific.
He dropped a church roof
on 34 of his worshippers
last Wednesday night
in Texas
as they were groveling
through a hymn
to his majesty.
Don't you think
that felt good?
Why does it feel good,
Dr. Lecktor?
lt feels good, Will,
because God has power.
And if one does what
God does enough times,
one will become as God is.
God's a champ.
He always stays ahead.
He got 1 40 Filipinos
in one plane crash last month.
Remember that earthquake
in ltaly last spring?
WlLL: l enter.
The glass cutter.
The piece of glass
l take out is mine.
The house is mine.
l walk up these stairs,
l pass the children's toys.
The children mean
nothing to me.
They were put
here to help me.
l move to the door.
l step into the room.
l see you there.
And l see me desired by you.
Accepted and loved
in the silver mirrors
of your eyes.
(STRONG AS l AM PLAYlNG)
(CAR APPROACHlNG)
Father, look in my eyes
See me as l really am
You made me
Now take me
RALPH: l'm gonna talk
to Fogel tomorrow. . .
Tell me how it feels now
Behold your flesh
has come of age
RALPH: Wait a minute.
Forsake me, you break me
Strong as l am
There's something about
this thing that scares me
Strong as l am
There's something about
this thing that dares me
Strong as l am
There's something about
this thing that haunts me
Strong as l am
There's something about
this thing that taunts me
Mother, let me heal you
Your pain has lasted
far too long
Release it, it kills you
What was it?
Pollen.
Oh.
Thanks for the ride.
See you tomorrow.
Yeah.
The love you would not share
grows tired of waiting
(GASPS)
Mr. Dollarhyde.
What are you doing here?
(GUN FlRlNG)
Strong as l am
There's something about
this thing that scares me
Strong as l am
(KNOCKlNG ON DOOR)
REBA: Who is it?
DOLLARHYDE: lt's me.
Who? Who is it?
Oh.
Francis?
No,
not Francis.
Francis is gone.
Francis is gone forever.
So, what are we doing?
The dream.
He dreams about
being wanted and desired,
so he changes
people into beings
who want and desire him.
Changes?
lt's a word.
Killing and arranging
the people to imitate it.
And Lecktor
told me something.
lf one does what
God does enough times,
one will become as God is.
You put it together,
you get,
if our boy
imitates being wanted
and desired enough times,
he believes
he will become one
who is wanted
and desired and accepted.
lt'll all come true.
This started
from an abused kid,
a battered infant.
There's something
terrible about. . .
JACK: What,
are you sympathizing
with this guy now?
Absolutely.
My heart bleeds
for him as a child.
Someone took a kid
and manufactured a monster.
At the same time,
as an adult,
he's irredeemable.
He butchers whole families
to pursue trivial fantasies.
As an adult, someone
should blow this sick
fuck out of his socks.
Do you think that's
a contradiction, Jack?
Does this kind
of understanding
make you uncomfortable?
What about the mirrors?
He uses the mirrors
to see it happen.
But he doesn't take anything.
There's no souvenirs
taken from the houses.
He needs souvenirs
or trophies
to re-live the event.
Maybe he records it somehow.
So he could see himself
accepted over
and over and over again.
VTRs, Polaroids,
stills, what?
How do l know?
How does he find them?
When we find out
how he found them,
we'll find him.
There is no connection
between the two families.
We've done a dozen
computer runs.
Jack, all the women
have a bloom on them.
He didn't win them
in a lottery,
he picked these women.
There's selection
and design in his choices.
Look, admit
we struck out
this month.
The Lear Jet is standing by,
the basic lab stuff is on it.
You, Zeller, Jimmy Price,
the photographer,
anywhere he hits,
we can be there
in an hour and 1 5 minutes.
We get the call, we roll.
The scene will be fresher
than we've ever had it.
lt's not over yet.
For Christ's sake!
That's a foregone conclusion.
lt's 1 1 :30 p.m. ,
the full moon
is happening tonight.
Give it up!
Forget this month,
it's too damn late!
l gave it up.
Till you showed up
with pictures
of two dead families,
knowing goddamn well that
l'd imagine families three,
four, five and six. Right?
You're fucking right l did,
and l'd do it again !
Great! But don't talk
to me about late, pal,
l'll tell you when
it's too fucking late!
Until then, we go as late
as l want to take it!
(WlLL SlGHS)
A padlock.
That's why the bolt cutter.
What's that?
He used a bolt cutter
to trim away the branch
when he was watching
from the woods.
Why didn't he use
the bolt cutter
on the garage door?
Because a deadbolt was there
when they were killed.
Donald Jacobi's
1 2th birthday party
was April 1 4th.
Sometime between
April 1 4th and August 1
they changed the lock.
But he thought there
was a padlock there.
From the street,
you can't see the glass
in the Leeds' kitchen door.
There's a big,
high fence there.
But he was ready
with his glass cutter.
So either he was
casing far ahead
and we didn't
check back far enough,
or. . .
JACK: We checked.
Don't talk.
Metcalfe, is the Leeds
and Jacobi stuff
still in the storeroom?
Have the guard
down there call me.
Do it.
You know that's
the Jacobis' cat.
You brought a bolt cutter
'cause you thought
there was a padlock.
The Leeds' dog
doesn't have a collar,
but you know
it's the Leeds' dog,
don't you, my man?
See the woman?
The bloom on the woman?
You can see her
again and again
anytime you want.
Doggie doesn't
have a collar,
but you know
it's the Leeds' dog.
And the Jacobi cat.
And the padlock
on the door.
And you know
you need a bolt cutter
and every other goddamn thing
because everything with you
is seeing, isn't it?
Your primary sensory intake
that makes your dream
live is seeing.
Reflections, mirrors,
images. . .
You've seen these films.
Haven't you, my man?
(PHONE RlNGlNG)
lt's the guard
in the storeroom.
The cans.
What cans?
The tapes were transferred
from home movies.
Where's the packaging
the films came in?
There's films of the families
in the document storage.
Find them.
You got them?
Are there any labels?
Leeds can, Gateway Lab,
St. Louis, Missouri.
The Jacobi label
will say the same thing
as the Leeds label.
Gateway Lab,
St. Louis, Missouri.
JACK: Who processed
the Jacobi film?
No. Bob's Photo Store,
Birmingham.
Stores send them out.
Have him peel
the top label back.
JACK: ls there
a label underneath?
lt does, doesn't it?
l want a chopper
on the roof in three
minutes to Meigs Field.
At Meigs Field,
l want the Lear Jet
prepped and a plan
filed with St. Louis.
Where are you?
Are you here?
(lN-A-GADDA-DA-VlDA PLAYlNG)
You're scaring me
with this!
Will you just stop it?
Francis,
why are you doing
this to me?
lt's ugly!
Don't you know that
l'll always be true?
Are you in this room?
Where are you?
You answer me!
And take my hand
Oh, won't you come with me
And walk this land
Please, take my hand
(EXHALES)
JACK: We're looking for a man.
We know he works at Gateway.
We don't have his name,
but we know he drives a van.
MAN OVER PHONE: Under
"Employee Facilities,"
l've got special
stickers for vans.
Yeah, l got 28,
29 van permits
in the computer.
JACK: Start feeding me names.
ls this Lieutenant Fisk?
Will Graham.
Listen,
l need you to punch up
the driver's licenses
of the names
l'm gonna feed you.
The man we're looking
for is blond, Caucasian,
twenty to forty years old,
over six feet taII,
1 80 to 225 pounds.
First name?
Alvaro.
A-L-V-A-R-O.
First name Joseph.
Alvaro. A-L-V-A-R-O.
No. Black hair.
No.
Next.
Dillon. D-l-L-L-O-N.
First name Lincoln.
FlSK: No. Next.
(MAN CHATTERlNG ON RADlO)
Male. Caucasian.
Six foot-seven, 21 7 pounds.
Eyes brown, hair blond.
Thirty-four years old.
Put it through
the data-fax. Fast.
You guys better buckle up.
We're on approach
to Lambert Field.
(MAN CHATTERlNG ON RADlO)
JACK: Fogel
has four more names.
He knows two,
both dark hair,
third's a woman,
fourth is a handicapped
parking permit.
This is our man.
Rural Route 3,
Chester, Missouri.
Where is that?
From the airport
you're a few minutes closer.
We'll 1 0-25 at the Hark Road
off ramp, Highway 94.
Let's go!
(SlRENS WAlLlNG)
(LOUD MUSlC PLAYlNG)
(SCREAMS)
Meet point's up ahead.
Go on to the house.
But Lieutenant Fisk said. . .
JACK: Will?
You're not gonna need that.
A SWAT team is gonna
take him down, not us.
Will?
(CAR SWERVlNG)
Will !
(SlRENS STOP WAlLlNG)
(DlSPATCHER CHATTERlNG
ON RADlO)
OFFlCER 1 : This ought
to be it right here.
Kill your lights.
(STEAM HlSSlNG)
OFFlCER 2: Are you all right?
OFFlCER 3: l'm okay.
Griffin's hurt bad.
l'll wait for the backup.
JACK: Set up
a roadblock on Route 3.
Graham and l
are in the trees
west of the house.
WlLL: (SOFTLY) How far
away is the backup unit?
l'm going around the back.
Stay in the trees.
He's in there, Jack.
And he's got somebody
in there with him.
JACK: What?
Will, what did you say?
JACK ON RADlO: Will.
Wait for the backup, Will.
He's got somebody
in the house with him, Jack.
JACK: Will.
Stop it.
Stop it!
(OFFlCER GROANS)
(COCKlNG GUN)
(GRUNTS)
Three, four
ln-a-gadda-da-vida, honey
Don't you know
that l love you?
ln-a-gadda-da-vida, baby
Don't you know
that l'll always be true?
Oh, won't you come with me
And take my hand
And walk this land
Please, take my hand
(SlRENS WAlLlNG)
(lNAUDlBLE)
lt's okay.
(SOBBlNG)
Who are you?
Graham.
l'm Will Graham.
(HEARTBEAT PLAYlNG)
l can hear your heartbeat
knocking on the window
KEVlN: Hey, Dad !
l can feel the weight
deep down below
Dad !
Hey!
lt looks worse
than it is, pal.
See the turtles?
Wow!
Hi.
lt was on the news.
l thought l had
to work things out
and call you after.
l thought
l wouldn't wait.
Sometimes l
understand it very clearly
Heartbeat, heartbeat
Listen to my heartbeat
How many of them made it?
Most of them.
Most of them made it.
Heartbeat
Listen to my heartbeat
l can hear your tiptoe
l can hear the door close
Anticipation in me grows
l can feel your dark eyes
Touch me in the darkness
Understand
the message never sent
Sometimes l
understand it very clearly
Heartbeat, heartbeat
Listen to my heartbeat
Heartbeat
l can hear your tiptoe
l can hear the door close
Anticipation in me grows
l can feel your dark eyes
Touch me in the darkness
Understand
the message never sent
Sometimes l
understand it very clearly
Heartbeat, heartbeat
Listen to my heartbeat
Heartbeat
Heartbeat, heartbeat
Listen to my heartbeat
Heartbeat
Heartbeat, heartbeat
Listen to my heartbeat
Heartbeat
Heartbeat, heartbeat
Listen to my heartbeat