We should've talked at the boatyard.
You don't wanna talk about it here.
I'm not falling all over myself to
talk about it much of anywhere, Jack.
How much do you know?
Not much.
The Birmingham one was in
the papers over a month ago.
The second one in Atlanta
was all over TV.
Did you ever think
about giving me a call?
- No.
- Why not?
I quit. Remember?
You look all right now.
I am all right.
If you can't look
anymore, I understand.
Don't try to run
a game down on me, Jack.
If I really didn't need you
to come back, I wouldn't ask.
This guy's on a lunar cycle.
I have three weeks and a few
days until the next full moon.
We have a better chance
to get him fast if you help.
I'll think about it.
Stay and eat.
Hi, Molly.
Think it'll keep them out, Dad?
Yep.
How many turtle eggs
do you think are in here?
In this hatchery?
I'll bet there's
40 or 50 of them.
Crabs get most
of the newborns, huh?
Yeah, but not now.
These are all gonna
make it, guaranteed.
What about the dogs?
- Are they gonna get in here?
- They can't dig under.
That's why we bury
the wire down in the sand.
We need more staples, pal.
You're supposed
to be his friend, Jack.
Why didn't you leave him alone?
If he decides to do it, Molly,
I'll keep him as far
away from it as I can.
We got it pretty good, don't we?
We have it more than good.
All that happened to you
before lets you know that.
If I went back,
I'd only look at evidence.
I wouldn't get deeply involved.
He'd never even
see me or know my name.
If they find him,
they'll have to take him down, not me.
What do you think?
I think you've already decided
and you're not really asking.
If I were asking?
Stay here with me, me and Kevin.
But it's selfish, and I know it.
Come here.
OFFICER: I'll come inside with you,
if you want, to show you around.
Mr. Crawford said maybe
you'd want to be alone, but...
That's right.
There's a VCR hooked up
in your hotel room.
They transferred some home movies
of both families onto half-inch VHS.
Thanks.
Intruder entered through
kitchen sliding door.
Used a glass cutter
anchored to a suction cup.
His entry was skillful.
All the prints
are smooth gloves.
Blond hair, strong,
size 12 shoe imprint.
Blood AB positive, typed from saliva
on glass from licking the suction cup.
Why didn't he care that
he left saliva on the glass?
It was hot out that night,
so inside the house
must have felt cool to him.
Intruder cut Charles Leeds'
throat as he was rising,
then shot Mrs. Leeds.
Bullet entered right of her navel
and lodged in her lumbar spine,
but she died of strangulation.
Moderate elevation of
serotonin and marked increase
of free histamine level
in gunshot wound
indicates she lived at least
five minutes after she was shot.
All her other injuries
were post-mortem.
Direction and velocity of bloodstains
on east wall indicate arterial spray.
Even with his throat cut,
Leeds tried to fight
because the intruder was
moving to the children's room.
Bloodstains on west wall
of master bedroom
and matted sliding marks on
hall carpet remain unexplained,
as does superficial ligature
mark around Mr. Leeds' chest,
also believed to be post-mortem.
What did the killer do with
them after they were dead?
(PHONE RINGING)
VALERIE ON ANSWERING MACHINE:
Hi, this is Valerie Leeds.
Sorry, I can't come
to the phone right now,
but if you'd like to leave a
message please do so after the beep,
and I'll call you back
as soon as I can.
(ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS)
(DIAL TONE SOUNDING)
Mrs. Leeds' injuries were post-mortem,
four or five minutes later.
What did he do in the interval?
(SIGHS)
The smeared bloodstains
on the west wall...
(SIGHS)
(PHONE RINGING)
- Hello?
- WILL: Molly?
- MOLLY: Will, is that you?
- Yeah, it's me, honey.
Look, I'll call you tomorrow.
Go back to sleep.
I love you.
I love you too, baby.
What are you dreaming?
That's something you can't afford
for me to know about, isn't it?
God, she's lovely, isn't she?
It was maddening to have to touch
her with rubber gloves on, wasn't it?
They found talcum
powder on her leg,
but there wasn't any talcum
powder in the bathroom.
The talcum powder came
out of a rubber glove
as you pulled
it off to touch her.
You took off your gloves
to touch her, didn't you?
Didn't you, you son of a bitch?
You touched her
with your bare hands,
and then you put
your gloves back on.
But while your gloves were off,
did you open all their eyes
so that they could see you?
JACK: Hello?
Jack, this is Graham.
Is Price still in Latent Prints?
Yeah, he's in charge
of the Single Print Index now.
What do you got, Will?
Get him to Atlanta.
Atlanta PD swears
they dusted everything,
and their guy is pretty good.
He is good.
He's not as good as Price.
I'll get him on a plane
in the morning.
What do you want him to do?
Dust Mrs. Leeds' finger and toenails
and the corneas of all their eyes.
I think he took off his gloves.
Our people swear he wore
surgeon's gloves the whole time.
They dusted everything.
Your report didn't mention eyes.
Why do you think
he took his gloves off?
WILL: Because Mrs. Leeds
was a beautiful woman.
All right, all right.
Settle down, now.
Sit down, please.
After-house interviews Will be
extended an additional four blocks.
RNI's loaned us a couple of clerks
to cross-match
the airline reservations
between Birmingham last month
and Atlanta now.
Dr. Princi.
This is what the subject's
teeth looked like.
The Smithsonian in Washington
reconstructed these
from the impressions that
we took of the bite marks
on the Leeds woman here
and the Jacobi woman
in Birmingham last month.
As you can see, he has
pegged lateral incisors,
that's these teeth
here and here.
All right.
Investigator Graham, you've worked
this kind of thing before.
Can you add anything?
Could you come up to the front?
I don't think he's a drifter,
acting upon victims of opportunity.
Skillful entry indicates
premeditation and planning.
Therefore, I believe
he's an organized individual
who probably lives life competently
with little or no leakage.
Meaning in appearance
he could be absolutely anyone?
That's right.
Bodies being arranged
into an audience and the mirrors
make me believe that there's a rich
and intense fantasy life
going on here.
The elevated experience
is the fantasy.
The act fuels the fantasy.
To discover what he thinks
he's doing in there,
why he picked who he picked,
did what he did,
to understand his motive,
you have to know his illusions,
his dreams.
Which are?
I don't know.
What else do you have for us?
That's all I have.
SPRINGFIELD: All right, Vice and Narcotics,
you take the K-Y cowboys
and leather bars.
Marcus, Whitman,
heads up at the funeral.
The rest of your assignments
are on the sheet. Let's go.
One more thing.
I've heard officers referring to
this killer as the Tooth Fairy.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Well, I don't want
to hear that in public,
and I don't want to see it in
internal memoranda. That's it.
(OFFICERS CHATTERING)
I know a burglar's
gonna fence what he stole
'cause his motive is cash money.
I know his motive,
so I go to work on fences.
This guy, we don't
even have motive.
None of us have shit,
and we know it.
WILL: It's in his dreams.
-His motive?
-WILL: Yeah.
The commissioner was saying
that you're the one
who got Garrett Jacob Hobbs,
and then Dr. Lecter
three years ago.
Lecter killed nine
people, didn't he?
Nine that we know of.
Two didn't die.
What happened to them?
One's on a respirator
at a hospital in Baltimore,
the other's in a private
mental hospital in Denver.
What did the psychologists
say was wrong with Lecter?
(SNICKERS)
The psychologists
call him a psychopath.
They don't know
what else to call him.
I understand he cut
you pretty good.
What about the dog?
It's at the vet's. The kids brought it
in with a puncture wound in the abdomen.
The Jacobis in Birmingham
had a cat, didn't they?
That's right.
We found a litter box downstairs,
but we didn't find a cat.
Why don't you get Birmingham PD a
methane probe out of Washington,
have them cover the back yard.
Maybe the cat's dead
and the kids buried it.
(PHONE RINGING)
SPRINGFIELD: Yeah?
OVER PHONE:
This is Jimmy Price, FBI.
- Let me put you on speakerphone.
- Who am I talking to?
Jimmy, it's Jack Crawford.
You got Will Graham here, too.
I got a partial print with a tented
arch, it's probably a thumb.
And the fragment of a palm off the
nail of Mrs. Leeds' left big toe.
Thumbprint came off
the oldest kid's left eye.
It stood out against
an eight-ball hemorrhage
from the gunshot wound.
Can we make an
identification off of it?
Maybe, if he's ever been
printed and he's in my index.
I want to work these up
in my own darkroom.
I'll fax the prints
down to you this afternoon.
Thanks, Jimmy.
(REPORTERS CHATTERING)
No comment.
JACK: If we get lucky
with that print, we're in,
if Jimmy can find him in the index
and if he's ever been printed.
-Hey, Will Graham!
-If not, I don't know.
Whadda ya hear? Whadda ya say?
You remember me?
Freddie Lounds,
covered the Lecter case for the Tattler,
did the paperback.
So, come on, Will,
when did they call you in?
What do you got? Hey, look,
I'm buying lunch, all right?
Lounds, why don't
you give it a rest?
Hey, he's news.
I'm doing my job.
So, how does this guy compare with Lecter?
How does he do them?
How's he do them, Will?
(GROANS)
Keep the fuck away from me.
JACK: Will, Will.
Son of a bitch snuck into the hospital
while I was sedated after Lecter.
He pulled back the sheets,
and he took pictures.
Yeah, I know.
Look, don't expect too much from
me, all right?
We only got three weeks left,
and you're our best shot.
You think I'm gonna see him standing
in the street and say, "There he is"?
That's Houdini
you're thinking about.
The Tooth Fairy's gonna go on
until we get smart or get lucky.
- He won't stop.
- Why?
He's got a genuine taste for it.
You do know something about him.
Not enough.
I think I'll go see
Lecter tomorrow.
Why?
Recover the mindset.
- Yeah?
- Hey, hotshot.
- You doing some good?
- Nothing you'd notice.
- I miss ya.
- Me too.
I miss my husband.
What's going on?
Day-to-day is boring.
Tell me what you're doing.
I'm eatin' room service.
They don't have a lock on anything,
Molly.
There's not enough
physical evidence,
or else I haven't done enough
with it yet.
Were you gonna be in Atlanta long?
I mean, you know, I'm not
bugging you about coming home,
but I was just wondering.
I don't know.
I gotta go to Baltimore tomorrow.
To do what?
Uh, I got to see somebody.
I was thinking about, um,
painting the kitchen.
What color do you like?
Will, are you there?
Uh, I don't know, paint it --
let's paint it yellow.
Yellow's kind of a bad color for me.
I'll look green at breakfast.
- Blue, then.
- I don't know about blue.
Look, paint the damn room
battleship Grey, what do I care?
I'm sorry.
Look, when I get back,
we'll go to the paint store together,
and we'll get some chips,
and we'll figure out...
Look, Will, I don't know why
I'm talking trivia.
I called to tell you that I love you
and I miss you.
And I'm --
you're doing the right thing.
And it's costing you, too,
I know that.
I'm here.
I'm right here, and I'll be here
whenever you come home.
I'll meet you if you need me to...
Anywhere.
Anytime.
That's what I called to tell you.
Molly...
I love you.
Goodnight.
That's the same atrocious aftershave
you wore in court three years ago.
Yeah, I keep
getting it for Christmas.
Did you get my card?
I got it. Thank you.
How is Officer Stewart?
The one who was first to see my basement.
Stewart's fine.
Emotional problems, I hear.
Do you have any problems, Will?
No.
No, of course you don't.
(SNICKERS)
I'm glad you came.
My callers are mostly
clinical psychologists
from cornfield
universities somewhere.
Second-raters, the lot.
Dr. Bloom showed me your
article on surgical addiction
in the Journal
of Clinical Psychiatry.
- And?
- Very interesting.
-Even to a layman.
-Layman?
A layman?
An interesting term.
So many experts
on government grants.
And you say, you're a layman?
But it was you who caught me,
wasn't it, Will?
- Do you know how you did it?
- What does it matter now?
It doesn't matter to me, Will.
I want you to help me,
Dr. Lecter.
Yes, I thought so.
It's about Atlanta
and Birmingham.
Yes?
- You read about it?
- In the papers.
I don't tear out the articles.
I wouldn't want them to think I
was dwelling on anything morbid.
You want to know how he's choosing
them, don't you?
- I thought you might have some ideas.
- Why should I tell you?
You'd get to see
the file on this case.
- And there's another reason.
- Pray tell.
Thought you might
be curious to see
if you're smarter than the
person I'm looking for.
Then by implication you think you're
smarter than me, since you caught me.
No. I know that
I'm not smarter than you.
- Then how did you catch me?
- You had disadvantages.
What disadvantages?
You're insane.
You are very tan, Will.
Your hands are rough.
They don't look like
cop's hands anymore.
And that shaving lotion is
something a child would select.
It has a ship on the
bottle, doesn't it?
Don't think you can persuade me with
appeals to my intellectual vanity.
I don't think
I'll persuade you at all.
You'll either
do it or you won't.
Besides, we have Dr. Bloom working on
it, and he's the best.
-Do you have the file with you?
-Yes.
-Pictures?
Let me have them,
and I might consider it.
No.
Dream much, Will?
Goodbye, Dr. Lecter.
You haven't threatened
to take away my books yet.
Let me have the file,
and I'll tell you what I think.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(PAGES FLIPPING)
This is a very shy boy, Will.
What were their yards like?
Big back yards. Fences, hedges.
Why?
Because, my dear Will,
if this pilgrim imagines he has
a relationship with the moon,
he might go outside
to look at it.
Have you ever seen
blood in the moonlight?
It appears quite black.
If one were nude, it would be better
to have privacy for this sort of thing.
That's interesting.
No, it's not.
You thought of it before.
I considered it.
You came here to look at me, to get
the old scent back again, didn't you?
I want your opinion.
I don't have one right now.
Well, when you have one,
I'd like to hear it.
- Can I keep this?
- I haven't decided yet.
I'll study them.
When you get more files,
I'd like to see them, too.
You can call me.
When I have to call my lawyer,
they bring me a telephone.
Would you like to leave me
your home phone number?
No.
Do you know how you caught me?
Goodbye, Dr. Lecter. You can leave
messages for me at the number on the file.
Lecter: Do you know
how you caught me?
The reason you caught me,
Will, is we're just alike.
Do you understand?
Smell yourself.
(PANTING)
(CLICKING)
Gotcha.
WOMAN ON PA:217
now boarding at Gate 12.
Eastern Airlines Flight 217 is
now ready for boarding at Gate 12.
Get up against the bunk
and face the wall.
Don't turn around,
or I'll Mace you in the face.
Thank you so much.
I'll call you when I'm finished.
FEMALE OPERATOR:
Are you ready for your call?
Yes, thank you.
(PHONE RINGING)
WOMAN 1: Paltrow,
Christiansen & Golub, Law Offices.
Excuse me.
I must have misdialed.
(PHONE RINGING)
MALE OPERATOR: Thank you for using AT&T.
This is Operator 24.
Operator, I don't
have the use of my arms.
Would you be so kind as to
dial a number for me, please?
Certainly. What's the number?
Area code 301, 555-6624.
(PHONE DIALING)
WOMAN 2: The University of
Chicago, Department of Psychiatry.
Dr. Sidney Bloom, please.
He's not in,
but I'll connect you to his office.
What's his secretary's
name again?
Martha King.
Just a moment, please.
- WOMAN 3: Martha King's desk.
- Hi, Martha.
Martha doesn't come in nights.
Maybe you can help me.
This is Bob Greer of Blaine
& Edwards publishing company,
Dr. Bloom asked me
to send a copy
of The Psychiatrist
and the Law to someone.
Martha never sent me
the address and phone number.
She'll be in in the morning.
Well, I've got to catch Federal
Express in about five minutes.
I'd be immensely appreciative if you
could pull it out of her Rolodex for me.
I don't see a Rolodex.
I'll bet she has a call caddy
right next to her phone.
Yeah...
Well, zip that little pointer
right on down to the letter G.
All right.
The name we're looking for,
last name Graham,
the man the book is
supposed to be sent to,
a Mr. Will Graham.
Federal Bureau of Investigation,
10th and Pennsylvania, Washington, D.C.
Now, I'll bet it has his
home address there, too.
3680 DeSoto Highway,
Captiva, Florida.
Thank you so very much.
(TAPPING)
I've finished.
(PASSENGERS CHATTERING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Mom! Oh, my gosh.
It's all right. Stewardess!
CAPTAIN ON PA SYSTEM:
Ladies and gentlemen,
we are beginning our descent
into Birmingham.
Yeah, this couple come down
from Duluth.
We was talking them down
the short-term mortgages.
And I'm figuring, "gee, Andy,
you're gonna unload this Turkey."
Well, and a squad car rolls up,
and they start asking questions.
Then the good old boys
give 'em the whole grand tour --
who was lying where, and what.
Terrific.
So, they get in their sedan Deville
and get the hell out of here.
Any single men
ask to see the house?
Haven't asked me.
WILL: You used a cutting tool on
the branch so that you could see.
Then you passed the time
whittling and dreaming.
When night came,
you saw them pass by their bright windows.
Then you watched
the shades go down,
then you saw the lights
go out, one by one.
Then after a while,
you climbed down
and you went in to them,
didn't you?
Didn't you, you son of a bitch?
You watched them
all goddamned day long!
That's why houses
with big yards.
WILL: I need Firearms and Tool Marks
section out here on a severed branch.
I need to know what kind
of cutting tool he used.
And then I need Bowman in
Documents to fall on this carving.
- JACK: Is it weird?
- The mark? Yeah.
If Documents can't do the carving,
I'll send it up to Langley.
WILL: Did Price get an
identification off the Leeds print?
No, Price hasn't found
him in the index yet.
It's a hand search.
He's got half his department on it.
Listen, have you seen
this week's Tattler?
It's not on my preferred reading list,
Jack.
(SCOFFS) It's not on my
preferred reading list.
Yeah, well, uh, your picture's
all over the front page.
Who the hell was it? Lounds?
Of course. Who else?
God damn it, Jack!
I promised Molly!
I promised her!
Come in.
- GUARD: Dr. Chilton?
- Yes?
When we were cleaning
out Dr. Lecter's cell,
he heard us coming and
hid something in a book.
We got him out of
there and dug around.
-Is that it?
-Yes.
Put it down on my desk, Bonner.
Has anyone else
seen this except you?
No.
SECRETARY: Special Agent
Crawford's office.
This is Dr. Chilton.
I need to speak to Mr. Graham right away.
He's not here,
he's in Birmingham.
Special Agent Crawford
is on the line with him now.
Please tell them
this is very, very urgent.
I'll hold on.
Dr. Chilton, it's Jack Crawford.
You have Will Graham
on the line, too.
CHILTON: I have a note,
or two pieces of a note
that appears to be from that man
who killed those people in Atlanta.
Dr. Chilton, where did you get it?
In Hannibal Lecter's cell.
It was hidden in a book.
WILL: Dr. Chilton, don't touch the note.
Can you read it to us?
It's written on toilet tissue.
"My dear Dr. Lecter,
"I wanted to tell you I'm
delighted that you've
taken an interest in me.
"I know that you alone can
understand what I am becoming.
"You alone know the people I
use to help me in these things
"are only elements
undergoing change
"to fuel the radiance
of what I am becoming,
"just as the source
of light is burning.
"I have a collection
of your press clippings.
"I think they are absurd,
as are mine.
"'The Tooth Fairy,' what
could be more inappropriate?
"Investigator Graham
interests me,
"very purposeful-looking.
"I hope we can correspond."
Mr. Graham,
there's a piece missing here.
Now I'll read the bottom part.
"After I hear back from you,
"I might send
you something wet."
Signed "Avid Fan."
It has teeth marks pressed
into it at the bottom.
Sarah, order a chopper, next thing smoking.
I don't care whose it is.
Two, call Alabama
Air National Guard,
and tell 'em to get Graham
back here right now.
Then call Documents and tell
them to scramble a team.
I want everybody moving five minutes ago.
You understand?
JACK: I have a Documents team on its way
to you by helicopter to pick up the note.
Listen, after we've
worked the note,
I want to replace
it in Lecter's cell.
I don't want Lecter to know
that we've found it,
he might try to warn
the killer somehow.
- Where's Lecter now?
- CHILTON: Holding cell.
How long can you keep him in there
without him getting suspicious?
CHILTON: Three, four hours.
Brian, we have a note
coming in on the flight,
possibly from the Tooth Fairy,
number one priority.
It has to go to Hair and Fiber,
Latent Prints, and then Documents.
Will Graham and I
will be walking it through.
One hair, Graham.
Maybe half an inch.
- And a couple of blue grains.
- Work the hair.
What do we have
for negative comparison?
Hair from Lecter's comb, whiskers
from Lecter's razor they let him use.
This is hair from
the security guard.
MAN: How many guys
handled this without gloves?
The guard, cleanup man, Lecter.
The cleanup man scrubbing sinks
probably had the oil
washed off his fingers.
But the others... One smudge.
Those aren't ridges.
It's just the texture of the paper.
I can fume for a print,
but can't guarantee the
iodine stains would fade out.
- Ninhydrin? Boost it with heat?
- No.
We couldn't wash it after.
I can't get a print off this in the
time you've got to get it back, Will.
- BOWMAN: How long do I have?
- JACK: Twenty minutes, max.
BOWMAN: The main thing
to find out is,
how was Lecter supposed
to reply to him?
Which is probably the missing
section, because at the top it says,
"I hope we can correspond,"
then comes the gap.
This note was written in
ballpoint, but it looks like
Lecter went over this
area with a felt-tip pen,
then tore it away.
You're so sly, but so am I.
The aniline dyes used in
the ink of the felt-tip
pens like Lecter used are
transparent to infrared.
The Tooth Fairy's
ballpoint isn't.
This looks like the tip
of a T here, here, and here.
At the end is what
could be the top of an R.
There's three Ts
and an R in "Tattler."
We know our boy reads it.
The article about me and Lecter.
I don't know anybody else
that's carried that.
Personal ads.
We believe the Tooth Fairy
told Lecter to reply to him
through the personal ad section
of the National Tattler.
The Chicago office is down there
right now running through their ads.
We have cut into
a line of communication
between the Tooth Fairy
and Lecter.
If we find Lecter's
reply we plan to pull it,
substitute it
with one of our own.
And this is what the Tooth
Fairy Will read. Bill?
"Dear Avid Fan, inherit my mantle
and surpass my achievements.
"Mementos for you at Baltimore
Central Left Luggage.
"Ticket number 72683."
It's a Secret Service letter drop.
We plan to stake it out.
When he shows, we'll grab him.
Anything from Chicago?
SARAH: Not yet.
When do they go to press?
JACK: Thirty-five minutes.
Christ.
Let's get to the physical.
There was no print.
Scale counts
and core size of the hair
match the blond hair
found in the Jacobis'.
That note was written
by your man.
Aside from the hair, three blue grains,
dark flecks, went to Brian's end.
The grains are commercial
granulated cleanser with chlorine,
from the cleaning man.
Several particles of dried
blood, but not enough to type.
(PHONE RINGING)
OVER PHONE: This is Chester.
Who am I talking to?
Will Graham, Jack Crawford.
Got a personal ad with "Avid Fan" in
it being telexed to you right now.
Read it. "Dear Avid Fan,
"You honor me.
You're very beautiful."
JACK: Oh, Christ.
"I offer 100 prayers
for your safety.
"Find help in Galatians
6: 11, 15:2,
"Acts 3:3, Revelations 18:7,
"Jonah 6:8, John 6:22,
"Luke 1:7."
JACK: Thanks.
Jimmy. Did you get anywhere at all
identifying him off the Leeds' prints?
Not yet.
Photography at Langley?
They got shot a telex.
They're on it now.
No. And our ad has to go out in
the same book code Lecter used,
or he'll know it wasn't
Lecter talking to him.
Book code?
"100 prayers" could be the page
number, the paired numbers could
be line and letter.
But what book?
-JACK: Not the Bible?
-No.
Galatians 15:2. Galatians only has
six chapters. The same with Jonah 6:8.
Jonah only has four chapters.
Lecter was not using the Bible.
Then the Tooth Fairy probably named
the book in the part Lecter tore out.
Right.
What about sweating Lecter?
They tried sodium amytal
on him three years ago
to find where he buried
a Princeton student.
He gave them a recipe
for potato chip dip.
JACK: Wonderful.
The Tooth Fairy would have named a
book he knew Lecter has access to.
He'd know it from articles
he'd read about Lecter.
JACK: Willingham,
when he tossed his cell,
took Polaroids so they can
get everything back in place.
Have him meet me with
pictures of Lecter's books.
JACK: Where?
BOWMAN: Library of Congress.
Twenty-five minutes.
He won't make it in time.
Lecter's ad runs as is,
we decode it later.
Or we pull it, figure out the
code and run our own ad next week.
And lose a week?
We got 17 days till the next full moon.
And I don't like Lecter's ad
running without knowing what it says.
It's your call, Will.
Run it.
And what if it encourages the Tooth
Fairy to do something else beside write?
We'll all feel sick
for a very long time.
JACK: And if Bowman
still can't figure it out?
Then we'll bait him with something
else in next week's Tattler.
JACK: What, for instance?
Me.
I don't think
that's a very good idea.
Why not?
Don't you think we can provoke him?
Maybe. Maybe he can be provoked.
What I was thinking
about is you.
You're getting deeper
and deeper into this.
Good night.
Sidney.
I'll talk to you.
Last time you did that you did a real good
job of pushing yourself all out of shape.
You try it on again or you
go through some big trauma,
you could relapse, my friend.
Sidney, don't worry about me.
I'm working the evidence,
making moves. That's all.
I'm fine.
Bowman just struck out.
- It is not books in Lecter's cell.
- Price?
He just heard. It's a bust-out.
As evidence, the Leeds print
will get us a conviction
if we could ever find the guy.
But he must never have been printed
because he is not in our index.
We are not gonna
identify him off the print.
I'll use Lounds.
What for?
Our boy doesn't read the New
York Times literary supplement.
He reads Lounds in the Tattler.
What else should we cover?
He put the shorts on Charles
Leeds after he was dead.
I believe he did this to make
sure we wouldn't think he was gay.
He's molested
all of his male victims.
He may be impotent with
members of the opposite sex.
Our forensic psychologists
have projected,
though I'm not sure,
that he may have had sexual
relations with his mother.
(LAUGHS)
So, how long do you plan
to stay in Washington?
Till we've taken
out the Tooth Fairy.
LOUNDS: Can the Tattler rely on
getting the straight stuff from you?
Absolutely.
How does working on this case
affect your sex life?
Mine? It doesn't affect mine,
it affects yours. Go fuck yourself.
- Look, pal of mine, you're news.
- Shoot the pictures.
All right, Stymie,
let's shoot them.
I'm in the shots with Graham.
-What?
-I'm in the shots with you.
Come on, you want this
to look real or not?
Make sure the theater sign across the
street is just slightly out of focus.
We want him to be able
to read it so he can find it,
but we don't want
to look too obvious.
-You make sure that I look excellent.
-All right, shoot it.
One more.
-One more.
-That's enough.
Okay, Graham.
Hey, always nice, huh?
Let's have lunch,
call my service.
Crawford, always a thrill.
Dr. Bloom. I need them
on my desk in two hours.
- Did Bowman break the code yet?
- No.
Tools and Firearms say
the cutting tool used on
the severed branch was
a common bolt cutter.
I got a call from
Asian Studies at Langley.
The mark you found on the tree?
Yeah?
It's a Chinese character considered
a lucky sign in gambling.
That same character appears
on a Mah Jongg piece.
It means "Red Dragon."
Mean anything to you?
No.
I'm having the bureau
fly Molly up tonight.
-Huh?
-Well, she said she can get away for one night.
I do something wrong?
No.
No, it's just the setting, Jack.
- Hm.
- Thanks.
If he shows, and he's smart,
he'll approach you
from the front, pass, turn,
try and take you from behind.
- How's your hearing?
- It's good.
You'll wear a wire, one-way.
We'll hear you,
you won't hear us.
You checked out a Charter
Arms .44 Special Bulldog?
Yeah.
Load these in it.
You ever fire them?
- Glaser Safety Slugs.
- Yeah. Number 12 shots.
Suspended in liquid Teflon
in a copper casing.
On impact it all
opens up in the target.
Guaranteed one-shot stop.
- You got body armor?
- Yeah, Kevlar Second Chance.
I hope you get one.
'Cause he's gone for the head
shot eight of eleven times?
Let's walk the route.
WOMAN ON PA: United Flight 849 to
Newark now boarding at Gate 7...
United Flight 849 to Newark
now boarding at Gate 7.
You didn't cancel the food.
So, where are things?
We got nine days left.
We're working on it, doing stuff.
You don't want to talk about
what you're doing, do you?
Hotel rooms...
Illicit romance.
We have to stop meeting like this.
Remember the first time we met?
Yeah.
When we were alone together
in that room.
Even though
I'd never seen you before,
we were sitting there, speaking.
And something flickered
across your face like a shadow.
I said, "what's that?"
Mm-hmm.
Remember what you said?
I said, "this is too good to live."
Time is luck, Will.
I know the value of every single day.
Someone's coming.
(GRUNTS)
Go!
Don't! Don't move!
Take the money!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
- Clear!
What you moving in slow motion for, man?
I'm being mugged!
For real. Can you believe that?
- Pay up.
- RADIO ANNOUNCER: in sports, the Cubs lost again.
Hey!
(MUFFLED SCREAM)
(BREAKING)
You know who I am?
Mm-hm. I don't want to know
who you are.
According to you,
I'm a sexual pervert.
"An animal," you said.
You know who I am now?
Yes.
Do you feel privileged?
I'm very scared.
Open your eyes.
Mr. Lounds, you're a reporter.
Your job is to report.
That's why you're here.
And if you don't open your eyes,
I'll staple your eyelids
to your forehead.
Well, here I am.
(PROJECTOR WHIRRING)
Look at the screen.
William Blake's
The Great Red Dragon
and the Woman Clothed
In The Rays Of The Sun.
-Do you see?
-Yes.
Mrs. Leeds. Do you see?
Yes.
Mrs. Jacobi. Do you see?
The next family as they Will
look when I go to visit them.
-Do you see?
-Yes.
Freddie Lounds, your photograph.
- No.
- No what?
Not me, please.
- Please.
- Are you a man?
Yes.
Do you imply that I'm queer?
God, no.
Before me,
you are a slug in the sun.
You are privy to a great becoming,
and you recognize nothing.
You are an ant
in the afterbirth.
It is your nature to do one
thing correctly, tremble.
But fear is not what you owe me.
No, Lounds, you and the others,
you owe me awe.
We have one more
piece of work to do.
If he takes off the mask,
I am a dead man.
Open your eyes.
Open your eyes!
You Will read this
into the tape recorder.
Go.
"I have had a great privilege.
"I have seen with wonder and awe
the strength of the Red Dragon.
"All I wrote
about him were lies.
"Will Graham made me write them
"to pull him into a trap in
Washington, District of Columbia.
"Will Graham,
you Will learn from my own lips
"how much you have to dread
because I was forced to lie.
"He Will be more merciful
to me than to you.
"You Will lie awake in fear of
what the Red Dragon Will do.
"I Will be a testament
to the truth of this."
(SHUDDERING)
You did very well.
Will you let me go now?
Please?
You will tell the truth?
I promise.
Good.
We'll seal your promise with...
We'll seal your promise
with a kiss.
(LOUNDS SCREAMING)
MAN ON RADIO: We'll be showing
five possible answers
to the questions I'll be asking.
Any member of a team
may buzz in an answer,
but if incorrect, then the other
team will have the opportunity...
to answer that very same question.
The team with the most points
at the end of three rounds
will compete and win...
will also compete in the right
to enter diamondhead
in our fourth and final round.
Uh, questions in round number one
are gonna be worth 10 points each.
(SQUEAKING)
Okay, that means
the round is all over.
So, Jane we're all ready.
Help us with round one.
All right, Bob, the first
category today is the far east.
And the choices are Vietnam,
Japan, Laos, Thailand, and China.
(FIRE ROARING)
(WHEELCHAIR SQUEAKING)
(SCREAMING)
Bowman, just skip the cryptography and
tell me what the hell it says, okay?
- Did he try to say anything at all?
- No, he sure didn't.
He never regained consciousness.
- Did you hear the tape?
- Yeah.
Listen, Bowman just broke the code that
Lecter used in the Tattler personal ad.
It was the State
of Maryland statutes.
You need to know
what it said right now.
- What?
- Listen to me.
Everything is okay.
I've taken care of it.
What is it, Jack?
The bastard gave him
your home address.
It said, "Graham home,
3860 DeSoto Highway,
"Captiva, Florida.
"Save yourself. Kill them all."
- Get me a plane.
- Will!
Will.
Mom.
Huh?
What time... What?
Someone's outside.
There are noises.
- Where?
- Outside.
Mom...
(WHISPERING) Mom...
Go back to your room
and close the door.
- Mom...
- Do it, now.
Ma'am, are you all right?
What? What is it?
What is it? What's going on?
OFFICER: Ma'am, I think
you should come back inside.
What's going on?
Come back inside.
Please. I think
you should come back inside.
I'm sorry, Molly.
I'm sorry about all of this.
This place is fine.
We'll be fine.
He's after you now, isn't he?
This is just a precaution.
Kevin, why don't you run down to the
water, check out the dock?
I want to hang around here.
- I'm in the kitchen, Mom.
- Okay.
What is that about?
What, he's afraid to leave
you alone with me now?
He saw the article
in the Tattler, right?
I wanted to talk
with him about it,
but he said he wanted to bring
it up to you, face to face.
Good for him.
Kevin, help me unpack, Will you?
Then we'll go
get some groceries.
You and Mom are very
well-protected, you know.
No one's gonna find
out where you are.
KEVIN: Is there anything I
need to know to see about Mom?
No.
KEVIN: This guy
is trying to kill us?
We don't know that.
When are you going to kill him?
I'm not.
It's only my job to find him.
Barry's mom had this newspaper.
It said you were
in a special hospital.
Well, it was a regular hospital,
then I was transferred
into the psychiatric wing.
That bothers you, doesn't it?
I don't know.
Was it because in the papers it
said it was this man Lecter?
Mmm-hmm.
What happened?
Well, Lecter was attacking college
girls, then he killed them.
How?
In bad ways.
He was a psychiatrist.
One of the girls was his patient,
and I went to talk to him about her.
I tried to build feelings in my
imagination like the killer had
so that I would know
why he did what he did,
because that would
help me find him.
When I was sitting in Lecter's office and
I looked up, I saw a book on his shelf.
It had pictures of
war wounds in it.
And I knew it was him.
So I went to a pay phone down
the hall to call the police
and that's when he attacked me.
You and Mom came to see me in the
hospital, and that helped a lot.
But after my body got okay,
I still had his thoughts
going around in my head.
And I stopped talking to people.
And a doctor friend of mine, a Dr. Bloom,
asked me to get some help. And I did.
Then after a while I felt
better, and I was okay again.
And the way
he thought felt that bad?
Kevin,
they're the ugliest
thoughts in the world.
So, what kind of
coffee do you like?
Huh?
You like that
Folgers stuff, right?
Yeah.
Mom likes that, too.
When can we go home, Dad?
I don't know, Kevin.
So, where are things?
Nowhere.
Everything we've tried is either
a dead end or it's backfired.
Crawford's already planning the next
crime scene so they can get it fresh.
We've got about six more days
till the next full moon.
Can you quit?
No.
What's next?
- I go to Atlanta.
- Crawford?
No.
I have to be alone.
You're talking about doing
exactly what you said you...
This killing, it's gotta stop.
William, you're gonna make yourself sick.
Or get yourself killed.
You and Kevin
should go to Montana.
See your dad.
He hasn't seen
Kevin for a long time.
And I'll come up
and get you afterwards.
(WOMAN CHATTERING ON PA SYSTEM)
VALERIE ON ANSWERING MACHINE:
Hi, this is Valerie Leeds.
Sorry I can't come
to the phone right now.
- I'm sorry, too.
- WAITRESS: Excuse me.
Coffee.
It's just you and me now, sport.
I'm gonna find you, God damn it.
- Mr. Dollarhyde?
- Eileen.
Bill told me to tell you
there was a variation
in the gamma of number three.
But he caught it in time.
Eileen,
good. Good.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
- REBA: Who's there?
- Mr. Dollarhyde.
I came about the low-light
infrared emulsion.
REBA: Oh, yeah.
Come on in, it's safe.
Put your back against the door.
There's a stool
just to your right.
You're the production
controller from Admin, right?
Can you give me an idea
of the conditions?
Um, shooting from maybe eight feet.
- I can't use any lights. Mm-hm.
Okay, what's being photographed?
The activities
of nocturnal animals.
When do you need it?
Four days.
Okay, let me stick
this in the black hole.
1000-C infrared sensitive has
to be handled in total darkness.
Remember to be
very careful with it.
But still, it's easier to
handle than the 1200 series.
It'll be fine.
In case you're wondering,
I keep the samples
straight by touch code.
No, I wasn't wondering.
Reba, I gotta fly. Maybe Mr. Dollarhyde
can drive you home tonight.
No, that's okay.
I'll take care of myself.
- RALPH: I can change things around.
- No, thanks, go on.
Okay.
- No, I'll take you.
- No, thanks.
I'll order you 1200 feet
of 1000-C in the morning.
Ride with me.
Thanks, but I'll take the bus.
I do it all the time.
Ride with me.
It would be because
I would like you to.
Okay, sure.
Let me get my stuff on.
How did you come to Gateway?
Oh, they had to hire
the handicapped
to shape up their employment practices
to get this defense contract.
You worked out well.
Yeah, well, everybody they hired did.
You know, you speak very well.
Although you avoid
fricatives and sibilants.
At the Riker Institute
for the Blind,
I trained in therapy for speech-
and hearing-impaired children.
I'll probably
go back to it someday.
Mmm-hmm.
You know, if you don't
want to talk, that's okay.
But I hope you Will, because you're
very direct, and I like that,
and I like what you have to say.
May I touch your face?
I want to know whether
you're smiling or frowning.
I guess I...
I guess I want to know whether
I should be quiet or not.
Take my word for it.
I'm smiling.
I didn't mean to offend you.
On the way,
can I take you somewhere?
Where?
It would be my surprise.
Okay, sure.
- Are you apprehensive?
- No.
The very protective Mr. Dollarhyde
over there is watching us.
No, no, I want to.
In about two hours
we're going to cap his tooth.
REBA: Yeah.
DOCTOR: It's warm.
(HEART BEATING)
Back a little bit. There.
You hear it?
Yeah.
You rearrange the dead families
into an audience to see what you do.
You think that what you do will
make you into something different.
You are becoming.
What is it you think
you're becoming?
The answer is in the way
you use the mirrors.
What do the mirrors make
you dream you're becoming?
(PROJECTOR WHIRRING)
A little to your left.
Francis, that was
a great dinner. Thank you.
I made you a gin and tonic.
It's right in front of you.
What are you watching?
It's just a little homework.
(THIS BIG HUSH PLAYING)
(INHALES DEEPLY)
You're a sweet,
thoughtful man, D.
♪ Is there a fire in the sky? ♪
Your heart's loud.
♪ Is there a moon up there? ♪
If you'll hold me...
♪ Is anything alive now? ♪
♪ This darkness is what I hear ♪
♪ This is a breathless silence ♪
♪ A moment out of time ♪
♪ I see your face in the shadows ♪
♪ The tell-tale signs
are in your eyes ♪
♪ Aching with a passion inside ♪
♪ Deep as the river ♪
♪ All desire ♪
♪ The ashes and the fire ♪
♪ Turning this night inside ♪
♪ And the light from you ♪
♪ Is there a flame in the dark? ♪
♪ Is there a bright heart star? ♪
♪ These creatures
look the same now ♪
♪ We freeze wherever we are ♪
♪ We wake alone in the blackness I
♪ we sleep wherever we fall ♪
♪ One dream all around us ♪
♪ This big hush infects us all ♪
♪ Forever in this half-light ♪
♪ All desire ♪
♪ The ashes and the fire ♪
♪ Turning this night inside ♪
(CRYING)
♪ And the light from you ♪
♪ All desire ♪
♪ The ashes and the fire ♪
♪ Turning this night inside ♪
♪ And the light from you ♪
REBA: Is that you, D?
DOLLARHYDE: Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
- Hi.
(DOLLARHYDE CHUCKLES)
- Good morning.
- Morning.
Well, you know, if you show me where
things are, I'll make us some coffee.
No, no, uh...
Don't go back inside the house.
Why? I left my purse inside.
I'll get it. It's okay.
♪ Deep as the river ♪
♪ All... ♪
I mean, you should stay
outside, it's... It's...
It's 'cause you look
so good in the sun.
(LAUGHING) Okay.
(SIGHS)
Um...
When, uh...
Reba, when can I see you again?
Oh! Um...
Hey, we could meet at my house.
JACK OVER PHONE: You got
the message Lecter called?
Yeah. I arranged
for him to have a phone.
I gotta call him
in a few minutes.
Good. Listen,
we identified the tire tracks left
when Lounds was delivered
back to the Tattler.
G-7816 Goodyear truck tires.
Looks like our boy drives a van.
I'm setting up our base in Chicago.
When are you coming back?
When I'm done, Jack.
(PHONE RINGING)
Yeah, this is Will
Graham of the FBI.
Dr. Chilton arranged for me
to talk to Dr. Lecter.
Hello?
Lecter: Hello, Will.
I wanted to congratulate you for
the job you did on Mr. Lounds.
I admire that enormously.
Oh, what a cunning boy
you are, Will.
I'm sick of you crazy
sons of bitches, Lecter.
You got something
to say, say it.
Lecter, I want to help you.
You'd be more comfortable
if you relax with yourself.
We don't invent our natures,
they're issued to us,
along with our lungs and
pancreas and everything else.
Why fight it?
Fight what?
Did you really feel so depressed
after you shot Mr. Garrett
Jacob Hobbs to death?
I didn't know you then,
but I think you probably did.
But it wasn't the act
that got you down, was it?
Didn't you really feel so bad
because killing him felt so good?
And why shouldn't it feel good?
It must feel good to God.
He does it all the time.
God's terrific.
He dropped a church roof
on 34 of his worshippers
last Wednesday night in Texas
as they were groveling
through a hymn to his majesty.
Don't you think that felt good?
Why does it feel good,
Dr. Lecter?
It feels good, Will,
because God has power.
And if one does what
God does enough times,
one will become as God is.
God's a champ.
He always stays ahead.
He got 140 Filipinos
in one plane crash last month.
Remember that earthquake
in Italy last spring?
WILL: I enter.
The glass cutter.
The piece of glass
I take out is mine.
The house is mine.
I walk up these stairs,
I pass the children's toys.
The children mean nothing to me.
They were put here to help me.
I move to the door.
I step into the room.
I see you there.
And I see me desired by you.
Accepted and loved
in the silver mirrors of your eyes.
(STRONG AS I AM PLAYING)
(CAR APPROACHING)
♪ Father, look in my eyes ♪
♪ See me as I really am ♪
♪ You made me ♪
♪ Now take me ♪
RALPH: I'm gonna talk
to Fogel tomorrow...
♪ Tell me how it feels now ♪
♪ Behold your flesh has come of age ♪
RALPH: Wait a minute.
♪ Forsake me, you break me ♪
♪ Strong as I am ♪
♪ There's something about this thing
that scares me ♪
♪ Strong as I am ♪
♪ There's something about this thing
that dares me ♪
♪ Strong as I am ♪
♪ There's something about this thing
that haunts me ♪
♪ Strong as I am ♪
♪ There's something about this thing
that taunts me ♪
♪ Mother, let me heal you ♪
♪ Your pain has lasted far too long ♪
♪ Release it, it kills you ♪
What was it?
Pollen. Oh.
-Thanks for the ride.
-See you tomorrow.
Yeah.
♪ The love you would not share
grows tired of waiting ♪
(GASPS)
Mr. Dollarhyde.
What are you doing here?
(GUN FIRING)
♪ Strong as I am ♪
♪ There's something about
this thing that scares me ♪
♪ Strong as I am ♪
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
- REBA: Who is it?
- DOLLARHYDE: It's me.
- Who? Who is it?
Oh.
Francis? No,
not Francis.
Francis is gone.
Francis is gone forever.
So, what are we doing?
The dream.
He dreams about
being wanted and desired,
so he changes people into
beings who want and desire him.
Changes?
It's a word.
Killing and arranging
the people to imitate it.
And Lecter told me something.
If one does what
God does enough times,
one will become as God is.
You put it together, you get,
if our boy imitates being
wanted and desired enough times,
he believes he will become one
who is wanted
and desired and accepted.
It'll all come true.
But he doesn't take anything.
There's no souvenirs
taken from the houses.
He needs souvenirs or
trophies to re-live the event.
Maybe he records it somehow.
So he could see himself accepted
over and over and over again.
VTRs, Polaroids, stills, what?
How do I know?
How does he find them?
When we find out how he found
them, we'll find him.
There is no connection
between the two families.
We've done a dozen
computer runs.
Jack, all the women
have a bloom on them.
He didn't win them in a
lottery, he picked these women.
There's selection
and design in his choices.
Look,
admit we struck out this month.
The Lear Jet is standing by,
the basic lab stuff is on it.
You, Zeller, Jimmy Price,
the photographer,
anywhere he hits,
we can be there in an hour and 15 minutes.
We get the call, we roll. The scene will
be fresh, fresher than we've ever had it.
-It's not over yet.
-For Christ's sake!
That's a foregone conclusion.
It's 11:30 p.m.,
the full moon is happening tonight.
Give it up! Forget this
month, it's too damn late!
I gave it up.
Till you showed up with
pictures of two dead families,
knowing goddamn well that I'd imagine
families three, four, five and six. Right?
You're fucking right I did,
and I'd do it again!
Great! But don't talk
to me about late, pal,
I'll tell you when
it's too fucking late!
Until then, we go as late
as I want to take it!
(WILL SIGHS)
A padlock.
That's why the bolt cutter.
What's that?
He used a bolt cutter
to trim away the branch
when he was watching
from the woods.
Why didn't he use the bolt
cutter on the garage door?
Because a deadbolt was there
when they were killed.
Donald Jacobi's 12th birthday
party was April 14th.
Sometime between April 14 and
August 1 they changed the lock.
But he thought there
was a padlock there.
From the street, you can't see the
glass in the Leeds' kitchen door.
There's a big, high fence there.
But he was ready
with his glass cutter.
So either he was
casing far ahead
and we didn't
check back far enough,
or...
- JACK: We checked.
- Don't talk.
Metcalfe, it's Graham. Is the Leeds and
Jacobi stuff still in the storeroom?
Have the guard
down there call me.
Do it.
You know that's
the Jacobis' cat.
You brought a bolt cutter 'cause
you thought there was a padlock.
The Leeds' dog
doesn't have a collar,
but you know it's the Leeds'
dog, don't you, my man?
See the woman?
The bloom on the woman?
You can see her again and
again anytime you want.
Doggie doesn't have a collar,
but you know it's the Leeds' dog.
And the Jacobi cat.
And the padlock on the door.
And you know you need a bolt cutter
and every other goddamn thing
because everything with you
is seeing, isn't it?
Your primary sensory intake
that makes your dream
live is seeing.
Reflections, mirrors, images...
You've seen these films.
Haven't you, my man?
(PHONE RINGING)
It's the guard in the storeroom.
-The cans.
-What cans?
The tapes were transferred
from home movies.
Where's the packaging
the films came in?
There's films of the families in
the document storage. Find them.
You got them?
Are there any labels?
Leeds can, Gateway Lab,
St. Louis, Missouri.
The Jacobi label Will say the
same thing as the Leeds label.
Gateway Lab,
St. Louis, Missouri.
JACK: Who processed
the Jacobi film?
No. Bob's Photo Store,
Birmingham.
- Stores send them out.
- Have him peel the top label back.
JACK: Is there
a label underneath?
It does, doesn't it?
Where are you? Are you here?
(IN-A-GADDA-DA-VIDA PLAYING)
You're scaring me with this!
Will you just stop it?
Francis,
why are you doing this to me?
It's ugly!
♪ Don't you know that
I'll always be true? ♪
Are you in this room?
Where are you?
You answer me!
♪ And take my hand ♪
♪ Oh, won't you come with me ♪
♪ And walk this land
Please, take my hand ♪
(EXHALES)
JACK: We're looking for a man.
We know he works at Gateway.
We don't have his name,
but we know he drives a van.
MAN OVER PHONE: Under
"Employee Facilities,"
I've got special
stickers for vans.
Yeah, I got 28,
29 van permits in the computer.
JACK: Start feeding me names.
Is this Lieutenant Fisk?
Will Graham.
Listen, I need you to punch
up the driver's licenses
of the names I'm gonna feed you.
The man we're looking
for is blond, Caucasian,
twenty to forty years old,
over six feet tall,
180 to 225 pounds.
First name? Alvaro.
A-L-V-A-R-O. First name Joseph.
Alvaro. A-L-V-A-R-O.
First name Joseph.
No. Black hair.
-No.
-Next.
Dillon. D-i-l-l-o-n.
First name Lincoln.
FISK: No. Next.
(MAN CHATTERING ON RADIO)
Male. Caucasian.
Six foot-seven, 217 pounds.
Eyes brown, hair blond.
Thirty-four years old.
Put it through
the data-fax. Fast.
You guys better buckle up.
We're on approach
to Lambert Field.
(MAN CHATTERING ON RADIO)
JACK: Fogel has four more names.
He knows two, both dark
hair, third's a woman,
fourth is a handicapped
parking permit.
This is our man.
Rural Route 3, Chester, Missouri.
Where is that?
From the airport
you're a few minutes closer.
We'll 10-25 at the Hark Road
off ramp, Highway 94.
Let's go!
(SIRENS WAILING)
(LOUD MUSIC PLAYING)
(SCREAMS)
- Meet point's up ahead.
- Go on to the house.
- But Lieutenant Fisk said...
JACK: Will?
Will?
You're not gonna need that.
A SWAT team is gonna
take him down, not us.
Will?
(CAR SWERVING)
Will!
(SIRENS STOP WAILING)
(DISPATCHER CHATTERING ON RADIO)
OFFICER 1: This ought
to be it right here.
Kill your lights.
(STEAM HISSING)
OFFICER 2: Are you all right?
OFFICER 3: I'm okay. Griffin's hurt bad.
I'll wait for the backup.
JACK: Set up
a roadblock on Route 3.
Graham and I are in the
trees west of the house.
WILL: (SOFTLY) How far
away is the backup unit?
I'm going around the back.
Stay in the trees.
He's in there, Jack.
And he's got somebody
in there with him.
JACK: What?
Will, what did you say?
JACK ON RADIO: Will.
Wait for the backup, Will.
Will!
He's got somebody
in the house with him, Jack.
JACK: Will.
Stop it.
Stop it!
(OFFICER GROANS)
(COCKING GUN)
(GRUNTS)
♪ Three, four ♪
♪ In-a-gadda-da-vida, honey ♪
♪ Don't you know that I love you? ♪
♪ In-a-gadda-da-vida, baby ♪
♪ Don't you know
that I'll always be true? ♪
♪ Oh, won't you come with me ♪
♪ And take my hand ♪
♪ And walk this land ♪
♪ Please, take my hand ♪
(SIRENS WAILING)
(INAUDIBLE)
It's okay.
(SOBBING)
Who are you?
Graham.
I'm Will Graham.
I'll get it, Ralph.
What do you want?
My name is Will Graham.
I'm with...
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, Jesus, right.
- Come on in.
- Please.
No, that's all right.
- You okay?
- We're fine.
We're okay, yeah.
Yeah, we're doing all right.
Thanks.
Listen, um,
that guy Crawford called
and he was telling me all about --
would you like to come in
and have a cup of coffee or a drink?
- No, thank you.
- Listen, I want --
I just stopped by to, uh...
Listen, I want --
I want to thank you. I-I...
I just stopped by... to see you.
That's all.
(HEARTBEAT PLAYING)
♪ I can hear your heartbeat
knocking on the window ♪
KEVIN: Hey, Dad!
♪ I can feel the weight
deep down below ♪
- Dad!
- Hey!
♪ I can hear your whispers ♪
Aw, it looks worse than it is, pal.
See the turtles?
Wow!
♪ Touch me like a hot ten
on my soul ♪
Hi.
It was on the... news.
♪ Anticipation in me grows ♪
I thought I had to work things out
and call you after.
I thought I wouldn't wait.
♪ Sometimes I understand it
very clearly ♪
I heartbeat, heartbeat
listen to my heartbeat ♪
Oh ♪
♪ heartbeat ♪
How many of them made it?
Most of 'em.
Most of 'em made it.
♪ Listen to my heartbeat ♪
Oh ♪
♪ heartbeat
listen to my heartbeat ♪
♪ I can hear your tiptoe ♪
♪ I can hear the door close ♪
♪ Anticipation in me grows ♪
♪ I can feel your dark eyes ♪
♪ Touch me in the darkness ♪
♪ Understand the message
never sent ♪
♪ Sometimes I ♪
♪ Sometimes I understand it
very clearly ♪
I heartbeat, heartbeat
listen to my heartbeat ♪
Oh ♪
I heartbeat, heartbeat
listen to my heartbeat ♪
Oh ♪
♪ heartbeat
listen to my heartbeat ♪
♪ Listen to my heartbeat ♪
♪ I can hear your tiptoe ♪
♪ I can hear the door close ♪
♪ Anticipation in me grows ♪
♪ I can feel your dark eyes ♪
♪ Touch me in the darkness ♪
♪ Understand the message
never sent ♪
♪ Sometimes I ♪
♪ Sometimes I understand it
very clearly ♪
I heartbeat, heartbeat
listen to my heartbeat ♪
Oh ♪
I heartbeat, heartbeat
listen to my heartbeat ♪
Oh ♪
♪ heartbeat
listen to my heartbeat ♪
♪ Listen to my heartbeat ♪
I heartbeat, heartbeat
listen to my heartbeat ♪
Oh ♪
I heartbeat, heartbeat
listen to my heartbeat ♪
Oh ♪
♪ heartbeat
listen to my heartbeat ♪
♪ Listen to my heartbeat ♪
I heartbeat, heartbeat
listen to my heartbeat ♪
Oh ♪
I heartbeat, heartbeat
listen to my heartbeat ♪
Oh ♪
♪ heartbeat
listen to my heartbeat ♪
♪ Listen to my heartbeat ♪
I heartbeat, heartbeat
listen to my heartbeat ♪
Oh ♪
I heartbeat, heartbeat
listen to my heartbeat ♪