CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
PARAMOUNT PICTURES CORPORATION
* HEY, LITTLE GIRL
* COMB YOUR HAIR
* FIX YOUR MAKEUP
* SOON HE WILL
OPEN THE DOOR *
* OH, DON'T THINK BECAUSE
* A-THERE'S A RING
ON YOUR FINGER *
* YOU NEEDN'T TRY ANYMORE
* FOR WIVES SHOULD
ALWAYS BE LOVERS, TOO *
* RUN TO HIS ARMS THE MOMENT
HE COMES HOME TO YOU *
* I'M WARNING YOU
* A-DAY AFTER DAY
* THERE ARE GIRLS
AT THE OFFICE *
* AND MEN WILL
ALWAYS BE MEN *
* NOW, DON'T SEND HIM OFF
* WITH YOUR HAIR
STILL IN CURLERS *
* YOU MAY NOT
SEE HIM AGAIN *
* FOR WIVES SHOULD
ALWAYS BE LOVERS, TOO *
* RUN TO HIS ARMS THE MOMENT
HE COMES HOME TO YOU *
Annie: OF THE FOUR OF US,
CYNTHIA WAS CERTAINLY
THE MOST LIKELY TO SUCCEED.
WHEN SHE DECIDED
TO DO SOMETHING,
SHE JUST WENT RIGHT AHEAD
AND DID IT.
[DOG BARKING]
HELLO, ROACHIE.
HELLO, HONEY.
IT'S MOMMY.
MOMMY'S HOME.
OH, GOSH, THINK
WE GOT ANY MESSAGES?
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
Tape: ANNIE, DEAR,
IT'S YOUR MOTHER.
IT'S 6 A.M.
PLEASE CALL ME URGENTLY.
OHH! OH, CHRIS,
OH, GOD.
HONEY, I THOUGHT
YOU WERE GOING TO
CAMPUS YESTERDAY.
WELL,
MY MORNING CLASSES
WERE CANCELED,
SO I DECIDED
TO STAY OVER.
WHERE WERE YOU
LAST NIGHT?
I WAS, YOU KNOW,
I WAS AT A FRIEND'S.
YOU WERE WITH
THAT MAN AGAIN,
WEREN'T YOU?
MOTHER, I'M
SO DISAPPOINTED.
I KNOW, SWEETIE.
I'M SORRY,
BUT HE IS YOUR FATHER.
YES, BUT
HE'S USING YOU,
AND YOU SHOULDN'T
LET HIM.
OH, CHRIS, IT'S
NOT THAT SIMPLE.
THE TRUTH
OF THE MATTER
IS--IS THAT--
I LOVE YOUR FATHER,
AND I'M SURE THAT
HE LOVES ME.
YOU'RE A DOORMAT!
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH YOU?
WHY ARE YOU SO
CRABBY TODAY, HONEY?
IS IT SCHOOL?
I KNOW WHAT IT IS.
IT'S A BOY.
I'M A LESBIAN, MOM.
WHAT?
I'M A LESBIAN,
BUT THAT'S NOT
THE ISSUE HERE.
WELL, SWEETIE,
WHEN YOU SAY LESBIAN--
AND DON'T
TELL DADDY.
I WANT TO TELL
HIM MYSELF WHEN
THE TIME IS RIGHT,
LIKE FATHER'S DAY...
OR CHRISTMAS
MORNING.
CHRIS.
Woman: OH, THANK GOD
YOU'RE ALL RIGHT.
WHERE WERE YOU?
WHO SAW YOU?
WHO SAW ME WHAT?
SHE WAS SLEEPING
WITH DADDY.
UHH.
OH, MUFFIN, YOU'VE
COME TO YOUR SENSES.
I'M SO HAPPY.
MOTHER, I AM
NOT SLEEPING
WITH AARON.
HE'S JUST HAVING
SOME PROBLEMS
WITH HIS PARTNERS.
HE'S FEELING
VERY CONFLICTED,
AND HE NEEDED
SOMEBODY TO TALK TO.
DOORMAT.
LESBIAN.
DO IT, MORRIS.
DO IT TO ME NOW.
I NEED IT.
YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE
WHO DOES IT THE WAY
I LIKE IT.
YOU'RE THE KING.
ELISE, IF I GIVE YOU
ANY MORE COLLAGEN,
YOUR LIPS ARE GONNA LOOK
LIKE THEY GOT STUCK
IN A POOL DRAIN.
MORRIS, I HAVEN'T
WORKED IN 18 MONTHS,
AND I HAVE A MEETING
WITH A DIRECTOR
FOR A PART THAT
I WOULD KILL FOR,
AND I HAVE
TO LOOK SEXY.
ELISE, YOU ARE SEXY.
LOOK. LOOK AT YOURSELF.
YOU'RE INCREDIBLE.
YOU'RE MY MASTERPIECE.
THERE'S NOT ONE LINE
ON YOUR FACE.
OH, REALLY? WELL,
WHAT DO YOU CALL
THAT?
AND THESE?
WHAT ARE THESE?
YOU'RE 45.
YOU KNOW, IF I GIVE YOU
ONE MORE FACELIFT,
YOU'RE GONNA BE ABLE
TO BLINK YOUR LIPS.
DON'T YOU WANT TO BE ABLE
TO PLAY PARTS YOUR OWN AGE?
MY OWN AGE? NO, NO.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
THERE ARE ONLY
THREE AGES FOR WOMEN
IN HOLLYWOOD:
BABE,
DISTRICT ATTORNEY,
AND DRIVING
MISS DAISY,
AND RIGHT NOW,
I WANNA BE YOUNG,
SCIENCE FICTION
YOUNG.
OH, OH,
THIS IS GOOD.
AND WHILE
YOU'RE AT IT,
YOU MIGHT THINK
ABOUT CUTTING DOWN
ON THE BOOZE.
LOOK, ELISE, I--
I KNOW YOU'RE UPSET
ABOUT THE DIVORCE.
UPSET?
I KNOW YOU'RE UPSET
ABOUT BILL'S MOVIE.
THIS IS
NOT ABOUT HIM.
ABOUT MY LIPS.
OK, NOW LOOK AT ME.
I WANT TINA TURNER.
I WANT JAGGER.
FILL 'EM UP.
NO, REALLY?
OH.
THIS IS FABULOUS NEWS.
THANK YOU. BYE-BYE.
JASON.
[MUSIC FROM HEADPHONES]
HONEY.
YOO-HOO.
BURNING SENSATION
JUST CONFIRMED.
JASON!
WHAT?
BURNING SENSATION
CONFIRMED.
I GOT THE BAND
YOU WANTED.
COOL.
AFFECTION.
GIMME THAT.
[MAN SPEAKING HEBREW]
WHAT IS THIS?
HEBREW.
YOUR BAR MITZVAH
IS IN THREE WEEKS.
IT'S THE ONE THING
YOUR FATHER IS
WILLING TO PAY FOR.
LEARN IT.
BUT, MOM--
DON'T "BUT, MOM" ME.
PLEASE LEARN IT.
DON'T SHAME ME
IN THE SYNAGOGUE.
AND HURRY UP.
IT'S TIME FOR SCHOOL.
THIS SEPARATION
BETWEEN YOU AND AARON
IS ABSURD.
HOW ARE YOU GOING
TO WORK THINGS OUT
IF YOU'RE NOT TOGETHER?
WELL, WE'RE PRACTICALLY
TOGETHER, MOTHER.
WE'RE BOTH SEEING
THE SAME THERAPIST.
COME ON.
WHAT?
ROACH, COME ON, GO.
UM, HER NAME IS
DR. LESLIE ROSEN,
AND I THINK SHE'S
JUST INCREDIBLE, MOTHER.
SHE'S HELPING AARON
WITH HIS COMMITMENT
ISSUES.
WE'RE WORKING ON MY,
UH, MY SELF-ESTEEM.
ROACH, HONEY, PLEASE--
YOU ARE MARRIED.
YOU HAVE A DAUGHTER.
YOU'RE VERY HAPPY.
YOU DON'T NEED
SELF-ESTEEM.
MOTHER...
DR. ROSEN SAYS THAT--
WELL, SHE SAYS YOU'RE
VERY CONTROLLING, MOM.
ME CONTROLLING?
OH, THAT IS RIDICULOUS.
MOTHER, I--
ROACH...
GO.
[WHIMPERING]
WELL, WHAT IF I FOUND
SOMEBODY ELSE, MOTHER?
I MEAN, IT'S POSSIBLE,
MAYBE.
OH, HONEY,
YOU'RE 46.
WELL, YES, BUT--
A WOMAN YOUR AGE
HAS A BETTER CHANCE
OF BEING SLAUGHTERED
BY A PSYCHOPATH.
OH, OK.
TV: CYNTHIA SWAN GRIFFIN
IS DEAD.
THE FORMER WIFE
OF WALL STREET WIZARD--
DIDN'T YOU
GO TO SCHOOL
WITH HER?
MOTHER, SHH.
...SUICIDE LEAP
FROM HER FASHIONABLE
PENTHOUSE APARTMENT.
AHH. MOM.
MRS. GRIFFIN HAD
RECENTLY DIVORCED
HER LONGTIME HUSBAND
GILBERT GRIFFIN.
THE WALL STREET BARON
AND PHILANTHROPIST
REMARRIED ONLY YESTERDAY.
AHH.
[DISTORTED]
MORNING, MOHAMMED.
MORNING, MISS ELIOT.
[GASPS]
ELISE.
OH.
GUNILLA.
OH. OH, GOD,
WHAT A TRAGEDY.
POOR CYNTHIA.
AND YOUR LIPS.
Annie: ELISE ELIOT ARRIVED
WITH GUNILLA
GARSON-GOLDBERG...
Man, whispering:
Brenda.
THE QUEEN
OF NEW YORK SOCIETY.
Look.
NOBODY GETS
ANYWHERE IN THIS TOWN
WITHOUT GUNILLA'S SAY-SO.
UH.
[ORGAN MUSIC PLAYING]
Brenda: PSST. Hey.
PSST. Hey.
ELISE.
SHE LOOKS WONDERFUL.
HAS SHE HAD
ANY WORK DONE?
HONEY, SHE'S A QUILT.
Annie: THEN CAME
CYNTHIA'S FORMER HUSBAND
GILBERT GRIFFIN:
A MAN MADE RICH BY HIS
FIRST WIFE'S CONNECTIONS
AND NOW MADE HAPPY
BY HIS SECOND WIFE'S
YOUTHFUL GOOD LOOKS.
AHH. THE VAMPIRE
LESTAT...
AND LOUIS.
WHAT A NERVE.
HE SHOULD BE
HANGING HIS HEAD.
YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT GIL IS FEELING
RIGHT NOW.
[GASPS]
OHH. AHH.
I KNEW YOU'D
BE HERE. OHH.
ALICE?
NO. ANNIE.
ANNIE.
IT'S SO WONDERFUL
TO SEE YOU.
OH, AND YOU'RE
WEARING OUR PEARLS.
YES.
OH. OH.
HI. BRENDA.
BRENDA MORELLI.
BRENDA.
ANNIE.
REMEMBER ME?
HOW GOOD
TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
YOU, TOO.
OH, YOU LOOK
WONDERFUL.
YOU DO, TOO.
YOU LOOK JUST...
UNCANNY.
THANK YOU.
DEAR, SWEET, FUNNY,
YEARNING BRENDA.
OH.
WHAT?
OH, THAT'S
JUST A BITCH.
OH, I HATE THAT GUY.
I KNOW THIS IS
GONNA REALLY SOUND...
HORRIBLE AFTER--
BUT I--I WOULD REALLY--
I JUST...
I'D LOVE TO--
LUNCH?
OH, NO. I KNOW.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
IT'S NOT RIGHT.
WHY? WE GOTTA EAT.
I HAVE A CAR.
A LIMO?
YEAH.
Elise: OH, IT
IS SO WONDERFUL
SEEING YOU ALL.
THANK YOU.
I CAN'T TELL YOU.
IT'S--IT'S--
ELISE.
WHAT?
YOU HAVE NOT CHANGED
A BIT IN 20 YEARS,
NOT ONE LITTLE BIT.
OH, MY, IT'S
UTTERLY BIZARRE.
BRENDA.
OH, EXCUSE ME,
I'M SO SORRY.
EXCUSE ME, LADIES,
WOULD ANYONE
LIKE A DRINK?
OH, YES,
I WOULD LIKE A...
VIRGIN MARY.
BLOODY MARY.
VODKA, ROCKS, PLEASE.
NOW, I JUST
WANT TO SAY THIS,
AND GET THIS
OUT OF THE WAY.
I'M THE MOST TERRIBLE
PERSON IN THE WHOLE
WIDE WORLD.
I TRIED
TO STAY IN TOUCH,
AND I SHOULD
HAVE WRITTEN
EVERY SINGLE MONTH,
AND SORRY, I--
OH, ANNIE, YOU HAD
A LIFE TO LEAD.
I MEAN, AND
IT MUST HAVE BEEN
SO TIME-CONSUMING
CHURNING OUT
ALL THOSE NEWSLETTERS.
Brenda: I KNOW IT'S
A TERRIBLE EXCUSE
FOR A REUNION,
BUT HERE WE ALL ARE,
SO HOW ARE
YOU GUYS, HUH?
OH, JUST FINE.
COULDN'T BE BETTER.
AND THINGS ARE JUST
ROLLING RIGHT ALONG
FOR ME. RIGHT HERE.
SAME HERE. KNOCK WOOD.
OH, KNOCK WOOD.
GREAT TO SEE
YOU GUYS AGAIN.
CHEERS.
HUGE KISSES.
I MEAN,
WHY'D SHE DO IT?
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
I MEAN, WAS
THERE SOMETHING
THAT I COULD HAVE DONE
TO HAVE HELPED?
WHAT HAPPENED
TO MAKE HER WANT TO--
WELL, SHE PROBABLY
GAVE GIL THE BEST
YEARS OF HER LIFE,
SACRIFICED HER YOUTH,
ALWAYS PUT HERSELF
LAST IN ORDER
TO BOLSTER HIS EGO,
HIS DRIVE, HIS AMBITION.
AND JUST AS HER DIGNITY
WAS HANGING ON
BY A THREAD,
HE JUST LOPPED IT OFF
BY RUNNING OFF
WITH SOME....
PRESCHOOLER.
I'M GUESSING.
ELISE, YOU, TOO?
YOU, BRENDA?
BRENDA?
MY MORTY GOT TO BE
THIS BIG SHOT ON TV,
SELLING ELECTRONICS,
RIGHT?
ON OUR 20th WEDDING
ANNIVERSARY IT HITS.
MIDLIFE CRISIS.
MAJOR.
HE STARTS WORKING OUT.
HE GROWS A MUSTACHE.
HE GETS AN EARRING.
I SAID, "MORTY, MORTY,
WHAT ARE YOU, A PIRATE?
WHAT'S NEXT, A PARROT?",
AND ALL OF A SUDDEN
I'M A BIG DRAG.
I'M HOLDING HIM BACK
BECAUSE I WON'T
GO ROLLERBLADING.
WHAT'S HER NAME?
SHELLY.
SHELLY THE BARRACUDA.
SHE'S 12.
OH, BREN.
OH, ELISE.
I, YOU KNOW,
I JUST AM SO SORRY
ABOUT BOTH
OF YOUR MARRIAGES.
I WISH THAT
I COULD'VE HELPED,
OR THAT I COULD'VE
BEEN THERE IN SOME WAY.
WHAT ABOUT YOU?
Elise: WHAT
ABOUT YOUR
YEAH. MARRIAGE?
MMM. OH, EVERYTHING'S
JUST FINE, REALLY.
I MEAN, AARON
IS SO TERRIFIC,
AND WELL, NOW,
LET'S THINK.
UH, WE'VE BEEN
MARRIED FOR 25 YEARS.
TCH TCH TCH. YUP.
AND CHRIS
IS JUST PERFECT.
I MEAN, LESBIANS
ARE GREAT NOWADAYS,
AND, UH, WELL, THE
MARRIAGE IS JUST,
IT'S GOING--
IT'S GONNA
BE REALLY FINE.
AARON AND I ARE
JUST, YOU KNOW,
WE'RE, UM,
WE'RE TEMPORARILY
SORT OF
KIND OF, YOU KNOW,
JUST A LITTLE BIT--
WE'RE SEPARATED.
SEPARATED.
SEPARATED?
[LAUGHS]
WELL, WE...
WELL.
Brenda: WELL.
OK, ELISE.
THE TIME HAS COME.
SPILL. THOSE LIPS.
WHAT'S IN THEM?
ARE THEY WAX?
EXCUSE ME.
WHAT ELSE DID
YOU HAVE DONE?
COME ON, ELISE.
YOU CAN TELL ME.
THE CHEEKBONES?
THE JAWLINE?
DID YOU HAVE
JUST A LITTLE BIT,
OR THE FULL
ENCHILADA?
I WORK OUT EVERY DAY.
I WATCH MY DIET.
I HAVE NOT HAD
PLASTIC SURGERY.
WELL, GOOD FOR YOU.
YOU LOOK TERRIFIC.
OH, COME ON.
ELISE, YOU'RE LYING
THROUGH YOUR CAPS.
OK. ALL RIGHT.
I HAVE BEEN
FRESHENED UP
A LITTLE BIT.
OH, GOD.
DOES IT HURT?
MMM. NO.
WHAT DO THEY DO
WITH THE STUFF
THEY TAKE OFF?
DO YOU GET
TO KEEP IT?
OH, COME ON, BRENDA.
IT'S THE NINETIES,
FOR GOD'S SAKES.
I MEAN, IT'S LIKE
PLASTIC SURGERY'S
LIKE GOOD GROOMING.
IT'S LIKE BRUSHING
YOUR TEETH.
ELISE, LOOK AT YOU.
YOU HAVE BEEN
YANKED AND STITCHED
AND STUFFED AND PULLED.
YOU'RE A TURKEY.
A WHAT?
AND TO PLEASE WHO?
YOUR EX-HUSBAND?
NO. TO PLEASE EVERYBODY.
TO PLEASE EVERYBODY.
Brenda: EVERYBODY.
MEN, WOMEN...
EVERYONE.
STUDIO EXECUTIVES.
I MEAN, COME ON. I MEAN,
YOUTH AND BEAUTY, MAN.
I MEAN, THAT'S THE TICKET.
WHEN MEN--
NO, WHEN WOMEN GET
TO BE A CERTAIN AGE...
BYE-BYE, LOVE.
HELLO, POP-TARTS.
THAT'S RIGHT, BABY.
IT'S A HOLOCAUST.
OH, GOD, I WISH
I HAD THE COURAGE
NO.
TO JUST GIVE IT
ALL UP, YOU KNOW?
TO SAY WHO
GIVES A RAT'S ASS?
AND JUST LET MYSELF GO
LIKE YOU TWO.
OH, NO.
NO OFFENSE.
NONE TAKEN.
OH, SPEAK FOR
YOURSELF, OK?
ELISE, YOU'RE GIFTED.
YOU'RE TALENTED...
THANK YOU.
AND SUCCESSFUL,
AND BRENDA,
YOU'RE WONDERFULLY
VERBAL,
AND I AM SEEING A VERY
TALENTED THERAPIST.
NOW, WE'RE IN OUR PRIME,
AND BY THE WAY,
MY MARRIAGE IS JUST FINE,
THANK YOU.
ANNIE,
YOU...
HAVE AN AMAZING
ATTITUDE.
YOU, YOU--
WELL--
YOU ARE SO CHEERFUL.
WELL, WE--
YOU ARE GEN--
LOOK AT ME.
WHAT?
YOU ARE
GENUINELY HAPPY.
IT'S A
BEAUTIFUL THING.
WELL, THANK YOU.
LITHIUM?
Annie: YOU WOULD
HAVE BEEN SO PROUD
OF ME, LESLIE.
I MEAN, I WAS THE
ONLY POSITIVE THING
AT THAT TABLE.
I MEAN, OF COURSE,
THERE ARE STILL TRACES
OF THE SAME WONDERFUL
WITTY WOMEN
I KNEW ALL
THOSE YEARS AGO,
BUT, AHH, I DON'T KNOW.
I JUST DON'T KNOW.
THEY ARE JUST SO...
ANGRY, AND
THEY'RE SO CONFUSED.
I MEAN,
WHEN WE WERE YOUNG,
WE HAD SUCH SPIRIT.
SAY IT, ANNIE.
HUH? WHAT?
WORK FROM LOVE.
OK.
GOOD.
GROW FROM LOVE.
SCREW THE WORLD.
I CAN'T SAY THAT.
I'M SORRY, LESLIE.
HEY, ANNIE.
UH, WHAT?
ANNIE, YOU ARE
STILL DOING IT.
I KNOW.
YOU HAVE A PROBLEM
WITH UNEXPRESSED ANGER.
WELL, I KNOW.
YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
YOU KNOW, IT'S MY MOT--
I DON'T KNOW WHAT IT IS.
IT'S MY MOTHER.
IT'S CONNECTICUT.
IT'S ALL THESE
LOUD NOISES.
AND AARON?
NO, I KNOW
WE'RE SEPARATED,
BUT I THINK THIS
IS JUST REALLY--
IT'S LIKE
A REST PERIOD, LESLIE.
WE'RE JUST KIND OF
GETTING--AAH! OHH.
DO IT, ANNIE.
GET ANGRY.
I COULDN'T. I KNOW
THAT I SHOULD, LESLIE.
I REALLY DO.
IT'S JUST THAT--
HIT ME.
STAND UP, ANNIE,
AND HIT ME.
NO. I--
I CAN'T, LESLIE.
I'M SO SORRY.
COME ON.
IT'S JUST--YOU KNOW,
MAYBE--I KNOW WHAT.
MAYBE NEXT WEEK.
ANNIE, LET IT OUT.
I WANT YOU TO HIT ME.
TRUST ME. COME ON.
IT'S OK.
O-OK.
OH. RAMBO.
OOH. A REAL
TOUGH GUY.
COME ON, ANNIE,
HIT ME.
I LOVE THAT.
OOH. OOH. WHOO.
OH. OH, MY GOD.
THAT WAS BETTER.
I'M SO SORRY.
OH, PLEASE
DON'T TELL AARON.
[BUZZER]
TIME'S UP.
I'M SO SORRY.
TIME TO GO.
DO YOU FEEL BETTER?
THANK YOU.
GOOD.
Elise: HE DOESN'T
HAVE THE GUTS
TO TELL ME HE WANTS
A DIVORCE IN PERSON.
I HAVE TO HEAR IT
ON TELEVISION.
ENTERTAINMENT TONIGHT.
HARD COPY.
ELISE, BE COOL.
BE CALM.
I AM.
I ACTUALLY SAW
THAT SHOW. IT WAS
RATHER INTERESTING.
OH, TOM, I DON'T
WANNA HEAR ABOUT IT.
Woman: THE MARRIAGE
BETWEEN MY CLIENT
AND MS. ELIOT
RESULTED IN MANY
SUCCESSFUL FILMS,
INCLUDING INNER URGES,
HUMAN INSTINCT,
AND--MY PERSONAL
FAVORITE--
ANIMAL NATURE,
IN WHICH SHE PLAYED
AN EXTREMELY SENSUAL
VETERINARIAN.
THANK YOU.
MY IDEA.
WAS NOT.
WAS TOO.
UM, MY CLIENT
PRODUCED THESE FILMS,
WHICH ENHANCED
MS. ELIOT'S CAREER.
THEREFORE, SHE IS
INDEBTED TO HIM.
I PRODUCED THESE FILMS.
YOU KNEW NOTHING
ABOUT FILMS
WHEN I MET YOU.
I TAUGHT YOU EVERYTHING.
SHH SHH SHH.
WHAT?
THOSE WERE GOOD YEARS,
ELISE. YOUR BEST.
AND THEREFORE
WE REQUEST ONE HALF
OF MS. ELIOT'S ASSETS
AND A MONTHLY STIPEND.
HE WANTS ALIMONY?
AS FOR THE POSSESSIONS:
THE SCULPTURE, ART...
THE POSSESSIONS?
AND IMPORTANT OBJETS
COLLECTED DURING
THE MARRIAGE...
I WANT TO TELL
YOU SOMETHING.
I BOUGHT EVERYTHING.
...DISPOSE
OF THE COLLECTION
AND DIVIDE THE PROCEEDS
IN AN EVEN SPLIT.
BECAUSE THAT--
THEY WERE ANNIVERSARY
PRESENTS.
THEY WERE
CHRISTMAS PRESENTS.
I GAVE HIM
EVERYTHING HE HAS,
AND NOW HE WANTS MORE?
GO FASTER. WE'RE
GOING TO HAVE LUNCH--
NOW, LOOK AT THIS.
DUARTO, I ASK YOU.
PLEASE.
NOW, WHO'S SUPPOSED
TO WEAR THAT?
SOME ANOREXIC TEENAGER?
SOME FETUS?
IT'S A CONSPIRACY.
I KNOW IT IS.
I'VE HAD ENOUGH.
I'M LEADING A PROTEST.
I AM NEVER BUYING
ANOTHER ITEM OF CLOTHING
UNTIL THESE DESIGNERS
COME TO THEIR SENSES.
WILL YOU SHUT UP?
Annie:
BRENDA WORKED FOR A MAN
NAMED DUARTO FELIZ,
ONE OF THE 10 WORST INTERIOR
DECORATORS IN NEW YORK CITY.
I THINK HIS REAL NAME
WAS DWAYNE HEMMELWITZ.
IT'S ELECTRIC! AND
LOOK AT THIS HIDEOUS--
DUARTO, I CANNOT
AFFORD IT.
YOU'VE GOT TO HAVE IT.
GO AND TRY IT ON.
WHO CARES? YOU COULD SELL
YOUR BROACH, YOUR SON...
OHH!
[WHISPERS]
Duarto.
MORTY. WELL,
LOOK AT YOU.
YOU LOOK PROSPEROUS.
AHEM. BRENDA,
DON'T EMBARRASS ME.
DON'T
EMBARRASS
DON'T MAKE YOU.
A SCENE.
DON'T MAKE
DON'T EMBARRASS
YOU! YOU'VE
GOT A NERVE.
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT'S
EMBARRASSING--
BEING HASSLED
BY MR. ZAWORSKY
IN THE ELEVATOR
CONTROL
YOURSELF.
BECAUSE I'M BEHIND
IN THE RENT.
THAT'S EMBARRASSING.
WORRYING ABOUT HOW I'M GONNA
GET MY KID THROUGH COLLEGE,
THAT'S EMBARRASSING!
BRENDA, YOU KNOW SOMETHING?
YOU NEVER LISTEN.
FOR 20 YEARS, YOU NEVER,
EVER LISTENED. HERE.
HONEY, WHY DON'T YOU
TRY THIS ON
IN THE FITTING ROOM?
IT LOOKS VERY NICE.
I COULD USE THIS.
IT'S VERY BEAUTIFUL,
AND I LOVE THE COLOR.
BUT WHAT AM I GONNA USE
FOR MONEY? HOW AM I
GONNA PAY FOR IT?
IT'S THE COMPANY
THAT IS EXPANDING.
DON'T YOU UNDERSTAND THAT?
THE COMPANY, NOT ME.
I'M A MERE LABORER, OK?
YOU'RE A LIAR
AND A FRAUD!
I HAVE NO MONEY.
I'M NOT RICH.
REALLY?
WHY DON'T YOU LOOK
IN YOUR PURSE?
THEY'RE STUNNING, MORTON.
I NEED ALL OF THEM.
Brenda:
MORTON?
OH, GOD,
MAKE IT GO AWAY.
SHELLY. LOOK AT YOU.
MY, MY. THE BULIMIA
CERTAINLY HAS
PAID OFF.
DON'T START.
WHAT'S THE MATTER,
MORTY?
CAN'T YOU BUY HER
A WHOLE DRESS?
STOP IT.
BRENDA, WHY DON'T YOU
TRY THESE ON
IN YOUR SIZE?
IT WAS REALLY A DELIGHT
RUNNING INTO YOU TODAY,
BRENDA.
YOU'VE...
READ THE SCRIPT.
OH, YES. OH, IT IS SO...
I MEAN, IT'S
UTTERLY ORIGINAL.
IT'S SO GOOD.
YOU'RE SO GIFTED, BRETT.
HEY. HA HA HA!
AND MONIQUE...
HA HA HA!
MONIQUE. YEAH,
C'EST MONIQUE.
UM...SHE IS, UH,
SHE IS A GREAT
CHARACTER.
THANK YOU.
MAN...HA HA HA!
WHAT A KICK.
YEAH.
ELISE ELIOT...
IN A BRETT ARTOUNION
FILM.
OH...OH. SO TELL ME,
HOW DO YOU SEE HER?
AHEM.
WELL, UM...
I THINK WE GO FOR...
GROTESQUE. HA HA.
WHAT?
YEAH, ALL THE WAY.
I MEAN, NO MAKEUP,
OVERHEAD LIGHTING.
YOU KNOW, BRING OUT
EVERY WRINKLE,
EVERY CRAG.
GOD, WITH YOU
IN THE PART...
MONIQUE'S MOTHER'S
NOT GONNA BE
JUST ANOTHER
JURASSIC FLESHBAG
IN A WHEELCHAIR.
SHE'S EPIC.
IT'S LIKE...
ELISE ELIOT...
THE CRYPTKEEPER.
HA HA. WOW.
[BEEP]
Jason: MOM, I'M SPENDING
THE NIGHT AT DAD'S.
DON'T WORRY,
I'M STUDYING.
BARUCH ATA ADONAI.
HAPPY NOW?
[BEEP]
MAURICE.
I WANT
ANOTHER ONE.
THEY WANT ME
TO PLAY THE MOTHER.
SORRY?
THE MOTHER.
LET ME ASK YOU
SOMETHING, MAURICE.
IS THIS THE FACE
OF A MOTHER?
NO, MA'AM.
WELL, CERTAINLY
NOT MINE.
HA HA!
MM-HMM.
SO I THOUGHT.
I DON'T MEAN TO
CRITICIZE, BUT YOU HAVE
NO FEELING FOR NOODLES.
THANK YOU, MOM.
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
MMM.
[RING]
HELLO. UM...UM...
OH, AARON?
OH, NOTHING.
I'M JUST HAVING
PASTA WITH MOTHER.
HA HA.
OH, NO. YOU SAY.
OH, SURE!
WELL, THAT'LL
BE GOOD.
BYE.
DO YOU BELIEVE IT?
WE'RE GONNA HAVE
DINNER!
DINNER! CAN YOU
BELIEVE THAT?
OH, MY GOD!
DO YOU KNOW
WHAT THIS MEANS?
I BET IT MEANS
THAT HE HAS
REPRIORITIZED.
HE'S WORKED THROUGH
ALL HIS RELATIONSHIP
PHOBIAS,
HIS FEAR
OF INTIMACY,
HIS THING
ABOUT MY, YOU KNOW,
POISONING HIS FOOD,
AND HE'S READY
TO RECOMMIT.
HERE WE GO.
THANK YOU.
ENJOY.
EXCUSE ME.
SO SORRY.
SORRY.
¿UNA?
[LOUDLY]
BY YOURSELF?
Sí.
[ORCHESTRA PLAYS
ISN'T IT ROMANTIC?]
HOW ARE YOU?
HELLO.
GIVE ME THAT.
OH. THANK YOU.
YOU WANT TO, UM...
OH, SURE.
OH!
HA HA HA!
[DRUNKENLY]
I'M NOT MONIQUE'S
MOTHER!
NO.
ANGELA LANSBURY'S
MONIQUE'S MOTHER.
AND SHELLY WINTERS
IS UNIQUE'S MOTHER.
NOW,
THAT'S GOOD.
UH, SEAN CONNERY'S
WUNIQUE'S MOTHER.
YEAH.
PERHAPS I SHOULD...
GET YOU SOME COFFEE.
OH, WAIT A MINUTE.
I TAKE THAT BACK.
SEAN CONNERY
IS MONIQUE'S BOYFRIEND.
HE'S 300 YEARS OLD,
BUT HE'S STILL A STUD.
[SOBS]
I'M UNHAPPY, MAURICE.
AND I'M GOING
TO GET YOU
THAT COFFEE.
[SOBS]
MMM...
HONEY, I...
OH, HONEY.
I THINK
I SHOULD GO.
OK. I KNOW.
TOMORROW...
WE COULD START MOVING
YOUR THINGS BACK IN...
I MEAN, IF THAT'S OK.
IT'S JUST--OH, SWEETIE,
I HATED SEEING YOUR SIDE
OF THE CLOSET ALL EMPTY.
OHHH...
YOU KNOW, DR. ROSEN...
SHE WOULD BE
SO PROUD OF US.
I WISH SHE WERE HERE.
WELL, NOT LITERALLY,
BUT I JUST CAN'T WAIT
TO TELL HER HOW WE'VE
WORKED EVERYTHING OUT.
IT'S LIKE WE SHOULD
GET THERAPY GOLD STARS.
OH...
OH, ANNIE.
HA HA.
I LOVE YOU.
HA HA HA.
NO, COME HERE.
COME HERE.
YES?
AARON...
AARON, AARON...
I LOVE YOU.
[SIGHS]
I WANT A DIVORCE.
HUHH...
BUT...
CALM.
STAY CALM.
BUT WE JUST
MADE LOVE!
I MEAN, YOU...
ASKED ME...OUT!
I ASKED YOU OUT
TO TELL YOU,
BUT THEN YOU LOOKED
SO GREAT,
AND I THOUGHT,
JEEZ, HOW ROMANTIC--
ONE LAST TIME,
A GOOD-BYE KISS.
BUT...THIS WASN'T JUST
A KISS! THIS WAS--
ANNIE, DON'T BE
CHILDISH! YOU KNOW
HOW YOU MANIPULATE ME.
WHAT? MANIPULATE!
I--
DON'T.
I--WHA...
OH, MY GOD.
IS THERE
SOMEONE ELSE?
OF COURSE NOT.
THIS IS ABOUT US.
BUT--
IT'S--WELL,
IT'S REALLY
NOT YOU, BUT--
BABE?
OH, MY GOD.
THIS IS VERY
AWKWARD.
NO, NO. ANNIE
WAS JUST LEAVING.
YOU TOLD HER?
I--I WAS
TOTALLY UP-FRONT.
WHAT? EXCUSE ME?
WELL...
ANNIE, THIS IS ROUGH.
I KNOW THAT.
ROUGH! WAIT A MINUTE.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
YOU ARE MY THERAPIST.
I'M A WOMAN.
HE IS MY HUSBAND.
OHH!
ANNIE! WE'VE BEEN
SEPARATED FOR MONTHS.
NOW, LET'S NOT
OVERDRAMATIZE, OK?
AARON, SHE'S ALLOWED
TO BE ANGRY.
ANNIE, LET'S USE THIS--
HE'S FOUND SOMEONE NEW.
YOU ARE FREE. CLOSURE.
I AM SORRY, BUT...
THAT..IS NOT...
WHAT THIS IS.
WELL, ANNIE--
NO!
NO, NO, ANNIE,
YOU'RE NOT HELPING
US OUT HERE.
NOW, I AM SORRY
IT HAPPENED THIS WAY.
WELL, SO AM I!
I AM...VERY SORRY
I EVER MET YOU!
AND I AM SORRY
THAT I ALLOWED MYSELF
TO LOVE YOU
FOR ALL THOSE YEARS!
I'M SORRY I DID NOTHING
BUT BE THERE FOR YOU
EVERY MINUTE OF EVERY DAY
AND SUPPORT YOU
IN YOUR EVERY MOOOVVE!
I'M SORRY!
OHHH!
[SOBS]
[ELEVATOR BELL DINGS]
OH...
[SOBS]
WHOO.
OH...
OH, MY GOD.
[SNIFFLES]
"I WISH I HAD
TALENT LIKE ELISE...
OR BRENDA'S HUMOR..."
"OR YOUR...
"STRENGTH, ANNIE.
"BUT MOST OF ALL,
"I WISH I STILL HAD
OUR FRIENDSHIP.
PERHAPS GIL
ISN'T THE PROBLEM."
OH, GOD.
"PERHAPS...
LONELINESS IS."
[CHUCKLES]
"PLEASE TAKE CARE
OF EACH OTHER.
LOVE, CYNTHIA."
[SIGHS]
AND ON SUCH
PRETTY STATIONERY.
I HAVE TO MAKE
SOME CALLS, MOM.
GOD. POOR CYNTHIA.
I KNOW.
IF ONLY SHE'D
HAVE CALLED ME.
IF ONLY I WERE
LISTED.
YOU KNOW SOMETHING?
SHE WAS RIGHT. SHE WAS.
IN COLLEGE, WE WERE
FOCUSED, AND WE WERE
BRAVE. WE COULDN'T WAIT.
Brenda:
IT'S ALL OVER.
I'M ALONE.
I DON'T HAVE
ANYTHING.
NO.
I DON'T HAVE ANYTHING.
BRENDA, YOU HAVE
A SON WHO ADORES YOU.
I'M ALONE.
I'M MONIQUE'S
MOTHER.
YES, BUT JASON'S GOING
TO GO OFF TO COLLEGE
PRETTY SOON,
AND THEN I'LL BE EVEN
MORE ALONE, PLUS I'LL BE
REALLY A LOT OLDER.
AND IF I HAVE
ANY MORE PLASTIC SURGERY,
I WON'T BE ABLE TO SLEEP.
I'M GOING TO
HAVE TO GET A JOB
AT McDONALD'S.
AND I'LL HAVE TO DO ADS
FOR ADULT DIAPERS.
I'LL HAVE TO
WEAR THEM.
NO.
I JUST SPENT
THE LAST 25 YEARS
WITH THE MOST
SELF-ABSORBED,
ARROGANT MAN ON EARTH,
WHO IS GETTING MARRIED
TO MY THERAPIST,
WHO I PAID A FORTUNE
TO LECTURE ME
ON SELF-ESTEEM.
OH, GOD. OH,
WORSE LIFE.
YOU WIN
HANDS DOWN.
I AM NOT GONNA BE
THAT WOMAN ANYMORE.
WHAT HAS HAPPENED TO US
IS UNACCEPTABLE!
IT IS UNACCEPTABLE.
I MADE ALL THOSE STUPID
MOVIES WITH THAT BILL.
YOU KNOW, I GAVE HIM
A CAREER, AND HE STOLE
MINE.
YEAH!
I WORKED
BEHIND THE CASH REGISTER
IN HIS FIRST STORE.
IN HIS FIRST 15 STORES!
WELL, I GAVE AARON
A HOME, AND I GAVE HIM
A DAUGHTER.
I WASHED HIS SHORTS,
I IRONED THEM,
AND I STARCHED THEM!
OH, YOU DID?
YOU DID?
WELL, I MEAN,
I SUPERVISED.
SO WHAT ARE--WHAT--
WHAT ARE WE SAYING?
WHAT DO WE WANT?
REVENGE?
NO! WE ARE NOT TALKING
ABOUT REVENGE.
NO. I AM TALKING
ABOUT JUSTICE.
I'M GONNA GIVE AARON
SO MUCH JUSTICE, HE CAN'T
EVEN SEE STRAIGHT!
IF HE THINKS
HIS PARTNERS
ARE TROUBLE...
YEAH, WELL,
BILL'S ALWAYS
HAD IT EASY.
LET ME TELL YOU
SOMETHING.
BILL'S HAD IT EASY.
EVERY INCH OF THE WAY,
HE'S HAD A WOMAN
TAKING CARE OF HIM.
EXACTLY.
YEAH. AND WHAT WOULD
HAPPEN...ONE DAY...
IF HE DIDN'T?
WHAT DO YOU THINK,
BRENDA? WHAT DO YOU
THINK ABOUT THAT?
Brenda:
I LOVE MORTY.
WHAT?
VERY DEEPLY.
I WOULDN'T WANT
TO SEE HIM HURT
OR--OR HARMED.
YOU DON'T?
I WANT HIM DUMPED!
OH.
BY LITTLE
MISS MIDRIFF.
BY THAT
STAIRMASTERED,
L'OREALED
CROTCH JOCKEY
IN FRONT OF EVERYONE
IN THE WESTERN
HEMISPHERE
ON THE 6:00 NEWS,
OK?
BRENDA!
AND AFTER THAT,
OF COURSE,
I WANT WORLD PEACE.
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S GET SERIOUS.
WE HELPED THEM RISE.
WE CAN HELP THEM FALL.
I DON'T KNOW HOW
WE'RE GONNA DO THAT.
HOW?
YOU KNOW, SHE'S RIGHT.
WE'RE HAS-BEENS.
WE'RE HANGING ON
BY A THREAD.
WE'RE JUST DISCARDS.
WE'RE NOT HANGING ON
BY A THREAD
AND WE'RE DISCARDS!
LOOK AT US!
BY BEING TOGETHER--
US! UNITY!
IF ALL THE FIRST WIVES
OF THE WORLD
GOT TOGETHER,
WHAT ELSE
DO WE NEED?
JUST ONE AMAZING
ATTORNEY.
NO, NO! ALL WE NEED
IS US--THREE WOMEN WHO
AREN'T AFRAID TO FIGHT,
TO STAND UP
FOR OUR DIGNITY!
HUH? FOR
OUR SELF-ESTEEM!
AND THEN WE'LL
LET 'EM HAVE IT.
OK. OK.
SEE THIS?
WHAT?
WAIT. RIGHT HERE.
OK?
OK.
YOU SEE THIS?
PUT IT IN THERE.
ALL RIGHT.
FIRST WIVES CLUB
WILL COME TO ORDER.
Annie: STARTING
THE CLUB WAS EASY.
FIGURING OUT
WHAT TO DO NEXT WAS
CONSIDERABLY HARDER.
WE EACH DECIDED
TO GATHER INFORMATION
ABOUT OUR HUSBANDS.
Brenda: UH, ELISE.
ELISE.
YEAH?
Annie:
I WENT IN SEARCH
OF A SPY.
BUT WHY? WHY CAN'T
WE JUST CALL CHRIS
AND ASK HER
TO HELP US?
I WANT HER TO KNOW
THAT I SUPPORT HER
COMPLETELY
IN HER...
HER LIFESTYLE.
HEY, I'VE NEVER BEEN
TO A GAY BAR BEFORE!
OH, MY GOD!
HERE WE GO! HI!
I THINK YOU'RE JUST--
YOU'RE TERRIFIC!
THERE YOU GO.
OH, YEAH.
THAT'S GOOD.
Elise: OH!
Annie: OH, MY!
LOOK AT THIS!
MY GOD!
OHH!
ISN'T THIS GREAT?
ALL THESE...
WOMEN!
Brenda: YEAH. MAYBE
WE'LL GET LUCKY.
ELISE ELIOT!
RIGHT? I MEAN, LIKE,
FROM THE MOVIES!
YEAH...
I KNEW YOU WERE GAY!
I TOLD EVERYONE.
I SAID, ELISE ELIOT
IS SO HOT.
YOU ARE, LIKE,
THE MOST AMAZING
BABE ON THIS PLANET.
OH, GOD BLESS YOU!
HA HA!
YEAH? SAY, DO YOU,
UH...WANT TO DANCE?
OH...YEAH.
HI, SWEETIE.
HELLO!
MOM!
MOM.
HI, HONEY.
HI!
THOUGHT I'D JUST
COME AND HAVE
A LITTLE--
WHAT--WHAT'S
THE MATTER?
SHE'S A--
ANYWAY, I THOUGHT
WE'D HAVE
A NICE LITTLE CHAT
ABOUT OUR PLANS.
MOM.
MOM,
YOU KNOW YOU'RE
IN A GAY BAR?
I KNOW, HONEY,
AND THAT'S
WHAT'S SO GREAT.
IT'S VERY
WOMAN-IDENTIFIED AND--
OH, BY THE WAY, I, UM...
I'M CHRIS' MOM.
HA HA!
ARE YOU GAY?
[SOBBING]
EXCUSE ME.
I'M SORRY.
[SOBS]
WHAT'S WRONG?
IT'S MY LOVER.
SHE LEFT ME
AFTER 18 YEARS
FOR SOME TEENAGER
WHO WEIGHS 12 POUNDS.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
I'M GONNA DO!
OH, MY GOD!
THAT'S JUST LIKE
ME AND MORTY!
WHO?
MORTY.
SHE'S BUTCH.
NAIL DADDY AND
THOSE OTHER LOWLIFES?
NO, CHRIS, I DON'T
MEAN NAIL THEM.
I MEAN JUST
TEACH THEM AND--
AND HELP THEM.
VAPORIZE THEM.
UH, YEAH. SURE.
YES! YES! YES!
OF COURSE!
OK.
I'M IN.
I'M REALLY IN!
WHOO!
AAH!
AAH! HA HOO!
HEY, PARDON ME.
OW!
OH, DAMN IT!
OH. ELISE?
SOMEBODY JUST
STEPPED ON MY TOE!
Annie: ELISE!
CHRIS IS IN!
WHOO!
CAN YOU
BELIEVE IT?
MISSION ACCOMPLISHED.
WE'D BETTER GO.
YEAH, COME ON.
HEY, HEY.
SHE'S STAYING.
SHE'S WITH ME, BABE.
COME ON, HONEY.
MY PLACE.
OHHH...
OH...
COME ON!
BRENDA, YOU'RE
SO POSSESSIVE!
I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S JUST SOMETHING
I WAS THINKING ABOUT...
YOU KNOW,
FOR MY RéSUMé.
WOULDN'T INTERFERE
WITH SCHOOL.
JUST SOMETHING
PART-TIME
TILL I GRADUATE.
COME ON, DAD.
HOW ABOUT
A LITTLE NEPOTISM?
NO, NO. I--
I'LL HIRE YOU.
I'M--I'M JUST, UH...
I'M SURPRISED.
I MEAN, YOU--YOU...
YOU'VE NEVER SHOWN ANY
INTEREST IN ADVERTISING.
I KNOW, DADDY.
I'M HERE TO LEARN.
GREAT. THAT'S GREAT.
HUH.
[SOUND TRACK PLAYS
MILITARY DRUMS]
Annie: FOR HER PART,
ELISE DECIDED TO PULL THE RUG
OUT FROM UNDER BILL...LITERALLY.
AFTER ALL, IT WAS
HIS LAWYER'S IDEA
THAT SHE DISPOSE
OF THEIR COMMON PROPERTY.
MISS ELIOT, YOU
KNOW HOW HE HATES
TO BE INTERRUPTED.
PLEASE JUST
LET ME TELL HIM
THAT YOU'RE HERE?
MISS ELIOT?
PLEASE? PLEASE?
Bill: OH, YEAH.
ELISE! WHAT A KICK.
BUT I'M ON
WITH THE COAST.
ALL THE GOOD STUFF GOES--
THE LAMPICO,
THE MING VASE,
AMARI HORSEMAN...
THE FABERGé EGGS,
THAT WINGBACK CHAIR,
THAT GREEN
TIFFANY LAMP,
BABE. LISEY.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
WELL, AS PER YOUR REQUEST,
I'M CONSOLIDATING
ALL THE ASSETS
WE'VE ACQUIRED
DURING OUR MARRIAGE
FOR LIQUIDATION.
I THINK
THAT WOULD INCLUDE
ALL OF THESE THINGS.
I BOUGHT YOU
THESE ANTIQUES.
YOU ARE THE BEST.
LOVE TOKENS.
ANNIVERSARY GIFTS.
JUNK! HERE,
TAKE THAT DESK, TOO.
ELISE. THIS HURTS ME.
I CARE ABOUT YOU...
ABOUT US...
ABOUT...ABOUT
THE MAGIC.
WHAT EXACTLY
IS GOING ON HERE?
AND THIS JAPANESE
SECRETARY.
I WANT THAT TO GO.
BACK OFF, JACK-O!
ELISE, THIS ISN'T RIGHT.
IT'S HORMONAL.
YOU CAN'T DO THIS!
WATCH ME.
BUT THIS--
THIS IS MY STUFF!
IT'S THE NINETIES,
BILL.
DOWNSIZE.
[CANTOR SINGS]
Annie: IT WAS
AT JASON'S BAR MITZVAH
TWO WEEKS LATER
THAT THE FIRST WIVES CLUB
GOT ITS FIRST BIG BREAK,
THANKS TO BRENDA'S
DEAR, DEAR SICILIAN UNCLE.
HUH. WHO'S HE?
UNCLE CARMINE.
MY FATHER'S SIDE.
MORTY AND I HAVE BEEN
PLANNING FOR THIS DAY
SINCE JASON WAS BORN.
MORTY'S GOING
TO BE HERE, BRENDA?
BUT NOT NEXT TO ME.
WE'RE NOT A FAMILY
ANYMORE.
WELL...
IT'S OK.
I'LL BE FINE.
EXCUSE ME.
[LOUD GASP]
OH! WHAT?
HE BROUGHT HER...
TO MY SON'S
BAR MITZVAH.
IS SHE A GIFT?
BRENDA,
CAN I SPEAK FREELY?
OH, SURE.
ANNIE'S COOL.
I SPEAK FOR
THE ENTIRE FAMILY
AND YOUR DEAR
DEPARTED FATHER,
MY BELOVED BROTHER,
WHEN I SAY THAT
MORTY IS GARBAGE.
AND IT WOULD BE
AN HONOR TO ME
TO TAKE HIM OUT.
OH! NO. NO.
UNCLE CARMINE, NO.
DON'T YOU DARE.
MORTY THE GARBAGE
IS MY PROBLEM.
I'LL WORK IT OUT
MYSELF SOMEHOW.
THANKS. THANKS
FOR THE THOUGHT
ANYWAY, THOUGH.
OH, MY ANGEL.
FOR MORTY
TO TREAT YOU
THIS WAY
AFTER EVERYTHING
YOUR FATHER
DID FOR HIM.
WHERE
WOULD HE BE
WITHOUT HIM?
YOU KNOW,
THE FIRST YEAR
OF HIS BUSINESS,
EVERY PIECE
OF STOCK
IN HIS STORE
FELL OFF ONE
OF OUR TRUCKS.
OH!
R-REALLY?
YOU'RE NOT...
YOU'RE NOT SERIOUS.
MM-HMM. OH,
WE WERE HAPPY
TO HELP.
YOU WERE
NEWLYWEDS.
MORTY...
MMM.
A CROOK?
MY MORTY?
CHECK HIS BOOKS.
THEY'RE FICTION.
BESTSELLERS.
HA HA!
CIAO.
GRAZIE.
ALL RIGHT.
BYE.
OH! I REALLY LIKED
YOUR UNCLE.
OH, HO HO!
MOTHER! MOTHER!
WHERE ARE YOU?
Bill:
OVER HERE, BITCH.
MOTHER. I MET A MAN.
HE'S AN ANGEL.
HE'S A GOD!
HE'S A DOCTOR!
THAT'S PERFECT.
OH, REALLY?
MMM!
WAIT. SO I...
I REALLY HAVE
THE PART?
OH, BABY,
YOU KNOW IT.
MMM! PIZZA!
MMM!
[DOORBELL BUZZES]
OH, MY GOD!
ELISE!
THERE'S
THE LICHTENSTEIN.
WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOING
HERE? HEY!
THE DYNE.
TAKE THAT.
THIS IS SO COOL!
ALL OF THIS
GYM EQUIPMENT.
ELISE, I'M GETTING
A RESTRAINING ORDER.
NO, BILL,
THIS IS GREAT!
I...ELISE, HI. I'M PHOEBE.
I'VE SEEN ALL YOUR MOVIES,
AND I WANT TO BE
JUST LIKE YOU.
ONLY ME.
PHOEBE, SOME ADVICE.
BE AFRAID.
BE VERY AFRAID.
PHOEB,
SHE'S BITTER.
AND TAKE
THE CAPPUCCINO MACHINE.
OH! BILL!
I HAVE A GREAT IDEA.
WOULDN'T SHE BE GREAT
TO PLAY OPPOSITE ME?
BILL IS PRODUCING THIS
NEW INCREDIBLE MOVIE
WITH THIS YOUNG, HOT
DIRECTOR, AND I'M GONNA
BE THE STAR OF IT.
I'M MONIQUE.
WHAT?
AND YOU CAN BE
MY MOM!
Annie: WHILE ELISE
CLEANED OUT BILL'S OFFICE,
HIS LOFT, AND THEIR HOUSE
IN THE HAMPTONS,
BRENDA AND I LOOKED
FOR AN OFFICE,
A BASE OF OPERATION
FOR THE CLUB.
OH.
WHOA! HI!
HI!
HI, ELISE.
COME ON IN.
HI. HA HA.
I JUST LOVE WHAT
YOU'VE DONE WITH THIS.
IT'S--UHH!
EARLY EVERYTHING, HUH?
OOH! OH, MY GOODNESS,
LOOK AT THIS!
AAH! HA HA! OOH!
KNOW WHAT IT SAYS?
IT SAYS,
"I BEAT MERYL."
IT DOES NOT,
BRENDA!
PUT THAT DOWN.
IS THERE CHOCOLATE
INSIDE?
NO.
PUT IT DOWN.
OK, OK.
PUT IT GENTLY
DOWN.
OK. LOOK AT THIS.
DO YOU BELIEVE
THIS STUFF? HUH?
NO!
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
TO DO WITH IT.
I DIDN'T HAVE ANY ROOM
IN MY WAREHOUSE.
I COULD'VE PUT IT
IN THAT BUILDING
I OWN DOWNTOWN.
YOU OWN A BUILDING?
YEAH, I DO.
I SUB--I SUBLET IT,
NORMALLY,
BUT, UM,
BUT NOW IT'S...
VACANT.
[ALL TALKING
EXCITEDLY AT ONCE]
OHH!
OH, IT'S SO...
IT'S SO...
I DON'T KNOW,
IT'S SOME SORT OF...
COME ON,
LET'S GO ON IN.
THERE'S A LOT OF WORK
TO BE DONE,
AND YOU HAVE TO SEE
THIS OTHER SPACE.
LOOK AT THIS.
HUH?
UH-HUH, OK.
ALL RIGHT, SO...
THIS IS PERFECT.
OH, MY! GIRL!
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
THIS IS THE FABS!
HOW ABOUT THIS?
HOO HOO!
Annie: WHILE BRENDA AND I
WORKED LIKE CRAZY
GATHERING EVERY PIECE
OF INFORMATION WE COULD
LAY OUR HANDS ON,
ELISE SPENT MOST OF HER TIME
ON THE PHONE TO HER AGENT.
DAN CARLIN, PLEASE.
ELISE ELIOT CALLING.
ELISE ELIOT.
Annie: AND FINALLY,
HE CAME THROUGH
FOR HER.
THIS IS A GREAT PLAY.
Brenda: I TOLD HER.
I TOLD HER.
SHE HAD TO DO IT.
I KNOW.
I DON'T WANT
TO DO THEATER.
I HAVEN'T DONE THEATER
IN YEARS.
AND BILL ALWAYS SAID
I SHOULDN'T DO THEATER.
HE DID SAY IT WAS BAD
FOR MY CAREER, WHICH
ACTUALLY I AGREE WITH.
EXCUSE ME, BUT THIS IS
A VERY GREAT PART FOR YOU.
THIS IS ABOUT A BITTER,
UNLOVED,
EMOTIONALLY BARREN WOMAN,
DESPERATE--
Elise:
BUT THAT'S NOT ME.
IT'S YOU!
THANK YOU.
PLEASE...
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
HELLO?
THIS IS BILL.
WHERE'S ELISE?
IT'S FOR YOU.
IT'S BILL.
HELLO?
LISTEN TO ME,
YOU PIECE OF GARBAGE--
OH, I CAN'T HEAR YOU.
I'LL SUE YOU!
I'LL BREAK YOU!
YOU VINDICTIVE
SACK OF SILICONE!
THAT'S MY CAR!
OH, THESE PHONES...
OH, DARN.
HOO HOO HOO!
BILL!
THE LAMBORGHINI!
Annie:
THE LAMBORGHINI.
HE'S MAD.
WHOO!
[GIGGLES]
Brenda: ELISE,
CAN I ASK YOU A QUESTION?
LOOK AT YOU.
AREN'T YOU FRUSTRATED?
YOU CLIMB AND YOU CLIMB,
AND YOU DON'T GET ANYWHERE.
Elise:
OH, I LOVE IT.
IT BURNS
OFF THE BOOZE.
AND YOU WANNA KNOW
SOMETHING?
I TELL YOU,
I GET MY BEST IDEAS
WHEN I'M WORKING OUT.
YOU?
YOU GET IDEAS?
IT CLEARS OUT MY HEAD.
I THINK STRAIGHT.
EVERYTHING JUST MAKES SENSE.
WELL, YOU'D BETTER
START THINKING,
BECAUSE WE NEED MORTY'S BOOKS
TO PROVE FRAUD.
WHERE DO YOU THINK
THEY ARE?
I KNOW WHERE THEY ARE.
MORTY JUST BOUGHT SHELLY
A PENTHOUSE.
WE HAVE TO FIGURE OUT
HOW TO GET IN.
DUARTO.
Annie:
DUARTO?
Elise: YEAH. SHELLY
HAS A NEW APARTMENT.
IT NEEDS TO BE DECORATED.
SHE'S RIGHT.
SHE DOES GET IDEAS.
GUNILLA?
I'D ADORE IT!
ENCHANTé.
AU REVOIR, JOLIE.
[HANGS UP PHONE]
GUNILLA GARSON GOLDBERG
PERSONALLY CALLING ME
TO INVITE ME TO ONE OF
HER SUPERSOCIAL LUNCHEONS.
WHY?
Annie: GUNILLA GOLDBERG
WAS HAPPY TO HELP US
WITH OUR LITTLE PLAN,
SHE BEING
A FIRST WIFE HERSELF.
INDEED,
GUNILLA WAS A FIRST,
SECOND,
THIRD,
AND FOURTH WIFE...
MMM.
WHICH ACCOUNTED FOR
HER VERY COMFORTABLE
SURROUNDINGS.
THIS IS DELICIOUS.
USUALLY I BRING
MY OWN DRESSING--
THAT FAT-FREE
RANCH STUFF--
BUT THIS IS
RESTAURANT QUALITY.
THANK YOU.
CAN I SAY SOMETHING?
WHEN I FIRST GOT
YOUR CALL,
I SAID TO MORTY,
I SAID..."THIS JUST
FEELS SO RIGHT.
ME AND GUNILLA."
SEE, I USED TO WORK
FOR MORTY. I WAS HIS--
I WAS HIS
EXECUTIVE ASSISTANT
BEHIND THE COUNTER.
OF COURSE,
HE WAS MARRIED TO THAT
NIGHTMARE THEN--BRENDA.
I MEAN,
COMPLETELY CLASS-FREE
DUMPSTER WOMAN.
I SAID TO HIM,
"MORTY, YOU'VE GOTTA
MOVE ON AND MOVE UP."
AND NOW...
HERE I AM.
[GIGGLES]
TASTE CENTRAL.
WELL, YOU KNOW,
THE MOMENT I SAW YOU,
MY FIRST IMPRESSION WAS,
I THOUGHT, "SHE'S SOMEONE.
SHE'S SOMETHING."
SEE?
THAT'S WHAT
I TOLD HIM.
BUT HE DOESN'T
GET IT.
HE DOESN'T GET
A LOT OF THINGS.
HMM.
ARE YOU FINISHED?
OH...YEAH.
I'M DONE.
TAKE THE FORK.
AHEM.
FORK.
OH.
YOU KNOW, ALL YOU NEED
TO TAKE YOUR PLACE
IN SOCIETY
IS PERHAPS A FEW WORDS
OF ADVICE, YOU KNOW,
AND A GUIDING HAND.
LIKE SUCH AS WH-WHAT?
WELL, YOU KNOW,
THE CORRECT FLORIST
AND THE UTTERLY IDEAL CHEF.
AND, OF COURSE,
A DECORATOR...
OF DEATH.
OH.
SEE, YOUR HOUSE
IS YOUR CALLING CARD.
IT HAS TO BE PERFECTED.
PHOTOGRAPHED. PUBLISHED.
OH, MY GOD.
CAN YOU REALLY
HELP ME?
I WOULD KILL FOR THAT.
THAT'S UNNECESSARY.
JUS--NO, JUST TWO WORDS...
DUARTO FELIZ.
NOW, HE IS A GENIUS.
A GEM.
OF COURSE, HE'S ALMOST
IMPOSSIBLE TO GET.
HE WORKS ALL THE TIME.
[GASPS]
OH, MY GOD!
Brenda:
THERE SHE IS.
Annie: HUH?
PRINCESS PELVIS.
GUNILLA SAID
SHE WENT FOR IT.
HOW FABULOUS.
ALL RIGHT.
JOHNNY, LET'S GO.
Annie: SO, DUARTO
MAKES HIS MOVE,
AND SHELLY FALLS FOR IT.
NOW, LET'S SYNCHRONIZE
OUR WATCHES.
Brenda: THIS IS JUST LIKE
MISSION: IMPOSSIBLE.
Elise: OH,
THAT WAS A BIG HIT.
YOU KNOW, THESE PEOPLE
ARE ALWAYS LATE.
SHUT UP, MORTY,
AND STAY SHUT, OK?
TAKE IT EASY.
WHAT IF HE DOESN'T
LIKE US? WHAT IF
HE SAYS NO?
[DOORBELL CHIMES]
CALM DOWN. GO AHEAD.
ANSWER THE BELL.
GET THAT.
YEAH, ALL RIGHT.
[SHELLY SIGHS]
OK.
GO AHEAD.
HELLO.
PLEASE...
DO COME IN.
IT'S AN HONOR...
AND BEYOND.
GUNILLA GARSON GOLDBERG
INFORMS ME THAT YOU ARE
MY NEW BEST FRIEND.
OOH, I HOPE.
DUARTO FELIZ.
UM, MAY I?
OH, PLEASE.
EXTRAORDINARY.
[CLOSES DOOR]
INTERESTING LITTLE...
LITTLE TOUCHES EVERYWHERE.
OH!
AAH!
WHAT?
THAT CHAIR IS...
AGONY.
OH, GOD! MORTY,
DO SOMETHING.
WHAT?
COVER IT UP.
JUST GET RID OF IT.
[DUARTO WHIMPERING]
TAKE IT EASY.
Shelly: IT'S HIS CHAIR.
I DIDN'T WANT THAT CHAIR.
IT'S COVERED.
THANKS EVER SO MUCH.
NOW THEN...
YES?
I FEEL...
YOU FEEL...
LIGHT.
OOH.
GET OUT.
WHAT?
I NEED TO BE ALONE
IN THIS SPACE
FOR AN HOUR AT LEAST.
IT IS VERY DELICATE.
I MUST BOND.
[WHISPERING]
We understand.
I MUST HAVE TOTAL ACCESS.
WHAT IS UPSTAIRS?
THAT'S JUST THE OFFICE,
I MEAN, UH...
LE OFFICE.
Morty: STAY OUT
OF LE OFFICE, OK?
LEAVE...ME...
ONE HOUR...
Shelly:
WE UNDERSTAND.
ONE HOUR! ONE HOUR!
THANK YOU!
OOH! BYE-BYE.
[WHISPERING]
Girls...
Girls!
Come on. Hurry.
Brenda: OH, MY KNEE,
DAMN IT!
Elise: WE DON'T HAVE
MUCH TIME.
Annie: NO.
ALL RIGHT, COME ON.
Elise: HONEY, DON'T WORRY.
HURRY. DON'T LOOK.
Annie:
LET'S GO.
Elise: LOOK IN HERE.
OH.
HERE WE GO.
OH!
[SOBBING]
OH.
OH, BRENDA.
[SOBBING]
Duarto: LISTEN, UH,
THERE'S AN OFFICE
UPSTAIRS.
Elise:
LET'S GO UPSTAIRS.
Annie: GOOD GIRL!
UPSTAIRS.
Elise: OH!
OH!
Elise:
I FEEL DIZZY.
Annie:
I'M GONNA GO DOWN.
Brenda: ANNIE,
YOU CHECK THE COMPUTER.
I'LL CHECK THE FILES.
OH, I NEED THE KEY.
WHERE'S THE KEY?
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
HELLO.
Gunilla: READY.
NO.
TAX--COME ON,
TAX RETURNS.
AHH.
HMM.
Annie:
WHAT IS THIS STUFF?
GOT 'EM!
COME ON.
HUSTLE, MORTY.
SOCIAL CLIMBERS
ON THE RISE.
OH, GOD!
THEY'RE BACK!
Brenda:
STALL THEM.
WITH WHAT?
MAKE SOMETHING UP.
IMPROVISE. WHAT'S
THE MATTER WITH YOU?
I'VE BEEN IMPROVISING...
I'M PUTTING THE FILES
RIGHT IN HERE.
KEEP THEM AWAY
FROM THE FRONT DOOR.
[YELLING HYSTERICALLY]
I'M CLEAN! I'M CLEAN!
HELLO.
I KNOW YOU SAID AN HOUR,
BUT I'M FREEZING DOWN THERE.
TELL ME EVERYTHING.
HOW MUCH?
WELL, I TELL YOU WHAT...
WE'RE GONNA LOOK OUT
THE LIVING ROOM WINDOWS.
WHY? BECAUSE
I'LL TELL YOU WHY.
THE WINDOWS ARE THE...EYES
OF OUR ROOM.
Morty: SO?
Shelly: OHH, DUARTO.
Duarto:
THE VALANCE...
THE VALANCE
IS OUR EYEBROWS.
THE DRAPES ARE OUR--
I GOTTA PEE.
OH, NO, YOU CAN'T--
WHERE WAS I?
OH, THE DRAPES,
THE DRAPES...
ARE THE, UH,
THE--THE EYELASHES--
Shelly: BUT I THOUGHT
YOU SAID THE WINDOW...
[WHISPERING]
What do we do?
Where do we go?
Oh...
Look.
The terrace.
Come on.
[SHIVERING]
Woo.
Elise:
WHAT DO WE DO NOW?
Annie: LET'S TALK.
WHAT DO WE DO?
Brenda: UM...
OK, OK.
HUH?
WE'RE GONNA GET
INTO THIS WINDOW
WASHING THING,
AND WE'RE
GOING DOWN.
OH, BRENDA...
AAH!
OH. SHH! SHH!
ANNIE...
SHH! SHH!
WE'VE GOTTA GO DOWN.
THAT'S THE ONLY WAY OUT.
NO, YOU DON'T
UNDERSTAND.
I HAVE A FEAR
OF EVERYTHING.
QUIET.
Brenda: COME ON.
YOU'RE THE NEW ANNIE.
Elise: YES, ANNIE, WATCH.
WATCH, ANNIE, WATCH.
I'M GOING IN FIRST.
I DO ALL MY OWN STUNTS!
COME ON!
Annie: AAH!
SHUT UP! SHUT UP!
Brenda:
GIVE ME THE CONTROLS.
GIVE ME THE CONTROLS!
DEAR GOD!
OH, DEAR GOD!
I CAN'T STAND IT!
AAH! AAH!
AAH!
Duarto: WELCOME
TO MY INSPIRATION.
THE WHITE OF THE SNOW
COATING THE TREES
OF CENTRAL PARK,
THE YELLOW OF THE TAXIS,
THE BLUE--AH!
B-B-B-BUT WHO CARES
ABOUT BLUE?
NO ONE COULD EVER FEEL BLUE
WHEN THEY SEE WHAT I'M
GOING TO DESIGN NEXT.
BUT WHO CARES ABOUT THAT?
WE'VE GOT SOMETHING
TO LOOK AT DOWN HERE.
WHAT ABOUT
THE DRAPES--
THE WINDOW MEETING'S OVER.
TIME TO CONSIDER THE STAIRS.
Morty: WHAT ABOUT
THAT DUMB FOUNTAIN?
Duarto:
WELL, I RATHER LIKE IT.
I'D RATHER LOOK
AT THE WINDOW.
NO!
AAH! AAH!
AAH!
JESUS!
OH, MY GOD!
IS THAT ELISE ELIOT?
ELISE,
YOU LOOK GREAT!
AAH! AAH!
AAH!
[GASPS]
AAH! AAH!
AAH!
Brenda:
GIVE ME THE CONTROL!
AAH! AAH!
AAH!
OH.
OH! OH!
OH!
YOU WANNA GO AGAIN?
Elise:
OH, MY GOD!
Annie: I HAVE NEVER BEEN
SO PETRIFIED IN MY LIFE!
NO. REALLY, REALLY.
UH--OH, OH,
EXCEPT FOR THAT ONE TIME--
NEVER MIND, I'M NOT GONNA
TELL YOU.
WHY NOT? WE'RE NOT
GONNA JUDGE YOU.
OF COURSE NOT.
TELL US.
WE'RE YOUR FRIENDS.
WE LOVE
AND CHERISH YOU.
WE WOULD NEVER, EVER
MAKE FUN OF YOU.
EVER. WOULD WE, HON?
NO, NO.
Annie: ALL RIGHT.
NOW, YOU REMEMBER...
IT WAS CYNTHIA'S BIRTHDAY--
HER 21st, REMEMBER?
OH, YEAH.
OH, NO.
AND HER PARENTS RENTED
THAT BIG HALL.
AND WE WANTED TO DO
SOMETHING SO SPECIAL
FOR HER BIRTHDAY.
AND ELISE THOUGHT
THAT WE SHOULD BE
THE ENTERTAINMENT.
WE WERE SUPPOSED
TO SING TO HER
LIKE A GIRL GROUP.
YEAH,
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE SANG THAT
LESLEY GORE SONG,
REMEMBER?
WE WERE A BIG HIT.
I TOTALLY HATED IT.
I WAS TOTALLY TERRIFIED
IN FRONT OF ALL THOSE PEOPLE.
I'D RATHER
GO UP THAT BUILDING
AND JUST JUMP.
BUT YOU WERE WONDERFUL.
BUT IT WAS FOR CYNTHIA.
Brenda:
I REMEMBER THAT.
WE WERE A GROUP.
WE ARE A GROUP.
WE SHOULD DO IT AGAIN.
WE SHOULD SING AGAIN.
Elise:
LET'S DO IT AGAIN.
I WANNA SING.
WHY NOT?
WE'LL BLEND.
WE'LL SING WITH YOU.
BUT ALL OF US, ALL TOGETHER,
REAL LOUD, OK?
YOU'RE GONNA SING WITH ME,
ALL RIGHT?
TO CYNTHIA.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY,
WHEREVER YOU ARE.
OK. CYNTHIA.
ALL RIGHT.
I'M READY.
[HUMMING]
YEAH.
[HUMMING
MUSICAL SCALE]
GO.
[HUMMING]
PICK A NOTE.
UM...
* YOU DON'T
* YOU DON'T OWN ME
* I'M NOT JUST ONE
OF YOUR MANY TOYS *
* YOU DON'T OWN ME
* DON'T SAY I CAN'T GO
WITH OTHER BOYS *
* BA-BA-BA
BA-BA-BA
DA-DA-DA *
* AND DON'T TELL ME
WHAT TO DO *
WHAT TO SAY *
AAH!
[GIGGLING]
DON'T DO THAT TO ME!
THAT'S JUST HORRIBLE!
I...HATE YOU!
[ANSWERING MACHINE
BEEPS]
Chris: HI, MOM,
IT'S YOUR LITTLE SPY
AT THE AD AGENCY.
I CAN'T REALLY TALK RIGHT NOW,
BUT HAVE I GOT NEWS FOR YOU.
I THINK IT'S TIME
YOU GOT BACK INTO
THE ADVERTISING BUSINESS.
CALL ME.
[BEEP]
Annie: BREN?
BRENDA, ANNIE.
LISTEN TO THIS:
AARON'S PARTNERS WANT
TO SELL THEIR SHARE
OF THE ADVERTISING AGENCY.
I MEAN, IF I COULD--
I COULD BUY THIS
IF I HAD THE MONEY.
CAN YOU IMAGINE?
OH, GOD.
OH, GOD,
AARON WOULD DIE.
[BEEP]
ELISE, THIS IS BRENDA.
ANNIE NEEDS TO MAKE
A DOWN PAYMENT ON
AN ADVERTISING AGENCY.
ANY IDEA WHERE SHE COULD
GET THAT KIND OF MONEY?
Annie: SO ELISE SOLD ME
ALL OF BILL'S THINGS
FOR AN EXTREMELY
REASONABLE PRICE.
AND I, IN TURN,
PUT IT ALL UP FOR AUCTION.
YOUR SALE
HAS GENERATED
A GREAT DEAL
OF EXCITEMENT,
MRS. PARADIS.
WELL, I'M TRYING
TO RAISE FUNDS FOR
MY ORGANIZATION.
HOWEVER, I MUST WARN YOU
THAT SOME LOTS
MAY FAIL TO SELL.
OH, I WOULDN'T WORRY
ABOUT THAT.
Auctioneer:
...AT $380,000 FOR
THE LIECHTENSTEIN.
380,000. SELLING THEN.
FAIR WARNING OF $380,000.
PADDLE 372.
[APPLAUSE]
$380,000 FOR THAT?
LOT 55 IS
THE LOUIS SEIZE CANAPé
SHOWING HERE ON MY LEFT.
AND I HAVE $45,000
ON THE TELEPHONE
TO START THIS NOW.
OH, IT'S GORGEOUS.
OH, FABULOUS.
ABSOLUTELY SUBLIME.
IT DOESN'T LOOK VERY COMFY.
MORTY LIKES HIS RECLINER.
Auctioneer:
...AT $48,000.
50,000 AT THE DESK NOW.
$55,000. THE LADY'S BID
UP FRONT.
OH, MY GOD!
DID YOU SEE WHO BID?
THAT'S--THAT'S ELISE ELIOT!
Gunilla: OH, YES. SHE
HAS IMPECCABLE TASTE...
FOR AN ACTRESS.
AT $55,000.
A WARNING THEN
AT $55,000...
IT'S A FABULOUS CHAISE.
OH, I DON'T KNOW.
WITH THAT SOFA,
ARCHITECTURAL DIGEST.
THE COVER!
REALLY?
OH, YOU?
GUARANTEED.
$60,000 THIS SIDE.
NEW BIDDER NOW AT 60,000
AND SELLING THAT THEN.
NOT YOURS HERE, MADAM.
IT'S $60,000.
TO YOU, MADAM, $60,000.
[APPLAUSE]
Shelly:
I GOT A CHAISE.
BEAUTIFUL.
AHH! OK.
Auctioneer: LOT 57,
THE FINE YUNG CHING CHARGER
SHOWING HERE.
AND $90,000 TO START.
90,000 IS BID.
THANK YOU, SIR.
$100,000.
NEW BIDDER NOW.
$110,000 THE LADY'S
BID HERE NOW. 110.
$115,000.
THANK YOU, SIR.
$115,000 NOW.
IT'S CUTE...
OH, GOD,
IT'S SUBLIME.
ESSENTIAL...
OXYGEN.
Auctioneer: 120.
$125,000.
Annie: 125.
Auctioneer:
IN A NEW PLACE NOW.
125,000 UP FRONT.
$130,000.
THAT ELISE ELIOT.
SHE MUST BE VERY RICH.
SHOW BUSINESS.
TEACH HER A LESSON.
COME ON. COME ON.
Auctioneer: 130.
FAIR WARNING THEN.
AT $130,000. 130.
135,000 AT THE BACK!
NEW BIDDER NOW AT $135,000.
135,000.
LADY'S BID AT THE BACK.
Shelly: HEY, WHO'S SHE?
SHE LOOKS FAMILIAR.
IT'S JUST SOMEONE
VERY, VERY GLAMOROUS.
PROBABLY EURO-TRASH.
SHELLY, I FORBID YOU
TO LET THAT PLATE
LEAVE THE COUNTRY.
IT'S JAPANESE.
DON'T THEY
HAVE ENOUGH?
135,000.
THE BID IS HERE
AT THE BACK.
AT 135,000...
OH!
Auctioneer:
LADY'S BID AT THE BACK.
135,000...
135,000 FOR THIS
AT THE BACK...
GO AHEAD.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
JACKIE O
HAD ONE JUST LIKE IT.
Auctioneer: 135,000...
$140,000 UP FRONT NOW!
$140,000...
HERE AGAIN
AND AGAINST YOU AT THE BACK.
140,000.
140,000...
SELLING IT THEN...
FOR YOU, MADAM.
PADDLE 560.
Shelly: WHOO!
THANK YOU.
Morty: SHELLY,
WHAT--WHAT HAPPENED HERE?
$140,000 FOR A PLATE?!
$47,000 FOR A CARPET,
A USED CARPET?
$300,000
FOR A LAMBORGHINI!
ARE YOU CRAZY?
I BOUGHT THE CAR
FOR YOU.
IT WAS
ONLY 300 GRAND.
IT WAS A GIFT!
WITH MY MONEY
YOU BOUGHT IT.
I BOUGHT ME THE GIFT.
JESUS, MORTY,
ALL I WANT IS
A LIFESTYLE.
WITH SOME AMBIANCE
AND--AND SOME CLASSIC,
ETERNAL GOOD TASTE.
BUT NOT FOR $300,000,
SHELLY!
WELL, I CAN LEAVE
IF YOU LIKE.
IT'S NOT LIKE...
YOU'VE ASKED ME
TO MARRY YOU.
WOULD YOU...
UNZIP ME?
UH-HUH.
THANK YOU.
SHELL,
I--I LOST MY TEMPER.
I'M SORRY.
THE LAMBORGHINI
IS A VERY GOOD DEAL.
Brenda: HI, JASE.
HOW WAS THE GAME?
THE KNICKS LOSE AGAIN.
OH. EVERY PLAYER
ON THAT TEAM'S
A MILLIONAIRE.
THEY CAN'T REALLY LOSE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
THAT'S NOT NEW,
IS IT?
IT'S BETTER THAN NEW!
IT'S THE FIRST TIME
I'VE BEEN ABLE TO GET
INTO IT IN THREE YEARS!
LOOK AT ME.
I HAVE A WAIST.
I HAVE LEGS. WHO KNEW?
HOW'S YOUR FATHER?
DID YOU HAVE FUN?
YEAH, BUT DON'T
LET THAT BOTHER YOU.
WHAT AN EVIL THING
TO SAY.
JASON, LOOK,
I--I--I REMEMBER
WHAT IT WAS LIKE
WHEN WE WERE A FAMILY.
IT WAS GREAT.
BUT EVEN THOUGH
WE'RE NOT TOGETHER
ANYMORE,
YOU STILL HAVE
BOTH OF US.
YOU GUYS CAN'T EVEN
PICK OUT MY BIRTHDAY CARD
WITHOUT A LAWYER.
JASON, I KNOW YOU WORRY
ABOUT YOUR FATHER.
HE'S A...
HE'S A VERY GOOD MAN.
HE'S A VERY GOOD,
VERY CONFUSED...
MAN.
AND--AND I KNOW
YOU WORRY ABOUT ME.
BUT YOU DON'T HAVE TO,
BECAUSE I'M GOING
TO BE FINE.
I'M LIGHTENING UP--
LITERALLY.
AND YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOUR FATHER AND I,
WE LOVE YOU
TO PIECES.
OK?
THERE. DID I
EMBARRASS YOU ENOUGH?
ALMOST.
WANNA GO TO A MOVIE?
ME AND YOU?
TOGETHER?
IN PUBLIC?
MOM, I'M SORRY.
I GUESS I WAS JUST
A LITTLE FREAKED OUT
ABOUT DAD GETTING
ENGAGED TO SHELLY.
OH, WELL...
YEAH, I--I CAN SEE
WHERE THAT WOULD
RIP YOUR HEART OUT.
THANKS, MOM.
WE GOTTA NAIL BILL.
WE GOTTA...
[SLURRED VOICE]
SLAUGHTER HIM.
RIGHT OFF THE FACE
OF THE PLANET.
HIM AND THAT TRAMP.
THAT INFANT.
I NEED A DRINK.
Brenda: OH, LORD,
SHE'S LOADED.
BRENDA, I'M WORRIED.
SHE HAD ME LOOK AT
BILL'S RECORDS,
AND THE GUY'S A SAINT.
HE'S CLEAN.
HE'S A SAINT
WITH A GREAT LAWYER.
THAT'S ALL.
WHAT?
WHAT? HUH?
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING,
YOU CAN'T FIND ANYTHING
ON HIM?
ELISE, I'M SORRY.
I'M GOING TO LOOK AGAIN.
THIS ISN'T FAIR, MAN.
AARON'S GONNA BE MASSACRED,
MORTY'S NOT GONNA KNOW
WHAT HIT HIM,
AND BILL'S JUST GONNA
WALK AWAY...
WITH ALIMONY!
WELL, WE'RE JUST GOING
TO KEEP TRYING, ELISE.
YOU'D BETTER KEEP TRYING,
BECAUSE THIS IS MY LIFE, OK,
AND MY MONEY!
WHAT DO YOU KNOW?
YOU DON'T GET IT.
YOU'RE...CIVILIANS.
I MEAN, YOU'RE JUST...
HOUSEWIVES.
THAT'S IT.
NO, WAI--
Elise:
YOU'LL NEVER UNDERSTAND.
GIMME THAT.
EXCUSE ME.
GIVE THAT BACK.
I'M SAYING THIS TO YOU
WITH LOVE, COMPASSION,
AND THE SPIRIT
OF TRUE SISTERHOOD.
YOU ARE FULL OF SHIT!
WHAT?
SO, OK,
ALIMONY SUCKS.
OK, YOU DIDN'T GET
TO PLAY A POLICEWOMAN
IN A WONDERBRA.
BUT LOOK AT YOU!
YOU GREW UP GORGEOUS!
AND THANKS TO CHER'S
PIONEERING EFFORTS,
YOU STILL
HAVEN'T HIT PUBERTY!
AND ONCE UPON A TIME,
YOU WERE A TERRIFIC ACTRESS!
YOU'VE EVEN GOT AN OSCAR
TO PROVE IT!
YOU SPENT YOUR WHOLE
LIFE WITH PEOPLE
SUCKING UP TO YOU!
I'M SURE ANNIE
WILL AGREE WITH ME
WHEN I SAY YOUR PERCEPTION
OF LIFE IS SOMEWHAT ALTERED!
WHAT?
ANNIE, DO YOU
AGREE WITH HER?
HUH?
COME ON!
OH, UH--
WELL, I DON'T--BRENDA,
SHE'S VERY UPSET.
TWO PINHEADS!
WHAT?
WAIT!
WAIT A MINUTE!
YOU'VE GOT SOME NERVE!
I DRINK BECAUSE
I AM A SENSITIVE AND
HIGHLY-STRUNG PERSON!
NO, THAT'S WHY
YOUR CO-STARS DRINK.
I AM NOT A DRUNK!
OH, REALLY? LET'S
EXAMINE THE EVIDENCE.
LOOK! ALL BOTTLES!
[GLASS CLINKING]
AND GALLON JUGS!
I HAD GUESTS!
WHO? GUNS 'N' ROSES?
COME ON, YOU TWO.
NOW, COME ON NOW.
THE ENEMY IS OUT THERE,
IT'S NOT IN HERE,
AND I THOUGHT
WE WERE FRIENDS.
OH, REALLY?
I THOUGHT WE WERE
BEST FRIENDS.
OH, YEAH? AFTER
ALL THOSE YEARS?
YOU NEVER
CALLED ME.
WELL...
YOU'RE UNLISTED.
AND YOU ALWAYS GOSSIP
BEHIND MY BACK!
OH, YOU DESERVE IT!
YOU DIDN'T INVITE ME TO
YOUR SON'S BAR MITZVAH!
YOU WOULDN'T
HAVE COME!
YEAH! IT WAS
IN HEBREW.
AAH!
OH, SHUT UP!
YOU THINK JUST BECAUSE
I'M A MOVIE STAR,
I DON'T HAVE FEELINGS!
WELL, YOU'RE WRONG!
I DO HAVE FEELINGS!
I'M AN ACTRESS!
I HAVE ALL OF THEM!
WELL, I WOULDN'T
UNDERSTAND.
YOU SEE, I'M JUST
A POOR LITTLE HOUSEWIFE
IN A LITTLE APRON
WITH A LITTLE CHILD
TO RAISE!
YEAH, YOU WERE ALWAYS
JEALOUS OF ME,
EVEN IN COLLEGE,
BECAUSE I WAS BLONDE AND
BEAUTIFUL AND TALENTED
AND I COULD HAVE
ANY GUY I WANTED!
AND DID! EVERY GUY!
MOST OF THE SENIOR CLASS
AND HALF THE FACULTY!
WELL, IT WAS
THE SIXTIES.
OH! LOOK AT THIS PLACE!
IS THIS WHERE
YOUR FAN CLUB MEETS?
DO YOU HAVE
RITUAL SACRIFICES?
OHH!
PUT THAT DOWN!
I WON THAT!
I REMEMBER!
YOUR FIRST TALKIE.
YEAH? WHAT DID
YOU EVER WIN?
A PIE-EATING CONTEST?
BEST DIGESTION?
OH!
AAH!
OH, NO!
BRENDA! THIS IS
A GOLDEN GLOBE!
IT'S SACRED!
OH!
IT'S TRADEMARKED!
ARE YOU CRAZY?!
STOP IT, BOTH OF YOU!
JUST STOP THIS
RIGHT THIS MINUTE!
WHAT?
ANNIE!
YOU CHOOSE!
WHO'S YOUR FRIEND?
WHAT?
ME OR BRENDA?
YEAH! FOR ONCE
IN YOUR LIFE,
MAKE A DECISION!
WHO'S YOUR BUDDY?
SOME BEVERLY HILLS
SCIENCE PROJECT?
OR A WOMAN
WITH HER OWN AISLE
AT THE SUPERMARKET?
Annie: WELL, I'M SORRY,
BUT I'M NOT GETTING
INVOLVED WITH THIS!
YOU BOTH HAVE SEVERE
PSYCHOLOGICAL PROBLEMS,
AND I--SEE, I'M--I'M--
I'M THE NICE ONE HERE!
I'M--I'M NOT LIKE THIS!
WHAT?
THE NICE ONE?
YES!
HA HA HA!
WELL,
I MEAN, I--
OH, MY GOD!
EXCUSE ME?
YOU MEAN
THE RAG MOP,
DON'T YOU?
I MEAN, THE ONE THAT
CAN'T MANAGE A SIMPLE
DECLARATIVE SENTENCE?
THE WIMP?
THE WUSS?
WELL, I...I'VE CHANGED,
AND I'M MUCH STRONGER
THAN I USED TO BE.
Elise: OH, YOU
ARE SELF-RIGHTEOUS!
YOU PIPSQUEAK!
OH, SHUT UP, YOU
ARTHRITIC SEX KITTEN!
OH, SHUT UP,
MORTY'S GIRL!
ALL YOU CARE ABOUT
IS MORTY--
MONIQUE'S MOM!
STOP IT! YOU'RE BOTH
SELFISH ASSHOLES!
AAH!
NO!
OH, MY FACE!
OH, MY GOD!
THAT IS ENOUGH!
HAVE WE FORGOTTEN WHAT
WE'RE DOING HERE?
WHAT HAS HAPPENED TO US?
I THOUGHT WE WERE SUPPOSED
TO BE HELPING EACH OTHER,
NOT RIPPING
EACH OTHER TO SHREDS!
SHE'S RIGHT.
[DOOR SLAMS]
YOU KNOW, I GOTTA
SAY, I--I ALWAYS
WONDERED,
HOW DRUNK DO YOU
THINK CYNTHIA WAS
WHEN SHE DECIDED
TO DO A JACKKNIFE
ONTO PARK AVENUE?
* MMM
* YEAH
* SUDDENLY ALONE
* AND MY TEARS ARE
ALL THAT FIND ME *
* IT'S GONNA TAKE
SOME TIME TO FORGET *
* 'CAUSE EVERYTHING
YOU KNOW *
* IS LYING BROKEN
ALL AROUND YOU *
[VACUUM ROARS]
* MY HEART IS ONLY
FILLED WITH REGRET *
* BUT I'VE GOT TO LET GO
OF THE HEARTACHE *
* OH, YEAH, YEAH
* GOTTA HOLD ON
AND TRY TO BELIEVE *
* LOVE IS ON THE WAY
* ON WINGS OF ANGELS
* I KNOW IT'S TRUE
* I'LL GET OVER YOU
* LOVE IS ON THE WAY
* TIME IS TURNING
THE PAGES *
* I DON'T KNOW WHEN
* BUT LOVE
WILL FIND ME AGAIN... *
OH, MOM...
WHAT'S WRONG?
I CAME RIGHT OVER.
OH, IT'S JUST THINGS
ARE NOT WORKING OUT
THE WAY I PLANNED.
AND YOU CALLED ME?
OH, MY GOD.
* I AM NOT AFRAID
* OF THE MYSTERY
OF TOMORROW *
* I HAVE FOUND THE FAITH
* DEEP WITHIN
I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S JUST COMPLETELY,
YOU KNOW, FALLEN APART,
AND WE'RE AT
EACH OTHER'S
THROATS,
AND I FEEL LIKE...
IT'S JUST LIKE
IT'S ALL MY FAULT.
I'M JUST USELESS.
Chris: YOU ARE NOT.
HONEY, I AM.
I'M REALLY--
MOM, NO.
NO, NO, FOR
THE PAST FEW WEEKS,
YOU'VE BEEN A TOTALLY
DIFFERENT PERSON.
YEAH?
YOU'VE STOPPED APOLOGIZING
FOR YOURSELF ALL THE TIME.
I KNOW.
I'M SORRY, HONEY.
IT'S JUST THIS WHOLE
FIRST WIVES CLUB THING,
IT JUST--IT CAN'T WORK,
AND YOU KNOW WHAT?
IT JUST--IT NEVER
COULD WORK.
YOU MAKE IT WORK. YOU CAN.
YOU CAN MAKE IT WORK.
WHAT?
CALL THEM.
CALL BRENDA AND ELISE.
I CAN'T CALL THEM!
WHAT AM I GONNA
SAY TO THEM?
THIS IS JUST--
I'M TELLING YOU,
I SHOULD'VE SEEN THIS.
I SHOULD HAVE
SEEN THIS COMING.
WHAT?
I KNOW.
WHY DON'T YOU WRITE
EACH OF THEM A NICE NOTE?
OR MAYBE SEND
A HANGING PLANT?
JUST A SUGGESTION.
NO, MOM. UH-UH.
NO, IT'S OVER.
IT'S OVER.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
BRENDA...
I DON'T WANT
TO BE LIKE CYNTHIA.
OHH...OHH.
I'M SORRY.
IT'S OK. IT'S OK.
COME ON IN.
OH, I'VE NEVER BEEN
TO YOUR APARTMENT.
I KNOW.
IT'S SO REAL.
[DOOR SLAMS]
Elise and Brenda:
ANNIE? ANNIE?
ANNIE!
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING?
WELL, ELISE,
IT'S YOUR LOFT,
AND I'M JUST STORING
THESE THINGS,
OR I'LL BURN THEM
IF YOU WANT.
B-B-BUT WHY?
WHY?
ARE YOU KIDDING?
WE HAVE JUST COMPLETELY
EMBARRASSED OURSELVES.
WE'VE BECOME EXACTLY
WHAT THE WORLD
THINKS WE ARE.
AND OUR EX-HUSBANDS!
WE ARE THE THREE WITCHES!
WITCHES?
WELL--WELL, I'LL
TELL YOU SOMETHING.
WHAT?
WITCHES HAVE POWERS.
WELL, THEY DO.
THEY HAVE POWERS
FOR GOOD AND FOR EVIL.
ANNIE, BRENDA AND I
ARE OK NOW.
WE'VE BEEN TALKING,
AND WE FIGURED OUT--
AND WE THINK WE KNOW
WHAT WENT WRONG.
OH, I KNOW WHAT
WENT WRONG!
THIS WHOLE CRACKPOT
IDEA WENT WRONG!
LOOK, REVENGE AND EGOS
AND ALL OF US
THINKING WE COULD
FIX OUR SILLY LIVES!
NO! EXACTLY! WE WERE
THINKING TOO SMALL.
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
WE WERE JUST TRYING
TO GET BACK AT
OUR EX-HUSBANDS,
WHICH IS A START,
BUT IT ISN'T ENOUGH.
IT'S SO PETTY.
IT'S SO LIMITED.
IT'S NO WONDER
WE'RE SNARLING
AT EACH OTHER.
NO WONDER WE'RE
AT EACH OTHER'S
THROATS!
LISTEN! WE HAVE
TO TAKE OUR PLAN
AND EXPAND IT!
FIRST THING, WE TAKE
CARE OF OUR OWN GUYS
BECAUSE THEY REALLY
HAVE IT COMING,
AND THEN...
THEN WE GO GLOBAL!
ARE YOU REALLY
INTERESTED?
HOW?
'CAUSE IF YOU ARE,
I'LL TELL YOU.
I DON'T KNOW
IF I'M INTERESTED.
WHAT IF WE ERUPT AGAIN?
OH, ELISE, WHAT IF
YOU START DRINKING,
AND BRENDA, YOU START
SNIPING AWAY?
DONE THAT.
BEEN THERE.
IT'S NOT ENOUGH
FOR ME.
ANNIE, TAKE
A GOOD LOOK
AT ELISE.
LOOK AT HER!
I'M SOBER,
AND I'M GONNA DO THE PLAY.
REALLY?
MM-HMM.
AND I'M GONNA BE
IN THE FRONT ROW
OPENING NIGHT.
THANKS.
FRIENDSHIP IS
EVERYTHING, ANNIE.
DON'T LEAVE.
I MEAN, WE CAN'T
FALL APART NOW!
BUT EVEN IF WE WANT TO,
WE DON'T HAVE
ENOUGH INFORMATION.
OF COURSE,
WE DO HAVE STUFF
ON AARON AND MORTY,
BUT WHAT ABOUT BILL?
I MEAN, ELISE,
YOU'RE STILL
AT SQUARE ONE.
NO, NOT EXACTLY.
I MEAN, YOU KNOW, I MEAN,
I'LL ADMIT THAT SO FAR,
EVERYTHING HE'S DONE HAS
BEEN COMPLETELY LEGAL.
AS FAR AS HE KNOWS.
YEAH!
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WELL, IT'S ALL
A QUESTION OF ANGLES.
ARE YOU IN?
ARE YOU BACK?
TALK.
WELL...
THANK YOU.
AFTER YOU.
SO, HERE'S
HOW IT GOES.
THIS HAS TO BE
JUST BETWEEN US,
BUT I AM
SERIOUSLY THINKING
OF TAKING THE ROLE
OF MONIQUE'S MOM.
OH!
AND I'VE JUST BEEN
THINKING ABOUT,
YOU KNOW, WHO SHE IS...
WHAT SHE'S ALL ABOUT...
AND YOU KNOW,
I'M SURE YOU'RE
DOING THE SAME THING
WITH MONIQUE.
OH, SURE! I MEAN, I-I'VE
BEEN THINKING LIKE...
STREAKS...
JUST AROUND MY FACE.
OH. YEAH.
AND WHAT
A BEAUTIFUL FACE.
THANKS.
ANYWAY, THE REASON
I CALLED YOU
IS BECAUSE IF WE'RE
GONNA WORK TOGETHER,
I THINK THAT WE SHOULD
GET TO KNOW ONE ANOTHER.
IT'S IMPORTANT.
BILL IS SO WRONG.
YOU ARE NOT SATAN.
OH, STOP.
DO YOU NEED A TV?
OR A VCR?
OR A PERSONAL COMPUTER?
WHO IS THE FIRST NAME
IN TOP-QUALITY, LOW-COST
APPLIANCES?
WHY, LET'S ASK
THIS BEAUTIFUL
YOUNG LADY HERE!
EXCUSE ME, MA'AM?
WHY, HELLO.
HI.
HELLO.
I'M IN THE MARKET
FOR A LOW-QUALITY,
TOP-COST APPLIANCE.
Director: CUT!
WHAT HAPPENED?
SHELLY...
A TOP-QUALITY,
LOW-COST!
OOH! OOH!
MORTON CUSHMAN?
TOP-QUALITY--
YEAH?
WHAT? YEAH?
YOU HAVE THE RIGHT
TO REMAIN SILENT--
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
I'M SHOOTING A COMMERCIAL!
Shelly:
WHAT IS THIS?
HEY! I'M SHOOTING
A COMMERCIAL HERE!
FEDERAL MARSHALS ACTING
ON BEHALF OF THE I.R.S.
HEY, BARRY,
CALL MY LAWYER!
Annie: ON NOVEMBER 28,
AT EXACTLY 1400 HOURS,
OPERATION HELL'S FURY
SWUNG INTO ACTION.
[MUFFLED YELLING]
GOOD MORNING.
HI.
HOW'S MY DAY
SHAPING UP?
OHH, POOR DADDY.
IT'S GONNA BE HELL.
YOUR 9:00'S WAITING
IN THE CONFERENCE ROOM.
OKEY-DOKEY.
SO, LET'S SEE.
WHAT DID I SAY HERE NOW?
WE WILL ALSO BILL YOUR
EXPENSES INCURRED INCLUDING
BUT NOT LIMITED TO--
WHAT IS THIS?
Secretary:
OH, OH, MISS ELIOT?
UH, PLEASE,
I'M BEGGING YOU,
PLEASE?
BRETT, WE LOVE
THE NEW DRAFT.
YEAH, PHOEBE'S
CRAZY ABOUT IT.
SHE'S GONNA READ IT.
HUH? ELISE, I'M TRYING
TO MAKE A MOVIE HERE.
HOLD YOUR CALLS.
THAT WAS A VERY
IMPORTANT PHONE CALL!
AND WHERE'S
MY FIRST CHECK?
JUST SIT DOWN
AND SHUT UP.
OK?
NOW, LET'S TAKE
A MEETING.
HELLO, SUNSHINE.
WELCOME.
THIS IS KIDNAPPING.
I WILL CRUCIFY YOU.
YOU WANT TO TALK
CRUCIFIXION?
HAPPY EASTER,
MORTY.
BIG DEAL.
LETTERS FROM
BRENDA'S FATHER
ABOUT STOCKING
YOUR STORES WITH
STOLEN MERCHANDISE.
WHAT DO THEY CALL IT
IN THE TABLOIDS?
HOT STUFF.
YEAH.
CRIMINAL ACTIVITY?
YOU SHOULD BE ASHAMED.
WAKE UP...
AND SMELL THE AUDIT.
AARON, I JUST HAD
A LITTLE TALK
WITH ERIC AND MARK,
AND IT SEEMS THE BUSINESS
IS VERY DYSFUNCTIONAL.
SORT OF LIKE OUR MARRIAGE.
SO...
I BOUGHT THEM OUT.
WHAT?
YEAH. I THINK
WE PROBABLY
OUGHT TO GO.
WHAT DO YOU
THINK?
THAT'S
A GOOD IDEA.
GOOD-BYE, ERIC.
ANNIE, GOOD LUCK
TO YOU.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
IT'S A PLEASURE.
ANNIE...
OH, MARK.
LOVE YOU.
[CHUCKLES]
I DO LOVE
THAT SUIT.
YOU--YOU COULDN'T
POSSIBLY PULL OFF
SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
WHERE WOULD YOU COME UP
WITH THIS KIND OF MONEY?
Elise: AS PER
OUR AGREEMENT,
I SOLD OUR ASSETS
TO A FRIEND OF MINE.
HERE'S YOUR HALF.
50 CENTS?
CONSIDERING OUR
HISTORY TOGETHER,
I THOUGHT A DOLLAR
WAS TERRIBLY FAIR.
OH, ALL RIGHT.
TAKE IT ALL.
SO, WHAT DO
YOU WANT? MONEY?
EVERY CENT.
YOU'RE OUT
OF YOUR MIND!
WELL, YOU CAN HAND
IT OVER AND LIVE
HAPPILY EVER AFTER,
OR YOU CAN GIVE IT
TO THE GOVERNMENT
AND GET 10 TO 20.
MAYBE DUARTO
CAN DO YOUR CELL.
"I SEE...BARS."
YOU CAN'T DO
THIS TO ME.
OH, BUT I HAVE
DONE IT TO YOU.
YOU WOULDN'T.
YOU...COULDN'T.
WELL, IT SEEMS
I COULD AND I DID.
OH, AND YOU KNOW
WHAT, AARON?
I FORGOT HOW MUCH
FUN WORK CAN BE.
LOOK, IF YOU TRY
TO TAKE MY AGENCY
FROM ME, I'LL WALK.
I'LL TAKE ALL
MY CLIENTS WITH ME.
BE MY GUEST.
I'M NOT KIDDING,
ANNIE!
I WILL TAKE EVERY
SINGLE ACCOUNT.
THIS PLACE,
WITHOUT ME...
WOULD BE WORTHLESS.
OH, I DON'T
THINK SO, BABE.
OH, REALLY?
NOT AFTER THE NEW
$45 MILLION ACCOUNT
I JUST LANDED.
NEW ACCOUNT?
WHAT ACCOUNT?
MORTY'S ELECTRONICS
WILL BE UNDER
MY CONTROL.
ADVERTISING,
MARKETING STRATEGIES,
EVERYTHING.
YOU WILL STAY
ON AS PRESIDENT
BECAUSE AFTER ALL,
YOU ARE MORTY.
YOU WILL RECEIVE
A SALARY
WHICH WILL KEEP YOU
IN THE LIFESTYLE
TO WHICH I THINK
YOU SHOULD BECOME
ACCUSTOMED.
MORTY, I DON'T SEE
WHAT ELSE YOU CAN DO.
IT'S THIS...OR JAIL.
SO I DUMPED YOU
FOR ANOTHER WOMAN.
GET OVER IT.
LIFT SOMETHING.
WAX SOMETHING.
HAVE SOMETHING
PEELED.
YOU'RE RIGHT...
I HATE TO ADMIT IT,
BUT I'M--I'M JEALOUS.
MISS LaVELLE IS
ABSOLUTELY GORGEOUS.
SHE'S A BRIGHT
NEW STAR.
INTERESTED, ELISE?
WANT TO DRINK
HER BLOOD?
HOW OLD IS SHE,
BILL?
25? 26?
21.
YEAH...
IN ABOUT 5 YEARS.
SHE'S 16.
WHAT?
2 YEARS AGO,
SHE DROPPED OUT OF
A LITTLE HIGH SCHOOL
IN NEWKIRK, IDAHO.
SHOULD HAVE DONE
YOUR HOMEWORK, BILL.
I DID.
OH, A COPY OF HER
BIRTH CERTIFICATE.
OH, GOD.
I DIDN'T KNOW.
OH, MY GOD. WHAT
ARE YOU GONNA DO?
OH...WHAT AM I
GONNA DO?
WELL...RIGHT NOW,
I'M JUST GOING TO
USE THE "F" WORD.
FELONY.
I THINK WE SHOULD
CONTINUE THIS DISCUSSION
IN MY OFFICE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
IN YOUR OFFICE?
IS THAT ALL
YOU CAN DO?
THINK OF YOURSELF,
YOURSELF, YOURSELF?
IF YOU GO
THROUGH WITH THIS,
I'LL HAVE NOTHING.
OHH.
LOOK, EVERYONE
IN TOWN IS LOOKING
FOR THE NEW GUY.
HOW CAN I COMPETE?
WHO THE HELL'S
GONNA WANT ME?
I'M 46 YEARS OLD.
I'D HAVE TO START
FROM SCRATCH.
I KNOW JUST
HOW YOU FEEL.
OH, AARON...
GROW FROM LOVE.
OH, I DON'T HATE YOU.
I WISH I COULD,
BUT YOU'RE STILL
KIND OF CUTE
FOR AN OVERBEARING,
CRADLE-ROBBING,
SPANDEX-SUCKING
CRIMINAL.
SO, I'M NOT GONNA
TAKE ALL YOUR MONEY.
OH, DON'T MISUNDERSTAND.
I'M GOING TO TAKE PLENTY.
AND I'M GONNA HANG
ONTO THESE 'CAUSE I'VE
GOT A FAVOR TO ASK.
BE THERE IN 2 HOURS.
WHILE WE WERE MARRIED,
I HELPED YOU.
NOW IT'S YOUR TURN
TO HELP OTHERS.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
TO SEE
BARBARA WALTERS.
OH, MY GOD!
SCARED?
YOU'RE NOT GONNA TALK
ABOUT THIS, ARE YOU?
WELL, THAT
DEPENDS ON YOU.
BE THERE AT THAT ADDRESS
IN 2 HOURS.
BABE.
Annie: YOU SEE, WHAT BRENDA
MEANT BY THINKING GLOBALLY
WAS THAT IT SIMPLY
WASN'T ENOUGH TO MAKE
OUR FORMER HUSBANDS SUFFER.
TO DO THE TRULY
CHARITABLE, UNSELFISH THING,
WE WOULD HAVE TO MAKE THEM
SUFFER OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
SO, WHAT ARE
YOU GUYS IN FOR?
GENTLEMEN...
AND DADDY.
HONEY?
HMM?
CAN YOU TELL ME
WHAT'S GOING ON?
I--I DON'T THINK
I CAN TAKE ANY MORE
SURPRISES TODAY.
OHH.
OH, DADDY?
I'M A LESBIAN...
A BIG ONE.
GENTLEMEN,
WE'VE GATHERED
YOU HERE TODAY
FOR A VERY
SPECIFIC REASON.
THIS IS NOT ABOUT
RETALIATION,
NEGOTIATION,
AND THIS IS NOT ABOUT
MEN VERSUS WOMEN.
YEAH? WELL,
WHAT IS IT THEN?
I'M GETTING SICK
OF THIS, OK?
PLEASE DON'T
MAKE HER MAD.
Elise: NO, NO, NO.
THIS IS NOT A REVENGE THING.
THIS IS
ABOUT JUSTICE.
HALFWAY THROUGH
THIS OPERATION,
WE REALIZED THAT
THE ONLY PEOPLE
THAT WOULD BE HELPED
BY REVENGE WOULD BE US.
AND THEN WE'D BE
NO BETTER THAN YOU.
Brenda: HAPPIER,
BUT NO BETTER.
EXHILARATED,
ECSTATIC,
BUT NO BETTER.
SO WE THOUGHT AGAIN.
A VERY DEAR
FRIEND OF OURS
DIED FROM NEGLECT.
AND YOU'RE GOING TO HELP
US MAKE VERY SURE THAT
THAT NEVER HAPPENS AGAIN.
LIKE HELL
WE ARE!
YOU CAN'T MAKE
US DO ANYTHING.
NO...BUT VITO CAN.
AND JOEY CAN.
AND UNCLE
CARMINE CAN!
WHAT DO WE HAVE TO DO?
YOU HAVE TO PAY.
OH!
OH, MY GOD!
HA HA!
* NOW, THERE WAS A TIME
* WHEN THEY USED TO SAY
* THAT BEHIND
EVERY GREAT MAN *
* THERE HAD
TO BE A GREAT WOMAN *
* NOW THEN, THESE
TIMES HAVE CHANGED *
* YOU KNOW THAT
IT'S NO LONGER TRUE *
* SO, WE'RE COMING
OUT OF THE KITCHEN *
* 'CAUSE THERE'S SOMETHING
WE FORGOT TO SAY TO YOU *
* IT'S THAT SISTERS ARE
DOIN' IT FOR THEMSELVES *
* STANDING ON
THEIR OWN TWO FEET *
* AND RINGING ON
THEIR OWN BELLS *
* IT'S THAT SISTERS ARE
DOING IT FOR THEMSELVES *
* YEAH!
* THIS IS A SONG
* TO CELEBRATE
* THE CONSCIOUS LIBERATION
* OF THE FEMALE STATE
* MOTHERS, DAUGHTERS
* AND THEIR DAUGHTERS,
TOO, YEAH! *
* WOMAN TO WOMAN
* WE'RE SINGING WITH YOU
* THE INTERIOR SEX
* HAS GOT A NEW EXTERIOR
* YEAH!
* WE GOT DOCTORS, LAWYERS,
POLITICIANS, TOO *
* YEAH, YEAH
* TAKE A LOOK AROUND
* CAN YOU SEE?
CAN YOU SEE? CAN YOU SEE? *
* THERE'S A WOMAN
RIGHT NEXT TO YOU *
* OHH
* SISTERS ARE DOIN' IT
FOR THEMSELVES *
* YEAH
* STANDING ON
THEIR OWN TWO FEET *
* AND RINGING ON
THEIR OWN BELLS *
* SISTERS ARE DOIN' IT
FOR THEMSELVES *
* DOIN' IT FOR THEMSELVES
* WE'RE DOIN' IT, HEY
* GO FOR IT, GIRL!
GO FOR IT! *
Annie: THE FUNNY THING
WAS THAT BY THE TIME
WE HAD OUR HUSBANDS
JUST WHERE WE WANTED THEM,
REVENGE SOMEHOW
DIDN'T SEEM SO IMPORTANT.
SO, WE CAME UP
WITH SOMETHING BETTER.
Kathie Lee Gifford:
IT'S A VERY EXCITING
AND IMPORTANT DAY
HERE IN NEW YORK CITY,
AND FOR WOMEN EVERYWHERE.
WE'RE HERE
AT THE GRAND OPENING
OF THE BRAND-NEW
CYNTHIA SWANN GRIFFIN
CRISIS CENTER FOR WOMEN.
IT'S
AN AMAZING FACILITY,
AND I'M STANDING
HERE TALKING TO
THREE AMAZING WOMEN.
WELL, YOU MUST
BE VERY PROUD.
PLEASE TELL ME
ABOUT YOUR FACILITY.
THIS CENTER IS DEDICATED
IN LOVING MEMORY
TO OUR VERY DEAR FRIEND
CYNTHIA SWANN.
WE PLAN ON OFFERING
COUNSELING, FAMILY THERAPY,
AND OF COURSE, ABUSE
INTERVENTION FOR ALL.
ABSOLUTELY.
THERE ARE SO MANY
WOMEN IN NEED
HERE IN MANHATTAN.
BUT I HAVE TO ASK YOU,
IS IT TRUE?
SOMEBODY TOLD ME THAT
THE IDEA FOR THIS
WHOLE THING STARTED
BECAUSE EACH OF YOU HAD
A HUSBAND THAT LEFT YOU
FOR A YOUNGER WOMAN?
OH, YES. YES.
YES.
IT'S TRUE.
THEY REALLY ARE
AMAZING WOMEN!
WELL, GOOD FOR YOU.
CONGRATULATIONS AGAIN
FOR ALL THE GREAT WORK
YOU'VE DONE.
THANK YOU.
THE CITY OF NEW YORK
THANKS YOU.
I'M ASKING YOU
AS A FAVOR.
COME IN FOR
ONE MINUTE WITH ME.
MORTY, YOU KNOW, WE HAVE
TO TALK ABOUT THE WEDDING.
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
YOU WON'T EVEN
SET A DATE.
EXACTLY! BECAUSE
THIS ISN'T WORKING.
I AM NOT FEELING SPECIAL,
I AM NOT FEELING LOVED,
AND NOW, THIS PLACE?
PLEASE, MORTY,
I AM NOT BRENDA.
NO, YOU'RE NOT.
DUH!
[BAND PLAYS
SWING MUSIC]
IVANA?
I WANT TO THANK YOU
FOR COMING SO MUCH.
YOU'RE AN ANGEL.
OH, OF COURSE, ELISE.
THANK YOU
SO MUCH AGAIN.
LADIES, WE HAVE TO BE
STRONG AND INDEPENDENT.
AND REMEMBER...
WHAT?
DON'T GET MAD.
GET EVERYTHING.
GOSH! HA HA!
BYE-BYE.
BYE.
Brenda: BYE, NOW.
MRS. GOLDBERG?
YES?
CARMINE MORELLI.
BRENDA'S UNCLE.
OH, YES.
OH, YES,
OF COURSE.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
IN THE 18th CENTURY...
OH, WHAT A WONDERFUL
OCCASION!
HELPING PEOPLE
THROUGH A BUFFET.
I KNOW.
MOM, IT'S
GREAT PARTY.
THANK YOU,
SWEETIE.
MM-MM.
YOU KNOW WHAT
I THINK, ANNIE?
I THINK THIS PLACE
IS TERRIFIC,
AND I THINK YOU DID
THE RIGHT THING BY
GETTING RID OF AARON.
OHH!
I SALUTE YOU!
I HAVE SOMETHING
TO ADD.
ANNIE, YOU'RE NOT
GETTING ANY YOUNGER
OR THINNER.
YOU KNOW WHAT
I THINK YOU NEED?
NOPE.
ABSOLUTELY
NOTHING.
OH, MOM.
OH, BABY.
I LOVE YOU.
OHH!
SWEETHEART.
COME ON, JASON.
JUST ONE TIME
AROUND THE FLOOR.
COME ON, MOM.
GET REAL.
LOOK,
I'M YOUR MOTHER.
I COMMAND YOU.
YOU GOTTA HAVE
SOMETHING TO TELL
YOUR SHRINK.
LOOK AT THIS.
ISN'T THIS
FANTASTIC?
I'M SO PROUD.
HEY, KIDS.
HI, MORTY.
DAD, SAVE ME.
SHE'S DOING IT
AGAIN.
SHE'S TRYING
TO DANCE WITH ME.
HEY, BREN,
LEAVE HIM ALONE.
HE'S A GOOD KID.
I KNOW THAT.
NOT LIKE HIS DAD.
WHAT?
I'M GETTING OUT OF
THE LINE OF FIRE.
YOU LOOK GOOD,
BREN.
YOU, TOO.
THANK YOU.
WHERE'S SHELL?
SHE'S IN THE CAR.
HMM. GLOVE
COMPARTMENT?
TRUNK.
LET ME ASK YOU
A QUESTION.
WAS I THIS OLD
WHEN WE WERE MARRIED?
YES.
BUT I LIKED YOU
THIS OLD.
ME, TOO.
[MUSIC TEMPO CHANGES]
YEAH?
WHY NOT?
GOT IT?
SURE.
Annie: IT WAS PRETTY
CLEAR THAT NIGHT
THAT BRENDA AND MORTY WERE
HEADED FOR A RECONCILIATION.
ELISE WAS DATING AN ACTOR
IN HER HIT PLAY,
AND AS FOR ME...
AARON AND DR. ROSEN
SPLIT UP.
HE WANTS
TO COME HOME AGAIN,
AND HE FEELS EMOTIONALLY
READY TO RECOMMIT
TO AN EQUITABLE AND
CARING RELATIONSHIP.
I TOLD HIM TO DROP DEAD.
EXCUSE ME, DO YOU
HAVE A LIGHT?
SURE.
NICE CAR. USED
TO HAVE ONE MYSELF.
THANKS.
SO, WHAT'S
GOING ON IN THERE?
IS IT JUST A LOT
OF BATTERED WOMEN
DANCING AROUND OR WHAT?
YEAH. SORT OF.
NOT REALLY MY SCENE.
ME, NEITHER.
SO, ARE YOU HERE
WITH ANYBODY?
NOT REALLY.
HOW OLD ARE YOU?
Annie: MMM. LOOK
AT THIS PLACE.
IT'S JUST
A TOTAL MESS.
Brenda: BUT
A GORGEOUS MESS.
Elise: YEAH.
JUST LIKE US.
YOU KNOW,
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
WE ACTUALLY DID IT.
WE ACTUALLY ACCOMPLISHED
SOMETHING TOGETHER.
WE DID IT!
OH, GOD, I WISH CYNTHIA
WAS HERE RIGHT NOW.
WELL, SHE IS.
SHE IS IN A WAY.
I KNOW.
OK, WE'RE WOMEN
OF THE NINETIES.
WHAT IS IT THAT
WE REALLY, REALLY NEED?
YOU KNOW, BRENDA,
YOU ARE NEVER
GOING TO CHANGE.
THAT'S RIGHT!
AND I HOPE NOT.
I HOPE NONE OF US
EVER CHANGE.
I HOPE WE ALWAYS
GET TO STAY THE SAME--
TIRED AND HAPPY!
AND MAYBE
A LITTLE BIT BRAVE.
BRAVE?
YOU MEAN... BRAVE.
LIKE, WHAT
DO YOU MEAN?
YOU'RE NOT FUNNY.
* YOU DON'T OWN ME
NO WAY. I'M OUT.
STOP IT! NO!
I'M NOT GONNA--
* I'M NOT ONE OF
YOUR LITTLE TOYS *
* YOU DON'T OWN ME
LEAVE ME ALONE!
* DON'T SAY I CAN'T
GO WITH OTHER BOYS *
ELISE! NO! OK?
Both:
* BA BA BA BA BA BA
HMM?
* AND DON'T TELL ME
WHAT TO DO *
WHAT TO SAY *
* AND WHEN I GO OUT
WITH YOU *
* DON'T PUT ME ON DISPLAY
YOU REMEMBERED!
PRETTY GOOD!
* YOU DON'T OWN ME
* DON'T TRY TO CHANGE ME
IN ANY WAY *
* YOU DON'T OWN ME
* DON'T TIE ME DOWN
* 'CAUSE I'LL NEVER STAY
* I DON'T TELL YOU
WHAT TO SAY *
WHAT TO DO *
* SO JUST LET ME
BE MYSELF *
* THAT'S ALL I ASK OF YOU
* I'M YOUNG,
AND I LOVE TO BE YOUNG *
* I'M FREE,
AND I LOVE TO BE FREE *
* TO LIVE MY LIFE
THE WAY THAT I WANT *
* TO SAY AND DO
WHATEVER I PLEASE *
* I'M YOUNG
* AND I LOVE
TO BE YOUNG *
* I'M FREE
* I'M FREE, AND
I LOVE TO BE FREE *
* TO LIVE MY LIFE
* THE WAY THAT I WANT
* TO SAY AND DO
WHATEVER I PLEASE *
* NO, NO,
YOU DON'T OWN ME *
* FOREVER
YOUNG AND FREE *
* DARLING,
YOU DON'T OWN ME *
WHOO!
* NO, NO,
YOU DON'T OWN ME *
* FOREVER
YOUNG AND FREE *
* DARLING,
YOU DON'T OWN ME *
* NO, NO,
* FOREVER
YOUNG AND FREE *
* DARLING,
YOU DON'T OWN ME *
OOH!
* YOU DON'T OWN ME
* NO, NO,
YOU DON'T OWN ME *
* FOREVER
YOUNG AND FREE *
* DARLING,
YOU DON'T OWN ME *
* NO, NO,
* FOREVER
YOUNG AND FREE *
* DARLING,
YOU DON'T OWN ME *
* YOU DON'T OWN ME
* FOREVER
YOUNG AND FREE *
* DARLING,
YOU DON'T OWN ME *
* OHH
* OOH
* SO YOU STOOD THERE
ON THE CORNER *
* WITH YOUR SUITCASE
IN YOUR HAND *
* READY TO QUIT
THIS PLACE *
* THERE WERE JUST
TOO MANY PEOPLE *
* WITH TOO LITTLE
LEFT TO LOSE *
* YOU WERE JUST
ONE MORE FACE *
* BUT YOU WEREN'T BORN
TO GIVE UP EASY *
* YOU WEREN'T RAISED
TO JUST LIE DOWN *
* AND YOU SAW THE SUN
THAT RISES UP IN THE MORN *
* OVER AND OVER
* YOU WATCHED THE WAVE
THAT WEARS AWAY THE SHORE *
* OVER AND OVER AGAIN
* AND IF THERE'S
ANY JUSTICE *
* IN THIS WORLD
* GOTTA KEEP FIGHTING ON
* OVER AND OVER
* OH, ALL THAT WE LOST
WE'LL FIND *
* IF WE JUST STRIKE
THE MATCH *
* AND FAN THE FLAME
* WE'LL BUILD A PLACE
* THAT LIGHTS THE WAY
* AND OVER AND OVER AGAIN
* THE WAVE THAT WEARS
AWAY THE SHORE *
* OVER AND
OVER AGAIN *
* AND IF THERE'S
ANY JUSTICE *
* IN THIS WORLD
* YOU'VE GOT TO KEEP
MOVING ON *
* OVER AND OVER
* YOU GOTTA KEEP
FIGHTING ON *
* OHH
* DOO DOO
* OH, YEAH
* OVER AND OVER
AND OVER AND OVER *
* AGAIN
* 'CAUSE IF THERE'S
ANY JUSTICE *
* IN THIS WORLD
* YOU GOTTA
KEEP MOVING ON *
* OVER AND OVER
* YOU'VE GOTTA
KEEP MOVING ON *
* YOU'VE GOT TO KEEP
FIGHTING ON *
* OVER AND OVER
CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
PARAMOUNT PICTURES CORPORATION
CAPTIONING PERFORMED BY
THE NATIONAL CAPTIONING
INSTITUTE, INC.
* OVER AND OVER AGAIN