[ Rustling ]
[ Man On Radio ] Now the latest
weather forecast for northwest Koriko.
Skies are clearing up,
thanks to a high-pressure front...
moving in from the continent.
Mild winds will be
blowing in from the west...
clearing out the clouds
by this evening.
We'll also have
a beautiful full moon tonight...
- so pack up your picnic baskets...
- [ Bee Buzzing ]
because the weather
is going to be just fine.
- More news in just a minute.
- [ Clicks Off Radio ]
[ Bird Chirps ]
Jiji, wake up!
Tonight's the night.
Hey, Mom! Oh.
Hi, Miss Dora. Hey, Mom,
it's gonna be clear tonight.
And, guess what. The radio says
there'll be a full moon!
Did you borrow your father's radio
again without asking?
Don't worry.
He doesn't mind.
Please excuse me, Miss Dora.
Mom, it's a perfect midnight for me to leave home.
You mean tonight?
Next month is what you told me.
Yeah, but the next full moon
might be on a cloudy night.
And, I want to leave
on the perfect midnight.
Huh?
But, Kiki-- Wait!
Ohh--
[ Gasps ]
Uhh--
[ Sighs ]
My, oh, my.
What's this all about?
It's one of our oldest customs
that when a witch turns 1 3,
she has to leave home for a year
to begin her training.
Your little baby is 13?
My goodness,
but time flies so quickly.
I know. She seems so young
to be leaving home now.
I remember very well the exact day
you arrived in this town.
A little girl flew down
from the sky on her broomstick.
And, I was certain she was much too
young to hold such an important job...
as resident witch.
But Kiki doesn't know
much besides flying.
And, I have had no time to teach her
how to mix potions like me.
Sign of the times,
I'm afraid.
Everything changes,
bit by bit.
But, I hope, you at least
get to teach her...
- the potion that cures my rheumatism.
- [ Laughs ]
You're always telling me to hurry!
Now who's the slowpoke?
I think it's better to leave
with decorum and great dignity.
And, if we put it off
for a month,
and I fiind some wonderful
boyfriend, then what'll we do?
We'll never leave!
I'm gonna put my paws together
and pray you're not serious.
Of course, I am.
You know ever since I turned 1 3, I've
been excited about making this trip.
[ Car Approaching ]
Dad!
Dad! Guess what!
I've decided to leave tonight!
- You're-- You're going away?
- Yeah, there's a full moon!
Well, yes, but what about
our camping trip for this weekend?
Sorry, Dad!
Aah, oh-- Uh, Kiki, wait!
Whoa! Ya-- Ow!
Ahh-- Ohh--
Ye-- Yeah,
I'll expect you then. Thanks.
Hi, Mom, it's me. I wanted to make sure
you knew that Kiki is leaving tonight.
Yes, midnight.
- Very pretty.
- Lilac would look prettier on me.
Witches have worn this colour
for a very long time, Kiki.
Black cat, black clothes.
It's not really important
what colour your dress is.
What matters is
the heart inside.
Well, I'm gonna be the very
best witch that I can be, Mom.
And, I know having
a good heart is important.
Just follow your heart
and keep smiling.
Yeah.
And, be sure to write home
as soon as you're settled.
Dad! Oh.
Can I please take the radio?
Mom, didn't you say
I could have the radio?
- Yea!
-All right. It's yours already.
Okay. Now let me have
a look at my little witch.
[ Giggles ]
You look just like your mother
when she was young.
Dad, can you lift me up high,
like when I was little?
Well--
Uhh-- Uh--
[ Grunts ]
[ Laughs ]
How come you never told me you were
growin' up so fast?
If things don't work out,
you can always come home.
And come back a failure?
Ooh-aghh!
[ Laughing ]
I hope you fiind a good town.
Mm-hmm.
[ Woman ]
After all, she is a baby.
[ Man ] I won't disagree
with you there. It's beautiful.
I bet it's real tough to fiind
a town to live in by yourself.
Don't worry.
Kiki will be fiine.
- What kind of town are you looking for?
- A big town?
Yeah. By the ocean,
I hope.
- Wow!
- I'm so jealous of you!
But I'm not going just
for a good time.
In order to be a good witch,
I have to train a year away from home.
Yeah. Be sure to tell
that to the boys.
- [ Girls Giggling ]
- Kiki, it's time.
'Kay!
That's the broom you're going
to be leaving on?
Yep! I just made it
this morning all by myself.
Honey, it's too small
to be really safe.
I'd rather you took my broom.
I know it better.
But, Mom,
that one's so old!
And, that's why it's good.
You can rely on it time after time
in any kind of weather.
Now, Kiki,
do this for me, please.
But I put so much work into this one.
Right,Jiji?
Your broom is nice,
but let's take your mother's.
- You're no help!
- Now, Kiki,
can't you make yourself another
fiine broom when you get settled down?
Mm-hmm.
Be careful.
- You be strong, okay?
- I will!
- Bye!
- Bye, Kiki!
- [ Girl ] Fly safely!
- [ Girl ] Go get 'em! Goodbye!
Go, Kiki!
Go, Kiki! Go, Kiki!
Go, Kiki! Go, Kiki! Go, Kiki! Go!
[ Gasps ]
Uhh! Uhh!
[ Bells Ringing ]
Aim your broomstick!
May our little baby be well
and have a safe trip.
I'm going to miss
the wonderful sound of those bells.
- [ Wind Howling ]
- Where are we going?
I'm headed south
to see the ocean.
Jiji, climb up
and turn on the radio.
I don't think I can handle it.
Can you do it?
[ Clicks On ]
?? [ Pop ]
KIKI'S DELIVERY SERVICE
EXECUTIVE PRODUCERS
Yasuyoshi Tokuma, Mikihiko Tsuzuki, Morihisa Takagi
PLANNING
Tatsumi Yamashita, Hideo Ogata, Iwai Seto
ORIGINAL STORY
Eiko Kadono (Published by FUKUINKAN SHOTEN PUBLISHERS)
DIRECTING ANIMATORS
Shinji Otsuka, Katsuya Kondo, Yoshifumi Kondo
ART DIRECTOR
Hiroshi Ono
CHARACTER DESIGN
Katsuya Kondo
MUSIC Joe Hisaishi
COLOUR STYLIST
Michiyo Yasuda
CAMERA SUPERVISOR
Juro Sugimura
EDITOR
Takeshi Seyama
RECORDING SUPERVISOR
Naoko Asari
SOUND ENGINEER
Shuji Inoue
SOUND EFFECTS
Kazutoshi Sato
ANIMATION PRODUCTION
Toru Hara
ASSOCIATE PRODUCER
Toshio Suzuki
PRODUCED, WRITTEN & DIRECTED
by Hayao Miyazaki
- Hey. Good evening!
- It was!
You're new, aren't you?
Yep! How'd ya guess?
I just left home tonight.
Uh-huh. Would you mind
turning off that radio?
I prefer to fly
without being distracted.
- Oh! Yeah, sure!
- [ Clicks ]
Could you tell me? Is it really hard
to get settled into a brand new city?
Oh, yes.
A lot can go wrong.
But since my skill is fortune-telling,
I can handle anything.
- Fortune-telling?
- Yes. I tell fortunes about love.
- Wow!
- And, what exactly is your skill?
Um-- Well, I haven't
really decided that yet.
Ah. Well, I'm nearly fiinished
with my training period.
I'm going home soon
to show off my new skills.
That's my town down there.
It's not big or terribly interesting,
but I like it.
-I hope you don't have too tough a time.
- Thanks!
Ciao!
Jeez, what a snob! And did you
see that cat? [ Blows Raspberry ]
What's my skill?
[ Thunder Crash ]
[ Kiki Screams ]
What was that
about good weather?
I hope you're not going to do
what I think you're going to do.
Huh?
We better rest here
until it's dry.
- Won't we get in trouble?
- Not if nobody fiinds us.
Oh-- I'm soaked through
down to the bone.
Do you feel anything moving?
Ahh! Mmm!
This smells great!
[ Horn Blowing ]
[ Engine Idling ]
[ Horn Blares ]
[ Train Wheels Clattering
Rhythmically ]
- [ Screams ]
- Yeoww!
Ahh! Ah!
[ Laughing ]
Aha! Aha-ha-ha.
[ Grunts ]
Oops! Sorry. We didn't mean to
fall asleep in your breakfast.
Wow!
Jiji, you've gotta
come see the ocean.
- It's beautiful!
- Big deal.
- It's just a big puddle of water.
- Look! Up ahead!
How lovely!
- I wonder if they have a witch there.
- Oh, great.
[ Train Horn Blares ]
Let's go!
You okay back there?
- Fine.
- Wow!
This is just the kind
of place I've always imagined.
[ Bell Tolling
In The Distance ]
Wow! A clock tower. A place like this
would be great to live in.
But there may be some witches
living here already.
And, there may not be.
Look at how many people
there are!
Too many,
if ya ask me!
Bless my hourglass.
It's a real, live witch!
Good morning!
- Do any witches live in this town?
- Why, uh--
Nobody's seen one
around here in a long time.
That's great! Our trip is over.
We're staying right here.
- Thanks, mister! Bye!
- Uh, no problem!
- Tell me we're not landing down there.
- Well, of course we are!
- Woo-o-o!
- Ooh!
They're looking at us.
I know. Smile, so we make
a good impression.
[ Kiki Screams ]
[ Tyres Screeching ]
[ Crowd Gasps ]
Um, hi! My name's Kiki,
and I'm a witch.
And this is Jiji.
He's my black cat.
And we'd be honoured
if we could live here.
Your city is so amazing.
And what a beautiful clock tower.
Oh-h-h-- Really.
That's very nice, dear. Bye.
- [ Footsteps Running ]
- Hey, you kid!
Who do you think you are,
jumping out into the street like that?
You were responsible
for a big accident,
zooming around
on your broom back there.
But I'm a new witch, sir.
We're supposed to fly around.
You're supposed to obey the law.
I'm gonna have to write you up.
- Now give me your name and address.
- Will you tell my parents?
Of course I'm going
to tell your parents!
- I have to do that with every minor.
- [ Boy ] Thief! Thief!
- [ Boy ] Thief!
- Now you stay right there!
Uh, Kiki?
[ Horn Beeps ]
Miss! Wait up!
I sure fooled that cop, huh?
Hey, that was me
yellin' ``thief.''
You'll be okay now.
Worked out pretty good, huh?
You gotta be a real witch,
the way you can fly that broom.
Do you think, maybe,
you can teach me how to fly it?
Hey, Tombo!
Isn't it a bit early
for girl hunting?
- [ Laughing ]
- Hey, shut up, all right? Who-o-a!
You know, miss, I love flying too.
Could I see your broom?
Thank you for getting me
out of trouble.
I didn't ask for your help.
It's very rude to talk to a girl...
before you've been introduced
and before you know her name.
- Hmph!
- [ Stammers ]
You're kind of old-fashioned, aren't ya?
You sound like my grandmother.
-Just go away and leave me alone!
- Hey!
Ohh!
What a cool witch.
Stay here tonight?
I'm afraid I don't understand.
Your parents are here
with you, aren't they?
No, sir, I'm alone.
I've come to this town because
I'm a new witch in training.
Do you have
some identifiication?
Oh, never mind.
[ Children Chattering ]
Kiki, aren't you
going to eat that?
No, you can
have it,Jiji.
Where are we going
to stay tonight?
[ Siren Approaching ]
Let's go.
Why don't we go
fiind another town?
I'll bet there are bigger
and better ones.
Ones that are
friendlier than this.
Hey there!
Your pacifiier!
Ma'am, you forgot
your baby's pacifier!
Oh! Poor baby.
Without this, the baby'll wake
up and cry all the way home.
I'm sorry, folks. But could you wait
just a minute? I'll be right back.
Excuse me. But would you like
me to deliver it for you?
What?
The woman with the baby carriage
who just went around the corner.
Really? You'd do that?
- Thank you so much.
- My pleasure.
Let's go,Jiji!
[ Gasps ]
Oh-- Wow!
Sorry to surprise you,
but the lady in the bakery...
- asked me to return this pacifiier.
- Oh!
[ Both Laughing ]
Here ya go.
Yes, sir. Oh, hi there.
Come in and wait a minute, will you?
There you are.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Now come back again!
When I saw you fly off,
I thought for a second I was dreaming!
The baby's mother told me
to give you this message.
Hmm?
``Thanks for returning
the pacifiier.
Your new delivery girl
is really quite special.''
- Well, I'll be on my way.
- Wait!
Wait a minute. I really must do
something to show you my thanks.
Huh?
Follow me.
Sit down and relax.
- Would you like some hot chocolate?
- Okay.
Thank you very much, ma'am.
And, this is for you,
little guy.
Let me guess.
You're a witch in training.
Yes, but people don't seem
fond of witches in this town.
Depends on the people.
Now, take me, for instance.
I just met you and I know I like you.
[ Meows ]
So, tell me, whereabouts
are you two staying?
Uhh--
Why didn't you tell me
you have no place to stay?
We have a spare room
in the attic.
- You can use that.
- You'd really let me stay with you?
[ Laughs ]
Why, of course! But we haven't
introduced ourselves.
- My name's Osono.
- And I'm Kiki, ma'am.
And Jiji here
is my very best friend.
It's not very clean at the moment,
but it's all yours.
- That's okay.
- All right then.
Water and bathroom are downstairs.
Give a shout if you need anything.
Thank you.
There's flour everywhere.
If you wake up tomorrow
and fiind a white cat, it's me.
Jiji, we can see
the ocean from here!
Can we look
for a new town?
Huh!
Pardon me, Miss Snooty Cat!
[ Siren Wailing ]
[ Man On Radio ]
I think the excitement is building...
for the moment when the big blimp
appears in our skies.
So, we're gonna go to Scott-- live--
as he reports in from Freedom Base One.
Jiji, I've decided
not to leave this town.
- Maybe I can stay and fiind some
other nice people like Osono, - You know, Jack, I think...
- who will like me
and accept me for who I am. - our audience would agree--
Spectacular if the ship
made some kind of landing...
so everyone
could get a closer look.
[ Clicks ]
- [ Boat Horn Blowing ]
- [ Groans ]
Oh.
[ Sighs ]
[ Toilet Flushing ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Sigh ]
[ Man On Radio ] There's a volleyball
tournament on the beach at noon.
Don't miss it!
How much do you think it would
cost to get a phone here?
- A phone?
- Yep. For my business.
- Morning, everyone!
- Well, look who's up!
- Did you sleep well?
- Yes. Oh, that smells good!
- Can I help out?
- Sure can!
- Whoa!
- Ooh, a delivery business, huh?
Well, I really only have
one skill and that's flying.
So I thought a delivery service
wouldn't be a bad idea.
It's a great idea--
Kiki's Flying Delivery Service.
And you can base the business
out of your room upstairs.
You mean it!
Oh, that's great!
I was planning on putting
a phone upstairs.
- But a phone is so expensive.
- I have a little saved up already.
Don't waste your money! What I think
you should do is use our phone.
You know it will take some time
to get regular customers.
I'll make you a deal. Since I'm
expecting a baby, I could use help.
If you mind the store,
once in a while, I'll let you have the room and the phone.
And, I'll throw in
a free breakfast, okay?
Yeah!
We've got a deal!
I'm gonna work
very hard for you.
Yo--
Osono, you're
the greatest!
[ Laughs ]
Huh?
Jiji! Come on!
I'm all through!
We're gonna go shopping.
Come on!
[ Horn Honking ]
Kiki, in the city, you can't
just run out into the street.
I'm sorry.
We're still alive, aren't we?
[ Giggling, Laughing ]
[ Girl ] I've never been
more embarrassed in my whole life.
- It was so terrible! [ Laughing ]
- Yeah!
I wish I had something pretty to wear.
My dress is so ugly.
Oh, wow!
This cost so much!
Kiki, look! It's me!
[ Cash Register Clattering ]
[ Bell Chimes ]
Any money left, Kiki?
Looks like all we can afford
to eat now is pancakes.
Aren't they beautiful!
- [ Youths Laughing ]
- Whoa! Whoa--
- [ Laughing ]
- Oh! Huh--
Hey! Pull over!
- Hey there!
- Nice goin', Tombo!
Not flying today?
You can tell she's a witch
'cause she always wears a dark dress.
Hey, wait! Come back, please.
I didn't mean to insult you!
- Yeah!
- Better luck next time, Tombo!
[ Laughter ]
Oh, Kiki,
perfect timing!
There's a lady here
who wants you to make a delivery!
- She's your first customer.
- Customer! Oh, my. I'll be right back!
- [ Footsteps Running ]
- [ Panting ] Ohh-h-h! Uh--
Now, where's that map?
[ Panting ]
Aah-- Uh.
Dear, this lady
is a customer of ours,
and we were talking about
your new delivery service.
- What a charming girl!
- My name's Kiki, ma'am.
Do you think you can
deliver this by tonight?
Yeah! I can.
It's a birthday gift
for my nephew.
But something came up at work, and
I can't make it to the party on time.
I can get it there
for you, guaranteed.
Huh? But that's me.
Are you sure
it won't be too far?
- I can fly there straight from here.
- Great. How much will it cost?
Oh. Well, I haven't really
thought about a price.
How about
this much then?
[ Gasps ]
This much for me?
That's great!
Thank you!
- [ Brakes Squeaking ]
- Huh?
Oh, wow! That's great!
[ Panting ]
- She's the most amazing girl!
- She sure is!
Hey, what can you
tell me about her?
Kiki, how high
do you intend to go?
This is my fiirst job, and I do not want
to be stopped by that traffiic cop.
I was afraid you were going to
deliver it to the angels.
It's just past the cape.
- Here we go!
- Whoa, boy!
I'm getting to like
this town more and more.
I'm getting sick to my stomach.
I can't wait to write Mom
and Dad about my new business.
[ Birds Calling ]
Look who's behind us.
Wild geese!
And they're
coming with us!
- [ Geese Calling ]
- [ Laughs ]
[ Calling Continues ]
- They seem awfully upset.
- They say they're going to fly higher.
- Huh?
- They say a gust of wind's coming.
[ Wind Howling ]
Aaaah!
[ Kiki Grunts ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Bird Squawks ]
- [ Squawking Continues ]
- [ Kiki Sighs ]
Ahh!
- Oh, I'm sorry! Ow! Oh!
- [ Squawking Continues ]
I wasn't trying to
steal your eggs! Really!
Oh, my goodness!
That was your fault. The geese were
kind enough to warn us of that wind.
- But would you listen?
- You're right.
That gust of wind
took them all the way up.
Kiki!
The toy fell out!
We've gotta go back!
- Back to where?
- Where we fell!
[ Birds Squawking ]
[ Gasps ]
They're saying,
``The egg thief's coming again!''
What are we gonna do?
[ Screaming ]
[ Screams ]
Hey! Stop that!
Go away! Oh--
Leave us alone!
Stop it!
Maybe we better
rethink our plan.
Frankly, I think
this is a major insult.
Crows used to serve witches
and do what you told them.
Hey, that was
a long time ago, okay?
How about if we go in after dark?
Go in. Get it. Get out.
We won't be able
to make it in time.
Unless we buy ourselves
some time.
You gotta be kidding!
You can just pretend to be the doll
until I fiind the real one.
- Is that the place?
- Yes. Don't move a muscle.
- Can I breathe?
- Hold it as long as you can.
[ Doorbell Buzzes ]
Yea! Give it to me! Ha!
This is dumb!
[ Laughs ]
You're a bit late!
After my sister telephoned,
- we were wondering where you were.
- Uh, I'm sorry.
Could I please have
your signature, ma'am?
Mom, can I put
the canary in here?
Uh-huh. But you be sure not
to let it fly away, Ket.
'Kay.
[ Laughs ]
Thank you very much.
Have a nice day.
[ Gasps, Whistles ]
Come on,
you stupid bird!
I got a brand new
home for you.
[ Whimpers ]
Please hurry, Kiki.
I know you fell close by,
so you've got to be here somewhere.
[ Gasps ]
There you are!
Hello! Anyone home?
Is anybody here?
Anybody? Hello!
- Anybody here?
- Yes!
I'm on the roof!
What do you want?
Why don't you come up?
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Crow Caws ]
[ Caws ]
- What do you want?
- Oh, well, you have a black cat...
in your cabin window, and, you see,
it's mine and I need it back.
You're a good birdie,
aren't you?
So, why was it alone
in the forest, huh?
That's where I dropped it.
Um, may I have it back, please?
I really need
to fiinish this.
That's my girl!
You're just about
through, okay?
[ Sighs ]
Well, why didn't you tell me sooner
why you needed it in such a hurry?
- I got sort of fond of it.
- Thank you. Oh--
- His head's falling off.
- Ooh, it must have been the crows.
They were making
such a big fuss over him.
This is terrible.
I can't deliver it like this.
Hey!
I know. How about
we work out a deal?
So, you're on your own at 1 3.
That's pretty exciting.
To be completely independent
and a witch!
How's it going?
Trust me.
He'll be good as new.
[ TV Character Growls ]
Ketto, time for your bath. Quickly!
The guests will be here soon!
[ Shouting ]
Ket!
[ Clicks TVOff ]
[ Whimpering ]
Uhh-h-h-- Yuck!
- I'm done!
- Thank you very much!
Better go get Jiji
before it's too late.
- But I haven't fiinished yet.
- Don't worry.
You've done enough.
Now, go on and get him!
Thanks!
[ Laughter ]
-Jeff likes my present more than me!
- [ Laughing ]
Jeff's such a funny dog.
He simply adores that stuffed cat.
He won't leave it alone!
[ Man ] I'll bet he thinks
it's a puppy!
[ Older Woman ] Your sister's
not going to be happy to hear that.
That's okay.
I gave it to Jeff anyway.
Just don't forget to send
your aunt a thank-you note.
[ Ket ]
Okay.
He's getting
to be such an old dog.
- Yeah. All he does is sleep all day.
- [ Laughs ] All day!
Ket, dear, go open the door.
Jeff wants to go out.
Jeff, shut the door
when you're done. Okay?
- [ Gasps ] There you are!
- What took you so long?
- I'm sorry!
- My friend,Jeff, helped me escape.
He said he'd be happy
to help us out if he could.
Could you take
this in, please?
- How are ya? Hungry?
- No, I'm tired!
Yeah, me too.
I'm very tired.
But it sure was
a wonderful adventure.
By the way, that painter
who found the stuffed cat...
told me she wants to do
a drawing with me in it.
- Naked?
-Jiji!
``Kiki's Delivery Service''
[ Sighs ]
Boring.
Hey!
Wake up! You're supposed
to be minding the store!
I am, but today
this place is boring.
But it always gets
busy about this time.
I know that.
That's not what I mean.
I mean, my customers.
Jiji, if nobody comes in, I'm gonna
have to eat pancakes forever...
and be fat, fat, fat!
And what am I supposed
to do about that?
Well, I like pancakes,
provided they're not burned.
[ Groans ]
Look, fur ball,
when you get as fat and round
as a pancake, you see if I care.
Beautiful, isn't she? They tell me
she's a clothes designer.
Her designs may be fabulous,
but her cat's still a snob.
[ Rings ]
Hello!
Good Cooking Pan Bakery.
What? Pardon?
Uh, yes, ma'am.
'Bout time we got
a customer, huh?
Uh, yes, ma'am, 4:30 will be
a perfect time to pick it up.
If you'll just--
Uh-huh. And the address?
Yes. The blue roof. Right.
Yeah. I'm pretty sure
I have it all.
- And thank you very much, ma'am.
- [ Door Opens ]
Hi!
I'll take this, please.
Okay?
Thank you very much.
Good afternoon.
Aw, come on.
You're not still mad at me, are you?
Listen. We're gonna have
a huge party at the club tonight.
It's called the Aviation Club.
And we'd really like for you to come.
Here's your invitation.
It really is a serious club.
And you know everybody would
be really excited if you came.
- Yes. May I help you, sir?
- They tell me you have a delivery service.
Oh-- Oh, I'm sorry. Yes,
of course, we can handle it.
It's very urgent this package arrive
as soon as possible.
That's no problem. Oh--
- Uh, are you all right?
- Uh-huh.
- Can I help you?
- [ Straining ] Uh-uh.
[ Sighs ]
Well, I hope you make up
your mind by 6:00, 'cause that's when I'll be by to pick ya up.
- See ya!
- Uh-ah-- Uh. - How much will that be?
Will that be inside
or outside city limits, sir?
- I wrote the address on the box!
- Oh-- Oh, the box! Oh, I'm sorry.
Osono!
I got an invitation to go to a party
at Tombo's flying club!
I'm sure it'll be
a great party, Kiki.
No! But my problem is,
what am I going to wear?
Kiki, you haven't got a problem.
You look fiine in that.
Besides, it makes you look
beautiful and mysterious.
- Really?
- How's work?
[ Gasps ] I almost forgot about that!
It's already 4:00! Oh, no!
Can you watch the store
until I get back, Osono?
Jiji?
[ Laughs ]
You were so mad at that boy.
I don't understand why you're going to his party.
Please don't talk.
I'm tryin' to fly this broom, okay?
[ Grunts, Pants ]
[ Strains ]
Thank you very much. Bye.
Come on,Jiji!
We can't keep our
next appointment waiting.
There's the blue roof.
[ Door Lock Rattles ]
My name's Kiki,
and someone telephoned for a delivery service, so here I am.
Right this way, dear.
- You are right on time.
- Thank you.
Oh, madam,
the delivery girl is here.
My, delivery time already?
Come in, dear.
Please make yourself right at home.
- Please do.
- Thanks.
May I take that for you?
Broom and a black cat.
Well, it's just as
my great-grandmother told me.
My name's Kiki,
and I'm a witch.
Oh, my,
what a pretty witch you are.
I'm so sorry, but that
special treat you were supposed to deliver... isn't ready yet.
[ Clicking ]
I think there's
something wrong with it.
It's got a mind of its own,
and it doesn't want to heat up.
It's old. Like me,
it's seen better days.
I was hoping you'd be
able to deliver a dish to my granddaughter's birthday party.
It's my speciality.:
herring and pumpkin potpie.
But I must admit defeat.
I'll have to phone her
and tell her I'm sorry.
I feel just awful having
you come here for nothing.
Barsa! Barsa!
Would you get
Kiki's money, please?
Certainly, madam.
- All of it. Pay her what we agreed on.
- Oh, no, I couldn't.
Please accept it.
This was all my fault.
Yes, but--
Ma'am, since I don't have any
other jobs, maybe I can help.
How about we use
that old oven over there?
Well, maybe?
It used to bake beautiful bread,
but I haven't baked in it lately.
Well, if it burns fiirewood,
I can help you.
I used to help my mom
bake all the time.
But it's such a big job
to build a fiire.
A great idea, ma'am.
I never liked that electric thing.
- I think her plan is perfect.
- Ma'am, it'll work, really.
You think so? All right then.
Let's try it.
Kiki! Kiki! Kiki!
This is crazy!
Don't blame me
if you're late for your party.
I can't take her money
and not help out.
[ Grunts ]
Okay,Jiji, let's go.
Madam, here.
Look what I found.
You're a very clever girl, my dear.
Your mother must be proud.
Oh, well, this is exciting.
Mm-hmm.
Yes, this is much better.
[ Sighs ]
[ Clicks ]
It should be about time.
Yes, very good.
Well done.
[ Sizzling ]
Now we wait.
You think 40 minutes
should be about right?
Exactly right.
So why don't we take a little break?
Maybe I can help around the house
while the pie is baking.
Oh, how nice of you
to offer.
- [ Squeaking ]
- What a wonderful witch.
There we go.
You're never gonna
make the party on time.
Stop worrying. It'll only take me
1 5 minutes if I fly there fast.
Would you like some hot tea?
It's no trouble.
Dear. What did you say to me
was the time of your party?
It's at 6:00,
but it's only 1 5 minutes away.
Oh, my goodness. I'm afraid my clock
runs about ten minutes slow.
[ Gasps ]
I'm gonna be late!
Check the potpie
and see if it's ready.
- [ Whimpers ]
- Help! Barsa, come!
[ Bubbling ]
Is the pie baked?
Is it ready?
-It seems fiine. Now, you'd better hurry.
- Uh-huh.
[ Panting ]
I got the broom.
We're ready! Come on!
- Okay!
- Let me pay you for your time.
But that's much too much.
Not for all of your help.
Hurry up!
- Have a good time now.
- Here you go.
What happened
to all that good weather?
My whiskers are tingling.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
Could we get out of the rain?
We can't! That'll make us even later,
and the food will get cold if we stop.
[ Tolling ]
[ Tolling Continues ]
[ Doorbell Chiming ]
[ Door Opening ]
- [ Chattering ]
- Yes? What do you want?
- I have a delivery.
- But it is soaking wet.
Oh, well, I'm sorry.
It began to rain on the way.
But don't worry.
The food came through all right.
Oh, no, I told Grandma
I didn't want that.
[ Girl ]
Hey, what'd you get?
Oh, Grandma sent me another one
of her crummy herring pies again.
Um, will you please
sign this receipt for me?
I hate Grandma's
stupid pies.
I cannot believe they're related.
[ Blows Raspberry ]
Maybe we still have time.
Kiki, there he is!
Come on!
We can catch him!
Kiki? We were all
so worried about you.
And that poor boy
waited such a long time.
It doesn't matter anyway.
I can't go in these wet clothes.
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
Kiki, what's wrong?
Are you not feeling well?
Maybe we should eat
something, okay?
[ Birds Chirping ]
- [ Scraping ]
- Wake up, Kiki!
- [ Scraping Continues ]
- [Jiji Meowing ]
[ Scraping Continues ]
[ Knocking ]
[ Meows ]
Not feeling
very well, huh?
Uh-uh.
- You have quite a fever.
- Uh-huh. My head's hurting so much.
Well, you flew in that weather
and you never really dried off.
Do you think
I'm going to die, Osono?
Huh?
[ Laughing ]
No, you're not. I'll bring
some medicine right up,
and maybe you should
have some potpie.
Not that.
Well, then, I'll just
make something else for you.
How about some nice hot oatmeal
with honey in it? You want some too?
[ Meows ]
This oatmeal
will pick ya right up.
There ya go. Here.
Oof! Now,
don't burn your tongue.
Ow!
You should come and eat your
meal while it's still warm.
- Here it is.
- Do I have to eat it?
Only if you want to get well.
Oh! You know that boy stopped
by to see you again today.
Huh?
When I told him
you were sick,
he asked me how a witch could
catch cold in the fiirst place.
Oh, and he said he wanted
to visit you a little later.
Oh, my gosh! No!
Well, I thought you might feel that way,
so I turned him down politely.
You must be tired.
You try to get some sleep.
Now, I'll just open up the window
so you'll have some fresh air.
- [ Window Opens ]
- [ Traffic Passing ]
- Osono!
- Hmm?
Um, never mind.
[ Birds Chirping ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Gasps ]
Oh!
Breakfast!
Jiji!
What? Hmm?
[ Gulps ]
Wow!
Where are you?
- [ Door Opens ]
- [ Osono ] Kiki?
- Are you feeling better?
- A lot better. Thank you.
I'm sorry I didn't
realize I'd overslept.
That's okay. Come down later.
I have a favour to ask you.
- All right?
- Okay.
- The name is ``Koppori''?
- Uh-huh. Now, take this money.
Oh, no, ma'am.
No money. It's on me.
Impossible. Work is work,
and make sure you deliver it in person.
Jiji!
- What is it?
- We've got a delivery.
- Hey, who's your friend there?
- Lily's her name. Be right there.
Stay there. I'll be right back.
He's all yours. Bye-bye.
[ Meows ]
- [ Wind Blowing ]
- Oh! Ah!
[ Seagulls Screeching ]
It's so pretty... and warm.
- Hey. Hey there, Miss Witch!
- [ Gasps ]
- Huh?
- Takin' a walk?
Uh-- Uh-uh. I'm looking
for someone named, uh, Koppori.
Hey, that's my name.
That's me.
[ Gasps ]
If you go around that way,
I'll be right with you, okay?
Osono, how could you
do this to me?
Gee, thanks a lot.
Um, about the other night?
I'm sorry I didn't show up.
Huh? Mmm. I'm sorry you had
to end up so sick like that.
Hey, come over to my place.
There's somethin' I wanna show ya.
Oh, you gotta see it.
The party was to celebrate
the completion of this thing. What do ya think?
This is the engine
of a man-propelled plane.
Watch this.
We're going to assemble the wings
and the frame at somebody else's house.
I'm plannin' on flyin' this thing
during most of my summer vacation.
[ Imitating Propeller Whirring ]
[ Giggles ]
Why don't we go down to the beach
where that dirigible landed yesterday?
Dirigible?
Don't tell me
you didn't hear about it?
- I was sick.
- Then we gotta see it! Let's do it!
- We're going on this?
- Why not?
I have to practise all the time anyway.
Gotta build up my legs.
'Kay. Ready?
Um, mm-hmm.
- This is my fiirst time on a bike.
- Oh, boy.Just hold on.
Brace the bike with your foot
until I get her revved up.
Let's go!
Okay!
- [ Grunting ]
- Should I get off?
No!
[ Laughs ]
[ Car Horn Honking ]
- [ Child ] Hey, look at that! Whoa!
- [ Child Giggles ]
Lean your body to the inside
when we go around the curve!
- Why?
- Because, otherwise, we're gonna have trouble turning.
Now!
Great! You're doin' fiine.
All right!
We're doin' great!
Wow!
- That's the dirigible, right?
- Right!
- [ Both Screaming ]
- [ Horn Honking ]
Whoa!
We're flying!
[ Horn Honking ]
- [ Screaming ]
- Hey! Watch it!
Whoa!
[ Groaning ]
- [ Groans ]
- What happened, Tombo? Are you okay?
- Yeah. Are you?
- I'm okay.
[ Giggles ]
Hmm?
[ Laughing Continues ]
Do I really
look that funny?
I'm sorry,
but when we flew up,
I was so scared.
Yeah, me too.
Was it your magic
that made us stay up?
I'm not sure.
Anything's possible.
- Your bike's a real mess.
- [ Gasps ]
My propeller!
I have to go get it, Kiki.
Will you keep an eye
on my bike for me?
- What went wrong?
- I think I pedaled too hard.
That's why it busted.
You wait here. I'll be right back.
How great would it be to go around
the world in a dirigible like that.
How'd it make you feel,
the fiirst time you ever went flying?
I can't recall.
I was too young to remember.
But my mom told me
I wasn't scared a bit.
Gosh. You're so lucky, Kiki.
I wish I could fly.
People like you can just
fly away on a broomstick.
But me? [ Imitates Propeller Whirring ]
That's all I can do.
Flying used to be fun
until I started doing it for a living.
Hey, wait. You can't not
enjoy flying. You're a witch!
I sort of feel
my confiidence slipping.
But I'm very glad
I came with you today.
I feel much better
sitting by the beach.
Why don't I bring you here
whenever you want and train myself at the same time?
- You're a very nice person.
- Huh? You just found that out?
Sorry, but at fiirst I thought
you were such a clown.
You know, my mom says the same thing.
``Don't be such a clown.
Quit looking up at the sky
and get back to your books.''
- Ha!
- [ Both Laughing ]
- Hey! Tombo!
- Huh?
- Guess what's up, Tombo!
- What?
Something really great!
Come on over!
I'll be back in a sec, okay?
We're all gonna get to go
for a ride in the blimp.
Really? Wow!
That's great!
- Hey, who's your friend?
- That's Kiki the Witch.
Hey, come over
and meet the gang, Kiki.
We're all goin' for a tour
inside the Spirit of Freedom.
Thanks, but I don't want to.
Oh, why not?
It'll be fun.
She made a delivery
to my house on my birthday.
- You mean, she's working at her age?
- Well, I'll be.
Come on. I'll introduce you
to everybody.
- No thanks. See ya later.
- What's the matter?
Hey!
What are you so mad about?
I'm not mad at all, Tombo.
I have a lot on my mind.
So, please,
just leave me alone.
Huh?
Forget her, Tombo!
Come on!
[ Horn Honking ]
- [ Clicks ]
- [ Man On Radio ] Don't forget that this summer the hit music--
[ Clicks ]
[ Meows ]
Jiji, I think
something's wrong with me.
I make friends, then suddenly
I can't bear to be with any of them.
Seems like that other me, the cheerful
and honest one went away somewhere.
Oh. Some friend you are.
[ Grunts ]
Hey! You know,
you can't be late for every meal...
just because you have
a new girlfriend.
And you can wash
your plate yourself!
- [ Meows ]
- Meow! Why are you talking like a cat?
[ Meows ]
Oh, my!
Oh, no!
Talk to me,Jiji!
You mean you can't
speak any more?
Jiji?
What's going on with him?
I can't understand anything
he's trying to say.
[ Gasps ] What if it means--
Oh, my goodness!
[ Whimpers ]
Oh!
[ Grunts ]
[ Gasps ]
I'm losing
my witch's powers.
[ Panting ]
[ Crickets Chirping ]
Oh!
[ Crashing ]
[ Groaning, Gasping ]
Huh? Oh!
What do you mean? You haven't
lost your magic, have you?
It's become very weak, so I--
Well, I think I've got to take
a break from my delivery work.
But I promise I'll be really good
with my work in the bakery,
so please let me stay
in the room upstairs!
Well, that's no problem.
I'll bet your powers come back
after you've had some rest.
I really don't know.
Maybe if I make a new broom.
- Hey! Look at that!
- [ Engine Approaching ]
Hi, Kiki? It's me, Tombo.
Did you see me today?
I was wavin' at ya from the dirigible,
'cause the captain let me come...
into the control cabin
during the test run.
Boy, did I have a cool time!
- Hello? Kiki? Are you there?
- Please don't call me any more.
What did ya say?
I can barely hear ya.
You know what the captain said?
He'd like to meet ya--
What? Kiki?
What's the matter, dear?
Is there anything I can do for you?
I'm still in training
to become a witch.
If I lose my magic, that means
I've lost absolutely everything.
[ Horn Honks ]
Kiki!
Hey!
- Hi!
- Well, since you didn't come and visit me,
- I thought I'd come here and visit you.
- I'm sorry.
Well, that's sort of a white lie.
I need to do some shopping too.
Come on in, 'cause I'm done now,
and I can take a break, okay?
- You better believe I will.
- [ Both Laughing ]
Nice place you have.
Help yourself to some of these,
and I'll go make us some tea.
No tea, thanks, but
some milk if you have any.
Sure.
Hey there. Unbelievable. You're
the spitting image of that stuffed cat.
I bet your name's
Jiji, right?
So how's the delivery biz?
You makin' any money?
- [ Milk Pours ]
- That bad, huh?
- I'm not working much now.
- Mm-hmm.
Hmm. I kind of thought
you looked unhappy.
I didn't know things
like that happened to witches.
Hey! Why don't you come
and stay at my cabin?
Huh?
It'll probably make you feel better.
Your boss would let you have a break.
How about it, kitty cat?
Wanna come?
[ Giggles ]
Rather be with your girlfriend, huh?
Come on, girl.
Why not? We'll leave now.
Uh-huh.
[ Meows ]
- Hurry! Hurry!
- [ Horn Honks ]
Oh. Ooh!
[ Both Laughing ]
Okay, now I'm
offiicially exhausted.
It's beautiful here.
[ Inhales ]
Mmm!
[ Car Approaching ]
Must've been blind, with two
beautiful girls in front of him.
[ Giggles ]
[ Tyres Screech ]
Huh? You-- You really
thought I was a boy?
Well, it's the way
you're dressed and all.
[ Groans ] Tell me. What kind
of a boy has these legs, mister?
- You get along with the crows.
- Yep, we've become real close friends.
Wow!
- Hello, everybody. I'm home again.
- [ Cawing ]
Good afternoon. I'm sorry
I bothered you before.
[ Cawing ]
Why don't you go inside,
and I'll go get some water.
[ Gasps ]
Oh.
- Like it?
- Yes.
I have to say I became inspired
after the fiirst time we met.
But... I really
haven't got the face right.
I've been waiting for you
to come back so I can try again.
- You mean that's me?
- Sure is.
You know, you'd make my life
a lot easier if you'd model for me.
But I'm not very beautiful.
What do you want me to do that for?
[ Laughing ]
Come on, Kiki. You have got
a great face. You're very pretty.
Now, don't you be nervous.
Sit down over here.
Raise your chin up a little.
Look straight ahead. Now, don't move.
Painting and magical powers
seem very much the same.
Sometimes I'm unable
to paint a thing.
You mean it?
Then what? What happens?
Kiki, please don't move.
Without even thinking about it,
I used to be able to fly.
Now I'm trying to look inside
myself to fiind out how I did it.
At times like that,
you know what I do? Paint.
That gets
rid of my frustrations.
Yeah, but still,
if I can't fly--
Then stop trying. Take long walks.
Look at the scenery.
Doze off at noon.
Don't even think about flying.
And then, pretty soon,
you'll be flying again.
- You think my problems will--
- Go away? That's right.
It's gonna be fiine.
I promise.
When I was your age, I'd already
decided to become an artist.
I loved to paint so much.
I'd paint all day until I fell asleep right at my easel.
And then one day, for some reason,
I just couldn't paint any more.
I tried and tried,
but nothing I did seemed any good.
They were copies of paintings
I'd seen somewhere before...
and not very
good copies either.
I just felt like
I'd lost my ability.
That sounds like me.
It's exactly the same,
but then I found the answer.
You see, I hadn't figured out
what or why I wanted to paint.
I had to discover
my own style.
When you fly, you rely on
what's inside of you, don't you?
Uh-huh.
We fly with our spirit.
Trusting your spirit! Yes, yes!
That's exactly what I'm talkin' about.
That same spirit is what makes me
paint and makes your friend bake.
I suppose it must be
a power given by God.
Sometimes you suffer for it.
I guess I never gave
witchcraft much thought.
That talk about discipline
and training was so old-fashioned.
I was so happy that you came
all that way to see me.
If I had been alone tonight, I would've
been one giant ball of frustration.
There have been
many times...
I've thought of
painting over that painting.
[ Kiki ]
But it ended up being so great.
You know, when I saw you today,
I looked at your sad face
and thought, ``I've found it!''
- I knew I could paint you.
- But that's not fair!
[ Laughing ]
All's fair in love and art.
Let's turn out the lights
and go to sleep.
Okay.
Sorry about taking
your bed from you.
Aw, no problem.
- Can I visit you once in a while?
- Sure.
Sure.
Anytime during the summer.
- That is, if I can visit you too.
- Uh-huh.
[ Man On TV ] And there it is, folks,
the Spirit of Freedom,
- recently downed in
a spectacular forced landing... - [ Phone Ringing ]
due to torrential rains
just outside the city limits.
Well, it's been repaired.
It is now in final preparation--
[ Osono ] Yes?
Good Cooking Pan Bakery.
Kiki! How are you?
Well, you take plenty of time
coming home. Oh, and by the way,
that older woman
you made a delivery for?
She has another delivery for you.
I said I wasn't sure you could do it.
She was really very insistent.
What do you think, Kiki?
Great! Stop there
on your way back. Bye.
[ Birds Chirping ]
[ Bell Dinging ]
- Afternoon, ma'am.
- Well, well, we've been expecting you.
[ Man On TV ] There are less than
fiive minutes to takeoff now.
Um, it's very nice
to see you again, ma'am.
I'm glad you came.
Please excuse me for not standing.
My legs are bothering me
more than usual.
Barsa, bring
the package now.
Gosh, I hope it
hasn't taken off.
Not yet. Barsa is absolutely
mad about lighter-than-air travel.
I'm the adventuresome type.
[ Man On TV] The local fire department
and the Coast Guard stand ready.
Could you turn it
down, please?
Would you do me a favour
and open the box?
Yep.
[ Gasps ]
I don't get it.
Would you please bring this
to a young delivery girl?
She was kind to me
and a very big help.
It's my way
of saying thank you.
Ah, yes, and can you fiind out
when her next birthday is?
Then I can bake her
another one.
Kiki.
Of course I will! And maybe
the young girl will want to know the lady's birthday,
because she'll be able to give
her a present to repay her!
- You've got a deal.
- [ Both Laughing ]
[ People Screaming On TV]
- [ Volume Increases ]
- [ Screaming ]
[ Gasps ]
- [ Static ]
- What happened?
- Oh, there's been a terrible accident.
[ Man On TV] Oh, no!
The tie-down ropes holding the blimp are breaking one by one!
[ Wind Howling,
Windows Banging ]
- [ Screaming ]
- [ Static ]
Oh, darn this old thing!
And just when it was getting good!
Midsummer is always
when these winds come.
They'll be hitting us
any minute.
It'll pass quickly.
Don't worry.
[ Barsa ]
It's back on. Look!
[ Screaming ]
Oh, look at that.
It's completely upside down.
Freak winds
blowing in from the sea!
- It has broken loose
from its mooring ropes. - My, my. How terrible.
A desperate last-ditch
effort is being made to tie the dirigible to the ground...
and keep it from
drifting into the air.
But it's extremely doubtful whether
or not this can actually be done.
Oh, no, no!
It's useless!
The tremendous lifting power
of the helium balloon is lifting the police patrol car--
- That's Tombo! That's my friend
hanging on that rope. - Huh?
It's being lifted
as though it were a toy!
Oh, no, there's a young boy
hanging onto the cable!
He's being lifted away
together with the police car!
I-I don't believe what I'm seeing. The
dirigible is being blown towards town!
-Are you sure it's your friend, my dear?
- I have to go!
- Be careful!
- Oh, dear!
- Come on! Over here!
- Over here!
- Look! There he is!
- Look! It's a man up there!
Hold on there, son!
Just hold your grip steady!
Release the helium
from the tail! Quick!
[ Straining, Grunting ]
[ Screaming, Grunting ]
Oh!
[ Screaming ]
[ Panting ]
[ Siren Wailing ]
[ Man On Megaphone ]
All citizens are kindly...
requested to remain calm!
Tombo! Sir, is there
any word about the boy?
All I know is that the radio said that
the police car dropped into a pool.
He's still up there!
The helium inside the dirigible
will not explode.
- [ Panting ]
- [ Sirens Wailing ]
[ Man On Megaphone ]
Stay out of the street!
Get on the sidewalks!
You there! Young lady!
Are you all right,
young lady?
Please, sir, may I use
your broom for a minute?
- What?
- Please! I promise I'll bring it right back!
- Huh? I'm not gonna
give you my broom-- - Thank you very much!
- Hey!
- [ Siren Wailing ]
[ Breathing Deeply ]
Fly.
[ Crowd Gasps ]
Oh, my goodness!
[ Screaming ]
- [ Crowd Gasping ]
- [ Screaming ]
- Did you see that?
- Unbelievable! Flew up in the air!
Straighten up and fly right,
or I'll burn you!
[ Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
Ladies and gentlemen, it appears
that the blimp is heading directly for the clock tower!
And, look, the young boy is safe, but
he's clutching that rope for dear life!
If the wind doesn't shift,
the Spirit of Freedom will smash into the tower!
We gotta get up higher or else
we'll hit the tower, Captain!
There's not enough helium.
Jump onto the tower before we hit!
Aye, aye, Captain!
Hey there!
Over here! Come on!
Get outta the way!
The blimp's gonna crash!
Grab a hold of this!
- [ Grunting ]
- Huh?
[ Straining, Grunting ]
Hurry up!
[ Gasps, Screams ]
- [ Siren Wailing ]
- Hey!
[ Gas Hissing ]
We are listening to the sound
of a helium gas leak!
The condition of the boy is unknown,
but from where I'm standing-- Oh, no!
- [ Man ] Oh!
- [ Man ] Oh, no! Oh, no!
It's falling! Too much gas has escaped.
It's coming down!
[ Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
It's snagged on the building
across the street where it's--
- Hey, look! Over there!
- It's a miracle!
The young boy has somehow managed
to keep his hold on the rope!
But how can anyone
rescue him now?
That brave young boy
is hanging on for dear life!
He can't--
Something just flew by!
It's a bird? No, it's not a bird.
It's a young girl.
No! It's a young witch soaring
through the sky, and she's riding--
- Go, Kiki!
- Oh, my!
- She can fly again!
- Get 'im, Kiki!
- Tombo!
- Kiki!
[ Grunts ]
Come on now!
Be a good broom!
Hold on, Tombo!
Hang in there, my good lad!
Tombo!
Kiki!
[ Both Straining ]
And she's trying
to reach the boy!
- You can do it! Yes!
- Don't give up now, sonny!
[ Crowd Chanting ]
Don't give up!
Don't give up! Don't give up!
- Don't give up!
- [ Screaming ]
She got him! She saved the youngster!
I've never seen anything so amazing!
[ Cheering ]
Congratulations, young lady!
[ Cheering Continues ]
Now she's bringing him
down to land, safe and sound.
And you saw it all live
as she saved his life.
That broom she used was mine.
That was my broom, you know!
- Oh, Barsa! Oh, my!
- Yippee!
Kiki was so brave.
She really saved the day.
Uh-oh! Uh, better
call the hospital, honey!
I think it's time now!
Ooh!
-Jiji!
- Meow!
?? [ Pop ]
Listen, we just got
a letter from Kiki.
Huh? Oh!
``Dear Mother and Father,
How are you doing?
I'm happy to say that Jiji and I
are doing fiine at the moment.''
[ Kiki's Voice ]
Regarding my work, it certainly seems everything is falling into place.
I'm even starting
to gain some confidence.
There are still some times
when I feel a little homesick.
But all in all,
I sure love this city.