Looking down on our planet,
it may come as a surprise
to find just how much of it
is blanketed in snow and ice.
These vast frozen wildernesses cover
more than a fifth of the Earth...
..yet some areas are so remote
and inhospitable that, even today,
the closest we've come to
exploring them is from space.
More than a decade ago,
the first series of Frozen Planet
examined life in the Arctic
and the Antarctic.
In this series, we will explore all
of Earth's frozen habitats...
..from its highest peaks,
to its snowbound deserts...
..to deep beneath the ice.
Between them, they contain an
astonishing array of animals...
..many that are found
nowhere else on Earth.
POLAR BEARS SNARLING
We will watch the extraordinary ways
by which they manage to survive.
WOLF YELPS
Using new technology,
such as racer drones,
we'll gain a new insight into
their remarkable lives.
But just as we're beginning
to understand its wildlife,
we are recognising
an alarming truth.
Our frozen wildernesses
are disappearing
at faster rates than ever before.
And never has it been more important
to understand
what is going on in these
icy territories.
In this first episode, we will
travel from pole to pole...
..to celebrate the
precious wildlife
found in our frozen wildernesses...
SEAL GRUNTS
..and witness their wonders...
..while there is still time
to save them.
This is Frozen Planet II.
We begin our journey in the
far south of the planet.
After six months of darkness,
the sun is starting to return
to the largest frozen expanse
on Earth...
..Antarctica -
a continent almost twice
the size of Australia.
Here, temperatures fall to
-80 degrees centigrade.
It's the coldest place on Earth.
WIND HOWLS
There is only one animal
here hardy enough
to raise its family in winter...
..the emperor penguin.
Winds here can reach speeds
of over 100mph,
and a chick is in real danger
of freezing to death.
But his parents are possibly
the most devoted in all nature.
They shield him from the full force
of the icy blast...
..and huddle together to create
a tight creche.
Within it, the chicks, remarkably,
can maintain their body temperature
of 37 degrees Celsius.
Until one spring day,
when the chicks have grown to
almost a metre tall...
..the parents simply walk away.
Their parental duties
are complete...
..and they will never again
return to their chicks.
As the days pass,
the chicks grow hungry...
CHICK CALLS
And their only chance of finding
a meal is out at sea...
..but that could be 30 miles away
across the frozen ocean.
When one makes the first
bold move...
HIGH-PITCHED CALLING
..the rest follow.
They set off at a steady pace.
But sliding on your belly
is an easy option.
Out on this ever-changing platform
of the frozen sea...
..towering walls of ice
stand in their way.
This will require
mountaineering skills.
Beaks come in useful as ice-picks.
And tobogganing is a quick way down.
As they near the sea,
the ice becomes more unstable.
Even the smallest crack is met
with suspicion.
And with good reason.
A crack can quickly turn
into a gaping chasm.
PENGUINS HONK
If they can't escape, the panicked
chicks will be doomed.
Made it.
Finally, the end is in sight.
The Southern Ocean.
In some years, the sea ice
is so unstable
that none make it as far as this.
These chicks are the lucky ones.
Not the most graceful entry.
But they are in their element...
..the sea.
They may have endured
the toughest of upbringings,
but now they can reap the benefits
of the long summer ahead
and feed in the richest waters
on Earth.
In winter, the seas around
Antarctica are so cold
that they form a platform of ice
twice the size of Europe.
But in summer, just off the shores
of the Antarctic Peninsula,
the ice cover breaks up into
millions of tiny ice floes.
It's an excellent place
for a Weddell seal
to rest up after a night's feed.
SEAL EXHALES
The bay is sheltered...
..and the water calm.
But there are great dangers here.
WAVES CRASH
Killer whales.
This pair of 15-year-olds
are learning what is perhaps
the most complex hunting technique
in nature.
After sizing up their prey...
..they assemble 30 metres away...
...and then launch an attack.
They swim in tandem,
synchronising their tail beats...
...to create a wave.
The seal is washed off...
..but it won't give up
without a fight.
The seal has escaped...
..this time.
But for the young killer whales,
help is at hand.
They live in multi-generational
family groups...
..led by an experienced female,
who can be over 100 years old.
Helped by her accumulated knowledge,
the whales have become
ruthlessly efficient.
They have a 90% hunting
success rate.
But a killer whale needs to eat
a seal a day...
..so this 14-strong family has
a lot of hunting to do.
Spreading out, they spyhop
to search the ice floes.
When a seal is spotted,
the scouts alert the family
with a rallying call.
HIGH-PITCHED CALLS
But if they are to catch
a seal resting on
such a large piece of ice...
..the hunters need to change
their tactics.
This time, they produce
a sub-surface wave.
THUDDING AND CRACKING
It breaks the ice into
smaller pieces.
But the seal still has a raft...
..and appears to be protected
from any oncoming wave.
The matriarch whale, however,
has a plan.
Working in a coordinated way,
the pod push the seal's ice platform
into clearer water.
The matriarch now tries
another tactic
which will avoid injury...
..blowing bubbles.
They disorientate the tiring seal.
And the whales move in for the kill.
Only about 100 killer whales in the
world hunt using this technique.
It's an ingenious solution
to the problem of finding prey
here in the most extreme frozen
habitat on Earth.
Antarctica is so cold
because of its position at
the far south of the planet.
But travel north, and
you'll find other icy worlds
that are created by altitude -
in the mountains.
The Andes, in South America,
with its 4,500 miles
of snow-covered peaks,
is the longest range on Earth.
These high icy worlds even exist
close to the equator,
where the sun is at its hottest -
as on Mount Kenya, in Africa.
But the highest mountains of all
stretch 1,500 miles across
the north of sub-tropical Asia -
the Himalaya.
At the western end,
bordering Pakistan,
stand the Karakoram.
They contain more peaks
over 8,000 metres high
than any other range on Earth...
...and include K2, which stands
over 8,600 metres tall.
The slopes of the Himalaya carry
the greatest accumulation
of snow and ice outside
the polar regions.
It's an area known as
the Third Pole.
But north of the Himalaya,
there are even more surprising
frozen worlds created by altitude.
A remote snow-bound desert...
..the Gobi.
CAMELS BELLOWING
And beyond it, a grassy plain
that stretches
for 5,000 miles across Central Asia.
It's known as the Great Steppe.
Here, sheltering from the elements
in his boulder den,
is a somewhat grouchy resident.
A Pallas's cat.
He has the densest fur of any cat
in the world.
Nonetheless, to keep warm, he must
catch up to five rodents a day.
Top of the menu are voles...
...and gerbils.
Relative to body size,
Pallas's cats have one of the
shortest legs of any cat...
..and that helps by giving them
a low profile when stalking.
But it's not so good for wading
through deep snow.
SNOW CRUNCHES
CAT MEOWS
Never mind. There are plenty more.
He just needs to stay focused.
Unfortunately, the longer
he's out in the snow,
the colder his paws become.
And he has only one way to get
the blood circulating again.
PAWS RUSTLE
That could be one shake too many.
GERBIL CALLS
Only one hunt in three by
a Pallas's cat is successful.
No wonder he has the reputation
of being
the grumpiest cat in the world.
To the north of the steppe,
in higher latitudes,
lies yet another frozen world.
The boreal forest.
750 billion snow-covered trees.
It's the largest forest on Earth,
encircling the top of the world
from Europe to Russia,
and across to North America.
At the far eastern end
of this vast Siberian forest
lies the hunting ground of one
of the world's rarest big cats.
The Siberian tiger.
Illegal hunting and destruction
of its habitat
have driven this tiger to
the very brink of extinction.
Now fewer than 500 remain
in the wild.
Weighing nearly 200kg, it's the
largest of all the big cats.
To keep warm, this male must
eat 10kg of meat a day.
But in winter, any prey
remaining here...
DEER CALLS
...is all too easily alarmed.
He must patrol his entire
700 square mile territory
if he is to find enough to eat.
PIGS SNORTING
His acute sense of smell tells him
that wild pig were here.
TIGER SNUFFLES
He's so hungry that he would tackle
even a 150kg black bear.
But it left here months ago...
...leaving only a faint trace
of its scent.
In the autumn, bears here escape
the coming winter
by hibernating inside caves.
But that wouldn't stop a tiger
from trying to catch one.
Remote cameras reveal
the bear's whereabouts.
TIGER SNUFFLES
It retreated into the farthest
recess months ago.
The tiger is simply too big
to reach it.
TIGER GROWLS
But ready for every opportunity,
this big cat is able to endure
the long Siberian winter.
And as long as this forest is kept
free from poachers,
these magnificent tigers have
a good chance of surviving.
In the northerly reaches
of the boreal forest...
...a strange phenomenon
illuminates the night sky.
The Aurora borealis.
Electrically charged particles
from the sun
collide with the Earth's atmosphere,
creating this otherworldly display.
Viewed from space, the aurora
brings light to the frozen poles,
which otherwise would remain in
darkness for almost three months.
This is the Arctic tundra...
...where temperatures can fall to
-50 degrees Celsius.
With little or no shelter,
few animals can survive
the winter here.
But some do.
WIND HOWLS
Muskox.
Relics from the last ice age.
Two layers of fur protect them
from temperatures of -30 degrees.
This allows them to give birth
in early spring.
At six hours old, a calf
is already able to stand...
LOW BELLOW
...ready to follow the herd in
the search for fresh grazing.
But until they gain in strength,
they are very vulnerable.
CALF BLEATS
They're being stalked.
Grizzly bears.
Weighing up to 300kg,
they have emerged after six months
of hibernation...
...and are extremely hungry.
One gets to within just
ten metres...
...and then attacks.
CALF BLEATS
Separated from their mothers,
the newly born are unable to
distinguish friend...
..from foe.
The bear instinctively kills
every calf it can.
Only a few escape.
But the herd is now far away...
...and he is too weak to follow.
CALF CALLS WEAKLY
90% of calves do not survive
their first year.
Even one without injury stands
little chance without its mother.
CALF BLEATS
CALF CALLS
Reunited.
If just a few calves survive
to adulthood,
the future of the herd
will be secure.
North of the tundra lies
the Arctic Ocean,
surrounded by three continents -
Europe, North America and Asia.
In winter, it remains almost
entirely frozen.
But as the spring sunshine finally
reaches the northernmost part
of the planet, the sea ice
begins to break up.
This marks the start of
the breeding season
for male hooded seals.
RUMBLING GRUNT
When they're six years old, the
males develop an inflatable nose.
They're ready to breed -
and the bigger their nose,
the more attractive they will be
to a female.
And now this one is eager
to prove it.
A female has just given birth.
A mother spends a mere four days
feeding milk to her pup...
...and then, and only then,
will she be ready to mate again.
That is too long for an impatient
youngster to wait around.
These females seem to have been
claimed by a larger male.
But if this youngster is to breed
this year, it's worth a try.
SEALS BELLOW
An inflatable nose can also be used
to intimidate a rival.
His bravado pays off.
He must now woo the
receptive female.
MALE SEAL CALLS
SEAL CALLS
She seems unimpressed.
But he has another trick.
He has an expandable sac within
his left nostril.
What is her verdict?
FEMALE SEAL GRUNTS
A sharp nip on the tail...
..and that means no.
With only one day in the year
in which to mate,
the female is understandably choosy.
And until the youngster has grown
a more impressive balloon,
he's unlikely to be chosen.
SEAL GROANS
No wonder he's deflated.
The spring not only transforms
the ocean,
it also triggers an important event
on the biggest of the
Arctic's islands.
Greenland - over 1,600 miles long.
WIND HOWLS
It's covered by a single
gigantic ice sheet,
the largest in the
northern hemisphere.
As spring advances,
the surface of the ice melts,
forming crystal-clear lakes...
..up to five miles wide.
Climate change is bringing
higher temperatures,
so there is more and more meltwater.
It drains down into the
mile-thick ice sheet...
...and a whole chain of events
is then triggered.
Time-lapse photography from space
reveals what happens next.
The increased meltwater accelerates
the ice sheet's slide downhill.
Eventually, it reaches the ocean.
ICE SHEET CRACKING
Here, it breaks up into icebergs,
some taller than the
Empire State Building.
Greenland is losing its ice
six times faster today
than it was 30 years ago.
It alone is responsible
for a quarter
of the rise in global sea levels.
Changes in the Arctic are
already affecting the lives
of its highly specialised wildlife.
Polar bears.
These one year old twins still rely
on their mother for her milk,
protection and crucial
survival lessons.
But they have yet to perfect their
swimming technique...
...and they can't wait to practise.
The cubs need to be as at home
in the water
as they are on the sea ice.
POLAR BEAR GRUNTS
Their mother calls them out.
Until they've accumulated a
significant layer of body fat...
...they feel the cold.
A roll in the snow is a good way
to dry off.
Then it's back to play...
..while their mother heads off
to hunt.
Over the coming months,
a mother must provide her cubs
with not just milk, but meat -
and lots of it.
By midsummer, the sea ice
has become so thin...
..that her best chance of
catching her preferred prey
is by ambushing it from the water.
It's a technique known
as aquatic stalking.
She approaches downwind...
..and tries to get within a metre
of a bearded seal.
But today there is less sea ice
to provide cover,
so she is having to target
riskier prey.
The hooded seal.
They are about the same size
as the bearded,
but more aggressive and dangerous.
She moves round to the other side.
The Arctic is now warming
more than twice as fast
as the rest of the world.
The sea could be ice-free in summer
by as early as 2035.
That will make it harder
for mother polar bears
to feed themselves...
...let alone their cubs.
Well adapted to live in the cold...
..the animals that inhabit our
frozen lands and seas
need one thing more than
any other...
..and that is for the planet
to stop warming.
It's now up to us
to make that happen.
Filming across the length and
breadth of our frozen planet,
one of the team's greatest
challenges was to capture
the enormity of Greenland's
rapidly melting ice sheet.
To do so, the crew launched five
separate filming expeditions,
installing specially designed
cold-proof time-lapse cameras
that were to run for three years.
Even commissioning satellites to
record the big-picture changes.
But the story would be incomplete
without documenting
the finale of this event -
the calving of Greenland's
Store Glacier...
...a wall of ice over
three miles long...
..and towering 120 metres high.
HELICOPTER ROTOR HUMS
The crew arrive at the height
of the summer thaw,
when, at any moment, fracturing ice
blocks the size of a small town
may be cast into the sea.
Camping out for the
next three weeks,
the team takes advantage of
the constant daylight
offered by the far north
at this time of the year.
We've got a lot of ice on the
glacier, 24 hours a day.
So, yeah, we're poised.
I started at about 8pm, and it's
currently, yeah, just after 2:00.
I've got until 4am this morning,
I think.
HE SNORES
INSECTS BUZZ
They're hoping to be one of
the first film crews
to use a camera drone for
unprecedented proximity
and a brand-new perspective.
Yeah, it's going.
DISTANT RUMBLING
It's not long before their new
technology is put to the test.
DRONE BUZZES
But it quickly reveals
its limitations.
The issue with the drone -
you've got to turn it on,
get it in the air, and fly it 1.5km
to the glacier fronts.
So, if you SEE a calving
happening...
..then you're too late.
With a flight time of
just 20 minutes,
gauging the moment of take-off
is critical.
Yeah, I feel like today
just every decision I've made
has been the wrong one.
It's really easy to trick yourself
into thinking,
"Oh, it's going to go, it's going
to go," so you get out there,
use up a whole drone battery
hovering, come back,
and as you're heading back...pfff!
Soon, the team face another problem
that comes with today's
warming Arctic.
Unseasonably wet weather makes it
impossible to fly the drone,
and acts as a catalyst
for further melting.
THUNDEROUS CRASHING
Absolute racket happening down in...
..the glacier.
Oh, my goodness.
DISTANT BOOMING
Even if it is a major
calving event...
..can't see a thing.
BOOMING ECHOES
That sound just went on and on.
HEAVY BOOM
That one was huge.
After five days of frustration,
the fog finally lifts
to reveal the bay choked
with giant icebergs.
It appears the crew have missed
their opportunity.
The morale of the crew has taken
a little bit of a downturn.
Do you know what,
I just don't know what to say.
I'm so tired.
To make matters worse, a plague
of mosquitoes descends,
further disheartening
the exhausted team.
INSECTS BUZZ
All your senses are all-go
all the time,
even when you're trying to sleep,
so it's just...
...a bit emotionally draining
sometimes.
Then, with just a few
shooting days left,
under a warming sun,
the glacier groans and rumbles
back into action.
GLACIER CREAKS
Ooh...
HEAVY BOOM
Guys, big one going!
This could be the opportunity
they've been waiting for.
Oh, my gosh, look at that! Ah!
A calving event lasting long enough
to film from the drone.
But no-one is prepared for
the sheer scale of it.
Just layer after layer of ice
broke away
and fell into the sea,
and then out came this enormous,
skyscraper-sized iceberg,
displacing vast quantities of water
and throwing enormous blocks of ice
around like they were nothing.
Sitting here, day after day,
crossing your fingers
and hoping that you get a big
calving and you see a big event,
and you manage to film it,
and when it does happen,
when it does go off,
it's so exciting,
and you get the adrenaline.
And then, afterwards, as you're
sort of coming down from that,
there's a bitter sweetness to it
as you realise that's another piece
of ice that's slowly raising
the sea level.
Such imagery provides an invaluable
record of the rapid changes
that are now taking place across
our frozen planet.
Next time...
..we travel to the Arctic Ocean.
Where life must adapt in
a changing world...
..of water and ice.
The Open University has produced
a poster exploring how animals
adapt to life in the world's
coldest environments.
To order your free copy,
please call 0300 303 0553,
or go to bbc.co.uk/frozenplanet2
and follow the links
to the Open University.