carlo: Yeah, I started the hostility log thing this week.
How's that working out?
Oh, yeah, good, yeah.
Um, had a bit of a situation Wednesday with somebody.
Yeah, it was just some guy eyeballing me at the pub.
But I was getting pretty pissed
and I used the stop technique, you know, we spoke about.
So, yeah, I'm...I'm getting pretty good at it.
- So that's good. - Great.
Um, ray, how have you been?
Yeah, good, mate.
- Yeah? - Yep.
Is there anything you want to talk about?
No. I'm good.
Are you sure? Nothing at all?
Hmph.
I beat my, uh, girlfriend's brother up over christmas.
Ok, um...
..What happened?
I went round to her parents' place
and, um, you know, we did the whole secret santa thing.
Me daughter got this unicorn candle,
which she was pretty chuffed about.
And me girlfriend's brother decided he wanted it
and when it was his turn he took it off her.
So you assaulted him?
Well, he was being a dickhead, so, you know...
- So you assaulted him? - Yeah, pretty much.
And how did your girlfriend feel about this?
Well, she's not my girlfriend anymore, so...
- Shit. Sorry, mate. - Mmm.
I mean, I...You know,
without wanting to state the obvious,
can you see how violence is perhaps not the best way
for you to resolve your disputes?
No, I think it generally is.
But, you know, just don't do it
in front of your girlfriend, you know?
uh, what's great about it?
It doesn't seem to have worked for you this time.
Yeah, well, sometimes it does, sometimes it doesn't, you know?
Can you give me one example of violence ever working?
World war ii.
- World war ii? - Mm-hm.
We didn't beat the nazis just by talking to 'em.
- We used violence. - Ok, sure.
So, every now and then,
violence is necessary as a last resort,
but for you with your girlfriend's brother,
I mean, would you call that an example of violence working?
Look, I shouldn't have done what I did. I'm not making excuses.
But I don't think you can say that all violence is bad.
I mean, I think there's good violence and bad violence.
- What's good violence? - World war ii.
Thanks, vince.
- Um... - Yeah.
Uh, alright, maybe... It's about time.
Maybe we should leave it there.
Thank you, everyone. Thank you.
Alright.
The german forces had already moved in
and now occupied the abbey ruins in force.
here you go, mate. You can have the fatty bit.
Mate, you didn't even chew that.
The 28th maori battalion
had led a successful attack on the cassino railway station,
only to then become trapped
and cut off from their support across the river.
cheers, love.
- hey. - How you doin'?
Good. What's news?
Not much. What's news with you?
Nothing. You ok?
Yeah.
Ok.
* you're a naughty, naughty girl and I love it... *
hello.
Ray, it's vinnie.
How you goin', mate?
I'm good, my friend. How are you?
Yeah, good, mate. What's news?
Oh, you know, same old shit in here, mate.
Listen, I thought I'd check in
and see if you want to catch up for a beer sometime.
Yeah, sounds good, mate.
Yeah.
I'm pretty...Pretty busy this week.
Um, what about next weekend?
Sure, weekend. Oh, fuck. No, no, no, no.
Fuck. No, I gotta go see my folks.
Got a farm up there in dorrigo,
so, yeah, I'll be away all weekend.
Ok. What about the weekend after that, then?
Weekend after. Sounds great. Let's shoot for that, eh?
Yeah, mate. I'll keep it free.
Alright, you take care of yourself, brother.
- Same, mate. Talk to you soon. - Alright, mate.
See you, mate.
you just gonna leave that there, are you, love?
- Excuse me? - Your dog just took a shit.
- Are you gonna clean it up? - So?
Just gonna leave it for somebody else to stand in, are you?
Well, if it bothers you so much, why don't you pick it up?
Why don't you fuckin' pick it up?
Oh, ok. Yeah.
Nah, it's been good.
I mean, it's still early days.
But, fuck, last night we're lying in bed
and she says to me,
"who have you had the best sex of your life with?"
and I'm lying there thinking, "fuck, how do I answer this?"
you know, because she's not the bird
I've had the hottest sex with.
But I can't tell her the best sex I ever had
was with some 52-year-old hooker in an alley, you know?
So, I have to say something and fast,
so I say, "you!"
but because I took a second to answer,
she's like, "why did you have to think about it?"
I said, "I don't know.
"the question kind of took me by surprise."
I tell you, mate,
women can ask questions that scare the shit out of you.
Hmm. Hmm. True.
- So, who is this dude, anyway? - Who?
- This guy? - Oh, simon gillespie.
- You know the gillespies? - The mining family?
- Yeah. - Oh, ok.
And what's his problem?
He's been having some lady trouble.
Oh, ok.
hey. Uh, simon's here.
- Do you want to see him now? - Yeah, yeah. Bring him in.
- Thanks, mandy. - You're good.
Oh. Thanks, mandy.
- G'day, mate. - Hey, freddy.
- well, there's a familiar face. - Good to see you.
Good to see you too.
- It's been way too long. - Yes.
Uh, simon, this is ray.