7 million strong,
marching shoulder to
shoulder with Calvin.
Jed "Duke" ducoyle's
an extremist pundit
with millions of followers.
This is a grift.
Calvin's an anonymous
online conspiracy theorist.
Think q but somehow
more extreme.
So Calvin posts five words.
Duke decodes it.
He's directing people
to kill in the real world.
- I don't recognize...
I don't recognize
your authority.
People are dead because of you.
Calvin posted all the intel.
You know, this conversation
would go a lot smoother
if you would just admit
that you are Calvin.
Don't move!
We have a shooter.
Now we just have to
prove Duke drove him to kill.
He trusted that... that I
could get the job done.
Jed ducoyle, you
are under arrest.
You've accomplished
nothing by arresting me today.
Get prepared, 'cause
a war is coming,
and Calvin's ready to fight.
- My god.
- You should have seen it.
She hit the fadeaway jumper,
half second left on the clock!
Thing of beauty.
Sounds like the basketball
hoop in the backyard's
- working out.
- Yeah.
Paint me a proud dad.
What do you think?
You got to be kidding
me with this thing.
Right? Best cannoli
I have ever tasted.
And my nonna's from sicily,
so that's saying something.
That makes this a real tragedy.
I take no joy in putting
this place six feet under,
but you don't pay what
you owe, things get ugly.
You about done?
Man, I hope they don't cry.
I hate it when they cry.
We need to talk to the owner.
Carolyn Eugene, head of
the New York IRS field office.
Agent bell. This is agent zidan.
I'm sorry to hear
about your guys.
Yeah, it's a... Hell
of a call to get.
Hank tamburello died on
scene of multiple stab wounds
from an unknown assailant.
His partner, Russell
kreider, tried to intervene,
was stabbed right over here,
died en route to the hospital.
Both of my guys
were special agents
with our criminal
investigation division.
Assuming there were
multiple witnesses.
Half the breakfast crowd.
My guys were here for an audit.
Business had been
underreporting, hiding money.
Guy must have
been waiting for them
jumped off his bike,
came in, started stabbing.
The owner know that
your guys were coming?
Maybe they were
prepared to fight back.
No.
No, owner had no idea.
NYPD get a description?
Guy had a motorcycle helmet on
dragon logo, full leathers,
visor kept their face hidden.
Medium build, sped
off around that corner.
They had the
knife in their hand,
according to multiple witnesses.
Okay, we'll get the joc
to run all the security
cameras in the area.
We'll find this guy.
We're here, and we're
going to do everything we can.
Thank you.
- Here's your oat latte.
- Amazing.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
We good here?
Yeah, Patrick, I'm good. Thanks.
Okay, so, earlier today,
IRS special agents
Hank tamburello
and Russell kreider were victims
of a brutal knife
attack in little Italy.
Both tamburello and
kreider died of their wounds.
These men were
federal agents just like us.
So, come hell or high water,
we are going to get them justice.
Agreed?
How we doing with surveillance?
Ert combed the area
for security cameras.
This is right across
from the café.
Okay.
Yeah, yeah, can we zoom
in on the mystery perp's bike?
- Plates or...?
- No can do.
Our suspect used a plate flipper
to conceal their license number,
and the helmet
prevented any facial rec.
But if you look
close, there is a decal
- of a dragon logo on the back.
- All right.
You guys want to
run with that image,
see what you can chase down?
Should stick to street cams,
see what else you can find.
You're profiling the victims.
Any enemies?
Long-standing grudges?
Well, both men
were special agents
in the IRS's criminal
investigation division.
Right, of course, they
worked major financial crimes
fraud, money laundering...
Tamburello put away
over 80 criminals
on various charges.
Could be motive there.
Right, so no
shortage of suspects
who might want to see him dead.
Maybe this was a
hired assassination.
Wait a minute. Got something.
Yeah? What? Show me.
71 seconds later,
our biker reappears.
But notice anything missing?
Let me get in
closer on the image.
- His pockets are empty, meaning there's...
- No weapon.
Must have ditched it between
this place and the café.
Good work. Get a team out there.
Knife attacks are
pretty rare in the U.S.
They only account for
one out of ten homicides.
To brutally stab two people...
Yeah, in broad
daylight in a busy café.
I don't know. This
one feels personal.
Yeah, or targeted.
Ooh, winner, winner,
chicken dinner.
Look at this.
We should be able to
get some DNA off of that.
Yeah. Look at that etching.
Well, that's a bit bolder
than I was expecting.
Yeah, according
to the ert report,
no fingerprints, but, let's
take a look at the design
- etched on the blade.
- Yeah.
It's called a maker's
Mark. It's like a signature.
Okay, yeah, we got a hit.
That's the hallmark
for ivar asghari.
He's a local bladesmith
working out of greenpoint.
Asghari's social media accounts
are full of libertarian
anti-tax sentiment.
We thinking the knife
maker hates the taxman?
Guy's got a rap
sheet half a block long
mostly drugs, resisting arrest.
I'd say it's time to pay
this bladesmith a visit.
Ivar asghari? FBI.
Appointment only.
And it's ee-var.
Did you like
something on my site,
or you want something custom?
Did you hear us? We're the FBI.
Not a little curious as to
what we're doing here?
Well, I'm not going
to incriminate myself.
What an incredibly
incriminating thing to say.
Two men were brutally stabbed
with a knife that was made here.
- Who bought it?
- You got a warrant?
If you'd like, we can
head down to 26 fed,
have this conversation
in the interrogation room.
I'm not legally obligated
to tell you anything
about my customers.
All right, call the
joc, get the warrant.
We're gonna tear
this place apart.
What?
Well, your personal maker's Mark
was on the steel of
the murder weapon.
So we're just gonna assume
that you were the
last one to use it.
We need to expedite
the search warrant
for ivar asghari,
suspicion of murder.
Okay, okay. Whoa, whoa,
whoa. Hold on, hold on.
- I sold that knife.
- To who?
I got it right here.
Name is Sandra longo.
All right, joc just
sent over the file.
She operates heavy machinery.
She has no priors,
and she's not connected
to any of the victims.
Yeah, something's not adding up.
The IRS criminal division
usually goes after
corrupt billionaires,
not blue-collar workers.
She's not right for this.
Well, maybe she can
lead us to whoever is.
Is that her?
Sandra.
Hey, Sandra!
- Turn it off!
- Sorry. What do you need?
We're the FBI.
I'm special agent bell.
This is special agent zidan.
Look, can you come down here?
We have a few questions for you.
Is there a problem?
Where were you this
morning before you clocked in?
Why?
Two men were murdered
in Brooklyn this morning.
The weapon used was this knife.
We were able to
track it back to you.
That... yeah, that was mine,
but I gave it to a consignment
shop a while back.
I can get you the name of
the place if you give me a sec.
No, no, no. Hold
on. Is that your bike?
- What?
- Your bike.
No, that's my boyfriend's. Why?
Okay, we need you to get down.
Yeah, get down
right now. Come on.
Hey!
Sandra longo, hands up!
You're under arrest for the
murder of two federal agents.
Drop the phone.
We can tie the murder
weapon back to you.
Also, your motorcycle
helmet is identical
to the one used
by today's assailant.
So, tell us, why did you
target Hank tamburello
and Russell kreider?
I don't recognize
your authority.
Okay, here's what's
gonna happen next.
You will be put at the
scene, and we will charge you
with first-degree murder
of two federal agents.
I don't get it.
You're getting stellar
performance reviews at work.
Your manager said
that you were on track
to be promoted within the year.
Why throw all that away?
What's this really about?
I don't recognize
your authority.
Well, that sounds familiar.
Yeah, I wanted to make sure,
so I got the joc to
pull these interviews.
I don't recognize
your authority.
Remember that's
all they would say
after they attacked the
greenwich monument?
Yeah, because
they're Calvin followers.
I can't believe there
are still people who think
there's a highly-placed
fed named Calvin
leaking classified information.
There are, but I thought
we silenced Calvin.
We did. The Calvin
account has been radio silent
for the last few months.
Then yesterday...
A new post on the
forums that reads,
"beware the brewing tempest."
We're not going to
play this game again.
Everybody knows
there is no Calvin.
It's Duke.
Duke ducoyle is the
one behind the mask.
He's the one decoding
the messages,
raking in the cash from all
of his brainwashed followers.
I am telling you right
now, Duke is behind this,
and I want to know how.
Isobel.
You okay?
Yeah.
I should have seen this coming.
Duke's trial for inciting
violence starts next month.
It's got to be related.
Duke's cocky, but he's smart.
You really think
that he would risk
violating the terms of his bond?
That doesn't track.
People have been following me.
What?
It started when I
went after Duke.
Like, I would... I
would feel them
standing behind me, watching.
You know, just today in
my coffee shop, this creep
he just stood there,
blocking my way like a pillar.
- What'd he say to you?
- Nothing.
He didn't have to.
I mean, the Calvin account
didn't mention me by name,
so can I prove
that it's Duke? No.
But they're only getting bolder.
I brought the issue
to adic Reynolds.
He assigned me and
Phillip a security detail.
I'm sorry.
This stuff can mess
with your head.
And you really can talk
to me about these things.
Maggie, I am your sac.
And I'm your friend.
You know, we need to
take Duke down for good.
I'm going to pay
that little snake a visit.
There he is.
- Not interested.
- We got a warrant.
Move.
So why'd you order Sandra
longo to murder two IRS agents?
I think we've done
this dance before,
and I'm a little busy right now.
Duke, is that a finger?
It is, but it's not
what it looks like.
Duke, whose finger is it?
- Obviously not yours.
- I have no interest
in dragging the
deep state into this.
Well, we're here,
and whatever that is
doing there now involves us,
so start talking.
My wife, trishelle,
disappeared two days ago.
Last night her finger showed
up on my doorstep, so...
I put it on ice, you
know, just in case.
Why wouldn't you call the FBI?
The FBI?
The U.S. attorney is already
giving me a free colonoscopy,
thanks to you.
Last thing I need are more feebs
tromping mud all over my brand.
Just tell us what happened.
Trishelle went to
hot yoga on Tuesday,
like always, but she
didn't come home.
When she wasn't back
by dinner, I got nervous.
And then she calls.
I answer it, but it's not her.
It's a gravelly voice.
This guy says,
"I have your wife."
"Await further
instructions." Click.
I call back, but her phone's
gone to voicemail ever since.
And then her finger arrived.
In a Manila envelope,
wrapped in two-ply.
Hey, you got security cameras?
Maybe we can see
who dropped it off.
Security cameras?
They steal your data.
It's like installing your
own personal narc.
Okay.
And the kidnappers, what
were their demands? Money?
I go to trial next month.
I'd like assurances that any
statement I make here today...
Will not be used against
me in a court of law.
- Duke.
- You had no idea...
What was going on
before you got here,
and I'm not in cuffs.
So you need me for something.
Fine, we'll recommend
that your statement
isn't used against you, in
the interest of public safety.
Now, what did the
kidnappers want?
They demanded my
password to the Calvin account.
Your password.
So you're finally admitting
that you were posting
as Calvin all along?
Yes. Who cares?
It's immaterial!
It doesn't matter!
What matters is,
they're holding my wife!
- We can't trust Duke ducoyle.
- The man is a professional liar.
- He's working an angle.
- Yeah. No, no, agreed.
Look, I-I know we... we all want
to connect this back to Duke,
but so far, we've
found zero connection
between him and our
two dead IRS agents.
I mean, look, i-i...
I want to see this guy go
down as badly as anyone,
but it looks like he has
no motive to lie here.
Okay, let's say Duke
is telling the truth.
Someone new is running
the Calvin account,
which means that person
can use the account
to communicate with
7 million loyal followers.
Yeah, so... How is the
new Calvin communicating
with Sandra longo?
That's the question.
He got Sandra longo
to carry out a specific hit.
Well, we've... we've
scoured her 4chan,
her discord accounts...
nothing so far.
We are missing something.
The me just confirmed
the severed finger
did belong to trishelle ducoyle.
So that supports Duke's story.
We've got to figure out how
to get Sandra to start talking.
Although if I have to hear
"I do not recognize your
authority" one more time...
You know, Sandra longo
she may not
recognize our authority,
but we happen to have
one of her idols in custody
the high priest of calvinism.
Duke ducoyle.
Before we go any further,
I'd like to address the
elephant in the room.
I missed you, too.
I know that you have been
sending your sycophants
to stalk me and my family.
I'm sure I don't know
what you're talking about.
This little game of yours
it is not gonna work forever.
I'm joining you in there.
I can get this
calvinite to talk,
but not with a deep-state
fed hovering over my shoulder.
You're everything
these people despise.
Thanks to your
propaganda. Follow me.
That woman in
there has information
that could lead us to your wife,
so there is no way in hell
I am leaving you in
there unsupervised.
All right. Better let
me do the talking.
- My god. Duke ducoyle?
- The one and only.
I-I've watched every
episode of "the path."
Thank you.
Wait, what are you
doing here with them?
Calvin has friends everywhere.
The real question, Sandra,
is, can we trust you?
Of course.
I-I've been following
Calvin from day zero.
I'm a true believer.
Good, because Calvin
might be in trouble.
And we need your help.
Did Calvin ever ask you
to go after anyone else?
Maybe that woman?
No.
He only contacted me about
the IRS agent, tamburello.
Wait, he contacted
you? Only you?
Yeah. He chose me.
Calvin... he doesn't
take chances.
He's careful. Why
did he choose you?
Because he knows
that I'm ready to fight.
I've been here since
the very first drop.
He knows I'm loyal.
Well, if that's true,
how did he contact you?
Through a new app.
Calvin messaged me privately.
He said there was this
deep-state detractor
causing him problems,
threatening to ruin everything.
But he said that I was the
warrior that could save him.
What app?
Okay, so Sandra just gave up
her method of communication
with the new Calvin plumage
some social media
app for birders
that has a hidden
encrypted messaging feature.
Yeah, should have known.
That app can't tell
the difference between
a blue warbler
and a house Finch.
It's whac-a-mole with these
illicit communication apps.
Shut one down, a
new one pops up.
But if the app exists,
we can get into it, right?
Has the dive team
recovered Sandra's phone
so we can scrape its data?
Yeah, but it still needs to
be cleaned and dried out
- before we can exploit it.
- Hey, good news...
Sandra's plumage account
is synced to the app's cloud.
- Downloading all of her dms.
- Really?
Okay, here we
go. Let's see here.
There, that avatar is
the same one Calvin uses
on the other accounts.
Here we go... "my
devoted warrior",
"a deep-state detractor
"could cost us everything
we've fought for.
"Silence an IRS agent
named Hank tamburello
in the name of justice."
Yeah, it doesn't get
any clearer than that.
He even gave her tamburello's
home and work addresses.
Can we try Calvin's
account on the bird app,
get a location on where
he sent the messages from?
Yeah, pulling 5g data from
plumage's mobile back end.
Triangulating tcp
and udp endpoints.
Calvin sent his messages
from an abandoned storefront
on Apollo street.
Freeze!
Got a runner.
Suspect got away.
Trishelle. It's okay.
It'll be okay. I got you.
You're safe now.
All right, so trishelle ducoyle
has been recovered... her
kidnapper remains at large.
"Oa describes a 6'3"
white male, beard,
jeans, and a brown jacket,
last seen heading south.
Okay, check cameras
within a four-block radius.
None are working
in that vicinity.
We're expanding our search.
Jubal, Calvin just
posted a new message.
- He... this one is live.
- What?
Hue and cry, Calvin
stands before you.
To my loyal warriors,
rattle the cages.
Be loud. Be known.
Make them fear us.
And to the FBI cabal who
just tried to capture me
and thwart our greater mission,
you listen to my words,
and you listen very closely.
Release the greenwich 41
those righteous soldiers
who were unlawfully detained
outside the greenwich
national monument.
You release them from your
custody by 2:00 P.M. today.
Or... Tomorrow your
deep-state puppets... Will die.
The greenwich
riot was a disgrace.
41 of Calvin's most
strident followers
showed up at his command.
NYPD were injured,
federal property destroyed.
Our own agents were
attacked and assaulted.
Now, make no mistake
we are not releasing
the greenwich 41.
But whoever gained
control of the Calvin account
has made their demands clear
release the 41, or two more
deep-state puppets will die.
Well, that is not
going to happen,
because we're
going to stop this.
Right now, the 41 are being held
at the mullin detention center.
Their joint trial is
set to start this week.
Which explains the timing
and urgency of the threat.
So who is the new
Calvin targeting?
Who are these two deep-state
puppets in his crosshairs?
Government employees, no doubt.
There are a dozen
agencies active on this case,
including our own people.
- Could be anyone.
- Right.
Our best lead is
Duke ducoyle's wife,
but she's elected not
to answer any questions.
I know how to make her talk.
- Doctor Carter...
- You again.
I'm here to see my wife.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa. This isn't a free visit.
She's not giving us the
information that we need.
Yeah, trishelle won't talk
to you unless I'm there.
- We know.
- She saw her kidnapper.
We need to find out who that is.
Fine. Let's go.
Baby love, I was a
wreck without you.
I didn't want them
here either, believe me.
Just answer their questions,
and they'll be gone.
Mrs. Ducoyle, again,
we are trying to
identify your abductor.
Anything you remember
could help us out right now.
I don't recognize
your authority.
Trish, it's okay. Just
tell them what you know.
And I don't recognize you.
Babe, enough.
No.
You used to care about
the deeper mission, Duke.
You were the king.
And then you gave it all
up. You just walked away.
Trishelle, I'm being
prosecuted by the state.
I thought we were both devoted
to Calvin, to his cause.
I thought you would be excited
to know that he chose me
me, Duke... to be a part
of something greater.
He cut off your finger.
I gave it to him!
Calvin needed a sacrifice,
he said, to free the 41.
And I was more
than happy to help.
What are you talking about?
This is war, Duke!
You used to know that!
Calvin told me you'd gone soft,
that you'd lost
the will to fight.
I didn't want to believe him.
I am Calvin, Trish!
I am! I invented him!
This other guy is
nothing but an impostor.
Calvin told me you'd say that.
Just tell us about
your kidnapper.
Or what?
I pity you, Duke.
You're asleep, and
you don't even know it.
Calvin is ready for war.
He was even willing to
punish the deep-state detractor
who was living in his midst.
What are you willing to
sacrifice for our cause?
What happened to you?
All right.
So we are down the rabbit
hole on this one, folks.
Trishelle ducoyle believes
the man who kidnapped her
was the real Calvin.
Be that as it may, she did
say something that might help
that Calvin punished
a deep-state detractor
living in his midst.
The message Calvin sent
from his account to Sandra longo
referred to agent tamburello
as a deep-state detractor.
Right, but the... the "living
in his midst," the new part
so is tamburello someone
our guy works with,
someone he sees every day?
Maybe he's someone
from the neighborhood.
Hey, check this out.
So here are the residents
of Hank tamburello's building.
Now, if we cross-reference
them with the families
connected to the greenwich
41, we might find a nexus.
Aha, here we go.
Rob Whitfield.
- Would you believe it?
- What? This is a neighbor?
They live across the
hall from each other.
Really? Okay.
And he's 6'3". He's got a beard.
He matches the description
of the guy oa ran into.
What do we know about him?
Rob Whitfield is a
software engineer.
No priors.
He's posted some
conspiratorial nonsense online,
but other than
that, no red flags.
Right, but he's got a
connection to the 41, right?
- What is it?
- His brother was one of them.
Chris Whitfield was arrested
that day at the monument.
He attacked a police
officer with a pipe.
And tamburello lives
10 feet from this guy?
That's right.
If you're so inclined,
that sounds a hell of a lot
like a deep-state
detractor living in his midst.
It's a hell of a way to
deal with a neighbor.
We need to ask Rob
Whitfield some questions.
Get a team to his house.
FBI!
Clear.
Okay, so if Hank tamburello
lived across the hall
from Rob Whitfield...
Thin walls.
So did he hear or see
something suspicious,
Rob got nervous
and had him killed?
I don't know. Come look at this.
Rob was following
all of the arrests
and pretrial motions of the
greenwich 41 prosecution.
Look, here's his brother, Chris.
So did Rob figure out
what we knew all along...
Duke ducoyle was
running the Calvin account?
Maybe he thought that if
he took over the account,
he could use it to his advantage
and help free his brother.
Check this out.
The way he was saying
the U.S. attorney that are
leading the prosecution
against the greenwich 41
if something happens
to them, that's a mistrial.
Deep-state puppets.
- Jubal?
- Yeah, Maggie?
Hey, you need to
call the courthouse.
Warn the U.S. attorneys
they're the next targets.
See justice done!
Release the 41!
They could just be protesters.
Or Rob Whitfield could
have used the Calvin account
to turn one of them
into an assassin.
Or he's here
hiding in the crowd.
Release the 41!
Jubal, don't let the
prosecution team exit
through the front entrance.
Take them to the side
door. We'll meet them there.
- Let's go.
- See justice done!
Okay, give me a status
on the courthouse.
I'm on with the U.S. marshals.
The attorneys are
aware of the threat.
They were about to exit
through the front door
but saw the crowd gathering.
Yeah, let's have them
exit the east-side door.
They'll wait for our signal.
Maggie and oa will
be waiting outside.
- Copy.
- NYPD,
you're circulating Rob
Whitfield's photo, right?
Good, okay.
How we doing with the
courthouse cameras?
Looking for anyone we can
ID, someone with a weapon.
Okay, jubal, area's
clear. Send 'em out now.
- Okay, stand by.
- Here they come.
U.S. attorney
harrington, with me.
Hurry up, you guys. Go.
- Stay close.
- Quickly.
Gun!
Down! Get down!
- Go! Go, go, go!
- Stay down. Take cover.
Down! Get down!
Marshal down. Send medical.
Is it him?
No.
Jubal, suspect is down,
but it's not Rob Whitfield.
I repeat... not Rob Whitfield.
We need to round
up the protesters.
He still might be out here.
Okay, what do we know about
our shooter at the courthouse?
His name is Theo haynes.
Calvin reached out to him
through the birdwatching app.
This is their exchange.
Calvin all but ordered him to
assassinate the prosecutors
to disrupt the trial.
It turns out Theo haynes's wife
is one of the greenwich 41,
so he was personally motivated.
And now his wife's a widow.
What do we know about
the other protesters?
NYPD rounded them up, but
Rob Whitfield wasn't on site.
He's still in the wind.
Which means he
still has the power
to mobilize more calvinites
to do his dirty work.
He just posted a
new Calvin message.
- Let's take a look.
- Okay, eyes up, folks.
"A hundred strong assemble.
Themis has failed
so jugheads must fall."
Okay, so we stopped Rob's
plan to disrupt his brother's trial.
He's obviously pivoting to
plan b, so what does this mean?
It's deeply coded
in calvinite language.
I'll get cybercrimes
up here to take a look.
No.
It's gonna take too long.
What am I, your
cleanup crew now?
Well, when you're in the streets
and you need
backup, you call SWAT.
Up here, you call
the assistant director.
I also answer to "boss"
and in some circles "rabbi."
Yeah, well, where we're going,
we'd be better
off with a priest.
Let me get this straight.
You're prosecuting me for
interpreting Calvin's messages,
and now you're here
begging me to interpret
one of Calvin's messages?
You are being prosecuted
for inciting violence,
and you know that.
Still, the irony is delicious.
We are asking for your
cooperation one more time.
As your agents know,
I don't work for free.
Look, I understand your wife
is still having a tough time.
You can help us catch
the guy who hurt her.
Yeah, I'm less motivated
by that than I once was.
Then consider it
a public service.
You tell us what
the message means
and stop violence
before it spreads.
Who is he?
I'm the assistant director
in charge of the
New York field office.
Cool!
What's it going to
take to get you onside?
You think I want to make
a deal with a fake-news,
low-life short-timer? I don't.
But innocent lives are
at stake, are they not?
I want full immunity from
all federal prosecution
related to the greenwich
monument riots.
We'll ensure the
Attorney General's office
- makes that happen.
- Peachy.
Should we shake on it or
just tell us what the
damn message means.
Calvinites speak to each other
in, coded language,
memes, online gobbledygook.
But if you know, you know.
"A hundred strong assemble.
Themis has failed
so jugheads must fall."
It's a call to arms for soldiers
to liberate the greenwich 41.
"Jug" is slang for prison.
"Themis" is the Greek
goddess of justice.
Justice failed.
So they're going to break in,
and they're going to free
their brothers and sisters
- before the trial.
- When?
You got to do
some work yourself.
- When?
- I don't know.
It's not in here.
Could be tomorrow,
could be tonight,
could be right
now, for all I know.
But whoever shows
up, according to this
they're going to be looking
for a righteous donnybrook.
See justice done!
Release the 41!
Jubal, it's a powder
keg over here.
Yeah, SWAT's right behind you!
Release the 41!
See justice done!
Freeze! Freeze!
Release the 41!
This doesn't make any sense.
Nobody's ever broken into
a federal detention center.
- This plan isn't gonna work.
- Right, right.
So... so why would Rob send
his Calvin followers to try it?
It's got to be something else.
We're missing something.
Private ambulance just
gained entry into the facility
through gate three.
A detainee was just
rushed into med bay
multiple stab wounds.
And here's the kicker... it's
Rob Whitfield's brother, Chris.
Well, we... we do not believe
in coincidences in this office.
Get back! Move! Move!
Hey!
Got the details.
Chris Whitfield was
stabbed ten minutes ago.
When the warden flipped the
block, they found his burner.
Look at his last message.
"Get to the med bay,
brother. I'll be waiting."
I want eyes on
that med bay, now!
Get back!
Piggybacking their
security feed now.
- Here we go.
- Okay.
Okay, the man on the
gurney is Chris Whitfield.
- Looks badly injured.
- Wait, wait, wait, stop it.
- Is that...
- Yeah, that is not an EMT.
That's Rob Whitfield.
Maggie, oa, Rob Whitfield
is not with the protesters.
He's driving an ambulance
parked in the med bay.
Riot was just a diversion.
He's trying to sneak
his brother out.
Maggie, oa, do
not let them leave!
I repeat... do not let
that ambulance leave!
Yeah, we got it.
Jubal, we're in pursuit
of the ambulance now.
Suspect's leaving the
yard, heading westbound.
Rob Whitfield!
Get out of the car
with your hands up!
What's he doing?
I don't have a clean shot.
Keep him busy.
Rob, this is the FBI!
You need to lay down
your weapon and surrender!
This is over!
I don't recognize
your authority!
Hey, hey, get out.
Rob, we know that
your brother's hurt!
Stand down so we can help!
We can get him the
medical attention he needs!
Oa, you good?
Yeah. Another calvinite.
He's dead.
No.
No, no, no, no. Chris! Chris!
Chris!
No, no, no!
I asked Chris to
go to greenwich.
I convinced him.
When things went bad, I ran.
I got away, but... He
got caught, and now...
I really thought I could
save him, you know?
I really did.
So you figured out
Calvin wasn't real.
It was just Duke spreading
his lies to make a buck.
But instead of exposing him,
you chose to become the lie.
If I didn't, somebody
else would have.
That's hardly a defense.
Look, I did what I had to
do to try to save my brother.
You took advantage of
people just like your brother,
who still believed in
the Calvin account,
who did your bidding,
and now they are facing
serious consequences for it.
That's their problem.
You knew what you were
posting wasn't the truth,
but you did it anyway.
Look around you, lady!
The truth does not
matter anymore!
The truth matters if
we choose that it does.
Give me the password
to the Calvin account
so I can shut it
down once and for all.
We're in.
It worked? We control
the Calvin account?
We do.
And this gives us access
to what, everything?
It should, yeah, every public
and private communication
that has ever come out
of the Calvin account.
- Should be able to see it all.
- Okay, good.
Archive everything... we're
gonna need it for the trial.
Send the whole
file up to my office,
along with the
password for the account.
Adic Reynolds.
That... that usually
stays down here with us.
Calling it audible.
You cut off the head
of the snake today.
Take the win, Valentine.
Hey, guys, you should see this.
Yeah? What do you got?
Calvin's private messages
going back five months
to the period right
after the greenwich riot.
Okay, so this is when Duke
controlled the account, right?
So they're sent from him?
Are those
direct messages to individual
followers with specific orders.
Looks like Duke's
back on the hook.
You bounced back quick.
I'm nothing if not adaptable.
Sadly, this little
shindig is invite-only.
Party's over, Duke.
I have a deal with your
superior, remember?
Full immunity.
You can't touch me.
Well, that was before
we found the proof
that you ordered your
followers to harass Isobel.
That's stalking a
federal employee...
Which is not part of
your little immunity deal.
Okay, wait, let's
let's think big
picture here, right?
You control the
Calvin account, right?
- I can help you.
- Yeah.
I can make it say
whatever you want
whatever you want!
You are pathetic.
And you're under
arrest, Duke ducoyle.
It only gets worse from here.