Damn it! Oh!
Ah!
Jes!
I can't stand it, help me!
Help me!
God damn!
God...
damn!
It's wanting out,
now darn it, push,
so we can see
what's coming out on the couch.
Head's out almost.
God damn!
Oh, God! Oh...
Shh.
Come on.
Oh, baby, come on.
Oh!
Don't worry, baby,
I'll get somebody.
Mama had the baby!
Come on, Josephine,
he wants two of us.
I can't.
I'm busy.
Get Agnes.
Mama had the baby!
It's a boy!
A boy?
God damn.
I lost my bet.
Listen,
I've already paid for two,
I'm ready now.
Sure you are, sweetie,
and we're going
to get someone nice.
Violet!
'Cause we're going
to have ourselves a time!
Go and fetch Agnes yonder,
will you, baby?
Tell her to haul it up
to the Blue Room.
We're going to have ourselves
a time.
It's a boy.
Well, Violet, old girl,
is it all over upstairs?
Uh-huh.
A boy.
A boy?
Does it really hurt
to have a baby?
Violet, you asking
the wrongest person,
the very wrongest person
in the world.
Come on and play
that thing, Professor.
Well, I certainly
will do that.
I'll play something for that
pretty baby your mama just had.
Brung into the cruel, cruel
world on a night like this,
against his will.
And today, I have attained
my 75th birthday, and
I intend to celebrate!
I haven't had a woman
in longer than I care to say.
You know, she doesn't
have to be beautiful,
just patient.
Well, how about Frieda?
How are you, Admiral?
Well, hello, Nell.
You've been to the North Sea.
I sure have, and now
I'm on an extended
leave of absence.
- Well, I'm...
- Going to be here a long time.
Ooh, you're my kind of man.
I like the way
you move.
All I want to hear from you
is that I'm handsome,
virile, generous, and kind.
Waffle man, waffle man...
Put your money in your hand
for the waffle man
For the waffle man
The waffle man is here,
the waffle man is there
The waffle man is everywhere
Waffle man, waffle man...
What's the matter, Will?
Shh, come on, hush up.
You don't want to wake
everybody up.
Shh! Be quiet now.
Violet!
What if you had woke him up?
He paid for all night,
and you know what he's like.
Well, Will woke me up.
You're not supposed
to wake me up.
I don't get to sleep late
anymore.
Where'd you get those earrings?
They're awful pretty.
Never mind where I got 'em.
He gave 'em to me.
He won 'em in a card game
or something.
Then I won them from him.
Don't!
Just pierced them
for me last night,
that's how I won 'em.
It's a lucky thing I was drunk.
Will you give them
to me when I grow up?
Are you
out of your mind?
These are real emeralds.
Otherwise,
I never would have let him
punch those ugly holes
in my ears.
Get my coffee.
I feel awful.
Ooka, dooka, soda cracker,
does your father chew tobacco?
- Ooka...
- Violet!
Give me my cane.
Oh, my absinthe.
Where the hell
is that black bitch
with my coffee?!
Yes, you handle that
with care, Joe.
And you ought to leave off
suckling that boy.
You're going
to turn him spoiled,
just like you did with Violet.
Oh, I think she likes it,
having big tits.
Hey, 'Tonia, Violet,
get off that pony.
I got something to tell you.
I went to see Mama Mosebery
last night.
I paid her two dollars,
and she gave me some
uncooked turtle heart
to bring me luck
for the lottery,
and I swallowed it whole!
Where you going?
I ain't here, you know,
to entertain you.
I gots deliveries upstairs.
Well, how'd it taste like?
What taste like?
Raw turtle's heart!
What do you think
it tasted like?
Aw, come on, please, tell me!
Well, I am the child
of a snapping turtle.
Raised by alligators
on panther's milk.
I'm a poisoned wolf
from Bitter Creek,
and tonight's
my night to howl!
Peddlers use the back door.
...four, five, six...
A peddler.
Violet, go sit down
and finish your okra.
I'm not raising you so's
your teeth will rot, you know.
What is this sheet
doing here?
It doesn't belong to the house.
Six, seven, eight, nine...
Look what's coming.
...eleven.
Aw, hush up now, come on, baby,
shh, shh, shh.
Hi, I'm Bellocq.
I'm looking
for Madame Livingston.
Is she receiving callers?
Harry, get down here.
You may come in,
Monsieur Bellocq.
Well, come in then.
Good God, you're in
the wrong place, Monsieur.
We're not
in the business of buying.
Madame, um,
perhaps you know my name.
I have... photographed
in the district many times.
Am I addressing
Madame Livingston?
Yes, you are,
Monsieur.
And you are too early.
My girls are all asleep.
They work late, you know.
It's 10:00 in the morning,
Monsieur.
I require the light
from the sun.
Now is the best time for me.
This young lady there,
she would be fine.
I run a good, old-fashioned
whorehouse, Monsieur.
And you seem
a little rabbity to me.
Photographs?
What the hell
kind of thing is that?
I don't cater to the inverts.
If you're looking
for something different,
I can assure you,
you can find it
right down here
in New Orleans.
Madame, please, don't tell me
about New Orleans,
I've lived here all my life.
I apologize, Monsieur.
You realize I'm willing
to pay for her time.
Violet, child, go get me
that package that Red brought.
Would you care
for an absinthe?
Madame, the light.
I beg your pardon.
Oh, the light.
I had quite forgotten.
Well, go and take our Hattie.
She's very good, you know.
She will do whatever you want.
Thank you, ma'am.
And go take care
of that child for her.
Want me
to take my clothes off now?
No, no, I'm liking you
just as you are.
You want me like this?
Uncombed,
I'm not even washed.
Yes, yes.
I don't like that face.
It ain't a pleasant face.
Now this is a pleasant face.
Quiet!
I must have quiet now.
Go away, Violet.
No, it's only
she mustn’t talk to you.
She's very beautiful.
She looks very like you.
Yes, everybody notices it.
She's my sister.
Ma, I ain't!
My face is very like
my mother's,
but I got a fat stomach,
just like all my fathers.
Where the hell is that
god damn whore's ass?
Hattie!
Maybe he's a voodoo man,
'cause he gots them bottles
and stuff.
Nah, he's just
another dumb john.
Jesus God, woman,
get up and get me something.
My head is killing me.
I need something...
laudanum, something.
Jesus Christ!
My mama's having
her likeness made,
and it's all paid for, so there.
Why, hell, man.
She's only good for one thing.
Why would anybody want
to take a picture
of a piece of ass?
Excuse me, I will have
to ask you to move away.
She must remain
absolutely still.
Come on, Honey Pie,
now, go along, now.
You're still just
a little bit drunk.
Where the hell
did you get those earrings?
What?
Give me those emeralds.
You skull-cracking,
cotton-brained whore!
You gave them to me
last night!
Well, why would I give
real emeralds to a whore?
God damn you,
you bet me I wouldn't let you
put those holes in my ears,
and I did, so those are mine!
I won them!
Them's mine!
Oh, my sweet
little piece of ass!
I remember now,
Hattie, I remember.
Go to the bed and take off
your stockings, child.
Mama Mosebery,
I've got this hair growing...
round my nipples,
and I'm tired of plucking it.
Oh...
You must pluck 'em
on Good Friday.
Bound that same day,
and they'll never grow back.
Another new frock from Paris?
It's too early
for a piece of tail.
It must be the bill collector.
Violet, you're going to be
a lucky little one.
You're going to have
so many men,
you won't know
what to do with them.
No, no, please,
if-if she's busy,
I'll come back later.
- Come on.
- No, no, please.
- I'd rather wait downstairs.
- Come on, come on.
Look who I found
skulking in the hallway.
He say he's a photographic.
Hey, voodoo man,
I just got my fortune told, see?
No, no, no, no, no.
He says he got something
for Hattie,
but he won't show it to me.
Hattie,
you got a gentleman friend!
Oh, excuse me, I...
I didn't mean
to disturb you ladies.
I... I have something
for Miss Hattie.
She's in the bathtub.
She's always in the bathtub.
Oh, she is in-in-indisposed.
I-I... would rather...
- What's that?
- No, no, no.
I-I'd rather leave this off
for Miss Hattie.
Don't give me that.
You is a sport.
Hey... let me see your camera.
Don't do that.
Stop, please.
Careful.
Oh, she's so pretty.
Christ be, she
looks like an angel.
Everybody knows
that ain't so.
Sure wish I had a picture
like that of myself.
Yeah, I could send
one home to my folks.
How'd you do that?
Nice. I want one.
Magic.
And I only need one second.
Well, my pretty baby
Won't you come on over here
Let your sweet papa
whisper in your ear
Well, I'm wild
about the jelly roll
Sweet jelly roll of mine...
Cheating is right.
You cheated me.
Well, there's my cards...
queens and aces.
Let's see yours.
What the hell is it?
Let me go!
I got three aces.
I don't know what
you've got there.
You're drunk, man.
Get out of my place!
Your place?!
To hell with you
and your kind!
And don't you know, madame,
that you are as common
as whale piss.
Oh!
Oh, Highpockets,
oh, what have you done to?
- Oh, God...
- Oh...
Where the hell is that bum,
Harry?
My God, you killed him.
Well, I hope so.
Hattie, you must take
the bitters with the sweets.
Lon, go back to your piano.
Violet, go make me a pipe.
I can't take
all this emotionalizing.
Harry, get in here
and throw him out.
You can't throw him out.
He'll come back and kill me.
Well, look what that goddamn,
son of a bitch
did to my place.
Well, you just can't
leave him to die.
Well, you just watch me.
Harry, go through his pockets
and take everything he's got.
He only has about a hundred.
Take it all.
Drop him on Emma Johnson's
doorstep.
Oh, no!
Go on then.
Pack up your bags
and go with him.
And get rid of that hammer
that accidentally
dropped on him.
We don't do no carpentry work
in here,
so we don't need no hammers.
Hattie, you know
Nell didn't mean that.
Something must've went wrong
when your ma was carrying you
in her pouch.
Oh, yeah, something
went wrong.
My mama was a whore.
She had me in a house
just like this.
Now I'm a whore,
and I don't know anything
except a man lying on top of me,
scared to death I'm going
to get the little casino.
Oh, here we go again.
You think you're
the only whore in New Orleans
scared of getting sick?
Oh, you just go
ahead and laugh.
You're going to end up
peddling gas
for a thumbnail of cocaine.
I'll send for my trunk.
Everybody has a right
to do what they want.
I want to be a
respectable person.
With a gambler?
It's those respectable people
who are lying on top of you
every night, Hattie.
You'll be back.
No, I won't!
I'm here for one purpose
and that's to live my life
to the hilt
and enjoy it the same way.
Come on, Violet.
Why aren't you packed?
I don't want to go.
Violet, I am your mother.
No, you're not.
You even say so all the time.
Violet, why are you acting
this way?
What ails you?
Violet?
Violet, I'm talking to you!
God, I have
a splitting headache.
I'm going to stay here.
I hate you.
lf... if it weren't for you,
I would've been out of here
a long time ago.
Oh, you're so selfish!
This isn't fair!
I... why does everybody else
get to do everything they want
to do around here except me
just when I get a...
a chance to do something...
for myself.
Sometimes I wish
I'd never been born.
The windin' boy,
don't deny my name...
don't deny my name
Pick it up and shake it
Like a stavin' chain
This is Josephine
who just loves universities.
- Hi, darlin'.
- Don't deny my name
Every time...
Actually,
my real name is Hildegarde.
My friends
all call me Hildegarde.
You from Tulane?
- Oh, yeah.
- I say, now, every time
Changing of that doggone moon
That old moon
That's very brave.
Every time,
the changing of the moon
Mmm, mmm, mmm-mmm-mmm
The windin' boy,
don't deny my name.
You two ladies are going
to change my luck.
Do you think I'm pretty?
Yes, I certainly do.
And the other girls,
do you like them?
Well, yes.
Then why do you sit here
night after night?
Why don't you go upstairs
with any of them?
That is for me to know
and for you to find out.
You're very old, aren't you?
Yes, very old.
Very, very old?
Yes, very, very old.
Do you think
you'll be dead soon?
No, I don't think so.
Well, why don't you think so?
Well, I don't feel
like being dead yet.
I'm too young.
You said you're old, so
how can you be too young?
Got to wet my whistle.
Well, I think
you'll be dead soon.
Oh, why?
'Cause Madame Nell said so.
She said you'd be
better off dead.
Oh, better off dead?
Uh-huh.
Madame says there's
something wrong with you.
That you're some kind of
cream puff, or something.
She thinks that you're pathetic,
missing all the fun in life.
Perhaps Madame Nell is imagining
she knows more than she does.
You think she's having fun?
She's as happy as anybody.
Are you afraid
you'll get little casino?
The clap?
Oh. No.
Well, why then?
Do I ask you questions?
I don't have to explain
myself to a child.
I'm not a child.
Excuse me,
that is your opinion.
Leave me alone.
You hate me.
I have no time
for hate or love.
Dear child,
you're so full of life.
You don't have to take mine,
do you?
Ah-hah.
Well, what have we here?
Are you selling little girls
now, Madame Nell?
White slavery, huh?
Hey, do you know how to kiss?
Of course I do.
Everybody does.
Well, you watch out for him,
Violet.
He's got a heart
like an artichoke...
a leaf for every girl
and a prick on the end
of each one of them.
Now tell me where'd you get
those pretty pearly teeth
and that beautiful brown hair?
My mama puts my teeth in
every morning with a crocheter,
and I chose brown hair
'cause it don't show the dirt.
Mmm.
No. No, no.
No, no, that's-that's-that's
not my style, you know.
I was just kidding around.
What will you give me
for a message?
I'll give you
the back of my hand
is what I'll give you.
Is there someone
down there for me?
Mm-hmm.
It's that horrible
old coot again. Ugh.
Do not be so snotty
about him.
That old fool's idea
that he likes me,
is my ticket
out of this place.
And besides,
he is rich.
I know because I looked him up
in the phone book,
and he lives on St. Charles.
And he could have whatever
he wants in the world...
and he wants me...
...who doesn't give a damn
for him.
Me... who doesn't give a damn
This is my little girl,
Violet.
And how old are you, Violet?
I don't know.
Do you like her?
She is very pretty.
Like Nell says,
she's only for friends,
so she's still a virgin.
Well, I have it now.
You may relax.
I feel like I'm going to croak.
Violet, honey,
go get us a drink.
Before the war,
we used to close down
in the summertime,
but since the naval base came,
we're busy all year round now.
Can I buy you a drink?
No, thank you.
Perhaps we could
make another one now.
Would you like to?
Yeah, why not?
My breasts are very nice.
They're nicer
than any of the other girls'.
Do you think maybe I should just
show 'em a little bit?
Yes, that would be better.
Let me... let me see.
Well?
You have fine skin.
Do you have any white powder?
Sure, surely... right over there.
Put it on your shoulders here.
Yes, and-and on your breast.
I love the one you made
of Fanny naked.
She sure is fat.
Fanny's beautiful...
but I wasn't pleased
with the light.
So, you're all
ready for me now?
Are you content?
Child, I'm afraid
you'll have to go now.
Me?
Lie back against...
put you head here.
Yes, uh...
Can you lay on-on your side?
That's it.
And put-put your hand
behind your head.
That's it.
That's perfect.
Don't move.
Don't move at all.
You look very beautiful.
Just beautiful.
I'm very happy just now.
Just a few seconds, and it will
all be there perfectly.
Now, don't move.
That one should be very nice.
Never, never do that!
You have no idea
what you might have done!
I only wanted to see
the picture.
I didn't do anything!
Violet...
you have to wait.
This is only a negative.
It has to be developed,
and printed, and...
and then...
You love her.
Don't tell me how I feel.
Now, Violet...
I'm very sorry...
but you might've ruined
a whole day's work for me,
so you should be sorry, too.
Don't tell me how I feel.
I know about you.
You love her.
Leave her be.
She's just showing off.
Come on,
let's go down and eat.
I like that one better.
Trying to rob
a poor working girl.
I'll give you 25 cents
and no more.
I am... three each.
- Sell it to you for a dollar.
- A dollar?
I saw the same blouse
on Canal Street for 50 cents.
Ah.
Course, uh... I likes my women
with a little more
on the top and bottom.
Stop being so cheeky with me,
or I'll get my voodoo woman
to put gris gris
all over your piano.
Violet, come on down here,
and let me see
the front of that dress.
Oh, Violet,
that ain't much of a dress.
When you're going to bust
your cherry,
you best wear red satin.
That's why
you're a dumb nigger...
'cause you think like that.
She's a virgin.
Do you want her to be dressed
like a Picayune whore?
My God, Frieda,
you're as green as a goose turd.
What's this?
Open it and see.
It's the ninth bone
from the tail
of a black cat...
guaranteed to bring you luck
tonight.
Red Top!
Do not forget
that this guy's
buying a virgin,
so she's got to act it right.
You've got to give him
the idea
that you don't know nothing.
Should be like a rape.
You don't know.
Could be a different kind
of guy...
someone that wants you to act
like she wants it.
The main thing is
to whimper and cry
at first when he starts,
but then you've got to
act like it feels good.
I know what to do.
Leave me alone.
Well, don't act
like you know it all.
You won't even get a tip
that way.
Violet, you should
touch him... there...
you know... like it's accidental.
I know... I know all that.
Violet, you is
a beautiful girl.
Now, all you need
is that handsome dress
and plenty diamonds
to elaborate the condition.
That was good.
You better enjoy it.
It's the last fine dinner
you'll get on me.
- Oh, hell, no.
- No, no, no.
Isn't that so, Senator?
The Navy's going to close
the district down.
Well, I can't fight
the United States Navy.
We tried that already,
and we lost.
Sit down, Violet, it's easier.
Honey, you want me to help you
put your powder on, or anything?
No, I can do it myself.
All right.
God, I could remember
when she was born,
and now she's busting
her cherry.
Jesus, Fanny, you were
only six years old
when she was born.
My, my, aren't you handsome?
Why haven't
you been here before?
You're just my kind of man.
Oh, look at that.
Where you been hiding
that thing?
How long has it been
for you, Cherie?
Lie down right here.
Give it to me, baby.
A virgin, bona fide.
How old is she?
Do you want to put me in jail?
She's just old enough.
The finest delicacy
New Orleans has to offer,
and it's her wish
that one of you gentlemen
be the first.
If you'll all join me
in the parlor,
you'll get your opportunity.
Come on, quick.
Give me the ribbon, child.
Come on.
What am I bid, gentlemen?
Don't we get a look
before we buy?
Kent, you can look
all you want.
Just don't break
the merchandise.
Hey, how do we know
she is a virgin?
Have I ever lied
to you before?
Satisfaction guaranteed.
Well, gentlemen,
I'm getting impatient.
I'll bid a hundred dollars.
Yeah!
I'm bidding $120.
$150.
Oh, well, now.
$50!
Beautiful, Senator,
just beautiful.
Remember, gentlemen,
she's as fresh
as a baby's lips.
$160.
$165.
$175.
$180.
Getting out of my reach.
$200.
Gentlemen, gentlemen... $210.
I'll top that with $225.
Well, I'll bid $230.
All right, $240.
$250.
$275, madame.
$280.
$300.
Will you take a check?
What would I do with a check?
Cash.
I got cash. $400.
Jesus Christ, who is he,
Rockefeller?
Hey, this is kind of
out of our league.
We don't have
that kind of money.
Look, this is our night.
You weren't invited here.
Who do you think you are?
Hey, watch what you're doing!
Watch out, fellas.
Sold to the man
with 400 cash.
Do not give him any argument.
You want some whiskey?
Well, Jesus, I didn't mean
the whole damn thing.
I'm glad it's you.
Why are you glad it's me?
Well... you look nice, and...
you have a nice chest.
I can feel the steam inside me
right through my dress.
Let him have his young peach.
I like my fruit ripe, eh?
Gives me queasy innards
to see a thing like that.
Isn't there a lock?
Madame Nell don't allow
no locks.
God damn, for $400,
I'd like to have
that door locked.
I hope you're going to be
real gentle on me,
being my first time.
Want a whiskey?
Please...
You want to go for
a little roll in the kip?
Are you sure
you don't want to go
for a little roll in the kip?
It smells bad in here.
You're feeling badly?
Oh, I feel fine.
I feel all right.
I'm happy.
I feel fine,
and I could probably
accommodate personally
every man of the house
if I decided to.
Violet?
Jesus.
Madame?!
Violet?
Get a doctor!
She's been murdered!
Violet? Oh, my baby!
Violet?
Baby?
Well, I'd like to know
where the hell y'all been?
I been lying here forever.
Oh...
You don't care about me at all.
Oh, Violet, that
really wasn't funny.
I know it's not funny.
Am I laughing?
So, you had a live one, huh?
Come on,
that's what it's all about.
Maybe now you'll let us sleep
in the morning
when we feel bad.
The war, father got killed,
mother forced to go to work.
You know, she's a virgin.
Oh, I ain't too particular
about the virgin part,
but I hear tell
there's disease.
I got no sick girls here,
monsieur.
Who told you about my place,
a friend?
Yes'm.
Well, if you can't trust
a friend...
Now, how about it?
Pure
as the driven snow.
Can I have a little bit of wine?
Thank you.
You spoil me.
Oh, my gosh.
That took my breath away.
There are only two things
to do on rainy days,
and I don't like
to play cards.
I propose a toast.
Oh.
To a quick end of the war.
Yeah.
To the end of the war.
A bird.
Catch it.
- Get it!
- Oh!
Oh, wow.
It's bad luck.
It means death.
Open the damn windows.
It'll fly out.
No. It has to go out
the same way it came in.
Oh, I better get
that little bird.
Come down here!
Come down... you...
Ain't it pretty?
It's so tiny.
Love
Oh, love
Oh, careless love
Come on, honey.
Don't be shy.
Please?
Won't you see
what careless love will do?
Now. Tell 'em for me now,
please.
Shh! Shh! Shh!
Well, uh...
I've asked Hattie to be my wife,
and she has personally agreed,
so we're going to be married.
Oh, that's great.
We're going to have a wedding.
When? 'Cause we are ready.
Well, actually,
we're-we're going to get married
in his hometown.
Yeah, you see, I, um...
I got me this little house
in St. Louis, Missouri,
so, uh...
I kind of thought
we'd be married there.
Well, Hattie,
you finally nailed one, huh?
Aren't you going to answer me,
Violet?
I had to do it this way.
I wasn't even sure
he really meant it
until he come today.
But he's got the ring
and everything.
It's going to be
really big things for us.
I told him that
you was my sister.
He don't know any different.
As soon as the
right time comes,
I'm going to tell him.
It's lucky
he doesn't even mind
about Little Will.
Want some?
Hattie, our-our train leaves
in a half an hour.
All right, honey.
I'm coming.
Auf Wiedersehen.
Honey, I'll send for you.
I promise you that.
Oh.
Do I look all right?
One card.
One card, Al.
Don't you fellows want
to do something?
It's our day off.
Well, we are doing something.
I tell you,
you put men in a room
with a bunch of whores,
and all they want to do
is play poker.
Never understand men.
Yeah, really.
Well, we still have Papa.
Shall I take you all
to the burlesque?
Or we could go
to the picture show.
I know.
Let's play Sardines.
- Yeah.
And Papa... Papa can be it.
I don't know this game,
Sardines.
I never heard of it.
- You'll learn.
- You'll find out.
We made it up.
It's really a lot of fun.
Well, how do you play?
One, two,
three, four,
five,
six, seven,
eight, nine,
ten!
Look under the bed.
Okay.
He's not in Agnes' room.
Papa!
Goddamn it.
Did you find him?
Papa?
I know you're in here.
We'll just have
to fly south. See?
I didn't look
in Gussie's room.
Damn it!
You're easy.
I heard you breathing.
Oh!
Did you like that?
Come on.
Hey.
He's been real bad.
It's been hard
to keep him quiet.
Get in, get in.
Sardine. Uh-uh.
Caught your sardine!
What's under there?
Bet they're ain't
no cream puffs!
All right.
Whoo!
It's just a trick.
She hates to be losing a game.
God, there sure was a fall.
Funny, I think
I broke something.
You broke something,
all right.
I love you once,
I love you twice.
I love you
more than beans and rice.
What did he say?
Come on.
Mademoiselle
from Armentières
Parlez-vous
Mademoiselle
from Armentieres
Parlez-vous
The officers
get all the take
And all I get is a bellyache
Inky-dinky parlez-vous.
How about a little something
for the professor?
What will become of her now?
What's going on with you?
You don't have
to worry about her.
She's made a lot of money.
She can do as she likes.
She's-she's only 12.
She's completely alone.
Bellocq,
you're in love with her.
Don't be absurd.
I've seen it a hundred times.
I am old.
And life is so long.
Oh, yeah, I love you,
little woman
She's my baby
My joy
and little woman
I love her...
She's crazy little...
Stop that goo-gooing.
Thank you, thank you. I...
You're quite welcome.
I knew you needed it.
Five.
What did I roll?
- Eight.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
I got an eight.
Yeah, you got an eight.
I'm winning.
Very good.
Five.
Nine.
Go ahead.
I'm standing here
thinking I'm ready
to get my picture took.
Violet, please go away.
Go away, Violet.
I got a five.
I won.
You're stupid and old.
Red Top...
...when you grow up, and you
have a beard and a mustache,
I'm going to think
you're very handsome.
And I'm going to love you up
hard and long.
Well, especially me,
'cause I am the lover boy.
I bet neither of you
never done nothing.
Huh?
I had me a piece of tail
yesterday.
All the girls in the district
give me free lovin'.
Yeah.
Nonny, you never did it,
did you?
Of course I have.
Lots of times.
Then tell me what
it feels like.
Well, it feels good.
For God sakes,
what else?
Tell me exactly how it feels.
I knows how it feels,
but-but I just don't know
how to describe it.
It's like you get this tingling
feeling along on your back,
and this funny feeling starts
creeping up your toes.
Do it, Nonny.
What?
You must be crazy.
Do it to me right now.
Prove you can.
I'm big, you're little, huh?
Get off me.
I'm going to make you
my lover man, Nonny.
I'm going to love you up
real hard and long.
Let me up!
What you gonna say, boy?
Nothing.
He ain't gonna say nothing.
Violet, baby...
you is very bold,
and the way you been raised,
you don't know nothing
about real world.
White and colored...
they can't be together,
as far as that's concerned.
I can do what I want.
Everybody does that
with everybody.
And colored?
Did you see colored men upstairs
for that?
No, you don't, Violet.
I'm a church-going woman
that was married by a preacher,
and what I can say
is you've gots to leave
my Nonny alone.
You pushing far, Violet.
She certainly is.
Harry!
Oh! Let me... go!
Let me go!
No! I want...
Oh, let me go!
No!
Ow!
You can't beat a child.
It only teaches her
to beat others.
I'll run my business,
and you tend to yours, Papa.
It didn't hurt.
Hard headed and hard-assed.
Hey, Papa, you sure
you won't stay for dinner?
No, no, thank you.
And how did you find me?
I looked you up
in a telephone book.
Anybody can think of that.
I don't have a telephone,
Violet.
Well, I followed you here...
lots of times.
Have you had your supper?
What's all this?
I've been working.
You mean, this is your work...
photographing?
Yes. This is how
I earn my living.
God, that's so easy.
Well, easier
than working in a house.
You've decided to run away.
Where do you sleep?
Upstairs.
I want to see it.
Why do you lock it?
I don't know... habit.
Sometimes children
break into my house.
Why?
I imagine they're curious
about me and my camera.
The neighborhood has turned bad.
Why?
Why, why, why.
I don't know why.
'Cause of the whorehouses.
How come you ain't
got no electricity?
Well, I like this room.
Ooka, dooka...
Well, you certainly did it,
didn't you?
Violet?
Can I stay here?
Yes, you may, if you want to.
I do! Will you sleep with me
and take care of me?
No.
And why not?
Because...
'cause I'm not
sure why, exactly.
Uh-huh. You're afraid of me.
- Perhaps.
- I want you
to be my lover,
and buy me stockings,
and clothes, and...
You don't know what
you're saying, Violet.
I won't even charge you
anything at all,
and you can visit me
at my house
and be my fancy man.
I thought you were running away
from the house.
Oh, yes.
They can't beat me like that...
well, not me.
I agree absolutely.
You do?
Otherwise I should already
have beaten you
for breaking my bed.
You hit me once.
Yes, and I'm sorry.
You love my mother
more than me.
I know about those
things better than you.
You always know those
things about men
when you're a woman.
Some men are different.
I'm different.
Well...
...maybe not after all,
because...
I'm all yours, Violet.
All mine?
Yes.
I love you once,
I love you twice,
I love you more
than beans and rice.
I'm going to make
you so happy.
You're just my kind of man.
You really are.
I'm really good,
you know, Cherie.
Don't talk to me
like that, please.
Don't talk like a whore.
And what do you want me
to say?
I feel something inside me,
so I say it,
and when you go away,
it hurts me...
right here.
You're only hungry, perhaps.
And what's wrong
with whores anyhow?
I thought you liked us.
Everybody says I'm pretty.
I'm getting to be
filled out soon...
and all the other men like me.
Don't you like me?
You left me all alone.
I left you a note.
Well, I can't read yet.
I brought you a present.
A present? Where?
Ugh!
Where is it?
She's beautiful.
Why did you buy me a doll?
Every child should have a doll.
I'm a child to you?
Violet.
Come out and play with me.
Violet!
Violet?
Oh.
Violet, what ails you?
What's the matter, Violet?
Violet, I'm talking to you.
I've got such
a splittin' headache.
You're so selfish, Violet.
It's just not fair.
People get to do
what they want except me.
Violet, did you
take those bottles
that I left on the table
in the front room?
The ones
with the glass stoppers?
Yes.
Yes. I was playing
with them.
Well, what did you do
with what was inside of them?
Well, I poured it out.
My God, Violet,
that's silver nitrate.
I use it for my photographs.
Whatever made you do
such a thing?
Well, it smelled so bad.
Because of your
thoughtlessness,
I have to go
all the way uptown
to replace those chemicals.
And they're very expensive.
Why are you crying?
For joy.
And to amuse myself.
You want to come with me?
No!
What are those?
What are what?
Those clothes.
Oh, these?
These are pajamas.
You aren't going to tell me
you've never in your life
seen pajamas?
No john I ever saw
wore anything like that.
I'm tired of lying here.
If you would have stayed quiet
for one second more,
I would have had it.
It's always one second more
with you,
and why do you want
to take my picture
again and again and again?
I'm tired of having
to deal with a child.
I don't have
to stay here
and listen to you yell at me.
Well, I'm leaving.
And you won't have anyone
to photograph anymore.
So this is how
you would repay me?
Repay you for what?
For what?
I don't owe you
anything at all.
Get out!
Get out, Violet,
before I kill you.
If you destroy any more
of my pictures.
Who cares about your pictures?
Who buys them?
No one.
Repent, sinners.
Sinners!
Pray! Pray!
These freaking pest holes
are inhabited by 1,500 angels
of death and damnation.
Four hags
in palatial palaces of guilt
imperil the virtue
of every innocent girl.
And what, dearly beloved,
can we do about the weakness
of lusting men and soft women?
Corrupting...
Violet, where you been?
We better get out of here.
If they catch us, we'll go
to the Home for Good Shepherds.
Brothers and sisters, unite!
Stupid puritans.
Nell says it's just horny men
who come around to snoop.
Well, this time,
they're really going to do it.
Mama Mosebery says
everything will be closed down.
So what if they do?
I don't know.
What'll become of me?
You can be my fancy man.
She's gone mad.
I told you.
Even Madame Nell.
The evil eye is on us all.
Look.
Circles of salt.
Somebody put a spell on you.
Ola Mae, take this holy water
and wash the kitchen
and Miss Nell's room.
In Rome...
times like these...
barbarians came.
Oh, did they.
It goes on
and on.
I heard the doorbell.
Where is everybody?
Death is keeping them away.
There are reasons for death.
Good reasons.
Oh, stop talking.
Would you... stop it?
Excuse me.
Dirty roughnecks
with their rotten manners.
Dirty roughnecks with
their rotten manners.
We'll be at the station
for an hour,
if you change your mind.
Bye.
Come on, Joanie, let's go.
Terrible piano anyhow.
Oh, you look so fine.
Violet, old gal,
we'll go to Chicago.
Chicago is the money town.
Oh, we'll have ourselves
a time there.
Take the northbound
New Orleans Central.
Hey.
Careful now.
These are delicate things.
Where are you going, Violet?
Where's that no-good mother
of yours?
I gots a postcard from her,
and a letter.
With no return address, huh?
Don't talk about her.
Aw, you're breakin' my heart.
Papa, what are you doing here?
I'm going to marry you.
Can I ask all the girls?
But Antonia and Justine
have gone,
and-and Odette and Josephine.
Can we go get them?
Of course.
Well, what'll I wear?
You can wear whatever
your heart desires,
just as long as
you do it with me.
Her father unknown,
and the mother
deserted the child.
My mama's name
was Hildegarde,
Hildegarde Marr... M-A-R-R.
And she was Caucasian or other?
She was a whore, Father.
Those whom God has united,
let no man put asunder.
In nomine patri et filii
et spritus sanctus.
You may kiss the bride.
Oh, where have you been,
Billy Boy, Billy Boy?
charming Billy?
Oh, I've been to see my wife,
she's the darling of my life
She's a young thing
and cannot leave her mother
Can she bake a cherry pie,
Billy Boy, Billy Boy?
charming Billy?
She can bake a cherry pie
quick as you can wink your eye
She's a young thing
and cannot leave her mother.
Papa, there's a good spot
over there... pull over.
Hell, no, turn around, Papa.
The other place was better.
No! Come on... over here!
Sit down!
Well...
We'll just have
to get out and push.
But I am wearing my new dress
for Chicago.
We're all wearing
our new dresses, you damn fool.
Well, let's get
our damn clothes off
and celebrate this thing.
Pass me some more oysters.
Anyone want some of this sauce?
Oh, yeah.
Try this, Odette.
Papa, come eat.
Yes, I'm coming.
Ooh, look at that one!
Papa, you didn't
eat anything before.
Now, eat.
How come one man
got so many women?
He just got married today.
And guess who he married?
Guess?
Well, it doesn't matter,
'cause he's the luckiest
son of a bitch
I ever seen on a wedding day.
Why are you ringing?
You have everything you need.
I want some hot chocolate
with brandy in it.
I feel poorly today.
Oh, I'm sorry.
What is it this time?
Oh, you know.
Oh, yes, of course.
I forgot.
I'm going to sleep
all day today.
Well, how is that any different
from the last two weeks?
Get me some cocoa.
And the bottle of brandy.
Do you... I mean,
did the girls teach you...
how to prevent yourself
from... becoming with child?
I mean,
did you know you can?
Don't tell me about that.
Don't tell me
about the things I know.
Hard-headed bird
don't make good soup.
That's what Ola Mae
used to say about me.
I know.
Violet?
Mama?
Yes, it's Mama!
Oh, Violet, my baby, my darling!
Look at the way you've grown.
We have been looking
everywhere for you.
Here we go.
I told him
all about you, Violet,
and he insisted that
we come and get you.
You smell good, Mama.
We've got a big, beautiful house
in St. Louis.
Mr. Fuller,
he's a pavement contractor.
You know, he's paved almost
every street in St. Louis.
And he wants you
to come home with us.
But I live here.
I and Papa,
Papa and I are married now.
Mrs. Fuller,
I'm so glad to see
you are doing so well.
And little Will.
Mr. Fuller and I want nothing
to do with you, Mr. Bellocq.
We had to go
to some-some awful places
to find out about you
and my daughter.
Hattie, we're married now,
so stop this.
It is not legal
without my consent.
Mr. Fuller has
already seen to that.
You deserted the child.
I don't mean
to be cruel, but...
- How dare you say that?!
- Now, Mr. Bellocq,
be sensible.
Now, I want
to send Violet to school,
and she has to be...
raised right.
Now, I know
that in a lot of ways
we've got no right
to get up on a high horse.
But now, Mrs. Fuller
has overcome her past,
and she wants the same
for Violet.
Well, you cannot take her!
I can't live without her...
that's all.
Papa, you can come with us.
Come on, Violet.
You don't need to pack.
We'll get you whatever you need
on Canal Street
while we're waiting
for the train.
Can't we all go?
You ready?
Uh-huh. Just a minute.
There, now, that's better.
Now we're ready.
Come on, look at Papa.
Okay, move in closer.
Good.
Now let's get one more.
Okay.
What's the matter, honey?
Is he okay?
No, he's fine.
Do you wanna take any more?