♪ Here we are ♪
♪ Born to be kings ♪
♪ We're the princes of the universe ♪
♪ Here we belong ♪
♪ Fighting to survive ♪
♪ In a world with the darkest power ♪
♪ And here we are ♪
♪ We're the princes of the universe ♪
♪ Here we belong fighting for survival ♪
♪ We've come to be the rulers of your world ♪
♪ I am immortal ♪
♪ I have inside me blood of kings ♪
♪ I have no rival ♪
♪ No man can be my equal ♪
♪ Take me to the future of your world ♪
...and the Tonga Kid.
Their opponents, in the corner to my right,
with a combined weight of 725 lbs,
the toasts of the coasts
from Brad Street, U.S.A., Atlanta, Georgia,
the Fabulous Freebirds!
Yeah!
Yeah, right! You're gonna love it!
Kill him! Stomp on the son-of-a...
Don't give them a chance!
Hey! Where are you going?
MacLeod!
Fasil.
Wait.
All right.
MacLeod!
May this year of our Lord 1536
bring victory to the clan MacLeod!
MacLeod! Victory to MacLeod!
- Are you scared, Connor?
- No, cousin Dougal, I'm not!
Don't talk nonsense, man!
I peed my kilt the first time I went into battle!
Oh, aye. Angus pees his kilt all the time.
Connor! Connor!
Connow, wait! Wait!
Take these flowers and think of me.
Remember, you fight with God on your side, Connor.
A girl like that can wound a soldier
more than a Fraser's sword, my friend.
Wait! Angus, you and Dugal keep him
in one piece, do you hear?
Aye, we all know which piece that is!
- There is one called Connor among them.
- Aye.
Remember our agreement, Murdoch.
The boy is mine.
It's begun.
Death to the MacLeods!
Death to the Macleods!
Death to the Frazers!
MacLeod!
Come on!
Macleod!
Stay under!
Forgive me,
my son.
Fight me, damn you!
No, that's Connor MacLeod!
Fight me, you cowards!
No, not him!
Castrate the heathens!
Nobody will fight me!
They all run away.
Here, laddie, stay by me.
Mother of God!
Fight me!
No!
Come on, quick!
There can be only one!
Another time, MacLeod!
- Get out of the car!
- Put your hands on the hood!
- Move!
- Okay!
- Watch it, freak! Just cool it! Watch him!
- Watch him, watch him!
Move! Come on, come on, come on! Move!
Come on, come on!
Spread them! Spread them! Come on!
See some ID, pal!
Well, Mr. Nash! Where were you going in such a hurry?
Give me it! Give me it! Give me it!
Don't move, pal.
Don't even breathe.
- It is over.
- No!
Other men are dying this day. I must attend them.
Quiet!
He's a Highlander, by God!
The last thing to hear should not be
that of a wailing woman!
Hey, come on. Let me through.
Damn it, Frank. Forensics are supposed
to be notified the same time as homicide!
Holy shit!
- Yeah, this one came unassembled.
- Did you made an arrest?
No. We're questioning some guy named Nash.
Antique dealer down on Hudson Street.
- Hello, Brenda.
- Hi, Walt.
You look pretty, Brenda.
What do you think of the cause of death, Lieutenant, huh?
Oh, Christ! You're a barrel of laughs, Garfield.
Get your hands off!
Hey, cop! When are you going to explain?
This was my wife's, man!
Hey, Walker, get me a cherry-cheese Danish toast, please!
What did they say? What time did he buy it?
Oh! About 10:00, 10:30.
Whatever made the cut was razor sharp.
Get out! I told you, you get out of here with these cameras!
Frank! Frank!
- Oh, my God!
- About two days ago, the telefax
told that a guy was killed just like this over in Jersey.
Yeah, but I figured what the hell, that's Jersey!
Hey, coppers, I want to get out of here!
Hey Frank, come here!
Oh, shit!
Oh, baby, look at you!
Garfield, cover that head.
- What the hell have you got?
- A Toledo Salamanca.
- A what?
- A sword, Frank. A very rare sword.
- Well, is it worth much?
- Only about a million bucks.
Any antique dealer on Hudson Street could tell you that.
You can't keep me here, asshole! I know my rights!
Ever see this guy before, Nash?
The name's Vazilek. Polish national.
Had his head chopped off in New Jersey two nights ago.
- You ever get over to New Jersey, Nash?
- Not if I can help it.
- You talk funny, Nash. Where're you from?
- Lots of different places.
- You're an antique dealer, right?
- Mm-hm.
Okay. What's that?
- A sword?
- Wise up, smart ass!
That's a Toledo Salamanca broadsword
worth about a million dollars.
So?
- So, you want to hear a theory?
- Mm-hm.
You went down that garage to buy this sword from that guy.
- What's his name?
- I don't know. You tell me.
Okay. His name is Iman Fasil.
You fought about the price and cut off his head.
Want to hear another theory?
This Fasil was so upset about the lousy wrestling tonight,
he went down to the garage and in a fit
of depression cut off his own head.
That's not funny, Walt.
You a faggot, Nash?
Why Garfield? You're cruising for a piece of ass?
I'll tell you what happened, Russell.
You went down to the garage for a blow job.
You just didn't want to pay for it.
Huh. You are sick.
Hey! Hey!
Hey, what are you doing?
Stop! Stop it!
- What, are you crazy?
- Break it up, goddamn it!
That's enough! That's it! Now, cut it out!
Goddamn it, I said cut it out!
- Am I under arrest?
- Not yet.
- Then we're through.
- Nash, we're just getting started!
...garage and water from the sprinkler.
It also left a man's decapitated body
lying on the floor next to his own severed head.
A head which at this time has no name.
I know his name.
♪ Here I am ♪
♪ I'm the master of your destiny ♪
♪ I am the one, the only one ♪
♪ I am the god of kingdom come ♪
♪ Give me the prize ♪
♪ Just give me the prize ♪
Okay, Mr. Victor Kruger. Room 315.
And I'm going to hit you for twenty in advance.
If there's anything you need, you know,
broads or blow, just dial 0, huh?
That's right, Mr. Kruger. Lucky Strike
means fine tobacco. I'll tell you that.
- Don't talk to the guests!
- I didn't do nothin'!
At last!
The Gathering!
Hi!
I'm Candy.
Of course you are.
Come on in.
- Hiya.
- Hi.
- Got a present for you from the coroner.
- Yeah, what's that?
Pieces of metal. Found them
on the dead guy under the Garden.
In the wound and on the clothes.
Real smooth shave.
That can't be right.
Son of a bitch!
Who's there?
- Hey, Brenda. The usual?
- Lots of it.
Say when.
When.
Excuse me a minute, Brenda.
A double Glenmorangie on the rocks.
Glenmorangie? Right.
- Go to the Garden often?
- What did you say?
What did you say?
Madison Square Garden.
Do you go there often?
Why?
Basketball,
the circus, wrestling...
Why are you asking me about the Garden?
Have you been following me?
I'd like to walk you home, Brenda.
I can take care of myself.
♪ It's always a rainy day without you ♪
♪ I'm a prisoner of love inside you ♪
♪ I'm falling apart ♪
♪ All around you ♪
Be quiet.
Here, take this.
Nice to see you again, Mcleod.
Nice yourself.
- Stop!
- There can be only one!
No!
Hey, you, on the ground. This is the police!
Put down your weapons. Put your hands on your heads.
Another time, Highlander. I will find you!
Hey! Hold it right there! Come back here!
Stop! Wait a minute!
Who in the name of God was that?
He called you Highlander. What did he mean?
"There can only be one." Only one what?
Listen, lady, you almost...
- I want to know...
- Shut up!
Don't you ever follow me again.
You only have one life. If you value it...
go home.
You saw the wound, Angus.
- He should have died.
- I say he's got the devil in him!
Drinking with us, are you?
- What's the matter, Dougal?
- You, talking and breathing.
Last night all but a corpse.
How did you manage that, Connor Mcloed?
Would you rather I was dead?
It's not natural.
He's in league with Lucifer.
Don't say that, Kate!
I'll say it! You've the devil in you.
We've been kinsmen 20 years!
Connor MacLeod was my kinsman. I don't know who you are.
- Angus.
- You'd better go, Connor.
I'm not going anywhere.
He's the devil! Kill him!
- Dougal!
- Leave him be!
Dougal...
Go on, kill him!
He's your cousin, man!
No, Angus!
Quiet! Quiet!
There'll be no burning here today.
We'll banish him.
No! Burn him!
Burn him!
- Can you walk?
- I'll bloody well walk out of here.
Then go, while you still can!
I'll not forget you, Angus.
That's a good dog.
- Pie and ale, do you want it?
- Aye.
Right now!
You filthy sod! You're all muck and muscle.
Aye, blossom. The way you like it.
You can do that to me forever, if you like, my Lord.
- Will you, Connor?
- Aye, blossom. I will.
Hello!
Greetings.
I am Juan Sánchez Villa-Lobos Ramírez,
chief metallurgist to King Charles V of Spain,
and I'm at your service.
Who?
- What do you want?
- You.
You're Connor MacLeod.
- Maybe I am...
- You're Connor MacLeod,
wounded in battle
and driven from your village of Glenfinnan
five years ago.
Connor!
Heather, go in the house.
I'll stay right here.
Do as I say, woman!
The sensation you're feeling
is the Quickening.
- Who are you?
- We are the same, MacLeod.
We are brothers!
I knew you guys were bottle-fed.
Yeah, well, there's not a hell of a lot
I can do about it, pal.
You see what I'm up against!
His Vietnamese neighbor ate his dog.
That's confidential.
- How are things over at forensics?
- Dull.
- How about some lunch?
- Lunch? It's a good idea. Who pays?
- Me.
- You're on.
- Oh, by the way, Frank.
- Yeah.
- The hairs in the Moretti case?
- Uh-huh.
- They matched up.
- What did I tell you?
Oh! I forgot my purse.
I'll meet you outside.
Garfield, Brenda and I are going to lunch.
Sometimes, MacLeod, the sharpest blade is not enough.
♪ B-A-L-A-N-C-E ♪
♪ Balance ♪
I don't like boats. I don't like water.
I'm a man not a fish.
As you complain endlessly.
You look like a woman, you stupid haggis!
Haggis? What is haggis?
A sheep's stomach stuffed with meat and barley.
- And what do you do with it?
- You eat it!
How revolting!
Be still for God's sake! You'll tip us over!
So?
I cannot swim, you Spanish peacock!
I'm not Spanish, I'm Egyptian.
You said you were from Spain.
You are a liar!
You have the manners of a goat,
and you smell like a dungheap,
and you've no knowledge whatsoever of your potential. Now!
- Get out!
- No!
Help! Help! Help!
Help!
- Help me, I'm drowning!
- You can't drown, you fool!
You're Immortal.
I'm drowning!
♪ We ask you Thy, ♪
♪ Heavenly Father... ♪
I'm alive!
I can breathe!
I'm going to slice you in half.
Crude and slow, clansman. Your attack
was no better than that of a clumsy child.
This cannot be.
It's the devil's work.
You cannot die, MacLeod. Accept it.
- I hate you.
- Good.
That is a perfect way to start.
Tell me, how did it happen for God's sake?
Why does the sun come up? Hmm?
Or are the stars just pinholes
in the curtain of night? Who knows?
What I do know is that because you were born different,
men will fear you, try to drive you away,
like the people of your village.
You must learn to conceal your special gift
and harness your power
until the time of the Gathering.
What Gathering?
When only a few of us are left,
we will feel an irresistible pull towards a faraway land
to fight for the prize.
Come on!
Faster!
Never lose your temper.
If your head comes away from your neck, it's over.
Never overextend your thrust.
You're vulnerable and off balance.
Connor!
Heather, please!
If it came down to just us two, would you take my head?
We must fight until only one remains.
You're safe only on holy ground.
None of us will violate that law.
It's tradition.
Now for the last.
Trust me.
Let yourself feel the stag.
His heart... beating,
his blood...
coursing.
Feel?
- Come on!
- I feel him.
MacLeod, come on!
- I feel him!
- Come on!
I feel him!
Come on, Haggis!
- Yeah!
- Yes!
Now, Pendejo, shall we see
what sort of swordsman you've become?
En garde!
Very good.
Give me your hand, brother.
That one there. How much is it?
Put him in.
But what I want is a family.
You cannot have a family. We cannot have children.
That won't please Heather. I'll tell you that for nothing.
He's full of life.
Connor!
Here's dinner.
I'll be off now. I fancy buying myself a new dress.
Oh, you little devils. Go on!
She is beautiful.
You must leave her, brother.
MacLeod,
I was born 2,437 years ago.
In that time I've had 3 wives.
The last was Shakiko, a Japanese princess.
Her father, Masamune, a genius, made this for me.
In 593 B.C.
It is the only one of its kind,
like his daughter.
When Shakiko died, I was shattered.
I would save you that pain.
Please, let Heather go.
When we first met, you felt ill, remember?
That wasn't the first time you felt that sensation, was it?
No.
When the MacLeods fought the Frasers, and a black knight...
I felt it then.
Only it was different, more painful.
That black knight was the Kurgan.
It's because of him that I sought you out.
Who is the Kurgan? And where does he come from?
The Kurgans were an ancient people
from the steppes of Russia.
For amusement they tossed children
into pits with hungry dogs to fight for meat.
The Kurgan. He is the strongest of all the Immortals.
He is the perfect warrior.
If he wins the prize, mortal man
would suffer an eternity of darkness.
How do you fight such a savage?
With heart, faith and steel.
In the end, there can be only one.
It must have been very dangerous for you.
Well, I was very much in love with her, my dear Heather.
She was the only thing on my mind, not danger.
So, holding the rose in my teeth,
I climbed up on the rooftop,
lowered a rope and swung in through the open window.
- Unfortunately, the lady was no longer there.
- What did you do?
I introduced myself to the lady that was there.
She was most helpful.
Would you like some more wine?
Yes, please.
- Heather, get out.
- What's wrong?
Get out!
Kurgan!
Ramírez!
The Highlander, where is he?
- You're too late. I've prepared him for you.
- You waste your time!
It hurts?
Now you die!
You cannot win, Ramírez. I'm the strongest!
My cut has improved your voice.
Yes!
Hurts?
Who is the woman?
She's mine.
Not for much longer.
Tonight you sleep in hell.
There can be only one!
Hello, pretty!
I'd like to speak to Russell Nash.
Oh, I'm sorry, Mr. Nash isn't here at the moment.
May I call him at home? I have to talk to him today.
I'm afraid that won't be possible.
- Good morning.
- This is Brenda Wyatt, Mr. Nash.
We've already met, Rachel. What can I do for you?
I'd like some advice.
Are you the kind of woman who takes advice?
- That depends.
- Advice about what?
What can you tell me about a 7" lunatic
hacking away with a broadsword
at 1 o'clock in the morning in Ney York city, 1985?
Not much.
What about a Japanese sword dated 600 B.C.? 375
The metal in the blade folded 200 times.
I don't deal in exotic weapons.
Can I show you something in 18th century silver?
That's not why I came here, and you know it.
- Do you cook?
- Why?
I thought we might have dinner.
- Did you?
- Yes.
So, I'm standing there, and there's Brenda!
Our little Brenda.
You're sure it was Brenda?
She was in Nash's shop. She was talking to him.
- What are you looking at, Rachel?
- The eyes in the back of your head.
People are asking about you. What am I supposed to say?
Tell them I'm Immortal.
Attention! Four men over here!
Quiet.
Don't be afraid.
- What's your name?
- Rachel.
- What happened?
- Everybody is dead.
I'm like you. I'm alone.
Come with me, Rachel.
- You're alive! Why didn't you die?
- Hey, it's a kind of magic.
- You should be dead!
- Move!
No! You'll have to shoot me first.
Whatever you say, Jack. You're the master race.
Let's go.
That was a long time ago.
Would you listen to me for one moment, please?
You can't hide your feelings from me.
I've known you too long.
- What feelings?
- How about loneliness?
I'm not lonely.
- I've got everything I need right here.
- Oh no, you don't.
You refuse to let anyone love you.
Love is for poets.
You're such a romantic, Rachel.
You always were.
Just a minute!
Good evening.
Do you want to dine in the hall, or shall we step inside?
Come in.
May I take your coat?
- No thanks.
- What?
- I'll hold on to it.
- Oh, fine.
- Where are you going?
- I forgot my earrings.
Make yourself a drink. There are glasses in the bar.
Do you know what you're doing?
I like your place, Brenda.
I've only been here 3 months. I'm still cleaning it up.
- Interesting view.
- What did you say?
I said, "interesting view".
Isn't it great?
You never told me what you do for a living.
I work for the Metropolitan Museum.
In Aquisitions.
That explains your interest in ancient weapons.
Right.
Especially the Samurai.
Very nice.
- Shall we have a toast?
- Yes.
Brandy.
Bottled in 1783.
Wow! That's old.
1783 was a very good year.
Mozart wrote his Great Mass.
The Montgolfier Brothers went up in their first balloon.
And England recognized
the independence of the United States.
Is that right?
Yes.
What's that?
- It's for you.
- Can I open it?
If you like.
You bastard! Where did you find this?
I have an extensive library.
Odd thing, your bio doesn't mention the Met.
It says you work for the police. In forensics.
- Are you and Moran trying to set me up?
- I don't work for Moran.
Then why is that bald policeman sitting
outside watching your apartment?
You remember him. Moran's had him tailing me.
What're you gonna do?
The question is what are you gonna do?
You're going to turn off the tape
or you're going to shoot me with the .45?
I am not looking for a killer. I am looking
for a sword, the one used on Fasil.
I found pieces of it under the Garden.
- I only want to see the Samurai.
- Why?
I told you! Because it's not supposed to exist!
I dated pieces of the blade at 600 B.C.
The metal had been folded 200 times.
The Japanese didn't start making
swords like that till the Middle Ages.
So where the hell did it come from?
If I could verify the existence
of such a weapon, it would be like...
discovering 747 a thousand years
before the Wright Brothers ever flew.
This is crazy.
Wait a minute, Nash, I want some answers.
You want?
Don't you ever think about anything except what you want?
You must leave her, brother.
♪ There's no time for us ♪
♪ There's no place for us ♪
♪ What is this thing that fills our dreams ♪
♪ Yet slips away from us? ♪
♪ Who wants to live forever? ♪
♪ There's no chance for us ♪
♪ It's all decided for us ♪
♪ This world has only one sweet moment ♪
♪ Set aside for us ♪
Heather!
♪ Who wants to live forever? ♪
Connor, I'm here!
♪ Who dares to love forever ♪
♪ When love must die? ♪
My beautiful man.
My husband.
I am that, my love.
I've never really known...
What?
Why you stayed.
Because I love you as much now as the first day we met.
And I love you.
I don't want to die.
I want to stay with you.
Forever.
I want that, too.
Will you do something for me, Connor?
What, blossom?
In the years to come, will you light a candle
and remember me on my birthday?
Aye, love.
I will.
I wanted to have your children.
They would have been strong and fine.
Don't see me, Connor.
Let me die in peace.
Where are we?
We're in the Highlands.
Where else?
Running down a mountain side.
The sun is shining.
It's not cold.
You've got your sheepskins on.
And the boots I made for you.
Goodnight, my bonny Heather.
Hey, Kastagir!
MacLeod. It's good to see you again.
It seems like a hundred years.
It's been a hundred years.
How've you been?
Hey!
This...
...puts hairs on your chest.
- What is it?
- Boom-boom!
A big strong man like you shouldn't
be afraid of a little boom-boom!
- Or maybe you think I'm trying to poison you?
- I think you're crazy, Kastagir.
So, the Gathering is here.
- Time has almost caught us, my friend.
- Has it? You think we should go on?
I think we should have a party.
Oh no! I remember the last time we had a party.
Really, when exactly was that?
It was 1783.
1783...
Oh yes! Your famous duel on Boston Common.
You were drunk.
- What was that guy's name again?
- His name was Bassett.
The heavier blade, Mr. Bassett! I implore you!
I am fighting the duel, Hotchkiss, not you!
See if the imbecile is ready.
- Mr. Bassett is waiting, Sir.
- Tell him I'm ready.
Christ, I've gone blind!
En garde, Sir!
- Wonderful, Sir.
- Thank you, Hotchkiss.
Bassett, is that you?
You missed him, Mr. Bassett.
Stop, Sir!
I beseech...
I apologize for calling your wife a bloated warthog.
And I bid you a good day.
- Shoot him, Sir?
- What?
Shoot him. Now, Sir. Now, Sir.
In the back of the head. Now, Sir!
Hotchkiss! Hotchkiss, stop it!
- Hotchkiss...
- Sir?
No, Sir.
That's the mood of New York at this moment.
- Get out of here! Get out of here!
- An angry city in the grip of fear.
Earlier today, in response to growing pressure,
the mayor's office issued the following statement.
- Give us a drink, pal.
- Got a joint?
Police departments are continuing the vigorous investigation
following up on a number of promising leads.
Hey, Rockefeller.
How'd you like Candy? She said you were kind of kinky, huh?
Don't ever speak to me.
Look, I didn't mean...
Don't ever speak to me again!
Do you understand?
Good.
I hope you get your head chopped off, asshole!
And you! Shut it!
- Hey, big boy.
- Slow down.
What the hell?
Okay, Marine, this is for real.
Let's go!
Go, go, go, go, go! Come on, come on!
What the hell's going on?!
For God's sake.
Look at that!
Mother of God...
Mom!
Hey, where're you going with my car?
Daddy, help me! Daddy! Daddy, help me!
Frank! Will you take it easy?
I'm telling you, I checked everywhere with
everybody. There just aren't any witnesses!
That's New York for you!
Twenty people standing around, nobody saw a goddamn thing.
Tell me about this Matunas. What is he, on drugs?
He's a survival man.
- What do you mean "survival man"?
- He's into guns. He was a Marine in Vietnam.
I talked to his ex-CO. He said that the guy
was a little paranoid, but he was good a man.
- How're you doing, kid?
- Okay, I guess.
For a guy who had 3 feet of steel crammed
through his gut. How're you doing old man?
I understand you saw the guy that stuck you, is that right?
You're kidding me, man.
Is that him?
Nope.
Come on, quit kidding, Matunas. It was dark in that alley!
The freak was trying to kill me!
I'll never forget his face. He had a scar
across his neck. That ain't him.
Shit!
- Depressed?
- Yeah.
You don't know grunt about depressed.
I got me a .357, I got me a trunk load of shotguns,
I got three big-bore rifles, and ammo up the ass.
And I ain't safe. I can't protect myself!
Okay, Take it easy, pal. Take it easy!
That weirdo, man. He got up,
after I'd put enough lead in him to drop a rhino.
Hey, listen, listen. You think you could
work with one of our artists,
maybe come up with a picture of this guy?
Sure. Sure. Yes.
Take it easy, pal.
- Hey, cop!
- Yeah?
I know you guys think I'm nuts,
but there's something else I gotta tell you.
After he threw me against the wall...
- This is getting like "One Step Beyond".
- Yeah.
Listen, when we get out there, remember.
All we've got is an eye-witness.
Now, don't say anything about swordfights in New York city,
or guys glowing in the dark for Christ's sake.
Hey, Moran!
Have you read what it says in here?
Are you kidding, Tony? You know cops can't read.
What does "incompetent" mean?
That mayor, he calls me at 2 o'clock in the morning!
I mean, I don't even answer the phone anymore.
What does "baffled" mean?
Karen Joan Nash.
Yeah, I remember this one.
I was practicing in Syracuse. Didn't get many of these.
What?
Unwed mothers. Nowadays, that's no big deal.
Back then in Syracuse, that was a stoning offense.
What happened?
- She had the baby and she died.
- So, Nash was illegitimate?
Oh, yeah. Yeah, he was illegitimate.
For about a minute and a half. He died right after she did.
He died?
Hello, Brenda.
I did what you asked.
I spent all night going through the old deeds
to Nash's house in Hudson Street,
all the way back back through the five previous
owners to the original guy, Montague in 1796.
In all five instances, Montague through Nash,
I found a death certificate for a kid
with the same name who died at birth,
years before he pretended to sign for his inheritance.
Jesus, Rick. Isn't there any heat in here?
No, heat is bad for the circuits.
Now, just in case there's any doubt...
So what you've got here, Brenda,
is a guy who's been creeping around since at least 1700,
pretending to croak every once in a while,
leaving all these goods to kids
who've been corpses for years
and assuming their identities.
It's not possible.
"Post" final! Cops release Headhunter picture!
- Reward offered!
- I'll take a "Post".
- Me too.
- Headhunter revealed!
For you, my bonny Heather.
Happy birthday.
And you, Juan Ramírez.
Take care of her, you overdressed haggis.
Kastagir is gone.
Only you and I remain.
Nice to see you, Kurgan.
Who cuts your hair?
I am in disguise.
This way no one will recognize me.
I do.
- What do you want?
- Your head.
And the prize.
Watch.
Happy Halloween, ladies!
Nuns! No sense of humor.
Ramírez's blade did not cut deeply enough.
He was right about you. You're slime.
Ramírez was an effete snob!
He died on his knees.
I took his head and raped his woman
before his blood was even cold.
I see!
Ramírez lied.
She was not his woman.
She was your woman.
And she never told you.
I wonder why.
Perhaps I gave her something you never could...
and secretly she yearned for my return.
Holy ground, Highlander!
Remember what Ramírez taught you.
You can't stay in here forever.
You are weak, Highlander.
You will always be weaker than I.
I'll be out front.
Goodbye, MacLeod.
We will meet soon enough.
This is the house of God.
People are trying to pray. You're disturbing them.
He cares about these helpless mortals?
Of course he cares.
He died for our sins.
That shall be his undoing.
Father,
forgive me.
I am a worm.
I have something to say.
It's better to burn out than to fade away.
I need to see him, goddamn it!
I'm afraid that's impossible. Mr. Nash is...
Mr. Nash is dead, Miss Ellenstein!
- What are you doing here?
- I'm looking for a dead guy named Nash.
He died at birth in Syracuse, New York.
All right.
Come on.
Are the claymores real?
What is this, a museum? This stuff must be worth a fortune.
I have been alive for four and a half centuries.
I cannot die.
Well, everybody's got their problems.
What are you goning to do with that?
Take it.
I am Connor MacLeod of the clan MacLeod.
I was born in 1518 in the village of
Glennfinnan on the shores of Loch Shiel.
And I am immortal.
You're not listening.
Brenda, it isn't going to work.
I can't get involved, not again.
You know what's weird?
Most people are afraid to die.
That's not your problem.
You're afraid to live.
Take care of yourself.
Don't lose your head.
Hello, pretty.
Come on, open up!
Mamma mia.
You ever played chicken?
Here we go!
Watch out!
Excuse me!
♪ New York, New York ♪
- ♪ I want to wake up ♪
- Shut up.
- ♪ In the city ♪
Sing along. ♪ That never sleeps ♪
Shut up!
- ♪ To find I'm king of the hill ♪
- Are you crazy?
Shut up!
♪ And ♪
♪ If I can ♪
♪ Make it there ♪
♪ I'll make it anywhere ♪
♪ It's up to you ♪
♪ New York ♪
♪ New ♪
♪ York ♪
I can entertain myself. Your friend
is a real screamer. Listen.
Which part should I cut off first?
I'll be waiting.
The endless killing's driven him mad.
Rachel, there are some instructions in the desk drawer.
I want you to follow them.
There is a power of attorney for you.
You'll have everything you need.
You're not coming back!
Even if you kill him, you're not coming back, are you?
Sweet Rachel, you always knew this would happen.
Russell Nash dies tonight.
Hey, it's a kind of magic.
Goodbye, Russell Nash.
So now it ends.
What kept you?
There can be only one.
The Quickening overcomes me!
I know everything!
I know! I know everything!
I am everything!
So, this is where it all began.
Can you tell me about the prize?
It's like a whirlwind in my head.
But if I concentrate, I know what people
are thinking all over the world.
Presidents, diplomats, scientists.
I can help them understand each other.
What am I thinking?
You're thinking whether or not you can love me. You can!
I'm just like you. I can love and
have children. Live and grow old.
You never prepared me for that, you Spanish peacock.
Patience, Highlander. You have done well.
But it will take time.
You are generations being born and dying.
You are at one with all living things.
Each man's thoughts and dreams are yours to know.
You have power beyond imagination.
Use it well, my friend. Don't lose your head.
♪ One dream ♪
♪ One source ♪
♪ One prize ♪
♪ One goal ♪
♪ One golden glance ♪
♪ Of what should be ♪
♪ One shine of light ♪
♪ That shows the way ♪
♪ No mortal man ♪
♪ Can win this day ♪
♪ The waiting seems ♪
♪ Eternity ♪
♪ The day will dawn ♪
♪ On sanity ♪
♪ Is this a kind ♪
♪ Of magic? ♪
♪ There can be only one ♪
♪ This rage ♪
♪ That lasts ♪
♪ A thousand years ♪
♪ Will soon be gone ♪
♪ This flame that burns ♪
♪ Inside of me ♪
♪ I'm hearing ♪
♪ Secret harmonies ♪
♪ The bell ♪
♪ That rings ♪
♪ Inside your mind ♪
♪ Is charging ♪
♪ The doors of time ♪
♪ The waiting seems ♪
♪ Eternity ♪
♪ The day will dawn ♪
♪ On sanity ♪
♪ This is ♪
♪ A kind ♪
♪ Of magic ♪
♪ There can be only one ♪
♪ This rage ♪
♪ That lasts ♪
♪ A thousand years ♪
♪ Will soon be ♪
♪ Will soon be gone ♪
♪ This is ♪
♪ A kind ♪
♪ Of magic ♪
♪ A kind of magic ♪