Mom, there is one thing
I'd like to ask you.
-Sure.
-How do they make that slime
-they're always dumping on you?
-Oh, well.
First they take some water.
Some liquid.
And then they add some
JELL-O powder and some flour.
Sometimes some soap.
Then they dump it all over me.
You gotta get going, kiddo.
We're going to be late.
Where do they dump it from?
Actually, Vanessa, I've always
wondered that, too. I just don't know.
Very interesting. Is it always green?
Well, yeah, it usually is,
but I guess it could be red.
Or it could be blue.
Or yellow.
-Daddy, telephone.
-Thanks, darling.
Hello?
Hi. No, I'm fine. I just stubbed my toe.
Hang on one second, will you?
Honey, it's Hildy.
I'll call her back.
She's in the bathroom.
She wants to know what you're wearing.
My black suit.
She's gonna wear her black dress.
Well, it's gonna be business.
You know how those things are.
Ellen, I don't want you messing with
my make-up now, honey, okay? I'm late.
-Is her red dress okay?
-It's perfect.
Did you hear that? You got it.
Okay, darling, see you later. Bye.
Oh, man.
I told you a million times
not to play with my lipstick, right?
So when are you gonna
listen to me, huh? Silly girl.
Honey, where's my blue suit?
It's on the back of the door.
Oh, shit!
Shit, shit, shit!
Shit, shit, shit.
-Hi, Ellen.
-Hi, Christine.
-How are you doing?
-Good.
-Where's Mommy?
-Mom? She's in the bathroom.
Ellen, I got you a present.
-You want to see what it is?
-Yeah, yeah.
Do you like it?
Okay. Come on, let's go find Mommy.
So then she's taking me to have...
She's pregnant,
she's going to give birth.
Hiya, Chuck. How are you? Good to
see you. You gonna make it Friday?
-Friday, I'm there.
-We need you, pal. We're in the cellar.
-You know that. Okay.
-Okay.
Dan, is my hair okay?
-You look great.
-I'm serious.
You're the prettiest woman
in the room, sweetheart.
You liar.
Dan! Danny!
-Hiya, Bob. How are you?
-Glad you could make it, Dan.
Listen, I'm sorry
about the meeting tomorrow.
I know it's a Saturday,
but we've got a real crisis here.
Oh, no, I understand.
You know my wife Beth? Bob Drimmer.
-Pleased to meet you.
-Nice to meet you.
-I hope you like sushi.
-Thank you. I love it, Bob. Love it.
-What did he do to his neck?
-He was screwing his wife.
-Are you serious?
-Am I serious?
Absolutely, you should see his wife.
They had to take her out on a stretcher.
-Hi, darling.
-You guys are bad.
Who wants champagne? Champagne?
Let's go.
-Champagne for everyone.
-Hemlock! With a twist.
Four champagnes over here.
Excuse me. Hi.
-Thank you.
-Thank you very much.
-Excuse me.
Jesus! Thank you. Fuck.
-Thank you.
-No, thank you.
So, what great cultural event
are we here to celebrate tonight?
-Some exercise manual.
-Not another one?
This one's different.
Based on ancient samurai discipline.
Danny, look at this guy nod.
What is that, part of the ritual?
Hey...
Hi, there.
-Jesus, if looks could kill...
-Glad to see you haven't lost your touch.
-I think she likes me.
-You do, huh?
-I think she wants me.
-I think you're batting zero for two,
and I don't want to know you.
-She was undressing me with her eyes.
-You think so? Good luck, pal.
She had trouble with the buttons.
A signed copy.
-Here you are, ma'am.
-Oh, thank you, dear.
-Can I get a champagne, please?
-You got it.
I'm not saying anything.
I'm not even gonna look.
Was it that bad?
Let's just say I was glad I wasn't
on the receiving end of that one.
Cheers.
Just gotta hate it when guys think
they can come on like that.
Jimmy's okay. He's just a little
insecure, like the rest of us.
-My name is Dan Gallagher.
-Alex Forrest.
Nice to meet you.
What is your connection here?
I'm an editor at Robbins & Hart.
And you?
I'm with Miller, Goodman and Hurst.
I do all your legal work.
I haven't seen you
around their office, though.
I've just been with them
a couple of weeks.
I have to go.
-Is that your wife?
-Yeah.
Better run along.
It was very nice to meet you.
"Make concessions with your body."
What does this mean,
"make concessions"?
-Oh, give me a break.
-Give you a break?
What does this mean?
How many did you buy?
-Well, thanks again, Christine.
-Any time, Mrs. Gallagher.
Good night.
Aren't you forgetting something?
Quincy, let's hit it, pal.
You're such a good boy, yes.
You did such good business.
You did good business.
You're the best boy.
Good night.
It's just for tonight, honey.
When you first see the house,
don't show any interest at all,
-otherwise we can't negotiate.
-Will you stop worrying about it?
-Ellen, are you chewing gum again?
-What's to worry, though?
-We can't afford it anymore.
-Daddy, is Granny going to be there?
-Just up the road from Mom and Dad.
-Yes.
-Which is another reason not to buy it.
-I didn't hear that.
What's to worry about?
Can't afford the goddamn thing, anyway.
Oh, come on. Hold on to him, honey.
Let's just not worry about it, okay?
I haven't even seen the damn place yet.
I may not even like it.
Ellen? The gum? Thank you.
Come on, Quincy. Come on, boy.
No, honey. Quincy's got to stay here
with Daddy. Daddy's gonna be all alone.
Sorry, Quincy. Now, you're not gonna
forget to walk him, are you?
-I promise.
-You promise.
Okay. You have a good meeting.
-Okay. See you tomorrow night.
-Love you.
Two times down, third time up,
he looked like a jellyfish.
-Hi, Bob.
-Hi, Dan. Sorry to ruin your weekend.
Please, give my apologies
to your lovely wife.
-David, hi.
-Help yourself.
-So, how are you feeling?
-Don't ask.
Henry's out of town, so I asked
Alex Forrest to stand in for him.
-Anybody know where she is?
-She's on her way.
Well, since we've got a little time,
maybe you can tell us exactly
what happened to your neck, Bob.
That's cute. Very cute.
Sorry I'm late. I was getting the file.
Dan, this is Alex Forrest,
our new associate editor.
-We've met before. Hi.
-Yeah, hello.
-Okay. Can we get started, Dan?
-Okay, here's the story.
You want to publish a novel
in which one of the characters
is a senator from New Jersey
who's fooling around.
Now, there's a certain congressman
from Ohio
who claims
the character's based upon him,
and he's filed an injunction
against the publication.
Look, the congressman's bald.
This guy has hair.
They're from different states,
for Christ's sake.
Look, if we don't sell those books,
we're screwed.
Well, that's all fine, but if I'm
gonna go to court to prove
the senator's not based upon
this congressman,
then I have to know the truth.
Now... Well, strictly between
these walls, all right?
Did the author have an affair
with Mr. Ohio or not?
Yeah, she did.
But she also had a lot of affairs
with other politicians.
Any one of them could
make the same claim.
She swears this character's fictitious.
I just got off the phone with her.
And you believe her?
Yeah, I believe her.
Okay, now that we've got that
on the table,
what can we do to lift that injunction?
If we believe the girl, is there some way
we can get to the congressman?
They take campaign contributions.
Can we buy him off?
Can we frighten him off?
Is there something in his past
that we can find out about?
I mean, we need to use some leverage.
I got 25...
Give me a break, will you?
Come on.
Come on!
-Was it made in Taiwan?
-Yeah. These are tough to find.
Wait, wait. Here. We got one.
Come on!
What do you say, you want to
go get a drink till it stops?
-Yeah, I'd love it.
-Okay.
Come on.
The strangest case I ever handled?
Well, the truth was,
I never actually handled a case.
The strangest case I ever came near to
was when my parents got divorced.
And my mother asked me
to represent her.
-You're kidding?
-That's what I said.
"What do you mean?" she told me.
"You know what an asshole the guy is."
"You've been a witness to this marriage
for the past 29 years."
Can you believe this?
This is coming from my mother.
No. How did you get out of it?
Well, you can't exactly
turn your mother down.
So, I escaped on a technicality.
-Which was what?
-I didn't practice family law.
And it was true, you know.
And she bought it.
-You're making this up.
-Could I make something up like that?
Waiter?
I've got a lot of pull here, you know.
My favorite restaurant.
-Yeah, I noticed.
-They know me well. Miss?
-You want coffee?
-I'd love one.
Can we have two coffees, please?
Well, I tell you, it's a...
-Do you want one?
-No, thank you.
It's funny being a lawyer, you know.
It's like being a doctor.
Everybody's telling you
their innermost secrets.
Oh, God.
-You must have to be discreet.
-Oh, God, yeah.
Are you?
Am I what?
Discreet.
Yes, I'm discreet.
Me, too.
-Can I ask you something?
-What?
Why don't you have a date tonight?
It's Saturday night.
I did have a date.
I stood him up.
That was the phone call I made.
Does that make you feel good?
It doesn't make me feel bad.
So, where's your wife?
Where's my wife?
My wife is in the country with her
parents, visiting them for the weekend.
And you're here with a strange girl,
being a naughty boy.
I don't think having dinner
with anybody is a crime.
Not yet.
-Will it be?
-I don't know. What do you think?
I definitely think
it's going to be up to you.
I can't say yet.
I haven't made up my mind.
At least you're very honest.
We were attracted to each other
at the party. That was obvious.
You're on your own for the night.
That's also obvious.
We're two adults.
Let's get the check.
-Oh, that was great.
-Oh, thank God. Thank God.
Are you feeling energetic?
What do you have in mind?
-How you getting home?
-I don't know, I live upstairs.
-This is the building?
-Yeah.
Well, where do I get a cab, you know?
Have you ever done it in an elevator?
-Not recently, no.
-I bet you haven't.
Oh, I'm sorry, baby. I'm sorry.
How are you?
Hi. What happened to you?
I tried you earlier. I'm gonna go...
I guess you're not back yet.
Well, I'm gonna go to bed now,
so call me in the morning. Bye-bye.
Hello? Oh, Dan, darling,
we were expecting you.
-I'm sorry. I had work to do.
-That's a pity.
We really wanted you to see that house.
-Well, I'll see it next time.
-Yes, of course.
You want to speak to Beth?
-Yes, please.
-Yes, all right.
The phone, it's Dan. Here you are.
Well, hello. What happened to you?
Hi...
Nothing. I just went out
and had dinner with Bill last night.
How is he?
He's... Bill's, you know...
Bill's Bill, the same as usual.
Is he still with that girl?
Well, he wasn't last night.
I think it's over.
He really didn't seem like
he wanted to talk about it.
-So, are you getting any work done?
-Yeah, I'm working.
Oh, listen, there's some of the spaghetti
sauce in the refrigerator,
if you get hungry.
Great. Okay. How's Ellen doing?
She is having the best time.
I just hope that Dad survives it.
Honey, I don't know how to tell you this.
But... She wants a rabbit.
Beth, no rabbits.
Jesus Christ! This goddamn family's
turning into Noah's Ark.
I mean, please! Give her a kiss,
all right? But no promises.
-All right.
-When are you coming home?
-Well, it's getting complicated.
-Why's that?
There's a problem with the house.
They sold it.
Very funny. No. We can't get in to see it
until late this afternoon.
I'm not up to fighting the traffic.
I thought I would come in tomorrow.
What about school?
She's only 5 years old.
What's she gonna miss? Trigonometry?
Yeah, okay. All right.
Well, then I'll see you
when I get home from work.
Okay. See you tomorrow.
Okay, thanks. Have a good time.
Yeah?
What happened? I woke up.
You weren't here. I hate that.
-You didn't get my note?
-What note?
I left you a note right by your bed.
Oh.
That's nice. I thought we were going
to spend the day together.
Alex, look, I've got so much work
to do today. I can't.
Why don't you just come over?
I'll cook us lunch.
I got to take the dog for a walk.
The poor dog has not
been out of this house all day.
I got to take him out.
Well, bring the dog. I love animals.
I'm a great cook. Come on.
Listen, I'd love to, but I can't.
All right? I really can't.
Do what you have to do,
then come over afterwards.
We can always eat late.
Or you can work here.
I won't disturb you, I promise.
I'll be a good girl.
Yeah, you don't give up, do you?
You just don't give up.
Come on!
Quincy, no! Quincy!
I got it! I got it! He's free!
Quincy, cover me. I'm on it.
Go deep. He fires. Throws...
-Okay.
-She's got it. Yes. It's back.
Over the head. He's got it.
Dan? Dan!
Dan? Dan, can you hear me?
Oh, my God!
-You bastard.
-Your face!
Your face!
-That was a shitty thing to do.
-I'm sorry. I was just fooling around.
My father died of a heart attack.
I was 7 years old.
It happened right in front of me.
Honey, I'm sorry.
Really, I had no idea. If I did, I never
would have done anything like that.
Wait, he didn't die? He's alive?
Yeah, he's alive and well
and living in Phoenix.
I guess you certainly got me, didn't you?
Let's hear it.
I hope you like spaghetti.
Specialty of the house.
It goes with the opera.
It smells so good.
-Anything else for me to do?
-No, nothing.
Just make yourself at home.
-You can change the tape if you want to.
-No, this is great.
I love Madame Butterfly.
-Really? It's my favorite opera.
-Mine, too.
It's the first opera I ever saw.
My father, he took me to the old Met.
I was 5 years old.
-Did it make any sense?
-I got most of it.
There was this US sailor setting up
house with this Japanese lady.
That was all fine.
But in the final act, after he left her,
my father told me,
"She's gonna kill herself."
And I was terrified.
I was...
I climbed right underneath the chair.
It's right here.
This is it. It's right...
It's funny.
-What?
-It's one of the only times
I remember my father being nice
to me when I was a kid.
Comforting me at Madame Butterfly.
What?
What are you thinking?
I was wondering why is it that all
the interesting guys are always married.
Well, maybe that's why
you find them interesting,
the fact you can't have them.
How long have you been married?
Nine years.
-Do you have any kids?
-I got a 6-year-old girl.
Sounds good.
Yeah, I'm lucky.
So what are you doing here?
Boy, you know how to
ask the wrong thing.
No, I really want to know.
I had a wonderful time last night.
I'd like to see you again.
Is that so terrible?
No.
I just don't think it's possible, now.
It's really strange.
I feel like I know you already.
I just want to know where I stand.
I think you're terrific.
But I'm married.
What can I say? I...
Just my luck.
Shit!
-What are you doing?
-I gotta go.
I thought you said she wasn't
coming back till tomorrow.
She's not, but I got things to do, honey.
I got to go home.
-You know, I don't think I like this.
-Like what?
The way you run away
after every time we make love.
Well, Alex, what difference does it make
whether I leave now or in the morning?
The fact is, I gotta go.
-Well, you're not gonna leave now.
-Oh, come on. Will you stop it?
-I mean it.
-Come on! Hey, Alex! Come on!
What's the problem?
I'm sorry.
Jesus Christ, I mean,
let's be reasonable.
Be reasonable? What?
"Thank you, goodbye.
Don't call me, I'll call you."
Look, you knew about me, all right?
I didn't hide anything.
-I thought it was understood.
-What was understood?
The opportunity was there,
and we took it.
-Come on now, we're adults, aren't we?
-What's that supposed to mean?
-I thought we could have a good time.
-No, you didn't.
You thought you'd have a good time.
You didn't stop for a second
to think about me.
That's crazy. You knew the rules, Alex.
What rules?
Look, Alex. I like you.
And if I wasn't with somebody else,
maybe I'd be with you. But I am.
Please, don't justify yourself.
It's pathetic.
If you'd tell me to fuck off,
I'd have more respect for you.
All right then, fuck off.
And you get out!
I'm going.
Why don't you come over here
and say goodbye nicely?
Let's be friends.
Baby, no.
It's okay.
-Sorry if I upset you.
-It's okay, it's okay, really.
It's okay. All right. That's okay.
Your hands are all wet.
Jesus!
Jesus Christ!
Come here, come here, come here.
Hold on. Hold on.
Nice and tight.
Hi. Did you just call me?
I was in the shower. I heard the phone.
I thought it was you.
So, how are you?
Did you have a good day?
Yeah, yeah.
Really? That's terrific.
That's really terrific.
You sound excited.
Yeah.
No, I'm not against the idea, I mean...
Don't get me wrong. It's just the money.
Yeah.
Okay, darling. I love you.
Bye.
Alex?
How are you feeling?
Okay.
I gotta go.
Will you call me sometime?
You don't have to, if you don't want to.
No, I want to.
You promise me you're gonna go
see the doctor?
Okay.
Goodbye.
-You take care.
-You, too.
Shit.
Look what I got.
Look what I got for you here.
A little spaghetti and meat sauce.
That's it, buddy.
We'll make an Italian out of you yet.
That's a good boy. Good dog.
Have a good one, yeah.
What are you doing here? It's 8:00 a.m.
I'm in the shitter, Martha. Got to be
in court by 2:00 and I'm really behind.
Will you do me a favor?
Cancel everything.
Then call Drimmer, tell him we're fine.
-I'll be there by 2:00.
-At 2:00? Okay.
Good morning, Martha.
-Daddy!
-Hey! Honey! Oh, God, I missed you.
-We had a great time!
-Yeah?
-I went for a walk with Grandpa...
-You did?
...and we saw rabbits
and chased them...
Well, good. Why don't you slow down?
I can't understand
one word you're saying.
-Daddy, I want a rabbit.
-I know you do, honey.
-Hi, darling. How are you?
-Good.
Good.
God, I missed you.
-Liar.
-I did.
Well, I should go away more often.
-I did this one.
-You did?
-Yes. Pick another one.
-I thought it was this row you picked.
-No. It was this one.
-I think you're in a lot of trouble.
-Okay.
-Now, pick a card, Dad.
Any card at all?
-Yeah? Where'd you learn this?
-Of course.
-Grandpa showed me.
-Oh.
Surprise.
So how was it?
Oh, come on, I'm a big boy. I can take it.
It had a place for rabbits.
Oh, no! She said it.
She said the R-word. Oh, no!
Not rabbits? Rabbits?
Rabbits!
-Rabbits!
-Not rabbits?
Rabbits!
Well, what can I tell you?
It's absolutely perfect.
-In this row?
-No.
So, when are you gonna come up
and take a look at it?
-Just for the hell of it?
-In this row?
How about tomorrow morning?
-Daddy, which row?
-You mean it?
If you get me back to the office
by 1:00, yeah.
Which row, Dad?
It's in this row, sweetheart.
Oh, I love this.
Dan?
Honey? Honey, come here.
I want you to see this.
Well?
It's... It's okay. It's okay.
-Come on, it's fantastic!
-It's great. It's great.
Just think of all the money we're gonna
save, not living in New York.
The local high school is excellent.
My own children went there.
-You see?
-This is a terrific area for kids.
Oh, I'm sure. I'm sure.
Is it okay if I go upstairs?
Please, go right ahead.
I'll wait for you down here.
Thank you.
You know, we still got to decorate.
We can fix up anything.
We can have painting parties.
Painting parties?
Beth, you're making me very nervous.
Well, now, look at this. This is fantastic.
This would make a terrific playroom.
What are you talking about, playroom?
This is my den!
It's a den!
I knew you were going to like it.
I like it.
I'll be in court. How you doing, Dan?
-Hi, Eunice. Martha back from lunch?
-Good afternoon, Mr. Gallagher.
-She just returned.
-Thank you.
Hi.
Hello.
This isn't a bad time, is it?
I was in the area. I figured that...
No, no.
You want to come into my office?
This is his account?
Hey, Danny. Danny, you gonna be
in your office a little later this...
-Excuse me? Have we met somewhere?
-I don't think so.
She looked at me first.
-Sit down.
-Thank you.
-You okay?
-I'm fine.
I was going to call you today.
I... This is terribly embarrassing.
I just wanted to say sorry
for what happened.
I had no right to put you through all that.
Nothing happened, okay?
I was going through a bad time.
And everything was coming
to a crisis, and...
But I'm fine. I'm really all right.
And thank you.
-You don't have to thank me.
-Oh, yeah, I do.
A lot of guys would have just run away.
I don't know what I would have done
if you hadn't been there.
Well, you look good.
As a matter of fact, you look great.
Thanks.
So that's past?
Yeah.
-May I ask you one more favor?
-What's that?
I've got two tickets to Madame Butterfly,
two weeks from Thursday.
I'd really love it if you'd come with me,
kind of as a peace offering.
Well, that's very nice of you.
But I don't think it's a good idea.
-No strings attached.
-Alex.
I know, you don't have to explain.
I just thought I'd ask.
So...
I'll see you around sometime.
Okay.
Come here.
-Take care.
-Yeah. Goodbye.
Goodbye.
All right. Come on, let's go, pal.
We're on a roll. We're on a roll.
-Let's see that action.
-Down the middle.
I like it. Very nice.
That is no good. I'm depressed.
What about
Rodgers v. whatchamacallit?
-Winitsky.
-Right.
I got your memo. You're going to
go for summary judgment?
Why not, Arthur?
I mean, the facts are not in dispute.
Rodgers admits
reading Winitsky's article.
The question is whether
he plagiarized it in his book.
As you know,
you can't copyright an idea,
only the expression of the idea,
and Rodgers sure as hell didn't use
any of the words in the book.
-Let me think about it.
-Okay.
So I hear you're about to
become a suburbanite.
Yeah, we're gonna take the big plunge.
-Got a buyer for the apartment?
-No.
-Got cold sweats about your escrow?
-Yeah.
But not about Rodgers vs. Winitsky?
-No, sir.
-Good.
He's still in a meeting.
Yes, I know.
I did expect him to be through by now.
I'd like you to have lunch with me
on Tuesday, if you're around.
Well, thank you, Arthur, that'd be great.
Let me just check my diary.
You are on his list of calls.
It's Alex Forrest.
Again? I thought you told her
I'd call her back.
-I did.
-All right. Put her on hold.
Would you mind holding?
He'll be free in a moment.
Tuesday would be great, Arthur.
-I look forward to it.
-Thank you. I will, too.
Put her through.
Hello?
Look, Alex, I thought we agreed
this was not a good idea.
Why?
Look, I'm sorry.
I thought you understood.
If I've misled you in some way,
I apologize.
But I don't think it's a good idea
if we talk to each other anymore.
Okay?
Goodbye.
Yeah, if she calls again,
tell her I'm not here. Thank you.
Wait, let me just...
Let me just look at you.
You're so beautiful.
Just so beautiful.
-Wouldn't you know?
-I know.
Open it, will you? That's my wife!
I wouldn't do it to my wife.
You know what? It's okay.
You don't know how many
injuries can happen?
-It's my wife he's doing it...
-Jimmy, don't terrorize them!
I'm a lawyer, I'm insured.
Oh, it's excited.
Now, don't forget who gave you this,
all right?
My cold sores are almost gone.
This is for you.
Ladies first. I use that term advisedly.
You're the best.
That's my wife! All right, ladies...
A little attention, please, ladies.
Gentlemen, my wife, ball and chain.
Mother of some of my children.
-I wouldn't be that confident about it.
-Absolutely.
Here is to Miller, Goodman,
Hurst and Gallagher!
-And to Mrs. Gallagher.
-Give me a break, will you, guys?
All he did is ask me to lunch, you know?
Yeah, and you're moving
to your country estate.
You'll forget you never knew us plebs.
Oh, no, wait a minute.
I read one of those self-help books.
Published by Robbins & Hart, of course.
Of course. Samurai Self-Help.
In it, it tells you how to deal
with the anxieties of your friends
as you move up the corporate ladder
and they stay put,
or God forbid, go down.
And in this book, it tells you not to
coddle your friends' anxieties.
So, I'm not gonna make
any false reassurances, guys.
I'm not gonna tell you you're gonna
be at the house every weekend.
I mean, let's face it.
Things have changed.
This is not a classless society.
As a matter of fact, this is it, guys.
Goodbye. Goodbye.
I knew he was gonna say that!
At least the man is running true to form.
Honey, I think we got to
make a clean break.
I mean, we're on a roll. We got to travel
light. You know, let's face it.
-Travel light. Exactly.
-Absolutely.
Thanks for the time
you've given us in your lives.
Here you, drink.
I want you with a lampshade
on your head by 10:00.
Why should today be any different,
you know what I mean?
Hello? Hello?
Here's to you.
Cheers.
Hello?
Hello!
Yeah?
Yeah, Richards. It's kind of late, isn't it?
If you refuse to take my phone calls
at the office, you leave me no choice.
It's 2:00 in the morning here.
Can't this wait till tomorrow morning?
Oh, is it awkward for you to talk?
You could say that, yeah.
I've got to see you.
I don't have the documentation
to answer that question right now,
but I'll call you from the office.
No. Meet me in front of the
Robbins & Hart building tomorrow. 6:00.
Don't disappoint me. Be there.
Okay.
This has got to stop.
Dan, if you'd agreed to see me,
I wouldn't have called you.
Do you get it, all right? It's over.
There is nothing between us.
You've mean you've had your fun,
now you just want a quiet life.
-Why are you doing this?
-Doing what?
You need help.
-Don't tell me what I need.
-You need a shrink.
Why are you so hostile?
I'm not your enemy.
Yeah, then why are you
trying to hurt me?
I'm not trying to hurt you, Dan.
I love you.
-You what?
-I love you.
-You don't even know me.
-Oh, how can you say that?
Alex, we spent a weekend
together, that's all.
You spent that second night.
You must like me a little.
Because I was concerned about you.
Jesus Christ!
Why do you read so much
into everything?
I mean, can't you understand?
I have a whole relationship
with someone else.
-I am very happy.
-Whole means complete.
If your life's so damn complete,
what were you doing with me?
Is this what you want to talk about,
our imaginary love affair?
I'm pregnant.
I saw my gynecologist on Monday.
Here's his card. You can call him.
You don't...
Use anything? No.
I had a very bad miscarriage last year.
I didn't think I could get pregnant.
And how do you know it's mine?
Because I don't sleep around.
I apologize.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Don't worry, all right? You're not going
to have to handle this alone.
Handle what?
The abortion. I'll take care of it.
I'll pay for it.
What makes you think
I want an abortion?
-You're not going to have the baby?
-Why not?
There are plenty of one-parent families.
-At least they don't end in divorce.
-I don't have a say in this?
I want this child.
It has nothing to do with you.
I want it whether you're going to
be a part of it or not.
Then why are you telling me? Why?
Why not just go ahead and do it?
I was hoping that you would
want to be a part of it.
This is crazy. This is totally insane.
I'm 36 years old. It may be
my last chance to have a child.
Alex...
Just think what you're saying.
Just think about it.
We are going to live with this
for the rest of our lives.
I know that.
I've thought of that. I know how you feel.
It's a big thing.
But it doesn't have to be a problem.
Really, it doesn't.
You play fair with me,
I'll play fair with you.
"He led Agnes and Nellie
into the hall closet and shut the door.
"Agnes and Nellie and Oink
giggled and laughed in the dark.
"Pearl listened outside the door.
'Oh, it works,' cried Nellie.
"'Of course,' said Oink.
'Look at the flying dog!' yelled Agnes.
"'Wow,' cried Nellie.
"Pearl frowned. 'Who cares
about flying dogs?' she said.
"Nobody heard her.
"'Look out for the worms!'
squealed Agnes.
"'Eek!' yelled Nellie and Agnes together.
"'Look at the monster cockroach!'
yelled Oink. 'Ick! Help!"'
So, you know what I did? Right.
I call the doctor.
And you know what he says?
"Congratulations!"
I can't even imagine what she told him.
Anyway, that's not the end of it.
So, after I talked to the doctor,
this morning, I broke into her apartment.
I know.
Me, a lawyer, breaking and entering.
I don't know, I'm looking for something,
anything to get a handle on
what I'm dealing with here.
I thought maybe if I can find out she was
sleeping with somebody else, you know.
I didn't find anything.
Anyway, I didn't find anything.
Jimmy, I don't know. I don't know
anything about family law, okay?
So you gotta help me now.
What kind of case
does she really have?
Well, it ain't good.
She keeps calling the apartment.
Every time Beth answers the phone,
she hangs up.
I'm scared, Jimmy. I...
I don't want to lose my family.
The facts as alleged are horrendous.
The instrument allegedly used
in all three cases
was an electronic shock device,
or stun gun, now standard
issue for New York City police.
The stun guns, which jolt
and incapacitate the body
by interrupting electrical waves
to the muscles,
are being used or experimented
with by 500 police agencies
across the country,
marketed as an alternative
to the nightsticks.
Operator, may I help you?
Operator, I've been trying to
get 555-812-9212.
The recording says
it's been disconnected.
Just a moment, please.
I'm sorry. The number's been changed
to an unlisted number.
Operator, this is a real emergency.
Please, you need to
give me that number.
I'm sorry, we're not allowed to
give out that information.
-Well, fuck you!
-Oh, my place or yours?
-I like it. I like it a lot.
-Well, we've been very happy here.
I'd definitely like to
think about it if I could.
-...to clean and all?
-Yes.
I have a lady that comes in
a couple times a week,
as a matter of fact.
And I can certainly give you her name
as well.
Oh, I'd love that.
And I have babysitters galore.
The whole works.
Whatever information you would need.
Hi, darling. Darling, this is Alex.
I'm sorry, I've forgotten your last name.
-Alex Forrest.
-Alex Forrest, this is my husband Dan.
Hi. Glad to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
-Haven't we met somewhere before?
-I don't think so. No.
No, we have. Weren't you at that party
at the Japanese place,
a few weeks ago?
Honey, the exercise book.
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
You're a lawyer?
And you work for the firm of...
What's the name?
Well, anyway...
We've definitely met.
-Well, you have a good memory.
-I never forget a face.
-It's a small world.
-It certainly is.
So, I gather you're going to the country?
-Moving to the country?
-Yes.
Have you found a place yet?
Actually, we found a place in Bedford.
Do you know it up there?
-Oh, it's beautiful.
-Yes.
So I guess you'll be moving out of here
almost immediately?
Actually, we wanted to do
some remodeling first.
I guess you're looking for a place
right away, aren't you?
Well, yeah. I'd kind of like to settle in.
Alex is expecting a baby.
Oh, that's...
Will you excuse me?
I have some work I've got to do.
Oh, I better run, too.
Thank you for the tea
and showing me the apartment.
-You're very welcome.
-I like it. I really like it.
-We've been very happy here.
-I'd like to think about it if I could.
Let me give you our number
so you can call us direct.
Thank you.
-I'll keep in touch.
-Great.
-Bye-bye.
-Goodbye.
She seemed really interested.
It's funny, she didn't mention a husband.
I get the feeling that she's on her own.
-What is it? You seem down.
-No, no. I'm just tired.
-Hello?
-Yeah, hi, it's me.
Who?
You know damn well who it is, okay?
Now, come on. Let me in. I want to talk.
Oh, so now you want to talk?
So, what can I get you?
I've got Scotch, I've got vodka,
there's a nice Chablis...
Cut the shit, will you? Just cut it!
I don't know what you're up to,
but I'm going to tell you
it's going to stop right now.
No, it's not going to stop.
It's going to go on and on,
until you face up to your responsibilities.
What responsibilities?
I'm pregnant.
I'm going to have our child.
Alex, that's your choice, honey,
that has nothing to do with me.
I just want to be a part of your life.
Oh, this is the way you do it, huh?
Showing up at my apartment?
Well, what am I supposed to do?
You won't answer my calls.
You change your number. I mean...
I'm not going to be ignored, Dan.
You don't get it.
You just... You don't get it.
Don't you remember our weekend?
Wasn't that wonderful?
Why can't we just be like that again?
I know you feel it, too.
I mean, what are you so afraid of?
Hey, just don't flatter yourself, Alex.
Go ahead, hit me. If you can't fuck me,
why don't you just hit me?
You're so sad. You know that, Alex?
Lonely and very sad.
Don't you ever pity me,
you smug bastard.
I'll pity you.
I'll pity you because you're sick.
Why? Because I won't allow you
to treat me like some slut
you can just bang a couple of times
and throw in the garbage?
I'm going to be the mother of your child.
I want a little respect.
You want respect?
-Respect.
-What are you doing?
Please, Dan. Please don't go.
I didn't mean it. Please, I'm sorry.
I'll tell your wife.
You tell my wife, I'll kill you.
It only takes a phone call!
Hello? Hello?
Got it.
Guys, that's on the second door
on the left of the landing.
Thank you.
Honey, you could've stayed
in the apartment.
Dan was in such a hurry to
get out of New York.
Momma, that's you, isn't it? Look.
Oh, Lord, put it away.
All right, easy on that door frame.
Good. Right. Nice. Just like a glove.
I got it. Sorry. I got it.
Hello?
Martha.
Martha. It's Martha.
Hello?
Hi, honey. How you doing?
Did the plumber come yet?
Oh, did he ever.
Well, I don't really want to
know about it, all right?
Hey, guess what I'm looking at.
-You got it?
-Yeah, yeah, I got it right here.
Or, I should say, I got her.
What's she like?
Well, she's cute. She looks like a rabbit.
I mean, she's white, she's got long ears,
little pink eyes.
-Soft.
-She sounds cute.
Yeah. Ellen doesn't know
anything about it?
No. She doesn't think
she's going to get one.
See what happens if you work here
too long, Eunice?
-Isn't he cute?
-Thank you.
Oh, I forgot. This arrived for you.
-Good night, Eunice.
-Good night, Mr. Gallagher.
And it's an inbound to Ewing on top.
Patrick gives it back to Gerald.
Gerald on the right to Sparrow.
Goes base line,
comes to the reverse side,
gives it off to Ewing.
He spins, knocks the man away,
throws the ball. Shot is good.
Hey, Joaquin!
Holton on the outside.
Holding down a left-handed dribble
against Sparrow.
Now looking inside, looking in.
Finds no one...
Jesus fucking Christ!
Fucking bitch! Jesus Christ!
No. No. It had something to do
with the electrical system.
The whole goddamn thing blew up.
It was smoking.
All right, honey.
I'll see you in a little while.
Mr. Gallagher?
You forgot your contract.
Thanks.
Hello, Dan. Are you surprised?
This is what you've reduced me to.
I guess you thought you'd get away
with it. Well, you can't.
Because part of you is growing
inside of me, and that's a fact, Dan,
and you'd better start
learning how to deal with it.
Because, you know, I feel you.
I taste you.
I think you.
I touch you.
Can you understand? Can you?
I'm just asking you to
acknowledge your responsibilities.
I mean, is that so bad?
I don't think so.
I don't think it's unreasonable.
And, you know, another thing is
that you thought
that you could just walk into my life
and turn it upside down, without
a thought for anyone but yourself.
You know what you are, Dan?
You're a cock-sucking son of a bitch.
I hate you.
I bet you don't even like girls, do you?
You flaming fucking faggot!
Daddy! Thank you.
You're welcome, honey.
Do you like her?
A bunny!
You like it?
You thought you could just walk
into my life and turn it upside down,
without a thought
for anyone but yourself.
You know what you are, Dan?
You're a cock-sucking son of a bitch.
You are.
I bet you don't even like girls, do you?
They probably scare you. I know I do.
So you're scared of me, aren't you?
You're fucking frightened of me.
You're afraid.
You're afraid, aren't you?
You gutless, heartless, spineless,
fucking son of a bitch.
I hate you.
You deserve everything you get.
-Jesus Christ!
-Sorry.
I was wondering what you were
doing up so late.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to scare you.
No, it's okay.
I was listening to a deposition.
I couldn't sleep.
Come on.
I'm going to give you a back rub.
-Back rub?
-Brandy, a back rub.
-You won't know what hit you.
-Sounds good.
My client wants it stopped.
He just wants an end
to the harassment.
He's positive it was this woman
who trashed the car?
Yes. Yes, of course.
-Any witnesses?
-No.
Welcome to file a complaint
if it'd make him feel better.
I mean, there's not a lot
you can do without proof.
Look, Lieutenant,
this woman is completely irrational.
There's no telling what she could do.
We can't go around arresting people
for what they might do. You know that.
I'm not asking you to arrest her.
I... He simply...
He wants her warned.
Well, we could talk to her.
It may make things public.
He's not going to like that.
It may even aggravate the situation
with the girl.
How's that?
Well, whatever resentment
she's feeling,
she's probably got it out of her system.
And any action we take
could provoke her.
What if she didn't get it out
of her system? What then?
You have to catch her in the act.
Then we can bring charges.
Well, you say he just has to
sit there and take it?
It's his bed.
I'm afraid he's going to have to lie in it.
Come on. Come on in, come on in.
Come on, Ellen,
we're going to Grandma's.
Grandma's? Let's go.
Come on, Quince.
Quincy, come on, hurry up.
Come on, get on in. Hurry up.
Watch his tail, sweetie.
Make him sit down.
-See you didn't get your car back.
-No, it's a total write-off.
-The electrical system's just shot.
-Extraordinary, those foreign cars.
-There you are, dear.
-Thank you.
-Want to try it again, sweetie?
-Okay.
Okay.
So?
Dear Priscilla, Miles asked me
to ask you to marry him.
Very good.
-You want to do it one more time.
-Okay.
Do it with your hat and do the bow,
so when you actually do it,
you know what you're doing.
-Let me see your bow.
-Okay.
And, what do you say?
Dear Priscilla, Miles asked me
to ask you to marry him.
-Very good. You got that.
-Ellen. Ellen.
Come here.
-That was good.
-Thank you.
That was really good.
That was so good.
-I love you.
-I love you, too.
Thank you, darling.
Come on, Quincy.
-Daddy!
-What?
Whitey's gone!
Dan!
It's all right, darling.
It's going to be okay, sweetie.
You should try and get some sleep.
-Is she okay?
-She's asleep.
-Did you call the police?
-Not yet, no.
Why not?
Honey, we've got to talk.
What is it?
I know who did this.
You do? Who?
Remember the girl
who came to the apartment?
The one I met
in the Japanese restaurant?
The one with the blonde hair.
You're scaring me.
What is it?
Did you have an affair with her?
Yes.
Beth?
Beth, I am so sorry.
The last thing I ever wanted to do
was to hurt you.
Are you...
Are you in love with her?
No, no. It was one night.
It didn't mean anything.
What has it got to do
with what's happened?
She's pregnant.
She's...
It's yours?
I don't know. That's what she says.
Honey, listen to me. Beth, please.
Get out! I want you out of here.
I want you out of this house!
And I want you out now.
How could you do that? I hate you!
Understand what I'm saying, honey.
I don't want to hear it!
I don't want to hear any of it!
Please, just listen to me, will you, Beth?
Please. Listen to me.
What is the matter with you?
Dan, what a pleasant surprise.
It's over, Alex. It's all finished.
I told Beth, she knows all about it.
Sure. You haven't got the balls.
Why don't you speak to her?
Why would I want to talk to her?
This is Beth Gallagher.
If you ever come near my family again,
I'll kill you, you understand?
That's the last one, Ellen. I mean it.
Hello? Hi, Daddy.
When are you coming home?
Honey, I don't know.
How are you doing?
Good.
Okay.
Yeah.
Grandpa taught me a new card trick.
Oh, did he?
What, the one with the jacks?
No, the one with the kings.
Good.
I won't.
How's Mommy?
Send her my love.
Okay. Goodbye.
Daddy?
Call me tomorrow.
I will. I promise.
You be sure you tell Mommy I called.
I will.
Love you a lot, too. Bye-bye.
Bye-bye.
Hi, Mrs. Gallagher.
Did you forget something?
I came to get Ellen.
Ellen? Why, I thought you picked her
up already.
Well, I'm sure she's left already.
Betty? Is Ellen in here with you?
-She's gone home already.
-Are you sure?
I'm positive. She's not inside
and she's not in the playground.
-I thought you picked her up.
-Who did pick her up?
Well, don't worry.
She can't have gone far.
-You don't understand.
-I'll check her locker.
-Alicia, where's Ellen?
-She's gone.
Call the police.
Ellen.
Please, let her be all right.
Christ.
Where are you?
Ellen! Ellen!
Ellen!
Look out!
Where are you?
-Bye-bye, Ellen.
-Bye.
Ellen, can I have a kiss?
Excuse me, I'm looking for a patient
named Gallagher. I'm her husband.
Room 22 at the end of the corridor.
-Is she going to be okay?
-Yeah, she'll be fine.
She was very lucky. It might have been
a lot worse. A lot worse.
-Daddy!
-Hi, baby. Oh, God, I missed you.
I missed you, honey.
Are you okay?
Have you seen Mommy yet?
Yeah.
Okay, you stay here with Granny.
I'm going to go see Mommy.
Howard.
You'll be okay.
-You guys want to go to Ziggy's first?
-Yeah!
-It's a hot place.
-That's a good idea.
All right! You know...
I came in here before.
I tried to explain the situation to you,
you didn't want to listen to me.
Now, the woman took my kid
and that's kidnapping, right? Am I right?
My wife's in the hospital.
She could've been killed!
If you're not going to
do something about...
Take it easy, okay.
You don't have to shout.
Okay.
Okay. What are you going to do?
We'll tell New York to pick her up
and bring her in for questioning, okay?
Okay.
Okay, then I'm...
I'm going to go to the hospital tomorrow,
pick my wife up
and hopefully,
I'll be home for the weekend
if you need to talk to me.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
You're welcome.
How's that feel?
Good and warm? Good.
Are you all cozy?
Is Mommy going to be all right?
Mommy's going to be fine, honey.
She's going to be fine.
Are you going to stay with us?
I'm going to stay with you, honey.
Now, you go to sleep, okay?
Good night, doll.
Forever?
I promise, honey.
You mean the detectives in Manhattan
have no idea where she's gone?
They don't know where she is?
Yeah.
No, I see. I see.
All right.
If you get any more information,
you'll be sure and let me know,
won't you, Lieutenant?
Thank you very much. Good night.
I think we just found out
where the beef is.
Okay. Cathy and Charlie, who do you
think held out for the most money?
The one who has to try out
the mysterious new shampoo,
or the man who has to try
on the sundress.
And remember,
it's possible that one of them...
-Here you go.
-Thanks.
How does the arm feel?
It hurts.
Get you some more painkillers.
Okay.
Welcome back. Our contestants
have been asked to decide...
Thanks.
Now, you just holler
if you need anything else, all right?
I'd love a cup of tea.
You got it.
What are you doing here?
Why are you here?
He tried to say goodbye to me last night.
But he couldn't,
because he and I feel the same way
about each other.
Do you know how it is when you meet
somebody for the first time
and you get this instant attraction?
And don't you think I understand
what you're doing?
You're trying to move him
into the country.
And you're keeping him away from me.
And you're playing happy family.
But you wouldn't understand that
because you're so selfish.
And he told me about you.
He told me about you.
He was very honest.
If you weren't so stupid, you'd know that.
But you're so stupid.
You're just so stupid,
you're a stupid, selfish bitch!
You're a stupid, selfish bitch!
Dan!
Dan! Dan!
No!
Stop!