There is one thing
I'd like to ask you.
How do they make that slime?
First they take some water.
Then they add some jello powder
and some flour. Sometimes soap.
Then they dump it over me.
- We'd better get going.
- Where from?
I've always wondered that, too.
I just don't know.
Interesting. Is it always green?
It usually is,
but I guess it could be red.
Or it could be blue.
Or yellow.
- Daddy, telephone.
- Thanks, darling.
Hello?
Hildy, I'm fine.
I just stubbed my toe.
Hang on one second.
Honey, it's Hildy.
I'll call her back.
She's in the bathroom. She wants
to know what you're wearing.
My black suit.
She'll wear a black dress.
It's business.
You know how those things are.
Ellen, don't mess with
my make-up. I'm late.
- Is the red dress OK?
- It's perfect.
Did you hear that?
You got it. OK, see you later.
I told you a million times
not to play with my lipstick.
So when are you gonna listen to me?
Silly girl.
Honey, where's my blue suit?
On the back of the door.
Shit! Shit, shit, shit!
Shit, shit, shit.
- Hi.
- Hi, Christine.
- How are you doing?
- Good.
- Where's Mommy?
- Mom? She's in the bathroom.
I got you a present.
You want to see what it is?
Do you like it?
OK. Come on, let's go find Mommy.
So then,
she's talking to me about sales.
Chuck. How are you?
Will you make it, Friday?
- I'm there.
- We need you. We're in the cellar.
Is my hair OK?
- You look great.
- I'm serious.
- You're the prettiest woman here.
- You liar.
- Hiya, Bob. How are you?
- Glad you could make it.
Sorry about the meeting tomorrow,
but we've got a crisis.
I understand. My wife Beth.
- Bob Drimmer.
- Pleased to meet you.
- I hope you like sushi.
- I love it.
- How did he hurt his neck?
- Screwing his wife.
- Are you serious?
- You should see his wife.
They took her out on a stretcher.
- You guys are bad.
- Champagne?
Let's go. Champagne for everyone.
- With a twist.
- Four champagnes.
Excuse me. Hi.
How are you keeping?
Excuse me.
Jesus! Thank you. Fuck.
- Thank you.
- No, thank you.
What cultural event
are we celebrating?
- Some exercise manual.
- Not another one?
This one's different.
Based on ancient Samurai discipline.
Look at this guy.
What is that, part of the ritual?
Hey...
Hi, there.
- If looks could kill...
- You haven't lost your touch.
I think she likes me.
I think you're batting zero for two.
She was undressing me with her eyes.
She had trouble with the buttons.
A signed copy.
- Here you are, ma'am.
- Thank you.
- Can I get a champagne, please?
- You got it.
I'm not saying anything.
I'm not even gonna look.
Was it that bad?
I was glad I wasn't on the receiving
end of that one. Cheers.
I hate it
when guys come on like that.
Jimmy's OK. He's just a little
insecure, like the rest of us.
- My name is Dan Gallagher.
- Alex Forrest.
Nice to meet you.
What is your connection here?
I'm an editor at Robbins & Hart.
And you?
I'm with Miller, Goodman and Hurst.
I do your legal work.
I haven't seen you at their office.
I've just been with them
a couple of weeks.
I have to go.
- Is that your wife?
- Yeah.
Better run along.
It was very nice to meet you.
"Obsessed with your body."
What does that mean?
- Give me a break.
- Give you a break?
What does this mean?
How many did you buy?
- Thanks again, Christine.
- Any time.
Goodnight.
Aren't you forgetting something?
Quincy, let's hit it, pal.
You're such a good boy, yes.
You did such good business.
You did good business.
You're the best boy.
Goodnight.
It's just for tonight, honey.
When you see the house,
don't show any interest.
- Otherwise we can't negotiate.
- Stop worrying.
- Ellen, are you chewing gum?
- Why worry? We can't afford it.
Just up the road from Mom and Dad.
- Another reason not to buy it.
- I didn't hear that.
We can't afford the goddamn thing.
Come on. Hold on, honey.
Let's not worry about it.
I haven't seen the damn place yet.
I may not even like it.
Ellen? The gum? Thank you.
Come on, Quincy.
Quincy's got to stay with Daddy.
Daddy's gonna be all alone.
Sorry, Quincy.
Don't forget to walk him.
- I promise.
- I hope you have a good meeting.
- OK. See you tomorrow night.
- Love you.
The third time up,
he looked like a jellyfish.
- Hi, Bob.
- Sorry to ruin your weekend.
- Give my apologies to your wife.
- David.
Help yourself.
- How are you feeling?
- Don't ask. Henry's away.
I asked Alex Forrest to stand in.
Anybody know where she is?
She's on her way.
Since we've got some time, tell us
what happened to your neck, Bob.
That's cute. Very cute.
- Sorry I'm late.
- Dan, this is Alex Forrest.
- We've met before. Hi.
- Hello.
- OK. Can we get started, Dan?
- Here's the story.
You want to publish a novel
about a Senator from New Jersey
who's fooling around.
A Congressman from Ohio claims
the character's based upon him.
He's filed an injunction.
The Congressman's bald. This guy's
not and he's from a different state.
- Without those books we're screwed.
- Fine.
But to prove that
it's not based on this Congressman,
I have to know the truth.
Now, strictly between
these walls, all right?
Did the author have an affair
with Mr Ohio or not?
Yeah, she did.
But she had a lot of affairs
with other politicians.
Any one of them
could make the same claim.
She swears this character's
fictitious. I just phoned her.
And you believe her?
Yeah, I believe her.
Now that's on the table, what can
we do to lift that injunction?
Can we get to the Congressman?
They take campaign contributions.
Can we buy or frighten them off?
Is there something in his past?
We need to use some leverage.
Give me a break, will you?
Come on.
Come on!
- Was it made in Taiwan?
- Yeah. These are tough to find.
Wait, wait. Here. We got one.
Come on!
Want to go get a drink
until it stops?
Yeah, I'd love it.
Come on.
The strangest case I ever handled?
The truth was,
I never actually handled the case.
But the strangest case
I ever came near to
was when my parents got divorced.
My mother asked me to represent her.
- You're kidding?
- That's what I said.
She said,
"You know what an asshole he is."
"You've been a witness
to this marriage for 29 years."
- This is coming from my mother.
- How did you get out of it?
Well, you can't
turn your mom down.
So, I escaped on a technicality.
- Which was what?
- I didn't practise family law.
It was true, you know.
And she bought it.
- You're making it up.
- Could I make that up?
Waiter?
- I've got a lot of pull here.
- I noticed.
They know me well. Miss?
- Coffee?
- I'd love one.
Two coffees, please.
Well, I tell you...
- Do you want one?
- No, thank you.
It's funny being a lawyer.
It's like being a doctor.
Everybody's telling you
their innermost secrets.
- You must have to be discreet.
- God, yeah.
Are you?
Am I what?
Discreet.
Yes, I'm discreet.
Me, too.
- Can I ask you something?
- What?
Why don't you have a date?
- It's Saturday night.
- I did have a date.
I stood him up.
That was the phone call I made.
Does that make you feel good?
It doesn't make me feel bad.
So, where's your wife?
Where's my wife?
My wife is in the country with her
parents, visiting for the weekend.
You're here with a strange girl
being a naughty boy.
Having dinner with somebody
isn't a crime.
Not yet.
- Will it be?
- I don't know. What do you think?
I definitely think it's up to you.
I can't say yet.
I haven't made up my mind.
At least you're very honest.
We were attracted to each other
at the party. That was obvious.
You're on your own for the night.
That's also obvious.
We're two adults.
Let's get the check.
- That was great.
- Thank God.
Are you feeling energetic?
What do you have in mind?
I live up here.
- In this building?
- Yeah.
Well, where do I get a cab, you know?
Ever done it in an elevator?
- Not recently.
- I bet you haven't.
I'm sorry, baby. I'm sorry.
How are you?
Hi. What happened to you?
I tried you earlier.
I guess you're not back yet.
I'm gonna go to bed now,
so call me in the morning. Bye-bye.
Hello? Dan, darling,
we were expecting you.
- I'm sorry. I had work to do.
- That's OK.
- We wanted you to see that house.
- Next time.
You want to speak to Beth?
- Yes, please.
- Hold on a second.
The phone, it's Dan. Here you are.
Hello. What happened to you?
Hi.
Nothing. I just had
dinner with Bill last night.
How is he?
He's... Bill's, you know...
Bill's Bill, the same as usual.
Is he still with that girl?
Well, he wasn't last night.
I think it's over.
He wouldn't talk about it.
- Are you getting any work done?
- Yeah, I'm working.
There's spaghetti sauce
in the refrigerator.
Great. OK. How's Ellen?
She is having the best time.
I just hope that Dad survives it.
I don't know how to tell you this.
But... she wants a rabbit.
Beth, no rabbits.
Jesus Christ!
We're turning into Noah's Ark.
Please! Give her a kiss, all right?
But no promises.
- All right.
- When are you coming home?
It's complicated.
There's a problem with the house.
They sold it.
Very funny. No. We can't see it
until late this afternoon.
I'm not up to fighting the traffic.
I'll come in tomorrow.
What about school?
She's only five.
What will she miss? Trigonometry?
Yeah, OK. I'll see you
when I get home from work.
OK. See you tomorrow.
OK, thanks. Have a good time.
Yeah?
What happened? I woke up.
You weren't here. I hate that.
- You didn't get my note?
- What note?
I left you a note right by your bed.
That's nice. I thought we were going
to spend the day together.
Look, I got so much work
to do today. I can't.
Why don't you come over?
I'll cook us lunch.
The poor dog
hasn't been out of the house.
I gotta take him out.
Bring the dog. I love animals.
I'm a great cook. Come on.
Listen, I'd love to, but I can't.
Do what you have to do, then come
over afterwards. We can eat late.
Or you can work here.
I won't disturb you, I promise.
I'll be a good girl.
You don't give up, do you?
Good boy.
Quincy, no!
I got it! I got it!
Quincy, cover me. Come on. He fires.
- OK.
- She's got it. It's back.
Over the head. He's got it.
Dan, can you hear me?
My God!
- You bastard.
- Your face!
Your face!
- That was a shitty thing to do.
- Sorry. I was fooling around.
My father died of a heart attack.
I was seven. It happened
right in front of me.
Honey, I'm sorry.
I had no idea. If I had,
I never would have done that.
Wait, he didn't die? He's alive?
He's alive and well
and living in Phoenix.
I guess you certainly got me,
didn't you?
Let's hear it.
I hope you like spaghetti.
Specialty of the house.
It goes with the opera.
It smells so good.
- Anything else for me to do?
- Just make yourself at home.
- Change the tape if you want.
- No, this is great.
I love Madame Butterfly.
- Really? It's my favorite opera.
- Mine, too.
First opera I ever saw.
My father took me to the old Met.
I was five years old.
- Did it make any sense?
- I got most of it.
There was this US sailor setting up
house with this Japanese lady.
That was all fine.
But in the final act,
after he left her,
my father told me,
"She's gonna kill herself."
And I was terrified.
I was...
I climbed right underneath the chair.
It's right here.
This is it.
It's funny.
- What?
- It's one of the only times
I remember my father being nice
to me when I was a kid.
Comforting me at Madame Butterfly.
What?
What are you thinking?
I was wondering why all
the interesting guys are married.
Maybe you find them interesting
because you can't have them.
How long have you been married?
Nine years.
- Do you have any kids?
- I got a six-year-old girl.
Sounds good.
- Yeah, I'm lucky.
- So what are you doing here?
Boy, you know how to ask them.
No, I really want to know.
I had a wonderful time last night.
I'd like to see you again.
Is that so terrible?
No.
I just don't think it's possible.
It's really strange.
I feel like I know you already.
I just wanna know where I stand.
I think you're terrific.
But I'm married.
What can I say?
Just my luck.
Shit!
- What are you doing?
- I gotta go.
I thought she wasn't coming back
till tomorrow.
She's not, but I got things to do.
I gotta go home.
- I don't think I like this.
- Like what?
The way you run away
after every time we make love.
What difference does it make
when I leave? I gotta go.
- You're not gonna leave now.
- Come on. Stop it.
Come on! Alex!
What's the problem?
I'm sorry.
Jesus Christ, let's be reasonable.
Be reasonable? What?
Goodbye.
Don't call me, I'll call you.
You knew about me.
I didn't hide anything.
- I thought it was understood.
- What?
The opportunity was there,
and we took it.
- We're adults, aren't we?
- What's that supposed to mean?
I thought we'd have a good time.
You thought you'd have a good time.
You didn't stop to think about me.
That's crazy. You knew the rules.
- What rules?
- Look, Alex. I like you.
If I wasn't with somebody else,
maybe I'd be with you. But I am.
Please don't justify yourself.
It's pathetic.
If you'd tell me to fuck off,
I'd have more respect for you.
All right then, fuck off.
And you, get out!
I'm going.
Why don't you come over here
and say goodbye nicely?
Let's be friends.
Baby, no.
It's OK.
- Sorry if I upset you.
- It's OK, really.
It's OK. All right. That's OK.
Your hands are all wet.
Jesus!
Jesus Christ! Come here,
come here, come here.
Hold on. Hold on.
Nice and tight.
Hi. Did you just call me?
I was in the shower.
I heard the phone.
I thought it was you.
How are you? Did you have a good day?
Yeah, yeah.
Really? That's terrific.
That's really terrific.
You sound excited.
Yeah.
No, I'm not against the idea.
Don't get me wrong.
It's just the money.
Yeah.
OK, darling. I love you.
Bye.
How are you feeling?
OK.
I gotta go.
Will you call me sometime?
You don't have to
if you don't want to.
No, I want to.
You promise me
you'll go see the doctor?
OK.
Goodbye.
- You take care.
- You, too.
Shit.
Look what I got.
Look what I got for you here.
Spaghetti and meat sauce.
We'll make an Italian
out of you yet. Good boy.
Have a good one, yeah?
What are you doing here? It's 8 a.m.
I'm in the shitter. I'm due in court
by two and I'm behind.
Do me a favor, cancel everything.
Tell Drimmer we're fine.
- I'll be there by two.
- At two? OK.
Good morning, Martha.
- Daddy!
- Honey! I missed you.
We had a great time.
I went for a walk with Grandpa.
We saw rabbits...
Slow down.
I can't understand a word.
- I want a rabbit.
- I know you do.
- Hi, darling. How are you?
- Good.
Good.
God, I missed you.
- Liar.
- I did.
I should go away more often.
- I did this one.
- You did?
- Yes. Pick another one.
- I thought it was this one.
- No. It was this one.
- You're in a lot of trouble.
Phooey on Dewey.
- OK.
- Now, pick a card, Dad.
Any card at all?
Yes? Where'd she learn this?
Grandpa showed me.
Surprise.
So how was it?
Come on, I'm a big boy.
I can take it.
It had a place for rabbits.
No! She said it.
She said the R-word. No!
Not rabbits? Rabbits?
Rabbits!
- Rabbits!
- Not rabbits?
Rabbits!
What can I tell you?
It's absolutely perfect.
- In this row?
- No.
So, when are you gonna come up
and take a look at it?
Just for the hell of it?
How about tomorrow morning?
- Daddy, which row?
- You mean it?
If you get me back to the office
by one, yeah.
Which row, Dad?
It's in this row, sweetheart.
Dan?
Honey? Honey, come here.
I want you to see this.
Well?
It's... It's OK.
- It's fantastic!
- It's great.
Think of all the money we'll save
not living in New York.
The high school is excellent.
My own children went there.
- You see?
- It's a terrific area for kids.
I'm sure. Is it OK if I...?
Go ahead. I'll wait here.
Thank you.
We still got to decorate.
We can fix it up.
We can have painting parties.
Painting parties?
You're making me very nervous.
Now, look at this.
This is fantastic.
This would make a terrific playroom.
What are you talking about, playroom?
This is my den!
I knew you were gonna like it.
I like it.
I'll be in court. How you doing?
- Eunice, is Martha back from lunch?
- She just returned.
Hi.
Hello.
This isn't a bad time, is it?
I was in the area.
No, no.
You want to come into my office?
This is his account?
Danny, will you be
in your office later?
- Have we met somewhere?
- I don't think so.
She looked at me first.
Sit down.
- Are you OK?
- I'm fine.
I was going to call you today.
I...
This is terribly embarrassing.
I just wanted to say sorry
for what happened.
I had no right
to put you through all that.
Nothing happened, OK?
I was going through a bad time.
Everything was coming to a crisis.
But I'm fine. I'm really all right.
And thank you.
- You don't have to thank me.
- Yeah, I do.
A lot of guys
would have just run away.
I don't know what I would have done
if you hadn't been there.
Well, you look good.
As a matter of fact, you look great.
Thanks.
So that's past?
Yeah.
- May I ask you one more favor?
- What's that?
I've got two tickets to Madame
Butterfly, two weeks from Thursday.
I'd love it if you'd come with me,
kind of as a peace offering.
Well, that's very nice of you.
But I don't think it's a good idea.
No strings attached.
You don't have to explain.
I just thought I'd ask.
So...
I'll see you around sometime.
OK.
Come here.
- Take care.
- Yeah. Goodbye.
Goodbye.
All right. Come on, let's go, pal.
We're on a roll.
- Let's see that action.
- Down the middle.
I like it. Very nice.
That is no good. I'm depressed.
What about Rodgers
versus whatchamacallit?
- Winitsky.
- Right.
I got your memo. You're going
for summary judgment?
Why not?
The facts are not in dispute.
Rodgers admits reading Winitsky's
article, but did he plagiarize it?
You can't copyright an idea,
only the expression.
Rodgers didn't use
any of the words in the book.
- Let me think about it.
- OK.
You're about to become a suburbanite.
We're gonna take the plunge.
- Got a buyer for the apartment?
- No.
- Got cold sweats about your escrow?
- Yeah.
But not about
Rodgers versus Winitsky?
- No, sir.
- Good.
He's still in a meeting.
Yes, I know. I did expect him
to be through by now.
Have lunch with me on Tuesday.
That'd be great. I'll check my diary.
You are on his list of calls.
It's Alex Forrest.
Again? I thought you told her
I'd call her back.
- I did.
- Put her on hold.
Would you mind holding?
Tuesday would be great.
- I look forward to it.
- Thank you. I will, too.
Put her through.
Hello?
Look, Alex, I thought we agreed
this was not a good idea.
Why?
I thought you understood.
If I misled you in some way,
I apologise.
But it's not a good idea
if we talk to each other any more.
OK?
Goodbye.
Yeah, if she calls again,
tell her I'm not here.
Wait, let me just...
Let me just look at you.
You're so beautiful.
Just so beautiful.
- Wouldn't you know?
- I know.
Go on, open it.
I wouldn't do it to my wife.
It's OK.
- Know how many injuries happen?
- Don't terrorise them!
I'm a lawyer, I'm insured.
It's excited.
Don't forget who gave you this.
My cold sores are almost gone.
Ladies first.
I use that term advisedly.
You're the best, sweetie.
That's my wife!
A little attention, please, ladies.
Gentlemen, my wife, ball and chain.
Mother of some of my children.
Don't be too confident.
Here is to Miller, Goodman,
Hurst and Gallagher!
- And to Mrs Gallagher.
- Give me a break.
He just asked me to lunch.
You're moving to your estate.
You'll forget us plebs.
Wait a minute.
I read a self-help book.
- Published by Robbins & Hart.
- Of course. Samurai Self-Help.
In it, it tells you how deal with
the anxieties of your friends
as you move up the corporate ladder
and they stay put.
In this book, it says not to coddle
your friends' anxieties.
I'm not gonna make
any false reassurances.
I won't say you can go to the house
every weekend.
Things have changed.
This is not a classless society.
In fact, this is it. Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
- I knew he was gonna say that!
- He's running true to form.
- We gotta make a clean break.
- We gotta travel light.
- Thanks for the time you gave us.
Drink. I want you with a lampshade
on your head by ten.
Why should today be any different?
Hello? Hello?
Here's to you.
Cheers.
Hello?
Hello!
Yeah?
Yeah, Richards.
It's kinda late, isn't it?
If you won't take my calls
at the office, I have no choice.
It's two o'clock in the morning.
Can't this wait till tomorrow?
Is it awkward for you to talk?
You could say that.
I've got to see you.
I don't have the... documentation
to answer that question now.
But I'll call you from the office.
No. Meet me in front of the Robbins
& Hart building tomorrow at six.
Don't disappoint me. Be there.
OK.
This has got to stop.
You should have agreed to see me.
It's over.
There is nothing between us.
You've had your fun,
now you just want a quiet life?
Why are you doing this?
You need help.
- Don't tell me what I need.
- You need a shrink.
I'm not your enemy.
- Why are you trying to hurt me?
- I'm not. I love you.
- You what?
- I love you.
- You don't know me.
- How can you say that?
We spent a weekend together.
You spent a second night.
You must like me.
I was concerned about you.
You read too much into everything.
I have a whole relationship
with someone else.
- I am very happy.
- Whole means complete.
If your life's complete,
why were you with me?
You want to talk about
our imaginary affair?
I'm pregnant.
I saw my gynecologist on Monday.
Here's his card. You can call him.
You don't...?
Use anything? No.
I had a bad miscarriage last year.
I didn't think I could get pregnant.
How do you know it's mine?
Because I don't sleep around.
I apologise.
I'm sorry.
Don't worry.
You won't have to handle this alone.
Handle what?
The abortion. I'll take care of it.
I'll pay for it.
What makes you think
I want an abortion?
- You're not gonna have the baby?
- Why not?
There are plenty of
one-parent families.
- They don't end in divorce.
- I don't have a say in this?
I want this child.
It has nothing to do with you.
I want it whether you're
part of it or not.
Then why are you telling me?
Why not just go ahead and do it?
I was hoping that you
would want to be part of it.
This... This is totally insane.
I'm 36. It may be
my last chance to have a child.
Just think what you're saying.
Just think about it.
We are gonna live with this
for the rest of our lives.
I know that. I've thought of that.
I know how you feel.
It's a big thing.
But it doesn't have to be a problem.
Really, it doesn't.
You play fair with me,
I'll play fair with you.
"He led Agnes and Nellie
into the closet."
"Agnes, Nellie and Oink
giggled in the dark."
"Pearl listened outside the door.
'It works, ' cried Nellie."
"'Of course, ' said Oink. 'Look at
the flying dog!' yelled Agnes."
"Pearl frowned. 'Who cares about
flying dogs?' she said."
"Nobody heard her."
"'Look out for the worms!'
squealed Agnes."
"'Eek!' yelled Nellie and Agnes."
"'Look at the monster cockroach!'
yelled Oink. 'Help!'"
You know what I did?
I called the doctor.
Know what he says? "Congratulations!"
I can't even imagine
what she told him.
Anyway, that's not the end of it.
So, after I talked to the doctor,
this morning,
I broke into her apartment.
I know. Me, a lawyer,
breaking and entering.
I wanted to get a handle
on what I'm dealing with.
I wanted to find out if she was
sleeping with somebody else.
I didn't find anything.
Anyway, I didn't find anything.
I don't know anything
about family law.
You've got to help me.
What case does she really have?
Well, it ain't good.
She keeps calling the apartment.
Every time Beth answers the phone,
she hangs up.
I'm scared, Jimmy. I...
I don't want to lose my family.
The facts as alleged are horrendous.
The instrument allegedly used
was an electronic-shock device...
- Operator, may I help you?
- I'm trying to get 555-8129-212.
The recording says it's disconnected.
Just a moment, please.
It's been changed to unlisted.
It's a real emergency.
I need that number.
We can't give out that information.
- Well, fuck you!
- My place or yours?
- I like it. I like it a lot.
- We've been very happy here.
I'd definitely like
to think about it if I could.
- It's very clean.
- Yes.
We have a cleaning lady who comes
in a few times a week.
- I can give you her name as well.
- I'd love that.
There's babysitters galore.
The whole works.
Hi, darling. This is Alex.
I've forgotten your last name.
- Alex Forrest.
- This is my husband Dan.
Hi. Glad to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
- Haven't we met somewhere?
- I don't think so.
No, we have. Weren't you
at that party at the Japanese place?
Honey, the exercise book.
Yeah.
You're a lawyer.
And you work for the firm...
What's the name? Anyway...
We've definitely met.
- You have a good memory.
- I never forget a face.
- It's a small world.
- It certainly is.
I gather you're going to the country?
- Moving to the country?
- Yes.
Have you found a place?
We found a place in Bedford.
Do you know it?
- It's beautiful.
- Yes.
You'll move of here
almost immediately?
Actually, we wanted to do
some remodeling first.
I guess looking for a place
right now?
Yeah. I'd like to settle in.
Alex is expecting a baby.
That's...
Will you excuse me?
I have some work to do.
I better run, too.
Thank you for the tea
and showing me the apartment.
- You're very welcome.
- I like it. I really like it.
- We've been happy here.
- I'd like to think about it.
I'll give you our number
so you can call us direct.
Thank you.
- I'll keep in touch.
- Great.
- Bye-bye.
- Goodbye.
She seemed really interested.
She didn't mention a husband.
I get the feeling she's on her own.
- What is it? You seem down.
- No, no. I'm just tired.
- Hello?
- Hi, it's me.
Who?
You know damn well!
Come on, let me in. I want to talk.
So now you want to talk?
What can I get you?
I've got Scotch, vodka,
a nice Chablis...
Cut the shit, will you? Just cut it!
I don't know what you're up to,
but it's gonna stop right now.
No. It's going to go on,
until you face your responsibilities.
What responsibilities?
I'm pregnant.
I'm gonna have our child.
That's your choice, honey.
It has nothing to do with me.
I want to be a part of your life.
So you do it by showing up
at my apartment?
You won't answer my calls.
You changed your number.
I'm not gonna be ignored.
You don't get it.
You just don't get it.
Don't you remember our weekend?
Wasn't that wonderful?
Why can't we just be like that again?
I know you feel it, too.
What are you so afraid of?
Hey, don't flatter yourself.
Hit me. If you can't fuck me,
why don't you hit me?
You're so sad. You know that?
Lonely and very sad.
Don't you ever pity me,
you smug bastard.
I'll pity you because you're sick.
Why? Because I won't allow you
to treat me like a slut
you can bang a few times
and throw in the garbage?
I'm gonna be the mother
of your child.
I want a little respect.
You want respect?
- Respect!
- What are you doing?
Please don't go.
I didn't mean it. I'm sorry.
I'll tell your wife.
You tell my wife, I'll kill you.
It only takes a phone call!
Hello? Hello?
Got it.
Guys, that's on the second door
to the left, over here.
You could've stayed
in the apartment.
Dan was in such a hurry to get out
of New York. Momma, that's you.
Lord, put it away.
All right, easy on the door-frame.
Good. Nice. Just like that.
I got it. Sorry. I got it.
Hello?
Martha.
Martha. It's Martha.
Hello?
Hi, honey. Did the plumber come yet?
Did he ever.
I don't really want to know about it.
Hey, guess what I'm looking at.
- You got it?
- Yeah, I got it right here.
Or I should say, I got her.
What's she like?
She's cute. She looks like a rabbit.
She's white, she's got long ears,
little pink eyes.
- Soft.
- She sounds cute.
Ellen doesn't know about it?
No. She doesn't think
she's gonna get one.
See what happens
if you work here too long?
- Isn't it cute?
- Thank you.
I forgot. This arrived for you.
- Goodnight.
Hey, Joaquin!
Jesus fucking Christ!
Fucking bitch! Jesus Christ!
No. I said it was
the electrical system.
The whole goddamn thing blew up.
All right, honey.
I'll see you in a little while.
Mr Gallagher?
- You forgot your contract.
- Thanks.
Hello, Dan. Are you surprised?
This is what you've reduced me to.
I guess you thought you'd get away
with it. Well, you can't.
Because part of you is growing
inside of me, and that's a fact.
You'd better start
learning how to deal with it.
Because, you know, I feel you.
I taste you.
I think you.
I touch you.
Can you understand? Can you?
I'm just asking you to acknowledge
your responsibilities.
I mean, is that so bad?
I don't think so.
I don't think it's unreasonable.
And you know, another thing is,
that you thought that you could
just walk into my life
and turn it upside down, without
a thought for anyone but yourself.
You know what you are?
You're a cock-sucking son of a bitch.
I hate you. I bet
you don't even like girls, do you?
You flaming fucking faggot!
Daddy! Thank you.
You're welcome, honey. You like her?
You like it?
You thought you could just walk
into my life and turn it upside down
without a thought
for anyone but yourself.
You know what you are?
You're a cock-sucking son of a bitch.
You are. I bet
you don't even like girls, do you?
They probably scare you.
I know I do.
You're scared of me, aren't you?
You're fucking frightened of me.
You're afraid.
You gutless, heartless, spineless
fucking son of a bitch.
I hate you.
You deserve everything you get.
- Jesus Christ!
- Sorry.
I was wondering why you were
up so late. I'm sorry.
It's OK. I was listening
to a deposition.
I couldn't sleep.
Come on.
I'm gonna give you a back rub.
- Back rub?
- Brandy, a back rub.
- You won't know what hit you.
- Sounds good.
My client wants it stopped.
He wants an end to the harassment.
He's positive it was this woman
who trashed the car?
Yes, of course.
- Any witnesses?
- No.
He can file a complaint
if it'd make him feel better.
There's not a lot we can do
without proof.
This woman is completely irrational.
There's no telling what she could do.
We can't arrest people
for what they might do.
I'm not asking you to arrest her.
I... He simply...
He wants her warned.
We could talk to her.
It may make things public.
He's not gonna like that.
It may even aggravate the situation.
How's that?
Whatever resentment she's feeling,
she's probably got it
out of her system.
Any action we take could provoke her.
What if she
didn't get it out of her system?
Catch her in the act.
Then we can bring charges.
He just has to sit there and take it?
It's his bed. I'm afraid
he's gonna have to lie in it.
Come on, come on.
Come on, Ellen,
we're going to Grandma's.
Come on, Quincy. Come on, hurry up.
Come on, get on in. Hurry up.
Watch his tail, sweetie.
Make him sit down.
- You didn't get your car back?
- No, it's a write-off.
- The electrical system's shot.
- Extraordinary, those foreign cars.
- Here you are.
- Thank you.
- Want to try again, sweetie?
- OK.
OK.
So?
Dear Priscilla, Miles asked me
to ask you to marry him.
Very good.
Do it one more time.
Do it with your hat and do the bow,
so that when you do it,
you know what you're doing.
Let me see your bow.
And what do you say?
Dear Priscilla, Miles asked me
to ask you to marry him.
- Very good. You got that.
- Ellen.
Come here.
- That was good.
- Thank you.
That was really good.
That was so good.
- I love you.
- I love you, too.
Thank you, darling.
Come on, Quincy.
- Daddy!
- What?
Whitey's gone!
It's all right, darling.
It's going to be OK, sweetie.
You should try and get some sleep.
- Is she OK?
- She's asleep.
Did you call the police?
- Not yet, no.
- Why not?
Honey, we gotta talk.
What is it?
I know who did this.
You do? Who?
Remember the girl
who came to the apartment?
The one I met
in the Japanese restaurant?
The one with the blonde hair.
You're scaring me.
What is it?
Did you have an affair with her?
Yes.
Beth?
Beth, I am so sorry.
The last thing I ever wanted to do
was to hurt you.
Are you in love with her?
No. It was one night.
It didn't mean anything.
What has it got to do
with what's happened?
She's pregnant.
She's...
It's yours?
I don't know. That's what she says.
Listen, Beth, please.
Get off!
I want you out of this house!
How could you do that? I hate you!
- Understand what I'm saying...
- I don't want to hear it!
Please, just listen to me, will you?
What is the matter with you?
Dan, what a pleasant surprise.
It's over. It's finished.
I told Beth. She knows all about it.
Sure. You haven't got the balls.
Why don't you speak to her?
Why would I want to talk to her?
This is Beth Gallagher.
If you come near my family again,
I'll kill you, you understand?
That's the last one, Ellen.
I mean it.
Hello? Hi, Daddy.
When are you coming home?
Honey, I don't know.
How are you doing?
Good.
Grandpa taught me a new card trick.
Did he? The one with the jacks.
No, the one with the kings.
Good.
I won't.
How's Mommy?
Send her my love.
OK. Goodbye.
Daddy?
Call me tomorrow.
I will. I promise.
You be sure you tell Mommy I called.
I will.
Love you a lot, too. Bye-bye.
Bye-bye.
Mrs Gallagher,
did you forget something?
- I came to get Ellen.
- I thought you'd picked her up.
I'm sure she's left already.
Betty? Is Ellen in here with you?
- She's gone home.
- Sure?
Positive. She's not inside
or in the playground.
- I thought you picked her up.
- Who did pick her up?
She can't have gone far.
- You don't understand.
- I'll check her locker.
- Alicia, where's Ellen?
- She's gone.
Call the police.
Ellen.
Please let her be all right!
Christ.
Where are you?
Look out!
- Bye-bye, Ellen.
- Bye.
Ellen, can I have a kiss?
Bye.
I'm looking for a patient
named Gallagher. I'm her husband.
Room 22 at the end of the corridor.
- Is she gonna be OK?
- Yeah, she'll be fine.
She was very lucky.
It might have been a lot worse.
- Daddy!
- Hi, babes. God, I missed you.
I missed you, honey.
Are you OK?
Have you seen Mommy yet?
Yeah.
Now, you stay here with Granny.
I'll go and see Mommy.
Howard.
You're gonna be OK.
- Want to go to Ziggy's first?
- Hot places.
I tried to explain the situation,
but you wouldn't listen.
The woman took my kid.
That's kidnapping. Am I right?
My wife could've been killed.
If you won't do anything...
Take it easy.
You don't have to shout.
OK.
What are you gonna do?
We'll tell New York to pick her up
and bring her in for questioning.
OK.
OK. I'm gonna go
to the hospital tomorrow
to pick my wife up.
Hopefully, I'll be home
for the weekend
if you need to talk to me.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
You're welcome.
How's that feel? You warm? Good.
Are you all cosy?
Is Mommy gonna be all right?
Mommy's gonna be fine, honey.
She's gonna be fine.
Are you going to stay with us?
I'm gonna stay with you.
Now, go to sleep, OK?
Goodnight, doll.
Forever?
I promise, honey.
You mean the detectives in Manhattan
have no idea where she's gone?
They don't know where she is?
Yeah.
No, I see.
If you get any more information,
you'll let me know, Lieutenant?
Thank you very much.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
How does the arm feel?
It hurts.
Can I get you some more painkillers?
OK.
Welcome back.
Our contestants have to decide...
Thank you.
Holler if you need anything else.
I'd love a cup of tea.
You got it.
What are you doing here?
Why are you here?
He tried... to say goodbye to me
last night.
But he couldn't,
because he and I feel the same way
about each other.
Do you know how it is when you meet
somebody for the first time...
...and you get
this instant attraction?
I understand what you're doing.
You're trying to move him
into the country.
And you're keeping him away from me.
And you're playing happy family.
But you... wouldn't understand that,
because you're so selfish.
He told me about you.
He was very honest.
If you weren't so stupid,
you'd know that.
But you're a stupid, selfish bitch!
You're a stupid, selfish bitch!
Dan!