Previously on this is us...
I love our life.
I love it right now.
And I'm so scared
of changing it.
I'm not gonna stand for
anything changing between us.
(Crying): I don't want
to be different from them.
Different from who?
Who, the kids at school?
If I get an "a,"
I'll get ice cream,
and Kate and Kevin won't,
and then they'll hate me.
Kate: I can't fall
for a fat person right now.
I guess I'll lose
the weight then.
What did I do to deserve this?
You've done a lot of
really nice things for me,
so I wanted to return the favor.
By cutting up cardboard
into little squares
and putting it in a bowl?
Yum.
Hey, so, Kevin, uh, it's
been a few days now, you know,
since you showed up.
Without calling.
Right.
I was just sort
of wondering...
When you leaving?
Yeah.
♪ ♪
(Washing machine running)
♪ I listen to the wind ♪
♪ to the wind of my soul ♪
(machine clatters)
Rebecca: Washing machine
is officially cooked.
Jack: Ah, she's still got
some life in her, at least
six more cycles.
Rebecca:
Jack, we have three infants.
We're gonna be doing
six cycles by noon.
Jack?
Yeah.
Rebecca:
Uh, I need your help.
It's leaking everywhere.
(Kids laughing)
Jack: This is bail out!
♪ I've sat upon
the setting sun ♪
Rebecca:
Oh, my God.
This is the best washing
machine in the entire world.
I'm actually turned on
by this washing machine.
Jack:
I'm gonna show you turned on.
(Rebecca chuckling)
Oh, you are?
I am.
♪ No, never, never, never ♪
Jack: Big three!
Kids: Big three!
Rebecca: I just want to do
a small kitchen remodel.
Just some new cabinets,
maybe some new countertops.
Young Kevin:
Give me those, Randall,
they're my bouncy balls.
Young Randall:
But mom gave them to me.
Young Kevin: (Chuckles)
You said "butt."
Young Randall: (Chuckles)
You said "balls."
♪ Take me where my heart
wants to go. ♪
what the hell, Kevin?
Turn the lights out,
man, it's 2:00 A.M.
Damn it, Kevin, you ruined it.
It's all ruined.
Hey, man, I'm...
I'm sorry, dude.
Don't.
What are you doing?
I'm trying to help you.
Look, I'm sorry I touched
your precious woobie.
That thing reeks by the way.
It's the blanket
i was left in, Kevin.
Well, it doesn't mean you
can't wash it once in awhile.
What's your problem?
What's my problem?
Yes, what's your problem?
Dude, it's 2:00 A.M.
And all the lights are still on!
Rebecca:
Hey, guys.
What in the name of God
could you possibly
be fighting about right now?
He threw a football at my face.
He keeps waking me up.
Shh.
And I need to get sleep because
i have a big game tomorrow.
Okay, Kevin, but Randall
has a lot of homework,
and now that he's on
the football team,
he has a lot less time do do it.
And why does he suddenly
need to be on the football team?
What do I have to do
with you guys?
Do I have to make you go sleep
in separate rooms?
Yes, actually that'd be great.
No, mom...
Okay, that won't work
because the only empty room
in the house
is the basement.
I want it.
Kevin...
(Sighs)
K... would you relax?
Hey. Dude, come on.
You don't have to
go into the basement.
I'll turn off my light,
and I'll do my homework
in the kitchen.
That's a very nice offer.
Kevin, do you hear what
your brother's saying?
Yeah, I heard him.
♪ ♪
hi, Kevin!
Ashley.
That baby teething?
You know it.
All right.
Ni hao, Mr. hwa.
Keep working on that core.
Hey.
What's up?
Uh.
Morning, gentlemen.
Kevin: Hey.
Randall:
Good morning.
Look at this,
i got six Miles.
Good for you, buddy.
Yup.
I did eight.
(Kevin chuckles)
Is William still asleep?
Yeah.
I feel like yesterday's chemo
took a lot out of him.
Mm. Morning hugs!
Give me my morning hug.
No, gross!
Daddy, you're all sweaty.
Beth:
All right, come on girls,
backpacks, lunches, car.
Let's go. I'll be right out.
Randall:
Have a great day, beautifuls.
Daddy loves you.
Bye, dad, love you.
Bye, kiddos.
Hey, Kevin.
Hmm?
Did you see a yellow legal pad
in my office?
You mean my bedroom?
Do I though?
All right, I am
gonna grab a shower.
Meet you at the office
before dinner.
Yeah.
Look, he and I are
having dinner tonight,
so you have
a Kevin-free evening.
Just the two of you?
Mm-hmm.
Alone?
No, we're meeting our mother.
(Chuckling):
Oh, okay.
Why?
No, I just couldn't imagine
you and Kevin hanging out.
What do you... well, the guy
lives in our house, Beth,
we hang out all the time.
Yeah, but you guys are never
in the same room alone together.
Uh, we just went for
a run together.
(Ice clatters)
Together?
Really?
So, what this
mean, "really?"
(Chuckles)
It didn't end well
for Cain and Abel, baby,
that's all I'm saying.
Well, we're not Cain and Abel.
Hmm.
Well, they were
much less repressed.
But if we were Cain and
Abel I'd be Cain, right?
'Cause he's the
brother who won?
All right.
I love you.
(Sniffs, clears throat)
Love you.
(Phone chimes)
Automated voice:
That was your fastest run yet.
Damn right it was.
Damn right.
♪ Ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh ♪
♪ ooh ♪
(machine beeps)
♪ woke up past 8:00 today ♪
♪ my neighbor paid my meter ♪
♪ oh ♪
♪ my boss gave me a raise,
didn't even say the reason ♪
♪ oh ♪
♪ there's kindness in the air ♪
♪ that takes me where
I'm going ♪
♪ oh ♪
♪ I think I'm happy
and I know it ♪
♪ know it, ha ♪
(Beeps)
♪ Don't know why ♪
♪ but it keeps getting better ♪
♪ 'cause it's
the best day ever ♪
♪ the best day ♪
♪ ooh ♪
♪ the best day ever. ♪
Kate: I should pee.
Toby:
You just peed.
Every ounce counts.
That's true.
And I'm crushing
this weigh-in.
Get it!
All right, Kate,
are you ready?
I am.
All right.
Let's do this.
Oh, will you hold this
for me?
Yeah.
(Scale beeping)
All right.
Congratulations, lady.
You are down a pound
and a quarter.
A pound?
Yeah, and a...
And a quarter.
Okay, I kill myself for weeks,
and I'm down a pound?
And a quarter.
Right. Yeah.
It's working,
all right?
You got to keep
going, though.
This is the tough part,
but you got this.
Yeah.
Good job.
Down. Down
is great.
Thanks.
Nice work,
nice work.
All right.
All right, Toby,
you ready?
Yup.
All right.
(Scale beeping)
Okay.
Oh, wow.
You lost eight
more pounds, mister.
Yeah.
All right.
You know
what that means?
Hey, guys, guess
who just met their month goal?
This guy!
(Laughs)
Nice. Hey, yeah, Toby, do you
mind if we take a victory pic?
Oh, no, no,
that's not necessary.
No, of course it is.
No, it's no biggie.
You hit your goal.
It's no biggie.
No. You are no
biggie... anymore.
Yeah.
I'm proud of you, Toby.
Go, give 'em what they want.
Okay, all right.
Uh, I'll do the...
I'll do the victory photo.
Woman:
Yes, let's do it.
All right, we're doing it.
Woman:
All right, guys,
let's get in here.
Toby: Victory photo.
Woman:
Come on, circle it up.
All right, one, two, three.
Toby: Ah!
All: Cheese!
Toby:
Cheese!
Woman:
Super cute.
Another one. Smile!
Yes! Beautiful!
♪ ♪
Randall: I want to make a big
push on rising temp futures.
Some of our clients don't
currently believe in science,
but we'll have 'em watch
an Al Gore documentary once
the cash starts rolling in.
Am I right, people?
Come on, guys, nothing?
That was...
Is that the Manny?
Yup. That's the Manny.
I'm early!
Right.
I'll be right there.
(Clears his throat)
You guys look sharp.
(Woman laughs)
I'll meet you in the...
Meet you in the office.
Okay.
Cool.
Just chill out
in your office?
Yeah.
That is the Manny.
It is. (Laughing)
♪ Straighten up and fly right ♪
♪ straighten up
and stay right ♪
♪ straighten up and fly right ♪
♪ cool down, papa,
don't you blow your top. ♪
sounds good.
Really?
Yeah.
I don't remember the last time
i was this nervous.
Oh, it's just rehearsal, right?
Yeah, but it's my first
rehearsal in ten years.
You're gonna do great, babe.
(Clears throat)
Hey, uh,
what are you planning on wearing
to the boy's game tonight?
Because I know we usually wear
Kevin's colors, but now
that Randall's playing
for another school...
The game. Crap.
Um, I'm meeting
Bob Parrish tonight
to close the doylestown deal.
Doylestown?
Yeah.
Really? So you got it?
I-i told you last week.
Well, I'm sure I would have
remembered if you said that.
Oh, I know that I did.
Okay, well,
is there any way
that you can move the meeting
because that coach
is coming to scout Kevin?
It's a really
big game for him.
It's a big day for me, too,
and a big day for you.
And a big day for Kevin, so...
(Sighs)
I'll see what I can do.
Okay.
Jack?
Yeah.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm all over the place.
Have a good day.
Have fun.
Thanks.
Yeah.
Randall:
No, of course.
Hey.
I totally understand.
We can do dinner another time.
That was mom?
She's not coming?
What'd she say?
Yeah. Well,
tell Miguel I hope
he feels better soon.
Let me talk to her.
Is Miguel sick?
Let me just talk
to her real quick.
Just give me the phone.
Yeah, I'll tell Kevin.
Just put her on speaker.
We can reschedule.
Just let me talk
to her before you go.
Love you, too. Bye.
Before she...
Let me talk to her for...
Oh. It's Miguel's gout.
Really? I didn't know
they made gout anymore.
Yeah.
So she's not
coming then?
No.
Not coming.
Oh, okay.
(Exhales)
It's the two of us.
Yes.
Yeah. I mean, if you got work
to do though, I...
We don't have to go.
No!
I'm, I'm okay.
You're all right?
Yeah. Uh, if you've
got lines to learn
or something, then we can...
I'm good. I'm up
to speed, so...
You and me.
You and I.
Beth: Hey, girls,
wash up and come down.
So, Kevin and Randall
are out tonight.
It'll just be you and us ladies.
Nothing for me, thanks.
(Coughs)
You know, my dad had cancer.
Lung.
I didn't want to say anything
'cause, you know,
it wasn't exactly
a happy ending for him.
Endings rarely are.
Weed helped.
With the appetite,
you know? But...
I just figured
with your history,
I didn't want to bring
that up because of...
No...
marijuana doesn't have
the same kind of trigger.
Even my doctor said.
Hmm.
Can't have you going out
in the night
scoring drugs on my account.
What... what if I was to tell
you I had a little stash?
Then I'd say, woman,
you surprise me.
And I'm not easily surprised.
How about I feed
the girls, right?
Get their asses in bed,
and bake us up some
special brownies.
I like that plan.
You like that?
(Chuckles)
Yeah.
Right.
Hey! How are you?
(Shouting): What do you think?
This place is great, right?
Yeah.
Yeah. The last time I was here,
i bro'ed out with Mario Lopez.
I don't know who that is.
Oh, okay.
(Laughs)
Oh, my God. We love you.
Yeah? All right, well, cool.
Let's, uh... do a selfie.
Give it to me, I'll take it.
No, no, it's a selfie.
It's a thing.
Right. Got it.
(Indistinct chatter)
Kevin: That's gonna
turn out great.
Thank you.
(Giggles)
I'm suddenly getting
why we came here.
What'd you say?
I said I'm su...
It's a great place!
Yeah!
You're... oh, you
got to walk around.
Yeah, yeah!
Big table.
He's never been here.
There he is!
Hey!
Hey, everybody.
Hey, guys.
All right.
So, he's got a piece
of egg salad sandwich
dangling from his moustache,
riding me about how
I don't take my job seriously.
Yeah.
Eventually, I just had to walk
out while he was talking.
Jack.
I forgot to kiss Rebecca
good-bye this morning.
(Chuckling):
Oh...
First time in 15 years.
Knock, knock.
Hey, Heather.
Sabatino's?
(Sighs)
Best in the city.
Please, I can make
a better meatball sub
than that, blindfolded.
Is that an offer?
Oh...
I need you to
sign off on these.
Okay.
Do you have a...
Here you go.
Thanks. Thanks, Jack.
Here...
Mm-hmm.
There you go.
And...
You missed one.
What would I do
without you?
Miguel:
There you go.
Thank you.
Okay.
What?
I was playing...
Are you...
So...
Took your pen.
Oh.
Thanks.
Your wife should've got that.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
Just...
♪ ♪
hi. I'm so sorry I'm late.
(Chuckling):
Hey, no,
you're not late.
(Groans)
Wow.
(Laughter)
Geez.
Oh...
Oh, my goodness!
Oh, my God.
It's been too long.
Guys, this is...
Rebecca Malone.
Um... it's Pearson now.
Oh. Right.
(Snaps fingers)
But, hi, hi, Rebecca.
Hi, nice to meet you. Hi.
Thank you so much for thinking
of me for this. It really...
It means a lot.
Are you kidding?
Our manager decided we
needed a female vocalist
and I told him it's...
It's got to be the girl
I used to play the keys for.
Well, I guess
you forgot this girl
you used to play keys for
got old.
Not from where I'm standing.
Really?
Yeah. Yeah.
Hey, what do you...
You want to jump in?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm ready. Okay.
One, two,
one, two, three.
(Band begins playing)
♪ A buzzard took a monkey
for a ride in the air ♪
♪ monkey thought that everything
was on the square ♪
♪ the buzzard tried to throw
the monkey off his back ♪
♪ the monkey grabbed his neck
and said, now, listen, Jack ♪
♪ straighten up and fly right ♪
♪ straighten up
and stay right... ♪
hey, you've reached Toby,
i can't take your call right now
'cause I'm out saving
the world from evil,
or it's Tuesday,
and I'm bowling.
Toby out.
(Beeps)
Hey, it's me.
Again.
I just...
Wanted to apologize for ducking
out of the meeting. Again.
Well, not like I've ducked out
of previous meetings, I'm...
Please call me.
(Knocking)
Hi.
Uh, hi.
Wow, uh, this is...
Not expected.
I know you're mad at me,
and I get it. I should have
handled myself better.
No, no, no.
No, it's fine,
it's fine. I literally
just saw that you called.
I've just, I've...
I've been busy,
is all.
Okay.
Good.
Yeah.
♪ ♪
can I come in?
Uh... uh, yep.
Yeah. Come on in.
Uh... it's the maid's day off.
(Laughs)
You binged?
No! What?
This is no big deal.
I just, I hit a goal
and I celebrated
by eating some food that
i actually like the taste of.
You know, I don't...
I don't have an eating problem.
Yeah. Well,
you didn't have a problem
eating all this food.
(Laughs)
All right, that's fair.
Listen, Toby.
We can just get back
on our program,
like, right now.
Here's the thing.
Depriving myself,
uh... makes me absolutely nuts.
So, I think I'm gonna need to
loosen the reins a little bit.
What does that mean,
loosen the reins?
That means...
I'm done dieting, Kate.
But I still
support you 100%.
(Chuckling):
Um... how?
Like, we were supposed
to do this together?
Or like, I agreed
to go out with you
because you were gonna
lose the weight
for me.
And... and I did.
I lost some of the weight.
And if
I gain it back,
i will lose it again.
All right?
You are not alone in this.
When we are together,
I will eat
the way that you eat.
I swear. I swear
on this bag of cool ranch...
Which is...
Way more disgusting
than I remembered, by the way.
I just don't know how
this is gonna work.
Then I'll show you.
All right?
Tonight.
We'll go to dinner.
We will eat sensibly, hmm?
We will talk as always.
We will laugh as always,
all right? We'll still
be us, I promise.
Okay?
(Rock song playing)
Hey.
Hey, congrats.
Heard you got your own room.
Yeah.
(Chuckles)
What's up with you?
Nothing.
Randall.
Why does he hate me so much?
Kevin doesn't hate you.
You guys are just so intense
with each other, you know?
Try lightening things
up a little.
Joke around with him more.
You know mom is gonna
kill you if she sees you
putting on all
that makeup, right?
(Chuckles)
Pop-tarts and yoo-hoo.
Breakfast of champions.
What do you want?
I just came to
see your dungeon.
I mean, your digs.
I think it's cool.
Yeah... totally.
In a couple days
you won't notice
that funky mildew,
and the asbestos.
I'd give it at least a year till
it's imbedded in your lungs.
Randall, can you please
just get out of here, man?
Look, I came down here
to get away from you.
Dude, I was just joking.
Are you deaf?
I said get out.
(Exhales)
Get a life.
♪ ♪
♪ comes easy to you ♪
(sighs)
You feeling anything yet?
Mm...
(Laughs)
I...
♪ I'm walking down ♪
...was I supposed to eat
a quarter of the brownie,
or a quarter of the pan?
Yes, definitely.
(Laughs)
(Laughing): What?
What's so funny?
That's not the answer.
It's not...
You did it right.
(Laughs)
You ate it.
Shh, don't laugh so loud.
I don't want to wake
up the girls, okay?
Ah.
(Footsteps)
I knew I smelled chocolate.
Why are you guys eating brownies
in the basement?
Can I have one?
No.
These are adult brownies.
(Laughs)
These are work brownies.
(Whispers):
Shut up.
Tomorrow, I'm gonna
make you some
kid's brownies, okay?
Okay.
All right. Go ahead
back upstairs. Go to bed.
And be gentle getting back
in that bed. I don't want you
to wake up your sister, okay?
All right.
Okay. Night.
Good night.
(Laughing):
You...
Was she walking
or was she floating?
(Laughing)
(Laughter)
Oh, I feel bad they have to
crowd themselves on my account.
I know Annie must be
wanting her room back.
You're not the one who's
cramping anybody's style
in this house.
Okay.
My office used to be
my haven.
Now, it's Kevin's hamper.
(Laughs)
(Both laughing)
Yes.
I wish he would leave.
(Both laughing)
Compliments of the owner.
Thank you very much,
appreciate that.
See? Don't I get
the hookup or what?
I haven't done so
bad for myself, right?
You're the mayor
of free shrimp.
(Chuckles)
(Sighs)
All right, so,
how's the play going?
Hmm?
The play.
Mm.
It's good.
Ha! See you still
working it, Pearson.
Hey!
Donny frickin' Watson.
What's up, man,
how you doing?
I'm good,
I'm good.
Yeah?
Oh, man,
i can't stay.
I got to take my
girl to see cats.
She even played grizabella
in high school.
It's a whole
thing but...
(Chuckles)
Let's connect soon, yeah?
All right,
yeah, yeah, yeah,
I'd like that very much.
You're looking good.
Donny Watson.
How you guys know each other?
Funny.
(Chuckles)
What, are you serious?
Yeah.
He...
Played my best friend
on the Manny.
Oh!
Yeah.
Out of context...
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I must have
missed that episode.
He was a series regular,
actually, on the show.
For four years, he was
a series regular.
Have you ever seen my show?
Of course I have.
Yeah?
Yeah.
What was my, uh,
what was my character's name?
Don't tell him.
What was my character's name
on the show?
(Whispering):
Wow.
(Sighs)
(Laughs)
Okay.
Kevin.
No, no, man, it's all right.
Just finish the dinner, man.
It's all right,
it's all right,
it's all right.
Good talk.
(Toby laughs)
And so this, uh, dog
just keeps getting
reincarnated.
(Laughs)
And so,
and so, it's like he...
I think he's a schna...
Like a schnauzer, like,
poodle mix and he's
running around town
trying to solve crimes, but he
keeps getting hit by cars.
Yeah, yeah, thank you.
Thank you.
And did you see
what happened here?
You had chicken.
I had the chicken.
We are in this together.
Right?
Thank you.
Would you two like
to see our dessert tray?
Uh, no, thank you.
Walk away, fine sir.
Hey, wait.
He'll have a look.
I will?
Dude, I know you want it,
and if you don't have it here,
you're gonna go home,
you're gonna stuff your face and
you're gonna lie to me about it.
(Sighs)
You'll have a full-on
food mistress and I...
But I will never love her
(whispering):
The way that I love you.
This is not a joke.
I'm being serious.
Okay, all right, okay,
okay.
How are we gonna make
this relationship work
if we're gonna keep things
from each other?
I'll just have to handle it.
All right.
Okay.
(Announcer speaks indistinctly
over speakers)
Hold both at
the same time.
You made it.
Hi.
(Sighs)
What's with, uh,
all the beige?
(Chuckles)
I'm trying
to remain neutral.
Yeah? Okay.
Yeah.
(Chuckles)
Wait, where's Kevin?
Uh...
Oh, there he is.
Twelve.
Down, set, hut.
Thank you.
Announcer:
We'd like to welcome tonight's
visiting team, hanes academy.
Now, let's go,
McKinley wildcats.
Rehearsal?
Rehearsal was good?
Oh, Jack, honestly,
it was amazing.
Yeah?
Yeah, just being on stage again,
and singing and I missed it.
Yeah.
The smell of the
microphone alone was...
The microphone
has a smell?
Hey, Jack!
Hey.
Big game
for Kevin, huh?
Yeah, and with your Bobby
opening up holes
in the backfield,
Kevin's not gonna have
to do a whole lot.
Announcer:
All right, folks, McKinley
middle school has possession
with visiting hanes academy
on defense.
You can finish telling
me the rest later.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
♪ Won't you please talk to me? ♪
man:
No, no, send him
down there.
♪ If you'd just ♪
♪ talk to me... ♪
set... hut!
♪ Come on, come talk to me ♪
(whistle blows)
Man: Go! Go, go, go!
♪ Can imagine the moment ♪
♪ breaking out
through the silence ♪
♪ all the things
that we both might say ♪
♪ and the heart,
it will not be denied ♪
blue 42!
Blue 42!
♪ Till we're both
on the same damn side ♪
get down, set!
♪ All the barriers ♪
hut!
♪ Blown away... ♪
go, go, go, go!
Rebecca:
Go, go, go, go, go!
♪ Talk to me ♪
♪ won't you please... ♪
(whistle blows)
♪ Come talk to me... ♪
what are they doing?
(Crowd groaning, shouting)
Man:
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
All right,
all right.
Hey!
Boys!
(Whistle blowing)
♪ Come talk to me... ♪
hey. Hey, come on, kev.
Would you stop?
No, it's all right, Randall. I'm
just gonna go back to my hotel.
Leave me alone, all right?
Look, hey, I'll give you
a thousand dollars right now
if you can tell me
what I do for a living.
Uh, you're a wall
street guy, right?
Yeah.
Okay, but what
does that mean?
Uh, you know, you do the-the...
The... like, the big short.
You do the ponzu schemes.
Oh, dude, it's ponzu sauce,
Ponzi schemes.
Whatever.
Look, the point is, you don't
know what I do, and that's fine.
What difference does it make
if I didn't watch the Manny?
You hated the show! You were
so ashamed of it, you quit.
Not at first. At first, I was
proud of that show, Randall.
And I invited every single
one of you to tapings.
Kate's the only one that came.
Well, she had to.
You were paying her.
Come on, dude. That was funny.
What are you...?
(Randall laughs)
Now that...
That is funny.
That's great.
Replaced by another
black man.
What the hell
did you just say?
No. "Replaced
by another black man."
Hey, you tell me
what that means.
Don't worry about it, Randall.
No. Please, Kevin.
Let's hear it, right?
What are you harboring?
'Cause God knows
I would really love
to hear this.
You always got
special treatment.
Because I'm black?
No, because you're black
and you're adopted.
Oh, yeah, hit the jackpot
with that combination.
Couldn't have had it any easier.
In our house, you did.
With our mother, you did.
Oh, right.
Okay, here we go.
Why can't you just
admit it, man?
Admit what?
Just admit that you were
more important to her, and that
she wanted to make sure that you
felt special every single minute
of every single day so that
yeah.
You wouldn't feel
like the odd man out.
Well, gee, Kevin, I wonder why
she was worried
about me feeling that way?
What the hell does that mean?
Just go back
to your hotel.
No. No, hold on.
Randall, hold... no.
What does that mean?
It means you treated me
like a dog.
And just like a dog, I kept
coming back again and again,
just hoping
for a scrap from you,
like a crumb of affection
or kindness or respect.
Respect? You
wanted my respect?
Yeah.
Yeah, okay. No, you wanted
to show me up, Randall.
Which is what you did
every single chance you got.
No, I did not.
You showed me up!
I'm done with this conversation.
Done with this conversation?
In any other family,
I would have
been the star!
Yeah, you know what, bro?
You're no star. That is a star.
Get your hands off me.
You don't push my body.
Don't touch me, okay?
Don't touch me.
What is wrong with you?
Oh, my God.
Don't put your
hands on my body.
(Indistinct grunting
and mumbling)
(Groaning)
Is that...
Is that the Manny?
Ow! My face...
Kevin? Hey, Kevin?
You're all right, man?
Hey, Seth.
Do you... want me
to call someone?
Oh. Oh, it's, uh...
(Camera shutter clicks)
No.
This is my brother.
Oh. Hey, man.
Hey, Seth meyers.
Okay.
Yeah.
(Distant siren wailing)
No. You know what? Let's go.
Yeah.
I'm still black.
Come on, let's go.
Yup, yup.
(Grunts)
Let's get the
hell out of here.
I'm sorry I couldn't help more
with moving the heavy stuff.
That's okay.
Did you know I grew up
in a house with 14 people in it?
Hmm.
My parents, four siblings,
aunts, cousins,
three bedrooms.
How many bathrooms?
One.
Oh, my gosh,
when I was young, all I did
was dream of living alone.
Like some hippie life,
you know?
(Chuckles)
Like in some artist
loft downtown.
No husband.
Definitely no kids.
So what happened?
I met your damn son.
(Laughs)
One look in his eyes,
he ruined everything.
(Laughs)
Me, I pretty much
always lived alone.
Hmm.
Now I have Randall.
And you.
And the girls
to fall asleep to,
wake up to every day.
I hope that's a good thing.
Mostly.
Makes me feel sad to die.
I love it when there's
a new moon like this.
"Splendid against the
night, the searchlights...
Both:
...The tracers' arcs,
and the red flare of bombs."
How do you know that?
It's in this book of poems
that Randall's had
since he was a baby.
(Chuckling):
Oh, yeah, that's right.
The one I gave Rebecca
back in the day.
Oh.
What?
What'd you say?
I'm feeling a little tired,
Beth, I think I'll...
Oh,
hell no, you ain't
cancering your way
out of this one, old man.
(William stammering)
You better talk.
(Warning beeps)
(Door chimes)
(Alarm chirps)
(Plastic bag rustling)
(Rustling continues)
(Sighs)
Get your asses in the car.
We're gonna talk big-time
at home.
(Engine starts)
You're right.
Mom did favor me.
She did.
Showered me
with attention.
Took my side more
often than not.
And I ate every bit
of her love up.
Ate it up like pac-man.
(Laughs softly)
You know why?
Because the one person
i wanted it from the mo...
You know, back there
with those people,
it's the first time in 36 years
you've said the words,
"he's my brother."
Come on, Randall,
that can't be...
Claiming me.
My brother.
Well, then, that really sucks.
Rebecca has known who you were
for Randall's entire life?
Yes, that's right.
And she never told him?
I don't know, Beth.
Lied to him,
when he asked. Huh.
I got to tell him.
No. No, no, no, no.
Beth, you can't do that.
Oh, "Beth you can't do that"?
This is my husband.
This is my marriage.
I know, but the closeness
he has with his mom,
you tell him this,
it'll destroy it.
(Door closes)
Whoa, someone's high.
Good night.
Night.
Uh...
You and my wife
got high together?
That's pretty cool.
(Chuckles)
Good for you.
All right, I'm gonna
head up to bed.
Not that way;
She moved you.
What do you mean, she moved me?
She moved me where?
(Sighs)
(Laughs)
Oh, back in
the basement.
No, we'll move
you back upstairs.
No, come-- hey, listen.
I should be getting out of
your hair soon anyway.
You know, until then, this is
actually a pretty sweet set-up.
There's no bathroom down here.
I can walk a flight of stairs.
(Sighs)
Well, uh... (Clicks tongue)
It's been a day.
Yeah.
Night.
Hey, uh, Randall.
Hmm?
Uh, do you want to...
Do you want to hang out down
here for little bit with me?
We could, uh, turn the
TV on or something.
For a little while.
Yeah?
Why not?
Cool.
Yeah.
Uh, Rebecca, this is Beth.
Yeah, um, so William just told
me something really interesting
about the two of you.
So, yeah, I'm gonna need you
to call me back, okay?
Right away.
As soon as you get this message.
Okay, bye.
Kevin (On the TV): ♪ Manny's
gonna buy you a mockingbird. ♪
(Laughs)
You hate me, don't you?
(Tv audience laughter)
(Randall laughs)
I told you to heat the bottle,
not hit the bottle.
(TV audience laughter)
You want me to open up
that big bottle of wine
you've been saving
for ten years.
Manny say, "what?!"
(Audience laughter)
♪ ♪
hey, you never
finished telling me
about your rehearsal.
It's okay; I'm tired.
We can talk about it tomorrow.
Okay.
Hey, can you turn
the light out, babe?
I just realized we didn't
eat dinner tonight, Jack.
(Sighs)
I had a pretty big lunch;
I'm good.
Well, I'm gonna go make
myself something then.
The light, babe.
♪ ♪
♪ I listen to the wind ♪
♪ to the wind of my soul ♪
♪ where I'll end up ♪
♪ well, I think only God
really knows ♪
Kevin:
Mom!
♪ I've sat upon
the setting sun ♪
what?
I can't turn
the washing machine off.
I think it's possessed.
Kev, you know you can always
go back to your old room
with Randall.
♪ But never, never, never ♪
♪ I listen to my words ♪
♪ but they fall far below ♪
♪ I let my music take me ♪
♪ where my heart wants to go ♪
oh, my God.
(Laughing):
This is the best
washing machine
in the whole world.
Mm-hmm.
I'm actually,
I'm turned on by
this washing machine.
Well, I can show you turned on.
(Shrieks and laughs)
(Calling):
Jack, help.
It's leaking everywhere!
(Kids exclaiming)
Kids, get the buckets.
Okay.
(Kids screaming and squealing)
This is bail out!
(Kids yelling)
Jack:
Okay, kids.
Oh!
Washing machine
is officially
cooked, baby.
Nah, she's still
got some life in her.
At least six
more cycles.
Jack, we have
three infants.
We're going to be
doing six cycles by noon.
We can do it. You
wash and I'll fold.
♪ I let my music take me ♪
♪ where my heart wants to go ♪
♪ I swam upon the devil's lake ♪
baby, one day,
I'm gonna buy you
the best washing
machine in the world.
(Chuckles)
♪ I'll never make
the same mistake ♪
♪ I'll never, never, never. ♪
captioned by
media access group at wgbh