The lost City 2022
Subtransl.ed balloumowgly
you are amazing
I want you to guide my heart
I felt that too
Thank you for your courage, Dash.
And on your intelligence,
which is similar to the intelligence of mathematicians
It's not
about my Ph.D. It's about my gender studies
And all about you,
Dr. Lovemore.
The truth is, I never expected
to find the lost city of D
If I were you, I would
choose my words carefully because they are the last
You brought me straight
to King Claman's tomb and his queen's legendary fire crown
Now I
will be very rich while you two will die
What is this... are these your snakes?
No, they were here from the start
There are hundreds of snakes in this
temple waiting for our presence
Who feeds them?  Do you feed them?
No, I don't even know what they eat
Why isn't this snake biting him?
Is he trained not to sting criminals?
...In fact
I mean, the number of snakes in the temple...
is exaggerated, I'll delete this part
I think my character in the novel is good
I will delete this part
You
started writing the story, Loretta, right?
I will delete this part
Hi, I'm Beth, I don't want to get into
a fight and I'm going to post your card
But I look
forward to seeing the final chapter of the novel
I don't want to put you under pressure, but you
know there's some kind of pressure that motivates you and doesn't paralyze you.
You have the power to
dinner date
Thank
Here I am again, everything is ready for the book tour but the
only thing missing is the book
I have a feeling you don't want to publish
the book, you don't want to leave the house
Look, I know the
last five years have been tough after Johnny died.
And that the easiest way is
not to get out of the bathtub drinking white wine with ice
But
girl, there is a big world waiting for you
And I can't cancel the book, so make sure you write it down,
okay? I love you, bye
We have to keep going,
let's see what's behind that door
What if there is nothing behind it?
There is only one way to find out
Lovemore realizes that the
treasure she wanted is lost forever and her adventures are over
Doesn't
sound right? - Yes, but it's over.
All right, John, here I am
"Pleasure comes after hardship"
The Lost City of D
Well honey, time for the review
Are you sure of that?
Because I feel a tingle in my pants
From the back
and from the front while I'm wearing this robe
I
feel like a snowboarder and weirdo
It's a beauty thunderbolt, I love you so much
I don't know how to go with this dress
don't touch it
I don't touch
it, but I want to control it - Stop, stop -
Set it now because you can't set it on
stage and you're great, you're great, okay
Is it necessary to wear a
bright leggings like this?
You only have to wear it for a couple of hours,
don't ruin it, do you hear me? it's rented
Everyone wears sequins these days
Why did that woman picture me?
This is Alice,
the new admin of our social media page
It will help us direct our message
to the younger generations
And by that I mean 30-year-old
women who want the look of their 20s
how are you guys?
I looked at your account this
morning and found a tweet for you
You say, "Where's
my woman? Meet me at Ballroom C at 5 p.m.
Hashtag (Shawn
Mendes) ""Hashtag (I can't wait to meet you all)
Well, we're having a good time, let's go
We wanted to remind you that you are still alive
People know I'm still alive
And to remind you that you
are the best-selling author
Only in romance novels
Yes, which brings a lot of profit
Profits
are not what I want people to know about
So you need a new description for you
Do you want a new description for me?
Listen, the only thing missing in this town is the writer herself
It lacked love and passion and lost its luster,
and this ranks fake history at its worst
Your book tour can
change all that We remind readers why they love you
Oh really? How about improving
our appearance with a little bit of the outdoors, too?
History has seen a lot of openness
Full search,
exploration and questions from the conscience
Will Lovemore and Dash find
Queen Taha's Crown of Fire?
Join them in their search
Well, listen,
I want to talk to you about something
There are a lot of people
I know
how much you hate doing these things
So I invited
Alan to do the question segment with you
What?
And the rest of the book tour
I expressed my express wish
that Dash would not show up with me, Alan would insult me
He won't insult
you. - Well, well done, thank you very much.
let me help you
It's like a body lotion,
it sparkles and spreads all over
There isn't a
single occasion he didn't take off his shirt
what a wish
He's
here, so act mature, let's go
Remember, try to be smiling
and your words are effective, away from any boredom
Yes,
let's go, let's start the event on TV
Yes, Lovemore lovers.
I am very excited to introduce you to a
world class writer. Welcome Loretta Sedge.
I can't - Are you kidding?
-
Listen, I'm on your
back, you can, go out and give people what they want
Nice to see you all, thank you
Yes like this
did you sit down  did you sit down  good
Are you ready?
And now the moment you have been waiting for, the most exciting and
influential heroine of our generation
You're Exaggerating - Cover
#20 from Angela Lovemore
(Dash McMahan)
Salute
the audience. - Already salute him.
Did you practice this?
My God, how I love the harmony between you two
And I have to say, I love your book
Thank
I'm going to burn some of the events of the novel, how did you two come to the
idea of ​​not entering the cemetery in the end?
This book is very
important to me personally
I don't know how to express my gratitude
that the extraordinary writer (Loretta) named the book after me
His name is
"The Lost City of Dash" or "The Lost City of D."
But the
word "D" is not an abbreviation of your name
Is it an abbreviation of the word
"bastard"? - No, not that either.
The name is based on the name of an ancient
tribe, which is (Dabka Disvim Mecha).
The name was too difficult for the
European colonists, so they shortened it
What an interesting piece of information
Well, we'll
answer some of the audience's questions
Actually, I'm the one who
wants to know what Loretta's most romantic moment is.
the wether is hot
My sexual desire for intelligence
...is this having to do with the sex around
No, I mean the feeling of sexual
gratification from intellect or intelligence
Me too -
Really? -
Take off your shirt, Dash.
No, no, I
won't do that today We're here for the book
Do you have any questions for Loretta?
Yes, the lady with
glasses who seems to like to read, what is your question?
Can you take off Dash's shirt?
No,
no, we won't do that today, I'm sorry.
Take off the shirt, take off the shirt
Of course, of course, yes, I will do that
really?
You don't have to?
- Yeah, people asked me for that.
Yes, yes, I will give the
people what they want Ladies and gentlemen Enjoy your time
The Lost
City of D is Dash's latest adventure.
If there's another book,
Lovemore will start getting the news of Dash's death.
Sorry, I stuck my watch in your
hair. - It's okay, it's okay.
Don't worry, take it off.
- Don't do that.
No, you're going to take my wig off
Oh my God, so sorry, so sorry
I am very sorry
What a spoiler of fun!
Don't
miss the fashion competition at 6 pm
Did you really say "if there would be another
book"? I invest everything I own in this round
I think my romantic
adventures with Dash are over
How will Dash die? A bite
from a snake? - no -
Well, one thing I have to take care of now is
that you two have an interview in 10 minutes
So, can you two act mature and go
there on your own? good? Thanks a lot
Will he die of staph infection?
So with staph
infection I knew it
Look, I get it, we can take a break from
each other, but you can't plan for my death
I don't like getting
into this, but did you know you're not the real Dash?
It's just a character I made up
(dash)
From here, Loretta.
- I want to go from here.
Don't you think Dash is so important
to people? - but for you -
No, not for me, well yes, but for
people too, what do you think of that?
Beth can find you other
writers with great ideas
Then you can go on with your
showmanship in your favorite T-shirt and I'll be free myself
And everyone will be happy, no from here
Beth says you should leave
the house because that's what will make you really happy
You have to go out into
the world and see a lot of adventures and experiences
I've seen enough I'm
already satisfied
Why lock yourself up at home when you can wrap the world around?
You can visit ancient Greece
I get why, because you're
afraid of planes - No, because ancient Greece is in the past.
Exactly like Dash.
Well, do you really know
who lives in the past? You
You're afraid that your feelings will be hurt again
so you stop living, you're like a human mummy
I do not know
Mummies are really human
Someraton Hotel
Die
I'm so sorry, sorry, I'm going to clean up
this mess, I'm not a liberal, I assure you
Do you know... Do you know if I could
order a car? thank you thank you
bring the car
Oh my God, does that make sense?
I
always ruined everything with my words
She makes me nervous because every
time I talk, she is beyond me
I didn't say anything right, do you know
she wants to end my character in the novel?
I just want these tomatoes please
You're right, no, you're
right I should apologize to her, thank you very much
Sorry
I'm Loretta Sedge, yes
Good day
I didn't order a group ride from Uber - Someone
wants to meet you, we'll take you back.
(Loretta)
Did you say
"Loretta"? - yes -
Follow this car. - No.
Please -
No, no -
I will never help other handsome
models, it won't happen again
What is happening? Was she kidnapped?
...Am I being sold? Is it done
Am I being sold to him?
No, no, stop. - Isn't
that weird? -
I'm so sorry for the place,
I just arrived and I had a hard time finding the right shape
I love cheese so much
I bought all kinds
Are you the one who sent me the
email asking for pictures of my feet?
No, I promise what
I'm going to show you now will make you very happy
But I will tell you more
about the mysterious room that you see in front of you now
My name is Abigail
Fairfax. - Abigail? -
Yeah,
it's a unisex name like Leslie and Beverly.
Yes, but are you
Abigail Fairfax, the owner of the famous media company?
Wasn't the ownership of your company bought?
Actually, that was my brother
(Leslie) we feel so proud of it
Yes, indeed,
you are still very young to have such wealth
My true passion, you know, is the
things that are hidden in the world, all that is hard to come by
Some say I like putting together things but
there's one thing I'm really obsessed with
It's the famous crown
of fire and red diamonds
Is this...
is this some kind of prank software?
So imagine my surprise when I
stumbled across your book... in the midst of all these sexual feelings
On something really cool
I understand, I understand now
Oh my
God, I really thought you two kidnapped me
I mean, this is
the kind of marketing that Beth planned, right?
This is really cool guys, this is amazing
You, with that gun and mustache,
and your majestic figure
Oh my God, oh
my God, with your GI-Joe look and your clothes
The archaeologist
in the novel was translating an extinct language
Something no one could do
In fact, no one has ever
tried to write something like this before, have they?
Except for you, right?
- Except for me -
Yes, it turns out that a young college girl
Loretta Sedge is writing her dissertation
About the language
of the extinct (Di) tribe with her future husband
And she dreams of
finding the tomb of (Calaman) and the crown of fire
I'm so sorry to know that
you stopped looking...when he died, but what I mean is
You have already started your journey
Where is my trip?
Here we are now
What is that?
I think it accurately describes the location of
Claman's tomb.
Where the invaluable crown
of the Queen (Taha) is buried
Even if these
are actually events you have to find out
The location of
a whole hidden city that no one has found before
Already found
it on an unknown island in the Atlantic Ocean
But what
I couldn't really find was Claman's tomb.
And this manuscript is the only
thing that can lead us to it
I need someone who can
decipher these codes
Of course,
you don't want the story to end like this
We've all lost our
dreams or, in my case, pandered to my little brother
But this is our chance to prove it to them
Come with me to the island and
help me translate these symbols and help me find the Crown of Fire
You can order any amount you want
I have to politely decline
Well, I can't say you
didn't disappoint me, but I understand how you feel
Will you allow us to deliver you?
No
thanks, I will order my own car and I will
I don't think you're
listening... to me, this is an emergency and we are
Police say they
have announced her disappearance in a flyer
He kidnapped her by car and 24
hours passed and they did nothing
What about the FBI and the CIA?
I'm sure Loretta is fine
In my college days, my
girlfriend (Nikki) disappeared and everyone freaked out
But she was only in her car
It is true that she
was dead but we found her, she did not disappear
What if... we might have called
a private investigator... or private security agencies or
We want a rescue - Yes, who does things like
this? -
Veterans, right?
- yes -
I think I know someone
who can help us
I did a meditation session before
And there
was a coach, you really should see this guy
He was a
former trainer in the Special Operations Force
What was his name?  Yes, Jack Trainer.
So is his name the same as his job?
This is how I write names on my phone
You see, Janice the mother,
Larry the doorknob, Stacey the butt
But
that's what this guy does, he finds
Missing people,
if we want help, he is the right person
I'm Jack
Turner - His name is actually Jack Turner.
Hi,
I'm Alan from Touch Your Inner Self.
Meditation session
(Jack Trainer)
Anyway, listen, our friend Loretta
has been kidnapped and we need help
How long has she been missing?
Maybe 2 hours ago now
who
is she? - This is Beth. I'm Beth.
Is her phone connected to wifi?
She has her phone, right?
- No, I have her phone.
She has an electronic watch, it
was the reason my wig fell out
What happened then? It's
okay, open her phone and go to the electronic clock app
Then
press the button: Find my electronic watch
...Oh my God, that's cool, and that's why we say
"Encounter difficulties by finding easy solutions"
Who said it?  Oprah or Deepak Chopra?
Laozi said it in his book Daodijing.
Oh my God, it's in the Atlantic Ocean
Is she on a plane?
- How did you know that? -
Because she can't
swim that fast
The target of the hijacker does not appear to be a ransom
My guess is it's a bloody
hunting mission, a coke-powered mission, a total mess
We have to move fast
How will we pay you?
- Cryptocurrency via the application (cash) -
If you find
it 48 hours before, you will get a free rescue
More than you can imagine
I'll need her phone.
- I'll get it for you.
Send me the location
where the plane landed and I'll meet you there
Welcome
where am I?
You're on my plane,
nice plane, aren't you?
I'm getting off your plane, untie me
It's the seat belt
Do you drug me?
Do people do such things?
So we consider it a classic method
I feel numbness all over my body
- It's going to wear off now.
Sorry about that but I can't
wait for you to change your mind, time is not on our side
As you can see, the
volcano that we are drilling into may erupt at any moment
And if that happens,
he will destroy everything in the Lost City
oh my god my legs hurt
So this is our
last chance to find the tomb and the crown
My God
Don't worry, this isn't our last landing, it's the
beginning, the greatest adventure of your life
Welcome to the lost city
Subtransl.ed balloumowgly
How did you find it?
When the volcano became active
and filled with lava, some things appeared on the surface
D city showed itself
The whole city?
- No, no, just its surface.
As soon as I heard the rumors,
I took my plane and bought the whole place
Site?
- No, the whole island -
I bought the
southern part at an affordable price, where it flows
Someone
here doesn't like romance writers
Yes, as the proverbs say
But Ravi doesn't like what's
going on, does he, Ravi?
He says we don't respect his heritage, but there
aren't many workers on the island, right, Ravi?
'Beggars have no freedom of choice'
Yes, anything you want, just order
Untie
one hand, it has to translate some things
so what?
I really want you to try to realize
the great opportunity that lies ahead
I think this text will lead us to
the exact location of the cemetery
It's an alphabet based on symbols
Like
cuneiform or hieroglyphic writing
So if you have
other documents...I can compare them to them
Yes, we found a lot of scratches
next to the waterfalls and they were nothing but pictures of women
Look, I'm like you, I wish your husband...the archaeologist
was still alive to help us, but he's dead, so...
Time to shine, Loretta,
you sexy writer
They will come looking for me
Who exactly?
Do you mean your many cats?
I don't have cats
I'm sorry to hear that
I have a hamster, provocateur.
- You have a hamster anus? -
No, there is...there
is a comma between the two words, let alone that
I'm sure your
brother didn't kidnap anyone like you did
happy to see you
Give me the phone. Right.
What?
I was thinking if I
could come with you
Why?
- for help -
I have CPR,
CrossFit and Karate skills
Well, well, listen, listen
It's my
fault, I don't mean kidnapping...etc, but I
I said bad things to
her and I want to see her to take back what I said
I told her it was a human mummy
Mummies are really human
I...
I knew it, yeah, that's right
Please
Well, I'm not responsible for
what happens to you, Alan.
well, okay
And you won't get out of the car?
- Yes.
In the car
- In the car -
All the time -
All the time? -
All the time
yes
that's cool
Oh really? Does the Special
Operations Force use cars like these?
Only a fool would choose a
horse based on its color
Right, is that a quote
from Daodijing's book?
No, it was
written on the sign there at the rental location
Thank
What?  What?
I was hoping to invite you to breakfast
but it looks like you have work to do
wait wait
I think the manuscript
refers to some burial
So the translation is "(Kalaman)
and his treasure" then the missing pieces and then the word: burial
And there's something about "tears" too
Where is that burial?
...nothing was mentioned about it, me
Miss
Sedge, I want to do better than that
So next
time don't kidnap a romance novel writer
It can't be this difficult, we are going
to build a building with an important purpose and impact for a great man
King Claman was ambitious and
powerful, he was the first to build a city in the Atlantic Ocean
He was always under the watchful eye of his subjects
He would have built a pyramid, a ziggurat,
or a tower to put the crown of fire in it
All I want is to know where it is
I don't know if you remember or
not but you asked me to translate it and I already translated it
translate it again
We'll laugh about this one day
Something is destined to happen
I have to
come with you to help you because I'm cool
But it's really great
atmosphere Nature and wireless
Yes, you are right, but it is very important
for me that she knows that I came to save her
Why?  Do you like that woman?
No, no, she just brought some snacks
and she gets pissed off when she's hungry and her blood pressure drops
And I
understand it easily because I eat 5 meals a day
Do you follow the keto diet?
Looks like you're following him
Yes, I mean you don't need it
What is the matter?
I don't want you to think
of me as a model in a novel
But you're much
more important than that, Alan, you're on guard
Well, I at least want to be the
one to get her into the car and say: Calm down, you're safe now
Of
course, hero, she'll love it so much
So will you start... will
the mission start now? good
he slept
(now what? -
It's dishonesty, Alan.
I can help, let me help you
Stay
around but don't get yourself killed
Welcome
he slept
I grabbed his head, what do you want me to do with it
now? I'll put it down
no
No no
Wonderful
Teamwork, awesome
Your effort is
great, Alan, but this guy was already unconscious
I was just getting ready
...don't do that, when I'm
Welcome
Look behind you
He regained consciousness, Trainer.
stay on the ground
You are gorgeous
Thank
where are you going?
What?
Are you Loretta Sedge?
yes
I'll get you out of here
Why are you so handsome?
My father was a meteorologist
what are you doing here?
Hey, no matter what,
I came to save you
Do you need a rescue in that area?
I think she's fine
Leave them, don't take their things
because they will chase after us
Why do you keep doing that, Alan?
You're
the one who keeps doing it, I just hit one
Seems wicked, it wasn't necessary
Sorry, I just wanted to win once
Excuse
me, can you untie me from the chair?
We don't have time - No time for that?
But you two have been gossiping now.
We have to go now
Why do explosions happen?
I'll take care of it
You're safe now?
- You're a mother.
How are you so calm?
This was... This was my sentence
there he is
What?
What is that? Is it a Reiki cure?
Are you treating me?
I think so
(Laoze) said: When the mind calms down
- the whole universe surrenders to it -
You know, I
know some good proverbs for this situation
"Ready for everything"
"Ready for anything"
Maybe you should stop looking each
other's eyes and act like I'm not here
who are
you? - Just a guy trying to do his job -
And now
my job is to get out...this beautiful lady
My God
What is happening?
I do not know what to do
I can't see, oh my god
there he is
Why are you throwing the gun at me?
- Oh really? -
Get
out of the chair. - No time for that.
Bring your legs together like a kegel exercise.
Do you know what a kegel exercise is?
What are you doing?  stop it
Oh my God,
get in the car, start the engine, come on
Put your leg in.
Which one? -
Both, come on
Move forward,
forward. - Well, well, I don't know what to do.
You are safe now
Oh my God, is this my blood?
- I don't think it's your blood.
a lot of blood
My God
Is this his brain?
- what? -
I think the remains of his brain are on my face
I'm sure his
brain is in my mouth, I can taste his thoughts
Focus on the road
He liked to train people
What are you talking
about? - He loved me -
I'll try to untie myself, I'll untie myself
watch out
...did you see
no
oh my gosh, no, no
(right Now)
Are you well?  Did anything bad happen to you?
Can you free me from the chair?
yes, ok
Don't worry,
we have the car. - Uncuff me, please.
ok i caught you
Get out of the chair,
get out of the chair - Yes, you're right, you're right -
Is this a nail file?
Just untie the rope - It works.
Maybe next time you can hold
the gun when I throw it at you
And you, when you throw a gun, you have to tell me
first, "Hold, Alan," and then you throw it at me.
The phrase "here is" is synonymous with the word: hold
No, it is not synonymous with it
Yes, synonymous with it in the
vernacular we say "Here is the jacket", we say "Here is the pen."
No,
the correct way is to say: Hold the thing
Then I'll grab whatever
you're throwing because you started the sentence with: Hold
This is another way when
you have a gun, that's all
Watch out...we have to ask.
We should call for help
and go to the airport and get out of here, and I'll drive
good
Well, ask... ask for help
where is your phone?
My God
They told me you caught her
- We killed the blond.
What do you think, Loretta?
You may have killed
one of them but her partner is still with her
He is clearly
skilled and trained at the highest level
and very dangerous
So Miss Sedge said she was leaving the party
and then got in a car and left the party
Have you tried to contact her?
- She doesn't have her phone.
So her
phone was stolen? - I didn't say that.
Where is my magnifying glass?
Listen, can you help my grandmother?
I don't want you to know what happened to Loretta, it will make her sad
What happened to Loretta?
- Nothing, Grandma. I went on a trip.
Awesome?
- Yes.
She had to get out of the house
Here's what happened,
Loretta's phone wasn't stolen, I took it
I gave it to
Alan and he gave it to Trainer, Jack Trainer.
So we found her watch
And who is Alan?
- (Dash) -
And who is it?
He's the hero of all her novels.
O provocative grandmother
Let's go to the next
room and talk about the wars you've been through
Come on, it's going to be fun,
sorry, it's going to be fun
Listen, Loretta Sedge is missing,
and when I look up the location of a watch
Her hand turns out
to be taking a plane to an island I've never heard of
This means that you
have to do something about it, and if you don't
Do something,
I'll do it, and your attitude won't be nice
I'm sure it's
out of our jurisdiction, you should use the FBI
good
And if you talk to the detective, say a
good word about me - and about me as well.
about us
What are you
doing? Are you trying to reinstall the car?
...in fact, we can
I said where is the phone?
- In the cabin, in the cabin -
My God
We don't have a phone, and the car doesn't work
Hold on - what
is this? -
jungle shoes
Not a shoe for walking in the woods
It occurred to me that your feet would
hurt because of your shoes, I couldn't
Something better than
that, Allison shoes, sorry
Well,
thanks. - And I brought the cheese.
Oh,
my God. - You should drink water.
I could only find plastic
bottles so we have to get rid of them when we're done
So
what we have to do now is find a phone
We call the authorities
and then wait here for someone to come to our rescue
We are already in the rescue
operation, no one will come but me
What? - I'm the savior -
I would have come alone
first and then (Trainer)... have mercy on his soul
So our
best option now is to get to the airport
Do you see this way?
We will take a shortcut
from this area to the bush and then to the forest
Short cut to the
bush? - yes -
Well, do you see us?
- yes -
You're not Dash and I'm not Lovemore, okay?
We're Loretta and Alan,
and the bush devours people like us
I don't want to
spoil my robe, it's a rental, so we'll stay here
We're not going to stay here without doing anything, okay?
So we'll go from the bush to
the airport and find a phone so you can eat the cake you want
And eat it too?
- If that's what you want, no problem, let's go.
It's the only thing that
can be done with a cake
I don't know what your people do with
it, but my people eat it
You can send it as a gift to someone
Even if,
eventually, they'll eat cake, everyone eats cake
What would a small person do if he fell
into it? He won't be able to eat it
My God
Why were you kidnapped? Is this some
kind of weird sex like '96th Hour'?
Oh, my God, thanks, I thought so too, but it
turns out my kidnapper was a Fairfax family.
Is it Beverly?
- No, big brother -
That moron
has a vlog for Montezuma's treasure hunt.
I saw it on
the news, he was looking for the Titanic.
Yes, he is looking for the Crown of Fire
What? Hey, you mean the
real fire crown... like the one in the remains of a city
Yes, the lost city of D
What?  Are you kidding?
This is exactly like your
novel so we are on an adventure
Realistic from
the adventures of Lovemore and Dash, right?
...how - what
is this? -
won't find it
Where will we go now?
We have to go into the water
What?
- We have to swim in the water -
No, I don't like water
We have to go
into the water I'm not asking you to live in it
My body doesn't get along with water
Does it agree with killing you?
You're okay, I caught you, I caught you
where
are you going? - I'll cross the river -
Don't stay in
the water, I researched security strategies
From the book "A Year in
the Woods" They won't be able to track us in the water
Why is the water warm?  Are you urinating?
Just swim away from the urine
I guess...
I think we ran from them, didn't we?
Yeah, it wasn't bad, yeah
...good
Don't panic
What do you mean not to
panic? - Don't panic -
No, stop saying that
There is something on your back
No, what is this?
- Stop screaming -
What is that?  Do you have one?
No, I don't - Why
don't you have one? -
Maybe
it's my non-stick cap, I don't know
Take
them off!
I can't touch blood-sucking
insects, try to take them off
Quickly
- You pick them up and take them off.
You pick them
up and take them off - Try to catch them.
Try to... I don't like it
I feel like I'm
going to lose consciousness they suck my soul
stop, stop
stop that sound
How many are they?
- Not a large number -
I feel
like they suck on me they suck on my body
oh my god oh my god
Why do you say oh my god? Is it that bad?
It can't be that bad, how many are there?
It's not great
They will suck every part of my body, help me
Please
stop talking, I need to take another look
My God, they will
suck up my body and only dry skin will be left of me
You can't
tell my dad I died this way, tell him I was
I wrestle with an anaconda, or while
I carry a sword or something similar
I feel like a jumba and
they suck every drop of me
Why are they on my ass?
It's like taking
anchovies out of my Caesar salad, it's not too bad
Why are you talking about food now?
Let's just find the queen and get out of here
I think you're
fine now I want to check you from the front
Well, I don't want to look
Is it bad?
Oh my gosh - what's up?
just talk -
I mean, when one has high expectations
and gets excited about someone
Everyone is excited -
why are you excited? -
What I mean is that
people ask, they don't know, they don't know, right?
They do not know until the moment
comes when they know, and they know something they did not know before
Are there parasites or not?
Don't worry, your brave warrior is alone now
Warriors of... What?
- are you okay -
It takes guts,
why do they like butts like this?
What are you singing?
It's a song I used to
hear when I was little
It says if you try to
take life from the island, the island will take your life
Did your
grandmother sing songs about the taking of life?
I can't even translate the song very well
What
diseases may be transmitted by parasites?
They don't eat eggs, do they?
The Queen (Taha)
"King (Kalaman) he and his treasure are buried."
Buried in a well of endless tears
What does
"buried in the well of endless tears" mean?
(Loretta)
You're going to give me a heart attack
where did you go?
What is that?
I'm not sure, maybe they meet here
Can you imagine they were here?
Exactly on our site
The stories they were telling, I'm sure
a lot of historical events happened here
Looks like
they're getting close to us. - We have to go up.
Do you see what I'm wearing?  Tight clothes with sequins
Don't worry, we'll go up, come on, let's go
I can't
do that. I'm old. - No, you're beautiful.
I didn't say I wasn't
pretty, I said I was too old to do things like this
All I do is sit and eat
when I can't think
Yes, you need better
shoes than this
You're the one who
brought me these shoes, I can't go up with them
I know you feel safe
hanging on to the past, but you can move forward, okay?
I can't, I can't
Do you smell this
scent? - what? -
There is smoke
What is the matter? Do they burn anything?
Are they hunting of some kind? what do you think?
Take a deep breath
Yes like this
Well done
That
was convenient, thank you - Yes, it was -
...I'll help you a little, one, two
What are you doing?  stop it
Don't
move. - This is my sensitive area.
Just go upstairs, head up!
You're
doing well, keep going, keep going up
Come on
"Pleasure comes after hardship"
What?
Nothing, it's like Johnny and I used
to say after we'd done something like.
The process of excavation or translation of a
manuscript, it is a Latin proverb that means: Pleasure comes after difficulties
How do you say "(Loretta) strong" in Latin?
Yes I am strong, I climbed a mountain
My
God, how I wish Beth saw us doing this
Oh,
my God, Beth - Don't worry about that.
I'm sure she sent the entire Special
Operations team to look for us
I understand you want to go to
the island authorities yourself
But don't worry,
I used her account on social media for that
She tweeted: I just
got hijacked Hashtag (FML) Hashtag (Shawn Mendes)
Are you traveling alone?
- Yes, I will travel alone.
Let's hope that works
Well, talk to me
You're going to New York,
then you'll take a plane to Guinea, then a high-altitude plane
plane what?
Small plane?
- Yes, with cramped seats.
It's
okay, I'll take it - Then you go home.
We want something
flammable, everything is wet now, what's in your bag?
a lot
what are you doing?
face masks
Yes, it is a gift basket
Did
you bring scented candles to the bush?
My mom gave me that wax it was a
weird gift from her on Mother's Day
Is your mother the one who
brings you gifts on Mother's Day?
Noir perfume
with the scent of eucalyptus and rosemary
What a good smell
well, okay
yes
Yes, I managed to start a fire
This is really amazing
Who would have imagined that?
Do you take off your shirt?
Sounds like a bad feeling, are
you okay? I mean your back
Yeah,
that's why I don't like water. - I see.
My body becomes full of pills like a child
Do you put something on it?
An ointment, for example, or something similar?
Yes,
I do, but it was in the little bottle
Was this?
Sorry, my God, I'm sorry
decent
Wait, yeah, come
here, come, sit down
here?
- yes -
good
You don't have to touch it, it's okay
I touched
your engorged vesicles, so... the parasites
good
It will be a little cold on your skin
Sorry, sorry
This is probably a very interesting
way for Dash to die in the novel
I can work on an ending like that
Oh really?
I like it
How will you write it?
good
"I feel the warmth of the fragrant fire"
strong start
"...the hands (Loughmore) have explored the"
And the familiar land
met each edge, new and exciting, round and crimson
...is this
Didn't make him alienate him?
no
Because with every crimson edge, Lovemore discovers another
letter of the language that only their bodies speak.
And what were their bodies saying?
"Take me"
How do you feel?
A wonderful feeling
Let's get back on your back.
- All right.
Yes, I also talk about my back
our supplies
Well, I'm cold I think I'll...
sleep a little
ok thanks -
are you ok? -
Yes, I'm on fire, I mean I'm fine
I didn't mean "on
fire", I meant I'm fine next to a blazing fire
good
It's up to you, but if you get cold we can
sleep here next to each other, if you want to
Clan... both of us?
It's okay
if you don't want to. - Yeah, it's all.
...OK how
Go up first and I'll follow you
No,
you go up first as you know women first
Keep your hands out all the time
That's
what I want to do, I'll keep it outside
Yes, that's it
what
should I do? - Just let's sit together -
Do we sit
together? - yes -
Looks like we're going to flip
this thing over like a sinking ship
Well, what... wait, I didn't come in
Why does this thing get into my ribs?
What would happen if... I couldn't breathe
Well, is everything all right?
- I can not breathe -
yes, ok
My hands
are out, our backs facing each other
good
cool, come on
Come on, I
want to hear the clap, let's clap for Loretta.
You
deserve it, old writer made you call
About
yourselves in the bush, well done, Loretta.
Boss, people are dying now
Don't you think we're
exaggerating what we're doing?
Is it worth it?
I'm
about to get something out of reach
A rare thing, something that no nation or
emperor could reach, not even flattering my brother would lead me to it
Legendary Fire Crown
So
yeah, I'll say it's definitely worth it
Excuse me
Excuse me, sir, my flight will resume
There is no flight,
the pilot is sick, come tomorrow
No, no, sir, I can't
come tomorrow. I want the trip today to Handeda Island.
Tonight, some
people's lives are in danger. - Come tomorrow.
Excuse
me, miss. - Yes.
I couldn't help myself from
snooping over you and overheard you talking about steak
Well, what I'm
going to say is crazy but I love steaks too
What?
I also like steaks...you might like...
I don't know, maybe
No, it's a similar word, I meant
their lives are in danger, I have to get to the island tonight
Well, I
think I can help you, I have a cargo plane
Maybe I can drop
you off to the island after the goods are delivered
I'm going to ask
you something but you have to answer me honestly
Have you ever killed someone before?
no
I don't believe you, but I will tell you something, if you think
for a moment about killing me, I promise I will kill you first.
It would
be my pleasure - You weirdo, let's go -
The treasure of King
(Kalaman) is buried in the well of endless tears
What is that?
...it's...it's...it's something
It's not what you think
Isn't this a piece of the
old Fairfax manuscript?
Well, maybe it's what you think
I thought you were smarter
than that, Loretta, Fairfax will never stop chasing us
What did you think?
There is a volcano that can bury the
cemetery before we reach it, before we see it, before we preserve its memory.
Excuse me, is that what we do?
Because nobody told me, when were you gonna tell me?
Why did I tell you that?
We're in it together
now, I came to save you
You know you're not Dash, right?
You don't ride a white horse and save people
You spray yourself bronze and stand in
front of the machines that extract the air and it's all great for you
How do
you know the truth about my personality?
I know
you well, you're an obvious person, Alan.
Well, then who am I?
I feel... well
I was a handsome boy who was
popular in college stadiums
And when you found yourself in an
unknown place with no hope of becoming a star, you came to Los Angeles.
Then one day a woman
appeared who could not publish her book on colonialism
The Spaniard in
the Atlantic decided to write a romance novel
She
randomly chose you to be the cover model
And fortunately for you and her
luck, the novel became widely known
She continued with her trivial writings,
and you continued with the photo sessions
And as you know,
none of us became what we wished to be in the end
Until one day we died in the bush
On one of the
Atlantic islands you wrote about years ago, right?
Subtransl.ed balloumowgly
It's called
Sarasota, by the way, and it's not an unknown place
Where I lived with my mother and two sisters
And yes, I started my modeling
career to get away from there
The only job I could think of was to
go to all the places I dreamed of going
Then finally to Los Angeles,
where I was modeling the cover of your romance novel
I was so embarrassed
when one of my friends saw me with a wig
on your cover
that I stopped talking to them for months
There was a woman running up to me
and she's so happy and saying "Dash"
I thought, How can I be ashamed of
something that makes people so happy?
Do whatever you want, Loretta.
But don't underestimate the
fans of your work and describe it with trivial writings
This is not fair to them
do you know? It's ironic to think
that you're the only one who wouldn't judge a book by its cover
You mean judge a book by the viewer's cover?
(right Now)
There are two of them
I'm
here, Loretta. - Alan.
Motorcycles
and pistols Motorcycles and pistols
Let's go from this direction
Don't shoot
Just
give them the manuscript. - I can't.
Yes you can,
just say “here it is” and throw it at them
I'll make sure they let us go
How do they find us?
Because of your disco ball gown.
We have to think of a trick.
- I have an idea.
We dig a hole and then make a
sound and say "come here" or you can imitate the sound of a bird
No,
I have a plan - Please, Alan, let me think.
...please just let me think of me
Hey, they
were shooting at you - Yeah, so we're hiding.
They didn't shoot me
they need my wits
What? I don't think you
hear what you're saying
I will protect
you as a shield. - I will protect you.
Why?  Because I'm a woman?  This is sexist
Using women as shields
wasn't really the change she was seeking (Gloria Seinfeld)
Do you mean Gloria
Steinem? - whatever -
Tell me about sexism from
a men's point of view
Oh my God, I'm a woman, I can't talk
about anything from a men's point of view
I belong to the feminist movement
and so I believe that a woman can do anything that men can do
We should
stay here until they get tired of chasing us
Why don't you just listen to my plan?
We're in a lot more
trouble than just loving you to take off your shirts
I'm not sure about that
three
yes
It wasn't really what I had planned
...I just wanted to stop
I think the wind caused that
I think we're the reason,
we're the ones who did it, we only dealt with one guy
I think we just
wanted to stop him but the other guy didn't move
So... he is to blame
Even if
we weren't here, that would have happened
Why didn't he stop before the slope?
But they were
wearing...helmets, so maybe
But the rest of their bodies don't wear
helmets, they only wear them on their heads
They were driving recklessly, right?
No harsh handling of bicycles
It is
forbidden to do bad things on bicycles
Maybe they are fine
Yes, maybe no, it's okay
...it's okay,
you know, things happen like this, let's go
You can't bring back the torn pieces
it's rented
What more can I do?
You've done a lot so far, Beth.
My poor beloved grandmother has lost her sight
The release of the book was disastrous
and I invested all my money in it so I am completely broke now
Most of all, I lost
a writer. Who would allow such a thing to happen?
You
remind me of my girlfriend Randy, Beth.
She always takes
care of others and never takes care of herself
Isn't that right, Randy?
She's like this little psychotherapist
I laugh so hard at that
...after you're done with your girlfriend's order
What do you think of going to a beach?
What?
- I have something to do in Hawaii.
It is not necessary for her to come with us
Well,
well, you can come with us, it's so funny
Let me ask you something,
we're sitting here talking, who's flying the plane?
Autopilot - what?
-
Go to the cockpit
and drive the plane
good
It's time to go down...
No,
no, take the goat please take the goat
That Englishman kidnapped her
Hi, I'm
Beth, leave a message and I'll call you back
hello beth
listen
I'm sorry I spoiled the book tour
I was scared and... selfish
Well, Alan came, I'll call you back
Police Department
The police will look for Fairfax
and protect us while we're here
Did
they say anything about our time here?
They'll try to book a plane for us
tonight, and until then we can clean ourselves up and change our clothes
good
Come on
Dance with your husband
not my husband
It's okay.
- No, let's dance.
No, no, she
doesn't like it, the shoes she doesn't have
In fact, that's
the only thing that fits with these shoes
You don't have to
It's okay, it's okay
Oh really?
What does the song say?
It's part of the heritage
This song is about a
woman whose mother died and did not want to leave her
So she slept next to her and she never woke up
Sounds like a scary song
The idea of ​​imagining the future
without the person with whom you planned to continue your life
What is that?
Excuse me, was the last sentence in
the song: Who is crying next to me?
The island
will cry for me, a well of endless tears
What is the "endless well of
tears"? Is it a real place?
It's a stream
Thank you very much, thank you
Come on, let's go - what's up?
-
It is written on the chart that the
treasure of King (Kalaman) is buried in the well of endless tears
I thought it was a metaphor
But it is not
The
well of endless tears is a real place
It's a stream
There is a stream on the map
I think the cemetery is there
This is much better than your novels.
- What? -
No, I didn't mean it, not in that sense.
- I'm kidding, I'm kidding.
What? No
- I can see your enthusiasm.
...that would be crazy, I just wanted to
It's
just that we're so close to him, we can't
This is your
story, and you are the one who wanted to write it
I just want to know
where it is and if everything that happens makes sense
Well, let's go
There will be no harm in one day, at sunrise we
will go in search of the endless well of tears
What if we don't find anything?
- what's the problem? We will have tried
What about Fairfax?
The police
are looking for Fairfax to arrest him
This is
crazy. Yeah, but look at your enthusiasm.
It's
the first time I've seen you so brave
full of life
I'll tell
them we've changed our plan, I won't be late
I see you met my friend here
Tell me you're going to get off on
a plane without even saying goodbye
I said it is impossible
And Loretta wouldn't do something like
that, especially since she's the only one who can lead me to the cemetery
Don't press my hand
keep your hands off me
I want a car, does anyone own a car?
I want
a car, I can exchange it for a watch
It's a very expensive watch, do you have a car?
It's a Bvlgari brand that glows
in the dark and is water-resistant
I have a motorcycle
Fabulous, isn't it?
I thought why your tank doesn't have a mini bar?
Do you want a drink?
Would you stop it?
Yes, I'm afraid he holds you grudges
Because of
an accident involving his friend's motorcycle
Why do you do that?
I want something that no one else has
...when my father gave
I was saying when my father...given
his empire to my little brother
Who is this?
Is this a Ken doll
on a motorcycle?
I know him from somewhere
I doubt it
Because what you're looking at right now
is someone highly trained to face battles
Learn a lot
in Afghanistan, Iraq, Kuwait and Sarasota.
His skin is
great and he does not suffer from dermatitis
And it won't stop until I'm safe
So stop this tank, unless you want
to perish like his friends did
He is responsible for their death
You may not
have met him before but remember their death
Who is this?  who is he?  I've seen it before
No no
That's your novel's cover model, isn't it?
Yes, I knew that
One of you can go upstairs and kill him
And kill him in
a creative way, I love seeing cute people lose
I think I'll have this drink
Die
Do you mind if I fill the cup?
No, it's okay,
my God, is this your first time holding a cup?
What would
Jack Trainer do in a situation like this?
It's hot in here, isn't it hot?
Are you trying to be sexy?
This is so weird, please stop it
I can burn your world
sleep, sleep, no, no, sleep
Time out
No, don't shoot her, I need her
My God
Get your foot away, get your foot away
Sleep you bastard
big man
Faster
you ride
He or I?
This isn't one of
your boring, fairy tales, Loretta, it's real life
We'll kill him, tell us where the cemetery is
The headquarters of the special care and protection of tourists
Hello, whoever is in charge here,
send the administrators to this place
this place
We are closed
did you shut down?
Did you know
I've been napping for a year and a half?
a year and a half ago
I try to work as hard as I can without
rest and have been working hard since before my girlfriend was kidnapped
I rest and drink
wine that I don't even have the energy to drink
I want a massage
I want someone to massage my
shoulders and my feet at the same time
I don't care if it doesn't make
sense from a logistical point of view because I did my best
So I'm kind of asking you
to open up for a few more minutes... because if we don't
One of my very best
friends is going to die, she and her book cover model
I don't see any ways
What about caves?
This is very dangerous
Well, we'll be careful then
Come on
from here
It's my rule not to go
into any scary caves
(Julian)
Is his name Julian?
He fits the names Buck or Bruce.
You go
Go, don't be afraid
Watch your step
good
We must not make his death for nothing
Moving forward - how do we move forward?
we will die -
We won't back down now after all
Listen, let's
go back to the boat so no one else dies
No, no, there's a breeze,
there's a tunnel, it might lead us to the cemetery
Nobody's
going to - Speak for yourself, come on.
It's like playing slides
He might
chase a rock - or the back of a troll -
...you're
going down the back, no, I mean the tunnel
Why is she? -
Because you'll stay in the cave to warn us.
...that's impossible, I can't
Tell us
when you arrive or we will kill your friend
Hey, am I in trouble?
decent
I can't reach, sorry
What?
Do you smell this scent?
You mean the smell of crap that's been
here for centuries? Of course I smell this
You should take a deep breath, woman
Here you are
You can, Loretta.
I think I see a way out
My God
It arrived
See?  It is very safe
go, your turn
I'm
crossing the tunnel, stay there, okay?
Why did they build it in this place?
How are they supposed
to worship or remember Him without seeing Him?
It's not supposed to
This is not a trace of Claman's power.
It is the lair of a sad woman
Queen Taha used to come
here for her dead lover
She wanted to be alone
Taha doesn't want us
to be here - Just shut up, Ravi. It's just the volcano.
Come on
We have to continue
Well, let's go strong
open it
Don't bother them
You're going to wear the crown,
come on, we didn't come that far to pay respects to the dead
I cannot
Sorry for that
What is that?
Are these sea shells?
The crown is made of seashells?
Where is the treasure?
She hugs him
Do you mean the dead man?
look
It's their courtship texts
Claman
was looking for something on the island
rare seashells
To prove his love for her, he would bring her a coincidence
every day of the year, then gather them in a crown that was red like the fire of their love.
Until the day he proposed to her marriage came
It was never about jewelry
Claman and Taha's
fortune was not material
It was their
love, that's the point, and that's enough
Is that all? All that
time and money wasted on an old, ridiculous metaphor?
We have to go
No, no, you'll stay here
Since you both
see it as beautiful and poetic then you will live
The rest of your lives contemplate
the richness of that metaphor
Get in - what?
-
All
right, okay? - Enter the cemetery.
Perhaps it
is better to bury alive than to bury the dead
do you know
that? It's really shameful, great story
But you will not live to tell it to anyone
Come
on, but they're going to die.
And you too,
if you don't stop being sensitive, come here
It's okay, no worse than my
nightmares when I was 14
Why are you going so fast?
We are not in a race
Oh my God, what are you doing?  come back here
You may own the island,
but now you are its slave
You can't leave me here
come back ravi
I want a boat
stop, stop
Have you seen a woman
with black hair and a tight dress with sequins?
No, is she in trouble?
It's funny
I thought a situation like
this would be romantic
Oh really?
Do you mean to stay in a grave? Or dumping
us with lava? Or stay with the dead?
I mean,
stay next to lost love, like Taha did.
Sorry I
couldn't save you Sorry I couldn't be Dash
You're
right, you're not like Dash at all
You didn't take your white horse and save me
I even took a borrowed
scooter with a broken muffler
yes
I couldn't have
made Dash like you
Because
I've never known someone like Alan.
I was so afraid that
life would hurt my feelings again so I stopped living
I couldn't
see the good things in front of my eyes
I'm so
sorry I didn't notice you were there before
I have a confession too
I really liked the direction
our story was taking
Maybe I
wanted to know what was going to happen
The Adventures of Loretta and Alan
That
would have been a great name, for sure.
Ravi must have left it to us
How did you forget that
lever? You will help us out
He left her on
purpose - Wow, I've always felt he was a good person.
one two Three
I wish he hadn't left
us here from the start
"Pleasure comes after hardship"
Pleasure comes after hardship
We will climb these trees
Don't
wait, you don't have to burn trees, okay
We can go back to the tunnel
No, we can't go back to the tunnel
I think I can do it
There is a
current, we can follow it to lead us to the ocean
How will we know what
is on the other side?
We won't know
There is only one way to find out
I wouldn't care if I got
a rash. - Really? -
(right Now)
oh my god, you're alive
Yes
- I thought I caused your death.
Is this Beth?
- (Loretta) -
(Beth)
You're here, Beth.
Why are you here?
I told you I'm on your back, girl
I'm so sorry, I messed up your dress
What?
No, I will tell you later
I found an Englishman in the cave
and thought he was a little boy but it turned out he had a beard
It's Fairfax that kidnapped us, Beth.
He's
a bad guy, Beth, he killed Turner.
stop it
I'm at your back, girl
Why were you running?
It's a ship, this guy is so funny
got U
We'll take you to the island
I caught you, no, I didn't catch you
We'll take you both, you'll be fine
They found sanctuary
on a nearby rock and lifted it out of the water
His strong
arms pulled her and tightened her body
Then he (Alan) whispered to her,
You are safe now
At that moment,
Loretta felt that a new adventure was about to begin
Novel (Crown of Fire)
The desire to miraculously escape from them made
her heart beat and ignited her desire for him
She was thirsty for the hot
lava that was emanating from
They taught you not to stop at the good part
It's not something you haven't read before
Didn't I tell you?
It is the most beautiful beach in the world
Maybe
later I can show you the Enchanted Bay
No, you can take Randy.
Remember, our friendship is a virginal friendship
virginity?  I love the pronunciation of this word
I don't know
what it means but I like the way it is pronounced
There you are, Randy.
Honey.
- You're an angel, thank you.
How do you know I'm an angel?
Great
way to end a book tour, isn't it?
You know, I have
a phrase I like to use in situations like this
"What's Next?"
It is a Latin phrase meaning: What next?
"What's your opinion?"
Restaurant (Boca de Bebo)
Yes, I don't know anything about Latin
I use it in these
moments, like now
So what's the next step?
How will you write the next novel?
- I don't know, how would you write it? -
Do you really want me to write it?
Try
- Ok, I'll write it down.
"We were there... standing on a beach"
Prepare
events for readers so they know how to start
Why are you laughing?
- I don't laugh, I smile -
There are palm trees above the brown
bark like the hair of a virgin girl
"And there's a dead jellyfish behind" - You're
just describing what you're actually seeing -
"He's nervous because he really likes her."
let's continue
He looks deeper into
her eyes and compares them to the pulse of the ocean
They are the only
thing that can compare to the pulse of the ocean
"...and beats"
You can't use the word:
beats - why not? -
The beats don't happen that fast
But the chimes happen all the time
The beats don't happen
so fast but gradually
What makes your statement true?
It's something
about Chapter 4 that should be scaled appropriately
I guess
the beats in all seasons, it's just a beat
There is even a prelude to the beats
Just go to chapter 5
What if they kiss each other?
- Do you mean an ordinary kiss? -
Yes, that
kiss is at the beginning of the chapters
...I have a good start
Do you have any comments?
- Fantastic, as a first attempt to start a chapter -
Oh my God, oh God... you're dead, your brain came
out of your face and reached behind my throat
It got in
my mouth...Don't say it got in my mouth.
I tasted yours
We can only use
10% of our brain, so I moved on to the next 10%
So... are you okay?
one hundred percent
This means 10 percent
We thought you were dead
I usually have anger issues
that I need to get rid of
Nice to see you man
Well, let's turn our conversation down
We close our eyes and connect with ourselves
Wonderful
Subtransl.ed balloumowgly