Our best minds have determined
我们最好的大脑决定了
that the whole universe is the dream of one ant
整个宇宙是一只蚂蚁的梦
A-Are you okay
你还好吗
I was just sleeping and I heard troubled breath
刚才我在睡觉然后听见了喊叫声
Nothing.Nothing.I-I'm fine.
没事 我还好
I just... had a nightmare.
我只是做了个噩梦
What are you accusing me of?
你在怪我？
I-I didn't shove anything
all up in your ear.
I never seen that thing
before in my life.
I don't even know what it is.
Besides, my thing would need
one twice that size.
What did you do to me?!
Stop this!
What d... What did you do?
- Huh?
- Get up!
W-W-What's happening?
W-Why are you hitting me?
What have you done to me
while I was sleeping?
What did you do to me?
I ... I didn't do anything.
I don't think I did.
Did I do something to you?
Oh, God!
What did I do?!
What did you do to me?
You monster!
I'm sorry.
I'm so confused.
It's okay.
I forgive you.
- These things happen.
- Why are you so good to me?
Because you have such tight,
pretty ears.
Not really.
You really wanna know?
I've never shown anyone this.
It's huge.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
_
1x01 - The Nurple Rainbow
Then again,
toddler prodigy Trudy Glimmer
was the greatest peekaboo player
the world had ever known.
Trudy?
W-Where's Trudy?
I just saw her.
She was just here.
Where'd she go?
Where'd she go?!
Oh, God.
She was just here!
Oh, my God! Trudy!
Where'd you go?!
Oh, my God.
Oh, Trudy!
My baby!
Where's my baby?!
911! Someone stole my baby!
Oh, God!
Someone stole my baby!
Oh, God, oh, God, oh God.
- Oh, God.
- What's going on?
Where's Trudy?
What happened?!
- Where is she?!
- Aah!
You get that bastard
that took her!
If he hurt a hair
on her head, I swear,
I'm gonna rip God's face off
and ... and ram it down his tip.
I promise
I will find your daughter,
even if I have to
kill her to do it.
Police rounded up
every pervert in the area,
torturing them for information,
which, naturally,
the perverts loved.
They undulated
orgasmically for more.
The cops were all
too happy to oblige.
Nipple twisting,
purple nurples, blue nurples,
every nurple in the rainbow
turned up a steaming pile of zilch.
The trauma of losing their child
tore the parents apart.
Last year, I let your brothers
sandwich my business.
Ah, yeah, so did I, Chachi.
So did I.
Before long, a father
finds a suitable outlet
to properly deal with his grief.
If I don't see my child again
soon, I'm gonna do this.
Some children
are just naturally talented.
- We'll never know why.
- Peekaboo!
Trudy!
Oh, sweetie, where were you?
Oh, my God, Trudy.
Don't ever disappear again.
Trudy?!
Trudy! Trudy!!
Peekaboo.
Mama? Papa?
We have long known
that chickens can live for years
with their heads cut off.
Recently, embedded Mideast
war reporters
have been dosing with huge
infusions of chicken blood
to frustrate
their terrorist beheaders.
- This is what western infidels get!
- Is that all you got, cha-cha?
Shut up and die,
you infidel pig dog.
Uh, correction ... chicken dog.
Bawk-bawk.
You are making me angry.
And you have schmutz
on your dress.
Bonk! Gotcha!
Bawk-bawk, playa!
Innocent
bystanders were so amused,
they took the act on the road.
Why will you not die already?
Uh, why don't you
brush your teeth already?
I'm warning you ...
keep it up and I'll stop
this holy war right now.
Bawk-bawk, homey.
A-bawk-bawk.
Mmm, check the hottie
in the front row.
Hey, uh, missy,
you care for a three-way?
Or at least a 2 1/4-way?
Hey, I'm not severed where it counts.
Please die, for the love of Allah.
Tell you what, I'll die
if you answer one question.
- You have a deal. Fire away.
- Why does your faith glorify hate?
You really want to know?
For me, it's ...
s-see, I never had a mother.
Wait, wait,
if you never had a mom,
then how do you exist at all?
Jumpin' Jihad, you're right.
At that precise moment,
only one man was having
a worse day at work.
We are so freaking
disappointed in your output, Dwyer.
Everyone else
in this department types
at least 10,000
random numbers a day.
- Your average is 19.
- Sorry, sir. It's just ...
- I ... It's just ...
- What's so hard about it?
Just type random numbers
as fast as you can.
See? Ding, ding, ding, ding.
That's it. Easy peasy.
- Now you try. Go!
- Uh. Um...
Let's see, uh...
Ooh...
- Uh... Um...
- Just hit numbers!
Faster. Faster!
But I can never decide
which number to choose.
Don't think about it.
Just type. It's random.
- I know, but I still want it to be good.
- Well, it isn't good.
And what's this?
There's some type
of Goddamn hole
in the back of your head here...
Whoa.
Weird little critter living in there.
Hey, little guy.
What the hell, Dwyer?
- I wish you could see this.
- What is it?
What is it?! What, Dwyer, how
the hell am I supposed to know?
Get your act together.
Let me feed
this little thing for you.
Damn thing was hungry.
Maybe that's why
you're doing a sucky job.
Did it eat?!
What is it?
Dagit!
The damn thing's allergic
to peanuts or something.
You're on thin ice
with this nonsense, Dwyer.
I'm sorry. Here, l-let me
help you wipe that up.
Just get back to work.
And get that thing checked out.
What are you doing?
Just keep working, Dwyer.
I'm having a look.
W-What the he...
What the hell is this thing?
- Ah! What the heck-fire?
- Just keep working.
Oh. Feisty little bastard.
Oh, wait.
That's what's going on.
Feisty little bitch, I should say ...
- protecting her eggs.
- Eggs?
- I'm a little scared.
- It's okay.
She got the little things
hatching right now.
- What does it look like?
- Christ, Dwyer!
Those things are loud.
Buddy, these are disruptive.
This is not appropriate
for a workspace environment.
I'm sorry. I could strap
a pillow to my head.
- Muffle it.
- I can't hear you, Dwyer!
- It's too loud!
- Or could you fill it with water
and drown them? Or piss?
Sorry, Dwyer!
Look, we gotta let you go.
You can fire me,
but one day I'll show you.
I'll show you all.
Christ, Dwyer!
It's too loud.
When he realized
that no one believed in him,
Doug rushed home to see
if he was there.
And the noble prize
for the Most Random Series
of Numbers of All Time goes to...
Dougie Dwyer!
When he reflected
on his strengths,
Doug finally began
to love himself.
And when a man
finds self-esteem,
he can coax himself
to go all the way.
It got so steamy, even
his vanity became aroused.
And Doug got to experience
every man's fantasy ...
a two-way with himself.
You're killing me.
Killing me.
Kill me. Kill me harder.
Kill me harder. Kill me deeper.
Kill me harder. Kill me harder,
kill me deeper, kill me harder.
But alas, someone
always gets hurt in love.
And when one raw-dogs it
with a mirror,
the fruit of your vain
comes home to roost...
Push! Push!
...and our lives are
filled with meaning forever,
as long as the screams
don't get so loud
that they wake the ants
that are dreaming us.
♪ Oh, master, oh, master ♪
♪ Don't lay blame on me ♪
♪ 'Twas the false nurse ♪
♪ And Lankin that
killed your lady ♪
♪ Long Lankin was hanged
on a gibbet so high ♪
♪ And the false nurse was burned
in a fire close by ♪
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~