Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
That's a beautiful pig.
Only the best, Father.
This way, Father.
The boy is showing all the classical signs
of possession, Father Amorth.
Has the family consulted a doctor?
Many, many doctors.
What are the signs of possession?
He converses in English, Father.
Has he spoken English before?
Never. Not once before.
Do they own a television?
Yes, I believe so.
Okay, thank you.
What are you drawing?
A bird.
That's good, kid.
I have a very important job for you.
Do you know the Our Father?
- Yes, Father.
- Good.
You can help your brother.
Repeat the Our Father, over and over.
Don't get distracted.
Relentless. Understood?
Yes, Father.
Good.
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name...
Bring me the pig.
Difficult to believe.
If you are Satan, what is my name?
Describe hell.
Are you avoiding my questions?
Answer me, Satan.
Why possess this boy?
Why not someone more influential?
Could you possess Father Gianni?
A bishop?
Have you possessed him, Satan?
Have you possessed it, Satan?
Be calm.
God blesses you.
Why do you think Saint Michael didn't
kill Satan when he had the chance?
Yes, of course.
Hold this.
At this time of the day? Are you crazy?
Double espresso, Sister.
Thank you.
Sugar is the work of the devil.
No, thank you.
Thank you very much.
Let's get on with this already.
All right, let's go.
It wasn't a--
I can't wait to finish this job.
This place freaks me out.
What is it?
I don't know. Can't see anything.
Come on, let's go. Come on, everybody out.
Quick, quick.
- Is that you, Gabriele?
- Yes, Holy Father.
They tell me you are sick.
Yes, they hope so.
They wish to see me weak.
But, no, they are.
- Help me.
- Yes.
Perhaps we've done our jobs too well.
Cardinal Sullivan
and the younger generation,
they don't believe in the devil
as we understand it.
It's only an idea for them.
For us, it is very real.
Two hundred fallen angels,
expelled from heaven, driven beneath
the soil where God is not welcomed.
It is not a fairytale.
Your search for truth
is delightful, Gabriele,
but pay attention
to your desire to educate.
Pride manifests itself in different forms.
Pride? Me?
Father.
Good morning.
I'm Father Tomás Esquibel.
- Spanish?
- Yes.
I am Father Amorth. Italian.
Good morning, good morning, good morning.
I am Father Amorth.
Gabriele, how are you?
Yes, yes.
Very nice, this.
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come, thy will be--
God is not here.
God is everywhere.
Show yourself, coward.
Show yourself.
Coward.
Show yourself, coward.
Yes.
And may the souls
of all the faithful departed,
through the mercy of God,
rest in peace.
The scent of heaven.
The abbey's records, Your Holiness.
God, by your name...
save me.
In the name of Christ, let her go.
In the name of Christ,
go away, Satan, go away!
"Your cardinal protector writes
to inform you of our worst fears.
A great evil has taken hold
of San Sebastian Abbey.
It must be buried here forever."
"All attempts at exorcism have failed.
Satan owns this ground now.
I have never seen
a demon this powerful before."
You are just agitated.
Almighty God.
God, by your name, save me.
Judge me in thy strength.
O God, hear my prayer.
Listen to the words of my mouth.
Behold, God is my helper.
Yes, Your Holiness.
Yeah, not too bad.
Thank you very much, Your Holiness.