Heat once the weather.
Land here tastes like dog shit.
You know, huh?
Fuck!
Break.
There are men of military force, are call,
pay attention to the convoy. over.
lf he reported troop movements please shoot.
Your turn. over
Maybe he called his wife.
Him down.
Moment. There were women and children,
within 200 yards, moving towards the convoy.
Arms were not moving.
He brought something.
He pulls out a grenade. RKG Russia grenade.
l think he gave it to the boy.
- Women and children? - You saw it?
Can insure?
Negative. You know ROE.
Your turn.
- They will burn you if you're wrong.
They will put you in jail. - Fuck.
You've done about it.
Come back here.
Never leave your
gun on the ground.
Yes, sir.
Good shot. You're talented.
One day you will
be a great hunter.
Listen to this book, several times.
That judgment ..
for the trust.
Time where we have to do it.
We can not see with his eyes.
So we do not know the
glory of his plans.
Eyes we see it as a
reflection in the glass.
- The day we arrived...
- Why are you doing this?
We will see it clearly. And
understand the mystery of how.
Let us pray.
There are 3 types of
people in this world.
Sheep, wolf and sheepdog.
Some people believe
devil does not exist
in the world--
And if hatred appeared at their door
do not know how to protect themselves.
lt was a sheep.
Then there are predators.
They use violence
to prey on the weak.
They are wolves.
Then there are those
blessed with talent aggression
and protect the flock.
They are a rare breed who
live to face serigala--
They sheepdog.
We do not raise sheep
in this family
and l would beat if you become wolves.
- Wayne--
But we protect our herd.
And if someone tried to fight
or protect your sister you get
my permission to finish .
He attacked Jeff.
ls that correct?
- Yes, Sir. True.
And you finish it?
You know who you are.
You know your goals.
There is not anyone there.
You're out with a waist belt.
- What should you do?
- Sleeping with it.
- l'll wear it and see her make mood changed.
- Strong winds make her mood changed.
ls that what they say?
- You know what they call it when
Sarah menghisap-- SMA-- - Do not say.
Jeez, Chris.
lt recompense.
- There are 2 ladies...
- She continues to see it.
- Wait till you see this.
- Yes l Do.
Hey, babe who wants rodeo star?
What the fuck?
You said he did not come
home until tomorrow.
- l said what?
- Do not bother him.
He did not do anything.
Chris, do not disturb him!
Leave him alone!
Fuck, what's with you ?!
- He does not know, okay?
- What does she know?
- You do not know?
- l take my hat.
He does not know.
- You do not know?
- What is wrong with you ?!
Why did you do that to everyone?
Get out of here!
What is it with you!
- Exit.
- l do not know what you expect of me.
You brought me here and exit together
with your brother every weekend!
Think why am l doing this?
l'm doing this to get attention!
Take your things and get out.
Good. Screw you!
Do you think you could
be a rodeo cowboy for?
You're not a cowboy. You
only farm administrators.
And you lowly!
Do not say.
Gosh.
l do not understand what you said.
We had to travel to another state.
Different city every weekend.
- Can not stay here.
- Maybe he's right.
- But he's right.
- True matter what, Chris?
He was not true. We cowboy.
Living in a dream.
Friend, friend see this.
- You're from Texas?
- Yes, Sir.
- You're a patriot.
- Yes l Do.
-And you're angry.
- l want to serve.
- Fight?
- Yes, Sir.
Meet elite fighters.
- Seals?
- Sea, air and land.
- l am less able to swim, sir.
- This is not for a broken heart.
- Most people will stop. - l'm not
most people, sir. l do not stop.
Lift your feet!
Thank this!
This is the first time.
lf you are swept away,
you're going to die!
Do not turn your face from me.
View and accept this.
Old are old, huh?
Did you join the Navy because they
want to have fun at Noah's Ark?
- How old are you? 30! You've dusty
and disappeared. - 30 years.
We will do it again.
We're going to be a fighter.
l never see him.
l come to deal with terrorists.
Who did it?
l do not know.
- Did l ask you?
- Do Not.
Look at you.
You bastard! That's what l said.
Biggles, the name now.
And the tickets very difficult.
What are you doing here
if you hate water ?
Never mind, sir. l'm not black.
- No? - l'm the new black. We
ran slow, low jump and swim.
And l make whites proud!
That people who quit!
You say goodbye.
lf he stops here, he stopped
on the battlefield.
When everything is in trouble,
he will not pull you out.
l am looking for a knight.
l can not hear? Do you want to call your
parents? Maybe they can replace you.
This is a game.
That's what l'm talking about.
- Where are you?
We will survive, sir!
They are warm!
Give her speech.
How are you, old man?
How are you?
Dangerous.
l felt dangerous.
- He feels dangerous.
Go!
Oh yes it penyiksaanmu!
Again.
lf you want the
target, use this.
- Hello.
- Hi There.
- What are you doing?
- Okay, thank you.
- Can l buy you a drink? - What makes
you drink 6 inches higher and charming?
What makes you not married?
l'm watching you.
Do not be a loser.
Go home.
lt might leather pants.
Oh yeah?
Pants what to wear women
so as not to be disturbed?
Maybe Corduroy.
What is kalian-- suddenly
single after 3 beers?
What happens after the third
beer is the fourth beer.
Good.
- Red-neck real. - l'm not
a red-neck, l Texans.
- What is the difference? - We
rode horses, they rode cousin.
What do you do before?
- l polish dolphins. They must polished or
broken skin. - Do l look stupid to you?
No, you look sad.
Am l high enough to buy a drink?
Not until you tell me yourjob.
- Okay, how about this ..
One glass for one question.
- How?
- Ok.
Okay asked.
You're military. Which branch?
l just completing BUD / S.
-Are you kidding? You Seal?
- Yes, ma'am.
That's two questions.
Shit.
l do not mean to do it.
Okay, honestly.
l know about all of you. My
sister was engaged to Seal.
- Really?
- Yes l Do.
What do you mean you
know all about our ?
You're a bunch of arrogant, self-centered
think could lie and do as you please.
l never dated SEAL.
What do you mean selfish? l
am devoted to my country.
- Why? - Because this is the best country
on earth and l deserve to be protected.
l'm sorry this happened to
your sister but it was not me.
Nice to meet you.
- Do you want to go? - l'm going
home, you say not be dating SEAL.
l said l'd never marry.
Hello, nice to meet you?
- What is your name?
- Taya.
Taya.
l'm Chris Kyle.
Nice to meet you.
You're very selfish thought could
protect us all, right Chris?
Our commander said
there are three things that should we
worry about: ego, alcohol and women.
Sounds like you are
being attacked.
You're beautiful.
So you're...
l got you.
l'm not going home with you
so do not think about it.
Feel the air fill every
cell in your body .
This is our ritual.
We master the breath, we
master the mind kita--
pull the trigger will
be no conscious effort.
You will notice but
not directing it.
When you exhale,
regarded as pause,
and the space
between heartbeats.
Hey this Taya, l can not pick up the phone.
Leave a message and l'll call behind.
Hey it's me. Men who
shoes you muntahi.
l think you did not receive my last message .
Or previous message.
- So l think...
- You think what?
Hey, how are you? How are you?
- Good.
- Well... okay...
What are you doing?
Lazing. Do you?
l just want to talk to you.
Keker small, little miss. lf you mengeker
buttons , missed 2 inches possible.
lf mengeker shirt,
maybe 2 feet escape.
You better shut it, Kyle.
Yes, sir.
l'm going to play it.
- You like that one?
- That one.
- This prize.
- Thank you sir.
- Thank you. Hello.
- Good afternoon.
lt looks nice with you.
Have you always wanted to be a soldier?
- No, l want to be a cowboy
l do and feel the need anything else.
- So you start saving woman from the bar?
l saved the bar it from you.
Do you like country music?
Only when l'm depressed.
- l love children. You like?
- One day.
My mom said l had a nose
for choose the wrong man.
lt was a bad thing
to say to a woman .
He was right.
lt brought you here.
Making you are now. l like it.
Do you ever think that happened?
l do not know. l wish
l could do the job.
Do we see the same target?
You spit in the dust.
Do not worry, we can wear substitute
for people who can not shoot.
Oh shit!
- You're trembling.
- l know.
- We do not need to do this.
- No, l would.
- Yes.
- l want to feel it.
Do you close your eyes?
lf l close my eyes, can
not see the target.
There was nothing there except the target.
- Negative. There's something there.
Come.
Give me 50 push-ups, Kyle.
l'm a better shot.
- Oh Lord, Chris. Do Not.
- What's up?
- You just know me.
- Yes l Do.
What are you afraid of?
None.
Everything. l do not know.
What if it did not work?
We'll get married
and start a family.
You've planned, right.
l finished. l love you.
You need a ring if you want
to talk such strong. - Ok.
Ladies and gentlemen, Mr.
and Mrs. Chris Kyle.
What happened to your neck?
Neck is no makeup.
Do you believe if l say that?
What?
Because of them. - Oh, God.
Cheers.
What he said, Chief?
We just received a call. Task!
Yes!
Yeah, wow!
- Let them.
- l am very scared.
There is nothing to fear.
This is part of the plan.
Heart beats.
Because l'm going to go to war.
Welcome to Fallujah.
Wild west new in the
old middle east.
AQl put up the price of your head
and extremist from around the world
come to the border to collect.
You sniper paired with someone who
take care of you and keep marines
were checking the position.
Yourjob protecting Marines
whatever it takes.
The city has been evacuated.
Militia still here
want to kill you.
Bring them home safely.
We can go home.
Exit. Run Out.
Lower the head, Tex.
Muj also has a sniper.
Sniper will not target the head.
They have a sniper
head that can shoot from
a distance of 500 yards.
They called Mustafa.
He followed the Olympics.
There is a sniper
shooting in the Olympics?
There are women and children within
200 yards towards the convoy.
Arms were silent, he
brings something.
He brings Russian grenades
and given to the child.
Do you see it? Can insure?
- Negative.
You know ROE. Your turn. - lf
one of them will menggorengmu.
Bitch asshole!
Good shot, Tex. Nice One.
Accepted. Nice AL.
- Damn.
- Do not touch me.
Where is everyone?
- Train the soldiers Hajj.
- Why do not you there?
l have a problem. - You
still read comics?
This graphic novel, bro.
There is a difference.
l heard you shot someone.
You made it?
True?
There is a child who has
not had fur on his cock
mother gave grenade
Send them out to
kill the Marines.
l've never seen it before.
Yeah, but you know that the child
could killed 10 Marines, huh?
You're doing yourjob.
End of story.
This is not like
the way l do it.
Fuck! What the hell!
Are you watching, Einstein?
You can thank him later.
Move!
Quick .
There is a car bomb!
Hold your fire!
Keep an eye on the roof!
There were shot.
Snipers visible enemy.
Location R155704.
Smell in here.
You protect us. lt
was a good shot.
- Clean, right?
- True.
Snipers enemy sneaked in.
Yes, it will not happen again.
Should not happen again. There is a
hot entrusted quarter mile away.
l will make a report.
- How much do you get?
- l can six.
No, l can be eight, but
they dragged two people.
- You can be six?
- Yes, why?
- You can be more than the others.
- Yes, but they can be one of us.
You can not hit what
you can not see .
- She said she brought the Quran.
- l do not know the form of the Quran.
But l can describe
what he was carrying.
Metal objects, firing bullets
7.62, and looks like the AK-47.
So what does he bring?
He came.
Ladies and gentlemen, listen up.
There is a legend among us.
Give him applause.
The legend is already making a record.
He killed 100 people with one shot.
One shot of a man.
He ''blew'' 100 men.
And he's still single.
Gosh.
Competition throw food? Come on.
The only way to make silent.
Did you kill people?
Not the way to start a
conversation, dear.
Do not behave like that to me.
l want you to tell
me everything.
There are some things that can
not be said on the phone .
You make me pregnant and l
sat alone put up cots ...
... and you can not talk to me?
That's your big plan?
All okay in there?
l can not stop thinking
pink dress it.
His name evening gown.
Yes.
Three days is not
counted as a honeymoon.
lt was three days of fun.
- l miss you.
- l missed you too.
- You want me to talk naughty to you?
- Yes, wait a minute.
l was holding a rifle.
You have to decide which
is more important, dear.
You really are lust.
l'm fat and horny.
lt was disgusting.
Although weight is 150 pounds, l
still want to make love to you.
- Really romantic.
- How is my son?
- No one said he was a man.
- You two would be amazing.
How do you know?
l know. l can see it.
- l hope you're right.
- l am right.
- Your father contacted you?
- l do not check my email.
Gosh.
You should call him, okay?
- What is it?
- l do not think straight.
What is it?
- Brother sent.
- What do you mean? To a school?
No, he did not go to school.
Contact your father.
What do you mean? Where is she?
There.
She toward lraq.
Sorry, dear.
The man who held the knife is a member of
the radical Jordan Bin Laden financed.
Trained by Bin Laden,
loyal to bin Laden.
Name was Zarqawi.
Bastard This is the prince
of Al-Qaeda in lraq.
Army, AQl, amounted
to 5 thousand people.
They are not ordinary
mercenary troops.
They are well
trained, well paid...
... and this time, they run the operation
biggest offensive since Vietnam.
Zarqawi and his Lieutenant,
they is our top priority.
There is only one
way to find their .
That check from door to
door, until we find them...
... Or someone who could
provide their location.
So we need to examine
10 building per hour.
l know it very much,
very aggressive .
Do not rely on air support.
This is the highest priority
targets until today.
l want them dead or
captured, understand?
Have a question?
lf the marines haste,
they could be shot.
They can not be
training like us.
Most of them civilians
6 months ago.
Let us train them. l
will show them how.
No, we need you to keep
an eye on the situation.
- The enemy already knows we're up there.
- Under extremely dangerous.
You want to be the savior?
l just wanted to catch them.
Can not see, can not shoot.
They all know your name. They
feel safe when you're up there.
- No.
- That's what they think.
So stay up there, watch them.
You said snipers AQl never
follow the Olympics?
While lraq has not qualified
for three Olympics.
Mustafa instead of lraq.
He is from Syria.
Once you get in, l could
not see anything.
So only slowly.
Good.
Go!
To hell with this.
l will go down
with the marines .
You coming?
Not.
l want to go home alive.
Not work knocking on the door.
l do not want to do that.
lf l do not see
you down there...
... sure l will not
see you again.
Hey, do you mind if
l come with you?
Course.
You're the legend that, right?
You've killed 24 people?
- l do not count them.
- lt was really cool.
There's a nigger in
Bravo the chase.
l know a few things.
There are several things
that could show you, how?
Okay.
- What does that mean?
- Break.
Get down on the floor right now!
- Do not!
- Get down!
Why are you here? You
should evacuate.
Who are you?
l do not care about this house.
This is a war zone, sir. Down.
Quick .
They hide behind.
Still no one else in this house?
He's going to blow us.
Search the clothes.
- He knows we're talking.
- Who are you talking about?
Who knew we talk?
He cut...
- Please...
- Target already secured?
Okay, take him. Put your
hands behind your head.
Now! Fast!
Take him into another room.
lf he spoke, a man will
come to his house.
Who is ''he?''
Someone called Butcher.
A son of the devil.
He was a bouncer?
Warrior number one Zarqawi.
- Zarqawi?
- Zarqawi.
Yes, we want to know the location of Zarqawi.
Do you know where he is?
Tell us where he is.
How can we meet?
You're no information
about Zarqawi?
Find Butchers, you
will find Zarqawi.
Okay, how do we find him?
Look at me when you're talking.
Where can we find it?
He asked for money.
- 100 thousand dollars.
- You need 100 thousand dollars?
You do not have any proof
of this person there.
Hello.
This proves it.
l want to help, but l need something.
Phone number, address, name.
- Pak, third team need help.
- Moving On!
Look at me when you're talking.
Hey, look at me.
l need something. l can help.
Give me a name,
we'll take care .
l can promise you. Will l
guarantee your safety.
Tell us.
-Amir Khalaf Fanus?
- lt was the original name of the Butchers.
He was the second-Zarqawi.
He's the one.
Yes, but you do not know his real
name, otherwise would have you write.
There are several pseudonyms.
lf your information is correct,
we have met the Sheik .
He asked for 100
thousand dollars.
lf he can submit Butchers,
he will get it.
lt Snead Agency, DlA. Check
the name Amir Khalaf Fanus.
Yes, l'll wait.
lf we're going back there,
3 team could just...
None. Contractor took center
if we would send money.
Yes, what you got?
Okay.
Let's meet the Sheik.
Who is our target?
Bouncer Zarqawi.
They say she likes to
wear a drill as a weapon.
Before joining the marines l
joined the seminary school.
- l'm almost finished pastor.
- Why do so?
l like to bet.
l love the game of dice.
Personal phone?
You have not heard? l legend.
- Hey, baby.
- You're right, the doctor told the boy.
What?
- Boys.
-A boy!
Good. Congratulations.
Chris?
Take the money. Refuge.
Take the bag!
Chris?
Let's get out of here.
Darling?
- l heard one shot.
- From high angle.
- 280 meters.
- Oh My.
- Did you see it?
- Do Not.
Damn, he took the
child from the Sheik.
Ask for help. We restrained.
Location, 4536237.
l will throw smoke grenades.
Wait.
Forward!
Who will die open mouth.
Come on!
Fuck you!
Gosh, messy once.
You're stupid.
What do you think? You failed
to secure the location.
Will this stop them all.
Back to headquarters.
- We have to go after them.
- No, the mission was canceled.
- What do you mean?
- They will develop plans.
We can not let them
run like that.
l'll be home in 3 weeks.
lt will be three weeks long.
-Are you okay?
- Yes l Do.
lt's okay.
l'm here.
-Are you okay?
- Yes l Do.
You're the most beautiful
woman l had ever seen.
There's an alien in my body.
-And there was a strange man in my room.
- Our room.
Hands are noticeably different.
This is my hand.
- Why am l so nervous...
- l was too nervous.
- No.
- l swear.
What if the alien
was holding me?
How?
Creepy.
You're laughing.
All will be fine.
- Promise?
- Yes, of course.
You're very good to me.
Maybe we could get out.
Are you listening?
- Chris?
- What Are?
What you want to do today?
We can relax here.
Okay, all right.
Let's relax.
- What are you doing?
- Tease.
You're good at teasing.
l'll be there.
All looks good.
- What do you feel?
- l am fine.
- Soon will come out.
- l hope so.
- What are you, Mr. Kyle?
- l'm fine, thank you.
l bet you still adapting.
Not.
This is the first time we left the house.
- l'm glad to be home.
Please use this.
l do not want to be checked.
-Are you a smoker?
- Do Not.
- Do you drink?
- Only when l'm thirsty.
- 170-110.
- Oh My.
- Chris...
- lt's a high figure?
lt's as if you just drank
40 cups of coffee.
l appreciate the thought.
- Thank you.
- You're going to check it?
Yes.
- You're pranking earlier.
- What should l do? You did not say anything.
-As if all is fine.
- Everything is fine.
No, Chris, your blood
pressure 170-110.
l'm driving on the highway
in bright daylight.
l'm fine. Currently
no war, people die.
And there's nothing to talk about,
as if nothing ever happened.
We're on the way home.
Living a simple life.
There is not even in the
news, no one cares.
While there is war
and l go to a mall.
l should be there.
- What is it? You are okay?
- lt is coming out.
Gosh, okay.
- You're crazy.
- lt is okay.
Gosh, dear.
You look beautiful.
Soon born.
Hi.
Hi, little man.
Baby we cry, l thought
you would calm him down.
l've been watching it.
l have to make sure you
do not have a mistress.
Recording enemy sniper victim. He
sold his recording on the streets.
Victim of the American army.
When we're on the
phone, what was he?
True, right?
Talk. You do not protect
me with silence.
- l do not want to talk.
- Very poor imagination.
- They are barbarians.
- Chris.
- This is not about them.
lt's about us.
What?
You have to get back to us.
Okay?
Welcome back. Colonel wait.
Back from vacation.
True.
- Hey, wait a minute.
- Okay, hurry up.
Hey.
Brother...
-Are you okay?
- l heard you in action here.
All talking about.
That's what they say?
How are you? You are okay?
You are my hero.
- Come on, Kyle! Colonel wait.
- The legend.
Are you okay?
Yes, l would skip tumpanganku.
l'm just tired.
l want to go home.
l'm proud of you.
Father proud of you.
To hell with this place.
- You said what? To
hell with this place.
Come on.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you sir.
Gronsky and the officers
on board was gone.
l've studied them.
l know everything.
This war is influenced by the
thoughts of our enemies.
Yes, sir.
- That's you?
- Yes, that's right, sir.
You're the most
wanted man in lraq.
There is a 180 thousand dollar reward
above your head. Congratulations.
Do not tell my wife.
He might fill my head.
Do you want to form a
team to hunt Butchers ?
Yes, sir.
There is intelligence that
indicates operations area.
l want you to kill him.
Search him.
Yes, sir.
Okay, let's get him.
Clean up all before going.
- Together with the legend in action.
- What Are?
- The legend.
- l'll tell you another time.
- You're great, man.
- Thank you.
What would you say?
The book is bulletproof?
- This?
- Yes, l have never seen you open it.
We must honor God, right?
You have a God?
Why not?
When l was a kid there was an
electric fence near our house.
Children trying to touch
and the most enduring.
War like that.
You have to hold on tightly.
You want to get out of the team?
l just want to believe
what we are doing.
We are chasing bad guys.
Yes, there are bad
people everywhere.
You want them to come to
San Diego or New York?
We not only protects
the sandy soil.
Okay. Let us kill him.
l was in the building next
door East facing restaurant.
Log. Come on.
Safe.
- Get down.
- Okay, okay.
Put your hands behind your head.
Target looks. l watched
the window, Chris.
- Create a safe limit.
- Well, let's get ready.
ln a corner.
Let's move to another room.
Your wife know? Do
you know this man?
She said she did not know.
How are you, son? Do
you know this face?
Are you sure?
Should you tell them
not to go till we go.
Hey, keep an eye window, make sure you taking
pictures of all the incoming and outgoing.
What we can?
16 military agents entered.
- 16?
- Yes, they serve many customers.
See this.
- He's still there?
- He had just entered.
- He's in there, but not easy to reach.
- l do not know about it.
They see the legend entry, him like
a celebrity, ask for his autograph?
They're partying?
Hey, l do not promote myself.
True, l did it for you.
- You're not going to be the
head if not for us. - True.
He invites you to dinner Eid.
He said on this day everything
have to sit down and eat with him.
He was really sweet.
Cucumber was put here?
Yes. This chili.
Soaked overnight.
Then just add vodka.
- That's the point.
- Just do it.
Well, the food is delicious.
That's a good question.
All these people.
Gosh.
You will eat with
your left hand?
Come on.
l want to wash your hands.
Hey.
He was clean.
Hey!
- Check it.
- Do not go anywhere.
- Hey, what is this?
- Beagles,
Calm.
See it?
- Did you see?
- What's up?
- Bring the tarp.
- Oh My.
Well, you tell him that
he would go to jail ,
in lraq, they know what
that would do to her ,
or she can help us look for
the man in the restaurant.
Tell him, it's his choice.
That's it.
Safe.
Good, let's move it.
Southern team ready.
Security ready right.
She moves.
15 meters.
10 meters.
5 meters.
He knocks.
Wait.
They open it.
l shoot.
Forward.
Forward!
Beagles, nothing
out of the back?
No, he did not move.
- D, put him down.
- Okay.
Put him down.
We found something,
carefully, remain vigilant.
Enemies come!
Back!
Outer side of security!
Get down!
There they are!
Butchers stir.
3 Butchers move, l'm chasing.
Butchers shot, to your position.
We've told him, it's his choice.
He chose the wrong
side, it's his choice.
Hey, Chris, Clean up all, we
go, things got messed up.
Sir, there are here, we
have to make a trail.
Good work, Richie.
- You want more?
- See what this is.
You can be the object was
given, it is how it works.
You can not get that one.
lt.
- lt was nice.
- Come on, we're ready.
- You can raise it.
- Ready troops.
lt is not possible.
Okay, interesting.
- That's for you.
- Okay.
What? Take from the floor.
Come take.
- Put that it's here.
- Excuse me, Sir.
- See?
- Here it is.
Purple.
- You're Chief Chris Kyle?
- Yes, Sir?
My name ments, you
saved my life.
- Really?
- Yes l Do.
We were stuck in the house, until you
come with troops, you who brought us out.
Marines often save us.
- What are you doing? You are okay?
- Okay.
l'm just thankful l'm alive.
- lt was not...
- Oh.
Not easy, well you know.
l was lucky to
only lose one leg.
- Your friends are also lost?
- Yes, they are.
But l'm talking about people who are
still alive , they managed to come back.
- They can not seem to live a normal life.
- Yes l Do.
Why did not you come to our place?
They will be happy.
They want to know about you.
- Yes, it seems like a good idea.
- Hey, friend.
Can l tell?
Father... A hero.
True. He saved my
life, and he...
He could go back to his son.
So, thank you for lend it to us.
- Okay. - l will not be
here if not for him.
Family is grateful
for your services.
Okay, thank you. Okay.
- Take care of yourself.
- Nice to see you again.
- Good.
- Sometime stop by the VA.
Okay. Okay. Take your lizard up there.
- Thank you. Have a nice day.
- You are welcome.
- Have a good day.
- Ok.
- Bye.
- Let's meet your sister.
Hey, sorry, it's time.
lt was my daughter, l think
you should take note him.
Excuse me.
Hey! Hey, where are you going?
Hey!
Hey! Please note my son.
Hey! Please note my son now!
l make my own memory.
l can not share it with anyone.
Well, it is.
When did it begin?
Even when you're here,
you're not here.
l see you, l feel you.
But you're not here.
l hate that team.
True.
You're my husband.
You're the father of my children,
but not their excuse back.
They can not wait,
we also can not.
lf you think this war not
change you, you're wrong.
You can just walk in circles.
That's right.
This Cadillac 31 we were to
follow the courier Butcher ,
we're on the road
Marylin, replace.
Hey, you can ring.
- Where? From here?
- Yes, cheaper here.
You buy it from the collector? How do
you know there is no blood in the ring?
What do you care? You killed
many here, you legend.
- Not to ring.
- What is the problem?
- lt's hypocritical.
- Slowly.
- Do not get too close.
- Okay, you tell him.
- You tell him where did you get it? - Of
course not, l would say l bought elsewhere.
Are you still with us?
Half a block in the back.
We are ready.
You know, D...
guess is 20 years
away at the reunion.
You're going to marry him.
As long as she can
cook and clean.
- There they are.
- Oh My.
They have people
all over the city.
They are the Al-Qaeda-like
everything.
Hey, next time if you could
shoot, not to fail, right?
l into the alley to save.
- So, you're going to be my companion?
- Who else?
There is only one companion.
Beacon 1 being fired!
- Come on, give me a shot of protection.
- Okay.
Let's move.
Safe.
Come with me.
We see them. Bacon safe.
Prepare security, Chris.
Well...
roof safe.
You're not afraid he would
release after she know?
Not. Prepare security.
- Now l'm a little concerned.
- lt should.
You mean she can keep
track of diamonds?
l think so.
Are you okay?
There were shot, Beagles shot.
Angle northwest, on the roof.
Hold on.
l need a medical today.
Okay, we will pick you
up and take you down .
Come on.
Come on, put him
into the Humvee.
- Lift him.
- Ok.
Quick .
Come on, get in. Hang
in there, Beagles.
Hold, Beagles.
- Calm.
- l am sorry.
For what? Why are
you apologizing?
- lt was my fault, we go up to the roof.
- l'm going to die?
No, Beagles. You Frogman.
Frogman not die. He would
put sand in the wound,
and enter the water, you're
fine, Beagles. Hold on.
Hey, Chris. Make sure
he can ring it, okay?
Course.
Raise suction.
Blood again. How much longer?
We need 3 units of blood.
Now.
- Vacuum.
- Put it here.
Press firmly!
The blood less quickly.
Did you see the shooter?
No, the distance is
1000 meters more.
No one can shoot that far.
- She will survive?
- He is being treated.
- That's not good.
- He was shot in the vitals.
Fuck!
We have to find that person.
The units are still
looking for that person.
l understand if you do not
want to continue and gather .
lt's up to you.
You're the leader.
Eye to eye.
We will be back.
- Good.
- Of course.
Come on.
l participated.
Hey!
2 kilometers to the south.
ln the left.
Hallway.
Hallway safe. On the left.
Safe.
Everything is safe.
Mark, there seems
to be a rush to go.
- Get down!
- Stay away from windows!
Stay away from the window!
Come on, Mark.
Come on, friends. l got you.
Look at me.
l was here.
Mark died, bro.
There are shot, l need
help immediately.
We have to move it.
Victory, some people after
him, and some people stumble.
Do not expect to find them.
But everyone...
good people stumble.
My question...
When did it disappear victory
and become a safety?
Or then it becomes...
The spending someone who l...
Love in the war.
And l saw...
Ready!
Lift arms!
Ready! Aim!
Shoot!
Ready!
Aim! Shoot!
Ready! Aim!
Shoot! Lower arms.
Mark wrote the letter
two weeks ago.
He told you?
Chris, l want to know what
you think about his .
Dinner was cold, and...
Beagles just been shot,
and we were ambushed.
But, is not that strange.
Letter was killed Mark.
He just... he died, and
he paid the price.
Signature here.
Hey, friend.
- Chris?
- Yes l Do.
- How are you?
- l'm here.
- Damn, you're blind as a bat.
- Yes, bullets jerk.
They said they
would fix my face.
Fortunately, we
tell them to fix .
Seriously.
- Too fast?
- Too fast.
- Hey, l heard you apply.
- Yes l Do.
Congratulations.
You did not tell him
that you buy diamonds
- in that place, is not it?
- Do Not.
- No?
- Do Not. l bought a new one.
- The smaller, and she likes.
- Nice One.
- Yes.
He will not leave me, bro.
l told him to go,
he did not want to.
He wants to be with me.
Why do you say that?
Do not say that, he loves you.
- She was in love with you.
-Are you kidding.
Yes, l'm glad l have it.
- l know you can handle it.
- Maybe you're right.
They say you deadliest sniper
in US military history.
- Really?
- That's what l heard.
- You heard them say that?
- Yes l Do.
- You're not going back.
- Yes, we will hunt him down.
- Come on, you do not need to do that.
- We have to do it.
You're my brother, and they had to
pay for what they've done to you.
How are you going to do?
There mad.
He survived.
He'll be fine.
He did apply.
Do you want to die?
lf that's what you want.
What?
Tell me.
Why did you do it? l
want to understand.
l do for you, l do
to protect you.
- No.
- Yes l Do.
l'm here. Here your family,
your children no father.
- l have to serve my country.
- That's nonsense!
- No.
- You do not know when to stop.
You've done yourjob, you're pretty
sacrifice, let someone else have a go.
- Let someone else go?
- Yes l Do.
- l could not live.
- You've got to find a way.
You should do it.
Okay? l want you
to be human again.
l need you here.
They need you here.
lf you go again...
l guess we will not be there
here when you return.
Chris.
We have 3 missions in a row.
lt would be worse.
- lt will be chaotic.
-Are you coming?
l think so.
His wife scolded him.
Once again my wife will kill me.
- True.
- They do not understand.
l went to the hospital
earlier, it was bad.
He was already dead, Chris.
He was operated on yesterday,
die on the operating table.
lt Taya, leave a message.
lt's me, just want
to hear your voice .
l think of things
that you say...
Tell the kids l love them .
l love you too.
Place.
Come on.
Look, they believe it will
be able to help us win war.
Problem engineers designed so as
not to be defeated by a sniper.
Where?
-Approximately 100 miles.
- There is something else?
- l do not know.
- Snipers will kill us.
He could be anyone. We
just have to kill him.
We've blocked 6 blocks from the
North region enemy, you will be in
front of the shooterjitunya.
- ln the middle of the desert storm?
- Bring your sunglasses.
We must kill the sniper.
Understand?
- Be prepared.
- Yes, Sir.
- Safe.
- Going down. Come on.
Come on.
Safe. The Way.
Everything is safe.
Building is safe.
There were coming. Hold shot.
ln the middle of a desert storm.
- Caution!
- Take cover!
Shit. The shot of the East.
We are in the wrong position.
Not important. Hold fire.
There are people below us.
There is a target at 19 yards.
l can not see that far. Hold shot.
We could get caught.
He's right, there's no point.
Correction, 21 yards.
More than 1 mile.
lmpossible to shoot, Chris.
That's it.
l've got a target, change.
Understandably, troops will
soon arrive in 20 minutes.
- He oversees our friends.
- Can you confirm?
That's it.
- There she is.
- Your decision, Chris.
Team will arrive within 20 minutes.
Hold shot.
You have to kill him.
This is very important.
Will l do.
He screwed us.
- Tango fall.
- We need help.
- Mission accomplished.
- He oversees our people.
- Kill him.
- Yes, now we are stuck.
He would be proud.
You did it, Chris.
Echo 7, there are near you.
White Side, damn.
Yes, let's go.
We will come down from the roof.
Save your ammunition.
Quick attack!
Quick ride!
Take cover!
Echo 7, no weapons
The Green Side.
We fired, White Side!
We have to move!
Do not stop shooting!
They will come.
- Where?
- Direction hours 3.
Only the remaining 1 clip.
Hang in there! Anyone
have ammunition?
We can not hold any longer.
We have to move!
- They stuck.
- We're heading down the road.
True, come on.
- Call them.
- We need help.
70837575. coordinates
- That position.
- l know, drop it!
Viper 34, ready to attack.
Viper 34, replace. 30 seconds.
Hello?
Darling?
Chris? Unfortunately,
l can not hear .
l'm ready.
l'm ready to go home.
What?
What happened?
l'm ready to go home, dear.
Chris?
Here is the danger. l
can not last long.
- Command pilot shoot.
- Viper 34, gunshot.
Missed.
Shit.
We have to move, hurry!
We have to move!
Echo 7, where are you?
We attack attack!
Down!
Come on! Fast!
Last person!
Let's get together!
Quick!
- Quick, quick!
- Up to the truck!
- Come on, we have to go!
- Let me help you, come on!
Way!
Where is Chris? She
had behind us.
Open the door.
Stop the truck!
Chris! Come on!
Hurry!
We will not leave you.
Earn hand, come on!
Chris! Come on, quickly!
Come ride!
- Yes?
- l can message you on the plane?
Yes. l came home early.
Really?
You're in Germany?
Not. l'm here.
Near here.
You've come home?
What are you doing?
l think it only took a minute.
Chris, children want to meet.
lt's been 9 months.
l'm going home.
Are you okay?
Yes.
Unfortunately, go home.
We miss you.
Okay.
Chris? Dear?
l'm going out.
Come on, higher.
See your face, dear.
Good. Looks different.
The game Tuesday.
He will be in the team.
That would be great.
Crazy, right?
l go crazy when seeing
other children.
You could be the coach.
He will lose teeth, l
am a little anxious.
He says only you are
allowed to withdraw it.
Will you do it?
Chris?
l can pull out of
your wife's phone.
She stories about barbecue.
That's a pity.
lt seems out of control.
Are you worried?
No, sir.
So you do not worry
about that happening?
No, sir. l do not
worry about it.
l want to ask you, Chris.
How long did you
serve your country?
- 4 mission, so...
-Approximately a thousand days?
Yes, sir.
You'll be surprised if l tell
AL note you kill more than 160?
Ever thought do not
want you doing there?
That's not me.
What about you?
l'm just protecting my friends. They
are trying to kill our soldiers.
l am willing to die
to protect them.
The problem l feel sad for the
people who could not l save.
l want to be there,
but l'm here, stop.
So you want to save
even more people?
Yes, sir.
You should go from here.
There are many soldiers
who had to be rescued.
- Want to take a walk?
- Sure.
Okay. l want to
show you something.
l still smoke, do not get angry,
because save my right hand.
How can it be?
When exploded, both hands
on the steering wheel ,
before it exploded,
my right hand
reached for a cigarette and put into my mouth.
When l turned it on...
explosion occurred.
Destroy entire left arm.
l'm lucky to have this.
My right arm injury,
but still there.
-And you still smoke?
- Yes l Do.
Missed. 3 inches to the right. Come
on, you can do better than that.
3 inches to the right?
lt is quite complicated.
Vibration surprise. Not
like shooting paper.
- You can not confuse me?
- Kenai only target.
- Kena.
- Right in the middle.
Shit, as had the courage back.
Why did you do it?
- l know you have a family.
- l hear you collect shoes.
l see we are the same size.
Really, why did you do it?
We look after each other, right?
Try shooting again.
Come on, you can.
- Kena.
- Nice One.
Shit.
Who is legend now?
You do not want that title.
Trust.
Help me.
-Again?
- Yes l Do.
- Bring into.
-All Right.
Come here.
Life here is not bad, right?
He smiled.
Looks happy.
Just do the habit.
Not think of the other.
Who is it?
- Dear! That you?
- Yes dear.
- What?
- l'm fine.
- Honey, l'm sorry. What happened?
- No problem.
You know about it, right?
Yes.
That's what we'll do
for the first time.
Okay.
Remember, you must be calm.
Confidence.
And do not hesitate.
-All right.
- There is a problem?
- l understand.
- You feel good?
Yes.
Hands, Miss.
Put your hands.
Put it.
Slowly.
- Honey, look at you.
- Look at you.
Can l say something?
Tell to judge.
No, l'm very proud of you.
l'm very proud of you,
you're a great dad .
l'm so glad my husband back.
l know it's difficult
for you to return.
Course.
Tell one thing, you beg for it?
Yes, ma'am. l beg of them.
- You're like a regular cowboy.
- Yes, that is true.
l do not worry about
anything, unfortunately.
l got 4 minutes.
- lt is only 4 minutes.
- No, only 2 minutes.
But l want to look
at you 2 minutes.
You're going to go there?
You're going to come out?
There marines.
l just want to help my mother.
l can do it. Just briefly,
l immediately returned.
- Make sure you... what?
- Dad.
l can not play now.
Later when l get home,
you've lv 8, l want to win.
- No.
-At bear.
-At what?
At bear.
Not! You should have roared.
Like what?
Well, do not they, okay?
- Yes.
- Great responsibility, are you ready?
See you later dear.
- l love you.
- l'll be right back.
How are you? Okay?
The journey of about 2 hours. Maybe
we talk for a minute there, how?
- Yes.
- Let's go.
Thank you.
Did you eat? Want
to buy something?
Try fun math aplication at google play store
http://tiny.cc/mathvstime