Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com
Get back inside! Get back inside!
Get back inside!
Hey! Don't be scared.
Don't be scared. They ain't gonna bite you.
Come back, little lost sheep.
I could be your shepherd.
Apollo 10 astronauts
Colonel Tom Stafford,
Commanders John Young
and Eugene Cernan
appear to be in excellent condition
after their splashdown
in the Pacific today.
They were picked up by
the USS Princeton...
Aw, poor little thing.
Long way from home.
Starving and dragging a suitcase
like a little baby chicken.
I'm not starving, sir.
I just had two hot dogs.
Oh, you want a third? Hmm?
I'm kidding.
You need somewhere to rest
your pretty little head
and collect yourself?
I happen to have a comfy little place
right around the corner.
No, I can wait. Thank you, sir.
Whoa, but I'm sure
they're worried to death.
I bet they're by the telephone
right this second saying...
"When will he call?"
Praying.
♪ The moment I wake up
♪ Before I put on my makeup
♪ I say a little
prayer for you ♪
Queen Tooey, leave him alone! Jesus!
You never stop, and you sound terrible.
Ray, darling, I sound just fine
for somebody who's had a
dick in his mouth all night.
Oops!
Girl, from the looks of you,
that's the least of your worries.
Listen up, kid.
Don't follow this one
unless you want to end up
tied to a chair and
smothered in pancake batter
or whatever that shit is.
- Coca-Cola, please.
- Yes, sir.
Have a nice day, boys,
and remember, don't talk to strangers.
Do you know him?
Her? Yeah, I know her.
Why did you call him Queen Tooey?
Because she goes into people's cabinets
and steals their Tuninal.
Beans? Jeebs? Downers?
Right.
Oh, baby, you don't know nothing, do you?
I know I don't want to be tied to a chair
and covered in pancake batter.
I don't know.
It could be fun. Sticky but fun.
I already got you all figured out, okay?
- Yeah? How's that?
- Hey, mama.
Let's see. Grew up in Kansas, right?
On like a pea farm or whatever.
Kissing goats and your
daddy was the preacher,
but secretly a little whoopsie, right,
and Mama probably baked apple pies
and, uh, wrote your name in your underwear
with tiny thread.
Okay, well, A, I'm from Brooktown, Indiana,
and B, I did not grow
up making out with goats,
and C, I'm here because I'm actually going
- to Columbia in the fall.
- Oh, Columbia.
That's right, and hang on,
what the hell is a pea farm?
Look, small details, baby.
Once you realized what you really were,
you had to run away from home
to find your ass and quick.
And what am I?
Well, you certainly didn't
come to Christopher Street
for the pizza.
I didn't run away from home. Kicked out.
Hey, look, run away, kicked out.
All that really matters
is now you're here, right?
And you don't know what is what.
Welcome to New York and keep up.
Yo, everybody. This here's Danny.
He's on his way to Columbia in the fall.
Danny, meet my little ladies of the night.
Queen Conga, straight off the boat
from some godforsaken island.
And this Beatle groupie
over here, that's Quiet Paul.
And the chicken bone is Little Lee.
What's up, man?
Hey.
Nobody gonna introduce me?
And this pathetic creature is Orphan Annie.
How long you been working the streets?
Annie, the boy just got
here. I mean, look at him.
Gee, he looks a lot like Justin.
I sure hope you don't end up like him.
What did you just say?
I didn't say nothing. I was just saying,
hope you don't end up like him.
Don't you fuckin' talk about
Justin, you little bitch!
Girls!
I'm the bitch? You're the bitch,
picking up a know-nothing,
white trash twink.
Just don't be talking about Justin, okay?
You gonna use it or not?
It's just too nice a day
to cut each other up, isn't it?
Blood, mess, tragically ruined outfits.
You fuckin' lucky bitch!
Yo, I'm starving. Is anybody else hungry?
- Moi!
- You wanna come?
Uh, no. I gotta, you
know, I got all this stuff.
Oh, Bob, will you take
his suitcase, please?
Yeah, of course.
It's cool. We take care of
his dog, he takes care of us.
Sure?
I'm upstairs. Just bring it
up to the top of the steps.
Okay.
Oh, now that's gorgeous!
What? That straw thing with the flowers?
Oh, I think it'll look nice on you, Annie.
Whoa!
Hey, what'd you do?
♪ We are the baddest girls
♪ We wear our hair in curls
♪ We wear no underwear
♪ We show our pubic hair ♪
Oh, shit! The law! The law!
Oh, I don't like that
coffee. I like Cavalier.
What's wrong? No, no, no.
Cavalier tastes like cat piss.
Chock Full o' Nuts?
Why can't we get both?
We can't afford both.
Why not?
Because Mama's in the hospital.
- My mom's in the hospital.
- Yes, she is.
And she's dying...
...of cancer.
Hey, I'm really sorry that your ma's sick,
but keep it down.
I got other customers.
Show a little respect.
Stop that!
You know what? From now on, you get...
Yes, you are. You get your
hot beverages on your own.
Anything else?
Barbra is a much bigger star.
Than Judy?
There's something so
broken about that junkie.
I like someone who ain't
gonna collapse any minute.
And that's Barbra.
Will someone please tell
this sticky, sugar-faced fool
that Judy's supposed to be tragic.
It's a part of her beauty.
In the Wizard of Oz,
man, she's just like us.
A girl just lost in a world
that don't understand her.
Midgets!
That is so true, my
little wretched darling.
I have so missed you!
Oh, she's back, the
Queen of Queens herself.
Danny, meet Marsha Johnson.
Marsha P. Johnson, if you please, darling.
What's the "P" stand for?
Pay no mind.
Marsha is the only drag
queen that's nice to us.
Those other nasty
bitches don't know one day
Jesus is gonna punish them for their sins
and fuck them up good!
Okay? Oh, shit! My
first appointment awaits.
It's a certain fat priest
who has to pray to Mary
as he comes.
Wait, wait, wait... Is he really fat?
Shit, I know him. Everybody knows him!
Now, Lee, you stay away from my regulars.
You don't want me to have to spank you.
Maybe I do.
Bye, girls.
Bye, lover.
Hmm.
Always on time.
By the way, Judy is not
that good of an actress.
All right, Danny Boy, I'm
gonna see you later, okay?
Mama's got to work. Bye, girls.
Don't do anything I wouldn't do.
Which is nothing, girl.
Bitch has got to book. You coming?
Mmm-hmm. No rest for the weary.
See ya later, Columbia.
But all homosexuals are not passive.
Public restrooms can often be
a hangout for the homosexuals.
Bobby and his friends
hadn't noticed the man
who had been in the
restroom when they changed,
and as it was late, he suggested
they take the shortcut
under the pier,
but the others preferred to take
the more traveled way home.
Bobby, run away from the
faggot behind you, Bobby.
Bobby had made a wise decision.
It may have saved his life.
Okay, kids.
These are the things
we have to be aware of.
You know there are sick people out there,
and they are waiting.
What is it that they do exactly?
Well, they're kind of like Count Dracula,
but instead of sucking your blood,
eh, they're sucking something else.
Nah, Trev, you got it all wrong.
A guy wears a dress,
the other guy takes that dress off,
and then they do it up the butt.
How do you know so much about it, Mattie?
Oh, Joe.
I still don't get it. Joe!
- Let's go!
- Sixty-eight!
Why you babies stopping back there?
Let's add 20 pushups.
On my whistle, Joe's gonna count 'em out.
One, two, three...
That's right, Joe. You set the pace here.
Keep going. Attaboy, Joe.
Come on, Danny. You gonna join us sometime
before 1970 rolls around?
Let's go.
Three, two. Come on, Danny, get up!
You never shower.
I never sweat. Some people don't sweat.
I'm one of 'em.
You around this weekend?
I can't be any easier on
you, Danny. I just can't.
You understand that, right?
Yes, Dad.
Hey, hey, hey!
For only 100 bucks?
Talk about taking advantage
of a little kid...
...who's a member
of a minority group.
I got it.
Coach Winters.
Who is this?
Dad, it's me. Can we talk, please?
I'm just calling 'cause I...
I hope you're still gonna
send in the papers for
my scholarship, all right?
You know that...
Dad?
Was that Danny?
I'm sorry, sir, but we're closed.
Can I just get a cup of coffee, please?
Sure.
Thanks.
Um, I don't suppose you're
hiring at the moment,
are you, sir?
Got any experience as a short order cook?
- No.
- Hi, everybody.
They all queers now.
It used to be poets and mobsters.
Now they just fags.
I'm real sorry, sir. Thank you.
Yeah, I'm actually late,
so I'm gonna head out now.
Good to see you.
- Be careful!
- As always!
Why, hello again, Mr. Danny.
Out for a stroll, are we?
No, no, I'm looking for Ray.
The new boys hang out a little further...
Yeah, how are you?
Hey, what's up? Yo, how you doing?
Hey, Ray? Ray!
Oh, shit.
Get out of my way!
Get out of here, God damn it!
You fuckin' faggots, move your ass.
Get out of here.
Get the fuck out of here!
You're disturbing my friends!
Get the fuck away from here.
You fucking cocksuckers!
What are you looking at, faggot?
Nothing.
Hey, where you going, cum stain?
He's pretty, yeah.
Oh, you're a pretty one, huh?
You wanna suck my dick?
I think he wants to suck your dick.
No.
- Come on.
- Suck his dick!
Suck his fuckin' dick!
Get in there right now.
Hey, hey!
Oh, shit! No! No!
She's got a temper, huh?
No!
Still got a temper, faggot? Huh?
No, no!
Stop. Stop!
You know what, I don't even want him
to suck my dick no more!
Look at his mouth. It's
all full of blood and shit.
That's disgusting.
Heavenly Father, we
thank you for this food.
For these and all your blessings,
God's holy name be blessed and praised
through Jesus Christ, our Lord, amen.
Amen.
They showed a film in school today.
We younger kids were not allowed to see it.
I wonder why.
Mr. Truman Capote,
who wrote In Cold
Blood, is also a homosexual.
Maybe that's why
I wasn't allowed to see that movie either.
Phoebe, we're having dinner, thank you.
Well, I also really want
to see Dr. Doolittle.
- He talks to animals.
- Hmm.
Maybe you should see that movie, Dad.
Maybe he could get you to talk.
You finding this amusing, Danny?
No, sir.
"No, sir."
Can I borrow your car tonight, Mom?
Joe wants me to hang out with him.
Don't be home too late.
I won't.
Brent, do you really think
it was such a good idea?
Sheriff Goodwin was great, honey.
He laid it all out.
I don't even think it's true,
and I don't know why you do.
There are signs,
and if you don't wanna see them,
that's fine, but I do.
This is WTTV FM,
rocking Brooktown all night long.
They're not gonna go, Joe,
I'm telling you right now.
Hey, Danny.
We're taking bets on who's
goin' to the World Series.
Joe picks the Mets.
Yeah, I guess.
See? He knows.
- Danny knows.
- Hi, Danny.
- Hey.
- Sarah got into Syracuse.
- Oh, yeah?
- Did you hear from Columbia?
Yeah.
Hey, about time you showed up.
Bye, guys.
I don't know. Danny's just weird.
He never wants to stick around.
Come on, babe. Let's go, too.
I gotta get the car back.
Okay. Bye, guys.
Hey.
God, that fuckin' film!
Yep. They were creepy-looking men.
Half the fuckin' faculty
look like those guys.
Joe, don't be stupid. He meant it for us...
At least he meant it for me.
He even dragged poor Sheriff Goodwin along,
telling me he was on to us.
Hey.
I can't wait to get out of this place.
Joe, wait. Wait, wait! Wait, wait!
What?
Do you think we're sick?
It's just nothing. It's not anything.
Cool it!
We're just fooling around.
Sarah won't do anything.
You don't even have a girlfriend.
It's more than that. I just...
I really like you, Joe.
Don't fucking say that.
This is just for now.
We're not faggots.
Just relax, Danny. Relax.
Looks like our Johnny Boy
didn't take his girl right home, huh?
A little stopover first.
A little bit of hanky-panky, man.
Excuse me.
Matt, where you going?
Shh!
Where are you going?
Going to surprise them.
Oh, no!
What was that?
Don't be a stranger!
Ray? Ray!
Hey, Columbia.
Wait!
Wow, nice digs.
Where you been?
I was away for a while.
Yeah?
The fuck happen to you?
Nothing. I've been lookin' for you.
Nothing?
Nothing will do that, all right.
Come on.
Where we going?
What, you got a better option?
No.
Hurry up!
What took you so long?
What are you waiting for?
You're handsome!
It's okay.
Listen, this is only temporary
because we could find a real place
'cause I just made some real money.
I got a cousin.
He went to pharmacy school in California.
You know, where Judy and Liza and Lorna,
they live there with a lot of palm trees.
You could go to pharmacy school, too.
I can't go because I'm not smart like that,
but I can make a nice home.
I could clean. I could
cook arroz con pollo.
I could drive to the
supermarket in our Chevrolet,
and I could buy groceries.
It'll be so nice.
Would you like that?
Danny?
Good night.
Daniel, the Coach wants
to see you right away.
Joe...
I know everything.
Don't bother denying it. Joe told me,
and I'd seen it coming, too.
The sickness...
You, seducing him,
taking the lead.
Oh, it's such a great way to attack me
and ruin my quarterback.
You got him drunk so
he wouldn't even realize
what was going on.
I wanna do the right thing, Danny.
You need help, son,
and we're gonna get you that help.
I need you to look me in the eye, Danny,
and tell me you need help.
This is a one-time thing, Danny.
Look at me.
Say it!
This is a one-time thing, Danny. Say it!
Your father called.
Please don't go, Danny!
Hey, hey, hey!
Please don't leave, Danny, please. Please.
Phoebe, look, I have
to, all right? I have to.
They said all these mean things at school.
I just had to get out of there.
I know, I know. You're
smarter than them, right?
They're gonna keep saying those things,
but you're not going to
believe them, are you?
No.
Look, I'm going to write you, okay?
I'm going to write you every single day.
I promise you, every single day.
Where do you want to go?
I'm going to go to New York maybe.
I'll come with you. I...
I can come with you. Please.
Oh, Phebes, you know you can't.
Cricket, you know you can't.
Come on.
Joe.
What do you want?
Joe, it's me.
Why did you lie about us?
You should go, Danny.
Please, just go!
Joe, who was that?
Asshole, we're trying
to get our beauty sleep.
Open up!
Someone answer the goddamn
fuckin' door, please!
Look, mister, you're
going to have to give us
a few more hours.
We're working girls in here, you know that.
No. You gotta get out.
I know what's going on.
There's at least a dozen
of you guys in there.
Oh, come on, mister.
We're gonna be really nice
to you, aren't we, girls?
I could be nice, but I don't want to.
We'll pay for tomorrow.
If you guys are not out
of here in half an hour,
I'll call the police.
You heard the bitch.
Fuck! It's a brand new
day, bitches. Wake up.
Mmm. Mmm.
What?
No, nothing.
Oh? College boy has a problem?
This weekend, I'll go
dancing at the Stonewall,
and I wanna look just
right when I'm dancing.
You look right now, mama.
I want to shine, bitches.
- You're shining, mama.
- Mmm.
So you just take whatever you want?
Yeah. That's right, farm boy.
I take whatever I want
and can 'cause if I didn't,
I'd have nothing at all.
That might be a lesson you wanna learn
before you go to college, okay?
'Cause the truth is,
you ain't going nowhere
other than the street,
just like the rest of us.
Everyone in this room thinks
they're on their way to somewhere better,
but I have not seen one dream come true
on Christopher Street, baby.
Not one.
And my dream has always been
to have this shade of red,
and bitches, I got it.
Nah. Look, there's nothing we can do.
We don't have the documents
from your folks, Mr. Winters.
But I'm still admitted, right? So...
Yeah, I can hold your place
until June, July maybe,
but after that...
I mean, there's kids on
the waiting list, right?
May I ask why you're incomplete?
I had to leave early for personal reasons.
Look, when a kid comes into
my office in this situation,
I say, do everything you can to graduate.
The City of New York
will let you do it here
at night for free, right
here at the college.
Night school.
And then you can come here in the fall,
scholarship intact and
even have somewhere to live.
- Frankie!
- Look.
I can't have you and half a dozen of
underage hustlers here.
Half a dozen? That seems
like the least amount
of hustlers you need, Frankie, baby.
Now I know some of your clientele
might come in for your
watered-down drinks,
but the only cock and tail
they stay for, honey, is ours.
Tata!
Ladies and gentlemen,
please address me as Queen Conga.
Do you like it?
Oh, yeah. No, it's beautiful,
except I think I've seen that
fabric before, Queen Conga...
- Oh, really? Mmm.
- ...but where? Mmm?
Oh, country mouse is learning
how to talk like a city girl.
- Sure is.
- Ah!
It's impolite to keep Her Majesty waiting.
Come on, Frankie, be a dear.
Ooh!
Follow me, boys!
What you waiting for? It's fun.
Hello, darling. Two tickets, please.
Look, you gotta sign in.
Don't use your real name.
This shithole is run by the mob.
They don't got a liquor license.
What do you mean, this
place is run by the mob?
Oh, listen, bitch. Don't
you know that selling alcohol
to us sexual deviants is illegal?
That's why these greasy
fucktards and bastards
own almost all the gay
bars in the Village. Mmm.
Nobody likes us, baby.
Plus, they got the drugs,
the pills and the booze.
Smart, smart businessmen.
Yeah, very smart, indeed.
I don't wanna know how
much y'all spend a week
paying off the cops, too.
Thanks, Frankie.
Voila!
Here. She'll make you feel good.
This way, Mr. Wayne.
Looking for me, Ray?
You see, now this is what
we need more of around here.
All-American kids,
clean-cut kids,
not gutter trash like you, Ramona.
What's your name, kid?
- I'm Daniel.
- Daniel?
Such a nice name.
Leave him alone, Ed.
Just a second.
Danny.
Look, whatever you do,
just avoid that guy, okay?
He used to be a wrestler.
Now he's into pimping
out little boys like you.
- Hey, you listening to me?
- Yeah, I heard you.
They don't call him
The Skull for no reason!
Skull. Right, right, right.
Come on.
Hector, two sunshines.
Hello, Danny, dear.
What do you think of this
nasty little gay place?
Cute, isn't it?
- Yeah.
- You're lucky.
People in New York like a
straight-looking boy like you.
You can do very well down here.
I need to go to the ladies' room.
No.
Don't drink the nasty booze here.
They don't have running water.
We'll be getting hepatitis.
They don't have running water?
Take the beer. It's in a bottle.
Oh.
You got a quarter, mama?
Only for you, honey.
Light me up!
Do you like my shoes, darling?
They were on sale at Lord & Taylor.
Take this.
Freshly cleaned and only smells of me.
You wanna change?
No, I'm okay. Thank you.
Forget it!
Come on, Danny, dance with me.
- Dance with me!
- Hey, I don't wanna dance.
What? Are you ashamed to dance with me?
No. I just don't feel like dancing. Okay?
Okay. Maybe later.
What the fuck?
Hey.
Hi.
I'm Trevor.
I'm Danny.
You know, you look like
you need a little rescuing.
Maybe just a little.
So, um, this particular shithole
does not look like Danny's natural habitat.
Now that is a very interesting picture.
If I were to ask you to dance with me,
despite this being a particular shithole,
what would you say?
Um, no, really. I'm a terrible dancer.
I mean, my little sister,
she's always telling me
I dance like Frankenstein's monster.
Come on, Danny.
Okay.
All right.
What's wrong? Why you so sad?
Who's that guy?
His name is Trevor.
He's very political.
And he clearly has money.
- Mmm.
Maybe your Danny Boy has found his way
without your help after all.
Mmm.
So if you hate this place so much,
what are you doing here?
I'm writing an article about the Stonewall.
You're a writer?
No, I'm a member of the Mattachine Society.
What's that?
We're an organization
that fights for gay rights.
Take Stonewall, for example.
You know it's run by crooks
who rip off and poison gay men.
We deserve the right to own our own clubs.
Just relax.
- All right, it's a raid!
- Fuck!
Let's go! Up against the wall.
- Come on. Get back.
- All right, ladies.
You know the drill, huh? IDs, please.
Get in a line up against the walls.
This'll all be over in a second.
They only arrest the trannies.
It's the "three article of clothing" rule.
They're also gonna arrest the dykes
because they're wearing men's clothes.
This is what we're fighting
against, this bullshit.
No, no. You stay right there, okay.
You should come to one of our meetings.
Around the corner on Christopher Street.
I'll be seeing you, Danny.
Let's see some IDs here.
Ray. Ray.
If any of you Lily Law girls wanna dance,
well, here I am.
Ten cents a dance.
For all men in uniforms...
Out of here. Let's go.
Life is free!
Hey, ain't your mother
never teach you no respect?
Jesus, God!
What a fuckin' disgrace you are.
More than you?
I know y'all pigs get paid off
every time you raid this place.
I probably paid for all
of your kids' Christmas presents.
Oh, Jesus Christ!
Fuck, man!
You fuckin' mention my kids, huh?
Officer!
Well, mister,
I actually only have
one item of clothing.
I made it myself.
Isn't it gorgeous?
Get this bitch out of my sight!
Get your hands off me!
I want everybody's ID
or everybody's cuffed.
I want some ID right now.
Get out of here. I want some ID!
Fuck! Danny! Ow!
Shit!
- Ray!
- Danny!
- You wanna go, too?
- Okay, okay.
Fairy queens of Sheridan Square are here.
Just my fuckin' luck.
Hi, Sam.
No sign of Murphy.
Somebody tipped him off.
Maybe.
Who's that guy?
- Fields?
- That sergeant out of the 6th.
He's a good man.
Is he?
Well, that'd be a new one
because the information I have
is the whole fuckin' precinct is rotten.
Keep an eye on him.
- Here.
- Thanks.
Why are they doing this?
I don't know, Sam,
but it's getting very, very predictable.
What else is there but to
enjoy the parade, right?
Enjoy it? I can't get arrested.
I have kids. I have a husband.
Fuck!
You don't know what you're
fuckin' talking about!
Sir, sir!
What precinct are they going to?
Sir?
Jesus Christ! Come on! Get off of me!
Hi, mommy!
Hmm.
Oh!
You okay?
Jesus, Jack. We do the raids.
This our... This is our gig.
Who's this Pine anyway?
Look, he's new. He's
a total straight arrow.
Yeah, just our luck, huh?
Hey, hey! That's my lipstick.
Get your pig hands off
my lipstick, motherfucker!
It ain't no deadly fuckin' weapon, bitch.
Can you spare a cigarette for a lady?
Start with this one.
Interpol has asked us to
look into the Stonewall.
This dump?
Yeah. Apparently some
bonds disappeared from
the Federal Depository,
then they appeared somewhere in Europe.
Interpol thinks that Ed's got some of those
nelly Wall Street boys, who hang out here,
by the balls and he's squeezing them.
It's a fuckin' sewer,
and you're up to your neck in it, Walt.
Don't blow smoke in my face.
Look, you cooperate with me,
you'll be out of here in a few minutes.
That's new.
I need to know about Ed Murphy.
Who?
Hey, you know exactly
who I'm talking about.
Has he asked you to be bait?
Bait? Like for fishing?
Can we skip the cute part?
You know what happens
to kids who play dumb?
What?
You know this kid?
- No.
- Justin Blake,
17 years old from Port
Jefferson, Long Island.
A frequent customer at the Stonewall
and a very desirable piece of hustler ass,
wouldn't you say?
What happened to him?
This.
Now we think that's Ed Murphy's handiwork.
One of the tricks he was
running out of the bar.
So what do you need me for? Go get him.
What do you know about this?
I told you. I don't know nothing.
You're fuckin' lying to me
'cause I can see it in your eyes.
What are you protecting?
This guy's a piece of shit.
He kills kids.
Help me.
Help me, please!
What the fuck is wrong with you people?
Are all of you just stupid,
is that part of being gay?
No!
But getting fucked up by
the cops sure seems to be.
I know. I'm sorry.
You can go.
Here's my card,
if you decide to remember anything.
Go.
Oh, no, I'm not talking to you.
At all.
I just waited a whole night for you.
Oh, she waited all night.
How Cinde-fucking-rella!
What have I done?
You danced with that guy?
Don't think I don't
know anything about him.
His name is Trevor, and he likes to impress
little boys like you with his politics,
when all he really wants to do is fuck you.
God, are you jealous?
- Oh, please!
- Come on!
He's so smooth. He's so smart.
You know what I learned about smart people?
They care about one thing, themselves.
Hey, come on.
All right. I'm sorry I
danced with him, all right?
Yeah.
How about I buy us breakfast?
We'll go to Big Daddy's.
Look, I got more than $5 left.
I never noticed you were such a rich man.
You can have whatever you want.
Baby, you know that's not true,
but it's sweet that
they raise boys in Kansas
to be such gentlemen.
Yeah, right. Yeah, in
Kansas they do. Right.
You do know who the most important person
in Kansas is now? Dorothy.
Dorothy Gale.
From the Wizard of Oz?
Jesus! You don't know nothing, do you?
So, we will be meeting
here three nights a week,
same time,
and at the end of this,
you will receive three
credits towards your diploma.
If you should miss three classes,
you will be automatically failed.
Any questions?
Lee.
Who's that?
He, uh, he wants you.
What? What do you mean?
Well, he fancies you, man.
He's one of my regulars.
Didn't you say you're out of cash?
- Here's your chance.
- Come on, man.
Oh, no, man. No. Come on! That's not my...
- I don't do that, man.
- His name is Jack.
He's an accountant with a wife
and a bunch of kids, all right?
Now I told him that you're
new and it's gonna be $25,
but he's gonna try to get
you to settle for less,
- just don't let that happen.
- Twenty-five?
Yeah, man. He's just gonna
suck you off. That's it.
Look, it's nothing, okay? Just go!
Have fun, man.
Hey. I'm Danny.
Nice to meet you. I'm Jack.
Jack, do you think maybe I could have
my money first, please?
- Your money?
- Yeah.
Oh, yes. Sure.
It was 15, right?
No, Lee said 25.
Oh, yeah.
Thanks.
Hey, Danny.
Here.
Still hanging out with your
little street gang, huh?
What have you got against them?
Nothing. It's just...
You don't seem like the type of guy
who wants to hang out at the Stonewall
and turn tricks with your girlfriends.
You know, wearing red
lipstick, nail polish.
Well that's because red's not my color.
They've been better friends
to me than most of the people
I thought were my friends my whole life.
That's 'cause you didn't
have the right friends.
Come to the meeting.
We got shitty coffee, crappy cookies.
Ray?
Oh, Jesus! What happened?
Who did this to you?
What do you mean, "Who did this?"
If you're lucky, they pay you for it.
Stop tricking, Ray.
And then what?
What?
Tell me!
You wanna know where home is for me, Danny?
Nowhere.
There is no home. There
is no family, Danny.
All there is,
is some guy in fuckin' Sing Sing
who might be my dad,
and I don't know where my mom is.
My sister, she's in foster care,
and I got a dead grandma in Ponce.
Happy fuckin' family!
What the fuck am I supposed to do, Danny?
Nobody wants me!
Nobody!
Not even you!
I don't have anything!
So what...
So what if I fuckin' get
beat up every now and then?
Who the fuck doesn't?
A faggot is always going to
get beat up, Danny, even you.
Either from another faggot,
or from a cop,
or from a trick,
who's got something to prove.
No big deal.
Maybe I can look, you know?
Maybe I can look and see if I
can find us something better.
Why do you care?
Because you're my friend.
What?
I'm sorry.
Come here.
Come here. Come here. Shh! Shh!
I'm tired.
- Wake up!
- What? What?
So, did he give this to you?
No, some other guy gave it to me.
Why are you lying to me?
What?
Oh, give it a rest, Ray, please.
You know, Danny,
you're turning out to be
a real New York cocksucker.
Learning how to lie before
you even get dressed!
What the fuck was that?
More and more we are
seeing that homosexuals
will no longer tolerate
discrimination.
People will recognize
that gay is good.
The American people
will start to understand
that firing us for being
gay is just plain wrong,
and that is the day
we are working for.
But we have to fight
in a peaceful way
and resist the radicalism
that I see starting to
take hold in some quarters.
Don't forget,
wearing a suit and tie
will make them understand
you're just like them...
That's how we win!
With the new appointments to the Court,
we're pretty optimistic
that the right action
in the right jurisdiction
might actually get us a little
closer to where we want to go.
Um, excuse me.
Do you mind if I ask you a quick question?
Not at all.
Um, you're an astronomer, right?
By training, yes, I am.
I'm actually going to Columbia in the fall
and was hoping to do the same thing,
and maybe end up at NASA.
I was wondering if you
might have some advice or...
They fired me.
You can't be a homosexual
and work for the government.
You're going to have
to find something else.
We're not there yet, I'm sad to say.
Sorry. But we will be.
It's a long journey, a long road.
Right. Thank you, sir.
Thank you.
Hey, Danny.
Thanks for coming.
Yeah. It was great.
I mean, aside from being told
that what I want to be in life
isn't available to me because I'm gay.
Sure. That's what we're trying to change.
People like Frank Kameny
have been fighting this battle for years.
No one has done as much
for our cause as he has.
What, by wearing a suit and tie?
Come on!
Is that really what you want?
To blend in?
I mean, we are different, right?
You know, I'm beginning to realize
just how different we really are.
Yeah, like wearing a dress
and prancing up and
down Christopher Street?
Hey, it takes a lot more
balls to wear a dress
than it does a suit and tie.
What would you have me do, huh?
Be a fuckin' florist or decorator?
Come on!
What, are these the options open to me?
Of course not.
You know, I'm getting to really feel like
I just want to break something, you know?
Me too.
But you're not gonna, are you?
Ever.
Look...
Why don't you let me buy you some dinner?
I don't know about you,
but I'm starving. Come on.
My folks are liberals,
or maybe I just outwitted them.
You outwitted them. What did you tell them?
Let me get this straight.
Your version of fairness and equality
ends with who you sleep with?
That's nuts.
So every family dinner,
I just threw it at them
until they surrendered.
That's how you do it.
- With words.
- Wow.
I mean, my family is like,
"He's turned to a pillar of salt."
Danny, you can't let them shame you.
I miss them so much,
especially my little sister, you know.
All of that just taken away
from me because I got caught.
With some guy?
No, not some guy.
I've known Joe my whole life.
I was in love with him.
You know, when we got busted, he just...
Turned his back on you.
Yeah... And you left.
Why didn't you fight back?
Do you know anything
about life in a small town
and what happens to you
when you suddenly become disgusting?
You will never be disgusting,
and I really wanna know everything.
Everything about you.
Hey.
I don't want you to go.
Look, I know this is sudden,
but you need a safe place to stay.
Why don't you just stay here, with me?
You know, for a little while.
You still drunk, or are
you just talking shit?
No.
You can get a job,
start paying me some rent
so it doesn't feel weird.
Look, Danny.
Something happened to me when
I saw you at the Stonewall.
I kind of fell into deep water.
So stay, okay?
Winters' residence.
Danny?
Are you still in New York?
Yes, Mom. Look, I called for Phoebe, okay?
Are you all right?
I pray for you, every day.
I don't need you to pray for me, Mom.
I need you to sign my goddamn
scholarship application
and send it in, all right?
That will be a lot
better than prayers.
Can you please just get Phebes, all right?
Phoebe, it's Danny on the phone.
Danny, Danny! Hold on.
Got it?
Trevor Nichols.
Okay. Got it.
So how's it going, Phebes?
Mom and Dad are fighting every day.
I stopped talking to either one of them.
I just can't wait
to get out of here.
I miss you so much.
Hey, have you met Jacqueline
Kennedy Onassis yet?
Or Andy Warhol?
Yeah. No, we have lunch
every other day, stupid.
Look what the cat dragged in.
Hey, guys.
So I just want to tell you
all that, um, I got a place
or somewhere, you know,
to live for a little bit.
Where?
It's Trevor's place.
Oooh, honey, honey, me oh my!
Columbia's leaving us for good.
Danny Boy's found himself a nice, rich,
smart sugar daddy.
Look, you only been here
for like two months, right?
Damn! A quick learner, right, girls?
Maybe you could teach me a trick or two.
Why are you such an asshole?
No! I'm proud.
Baby, you played it right,
moving your little country boy ass indoors.
And what's wrong with that, huh?
Well, like your life is so great, Ray?
Getting beat up all the time
and blowing guys in doorways?
Yeah! A life of excitement, baby!
You know, the last time I saw you,
you were begging me to
get out of this life.
Let me tell you something, hmm?
The difference between
us, I don't have a choice,
and you just wanted a little time
with someone in the streets.
What, so tricking was just
an adventure in your story?
I know what this is, this
is a little funny story
about Ray and Lee and
Paul and Cong and Annie.
Funny fuckin' story, isn't it?
Let's go!
I guess I need my stuff.
- Are you sure about that?
- Yeah, I'm sure!
I can't sit in the park like you all day
watching the world go by, can I?
Fuck! I'm sorry. I didn't mean that.
I was rude. I'm sorry.
Yes, but like a lot of rude
things, very, very true.
You were in the Navy?
South Pacific.
I was 18.
You had to be a total dick
not to serve in that one.
But Vietnam, wouldn't go near it.
Oh, thanks.
Yeah, I thought about enlisting
when my parents kicked me out.
You know, just to spite them.
You're damn lucky you didn't.
Look, Ray started tricking in
Times Square when he was 12.
This isn't him being mean to you.
He just loves you, is all.
And love isn't always pretty.
They should put that on a poster.
He'll get over it.
Eventually.
Every guy has to get over
being in love with someone
who can't love him back.
What makes you so sure that's what it is?
I know the look.
He just needs friends, is all,
and if he can stick the
endless goddamn abuse,
he'll be there for you, Danny.
Hi.
Hey.
And he is...
Danny, Terry.
Terry, Danny.
- Hi.
Staying for dinner?
I'm making spaghetti and meatballs.
Wait, sorry. You guys live together?
- Uh-huh.
- Yeah.
Haven't killed each other yet,
even though this is a storage facility
for every street kid below 14th Street.
And he loves you a lot
more than he loves me.
Yep, sure do.
Mmm-hmm.
'Cause you're so square.
How long have you...
Put up with this bullshit?
Almost four years.
Stay for dinner. We, uh, love company.
That just sounds just great,
but I gotta be somewhere.
Thanks, Bob.
It was real nice meeting you.
Nice meeting you, too.
Judy Garland
entertained an entire
generation of Americans,
but sadly she is dead
at the age of 47.
Her body will be flown
from London to New York
- for a funeral Friday.
- Hey!
Guess what?
Your boyfriend is working
at the Italian grocery store.
How do you know that?
'Cause we saw him there.
Baby, you want a plum?
So you got a lady's stocking in a size one
or is that on the other floor, miss?
No, all right.
What about a Puerto Rican Koko Blanco bar?
What do you want, Ray?
I just need a pack of cigarettes, Danny.
Look, I wouldn't ask. I'm sorry.
It's an emergency.
Ray, I've had this job
for two weeks, all right?
Danny, Judy just died.
Judy who?
Garland!
- Oh, shit. I'm sorry.
- In London.
They're flying her body
over to Frank's Mortuary
on the Upper East Side.
I mean, I'm going to go
pay my respects and...
I'm sorry, man.
You won't even give me
a pack of cigarettes?
Look, Ray, I cannot
lose this job, all right?
I got rent and stuff to pay now.
Okay? Oh, come on!
You just gonna walk away from me like that?
It's people like you, Danny,
who misunderstood Judy.
You know, you misunderstand people like me,
but that's okay.
That's okay. Don't worry about it.
Go pay your rent. Talk to your boyfriend.
Do what you gotta do. Forget it.
Have a nice one.
Hey!
Wait there.
Sorry, sir. Can I get a pack of Dorals?
- There you go.
- Thanks.
Can I please get menthol?
I'm really stressed out. I...
A pack of menthol, please.
Thank you.
Thank you. I...
I miss you guys, okay?
Really?
Of course I do!
Good!
Hey, Trevor. I got a letter from Phoebe.
And there's also some stuff here for you.
From a bank or something.
Hey, Trevor?
Her transition
into adulthood was troubled.
Despite being loved by generations,
she lived a difficult
and often tormented life,
struggling with emotional problems
and drug addiction.
Miss Garland was hoping
to stage a comeback
and regain her
happiness and stardom.
Unfortunately now,
that will never happen.
Hey, Stevie, can I get a beer?
Oh, it's so hot.
Oh. Well, hello, hello.
Well, hello yourself.
So we are going dancing after all.
Yeah, one day, all right?
You just keep trying.
You owe me the first dance.
Everything okay, honey?
Yeah, yeah. Fine.
Give me a minute.
Danny!
- Daniel!
- What?
I'm sorry.
I bit off more than I could chew.
Look, it was a mistake to...
To what? What, to lie to me?
God, you know, you're just
a lot of fuckin' words.
You know that?
God, I hate this fuckin' city!
Stupid, fuckin'...
- Go, business.
- Say, Bob.
Bob?
You seen Ray?
No. You okay?
Yeah.
Want me to take care of that for you?
Listen, could you, uh, when you see him,
could you tell Ray I said goodbye?
- Yeah.
- And thank you.
You, too.
You know, you've both been...
You've both been real nice.
Where you gonna go?
Fuckin' Army's looking
pretty good right now.
Don't do anything stupid, Danny.
He might be over at Big Daddy's.
Come on.
Hey!
What...
Shut up!
Danny! Hey, hey!
Hey!
Wait here.
Relax, kid.
This is Danny.
He's the guy what you
gents were asking for.
It's not like you ain't
done this before, kid.
Just do whatever they ask.
Please, have a seat.
Let's have some music, shall we?
Would you like something to drink?
Um...
Campari.
Hey. What did you do with him?
Get the fuck out of here.
Oh, but I know all about
you and little Georgina Vee.
I mean, George Vasquez.
Maybe I should spread the news,
see what happens.
A faggot club owner and
a driver for the mob.
I give it a day.
I see you've been given a drink.
Good.
Danny, right?
A nice American name.
Like Scott or Justin.
I, uh, I wish I could live
in New York, but my work...
I have to tell you my work is very hard.
Leaves very little time for pleasure.
I was in the bedroom
watching The Lucy Show
and she was struggling so hard
to put the candies in the box.
And I understood,
I understood that
metaphor because that's me.
I'm always working so hard,
putting the candies in the box.
Do you know the Bible, Danny?
Mmm-hmm.
Anything from the New Testament?
- Yeah.
- Ahh.
The Book of John.
"You are my friends if you
do what I command of you."
John 15:14.
Ahh. And I am a good friend, Danny.
I am a very good friend to nice young boys.
We have to leave.
I can't go like this.
Danny! Danny!
What the fuck are you doing here?
What, you didn't notice
there was a fire, man?
Stop kidding around.
Just get me out of here.
Come on, come on. This way.
Taxi! Taxi! Whoa!
Hey, taxi. Hop in.
Christopher Street, Sheridan Square.
He had a fuckin' gun, Ray.
This will not go away, Danny.
We gotta make a deal with him.
You're gonna make a deal that...
How do you want to do that?
I'll handle it, okay?
How long have they been in there?
About half an hour.
Half an hour. Should I be worried?
Nah. Those girls are vice cops.
They can handle themselves.
Keep it.
- Frankie...
- Who's that kid?
Where is he? Where is he?
He's in the back.
Okay. You guys just stay here, all right?
I got a call about a fire alarm
and you running out,
like some thief in the night.
You go back there
and you finish that fuckin' trick.
He's not going back there, Ed.
What the fuck is this, hustler love?
Why do all you guys
gotta be such romantics?
How about I go to the cops and I tell them
you were the last person with Justin?
'Cause that would be
the dumbest fuckin' idea
you ever had, and probably your last.
All I'm saying is let Danny go.
Everybody knows, Ed.
The cops are on to you.
They can't lay a finger on me.
Come on. Get off him.
Now you play close attention to me.
You get your faggoty ass
and you get back to that fuckin' trick.
He likes you. You're lucky.
Let's do this.
All units, we're moving in.
Roger.
Let's go! Let's go either way.
Police. We're taking the place.
But you guys did us a couple days ago.
I'm aware. That was the 6th.
I don't take payoffs. I'm Morals.
Why do I get the impression
you just don't fuckin' get it?
All right. This is a raid.
All right. Let's go. Up against the walls.
Ed. Raid.
We just had a fuckin' raid!
Where the fuck is the backdoor key?
I'm not finished with you fuckin' faggots.
Get out your false IDs.
Come on, ladies. I don't have all day.
- I got that.
- Mmm.
Let's see some ID, come on.
- You okay?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Come on, let's get out of here.
Get out your IDs. Let's go!
All right, girls. Pull them IDs.
Come on, open up those wallets.
Well, look who it is.
The elusive, untouchable Mr. Murphy.
Guess what? You're under arrest.
Really? What are the charges?
You really want me to go
through all of them with you
right now in front of these nice people?
Yes, I would like that, yeah.
I don't have the fuckin'
time. Put up your arms.
You're hurting me, handsome.
Not so rough, mister.
Hey, Miller. Stop.
Jack, handcuff these two together.
Really? What the fuck are you doing?
Trying to be a hero or something?
Mr. Murphy, some girls look good in Chanel.
But you look perfect in a
pair of nice shiny handcuffs.
Shut the fuck up, will you?
Let's go! Get out of here.
All right, ladies. Let's go. Come on.
I said, not so rough.
Come on. Let's go. You
got IDs, you can leave.
You can go.
Hello, hello!
Our lovely Annie!
Dressed from the Raggedy Ann collection.
Work the runway, girl.
What a fuckin' circus.
And Paul in a fabulous suit by Givenchy.
Next up, Queen Conga coming to the rescue
in her backpack day look.
Work the runway, mama.
Little Lee Boy up in his Jimmy
Dean tres boy realness,
and last, our Danny Boy,
straight off the runway from
the Ken Doll summer line.
Available only at Boy Toys "R" Us.
Looks like you're going down, Eddie.
I thought I told you to shut the fuck up.
All right. Put 'em inside.
Back up.
This is an unlawful assembly.
You will all be arrested.
Back up.
Go home.
If you stay here,
we're gonna arrest you.
What's going on?
Another raid.
Who's the lucky lady?
All, go home.
Get your fuckin' hands off of me!
Fuck off! Fuck you!
No! Fuck off!
Fuck off! Don't touch me.
No! No!
Okay, okay.
Fuck you! Fuck you!
No! No! Get the fuck off!
Get your fuckin' hands off of me!
Hey, hey! Hey!
No, no! Fuck off!
Why are you all just standing there?
Fuckin' help me!
You follow me.
Get me out of here!
- Let's go.
- Get me out of here!
All right, everybody. Back off.
Move away from the car.
- You will be arrested.
- Hey!
Are you taking me on a date, Mr. Murphy?
Taxi!
Hey, hey! Murphy's getting away!
Get away from the car.
Ray, Ray, Murphy's getting away!
Stop! Stop!
Back off and get away
- from the car.
- Did you see that?
Huh? Right there!
Why wouldn't you do anything?
What's going on out there?
Murphy got away.
We just took him out of here
and put him in a fuckin' paddy wagon.
- What happened?
- I guess you're right.
I guess he's got the 6th in their pocket.
You gotta take a look outside.
Every fag in New York is out there.
Jesus fuckin' Christ!
Why won't you do anything?
You fucks!
Look at these asses.
They're all the fuckin' same.
Where did all these people come from?
I told you.
This is gonna get out of hand really fast.
You mean the 6th just fuckin' left?
I've had it with this bullshit!
Oh, no, no, no!
No, no! Cong, you're gonna make it worse.
How can it get worse?
Between the mob
and those fuckin', money grabbing pigs,
a society hating and oppressing us
for being gay, and you
still wanna be polite?
'Cause it's gonna take away your precious
fuckin' scholarship if you get arrested?
Come on!
Danny?
What are you doing?
No. That's not the way, Danny.
No, Trevor. It's the only way!
Gay power!
Come on!
Now, now. Hey, hey!
Everybody inside.
Inside! Back inside!
Welcome to the fuckin' club, man.
Gay power!
Hey!
Put that jukebox against the doors.
They cut the phone lines. Jack...
- Yeah.
- Radio.
This is Seymour Pine.
We have an emergency situation.
Do you copy? We
are 10-41, 10-41.
Do you copy?
Shit!
Okay. We need to find a way out of here.
Maybe in the back. Find a phone.
Get us back up. Call TPF. Go!
All right. I need these kids over here.
Everybody in the back.
Over here.
Uh-oh.
Come on, girls, help me!
I got an idea. Come on, come on!
Hey!
Oh, yeah.
Sir, she got through the window.
TPF should be on the way.
Push!
Push that back! Keep that shut!
There will be no shooting
unless I shoot first.
You got it?
Oh, shit, there we go.
Let's go! Let's go!
Christ.
I hope they're not gonna burn
some old lady's house down.
That'll set us back years.
Would it, though? They're
not like us, Trevor.
These kids have nothing left to lose.
Let's organize a meeting for tomorrow.
Great idea.
Get away from the window! Jesus!
What the fuck?
It's like a campfire.
Look for a fire extinguisher! Fuck!
Keep the door shut!
There's people in here, you fucks!
This is not the way I was planning to die.
Can you imagine the headlines?
New York City cops killed by
a screaming mob of homosexuals.
Ha!
Oh, shit!
All right, people. Back up!
Drop your bricks and your
stones and your bottles,
and back the hell up.
Go home!
If you stay here,
we're gonna arrest you.
Come on, pick something up.
Hey.
Danny! Girls, girls! Line up!
Line up, girls, come on! Come on!
Come on, line up! One, two, three.
♪ We are the baddest girls
♪ We wear our hair in curls
♪ We wear no underwear
♪ We show our pubic hair
♪ We are the baddest girls
♪ We wear our hair in curls
♪ We wear no underwear
♪ We show our pubic hair
♪ We are the baddest girls
♪ We wear our hair in curls
I cannot believe what
I'm looking at right now.
♪ We show our pubic hair ♪
All right, boys. Move in!
Back up.
This is an unlawful assembly.
If you stay here, you'll
be arrested. Go home.
Paul, get the fuck out of there!
Go, go, go. Let's get the fuck out of here!
We okay?
Yeah, we're okay.
Open that.
Where the fuck have you guys been?
Hey, you wait here.
Auntie, darling, I need your help.
Thank you very much.
You know what, Mr. Murphy? You're done.
You think?
One night of faggy temper
tantrums in the Village
changes anything?
I can't wait to watch you
figure it all out, honey.
Just don't call me honey, you freak.
Come on!
Whoo!
Fuck you!
Oh, shit!
Ray!
Ray! Ray!
You fuckin' pigs! You fuckin' pigs!
You lily pig! Everybody help him!
We've got our civil rights!
Come on! Run, you fuckin' pigs!
Why don't you start by handing them out?
Okay.
Thanks.
Here you go.
"If you are..."
"Do you think homosexuals are revolting?"
You bet your sweet ass we are!
Guess who wrote this piece of shit?
- Oh.
- Mmm-hmm.
Danny's man Trevor.
We out fighting,
and this motherfucker's home making flyers.
Oh, Mary, he's called for a meeting.
Ooh! Free sandwiches.
He's a brave man, your boyfriend.
Yeah, well, he's not my boyfriend.
God!
Ooh, the attitude.
Wait! I'm sorry. Look, I'm sorry!
No, you're right. He's all
talk, and talk is cheap.
You know, maybe you'll
figure that out one day.
Danny, don't go. Where you going?
I don't know, Ray!
Danny. I guess everything is different now.
Things are changing, like...
We could really get a place, you know.
I could get a real job. Screw this!
Ray, come on.
Don't you understand?
No. I mean, what am I
supposed to understand?
That I can't love you.
You and me...
I mean, different isn't even the word.
Danny, you don't think I know that?
I know.
I'm sorry, but I'm too mad
to love anyone right now.
This...
All this is so new to me,
but, you know, I like being mad!
I like not being the nice kid.
And last night felt so good.
You're always gonna be the nice kid,
you know that, right?
You can't help it.
Fuck you.
Thank you for showing me New York.
You'll always be my sister.
Yeah. My brick throwing sister.
I didn't know they made
farm boys from Kansas
that could throw like that.
Yeah, right. In Kansas.
I'll see you around, Ray.
Hi, Sarah.
Is Joe home?
Danny...
Why don't you come
inside? He's in the garage.
Hi, Mrs. Altman.
Hello, Danny.
Joe's outside.
How's New York treating you?
It's good. It's weird.
I just finished my first year at Columbia.
That's what you always wanted.
Yeah, I guess.
Why'd you come here, Danny?
'Cause I just wanted you to know that
I really did love you.
Maybe I still do.
Danny.
I'm married.
Yeah.
I'm gonna have a baby.
I don't know what it was, what we had.
Maybe it was kind of like love.
Danny, whatever we...
I'm not like you.
If I'd known you'd hold
onto it like this, I...
I just think you should leave.
Okay.
I'm sorry, Danny.
How's the book, Phebes?
- Danny!
- Hey.
I've missed you!
Wait!
If you didn't bring me
Andy Warhol's autograph,
you can just leave right now.
Oh, really?
What is it with you and Andy Warhol, huh?
What is it?
He's the opposite of this.
Hello, Danny.
I thought you and your
sister might be thirsty.
Thanks, Mom.
And thank you for sending in my papers.
I never would have got my
scholarship without them.
Thank you for writing.
Are you happy?
More than I was.
Well. Okay.
I'll leave you to be with Phoebe.
I don't go to church with them anymore.
No?
You got me out of that.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
How's that?
Well, I told them that their behavior
was not at all Christian towards you,
and that I was disappointed with them.
They're doing the best they can.
That's what they say about
anyone who's not good enough.
So...
So?
Do you have a boyfriend?
No.
I'm just asking.
But I do have friends. Good friends.
Wayne Mortal in my class is gay.
He told me.
And only me because he knows all about you.
Oh, yeah?
So I'm famous now.
Why'd you come back, Danny?
I had some unfinished business, I guess.
And to see you, stupid.
Why else would I come back? Huh?
Hey, so we're having a
parade in Manhattan next month
to commemorate the fighting.
We're gonna go all the way
uptown from the Village,
right up to Central Park,
and they're gonna call it
the Gay Liberation March.
Okay. I'm coming.
I'll take the train.
You know they're not
gonna let you go, right?
I know they won't.
They're trying not to make
the same mistakes with
me as they made with you.
Hey, hey.
I have to go, Phebes.
I can't miss my bus.
I love you.
Say hi to your friends for me. Okay?
If that isn't Danny Winters.
Well, hey, sister!
You know you can bring
your country ass downtown
more often, right?
Yeah, I know.
Look what I found!
Well, look who it is. How're you doing?
And how are you doing, huh?
- Same old, same old.
- Yeah?
Well, you got yourself some new clothes,
so it can't be all that bad.
Well, we had to dress up
'cause today's a special day.
How's school, Columbia?
It's great.
It's really great.
All right, people.
Let's get the show on the road.
Okay, bitches, you heard the man.
Let's face New York fuckin' City.
Out of the closet. In the street.
I love you.
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com