♪ Tulou... ♪
Pardon us...
♪ Sei e va'ai mai ♪
Look down...
♪ I le tātou lalolagi ♪
Upon our world
♪ Sei e va'ai mai ♪
Look down...
♪ I le tātou lalolagi ♪
Upon our world
♪ Sei e mālamalama ♪
The light
♪ Ko au e tu atu ♪
I stand before you
♪ E lelei ma le mānaia ♪
It is good and beautiful
♪ Sei e va'ai mai ♪
Look down...
♪ E taunuku te malaga ♪
The journey has begun
♪ Mānaia o le tātou ōlaga. ♪
At how beautiful our lives are.
In the beginning.
There was only ocean.
Until the "Mother Island" emerged.
Te Fiti.
Her heart held the greatest
power ever known.
It could create life itself!
And Te Fiti share it with the world.
But in time, some began to seek
Te Fiti's heart.
They believed if they could possess it.
The great power of
creation would be theirs.
And one day...
The most daring of them all...
Voyaged across the vast
ocean to take it.
He was the demigod of the wind and sea.
He was a warrior ...
A trickster!
A shape shifter who could change form.
With the power of his magical fish hook.
And his name was Maui!
But without her heart.
Te Fiti began to crumble.
Giving birth to a terrible darkness.
Maui tried to escape.
But was confronted by another,
who sought the heart.
Te Ka! A demon of Earth and Fire.
Maui was struck from the sky!
Never to be seen again.
And his magical fish hook ...
And the heart of Te Fiti,
were lost to the sea.
Where even now, a thousand years later.
Te Ka and the demons of the deep
still hunt for the heart.
Hiding in a darkness that
will continue to spread...
Chasing away our fish!
Draining the life from island after island!
Until every one of us.
Is devoured by the blood-thirsty jaws.
Of inescapable death!
But one day...
The heart will be found.
By someone who would
journey beyond our reef.
Find Maui.
Deliver him across
the great ocean...
To restore Te Fiti's heart.
And save us all.
Thank you mother, that's enough.
Papa...
No one goes outside the reef.
We are safe here!
There is no darkness.
There are no monsters.
- Monster! Monster! Monster!
- There's no monster... no monsters!
It's the darkness!
No, there is nothing beyond
our reef but storms!
- And rough seas!
- I gotta throw up!
As long as we stay on our very safe island.
We'll be fine!
The legends are true.
Someone will have to go!
Mother...
Motunui is paradise!
Who would want to go anywhere else?
Moana!
There you are Moana, what are you doing?
You scared me!
But I want us to go back.
I know, I know...
But you don't go out there.
It's dangerous.
Moana, come on...
Let's go back to the village.
You are the next great
chief of our people.
And you do wonderous
things, my little Minnow.
Oh yes, but first...
You must learn where you're meant to be.
Moana...
Make way .. Make way.
Moana, it's time you knew.
The village of Motunui is all you need.
The dancers are practicing
They dance to an ancient song.
Who needs a new song?
This old one's all we need
This tradition is our mission.
And Moana there's so much to do.
Don't trip on the taro root.
That's all you need.
We share everything we make.
We joke and we weave our baskets.
The fishermen come back from the sea.
- I wanna see.
- Don't walk away.
Moana stay on the ground now.
Our people will need a
chief and there you are...
There comes a day.
When you're gonna look around.
And realize happiness
is where you are.
Consider the coconut!
Consider it's tree...
We use each part of the coconut.
That's all we need.
We make our nets from the fibers.
The water is sweet inside.
We use the leaves
to build fires.
We cook up the meat inside.
Consider the coconuts!
The trunks and the leaves!
The island gives us what we need.
- And no one leaves.
- That's right we stay.
We're safe and we're well provided.
And when we look to the future...
There you are.
You'll be okay.
In time you'll learn just as I did.
You must find happiness right
where you are!
I like to dance with the water.
The undertow and the waves.
The water is mischievous, ha!
I like how it misbehaves.
The village may think I'm crazy.
Or say that I drift too far.
But once you know what you like.
Well, there you are.
You are your father's daughter.
Stubbornness and pride.
Mind what he says, but remember.
You may hear a voice inside..
And if the voice starts to whisper.
To follow the farthest star.
Moana, that voice inside
is who you are....
Dad!
I was only looking at the boats.
I wasn't gonna get on them.
Come on.
There's something I
need to show you.
I've wanted to bring you here from
the moment you opened your eyes.
This is a sacred place.
A place of Chiefs.
There will come a time
When you will stand on
this peak and place...
A stone on this mountain.
Like I did.
Like my father did.
And his father and every chief
that has ever been.
And on that day...
When you're at your stone.
You will raise this whole
island higher.
You are the future of
our people, Moana.
And they are not out there.
There are right here.
It's time to be who they need you to be.
- We make our nets from the fibers.
- We weave our nets from the fibers
- The water is sweet inside.
- The real taste of tree's inside.
- We use the leaves to build fires.
- We sing these songs in our choirs.
- And cook up the meat inside.
- We have mouths to feed inside.
- The village believe in us.
- That's right!
The village believe!
The island gives us what we need.
And no one leaves!
So here I'll stay.
My home, my people beside me.
And when I think of tomorrow.
There we are.
I lead the way.
I'll have my people to guide me.
We'll build our future together.
Where we are.
'Cause every path leads you back to.
Where you are.
- You can find happiness right...
- Where you are
Where you are....
Every storm, this roof leaks
no matter how many fronds I add.
Fixed!
Knot the fronds!
Wind shifted the post.
That's good pork!
Oh, I mean...
No, I wasn't ...
What? They're calling me! So I gotta...
Bye!
You're doing great.
Is it done yet?
So close.
I'm curious about that chicken.
Eating the rock!
I think he seems to lack the
basic intelligence required for
Pretty much everything.
Should we maybe just...
Cook him?
Sometimes our strengths
lie beneath the surface
Far beneath
In some cases.
But I'm sure there's more to
Hei-hei than meets the eye!
It's the harvest.
This morning I was
husking the coconuts and ...
Well...
We should clear the diseased trees.
And we will start a new grove
There!
Thanks, Moana.
She's doing great!
This suits you.
Chief!
There's something you need to see.
Our traps in the east lagoon.
They're pulling out less and less fish.
Then we'll rotate
the fishing grounds.
We have. There's no fish.
Then we'll fish the far side of the island.
We tried.
The windward side?
And the leeward side.
The shallows, the channel.
We've tried the whole lagoon!
They're just... gone.
Well, have you tried using
a different bait?
I don't think it's the bait.
I will talk to the counselor.
- I'm sure we ca...
- What if...
We fished beyond the reef!
No one goes beyond the reef.
I know! But if there are no fish in the lagoon...
- Moana!
- And there's a whole ocean...
We have one rule!
An old rule when there were fish!
A rule that keeps us safe!
- But dad...
- Instead of endangering our people
So you can run right back to the water!
Every time, I think
you're past this.
No one goes beyond the reef!
Well, it's not like you said it in
front of your dad
Standing on a boat.
I didn't say go beyond the reef.
Because I want to be on the ocean.
But you still do.
- He's hard on you, because...
- Because he doesn't get me.
Because he was you.
Drawn to the ocean.
Down by the shore.
He took a canoe, Moana.
He crossed the reef.
And found an unforgiving sea.
Waves like mountains.
His best friend begged
to be on that boat.
Your dad couldn't save him.
He's hoping he can save you.
Sometimes, who we wish we were
What we wish we could do
It's just not meant to be.
Okay, Pua.
I can do this.
There's more fish
beyond the reef.
There's more beyond the reef.
Not so bad!
Pua!
Whatever just happened.
Blame it on the pig!
Grandma!
Are you gonna tell dad.
I'm his mom.
I don't have to tell him anything.
He was right.
About going out there.
It's time to put my stone on the mountain.
Okay!
Well, then head on back
Put that stone up there.
Why aren't you trying to talk me out of it?
You said that's what you wanted.
It is.
When I die.
I'm going to come back as one of these.
Or I chose the wrong tattoo.
Why you're acting weird?
I'm the village crazy, lady.
That's my job.
If there's something you
want to tell me.
Just tell me.
Is there something you
want to tell me?
Is there something you want to hear?
You've been told all our people stories.
But one.
What is this place?
Do you really think our
ancestors stayed within the reef?
What's in there?
The answer.
To the question you
keep asking yourself.
Who are you meant to be.
Go inside.
Bang the drum.
And find out.
Tatou o Tagata Folau
(We read the wind and the sky)
E vala’auina.
(When the sun is high)
E le Atua o le sami tele
(We sail the length of the seas)
E o mai.
(On the ocean breeze)
La ava'e le lu'itau e lelei.
(At night we name every star)
Tapenapena.
(We know where we are)
Aue, Aue.
Nuku i mua.
(We set a course to find)
Te manulele e tataki iei.
(A brand new island everywere we roam)
Aue, Aue.
Te fenua te malie.
(We keep our island in our mind)
Nae ko hakilia
(And when it's time to find home)
Kainga e
(We know the way)
We read the wind and sky.
When the sun is high.
We sail the length of the seas on
the ocean breeze.
At night we name every star.
We know where we are.
We know who we are.
Who we are.
Aue, Aue...
We set a course to find.
A brand new island everywhere we roam.
Aue, Aue....
We keep our island in our mind.
And when it's time to find home.
We know the way.
Aue, Aue....
We are explorers
reading every sign.
We tell the stories of our elders.
In a never ending chain.
Te fenua, te malie.
Nae ko hakilia.
We know the way!
We were voyagers.
We were voyagers!
Why'd we stop?
Maui!
When he stole from the Mother Island.
Darkness fell.
Te Ka awoke.
Monsters lurked and boats
stopped coming back.
To protect our people,
the ancient chiefs
Forbid voyaging.
And now we have forgotten
who we are.
And the darkness has continued to spread.
Chasing away our fish.
Draining the life
From island after island.
Our island
But one day
Someone will journey beyond our reef.
Find Maui.
Deliver him across the great ocean.
To restore the heart of Te Fiti.
I was there that day.
The ocean chose you!
I thought it was a dream.
Nope!
Our ancestors believed, Maui lies there.
At the bottom of his hook.
Follow it, and you will find him.
But...
Why would it choose me?
I don't even know how
to make it pass the reef.
But I know who does.
The crops are turning black!
What about the fish?
- This is happening all over the island.
- Please. please.
- Settle down!
- What are you going to do?
We will dig new fields.
- We will find a way to...
- We can stop the darkness!
Save our island!
There's a cavern boats!
Huge canoes!
We can take them, find Maui
Make him restore
the heart.
We were voyagers.
We can voyage again!
You told me to help our people.
This is how we help our people!
Dad?
What are you doing?
I should've burned those
boats a long time ago!
No! Don't!
We have to find Maui.
We have to restore the heart.
There is no heart!
This...this is just a rock!
No!
Chief!
It's your mother!
Mother.
What can be done?
Go.
Grandma.
Not now.
I can't.
You must!
The ocean chose you!
- Follow the fish hook.
- Grandma.
And when you find Maui.
You grab him by the ear!
You say...
I am Moana of Motunui!
You will board my boat!
Sail across the sea!
And restore the heart of Te Fiti!
I... I can't leave you.
There is no way you could go,
that I won't be with you.
Go!
There's a line where the sky meet the sea.
And he calls me.
But no one knows.
How far it goes.
All time wondering where
I need to be is behind me.
I'm on my own
Towards unknown!
Every turn I take.
Every trail I track.
It's a choise I make.
Now I can't turn back.
From a great unknown.
Where I go alone.
Where I long to be.
See her light of the night.
in the sea, she calls me.
And yes, I know.
That I can go.
There's a moon in the sky and the
wind is behind me.
So now I'll know.
How far I'll go!
I am Moana Motunui.
You will board my boat.
Sail across the sea!
And restore the heart of Te Fiti.
I am Moana.
Of Motu... nui.
Hei-hei?!
It's okay.
You're alright.
See?
There we go.
Nice water.
The ocean is a friend of mine.
Hei-hei?
Hei-hei!
Stay!
Okay.
Next stop.
Maui.
I am Moana of Motunui.
You will board my boat.
Sail across the sea.
And restore the heart of Te Fiti.
I am Moana... of .. Mo..tu....
Board my boat!
Oh, no!
No ... no... no...no!
No!
Ocean?
Can I get a little help?
No... no.
Please.
Come on!
Help me!
Please!
What?!
I said help me!
And wrecking my boat?!
Not helping!
Fish pee in you... all day!
So...
Maui?
Maui!
Maui, demigod of the wind and sea
I am Moana of Motunui!
You will board my boat!
No!
Yeah!
Hi, I'm Moana of Motunui.
- You will board my...
- Boat!
A boat!
The Gods have given me a...
Maui
Shape shifter.
Demigod of the wind and sea.
- I am Moana of Mo...
- Hero of Men.
Wha..What?
It's actually Maui, shape shifter.
Demigod of the wind and sea!
Hero of Men.
I interupted. From the top.
Go!
- I am Mo...
- Sorry, Sorry, Sorry, Sorry.
And women.
Men and women. Both! All!
Not a guy-girl thing.
You know? Maui
is a hero to all!
You're doing great.
What?
- No! I came here to ...
- Of course, of course.
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Maui always has time
for his fans.
When you use a bird to write with
It's called "tweeting".
I know, not every day, you get a
chance to meet your hero.
You are not my hero!
And I'm not here so you
can sign my oar!
I'm here because you stole
the heart of Te Fiti!
And you will board my boat.
Sail across the sea and put it back!
Yeah.
It almost sounded like you
don't like me.
Which is impossible
because I got stuck here.
For a thousand years,
trying to get the heart...
As a gift for you, mortals...
So you could have the power
to create life itself!
Yeah, so what I believe
you're trying to say.
- Is thank you.
- Thank you?
- You're welcome.
- What? No, no, no.
I .. I didn't ...
I wasn't ...
- Why would I ever say... I mean...
- Okay, okay, okay...
I see what's happening, yeah.
You're face to face with
greatness and it's strange.
You don't even know
how you feel.
It's adorable!
Well, it's nice to see that humans
never change.
Open your eyes let's begin.
Yes, it's really me, It's Maui.
Breathe it in.
I know it's a lot the hair, the bod!
When you're staring at a Demigod
What can I say?
Except you're welcome.
For the tides, the sun, the sky.
Hey, it's okay. It is okay.
You're welcome.
I'm just an ordinary demi-guy, Hey!
Hey, what has two thumbs
and pulled up the sky.
When you were waddling yay high.
This guy!
When the nights got cold.
Who stole you fire from down below?
You're looking at him, yo!
Oh, also I lasso'd the sun.
You're welcome.
To stretch your days and bring you fun.
Also I harnessed the breeze.
You're welcome, to fill your sails
and shake your trees.
So what can I say except
You're welcome.
For the islands I pulled from the sea.
There's no need to pray, it's okay.
You're welcome.
I guess it's just my way of being me.
Well, come to think of it.
Kid, honestly I can go on and on.
I can explain every natural phenomenon.
The tide, the grass,  the ground.
Oh... that was Maui just messing around.
I killed an eel, I
buried its guts.
Sprouted a tree, now you got coconuts.
What's the lesson?
What is the takeaway.
Don't mess with Maui when he's
on the breakaway.
And the tapestry here in my skin.
Is a map of the victories I win.
Look where I've been, I
make everything happen.
Look at that mean mini Maui just
tikitty tappin'
Well anyway, let me say,
You're welcome
For the wonderful world you know.
Hey, it's okay... it's okay.
You're welcome
Well, come to think of
it, I gotta go.
Hey, it's your day to say
You're welcome.
Cause I'm gonna need that boat.
I'm sailing away... away.
You're welcome.
Cause Maui can do
everything but float.
You're welcome.
And thank you!
Hey, let me out!
You lying, slimy, son of a...
You're welcome.
No!
I'm not going to Te Fiti
with some kid.
I'm gonna get my hook.
You have yours. And I'm not Maui
without mine.
Okay, talk to the back.
Boat snack!
Good riddance you filthy pile of pebbles!
Oh, no, no, no.
Don't look at me like that.
It's a beautiful cave, she's gonna love it.
And I'm going to love you.
In my belly.
Now let's fatten you up, drumstick!
I could watch that all day.
Okay, enjoy the island!
- Maui, out!
- No!
Stop!
Hey! You have to put
back the heart!
Did not see that coming.
I am Moana of Motunui.
This is my canoe.
And you will journey to...
Alright, get over it.
We gotta move.
And she's back.
I am Moana of Motunu...
- It was Moana, right?
- Yes.
And you will restore the heart.
Alright, I'm out.
Oh, come on!
What is your problem?
- Are you afraid of it?
- No.
No. I'm not afraid...
Stay out of it or you're
sleeping in my armpit.
You stop it.
That is not a heart.
It is a curse. The second I took it
I got blasted out of the sky
And I lost my hook!
Get it away from me.
Get this away?
I'm Demigod, okay?
Stop that!
I will smite you!
You wannna get "smote"?
"Smoten"?
Listen, that thing doesn't give you
power to create life.
It's a homing beacon of death.
If you don't put it away, bad things
are gonna come for it.
Come for this? The heart?
You mean this heart right here!
Come and get it!
You are gonna get us killed.
No, I'm gonna get us to Te Fiti.
So you can put it back.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Kakamora.
Kaka... what?
Murdering little pirates.
Wonder what they're here for?
They're kind of cute.
Ocean do something, help us!
The ocean doesn't help you.
You help yourself!
Tighten the halyard. Bind the stays!
You can't sail?!
I...
I am self taught?
Can't you shape shift
or something?!
Do you see my hook?
No magic hook, no magic powers.
Their boat is turning into more boats!
Yup! I just did that.
No, no, no, no!
Hei-hei!
Maui! They took the heart!
That a chicken.
The heart is in the...
We have to get him back!
Maui!
There! Right there!
You're turning?!
What are you doing?!
Escaping.
- The heart!
- Forget it, you'll never get it back.
Beside, we got a better one.
Hey!
What do I gonna steer with?!
They're just gonna kill you!
Coconuts.
Got it!
Hey!
Yeah!
We did it!
Congratulations, on not being dead, curly.
You surprise me.
But I'm still not taking that thing back.
You wanna get to Te Fiti.
You gotta go through
a whole ocean of bad.
Not to mention Te Ka.
Lava monster?
Ever defeat a lava monster?
No.
Have you?
I'm not going on a
suicide mission with some mortal.
You can't restore the heart
without me.
And me says no.
I'm getting my hook.
End of discussion.
You'd be a hero.
That's what you're all about, right?
Little girl, I am a hero.
Maybe you were but now...
Now you're just the guy who
stole the heart of Te Fiti.
The guy who cursed the world!
You're no one's hero.
No one?
But, put this back.
Save the world.
You'd be everyone's hero.
Maui! Maui! Maui!
You're so amazing!
We'd never make it without my hook.
Not pass Te Ka.
Then we get your hook.
We get you hook, take out Te Ka.
Restore the heart.
Unless you don't wanna be
Maui, Demigod of the Wind and
Sea, Hero to all
First, we get my hook.
Then save the world.
Deal?
Deal.
Worth a shot.
Okay, we go east.
To the lair of Tamatoa.
If anyone has my hook,
it's that beady-eyed bottom feeder.
Teach me to sail.
My job is to deliver
Maui across the great ocean.
I should...
I should be sailing.
It's called Wayfinding, Princess.
And it's not just sails and knots.
It's seeing where you're going
in your mind.
Knowing where you are.
By knowing where you've been.
Okay, first,
I'm not a princess.
I'm the daughter of the chief.
- Same difference.
- No.
If you wear a dress, and you have an
animal sidekick.
You're a Princess.
You're not a wayfinder.
You will never be a wayfinder.
You will never be a way...
Really?
Blow dart in my butt cheek.
You are a bad person.
If you can talk, you can teach.
Wayfinding.
Lesson one. Hit it!
Pull the sheet.
Not the sheet.
No.
Nope!
Tried that one already.
You're measuring the stars.
Not giving the sky a high five.
If the current's warm,
you're going the right way.
It's cold.
Wait, it's getting warmer.
That is disgusting!
What is wrong with you?!
We're here?
See? Told you I can do it!
Motunui.
I'm home?
Moana!
Dad?
Mom?
Help!
No!
Moana!
Enjoying your beauty rest?
You know, a real wayfinder, never sleeps.
So they actually get where they need to go.
Muscle up buttercup!
We're here.
You sure this guy's gonna have your hook?
Tamatoa? Oh, hell have it.
He's a scavenger.
Collects stuff, things that makes
him look cool.
And for Tamatoa?
Trust me, my hook
is the coolest collectible.
And he lives up there?
Oh, no, no, no...
That's just the entrance
To a Lalotai.
Lalotai?
Realm of Monsters?!
We're going to the Realm of Monsters?
We?
No.
Me.
You are gonna stay here
with the other chicken.
That's what I'm talking about,
give me some!
Come on, that was a good one,
how do you not get it?
I called her a chicken, there's
a chicken on the boat.
I know she's human! But that's not the...
You know what? Forget it.
Forget it! I'm not explaining it to you.
'Cause then it's not funny.
So...
Daughter of the chief.
I thought you stayed in the village.
You know, kissing babies and things.
Hey, I'm just trying to understand
Why your people decided to send...
How do I phrase this?
You!
My people...
Didn't send me.
The ocean did.
The ocean? Makes sense!
You're what? Eight?
Can't sail?
Obvious choice.
It chose me.
For a reason.
If the ocean's so smart
Why didn't it just take the heart
back to Te Fiti itself?
Or bring me my hook?
The ocean's straight up pooky dooks!
But I'm sure it's not wrong about you.
You're the chosen one.
The ocean chose you for a reason.
If you start singing, I'm gonna throw up.
So, not seeing entrance.
Yes, because it only
appears after a human sacrifice.
Kidding!
So serious!
Don't worry. It's a lot farther
down than it looks.
I am still falling!
Go!
And he's sticks the landing.
What?
Dumb-dumb, she's not even here.
No mortal's gonna jump
into the realm of mon...
Well....
She's dead.
Okay, let's get my hook.
Maui's fish hook.
Yeah!
Sorry!
I thought you're a monster, but...
I found your hook! And you're right...
- This Tamatoa really likes his treasure.
- Stay!
What? No!
- I... I'm the one who found...
- Listen...
For a thousand years...
I've only been thinking of
keeping this hair silky
Getting my hook, and being awesome again.
And it's not getting screwed up
by a mortal.
Who has no business
Inside of a monster's cave except...
Except...
Maybe as bait.
Huh?
Wow! The shiny, glittery cave.
And just like me.
It is covered in sparkly treasure.
Sparkle, sparkle
- Sparkle.
- You're not selling it.
This is stupid! I'm just gonna
walk up and get it.
You go up there,
he will kill you.
Just stick to the plan.
Oh, when he shows up,
keep him distracted.
Make him talk about himself.
He loves bragging about
how great he is!
You two must get along as well!
No. Not since I ripped off his leg.
You ripped off his le...
Maui?
What have we here?
It's a sparkly, shiny.
Wait a minute...
It's a human!
What are you doing down here?
In the realm of the mons...
Just pick an eye, babe.
I can't... I can't concentrate
on what I'm saying
If you keep...
Yep, pick one, pick one!
You're a funny looking
little thing, aren't you?
Don't! That's my grandma's.
"That's my grandma's"
I ate my grandma!
And it took a week 'cause
she was absolutely humongous.
Why are you here?
'Cause you're amazing!
And we mortals, have heard of
the tale of the crab.
Who became a legend!
And I just had to know...
How you being so crab...
-oulous?
Are you just trying to get me to
talk about myself?
Because if you are...
I will gladly do so.
In song form!
Well, Tamatoa hasn't always been this glam.
I was a drab little crab once..
Now I know, I can be
happy as a clam.
Because I'm beautiful, baby.
Did your granny say listen to your heart.
Be who you are on the inside.
I need three words to tear her
argument a part.
Your granny lied.
I'd rather be shiny like a treasure
from a sunken pirate wreck.
Scrub the deck and make it look shiny.
I will sparkle like a wealthy woman's neck
Just a sec, don't you know?
Fish are dumb, dumb, dumb
They chase anything that glitters
Beginners. Oh, and here they
come, come, come.
To the brightest thing that glitters.
Mmm, fish dinners.
I just love free food.
And you look like seafood
- No!
- Hey! Crab cake.
I'm back!
It's Maui time!
What do you say, little buddy.
Giant hawk? Coming up!
Well, well, well....
Little Maui's having trouble with his look.
You little semi-demi-mini-god.
Ouch! What a terrible performance.
Get the hook! Get it?
You don't swing it like you used to, man.
Yet I have to give you credit for my start.
And your tattoos on the outside.
For just like you I made
myself a work of art.
I'll never hide, I can't.
I'm too shiny! Watch me dazzle like
a diamond in the rough.
Strut my stuff, my stuff is so shiny.
Send your armies but
they'll never be enough.
My shell's too tough, Maui man.
You could try, try, try...
But you can't expect a demigod.
To beat a decapod.
Look it up!
You will die, die, die.
Now it's time for me to take apart.
Your aching heart.
Far from the ones who abandoned you.
Chasing the love of these humans.
Who made you feel wanted.
You try to be tough.
But your armour's just not hard enough.
Maui! Now it's time to kick your hiney.
Ever seen someone so shiny?
Soak it in cause it's
the last you'll ever see.
C'est la vie mon ami, I'm so shiny!
Now I'll eat you so prepare
your final plea.
Just for me.
You'll never be quite as shiny
You wish you were nice and shiny
Hey!
I got something shiny for you.
The heart of Te Fiti.
You can't run from me.
Oh, you can?
You keep surprising me.
It's only so far you can get on
these two little legs.
The power of creation!
For a crustacean!
Where is it?
We gotta go!
Well, what about the heart.
He can have it.
I've got a better one.
Yes, I have the ...
Wait a minute.
I see she's taken a barnacle
And she's covered it in
bioluminescent algae.
As a diversion.
Come back here!
Hey! Hey!
Did you like the song?
We're alive!
Listen
I appreciate what you did down there.
Took guts.
But... I'm sorry.
I'm tryin' to be sincere for once,
and it feels like you're distracted.
- No, no, no way!
- Really?
'Cause you're looking at
me like I have a ...
Shark head.
- Do you have a shark head? 'Cause I ...
- Look ...
The point is ...
For a little girl, child thing, whatever
who had no business being down there.
You did me a solid.
But you also almost died.
And I couldn't even beat
that dumb crab!
So chances of beating Te Ka.
We're never making it to Te Fiti.
This mission is cursed.
It's not cursed.
- Shark head.
- It is not cursed!
Cursed.
What can I say, except
we're dead soon.
We're dead soon.
Can you at least try?
Giant hawk.
Hey, it's okay, it's okay.
We're dead soon.
Alright, breaktime's over.
- Get up!
- Why?
You're gonna give me a speech
Tell me I could beat Te Ka
'cause I'm "Maui"?
Take a hike, tiny.
How do you get your tattoo's?
They show up when I earn them.
How'd you earn that one?
What's that for?
That's a man's discovery of Nanya.
What's Nanya?
None ya business.
I'll just keep asking.
What's it for?
You need to stop doing that.
- Back off!
- Just tell me what it is?!
I said back off.
Is it why your hook's not working?
You don't wanna talk.
Don't talk.
You wanna throw me off the boat.
Throw me off.
You wanna tell me, I don't
know what I'm doing?
I know I don't.
I have no idea why
the ocean chose me.
You're right.
But my island is dying.
So I am here.
It's just me and you.
And I want to help.
But I can't  if you don't let me.
I wasn't born a demigod.
I had human parents.
They...
They took one look and...
And decided they
did not want me.
They threw me under the sea.
Like I was nothing.
Somehow I was found by the Gods.
They gave me the hook.
They made me... Maui.
And back to the humans I went.
I gave them islands, fire, coconuts!
Anything they could ever want.
You took the heart for them.
You did everything for them.
So they'd loved you.
It was never enough.
Maybe the Gods found
you for a reason.
Maybe the ocean brought you to them.
Because it saw someone who is
worthy of being saved.
But the Gods aren't the ones
who make you Maui.
You are.
Okay, okay.
I... I love you too, buddy.
Yeah!
Next stop, Te Fiti.
- What?
- I figured it out
You know the ocean used to love
when I pulled up islands.
'Cause your ancestors would sail our seas.
Find them!
All those new lands, new villages...
It was the water that connected them all.
And if I were the ocean
I think I'd be looking for a...
Curly haired, non-princess.
To start that again.
That is literaly the nicest thing
You've ever said to me.
Probably should've saved it for Te Fiti.
I did.
Moana of Motunui.
I believe.
You have officially delivered Maui.
Across the great sea.
Moana!  Moana!  Moana!
You're so amazing!
It's time.
Go, save the world.
Maui!
What... What are you doing?
Finding you a better way in!
- We won't make it!
- Yes, we will!
- Turn around!
- No!
- Moana, stop!
Are you okay?
Maui?
I told you to turn back.
I thought we could make it.
We?
I thought I could make it.
We can fix it!
It was made by the Gods.
You can't fix it!
Next time we'll be more careful.
Te Ka was stuck on the barrier islands.
It's lava!
It can't go in the water.
We can find a way around.
I'm not going back.
What... We still have to restore the heart.
My hook is cracked.
One more hit and it's over.
Maui, you have to restore the heart.
Without my hook, I am nothing.
That's not true.
Without my hook, I am nothing!
We're only here because you
stole the heart in the first place.
No, we're here because
the ocean told you
You're special and
you believed it,
I am Moana of Motunui.
- You will board my boat.
- Goodbye, Moana.
- Sail across the sea,
- I'm not killing myself
So you can prove you're
something you're not!
And restore the heart of Te Fiti!
The Ocean chose me!
They chose wrong.
Maui!
Why did you bring me here?
I'm not the right person.
You have to choose someone else.
Choose someone else!
Please!
You're a long ways past the reef.
Grandma?
Guess I chose the right tattoo.
Grandma!
I tried, grandma.
I...
I couldn't do it.
It's not your fault.
I never should've put so much
on your shoulders.
If you are ready to go home.
I will be with you.
Why do you hesitate?
I don't know.
I know a girl from an island.
She stands apart from the crowd.
She loves the sea and her people.
She makes her whole family proud.
Sometimes the world seems against you.
The journey may leave a scar.
But scars can
heal and reveal
Just where you are.
The people you love will change you.
The things you have learned will guide you.
And nothing on earth
can silence
The quiet voice still inside you.
And when that voice starts to whisper
Moana you've come so far.
Moana listen.
Do you know who you are?
Who am I?
I am a girl who loves my island.
I'm the girl who loves the sea.
It calls me...
I am the daughter of the village chief.
We are descended from voyagers.
Who found their way across the world.
They call me ...
I've delivered us to where we are.
I have journeyed farther.
I am everything I've learned and more.
Still it calls me.
And the call isn't out there at all.
It's inside me.
It's like the tide always
falling and rising.
I will carry you here in my heart.
You remind me.
That come what may.
I know the way!
I AM  MOANA!
I am Moana of Motunui.
Aboard my boat, I will
sail across the sea.
And restore the heart of Te Fiti.
Te Ka can't follow us into the water.
We'll make it pass the barrier islands.
We'll make it to Te Fiti.
None of which you understand.
Because you are a chicken.
No!
Hei-hei!
No, no, no, no, no!
Nice work!
Te Fiti!
Maui!
You came back.
But your hook.
One more hit, and ...
Te Ka's gotta catch me first.
I got your back, chosen one.
Go, save the world.
Maui.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Hey... Te Ka!
Shark head.
Moana!
Get the heart to the spiral!
Te Fiti.
It's gone.
TE KA!!
Let her come to me.
I have crossed the horizon
to find you.
I know your name.
They have stolen the heart from inside you.
But this does not define you.
This is not who you are.
You know who you are...
Who you trully are.
Te Fiti.
The chicken lives.
I'm sorry about your hook.
Well, hook, no hook,
I'm Maui.
Te Fiti!
How you've been?
Look, what I did was wrong.
I have no excuse.
I'm sorry.
You know, it'd be rude
to refuse a gift from a Goddess.
Thank you.
Your kind gesture is deeply appreciated.
Gonna miss you, drumstick.
You could come with us, you know.
My people are going to need a
master wayfinder.
They already have one.
See you out there, Maui.
See you out there, Moana...
Mom! Dad!
Moana!
I may have gone a little ways past
the reef.
It suits you.
- She's back!
- Moana!
Pua!
Moana!
Aue, Aue
We set a course to find...
A brand new island everywhere we roam.
Aue, Aue
We keep our island in our mind.
And when it's time to find home,
We know the way
Aue, Aue
We are explorers reading every sign.
We tell the stories of our elders
in a never ending chain.
Aue, Aue
Te Fenua, te Malie.
Nae ko hakilia.
We know the way....
M O A N A