- What's your highest bounty?
- There is one job.
THE MANDALORIAN: Underworld?
GREEF KARGA: Deep pocket.
Greef Karga said you were the best
in the parsec.
I have a camtono of Beskar waiting for you
upon delivery of the asset.
You are Mandalorian!
I will help you.
Many have passed through.
They seek the same one.
THE MANDALORIAN: IG Unit! Stand down.
(GROANS)
IG-11: You are a Guild member?
THE MANDALORIAN: I have a suggestion.
We split the reward.
IG-11: This is acceptable.
IG-11: The tracking fob is still active.
There is a life form present.
(INSECT BUZZING)
(INSECTS CHITTERING)
(RUSTLING)
(WIND WHISTLING)
(HISSING IN DISTANCE)
(RUSTLES)
(GRUNTS)
(BEEPING)
(GIGGLING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
- (GRUNTS)
- (GROANS)
- (GROWLS)
- (GRUNTS)
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
(PANTING)
(COOS)
- (SIZZLING)
- (THE MANDALORIAN GRUNTING)
(CONTINUES GRUNTING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
(WIND WHISTLING)
- (CLICKS)
- (TRILLING)
- (THE CHILD COOING)
- (GASPS)
- (COOING)
- (THE MANDALORIAN SIGHS)
(BEEPING)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING IN DISTANCE)
(SCREAMS)
(ALL CLAMORING)
(GROANS)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
(SPEAKING JAWA)
- (THE MANDALORIAN GRUNTING)
- (MUTTERING IN JAWA)
(PANTING)
(SPEAKING JAWA)
(RADIO SIGNAL BLARING)
(BEEPING)
(CACKLING)
(GRUNTING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(GRUNTS)
(JAWAS SHOUTING)
(YELPS)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
(JAWA SCREAMS)
(ALL CLAMORING)
(SCREAMS)
- (GRUNTS)
- (JAWA GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
(GROANING)
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
(CRACKLING)
(WIND WHISTLING)
(GRUNTING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(SIGHS, GRUNTS IN FRUSTRATION)
(ENGINE POWERS ON)
(ENGINE POWERS DOWN)
(SPUTTERS)
- (CLICKS)
- (SPUTTERS)
(SIGHS)
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
- (THE CHILD COOING)
- (SIGHS)
(CONTINUES COOING)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
I thought you were dead.
(CHIRPING)
(THE CHILD WHIMPERS)
This is what was causing all the fuss?
THE MANDALORIAN: I think it's a child.
It is better to deliver it alive then.
THE MANDALORIAN: My ship
has been destroyed. I'm trapped here.
UGNAUGHT: Stripped. Not destroyed.
The Jawas steal. They don't destroy.
THE MANDALORIAN: Stolen or destroyed,
makes no difference to me.
(COOING)
They're protected
by their crawling fortress.
There's no way to recover the parts.
You can trade.
THE MANDALORIAN: With Jawas?
Are you out of your mind?
I will take you to them.
I have spoken.
Hey! Spit that out.
(GRUNTING, GULPS)
(BURPS)
(MUTTERING IN JAWA)
(EXCLAIMS)
(UGNAUGHT SPEAKING JAWA)
(JAWAS EXCLAIMING)
(SPEAKING JAWA)
(IN ENGLISH) They really don't like you
for some reason.
THE MANDALORIAN:
Well, I did disintegrate a few of them.
(JAWAS CLAMORING)
(SPEAKING JAWA)
UGNAUGHT: You need to drop your rifle.
THE MANDALORIAN: I'm a Mandalorian.
Weapons are part of my religion.
Then you are not getting your parts back.
(THE MANDALORIAN SIGHS)
THE MANDALORIAN: Fine.
(MUTTERING IN JAWA)
And the blaster.
Good day.
(CONVERSING IN JAWA)
(IN ENGLISH) They will trade all the parts
for the beskar.
I'm not gonna trade anything.
These are my parts.
They stole them from me.
(SPEAKING JAWA)
(JAWAS LAUGHING)
- (IN ENGLISH) You understand this?
- No!
- (JAWAS SCREAMING)
- Whoa. Easy, easy.
(SPEAKING JAWA)
(JAWAS CHATTERING)
THE MANDALORIAN: (IN ENGLISH)
Get away from it!
(THE CHILD WHIMPERING)
(SPEAKING JAWA)
THE MANDALORIAN:
(IN ENGLISH) The egg? What egg?
(JAWAS CHANTING GLEEFULLY)
(THE MANDALORIAN SIGHS)
- (GRUNTS)
- (JAWA CACKLING)
(WATER DRIPPING)
(INSECTS CHIRPING)
(CREATURE GROWLS LOWLY)
(GROWLS)
(BLASTER FIRING)
- (CREATURE ROARS)
- (GROANS)
(ROARS)
(GROANING)
(CRYING)
(GROWLS)
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
(LOADS WEAPON)
(GROANING)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(MUDHORN GROWLS)
(MUDHORN BELLOWS)
(PANTING, GASPS)
(MUDHORN ROARING)
(UPLIFTING MUSIC PLAYING)
- (MUDHORN ROARS)
- (GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
(CONVERSING IN JAWA)
(UGNAUGHT SIGHS)
Mando!
THE MANDALORIAN: (IN ENGLISH)
I have it.
I've got the egg.
(JAWAS CHEERING)
(JAWAS CHATTERING)
I'm surprised you waited.
I'm surprised you took so long.
Is it still sleeping?
THE MANDALORIAN: Yes.
Was it injured?
THE MANDALORIAN: I don't think so.
Not physically.
UGNAUGHT: Explain it to me again.
I still don't understand what happened.
THE MANDALORIAN: Neither do I.
There's no way we're gonna get this to
work without a full maintenance facility.
This is gonna take days to fix.
If you care to help, it might go faster.
There is much work to do.
(FAST MUSIC PLAYING)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(ENGINE POWERS ON)
(WHIRRING)
(CLICKS SWITCH)
THE MANDALORIAN:
I can't thank you enough.
Please allow me to give you
a portion of the reward.
I cannot accept.
You are my guest
and I am therefore in your service.
I could use a crew member of your ability,
and I can pay handsomely.
I am honored,
but I have worked a lifetime
to finally be free of servitude.
THE MANDALORIAN: I understand.
Then all I can offer is my thanks.
And I offer mine.
Thank you for bringing peace to my valley.
And good luck with The Child.
May it survive and bring you
a handsome reward.
I have spoken.
(UPLIFTING MUSIC PLAYING)
(ENGINE POWERING ON)
(CLICKING SWITCHES)
(DEVICE BEEPING)
(THE CHILD COOING)