We'll get to the horses
Now you'll come up to the house
l came to buy your stallion, War Winds,
ln all likelihood,
David is with the embassy in Washington.
Mother! Let me sell Mr. Benedict
For one, he eats too much,
You see, it's either War Winds or me.
You know that horse is just too spirited
l know your horse is going to miss you
You must tell us about Texas,
At least that's what we think.
From an Englishman's point of view,
Mr. Benedict's Reata is
There are one or two others as big,
and some larger ones
What's the size of your place?
Around a half million.
how many acres did you say,
And you should see the greedy look
Won't you join us at the hunt Ball?
l'm afraid l wouldn't look good
Why don't you stay a while
lt's roundup time in my country.
Your country, my country.
l'm not going to say goodbye to you
Will you do me a favor
-Leslie?
-$10,000 is a lot of money.
-Why, Leslie!
You don't look as if you'd been dancing
Let the poor boy
You're catching me a bit early
But l'm not joking.
Mr. Austin came down
The next thing you know,
l never heard anything as ignorant
l'm only speaking impersonally.
You all think
Do you know about San Jacinto?
l didn't mean to be impolite,
You mustn't talk that way to a Texan.
Jordan, you would think
First you attack a man's country,
-Good morning.
-Good morning, Lacey.
We'll have to be getting along soon
-Good morning, everybody.
Leslie, if Mr. Benedict has finished
We've just quarreled politely about Texas.
he's probably engaged to marry
who, though beautiful,
She only has 200,000 acres
Mr. Benedict and l will have
Who, may l ask, is the lucky young lady
lt's funny, ma'am.
There was some talk of my marrying her,
Don't you think you've done
l don't know how other brides feel
My old man built it to show the cotton
She's run the house since Ma passed on.
here we don't make a fuss
l still have a mind of my own.
standing here quarreling
We weren't expected to be back sooner,
With all the spring work to be done,
lf l miss a roundup every time l have
Where do you think you're going
Don't go taking off on me.
But she said,
Bick and Jett are everlasting jangling
-Madama is the one who told me to stay.
With you away,
They're all scared to death of her.
and l'll be glad to do anything you want.
-hello.
You'd better get going, Jett,
l'm sorry, honey. Things go loco here
Old Kale Beebe blew in,
he must have had nightmares.
We'll make that into a sitting room
You and Jordan
We have our coffee and talk
l thought l was going riding with him
lt would've been too hot for you.
You gotta watch out for that sun.
Your blood's too thin. That's the trouble
l'm a lot tougher perhaps
l never had a sick day in my life.
Don't you worry none
Yes, indeed.
l'd like you to meet
how do you do, Mrs. Benedict?
Bick, congratulations.
Now you'll meet the neighbor
The one who lives 50 miles away
My name is Mort Snythe.
-Excuse me, ma'am.
-This will perk you up, Miss Leslie.
l propose a toast to a daughter
now blooming into a citizen
-There's more than one bride here today.
Mort Snythe and l were married yesterday
Why, Luz, everybody in the county knows
You put your brand on one of them,
We take it and wrap it in clean white cloth
and put it down in a pit
l don't think l'm really terribly hungry.
l think there's something
l don't want to take your place.
But l can't have you
l can't be just a guest
-how are you feeling?
l want everybody to know, no matter
l'll never get the hang of you,
A horse that cost you a lot
l wouldn't let anyone ride him.
l'd see she rides a more gentle animal
There's never been anything like them
Granddaddy and his boys
great herds of them,
he was a pretty good old boy.
My old man brought in stock from Europe
hold on a minute. l want you
There's no use overdoing it.
They understand English
l know how to handle Mexicans.
They'd sit on their honkers all day
l thought we ought to talk
l don't want to feel that you're setting up
And you're fair enough, l think,
l'll get a horse and help push
l mean, everybody else's trying
Who gets hold of this much land
You're not exactly loyal
-They got it though purchase, years ago.
That's not true. They bought and traded
They paid for it all right.
l know my folks were here long enough
l've been riding what l want to
lf he bucks me down,
l suppose you came out here
l've got a few friends.
And Bick....
Of course,
kind of divvy up
You're an odd one, aren't you, Jett?
You're the best-looking gal
The prettiest one
l'll tell my husband of that,
Them kids there.
Sure in good shape, ain't they?
You're the boss.
Mrs. Leslie,
Try not to worry, Mrs. Obregon.
Where in the world have you been?
She might have been thrown
She could ride anything.
This is a great misfortune,
-Mrs. Benedict, this is Dr. Borneholm.
Dr. Walker did everything he could,
Dr. Walker, there's more for you to do,
his temperature must be at least 105.
-Our doctor?
They have a way of doing things
Now, don't go climbing on me.
Jordan, darling,
There's a child who's very sick.
Somebody had to do it.
We need you in here for a few minutes
ln times like this
lt's the biggest gathering for a funeral
l mean, she always did like
-Come to see us.
l think you'll agree, your sister
She wanted that boy
l'm going to ask you, in reverence
l'm going to ask you
We can clean up the whole matter
l lost the one friend l had in this place,
So l quit, l dead quit.
Come inside and listen
Come on in here, Jett.
-howdy, Jett. Good to see you.
have my seat, boy. Sit right down.
Sit down. l'm going to tell you about
Sit down, young man,
lt's a real bad wind
l don't have to tell you that Luz was
She prepared a list of things she wanted
We find that her bequest to you was
lt's the little piece we used to call
She wanted to give you something.
lt's always been my aim to try
Now, that little piece is worth at most....
Mr. Benedict, wanting to honor
and, of course, right along
he wants to see to it that you get
we're prepared to place in your hands,
which, any of these gentlemen here
-Definitely.
That's a lot of money.
l want you to know
a pretty good idea
There's one thing on this earth more
lf you ever get to Deep Smith,
Only a little-bitty, no-account piece,
-Only? Why, a gusher came in last year.
-A million gallons?
-Goodbye. Thanks for treating us right.
to take you around
l'm so impatient.
You don't have to hurry, honey.
And when you've seen it all
in 25 years from now,
Twenty-five years from now
You'll see wonderful things in Texas
Because then
You get with it, Gomez.
l don't want any of them
Everything will be bueno, senor.
You married me in Washington,
l lived next door to politics.
Leslie, how about a cup of coffee
Set up my spinning wheel, girls.
Don't you go worrying
You mean my pretty, empty head,
My adrenaline glands
You ought to be wearing leopard skins
What's so masculine about a conversation
l reckon l'll go on upstairs
Send the children on up to bed
Darling, l am sorry
l'll apologize to the others first thing,
You certainly distinguished yourself
-Shh, they can hear.
Every word you said out there.
You come down here
l'm asking you, when will you settle down
-Never!
Preaching stuff that's none
honestly, Jordan.
You knew what a frightful girl l was
From the first moment,
That fine mind of yours
l thought what we said on the train
But l'll never forget a single word
What a glorious, gorgeous,
And a woman
The best part about quarreling
When we make up, we make up.
Why can't we take a trip, really see Texas?
Everything that's in it and on it
Everything that has a Reata brand on it
That's the way my father ran this outfit
he kept it together for his son,
Don't you think that might be
Why didn't you tell me?
-Are you sure?
And our baby is going to be a boy.
Shouldn't she be putting on
lt's natural, l think,
''l'm helping a young Dr. Guerra
''Almost every day l find myself
''through the dusty and dirty streets
Mr. Gomez, l'm going to leave
he'll tell you things
Thank you, Dr. Guerra.
-howdy, Miss Leslie.
-You made some improvements.
Truthfully, l didn't expect this sort
That's the first time l was ever accused
l'll have a place
l thought maybe they'd kind of
Do you want to come on in here,
having kids seems to agree with you,
l love it. lt seems down here everybody
Mind if l pay you
Don't you need somebody to help you
When l get some time to look around,
You got any attractive sisters there that
why don't they help themselves
When you say ''other people,''
You don't go mixing me up
l'm just as much of Texas
-l'm no wetback.
You're very like Jordan in that respect.
But your situation is so different.
Gomez telephoned.
l've told you before....
You can't go around this place
You've been a powerful Texan for
if l ever hear you get mixed up
-What?
Did you think your naughty mama was
One of these days l'll run
l don't care what you say.
We're all gathered for the fourth
And l want to take
is gonna grow up to be
Maybe he'll even grow up
But that was you.
he is a Benedict. he's gonna stay
-No.
Bick knows everything about running
he doesn't know a thing
and help those children grow up to be
-Good night, Leslie.
-Good night.
-Good night, Bick.
Good night, everybody.
What's happening is we're getting
We've been together every day and night
We're getting in the habit
about things
l think it would be a good idea
-That's not the way l want it, Jordan.
lt'll be better for us
lt'll give us both a chance
-hi, there.
lf l had it to do again,
with this wedding and Thanksgiving
Merciful Father, we bow our heads
We give thee humble and hearty thanks
beseeching thee to continue
that our land may still yield her increase,
lt's a day
but he says,
''l want them to know l miss them
l could see you coming.
We're having a wedding.
''we are gathered here in the sight of God
''to join together this man
''which is an honorable estate
''David, wilt thou have this woman
''To live together after God's ordinance
''Wilt thou love her, comfort her,
''and keep her in sickness and in health,
''keep thee only unto her
''Lacey, wilt thou have this man
''to live together after God's ordinance
''Wilt thou love him, comfort him,
''and keep him in sickness and in health,
''keep thee only unto him
''that he who gives it and she
''and continue in thy favor
''Those whom God hath joined together,
''For as much as David and Lacey have
Are you ready to come back
We Texans like a little vinegar
When Bick finishes this breeding program,
that's 99 percent beef
l don't want him
Jett's got the easement, Bick.
l'm tired of his prospecting.
he's borrowed about all he could.
Buy him out, Ollie.
You all thought Spindletop and
There ain't a dang thing
And there's more down there,
l'm gonna have more money
You and the rest of you
Leslie, go into the house.
He is to cease using the name of my ranch
l won't have oil digging on Reata.
They say Aunt Luz was really in love
Even if she was old enough
She was always trying to keep him
That every girl in Texas was trying
''There wasn't a prize bull like him
l'm sure it's quite true, darling.
Really? lt all sounds so fascinating
_Howdy, Mr. Benedict.
l want to go to Harvard
How about Reata, Jordy?
But there are 50,000 guys who can do it
l don't want to live my life
Your father doesn't want you to die
You can persuade him, Mom.
l wonder if we love them enough
So much that we keep from doing
The theory is she doesn't want
girl's school in Switzerland
Of course she isn't.
lt's got the best animal husbandry course
She wants to be a rancher,
She's just got her little schoolgirl crush
lt seems we've hatched
He wants to be a doctor.
Over my dead body!
He'd die for you, but he's not gonna
He wants to go to Harvard first,
this would mean a big sacrifice
''...unless oil or gas shall have been struck
_Take your social life on the other phone.
_Who's nice?
This is a cattle ranch, not an oil field.
That's about the most expensive
lt'll cost you a billion dollars a year
Couldn't we have just one little, itty_bitty
After reporting to President Roosevelt,
that the battleship Arizona
in the Japanese air raid
Judy, you're gonna get it.
_Merry Christmas, Polo.
Today the wish of all of us is
and that you, Angel,
and to all of those
_Hello, Dr. Guerra.
Don't tell me you haven't learned that
are not the only means of creating
Could you stay and give me the lowdown
_Very nice to meet you.
_Goodbye.
_Let's get some Christmas cheer.
Friends, we're gonna have
l'm gonna drink a toast
That boy is the best dang man
lt's time for you to take your place here,
They need doctors, Dad.
l never would be any good
You're the one with a responsibility
Your blood pressure is going up
lt's Christmas morning. lsn't this
When l come home,
l love Texas as much as you do.
l just want to work in a different way,
lf not, it's about the only thing
l've got some serious talk
l've been watching you pretty close
You could never be anything but a rancher,
_No, sir.
_No, sir, it's not Judy.
''Greetings from the President
''You are hereby notified to report
lt'll make you stay right here.
But this is one thing
When you come back
Can you imagine you'll ever have
Just a little place that'll allow us time
Bob didn't mean to upset you.
We just want something little
l might just as well give it back
Feel free, it's Christmas.
l thought that was next week.
Christmas greetings
l guess Christmas is as good a day as any
The reason l'm going
lt seems that every time we made a deal,
All this oil around here hasn't made
We live pretty much like we always have
The Lord was good to you, to set
We'd have made improvements
But that 27.5 percent tax exemption
That oil tax exemption is the best thing
One of the finest laws ever passed
we're not adverse to accepting
How about an exemption for depreciation
My father's, for instance. He spent his life
Leslie has always been a real sharp talker,
Fair enough, Judge. You've always been
''Do you take each other
''for your lawful wife, according to
''for your lawful husband, according to
l didn't think he was going
On behalf of the U.S. Army, l am proud
l'm gonna fly up to Dallas,
l'll buy myself
you'd better hear
He likes me. He likes my family, too.
if l didn't know you had a level Benedict
He's a rough rhinestone.
You got to have $10 million
The most important people
lt'll be heard across the nation
lf you people stay away, Leslie, you'll be
You'll be putting on your pink shoes and
We're oil rich, like the rest of them.
lnvite everybody.
We'll show that so_and_so
We'll fly in low and shake the tiles
_lsn't this something?
Jett always tries to do things
To some folks, he's just
lsn't this terrific?
My daughter, queen of Jett Rink Day!
She's done things before l haven't
lt's not exactly sneaky,
But Luz is intelligent enough
Did my daughter
Get this. As soon as she comes in,
Some girls might like a hotel
Me, l like company, Jett.
You want lots of people?
lf there's anything you want,
No, that's impossible.
You know as well as l do, Cokes are taboo.
Do you like things your way?
And you won't either,
and get your man
So if l was you,
You looked like a queen
You could be the head lady
if you wanted to.
with all them thousands
You want me to say something
You're fascinating to me.
l hope this storm doesn't louse up
A slip_up, boy. l just forgot
What's wrong with you?
l'm Jordan Benedict,
Mr. Rink said he'd have my neck
You Benedicts are all close together.
Grand opening of the Jett Rink Airport
is the latest milestone in the dramatic
_lt's time you got here.
_Who's calling, please?
Keep everybody freshened up, will you?
We're anxious to see old Jett come out
Why couldn't they ride with us
Luz had to fly her own plane
Their behavior is odd,
l wouldn't be here unless you let them
Now, for heaven's sake,
Cool down, go on with your shaving, finish
Hurry on in there.
Stay right there, honey.
You wanted me to go over
l'm sorry, but it happens to be
The young lady should have gone
_Are you having fun?
_How are you doing?
lf you can spare me a moment,
Jordan, we must hurry to be in time
Help me round everybody up.
We haven't changed a single comma.
''Columbus discovered only the shell
''You've heard of Paul Revere?''
''Oh, yes. Ain't he the fellow
Where we had our hair done. Jordy wants
On account of Juana. The girl said
What's the matter, boy?
Get them up, Rink! Everybody knows
You want it in front of everybody,
l don't care much whether it's here
so long as l get one punch
And now, to introduce our guest of honor,
known from the rocky coast of Maine
You had this coming to you
l'm going to ask you
as l turn back the pages
and l recall the first time
_Where's the boy?
afraid of neither opposition
to the greater glory of the state
which, in turn,
and to the thousands of you
l have the great honor to introduce
Dr. Guerra set up an auxiliary hospital.
You'll make better time
Me, too. lf we weren't transporting
l hope she doesn't let this
it's just one of those things.
Go ahead and forget it.
We've had just about enough excitement
You've always had a mind of your own
You knew what you were doing
l told you myself the morning
l told you then that l knew
but that marrying her was asking
Lots of folks in these parts
l know those people. We've run
l'm concerned it has to do with the people
Just the simple truth. That's you.
l don't care about Jett Rink,
l'm a fair man. l've been fair all my life,
And you, my own son,
there's ways of living,
that folks abide by when they want
l always say that Juana is
Don't sit there and prove what l say!
When that ruckus started,
_Who took him to account? Your old man.
_Yes!
descendant of the long, proud line
got knocked flat on his back
Mom, you made a mistake when you got
l'm shocked at you! l'm shocked
l'll never forget the sight of my brother
with all of our friends, disgracing us!
lf you keep seeing Jett,
lt seems that my family
lf l only knew how to apologize to him,
He passed out like a light
The party broke up early,
You're not going up there,
Luz, it's not like you
l know where he is, honey.
l've always held a strange power
What do you say, doll face?
Leave him alone.
Ladies and gentlemen
that this great domain
You've got to work and sweat
Pretty Leslie.
Juana, how does a hamburger
Let's stop at this drive_in
Nice place you have here. l've been
What do you recommend?
The plane should arrive in Benedict
Look here, Sarge. l'd sure appreciate it
l'm Bick Benedict.
The name Benedict's meant something
Go sit down,
But this bunch's gonna eat
ls that the best
There's a lot of Clair de Lune
Those kids, in their infinite wisdom,
They know l'm a disgrace.
Hello, Vashti. We're all fine.
_They all made it back in one piece.
Yes, all our guests have finally gone.
Luz has gone on to Hollywood with Lola,
She decided she would like to see
All you can do is raise them.
Jordy and Juana are gonna move
The sun's going down over the yardarm.
Remember, one of these days
l'm going to stay right here.
Roundup time is no time
Honey, everybody's on the move.
l wouldn't mind it too much if you wanted
Where do you think l've been
You really want to know
My own grandson doesn't even look
There's times when a man
l just feel like my saddle's turning
Don't ask me why.
You know all that fine riding
and all that glamour stuff
But none of it ever made you
as you were on the floor
and landed crashing
When we went into that place,
Before we went in,
''Jordan and l, and the others behind us,
You wound up on the floor, on your back,