Put some stones in the vase,
or it'll fall over.
This bloody wind!
Polish the letters well, they have to shine!
There are so many widows in this village!
The women here live longer than the men.
Except our poor mother.
She was lucky.
Raimunda! Don't say that!
She died in Dad's arms,
and she loved him more than anyone.
Burned to death!
I can't imagine a worse way to die.
They were asleep
They didn't even realize.
Even so, how can you say
something like that!
Hello, Agustina.
Good morning, Agustina.
Good morning, Manola.
- Good morning.
Is that everything, Mom?
I'll get the rest.
What a pleasant surprise!
Good Lord!
- Could this be Paula?
- Of course.
She's all grown up!
Give her a kiss
She's got your father's eyes
How are you?
Not good
Don't say that...
I just came to check on my grave
with this wind,
you can't keep it clean.
It looks lovely.
Cleaning it relaxes me.
I often come here on my own,
I sit down and the hours pass by...
We'd better leave,
we're going to visit Aunt Paula
Come and see me afterwards.
Sure.
And... how's Paco doing?
Fine, he stayed in Madrid, working
Mom, does Agustina really come
and clean her own grave?
Yes, it's custom here
They buy a plot
and look after it all their lives,
like a second home.
That's creepy!
It's tradition here.
Shall I drive?
Yes.
Aunt Paula!
Who is it?
Raimunda.
Don't take all day.
...And you, don't start rushing me
I don't like going back
after dark.
Be nice to Auntie,
don't laugh at her.
All right.
This house still smells like Mom.
How are you, Auntie?
Look at how thin you are!
Have you had the baby?
Fourteen years ago.
Doesn't time fly!
Who are these people?
Who do you think?
Sole and my Paula!
The same name as me!
...and Sole
Shall we go into the dining room?
That Sole looks
like quite a sourpuss.
Auntie, please!
... the wind carried
the cinders to the bushes.
The result is the most tragic fire
in the last 13 years.
Do you mind if I turn it off?
I'm not even watching it...
Fires are a terrible thing.
That's the way your parents died, my dear
Why did I come in here?
I don't know, Auntie.
...to talk maybe?
No
Maybe for something to eat?
Yes! Look in the cupboard.
My joints are killing me...
Look, these pastries...
Just like mom's... have one
Well... How did it go in the cemetery?
Your mother is delighted.
Did you scrub
the headstone properly?
Of course, Auntie.
She likes it very clean.
If she could, she would do it herself...
but of course, the poor thing can't.
Of course, she can't.
Auntie, don't you ever get lonely
in such a big house?
No.
You'd be better off in a home,
where you'd be looked after.
I'm fine as I am, thank you.
I'm going to the bathroom.
Permission granted.
You can't live on your own.
I'm worried about you.
How do you manage your meals?
Very well...
Agustina brings me bread,
your mother does the cooking,
...and if I need anything from the store,
I just call them and they bring it over.
I'm fine.
What a lovely gesture, Auntie!
Look!
It's got your name on it.
Shall we go?
Yes.
Aunt Paula, we're leaving now.
God, my joints are bad...!
Don't get up.
How am I not going to get up?
Next time I come back,
I'm taking you home with me.
Yes, that's fine, next time.
The important thing is that you
come back, Raimunda
You've gotten very wobbly.
Take care of yourself.
I will
And you be careful!
We'll do that.
I love you so much!
Are we stopping by Agustina's place?
Yes.
Come on in!
So, how did you find your auntie?
Bad.
Terrible.
She's very clumsy.
I don't know how she manages
She does very well
without going outside.
Every day she has her chunk of bread,
when I arrive she has the money ready
Let's go out to the patio.
She's in an awful state,
She doesn't know what year it is.
She talks about Mom
as if she were still alive.
Yes.
It's because for her, she's not dead
and she can't get used to it
Have a seat for a while, please...
I was thinking about paying you something
to look in on her every day.
No need to give me anything.
It's my pleasure.
I'd take her with me...
but I'd have to throw
my husband out to make room.
but we have to do something
Every morning, before I go shopping,
I tap on her window
and I don't leave
until she answers me.
I keep an eye on her.
You can't imagine how
grateful I am, Agustina
I just think that hopefully...
someone is doing the same
for my own mother...
...wherever she is.
See how modern she was?
The only hippie in the village.
Look at her plastic jewelry
They're cool!
Top quality plastic
Every time I smoke a joint
I think of her
Oh please! Look at the example
you're setting for Paula!
Still no news?
Nothing. It's like she's disappeared
from the face of the earth
How's your sister Brigida?
Her? Still in Madrid,
she's a big hit on trash TV.
Mom, I ran out of credit...
Good, we'll get a break
from your phone.
Use mine if you like...
Don't! She'll bankrupt you.
forget it then...
As I was saying,
Brigida is on so many shows
That she's going to put a deposit
on an apartment in Madrid.
And she's going to record an album
Your sister always liked singing...
You did too! Do you remember
when the two of you...
you were 13 or so, weren't you?
You went to an audition
for young talent.
Really?
You never told me about that!
It was your granny's idea.
She was up for anything.
Talking about mothers,
maybe yours hasn't shown up
so as not to ruin
your sister's career.
I don't think so...
Mom would love to be on TV...
She'd have the time of her life.
Would you like some?
No, no, no, no...
I grow it myself.
Check out my plants!
No, no, no...
Girl, we should get going.
Right. Listen... did you report her
disappearance to the police?
We didn't,
Brigida thinks it's not necessary...
since she's mentioned it so often on TV...
Yes, but you have to report it
to the police, not say it on TV.
Look, I don't know...
Anyway, It's not the first time
your mother left home
Yes, but never for this long.
It's been three and a half years already
Don't give up hope.
and take care of yourself, you don't look well...
Your oleander is gorgeous.
Yes, this year it managed to escape from the aphids.
But I've really lost my appetite
Maybe it's because of the pot...
No way, if it weren't for the pot,
I would never eat
You have your grandpa's eyes.
Pot gives me an appetite,
and mellows me out
Right then, have a nice trip home!
You won't believe what I saw
upstairs outside the bathroom...
What?
An exercise bike.
That's nuts
Why would Auntie want an exercise bike,
when she can barely walk?
Exactly, she's lost her mind.
Don't talk like that about her, Sole.
Mom, she didn't even recognize us.
It's the hot, dry wind there
that makes so many people crazy.
The donuts are very tasty, don't you think?
How does she manage to make pastries
when she can barely see?
Hello, Regina.
You off to work?
I have no choice, my dear
Hey listen, why don't you give her a lift?
Where to?
To casa de campo, but if you could drop
me downtown that would be great
OK.
- Thanks.
Later.
Hi, dad.
- Hi.
What's up?
How was it?
Did you enjoy yourselves?
At the cemetery? Are you kidding me?
No, no.
So, taking care of yourself?
Me? What are you talking about?
Paula, sit properly!
Close those legs, dammit!
Will you bring me another beer?
You must be joking...
Get me another beer, please.
Paco, you've had enough already.
You have to go to work tomorrow.
I'm off tomorrow, and the day after.
- How's that?
They fired me.
Hang on a second...
Goddamn it!
I'll have to look for a job on Sundays,
my only day off
I'll look for a job, but let me
watch the game in peace and quiet.
You can kiss goodbye
soccer and cable TV, too
Aren't we a poor family?
So we'll live like one!
Paula, get off the phone right now!
Here's supper if you want it
Are you mad?
- No.
I'm worried about my aunt.
She's worse than ever.
She didn't recognize Paula or Sole.
How can anyone live like that?
- Well she can.
Paco, leave me alone.
What's with you?
I'm wiped out,
and I have to be up early tomorrow.
OK, I'll do all the work...
Paco please, don't be a pest
Don't you call me a pest again
I'm sorry
What are you doing here?
Waiting for you
How come?
I called to remind you
to get bread, we're out
I didn't occur to you to buy some?
- No
You're soaking wet.
How long have you been out?
I don't know. A while.
Where have you been?
With your girlfriends?
No.
I wasn't anywhere.
Then why didn't you answer your phone?
What's the matter with you? Huh?
Is something wrong?
What is it, tell me!
And your father?
He is...
Where?
He's in the kitchen.
What happened?
I was in the kitchen...
standing at the counter...
suddenly he started pressing
himself against me...
He was drunk.
I shouted at him what was he doing,
He said he wasn't really my father.
I turned around and
shoved him off of me...
but he just grabbed me again, harder
I pushed him off
He unzipped his pants. He kept
saying that it wasn't wrong
because he's not my father.
I opened a drawer, took out a knife...
and threatened him
just to scare him off
It didn't faze him
He said I wasn't brave enough...
pulled me to the floor...
...and jumped on top of me
What are you going to do, Mom?
I don't know.
Go and get changed, you'll catch pneumonia
Paula!
Remember this: I killed him
and you didn't see anything
because you were out.
It's important that you remember that.
Don't answer
Who can that be?
- I don't know, go to your room
Raimunda, it's me, Emilio.
I'm coming, Emilio
What's up?
Sorry to bother you so late,
but I'm going to Barcelona tomorrow.
I wanted to leave you the keys to the
restaurant, in case someone wants to see it.
I wouldn't mind showing it,
but I'm hardly ever here.
How about Paco?
He's usually here all day, isn't he?
Well Paco...
...finally found a job.
He's starting tomorrow.
Are you hurt?
No.
Just my monthlies.
Actually, the thing is...
now that Paco is busy,
I'll have more free time...
Give me the keys, I'll manage
Here's my phone numbers.
My brother's, where I'll be staying...
the other is my cell phone.
So you're leaving tomorrow?
In the morning...
Just out of curiosity, how much are you
asking? I've always liked your restaurant...
It's a pity you don't like the owner as well...
Emilio, for God's sake...
For the business sale I'm asking 30,000,
but it's negotiable
OK, we'll miss you.
And I'll miss you girls.
Good luck.
- Thanks.
Is Emilio leaving?
- Yes.
Go back to your room, Paula.
No, I want to stay with you.
Listen, I'll need your help later.
Don't answer it!
It'll be one of your girlfriends.
Get it and say
you can't talk now...
... it's too late
I can't talk right now.
- What are you saying?
It's your Aunt Sole...
Put your mom on the phone.
Mom, it's Aunt Sole
Tell her I'm busy.
Auntie, she's busy right now.
Get her on the phone, it's important
Mom, you have to take this.
Sole, I have loads of clothes to iron
and I've been working
all evening at the airport
Agustina called.
Aunt Paula died.
When?
A little while ago
Aunt Paula died.
I was just thinking
about moving her in here.
The poor thing must have died all alone.
Don't cry, dear
Look, Agustina said not to worry.
She and Squinty will lay her out
before we get there.
Auntie had everything prearranged!
She'd already chosen her coffin,
and paid for everything!
It's amazing that
she was so lucid at the end.
I can't make it to her funeral.
As much as it hurts me but I'm too busy.
How can you not come, Raimunda?
You can't come with me?
I just can't, no way...
You'll have to go alone.
- Alone?
No way! You know how scared
I am of dead people.
But you don't have to see Auntie
I'll ask Agustina to take care of that
And if they ask me about you?
Tell them then that I just had a
gall bladder operation... whatever
Look, I'll go as soon as I can,
but right now it's completely impossible
I don't understand you, Raimunda.
Aunt Paula loved you so much!
and I loved her, too.
Look, Sole, I'll explain it to you someday,
and when I do, you'll flip out.
I'm flipping out already.
All right, take a tranquilizer,
I'll take one too...
And in the morning, you go
Okay?
- Okay.
The door.
Wait.
You stay here.
Stay here and stand guard.
I hope it hasn't changed
since I worked here.
Don't come in here!
Sorry.
What do you want?
I wanted to see
if the restaurant was open.
We're closed. Why?
Give me a hand...
We're shooting a movie in the area
and I'm looking for a place
to cater for the crew
Do you know of a restaurant nearby?
How many of you are there?
25 plus 5... 30 people.
Help me out here.
I can do it myself, if you want.
We were supposed to be closed today.
So dinner for 30...
When?
We stop at 3:30, and we're close by...
Say around 4:00?
- Fine.
Good
Right and... how much would you pay?
10 euro each
That's fine.
Sorry for shouting at you before,
you scared me
I'll see you at 4:00 then, thanks very much
OK, thanks
See you later
Damn! It's 10:00 already.
Two kilos
Can I have two more?
How much are the potatoes?
1.60 for 4 kilos
I'll take 8 kilos
- Okay.
How are you Regina?
- Hello, Raimunda. That's quite a load of groceries!
I'm cooking dinner for 30 people
Can you lend me 100 euro?
I'm broke, I just bought a
huge pork roast...
That'd be perfect! I'll buy it off you!
It cost me 10.80,
and it's the only thing I got
I'll pay you for it tomorrow.
Please! do this favor for me!
All right. I'll bring it over
Thank you, sweetie!
Today I go on a diet.
Why not, it'll be good for you
Hi, Ines.
So you're back from the village?
Yes, I got back last night.
How are you?
Did you happen to bring
any sausage or chorizo?
I certainly did!
The sausages are fantastic.
My mother-in-law orders them
specially for me.
I need one and a half kilos.
How's that?
I'm cooking dinner for 30.
- Who's coming?
Is a long story, I'll tell you some other time.
Can you sell it to me? I'll pay you tomorrow
Of course. Don't you worry, I'll bring it over.
Thanks! and... wait,
did you get any sweets?
I got some cookies that will melt in your mouth...
With your high cholesterol and glucose
cookies are the last thing you need!
It's my only vice.
I've got three boxes of them.
You shouldn't be eating them.
I shouldn't? And what should I do,
give them away?
Sell them to me
OK, but let me at least try them
Of course, have two, three, four...
But don't be a glutton.
- Bring them round to me, love.
- I'll do that.
See you later.
- Bye, doll
Anybody for roast pork? It's delicious...
You too?
Pork roast? It's yummy.
Agustina?
Is that you, Agustina?
Soledad, my dear child
Sole, I have to talk to you.
Sole!
All right.
It's okay, calm down, Sole.
Agustina...
Where is she?
- Upstairs, in my mother's room.
The best room in the house
I brought her here,
so we can give her a better wake.
Thank you very much, Agustina.
Come on,
we're the principal mourners.
Good afternoon.
- Good afternoon.
I spoke with your sister, poor thing,
just out of surgery!
Yes, unfortunate timing, huh?
She told me not to let you see the body.
Don't worry, you won't have to see her...
I'm sorry my dear
My condolences.
And you remember Squinty, don't you?
Say hello to Vicenta's daughter.
Let her catch her breath,
she's exhausted.
Come here, Sole,
don't fret, sit here beside me
It was already dark
I had finished supper and was
watching TV
when I heard someone knocking at the door.
I wasn't sure if I had heard right,
but then I heard it again.
"Who is it?" I asked.
And then I heard a voice say:
"Agustina"
I wasn't afraid
I looked outside,
but I didn't see anyone
I looked over at your aunt's house.
and I noticed the front door was standing open.
I thought that was odd,
so I went over...
I called out for your aunt,
but she didn't answer.
And how could she, poor thing?
I went into the bedroom
and there she was, in bed
utterly still and quiet.
Her spirit called you.
But was it Paula's spirit
or the other one's?
One of them.
I can't say who it was
because I didn't see
But, as true as I'm talking to you now
someone or something
warned me that Paula had died
and opened the front door to let me in.
Come into the kitchen.
I bet you haven't eaten yet.
- No, I haven't
Not since last night,
but I'm all right.
I thought as much.
This'll do you good.
Don't give me any more, that's plenty.
What did the women mean, Agustina?
Nothing, just talk.
You know what villages are like.
They were talking about my mother.
Some people say they've seen her.
They say she came back
to take care of your Aunt Paula.
Has she ever appeared to you?
- No. What about you?
- No, me neither.
But those things happen.
I know.
My grandfather, rest in peace,
appeared to my grandmother
At first she was scared
Go on, eat!
But then, she asked him what he wanted
and my grandpa's ghost told her
that he had left an unkept promise
My grandmother carried out the promise
and the whole village
went with her to the cemetery
where they left my grandfather
so he would rest in peace...
...and he never appeared again.
This isn't just some story I heard
It's what really happened
I see...
Do you want to come have a look
around your auntie's house?
in case you want to take anything?
No, I'll leave that to Raimunda
Tell her everything went very well,
and that the whole village came.
I'll tell her
I'm going to miss her so much!
Go on...
Sole!
Open up!
It's your mother.
I'm not going to harm you
My mother is dead.
You must be her ghost or her spirit
OK, have it your way,
but let me out of here!
I'm in the trunk!
Right, it's unbelievable the
things you come up with, Mom...
Soledad...
my dear daughter...
Don't be afraid of me
I am your mother.
Aren't you going to hug me, my love?
OK... give me a hand
here...
Aunt Paula's suitcase!
- Yes.
What's in it?
- Clothes, and some of her valuables.
I took them before the neighbors got there.
Except for Agustina, they were all
picking through her drawers and cabinets
But I had already done the "cleaning"
You'll have to get a nice gift for
Agustina, she's behaved properly
Much better than you sister did
It's shocking she didn't go to the funeral!
If you'd heard
what Squinty said about her!
Thank God you came
I'm sore from that ride
Are you staying the night?
- Where else would I go?
Ugh! I look terrible.
No wonder you were scared!
Do you still have the illegal hair salon?
- Of course, that's how I make a living
Is that the guest room?
Yes, that's it.
Tomorrow, give me a haircut and dye my hair.
And I'll need sunglasses
I don't want to be
stuck in the house all day.
I have to go out.
Nobody knows me here.
In the village, I couldn't
even go to the front door.
I need some fresh air
Are you staying long?
You want to get rid of me already?
- No, just asking...
I'm not planning to leave anytime soon,
if you don't mind
When you get tired of me,
just let me know.
But a for separated woman, who would
be better company than her mother?
Unless you've got a boyfriend...
No, Mom.
I'm alone, as usual.
Not anymore.
Answer the phone.
- Are you back yet?
- Yes, I am.
You were out of range,
so I phoned Agustina.
She said everything went very well.
The whole village came.
I've been thinking about you all day.
I would have loved to be there.
Hold on a second, Sole...
300, right?
What do I owe you for the drinks?
- Nothing, drinks are on the house.
OK then... Same time tomorrow?
Everyone in the crew was very happy
Glad to hear it.
and if you don't mind,
even if you have to charge more
could the portions could be a bit larger?
Tomorrow I'll feed you until you burst.
Great. See you tomorrow, then.
- See you tomorrow
Sorry, Sole...
- Did you get a job in a restaurant?
Yes, I took over Emilio's.
Oh!
He was sick of it,
but that's not the only news...
Paco left us.
That's why I couldn't
make it to the funeral.
When you called,
we were in the middle of an argument.
I knew there was something wrong
Did he beat you?
- No, he wasn't violent
He just left.
Forever.
He'll be back, you'll see.
I seriously doubt it.
How can you be so sure?
Call it intuition.
All right, kiss, kiss
To you, too.
- Bye
You know, none of us
have had any luck with men.
Raimunda and I haven't
but you...
Me, what?
Dad adored you.
Raimunda said you were lucky
because you died in the arms
of the person you loved most.
Raimunda is not a bad person,
but she's got a nasty streak.
I was blindly in love with your father.
and he cheated on me
until the day he died!
What are you saying, Mom?
It's true. I've kept that quiet all my life.
I never wanted you two to know.
But let's drop it. I don't want
to speak ill of the dead.
- Is his ghost going to appear?
- I hope not.
How about your husband?
What about my husband?
Could he show up here any day?
- I don't think so.
I haven't heard from him
in two years.
All the better,
that way it'll just be the two of us
The pork was 10?
- 10.80.
- I'll give you an extra 3 euros.
- Thanks, Mundi.
And I'll pay you for 4 boxes of
cookies instead of three.
Thank you.
- I don't want you to think that I took advantage of you
Can you give me a hand with this?
I can't move it on my own.
Where are you taking it?
To the restaurant
You're the moving expert, tell us how...
Get ahold of it,
tip it over, but not all the way.
Otherwise, we won't get it through.
Is this all right?
Yes, straighten up, veer a bit to your right,
more to the right...
We can't see anything.
I'll guide you.
Now, careful, it'll come this way.
All the way...
Don't rush it
Are we at the door?
Yes, OK. Let's go, the elevator is here
Wait, wait.
This has to go in straight.
I'll take this end.
You take it.
That's it, that's it...
My God, what an ordeal!
Ouch!
Careful!
My God!
Press the button downstairs
I want them to see that
we don't use frozen food
It's all natural, fresh every day
Over to the corner
and the other freezer?
That's not working
Right, so you're taking over the restaurant?
At least until yesterday's customers
finish their movie
Then I'll see.
You can count on me.
I make great desserts.
And I could serve drinks at night!
I don't know yet if we'll work nights,
but I'm counting on both of you.
- Sure
- Thanks a lot
Mom?
Hm?
There's something you want me to do, right?
Cut my hair.
I mean...
...is there anything you couldn't do
while you were alive,
that's still bothering you
There's always things
that are left unfinished,
or badly done
And my life was no exception
but I don't know if things can be fixed,
And even if they can,
it is up to me to fix them
Customers will start arriving any minute now.
What will we do?
Attend to them. I'll help you.
I can't introduce you as my mother,
everyone knows I'm an orphan.
I can pretend I'm a foreigner
A foreigner? From where?
The Dominican Republic?
No, that won't work. Too many in the
neighborhood, they'll notice your accent's all wrong.
Chinese?
Madrid is full of Chinese people
Now who's going to believe
that you're Chinese, Mom?
We need something rare,
that's not in the neighborhood.
Russian!
Do you really think I look more Russian
than Chinese?
Yes, Russians look just like us.
Look, whatever you hear,
keep your mouth shut.
and don't make it obvious
that you understand
I'll show you how everything works
In the main room I cut, dry and color
In here I do the hair washing
If the customer is tall,
remove the pillow.
If she's short, you use it.
This towel is so you won't slip.
I have this here
because up there is not handy,
and if I leave it down
I have to bend down so many times
it kills my back
Yeah, my back hurts me, too
The shampoo is automatically dispensed.
Have a seat, Mom.
Are you OK?
- Yes
Just one towel
or the client will feel suffocated.
I know the feeling...
Afterwards, with the same towel,
you dry her a bit,
so it won't drip down her back
You've got everything so well organized...
Hi
Hello.
- Hi dear
- Hi
- Hello
She doesn't speak Spanish, she's Russian
Oh! they're having a terrible time,
the poor things
Yes, I took her in out of charity.
When I saw her begging in the street,
she reminded me of my mother.
Don't trust all the old women you see
Especially Russians. Most of them are in the mafia.
You're too good, people take advantage of you
You want highlights? Sit here
Wash hair, right?
She was a hairdresser back in Russia.
How do understand each other?
With gestures. She's very smart,
as sharp as a tack!
She'll be speaking Spanish in no time
I wouldn't be surprised... look how many
Russian top models are there nowadays
Dear me!
So Russian then?...
- Russia
The water...
Not hot...
not cold... no
Very good
Thank you
Hi
What's up?
We have tomorrow off
Then, so do we.
We're due for a break.
And we finish up next week.
We want to have
the wrap party here.
That's great! Do you want a
sit-down meal or a buffet?
A buffet would be great.
And we'd like to have
the terrace just for us.
Sure, no problem, I can do that.
And don't look at me like that,
you make me nervous.
likewise
Go and get yourself a drink,
I have work to do.
OK
Since she came back from the village,
she sounds strange over the phone.
If she asks you about Paco,
you know nothing.
Which is the actually the truth
Paula, the less you know, the better
And, above all, try not to think about it
Hello.
Hi
Do you have company?
- No
I'm going to the bathroom
The bathroom, what for?
I have to pee.
It's out of order.
I'm waiting for the plumber.
I'll throw some water down,
I really need to go, for heaven's sake.
Uh, Hello.
And what's with you?
I'm at a difficult age
Same as myself!
I'll trim your hair a little
Don't, I can see you coming
Just the split ends
Less than an inch
Listen...
Is your father back yet?
Nope. He said goodbye forever.
That's incredible.
I just don't understand.
Yuck, it stinks in here!
And your mother?
- What?
She's such a pain!
Ever since she was a child.
Realize that in those days
we didn't have a bathroom
We did our business in the backyard
We had to be constantly waiting for her
She spent all day long in the backyard,
with the chickens
Raimunda!
Raimunda.
What's this robe doing here?
It's Mom's
I know.
And that smell!
What smell?
In the bathroom, and in here!
It's like she was just here farting
up a storm...!
Don't you smell it?
My God, she cut some killers!
And she could never hide it
because she was the first to crack up!
It's as if I can hear her laughing now.
Don't be silly!
Why did you bring these clothes?
No wonder you have nightmares.
Dead people's clothes should be given away.
- Right
Aunt Paula's suitcase!
The antique dolls!
Her jewelry case!
What were you planning to do with all this?
Nothing.
- Nothing? You were going to keep it!
Who would've said, Sole...
Raimunda, please, it's not what you think
I didn't bring the suitcase.
Yeah, right! Then how did it get here?
When I arrived at Aunt Paula's...
What?
Look, if they had told me
I wouldn't have believed it
Stealing the few things she had
before she was even in the grave.
You should be ashamed of yourself!
Raimunda, don't leave this way!
We have to buy another fridge.
Why don't you repair the one in the storeroom?
That one is no good.
Well, the motor's making a noise.
I told you nobody goes in there,
including you.
I saw the door was open
and went in to get a hammer.
Has anyone else gone in there?
I don't think so.
Mom, you said
you got rid of him
Well I couldn't, Paula
Do you think I like
having him in there?
Paula, get ready,
they'll be here in half an hour.
Paula?
What is this?
How come you're still like that?
I'm not in a party mood.
Me neither, but it's work
Don't be lazy.
Come on, I'll give you a hand
What's wrong?
I can't get him out of my head,
having him there, in the storeroom
That's the best way for you to go mad,
and to drive me crazy, too.
Mom, you don't know what it's like
to have killed your own father.
Paco was not your father.
Stop lying to me.
I know you're doing it for me,
but please, just stop lying to me
I'm not lying to you
Paco took you as his daughter
but he knew that he was not
your biological father
So he was telling the truth then?
Yes, but that doesn't justify what he did
Paula, I promise I'll tell you
everything, I swear, but some other time
Now let's get ready.
We won't fix anything staying here
So who was my father?
A guy from the village.
Do I know him?
He's dead
Paula, I swear that I'll tell you
everything, but later.
I'll hold you to your word on that
- Two mojitos!
- Two mojitos coming up!
What would you like, handsome?
Two mojitos as well?
With lemon.
It's perfect.
We need more glasses
I can hardly keep up.
Doesn't Paula look pretty?
Here...
- Thanks.
How scrumptious!
I'm not drinking anymore, they're too good!
Between your cleavage and my mojitos
we can make a fortune
We should stay open nights
and try to liven up...
...this lousy neighborhood.
We'll talk about it, but for now the important
thing is...
...that they're satisfied tonight.
Have a mojito!
Stay down, so they don't see you.
I'd love to see Raimunda
and Paula.
The other day I could only see their feet
And look at the fuss you caused!
Is that the restaurant?
She said she was doing well,
but I never imagined this!
She deserves it.
The poor thing has suffered a lot
Don't get out of the car,
and stay down, and don't let anyone see you.
No one can see me here!
What are you doing here?
I'm glad to see you.
I brought you Aunt Paula's things.
I didn't know you were having a party.
It's the film crew's party,
celebrating the end of the shoot
I've been catering for them.
Let's put away the suitcase
Why did you bother?
It would have never occurred to me
To take anything from Auntie,
much less hiding it from you
I know, I'm sorry for what I said
But you know me, I fly off the handle.
Hi, Auntie
- Hi
Would you like anything?
- No, thank you.
Tacata, tacata
I can see the twinkling
of the distant lights
guiding my return
You remember?
How could I forget?
It's been so long since I heard you sing!
I've never heard her sing
Really?
- Yes Mom, really
And would you like to, my dear?
What do you think? Of course!
Come on!
I can't believe it.
Where should I sit?
There
Quiet! Sit down, this woman is going to sing!
Good evening.
I would like to thank the crew
for the work you've given us
these past weeks.
Thank you very much, with all my heart.
I haven't sung for a long, long time
but I'll give it a try
and see how it goes.
I'm afraid of the encounter
the past that is coming back
to confront my life
Your grandmother
taught your mother this song
for the young talent audition
I'm afraid of the nights
that, full of memories
enchain my dreams
but the fleeing traveller
sooner or later must come to a halt
and even though oblivion,
which destroys everything
has shattered my illusions
I keep holding on to
a humble hope
And that is all
of my heart's fortune
Coming back
with a wrinkled forehead
the snows of time
silvering my temple
feeling
that life is an instant,
that 20 years is nothing,
that the feverish eyes,
wandering in the shadows
looks for you and names you
Living
With my soul clinging
to a sweet memory
that I weep for again
Bravo!
Autos Amigo, can I help you?
Hi, good morning. I'm calling about your ad
I'd like to rent a van
What kind and for how long?
The cheapest one you have.
It's just for one day.
Hello?
- Can I speak to Mrs. Raimunda?
Speaking.
Mr. Emilio gave me your number
so you could show me the restaurant.
I've been trying to see it for a few days now.
My name is Carlos.
The thing is...
Pity you didn't call earlier.
because a neighbor has taken it over.
But Mr. Emilio didn't tell me anything about that.
Of course, he has his strategies,
just in case
Could I talk to the person that took it?
This is her day off, I'm sorry
If you call Mr. Emilio, I'm sure
he'll explain everything to you
OK. Thank you.
Good bye.
Hello?
- Emilio, hi. It's Raimunda.
Good to hear from you!
Did a man go to see the restaurant?
Yes, but I got a bad feeling about him.
I think he wants it as a cover
A cover? For what?
For drugs, to set up a brothel... I don't know
When I told him that the business wasn't
doing well, he said that was even better
How could you say that?
Look, Emilio, I wanted to call you days ago
and I hope that you understand me
I know I'm not supposed to do things this way but...
I kept the restaurant for myself.
You did? What do you mean?
If you give me five minutes, I can explain to you
You went too far, Raimunda, way too far
Yes
You took advantage of my trust in you
I know it's no excuse,
but when the film crew showed up
I was desperate,
and now that Paco left us.
Paco left you?
Yes. We had a big fight
He left and I don't think he's coming back
He left the same day
you left to Barcelona.
How are you coping with it?
Me? I'm hysterical.
Clutching at straws.
Well, OK, so... we'll try to sort it out
Tell me how much I owe you for a month's rent
and I'll send it to you, but give me a few days
Yes?
- Raimunda?
Yes, who is it?
It's Agustina. I'm in Madrid,
and I'd like to see you.
Agustina, today is a bad day, I'm very busy
And tomorrow?
No, the whole week is a real mess.
Don't tell me that, I'm in the hospital.
What happened?
I've got cancer. The doctors told me yesterday
I need to see you.
Tell me which hospital you're in,
and I'll come by today.
I'm in the Central Hospital
God bless you for this, Raimunda.
Thanks.
You go up, I'm in a hurry.
Give this to your aunt
Hi, Auntie.
- What are you doing here?
Sole!
Is that your mother shouting?
Sole, come to the window!
What?
I'm leaving Paula with you!
Raimunda, I've got work to do.
I have to go to the hospital.
Agustina has cancer.
That's terrible! Poor thing!
Paula has Aunt Paula's suitcase,
you keep it.
I'm going to run errands, I'll be back
as soon as I'm finished
Say hi to Agustina.
Tell her that you saw me
Yes, nuisance.
Can I come in now, Auntie?
Yes, sweetie, come on in.
How are you, dear?
They opened me up and then closed me again
I knew that I had something bad
Don't lose hope.
The flowers are beautiful
You shouldn't have bothered
Put them there...
Raimunda,
I have to ask you for a favor.
Whatever you want, Agustina.
Close the door.
Grab a chair.
I don't have much time left.
But I don't want to die without knowing
what happened to my mother.
But what can I do?
You can tell me
if she's dead or alive.
And how would I know?
Ask your mother.
My mother?
But she's dead, Agustina!
I know. But she appeared to your Aunt Paula
and she took care of her until she died.
The whole village knows.
If she appears to you,
ask her about my mother.
That's all I'm asking from you.
Agustina, what you're asking me is insane.
Did you ever see her...
...with your own eyes?
No.
Then, since you live across the street,
and never saw her...
I think she hid from me.
But I heard your aunt a thousand times,
God bless her, talking to her
Look, if I find out anything, I'll be sure to tell you.
But it's quite unlikely
You owe it to me, Raimunda
I'm only asking you for this one thing
OK, I have to go, I have a lot of things to do.
Wait, my sister wants to see you.
She'll be here any minute.
Some other day.
I really have to go.
She wants you to go on TV.
You know she works on
"Wherever You Are"
They want to produce a special
and they thought of you
Since you were friends as children,
and you both went to the audition...
...with all that, they figure they have
enough for three or four programs...
...with interviews, music and songs...
...from all the time you've known each other.
Tell your sister that I don't like TV.
Me neither. I'll tell her.
But don't forget what I asked you
OK, I won't
The Russian really likes watching TV!
I'm not sure what she understands,
but she's glued to it.
There's something about trash TV.
Myself, when I sit in front of it,
I can't quit watching.
I feel worse every minute,
but I can't get up
It's like a drug
I had to stop watching it at night,
because I slept so badly afterwards
All that screaming drives you crazy.
Do you like dolls?
I like these, they look like
they're from a horror movie.
They're quite ancient.
Your mom played with them
when she was pregnant with you
Why didn't Mom live with you?
We were broke
Your grandfather went to work in Venezuela
I kept Sole
and your mother moved in with Aunt Paula.
What has she told you?
Nothing, she doesn't like talking about that time
Do you get along well?
Better now
But she's unbearable at times, grandma
She's got a strong personality.
And a temper.
How did you get along with her?
As a child she was the apple of my eye
but when she was a teenager...
for some reason I didn't know
she grew away from me
until I lost her completely.
Your mother didn't love me.
It's very painful when a daughter
doesn't love her own mother.
That's why now that it's just the two of you,
you have to love her very much,
so there's no way she can miss it.
Why have you come back, Grandma?
Because I felt very lonely.
Good afternoon
Hello
I'd like 8 meters of plastic clothes line
And some packing tape
How much tape?
Maybe 4 or 5 rolls
Very well
Here's five
One,
two...
And a pick and a shovel
Sure
Sole, see you later
Thanks
Hi. It's your sister
How are you, Raimunda?
Fed up.
How's Agustina?
She's lost it completely.
Hi, Mom.
And what's wrong with you?
Nothing.
Go on, honey, bring me a glass of water
Can she stay with you tonight?
Sure, but where should I put her?
In the spare room.
Paco's coming home tonight
He wants us to talk
and I'd like to be alone.
Sure.
You're staying here tonight.
Okay, I'm off, I've got a long night
ahead of me.
Hello!
- Hi!
- What's up?
I need you to do me a favor tonight.
Tonight? Can't it wait until tomorrow?
No. But I'll pay you
like a regular customer.
No, sweetie, I'll give you a discount.
But girl, I didn't know that you liked pussy.
I don't!
You don't? So if it's not for fooling around,
what do you want from me?
I'll tell you on the way
We have to put the freezer locker in the van
And take it out to the country
We can't manage that
just the two of us
We'll get the neighbors to help.
Wear something comfortable.
I'll wait for you on the terrace
Like what?
Something you don't look like
you're about to burst out of
Wait! Hold on a second
It sticks out here.
Get it on the sidewalk.
It's slipping!
No, it's not.
Keep it moving
Now we have to align it
One, two, three... UP!
Come on, on the count of three.
One, two,
Three!
Push!
Ouch!
That's it, It's in!
Fuck this shit!
Did you hurt yourself?
No. What do I need the arm for, anyway?
Come on
Where are we going?
To the Jucar river
And where's that?
- About 180 kilometers away.
180 kilometers? It'll take us the whole night
just going there and back
I told you I'll pay you by the hour
Only for coming along with you?
To come with me to the river, dig a hole,
bury the freezer, and not ask questions...
Look, Mundita, I appreciate your trust in me,
but my life is already troubled enough!
I have no job, no papers,
I have to work the streets to survive
Christ, you could've just asked me!
OK, I'm asking you now, tell me how much
- Still...
You should've asked first
Okay, then...
Give me the nights
What nights?
The drinks at night, for a month.
And I keep what I make from my cocktails.
And you buy the bottles.
OK, partner, but not a word
about this to anyone, OK?
What choice do I have! I'm your accomplice now.
If it makes you feel better,
I haven't killed anyone.
No, don't tell me anything about it.
I wasn't going to tell you...
Move aside.
Move, move, move. Give me that.
Wait...
Oh, my God!
I can't do any more, I'm dead.
You take a break, I'll fill it in.
What are you doing here, Agustina?
Can we talk?
I'm very busy
Okay, come in, come
How's your thing?
The same. Did you find out anything?
About what?
About what I asked you.
I didn't think you were serious.
Do you mind if I sit down?
Oh, Raimunda...
Have pity on me.
I do, all the pity you want,
but don't ask for crazy things.
I just want to know if she's dead or alive!
Agustina, I understand that
between the wind and the cancer
you've lost your mind
but that doesn't give you the right
to complicate our lives
They're complicated enough already!
The day your parents died in the fire,
my mother disappeared from town
Doesn't that strike you as a big coincidence?
Not really, it's just a coincidence
According to you, your mother
left in the morning
and it wasn't the first time she disappeared
Your grandmother had to raise you
because she was never home!
Don't make me say more.
My mother went off that morning,
but it was to join your father
in the shack.
That's a lie.
No one saw her.
Of course, she was careful not to be seen
Raimunda,
My mother was having an affair with your father
What are you talking about?
My mother adored my father,
she would never have allowed it.
That's why she left him,
and moved in with Aunt Paula.
She went to live with her
because my aunt was not well.
But she never left my father.
She divided her time between the two houses.
You don't know, because you weren't there
and you hardly had any contact
with your mother for years.
She always complained that
you treated her like shit.
Those were her very words.
I've heard lots of things.
I once overheard your mother
and mine arguing.
Your mother told her she could have your father,
she didn't care.
And she didn't envy her
because he'd been born
to hurt the women who loved him.
What are you trying to prove, Agustina?
That your parents' death
and my mother's disappearance
are connected.
Then, why haven't you gone to the police?
Because the police ask too many questions,
and we should wash
our dirty laundry at home.
That's why I don't want to go on TV,
even though my sister keeps insisting
You and I have to sort this out.
Agustina, I have to go back to work.
Think about what I said.
How's Paco?
He's fine
Good
Shouldn't we call Auntie
to say we're coming?
She never leaves home
We should warn her
What for?
It's not polite to show up at
someone's home without calling first,
even if it's your sister.
What's with you and Aunt Sole now?
It's a matter of good manners, Mom.
Look, you can fuck off, you and your auntie!
You're gross!
What have you brought, Raimunda?
- Lunch for three
What am I going to do with him now in my house,
all summer long, as hyper as he is
Why did you bother?
Why are you shouting?
Are you going deaf?
Deaf as a post, yes!
We'll stay for a while
and I'd like you to cut my hair
Why didn't you call? I have a client.
Don't worry, I'm not in a hurry. We need to talk.
About what?
Aunt Paula's house.
Can I go watch TV?
Go on...
We need to decide what to do
and deal with the paperwork.
Grandma?
I'm here
Don't make a sound, my mom's here
I heard her
Sole, where's the Russian?
Who's the Russian?
A woman who's helping me.
I was telling her how my son's been expelled
from school again,
He slashed the tires of the priest
who teaches him religion.
I was telling her and she left me here,
talking to myself and without rinsing my hair
She must have gone out.
no shit... she practically vanished!
I'll finish you up.
She's got claustrophobia
and at times
she has to go outside.
Some help she is.
Do you pay her?
Nope, I took her in.
She eats and sleeps here
I gave her Mom's clothes
I don't like you taking in
complete strangers.
We told her that.
People take advantage of her.
Look at the Russian.
She's living in luxury here.
How did it go with Paco the other night?
Very bad. He came home to collect his clothes.
I think he's moved in with someone,
but I don't know where, and couldn't care less.
Why didn't you tell me that you had a Russian?
I don't know, it must've slipped my mind.
Look! It's Agustina on TV!
Good afternoon, Agustina.
Good afternoon
We know from your sister that your mother
had you when she was a single, isn't that right?
Yes. The thing is... my mom was a hippie...
It's Agustina!
...and she never married
Right, so, she practiced free love
Your mother had a girlfriend
who died on the same day
that she disappeared, isn't that right?
Yes
How did this friend die?
In a fire.
They're common in our village
because of the hot wind.
Agustina's village is
the wonderful Alcanfor de las Infantas.
which, according to statistics,
has the highest rate of lunatics per capita
Agustina, do you think your mother suffered
from some kind of mental disorder?
No, no, no, no.
Mi mother, when she wasn't feeling well,
since she was a hippie...she'd just leave the village,
Until one day she left
and never came back
Yes, that was almost four years ago.
And her friend? We're very interested
about that friend that died
Right on the same day that your
mother disappeared. Tell us.
Tell you what?
Tell us about the woman
who died in the fire.
You know there are rumors...
I don't believe in rumors.
I'd like you to explain
what you told our producer.
Something about this woman and her husband,
that linked them to
your mother's disappearance.
About that...
...I'd rather not talk about that.
Those were suppositions of mine.
But that's what you came here for,
to talk about that woman and your mother, right?
Yes, but I've changed my mind.
What's wrong? You look
uncomfortable, a bit nervous
I'd also like to mention,
that Agustina also came here
To tell us she's been diagnosed
with a terminal illness, isn't that so?
Agustina has cancer.
Ow, ow, ow...
You have cancer, Agustina
But don't be nervous...
you're among friends.
Come on, let's give her
a big hand.
Agustina has a wish:
To go to a private hospital in Houston.
But to go to Houston,
you have to speak frankly.
I remind you that you made
a commitment to this channel.
Agustina!
Agustina came to see me at the restaurant
Really?
She insists that
Mom appears to us.
She wants me to ask her about her own mother.
She also says that when she disappeared
her mother was having an affair with Dad
Do you know anything about that?
No.
Okay... Mother told me,
after...
After what?
After she found out
Sole, look at me.
Is there anything else I should know and I don't?
Plenty...
but if I tell you
you'll get mad or you won't believe me
I promise I will believe you and I won't get mad
Mom has been appearing all the time.
To who?
Take a seat.
She was with Aunt Paula until she died.
She alerted Agustina
and opened the front door
so she could find the body
She been putting out the money
so they'd bring her daily bread
and she arranged all the expenses of the funeral
You did all that, Grandma?
Yes.
Who told you all that, Agustina did?
See, you don't believe me.
Sole, Agustina's lost it!
The last time we saw Auntie
you said yourself that it was incredible
that she could manage so well,
half senile and half blind
Don't you remember?
I do, but what are you saying?
Auntie was not alone.
Who do you think made those donuts
and had them packed in a container,
one for each of us?
Who brought the dolls and Auntie's things
before the neighbors looted the place?
Do you understand now?
Have you seen her?
Yes.
Is she by chance...
...the Russian?
Yes.
Where is she?
In there.
Mama.
What are you doing under there?
Weren't you dead?
I came back to ask for your forgiveness.
I knew nothing about it, my dear
I couldn't even imagine
Come on, Paula
Raimunda!
My girl!
The worst part is over
she saw me
and she didn't reject me, right?
No she didn't
Is it true that you came back
to ask for her forgiveness?
And also to be with you.
Will you explain to me one day what's going on?
I will, and when that day comes
I hope you'll understand me, Sole,
and that you'll also forgive me.
Mom...
Here.
I have to talk to her.
Why don't we go back.
Now?
Yes.
I've dreamed of this so often!
Me too.
I don't know where to begin.
You're not a ghost, right?
You're not dead.
No, love, I'm not
That's a relief
But if I had died,
I would've returned
to ask you for forgiveness
for not seeing what was going on.
I was blind.
I found out on the day of the fire.
Is it true that you had left dad?
Yes.
I couldn't put up with his cheating anymore.
On the evening of the fire
You called and talked to Auntie.
And as usual, you didn't ask about me,
I got angry and I told your aunt
that you were heartless,
and as I continued berating you
She defended you...
...and told me everything
That your father had raped you,
that you'd gotten pregnant,
and that Paula...
is your daughter...
...and your sister.
I couldn't believe it.
How could such a monstrous thing
happen right in front of me
without me realizing it?
Then I understood everything,
your silence, your distance,
and your coldness.
I understood why your father
went to work in Venezuela.
He couldn't cope with the shame
of what he'd done.
I understood
why, after marrying Paco,
you went to Madrid
and wanted nothing to do with us.
I hated you for not having noticed a thing, Mom.
And you were completely right, my dear.
When I found out,
I was enraged
I went to the shack ready to scratch his eyes out.
and I found him asleep,
with Agustina's mother,
both of them worn out
from their exertions
They didn't see me
I set the shack on fire.
It was a windy day,
and within seconds the flames
had devoured everything.
They didn't have time to wake up.
So the ashes in your grave
are Agustina's mother?
Yes.
Afterwards,
I wandered the fields for a few days
Hiding,
like an animal.
I was going to turn myself in,
But first
I went to see Paula,
And found her in such bad shape...
When she saw me,
she wasn't a bit surprised
I had come from the past, where she was living
and she greeted me
as if I had just gone out the door
The tragedy had taken away
the little sanity she had left.
I couldn't leave her on her own...
so I stayed to take care of her
until she died.
In the village
they think you're a ghost.
That's one good thing
about such superstitious places.
It was easier for me
to go along with them
than to speak the truth.
I thought I'd be arrested.
I never imagined
that no one would investigate
or punish me,
although all this time
I swear I've gone through purgatory
in the real sense of the word.
It's too early to go to the village.
We shouldn't arrive in daylight.
Why don't we drive by the river?
It's been so long since I saw it...
Is not what it was Mom, it dried out.
How do you know?
Because there's drought all over Spain.
Sole, how can you be so clueless?
We often came here for a picnic.
Do you remember, Raimunda?
I do.
The river was much wider then.
I told you it dried up.
Let's have a snack.
Not for me.
I'm having a donut.
Me too.
This was your father's favorite place.
You mean Paco?
Yes, him.
It was the only place he really missed.
This river.
I'm glad he's resting here.
Come on!
Nobody'll see you now!
If only Paula could see us,
all together...
...she'd be so happy!
Have you always had such big chest?
Yes, Mom, ever since I was small.
I remember them smaller.
I hope you didn't do anything to them?
What could I have done?
Don't say nonsense...
Oh, OK...
Grandma, was it you
that used the exercise bike?
Yes. Half an hour every day
It's good for your heart
And what did Aunt Paula say when she saw you?
She couldn't stop laughing.
See you later.
It's Aunt Paula!
Knock it off, Sole.
I'll see who it is.
Hide Mom's plate and silverware
Who is it?
It's me, Agustina.
We're having supper.
We just arrived.
Sorry to interrupt.
Come on in, don't just stand there.
- Thank you.
Good evening
- Good evening
Have a seat.
- Thank you.
I came to apologize about the TV show
You shouldn't have gone Agustina,
it wasn't right.
I know
It's no excuse,
but they offered to send me to Houston
where, apparently, they cure everything.
But I couldn't do it.
I'd rather die alone in my house,
but at peace,
and be able to look at you in the eye.
Mom, I'll be upstairs, OK?
- Yes, go on.
- Will you have some supper?
- No, no, thanks.
I heard you're going to sell the house.
- Yes
That was the idea, but once we got here,
there are so many memories that I'm not sure...
OK then, I better go.
Stay for a while. Why hurry?
I have to go see the nurse
to get my injection.
In Madrid they told me I'd better
get used to doing it myself,
but I find it disgusting.
Your sister has no excuse for letting you
live on your own in your condition.
Don't even mention her.
After what happened on TV
she won't even talk to me.
She's very angry with me,
but I'm even more angry with her.
You've plenty of reasons to be.
I envy you two.
You're so close.
Irene!
I couldn't wait to see you!
Here I am.
I heard about what happened
and I guess you must be feeling pretty lonely.
Very lonely.
If only Paula were here.
I'm here now to take care of you,
whatever it takes.
You left the door open.
Don't worry, I closed it.
Did you go to the nurse?
- No, I'm too tired, tomorrow.
Tomorrow you'll be in a lot of pain.
Do you have the medicine
and the needles?
- Yes, I bought everything in Madrid.
All right, I'll give you the shot.
I was born in this bed.
My mother slept here.
And on this very bed, we held your sister Paula's wake.
I know, Agustina
and I'm deeply grateful for it.
We have to talk, Irene.
About anything you wish,
but don't tell anyone that I've returned.
Don't worry, I won't.
Oh, and thank you for not
talking about me on TV.
That's our business,
Of course.
And no one else's.
It's me, Mom.
Open up.
Raimunda, what are you doing here? Come in.
I missed you
Are you going to stay here?
Yes. Until the end.
Agustina is very very ill.
After what I did to her mother,
it's the least I could do for her
until she dies, don't you think?
Yes. Mom, I've so many things to tell you...
I haven't told you about Paco
or what I've done.
I can't wait for you to tell me,
but you have to leave now.
We'll see each other every day.
Between us we'll manage.
Yes.
I need you, Mom.
I don't know how I could have lived
all these years without you.
Don't say that, Raimunda,
or I'll start crying
and ghosts don't cry.