(Train Engine Chugging]
(Train Whistle Blows]
(Chattering]
(Man Narrating]
Working in the store Sunday all day.
(Man]
Can I help you?
(Narrator] I want to drink this Mexican boy,
Johnny Alonzo, from L.A. near Riverside.
He makes my heart throb...
# Thumpety, bum, bum, bum, bum, bum #
when I see him.
He says he's 1 8,
but he could be 1 6.
Do you want some chips?
(Narrator] All I want to do is caress him.
I want to hold him.
- What's that?
- He has these hickeys on his neck.
- What have you got there?
- He likes men.
What's that?
That looks like a hickey.
Gonna be your friend.
Su amigo.
(Narrator] He's out on the street
with friends staying in a three-dollar-a-night...
cheap hotel room on Sixth off skid road.
- And he speaks almost no English.
- Hey, tell him I'm not the Immigration.
Como se llama?
Me llamoJohnny Alonzo.
(Man]
And you don't have any place to stay, do you?
Look here, man.
Let me have a pack ofTop, will ya?
That's all I wanna hear.
- There you go, huh?
- All right. Thanks a lot.
Thanks.
Hey, Johnny.
Hola.
Que pasa?
Es muy fr/o.
(Speaking Spanish)
Come here, you little cutie.
You need a place to stay tonight?
I mean, there's always my place.
Okay?
And it's right across from
the Y.W.C.A. over there.
Hey. Wait a minute. Come back.
No way.
I'm in love with this boy.
- Really.
- You are always in love.
No. I mean, Sarah,
he just came into the store.
I mean, I'm sure he just got into town.
You see people
come into the store all the time.
Let me invite him to dinner.
Okay.
So where are we gonna fnd him?
- I don't know.
- Hmm.
The street.
How old is he?
- He says he's 1 8, but...
- Oh.
I don't know. He's probably...
Vegetables and rice.
Sounds good.
- ##(Speakers. ; Woman Singing In Spanish]
- (Coin Rattles]
I don't care. Even...
Even if it jeopardizes
working at the store...
I have to show him that...
that I'm gay for him.
I have to show him how I feel.
What are you doing out here
by yourself, honey?
Oh, I... I'm waiting for
some friends of mine, actually.
- Oh, okay. You're all right?
- Yeah, I'm fne. Thanks.
- ##(Speakers. ; Rock]
- (Video Game Sound Effects]
Hello. Hola.
You ran out without paying?
Are they looking for you now?
Are they after you?
Um, we're gonna be
leaving pretty soon actually.
- I'm sorry. I didn't know you're... Are you married?
- Well, no. It's a... It's some friends of mine.
You know, usually people cook,
you know, they're married.
- It's kind of dumb.
- No. Um, you're gonna get hit, you know.
Oh, God. I've been hit before, you know.
Hey. What are you doing under my car?
johnny.
No, we'd like to invite you over...
Excuse me.
We'd like to invite you for dinner.
We're gonna make you some good food.
- We're hoping to cook him for dinner tonight.
- You're gonna cook him for dinner?
Gonna make something
for them to eat actually.
Tienes hambre?
Are you hungry?
- (Car Tires Squeal]
- Come on.
Sure. Sure. Come on.
- Take care, okay?
- Okay. You too, lady.
- Be careful.
- Bye-bye.
; Guau!
Hey. Hey. What are you doing?
I am gonna be making you some good food.
Where'd you get this stuff at?
- No, no. I'm gonna be cooking some vegetables.
- Listen to her.
All right. All right. He is a sugar freak.
Permiso?
- (Blowing)
- (Chattering]
(Johnny]
Si.
(Chattering)
It's okay. Sure. We can go back.
It's all right. Don't freak out.
- What's the matter?
- He wants to go back to the hotel.
It's okay. S/. Es posible.
Okay. I'll take him back. Then we'll...
Si. Es posible.
##(Car Stereo. ; Rock]
Hey.
Sure. Sure. Tell him to come.
Let him get in the front. Get in the front.
- (Spanish)
- There's room up here.
##(Continues]
Hola.
Un momentito.
(Spanish)
(All Speaking Spanish)
(Train Whistle Blows]
(Bell Clanging]
(Footsteps]
Shh.
(Chatter On Police Radio]
- (Sarah] What'd he say?
- (Spanish)
Well, he says that when, um,
they frst came on the train...
they had another friend
with them, and...
and the police came...
Tres policia?
S/. There were, like, three police.
jumped him, and they...
They hurt their friend.
Killed him?
- That's horrible.
- I think he, like, killed him.
- What's this...
- The biggest pro...
The biggest problem is you get too
far removed from the death aspect.
It's like you walk into McDonald's,
and they just line the cows up...
and they bump 'em all off for you
and you never have to see it happening.
If you had to go out there
and kill every piece of meat that you ate...
that's a... that's a little easier for me to buy,
you know, because you experience the death.
You see it happening, and you realize
what you're doing when you eat it.
But when you walk into a McDonald's
and say, "Uh, give me a Big Mac"...
you know, you're just getting dead cow
and you never see the cow die.
- That's...
- (Sarah] All those poisons release
at the time of death too.
(Man]
Bad for your karma.
So it's not bad to eat food without meat
in it. You know. You can survive.
##(Ballad. ; Men Singing In Spanish]
- ##(Continues]
- (No Audible Dialogue)
- (Sarah] Nice meeting you.
- Adios.
- Gracias.
- Gracias. De nada. De nada.
(Narrating] We returned downhill
through the tunnel curves fast.
Jesus Christ. The boy's insane, like
all Mexicans, about driving fast and crazy.
In the front seat next to him I cover my eyes,
tell him to slow down.
It's too late to get control
of the wheel.
The look on his face is pure ecstasy.
The incredible, beautiful, turned-on face
of an ignorant Mexican teenager.
His friends laughing in the backseat...
driving a maniacal machine
downhill as fast as he can go.
(Thunder Rumbling]
I'll give you $1 5 if I can sleep with Johnny.
Quince dolares.
Si? Para me and Johnny.
Is okay? Bien?
Quince dolares. I wish I had more.
I wish I had a hundred.
I love you.
Come on.
Ask him.
Mm-mmm.
I'd give you 50 if I had it,
but I only have 1 5.
Quince dolares para tu.
Fifteen dollars?
(Rain Pattering]
Come on. Angel face.
- I want to sleep with him.
- Okay, vamos.
(Coughs)
Where the hell do you think you're goin'?
- Upstairs.
- No visitors.
No, we're not visitors.
Uh, I'm with him. We're going upstairs.
Got a key?
- The key.
- (Spanish)
- Doesn't have it.
- No visitors.
- Oh, come on. We're going upstairs.
- You're not going anywhere.
- He lives here.
- Where's his key?
- Get out of here.
- We're going upstairs.
- No, you're not going anywhere. Open the door.
- No.
- Come on. Just open the door.
- Get out.
- What's it gonna hurt you? Just open the door.
- Get out. Get out.
Bitch!
You fat cow!
Shit!
Damn slut!
Fat cow!
What are you gonna do?
You're locked out too.
You want to stay at my place?
You can stay there.
It's better than out here.
Okay?
Fuckin' bitch!
##(Bells Chiming. ; "Silent Night"]
I have to go work for about an hour.
I'll be right back.
- Make yourself at home.
- ##(Continues]
##("Silent Night"Ends]
##(Bells Resume Chiming]
##(Continues]
(Alarm Ringing]
- (Alarm Continues]
- ##(Chiming Continues]
- (Alarm Stops]
(Train Whistle Blows]
(Bell Clanging]
- (Bell Clanging]
- (Train Passing]
##(Chiming Continues]
(Train Engine Chugging]
- (Chugging Continues]
- (Train Whistle Blows]
Mas lento. Mas lento.
Slow down.
(Train Whistle Blows]
##(Chiming Continues]
- (Bell Clanging]
- (Train Passing]
(Train Engine Chugging]
(Narrator] He said he needed to
tomar agua... get some water.
Is that when he slips the $ 1 0 bill
from my pants, or did I lose it?
I think he got it.
##(Ballad. ; Woman Singing In Spanish]
(Narrator] They need money...
Johnny and him. I hope they got it.
Though I was upset that I'd been fucked,
violated and lost the money too...
for a few moments,
thinking about it, in the morning...
of the Mexicans gloating over having fucked
the gringo puto and got his money too...
talking about it and laughing,
my ass sore.
And the more I think about it,
the more I know I asked for a reckless evening.
##(Continues]
(Narrator] Johnny'll probably never
look at me or talk to me as a friend.
He probably wouldn't have in the fiirst place.
I had to fiind out...
to get as close to him as I could...
even if it turned into a shit-bad night.
(Woman)
Hey, buddy, how's it going?
- All right. What can I get ya?
- Oh, we need a ffth of Night Train.
- Fifth of Night Train.
- Yeah.
(Narrator] He said he was gonna
return to L.A. in 1 5 days...
as soon as he got
traveling money together.
He lives with nine or 1 0 brothers.
Maybe when they're making love they can
think about Roberto having fucked me.
Roberto's cock fucks Johnny fucked me.
That's about as close toJohnny
as I'll ever get.
Unless I had the money.
Poor boys never win.
Who fucks whom?
Mala noche.
Every street Mexican on Sixth
will think he can stick it in me.
Well, they're wrong. But they never were
too smart to begin with, or they wouldn't be here.
Chingalo. My ass is sore.
It's true. L... I think he tried to use his cock
like a weapon on me, macho fucking prick.
##(Continues]
Johnny comes into the store often.
An acquaintance of mine brought a camera
into the store the other day...
and I gave him $ 1 0 for it.
We decided to go out
and see if it worked.
It does! (Laughs]
Hey!
Pepper talks to a dog we fiind on the street...
and I say, "You lead a dog's life. "
I don't think he understands.
Johnny doesn't want...
doesn't want to be in our movie...
and tells me Ro... Roberto wants to
learn to drive the car.
- Tell me.
- Randy. Is that your name?
- No, no. My name's Walt.
- (Man] Walt. All right, Walt.
- Okay, Walt. I'm Dieter.
- (Walt] Yeah.
- This is my cousin Franz.
- Ah. Good to meet you, Franz.
(Dieter]
We went through the Second World War.
Yeah, can I have some Night Train?
- (Franz] Right where his daddy was born.
- Buck and a half.
(No Audible Dialogue)
Hola. What happened with the police?
Are they after you, or...
Can I get you something?
Tienes hambre?
(Walt]
Cuidado.
Veinticinco.
Para tu, nada.
- Yeso por que?
- Cuidado.
Un momentito.
Hey!
(Walt]
Hasta luego.
(Door Closes]
- (Man] Shut up.
- (Woman) Hey. Little brother.
Come here.
Me speak a little English.
"A circuit court jury in Portland unanimously
convicted 22-year-old Armando...
'Zamora Flores, a transient,
of murder and fiirst-degree robbery...
in the slaying
of William Somerset, 53."
Night...
"1 543 Bidwell Street."
- (Spanish)
- Hey, hey, hey.
Look. "Flores, through
a Spanish-speaking interpreter"...
- (Spanish)
- "maintained that they thought
they were going to another tavern...
but went instead to Somerset's house."
- Hey, hey. (Spanish)
- Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
"He said there a man made
homosexual advances towards him...
"and when he refused,
came at him with a knife.
They struggled, and Flores said
he stabbed Somerset."
Friend of yours?
You see how sad that is?
Nope.
- Vamonos.
- You any...
Great. You got a gun, huh?
You can't just carry it around like that.
What are you trying to prove?
You're gonna shoot your balls off.
What if... What are you gonna do if somebody
pulls a gun on you and you have to use it?
Look. Don't point that thing.
It's not a toy.
Take it out ofhere.
Man.
Get it out of the store.
You're just gonna get in trouble.
Take the pie. Vamoose.
Take it and go.
(Walt Narrating] Roberto never
acknowledges the fuck of the night before.
It's as though it never happened.
Johnny has two tiny pimples...
zits from bad food on his chin.
And he looks sleepy all the time.
(Walt Laughing]
(Horn Honks)
(Horn Honking)
##(Stereo. ; Ranchera]
- (Continues)
- (Walt Speaking Spanish]
(Spanish)
Look, driving's not a game for kids.
All right? It's serious.
Johnny!
No!
(Roberto] iuanito!
(Whistles]
Muchachos!
The police are gonna pick us up.
(Whistles)
; Muchacho!
(Whistles]
Pull over right now.
I'm gonna drive.
You can drive later.
I just don't want you to kill me.
We can't stay here forever.
Get in the car.
Get back in the car.
(Men Shouting, Whistling]
##(Ballad]
##(Men Singing In Spanish]
(Walt Narrating]
We're heading west towards the Pacifiic Ocean.
Johnny will never, never
go anywhere with me alone.
I fiind that sad and absurd.
But it's part of the game that he and I play
in having a relationship at all.
I don't take it personally.
He feels more comfortable
surrounded by his friends.
##(Continues]
(Giggling)
(Roberto Speaking Spanish)
(Mariachi)
(Walt Narrating]
I don't want to interfere with their lives.
If these two friends are happy,
that's the way it should be.
A gringo like me has an easy life...
a privileged life...
and just because
I see someone attractive likeJohnny...
doesn't mean I should be able to have him...
to buy him or whatever, just because
he's hungry and on the street...
desperate, good-looking.
That wasn't my intention exactly,
but it could be misunderstood that way.
Get back here!
(Shouting)
##(Stereo. ; Mariachi]
##(Stops]
Cough 'em up, you little nino.
Muchacho.
Give me the keys, you little shit!
(Engine Starts)
Open the door! Open the...
Open the door.
Open it. Where you goin'? Sto...
What are you doing?
Oh, great.
Look. Open the door. Open it up.
Open the fucking...
Stop the car! Bring it back here!
(Engine Starts)
##(Stereo. ; Rock]
##(Stops]
(Wind Howling]
##(Rock. ; Man Singing, Indistinct]
- ##(Stops]
- (Wind Howling]
- (Mumbles)
- The drink's...
- That's for credit.
- No credit. I'm sorry, buddy.
It's 3.69. You got cash,
I'll sell it to you. No credit.
Credit's like sex.
Some get it, some don't. Sorry, mate.
(Rain Pattering]
(Walt Narrating]
The plan is simple.
I go to his room at midnight.
(Knocking]
He opens the door,
sees that I want him that badlly...
I lay down at his feet like a dog.
Or rather, at the feet
of Roberto and him and...
(Howling)
And after an hour or so, when none of us knows
what to do any longer, I get up and I leave.
My point is being made,
that I want to see him badlly, right?
That must mean something.
How many gringos...
have acted that dramatically
toward him ever?
And whether or not he could respond
in any meaningful way doesn't matter.
He would think of it
as a dramatic macho act.
##(Acoustic Guitar]
##(Woman Singing In Spanish]
(Rain Pattering]
(Thunder Rumbles]
##(Continues]
(Thunder Rumbling]
(Glass Shatters]
- Oh, shit. Shh.
- (Dog Barking]
(Barking Continues, Stops]
##(Continues]
(Speaking Spanish)
No. Look, no... I'm not...
I'm not Immigration.
- (Walt] Yo no migras.
- (Spanish Continues)
Que... No. N-No. No... Shh!
No, wait. Wait.
(Spanish Continues]
It's okay.
I'm not the Immigration. All right?
It's a mistake. Shh! No! W...
(Woman Continues
Speaking Spanish]
What the hell are you doin' out there?
- Look, I'm just looking for some...
- Get off of there!
- I was looking for some friends of mine.
I got the wrong apartment. It's a mista...
Don't you remember me from the store?
- Goddamn sleazeball.
- (Spanish Continues)
Get out of here! Get!
- (Spanish Continues]
- Okay, I'm leaving. I'm going, all right?
It was a mistake. I'm sorry.
j-Just...
Damn!
##(Whistling]
(Man] I think there was one kid.
He moved out this morning.
(Walt Narrating] Do they know that I'm here
because I'm in love with the boy?
Why would a gringo be here?
Who would he be looking for?
Ajunk dealer?
A whore? A queer?
Well, at least I tried.
Excuse me. Have you seen a guy
come in here, a Mexican kid?
He's about this tall, he's got long hair,
he's wearing a... a jean jacket and jeans...
and, like, a plaid shirt,
and he's got boots...
(Cash Register Closes, Dings]
I seen a lot of...
a lot of Mexicans coming in here.
(No Audible Dialogue)
It's, like, Saturday and Sunday
we were so close...
and then, phfft...
it's all over.
I really thought
he was starting to like me.
But I guess not.
just another fantasy.
Or maybe we can only communicate
to a certain point.
I've always had that problem
with you.
(Walt Narrating] I go to the Grecian
Gardens raving, Johnny's gone. "
I have a couple ofbeers
and tell my old buddy George...
about the impossibilities oflove.
(Walt] So, is he gonna
come back and get you, or what?
No se.
(Walt]
Where did they go? Thanks.
- What do you need?
- No se. Maybe Idaho.
Um, get me a big bottle of Night Train.
- All right. A big one.
- And a pack of Pall Malls.
(Walt]
$2.60... Buck and a quarter.
Well, I can't believe that they
just took off and left you here.
You sure he's coming back?
What do you need?
Hey, you can't bring that cart in here!
Take that out. Take that out!
- I'll take it out.
- Yeah, right.
(Roberto Speaking Spanish]
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
It's worth about two bucks.
I don't... I can't use it, though.
Yeah. Veinticinco. Veinticinco.
Right. That's the price tag.
That's what people pay in the store for it.
But it's worthless
unless you want a pot like this.
Por tu, quince pesos.
But it's not worth anything
unless you happen to want a pot like this...
and then you go into the store
and get it.
I can't do anything with it.
Don't you have a place to stay?
No.
You're welcome
to stay at my place.
- No se eso.
- No, no, it, um... We'll have a beer.
This is my amigo...
my friend Pepper.
- (Man] Habla espanol?
- (Speaks Spanish)
Okay, Pepper, this is...
this is Esther, and this is Mike.
- Hi.
- Mucho gusto.
- This is Frank the homophobe here.
- (All Laughing)
That's Henry, Hannah Duncan, Betty...
Don Chambers...
the incredible Mr. Don Chambers...
Yeah. This is Sharon,
and this is Marty.
- Marty the poet.
- Marty the poet extraordinaire. Right?
You're never gonna remember that.
How can you remember
one name to 40 names, huh?
(Sharon]
The deal with Marty is...
(Coughs)
Que es tu problema?
Tu es muy serio.
Preocupado?
- Que es tu problema?
- (Grunts) No problema.
(Coughs)
- So...
- Que tal?
No.
I'm off.
Hasta luego.
(Walt Narrating] Fuck it.
Do I need him that badlly? Am I that desperate?
Of course I am.
(Man] Okay, you wanna pick up
a couple extra dollars?
You go up to this club, okay?
It's up on Fifth Street.
You go up there, be nice to the guys,
they'll pay you a little bit. All right?
Okay? Got that?
If that don't work out for you,
you go up to another club up on Sixth Street.
just about a block up.
Go down about a half a block. Okay?
Do some nude dancing, maybe,
pick up a couple extra dollars, no problem there.
If nothing like that works out for you,
go talk to a guy named Bill. Okay?
He'll take care of you.
just be nice to him.
He'll do everything for you. All right?
That's all you gotta do. You got that?
You understand what I'm saying?
Okay.
A poor Mexican
has a snowball's chance in hell, man.
It's because disaster
is right around that corner.
HopeJohnny comes back.
Look, take care of yourself, man.
Come by the store and I'll give you
some cough medicine, all right?
Look, I wanna be your friend,
your amigo.
I'll help you any way I can.
Wait a minute.
Take care of yourself,
all right?
Gracias. Hasta luego.
(Knocking]
(Knocking Continues]
##(Bells Chiming. ; "Silent Night"]
- (Knocking]
- ##("Silent Night"Ends]
What do you want?
What?
Look, Juan,
we can't go driving now.
Later. Despues.
- ##(Bells Resume Chiming]
- Is Johnny back?
Shit.
- (Speaking Spanish)
- ##(Ballad. ; Spanish]
- Hola.
- (Spanish)
(Coughs)
Hi.
(Men]
Adios, adios
(Coughs)
##(Singing Continues In Spanish]
(Spanish)
(Man Continues Speaking Spanish]
(Coughing)
##(Ends]
(TV. ; Woman] Everything comes out beautifully
with Spray 'n'Starch.
##(TV. ; Instrumental Theme]
(TV. ; Static Bursts]
Hey.
##(Acoustic Guitar]
##(Woman Singing In Spanish]
##(Singing Continues]
(No Audible Dialogue)
(Water Running In Sink]
##(Ends]
(Groaning)
(Speaking Spanish)
(Roberto]
Pizza, taco, burrito.
Comida...
Como se llama...
Mil... Milk shake.
(Roberto]
Andale!
(Car Door Opens]
(Car Door Closes]
(Roberto Coughs, Speaks Spanish]
Hello!
Hello?
(Tapping]
(Tapping Continues]
Howdy.
My friend's looking for work.
Do you know if there's any work?
I remember your friend from last year.
He's a good worker.
But you guys came at the wrong time
of the year. It's the wrong season.
And I'm not really the guy to talk to.
We don't really have
a lot of work right now.
##(Bells Chiming. ; "Silent Night"]
Donde vas?
(Coughing)
What are you doing?
What's that stuff?
- What is that?
- Es por granos.
Granos.
Que es tu problema?
Granos. Granos.
- Granos?
- No me molesto.
- En su boca?
- I; Por favor, no me molesto! Para.
Pobrecito.
- Me lo hago?
- I; Para!
What... Oh.
Para, para. No me molesto.
Hey!
- (Record Scratches)
- I; No mas! I; Para!
- Pendejo.
- H-Hold...
- I; No mas! I; No mas!
- Pendejo.
(Both Grunting)
- (Spanish)
All right, stop!
Stop! Hey!
Look! Wait! Look, all r...
Hey! Alto.
Go.
Puto.
(Roberto]
Tu eres un pendejo.
(Walt Narrating] He only wants to
have sex at night, not during the day.
And certain aggressive acts...
that's what he wants and needs.
That's not what I want.
I mean, I'm not an invert.
His sexual desires are very stereotypical,
and mine aren't.
(Walt]
These buggers. Little varmints.
Shh-shh-shh-shh.
(Needle Lands On Record Surface,
Scratching, Popping)
##(Stereo. ; Classical]
##(Continues]
- ##(Ends]
- I love the countryside here.
This is great.
You're doing good. You're doing real good.
This is your frst curve coming up right up here.
It's your frst one. Do you see it?
Now, all you're gonna want to do
is turn to the left.
It's real easy. All right, get ready.
See it there?
Okay, turn... Turn... No, turn...
Turn the car! Turn
What are you doing? Turn the car!
Why would... Look!
What? All you had to do
was turn the car!
What did you do?
Shit! You drive like you fuck!
Get...
How...
It's a simple little thing.
All you had to do was turn the car.
(No Audible Dialogue)
Thanks a lot.
(TV: Woman)
For $300, the Ebony store gift certifcate.
(TV: Man)
Okay, that is... What? That is 401.
(Applause)
(TV Continues, Indistinct)
(Walt Narrating] I can't help feeling that
his well-being depends on Johnny coming back.
I know he accepts me
and that we're friends, but...
johnny may have been arrested.
He says one of their friends told him
that he saw him in the back of a police car.
So, your grandfather
sent you out for milk?
Es pepino.
That's a cucumber.
Cucumber. Cucumber.
Cu... cum... cumber?
They make pickles out of'em.
- Leche.
- Mm-hmm.
Huevos.
- Huevos.
- Right.
We're gonna have some beans.
No se ese. No se ese.
- Garbanzo beans.
- S/.
Shall we put 'em in the...
in the tortilla?
- Tortillas aqu/.
- Tortillas aqu/. S/.
Manteca.
Butter. Margarine.
It's not margarine.
It's shit.
And Pepper has girlfriends too.
I don't think he likes me that much.
I don't blame him.
We're just not compatible.
But why isn't it easy for them?
I mean...
they don't have any imagination
about sex or anything else...
like fantasies or erotic friendship.
Friendship?
I guess it's not their fault.
- Let me in. Let me in.
- (Knocking)
- (Man] Who is it?
- It's me, Polly. Let me in.
- What do you want now?
- There's a guy... There's a weird guy upstairs.
H-He followed me in.
Wh-What kind of... Did you look?
There is a guy who makes Son of Sam
look like Tweety Bird.
We've gotta call the cops.
He's a derelict, man.
We gotta call the cops.
All right, I'll call the cops.
But, look, you handle it.
- Okay. I will.
- You talk to 'em.
- I don't want anything to do with this.
- All right, all right.
Hey! Let me in.
Wait a minute.
(Siren Wailing]
- Oh, I like it!
- (Audience Laughing)
- You must love that fiavor.
- I've never had that.
(Siren Continues]
(TVContinues, Voices Indistinct]
(TV. ; Applause]
(Thunder Rumbling]
(Police Radio. ; Dispatcher]
Offiicer 2, where is the Code 5?
(Police Radio. ; Offiicer #1]
Barney's, 1 4th and Davis.
- (Dispatcher] 1 4th and Division?
- (Offiicer #1] Davis.
(Radio. ; Static Bursts]
(Police Radio. ; Offiicer #2]
Horton, are you there?
(Police Radios. ;
Overlapping Responses, Indistinct]
(Police Radio. ; Offiicer #3]
We'll be out talking to him.
(TV. ; Audience Laughing]
(TV. ; Voices, Indistinct]
(TV. ; Applause]
Freeze, or you're wallpaper!
- (Gunshots)
- (Glass Shattering]
(Police Radio. ;
Dispatchers, Offiicers, Indistinct]
(Police Radio. ; Offiicer #4]
Second man down.
(Offiicer #4 Continues, Indistinct]
(Walt Narrating]
They're people like we are.
I found out they call him Papas, not Pepper,
because he likes to eat papas... french fries.
El Loco Papas is smart like a fox,
staying offby himself...
but they got him anyway.
This kid shouldn't be out on the street, man.
They get into trouble that way, man.
Dealing marijuana... The cops
are gonna get him, man. You know that.
jesus Christ.
It ain't fair, but...
(No Audible Dialogue)
(Muttering)
Hello, everybody, goddamn it.
(Laughs)
Senor.
Amigo... Mexico.
(Walt] I'm gonna have to boot your ass
out ofhere pretty soon if you don't mellow out.
(Mutters]
Go ahead. Make me go...
Watch out.
- Sorry.
- All right.
- Love a...
- Love a duck.
You see?
So, what I told him was the story about
the lady with one in her bedside stand.
I said, "What the fuck is that?"
And she said, "That's for burglars."
And I said, "You will not
blow a burglar away with that.
You'll blow him into little pieces."
And she said,
"That's what it's for, George."
- (Rain Pattering]
- (Thunder Rumbling]
- (Video Game Sound Effects]
- (Man Talking, Faint]
Okay, great.
(Singing In Foreign Language)
- Everybody knows that?
- (All Laugh)
(Continues In Foreign Language)
(Walt Narrating]
Looking forJohnny, I saw no sign.
I think they got you too.
You have no place to go or to hide.
I don't know
what's gonna happen to you.
Or, I do know what's gonna happen to you,
and so do you, probably.
And that's why I fell in love with Johnny
in the fiirst place.
And that's why Roberto was silent most of the time
and chased white butt...
if you know what I mean...
hoping some of that sticky good comfort,
luck and security might rub off on him.
Or at least he could make it squeal.
(Engine Starts, Revs)
Are you all right?
Hey!
Man, don't be afraid.
I'm your friend.
(Man] Hey, assholes! Shut the fuck up!
I'm tryin'to get some sleep!
Give me a break!
I gotta work for a living, huh?
- Damn!
- Johnny!
Hey! Johnny!
(Laughing)
Hey! What happened to you?
They didn't get you.
Were you in Idaho?
(Whispers)
Shit!
So, come on.
Tell me what happened.
(Johnny Speaking Spanish]
(Walt Narrating] All this time
we think Johnny's on vacation in Idaho.
Well, it seems that Immigration picked him up
and shipped him back to the border...
not to Idaho.
Swimming the Rio Grande by moonlight,
he's back in less than two weeks.
He rode the rails,
hopped the freights.
(Laughing)
; Toro! I; Toro, muchacho!
; Ole! I; Ole!
; Toro! I; Toro!
Whoa!
(Train Passing]
The police came.
I told you to get rid of that gun.
(Laughs)
(Spanish)
- (Ranchera, Upbeat)
- How you doing?
##(Continues, Man Singing In Spanish]
Hey, how you doing?
Good to see you.
Hey!
(Chuckling)
##(Continues]
##(Fades]
(Sarah] I'm thinking ofleaving
for Anchorage tomorrow.
What's in Anchorage?
I can do nude dancing
in just about any bar in town...
and make 1 50 bucks a night.
Why do you wanna do... Look!
(Walt]
I can't believe he's there.
Hey, hey! What are you doing?
Hey, come down to the store
and see me sometime. All right?
Come... Come down to the store
and talk to me. All right?
##(Rock]
#I'm gonna see your face appear #
#Like mirrors shown to a blind man #
#Once a black sheep of the flock #
# Will you stop #
# When they come for the rich man #
#Are you #
#An answer to a rich man's prayers #
# Will you stop #
# When they come for the rich man #
#Standing there #
# Waiting
on the corner #
# Your kiss
gives a #
#Lift on
the shoulder #
#How, girl
is he #
#Comin'
and goin'#
# Will you stop #
# When they come for the rich man #
#Are you #
#An answer
to a rich
man's prayers #
# Will you stop #
# When they come for the rich man #
#In and out #
# To in front of us #
#Eat me
Not like in the restaurant #
#Beg her to tell me
I didn't warn you #
# Will you stop #
# When they come for the rich man #
#Are you #
#An answer
to a rich man's prayers #
# Will you stop #
# When they
come for
the rich man #
# Will you stop #
# When they come for the rich man #
#Are you #
#An answer
to a rich man's prayers #
# Will you stop #
# When they come for the rich man #
#History
police #
#Can't
keep it from
exposure #
#Runnin'
wild child #
#Peaceful
streets #
#Can't go along #
# These thin enrichment streets #
# Will
you stop #
# When they
come for
the rich man #
#Are you #
#An answer
to a rich man's prayers #
# Will you stop #
# When they come for the rich man ##