I am sure the congregation, the media,
your family, would love
to see you enjoying yourself.
One million dollars.
Jesse, what in God's name?
I'm being blackmailed.
Somebody sent me this video.
They said they're gonna leak
the whole damn thing unless I pay them
a million dollars by Sunday.
Johnny Seasons thinks he's a big shot.
What do you got to say to me?
Gemstones are an absolute
disgrace to all ministries.
I finally figured out
who the blackmailer is.
- Who?
- Johnny Seasons.
We're gonna ambush him at his house.
Get him while his guard's down,
overpower him,
and get him to give us that damn tape.
Had enough of me?!
This is the downfall of the Gemstones.
I'm supposed to make the drop at ten.
Then pay him, Jesse.
I don't have the money, Judy!
Get in.
I love you guys.
I think the biggest
misconception about Thailand
is that it's gonna all
be about the ladyboys,
like they're just gonna be everywhere
hanging out of windows with
their cocks in their panties.
But it's not, okay?
The food, no joke.
Beaches are unreal.
And we're gonna be
taller than everybody.
He's here.
Oh, fuck. Here we go.
Wait a minute. He's not alone.
Jesus, that wasn't part of the deal.
- Who's in the car?
- Nobodies.
My brother and sister.
Tell them to get the fuck out!
Hi.
Assholes.
Walk slowly to the rear of the van
and place the bags on the ground.
I don't really feel
comfortable doing that.
I don't know who y'all got back there,
so I'm just gonna put
the bags right down here.
No, bring 'em to where I told you.
Baby, I don't like this. Let's go.
Fucking asshole.
He wants to be a big shot.
I got this.
What? No, no, no.
Don't get out of the car.
- God damn it, Scotty!
- Scott, Scott.
Oh, fuck. Shit.
What's happening now?
He's handing him the thumb drive.
- And now he's air-fucking.
- Ugh.
I hate when he air-fucks.
Oh, shit.
Oh, shit, they're fighting!
They're hurting him!
- Who do you serve?
- Fuck!
No, don't shoot. Don't shoot, Lucy!
Shit!
God damn!
They're getting away.
Shit, fuck, fuck, he's hurt.
Fuck. Scotty!
No, no, no, no. Stay in the car.
Stay in the car. Lucy!
Lucy, stay in the...
Oh, fuck!
Fuck!
Hey!
Oh, God. Scotty?
Scotty!
Mask.
Scotty.
Where's Lucy?
Lucy.
Lucy!
Fuck, fuck! She's fucking dead.
Scotty, don't say that. Come on.
- Is she breathing?
- She's not breathing.
She's fucking dead, man.
Fuck.
We gotta get rid of her.
What?
Ready?
One, two, three.
- Should we say something?
- Shh.
Help.
Oh, shit.
Synced & corrected by QueenMaddie
www.addic7ed.com
What are we supposed to be thinking?
They just disappeared,
just got up, and waltzed away?
I think maybe what we've witnessed here
is nothing short of a miracle.
We need to go home and love one another,
be good to each other.
That's the lesson to take from this.
Maybe it was never even
real to begin with.
Maybe it was all just, like,
a figment of imagination,
a spiritual test that we overcame.
Okay, well, they certainly felt real
when we drove over what
felt like their skulls.
Don't say that, Kelvin.
Don't be like that,
projecting negativity.
Yeah, seriously, trying to act like
we're gonna get in trouble or some shit.
There is one matter I'd like
a little clarity on, though.
- 'Sup?
- The money.
Where'd it come from, Judy?
Cutting grass, cutting hairdos.
Bullshit. You stole it from the church.
Yeah, duh.
So technically, it's not yours.
Uh, 'cept it is mine,
'cause I'm the one who
found a hiding place.
I had to sneak. I had to climb stuff.
I had to think it through.
I stole that money fair and square.
You did not.
That money would be gone if
it was not for my bravery
and... and knowledge and courage
to go back into the whole melee
and grab those fucking bags.
That's true facts.
So now we need to figure
out a meaningful way
in which we can divvy it up.
No, no, no, no,
how 'bout nobody gets a cut, okay?
- Yeah.
- How 'bout it all goes back
- to the church?
- I like that plan.
That's a good plan.
Yes, now we're talking.
No, I don't like that plan.
How 'bout this?
How 'bout we give half
of it back to the church
and the other half we split 50/50?
How 'bout give a third
of it to the church,
the other half 70/30?
70 to me, 30 to you.
How about a quarter back
to the church, 60/40 split?
How about 1/8 back
Church gets nothing, 60/40?
- Deal.
Hold on. Wait a second.
See some new shoes?
Got some 22s you want?
Security camera right there.
Oh, my God.
Oh, we're gonna need that.
This hit-and-run story is
only gonna hold for so long.
We gotta get out of here
before anybody else comes
and asks more questions.
How's Lucy?
Yeah, uh, she's still...
Pretty fucked up?
Yeah.
She can never know
what happened to her back at that hill,
how she got down there.
- What are we supposed to say?
- I don't know.
You know, that they did it.
And they fucking ran us over,
then they picked us up and
tossed us down the hill.
And then you showed up
when the coast was clear.
Man, this whole thing has
just gotten so messed up.
I need to see her.
Scotty, seeing her like this
is not gonna make you feel any better.
Eh, if I can get her
to make me cum, it will.
Hold my sauce.
Hey, you hang out here,
and you keep a lookout.
Scotty, she's in no shape
to do the things that you are
thinking about doing in there.
She's fighting for her life.
She is my girl, and I will
decide what she's in shape for.
Now don't come in.
No. Scotty, Scotty.
Don't do that. Scotty, Scotty.
Shit.
What are you doing?
Getting her the hell out of here.
You didn't really think I'd
try and get a blowjob, did you?
That's disgusting.
Hello?
There he is.
But I do a little bit.
- He was a baby.
- He was a little baby bird.
What the heck are y'all doing?
Baby, you're home early.
Nobody's supposed to be in here.
We were just looking at pictures.
Guess what? Y'all hear about this?
Gideon got cast in a Netflix movie.
Say what now?
I think y'all should just
go brush your teeth, okay?
He seems to be doing well in LA,
following his dreams.
What, to be a bum in California?
Congratulations.
He's not a bum. He's a stuntman.
Same damn thing.
Hollywood.
Did you just blow a kiss at me?
Abraham, stop blowing on them coins.
Go brush your teeth.
What the hell, Amber? He called?
- He did.
- And you spoke with him?
I can't just cut off our son.
Well, I don't know why not.
He did that to us,
snipped our nuts like
we're damn street dogs.
Well, he's a child,
and he's reaching out.
To you, he is.
He ain't reaching out to me.
I didn't hear my damn phone ringing.
You know what, as far as
I'm concerned, he's cancelled.
If he don't give a flip about
this family and don't want
to be a part of it, that's fine with me.
But what I do give a flip about
is you not being honest with me.
Baby, I'm being honest with you.
I'm telling you right now that
he called and that we spoke.
I know, and we said that we
weren't gonna speak to him.
- Okay.
- Now he got you and the boys
aligning behind my back
with our apostate son.
I look like the bad guy.
Oh, baby, you're not the bad guy.
- You're not.
- I know I'm not the bad guy.
Now, you know, I-I'm working big time,
overtime to keep the unity
and sanctity of this family.
- I hear you.
- I don't need people undercutting me.
You don't.
I don't know why you wanna
hang out in this dumbass room anyway,
all this stupid, childish shit.
Boring.
How you feeling?
Shitty.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Don't treat her like she's handicapped.
She shall not recover
lest she be challenged.
Come on.
There you go, sunshine.
Ah, there you go, coming back already.
Squeeze it. Squeeze it.
Mm-hmm. You got it.
Love that. Love that.
I've been thinking about
what we should do next.
I think we should murder them.
Murder?
Vengeance. Yes, please.
If they're dead, we get nothing.
I fucking love you.
Of course we should stick 'em
for more money. That's smart.
How are we gonna do that?
We have no leverage.
With the backup copy of the tape.
- Backup copy?
- Yeah.
I got a backup on my jack off drive,
my LaCie Rugged,
indestructible weatherproof.
- I have a question.
- Mm-hmm.
How did I end up down
that hill after the drop?
You don't wanna know.
Yeah, I do.
They're ruthless, baby.
They threw both of us down there
like a sack of cats.
The security footage from
that camera is stored
on a local server in the
back office of RimTyme.
I spoke with an employee
on his smoke break.
Don't worry.
I disguised myself as a regular man.
I want you guys to go in there
and get me that footage, all right?
- Let's wrap this up.
- Okay.
Why can't you do it?
What'd you say?
- I said...
- What's that?
Why can't you...
Don't challenge me, Levi.
"Why can't you do it?
Why can't you do it?"
Do it.
Get in there. Get that fucking footage.
I wish Chad wasn't in a coma!
He sure as hell would
do what I asked of him
without asking a bunch
of fucking questions!
Sir, I spoke with a manager about
a break-in I had in my
car in this parking lot.
He said I can come by,
sort through the security
cam footage in the back.
- You spoke to who?
- The manager.
I'm the manager.
Oh.
Okay. Uh...
It wa... it was somebody else,
a man.
- I'm a man.
- Yeah.
He looked like you.
But...
Did you get it?
No, he didn't know nothing.
He was acting like a bitch.
- Y'all didn't get the tape?
- He... he wasn't very helpful.
Get the fuck back in there!
Get the fucking tape.
Get the fuck back in there.
Y'all forget something?
Uh, okay, rolling.
You can't kill the devil, son.
I'm coming after you.
I still got footage of you.
I made a copy.
So fuck you.
Now you're gonna pay me $2 million
or else this will get
released nationwide,
and once your reputation is smeared...
I'm gonna fucking kill you.
It doesn't really seem
like you're gonna kill him. It...
- No.
- It kinda rang false.
What are you talking about, rang false?
The voice is fucked up.
It's almost becoming,
like, a parody of itself.
It feels like an empty threat,
like you're trying to be a movie.
Trying to be a movie? Fuck you.
You wanna do it? No, you don't.
So shut the fuck up. Look, I got this.
I got this. Fuck you.
Go. Record this one.
It's been recording
the whole time, Scott.
All right, shut the fuck up, dude.
Fucking piece of shit.
This mask smells like shit.
All right, go again.
Hey, motherfuckers.
You scared?
No, not really.
You know, this whole thing was my idea.
Scotty can act like he's
the leader of it and all,
but, I mean,
he wouldn't have anything
if it weren't for me.
You two threw me
down the hill, didn't you?
No.
No way. No, of course not.
You're a terrible liar.
I weirdly expected this from him
but not from you,
you pussy bitch.
No, seriously, Lucy.
Lucy.
It's when we start believing
we can take life into our own hands,
resolve matters ourselves
without the guiding hand of the Lord
that we fall victim
to the snakes of the world.
- Mm.
- Amen.
Though cleverly disguised
as a loving neighbor,
a trusted friend,
- they will find their way in, folks.
- They will.
Sometimes a snake will
come into the garden,
and when one does,
you need to close them eyes,
tilt that head up and say,
"Good afternoon, Jesus."
- Yeah.
- "Good afternoon, Lord."
That's not gonna bother Him a bit.
- I promise.
- I'll be right back.
He's ready to hear your call,
always there to help you
deal with the snakes.
Let's turn to 1 Corinthians 10:13.
Y'all wonder where those devils went,
why there was no crime scene,
no police tape stuff,
no sign of nothing?
Stop doing theatrics, Jesse.
Just show us your TV show.
Security camera footage.
It's not a TV show.
Shh, shh. Just be quiet. How 'bout that?
- I'm not gonna shush.
- Shut up.
I'm watching TV.
Oh, shit. There's three of 'em?
Ding, ding.
They're not dead?
Least the one I runned over's not.
The one you got has passed.
Nuh-uh, mine looked like
he was gonna be fine.
The back fender probably just gave
him a charley horse or something.
- Looks worse than that.
- Kelvin, shut up.
Who cares, all right?
What we need to do here is figure out
who these idiots are, and apparently,
there's three of 'em.
Let's brainstorm, okay?
Let's have a spitball sesh right now,
come up with some ideas.
How are we gonna find these guys?
Levi.
We can make a flyer
with a pic of the van,
see if anybody's seen it.
They ain't a lost cat, Levi.
Jeez, man.
They ain't running for school president.
- Yeah, dumb.
- Fuck off outta here
with that idea, Levi.
Okay, this is a safe space.
We can pitch freely.
Anybody else got anything?
Gregory, you got something?
- Not yet.
- Yeah, not yet.
Of course. I'm not gonna hold my breath.
- Uh, I have a real idea.
- Oh, well, let me guess.
"We should tell Daddy
and turn ourselves in."
All right, do you...
Do you want my idea?
- Well, let's hear it.
- Okay, then shut up real quick.
Thank you. Traffic cams, right?
They got videotapes on them,
and when cars drive through 'em,
it will videotape that footage.
So I say we go and get
traffic cam footage from,
like, the area that night,
and then we can track where they went.
Well, is that, like, a real thing?
Yeah, it is.
Every red light has a camera and, like,
tons of technologies on it.
Look at him.
That's my baby bro-bro right there.
- Don't touch me.
- Thank you for participating
instead of being mopey
for once in your life.
This is good.
This is exactly what we need.
Thank you, buddy.
So Kelvin's figured out that much.
I need that traffic cam footage.
Who in here's gonna get it for me?
Not me. I've done enough already.
Gregory, what if Jesus Christ
just did one or two things
and was like, "I'm good.
I don't need to die on the cross."
- Where would we be then?
- I don't know, Jess.
Get your head out of your asshole, okay?
I think I know someone who could help.
See, you have form RG004A.
You need form FR309 for a fleet
policy of 25 or more vehicles,
which is the situation you're in.
So once you fill that form out,
you can come back up
here and we'll get...
I'll... I'll help you
with further assistance.
God bless you.
Yo, what's up?
Okay, yeah. Over... over back?
I could lose my job for this,
but I'd do anything for you.
- You know that, Kelvin.
- I know.
You saved me from the darkness,
brought me to the light.
I owe you everything.
You know, I'd even
kill myself if you asked me to.
- What the hell?
- I know, buddy.
You tell me that a lot.
Okay, I would, though.
I'm not gonna tell you to kill yourself.
Okay.
So these guys in the red van here,
they're... uh, they're our
buds and our friends, you know?
And we're just playing
some pranks with them.
Yeah, just car pranks,
your average car prank.
- Well, I trust you, friend.
- I know.
Here's that van crossing the
intersection that you gave me.
And then cameras catch the van
for about a mile, and then we lose 'em.
- Huh.
- But then we pick them up again
on a cam near the hospital.
And, uh, a few hours later,
a camera picks the van up as
it's leaving the hospital.
And then, um, we end up
following them all the way
on cams to right there.
And how long ago was that?
- A week ago.
- And where are they now?
They're still there,
the same place they were a...
A week ago.
You can't kill the devil, son.
I'm coming after you.
Eat shit, Gemstones.
What the fuck?
Did you fuck us?
- What are you talking about?
- Chicken shit.
- You did this.
- No.
It was me.
You did this?
I'm going home.
You left me for dead, Scotty.
You dumped my body down a fucking ditch!
No, I didn't.
Is that what he told you? Huh?
This was our ticket.
This was everything.
You and me, Thailand, piña coladas.
Fuck you.
Lucy!
You told her.
No, I didn't.
Why'd you tell her?
You like her? You think she likes you?
No, no. Don't do this, okay?
- You're hurt.
- Yeah, you're about to be hurt.
Enough, okay?
Ow!
Whoa! Okay.
I got something else.
What the fuck was that?
All right.
Come on, man.
Oh, oh.
Oh, my God, you broke my back.
Okay, enough, all right?
I'm gonna get you up and no more.
You broke my fucking back.
Come on, Scotty, you gotta work with me.
Come on.
Oh, what's up now, bitch?
Fuck you.
What are you gonna do?
Quit fucking doing that shit.
Enough, all right?
You fucked up, man!
I'm tapping out. I submit.
- Fuck you.
- Fuck you!
You lost the fucking money,
and you're gonna get it
back one way or the other.
- I'll get the money.
- Okay?
I'll get the fucking money, okay?
All right. Truce.
- Truce?
- Yeah, come on. Fuck you.
Jesus Christ, Scott.
If you don't, I will kill you.
Does that sound believable?
Do I sound like I'm trying
to be a fucking movie?
You're fucking crazy.
Get me the money.
Ugh.
Oh, fuck.
Quick question, friend.
You seen this van around?
Seen a lot of vans around, man.
Kelvin, plan B.
Maybe this will refresh
your memory, hmm?
- How you like that, huh?
- Mm-hmm.
- Does that help a little bit?
- Got some answers now?
- He loves it.
- Okay, yeah.
They've been staying here
for, like, a week.
- Yeah!
- Okay, all right.
- I told you.
- There you go.
Though they checked out today.
- They checked out today?
- Ah, shoot.
Hey, Honey Bunches of Oats.
♪ Doo-doo-doo-doo ♪
What'd they look like?
Huh? Details.
Think hard.
Just like regular white people.
Did this whites happen to tell
you where they were heading?
No, man, fuck you think?
People don't say shit to me.
Perhaps that's because
of the customer service.
- Is this little boy your son?
- I'm fully grown.
Thank you. I'm an adult man.
Okay, well, uh,
y'all want a room or what?
No, we don't want a room!
We want answers!
Fucking guy thinks I'm old enough
to be your daddy. Jesus H.
Well, you are aging horrifically.
Look, Jesse, I know you're disappointed,
but I think it's for the best.
I don't know what you're capable of.
I don't want our paths to cross
with those guys ever again.
Shit, maybe that's that.
No, I don't think so.
Damn it.
You're leading too much.
Funny.
I wasn't having any trouble
'fore you got here.
You know, I would have come with you
if you wanted to shoot
'em like we used to together.
You're the one who stopped, not me.
I'm sorry, baby.
I'm so sorry that I didn't
tell you I was talking to him.
I never should have kept that from you.
I agree.
Can't keep secrets from family.
It's not right.
No. No more.
Deal.
Deal. Come here.
Ooh.
Good afternoon, Jesus.
Thank you for watching
after my family and myself.
And thank you for letting me be born
into this world as a Gemstone.
The legacy of my family
carries immense weight...
But I take it you are no
stranger to that, Dear Lord.
We gotta get off the compound, baby.
Oh, take me right here.
My duties are great,
but many are the pleasures
you have bestowed upon me.
Oh, no.
I came.
I'm so sorry.
Grant me strength, Dear Lord,
to lead the people...
To bring them to your righteous kingdom.
And thank you, Lord,
for forgiving me of my wrongdoings,
which you know are not who I am.
Your ability to accept
me for the sinner I am
only speaks to your greatness...
His righteous grace...
Your guidance and mercy is all
that the Gemstones require.
Please, teach me your patience.
Teach...
Fuckin' A.
Somebody get the door, please.
Get the door!
I'm praying, God damn it!
Hey, Mama.
I'm home.
Gideon. Oh, my baby.
Oh!
Hi.
Synced & corrected by QueenMaddie
www.addic7ed.com