Are you lost, Father?
Sorry?
Are you lost?
No.
I suppose not.
According to this, I am in Nevada.
I've never been to Nevada before.
What's it like?
Oh... It's not bad.
Looks like it might rain.
What's California like these days?
Well...
still sunny.
Can I give you a hand there?
That's very kind of you.
Thank you.
Oh!
Please.
How are you enjoying Nevada so far?
So far, so good.
Those are my accouterments.
Over there by the front desk.
That's my trunk. That's my fortnighter.
That's my hat case.
And I would ask you folk...
to please respect my claim
when it comes time to divvyin' up the rooms.
But when that'll be is anybody's guess.
Been ringin' that dang bell so much my hand is tired.
My ears are sore.
And my constitution needs coffee.
That's why I was scratchin' around back there.
I did find some...
though I can't vouch for the quality.
Laramie Seymour Sullivan.
Sales manager, Calhoun Appliances.
My name might not be on the masthead there...
but that don't mean we aren't a family business.
Ma'am.
Hello.
And what may I call you, Father?
Daniel Flynn. Nice to meet you.
Oh, Father Flynn. That's easy to remember.
Alliterative and such.
Whereabouts is your parish?
The Immaculate Heart of Mary's in Bloomington, Indiana.
Well, let me just say up front that myself
and the good people of East Biloxi Baptist...
may have our differences with your pope...
but I do believe we all carry
the divinity of Jesus Christ in our hearts.
And that makes us brothers as far as I'm concerned.
You're more than welcome to give that bell a whirl
if you'd like.
You might have better luck than I did.
So what about you, darlin'?
Are you in the hospitality business?
I do not work in the hospitality business, no.
Well, I am going to give you my card anyway.
I bet you know some gals who just might need a vacuum.
Your first time at the El Royale?
Ooh.
Well, it wasn't always like this.
And I don't just mean
you could find a clerk come check-in time.
No, no, no.
This place used to be hustlin' and bustlin'.
Tahoe's best-kept secret.
I mean it was always a bit of a novelty,
yeah, sure, of course.
But there's state fair novelty
and then there's old horse novelty.
And I believe we are firmly in the old horse variety.
Yessir! 1966, this place had swing.
Hell, I don't even think I could get a room here
in the main lodge if I tried.
It was a hidey-hole for the Tahoe swells, you know?
Old Dean Martin even sang a song about it.
"Half in California with Judy."
No?
Well, wasn't one of his best. Coffee?
Oh, no, thank you.
Oh, come on, girl.
I made a whole pot. Shame for it to go to waste.
There you go.
Atta girl.
I'll let the clerk give you the whole spiel
if he ever shows up again, that is.
But the thing they always leave out...
is that this place lost its gambling license
about a year ago.
Something to do with the commission or some such.
So all the swells took their business elsewhere.
Now the main lodge is all that's open.
The pool is filled with ducks.
And they'll even rent you a room by the hour
if you ask real quietlike.
There you go, Father.
Thank you.
Mmm-hmm. Although if we're bein' honest...
that's probably the only reason that a priest,
a vacuum salesman, and a negro...
could afford freight here, am I right?
I'm just funnin'.
Truth be told, my stay is on Calhoun Appliances...
which is why room choice is so important to me...
and why I ask you to respect my accoutrement
as proxy to my person.
I intend to lavish myself.
I always wanted to stay in the honeymoon suite...
although I'm not currently on my honeymoon.
The lady's got a harder hand than we do, Father.
Oh...
I am very sorry to keep you waiting.
Damn, boy, where you been?
Waitin' in this lobby so long, I could use a shave.
What's wrong with you?
I am very sorry.
What are you doing here, Father?
Do I know you, son?
No. But, I mean, this is not a place for a priest, Father.
You shouldn't be here.
We might need to work on your sales pitch, son.
"The El Royale, no place for a priest."
There are other hotels, Father.
Maybe closer to Tahoe. I could help you find one.
I'm sure you would be happier there.
Uh, Miles, is it?
Mmm-hmm.
If this is not a place for a priest, Miles...
then this is exactly where the Lord wants me.
Well, the Lord don't want you in the honeymoon suite.
I can promise you that.
Miles, those are my accoutrement there
and I stake my claim as such.
But you can go ahead and check them in first.
I don't mind.
It's all right, son.
Come on, boy.
Give him the whole spiel.
The El Royale. And blah, blah, blah.
The El Royale is a bi-state establishment.
You have the option to stay
in either the great state of California...
or the great state of Nevada.
Warmth and sunshine to the west...
or hope and opportunity to the east.
Which would you prefer?
What's the difference?
Between California and Nevada?
Between the rooms.
Well, for starters,
rooms in California cost a dollar more.
Really? When did that happen?
What makes 'em a dollar better?
They're in California.
And that's worth a dollar?
Some people think so.
You got a phone number for any of those people?
'Cause I sure would like to sell them
one of these vacuum cleaners.
Hey, speaking of which,
who handles your hospitality here at the hotel?
Currently, that is also me.
Oh, well...
Shit.
We'll have to worry about that later.
May I see a map of the hotel, please?
Mmm-hmm.
Only the main lodge is available in the off-season.
You could still use the California amenities
if you choose to stay in Nevada.
What exactly is a California amenity?
Uh, for instance,
we're not allowed to sell liquor in Nevada.
So if we wanna drink,
we gotta do it on that side of the room?
That is correct, sir.
Also, coffee is 25 cents a cup.
Let me guess. You're also the bartender?
That is correct, sir.
All right. Well...
Feel free to flip that
if you need to make a decision, Father.
Startin' to cost me money waitin' around this place.
Oh.
Four. I'll take room four.
I'll need one night in advance. Eight dollars.
And it's 25 cents for the coffee.
Please sign the ledger.
Who's next?
May I have a room in Nevada please, Miles?
Room five.
Um, is there another room available?
Possibly further away?
Uh, those rooms have not been serviced and are unsuitable.
He also does the housekeeping, remember?
There are rooms in California available, ma'am.
Miles, she don't wanna be near the priest.
It's not like we didn't see her walkin' in here...
with her own bed rolls under her arms.
No judgment on you there, darlin'.
Maybe you can talk to the Father here...
about, uh, Mary Magdalene and forgiveness and whatnot.
Room five will be fine.
Please sign the ledger.
And it's 25 cents for the coffee.
Okay. Of course.
Thank you.
Can I give you a hand to your room?
No.
Sorry, Father. Uh...
That's very kind of you. But I can manage from here.
Ma'am.
Good afternoon.
Who's next?
Please, be my fuckin' guest.
I need a room.
The El Royale is a bi-state establishment.
You have the option to stay in either the great state of...
I'll take this one.
Um...
Don't fuckin' tell me.
I'll take room one.
You can't have room one.
Do you not see my fortnighter right there at your feet?
Do I really have to explain
the concept of a free-market claim stake...
to the goddamn hippie?
Give me something along this wall then.
The available rooms on that wall
have yet to be cleaned, and...
I don't give a shit. How much?
Eight dollars.
Please sign the ledger.
You have yourself a pleasant day, ma'am.
Nice.
I'll take room one.
Hello, my love. I'm sorry.
I know.
Check-in took a little longer than expected.
Is she still up?
Good.
Hello, bunny rabbit.
Yes.
The clock is right and Daddy is wrong.
I'm sorry. I was delayed.
I am ready.
Yes, I am on my knees.
Now I lay me down to sleep...
pray the Lord my soul to keep.
If I should die before I wake...
We're not saying that part anymore?
Where did you hear the word "morbid"?
Well, what does Mommy want us to say?
"And when I wake in the morning light"? Okay.
And when I wake in the...
From the beginning?
Okay.
Now I lay me down to sleep...
I pray the Lord my soul to keep.
And when I wake in the morning light...
teach me to do what's right.
Amen.
Okay, bunny rabbit, Daddy has to go.
Will you tell Mommy I love her?
And I love you, too. Sleep tight.
Together can serve the cause of peace.
Mr. President, do you consider it possible
to have a ceasefire in Vietnam...
so long as the Viet Cong still occupy Vietnamese territory?
I think that it is not helpful in discussing Vietnam...
to use such terms as "ceasefire"...
because ceasefire is a term of art...
that really has no relevance,
in my opinion, to a guerrilla war.
When you're talking about a conventional war...
then a ceasefire, agreed upon by two parties,
means that the shooting stops.
But when you have a guerrilla war in which
one side may not even be able to control...
many of those who are responsible
for the violence in the area...
the ceasefire may be meaningless.
This is a Channel 7 News Special Report.
Police are searching for suspects
in the grisly murders...
of noted Malibu County pediatrician
Bernard Webber and his wife, Etheline.
The couple was found stabbed to death
early this morning in their beachfront home.
Director's office. Case 246673.
Director Hoover, it's Special Agent Broadbeck.
I'm here on site at the El Royale.
Sir, we have a problem.
Good morning, everyone. Let's have a listen, shall we?
Cut. Cut.
Cut it.
All right, let's take a break, everyone. Shall we?
And, Darlene, a word, please.
Darlene...
do you know how much my time is worth?
No, sir, um...
Mr. Sunday.
Well, Columbia Records does.
Columbia Records currently values my time
at $200 an hour.
Are you currently in a position
where you can afford to turn down...
two, four, $600 when it's offered to you?
No, I'm not.
Mmm.
$600 of my time...
and still you wanted to stay, what was it?
"Fresh."
Which apparently means flat on the intro
and sharp on harmonies.
I'll get it right next time, Mr. Sunday. I promise.
Yeah.
Do you know how much your time is worth, Darlene?
$12 a session.
No matter how long the session.
Which, I suppose, means the longer I keep you,
the less your time is worth.
Right?
Darlene...
I think that you have a choice here.
Give me one year of your time.
I can make you a star.
You'll be singing lead...
headlining the Riviera.
Or...
you can continue to treat my time as disposable.
Keep scrounging for $12 backup gigs until they dry up.
Five years from now, you'll wake up...
find yourself shuffling between shit hotels...
begging for the opening slot on pancake night...
in Reno.
Darlene.
Do we understand?
Good.
All right then.
Yes?
Hello, Darlene.
It's Father Flynn from earlier.
I'm so sorry. I was making too much noise, wasn't I?
Oh, no. No, not at all.
I have to rehearse and I was trying
to keep it quiet, but...
I'm sorry, I won't bother you.
No, it was no bother.
Quite the opposite, actually. It's lovely.
Thank you.
That song that you were singing,
did you write that?
Oh, no, it's by The Isley Brothers.
Your brothers wrote that?
No, um, it's a famous song.
It's been on the radio.
Oh. I don't know too much about the radio these days.
I was gonna go find some food in the lounge...
and I thought I'd see if you'd like to join?
With this place, there's probably strength in numbers.
No, that's all right.
You sure? It's on me.
Consider it payment.
For letting me listen to you sing.
That's a very nice thing to say.
Why even have a bell?
I suspect we're on our own.
I handle food. You handle entertainment?
Deal.
We're told both the husband and wife
suffered multiple stab wounds...
and were dead when the deputies arrived.
Bernard Webber was well known in the Malibu community...
and was very active in local philanthropic endeavors...
mostly concerning homeless children.
You really never heard of The Isley Brothers?
Then we have some work to do.
How are you making out over here?
You're definitely better at your job
than I am at mine.
How lucky are you feeling tonight?
Definitely not eat-that-sandwich lucky.
Pie?
Pie's good.
We have a very good, uh...
Well, no. Now that I've heard you sing...
we have a pretty good choir at the Heart of Mary.
That's actually how I got started.
Church choir.
Ah.
St. Paul's Evangelical in Decatur.
Lutheran. But we don't have to get into that.
You're forgiven.
I'm sure we must've sung some of the same stuff.
Do you know, um, Nearer, My God, to Thee?
Mmm.
And Alleluia! Sing to Jesus?
What about Hold Me in Your Arms, Lift Me on High?
That was my first solo.
Oh.
It goes...
You got that?
To be honest, my memory, um...
isn't quite what it was.
Okay.
I think I'm gonna have a toddy.
Can I interest you?
No, I'm fine.
No? You sure?
Nothing like a warm whiskey on a cold night.
I'm fine. Thank you.
So, what are you doing out here?
Oh, I live in Bakersfield now,
but I got a job singing in Reno tomorrow.
Oh, that's exciting.
That's not exactly the word I'd use
to describe a 6:00 shift at the keno lounge.
But, um, it's a job.
Why are you staying here?
It's not a good job.
Don't pay nothing.
But if I stay in Reno proper, I'd be in the hole.
Outskirts are cheaper.
Ah.
Why do it at all?
You know, I ask myself the same question sometimes.
Mmm.
Singing's singing.
How about you?
How'd you end up at the El Royale?
I was visiting my brother in Oakland...
and, uh, I had to get off the road before dark.
Well, my eyes, they're no good at night.
And the Ritz-Carlton was booked...
so here we are.
I'm guessing church pays about as much as a keno lounge?
Mmm-hmm.
About that, yeah.
How about your brother?
You and him close?
Used to be.
Used to be, yeah.
Hmm.
Darlene...
can I confess something to you?
When I said that my memory isn't quite what it was...
I think I might have been understating things a bit.
For the last couple of years, my recall...
well, I've been having problems with it.
And, uh, I don't think it's just my age.
I'm certain it's not just my age.
I wake up some days...
and I can't remember who I am.
I have moments when I lose time.
When you saw me earlier today in the parking lot...
actually, I had completely forgotten
where I was, what I was doing.
Strangest feeling. You know, you look around
and you're someone else...
and you don't know who that is.
Can I say something, Father?
Please.
I think you should see a doctor.
Yeah, I have, and he agrees with my assessment
that it's not just age.
I'm sorry.
Oh, I'm not looking for pithy.
Pithy.
I'm just letting you know
in case I've seemed scattered...
I don't mean offense, ma'am.
No.
None taken.
It might be for the best.
There are parts of my life that aren't worth remembering.
I have those, too.
I could use another.
You sure I can't tempt you?
No, I'm fine.
Are you sure?
Now, I may have a spotty memory...
but I do recall it is a sin to let an old priest drink alone.
All right. Just one.
Grand.
Perhaps I can even tempt you...
to grace me with a song again later?
Don't push your luck, Father.
But if you happen to be in Reno tomorrow,
I go on at 6:00.
Oh, I'd like that.
I'd like that.
But until then...
In the course of
retrieving our equipment...
I discovered another wiretap
along with several other microphones.
Did you recognize the equipment?
I don't believe they were ours, sir.
Additionally, I discovered
the hotel room had a two-way mirror.
I also found several other hotel rooms
with the same setup along an observation corridor...
as well as a camera.
Did you find film?
No, I called in as soon as I found the camera.
We must assume
our operation has been compromised.
No one is to leave there, Agent Broadbeck...
until you have any and all
existing surveillance materials in your possession.
Understood, sir.
Sir, there is something else.
Upon investigating the observation corridor...
I came across what appeared to be a kidnapping in process.
A young woman, Caucasian,
appeared to be holding another young woman hostage.
Also Caucasian.
The priority is the surveillance materials,
Agent Broadbeck.
Peripheral matters are not our concern.
Sir...
I am not in the habit of repeating myself,
Agent Broadbeck...
but I will do so here to ensure there is no confusion.
Hiya!
Hi.
I like your boots.
They're my daddy's.
Well, they don't look like your daddy's no more.
Is that why you're so sad?
We don't get a lot of girls down here in boots.
You must have come straight from the station, huh?
It's all right, Boots. You don't got to say nothin'.
I'll figure it out in three guesses. Watch.
Tennessee?
Nah, that's too easy.
You ain't no Texas girl. I know that much for sure.
West Virginia?
Nah, of course not.
Don't insult the girl, Billy Lee.
Hey, I'm just messing with you.
I knew it the second I saw
these boot prints on the beach.
You're an Alabama girl.
See?
Told you I could do it in three.
Now, you gotta come swimming with me.
That wasn't the deal.
Sure it was.
You knew the game the second we started playing.
Come on, Boots. You got no reason to cry no more.
You're in California now.
Rose?
Rosie.
Rose, hey. It's okay.
It's okay.
You're safe. You're with me.
It's okay. It's okay.
Rosie, I can't untie you.
Stop it.
I expect you're all kinds of mad at me,
and to some extent you're right to be...
but we're gonna wait this out.
I'm gonna get you clear...
and then we can have it out.
We have to get as far away from him as possible.
He's all kinds of bad.
It doesn't matter what you did, Rose.
I'm gonna get you clear...
and then we'll just start over.
Ma'am?
Hello. I'm sorry to disturb you.
What do you want?
Oh. Ma'am, yeah. It's Laramie Sullivan.
We met in the hotel lobby there earlier?
Would you mind opening the door?
No, I ain't gonna do that.
I certainly
understand that, yes.
It's good to be cautious.
We can talk through the door, if you like.
What do you want?
Oh, well, ma'am, the storm's just wreckin'
all kinds of hell on the hotel.
People are having complaints about losing power and such...
and so the boy up front had asked me to come around...
check on some of the women and make sure they're safe.
I'm fine.
Well, that's good to hear. That's good to hear.
Uh, listen, if you wouldn't mind...
Fuck off.
I'm very sorry to have spooked you, ma'am.
You have a safe night.
Hey, hey, hey. Look at me!
It's gonna be okay. It's okay.
Okay? It's okay.
You're safe now.
Let's get you untied.
Don't touch it.
You let it bleed.
Next time you wanna get smart,
look down at all that red and think twice.
Where's Rosie?
Rosie, Rosie?
Don't you come out, okay?
No matter what you hear, you stay put.
Where's Rosie?
No matter what you hear, don't make a sound.
Okay, listen to me.
You don't have to be afraid anymore.
Okay, good.
Rosie.
Get out of the way.
Listen.
Father Flynn.
Father?
Hey. Don't try to move, Father.
I'm not your father.
Take it easy. Take it real easy.
What the heck happened?
Oh, what's this song?
Father, do you know where you are?
What happened?
That's what I'm asking you.
I just found you like this. On the floor.
You got glass in your head.
Where...?
Was I alone?
Yeah. Why? Was you with somebody?
No.
Kid, what's your name again?
Miles.
Miles. I need a drink.
Fix me a drink.
Oh, I'm not so sure that's a good idea.
Just one drink to clear my head.
I'd get it myself, but look what happens.
Miles, I fell down.
I'm old.
Shit happens. Get the whiskey.
Father...
I was hopin'...
I was hopin' I could ask for your help.
I've been gone...
gone from the church for a while now.
But I was devout my whole life.
Baptized, confirmed...
never missed a Sunday till I left Indiana.
I was born in Indiana.
Really? No kiddin'?
Whereabouts?
Okay.
Father, I was hopin', see...
I got things I need to confess.
Not now, kid.
Okay, Father. Right.
Of course.
It's just...
I'm penitent, Father.
I promise I'm penitent.
And I'm afraid for my soul.
I've done horrible things.
So? So has everybody.
You'll be fine.
You have a master key to this place?
Did you lock yourself out of your room?
Like I said, kid, I'm old.
I'm old.
Should be right here.
Father...
Where's the key?
Miles.
I told you...
this wasn't a good place, Father.
You watched me?
What did you see?
I didn't see nothing! I didn't, I didn't.
I only watch who they tell me to watch.
Who's "they"?
Management.
I get a call...
"So-and-so is checking in, set up the camera."
Hasn't happened much since the election.
Mostly they just want, you know, people screwin'.
What do you do with the film?
Develop it in one of the back cabins,
mail it to management.
P.O. box in Pennsylvania.
Do you ever keep any of the film?
Do you ever keep any of it?
Miles?
Last year. The big celebration.
A man stayed with us.
He was a big deal, you would know him.
Management wanted him. They really wanted him.
But he was kind to me.
Nobody's ever kind to me...
so I told them there wasn't no woman in his room.
So you kept it, the film?
Father, this ain't even what I was trying to confess.
I've done so much worse than this.
Who is that?
Oh, Jesus!
Oh.
It's okay.
You're safe.
You're with me.
We gotta help her.
We gotta help her, Father.
We gotta do something. We gotta help her.
Miles, listen to me. Miles!
Listen to me.
The Lord wants you to tell me where the film is.
He's all kinds of bad.
Father Flynn.
Ma'am? Hello?
I'm so sorry to bother you.
What do you want?
Ma'am, it's Laramie Sullivan.
Father Flynn!
Father Flynn, get down here!
That vacuum man just busted down the door...
and he beat up that other girl, and he's got a gun!
Get away from the window! Kid!
Help me.
Help.
What the fuck?
Jesus fucking Christ!
Don't push your luck, Father.
But if you happen to be in Reno tomorrow,
I go on at 6:00.
Oh, I'd like that.
But until then...
Come on.
Come on! Come on!
Lord...
I need your guidance.
I'm in darkness, and I need your light.
Rose, get out of the way.
Jesus fucking Christ!
Rosie...
you stay here.
Please don't kill...
Come on.
Keep your fucking hands where I can see them.
What are you doing?
Hi, it's me.
I don't know.
I'm with Em.
She had me all tied up. Think she shot a cop.
We're in a hotel.
I don't know.
You will?
Okay.
Let me look.
It says "El Royale."
Rosie!
Rosie, get in here.
I gotta go.
Okay. See you again soon.
Rosie!
Come on! Come on!
No, no, no!
Lord...
I just wanna talk.
Roll down the window.
I just wanna talk. Can I get in?
I will shoot you in the face.
Believe me.
I believe you.
Well, we're in a bit of a pickle here.
I'm sorry that I tried to drug you back there in the lobby.
I wasn't trying to diddle you or nothing like that...
I just needed to break into your room.
And I didn't wanna hurt you.
Any more than need be, I mean.
No hard feelings about bashing me in the head
is what I'm saying.
I'm pretty sure those girls killed a cop of some sort.
They did.
You saw it?
Yeah.
That his gun?
Mmm-hmm.
This is not so good for us.
I'm not really a priest.
Yeah, no shit.
- Are they dead? - Nah, they'll live.
Where'd you learn to drive?
They swerved.
Yeah, they tend to do that when you're box sweepin' 'em.
"Stay on his fender," you said. "I want him scared."
"Scared," not comatose.
Oh, here we go.
Are they dead?
Okay.
Where'd you learn to drive?
We've been over this!
Shut the fuck up! Get the money!
They ain't dead.
Praise the Lord.
Well, can't leave this here.
Yeah.
Will it run?
Let's go with yes.
Think the new guy is bent or just stupid?
Oh, I'm going with stupid, but I can be persuaded.
What are we doing, Dock?
Get out of the car.
Get out of the car, Felix.
Here, here.
Take the kid...
ditch the Chevy at Rocklin. Split up.
I'll lead 'em south,
I'll burn this once I'm in the clear.
We all meet at the El Royale, huh?
Felix.
You play it close with these assholes. Huh?
You sure about this, Dock?
Oh, we got this, Felix, piece of cake.
I got it under control.
All rise.
Donald O'Kelly...
on the charges of grand larceny
and conspiracy to commit larceny...
I sentence you to 15 years in the federal penitentiary.
What? Where?
Dock.
Where am I?
Hey, hey, Dock.
It's okay.
What? Where am I?
Same place you've been the last ten fucking years.
You're gonna be okay, man.
Jesus, Dock.
We gotta do something about this.
What do you think?
I think you should stop fighting
with the negroes, for starters.
Mesican... Mesican...
Mexicans.
Yeah, them this time.
And I didn't do nothing.
Hate to see what happens when you do something.
Oh, well.
Tell me that boy down the hall may not walk again.
He jumped me.
Mmm-hmm. Yeah, sure.
It's not about the fighting.
No.
It's not about the fightin'.
Tell me about your family.
Any history? Dementia? Alzheimer's?
My mother.
Her father.
How long I got?
When you up for parole?
Six months.
You should make it till then.
Felix, my brother, and I...
we robbed an armored car, outside of Stockton.
The job went bad.
I think we got burned by our crew.
Felix was killed at the meetup,
which was here, at the El Royale.
We had a plan in case things went south.
Bury the money in the floor of the room.
I couldn't remember what room we said.
It was either four or five.
It's true what I told you back there.
My mind, it isn't what it was.
I guessed wrong.
So, I think there's a bunch of money
buried in your room, Darlene...
and I need your help to get it.
You expect me to believe all that?
Well, it's the truth.
It's the truth, so there is that.
But, no, I get it.
How did you know I wasn't
on the up and up in the first place?
You spend your life getting shook,
you learn how to spot a shaker.
Is that from a song?
No.
If you'd have been wrong...
you'd have bashed a priest in the face for no reason.
I would've found a way to forgive myself.
Yeah, I guess I'd have done the same thing
in your situation.
And now?
What would you do if you were me?
Well, my first impulse would be
to shoot the old man in the face...
and clear out of Dodge.
You're dead right.
Oh, but I would think that through.
You know, the cars aren't working.
The storm's not lettin' up.
People are gonna come looking
for that dead cop soon enough...
and I don't want to be the black woman
in the woods at night with a gun when they do.
So then, I'd start thinking about my other options.
I suppose I could go back in there...
take my chances with those kids.
I promise you I'm not thinking that.
Which leads me to option three.
Maybe I hear the old man out, maybe he's telling the truth.
Maybe there really is money buried in my room.
Maybe the old man...
he doesn't have a lot of time left.
He's fine with 50% of whatever we find in that floor.
If I'm wrong, I can still shoot him later, huh?
But if I'm right...
I might just survive tonight.
If I'm right...
I can walk out of here with enough money
to change my life forever.
How much money are we talking exactly?
So...
What is this? Some kind of pervert hotel?
Hey.
No.
Yes...
I don't know.
You just shot me in the face.
Well, now, let's be clear.
I shot another man who had it comin'...
and you just happened to be back there being creepy...
and you caught a face full of buckshot for your trouble.
Wait, hold still a sec.
You got glass in your head.
How does it look?
To be honest, I don't remember
what you looked like before this.
But I think you should make peace
with the fact that things have changed.
Are you gonna kill me?
How can I not after what you've seen?
I seen worse.
And I ain't said a thing.
You've seen worse than a man
getting sawn in half with a shotgun?
I seen all sorts of bad.
I seen, um...
a senator beat up a whore so bad...
she had to shove her own stockings
back where her teeth used to be...
just to keep from bleeding out through the mouth.
I saw...
a junkie paint "Sorry" on the wall in his own filth.
Like that'd make it easier
when I cleaned all that shit off his cold body.
I saw a man lay with a wolf once.
Guy drags a full-grown feral wolf
on a choke chain into his room...
ties it up to the bed...
and takes off all his clothes...
climbs into bed beside it, and holds the thing.
All night.
It wasn't sexual...
but it wasn't not sexual, either.
Guy just laid there crying, sayin', "Help me..."
while he held that wolf.
All night.
I never told nobody about none of that.
Oh...
I ain't so sure you should've told me that.
Uh...
You don't have to kill me.
What could I even say about you, anyway?
"Some girls shot some guy who was gonna shoot them"?
I don't even know your names.
I'm Rose.
Don't say...
Rose Summerspring.
Oh.
That's my sister, Emily.
What's your name?
Miles.
Miles Miller.
Well, it's nice to meet you, Miles.
Where are the others?
Rose? That's your name, right?
Please, Rose. Please don't kill me.
It ain't entirely up to me.
You can talk to her.
She's your sister, she'll listen to you.
It ain't up to her either.
Well, who's it up to?
Where's the priest?
Miles...
I don't know.
But you do know something, don't you?
Is this yours?
Do you want it?
Where's the priest?
I don't know.
I promise.
I wanna find him too.
Please.
I'll do whatever you want.
Just let me talk to the priest when you find him.
Just let me talk to him before you kill me.
I've been trying to tell him
that we might not have to kill him.
But it's not up to us.
Who's it up to, Rose?
Rose, what did you do?
Howdy.
So how long you lookin' to stay with us?
However long my sister stays, I suppose.
No, you don't get to be a part of the family
just 'cause you're kin.
Why do you wanna be here?
Rosie says you treat her pretty nice.
I appreciate that.
What does God mean to you?
What does God mean to all of you?
Is He some being in the sky?
Do you pray to Him at night?
Do you ask Him to watch over you?
Is He here with us now?
Or maybe there is no God, huh?
Maybe it's all lies.
Listen, I ain't saying I got it all figured out.
I'm not. But I do see the game.
They define right and wrong, and then they make you choose.
And that's how it all starts, with a simple choice...
which side are you on?
Up, down? Good, evil? Right, wrong?
God or no God? It's simple, just pick.
Boots. Quick. Choose. Are you good or are you bad?
I'm neither.
Now, she's cheating 'cause she knows
what answer I'm looking for.
Boots, I'm giving a whole speech here
in front of people. Don't mess it up for me.
They'll get you to pick.
Watch.
I'll do it right now.
I'll do it right now with my star pupil.
Boots, why don't you come up here
and help me out for a sec?
And, what about...
Millie, why don't you come join us, too.
Come on.
We're gonna have ourselves a tussle tonight.
It's been a while since we've had a tussle, right?
Oh, but wait a second. Rosie don't wanna tussle.
She's smart enough to know not to play the game, right?
But this is how I get her.
I dangle something she really wants.
You two are gonna have a proper tussle tonight...
and the winner...
Well, the winner gets to sleep with me
in the big house tonight. How'd that be?
See?
Now we got skin in the game, as they say.
So what do you think, Boots? You wanna play?
Yes.
So, pick a side.
Do you wanna be Right or do you wanna be Wrong?
I wanna be Right.
She wants to be Right.
Well, Millie, I guess that makes you Wrong.
Let's have ourselves an allegory.
All right. Have at it.
Whoa. Easy, Emily.
She's a big girl. She can take care of herself.
Now, here's the important part.
While they're fighting, what am I doing, huh?
'Cause I sure as hell ain't fighting. What am I doing?
I'm watching them.
I'm getting off on it. Then I'm coming over here...
and I'm takin' what's theirs.
And they didn't even notice...
'cause they're too busy playing my game.
All right, all right.
Rosie, Rosie.
Come on. Hey, okay, okay.
All right, all right. Tussle's over, okay?
Okay, tussle's over.
Rosie, Rosie.
Hey, tussle's over.
Love each other.
All right, all right.
You did good. Both did good. Okay.
So, what have we learned, huh?
Maybe we won't play their games no more.
Maybe we won't listen to their lies.
Maybe the only truth in this world is right here.
And here.
And here...
and here, and here...
and here. Just us.
And maybe for tonight...
we get to be our own Gods.
Father Flynn.
Bless me, Father, for I have sinned.
Please, Father...
Kid, if you don't shut up, I'm gonna tie your mouth shut.
Father, please, forgive me for the sins of my life.
Please, Father...
No, no, no.
Hmm.
So, I'm guessing you're Father Flynn.
Which makes the dead guy Laramie Seymour Sullivan.
And you, miss, must be Darlene Sweet. Hmm?
Well, I suppose you could be Fuck You...
but, uh, something tells me that's my Emily here.
Any other people in the hotel?
Hmm?
Wade, Annabell...
stand behind these four,
and if they try to get out of those seats...
you just shoot 'em in the back of the head.
Flicker, Roman, come here.
Go to room seven, get the dead guy...
and put all of his stuff
and the body in the trunk of the car.
Then go room to room, see if you can find anybody else.
If you can, you bring 'em here.
What about them?
Well, first I got some questions
that need answering.
But leave some room in the trunk.
Hiya, Em.
Billy Lee.
You know, uh...
you left without saying goodbye.
What'd you think, I wouldn't take offense? Hmm?
Naw, I figured you would.
But I'd be ready when you did.
You don't look ready.
You caught me on a bad night.
Ain't that the luck, huh?
Did you tell 'em what she did? Hmm?
Did you tell them what she did?
What'd I do?
Oh, right.
Sorry about all that.
She's sorry.
It's all right, Boots. We'll deal with that
when we get back to California.
We got us a Nevada problem now.
So, uh, Miles...
What is this? Some sort of pervert hotel?
Kid can't answer you.
You tied his mouth shut.
Well, why don't I ask you then? Huh?
Why don't I ask the priest who was walking
out of the hotel with a bag full of money?
All right.
Yeah. I think it's some sort of pervert hotel.
Huh.
The kid told me, he films people doing whatnot...
and sends it to his bosses.
Who are his bosses?
People who own the hotel. I don't know.
Does it really matter?
Maybe.
And what, he just offered this up to you, did he? Hmm?
I think he was trying to confess.
Oh.
I think it's been weighing on him.
I think he's trying to confess right now...
because he knows how this is gonna go...
and he fears for his soul.
Hey, buddy. Uh...
Listen, if you're so worried about your soul...
maybe you shouldn't have been doing
all this bad shit in the first place.
Is that who I think it is?
I wanna see.
Now, wait a second.
What's a man of God like yourself
doing with this in his coat?
It's just people fuckin'.
No. You take a closer look, Rose.
Wait, I know him.
Uh-huh.
He's dead.
That he is.
All right.
Where's the money come from?
Well, that money...
I ain't asking you right now, Father.
Ms. Darlene Sweet, where's the money come from, hmm?
It's mine.
It's yours?
Really?
Where's a girl like you
get all this kind of money from, huh?
I earned it.
Singing.
Well, you must be one hell of a singer then.
I am.
All right, your turn.
Where's the money from? Hmm?
She's telling you the truth.
That's her money, she earned it singing.
Yeah, and you're a man of the cloth, huh?
I am.
You know, I forgot to mention...
I hate priests.
You wanna change your story?
Nope.
Alrighty then.
Boots, why don't you find something
to listen to on that there jukebox?
It's too quiet in here, don't you think? Huh?
Gives me the willies.
Who is this?
Um...
It's Deep Purple, I think.
Uh...
It's not for me.
Now, I want you two to pay
real close attention to what happens next, okay?
And keep it right up there in the front of your minds...
when I'm asking questions
looking for truthful answers, okay?
All right.
Emily.
Pick a color.
Red or black?
No.
No?
Well, that's just not hardly nice.
I'm offering you a chance here, right?
On account of the fact that
we're practically family, all right?
And that's downright
charitable of me, considering...
Boots, you hearing what your sister's doing?
Em, if Billy Lee is offering you a chance,
I think you should take it.
Did you think you could just take what's mine,
and I wouldn't come a-huntin'?
She ain't yours.
Rosie, are you mine?
Of course.
There was no violence till you.
Yeah, maybe.
Maybe not.
But it's there now, isn't it?
Pick a color, Em. I ain't asking again.
Pick a color.
Red.
I guess that makes you black, altar boy.
What? No, no, no.
Come here. You got some prayers, you can say 'em now.
Forgive me, Father, for I have sinned.
I have done so much worse than you know.
Kid...
Father Flynn, I have sinned and I repent.
Forgive me, Father.
I have sinned and I...
Father Flynn, please!
Do you want to tell him or you want me to do it?
I have sinned and I repent!
Miles...
Please!
Forgive me, Father!
He's not a fucking priest, kid!
Well, it looks like the Lord hasn't forsaken you yet.
No!
Now then, who wants to play next?
Ah, whoa, Wade, Annabell...
keep a close eye there.
See, everyone's liable to get a little more squirrelly
now they know the stakes.
You two gonna be more forthcoming?
Sure.
Could I have some of that whiskey?
Yeah, sure. Why not?
Boots, can you pour the padre a glass, please?
I can't do it anymore.
I can't...
Hey, kid...
if you don't shut the fuck up,
I'm gonna make you play the game again.
So, let's try this again.
Where's the money from?
I stole it...
about a decade ago.
I hid it here, did some time...
got out a few days ago...
came back tonight to retrieve it.
Why you dressed up like a priest, then?
Didn't want too many questions.
People tend to look the other way
when you're wearin' a collar.
And you?
Um...
I'm just a singer.
The money happened to be hidden in my room.
He said he would split it...
if I could help him get it back.
Of course he did. Of course he did.
Yeah, yeah.
'Cause that ain't even the real score,
is it, padre, huh?
'Cause you found this.
I bet you he didn't even tell you about this, did he?
Huh? Don't you even wanna see who's in it?
No.
It doesn't matter.
Oh, no. Then, darlin',
you ain't understanding what's on this film.
Let me guess.
Um...
It's some man...
who talks...
a lot.
He talks so much
that he thinks he believes in something.
And really just...
wants to fuck who he wants to fuck.
I've seen it enough.
I'm not even mad about it anymore.
I'm just...
tired.
I'm just bored.
Of men like you.
You think I don't see you for who you really are?
A fragile little man.
Preying on the weak and lost.
Yeah, well, if I...
I've heard it.
And I don't care.
I'd rather sit here and listen to the rain.
You go right ahead.
Why didn't you just leave
when you had the film?
It's worth way more than some bag of money.
I did time for that money.
My brother, he died for that money. That money's mine.
That money's ours.
Why is that film worth so much anyway?
Guy's dead. Who cares?
Well, Boots...
sometimes the memory of a man
matters more than the man himself.
Ain't that right, padre?
Yeah, if you say so.
Who's gonna come looking for their money?
Nobody.
Somebody's always looking for money!
No, they're all gone. Except me.
And who are you exactly?
Let's just say I wanna check this story out.
What's your real name, Father?
It's, uh...
Did I tell you my real name?
You never did. No.
Oh, really?
Now you wanna
Start playing games again?
He can't remember.
His mind's not all there.
That's what he told you?
He did.
And you believe anything this old crook says?
I believe that much. Yeah.
All right, all right.
Let's see if we can't jog his memory, huh, Darlene?
Pick a color.
Now it's quiet again.
I don't like it.
No, I don't like it either.
Hey, ain't you supposed to be a singer? Huh?
Why don't you sing something for us, Darlene.
No, thank you.
Hell, I'll tell you what.
If you sing something for us
and if you're as good as you say you are...
I won't make you play the game.
Don't do it.
He's gonna do what he's gonna do,
but he don't deserve to hear you sing.
Suit your fucking selves!
Wait...
I've heard better.
No! You'll hit Billy Lee!
No, I can't do it.
I can't do it no more.
- I can't. I can't do it. - Miles.
I can't kill no more people.
Miles!
Help us.
I can't kill no more people.
How many people have you killed, Miles?
123.
My heavens, Ginger! Look what your boy can do.
Miller! Why the fuck have you stopped shooting?
Miles.
I can't do it.
I can't kill no more people.
Miles...
It's all right.
You don't have to kill any more people.
Motherfucker!
Let's see if you can't remember this.
Easy there, altar boy...
Take the gun.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
No!
Help him.
I can't.
No, God. No, God, please.
Help him.
Please, God.
I don't wanna...
Confess.
My son, confess.
You're not a...
You're not a priest.
Of course I am.
Miles Miller, my name is Father Daniel Flynn...
and I'm here to absolve you of your sins.
Bless me, Father, for I have sinned.
Yes.
I've sinned.
I've sinned more times than I can count.
I've killed.
I've killed so many people.
I'm so sorry, Father.
It's all right.
No, it's not.
I did so much bad.
I lied. I stole.
I hurt people.
I did it all even though I know it was wrong.
I'm so sorry, Father.
Do you seek absolution for your sins?
Yes, I do.
Do you give yourself to the mercy of the Lord?
Yes.
Will you give to Him the time that you have left?
I'm too late.
No.
It's never too late.
Yes. I will try.
I'll try to be better.
I'll try to be a better man.
I repent.
Father Flynn, I repent.
You are forgiven.
Miles Miller.
In the name of the Father,
the Son, and the Holy Spirit...
you are forgiven.
Good luck, everyone.
And 47.
Now, we have got a special treat for you tonight.
Coming to you all the way
from beautiful Los Angeles, California...
Ladies and gentlemen, let's give a warm Reno welcome
to Darlene Sweet.
Thank y'all for coming to listen to me tonight.
It means a lot to me.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
That's very kind of you. Thank you.
God, come on in. There's enough room for everyone.
Come on in.
Now, if it's all right with you...
we'd like to do a few more for you now.