Wat do you got there ?
God !
Baxter ?
Ah !
He got our dog.
He got Baxter.
Shut up, Norman.
Baxter's fertilizer.
En everyone's just
standing there like... staring.
Why they'd just catch that thing ?
How hard could it be in
a place for dead ends ?
Fuck !
Wrists are for girls...
I'm slitting my throat.
You should definatly hang.
Maybe even your final
moment's a cliche around here.
Not ours. Bee ours are rock.
You don't think our death should be
a little more than a scheap entertainment?
You jazzed me on this.
Don't wuss out now.
It's the idea of everyone
staring at me just lying there.
I mean, what if they just... laugh?
Don't be (???).
Bee, suicide is like
the ultimate "fuck you"
Come on it's so "us".
It's the pact.
See, it's easyer for you. You don't care.
We swore we'd go
together, one way or another.
When we were eight.
- So ?
Out by sixteen or dead in
this scene but together forever.
Together forever.
United against life as we know it.
Our deaths will be the shit Bee.
Trust me!
To much blood...
...and I can see your gonch!
- Just do it.
Please bury me in this dress. Thanks.
I was completly disturbing, wasn't I ?
You now, the Fitzgerald sisters
clearly worked very...
God !
I mean...
I am completely sicken.
Sicken... by that, wasn't I ?
Look, see me at the guidance office,
after class. You tow, separately.
Can we see the ones
with Ginger again ?
No !
Hey...
'Life in Bailey Downs'.
Who's next ?
Oh yes ladies run. Run for daddy!
Bounce.
Those she's good to go.
You wanna do a Fitzgerald ?
- You're kidding ?
Not the little twig (???)...
...the one with the rack !
The red head.
I think McCardy just checked me.
Like you care, right ?
High school is just
a mindless breeders machine.
Total hormonal toilet.
I'd rather wait it all out in our room.
Wat is with your back?
- I don't now.
'Search and Destroy'
Okay. Trina Sinclair ?
Excellent selection. Continue.
Trina Sinclair, D.O.A. at the hair dye aisle.
Perished while seeking matching
barrettes on nothing but diet pills and laxatives.
...likes her shorts stuck up her ass crack.
Favourite homework excuse:
my nail glitter ate it.
Basic pleasure model.
- Your standard, cumbuckety date bait.
Good one.
Line change. Lest go, girls.
- Fucking Bitches !
Oh. Oh.
Lets do this again.
I'll cover you.
Good.
Bounce, baby. Bounce!
Keep running.
You want me baby.
C'mon, honey!
Oh yeah, baby!
You want me baby.
- Fuck off!
'The Beast of Bailey Downs'
strikes again.
That's four dogs this week.
Oh! Whow... Bonus!
I guess you D.O.A. on a dog. Completly.
That's enough.
Are you OK ?
Terrific.
- That is one mother fucking mad dog.
Brigitte, go get cleaned out.
Don't ever touch my sister again.
Stop me. Freak.
Enough ! Break it up !
Hey, that janitor is loking
right down your shirt.
Sure.
Want me to kill her ?
I kill her for you Bee.
Whatever.
No, not whatever.
This isn't wathever.
Seriously whatabout torture ?
Anything you want.
or...
She has that dog.
We could kidnap it, make it look like he
got eaten by 'The Beast of Bailey Downs'
We got all that blood en fake guts
from the slide show.
Let's do it.
She screws a drug dealer.
she's begging for negative attention.
So, Sam are you...are you gonna call me?
Okay you have my number right?
Remember when I gave it to you ?
Sam.
Ok, bye...
Let's go.
Such a dickhead.
See...
You let idiots get
away with fucking you up.
That's why the big Buddha made me...
...to stop them.
Yeah so far you 're really
kicking ass.
Just give me one clean shot.
Just one, I fucking promise you.
Don't humor me!
- So Fitz...
I think we should get together.
Ehm...
No.
Bitch!
Jump, Norman. Come on.
Bee...
Just say you won't go average on me.
Just cause some gonad gets
his zipper going?
I'd rather be dead.
Rather die than be here without you.
- Relax, you know I (???)
Ginger, don't push your sister.
God, I hate our gene pool.
Look, girls.
Come on. Let go. Let go. You're ruin it !
Ginger why are you rubbing your back ?
It hurts.
- Why ?
Well, pain flows up your nerve
endings to the synapses in your brain...
She is not funny.
How did you hurt it ?
- Being dead.
Does it hurt down by
your tailbone or is it up higher ?
Is it tied through out here ?
- Maybe.
Does it ache back here ?
Mayb...
- Oh my god.
Do you think it's cramps ?
Give it a rest... for two seconds ?
Pam, we're eating.
Henry, the girls are both three years
late menstruating. Okay ?
It's not normal if it's (???) happening...
- It's not.
Honey, it's nothing to be scared off.
It's the most normal thing in the world.
Maybe it's cancer of the spine.
- Ginger...
Or tuberculosis.
See what your attitude does.
- Or spondylitis.
Spondo... what ?
- Fuses your vertebra together.
Nice.
- Brigitte stop it.
Have a fit !
I've had just about enough of that tone.
That makes two of us. Fuck !
- That's it to your room.
Gladly.
Brigitte you're not connected at her waist.
Your father and I have councilling tonight.
I don't want you leaving the house.
The news says there's still
some wild animal on the loose.
They never go out.
Well, you're a big help.
As usual.
Ginger.
- What ?
We'll get caught.
- No, we won't.
The dog won't even be out.
- He has to pee some time.
People don't leave
their dogs out alone anymore.
Then you'll just have to distract her
while I nab the pooch and make with the gore.
I can't distract her.
- The fuck, Bee. This is your idea.
If you don't like
your ideas, stop having them.
Sorry.
- I just (???)
Check it out.
Now we can even leave a body.
She'll freak.
Oh, wicked.
Teake his...
...leg ?
He's still warm.
Oh gross.
Shit !
Leave it then. (???).
You got some on you.
Nice.
What ?
Bee...
I just got the curse.
Ehw.
Well, it's not contagious !
I know that.
God !
I mean, kill yourself to be different
and your own body screws you.
But if I start simping
around tampon dispensers...
...moaning about PMS, shoot me ok.
Lets get out of here.
Ginger ?
Ginger !
Aaah !
Oh God. He's still right there.
Oh, my God !
Ginger !
Get up. Come on, get up !
Oh, fuck me !
Shit !
Mom !
Dad ! Help !
Let me see.
No, it hurts, it burns...
- I got to see it Ginger.
What was it ? What was it ?
- I don't know. A big dog maybe.
What's wrong ?
What did I do ?
Shut.
I saw this thing once...
(???)
It wasn't a fucking bear !
It wasn't any fucking bear !
There isn't anywhere here.
Does it hurt ?
- No.
That's impossible.
They 're already healing.
No, this isn't right.  I'm calling 911.
- No ! No !
Bee, I'm not bleeding anymore. Right ?
I mean... just...
...spare me Pam finding out.
Okay ? I'm okay, Okay ?
Okay.
- I'm okay.
I though you're gonna die.
Preying upon normal healthy cells...
the intruder gradually devours
the host from within...
Eventually the invader consumes
its host completely...
...and finally destroys it.
Complete myosis involves
two successives divisions sequences...
...which results in four new
cells, each of which is...
This one comes with a free calendar.
Are you sure it's just cramps ?
Just so you know...
...the words ' just ' and
' cramps ' tey don't go together.
Ok, you realy (???)
One day, you too will know my pain.
Hey, diss me or whatever
but, I got three sisters...
...and nothing quite takes
the edge off like a good toke.
Well, maybe I like my edge...Thanks.
Or maybe you're just chicken to lose it.
Pass the fag.
That's a girl.
-Yeah.
An eighth's fifty.
I don't want any drugs.
- Then amscray.
I was just wondering
what you hit.
Well, officer, looked like
a lycanthrope to me, sir.
I know what a lycanthrope is.
- Sure you do.
Think you see werewolves a lot ?
Why, do you ?
Is it working ?
No ...and now I just don't care.
What the hell are you guys doing in here ?
Sam, the Man.
Sam, man, we just needed
a place to come and smoke.
Hey, you know, I have an idea.
Why don't you guys get
the fuck outta my van, assholes !
No I'm serius. Get out !
Samuel, what happened in your truck ?
- I (???) a tree, all right. Good bye.
Ginge, lets go.
Yeh, why don't you
stick to your own species Fitzenstien ?
Trina, stick my (???)
Oh you bitch !
Okay, baby.
Ging, what's going on ?
Something's wrong.
Like more than you being just...
...female.
Can you just say something please ?
Woah !
Woah ? That's it ? 'Woah' ?
I can't have a hairy chest, Bee.
That's fucked !
No way.
The fuck ? What the fuck ?
This isn't...
- What ?
No way, like...
Bitten on a full moon.
Now you're hairy ?
I know, but think about it.
Well thank you for taking my
total fucking nightmare so seriously !
Oh shit !
What if I'm dying or something ?
We gotta see the nurse.
I'm sure it seems like a
lot of blood. It's a period.
But (???) it was like...
Geyser.
Everyone seems to panic their first time.
Neither of you have had
a period before and you're how old ?
I'm almost sixteen, she just
turned fifteen. She skipped a grade.
A thick, syrupy, voluminous
discharge is not uncommon.
The bulk of the uterine lining is
shed within the first few days.
Contractions, cramps,
squeeze it out like a pump.
In three to five days you'll
find lighter, bright-red bleeding.
That may turn to a brownish or blackish
sludge, which signals the end of the flow.
OK, so it's all normal ?
- Very !
Expected every twenty-eight days,
give or take, for the next thirty years.
Great. Thanks.
What about hair that
wasn't there before, and pain ?
Uhuh, comes with the territory.
Thank you. Lets go Bee.
Wait, you'll have to protect
against both pregnancy and STDs now...
Play safe !
Wish this where baby's legs.
Ginger's very favorite.
Congratulations sweetie.
You know you can ask me anything.
You're so dead.
I didn't.
Our little girl's a young woman now.
I'd never tell her anything.
- Unless you wanted to piss me off !
I want you to be okay.
- I am, I just got my period...ok ?
Now, I've got weird hairs, so what ?
That means I've got hormones...
...and they may make me butt-ugly,
but they do not make me a monster.
So you got bit by a great big hormone.
Well not by what you think.
They don't exist !
Norman shut the fuck up !
Maybe he's barking at you.
Did I change last night ?
Howl at the moon, kill shit and
change back this morning ? Huh... No !
Did it take a silver bullet
to stop that thing ? No !
It got killed
by a fucking truck.
You always blow off anything you don't get.
- Yeah, when it's bullshit !
You're doing drugs with guys.
Something is definitely wrong with you.
You know, maybe you're right.
Maybe I do see a monster.
Yeah, it's got these little green eyes.
Oh yeah, like I really wish I was haemorrhaging
and hairy and sucking off jason McCarty.
Well you always wanted to be me !
- Well this isn't you, so.
Oh, poor Bee. I'm growing up
and obviously you're not, huh ?
Well don't let me hold you back or anything.
- Oh well don't worry, I won't.
Only one creature on earth destroys
for pure plesure. It's a weerwolf.
Oh my god, here it is.
He's hideous !
Get the fuck outta the bathroom !
I'm trying to get ready !
Ginger ? Oh my god.
Oh babe...
Sheck it out.
Hello, hello, hello...
Hey !
Kid, you got a smoke ?
No.
You got a light then?
Oh, thank you.
I just spent a week of my life
looking for you. Give me a sec.
You dropped this on my truck.
Okay, we both saw it.
What the fuck was it ?
It's what you hit.
- Hum ! I know...
...but what the fuck was it ?
See, I flattened an animal.
Furry, all-fours, could be anything...
...but here I am thinking 'lycanthrope'
That's crazy, huh?
Book me in to the rubber motel,
I'm officially all fucked up, right ?
What if you're not ?
Well, that would explain
the human circumcised dick...
...and why you were
running for your life from it.
I have to go. Thanks for my stuff.
What's your name ?
Bullshit.
- Thanks.
No, hey bullshit ?
What do you say ?
Swear you won't call a freak show.
Yeah, I swear.
I'm Changing like right now and
full moons have nothing to do with it.
You're serious ?
...and everything I look it goes silver
bullet in a gun to my head, the end.
Wow.
Lets not panic here. I mean...
...for one, that thing on the road,
my van did a pretty good job on it.
What are the benefits of silver bullets ?
So, let's just forget the Hollywood rules.
It's got to be a cure right ? Otherwise,
it would be a hell of a lot more of them.
It's like an infection, it works
from the inside out. It's like a virus.
Biology, there's something
you can sink your teeth into.
So to speak.
You're real, your problem's
real, the solution's real.
(???)
The again when I  (???) , I got infections...
a girl says try pure silver...  clered up like that.
The ancients thought
pure metals purified the blood.
They thought leeches did too.
- They do.
Hey, why don't you get
your slut-bitch sister a leash ?
What a freak.
A nice bird necklace.
Ginger, a word ?
Is it sorry ?
- No.
Come on Jason, lets go.
Oh yes.
Ginger !
Hey. She is ovulating !
- See you freak.
- Bye bye.
This is a very exciting,
confusing time for your sister.
Boys, her body,
trying to fit in.
Maybe if she found that she
could share more with you...
...you'd both be a lot happier.
You know, Brigitte,
your turn's coming too ...one day
My stomach.
Hey, take it easy, allright ?
We've got all night.
Sorry, you just taste really good.
Just lie back and relax.
- You lie back and relax !
Who's the guy here ?
Who's the guy here ? Huh ?
Who's the fucking guy here ?
Don't we need protection here ?
Stop it !
Wait a second !
You're fucking hilarious cave boy.
Ginge ?
What happened ?
Did he hurt you ?
If he hurt you, you should tell.
Oh, my god !
Get out ! Get out !
- What happened ?
Something is really... really wrong, Bee.
What happened ?
I get this ache and...
...I thought it was for sex, but it's
to tear everything into fucking peices.
Where is he ?
Next door.
Oh, my god !
You killed Norman.
He barked and he barked and
he kept fucking barking !
I just... I just...
...I couldn't stop myself.
Bee, what am I suppose to do ?
It wasn't at all like
I thought it would be...
...there was just all this
squirming and squealing...
...and than he's done and you're like 'Oh ?'
(???) telling everyone
what a freak I am.
They'll say the same thing about hem.
It doesn't work like that.
I mean, he got laid.
I'm just a lay. He's a hero and
I’m just a lay, a freak mutant lay.
Did you use something ?
No.
And you think this thing work ?
We have to try something.
Where did you get that...that ring ?
I found it.
Too bad.
You should have one too.
I mean for being with me on this.
Ready ?
Yeah.
Shit, it stuck !
Hold still.
Fuck ! Hurry up !
- Sorry, sorry
It's almost there.
How do you feel ?
Wicked.
Norman ?
Hey, Norman.
Hurry up !
Hold it still.
- I am, I hurry up.
Go ahead, baby.
Oh, McCardy what happened to you ?
- Ginger Fitzgerald rocked my world.
(???) rag, too ?
Oh, shit !
It must be ink. Fuck !
Hi !
Brigitte !
Brigitte, come here.
What the fuck, Bee ?
Do you got a boyfriend or something ?
No, we just...
I'll be right back.
Oh my god.
Hey, what's up ? Look, if silver's shot,
I've been reading and I got another idea.
Are you on drugs, like right now ?
I'm in class here.
Yeah, excuse me for giving a shit.
I'll come see you later, ok ?
- Whatever.
The Fitz sister are really (???).
Okay, line change. Lets go.
- He thinks I got bit.
I trust you and you (???) the
first fuck up who comes along.
He knows stuff, he wants to help.
He wants to get in
your pants, Stupid !
So sluts run in the family... quel shocker !
Get out !
Ginger, no !
Ginger, no ! Stop !
Fitght, fight, fight...
You started it.
- Ginger to the office.
This school has a zero
tolerance for violence policy...
...I mean a temper like that is inexcusable...
(???) substantial extenuating circumstances.
What are you looking at ? Euh ?
My pen exploded ok. My red pen.
That was fucking incredible.
Did you (???)
You gave it to Jason.
You had unprotected sex
and you infected him.
Oops !
I have to see Sam. He's got an idea.
- Oh bet he does. Well, lets go.
If you come,
you can't be weird Ginger.
If he gets I lied. If he get
you're really the one who's really...
a what ? ...a monster ?  Euh, a freak ?
If he thinks I (???)
I'll behave.
Romeo, Romeo, wherefor art thou Romeo ?
Sorry about before I was just afraid
someone would hear us, that's all.
Yeah, she is just a litlle moody lately.
That hole silver thing didn't (???)
I wasn't expecting company.
My sister Ginger. She knows.
If you two come in here, you see
sweat fuck all. Understood ?
Jesus !
Wicked ! Smoke us up !
Yeah, wicked huh ?
Get the fuck out !
Hi, Brigitte.
(???)
I compared homeopatic treatements...
...of infections to the
(???). Take a look.
Aconitum dilycotonum.
Lyko as in wholf ?
- Right.
It's called Monkshood. It's a cousin of wolfsbane
except this stuff is safe in small dosis.
It's a super oxydent (???) radical detox.
It promotes white blood (???) .
- Which fight infection. Do you have some ?
Well, it's prenennial.
It grows everywhere but only in the sping.
Fuck ! This is bullshit ok.
(???).
- She does not have time for that.
She's killed a dog already.
She's fucked.
She's going a tail.
Did you tell him that ?
- Ginger !
You growing a tail ?
Yes.
Look, he's just another wank job. Okay.
- What the fuck do you think you are ?
Wat the fuck are you ? Pervert, she's 15 !
- Ginger, wait outside !
Fine, if he rapes you,
don't come crying. I'll be at home.
She's just freacking.
I do not think of you that way.
Your dad's battery is dead again.
(???) supermarket.
Wanna go for a ride ?
- Jesus can't you knock ?
Don't you Jesus me.
You don't have anything I haven't seen before.
- That's what you think.
What is that suppose to mean ?
- Nothing, i'm just, i'm fat alright get out.
Ginger you are not fat, these
fashion models are all on speed to look like that.
Get out !
Ok. Gosh.
I'll be back soon.
Give me back my dog.
Trina I don't have your dog.
- Ginger took him. I saw her.
Now, I feel sorry for you.
He dosn't like you.
He's a cherry-hound. He's in to virgins.
Trina you're bleeding. Go home.
If you are so fucking smart,
you won't give him the satisfaction.
Somebody just once shouldn't give
that fucker the satisfaction!
Trina go now.
- You are as very cunt as your sister .
I am not.
Hi meat. Back for more?
- What are you doing?
I don't know, Bee. What am I doing?
Call Sam. Ask the Pro.
What ?
You play with your new friends
and I'll play with mine.
Ginger what the hell are you doing ?
You smell yummy. What is that?
Citrus? antiseptic? I'm not sure.
Are you crasy ?
Okay that's enough. Let her go.
- Shut up.
Ok, lets just (???).
You know what Trina? She is doing (???) .
(???)
Stop, it is not like that.
- I think she scare for you (???)
She is an asshole. She's not worth it.
- You ask for this !
You picked Sam over me.
Whatever happens now it is your fault !
This is not you. Just lets cope...
- Oh, with what ? With this kind of shit.
He's wrong (???à). You can't fix this !
You don't know that. Just give me a chance.
- What an other one ? God gee, I don't know Bee...
...see I'm going way way out there...
...way way far from (???) and
your pretty much fucking rules.
Oh god, that's disgusting you
fucking gross fucking bitch...
Back, don't touch me you freaks.
You're both just totally fucked.
Trina we were just...
Oh. Oh.
Get up.
Get up. Now.
Henry, what on earth are you doing out there ?
Com' on, don't eat it until we get inside.
Jesus Christ on a bicycle! What the...?
Girls, I told you, no more deaths in the house!
- Don't be mad, it's for extra credit.
Back to immaculate in ten minutes.
Corn syrup, daddy want some ?
I go to get this meat away.
I'll do that.
Mom.
- What ?
What do guys want ?
Brigitte, I'm so glad you asked.
That's what men want.
Some of them might seem cool or diffrent
but they are pretty much the same.
Totally.
- Thanks for sharing.
Oh, honey, that's what we're here for.
Bed time. (???).
Beauty rest.
This is just great.
Yeah, feild hockey will suck now.
Get me a screwdriver.
Oh, god !
Way to go.
Here it is: 'Why your daughter dates dummys' ?
I'm so glad I held on to this.
I think they're up to something.
- They're just being normal teenage girls.
Then why are they suddenly
so interested in what you have to say ?
Stay in your own little world, Henry.
This one just confuses you.
Shit. (???) worms.
Remember when I used to
make you eat them just to get in here ?
Shallow grave ?
... oh well, seems appropriate.
You dig for a while.
Look...
No one ever thinks chicks do shit like this.
Trust me, a girl can only be a slut...
...a bitch, a tease, or the virgin next door.
We'll just coast on how the world works.
Think she's pretty ?
If I wasn't here, would you eat her ?
No.
God, that'd be like, fucking her.
- You can't go out anymore.
Well I can't stay in, I'll go mental.
We'll make Pam think you're at school.
We'll make school think you're home sick.
Just sure there is no doubt about us in this.
Then we blow, as far away from here as possible.
Your attention. Please.
(???) immediatelly certain students
wil be (???) to the office...
...to assist the police regarding
Trina Sinclair's dissapear.
She is dead, men.
When your name is called,
please come to the office.
Is Ginger avoiding me ?
...cuz I'am feel pretty good right now.
I just got a few questions for her, like uh...
I'm growing a goddamn tail outta my ass...
...and I thought she might have a few tips
on how to deal with keeping that quiet !
Hurting me won't help.
- See? I'm up to some whack shit right now.
I'm way out on the corner of 'Fucked-Up and Evil'.
You wanna know what I did for fun last night, huh?
I killed my own freakin' dog, OK ?
What am I suppose to do about that ?
You gonna be in deep shit.
- I'm right in your deep shit...
...and I think you konw why.
What's going on here ?
Thanks.
Ginger, how was school today ?
- I don't know, I didn't go.
We had a field trip.
- Really ?
I didn't sign any form for a field trip.
Daddy, will you teatch me how to drive tonight ?
- Next year. Maybe.
So where did you go ?
What if next year never comes ?
- Ginger.
Mr. Wayne called today.
He wanted to know if you where feeling any beter.
When you might be
comming back to school.
De police wanna talk to you
something about a fight with a missing girl.
Daddy, might I be excused ?
- No, you might not.
Ginge whait.
- For what Bee ?
Oh. No, no.
I want to know what's going on. Right now.
What are these ?
- Monkshood. Brigitte...
Where did you get them ?
- From a grave store. Now, I want an answer.
Trina Sinclair tried to beat me up,
cause Jason McCardy liked us beter...
...so Ginger beat her up. That's all.
- That's all ?
Beating up other girls ? Cutting classes ?
I'm very disappointed, Brigitte.
- Sorry.
You just do whatever she wants you to.
You always have.
I really wish you'd start thinking more for yourself.
Do you think I should talk to her ?
Check in ?
She thinks it's cool you let us
figure stuff out for herselfs.
Oh ?
Really ?
I wandered if that (???).
Look what Pamela had.
What are you doing ? Stop !
- I'll just take it off.
No !
I killed their pets Bee, and nothing helps
except tearing life things to pieces.
I can't be like this.
This is monkshood. First thing tomorrow
we find out how we use it and we take off.
You give up now and leave me here
alone, I would never do that to you!
I 'm sorry. I 'm just scared.
BCX radio wish you a happy hallowe'en...
Bee, what the fuck are you doing ?
Hey... Bee, let me out !
I have to deal with the cure. This way,
you can't hurt yourself or anybody else.
Fuck you. You fucking sissy little girl.
You're going let me out ?
Just shut up and wait for me.
(???) little bitch ! Fuck you !
Bee let me out. Come on.
Bee ?
Bee !
Let me out !
Holly shit, that's monshood.
How the fuck did you get that ?
I don't know if you smoke it or eat it
or what but I need to try it now.
Well, you got me but...
...to be sure, I 'ld have to say direct road. Inject it.
But see, that's a bad idea Brigitte, because
neither of us know what this stuff does.
It can't be worst than being road killed.
The dose should be a guess. I mean...
It have to be, there is no way to match for
metabolism, bodyweight it could be side effects.
You can not try this alone.
- My sister will be there.
Understand you may kill her trying to save her.
What ?
It's for Ginger, isn't it?
Look, worst-case scenario,
you put her out of her misery.
Just as long as you're prepared
for that, and I mean sure.
Try to come to that.
Hey, have you seen Jason ?
Umm... you got a little...
You 're going to
the greenhouse bash tonight ?
Ehm, yeah.
-Good.
I'm in charge of the prizes.
You, too, could be winner.
Ginger. My office. Now.
Help ! Help !
Let me go.
Let him go, McCardy.
Oh yeah, a chick. Excellent.
Come to pap baby.
Come and get some candy.
I have to go.
I've a class.
Attention please...
...Brigitte Fitzgerald please report to guidance...
...Brigitte Fitzerald to guidance.
He wanted to call fucking Pamela,
Bee and tell her we needed help.
So, I stop him. You see how that works ?
How I would not betray you ?
I didn't betray you.
You locked me up.
You need to get this fixed.
Why ? So I can go to the jail,
for the rest of my life ?
We wait till everyone leaves.
...dan we'll clean this up, some how.
I think you've fucked up enough.
Oh my god !
Henry ?
- Oh god...
What is it ?
Henry, (???)
It's only girl's death project.
Tey are fake, you big baby.
I'm gonna find something to clean this up.
Stay here and lock the door.
Oh my god !
Hello, Birgitte.
Stop it !
- Can I touch your boobies ?
I like little girls.
Leave him alone !
Ginger. Stop ! Stop !
Ginger, fucking stop !
Please stop !
Ginger stop ! He hasn't done anyting !
I don't like how he looks at you.
Oh my god !
He found me. Brigitte...
...the mess I had to.
- Go to hell.
He's not dead, and you infected him.
Let me call help for him.
Oh fuck !
Fuck !
You like it.
It feels so... good, Brigitte.
Its like touching yourself.
You know every move...
right on the fucking dot.
And after...
... you see fucking fireworks, supernovas.
I'm a goddamn force of nature.
I feel like I could do
just about anything.
You know we're almost not
even related anymore.
You're fucked !
You love it. Should come for the ride.
A little scratch. Swap some juice.
We'll be our own pack, like before.
It's so 'us' Bee.
I'd rather be dead than be what you are.
We have a pact !
Out by sixteen or dead on the
scene, but together for fucking ever !
I said I would die for you!
No. You said you'd die with me.
Cause you had nothing better to do.
Fuck you too.
You think I wanna go back to being nobody ?
You're fucked !
Go the hell out of my way, Brigitte.
And I tell Sam you said Hi.
Stop ! Stop !
Where is your sister ?
In coutry greenhouse.
Get in the van.
All right, Fitz. Wicked, kostum baby.
Where is Sam ?
Shit !
Hey.
Hey Ginger, where is Brigitte ?
- She couldn't make it.
Yeah why is that ?
- Cramps.
She says Hi.
You wanna buy or something ?
Or something.
Go get your sister.
- Mom, I don't think...
You've done a terrible thing.
But...
...you're my tiny babys.
As one thing if you leave, it's almost normal
but no one is gonna take you from me.
First thing tomorrow I'll let the house
fill up with gas, and light a match.
What ?
We start fresh.
Just us girls. It will be fun.
What about dad ?
He'll just blame me,
tey all will.
This isn't your fault, mom.
Yes it is.
Lock the doors. Okay.
Ginger, come on.
- No, you come on.
What are you doing ?
- I know you want too. Everybody does.
Really. What have you like ?
What would I do ?
What would I feel like inside ?
- Ginger, stop.
Take me.
- Ginger, your sister...
This is fucked !
Ginger, get out from me.
Jerk !
What ? I told you to stop.
God, Ginger get up. I'm sorry.
Get up, Ginger.
You bitch. You want me ? You want me ?
Stop hurting everybody else and take me !
I don't want you ! I don't even know you !
Brigitte don't.
Brigitte don't !
You wrecked everything for me
that isn't about you.
No. Shit.
Now I am you.
I know you are. But what am I ?
We got to go.
Bee I can't.
I'm turning too fast.
What the hell did you do that for ?
- I won't let you do this Brigitte.
You both need help.
You fucking idiot.
The cure works. I had to use it on
somebody else but there is more at the house.
This is the only way I could
get her to come back with me.
Oh shit !
What ? How I'm supposed to know that ?
Just help me. OK ?
Just get her in your truck and drive us home.
Fine, she rides in the back.
This is nuts, you need a doctor.
Oh !
Jesus.
She could have killed you Brigitte.
She needs me.
Get home. Cure her, cure me.
And then ?
Run.
You know you're kidding yourself.
I'll be right back. Give me the syringe.
Dad ? Hello ?
Oh shit !
I had to fix that.
Did she get out ?
- Oh god, I hope not.
I can't see anything.
(???) me that flashlight.
Fuck !
It was your god damn sister !
Oh fuck !
The monkshood is in there.
Oh, you're out of your mind.
Not yet.
Be quiet. I gotta get this stuff.
Great.
Fuck ! Where the fuck is she ?
Shut.
Lets do this fast.
- Oh yes.
Allright, golds.
Alcohol.
Brigitte...
...have you a lighter ?
- I can't feel my hand.
Jesus Christ.
Oh fuck !
Go ! Go !
Alcohol.
- What ?
Oh shit. Yeah.
Start (???) up the buds.
Put in.
Easy, easy, easy...
What was that ?
Shit keep going. Go, go...
I handle this.
Great, that's real fucking hygienic.
- I doubt it matters.
How about you take this and we blow ?
How about No ?
Then let me do it, you can hardly move.
No !
You can't do this by yourself.
Let me take the needle,
I'll go into the livingroom...
...you lead her in bam we're done.
Okay.
I'm going.
- Be careful.
Sam ?
Ginger ?
I can't.
I won't.
Fuck !
Fuck off !
Let me alone !
Ginger ?
Come on. It's me.
Okay ?
Ginger, please it's me !
You want this ?
I'm not dying in this room with you !
I'm not dying !
English subtitel: Yaza.