1
00:00:45,128 --> 00:00:46,129
The Vampire and Lycan...

2
00:00:46,296 --> 00:00:47,422
...clans had been at war...

3
00:00:47,714 --> 00:00:49,258
...for centuries before I was born...

4
00:00:51,218 --> 00:00:51,927
...their conflict...

5
00:00:52,135 --> 00:00:52,803
...hidden from...

6
00:00:53,011 --> 00:00:53,679
...the human world.

7
00:00:55,806 --> 00:00:56,557
I was turned...

8
00:00:56,723 --> 00:00:57,641
...by a Vampire.

9
00:01:01,436 --> 00:01:02,104
Given the strength...

10
00:01:02,271 --> 00:01:02,938
...to avenge...

11
00:01:03,105 --> 00:01:03,772
...my family...

12
00:01:03,939 --> 00:01:04,648
...against the Lycans.

13
00:01:11,446 --> 00:01:12,781
And I was good at it.

14
00:01:21,665 --> 00:01:23,625
Then I found Michael Corvin...

15
00:01:26,962 --> 00:01:27,838
...a human that was...

16
00:01:28,005 --> 00:01:29,464
...turned to neither Vampire...

17
00:01:29,631 --> 00:01:30,340
...nor Lycan...

18
00:01:32,092 --> 00:01:32,759
...but a hybrid...

19
00:01:32,926 --> 00:01:34,136
...of the two.

20
00:01:34,303 --> 00:01:35,262
Everything changed.

21
00:01:38,640 --> 00:01:39,516
Allies turned...

22
00:01:39,683 --> 00:01:40,517
...enemies...

23
00:01:40,809 --> 00:01:42,394
...and the Vampire elders I had...

24
00:01:42,561 --> 00:01:44,354
...protected for over six centuries...

25
00:01:45,314 --> 00:01:45,981
...wanted me dead.

26
00:01:48,317 --> 00:01:49,610
We retaliated...

27
00:01:51,820 --> 00:01:52,946
...killed the elders...

28
00:01:54,364 --> 00:01:55,324
...and for a moment of time...

29
00:01:56,366 --> 00:01:57,159
...we were safe.

30
00:02:01,955 --> 00:02:02,789
But then...

31
00:02:04,124 --> 00:02:05,918
...a new darkness arose.

32
00:02:08,170 --> 00:02:08,921
In the nine days...

33
00:02:09,129 --> 00:02:11,840
...since the first discovery
of the non-human species...

34
00:02:12,007 --> 00:02:14,051
...scores of so-called "covens"
have been uncovered.

35
00:02:15,219 --> 00:02:17,638
Estimates of the number
of infected have skyrocketed.

36
00:02:17,930 --> 00:02:18,847
Military sources confirm...

37
00:02:19,806 --> 00:02:20,516
...that the primary measures...

38
00:02:20,682 --> 00:02:23,101
...of defence
against the non-humans are...

39
00:02:23,268 --> 00:02:24,978
...ultraviolet light and silver...

40
00:02:25,145 --> 00:02:28,065
...to which the infected
appear to have fatal sensitivity.

41
00:02:28,732 --> 00:02:31,318
Tents are posted at every
barricade throughout the city.

42
00:02:32,778 --> 00:02:33,820
A test will be administered...

43
00:02:33,987 --> 00:02:34,655
...to verify...

44
00:02:34,821 --> 00:02:36,281
...if you're clear of infection.

45
00:02:36,740 --> 00:02:37,908
Spray her!

46
00:02:38,075 --> 00:02:38,909
Spray her with silver!

47
00:02:42,621 --> 00:02:44,665
- Get it out here!
- Help! Run!

48
00:02:44,873 --> 00:02:45,624
No, no! Run!

49
00:02:52,673 --> 00:02:54,383
We've begun our second
attack wave...

50
00:02:54,591 --> 00:02:55,717
...using ultraviolet...

51
00:02:55,884 --> 00:02:56,718
...and silver-nitrate...

52
00:02:56,885 --> 00:02:58,095
...munitions, which are...

53
00:02:58,262 --> 00:02:59,471
...deadly to the infected.

54
00:02:59,638 --> 00:03:00,764
Due to the volatile...

55
00:03:00,931 --> 00:03:01,723
...situation...

56
00:03:01,890 --> 00:03:04,852
...martial law was declared
two hours ago.

57
00:03:08,021 --> 00:03:08,897
Many of us have...

58
00:03:09,064 --> 00:03:10,732
...lost loved ones to this.

59
00:03:15,070 --> 00:03:18,949
Please know that you cannot
help them or yourself.

60
00:03:19,408 --> 00:03:20,158
It's shocking...

61
00:03:20,325 --> 00:03:21,159
...that not one...

62
00:03:21,326 --> 00:03:22,244
...but two distinct...

63
00:03:22,411 --> 00:03:25,372
...species may have been
coexisting within human populations.

64
00:03:26,540 --> 00:03:28,584
The existence
of Vampires and Werewolves...

65
00:03:29,001 --> 00:03:31,253
...now appear to have
actual basis in fact.

66
00:03:31,920 --> 00:03:33,922
The city remains reluctant
to share new...

67
00:03:34,089 --> 00:03:34,882
...information.

68
00:03:35,382 --> 00:03:38,343
We are getting reports on what
appears to be a mass cleansing.

69
00:03:38,510 --> 00:03:39,595
Fire!

70
00:03:41,513 --> 00:03:42,556
Get back! No cameras!

71
00:03:43,432 --> 00:03:45,267
There's no cure.

72
00:03:50,439 --> 00:03:51,690
There it is!

73
00:03:52,441 --> 00:03:53,192
Engage contact!

74
00:03:53,817 --> 00:03:54,484
Man down!

75
00:03:54,651 --> 00:03:55,819
- Man down!
- Cover me!

76
00:04:31,313 --> 00:04:32,648
The Purge.

77
00:04:33,148 --> 00:04:36,109
Human beings no longer
kill each other.

78
00:04:37,319 --> 00:04:40,113
We are the enemy
they've been waiting for.

79
00:04:41,615 --> 00:04:44,826
Escape has become
our only chance of survival.

80
00:04:46,245 --> 00:04:46,954
Therefore...

81
00:04:47,120 --> 00:04:49,498
...Michael and I are leaving tonight.

82
00:04:53,836 --> 00:04:54,503
Halt!

83
00:04:59,007 --> 00:04:59,883
Delta 6 in pursuit!

84
00:05:29,371 --> 00:05:31,248
Stop! Get down on the ground!

85
00:06:04,489 --> 00:06:05,699
She'll be here any minute.

86
00:06:05,866 --> 00:06:07,534
- You be ready to go.
- Better hurry.

87
00:06:11,914 --> 00:06:14,041
Tango Unit moving into position.

88
00:06:16,710 --> 00:06:18,045
We have the hybrid in sight.

89
00:06:18,212 --> 00:06:20,255
Hold your fire. Leave this one alive.

90
00:06:26,220 --> 00:06:27,596
Delta in position.

91
00:06:27,763 --> 00:06:28,722
- Watch your flank.
- Secure.

92
00:06:28,889 --> 00:06:29,681
Move, move, move!

93
00:06:30,015 --> 00:06:32,017
Alpha Unit in position.

94
00:06:36,230 --> 00:06:37,439
Arming silver grenade!

95
00:06:39,566 --> 00:06:40,442
Michael!

96
00:06:40,859 --> 00:06:41,860
Fire!

97
00:06:53,789 --> 00:06:55,082
- Move in!
- Alpha 4, move in.

98
00:06:56,250 --> 00:06:57,751
Grenades, fire!

99
00:07:38,500 --> 00:07:40,127
Retrieve the bodies.

100
00:07:58,520 --> 00:08:02,441
Subject 2 has escaped.
Security units on alert.

101
00:08:02,608 --> 00:08:04,401
Subject 2 has escaped.

102
00:08:04,568 --> 00:08:06,486
Security units on alert.

103
00:08:07,404 --> 00:08:10,574
Subject 2 has escaped.
Security units on alert.

104
00:08:10,866 --> 00:08:14,620
Subject 2 has escaped.
Security units on alert.

105
00:08:15,245 --> 00:08:16,997
Subject 2 has escaped.

106
00:08:17,164 --> 00:08:18,874
Security units on alert.

107
00:08:19,041 --> 00:08:20,042
Subject 2...

108
00:08:20,250 --> 00:08:22,336
...has escaped.
Security units on alert.

109
00:08:23,629 --> 00:08:25,547
Defrost sequence initiated.

110
00:08:25,714 --> 00:08:26,757
Lowering compression...

111
00:08:26,924 --> 00:08:28,342
...in Subject 1 cryo-chamber.

112
00:08:34,306 --> 00:08:35,057
Look out!

113
00:08:35,265 --> 00:08:36,225
Defrost sequence...

114
00:08:36,391 --> 00:08:37,643
...complete.

115
00:08:37,809 --> 00:08:39,853
- Subject 2! Get it!
- Over there...

116
00:08:40,020 --> 00:08:42,272
...by the chamber!
Don't let it get away!

117
00:09:42,666 --> 00:09:44,710
Security violation, Level 6.

118
00:09:44,877 --> 00:09:47,212
All containment personnel to Level 6.

119
00:10:07,441 --> 00:10:08,442
Jacob.

120
00:10:08,609 --> 00:10:10,611
Subject 2 escaped,
it's in the building.

121
00:10:13,697 --> 00:10:15,782
We've got Subject 1
in full lockdown.

122
00:10:16,742 --> 00:10:19,119
- Give me the status.
- Subject 1 has broken free.

123
00:10:19,286 --> 00:10:22,748
- We need to flash-burn immediately.
- No, wait. Let me see.

124
00:10:23,415 --> 00:10:24,750
Open it.

125
00:10:34,176 --> 00:10:36,220
Put it back to sleep.

126
00:10:38,680 --> 00:10:39,890
Hurry.

127
00:10:42,476 --> 00:10:43,393
Releasing...

128
00:10:43,560 --> 00:10:45,479
...maximum dose of fentanyl.

129
00:11:07,376 --> 00:11:08,877
What is this place?

130
00:11:10,712 --> 00:11:11,547
Where's Michael?

131
00:11:15,968 --> 00:11:17,302
No, no, no. No, no, no.

132
00:11:33,318 --> 00:11:35,237
All non-security personnel...

133
00:11:35,404 --> 00:11:36,572
...clear the building!

134
00:11:36,738 --> 00:11:38,615
Security command, outside now!

135
00:11:43,745 --> 00:11:45,539
- There she is!
- Stop!

136
00:11:45,706 --> 00:11:47,040
Don't move!

137
00:11:58,260 --> 00:12:01,054
Multiple casualties on Level 6!
Medical to alert status!

138
00:12:01,221 --> 00:12:02,097
Prepare for full...

139
00:12:02,264 --> 00:12:04,099
...containment on Level 6!

140
00:12:04,600 --> 00:12:06,018
I repeat, full containment...

141
00:12:06,185 --> 00:12:07,436
...on Level 6!

142
00:12:27,623 --> 00:12:28,457
I see her.

143
00:12:28,624 --> 00:12:29,458
East corridor. Send security.

144
00:12:29,625 --> 00:12:30,667
No. Let her go.

145
00:12:30,834 --> 00:12:31,627
She'll lead us...

146
00:12:31,793 --> 00:12:32,586
...to Subject 2.

147
00:12:32,753 --> 00:12:33,795
No, don't shoot!

148
00:12:35,005 --> 00:12:35,672
Let her go.

149
00:13:05,827 --> 00:13:06,995
Attention, all units.

150
00:13:07,162 --> 00:13:09,998
Subject 1 and Subject 2
have escaped the perimeter...

151
00:13:10,165 --> 00:13:12,835
...and are no longer
under Antigen control.

152
00:13:13,001 --> 00:13:16,755
Secure the outer gates and use
extreme caution upon encounter.

153
00:13:16,922 --> 00:13:20,300
Report immediately upon
coming into contact...

154
00:14:56,438 --> 00:14:58,315
Hey, how did you get in there?

155
00:14:58,941 --> 00:15:00,734
You're not allowed in here.

156
00:15:01,610 --> 00:15:03,028
The pier is closed.

157
00:15:03,654 --> 00:15:04,947
Since when?

158
00:15:05,531 --> 00:15:08,283
A long time ago. Come on.

159
00:15:09,618 --> 00:15:10,494
How long?

160
00:15:12,871 --> 00:15:14,832
About 12 years ago.

161
00:15:15,624 --> 00:15:18,418
Since the cleansing. Why?

162
00:15:19,127 --> 00:15:20,295
You okay, ma'am?

163
00:15:20,462 --> 00:15:22,297
Attention, all units, code three call.

164
00:15:22,464 --> 00:15:25,259
Receiving a report of an assault,
Exit 39 underpass.

165
00:15:25,926 --> 00:15:29,638
Possible non-human aggressor.
Proceed with caution.

166
00:15:29,805 --> 00:15:32,391
CDC already en route.
All area units respond.

167
00:15:34,852 --> 00:15:36,979
Ma'am? Hey!

168
00:15:37,187 --> 00:15:38,313
Ma'am?

169
00:16:07,009 --> 00:16:09,178
- What are you doing?
- Stay there! Don't move!

170
00:16:09,344 --> 00:16:11,513
- Identify yourself!
- Get back here right now!

171
00:16:30,699 --> 00:16:33,285
Whoever it is,
they couldn't have made it very far.

172
00:16:33,452 --> 00:16:35,037
I'll alert CDC to keep an eye out.

173
00:16:35,245 --> 00:16:36,330
They're en route.

174
00:16:36,497 --> 00:16:39,500
- There's no way this attack was human.
- You don't know that.

175
00:16:40,542 --> 00:16:42,252
Don't know what?

176
00:16:42,503 --> 00:16:44,213
The guy's shredded.
His throat was...

177
00:16:44,379 --> 00:16:46,381
- ...in the gutter.
- Just let me handle it.

178
00:16:46,548 --> 00:16:49,051
What's to handle?
This has Lycan written all over it.

179
00:16:49,218 --> 00:16:49,885
Detective...

180
00:16:50,052 --> 00:16:53,555
...when was the last time you heard
about a reported Lycan killing?

181
00:16:54,640 --> 00:16:55,724
A couple years ago.

182
00:16:55,891 --> 00:16:58,227
How many years
have you been with this department?

183
00:16:59,019 --> 00:17:00,729
What? I've been here
for three months.

184
00:17:00,896 --> 00:17:02,272
Exactly.

185
00:17:03,565 --> 00:17:05,901
You question me less
until you know a bit more.

186
00:17:06,068 --> 00:17:08,320
- We clear?
- Crystal.

187
00:17:11,698 --> 00:17:13,075
Detective Sebastian.

188
00:17:13,242 --> 00:17:15,244
Detective, we've just
received a report.

189
00:17:15,410 --> 00:17:17,412
There's been a disturbance
at Antigen Labs.

190
00:17:17,579 --> 00:17:19,206
A witness says
there was an escape.

191
00:17:19,373 --> 00:17:20,916
They said someone jumped...

192
00:17:21,083 --> 00:17:23,252
...out of a window.
This is a priority...

193
00:17:23,418 --> 00:17:24,419
...investigation.

194
00:17:24,586 --> 00:17:26,088
We need you over there ASAP.

195
00:17:26,255 --> 00:17:27,756
We're on our way.

196
00:17:27,923 --> 00:17:30,175
Hey, let's go.
Johnson, you're the lead.

197
00:17:30,342 --> 00:17:32,094
You got it, detective. Will do.

198
00:17:48,527 --> 00:17:49,903
Who's in charge?

199
00:17:51,822 --> 00:17:55,784
There's a Detective Sebastian
here to see you, sir.

200
00:17:57,703 --> 00:17:59,413
Where is he?

201
00:17:59,580 --> 00:18:01,623
In the lobby, sir.

202
00:18:05,335 --> 00:18:06,712
You'll be relieved to know...

203
00:18:06,879 --> 00:18:08,714
...the situation is well under control.

204
00:18:08,881 --> 00:18:11,216
- What happened?
- I repeat, well under control.

205
00:18:11,383 --> 00:18:13,051
I repeat, what happened?

206
00:18:13,552 --> 00:18:16,889
Yes, there are reports to be filed.

207
00:18:17,556 --> 00:18:22,186
One of our test subjects attempted to
escape. We were forced to put it down.

208
00:18:22,352 --> 00:18:24,938
- So nothing got out?
- Only a stray bullet.

209
00:18:25,105 --> 00:18:27,774
- And the test subject?
- Flash-burned.

210
00:18:28,066 --> 00:18:28,984
Will that be all?

211
00:18:29,568 --> 00:18:31,945
A few things to attend to.
You could imagine.

212
00:18:32,404 --> 00:18:34,323
Doctor, we received
an anonymous call...

213
00:18:34,489 --> 00:18:36,825
...that something else
escaped through a window.

214
00:18:36,992 --> 00:18:40,787
Detective, our mission at Antigen
is to develop ways of preventing...

215
00:18:40,954 --> 00:18:44,750
...infection, not releasing it
into the general population.

216
00:18:45,417 --> 00:18:48,003
I lost my son to this disease.

217
00:18:48,170 --> 00:18:51,548
There's no room for error with me
when it comes to the safety of...

218
00:18:51,715 --> 00:18:54,051
...the public.
If something had escaped...

219
00:18:54,218 --> 00:18:56,345
...the authorities
would have been notified.

220
00:18:56,512 --> 00:18:58,138
You are an authority, are you not?

221
00:18:59,932 --> 00:19:01,850
Now, if you'll excuse me...

222
00:19:25,499 --> 00:19:28,877
The guy in charge says it's nothing.
Let's go.

223
00:19:29,044 --> 00:19:31,880
Yeah, and he's full of shit.
Look at this.

224
00:19:33,549 --> 00:19:34,883
Want me to report it, sir?

225
00:19:35,092 --> 00:19:36,635
No. I'll do it.

226
00:19:36,802 --> 00:19:38,971
I don't mind. I can do it for you.

227
00:19:41,598 --> 00:19:42,891
All right, sir.

228
00:20:06,540 --> 00:20:10,586
The prisoner that helped me escape,
the one you called Subject 2...

229
00:20:11,837 --> 00:20:12,921
...was it a hybrid?

230
00:20:14,339 --> 00:20:15,382
Yes.

231
00:20:15,549 --> 00:20:17,092
What were you doing with us?

232
00:20:18,010 --> 00:20:19,178
We...

233
00:20:19,887 --> 00:20:22,764
We help the government
identify the infected.

234
00:20:22,973 --> 00:20:25,601
We were using your DNA
to try to find a cure...

235
00:20:25,767 --> 00:20:28,061
...to prevent another outbreak.

236
00:20:28,228 --> 00:20:29,813
You were told that I would...

237
00:20:29,980 --> 00:20:31,773
...lead you to the hybrid. Why?

238
00:20:32,608 --> 00:20:35,319
Subject 2 is restricted information.

239
00:20:35,485 --> 00:20:37,112
I don't have the clearance.

240
00:20:37,487 --> 00:20:39,239
You're lying.

241
00:20:40,282 --> 00:20:41,658
No!

242
00:20:43,035 --> 00:20:44,411
No, please!

243
00:20:44,578 --> 00:20:45,412
All I know is...

244
00:20:45,579 --> 00:20:47,122
...there's a connection between you.

245
00:20:47,789 --> 00:20:48,790
Your brain waves...

246
00:20:48,957 --> 00:20:50,751
...fall into sync
when you're close...

247
00:20:50,918 --> 00:20:51,793
...to each other.

248
00:20:51,960 --> 00:20:53,212
You can see through
each other's eyes!

249
00:20:55,422 --> 00:20:56,423
Please don't!

250
00:20:56,590 --> 00:20:58,091
I'm the one who let you go!

251
00:20:58,634 --> 00:21:00,135
Now we're even.

252
00:21:32,960 --> 00:21:34,628
What the hell was that?

253
00:21:35,295 --> 00:21:37,005
Creepy is what.

254
00:21:37,172 --> 00:21:38,924
- I'm calling it in.
- Let's go.

255
00:22:28,056 --> 00:22:28,724
Shit.

256
00:22:39,234 --> 00:22:40,027
Don't.

257
00:22:40,194 --> 00:22:41,278
Why not?

258
00:22:41,778 --> 00:22:43,197
We're the same.

259
00:22:46,700 --> 00:22:48,202
Why are you following me?

260
00:22:48,368 --> 00:22:50,078
We monitor the police frequencies.

261
00:22:50,787 --> 00:22:51,788
"We"?

262
00:22:51,955 --> 00:22:54,750
Do you know what attacked
that human under the bridge?

263
00:22:55,584 --> 00:22:56,877
No.

264
00:23:00,380 --> 00:23:01,715
Lycans.

265
00:23:01,882 --> 00:23:03,091
What remains of them, yes.

266
00:23:05,761 --> 00:23:07,763
They've been hiding
down here like rats...

267
00:23:07,930 --> 00:23:08,847
...since the Purge.

268
00:23:09,014 --> 00:23:12,267
Diseased and starving, they rarely
show themselves above ground.

269
00:23:12,643 --> 00:23:15,187
Which means that something
has got them riled up.

270
00:23:16,813 --> 00:23:18,440
Something you're not telling me.

271
00:23:34,331 --> 00:23:35,082
Michael!

272
00:24:17,958 --> 00:24:19,751
Do you know her?

273
00:24:19,918 --> 00:24:21,170
No.

274
00:24:27,718 --> 00:24:29,344
They will come back in numbers.

275
00:24:30,846 --> 00:24:32,598
We can't leave her here.

276
00:24:37,769 --> 00:24:38,520
Come on.

277
00:24:50,866 --> 00:24:52,159
Let's try the van.

278
00:24:57,414 --> 00:24:59,291
Get in. Move! Move!

279
00:25:17,059 --> 00:25:18,519
Three of them behind us.

280
00:26:30,549 --> 00:26:31,216
Go!

281
00:26:34,970 --> 00:26:35,679
Hurry, Selene!

282
00:26:35,846 --> 00:26:37,014
They're getting in the back!

283
00:26:44,980 --> 00:26:46,815
Fucking piece of shit!

284
00:26:54,406 --> 00:26:55,782
The girl! They're taking her!

285
00:27:31,193 --> 00:27:32,611
You drive.

286
00:28:19,283 --> 00:28:20,951
She's not healing.

287
00:28:21,118 --> 00:28:23,537
We have a doctor that can help her
at our coven.

288
00:28:25,038 --> 00:28:25,747
How did you...

289
00:28:25,914 --> 00:28:27,124
...find me?

290
00:28:29,459 --> 00:28:30,794
What's your name?

291
00:28:31,545 --> 00:28:33,255
Subject 2.

292
00:28:33,422 --> 00:28:36,216
And you are Subject 1.

293
00:28:37,176 --> 00:28:39,219
I freed you.

294
00:28:41,430 --> 00:28:43,557
Do you not know who I am?

295
00:28:44,975 --> 00:28:47,769
They told me that I had no mother...

296
00:28:47,936 --> 00:28:50,147
...that she died when I was born.

297
00:28:51,648 --> 00:28:53,775
I never believed it. I...

298
00:28:54,276 --> 00:28:56,486
I felt you.

299
00:28:56,653 --> 00:28:58,906
Saw images through your eyes.

300
00:28:59,573 --> 00:29:02,117
But then someone outside my door...

301
00:29:03,243 --> 00:29:07,456
...they said since I was no longer
a child, the wait was over...

302
00:29:09,166 --> 00:29:10,751
...that I'd be dead soon.

303
00:29:11,418 --> 00:29:14,296
And that my own mother,
right next door...

304
00:29:14,796 --> 00:29:17,508
...would never even know I'd existed.

305
00:29:19,384 --> 00:29:21,637
What did they tell you of your father?

306
00:29:22,721 --> 00:29:24,473
They must have told you something.

307
00:29:24,640 --> 00:29:26,683
Do you see images through him?

308
00:29:27,142 --> 00:29:28,393
No.

309
00:29:28,769 --> 00:29:30,145
Only you.

310
00:29:35,067 --> 00:29:35,984
No, please!

311
00:29:48,121 --> 00:29:50,165
She's never stepped foot
outside the lab.

312
00:29:50,332 --> 00:29:51,834
How can she possibly survive?

313
00:29:52,000 --> 00:29:55,003
I understand the risk of reporting
her escape to the authorities.

314
00:29:55,170 --> 00:29:56,296
No record of her birth.

315
00:29:56,463 --> 00:29:58,799
Questions will be asked.
I'm well aware of that.

316
00:29:58,966 --> 00:30:01,051
But if she dies,
all our years of research--

317
00:30:01,218 --> 00:30:02,845
Rather than tell me
how to do my job...

318
00:30:03,011 --> 00:30:06,014
...why not take a look
at your own professional conduct?

319
00:30:06,181 --> 00:30:08,851
And how your continual need
to endow this creature...

320
00:30:09,017 --> 00:30:13,021
...with human traits has led to
the laxness of its security protocols.

321
00:30:13,188 --> 00:30:15,858
It's not a human being, Lida!
It's not your child.

322
00:30:16,024 --> 00:30:17,192
It's not to be coddled.

323
00:30:17,359 --> 00:30:19,361
It's a blight of nature.

324
00:30:23,073 --> 00:30:25,325
Stop worrying. It'll come back to us.

325
00:31:57,918 --> 00:31:59,670
Get Olivia at once.

326
00:32:04,466 --> 00:32:07,135
Again you break my rules. Why?

327
00:32:07,302 --> 00:32:09,429
She was attacked.

328
00:32:09,930 --> 00:32:11,014
She is not healing.

329
00:32:11,181 --> 00:32:13,600
And for this
you compromise our safety?

330
00:32:13,767 --> 00:32:14,518
You have...

331
00:32:14,685 --> 00:32:16,812
...no reason to fear us.

332
00:32:18,814 --> 00:32:21,817
Do you think I'm foolish enough
to take you at your word?

333
00:32:23,318 --> 00:32:24,194
No reason...

334
00:32:24,361 --> 00:32:27,156
...to fear a Death Dealer
who fell in love with a Lycan...

335
00:32:27,322 --> 00:32:29,366
...who murdered two of our elders...

336
00:32:29,783 --> 00:32:31,869
...and who, at every turn,
has betrayed...

337
00:32:32,035 --> 00:32:33,328
...her own kind.

338
00:32:35,622 --> 00:32:37,207
Do you know who this is?

339
00:32:39,376 --> 00:32:40,043
Yes.

340
00:32:41,837 --> 00:32:43,881
But it was we
who betrayed her, Father.

341
00:32:45,757 --> 00:32:46,925
Let her through.

342
00:32:49,344 --> 00:32:50,804
She's not healing.

343
00:33:01,690 --> 00:33:03,775
She was attacked by a lower Lycan.

344
00:33:04,651 --> 00:33:05,652
Two hours ago.

345
00:33:08,363 --> 00:33:10,199
Her cell repair is...

346
00:33:10,699 --> 00:33:13,702
...active but weakened.

347
00:33:16,622 --> 00:33:17,706
She has no...

348
00:33:18,832 --> 00:33:20,501
...origin bite marks...

349
00:33:21,585 --> 00:33:23,128
...or scars.

350
00:33:24,796 --> 00:33:27,090
I've never seen a child like this before.

351
00:33:27,799 --> 00:33:29,885
When did you last feed?

352
00:33:30,260 --> 00:33:31,553
Feed?

353
00:33:32,930 --> 00:33:34,515
Give her blood.

354
00:33:43,232 --> 00:33:44,024
Child...

355
00:33:44,191 --> 00:33:45,567
...you must.

356
00:34:03,627 --> 00:34:04,920
Slowly.

357
00:34:05,629 --> 00:34:07,089
Slowly.

358
00:34:09,925 --> 00:34:10,926
There.

359
00:34:12,094 --> 00:34:13,762
There, now.

360
00:34:17,975 --> 00:34:19,518
She's healing.

361
00:34:21,353 --> 00:34:23,438
- And quickly.
- Good.

362
00:34:23,605 --> 00:34:25,440
Take her to my room.
She needs to rest.

363
00:34:25,607 --> 00:34:26,608
No.

364
00:34:27,943 --> 00:34:29,278
Look at the eyes.

365
00:34:39,580 --> 00:34:41,665
I never believed it.

366
00:34:42,082 --> 00:34:43,667
They do exist.

367
00:34:45,043 --> 00:34:47,421
This is not one of us.

368
00:34:47,588 --> 00:34:50,007
No, it's something more, Father.

369
00:34:52,593 --> 00:34:54,595
What do you know of her?

370
00:34:57,181 --> 00:35:00,058
I was held captive
at a place called Antigen.

371
00:35:01,643 --> 00:35:03,896
One of the other prisoners freed me.

372
00:35:04,646 --> 00:35:06,315
I believed it was Michael Corvin...

373
00:35:06,481 --> 00:35:08,984
...the only hybrid I knew
existed at that time.

374
00:35:09,151 --> 00:35:11,195
Yes, yes, your Lycan lover, long dead.

375
00:35:11,361 --> 00:35:13,030
What is this, then?

376
00:35:14,656 --> 00:35:16,366
None of your concern.

377
00:35:17,075 --> 00:35:19,870
As soon as she regains her strength,
I will leave with her.

378
00:35:58,200 --> 00:35:59,409
I used to hear stories...

379
00:35:59,576 --> 00:36:00,911
...of the Death Dealers.

380
00:36:02,204 --> 00:36:05,749
That they were a thing of the past...

381
00:36:05,916 --> 00:36:07,793
...never to return.

382
00:36:09,253 --> 00:36:11,046
I'm glad they were wrong.

383
00:36:12,714 --> 00:36:14,550
You knew who I am...

384
00:36:16,552 --> 00:36:18,720
...and yet you still brought me here.

385
00:36:21,056 --> 00:36:22,683
Thank you.

386
00:36:22,850 --> 00:36:24,643
You're a fighter.

387
00:36:25,018 --> 00:36:27,521
We could use more like you
to teach us.

388
00:36:27,688 --> 00:36:28,438
I'm not sure...

389
00:36:28,605 --> 00:36:30,023
...your father would agree.

390
00:36:30,190 --> 00:36:33,902
There was a time when he would have.
That's why he dislikes you so much.

391
00:36:34,069 --> 00:36:38,323
I think it reminds him of the days when
he defended us with fire and steel...

392
00:36:38,490 --> 00:36:42,035
...rather than hollow words.
He knows how much we need you.

393
00:36:43,579 --> 00:36:46,582
- I'm not a leader.
- But you fight for what you believe in.

394
00:36:47,583 --> 00:36:48,750
You always have.

395
00:36:48,917 --> 00:36:49,793
I don't know...

396
00:36:49,960 --> 00:36:51,336
...what I believe in anymore.

397
00:36:51,503 --> 00:36:54,047
I don't recognise this world.

398
00:36:54,214 --> 00:36:56,091
But you haven't changed.

399
00:36:56,758 --> 00:36:59,261
I saw it in your eyes
when you looked at the child.

400
00:37:00,179 --> 00:37:02,681
You will protect her.

401
00:37:02,848 --> 00:37:04,141
It's in your blood.

402
00:37:04,308 --> 00:37:05,893
It's who you are.

403
00:37:07,477 --> 00:37:09,938
When you leave, take me with you.

404
00:38:14,378 --> 00:38:16,296
You distrust me.

405
00:38:22,803 --> 00:38:26,014
Of course you do.
I made you feel unwelcome.

406
00:38:26,181 --> 00:38:28,267
And for that, I'm sorry.

407
00:38:33,021 --> 00:38:34,773
Those eyes...

408
00:38:35,691 --> 00:38:37,359
...they're special.

409
00:38:39,153 --> 00:38:42,739
I know exactly what you are.

410
00:38:54,918 --> 00:38:56,086
My father says that...

411
00:38:56,253 --> 00:38:59,673
...should we survive as a species,
these relics will help...

412
00:38:59,840 --> 00:39:02,384
...our descendants know
who we were and how we lived.

413
00:39:02,551 --> 00:39:04,178
And what do you say?

414
00:39:04,344 --> 00:39:06,722
That if we continue to live
as we do now...

415
00:39:06,889 --> 00:39:09,725
...then we disgrace the past
and don't deserve a future.

416
00:39:09,892 --> 00:39:12,227
We must resist the humans...

417
00:39:12,895 --> 00:39:14,855
...wherever and whenever possible.

418
00:39:15,022 --> 00:39:17,191
Between the first and second Purges...

419
00:39:17,900 --> 00:39:22,571
...Lycan youth rallied in the same way
against the prudence of their elders.

420
00:39:22,738 --> 00:39:26,283
Their calls for violent action
carried the day.

421
00:39:26,450 --> 00:39:27,951
The result?

422
00:39:28,160 --> 00:39:30,996
The Werewolves are nearly extinct.

423
00:39:31,872 --> 00:39:34,875
Is that what you wish for us,
extinction?

424
00:39:35,501 --> 00:39:36,627
Yet you bring...

425
00:39:36,793 --> 00:39:39,087
...her offspring into our home.
Do you honestly...

426
00:39:39,254 --> 00:39:42,216
...believe the humans
will allow her to remain free?

427
00:39:42,549 --> 00:39:44,468
They will hunt her down
at any expense.

428
00:39:44,635 --> 00:39:47,554
- Then we can help protect them.
- Protect them?

429
00:39:48,222 --> 00:39:49,932
They leave tonight.

430
00:39:50,265 --> 00:39:50,933
This isn't...

431
00:39:51,099 --> 00:39:51,767
...prudence.

432
00:39:51,934 --> 00:39:53,810
This is cowardice, plain and simple.

433
00:39:55,812 --> 00:39:57,689
How dare you?

434
00:39:58,440 --> 00:40:00,108
How dare you...

435
00:40:01,276 --> 00:40:02,444
...do so little?

436
00:40:33,725 --> 00:40:36,103
I dreamt of the day we would meet.

437
00:40:38,981 --> 00:40:41,275
Like a silly little girl.

438
00:40:47,614 --> 00:40:50,409
You're as cold as one already dead.

439
00:40:54,955 --> 00:40:56,498
Yesterday...

440
00:40:57,124 --> 00:40:59,293
...I was with your father.

441
00:41:02,296 --> 00:41:05,757
He was only a little further away
from me than you are now.

442
00:41:08,093 --> 00:41:09,803
I went to sleep.

443
00:41:11,722 --> 00:41:13,807
And when I awoke the next day...

444
00:41:15,225 --> 00:41:17,102
...I learned that, overnight...

445
00:41:18,312 --> 00:41:20,522
...12 years had passed.

446
00:41:22,232 --> 00:41:25,360
And instead of the only man
I've ever loved...

447
00:41:26,778 --> 00:41:29,198
...there stood a girl with his eyes.

448
00:41:33,785 --> 00:41:36,079
My heart is not cold.

449
00:41:36,246 --> 00:41:37,915
It's broken.

450
00:41:42,044 --> 00:41:43,754
I'm so sorry.

451
00:41:54,181 --> 00:41:55,432
What is it?

452
00:41:57,643 --> 00:41:58,727
They're here.

453
00:41:59,895 --> 00:42:02,272
Stay here. Wait for me.

454
00:42:02,439 --> 00:42:03,899
No, take me with you.

455
00:42:04,066 --> 00:42:05,234
Please.

456
00:42:05,400 --> 00:42:08,737
I won't let anyone hurt you. I promise.

457
00:42:08,904 --> 00:42:09,947
Lock the door.

458
00:42:11,949 --> 00:42:14,034
Everybody to the shelter. Now!

459
00:42:15,744 --> 00:42:16,954
No!

460
00:42:17,120 --> 00:42:19,081
Prepare the armoury.

461
00:42:19,248 --> 00:42:21,333
Do as I say! Go, go!

462
00:42:22,417 --> 00:42:24,753
Pay heed to me!

463
00:42:24,920 --> 00:42:28,090
No! We stand and we fight.

464
00:42:43,939 --> 00:42:46,441
No! Have you no sense?

465
00:42:50,696 --> 00:42:51,613
Stop this now!

466
00:42:53,031 --> 00:42:56,118
We lived safely for years
and you brought humans into this coven.

467
00:42:56,535 --> 00:42:57,452
They want the girl.

468
00:42:57,619 --> 00:42:59,288
They'll stop at nothing
to get her.

469
00:42:59,454 --> 00:43:02,332
This day was bound to come,
with or without us.

470
00:43:02,499 --> 00:43:05,085
Let's move!
Munitions, let's go! Everyone!

471
00:43:05,252 --> 00:43:06,503
Are you mad?

472
00:43:06,670 --> 00:43:09,965
We have no more than a handful
of fighters. We will be annihilated!

473
00:43:10,924 --> 00:43:12,384
And what's your plan, Father?

474
00:43:12,551 --> 00:43:14,136
Let's go! Now!

475
00:43:15,762 --> 00:43:18,307
- Where are you going?
- To get her away from here.

476
00:43:18,473 --> 00:43:21,185
- He's right. I shouldn't have come.
- He doesn't understand.

477
00:43:21,351 --> 00:43:23,896
The humans will follow us out.
Hold them off till then.

478
00:43:25,063 --> 00:43:26,315
They're only here for her.

479
00:43:27,483 --> 00:43:29,318
She's more powerful than any of us.

480
00:43:29,485 --> 00:43:31,153
They fear the day she discovers it.

481
00:43:32,321 --> 00:43:34,031
I have to get her out of here.

482
00:44:11,944 --> 00:44:13,654
Lycan!

483
00:44:17,699 --> 00:44:19,076
Silver ammunition!

484
00:44:19,243 --> 00:44:20,077
Now!

485
00:44:20,494 --> 00:44:21,453
Defend the second...

486
00:44:21,620 --> 00:44:22,287
...rotunda!

487
00:44:22,454 --> 00:44:23,747
Move! Move!

488
00:45:08,041 --> 00:45:09,418
Open the door!

489
00:45:11,503 --> 00:45:12,254
Let's go.

490
00:45:36,278 --> 00:45:37,571
Move! Move!

491
00:46:17,986 --> 00:46:19,238
We need to go.

492
00:46:44,847 --> 00:46:46,014
What the hell was that?

493
00:46:49,560 --> 00:46:51,687
- Take her somewhere safe.
- No.

494
00:46:51,854 --> 00:46:53,313
Take her. Go.

495
00:49:35,225 --> 00:49:36,727
Where is she?

496
00:49:37,186 --> 00:49:38,687
They took her.

497
00:49:39,688 --> 00:49:41,523
They accepted her.

498
00:49:43,233 --> 00:49:45,319
As a gift from me.

499
00:50:25,067 --> 00:50:26,401
Do you know what you've done?

500
00:50:27,778 --> 00:50:28,987
Do you have any idea?

501
00:50:29,154 --> 00:50:31,406
What would you have had me do?

502
00:50:31,615 --> 00:50:35,869
Fight to the last to protect
the very one who brought this upon us?

503
00:50:36,453 --> 00:50:37,412
We're defeated.

504
00:50:38,413 --> 00:50:40,457
Our coven is destroyed.
My son...

505
00:50:40,624 --> 00:50:41,458
...is dead.

506
00:50:41,917 --> 00:50:43,544
Because of you.

507
00:50:44,628 --> 00:50:45,796
Why?

508
00:50:47,422 --> 00:50:48,715
Because he helped that...

509
00:50:48,882 --> 00:50:50,509
...child of yours.

510
00:50:50,676 --> 00:50:52,761
If they kill her, so be it.

511
00:50:52,928 --> 00:50:56,265
Your son died because
he was fighting for all of you.

512
00:50:57,933 --> 00:51:00,102
Because he knew that running
is not survival.

513
00:51:01,979 --> 00:51:03,564
Those were Lycans.

514
00:51:03,730 --> 00:51:06,817
Not extinct. More powerful than ever.

515
00:51:07,192 --> 00:51:10,112
That thing was more than twice the size
of any Lycan I've seen.

516
00:51:11,905 --> 00:51:12,781
They risked...

517
00:51:12,948 --> 00:51:17,077
...showing themselves after more than
a decade in hiding because of her.

518
00:51:17,244 --> 00:51:19,538
And you handed her over to them.

519
00:51:21,456 --> 00:51:22,457
She is the last...

520
00:51:22,624 --> 00:51:26,628
...direct descendant
of Alexander Corvinus.

521
00:51:27,254 --> 00:51:30,507
The only hybrid child
that has ever existed.

522
00:51:32,968 --> 00:51:35,387
Whatever it is the Lycans
want from her...

523
00:51:36,430 --> 00:51:38,765
...your son knew it was
worth dying for.

524
00:51:45,731 --> 00:51:47,024
What are you doing?

525
00:52:16,512 --> 00:52:17,846
David.

526
00:53:32,087 --> 00:53:33,630
A force of two dozen Lycans...

527
00:53:33,797 --> 00:53:36,967
...attacked and destroyed
one of our covens last night.

528
00:53:38,927 --> 00:53:40,220
You're not surprised.

529
00:53:42,598 --> 00:53:44,266
You knew the Lycans
were not extinct.

530
00:53:45,225 --> 00:53:47,144
- How?
- Just a feeling.

531
00:53:47,603 --> 00:53:49,605
I'm not good with feelings.

532
00:53:49,771 --> 00:53:51,607
I want to know how.

533
00:53:51,857 --> 00:53:54,026
This is not the place for this.

534
00:53:54,860 --> 00:53:56,278
And you're not gonna kill me.

535
00:53:56,445 --> 00:53:57,446
Really?

536
00:53:57,613 --> 00:53:58,739
No.

537
00:53:58,906 --> 00:54:01,200
Because you wouldn't need
a fucking gun to do it.

538
00:54:04,119 --> 00:54:05,037
A few years ago...

539
00:54:05,204 --> 00:54:08,123
...the government declared
"mission accomplished" on Lycans.

540
00:54:08,290 --> 00:54:10,542
The feds announced that
we were to only focus...

541
00:54:10,709 --> 00:54:12,377
...on your kind now.

542
00:54:13,003 --> 00:54:15,839
Three months ago,
a friend of mine sent me this.

543
00:54:17,132 --> 00:54:20,761
It arrived two days after he was found
hanging from his own ceiling fan.

544
00:54:23,305 --> 00:54:25,432
Two hundred suspected
Lycan captures.

545
00:54:25,599 --> 00:54:27,142
Every case was investigated.

546
00:54:27,309 --> 00:54:29,478
Every blood test came back negative.

547
00:54:29,645 --> 00:54:30,938
My friend began to wonder:

548
00:54:31,104 --> 00:54:34,566
Were they all false leads or was
someone trying to protect the Lycans?

549
00:54:35,609 --> 00:54:38,320
Helping them replenish their packs,
letting them regroup.

550
00:54:38,529 --> 00:54:40,489
What about your own department?

551
00:54:43,283 --> 00:54:46,829
They have my daughter.
All I care about is getting her back.

552
00:54:48,539 --> 00:54:52,960
If you're protecting someone, I don't
care. I'm not after them. I just want her.

553
00:54:53,293 --> 00:54:54,545
No.

554
00:54:55,504 --> 00:54:59,424
Even if there are others in my
department, they don't have authority.

555
00:54:59,758 --> 00:55:01,301
This goes much higher.

556
00:55:02,052 --> 00:55:04,304
I believe, all the way to the top.

557
00:55:05,889 --> 00:55:06,849
Or to the bottom.

558
00:55:07,641 --> 00:55:08,684
What do you mean?

559
00:55:09,768 --> 00:55:11,895
Who administers the tests?

560
00:55:12,688 --> 00:55:16,150
We're a bit short on time,
so if you please, take a look at these.

561
00:55:17,025 --> 00:55:19,528
This schedule takes you
from the moment we adjourn...

562
00:55:19,695 --> 00:55:22,114
...through to the final manufacture
of the vaccine.

563
00:55:23,365 --> 00:55:27,536
If we stick to this plan, inoculations
should begin within three months.

564
00:55:27,703 --> 00:55:29,538
Any questions, now's the time.

565
00:55:29,705 --> 00:55:32,958
After today's surgery, there will be
no communication between us...

566
00:55:33,125 --> 00:55:35,377
...until we meet again
in the inoculation centre.

567
00:55:35,586 --> 00:55:37,004
Doctor, in terms...

568
00:55:37,171 --> 00:55:38,505
...of your test subject...

569
00:55:38,672 --> 00:55:41,383
...he continues to demonstrate
immunity to silver?

570
00:55:41,550 --> 00:55:42,885
Absolutely.

571
00:55:43,218 --> 00:55:47,472
And additional inoculations,
administered only as a precaution...

572
00:55:47,639 --> 00:55:49,725
...triggered side effects
we never imagined.

573
00:55:50,100 --> 00:55:51,226
Vast increases...

574
00:55:51,393 --> 00:55:53,645
...in strength, muscle mass...

575
00:55:53,812 --> 00:55:55,481
...self-healing...

576
00:55:55,689 --> 00:55:56,815
...stamina.

577
00:55:58,984 --> 00:56:00,319
You said she was essential
to our research.

578
00:56:01,069 --> 00:56:03,572
- Yes, and will continue to be.
- How?

579
00:56:04,448 --> 00:56:05,949
By vivisecting her?

580
00:56:06,533 --> 00:56:08,118
You weren't meant to have that.

581
00:56:08,285 --> 00:56:09,912
I cared for this little girl...

582
00:56:10,496 --> 00:56:13,749
...all these years,
and you expect me to sit by...

583
00:56:14,249 --> 00:56:16,752
- ...while you--
- Harvest its genetic material?

584
00:56:18,504 --> 00:56:20,214
I expect nothing from you.

585
00:56:21,173 --> 00:56:22,925
I hired you to look after it...

586
00:56:23,091 --> 00:56:26,428
...and for the most part,
you did an excellent job.

587
00:56:26,637 --> 00:56:28,764
Saving the lives of thousands.

588
00:56:29,806 --> 00:56:31,808
What are you talking about?

589
00:56:31,975 --> 00:56:34,436
An entire species
saved from extinction.

590
00:56:40,400 --> 00:56:41,568
Jacob.

591
00:57:26,488 --> 00:57:30,492
After today, you won't have to
wait so long between injections.

592
00:57:31,118 --> 00:57:33,162
Are you sure she's ready?

593
00:57:33,328 --> 00:57:35,080
Oestrogen levels high...

594
00:57:35,247 --> 00:57:38,333
...intervals between menses
holding steady.

595
00:57:38,542 --> 00:57:40,502
It's come of age.

596
00:57:41,253 --> 00:57:44,631
Everything's worked out
just as we'd hoped.

597
00:57:48,552 --> 00:57:50,554
You're the first proof of it.

598
00:57:52,389 --> 00:57:54,141
I'm proud of you, son.

599
00:57:58,896 --> 00:58:00,689
Now that it's with us again...

600
00:58:00,856 --> 00:58:04,026
...we'll have all the genetic material
we need, ready for cloning.

601
00:58:04,193 --> 00:58:07,696
Enough to produce
an endless supply of vaccine.

602
00:58:08,864 --> 00:58:09,740
Imagine.

603
00:58:10,324 --> 00:58:13,160
Our species immune to silver.

604
00:58:13,327 --> 00:58:14,995
No more hiding.

605
00:58:15,162 --> 00:58:18,624
Every Lycan under our command
as powerful as you are.

606
00:58:19,458 --> 00:58:22,044
I've even begun injecting myself.

607
00:58:22,711 --> 00:58:25,297
I only wish Mother
were here to see it.

608
00:58:26,048 --> 00:58:28,509
Your mother chose to
remain human.

609
00:58:30,302 --> 00:58:32,346
She abandoned us.

610
00:58:34,598 --> 00:58:36,350
Remember that.

611
00:58:50,405 --> 00:58:51,990
Of course, Father.

612
00:58:59,248 --> 00:58:59,915
Look...

613
00:59:00,082 --> 00:59:04,169
...if you're right about Antigen, who
knows how many Lycans will be there?

614
00:59:04,545 --> 00:59:07,256
The second you step foot inside,
you'll be surrounded.

615
00:59:07,422 --> 00:59:08,507
I'm hoping so.

616
00:59:11,093 --> 00:59:13,303
I know you want her back.
I can help you.

617
00:59:13,470 --> 00:59:16,098
- Why?
- Just tell me what your plan is.

618
00:59:40,747 --> 00:59:42,791
It's worse if you try to fight it.

619
00:59:43,959 --> 00:59:45,210
Trust me.

620
00:59:47,713 --> 00:59:49,298
So how is it you're actually...

621
00:59:49,464 --> 00:59:51,884
...able to survive in the sunlight?

622
00:59:53,802 --> 00:59:55,429
It was a gift.

623
00:59:56,430 --> 00:59:58,473
From a man named
Alexander Corvinus.

624
00:59:59,474 --> 01:00:00,851
The founding father.

625
01:00:04,813 --> 01:00:07,316
I used to be married, to a nurse.

626
01:00:09,151 --> 01:00:11,028
One day at work, she was bitten.

627
01:00:12,988 --> 01:00:16,992
Nobody knew but us.
We lived like that for a few years.

628
01:00:19,161 --> 01:00:20,829
Then came the Purge.

629
01:00:22,289 --> 01:00:26,043
The feds were conducting door-to-doors
and when they knocked on ours...

630
01:00:31,798 --> 01:00:34,468
...well, she told me she loved me...

631
01:00:36,345 --> 01:00:38,597
...and then she let the sunlight in.

632
01:00:39,932 --> 01:00:41,934
I had to watch her burn.

633
01:01:03,872 --> 01:01:05,082
Okay.

634
01:01:07,501 --> 01:01:09,002
You got me?

635
01:01:09,628 --> 01:01:10,921
Yes.

636
01:01:12,005 --> 01:01:13,382
Good luck.

637
01:01:28,230 --> 01:01:29,523
- Shit. It's her.
- In daylight?

638
01:01:29,690 --> 01:01:30,357
It's her!

639
01:01:30,524 --> 01:01:31,441
- Go!
- Okay.

640
01:02:02,806 --> 01:02:03,765
Wait for my cue.

641
01:02:03,932 --> 01:02:04,725
I'm ready.

642
01:02:11,106 --> 01:02:14,276
Ops Code A. Repeat, Ops Code A.
Breach on Level 1.

643
01:02:14,443 --> 01:02:16,278
Intruder ascending in Elevator 4.

644
01:02:16,445 --> 01:02:18,697
I want all levels ready
on that elevator now!

645
01:02:23,118 --> 01:02:24,786
- Anaesthesia ready?
- Yes, sir.

646
01:02:24,953 --> 01:02:25,829
Good.

647
01:02:49,520 --> 01:02:50,938
Security units on alert.

648
01:02:51,104 --> 01:02:53,816
Ops Code A.
Intruder on premises.

649
01:02:53,982 --> 01:02:56,610
Secure the east wing.
All units, intruder's ascending...

650
01:02:56,777 --> 01:02:57,653
...in the elevator.

651
01:02:57,820 --> 01:02:59,196
Come on.

652
01:02:59,696 --> 01:03:00,906
Let's go.

653
01:03:20,342 --> 01:03:20,926
Move!

654
01:03:38,193 --> 01:03:39,736
There's your cue.

655
01:03:39,903 --> 01:03:41,029
Copy.

656
01:04:10,517 --> 01:04:13,896
They're using silver-nitrate gas.
Bombs on all the floors.

657
01:04:14,897 --> 01:04:18,192
It's Subject 1. We need to evacuate.

658
01:04:18,525 --> 01:04:19,735
Fine.

659
01:04:19,902 --> 01:04:20,736
Start a propofol...

660
01:04:20,903 --> 01:04:21,653
...infusion.

661
01:04:21,820 --> 01:04:25,866
We're not cancelling this procedure,
understood? We're moving it.

662
01:04:27,201 --> 01:04:28,619
You find her...

663
01:04:29,203 --> 01:04:30,871
...and you destroy her.

664
01:04:31,038 --> 01:04:32,539
With pleasure.

665
01:04:46,261 --> 01:04:46,929
I'm here.

666
01:04:47,095 --> 01:04:48,555
I got movement on a van in...

667
01:04:48,722 --> 01:04:49,598
...Parking Level 3.

668
01:04:49,765 --> 01:04:51,266
No sign of the girl.

669
01:04:51,433 --> 01:04:54,770
They'll be on the move.
Just don't lose them.

670
01:04:59,942 --> 01:05:01,068
She's in the service elevator.

671
01:05:02,945 --> 01:05:03,821
Get her.

672
01:05:04,029 --> 01:05:04,947
I'm coming down.

673
01:05:27,886 --> 01:05:30,556
Selene. Selene!

674
01:05:31,723 --> 01:05:34,017
They're heading for Parking Level 2.

675
01:05:36,520 --> 01:05:37,855
Selene.

676
01:05:38,021 --> 01:05:38,981
I need to know...

677
01:05:39,148 --> 01:05:39,898
...where you are!

678
01:05:50,993 --> 01:05:51,660
Shit!

679
01:06:06,717 --> 01:06:07,843
Do you copy?

680
01:06:08,010 --> 01:06:09,469
Selene, where are you?

681
01:06:39,958 --> 01:06:41,043
I see her. I see her.

682
01:06:41,835 --> 01:06:42,628
Parking Level 2.

683
01:06:42,794 --> 01:06:44,004
They're loading her...

684
01:06:44,171 --> 01:06:45,380
...into the van.

685
01:06:45,672 --> 01:06:47,174
Selene, where are you?

686
01:06:49,760 --> 01:06:51,011
Fuck it.

687
01:06:54,473 --> 01:06:57,518
Hold it right there! Stop! Stop now!

688
01:07:09,738 --> 01:07:10,405
Michael?

689
01:07:10,572 --> 01:07:11,573
Get her!

690
01:07:11,740 --> 01:07:12,699
Take her out!

691
01:07:23,168 --> 01:07:24,670
Selene, Lane has her...

692
01:07:24,837 --> 01:07:27,422
...in the van.
They're on the move. Where are you?

693
01:07:27,589 --> 01:07:29,508
They are leaving with her!
Do you hear me?

694
01:07:31,718 --> 01:07:33,053
I'm on my way.

695
01:09:01,683 --> 01:09:02,851
Come on, faster.

696
01:09:21,829 --> 01:09:22,663
Don't stop.

697
01:09:22,830 --> 01:09:23,497
Hit him!

698
01:09:50,899 --> 01:09:53,110
Selene, they're heading
for Parking Level 1.

699
01:09:55,571 --> 01:09:58,532
Selene, they're getting away
on Parking Level 1. Do you copy?

700
01:09:58,824 --> 01:10:00,409
I'm coming.

701
01:10:23,515 --> 01:10:24,433
Everything okay?

702
01:10:24,600 --> 01:10:25,434
Levels are...

703
01:10:25,601 --> 01:10:27,603
...holding stable, sir. Baseline vitals--

704
01:12:09,913 --> 01:12:10,831
Fuck you.

705
01:12:54,124 --> 01:12:55,125
Get away from her!

706
01:14:54,745 --> 01:14:56,997
It's worse if you try to fight it.

707
01:15:00,209 --> 01:15:01,585
Trust me.

708
01:15:59,184 --> 01:16:01,937
I heal instantly.

709
01:16:02,187 --> 01:16:03,272
I'm counting on it.

710
01:17:02,206 --> 01:17:04,208
You came back for me.

711
01:17:08,712 --> 01:17:10,339
I said I would.

712
01:17:11,381 --> 01:17:12,799
Selene.

713
01:17:16,345 --> 01:17:17,846
You should go.

714
01:17:20,474 --> 01:17:22,476
There's a safe house
not far from here.

715
01:17:22,643 --> 01:17:23,644
Go. I'll send them...

716
01:17:23,811 --> 01:17:26,480
...on a different path,
buy you some time.

717
01:17:27,523 --> 01:17:29,566
Thank you. Come on.

718
01:17:29,733 --> 01:17:31,193
David.

719
01:17:33,612 --> 01:17:35,364
Are we going back in?

720
01:17:35,531 --> 01:17:36,865
We are.

721
01:17:54,633 --> 01:17:55,676
What is it?

722
01:17:57,219 --> 01:17:58,053
Michael?

723
01:18:00,264 --> 01:18:01,515
The roof.

724
01:18:07,729 --> 01:18:12,109
Though the world has changed,
our enemy remains the same.

725
01:18:12,985 --> 01:18:13,902
The Lycans...

726
01:18:14,069 --> 01:18:15,070
...will rebuild.

727
01:18:15,237 --> 01:18:17,322
And will hunt for her father
as they did...

728
01:18:17,489 --> 01:18:18,282
...for her.

729
01:18:21,076 --> 01:18:22,578
But as they grow stronger...

730
01:18:23,078 --> 01:18:24,580
...so will we.

731
01:18:25,497 --> 01:18:27,207
The Vampire coven will not only...

732
01:18:27,374 --> 01:18:29,084
...survive this world...

733
01:18:29,751 --> 01:18:31,670
...we will reclaim it.



2
00:00:45,120 --> 00:00:49,593
发生在人族（英法）之前的一场百年血战

3
00:00:50,032 --> 00:00:54,003
余波依然在人间持续

4
00:00:54,827 --> 00:00:57,233
我成了血族

5
00:01:00,506 --> 00:01:04,262
对抗狼族为血族复仇

6
00:01:11,344 --> 00:01:12,557
我一直这样活着

7
00:01:21,316 --> 00:01:24,020
直到我遇到了 Michael Corvin  （麦克尔·柯文）

8
00:01:25,934 --> 00:01:30,071
一个能被两族共同感染的人类（混种）

9
00:01:31,105 --> 00:01:36,023
因为他的出现 一切都变了

10
00:01:37,805 --> 00:01:40,343
盟友成了死敌

11
00:01:40,468 --> 00:01:44,637
而我保护了近六个世纪的长老们

12
00:01:44,764 --> 00:01:46,509
一心要除掉我

13
00:01:48,029 --> 00:01:49,469
我们开始反击

14
00:01:50,993 --> 00:01:53,511
杀了所有长老

15
00:01:54,010 --> 00:01:58,301
我们暂时安全了

16
00:02:01,890 --> 00:02:06,568
但新的黑暗来临了

17
00:02:07,043 --> 00:02:14,500
九天后 异人类被发现 其异族体系也大白天下

18
00:02:14,628 --> 00:02:17,219
被其感染人数的也在不断增加

19
00:02:17,345 --> 00:02:24,479
军方确认 对抗这些非人类的最好武器是紫外光和银

20
00:02:24,607 --> 00:02:28,213
它们对异族是致命的

21
00:02:28,341 --> 00:02:31,854
临时医护救助中心已建立

22
00:02:32,654 --> 00:02:36,748
通过测试我们可以了解控制感染

23
00:02:52,829 --> 00:02:56,907
第二轮进攻 会用上紫外光和硝酸银武器

24
00:02:57,032 --> 00:02:59,157
消灭这些感染源

25
00:02:59,285 --> 00:03:04,385
紧急事态 戒严令两小时前宣布实施

26
00:03:07,862 --> 00:03:10,020
我们中的这些异种

27
00:03:15,154 --> 00:03:17,011
谁也救不了他们

28
00:03:17,261 --> 00:03:18,054
也救不了自己

29
00:03:19,442 --> 00:03:25,831
在辖区内发现的   是两种截然不同的类人异族

30
00:03:25,956 --> 00:03:27,970
它们就是常说的的血族和狼人

31
00:03:28,098 --> 00:03:30,596
今天   它们的存在被证实了

32
00:03:31,151 --> 00:03:33,687
城市一片狼藉 无法得到最新状况

33
00:03:33,939 --> 00:03:38,012
但毫无疑问的 这是场大清洗

34
00:03:43,224 --> 00:03:44,372
无药可治

35
00:04:13,745 --> 00:04:25,354
-= 黑夜传说4: 觉醒 =-

36
00:04:30,683 --> 00:04:32,137
在这场清洗中

37
00:04:32,947 --> 00:04:35,698
人类停止了自相残杀

38
00:04:37,559 --> 00:04:40,014
我们才是他们一直渴望的敌人

39
00:04:41,803 --> 00:04:44,696
唯有逃离才能活命了

40
00:04:46,490 --> 00:04:49,181
今晚 Michael (麦克尔)和我一起走

41
00:04:53,714 --> 00:04:54,733
别动

42
00:04:58,438 --> 00:05:00,265
请求支援

43
00:05:29,301 --> 00:05:30,762
别动 趴下不准动

44
00:06:04,643 --> 00:06:06,629
你们快点离开

45
00:06:06,750 --> 00:06:07,795
好的马上

46
00:06:11,448 --> 00:06:13,844
所有人员就位

47
00:06:16,219 --> 00:06:17,898
里面发现混种

48
00:06:18,264 --> 00:06:19,275
不要开火

49
00:06:19,397 --> 00:06:20,734
这只要活的

50
00:06:26,159 --> 00:06:27,292
德耳塔小队就位

51
00:06:27,413 --> 00:06:28,005
后面

52
00:06:28,125 --> 00:06:29,518
安全 快 快 快

53
00:06:29,640 --> 00:06:31,939
阿尔法分队已进入

54
00:06:36,619 --> 00:06:37,914
银榴弹已装

55
00:06:39,963 --> 00:06:40,690
Micheal (麦克尔)

56
00:06:40,812 --> 00:06:42,080
开火

57
00:06:54,331 --> 00:06:57,229
-阿尔法4前进  -目标锁定  -开火

58
00:07:11,011 --> 00:07:12,178
-注意附近状况 -收到

59
00:07:38,733 --> 00:07:39,650
重新安放实验体

60
00:07:58,155 --> 00:08:00,328
实验体二号逃脱

61
00:08:00,690 --> 00:08:22,043
警报  实验体二号逃脱  警报

62
00:08:23,000 --> 00:08:28,509
实验体一号冷冻舱 解冻程序启动

63
00:08:35,113 --> 00:08:39,288
解冻完成  实验体二号脱逃

64
00:08:39,409 --> 00:08:42,050
决不能让她跑了

65
00:09:42,189 --> 00:09:44,878
六层侵害警报

66
00:09:45,000 --> 00:09:47,133
安保人员去六层

67
00:10:08,043 --> 00:10:08,472
头儿

68
00:10:08,718 --> 00:10:10,976
实验体二号已逃出躲在这楼里

69
00:10:14,245 --> 00:10:15,875
一号实验体是否已锁好

70
00:10:16,707 --> 00:10:17,723
情况如何

71
00:10:17,846 --> 00:10:19,056
实验体二号已彻底脱出

72
00:10:19,177 --> 00:10:20,519
我们需要启动焚化装置

73
00:10:20,820 --> 00:10:21,296
不 等等

74
00:10:21,417 --> 00:10:22,488
我先看看

75
00:10:34,334 --> 00:10:36,043
让她睡吧

76
00:10:39,060 --> 00:10:39,953
执行吧

77
00:10:43,272 --> 00:10:45,576
麻醉气体释放中

78
00:11:07,613 --> 00:11:08,930
逃走的是什么

79
00:11:10,684 --> 00:11:11,430
Micheal 在哪儿

80
00:11:33,358 --> 00:11:35,832
紧急事态 全楼清查

81
00:11:37,108 --> 00:11:38,508
其他人马上撤离

82
00:11:43,511 --> 00:11:44,346
她在这儿

83
00:11:44,376 --> 00:11:45,137
停下

84
00:11:45,258 --> 00:11:46,731
别动

85
00:11:57,524 --> 00:11:59,642
六层出现伤亡

86
00:11:59,524 --> 00:12:03,847
六层保持警戒状态

87
00:12:03,968 --> 00:12:07,115
重复 支援六层

88
00:12:27,907 --> 00:12:29,713
她要逃了 派保安来

89
00:12:29,834 --> 00:12:31,034
不用 让她走

90
00:12:31,154 --> 00:12:32,722
她会带我们找到二号实验体

91
00:12:32,843 --> 00:12:33,634
不要开枪

92
00:12:34,963 --> 00:12:35,614
让她走

93
00:13:06,806 --> 00:13:10,629
一号二号实验体已逃出包围

94
00:13:10,749 --> 00:13:13,266
加强出入口防御

95
00:13:13,388 --> 00:13:19,184
外部安保人员···

96
00:13:44,377 --> 00:13:47,049
[军用装备库房]

97
00:13:47,090 --> 00:13:49,496
上报联邦所有疑似感染事件
不得外出 任何反常现象须上报···

98
00:14:04,013 --> 00:14:07,276
[ 血族和狼族牙齿 ]

99
00:14:56,594 --> 00:14:57,855
嘿 你怎么进去的

100
00:14:59,170 --> 00:15:00,322
这里不准进入

101
00:15:01,531 --> 00:15:02,730
这里封闭了

102
00:15:03,428 --> 00:15:04,503
多久了

103
00:15:05,845 --> 00:15:06,797
好久了

104
00:15:07,390 --> 00:15:08,118
出来吧

105
00:15:09,775 --> 00:15:10,633
有多久

106
00:15:12,902 --> 00:15:14,345
十二年了

107
00:15:15,600 --> 00:15:17,280
从那次事件之后

108
00:15:17,402 --> 00:15:17,858
怎么了

109
00:15:19,140 --> 00:15:20,103
你没事吧 女士

110
00:15:20,545 --> 00:15:21,585
各单位注意

111
00:15:21,708 --> 00:15:25,683
接到报案 39号地下过道 发生遇袭案

112
00:15:25,805 --> 00:15:28,844
小心排查附近可疑生物

113
00:15:28,967 --> 00:15:31,997
数字中心已开启 附近各单位请回复

114
00:15:34,498 --> 00:15:35,427
女士

115
00:15:37,155 --> 00:15:37,693
女士

116
00:16:06,724 --> 00:16:08,031
你在那儿做什么

117
00:16:08,152 --> 00:16:10,188
离开那里

118
00:16:10,310 --> 00:16:11,404
快过来

119
00:16:30,772 --> 00:16:33,192
不管是什么做的  都不可能逃太远

120
00:16:33,746 --> 00:16:36,203
整个城市都开始围捕了

121
00:16:36,551 --> 00:16:37,946
这不是人类的手法

122
00:16:38,370 --> 00:16:39,289
你不懂

123
00:16:40,734 --> 00:16:41,592
不懂什么

124
00:16:42,297 --> 00:16:44,794
气管被撕碎 整个脖子都快没了

125
00:16:44,916 --> 00:16:46,292
让我处理吧

126
00:16:46,413 --> 00:16:47,760
还用想么

127
00:16:47,883 --> 00:16:49,175
肯定是狼人

128
00:16:49,296 --> 00:16:49,989
探员

129
00:16:50,111 --> 00:16:53,003
你最后一次听到狼人袭击事件是多久前

130
00:16:54,820 --> 00:16:55,825
有好几年前了

131
00:16:55,945 --> 00:16:57,939
你来这个部门多久了

132
00:16:59,502 --> 00:17:01,136
你什么意思 我来了三个月了

133
00:17:01,257 --> 00:17:01,961
就是那个意思

134
00:17:03,180 --> 00:17:05,488
你的问题是 知道得太少了

135
00:17:06,082 --> 00:17:06,931
清楚了么

136
00:17:07,392 --> 00:17:08,090
清楚了

137
00:17:11,837 --> 00:17:13,090
我是 Sebastian (赛巴斯蒂安)探长

138
00:17:13,740 --> 00:17:15,034
刚收到报告

139
00:17:15,155 --> 00:17:16,936
Antigen (抗原研究所)发生状况

140
00:17:17,369 --> 00:17:21,497
目击者说有人跳窗逃了

141
00:17:21,619 --> 00:17:24,162
这作为重点调查

142
00:17:24,284 --> 00:17:26,105
你要亲自去查证

143
00:17:26,226 --> 00:17:27,120
这就去

144
00:17:28,093 --> 00:17:28,995
咱们走吧

145
00:17:29,555 --> 00:17:30,504
Johnson 交给你了

146
00:17:30,625 --> 00:17:31,483
好的

147
00:17:48,745 --> 00:17:49,486
谁是主管

148
00:17:51,882 --> 00:17:52,281
来了个

149
00:17:53,480 --> 00:17:55,254
凶案科的探长 Sebastian

150
00:17:57,752 --> 00:17:58,681
人呢

151
00:17:59,895 --> 00:18:01,132
在大堂

152
00:18:05,715 --> 00:18:08,479
请放心 状况已被完全控制

153
00:18:08,960 --> 00:18:09,406
这出了什么事

154
00:18:10,171 --> 00:18:11,203
我再说一次 已完全控制

155
00:18:11,327 --> 00:18:12,550
我再问一次 出了什么事

156
00:18:13,752 --> 00:18:14,324
好吧

157
00:18:14,832 --> 00:18:16,578
会有个书面报告

158
00:18:17,705 --> 00:18:18,960
有个实验体

159
00:18:19,082 --> 00:18:19,896
企图逃脱

160
00:18:20,017 --> 00:18:21,335
我们不得不消灭它

161
00:18:22,448 --> 00:18:23,579
这么说 没东西逃走

162
00:18:24,193 --> 00:18:25,130
的确如此

163
00:18:25,823 --> 00:18:26,436
实验体呢

164
00:18:26,949 --> 00:18:27,286
焚化了

165
00:18:28,266 --> 00:18:28,956
常有的事

166
00:18:29,662 --> 00:18:30,853
总有不安分的

167
00:18:31,193 --> 00:18:31,926
不是什么大事

168
00:18:32,469 --> 00:18:34,576
博士 有匿名举报说

169
00:18:34,696 --> 00:18:35,417
有东西

170
00:18:35,540 --> 00:18:36,425
跳窗逃了

171
00:18:37,011 --> 00:18:37,732
探长

172
00:18:38,069 --> 00:18:41,812
我来这里是为了找到防止感染方法的

173
00:18:41,932 --> 00:18:44,678
不是让大众受其伤害的

174
00:18:45,178 --> 00:18:47,790
我要告诉你   我儿子因为感染死了

175
00:18:48,385 --> 00:18:50,016
我没有犯错的权利

176
00:18:50,317 --> 00:18:52,473
我是为了保证大众安全才来的

177
00:18:52,595 --> 00:18:55,513
真有东西逃了肯定会请当局支援

178
00:18:56,602 --> 00:18:58,096
您就代表当局 不是么

179
00:19:00,027 --> 00:19:01,395
好了 再会吧

180
00:19:25,761 --> 00:19:27,275
管事的说没有

181
00:19:28,066 --> 00:19:28,710
走吧

182
00:19:29,119 --> 00:19:30,307
真的那么肯定么

183
00:19:31,123 --> 00:19:31,833
看这个

184
00:19:33,759 --> 00:19:34,867
上报不

185
00:19:34,989 --> 00:19:36,980
这个我来

186
00:19:37,104 --> 00:19:38,284
我不在乎 我来帮你

187
00:19:41,175 --> 00:19:42,641
听你的

188
00:20:06,831 --> 00:20:08,198
那个帮我逃走的人

189
00:20:09,132 --> 00:20:10,790
就是你们说的 实验体二号

190
00:20:12,036 --> 00:20:12,899
是不是混血的

191
00:20:14,445 --> 00:20:15,327
是的

192
00:20:15,751 --> 00:20:17,087
你们对我们做了什么

193
00:20:20,076 --> 00:20:23,125
为政府甄别感染者

194
00:20:23,247 --> 00:20:25,727
用你们的DNA研究抗感染药物

195
00:20:26,417 --> 00:20:27,710
防止感染再次爆发

196
00:20:28,305 --> 00:20:30,642
告诉你 我跟混血间有特异连系

197
00:20:30,937 --> 00:20:31,935
为什么会这样

198
00:20:32,789 --> 00:20:34,920
实验体二号是保密的

199
00:20:35,474 --> 00:20:36,993
我没有权限

200
00:20:38,053 --> 00:20:38,862
撒谎

201
00:20:43,588 --> 00:20:44,743
不 不要

202
00:20:44,864 --> 00:20:47,529
我只知道你与二号有特殊感应

203
00:20:47,652 --> 00:20:51,136
只要你们靠近 相互就会产生同种反应

204
00:20:51,257 --> 00:20:53,828
你们能相互传达视感

205
00:20:55,864 --> 00:20:58,036
不 相信我 放了我吧

206
00:20:58,158 --> 00:21:00,272
咱们离开这儿

207
00:21:33,580 --> 00:21:34,243
什么东西

208
00:21:35,210 --> 00:21:36,478
爬来爬去的玩意

209
00:21:36,599 --> 00:21:38,526
走吧

210
00:22:39,015 --> 00:22:40,071
别开枪

211
00:22:40,609 --> 00:22:41,069
给个理由

212
00:22:41,810 --> 00:22:42,695
同族

213
00:22:46,796 --> 00:22:48,384
跟着我干嘛

214
00:22:48,820 --> 00:22:50,255
我们监听了警察的线路

215
00:22:50,844 --> 00:22:51,412
我们

216
00:22:51,533 --> 00:22:53,422
你知道是什么袭击的人类么

217
00:22:54,133 --> 00:22:54,796
就在桥下那里

218
00:22:55,762 --> 00:22:56,212
不知道

219
00:23:00,441 --> 00:23:01,381
狼人

220
00:23:02,210 --> 00:23:03,161
真奇怪

221
00:23:06,172 --> 00:23:08,650
大清洗后 从没见过这种情况

222
00:23:08,775 --> 00:23:10,855
这么密集的追捕

223
00:23:10,975 --> 00:23:12,823
这后面的关联

224
00:23:12,946 --> 00:23:15,372
肯定找着什么

225
00:23:17,204 --> 00:23:19,141
告诉我到底是怎么回事

226
00:23:34,633 --> 00:23:35,043
Michael  (麦克尔)

227
00:24:18,280 --> 00:24:18,847
你认识她么

228
00:24:20,087 --> 00:24:20,748
不认识

229
00:24:28,028 --> 00:24:29,211
它们等下会带来一群

230
00:24:30,951 --> 00:24:32,181
不能再待在这儿

231
00:24:50,960 --> 00:24:51,939
选那辆货车

232
00:24:58,505 --> 00:24:59,349
上去 快快

233
00:25:17,269 --> 00:25:18,709
后面追来三只

234
00:26:35,311 --> 00:26:37,461
别怕 待在后面

235
00:27:03,844 --> 00:27:08,985
[   杀 ! ! !   ]

236
00:27:31,394 --> 00:27:32,276
你开吧

237
00:28:19,823 --> 00:28:20,507
她无法自愈

238
00:28:20,911 --> 00:28:22,169
我们有医生 能救她

239
00:28:23,018 --> 00:28:23,876
在洞穴营地

240
00:28:25,518 --> 00:28:26,821
你怎么找到我的

241
00:28:29,727 --> 00:28:30,500
你叫什么

242
00:28:31,825 --> 00:28:33,130
实验体二号

243
00:28:33,651 --> 00:28:35,842
你是实验体一号

244
00:28:37,554 --> 00:28:39,014
是我放的你

245
00:28:41,767 --> 00:28:43,246
你不认识我么

246
00:28:45,350 --> 00:28:47,193
他们说我没有妈妈

247
00:28:47,930 --> 00:28:49,746
我出生后她就死了

248
00:28:51,992 --> 00:28:52,909
我不信他们说的

249
00:28:53,132 --> 00:28:53,554
我

250
00:28:54,207 --> 00:28:56,021
我能感应到你

251
00:28:56,967 --> 00:28:58,657
看到你双眼所见的

252
00:29:00,008 --> 00:29:02,249
但是 有人在我门外说

253
00:29:03,579 --> 00:29:06,998
他们说 我不再是小孩了

254
00:29:09,520 --> 00:29:10,845
很快就会被杀掉

255
00:29:11,943 --> 00:29:14,213
接着 就会是妈妈

256
00:29:15,071 --> 00:29:17,113
那个我都不知道是否存在的

257
00:29:19,608 --> 00:29:21,751
他们有没有说起你父亲

258
00:29:23,169 --> 00:29:24,479
说过他的事么

259
00:29:25,064 --> 00:29:26,405
你能感应他的所见么

260
00:29:27,263 --> 00:29:27,998
不能

261
00:29:29,042 --> 00:29:30,053
只有你

262
00:29:48,288 --> 00:29:50,074
她从未离开这栋楼

263
00:29:50,197 --> 00:29:51,852
她怎么活下来

264
00:29:52,185 --> 00:29:54,725
我想你该向上汇报此事

265
00:29:55,225 --> 00:29:58,440
她是混血 不知道会造成怎样的后果

266
00:29:58,970 --> 00:30:00,019
她要死了的话

267
00:30:00,721 --> 00:30:01,613
这么多年的研究

268
00:30:01,734 --> 00:30:03,100
不用你告诉我该怎样做

269
00:30:03,221 --> 00:30:04,986
拿出你专业的冷静来

270
00:30:06,190 --> 00:30:07,918
你怎么能一直坚持

271
00:30:08,041 --> 00:30:10,007
把她当人来看

272
00:30:10,132 --> 00:30:12,342
没把她看严

273
00:30:13,347 --> 00:30:14,393
那不是人

274
00:30:14,812 --> 00:30:15,663
也不是你家孩子

275
00:30:16,059 --> 00:30:17,551
更不是可以抱的萌物

276
00:30:17,674 --> 00:30:19,298
那是人间霉烂的恶源

277
00:30:23,494 --> 00:30:24,101
不要急

278
00:30:24,224 --> 00:30:25,031
她会回来的

279
00:31:57,941 --> 00:31:59,508
快叫奥利维亚来

280
00:32:03,930 --> 00:32:06,922
你又违反我的禁令  为什么

281
00:32:07,241 --> 00:32:08,702
她被咬了

282
00:32:09,507 --> 00:32:10,542
自愈力有问题

283
00:32:10,773 --> 00:32:12,645
就为这 连大家的安危都不顾了

284
00:32:13,547 --> 00:32:16,534
不必对我们有顾虑

285
00:32:19,014 --> 00:32:21,888
你当我是傻子 会信你那套

286
00:32:23,590 --> 00:32:27,328
对你这位跟狼人相爱的死神谁不害怕

287
00:32:27,870 --> 00:32:29,466
谋害了几位长老

288
00:32:30,108 --> 00:32:33,235
这些都是背叛同族的铁证

289
00:32:35,751 --> 00:32:37,529
你知道她是谁

290
00:32:39,928 --> 00:32:40,553
是的

291
00:32:41,116 --> 00:32:42,778
但那是因为你们先背叛了她

292
00:32:45,421 --> 00:32:46,266
让医生过来

293
00:32:47,905 --> 00:32:49,880
她自愈不了

294
00:33:01,143 --> 00:33:02,878
她被低阶狼人咬了

295
00:33:04,451 --> 00:33:05,215
有两个小时了

296
00:33:08,048 --> 00:33:09,378
她的自愈力

297
00:33:10,516 --> 00:33:11,394
是有的

298
00:33:12,257 --> 00:33:13,028
但是很弱

299
00:33:16,441 --> 00:33:17,860
她没留下

300
00:33:18,636 --> 00:33:20,340
最初的咬痕

301
00:33:21,506 --> 00:33:22,584
也没有疤痕

302
00:33:24,100 --> 00:33:26,133
我从未见过这种情况

303
00:33:27,672 --> 00:33:29,013
你 "上一餐" 是什么时候

304
00:33:29,855 --> 00:33:30,849
进食 ?

305
00:33:32,734 --> 00:33:33,455
把血给她

306
00:33:42,502 --> 00:33:45,014
孩子   你必须喝

307
00:34:05,405 --> 00:34:06,366
慢一点

308
00:34:09,967 --> 00:34:10,973
就这样

309
00:34:11,903 --> 00:34:13,601
很好

310
00:34:17,763 --> 00:34:18,877
她开始自愈了

311
00:34:21,356 --> 00:34:22,454
非常快

312
00:34:23,010 --> 00:34:23,467
好了

313
00:34:23,595 --> 00:34:25,391
抬我房里 她得休息

314
00:34:25,519 --> 00:34:26,579
慢着

315
00:34:27,857 --> 00:34:28,984
看她的眼睛

316
00:34:39,792 --> 00:34:41,491
真难以置信

317
00:34:42,204 --> 00:34:43,161
它真的存在

318
00:34:44,906 --> 00:34:46,926
她不属于任何一族

319
00:34:47,666 --> 00:34:48,749
还有更多的不同

320
00:34:52,353 --> 00:34:53,635
你了解她的情况么

321
00:34:57,049 --> 00:34:59,256
我被囚在个叫 Antigen (抗原研究所) 的地方

322
00:35:00,962 --> 00:35:02,457
一个被囚的同伴救了我

323
00:35:04,064 --> 00:35:05,799
我想是 Michael Corvin -麦克尔·柯文

324
00:35:06,648 --> 00:35:09,119
就是那个被两族感染而成的混种

325
00:35:09,245 --> 00:35:11,208
你那个人狼小哥不是早死了么

326
00:35:11,338 --> 00:35:12,879
她到底是怎么回事

327
00:35:14,464 --> 00:35:15,279
这不用你管

328
00:35:17,079 --> 00:35:19,165
等她恢复了我们就走

329
00:35:58,139 --> 00:36:00,058
我听过死亡组合的传说

330
00:36:02,311 --> 00:36:07,858
只是永不会归来的老式人物

331
00:36:09,197 --> 00:36:10,536
我很高兴他们都错了

332
00:36:12,560 --> 00:36:13,404
你知道我是谁

333
00:36:16,396 --> 00:36:17,927
仍然带我们来这儿

334
00:36:20,822 --> 00:36:21,476
谢谢

335
00:36:22,526 --> 00:36:23,610
你是战士

336
00:36:24,812 --> 00:36:26,687
你能教我们战斗

337
00:36:27,625 --> 00:36:29,293
你父亲不会同意的

338
00:36:29,809 --> 00:36:31,221
过一段时间就好了

339
00:36:31,706 --> 00:36:33,727
毕竟相互间有过不愉快

340
00:36:33,853 --> 00:36:37,647
他会想起来的   是你在为保护血族一直战斗

341
00:36:37,775 --> 00:36:40,221
想起以前的种种血族荣光

342
00:36:40,349 --> 00:36:41,708
他知道我们需要你

343
00:36:43,690 --> 00:36:44,760
我做不了领袖

344
00:36:44,888 --> 00:36:46,778
但你要为自己的信念而战

345
00:36:47,378 --> 00:36:48,768
你一向如此

346
00:36:49,071 --> 00:36:51,359
我有点搞不清状况了

347
00:36:51,486 --> 00:36:53,942
这个世界变了

348
00:36:54,069 --> 00:36:55,648
但你还是你

349
00:36:56,959 --> 00:36:59,338
你看那孩子的激动眼神  我见到了

350
00:37:00,325 --> 00:37:01,984
你要保护好她

351
00:37:02,900 --> 00:37:03,937
她你的血脉

352
00:37:04,472 --> 00:37:05,605
是你们的孩子

353
00:37:07,697 --> 00:37:09,516
要走把我带上

354
00:38:14,499 --> 00:38:16,280
你不喜欢我

355
00:38:23,584 --> 00:38:25,789
不怪你  我的确不欢迎你

356
00:38:26,342 --> 00:38:27,734
这个很抱歉

357
00:38:29,873 --> 00:38:30,923
我真切看到的

358
00:38:33,116 --> 00:38:34,354
你的双眼

359
00:38:35,721 --> 00:38:36,941
的确与众不同

360
00:38:39,511 --> 00:38:42,380
我知道你是什么

361
00:38:55,242 --> 00:38:57,499
我父亲说他能挽救整个种族

362
00:38:58,683 --> 00:39:01,885
大家全靠这里所有的一切幸免于难

363
00:39:02,632 --> 00:39:03,596
你的意思是

364
00:39:04,801 --> 00:39:06,756
不能继续藏在这儿了

365
00:39:06,903 --> 00:39:09,113
不修正自身的错误怎会有未来

366
00:39:10,220 --> 00:39:12,485
我们必须反抗人类

367
00:39:13,109 --> 00:39:14,529
无论如何都要反抗

368
00:39:14,968 --> 00:39:17,176
那你就是第二个样板

369
00:39:17,895 --> 00:39:19,093
狼人已经用过了

370
00:39:19,220 --> 00:39:22,683
挑起血族内部叛变 反抗长老们

371
00:39:22,918 --> 00:39:24,561
引发一场血难

372
00:39:24,689 --> 00:39:25,850
那次之后

373
00:39:26,458 --> 00:39:27,306
唯一成果是

374
00:39:27,820 --> 00:39:30,326
狼族的兴旺

375
00:39:32,142 --> 00:39:34,471
你就这么希望我族灭亡么

376
00:39:35,757 --> 00:39:38,043
你还擅自把她的崽子也带来这里

377
00:39:38,661 --> 00:39:42,218
你该明白 人类绝不会放过她的

378
00:39:42,661 --> 00:39:44,604
会不顾一切的把她逮回去

379
00:39:44,732 --> 00:39:45,817
我们可以保护她们

380
00:39:46,124 --> 00:39:47,337
保护

381
00:39:48,367 --> 00:39:49,884
今晚让她们走

382
00:39:50,647 --> 00:39:51,766
这是短视的

383
00:39:51,892 --> 00:39:53,600
是死板和懦弱

384
00:39:56,228 --> 00:39:57,470
你敢这么说

385
00:39:58,535 --> 00:39:59,660
那你呢

386
00:40:01,443 --> 00:40:02,455
那么自私

387
00:40:33,836 --> 00:40:35,436
我一直想着 遇见你的这天

388
00:40:39,201 --> 00:40:40,812
像个傻瓜一样

389
00:40:47,923 --> 00:40:50,128
是啊 她心真冷 她是死了

390
00:40:55,042 --> 00:40:57,237
想象一下 在前一天

391
00:40:57,363 --> 00:41:00,013
我还跟你父亲在一起

392
00:41:02,653 --> 00:41:05,311
就跟你我现在这样亲近着

393
00:41:08,236 --> 00:41:09,237
睡下了

394
00:41:11,799 --> 00:41:13,199
第二天醒来

395
00:41:15,309 --> 00:41:16,568
一夜之间

396
00:41:18,356 --> 00:41:19,441
就过去了十二年

397
00:41:22,370 --> 00:41:24,694
这世间我最爱的男人

398
00:41:26,980 --> 00:41:29,432
在他的眼眸里还留着我的身影

399
00:41:33,894 --> 00:41:35,439
我不是心冷

400
00:41:36,488 --> 00:41:37,730
是心碎了

401
00:41:42,178 --> 00:41:42,978
对不起孩子

402
00:41:53,913 --> 00:41:54,738
怎么了

403
00:41:57,540 --> 00:41:58,631
他们追来了

404
00:42:00,224 --> 00:42:02,197
留着这里 等着我

405
00:42:02,344 --> 00:42:03,918
求你了 带上我

406
00:42:04,912 --> 00:42:06,537
我不会让任何人伤害你

407
00:42:07,231 --> 00:42:08,231
我发誓

408
00:42:08,875 --> 00:42:10,326
锁好门

409
00:42:11,838 --> 00:42:13,538
大家都进庇护所

410
00:42:15,485 --> 00:42:16,365
都回来

411
00:42:17,340 --> 00:42:18,220
准备武器

412
00:42:18,780 --> 00:42:20,191
按我说的办 快走

413
00:42:20,319 --> 00:42:21,773
都快离开

414
00:42:22,361 --> 00:42:24,614
跟我一起去藏身地

415
00:42:24,741 --> 00:42:25,561
不

416
00:42:25,686 --> 00:42:28,180
我们不走 我们要战斗到底

417
00:42:43,475 --> 00:42:44,410
不要

418
00:42:44,814 --> 00:42:46,018
太危险了

419
00:42:50,180 --> 00:42:51,479
都给我停下

420
00:42:52,812 --> 00:42:56,254
这么多年 我们一直很安全 现在你把人类给招来了

421
00:42:56,381 --> 00:42:59,560
他们铁了心要抓那个女孩

422
00:42:59,685 --> 00:43:00,772
没这事 这天也会来

423
00:43:00,899 --> 00:43:02,071
我们来不来都一样

424
00:43:02,196 --> 00:43:03,074
-可我认为      -开始行动

425
00:43:03,209 --> 00:43:05,072
剩下的人都跟我来

426
00:43:05,199 --> 00:43:06,303
你疯了

427
00:43:06,430 --> 00:43:08,564
我们再也不是刀枪不入的战士了

428
00:43:08,691 --> 00:43:10,432
会被连锅端的

429
00:43:10,581 --> 00:43:11,891
父亲 那你有什么计划

430
00:43:12,018 --> 00:43:13,398
大家跟我来

431
00:43:14,617 --> 00:43:16,217
你女儿呢

432
00:43:16,343 --> 00:43:17,939
我跟她一起离开这儿

433
00:43:18,066 --> 00:43:19,718
你父亲是对的 我不该来

434
00:43:19,844 --> 00:43:21,050
他不明白现状

435
00:43:21,177 --> 00:43:22,572
人类会一直跟着

436
00:43:22,699 --> 00:43:24,024
你们挡住他们一阵就行

437
00:43:25,112 --> 00:43:26,228
她不能待这里

438
00:43:27,042 --> 00:43:28,765
她会比我们任何人都强大

439
00:43:29,380 --> 00:43:31,017
他们害怕这点

440
00:43:31,947 --> 00:43:33,283
我必须走了

441
00:44:11,667 --> 00:44:13,575
是狼人

442
00:44:17,670 --> 00:44:18,671
换硝酸银子弹

443
00:44:18,798 --> 00:44:19,528
马上

444
00:44:19,889 --> 00:44:21,511
保护族人

445
00:44:21,637 --> 00:44:22,290
快

446
00:45:07,560 --> 00:45:08,379
开门

447
00:45:11,329 --> 00:45:11,654
走吧

448
00:45:35,679 --> 00:45:36,698
快走

449
00:46:17,685 --> 00:46:18,424
咱们走吧

450
00:46:44,581 --> 00:46:45,620
那是什么鬼东西

451
00:46:49,185 --> 00:46:50,524
把她带到安全地方

452
00:46:50,651 --> 00:46:51,253
不

453
00:46:51,380 --> 00:46:52,753
快带她走

454
00:49:35,396 --> 00:49:36,632
她呢

455
00:49:37,357 --> 00:49:38,532
让他们带走了

456
00:49:39,819 --> 00:49:42,356
他们收下她了

457
00:49:43,243 --> 00:49:44,605
我的一份厚礼

458
00:50:25,277 --> 00:50:26,557
你知道你做了什么吗

459
00:50:27,570 --> 00:50:28,721
你根本不明白

460
00:50:29,103 --> 00:50:30,683
换你又该如何

461
00:50:31,668 --> 00:50:32,888
死战到最后一人么

462
00:50:33,014 --> 00:50:35,878
为了保护这个外人

463
00:50:36,515 --> 00:50:37,754
我们败了

464
00:50:38,497 --> 00:50:40,860
也毁了我儿子

465
00:50:40,987 --> 00:50:41,842
他死了

466
00:50:41,969 --> 00:50:43,217
就因为你

467
00:50:44,781 --> 00:50:45,452
为了什么

468
00:50:47,395 --> 00:50:49,915
为了要救你的孩子

469
00:50:50,269 --> 00:50:51,430
要是他们把她杀了

470
00:50:51,557 --> 00:50:52,406
随他们好了

471
00:50:52,541 --> 00:50:53,998
你儿子战死

472
00:50:54,576 --> 00:50:56,553
是为了你们

473
00:50:57,187 --> 00:50:59,730
他知道逃跑解决不了问题

474
00:51:01,882 --> 00:51:02,761
狼人已经

475
00:51:03,691 --> 00:51:04,703
明显变了

476
00:51:04,828 --> 00:51:06,305
比以前强大得多

477
00:51:07,258 --> 00:51:10,355
我从未见过 这种两倍大的 巨型狼人

478
00:51:12,033 --> 00:51:16,726
他们一直藏着  藏了十多年  就为了研究她

479
00:51:17,305 --> 00:51:19,427
你却把她拱手相让

480
00:51:21,796 --> 00:51:26,444
她是 亚历山大·柯文纳斯 的直系血脉

481
00:51:27,385 --> 00:51:28,509
这世上唯一的两族混血儿

482
00:51:28,878 --> 00:51:30,324
唯一的存在

483
00:51:32,346 --> 00:51:34,535
不管狼族想从她身上得到什么

484
00:51:36,330 --> 00:51:39,081
都是你儿子为之死战到底的东西

485
00:51:45,199 --> 00:51:45,938
你要做什么

486
00:52:16,619 --> 00:52:18,075
David  大卫

487
00:53:32,262 --> 00:53:36,302
昨晚两个狼人小队突袭了我族的一个避难所

488
00:53:38,998 --> 00:53:40,430
你一点也不吃惊

489
00:53:42,736 --> 00:53:44,438
你知道狼人没有灭绝

490
00:53:45,039 --> 00:53:45,531
怎么知道的

491
00:53:45,656 --> 00:53:46,550
只是直觉

492
00:53:47,669 --> 00:53:48,833
这我可不擅长

493
00:53:49,958 --> 00:53:51,209
告诉我要知道的

494
00:53:52,060 --> 00:53:53,673
在这儿不能说

495
00:53:55,004 --> 00:53:56,054
你也不会杀我

496
00:53:56,367 --> 00:53:57,007
你确定

497
00:53:57,612 --> 00:53:58,264
对

498
00:53:58,928 --> 00:54:00,600
你干掉我不需要这枪

499
00:54:04,400 --> 00:54:07,781
几年前政府就完成了狼人清洗任务

500
00:54:08,609 --> 00:54:11,617
现在一心集中精力处置你们

501
00:54:13,117 --> 00:54:15,133
三个月前 我朋友给我的

502
00:54:17,257 --> 00:54:21,740
收到这份文件两天后  他被发现在自家天花板上吊了

503
00:54:23,498 --> 00:54:26,162
两百多个狼族嫌犯

504
00:54:26,288 --> 00:54:29,504
全部都做了彻查 每个血样结果全是正常

505
00:54:29,632 --> 00:54:31,123
所以他怀疑

506
00:54:31,272 --> 00:54:33,895
有人暗中保护狼人

507
00:54:35,974 --> 00:54:38,162
保护他们组织他们

508
00:54:38,544 --> 00:54:39,988
那你所在的部门呢

509
00:54:42,715 --> 00:54:43,792
我女儿在他们那里

510
00:54:45,213 --> 00:54:46,745
我只想把她救回来

511
00:54:48,678 --> 00:54:50,737
我不在乎你想保护谁

512
00:54:50,963 --> 00:54:53,043
这不是在请求 我只要我女儿

513
00:54:53,523 --> 00:54:54,413
不行

514
00:54:55,732 --> 00:54:58,911
我的部门没有权限

515
00:54:59,813 --> 00:55:01,094
需要非常高的权限才行

516
00:55:02,254 --> 00:55:03,786
估计只有上面才有办法

517
00:55:06,134 --> 00:55:07,053
这底下是

518
00:55:07,918 --> 00:55:08,910
怎么了

519
00:55:09,856 --> 00:55:11,049
谁主持的检测

520
00:55:12,145 --> 00:55:15,810
时间紧迫 先看看这些资料

521
00:55:17,219 --> 00:55:22,172
这份表格是今后的几个月的行动计划

522
00:55:23,795 --> 00:55:27,716
一旦我们展开计划 三个月之内便能成功

523
00:55:27,869 --> 00:55:29,949
有问题现在就提

524
00:55:30,075 --> 00:55:35,560
今天讨论后 为了保密不能再有任何直接和间接的联系

525
00:55:35,685 --> 00:55:36,072
博士

526
00:55:36,333 --> 00:55:38,303
你的实验体

527
00:55:38,851 --> 00:55:41,349
他保持了对银的免疫么

528
00:55:41,631 --> 00:55:42,575
是的

529
00:55:43,361 --> 00:55:45,165
额外持续接种

530
00:55:45,539 --> 00:55:47,442
已是主要的免疫措施

531
00:55:48,010 --> 00:55:49,952
难以想象的两倍身材

532
00:55:50,260 --> 00:55:51,937
大幅度的力量增长

533
00:55:52,649 --> 00:55:53,519
肌肉变强

534
00:55:53,960 --> 00:55:54,934
自愈力

535
00:55:55,937 --> 00:55:57,030
强耐力

536
00:55:58,882 --> 00:56:00,892
你说她是我们研究的根基

537
00:56:01,220 --> 00:56:02,680
是的 我们会持续研究的

538
00:56:03,271 --> 00:56:03,937
怎么研究

539
00:56:04,352 --> 00:56:06,098
切开两半再研究么

540
00:56:06,777 --> 00:56:08,308
这是工作的一部分

541
00:56:08,435 --> 00:56:10,427
我照顾这个小姑娘

542
00:56:10,675 --> 00:56:11,995
这么多年

543
00:56:12,121 --> 00:56:14,162
你却要把我一脚踢开

544
00:56:14,458 --> 00:56:15,241
我为你

545
00:56:15,367 --> 00:56:17,215
收取她的基因材料就够了

546
00:56:18,310 --> 00:56:19,593
对你 我不期望什么

547
00:56:21,322 --> 00:56:22,947
我雇你来照顾她

548
00:56:23,332 --> 00:56:25,694
我不得不说 你做得很好

549
00:56:26,794 --> 00:56:28,972
救了上千人的命

550
00:56:30,143 --> 00:56:31,465
你在说什么

551
00:56:31,939 --> 00:56:34,757
整个种族免于灭亡

552
00:56:40,291 --> 00:56:40,939
我的天

553
00:57:26,335 --> 00:57:29,766
今天之后 你就可以随意注射药剂了

554
00:57:31,112 --> 00:57:32,370
你确定用她可以么

555
00:57:33,147 --> 00:57:34,432
激素在最高水平

556
00:57:35,120 --> 00:57:37,633
正是初潮来前的峰值状态

557
00:57:38,553 --> 00:57:39,710
就是她这个年纪

558
00:57:41,102 --> 00:57:42,255
一切就绪

559
00:57:42,873 --> 00:57:44,198
跟我们预想的一样

560
00:57:48,554 --> 00:57:50,330
你将成为第一个完美体

561
00:57:52,354 --> 00:57:53,455
我很高兴 儿子

562
00:57:58,772 --> 00:58:00,113
再来一轮注射

563
00:58:00,732 --> 00:58:03,396
我们会得到那些需要的遗传信息

564
00:58:04,221 --> 00:58:06,885
用它们生产源源不绝的新疫苗

565
00:58:08,805 --> 00:58:09,398
想想看

566
00:58:10,342 --> 00:58:12,554
我族不会再受银的伤害

567
00:58:13,188 --> 00:58:14,071
不再躲躲藏藏

568
00:58:15,130 --> 00:58:17,985
每个狼族首领都会跟你一样强大

569
00:58:19,399 --> 00:58:21,444
我真想先给自己一针

570
00:58:22,564 --> 00:58:24,210
看到这些 老妈会高兴的

571
00:58:26,178 --> 00:58:27,891
你母亲只想做凡人

572
00:58:30,345 --> 00:58:31,638
她不要我们了

573
00:58:34,699 --> 00:58:35,452
你记牢喽

574
00:58:50,371 --> 00:58:51,262
好的父亲

575
00:58:59,317 --> 00:59:00,580
现在去  Antigen（抗原研究所）

576
00:59:00,707 --> 00:59:03,102
我们不知道有多少狼人藏在哪里

577
00:59:04,955 --> 00:59:07,142
再说 直接闯进去会被包围的

578
00:59:07,270 --> 00:59:08,720
我要救她

579
00:59:10,366 --> 00:59:11,010
你要救她

580
00:59:11,137 --> 00:59:12,210
我能帮你

581
00:59:13,532 --> 00:59:13,934
怎么帮

582
00:59:14,061 --> 00:59:15,305
告诉我你的计划

583
00:59:40,871 --> 00:59:43,833
不要做无谓的反抗了

584
00:59:44,102 --> 00:59:45,461
相信我

585
00:59:48,106 --> 00:59:51,075
你在白天怎么还能行动自如

586
00:59:53,919 --> 00:59:54,927
别人送的礼物

587
00:59:56,330 --> 00:59:58,725
他叫 亚历山大·柯文纳斯

588
00:59:58,852 --> 01:00:00,946
两族之父

589
01:00:04,614 --> 01:00:07,007
我跟一个护士结的婚

590
01:00:09,278 --> 01:00:10,904
某天我上班 她被咬了

591
01:00:13,265 --> 01:00:17,011
没人知道 我们这样过了好几年

592
01:00:19,249 --> 01:00:20,741
然后清洗开始了

593
01:00:22,306 --> 01:00:25,866
他们挨家的敲门  却没有敲我们的

594
01:00:31,959 --> 01:00:34,058
她跟我说 她爱我 还说

595
01:00:36,588 --> 01:00:38,271
她喜欢白天

596
01:00:39,677 --> 01:00:42,414
然后 我看着她面向太阳化成了灰

597
01:01:07,629 --> 01:01:08,424
能听到么

598
01:01:09,904 --> 01:01:10,277
可以

599
01:01:11,767 --> 01:01:13,230
祝你好运

600
01:01:28,390 --> 01:01:29,109
靠 是她

601
01:01:29,235 --> 01:01:29,758
在白天

602
01:01:29,885 --> 01:01:31,339
别让她跑了

603
01:02:02,889 --> 01:02:04,253
我开杀之后  你跟上

604
01:02:04,381 --> 01:02:05,002
准备好了

605
01:02:10,720 --> 01:02:14,344
已从A门闯入 重复 目标从A门闯入 这里是一层控制台

606
01:02:14,470 --> 01:02:16,402
闯入者搭乘4号电梯

607
01:02:16,529 --> 01:02:19,209
所有警卫快去守住电梯出口

608
01:02:23,636 --> 01:02:24,418
都准备好了么

609
01:02:24,544 --> 01:02:25,128
是的

610
01:02:25,254 --> 01:02:25,605
很好

611
01:02:49,840 --> 01:02:52,796
所有人注意 围住电梯门

612
01:02:52,820 --> 01:02:55,716
闯入者将冲出 守住西出口

613
01:02:55,741 --> 01:02:58,006
所有警卫到电梯支援

614
01:02:58,032 --> 01:02:59,063
好了

615
01:03:00,085 --> 01:03:00,949
开始吧

616
01:03:20,177 --> 01:03:21,614
快跑

617
01:03:38,116 --> 01:03:38,968
该你了

618
01:03:39,610 --> 01:03:40,212
收到

619
01:03:41,255 --> 01:03:50,640
调教：dianwanren

620
01:04:10,531 --> 01:04:12,300
他们用了硝酸银粉末

621
01:04:12,436 --> 01:04:13,354
全楼都是

622
01:04:14,492 --> 01:04:15,570
是实验体一号

623
01:04:16,418 --> 01:04:17,425
我们需要转移

624
01:04:18,198 --> 01:04:18,735
好吧

625
01:04:19,632 --> 01:04:21,020
保持输液状态

626
01:04:21,657 --> 01:04:23,906
我们不是要取消操作 明白了么

627
01:04:24,725 --> 01:04:25,280
转移吧

628
01:04:27,177 --> 01:04:27,947
找到她

629
01:04:28,905 --> 01:04:30,751
撕了她

630
01:04:30,878 --> 01:04:32,131
好主意

631
01:04:46,074 --> 01:04:46,911
我就位了

632
01:04:47,234 --> 01:04:49,323
有车刚停在三层车库

633
01:04:49,452 --> 01:04:50,682
没见到孩子

634
01:04:50,809 --> 01:04:52,305
监视住他们

635
01:04:52,849 --> 01:04:54,402
别跟丢了

636
01:04:59,646 --> 01:05:00,810
他们在工作电梯

637
01:05:02,842 --> 01:05:03,647
抓住她

638
01:05:03,775 --> 01:05:05,044
来吧

639
01:05:28,606 --> 01:05:31,166
Selene  （ 塞琳娜 ）

640
01:05:31,619 --> 01:05:33,331
他们在二层车库

641
01:05:36,540 --> 01:05:37,170
Selene

642
01:05:37,957 --> 01:05:39,470
Selene 告诉我你的位置

643
01:05:50,944 --> 01:05:51,686
该死

644
01:06:06,593 --> 01:06:07,467
听到了么

645
01:06:08,308 --> 01:06:09,505
Selene 你在哪儿

646
01:06:39,643 --> 01:06:41,452
我看到她了 看到她了

647
01:06:41,823 --> 01:06:44,401
在二层车库 他们把你女儿运上车了

648
01:06:45,469 --> 01:06:46,768
Selene 你在哪儿

649
01:06:54,584 --> 01:06:56,148
不许进入 停下

650
01:07:09,892 --> 01:07:10,600
Michael  （ 麦克尔 ）

651
01:07:11,183 --> 01:07:11,999
在这儿呢

652
01:07:23,302 --> 01:07:24,363
Selene

653
01:07:24,489 --> 01:07:27,127
他们带她上车要走了  你在哪儿

654
01:07:27,693 --> 01:07:29,462
他们要带她跑了 你听见了么

655
01:07:31,649 --> 01:07:32,364
我马上来

656
01:09:01,748 --> 01:09:02,585
快点再快点

657
01:09:21,700 --> 01:09:22,465
别停

658
01:09:22,630 --> 01:09:23,739
撞过去

659
01:09:50,660 --> 01:09:52,484
他们到一层车库了

660
01:09:55,213 --> 01:09:57,324
Selene 快到一层车库出口

661
01:09:57,452 --> 01:09:58,547
听到没有

662
01:09:58,975 --> 01:09:59,781
我立刻到

663
01:10:23,492 --> 01:10:24,321
没问题吧

664
01:10:24,447 --> 01:10:25,959
情况稳定

665
01:10:26,086 --> 01:10:27,584
所有体征平稳

666
01:12:09,941 --> 01:12:10,673
去你的

667
01:12:54,106 --> 01:12:55,190
放开她

668
01:14:55,102 --> 01:14:57,188
有努力有回报

669
01:15:00,155 --> 01:15:01,533
你懂了吧

670
01:15:59,275 --> 01:16:01,863
我恢复很快的

671
01:16:02,718 --> 01:16:03,630
真的么

672
01:17:02,272 --> 01:17:03,651
你来找我了

673
01:17:08,829 --> 01:17:10,059
我说过的

674
01:17:11,590 --> 01:17:12,356
Selene

675
01:17:16,435 --> 01:17:17,795
快走吧

676
01:17:20,701 --> 01:17:22,172
离这儿不远有个安全屋

677
01:17:22,527 --> 01:17:25,007
快走吧  我支开他们

678
01:17:25,402 --> 01:17:26,445
帮你们争取点时间

679
01:17:27,561 --> 01:17:28,452
谢谢

680
01:17:28,803 --> 01:17:30,334
David  一起走

681
01:17:33,709 --> 01:17:34,595
我们还要进去么

682
01:17:35,507 --> 01:17:36,631
是的

683
01:17:54,544 --> 01:17:56,060
那是什么地方

684
01:17:56,564 --> 01:17:57,567
Michael 呢

685
01:17:59,964 --> 01:18:00,967
在顶层

686
01:18:07,542 --> 01:18:09,095
世界变了

687
01:18:10,057 --> 01:18:11,638
敌人却仍相同

688
01:18:12,955 --> 01:18:14,659
狼人被重新调制了

689
01:18:15,091 --> 01:18:18,657
孩子的父亲也因为同样的原因被追捕

690
01:18:20,112 --> 01:18:21,782
他们变强大了

691
01:18:23,312 --> 01:18:24,570
我们呢

692
01:18:25,571 --> 01:18:28,727
虽然血族的优势不再

693
01:18:29,760 --> 01:18:32,147
但我们仍会战胜狼族


