Jesus Christ!
It gets worse all the time!
Your job
doesn't get any better.
All shot in their beds,
execution style.
Only the mother
shot in the head.
What time you make it?
Give me a ballpark guess.
3:00... 3:15.
And that's pretty close.
Thanks.
How long
have you been waiting?
- Half an hour.
- Just a couple of minutes.
Over there,
that's the little gardening hut.
- You mean that's included?
- Sure.
It could be a guesthouse
with a little fixing up.
- A guesthouse?
- Sure.
Come on.
Right up here.
See how much property you have?
Isn't that lovely?
Be careful. Don't trip.
You'll see what a beauty this is.
There's nothing like it
on the market.
Not at this price.
- Come in.
- Thank you.
Impressive, isn't it?
I mean,
that's what I call charming.
- I'll show you the living room.
- Thank you.
That's a wood-burning fireplace.
It'll be nice on cold nights.
That's the sun porch.
Nice, isn't it?
- George, I don't think...
- Be cool.
- Would you like to see the kitchen?
- Yes, thank you.
This is the kitchen.
Nice and spacious, isn't it?
Really big.
Has all the original hardware,
and everything works.
This your first house?
We just got married.
Shall we look at the upstairs?
I like to refer to this as a fixer-upper
that can be fun.
We'll start with this.
This is an extra room.
This is the bathroom
connecting with the next bedroom.
This is the second bedroom.
There's a nice view
of the river from here.
If you're planning on a big family,
there are three full bedrooms.
We already have a family.
Two boys and a girl.
Great kids.
You are so bad.
- What?
- Cut it out.
Next is the master bedroom.
I love it.
There's just one more floor.
See anything you like...
we can include it in the price.
- Really?
- Sure.
This can be another bedroom...
or a playroom, whichever you prefer.
We'll wander around on our own again
now that we got the layout.
We can meet you downstairs.
How would that be?
I'll be in the kitchen.
Take your time.
We won't be long.
- What do you think?
- I love it.
Honey... $80,000?
I mean...
it might as well be $800,000.
Listen...
The house is worth
$120,000 easy.
If I move my office into that cottage
out back, that'll save that rent.
And the boathouse...
means I won't have to shell out
for mooring charges,
which they're raising,
by the way.
You didn't tell me that.
There was nothing
to be done about it.
I just wish that...
all those people
hadn't died here.
A guy kills his whole family?
Doesn't that bother you?
Sure, but...
houses don't have memories.
I don't know.
I do. The house
wouldn't even be for sale,
and if it was,
we couldn't afford it
if we had...
tuna casseroles for a year.
You're gonna be very happy.
It's a wonderful house.
I'm sure they'll accept your offer.
Don't worry about a thing.
I'll handle the details.
Just go on
and get ready to move.
They're not getting
too close to the river?
Uh-uh.
Sounds like a regular daddy
I hear over there.
I might feel like one if that's what they
started calling me instead of George.
Which I admit is better than that
Mr. Lutz crap they were giving me.
What do you
want to do with this?
Put it in the living room
on that wall beside the bookshelf,
and the light will come through...
it'll look beautiful.
You got it.
Voilà!
Aw, shit. Come on.
I'm tired of
this damn sticky paper.
I wish I'd listened to my mother
and gotten the kind that you tack down.
Nobody likes a quitter.
But I got an idea.
Get a couple of beers
and go outside and play?
What are those monsters up to?
Hello?
Anybody home?
George?
Kathy?
Anybody home?
Hello?
God's peace in this house.
Get out.
Get out!
Amy?
Honey, dinner's ready.
- I'll get her.
- I've got her.
You and the boys start.
I'll take her upstairs
and put her to bed.
She wasn't outside!
Where was she?
Be getting in there
and eat your hot dogs.
- Hello?
- Hell...
Hello, Kathy?
Can you hear me?
Father Delaney.
There's something very import...
Hello? Hello?
- Who was that?
- On the phone?
Yeah.
Just a bunch of static,
a bad connection or something.
I think Ma Bell's
gone wacko again.
Probably discover it was a collect call
from Japan when the bill comes.
Did you make sure that
Amy's got her doll with her?
Yeah. She's sleeping with it.
You hungry, honey?
You don't want one of those charbroiled
hot dogs I did especially for you?
No, I'm not hungry.
Damn, it's cold in here.
It felt cold a bit earlier,
but I think I've warmed up now.
It says 72.
It feels like 32.
Do you know
what I think it is?
There's a draft that
comes up from the basement
through that door down there.
This house is supposed to be
well insulated.
They'll nickel-and-dime you
to death.
Matt?
- Are you all right?
- Yeah.
- Did you hurt yourself?
- No.
Those stairs are tricky.
Come on.
I'll take you upstairs.
We'll check
this all out tomorrow.
I'm sorry, baby.
I didn't mean to scare you.
I look at you all the time.
I can't get used to you.
Who loves you?
I'm lucky.
- Come here.
- I just wanted to clean up first.
I love the way
you smell right now.
I love you.
I love you back.
You make me feel like a kid
in the back seat of a car.
I want us to work.
I want to be the best.
I don't want you
to have any regrets.
I love you, Kathy.
I want to go home.
Mommy, I want to go home.
What's this trouble?
Come on, back to bed.
This is our home.
Don't you know that?
There we go.
There you go, sweetie.
What's the matter,
having mean dreams?
Sleep tight.
It's not so easy, is it?
I guess people
have had to deal with this
ever since Adam and Eve
got kicked out of the Garden.
Just have to learn
to live with it.
Thank you.
You're one hell
of a watchdog, Harry.
Come on, boy.
Come on.
What do you say?
Looks okay, huh?
Don't ever do that.
Not to a man
with an ax in his hand.
I thought
I could get a little help.
- Look what you made me do.
- I made you do?
There's a week's worth of groceries
rolling down the walk.
- Wait till I finish this stuff.
- George, finish?
You have got enough wood here
to heat the whole South Shore.
You take this.
I'll get the rest.
I love you.
Broke a bulb.
Who drinks this
fancy kind of tea around here?
That's for Aunt Helena.
She's coming by around 2:00.
- Give me a break.
- Come on, be nice.
This is a big event
in my family.
We've always been
a bunch of renters.
This is the first time
anyone's bought a house.
Damn regimental inspection,
and we're not ready.
Sweetie pie, you scared me.
What do you want?
My friend Jody
wants to play upstairs.
Huh, Jody? See?
You and Jody go on up
and enjoy yourself.
Does your friend Jody
like sugar cookies, too?
- I don't think so.
- No?
Off you go.
This is Kathy Lutz.
Could I speak with Father Delarey?
I'm sorry, Mrs. Lutz.
The Father's not
feeling very well today.
He's asleep right now.
This is Father Bolen.
May I help you?
Father Bolen...
He was supposed to come by
and bless the house yesterday,
but it can wait
till he feels better.
I hope he's not too sick?
I think it's just
one of those flu things.
But, Mrs. Lutz, the Father
was at your house yesterday.
We were expecting him,
but he never showed up.
I know he left
to go there.
He didn’t come.
We waited all day.
Must've been
some kind of mix-up.
No big deal.
Just tell him "hi" and...
and that we hope
he's feeling better.
I sure will.
Thank you for calling.
I'll check Amy's bathroom.
Oh, does it stink!
Mom, it stinks!
Go down and let Aunt Helena in
and don't tell her about this, okay?
Do we have to?
She's always pinching!
- Go now!
- Come on.
Go on!
And be polite.
Well, hello... Matthew!
And Gregory!
And Harry!
Where's your mother, dear?
She said she'd
be down in a minute.
Aunt Helena?
Kathleen! I'm sorry.
I must've set it
too near the edge.
- I have to go.
- I don't understand.
I don't feel well at all.
I bought your favorite tea,
and I'll make you a cup.
I have to go.
I really feel terrible.
- If you rested a while, you'd feel...
- I can't stay!
- Please stay.
- I don't feel well!
- If you just rest and...
I can't stay. Forgive me.
George, please make her...
- Aren't you gonna come to bed?
- In a minute.
The fire went out.
Are you still cold?
I hope you're not
coming down with something.
I'll be all right.
I gotta stay healthy
for your brother's wedding.
Your hair's getting long.
Maybe you should
sleep in tomorrow.
I got work to do.
I don't want to be
up to my ass in boxes forever.
I'm sorry.
I don't know what
the hell's the matter with me.
- Silly, this happens all the time.
- Not to me it doesn't.
Stop pushing. You don't
have to prove anything to me.
Turn out the light.
I love you.
I love you back.
She was shot in the head!
You all right?
- Tell me something, Father.
- What?
Why couldn't this
wait till tomorrow?
I don't know. I...
All I know is
I have to get back to that house.
- Are you feeling all right?
- I'm fine. Fine, fine.
Father, there's something wrong
with the steering wheel.
I can't move the wheel.
What's wrong with this?
Harry, be quiet!
Be quiet!
Will you check this, please?
It's gotta come to 1,500 bucks
for the caterer.
- That sucker wants cash.
- Jimmy, will you relax?
You've counted it
about a thousand times.
You sure do look terrific.
You're not gonna
start to cry already?
It's just that yesterday,
I was riding you around
on the back of my bike.
And now you're getting married.
I sure am.
I'm just real happy for you.
That's all, hon.
Hey, there he is.
- George, you look terrible!
- So she keeps telling me.
It's some kind of
flu virus going around.
Amy's got it, too.
It's nothing.
If you're not up to it,
I'd understand.
I'm your best man.
- Come on, let's go.
- Okay.
Mrs. Lutz, am I supposed to
give Amy an aspirin or anything?
Just give her one
before bed, okay?
Okay.
- Are you gonna be okay?
- I don't know.
What's the matter?
- The money.
- What money?
The money for the caterer.
$1,500.
I put it in this pocket.
- It must've fallen out.
- It's not here.
I'll look under here.
Did you check your pants?
Calm down. It can't have
gotten up and walked away.
If you had it here,
it's gotta be here.
What am I gonna do?
I can't believe it!
Will you get those kids
off that horn?
Jimmy, George.
We have to go.
We're getting very late.
What am I gonna do?
It's gotta be here someplace.
We'll look when we get home.
What about the caterer?
I'll take care of him.
I'll write him a check.
Sweetie.
Okay?
I'll get the kids.
It's freezing in here!
It's time for bed, Amy.
I gotta give you an aspirin.
I don't wanna go to bed.
I wanna play with Jody.
Your mom said I had to
put you to bed early
because you've been sick.
Don't smart off to me.
I wasn't sick.
I just didn't like meatloaf.
Let's get you
into your pajamas.
Amy, open the door.
I'm in the closet.
Open the door.
Amy, I mean it!
Come to the door!
Open it!
For Christ's sake!
Open the door!
Amy, open the door!
For Christ's sake,
open the door!
How are you?
- Are you feeling better?
- Fine.
I want to apologize
for the other day.
- Don't worry.
- I don't know what happened.
I hadn't gone half a block
from your house,
and I was violently ill.
I think there's a virus
going around.
Father Delaney's got something,
and Amy's got something.
And I don't know
what's the matter with George.
I'll talk to you later, okay?
I'm gonna write you a check.
The deal was cash. Cash.
The cash is lost.
You gotta take a check.
I don't like checks.
Let me tell you something
about checks.
Checks get cancelled.
Checks bounce.
Checks is not cash.
Cash is cash.
Listen to me, pal...
I don't like lectures,
and I don't like
being hassled in the men's room.
I'm gonna write you a check.
Either that's
good enough for you,
or you're gonna eat
your own goddamn food.
Look at this...
I want cash,
and they're giving me checks.
You all right, honey?
I don't think I can make it
through the reception.
Let's get the kids and split.
I'll get the kids.
You take it easy.
Down.
Matt, get over here.
Matt, straight upstairs
and right to bed.
- But why?
- Upstairs.
- I'm not even tired!
- You are so tired.
I am not!
You're tired
'cause I said you're tired.
Cut that out.
I'll bring you
some milk and cookies.
Let me out.
Amy? Amy, are you okay?
Jackie?
- Oh, my God!
- I couldn't get out!
The door closed
and it locked,
and I couldn't get out!
- There's no lock on this door.
- It wouldn't open.
- Take a look.
- Look, see?
It wouldn't open!
Why didn't you open the door?
Why didn't you answer me?
Why didn't you unlock the door?
You heard Jackie knocking.
Jody wouldn't let me.
Jody? Who's Jody?
She's my friend.
She comes to play with me.
Jesus Christ! What the hell
are we standing here listening to?
And weren't you told
to go to bed?
Go on! Get out of here!
These kids of yours need
some goddamn discipline.
Here, let me see.
I'll go get something for them.
- George yelled at me.
- You should've opened the door!
Jody doesn't like George.
Where the hell is it?!
There's an explanation for all of it.
I'm not in the habit of blaming Satan
for every phenomenon.
Neither am I, Father.
Well, for a modernist,
who thought Vatican II
didn't go far enough,
don't you think
you sound a little medieval?
My being a modernist
has nothing to do with it.
I happened to
check into the murders
and the 20-year-old boy
who killed his parents
and his four brothers and sisters.
When he was at trial, he testified
that he heard voices in the house.
The voices told him to do it!
I was in the house,
and I heard the voices, too!
And I also felt
the presence in the house.
There was a presence
in that house!
Half the killers in this country
say the same thing.
"The voices.
The voices told me to do it. "
I heard them, Father!
I heard voices!
Then explain my hand
if you can do that.
Go on! Explain how
the car went out of control.
Father Bolen was with me.
You tell him.
The wheel locked,
and then the...
The wheel locked.
How about
a mechanical defect?
I'd blame Detroit
a lot faster than the devil.
Seems like every month
there's some kind of recall.
I see. We're just gonna
walk away from it.
Has that become
the fashion now, to cover up?
Nothing to walk away from.
- I think it's nonsense!
- There's nothing to cover up.
I think
it's bureaucratical bullshit!
What do you think I am?
I am not some
pink cheat seminarian
who doesn't know the difference
between the supernatural
and a bad clam.
I am a trained psychotherapist!
I went into that house!
What I saw there was real,
what I felt there was real,
and what I
heard there was real!
Gentlemen, I have a family
in my parish that's at great risk!
And they are facing
real danger.
Who the hell
do you think you are?!
You think your secular education
gives you the right
to question the Church?
Sit down!
Sit!
You haven't told us one thing
that can't be written off
as simple hysteria.
Even psychotherapists
lose touch with reality sometimes.
Your education
doesn't give you any immunity.
Father Nuncio and I
have seen our share of phenomena,
and never once did any of them
turn out to be Satanist!
Let's understand each other, Father.
To me, the Church...
It's my home.
The Church is my strength.
And I need her now.
And that family...
needs her... now.
Frank...
How long has it been
since you've seen your family?
What do you mean?
We think you
should take a vacation.
Good morning, Father.
Good day, Father.
You could do
with a haircut and shave.
- What do you think?
- Very uptown.
I thought you guys
had a small business.
Believe me, we do.
Getting smaller all the time.
What's the matter?
I don't want to go any closer.
Carolyn, what are you
talking about?
It gives me the creeps.
Hiya, George.
How's it going?
I wouldn't have come out
and bothered you,
but your line's always busy.
Nobody's seen you for days.
You haven't been in
to sign the payroll checks.
I did us both a favor
and brought them along.
- Here.
- What day is this?
Thursday.
I promised the men
I'd hand-deliver these.
Should've been paid yesterday.
Some caterer's screaming you wrote
him a personal check that bounced.
I should've covered that.
And some guy from the IRS
has been calling.
Don't you have any good news?
Yeah... I brought you
the spotlight for your boat.
Come on.
I'll put it on for you.
You girls think I don't know
what you're up to?
Well, I do.
And if I ever catch you again,
you're gonna be in big trouble.
You girls hear me?
Janet, you listening?
Now, don't be a smart-ass.
You quit that!
Stop teasing me!
What are you two rascals
doing in my room?
Oh, my God!
Goddamn thing feels like
it's nailed shut.
Push! Can't you just get it up?
Hold it up.
Don't let that down.
I'll drive, honey.
- Amazing.
- What?
Not one broken bone.
George, are you awake?
Isn't it strange that none of the bones
are broken in Greg's hand?
I have to talk to you.
- What was that?
- I don't know.
- You stay up here.
- Like hell!
Wait, wait.
Goddammit!
Don't sneak up on me!
You call the police.
I'm gonna go check on something.
It's okay, sweetie.
- Sarge, what brings you out?
- Insomnia.
- What do you got?
- Beats the hell out of me.
- This is Mrs. Lutz, Sergeant.
Mrs. Lutz.
And George Lutz.
- Is that L-u-t-z-e?
- No "e".
The basement door's
the same as the front.
- Where's the basement?
- Come on, I'll show you.
Who let you in?
What are you
doing there, boy?
No broken windows.
How long you been living here?
A couple of weeks.
Are you related to the family
that was here before?
Uh-uh.
You look a lot like them.
The kid had the same...
Harry, knock it off!
Have you had any trouble
with vandals or trespassers?
What's that supposed to mean?
Well... you've got a door
that was broken outward
from the inside.
Burglars break in, and you've got
a front door that's broken out.
Let me tell you something...
somebody broke into my house,
they heard me coming,
and they took off.
Okay. Then who broke
the basement door?
Maybe they came in
through the cellar...
then ran out the front door.
No. I checked all the windows
down there. None broken.
You think it was faster
to break it down than to open it?
There'll be a tighter watch
on your house.
You call us
if anything happens, okay?
Uh-huh.
Good night.
Night.
Why is it all going wrong?
We have to do something.
Jody says everything's
gonna get better.
What does Jody look like?
I mean... is Jody big
or thin or fat or...
She's nice.
- She tells me things, too.
- Like what does she tell you?
She tells me about the little boy
who used to live in my room.
He got hurt, and he died.
And what else
does Jody tell you?
She says she wants me
to live here forever and ever
so we can all play together.
Bye, sweeties.
Be home by 3:30, okay?
Be careful.
Oh, answer.
Please answer.
Hello?
Father, this is Kathy Lutz,
and I have to talk to you!
Listen to what I'm telling you...
Father?
O Lord, hear my prayer...
and hasten to answer me.
Hello.
Everybody wanted to come over
to welcome you to the neighborhood.
It's all right, isn't it?
Just a minute, please.
Hello?
Thanks for coming.
I thought I might be stood up.
Don't give me any crap.
I don't have time for it.
Relax, will ya?
I just wanna buy you a drink.
- Couple of beers, please?
- Gotcha.
Are you all right?
I mean, you look terrible.
Here you are, pal.
Jesus, I'm sorry.
You look just like that kid.
He was sitting right in that seat
when he was arrested.
What are you talking about?
The kid last year
that killed his family.
The house down by the river?
You're the spittin' image.
- So?
- So, I'll bring you another brew.
No offense.
I gotta get out of here.
I'll talk to you later.
No, now.
We gotta talk now.
The business is falling apart.
People are calling.
Bills have to be paid.
I know you're busy unpacking,
but life goes on.
I'm warning you,
I don't have the patience.
You're warning me.
Give me a break. Talk to me!
I knew this would happen.
I told you you were taking on too much.
- Just drop it!
- You marry a dame with three kids,
you buy a big house
with mortgages up to your ass,
you change your religion,
and you forget about business.
Okay... now can we talk?
Christ, man, I'm sorry.
I don't know
what I was thinking.
Okay. Come on.
Jesus loves me,
this I know
For the Bible tells me so
Little ones to Him belong
They are weak,
but He is strong
Yes, Jesus loves me
The Bible...
Who you singing to, princess?
You scared Jody.
Jody?
Look, there's no one here, see?
You scared her.
She went out the window.
She went out the window?
I'd better check and make sure
she's not still there.
The house is doing things.
I mean, windows open
by themselves.
Rooms full of flies
at the wrong time of year.
You saw what happened
to Greg's hand.
It's crazy.
Last night the front door
was ripped off its hinges
from the inside.
Of course!
It's right here, it's history.
John Ketchum.
- So?
- Listen.
They ran him out of Salem
for being a witch.
And he built his house
exactly where you're living.
You're living on
some sort of special ground...
devil worship...
death... sacrifice.
There's one simple rule...
Energy cannot be
created or destroyed.
It can only change forms.
Carolyn, will you get a grip
on yourself?
You sound like
some kind of psycho weirdo!
Come on, Jeffrey. Don't be
such a hard-core rationalist.
Everything in life
cannot be explained by a slide rule.
Thank you very much
for your cosmic views.
Now do me a favor, shut up!
Can I make
a rational suggestion, please?
Sure, man. Anything.
Go home, get cleaned up...
take Kathy out to dinner.
Carolyn and I
will baby-sit the kids.
You gotta get away from it,
even for a couple of hours,
and when you get back...
we'll add it all up.
We'll talk this thing through.
Okay.
Let's go home.
I'll go in and talk to Kathy,
and you all come in
in a couple of minutes.
He told us to wait out here.
Jeff...
I gotta see it for myself.
I thought that place
gave you the creeps.
Are those vibes ever strong.
It really pulls on you.
I gotta see the basement.
That's where it's coming from.
I'm very sensitive
about these things.
And I know about them.
Come on,
knock it off, will you?
What I saw was not a cat.
It could've climbed up the ivy.
It's all over the side
of the damn house.
I don't have
all the answers yet.
We gotta get
some perspective on this thing.
Come on,
let's take Jeff's offer.
Put yourself together.
Let's get the hell away from it
for a couple of hours.
We'll get dressed...
I just gotta check
the fire first.
Demons are smart.
They're not just monsters. They...
They think
just like you and I do.
Just in reverse.
It's a closed system.
Now you're beginning
to give me the creeps.
There was a tribe of Indians
called the Shinnecocks,
and they used this land
as a sort of exposure pen.
They put all the crazy people here
and left them here to die.
- My God!
- That's where it is.
What the hell
are you talking about?
There are people buried here.
Easy. Easy.
Easy, there.
What the hell are you doing?
- What is the matter with you?
- Don't you understand?
It has to be done.
That is where the room is.
What are you doing
to my house?
I'm sorry.
I don't know what got into her.
I'm trying to tell him
that's where it is.
She's right.
There is something here.
Give me that.
What's going on?
Have you all gone mad?
They... come
and go through here.
Find the well.
It's the passage...
to hell!
Cover it!
Hello?
George, you heard that voice.
You know whose voice that was.
You heard it.
I know you heard it!
We have to do something, George.
We have to do something now.
Peace to this house
and all who enter here.
Forgive us our sins
and save us from all illness.
Grant this
through Jesus Christ, our Lord.
What is going on here?
Weird people.
Bless this house
and all who enter here.
Bless this house...
What's happening?
Don't touch me!
Leave me alone, please.
Please.
Father, since I've come back
from Vietnam,
you've had
a tremendous influence in my life.
I look up to you.
I respect you, I admire you.
And what is your point?
I believe that...
that I know about fear.
I've seen it.
I've experienced it.
I wish you'd make your point.
I've got a lot of things to do.
My point is I believe we create
our own demons in our own minds.
I'm sorry, Father.
In the name of the Father,
the Son, and the Holy Spirit.
Let us pray.
Father...
by the power of Your spirit...
You have filled the hearts...
of Your faithful people...
with gifts of love...
for one another.
Hear the prayers that we offer
for our relatives and friends.
Give them health.
Give them health
of mind and body that...
of mind and body
that they may do Your will
with perfect love.
Give them health
of mind and body
that they may do Your will
with perfect love!
We ask this through
our Lord, Jesus Christ, Your Son!
Give them strength
of mind and body!
Oh, Lord...
I beg Thee!
Give them strength
in the name of our Lord,
Jesus Christ, Your Son!
Oh, Lord!
Oh, Jesus Christ!
Richard.
What is it, Father?
I can't see.
I'm blind.
What do you want from us?
Goddammit!
This is my house!
No!
Oh, no.
I'm coming apart!
Oh, Mother of God,
What happened?
I was just dreaming.
I'm sorry if I woke you.
Honey, are you okay?
Oh, sure.
Are you sure?
Oh, my God,
what happened to your foot?
Look.
Nothing.
I just tripped.
- It looks like teeth marks.
- Will you stop nagging at me?
It's always so cold in here.
Let's get out of here, huh?
Let's just
pack up our stuff and go.
Would you please leave that
damn fire alone and listen to me?
I'm not going anywhere!
You're the one that wanted a house.
This is it, so just shut up!
You bastard!
Excuse me. Somebody told me
you could tell me where...
Excuse me.
Someone told me that...
I'm Kathy Lutz, and I'm
looking for Father Delaney.
Hi, I'm Father Bolen.
I believe the Father
has gone on vacation.
He's been very overworked...
I must speak to Father Delaney.
I simply must.
You don't understand.
He's more than a priest to me.
He's like a friend of mine.
He's helped me through
some very difficult times,
and I have to
talk to him now.
It's out of my hands.
Hello, Father.
How are you feeling today?
I brought you some mail.
Would you like me to read it?
I notice there's one here
from a former patient.
Would you like to hear it?
It certainly is beautiful here.
Why don't I arrange
so we can have our lunch here?
Would you like that, Father?
Excuse me, Father.
Can I have a word with you?
Of course, Sergeant.
What can I do for you?
Well...
I don't really know exactly.
It may be just a wild-goose chase,
but I'm the curious type.
Like the man says,
it goes with the territory.
I have a great deal
of work to do.
Could you
make your point, please?
What's happening
to Father Delaney?
He's an old friend,
and I can't get the story right.
There's no "story" to get right.
Maybe I am
just chasing shadows.
If you could excuse me, please.
I think this has
all the good stuff.
I mean the major coverage.
If there's anything else
you want to see,
- I'll go and get it.
- No, I think this should be fine.
This is the November 14th issue,
the day after the murders.
You turn that crank...
- That one there?
- Right there.
It advances the film.
Each frame is a whole page.
To get it in focus,
you just turn this knob right here.
- I've got it.
- You all set now?
- I'm fine.
- Good.
Oh, my God, George.
Matt! Greg! Matt!
Amy!
Don't hurt my babies.
Jesus.
I saw your picture
in the newspaper.
Kathy, I wouldn't hurt you.
Get going!
Now! Get going!
Hold on!
Go!
Here, let me try.
- I got it.
- I can't open it!
Go! Go!
Mom!
The keys...
Oh, God! Where are the keys?
What? Wait a minute.
I can't find them.
I want Harry!
- Please, George, drive.
- Mom.
George, no! No!
Harry! Come on, boy!
Harry, come on!
No, it's me!
Harry, no!
Pull! Pull!
Harry, pull!
Good boy.
Come on, boy!
Thank God.
Oh, thank God.