[VIOLIN MUSIC PLAYING]
I am here to discuss the
so-called flying saucers.
Air Force interest
in this problem
has been due to our feeling
of an obligation
to identify and analyze
to the best of our ability
anything in the air
that may have the possibility
of threat
or menace to the United States.
In pursuit of this obligation
since 1947,
we have received and analyzed
between 1,000 and 2,000 reports
that have come to us
from all kinds of sources.
We can say that
the recent sightings
are in no way connected
with any secret development
by any department
of the United States.
Major Keyhoe,
as author of the book
Flying Saucers Are Real,
what is your opinion of these new
sightings of unidentified objects?
With all due respect
to the Air Force,
I believe that some of them
will prove to be
of interplanetary origin.
During a three-year
investigation,
I found that many pilots
have described objects
of substance and high speed.
One case, pilots reported
their plane was buffeted
by an object which passed
them at 500 miles an hour.
Obviously, this was a solid object
and I believe it was from outer space.
[SOMBER INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC PLAYING]
[CHILDREN CHATTERING]
BOTH: ♪ ...Liberace,
I love you ♪
♪ Take a peach, take a plum
♪ Take a stick of bubble gum
♪ No peach, no plum
No stick of gum
- ♪ Saw you With your boyfriend... ♪
- Girls, dinner's ready.
Mom.
Let's take it
from the top, okay?
♪ Eenie Meanie Sassaleeny
♪ Oops ah tumbalini
♪ Achi cachi Liberace
♪ I love you
♪ Take a peach, take a plum
♪ Take a stick of bubble gum
♪ No peach, no plum
♪ Saw you with your
Boyfriend last night
- [DISHES CLATTERING]
- Dinner's ready.
I know your boyfriend.
Saw you with your boyfriend.
Wait, what night is it?
It's the boring chickpea
Tuesday night.
You girls be grateful now.
Did you know there's 168 million
child laborers in the world?
Some carry books on their head
all day
in 100 degree heat
for a can of chickpeas.
And they're considered
the lucky ones.
Is that true?
Momma says so.
God is great.
God is good.
Let us thank Him for our food.
By His hands we all are fed.
- Give us Lord our daily bread.
- [RUMBLING]
Amen.
[RUMBLING]
What happened?
[OBJECTS CLATTERING]
Dad!
[ELECTRICITY BUZZING]
- [WHOOSHES]
- [GLASS BREAKING]
[COUGHING]
[CONTINUES COUGHING]
Rob? [COUGHING]
[ROB COUGHING]
Oh, oh, Lord.
Help me, Jesus.
Valerie?
Val?
- Valerie, honey.
- [COUGHING]
- [SIGHS SOFTLY]
- Oh.
[SOFTLY] Valerie.
Honey, wake up.
[COUGHING]
Okay?
Sarah?
[COUGHS]
[VALERIE COUGHING]
Oh, honey, come on.
Give Mommy your hand.
Come on, it's over.
It's over. It's all over.
It's all over.
[SIGHS WEARILY] Oh!
- [BREATHING HEAVILY]
- [COUGHING]
Baby.
[COUGHING]
[MYSTERIOUS MUSIC PLAYING]
[SOFTLY] Looks like
a plane crash.
It was a terrorist attack.
It's not a terrorist attack.
[THUDDING]
What's happening?
[THUD]
Get away from the window.
What? [BREATH TREMBLING]
The air is toxic.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[BREATHING HEAVILY] Mom?
Honey. Rob?
[CHOKING]
[GRUNTS]
[COUGHING] Help me, Jesus.
[ROB COUGHING]
[SOBBING] Rob, please!
[ROB GRUNTS]
- No, no.
- [MUSIC INCREASES IN TEMPO]
- No.
- [ROB COUGHING]
God damn it, please don't
do this to me, Rob.
[SOBBING]
What's happening?
[BREATH TREMBLING]
[SCREAMS] Rob!
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[COUGHING]
[RETCHING AND COUGHING]
[SOBBING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[MYSTERIOUS MUSIC PLAYING]
[GASPS]
[CONTINUES BREATHING HEAVILY]
[MUSIC INCREASES IN TEMPO]
[COUGHS]
[THUD]
[RUMBLING]
- [SIREN WAILING]
- Look, Phoenix is a good team.
But the last three minutes
of the game,
they did it again.
This could have been
the game of the century.
I mean, they had it all.
I have a lot of respect
for David Quaid though.
I think he's made
a remarkable comeback.
WOMAN: Okay, I see what you're
saying, but I'll leave you with this.
They generate twice
as much revenue in sponsorship
than any other
NFL team out there.
All right, see you tomorrow.
Back to you, Marcus.
Now to a dire warning
about climate change.
According to a new report,
experts say that we have until
2030 to avoid catastrophe.
Report also says that if
unprecedented changes
aren't made soon,
there'll be dire consequences
for the planet.
The report focuses
on what could happen
if global temperatures rise by
2.7 degrees Fahrenheit.
CNN meteorologist Geoff Smith
is at the international
weather center.
Geoff, what can you tell us
about this serious warning?
GEOFF: Well, 2030, uh,
getting pretty close.
And, of course, we're seeing
that climate change
is already taking its toll
on the planet.
I mean, let's talk about
2016, '17, '18,
the three hottest years
on record.
During this time,
the polar ice caps
really started to melt...
Uh, I'm going to have to
interrupt you there, Geoff.
I'm sorry.
We're getting breaking news
at this hour.
Breaking news
of a massive explosion
in the town of Badger,
which is a small community
of 1,300 people
in northern Pennsylvania.
There have been casualties,
many,
but the exact numbers
are not known at this stage
and the Pentagon
is yet to clarify
whether this has been
an act of terrorism
or a natural disaster.
Our reporter,
Samantha Bransgrove,
is on-site, live.
Samantha, what can you tell us
about this explosion?
Marcus, the entire town
has just dropped dead.
I repeat, nothing and no one
has survived
this mysterious explosion.
The town
is currently sealed off
and we're at least 50 miles
from ground zero.
The air around the town
is considered to be
highly toxic.
Now, as you can see behind me,
the entrance to the town
is heavily guarded
and no one is allowed in
without a hazmat suit.
Do we have any leads
at this stage
as to who or what could have
caused this explosion?
Marcus, unfortunately
at this point,
we have no solid leads.
There is, however,
a lot of speculation.
Some say that
it was a deadly explosion
from a chemical plant
that has contaminated
the entire town.
Others say
it was a chemical bomb.
The question is, Marcus,
if this was a chemical bomb,
why a small farming community?
If this really
was a terrorist attack,
why not a major city?
L.A., New York, Chicago.
We have no more information
at this stage, Marcus,
however, clearly,
something very devastating.
[SLOW CAPTIVATING
INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING]
[INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
MAN: Dr. Lauren Stone?
Yeah?
I'm Sergeant Clayton.
This is Sergeant Jones,
U S. Army.
You're coming with us, ma'am.
JONES: You've heard about
the explosion in Badger?
Yeah.
It's a matter
of national security.
You are urgently needed.
You must be mistaken.
JONES:
It's not a mistake, ma'am.
We're also authorized to use
excessive force if needed.
[SIREN BLARING]
[HELICOPTER HOVERING]
[INAUDIBLE CONVERSATION]
Colonel Roger Emmerich.
Lauren Stone.
I know who you are.
I've heard a lot about you.
Why am I here?
Follow me.
This is
Professor David Santiago,
astrobiologist.
Exobiologist Dr. Lauren Stone.
She works for NASA.
Geologists have confirmed
it's a meteorite,
estimated to be the size
of a basketball when it hit.
No one saw it coming.
A meteorite?
I know what you're thinking.
Meteorites don't release
toxic gas and kill people.
Well, this one did.
And it unleashed hell
within a 20-mile radius.
We managed to gather up
a few little pieces
here and there.
But it appears to have just hit
and dissolved into the soil.
No leads?
No.
No, all we know
is a space object
is responsible
for 373 innocent lives,
and no one can figure it out.
But whatever it is,
it's highly toxic,
it's airborne,
and you just
don't want to breathe it.
So, uh, why are we here?
We're dealing with something
[SIGHS]
we haven't dealt with before.
I just need you to get in,
do your thing,
and get out. And remember,
any information will be vital.
No more questions?
- Yeah...
- Good.
I need you to suit up.
Bus leaves in ten.
Lauren.
[INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Do you know why I chose you?
Because I needed a believer.
I read your file.
They say
if it's out of this world,
you will find it.
Now something is buried
in there somewhere.
Oh, and...
...a sobriety test
will be conducted on you.
It's mandatory,
nothing personal.
[CAPTIVATING INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC PLAYING]
I did read your book.
Found it pretty insightful,
actually.
I know you caught
some flak for it, but...
"Microbial Ecosystems
of the Antarctic."
Yeah, that bit about
morphological signatures
of extraterrestrial life...
...it's kind of like
when you read something
and it makes you
want to keep going.
Anyways...
These are my boys.
Sam and Michael.
Sam says to me, he says, uh...
[CHUCKLES SOFTLY]
he says, "Dad, when I grow up,
"I wanna follow
in your footsteps."
I say, "No."
You have to follow your own
passions, you know?
I say, "You're not gonna
follow my footsteps,
"you're gonna play ball."
Pretty good at baseball.
Then Michael... [CHUCKLES]
Michael says to me, says, "Dad,
why do you do what you do?"
I say,
"Don't you wanna find out
"if there's life
outside this planet?
"Aliens?
"Other species?"
He's like,
"No, I can live with that."
He pauses for a moment... Get this.
He pauses for a moment,
and I can see he's thinking something.
He looks at me,
right in my eyes,
deep into my soul,
and he says... he says, "Dad, why don't
you get a real job like Jason's dad?
"He's a plumber." [LAUGHS]
Anyways,
makes you wanna find
something even more, you know?
Just don't want to feel like
you're wasting your life.
What do you think?
[CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY]
What do I think?
I think Michael was right.
Plumbing job doesn't sound
so bad right about now.
What the hell are we looking at?
There's nothing here.
Think I wish I had
a more form-fitting suit.
Really bunching up
in the nether bits, you know?
Think I just stepped in shit.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[SENTIMENTAL
PIANO MUSIC PLAYING]
Hey, there.
[SIREN BLARING IN THE DISTANCE]
[TYPING]
[LOUD EXPLOSION]
[RATTLING]
INTERVIEWER: Could you ask her,
"One side of the town is barricaded.
"What are they trying to hide?"
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Um, after that explosion,
some kind of chemical
was spread
and a lot of people died.
INTERVIEWER: Chemicals? Ask her where
is she getting her information from.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Kohler, the neighbor's son,
he's in army, so that's where
they get this information from.
The neighbor's son?
I see.
So why are they hiding it
from the rest of the world?
Can you ask her, most
importantly, what are they hiding?
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Something else happen
after that explosion.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
It was some kind of seed,
and something else grew out of
it, something big,
and after that,
everything died,
birds, animals, everything.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
And some kind of tree
grew out of it
but it doesn't exist anymore.
They destroyed it.
[KEYBOARD CLACKS]
And some kind of tree
grew out of it
but it doesn't exist anymore.
They destroyed it.
INTERVIEWER:
Okay. I need more.
A tree? What kind of tree?
You mentioned a seed.
Tell me more about this seed.
Sir, she said enough
and she just doesn't know...
she doesn't have more information.
- [SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
- And she asked you to leave.
[OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING]
- I'm Dr. Maria Paselo.
- And I'm Dr. Keith Herd.
Today's Monday, the fourth of
March and the time now is 8:45 a.m.
And I'm here to perform
an autopsy on Robert Windsor.
I will be assisted
by my colleague, Dr. Herd,
and this autopsy will be
carried out in four stages...
an external evaluation followed by an
internal evaluation with the heart,
lungs, digestive organs
and finally, the brain.
Skin seems normal.
Far too normal if you ask me.
No rigor mortis.
[CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS]
Attempting primary incision now.
[WHISPERS]
What the hell is that?
MARIA: What's happening?
He's healing.
He's moving.
- What? [GASPS]
- [THUDS]
[ALL GASPING]
Sweet Mary, Mother of Jesus...
[BREATH TREMBLING]
I'd like to leave the room.
This is Karen McKnight.
I'm the acting director for
the Center of Disease Control.
You're in a quarantine facility.
Can you hear me?
I need you to raise your hand
if you can understand me.
Or... even a blink will do,
anything.
I'm staying.
What would you like me to do?
Check his pulse.
There's no pulse.
The body is cold.
No blood pressure.
No, um...
[WHISPERS]
How is this possible?
[BREATH TREMBLING]
You, um...
You've been a victim
of a biological attack.
There was an explosion.
[CELL PHONES RINGING]
[WOMAN SCREAMS]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[REPORTERS CLAMORING]
REPORTER: These people were examined
and pronounced dead two nights ago,
- following a massive chemical explosion...
- Back off now!
However at 9:00 AM
Eastern Standard Time today,
these people rose
from the dead
and are now once again alive. They came...
They came back to life, Tom.
[REPORTERS CLAMORING]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
Scientists and religious groups are
absolutely baffled by this event.
I heard various
commentary suggesting
that this could be an act
of evil or perhaps a miracle,
while some are trying to find
a scientific explanation
behind this
unprecedented event.
And this is unprecedented, Tom,
nobody knows why this happened
or why these people
have returned.
But the feeling is that they
must be here for a reason.
Rough day, huh?
Look, can I get you something?
Look, I don't know what
happened out there today, but...
I'm on your side.
Just... let me know how I could help
you, all right?
I...
I just need a minute.
Yeah.
We're partners, right?
Look, you sure you don't
need something to drink?
[EXHALES]
Home.
An entire town
of 1,300 people drops dead.
49 of those victims
rise up from the dead.
Can someone
explain to me...
why them?
What happened to
the rest of the town?
We, uh...
We do have a theory, ma'am.
Enlighten me.
The 49 Badger victims
who were resurrected
resided in close proximity
of the initial explosion.
Now these victims didn't
just inhale the toxic air,
but they also swallowed a substance
which was spread from the explosion.
What kind of substance?
It's the...
the fragments of the meteorite
which resulted in transforming
their internal organs.
I guess you can say it's a
formation of a new life form
within the human body,
Governor.
The rest of the town died just
by breathing the toxic air.
In other words,
anyone who's exposed
to the air
in Badger today...
will die.
And nothing
can bring 'em back.
[GASPS]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
By the way,
they seem to be doing that a lot.
Facing one
particular direction.
How you doing, kid?
You okay?
This is a repeated event.
Pardon me?
The meteorite or whatever
they're calling it.
How so?
February 15th, 2013.
There was a similar
explosion in Russia.
Chelyabinsk.
Yeah, Chelyabinsk, Russia.
I'm aware of it.
People died from similar symptoms,
but it didn't just end there.
- Colonel...
- I'm listening.
[SIGHS]
- The Russians are hiding something.
- You think it's the Russians?
No...
The Russians
were the victims.
Hm.
This wasn't an accident.
We were targeted.
That's a very
interesting theory.
Tell me, how did you
come up with this?
- I found a report online.
- Online?
- The dark web.
- Dark web?
Okay.
Colonel, I know
how it sounds.
Good.
They have no heartbeat,
no respiration,
no detectable signs
of any brain functionality.
They don't eat,
they don't sleep.
In other words,
they're as dead as Elvis.
No respiration,
no brain functionality, um...
Excuse me, Miss McKnight,
um...
what exactly
is moving them?
Well, Mr. President,
they most certainly appear to be dead.
I... I'm listening.
Blood and tissue
analysis have revealed
a number of compounds we're
still struggling to identify.
At a deeper level,
we've seen a wholesale breakdown
and a resequencing of DNA in
what used to be red blood cells.
Resequencing?
Yes, sir. A purposeful
resequencing.
This isn't some
random change.
The same new sequence is
repeated in each victim.
They're changing.
What the hell
does that actually mean?
We believe the DNA is being
deliberately modified
into an unknown DNA sequence.
An extraterrestrial sequence.
Aliens, General.
I say we put them down.
Problem solved.
Incinerate them.
I'm with the general.
I see.
Ms. Stone.
You clearly have
an opinion on all this.
Would you mind sharing
that with everyone?
Chelyabinsk, by a small village in the
Ural Mountains near the Kazakhstan border,
an almost identical meteorite strike
and reports of almost identical deaths
in a large area
surrounding the impact zone.
The world is aware
of the meteorite strike,
but the Russians kept
the remaining a secret.
They incinerated
an entire village.
My point exactly.
The Russians
made a smart move.
All I'm saying is this has happened
before, it may happen again.
We need to be
able to stop it.
We need answers.
First Chelyabinsk,
then Badger.
What's next?
Manhattan?
Population 1.6 million.
Do you have any other
evidence to support this?
Other than some video
on YouTube or a few images could
easily have been Photoshopped?
No, Mr. President.
Oh, boy.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
WOMAN: Is there even a point
in keeping these resurrected?
- Any sign of any life or communication?
- Hey.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
- Do you mind?
- [SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
...as to whether they should be
incinerated and put to rest or not.
The president has made an executive
decision to keep them a little longer,
- and I believe that decision was made...
- Keep the change.
...based on theory
by my colleague
and one of the lead scientists
on this case, Ms. Lauren Stone.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
MAN: We're going
someplace secret.
Now I need you
to be a good girl
and don't tell anyone.
I mean nobody
about our secret place.
Not even Mommy, okay?
[BANGING ON WINDOW]
You okay in there?
Yeah, yeah,
I'm... I'm fine.
I... I was just
looking for my ID.
I...
I found it.
- Okay.
- All good.
Just checking.
WOMAN: We miss you.
I miss you.
The baby's been
kicking like crazy.
Say something.
Please.
Anything?
I know you're in there.
Not even a blink.
Look at your daughter.
Look at her.
[CRYING SOFTLY]
By the way...
you're wasting your time.
Nothing's going to happen.
Something's got to happen.
[DOOR CLOSES]
Hey.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
I brought you something.
A Galaxy Far Beyond.
It was my favorite book
when I was a kid.
It still is.
My mom used
to read it to me.
She died when I was 10.
I was 10 years old. I...
I didn't even cry.
That's not normal.
You're a good listener.
You have to
give me something.
Anything.
[PHONE VIBRATING]
[GASPS]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Could just be the color red.
It's often used as
an expression of love,
or the opposite to symbolize
war, destruction.
It's the plant.
Someone in there needs
to be taken to this plant.
Why wasn't this plant reported?
It was just
a two-inch seedling.
Yeah.
Two-inch seedling.
Happens to grow in the middle
of a toxic impact crater
and wiped out an entire town.
Listen, this is a matter
of national security.
We're not sure what
we're dealing with here.
Call them zombies, aliens.
We don't know what
they're capable of.
We can't just take them there.
You know, Muslims,
when they pray,
they're commanded to face
a specific direction.
No matter where they are in the
world, they always face Mecca.
The holiest city to them.
DAVID: They're
all facing north.
So, what are you saying?
They're all Muslims?
I'm saying...
that we're here.
Now go north.
DAVID: Badger.
There's something there.
[EXHALES]
What?
What is it?
We found your seedling.
Colonel!
It's breaking news.
It's gone viral.
Follow me.
Now, Tom, we're not sure
exactly what it is.
Whatever it is,
it's an unearthly beast
a mysterious giant
extraterrestrial phenomenon.
And it's still growing.
Susan, I'm just
a bit baffled in here.
I mean, how did a monstrous
object that size go unnoticed?
Were they trying to hide it?
Surely someone would
have noticed it at some point.
Now, Tom, as you're aware,
the town has been highly guarded.
It's been a no-go zone.
No one's been in or out
since the incident.
The scientists got what
they needed.
I believe the last two
who were on site
were astrobiologist Dr. David Santiago
and exobiologist Dr. Lauren Stone.
Nothing was seen or
reported by them.
So clearly, this thing did not
exist two days ago.
It's grown to this enormous
size in a short period of time,
and it's highly toxic.
You wouldn't be able to go
near it without a Hazmat suit,
and it's creating
its own atmosphere.
What was once speculated
to be a meteorite
is now confirmed to be a seed
that's resulted in
growing this phenomenon.
Now we're not sure
its purpose just yet.
But it's here for a reason.
[HELICOPTER HOVERING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
So that's your seedling, huh?
Don't get too attached to it.
Be shut down
before you know it.
COLONEL: As toxic as hell.
DAVID: You know...
part of me wants him to move.
Part of me doesn't.
Bet you 20 bucks
he ain't moving.
Make that 40.
- You're on.
- Count me in.
He ain't moving.
Shouldn't we be getting him
a blanket or something?
How about you get me a blanket?
Can't feel my goddamn toes.
What toes?
Exactly.
Come on.
Come on. Damn it.
[EXHALING]
DAVID: He's moving.
Welcome to Earth.
I cannot go back with you.
I will not
survive your environment.
It has a reverse effect.
We cannot survive
the environment around it.
But just as our plants
here on Earth
provide oxygen for us,
it's life-giving for them.
Our closest neighboring star
is 4.2 light years away.
How did they reach us out here?
There are reports of portals a few
tens of thousands of miles from Earth.
They're also
known as wormholes.
A wormhole is a tunnel
that creates a shortcut
for long journeys
across the universe.
REPORTER 1: Are you saying
that if these victims,
the resurrected, were taken
to this tree object,
they'd also communicate
or show signs of life?
REPORTER 2: Miss Stone, is it true that
you're on probation for DUI charges?
REPORTER 3: Did NASA know or
predict anything about this?
Surely someone would
have known something.
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
[SIREN WAILING]
Please leave a message
after the tone.
[BEEPS]
Lauren, hi.
It's Dr. Mason calling.
Look, I'm just a little concerned,
you missed a couple of sessions.
I mean, it's good to see
you on TV.
You're back on the field.
You're doing great things.
But, Lauren, the sessions
are mandatory.
It's part of your DUI arrest.
It's by court order.
As your counselor,
I have an obligation to report
it to your parole officer.
I hope you understand.
And we ran out
of time last session.
But I also want to talk to you
more about the ongoing flashbacks,
dreams you're having.
You also mentioned flying.
Flying normally
represents a sense of freedom
or an escape.
Maybe related...
Look...
Why don't you just
call me, okay?
Call me directly.
555-212-4545.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Hey.
I was in town, thought I'd come
by and say hello.
That smells terrible.
May I?
I...
haven't had a chance
to clean up.
I don't mind.
[EXHALES]
The cap's on.
MAN: You were
turning eight and...
and I asked you what you wanted
for your birthday.
You asked for a science lab.
Not a pony.
Not a bike or a Barbie doll.
But a lab.
We let you use the old shed.
Your passion,
your, your obsession
with science and space,
building projects...
Things got out of hand.
I...
guess your mom
got a bit worried.
How's things back home?
Things.
I guess lonely would be
about the right word.
I lost your mother.
And then I... lost you.
It's been hard, you know?
I've missed you.
Well...
it was good to see you.
It's refusing to talk to anyone
but you.
Uh, just give us a second.
Thank you.
It wants to talk to Lauren.
Homeland security,
all its bag of tricks,
all their techniques
couldn't make it budge.
It just wants to talk to you.
Seems it's found a friend
in you.
I see the feeling is mutual.
It won't be needing these.
This thing...
it's not like us.
It is not human.
You remember that.
I've prepared a list
of questions.
It's important you look at them.
I need you to find out
what it is,
where did it come from,
and most importantly,
what does it want?
Our home was no longer habitable
for our species.
We searched for a new home.
We found one.
Why Earth?
It doesn't grow anywhere else.
We were given the coordinates
to find this planet.
Coordinates?
By who?
One of your kind.
He calls himself
Supernova 94.
He searched for us.
He made contact with us.
We know your strengths.
We know your weaknesses.
Ask them to leave.
I can't do that.
They won't let it go on
much longer.
It's harming our environment.
Our home.
We will change your environment.
You cannot stop us.
We come from a hostile world.
We will not descend in peace.
We have abilities.
George?
Do you hear me?
What are you doing?
[OVERLAPPING CONVERSATION]
- [INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
- [GRUNTING]
Stop it!
Stop!
Son of a bitch!
[GROANS]
Major Dean!
Goddamn it, Serge!
What are we doing?
It's all bullshit!
It's killing him.
God damn it, Serge, make the call.
Serge, come on!
Serge, make the fucking call!
This is bullshit!
Serge, what are you waiting for?
Shoot him.
[HIGH-PITCHED TONE]
[SOLDIERS SCREAMING]
WOMAN: What's happening to me?
- Fuck!
- Get him out of my head!
Stop it!
Get the fuck out of here!
- No!
- [GUNSHOT]
Approaching target.
WOMAN: Laser on.
Target is locked.
Light him up.
Copy that.
Three, two, one, rifle.
WOMAN: Captain, the missile
did not reach the target.
Something is blocking it.
Captain, we're losing him.
MAN ON RADIO: Copy...
[INDISTINCT]
MAN ON RADIO:
The target still remains.
It has created a shield
around it.
I repeat,
the target still stands.
Permission to abort.
- Return to base.
- Copy that.
MAN ON TV: We have unconfirmed
reports of shootings.
And we do not know if there's
any causalities at this stage.
And just when we thought things
couldn't get any worse,
we now have some reports that this thing
has apparently created a shield around it.
And no missiles
can get through it.
WOMAN: This is getting weird, and I
mean, it's getting really weird.
Tom, look, I really want to
talk about this Supernova guy.
MAN: Supernova 94.
Yeah, I mean, it sounds like
a user name, don't you think?
MAN: Yeah, an unusual
user name for a terrorist.
- WOMAN: A terrorist?
- MAN: A terrorist, a desperado.
Or call him a jihadi.
He's officially now
on the FBI's most wanted list.
WOMAN: So let me
get this straight.
We've been trying to intentionally
send signals into space
in search
of extraterrestrial life,
all the SETI missions and the
fancy telescopes, the golden disk,
but when an average Joe
makes contact with ET,
all of a sudden it's an act of terrorism.
This doesn't make sense.
I mean, shouldn't they be
giving this guy
a Nobel Prize
or something?
MAN: Now what
in the world is going on?
There have been a number
of cases of strange events
being reported
all around the world.
Let's start
with these weird sounds.
I invite you
to listen carefully
to the sounds
you're about to hear...
Not sure what it is.
[OMINOUS WAILING]
I think,
I think the sky...
MAN: So what exactly
is everyone hearing?
There have been
many theories, of course.
Something...
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Something really strange
is, is happening
here on my dad's,
my dad's property.
- There's...
- [OMINOUS INDISTINCT SPEECH]
[WHISPERS] There's these...
these...
these noises
[PANTING]
coming out of the woods.
Last night, we could,
we could feel the ground shake.
FEMALE REPORTER: We've just received
some reports of a mysterious fog
or some call it
a thick smoke
- that's just appearing out of nowhere and killing people.
- [CLAMORING]
REPORTER:
Reports of many explosions
in the city
of Bangalore, India.
Officials are saying
there's been
mass casualties
with bodies everywhere.
The Governor ordered shutting
down all non-essential businesses
and telling people
to remain in their homes.
MALE REPORTER: Millions of people
have gathered around the world
and held mass prayer.
Martial Law has been declared
as the military
take control
of all civilian governments.
I think, I think
they're already here.
That Supernova guy
works for NASA.
[MAN SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
The ground has been shaking.
All the crops are dying,
This all happened overnight.
There's something wrong
with the soil.
Let me show you
something.
See? It's all rotten.
I can actually feel
the ground vibrating.
- Do you feel that?
- Yeah.
We're on the edge
- of a mass...
- [MEN CLAMORING]
- extinction.
- [CHAOTIC CHATTER]
[TV SWITCHES OFF]
[INAUDIBLE]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[TWIG SNAPS]
[BREATH TREMBLING]
[DOG WHIMPERS]
Max?
[BREATH TREMBLING]
[OMINOUS MALE VOICE
SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[PANTING]
[BREATH TREMBLING]
[TRAIN HORN BLARING]
LAUREN: Who am I?
What am I?
Do you ever feel like
you're suffocating
and want to crawl
out of your skin?
But you're trapped
in your own body
like you're abandoned
and you don't belong
anywhere.
The world is coming
to an end
but why is it that I'm feeling
a sense of relief?
Like I'm...
I'm finally being
put out of my misery,
like I can finally breathe.
All the suffering.
I used to think
my answers
lay somewhere
in distant space
among the stars.
But for the first time
I feel that the truth
is finally within
my reach.
Right here.
It looks different.
She is...
going through a process.
[RUMBLING]
[MUFFLED BREATHING]
What's happening?
It's time.
[INDISTINCT DISTINCT CHATTER]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
It's life...
growing.
Beautiful, isn't it?
[MUFFLED INDISTINCT CHATTER]
How is this even possible?
You made it possible.
She was our only hope.
Our only proof of existence.
She was our last chance.
You fought for her.
You were involved
in an incident.
You don't remember anything?
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Daddy,
where are we going?
We're going someplace secret.
Now I need you
to be a good girl
and don't tell anyone,
I mean nobody,
about our secret place.
- Not even Mommy, okay?
- Okay.
I love you, honey.
Tell me more about it.
MAN: It was captured and killed
early this morning
at 0400 hours
in Northern Alaska, sir.
An unidentified flying object
was reported
by the locals.
I see.
WOMAN: Welcome
to Area 51, Senator.
Now, you need to wait
out here, sweetheart.
Okay?
I'll be back in a minute.
I love you.
[MEN CHATTER INDISTINCTLY]
[CHATTER CONTINUES]
MAN: My God,
it's a beast.
- You sure it's...
- WOMAN: Dead as a doornail, sir.
MAN 2: It seemed that it was
trying to plant something.
It was incredibly strong,
hostile but highly intelligent
with a high-tech spaceship
and advanced weapons.
WOMAN: Thanks
to the Earth's atmosphere,
it appears they haven't
adapted to our environment,
which slowed it down, sir.
MAN: Oh, and they have
an ability to fly, sir.
[SCREAMS]
MAN: Our home was no longer
habitable for our species.
WOMAN: Hey! Get up!
God damn it, kid, you're not
supposed to be in here.
MAN: Where was she?
WOMAN:
She was in the bathroom, sir.
[CAPTIVATING INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC PLAYING]
My God, what is that?
- Is that...
- It's a blueprint.
Looks like a rocket.
She's eight years old
for God's sake.
What kind of school...
I don't think
it's a school project.
She seems to be
showing an interest in science
and the extraterrestrial life.
She's also becoming
more isolated.
She has this ability
to manipulate
not just the students
but also some of the teachers.
She also says that
she's an alien
and she wants to go home.
Hello?
[ETHEREAL MUSIC PLAYING]
Is anyone there? This is...
This is Supernova 94.
Do you copy?
[ORCHESTRAL MUSIC PLAYING]
You said
she was building a rocket.
Who have you been talking to?
There are some bad people
out there. You hear me, Lauren?
I need you to put a lock
on this thing.
That's it.
You are not allowed
in the shed anymore, missy.
[INAUDIBLE]
God damn it!
What is wrong with you?
What have I told you about
painting on the walls?
You will die
a most horrible death.
We have abilities.
MAN: Senator,
we found a mysterious
new form of DNA
in Lauren's blood cells.
We can't really figure it out.
She's changing
into something else.
It's like she's half-human
and becoming...
SENATOR: Shh, you might want to
keep your voice down, Doc.
I know she's in the other room,
but she can hear
through the walls.
[SOBBING]
Welcome home.
[ORCHESTRAL MUSIC PLAYING]
...a space composed
that's 78.09% nitrogen,
20.95% oxygen,
0.93% argon,
and 0.04% carbon dioxide,
and a small amount
of other gases.
MAN: Who is this?
Kid, can you hear me?
Who are you talking to?
JACK: Ask her her name.
This is the goddamn CIA.
She called herself Supernova 94.
- What the hell is Super...
- I don't know, Jack.
JACK: We're trying to decode
sensitive
military operations here.
WOMAN: Strange objects
are appearing around the world.
What began in Indiana
and Alberta, Canada,
has now occurred in several
places across the globe,
including Australia
and Greenland.
They're appearing everywhere,
in forests,
the Sahara Desert, farms,
lakes, major cities.
They are everywhere.
MAN: Well, I've seen on TV
and a lot of video
that has been shown to me,
it's the shape of an egg.
REPORTER: The strange noises
once reported are now confirmed
to be coming out of these
mysterious egg-shaped objects.
There many wild theories.
Some say they arose
from the ground,
while others say they were
placed there overnight
by a giant alien spacecraft.
It's crazy.
MAN 1: This could be an act
of alien invasion on...
MAN 2: We don't understand
what it is.
MAN 3: I mean, this is it.
They're here.
They're inside those pods
and they're ready to come out
any second now.
They've risen.
MAN:
I guess the big question is
how will they survive
Earth's environment.
[EXPLOSION]
[ALARM BLARING]
MAN 2: It's like doomsday as they
call it in the Bible or Koran...
WOMAN: I haven't
really seen it,
but those who've seen it
from a distance
describe it as a wave
of this energy or smoke
that's just bursting through
the towns and killing people.
It's actually
very heart wrenching
because you know
a lot of these people
didn't get a chance to evacuate
when this happened.
They're creating a habitable
environment for themselves
before they pop out.
Where do they come from?
[WHISPERING] These pods
are connected to these roots.
They contaminated the soil.
They were growing
right beneath us.
But the main question
still remains.
Where did these roots
come from?
LAUREN: Earth no longer supports
life for the human species.
The planet has transformed
and an evolution has begun.
There was nowhere to run
and nowhere to hide.
All earthly species
and plants became extinct.
- Nothing survived.
- It's been six months
since the invasion.
I'm on my last oxygen tank.
I don't want to die.
[ETHEREAL MUSIC PLAYING]
[INAUDIBLE]
It's a different world
out here now.
As for me,
my journey
finally came to an end.
I'm finally home.