According to our system,
we allow the prisoner
the freedom to accuse himself.
His confession, even though slightly forced,
has its advantages,
when the prisoner is willing
to name his collaborators.
Do you know two African princesses?
The longer your silence,
the worse I'll be for you.
I can see I'm going to have to help you.
Let's start the first trial.
You're going to faint soon,
but with salt and alcohol,
we'll bring you round.
Let's start the second trial
Alfonso!
You're saved, Alfonso!
Señor Zoto is coming to rescue you.
Dear Alfonso!
You've shown great courage, dear cousin.
This is no time for kisses.
By the time the guards arrive,
you should be far away.
This is Señor Zoto.
Señor Alfonso, I have the honour
of introducing my brothers,
Chico...
Muma and Chico.
How come, Zoto?
Your brothers were hanged, weren't they?
You heard right.
But as you can see for yourself,
they're fine.
But I saw them my self!
What you saw were two shepherds,
hung to pacify the neighbourhood.
This is unbelievable.
Undoubtedly, it's thanks to our horses.
I'm pleased to see you are yourself again.
Bless you, señor.
They're surrounding us.
Chico, you cover us
while we get to the horses.
Where's my sword?
My sword!
Kiss me.
And me.
Oh, how happy I am.
Are you pleased about our meeting, cousin?
Cousin, this locket is horrible.
It's cooling our passion towards you.
Are you happy, cousin?
Yes, although I must say
that the end of the night
I spent with you, didn't please me at all.
You'd better accuse us with pleasures.
It wasn't so nice in the morning.
Let's say no more about it.
Here's a plait made of our hair, a talisman
to remind you of us.
Talisman?
It's widely assumed
one can only love one woman.
It's a fallacy.
I fell in love with you both equally.
My heart sees no difference.
Adopt our faith.
You would sit on the throne in Tunis
among harems, gardens and fountains.
No, no.
Let's not talk about kingdoms
flooded with sunshine.
We're in the abyss, close to Hell.
How dare you be in the company
of Golomez women!
Cousin, you're done for!
Forgive us.
Either you'll be killed
like a coward with an axe
and your corpse hung next
to the Zota brothers
at the mercy of crows and devilish powers, or
But the brothers
Or you'll drink the potion from this chalice.
Gulp it down!
Father, you'd do the same in
the name of honour, wouldn't you?
What an unpleasant misunderstanding.
Evil spirits take so many shapes,
it's completely confusing.
You're here too?
You're too young to be a Cabalist,
though you too are carrying
a rope around your neck.
Don't worry.
You are brave, I know,
though you've not had much experience.
You're Alfonso?
Your mother is a Gomelez
and you are a captain of the Walloon Guard.
Let's leave this unpleasant place
and decide what to do next.
My name is Alfonso Van Worden.
That's evident.
I can see you have mellowed.
I have a miraculous potion
to restore your strength.
No, no, no more miraculous potions!
Where are you going, señor?
To Madrid.
Good.
On our way we'll stop at a place
where I left a good meal.
Not miraculous, but sumptuous.
Now listen, the books of Nach Sou Chasi
contain wise Chaldean knowledge,
while the verses of Shir Ha Shi Mir
contain the purest beauty of poetry.
In Hebrew, every letter is a number,
every word a very wise combination.
If it is pronounced with
the right exhalation and accent,
one may move mountains and drain rivers.
You must know that Adonai
created the world with a word...
Someone played a joke on me here last night,
But let's go in anyway.
My horse!
Unbelievable!
Mine too.
I don't understand.
The horse follows his master.
It's lucky that devils do not need food.
Good, isn't it?
What's good?
Just asking.
I am pleased to be able
to satisfy your hunger.
What's that?
It must be your property.
Then you too have spent
the night here?
Yes, but I won't tell you the whole story.
It was a wonderful night...
in spite of everything.
In spite of what?
I have also given my word.
To whom?
Two beautiful women,
but do not ask for more.
Let's set off.
It's still a long way to Madrid.
Do you know a quicker way, señor?
Yes, that way.
That's where the Inquisition fell upon me.
You're right, it's better to avoid an ambush.
Is there any other path?
Of course, for a Cabalist.
We'll go around and come out
on the one to Madrid.
Seter So Har shows us
the depth of the ten elements,
creating integrity of taste.
All this enables us
to get to the powers ruling pandemonium.
Must you always talk in riddles?
It makes my journey more interesting.
And they rule nightmares and demons,
among which we can distinguish
Hungarian and Polish zombies...
Help!
I arrest you in the name of the Inquisition!
Give up your sword!
Do not resist, Alfonso Van Worden!
I am Don Pedro Velasquez!
Are you crazy, señores?
Indeed.
It's not him.
Who is he?
Don Pedro.
He looks rather similar.
What are you doing here?
I thought the roads were for everybody.
Señores bandits!
There is no road here.
Get off!
He must have gone the other way.
Maybe he went back to Venta Quemada.
I was told he was coming this way.
You don't seem eager
to apologise for this mistake.
Stop bothering us!
In that case, I will apologise
to the honourable señores.
A thorn.
There is nothing with which to take it out.
And there is no place to hide,
just to examine the situation, of course.
Señor Alfonso Van Worden?
Some ill mannered thugs await you over there.
The Inquisition?
Yes.
Why should the Inquisition be here?
they didn't recognise you weren't Van Worden?
they probably didn't, if they held me up.
That's what logic would dictate.
And what now?
You will ride to my castle,
señor, a few miles away.
You have a castle in the neighbourhood?
You didn't mention it.
It just proves the beauty of modesty.
What if they find me?
they cannot enter my castle.
We'll take the shortest route.
If I too could take advantage
of your hospitality,
I could hope for a quiet night.
Knowing the señor Cabalist,
I know he won't refuse shelter.
Yes, of course.
Thank you.
I will have time to reconsider
everything that's happened to me.
That could drive
an inexperienced person insane.
The human mind is ready to accept anything,
if it is used knowingly.
End of Part One
The Saragossa Manuscript,
Part Two
Enrico, the master has arrived!
Has something happened?
I don't know.
Let's rest after the rigours of the journey.
Señor, you're completely safe here.
My house is at your disposal.
Fifteenth century.
You're an expert on everything.
Curiosity distinguishes us from animals.
I look, listen and draw conclusions.
Señor, I am pleased to have met you
and to be in your company.
Good company is more precious
than wealth or black magic.
Gentlemen, this is not
the place for disputes.
Please go in.
Enrico, show the gentlemen the way.
You were to be here in three days time.
Unforeseeable complications.
Everything got mixed up.
And what now?
What now?
I don't know.
We must keep him here.
I await new instructions.
Who's the other one?
Careful!
Ask no more.
Go and make yourself becoming.
You might have told me.
You're boring me, my dear.
It was not possible.
I have the impression
that all this is happening
because of evil spirits.
I'd rather blame people, señor.
Someone must be after you
to put you through all these misfortunes.
I'm in your debt, señor,
as it seems that thanks to you,
I'll find the key to this riddle.
I like it here.
Peace and quiet.
Think it all through once again.
have all your needs been met, señor?
I don't know how to thank you.
Not at all.
Make yourself at home.
Thank you. I feel fine here,
I'm really well.
I've thought everything through.
And?
It'd be best for me to go to Madrid
as soon as possible.
I hope I'll be able to make it in the dark.
The Inquisition is still
guarding all the roads.
Maybe Señor Velasquez has some good advice?
He's an unbeliever.
What shall I do then?
Wait.
You have books here.
All the wisdom in the world
is to be found on these shelves.
I particularly recommend the Spanish stories.
Señor Don Pedro, I've found the answer.
Let's have some wine.
Perhaps this midnight oil will mark our vigil
for the last time tonight.
Come, señor, please,
I'd like to show you something.
You're sad.
Let's drink this fine wine.
We'll all soon come to rest
in the eternal night.
How could you be so careless?
If he had read the end,
the events which are to follow
would make no sense.
Luckily, I arrived in time.
Strange things are happening here, señor.
I've seen it with my own eyes,
I even had it in my own hands.
It must be all due to the evil spirits.
I understand, señor,
that your mind is rebelling against
inexplicable phenomena,
but be so kind as to explain in detail.
What are you looking for, señor?
There was a book here.
I saw the gallows.
Where has it gone?
Here?
There's never been a book like that here.
Demons again?
they are tiring, I admit.
Unfortunately, the world is full of them.
Incantations stop their mischief.
Nonsense.
Don't you believe in incantations then?
No.
What if I prove it?
Only if I can perform them my self.
Go on, señor.
This is not the place
for philosophical disputes.
I am so glad to see you, brother.
When did you get back?
This is Alfonso Van Worden,
captain of the guard.
Captain, my sister Rebbecca.
Don Pedro Velasquez.
Señora.
I will do my best.
I am glad to convince you
of the power of the supernatural.
Of course.
From Aristotle came the
principle that in the mind...
Señor Alfonso, I implore you
to tell me what you think
of everything you've experienced
since arriving here.
I wouldn't know where to start.
I must have been put to sleep with a potion
and taken to the gallows.
Then you got under
the Zota brothers' gallows?
And found them both hanged?
Do they, by any chance,
have the habit of coming down?
Very often, usually at night.
Your hand shows that
you are possessed with love for the demons.
Such people have no fear of humans.
I am afraid of nobody.
I am afraid for you.
I am so glad they came.
Gaiety and fun will prevail now.
I am sorry, señora,
but I have different plans.
Whatever your decision,
you won't refuse to spend
a few hours in our company.
Your brother is greeting a gypsy so warmly.
A gypsy?
You'll see in a while what a gypsy he is.
Welcome, Señor Alfonso.
How do you know who I am?
Our camp moves from one place to another,
and my daughters keep
their eyes and ears open.
An enchanted place.
The people of the Sierra
are afraid to go near.
I have no reason to tell them they're wrong.
It is better that most of
my retinue was left outside.
Señor Avadoro, in this errant life
you must have encountered
many unusual adventures.
I have.
Then tell us,
and Señor Velasquez will
teach us how to experience poetry
without the help of ghosts.
I do not succumb to ghosts,
but I fear your magic power, señora.
I reckon that from one end
of the world to the other,
the story of love is always the same.
I think you will enjoy hearing
about my youthful adventures.
Some are surprising,
I could even say, miraculous.
Whenever I go back to those
long gone times of my life,
I hear the noise of a variety of passions
and a mixed roaring of storms.
You seem wiser than others,
and I have a delicate problem.
Will you follow me?
I am the lover of a certain young person.
She tends, I think, to be fickle.
When you see a woman whose dress suits this,
you'll see whether she goes to church,
or in another direction.
Here.
You'll get another if you do well.
You're her husband, not her lover.
I'm paying you to discover treason,
not who I am.
Sharpen your sight, it's time for vespers.
I'll wait at the inn.
Of lovers.
What is this?
Your beauty troubled me.
Somebody suspects you of betraying him.
Follow me.
You will give this to Caballero Toledo.
Noble caballero.
My conscience forbids me taking
payment from both sides.
What is my fortune?
We'll get married under a big chestnut tree.
Nature will accept our vows.
The rosy glow of dawn will bless us.
I've lost Caballero Toledo's address.
He invited me to a grand feast.
On the other side of the square.
Until we meet again.
Maybe.
Señor Toledo,
a lady wanted me to give you
this little token.
I appreciate your wit, my friend, and honour.
Would you like to become one of my servants?
That's impossible, I was born a nobleman.
I chose the position of beggar
as it does not dim a nobleman's jewel.
An answer worthy of a Spaniard!
Let's have a drink.
Human life is fragile.
Why these dark thoughts, señor?
I am a sinner.
I used to leave one mistress for another,
but I concluded that
I was losing too much time that way,
so I started a new affair before
having broken off the last,
and while planning a third.
Spanish women have something...
insistent.
I swore love to each.
The punishment for
breaking oaths is terrible.
Indeed, in the other world.
Yesterday, a friend from Malta visited.
His name is Aquillar,
a noble person and a good Christian.
I cannot understand how,
being endowed with such
contradictory characters,
we have lived in such friendship.
Aren't you drinking?
I've nearly finished the bottle.
You haven't touched your glass.
What are you thinking about?
I was thinking of the sun which I saw today,
whether I would see it again tomorrow.
You doubtless will, if there is no mist.
I may not live to see tomorrow.
Are you planning a duel?
I could act as your witness.
You are the last man
I would ask for this favour.
Good heavens!
You took up your old squabble
with my brother?
Shall I lose my friend
or my brother in one duel?
I have an ominous feeling...
wait until midnight.
If I die, I will come to warn
you about the penalties
a sinner faces after he dies.
I didn't want to see you,
but a voice from heaven ordered me to come.
Were you killed?
I was.
Is there a purgatory in the other world?
There is one.
And that's where I am!
Who died?
Tell me, who died?
Toledo fell unconscious.
I'm sorry, but my duties are calling me.
At such an interesting point!
Doses of suspense are the sign of a master.
All that has made me confused.
I've lost the feeling of where reality ends,
and fantasy takes over.
You meant to say poetry.
I do not know what you are aiming at.
I will tell you something
that is based on the principles of geometry.
Wanting to define an infinite number,
I write a horizontal eight
and divide it by one.
If I want to express infinite smallness,
I write a one and divide it by
the horizontal eight.
All these signs give me no idea
about what I want to express
infinity... greatness...
In the cosmos,
infinite smallness is an infinite root
of the smallest part of an atom.
So I am defining infinity,
but without comprehending.
Well, if I do not comprehend
but I can define it,
I am getting near poetry,
which seems to be nearer to life
than we suspect.
Empirical science leads to lack of faith.
Only an uneducated man
who sees a thing every day
thinks he understands it.
A true researcher proceeds among riddles.
He errs, but he gets nearer
his goal every day.
Señor Avadoro,
will you finish Toledo's story?
I remember he was disturbed
by a voice from the other world.
Yes.
His tender soul was very sensitive.
So he was in deep despair.
What will you do?
I want to rethink my life.
Señor Caballero, let me make one comment.
The voice you heard yesterday
said what you could find in any catechism.
Do not burden oneself with premature worries.
My friend, he who once heard
the voice of the dead,
will surely not spend
much more time among the living.
Farewell, my friend.
Tell the lady everything
without getting into detail.
I have chosen you
as I have a delicate problem.
I would be glad to help,
but I am afraid to leave my client.
I can substitute for you, it won't be long.
Listen.
I warn you, he is a prattler and a bore.
You can find something
interesting in every story.
You remember the señor with
whom I drank wine at your inn?
He is the husband of a young noblewoman.
Discreetly hand this little jewel
over to her.
Señor Lopez Suarez?
like fortune telling, love has its magic.
This tells me you'll see me again soon.
Maybe.
You are kind, but the medicine is awful.
I would give you a more tasty one,
but the medic won't let me.
Sit down.
Sit down, when I tell you to.
I have one soft spot
and you will do me a favour.
Take this instrument in your hand...
and now listen carefully.
I am the son of Gaspar Suarez,
the richest merchant in Cádiz.
You're wasting time again on romances.
I'm listening, Daddy.
It's time you departed for Madrid.
You have to get to know the world.
Daddy, I want to get married.
First, pass your examination in life.
These are the rules you have to follow.
I forbid you to get into
discussions with noblemen.
The lords honour us while
actually they just want credit,
but cannot repay, understand?
I forbid you to use the title of "Don".
You are Suarez and that's that.
And I also forbid you to use your sword.
The habit brings more discredit than good.
Last but not least, under no circumstances
may you enter into any connections
with the house of the banker, Moro.
Moro.
And I will reveal to you why.
Though I am related to
the greatest bankers in Spain,
seeing how well you are trading
with the Philippines,
I will deposit a million with you
for a limited partnership.
I am honoured.
I'll try to double your deposit
as soon as possible.
You do not need to hurry, señor.
Too bad I didn't hurry.
I am Moro, the royal banker, as you know.
My relative, Señor Livardez, has passed away.
In his accounts,
there is your cheque for a million.
Will you please return the capital?
I have legally taken over his estate.
The million was invested.
It will be doubled in the future,
maybe even...
I am very sorry.
All right.
Here is your late relative's share.
And now listen carefully.
Years later, my ships returned,
having tripled the fortune,
so I wrote to the banker Moro
that I had his two million.
My principal received your letter
and begs to inform you
that the Livardez capital
was entered into the books.
He will not claim any more
I owe him two million!
My principal does not even
want to hear of it.
This is an insult!
I do not need his generous donation!
He is insulting me!
I began to claim my rights,
considering my good name
and that of my profession.
I started proceedings.
The tribunal of Sevilla
pronounced Moro right.
We are to pay court fees of 600,000 piastres.
We got no justice.
Six years wasted.
And the two million is supposed to be mine?
That's vile!
You will appeal.
So you see, my son,
I have good reasons to forbid you
any contact with the house
of the banker Moro.
And then?
I said goodbye and,
filling my carriage with love stories
I had bought in Cádiz,
I left for Madrid.
Pour me some more of this good mixture,
good man.
I feel my strength returning.
These sentimental stories
had softened my soul so much
that arriving here I was madly in love,
although I didn't know
the object of my desire.
Oh, sorry.
Who is that?
Come on in, señor.
Señor Don Lopez Suarez.
I came to pay my respects.
I am generally known under the name of...
under the name of...
Don Roque Busqueros,
a family from Old Castile.
My father has forbidden me
to use the title of "Don",
and to get involved with noblemen.
Señor Don Lopez, my father,
in turn, ordered me
to give the title of "Don"
to all prominent merchants,
and to seek their company.
I also respect my father's will.
Your attitude and the elegance
with which you got out of
your carriage impressed me.
Is it yours, Don Lopez?
Mine.
Lucky coincidence!
This is what I passionately collect.
Here, I'll be glad to oblige.
A real collector always has copies,
should one get lost for unknown reasons.
And the third could come in handy,
when the chance arises.
Don... Roque, I just got out of the carriage.
I am tired and hungry.
Exactly.
Well, Don Lopez, it isn't becoming
that we eat off one plate
and use the same spoon and fork.
Hey, boy!
Hey, boy.
Get another set!
Hey boy, get another set!
Busqueros entertained me with
gossip from Madrid, while I was
impatiently looking forward
to getting back to Buen Retiro.
This depopulated park is famous
in our romantic stories,
and I don't even know what was telling me
I would enter into some
tender relationship there.
Señora, I probably found
what you are looking for.
I lost my locket and gold chain.
Was anything written on it?
You read my name was Inez,
and that the original
of the portrait is mine.
May I comment, lovely lady,
that the finder usually gets a decent prize?
You're forward for a first meeting.
Congratulations!
You've met the son
of Cádiz's richest merchant.
I did not give any reason
to have strangers talk to me.
Lopez Suarez.
Be kind enough to return my locket.
Begone!
Señor Don Lopez,
I've refused twenty invitations
to come and see you.
Well, you have to admit
I did you a favour yesterday.
Feigning unwittingness, I told the lady
you were the son of
one of the richest merchants.
Though she pretended to be angry,
it was only
to convince you she was not
at all impressed by wealth.