[ominous music]
[romantic music]
[soft moaning]
[snickers]
What is your deal?
I got a big game
on Friday, I mean...
Look, it's no good,
I need my fluids.
Your fluids?
Yeah.
Hey Mary Jo, I'm curious.
Why would you do
something like that?
Why not?
It's self-mutilation, really.
Self-mutilate this, fluid boy.
[moaning]
Good find, girl.
Yeah, good find.
Who's that?
Oh shit, no.
[foreboding music]
[cheesy rock music]
[soft moaning]
[groaning]
Slut.
[window tapping]
Hey Andy.
You want to step out
for a minute Andy?
You know you kids shouldn't
be out past curfew.
Andy Effkin,
toast with the most.
So you like our chances against
Knight's Ridge on Friday?
We should do fine.
Oh, thrown for a loss.
How's that arm of
yours, okay for the game?
It's good.
That offensive line up to par?
Son of a bitch.
Hey Andy!
Huh?
[gun fires]
Fuck!
Easy Eff, easy buddy.
I need my fluids.
Give me the gun.
Get out of here Eff, now.
[ominous music]
What the fuck?
You gotta be shittin' me.
That's Mary Jo.
[car engine revving]
Hey Clarice, it's Cox here.
We got a wet one out
here on the bluff.
[dog barking]
[ominous music]
[ferry horn honking]
Hey!
I can't wait Steve,
I just can't wait!
To do what?
To see my new room, my new
school, my new everything.
Yeah, new everything.
It's gonna be awesome, Steve.
It's gonna be better.
Way better.
Come on.
[ominous music]
[ferry horn honking]
[chattering]
[car engine revving]
Looks like you're
moving to Cradle Bay.
We sure are.
I'm sure you're
gonna like it here.
You'll never want to leave.
Have a good one!
Did you hear that?
[eerie music]
[tranquil music]
Hey you, I thought you
were gonna help me, huh?
Come on.
Fridge.
Thank you.
You all right?
Yeah.
Just trying to put some
of this stuff away.
Nervous?
About what?
First day at school.
Dad?
What are you
doing dipshit, huh?
Don't worry about
snakes in the garden
when you got
spiders in your bed.
[heaving]
[rock music]
"And they had been so
innocent and little there,"
"and all beyond was
so unknown and great."
Very good, Trent.
To wit, when Pip says this,
Dickens is speaking of
the joy of discovery,
of newness, of change.
Mr. Clark, perhaps
you can relate?
Mr. Clark is new
to us from Chicago.
Do they read Dickens in Chicago?
Dickie Atkinson.
Welcome.
Tell us why you're late,
trouble with the camshaft?
Like you know what one is.
Somebody woke up
on the wrong side
of the carburetor this morning.
Peckerhead.
[laughing]
What is, if I may be so
forthright in displaying
my ignorance, a peckerhead?
What'cha laughing at, Whalen?
Nothing, Richard.
I was just thinking
how ignorance kills.
What does that mean?
Exactly.
You ass-kissing little fuck!
Boys, boys, boys!
Dickie, Dickie!
Perhaps, Mr. Atkinson,
yet another little sojourn to
the principal will
serve you well?
Want to know what
a peckerhead is?
That's a peckerhead.
Thank you for
the clarification.
Please send Principal
Weathers our hosannas!
"Youth is wholly experimental",
Robert Louis Stevenson.
♪ It's so hard, it's
so hard to stay alive
♪ When there's no
room to breathe
♪ And you stay alive,
you stay alive
♪ I know, what...
♪ Every little thing counts
♪ Thats why every
little thing counts
♪ Every little thing counts
Are these seats taken here?
No, go ahead.
I am Gavin, this is U.V.
I'm Steve.
Munchies.
U.V. here has some primo weed.
We smoked a fatty during gym.
Check him out, he looks
almost tan, don't he?
Hello Lorna, how are
you today, my dear?
Drop dead.
Contact.
Who's that?
That, my boy, is Lorna
"Love-itis" Longley.
Fire of my loins, purveyor of
my every masturbatory fantasy.
The entire female gender is
separated into two groups.
Lorna comprises one group.
All of womankind
comprises the other.
You ever take her out?
Alas, Lorna is
largely untouchable for
someone of my social standing.
What do you mean?
It's a class system here
at C.B. High, Stevie Boy.
Check it out.
There you got your
motorheads, car jocks.
All the world's a
gasket and a lube job
and a pack of Luckys.
Music of choice: Posi-traction
overdrive, classic rock,
Skynyrd, The Allmans, Bruce.
Drug of choice: Beer,
Miller Genuine Draft.
Keggers can't be choosers.
Freaks who fix leaks.
Ah, and over here you
have your microgeeks,
nerds, whiz kids and various
other bottom feeders.
Music of choice: The sound of
an Apple PC being booted up.
Drug of choice: Stephen Hawking's
A Brief History of Time,
and a cup of jasmine
tea on a Saturday night.
Freaks that go squeak.
Over there you
have your skaters.
Riffin', ragin' kids
and their ramp tramps.
Baggy pants, Dickie
wools, doing 50-50 grinds
with a gnarly grab finish on
a homemade halfpipe
in the woods.
Music of choice: The
whack of a hacky sack.
Drug of choice: Ecstasy, E-tab.
Baby, longer lovin'
through science.
Freaks in sneaks.
Here's where it
gets really nasty.
Lorna runs with that group
there, the Blue Ribbons.
What's that?
It's a community
group of good kids.
Have bake sales, car washes.
Kiss a lot of adult sphincter.
Blue Robots.
Hear, hear.
Those three guys:
Cradle Bay's answer
to Manson, McVeigh and O.J.
Trent Whalen, Andy
Effkin, Robby Stewart.
Hey, I bet you
didn't know that toast
came in three flavors.
This group's music of choice:
The hum of perfection,
the buzz of ambition.
Drug of choice: Life, the
pursuit of clean living
at the expense of all who sniffle
at the hem of their gowns.
Freaks, so chic.
Then you got kids
like me and U.V. here.
Lames who like our metal
heavy, our Marlboros light.
Music of choice:
Harvester of Sorrow,
Language of the Mad.
Drug of choice:
What do you got?
Freaks all week.
[school bell ringing]
That's it, lesson over.
Class dismembered.
Welcome to Cradle
Bay High, Stevie Boy.
Welcome to my nightmare.
[funky guitar music]
Yo, wait up!
[engine roaring]
[tires squealing]
(Boy): Why can't we help you
with your math, Johnny?
Just leave me alone.
Hello.
Hey.
Phlegm.
Phlegm, P-H-L-E-M-G-H.
Ehh, wrong.
Let me see that.
What are you two girls doing?
We're having a spelling bee
against Hessel Junior High.
Oh...
My brother Allen
was the best speller.
I thought your name was Steve.
It is.
Uhm, Allen's my
brother who died.
Oh, I have a
grandfather who died.
Why don't we
change the subject?
Pass your plate.
Why?
- You know why.
- Nathan.
Tell me Shannon,
do you get yelled at if you
talk about your
dead grandfather?
Steve!
Because around
here people go crazy
if you talk about
a dead brother.
[rock music]
[foreboding music]
Hello?
I'm here for the Mustang parts.
What the fuck?
What are you
doing here, man?
The troops shall set you free.
[ominous music]
What do you guys want?
Sweet Dickie, we want you.
We've got it for you, Richard.
We've got all the
winning numbers.
[rock music]
[shouting]
We like to welcome all
new students, Steven.
Standard procedure.
And as soon as Dr. Caldicott
arrives we can begin.
Dr. Caldicott?
He's the resident faculty
fellow, an outstanding educator.
He's been with us, what,
almost two years now?
Mm-hm.
Works with the students
in a counseling capacity.
I think you'll like him.
I'm sorry I'm late.
Hi, Edgar Caldicott.
It's nice to finally meet you.
Everything okay?
Fine.
Have you given any thought to
extracurricular
activities or sports?
Not really.
There's the Blue Ribbons.
The Blue Ribbons?
Yeah, they help each
other study and practice.
It's a team effort.
It's a motivational
workshop, really.
The Blue Ribboners have
truly been making the grade
and they're doing wonderful
things on the playing field.
Steven, all of
us here are aware
of the tragedy back in Chicago.
We want you to know if
there's anything we can do...
I said everything's fine.
Steven, we know
how tough it can be.
So whether or not you want to
be involved with the school,
we want to be involved with you.
That's really all the
meeting is about, okay?
Okay.
So go make some new friends.
[rock music]
[romantic music]
Like that?
What is it?
It's a bona fide jitterbug.
It's my buddy, Rachel,
Cook's Ridge trash.
She's a great chick,
don't get me wrong,
but she's Cook's Ridge trash.
Come on.
Hey there, dancing queen.
Rachel, this is Stevie Boy.
Good man.
Stevie Boy, this is Rachel,
Cook's Ridge trash.
Bite me.
Hey.
Wow, appropriate
sparks are flying.
Somebody cue power ballad.
Fail to be a tumor, Gavin.
What do you say we
cruise town, chase a case,
hit the bluff and
drink some beer?
You know, consecrate
Stevie Boy's arrival
to this new and
pathetic tank town.
You down?
Sounds razor.
Stevie Boy?
Sure.
[romantic music]
Excuse me, sir.
I'm wondering if you
can you help me out?
What was that all about?
I'm trying to buy some beer.
I have the money and everything,
I'm just a month from...
Get off my case, kid, okay?
You know, the
problem with America...
is mankind's abject
unwillingness
to contribute to the
delinquency of minors.
That was like the 10th guy.
Hey, Rachel.
- Chug.
- What are you doing?
Chasing, nobody's willing.
Yeah?
Hello, Charles, cycle any
anabolic goodies lately?
You're funny, Strick.
Thanks. I'm here all week.
Anyways, Rachel,
there's a couple of us guys
going to the Yogurt Shoppe
later if you want to come by.
The Yogurt Shoppe?
Yeah!
You wanna make an
"active culture" joke
here, Stevie Boy, or
should I handle this one?
See you later, Rachel.
Bye.
Oww...
- What?
You're actually flattered
that that barn door
has a thing for you?
Bullshit.
Right.
There's for the syrup.
Is that the right one
for the orange juice?
I don't know what I did with
the coupon for the deodorant,
it was here somewhere.
Hey Miffin, what's a hooker
say after 12 hours on the job?
What was that all about?
[spitting]
[laughing]
Clean up on aisle four.
[sound distorts]
Whoops, sorry.
[growling]
Come here!
[screaming]
[grunting]
[gasping]
Easy, Chug, easy, easy.
Fuck, you Blue
Ribbon shithead!
[growling]
What was that all about?
Toxic Jock Syndrome.
You'll be fine.
Where's my shake?
[foreboding music]
So what the hell would make
a kid freak out like that?
It's gotta be a steroid thing.
All those jockos are into it.
Kelly Connor said she saw
Andy Effkin bite the head off
a kitten in a fit of rage.
No way.
I'm serious.
I think it's bullshit, though.
No, it is not bullshit,
and it's not steroids.
Here we go.
What is it you got there?
Gavin thinks some
sinister force is
taking over the
Cradle Bay meatheads.
Nah, you know what
it is, you know.
A sinister force?
You know, evil, nowhere
to turn, no one to trust,
all together ookie.
Fail to be a
bimmy bitch, Rachel.
Fail to be a pucker-ass, Gav.
What is it you got there?
Nothing.
[engine revving]
[school bell ringing]
Andy killed her.
Everyone's saying she ran away.
I saw her dead body,
but I can't prove it.
God, those fuckers.
So why didn't you
go to the police?
Cox was there, man.
The cop, he didn't do shit.
Fuck, nobody listens to me.
Cancer Corner.
Best place in the school
by far to sneak a smoke.
[clattering]
What are you shitbirds
doing down here?
Relax, Mr. Newberry.
You ain't supposed
to be down here!
Relax, this is
my friend, Steve.
He's new to the Bay.
New to the Bay?
Gnaw, gnaw, gnaw.
Ratice, ratice, aha!
Excreta!
Drag marks.
Drag marks of a rat's tail.
What is it you got there?
It's an "E-rat-icator."
Sounds are supposed to
scare the rats away.
[humming]
You hear that?
Yeah.
Scary, ain't it?
Piece of crap.
Doesn't work worth spit!
A dollar for everything
that didn't work worth spit.
Mr. Newberry has
got the full on
Boo Radley village idiot
Quasimodo thing going.
Don't you, Mr. New?
What is it you got there?
And he's currently involved
in a war against the rodent
population of Cradle Bay.
[humming]
[spits] Gotta fight 'em!
Gotta fight 'em!
Rats from the Bay,
rats from the Bay!
Incoming,
you think you can run,
but you can't hide!
[rock music]
[cheering]
A day at the master races.
Check that out.
Jesus.
Is that Dickie,
what is he doing?
He's one of them now, bud.
He's a Blue Robot.
Watch and learn,
watch and learn!
What the fuck?
They're peckerheads.
Look at him.
He's killing his hard-on.
Fore!
Maybe he turned
over a new leaf.
I would like to own
the new leaf concession
here in Cradle Bay.
[glass shattering]
Did you tell Steve
about the murders?
Steve is a disbeliever.
Yeah, about the
mysterious disappearance
of Mary Jo Copeland and
Officer Kramer, uh-huh.
This is where he accuses
me of being paranoid.
Denial ain't just a
river in Italy, bud.
Check your weed, boys.
You are beige, boy.
See you, Rachel.
Bye.
[rock music]
[cheering]
Here's your chocolate sundae.
Hope you guys...
Can I help you?
Steven, good to
see you, brother.
- Hey, Trent.
- Come sit down.
Steven, this is Kathy, Andy,
Tom, Randi.
Hi.
Lorna, Chug.
You know Robby and Dickie.
This is Steven.
Sit down.
Steven's new to the
Bay from Chicago.
So do you like it here?
Yeah, it's okay.
You had friends in Chicago?
Yeah.
You can have friends here.
Didn't you guys get
into a fight in English?
We've made peace, Steven.
That's what separates
us from the animals.
Uh-oh, dirtbag alert.
Steve, hey, I gotta
talk to you man.
Easy, slick,
Steven's relaxing.
This place,
The Yogurt Shoppe.
Yogurt Shoppe, what
the fuck is a "shoppy"?
Why don't you make
like a tree and leaf?
Clever girl.
What, Steve?
What is it, we get
in one argument,
and you go bond
with these guys?
- Hello, Charles.
- Hey.
What happened to you, man?
Did you eat too
much flank steak?
Let's go.
You don't have to
go anywhere, brother.
I'm not your brother.
All right, you said you
wanted to tell me something?
Here I am, what?
They're hypnotized.
What?
Maybe not hypnotized,
then brainwashed,
lobotomized, programmed.
Want proof?
Here, here's proof.
Look, that's Robby,
Randi, Trent.
They used to be my friends.
All right, well maybe
they got sick of your rap.
I can relate.
Yeah, I thought
you'd say that.
That is the purpose of
tonight's excursion.
After tonight, you'll strap
on a hog and be a man.
[ominous music]
(Girl): Cross-pollinating the
efforts from different
student groups has
always been our goal.
And it's something
that benefits everyone.
The Thespian Society,
for example...
Blue Ribbon meeting,
every Monday.
This is where the shit
goes down, listen.
And by conducting the
bake sale in conjunction
with the pep rally, we can
be selling cakes and cookies
at a time when school spirit
is at its optimum level.
Wow, I had no idea the
evil was this pervasive.
Shh!
Yeah Jen,
what's on your mind?
This may sound kind
of strange but...
although we couldn't be
more pleased with Andrew's
improved studies, he's
become somewhat different,
since returning from your
weekend enlightenment seminar.
Different how?
He seems unkind to almost
everyone outside of the club.
Okay, well, I can
understand your concern.
And let me address it.
Kids being kids have,
you may have noticed,
a tendency to overreact.
We've found they go
through a brief period
of being, shall we say, snobby.
But what it really is, is a
feeling that's new to them.
And the feeling is pride.
They're improved.
When you soar with the eagles,
sometimes the pigeons below
tend to look a
little pedestrian.
- Just give it a little time.
- Dork.
Okay, now, a new candidate
has been nominated.
His parents have been
counseled and consented.
So Colleen, if you will.
- (Girl): Male 17 years old.
- Superstar.
Suspended four times
last school year.
Parents feel candidate
is depressed,
spending far too
much time listening
to rock music and masturbating.
Candidate has a
history of truancy.
Poor son of a bitch.
And a general
lack of direction.
Candidate is C-minus student,
yet has A-plus potential.
So, all in favor?
[ominous music]
Great, February
candidate confirmed.
Training to begin ASAP.
Shit.
What are they gonna do?
Now join me in welcoming
into our circle of friends,
Ernest and Lucille Strick.
[applauding]
The parents of our next
superstar, Gavin Strick.
So they want you
to join their club.
Shine 'em on and blow 'em off.
What are they gonna do?
No, you still don't get it.
You still think this is about
blood drives and bake sales.
Wait a second.
Maybe you should
lay off that shit.
Maybe you should eat me.
Yeah, okay.
This is huge, Steve!
Why don't you see that
this is so fucking huge?
Gavin...
Don't fucking "Gavin"
me, I'm a dead man.
My parents sold me out.
You saw it, you were there.
Why don't you see this?
Look, why don't you stay
over at my house tonight?
No, I have to go home.
When I get there and
they're waiting for me,
I'm gonna smoke 'em
all, you hear me?
Everyone who's at my house:
Robby, Whalen, Caldicott,
even my olds, man.
Give me the gun.
No fucking way.
Let me have it!
No, you're fucking
losing it Gavin!
You're gonna wind up
shooting the paperboy.
Just go home.
Give me my fucking gun.
Hey, hey!
Good night, Gavin.
Give me my fucking gun!
Don't leave me alone like this!
Hey, Stevie Boy?
I would have smoked
them all, fuck, man.
[foreboding music]
Fuck man, fuck.
[anticipatory music]
Wait a minute.
Wow...
- What is this?
- I don't believe it!
Show time.
[mellow music]
Who put the acid in my Spam?
Rachel!
Gavin!
Hello, Rachel.
What are they gonna do?
I just want to apply myself.
I think I'll get better results
on this side of the caf.
Gavin...
Why don't you beat it, honey?
This is rarefied turf.
Sluts need not apply.
Gavin.
Later, Rachel.
How much do I owe you for this?
Treat yourself.
Indeed.
Where you going?
I'm going to talk to Gavin.
You're not wanted,
Steven, just leave him be.
Get the fuck off me.
Hey guys, come on.
[scuffling]
What's your
maladjustment, Andy?
[screaming]
[anticipatory music]
You okay?
Steve!
Forget it!
Stop it!
That's enough!
[heaving]
[coughing]
What happened to you?
We shall overcome, Steven.
You okay?
Oh man, fantastic.
[groaning]
You'll see.
Retard.
[laughing]
Are you okay?
[relaxing music]
[applauding]
[cheering]
Yeah, yeah!
We should have a toast!
A toast to Gavin Strick!
[glasses clinging]
[laughing]
What are you doing here?
You're not supposed to be here.
I hate the caf.
Everybody hates the caf.
They hate the ketchup.
I got...
Oh, that's not good.
Doesn't even look like ketchup.
Slaughterhouse-Five?
What? Give me
that, give me that!
What the hell's the
matter with you?
You rats from the Bay.
You rats, rats everywhere.
You kids are so smart, you
think you know everything!
You don't know nothing!
Forget the rats.
It's all an act, isn't it?
You don't know.
It's an act isn't it.
It's all bullshit.
Will you get away from me!?
Oh brother!
[serene music]
Wait.
Do you like Kurt Vonnegut?
I don't get it.
Didn't you ever want to
just disappear, lunch boy?
Poof, you're gone.
You'd be surprised how
interesting people become,
when they think you
are really stupid.
[foreboding music]
(Boy): Steven!
Where are you going, Steven?
Who is it?
(Boy #2): Calm down, Steven,
(Boy #1): It's past
your bedtime, Steven.
Where you going, Steven?
[various voices calling]
There's nothing to
be afraid of, Steven.
[laughing]
Hello, Steven.
What are you doing here?
I'm helping Lindsay, I'm
tutoring her in algebra.
Where is she?
Shh.
Where's my sister?
She's upstairs sleeping.
Where are my parents?
At a meeting.
At what meeting?
Steven, you're hurt.
I'll live.
Let me put something on that.
It's fine.
Maybe you should go.
I mean it.
If that's what you want.
Yeah.
Can I go to the
bathroom first?
Sure, it's around the corner.
I know where it is.
Of course you do.
Everyone knows where
everything is around here.
Steven, your sister's a
great kid, she's very special.
[ominous music]
Hello, Steven.
What are you doing?
I'm not sure, really.
Go home, Lorna.
You don't even find
me slightly attractive?
I find you very attractive.
It's just that you're a
Blue Ribbon and I'm not.
So...
[eerie music]
Wait a second.
I know I'm not supposed
to be doing this.
It's bad, wrong,
wrong, bad.
No it's not bad, it's...
[glass shattering]
Jesus Christ.
Wrong, bad, bad, wrong,
wrong, bad, bad, wrong,
bad, wrong, wrong, bad,
bad, wrong...
Lorna!
[foreboding music]
I have to go home.
I have a big physics
test tomorrow.
[ominous music]
(Woman):
After extracting the implant,
I tested its integrity to the
optic nerve and it was intact.
The chip is
functioning properly.
But what I did find is
that excess stimulation
to the pineal gland
caused the dopamine levels
to go through the roof.
Every time one of these
kids gets a hard-on,
they go out and beat
somebody with it.
We could do a cingulotomy.
No just cut a craniotomy flap.
I'll get elbow deep,
see what happens.
What you looking at, retard?
You gotta cut the
bruises out of the banana.
What you looking at, retard?
Just tell them
she'll be missing
cheerleading practice this week.
[saw whirring]
Oh look, Cook's Ridge trash.
(Caldecott): Oh, you know,
once you've all settled in,
and if you give her
a little bit of time
I'm sure she'll
fit in just fine.
Well, thanks,
Dr. Caldicott.
Did you hear that, Nancy?
Yeah, alright, Mom.
[foreboding music]
Hey, come on, let's go.
I gotta sell this bud.
I got like two customers left.
If this keeps up I'm
gonna be the 7-Eleven guy.
I'm gonna go grab a smoke.
[door opening]
[door slamming shut]
Come out, come out,
wherever you are.
I saw you come
down here, Rachel.
Look, I just want to
ask you something.
What you looking at, retard?
I just want to know...
It's me asking,
my friends not.
Rachel, uh, will
you go out with me?
You're kidding, right?
Will you, please?
No, Chug, I won't.
Why not?!
How about this?
You couldn't repulse me
more if you were made out
of equal parts of
shit and maggots!
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Yeah, you want to be that way?
Stop it Chug,
I'll scream, I swear to God.
- Yeah?
- Yeah!
Yeah, and what do you think
will happen if you do, huh?
I'm a Blue Ribbon,
baby, team captain.
You're just a trashy,
tattooed love doll.
Come on Rae-Rae, give up the
plate for Chug huh, come on!
Ah, fuck!
[humming]
[screaming]
Oh fuck!
Stop it!
[groaning]
What you looking at, retard?
Wow.
I guess I just think that you
should try and fit in, Steve,
because we're gonna be
here for a long time.
You, me, Mom and Dad.
And Chip and Dale.
Chip and Dale.
[playfully groaning]
What you looking at, retard?
What?
This, where did you get this?
I got it at school.
They were handing them out,
we all got one.
[funky music]
Go inside.
Why?
Hi Lindsay.
I said go inside!
Spaz.
[melancholy music]
[knocking]
We should talk.
Yeah.
There's something
you need to see.
Rae, Gavin Strick here.
Live and unplugged.
Guess if you found
this then you know.
Am I hanging with
Trent and Robby,
and the rest of the Robots?
God, I hope not.
I hit the vents tonight when
I split up with Stevie Boy.
He doesn't believe.
I went back to school
and I overheard Caldicott
talking to some wonk.
Mentioned "Bishop Flats Eleven".
Caldicott called
them his children.
And then he freaked
out on the guy
and kicked him
out of his office.
So, you know, I figure
something's up with that, right?
Keep an eye on U.V.
for me, though I doubt
that they'll want him.
I doubt that they're
interested in
the pigmentally challenged.
That's not their style.
I gotta go get paranoid.
This is Gavin Strick,
reporting live from
the Reconstruction.
I pulled this off
the AMA database.
Caldicott's last
place of employment
was just across the
bay in Bishop Flats,
at a place called the Bellknop
Psychiatric Facility.
He spent seven year
doing neuropharmacology.
Mind control.
Next ferry's at six.
Bishop Flats?
You down for it?
Razor.
Let's go.
I miss Gavin,
he's almost like a...
A brother?
Yeah, exactly.
[sad music]
I had a brother.
Sorry.
His name was Allen.
He was a couple
years older than me.
If he would've made
it through his teens,
he would have been
something amazing.
But he was always in pain.
[gun fires]
And eight months to the
day he shot himself,
Dad said we were
moving to Cradle Bay,
where everything was
gonna be all right.
I'm sorry.
No, don't.
Let's go.
[ominous music]
You know, maybe this
isn't such a good idea.
Think of it as our first date.
[frightening music]
[snarls]
[screaming]
[machinery beeping]
[rumbling]
[groaning]
That's why my
tooths are clean.
[pleasant music]
Be pretty,
and do it just right.
[groaning]
[screaming]
Children, children.
[chattering]
Meet the musical
little creatures
that hide among the flowers.
Meet the musical
little creatures
that hide among the flowers.
Meet the musical
little creatures
that hide among the flowers.
Meet the musical
little creatures
that hide among the flowers.
[moaning]
[screaming]
Shut up!
[mellow groaning]
[foreboding music]
Let's get out of here.
It's Caldicott's daughter.
♪ Paranoia, paranoia
♪ Everybody's coming to get me
♪ Just say you never met me
♪ I'm running underground
with the moles
♪ I'm not sick but I'm not well
♪ Because I'm in hell
His daughter,
his own daughter.
How can nobody not
know that there's
something fully fucked
up in Bishop Flats?
Shit, his own daughter was
in there, nobody's safe.
[relaxing music]
Listen, the last ferry
leaves at 11:30.
Just tell me you
have a razor plan.
I am making this
shit up as I go.
Great.
Shit.
Hi, Officer Cox.
Closing time, Frankie.
Yeah, it's getting late.
Just be cool.
It's past curfew.
She's just driving me home.
From?
Studying.
Where are your books?
[foreboding music]
Evening, Officer.
What are you doing?
I'm getting rid of rats.
The pink-eyed vermin
can't see for spit.
Quarter a rat.
Town council gives
me a quarter a rat.
I'm going to be
rich at this rate.
I'll be on "Lifestyles
of the Rich and Famous".
Moron.
[car engine revving]
Where are you going?
Can we go now?
Step out of the truck, now.
[ominous music]
What are you doing?
Hey!
Hey, let her go!
What do you want from...
[groaning]
Get in.
That's a big rat.
Come on, get out of there!
What are you waiting for,
get, get, get, get, get!
Fine, come on, Linds.
Let's get out of here.
You have to trust me for now.
You trust me, don't you?
Steve!
Where are you going?
I'm taking Lindsay
away from here.
We're going back to Chicago.
Don't do this Steve,
you're scaring me.
I'm scared too,
Mom, believe me.
Look Stevie, you have to know
that we're here for
you no matter what.
Oh God, do you
really mean that?
Of course we do.
Okay, then let's all go home.
Steven, you are home.
Cradle Bay is
where you belong.
Here with your family.
You signed me up
for the program?
We want what's best for you.
What about what I want?
Look, Steven, do you
really like the way you feel?
Oh, shut the fuck up!
You sold me out.
No we didn't,
we just want you back.
Steven, please...
My name is Steve, okay?
Nobody calls me Steven
except for them.
Fine, come on, Linds.
Steve.
[anticipatory music]
May I have this dance, Steven?
Where's Rachel?
She's gone to an institute
of higher learning, Steven.
[groaning]
Steve!
Steve, help!
[screaming]
Don't worry, everything's
under control.
Who's your daddy, huh?
[intense music]
Respect yourself, Steven.
Ice, ice, baby.
[foreboding music]
It's not what you think, Steven.
It's a new kind of cool.
You feel better, freer.
I've never felt so
alive in my life.
It's humanity's
sacred essence.
A new and finer age.
Go forward.
Be the ball.
[foreboding music]
People are gonna know
when I get out of here.
That's right Steven,
they will know.
They'll know because
you'll be better.
Adolescence is a minefield.
But soon, you'll be fully equipped
to walk right through it.
Yeah, straight A's
and a letter jacket.
And every now and then,
you rape and kill.
To cure cancer, you gotta
kill a few white mice.
Meet the musical
little creatures...
that hide among the flowers.
That's a battle I didn't win.
You'll be different.
I know so much more now.
She wasn't that
bright to begin with.
[frightening music]
(Distorted voice):
Be all that's good.
Stop fooling around.
Let the light in.
[sizzling]
[laughing]
[fireworks exploding]
Be excellent.
You're number one.
You're an ace.
Achieve.
[multiple voices chanting]
[alarm beeping]
[groaning]
[alarm blaring]
[exciting music]
[clanging]
Rachel?
Rae?
You'll be okay.
You'll be okay, Rachel.
Going somewhere with
my custard there, Steven?
Let's go, Chug.
That's my girl you
got there, Steve.
I can't let you take her,
now can I?
Come on! Get up!
Come on, Rae-Rae, give up
the plate for old Chug, huh?
[foreboding music]
Come on.
Lindsay!
Hey, not so fast!
What are you doing?
What's the capital
of North Dakota?
How the fuck should I know?
Okay, you're cool, get in.
We gotta book, early bird
ferry is in 20 minutes.
Oh shit, man.
It's time to leave
mediocrity behind, Steven.
Step up on the bus.
[car horn honking]
What is it?
[cheering]
[humming]
[screaming]
Come and get it,
you blue bastards!
What are you doing?
Come on.
Get them to the ferry.
I'll meet you down there.
Don't leave without me.
[engine revving]
Hey, lunch boy.
What are you doing?
We can't very well
have these shitbirds
graduating and going off
into the world, can we?
Maybe they can be helped?
No, they can't
and neither can I.
Do good things,
lunch boy.
[signal reverberating]
[screaming]
Hey, teacher!
Leave those kids alone!
No!
[screaming]
[panting]
It's over, you son of
a bitch, it's finished.
Finished?
There will always
be other towns,
and other troubled teens,
and other worried parents.
Science is God.
[rock music]
Be the ball.
[screaming]
[melancholy music]
[motorcycle engine revving]
What are you doing?
We're the only ones left.
So, what do we do now?
We go home.
And where's that?
Wherever.
Wherever we are.
Oh, appropriate
sparks are flying.
Somebody cue up the
power ballad, man.
[rap-rock music]
Hey!
All right now, settle down.
Turn that damn thing off.
Now, y'all got a new student
teacher starting today.
And I want you to
show him a little bit
more respect than the last one.
Speak of the devil.
[funky music]
Say hello to your new
student teacher, class.
They're all yours.
Peckerhead.
Hello class, welcome.
♪ I've got you where I want you
♪ Yeah
♪ Ah-ooh
♪ I've got you where I want you
♪ Yeah
♪ Hey
♪ Maybe just a smile
♪ Oh, hey
♪ Did you know that I can dance
♪ Could we talk for a while
♪ Well, I think you're smart
♪ You sweet thing
♪ Tell me your sign
♪ I'm dying here
♪ Ah-ooh
♪ I've got you where I want you
♪ Yeah
♪ Ah-ooh
♪ I've got you where I want you
♪ Where I want you, I want you
♪ Suffer, suffer
♪ Me don't get no rougher
♪ Rub it up, baby girl
♪ Torture me like no other
♪ Suffer, suffer
♪ Me don't get no rougher
♪ When me rock me, baby
♪ Put me pain on me, lover
♪ Suffer, suffer
♪ Me don't get no rougher
♪ Rub it up, baby girl
♪ Torture me like no other
♪ Suffer, suffer
♪ Me don't get no rougher
♪ When me rock me, baby
♪ Put me pain on me, lover
♪ Well, I think you're smart
♪ You sweet thing
♪ Tell me your name
♪ I'm dying here
♪ Ah-ooh, suffer, suffer,
me don't get no rougher
♪ Rub it up, baby girl,
torture me like no other
♪ I've got you where I want you
♪ Suffer, suffer, me
don't get no rougher
♪ Hey, yeah
♪ When me rock me, baby,
put me pain on me, lover
♪ I've got you where I want you
♪ Suffer, suffer, me
don't get no rougher
♪ Yeah
♪ Rub it up, baby girl,
torture me like no other
♪ I've got you where I want you
♪ Suffer, suffer, me
don't get no rougher
♪ Want you, want you, yeah
♪ Where I want you
♪ I've got you where I want you
[funky music]
♪ Now it's time
to live your life
♪ Sitting back and out of sight
♪ You almost get the
feeling that you're free
♪ Lay back in your easy chair
♪ Close your eyes
like you don't care
♪ It's easier to
follow than to lead
♪ Sometimes
♪ You feel the need inside
♪ Leave it all behind
♪ Sometimes
♪ Let it slide
♪ It's time to find your wings
♪ And fly away
♪ Time is growing back
♪ Tell me you can
feel it sliding
♪ Dreaming all the dreams
♪ Floating free now yeah
♪ Fly
♪ Sometimes
♪ You feel the need inside
♪ Leave it all behind
♪ Sometimes
♪ Let it slide
♪ It's time to find your wings
♪ And fly away
♪ Sometimes
♪ You feel the need inside
♪ Leave it all behind you
♪ Sometimes
♪ Let it slide
♪ It's time to find your wings
♪ And fly away
(Man): Let the light in.
[intense music]
Be excellent
Yes, wonderful.
(Girl): Meet the musical
little creatures
that hide in the flowers.
Treat yourself.