My father's name was John Kinsella.
It's an Irish name.
He was born in North Dakota in 1896...
...and never saw a big city...
...until he came back from France in 1918.
He settled in Chicago, where he learned
to live and die with the White Sox.
Died a little
when they lost the 1919 World Series...
...died a lot the following summer
when eight teammates...
...were accused of throwing that Series.
He played some in the minors,
but nothing came of it.
Moved to Brooklyn in '35...
...married Mom in '38...
...was already an old man
at the naval yards...
...when I was born in 1952.
My name's Ray Kinsella.
Mom died when I was 3,
and I suppose Dad did the best he could.
Instead of Mother Goose, I was put to bed
to stories of Babe Ruth, Lou Gehrig...
...and the great Shoeless Joe Jackson.
Dad was a Yankees fan then,
so I rooted for Brooklyn.
But in '58, the Dodgers moved away,
so we had to find other reasons to fight.
We did.
When it came time to go to college...
...I picked the farthest
from home I could find.
This drove him up the wall,
which, I suppose, was the point.
Officially my major was English,
but really it was the '60s.
I marched, I smoked some grass...
...I tried to like sitar music,
and I met Annie.
The only thing we had in common
was that she came from Iowa...
...and I'd once heard of Iowa.
After graduation,
we moved to the Midwest...
...and stayed with her family
as long as we could.
Almost a full afternoon.
Annie and I got married in June of '74.
Dad died that fall.
A few years later, Karin was born.
She smelled weird,
but we loved her anyway.
Then Annie got the crazy idea
that she could talk me into buying a farm.
I'm 36 years old, I love my family,
I love baseball...
...and I'm about to become a farmer.
But until I heard the voice...
...I'd never done a crazy thing
in my whole life.
If you build it, he will come.
Hey, Annie!
- Annie, what was that?
- What was what?
That voice just now. What was it?
We didn't hear anything.
All right.
If you build it, he will come.
- Okay, you must have heard that!
- Sorry.
Hey, come on in to dinner.
Let's go, pumpkin.
Is there a sound truck on the highway?
Nope. Hey, Karin, dinner's ready!
- Kids with a radio?
- Nope.
- Are you really hearing voices?
- Just one.
What did it say?
"If you build it, he will come."
- If you build what, who will come?
- He didn't say.
- I hate it when that happens.
- Me, too.
If you build it, he will come.
Build what? What is this?
It's okay, honey.
I'm just talking to the corn field.
Anyway, I was walking
down along the street...
...and I heard this voice saying...
..."Good evening, Mr. Dowd."
Well, I turned around...
...and here was this big six-foot rabbit
leaning up against the lamppost.
- Why did you do that? It was funny.
- Trust me. It's not funny.
The man is sick. Very sick.
Honey, get your book bag. Let's go!
I'll take her today.
I've got some errands to do in town.
Far-out.
- What if the voice calls while you're gone?
- Take a message.
- 'Bye.
'Bye.
In all those years, did you ever...
It's just I've heard
that sometimes farmers in the field...
They hear things. You know, voices.
- You hearing voices?
- No. It's just I heard some farmers do.
I, of course, don't, so I was wondering
if I was doing something wrong.
Did you ever hear voices out there?
- Who's hearing voices?
- Ray is. Out in the fields.
No, I'm not.
I'm...
Noises.
That darned tractor...
I'm just going to get some 3-in-1oil.
That ought to do it.
Nice talking to you.
If you build it, he will come.
All right, that's it! Who the...
Who are you? What do you want from me?
Son of a bitch.
If you build it, he will come.
If you build it...
...he will come.
You don't suppose
this is like an acid flashback?
I never took acid.
Maybe you will someday.
It's like a flash-forward.
Annie, there's more.
Honey, why don't you eat a little bit?
I think I know what
"If you build it, he will come" means.
Why do I not think
this is such a good thing?
I think it means
that if I build a baseball field out there...
...Shoeless Joe Jackson
will come back and play ball again.
You're kidding?
You're kidding.
Boy, I thought my family was crazy...
...but this is the craziest thing
I've ever heard.
I know it's totally nuts.
- I mean, Shoeless Joe!
- He's dead. Died in '51. He's dead.
- They suspended him, right?
- Right.
- He's still dead?
- As far as I know.
Did you know Babe Ruth copied his swing?
If I did, I've forgotten it.
He was supposed to be
so graceful and agile.
I'd actually like to see him play again...
...to let him play, to right an old wrong.
Wait. Wait a minute.
- Are you actually thinking of doing this?
- No.
I can't think of one good reason
why I should, but...
I'm 36. I have a wife,
a child, and a mortgage...
...and I'm scared to death
I'm turning into my father.
What does he have to do with all this?
I never forgave him for getting old.
By the time he was as old as I am now...
...he was ancient.
He must have had dreams,
but he never did anything about them.
For all I know,
he may have even heard voices, too...
...but he sure didn't listen to them.
The man never did one spontaneous thing
in all the years I knew him.
I'm afraid of that happening to me...
...and something tells me
this may be my last chance...
...to do something about it.
I want to build that field.
Do you think I'm crazy?
Yes.
But I also think
if you really feel you should do this...
...then you should do it.
- What the hell is he doing?
- He's plowing under his corn.
Why?
Ty Cobb called him
the greatest left fielder of all time.
He said his glove
was the place where triples go to die.
- Could he hit?
Lifetime average .356,
third highest in history.
Why'd they call him "Shoeless Joe"?
When he was in the minors...
...he bought a new pair of spikes
and hurt his feet.
In the 6th inning, he took them off
and played in his socks.
The players kidded him, called him
"Shoeless Joe" and the name stuck.
He's going to lose his farm.
Damned fool.
Then in 1919,
his team the Chicago White Sox...
...threw the World Series.
- What's "threw"?
- It means they lost it on purpose.
Gamblers paid them to.
Except Shoeless Joe.
He did take their money,
but nobody ever proved he did one thing...
...to lose those games.
If he threw it, how do you explain
that he hit .375 for the Series...
...and committed no errors?
I can't.
Twelve hits including
the Series' only home run...
...and they said he's trying to lose?
It's ridiculous.
The commissioner of baseball
suspended eight of the players...
...including the great Shoeless Joe
Jackson, for life.
What's "suspend"?
It means they never
let him play the game again.
My father said he saw him years later...
...playing under a made-up name
in some 10th-rate league in Carolina.
He'd put on 50 pounds,
and his spring was gone from his step...
...but he could still hit.
Dad used to say
nobody could hit like Shoeless Joe.
I think that's the first time
I've ever seen you smile...
...when you mentioned your father.
I have just created something
totally illogical.
That's what I like about it.
Am I completely nuts?
Not completely.
It's a good baseball field, Ray.
It's kind of pretty, isn't it?
Any sign?
Something's going to happen out there.
I can feel it.
So, for the veteran southpaw,
his summer of woes continues.
That's four straight hits in the inning.
Daddy, what's a "southpaw"?
It means a left-handed pitcher, honey.
- So how bad is it?
- Well.
Considering how much less acreage
we have for corn, I say we'll probably...
...almost break even.
We used up all our savings on that field.
- Daddy?
- Just a minute, Karin.
So what are you saying?
We can't keep the field?
Makes it real hard to keep the farm.
- Daddy.
- In a minute, Karin!
There's a man out there on your lawn.
I'll put up some coffee.
Why don't you go on outside?
Sorry.
I'll get some out there.
Hi.
Ray Kinsella.
Joe Jackson.
I bet it's good to be playing again.
Getting thrown out of baseball...
...was like having part of me amputated.
I've heard that old men wake up...
...and scratch itchy legs
that have been dust for over 50 years.
That was me.
I'd wake up at night...
...with the smell
of the ballpark in my nose...
...with the cool of the grass on my feet...
...the thrill of the grass.
Can you pitch?
Yeah.
Not bad.
- Don't we need a catcher?
- Not if you get it near the plate.
Right.
I'm pitching to Shoeless Joe Jackson.
Nice hit.
See if you can hit my curve.
- You can hit the curve ball.
- Put one right here.
Right.
Right, you're a low-ball hitter.
Man, I did love this game.
I'd have played for food money.
It was the game, the sounds, the smells.
Did you ever hold a ball
or a glove to your face?
Yeah.
I used to love traveling on the trains
from town to town.
The hotels, brass spittoons in the lobbies...
...brass beds in the rooms.
It was the crowd...
...rising to their feet
when the ball was hit deep.
I'd play for nothing.
It's my family.
What's with the lights?
All the stadiums have them now.
- Even Wrigley Field.
- It's harder to see the ball.
The owners found that more people
can attend night games.
Owners.
Mr. Jackson, this is my wife Annie
and my daughter Karin.
Ma'am.
Are you a ghost?
- She's kidding.
- That's okay.
- What do you think?
- You look real to me.
Then I guess I'm real.
Would you like to come inside?
Thanks. I don't think I can.
Can I come back again?
Yeah. I built this for you.
There are others, you know.
There were eight of us.
It would really mean a lot to them.
Yeah. Anytime. They're all welcome here.
Is this heaven?
No.
It's Iowa.
- Where's he going?
- I don't know.
We're keeping this field.
You bet your ass we are.
- You're going to lose your farm, pal.
- How can you lose something so big?
- He misplaced the house once.
- Yeah, but it turned up two days later.
Come on. Ray?
This stupid baseball field will bankrupt you.
Everybody knows it.
If you default on your loan,
you'll lose everything.
If you sell now,
my partners will give you a fair price.
- Thanks, Mark, but no.
- No.
What are you holding onto this place for?
- You never liked Iowa.
- That's not true.
You never liked farming. It is true.
You don't know about farming.
I know a lot about farming.
More than you think.
Well, then how could you plow
under your major crop?
What's a crop?
- Come on. That is funny.
- "What's a crop?"
- Daddy, the baseball game is on.
- Excuse us.
Excuse us.
Annie, I don't believe this guy.
I'm trying to bail him out,
and he leaves to watch television.
- He used to be so normal.
- Yeah.
Hoy! Hoy! Hoy!
All right!
Watch Joe's feet.
A good left fielder
knows what pitch is coming.
He can tell from the bat's angle
which way the ball's heading.
- Show off!
- Stick it in your ear, Gandil.
If you'd have run like that against Detroit,
I'd have won 20 games that year!
For Pete's sakes, Cicotte,
that was 68 years ago. Give it up!
Hey! You guys want to play ball or what?
- Muscle-bound jerk.
- Oh, yeah? At least I got muscles.
- At most, you got muscles.
- Come on, asshole! Pitch!
Weaver, be nice.
- Sorry, kid!
- It's okay. I don't mind.
- All right, Karin.
- Hey, hey, hey!
Mom and everybody are leaving now.
Oh, well, it was...
You know. Thanks for coming.
Think about what I said.
I'm just trying to help.
I know.
Thought you were watching some game.
It's not really a game.
It's more like practice.
There are only eight of them.
They can't play a real game.
- Eight of what?
- Them.
- Who "them"?
- Them them.
- You don't see them?
- Karin, honey, what are you watching?
- The baseball men.
- Baseball men?
- Do you see the baseball men right now?
- Of course, I do.
You really don't see them?
I don't think it's very polite
to try to make other people feel stupid.
Mom, wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Dee, wait. You don't see these people?
It's not funny, Annie.
They couldn't see it.
This is really interesting.
Hey, Ray, look at this.
68 years since I wore this uniform,
still fits me like a glove.
You must keep in pretty good shape.
Now let's see, I died in '70.
That means I haven't had
a cigarette in 18 years.
- You don't smoke, do you?
- No.
Karin! Ray! Dinner!
"Ray, dinner."
- All right.
- Come on. Let's hit the showers.
See you later.
See you, guys.
"I'm melting! I'm melting!"
Come on, you knucklehead.
That is so cool.
- Ease his pain.
- What?
I'm sorry. What?
I didn't understand. What?
Ease his pain.
"Ease his pain."
What the hell does that mean?
"Ease his pain"? What pain?
All right. Whose pain?
Thanks a lot.
Come on, honey, wash up.
We got the PTA meeting after dinner.
They're talking about banning books again.
Really subversive books like
The Wizard of Oz, The Diary of Anne Frank.
- What happened to you?
- The voice is back.
Oh, Lord! You don't have to build
a football field now, do you?
He said, "Ease his pain."
- Ease whose pain?
- I asked him. He wouldn't tell me.
- Shoeless Joe's?
- I don't think so.
- One of the other players?
This is a very nonspecific voice out there,
and he's starting to piss me off.
I was having a fun day today. A good day.
Want a fry?
And I say smut and filth like this
has no place in our schools.
Fascist. I'd like to ease her pain.
Mrs. Kessinik, that book
you're waving about is hardly smut.
It's considered by many critics
to be the classic novel about the 1960s.
- It's pornography!
- No. The Supreme Court says it's not.
- And it's author, Mr. Mann...
- Is sick!
Terence Mann is a Pulitzer Prize winner.
He's widely regarded
as the finest satirist of his time.
Yeah, well, I think he's a pervert!
Probably a communist, too!
What planet are these people from?
The so-called novels of Terence Mann...
...endorse promiscuity, godlessness...
...the mongrelization of the races,
and disrespect to high-ranking officers...
...of the United States Army.
And that's why
right-thinking school boards...
...all across the country
have been banning this man's s-h-i-t...
...since 1969.
Terence Mann?
You know why he stopped writing books?
Because he masturbates.
Excuse me, madam.
Excuse me.
Terence Mann was a warm
and gentle voice of reason...
...during a time of great madness.
He coined the phrase,
"Make love, not war."
While other people chanted, "Burn,
baby, burn," he was talking about love...
...and peace and understanding.
I cherished every one of his books,
and I dearly wish he had written more.
Maybe if you had experienced
even a little bit of the '60s...
...you might feel the same way, too.
I experienced the '60s.
No, you had two '50s
and moved right into the '70s.
Annie, look at this.
Your husband plowed under his corn
and built a baseball field.
- Now, there's an intelligent response.
- The weirdo.
- Annie.
- Honey, it's all right. I'll be cool.
At least he is not a book-burner,
you Nazi cow.
At least I'm not married to the biggest
horse's ass in three counties.
All right, Beulah,
do you want to step outside?
Fine!
All right, I've got a better idea.
Let's take a vote. Who's for Eva Braun?
Who wants to burn books?
Who wants to spit on the Constitution of
the United States of America? Anybody?
All right.
Now, who's for the Bill of Rights?
Who thinks freedom
is a pretty darn good thing?
Come on! Let's see those hands!
Who thinks we have to stand up...
...to the kind of censorship
they had under Stalin?
All right. There you go.
America, I love you. I'm proud of you.
- We got to go.
This is great!
I figured it out.
Was that great, or what?
- I figured it out.
- It's just like the '60s again!
- Step outside, you Nazi cow.
- I know whose pain I'm supposed to ease.
- What?
I just halted the spread
of neofascism in America...
- Terence Mann.
- What about him?
- That's whose pain.
- How do you know that?
I just know.
I was right about building the field,
wasn't I?
- Yes. What's his pain?
- I don't know.
- How are you supposed to ease it?
Look, he's my favorite writer, too...
...but what's Terence Mann
got to do with baseball?
It's incredible. By the early '70s,
the guy decides people have become...
...either too extremist
or too apathetic to listen.
So he stops writing books,
he starts writing poetry about whales...
...and then he starts fooling around
with a home computer.
Know what he does now?
He writes software
for interactive children's videos.
They teach kids
how to resolve their conflicts peacefully.
- God, what an amazing guy.
- What's that got to do with baseball?
In the April 1962 issue of Jet magazine...
...there's a story called
"This Is Not A Kite."
It's not his best work, but the story's hero
is named John Kinsella.
- My father.
- Wow.
What do you mean, "Wow"?
What should I say? Big wow!
What's it got to do with baseball?
You drive.
Okay, the last interview
he ever gave was in 1973.
- Guess what it's about.
- Some kind of team sport.
The guy was a baseball fanatic.
Listen to this:
"As a child, my earliest recurring dream
was to play at Ebbets Field...
"...with Jackie Robinson
and the Brooklyn Dodgers.
"Of course, it never happened.
The Dodgers left Brooklyn.
"They tore down Ebbets Field,
but even now, I still dream that dream."
That's sad.
The man wrote the best books
of his generation.
He was a pioneer in the civil rights
and the antiwar movement.
He made the cover of Newsweek.
He knew everybody. He did everything.
He helped shape his time.
The guy hung out with The Beatles.
It wasn't enough.
What he missed was baseball.
- Oh, my God!
- What?
As a small boy,
he had a bat named Rosebud.
- Give me that.
- Sorry.
The guy hasn't been
to a baseball game since 1958.
So, to ease his pain, you're supposed
to take him to a ball game.
Yes.
Ray, this is nuttier
than building the baseball field.
No, it's not. It's pretty weird,
but building the field was weirder.
Five, ten percent weirder.
I'm sorry, I'm going to have
to nip this one in the bud.
We're having moderate to heavy
financial difficulties here.
You can't take off for Boston
while we're going broke in Iowa.
This is really new territory for us...
...but we're dealing
with primal forces of nature.
When primal forces of nature tell you
to do something...
...it's not prudent to quibble over details.
- Why do you have to go?
Why can't the voice send somebody else?
How about Shirley MacLaine?
Is she too busy?
What does this have to do with you?
That's what I have to find out.
We are behind on the mortgage.
That field ate up all of our savings.
We could lose this farm.
I won't even stay in motels.
I'll sleep in the car. I'll beg for food.
No. Now, this is too much.
I understand your need to prove
to yourself and to the world...
...you are not turning into your father,
but you have.
You believed in the magic.
It happened. Isn't that enough?
It's more than that.
I know this is totally nuts...
...but there's another reason
I'm supposed to do it.
I feel it as strongly as I've felt anything
in my life. There's a reason.
What? Just tell me what it is.
Something's going to happen at the game.
There's something at Fenway Park.
I got to be there
with Terence Mann to find it out.
Is Fenway the one
with the big green wall in left field?
Yeah.
I dreamt last night
you were at Fenway with Terence Mann.
- Was I sitting on the first base side?
- Yes.
About halfway up on the aisle?
- Yeah. Eating a hot dog.
- Eating a hot dog.
- I had the same dream.
- I'll help you pack.
Hi, I'm Ray Kinsella.
Hi. No.
It's a great pleasure to finally get to...
Hi, I'm Ray Kinsella. I'm a big fan of yours.
Hi.
How do you do, Mr. Mann?
I have to take you to a base...
All right, stupid,
put your hands up and get in the trunk.
Good.
He lives right around here.
Do you know him?
He's sort of a tall black man.
I'm a friend of his.
If he was much of a friend,
he'd have given you the directions himself.
That's a good point. Thank you.
I don't know where he lives.
Get away from me.
I ain't going to tell you nothing.
Go away. You're a pest.
Two blocks down, right-hand side.
First door that doesn't have
a chicken in the window is his.
No chicken.
Who the hell are you?
Sir, my name's Ray Kinsella.
- We got a learning disability here?
- If I could just have one minute, please.
I can't tell you the secret of life,
and I don't have any answers for you.
I don't give interviews,
and I'm no longer a public figure.
I just want to be left alone, so piss off.
Wait! Wait!
I've come 1,500 miles to see you...
...at the risk of losing my home
and alienating my wife.
All I'm asking is one minute. Please.
One minute.
I understand your desire for privacy...
...and I wouldn't intrude
if this weren't extremely important.
Oh, God. I don't do causes anymore.
This isn't a cause.
I don't need money or an endorsement.
Refreshing.
You once wrote, "There comes a time...
"...when all the cosmic tumblers
have clicked into place...
"...and the universe
opens itself up for a few seconds...
"...to show you what's possible."
- Oh, my God!
- What?
- You're from the '60s.
- Well, yeah. Actually...
Out!
Back to the '60s!
There's no place for you here in the future.
Get back while you still can!
You've changed, you know that?
Yes, I suppose I have.
How about this? Peace, love, dope.
Now get the hell out of here!
- You've really pissed me off.
- Just hold it right there.
I didn't want to do it this way.
- What the hell is that?
- It's a gun, what do you think it is?
- It's your finger.
- No, it's a gun.
- Let me see it.
- I'm not going to show you my gun.
I'm not going to hurt you.
I just need you to come with me...
What are you doing?
I'll beat you with a crowbar
until you go away.
Wait! You can't do that.
There are rules here?
Oh, no. There are no rules here.
You're a pacifist!
Shit.
Thank you.
So, what? You're kidnapping me?
What's the deal here?
I was hoping I could just convince you
to come with me.
So you are kidnapping me?
I have to take you to a baseball game.
You what?
Tonight's game. Red Sox, A's.
Why?
Something will happen there.
I don't know what,
but we'll find out when it does.
My name's Ray Kinsella.
You used my father's name
for a character in one of your stories.
John Kinsella.
You're seeing a whole team
of psychiatrists, aren't you?
I don't blame you for thinking that,
but no, I'm not.
I swear to God,
I'm the least crazy person I've ever known.
Why are you kidnapping me
to a baseball game?
- May I?
- Oh, please. Want a cup of coffee?
No.
Want some cookies?
I read an interview you gave...
...about how you always dreamed
of playing at Ebbets Field...
...and how sad you felt
when they tore it down.
I never said that.
You didn't?
I don't even recall thinking that.
Weird.
This whole thing is so weird.
Then why go through with it?
It's a long story.
But it's a really good story.
I'll tell you on the way.
- I'm not getting rid of you, am I?
- No.
If you come to this game with me,
I swear I'll never bother you again.
Not even a Christmas card.
So what do you do with yourself
these days?
I live, I work. I learned how to cook.
I take walks and watch sunsets.
Don't you miss being involved?
I was the East Coast distributor
of involved.
I ate it and drank it and breathed it.
Then they killed Martin, and Bobby...
...they elected Tricky Dick twice...
...and now people like you think
I must be miserable...
...because I'm not involved anymore.
I've got news for you.
I spent all my misery years ago.
I have no more pain left for any of you.
I gave at the office.
So what do you want?
I want them to stop
looking to me for answers...
...begging me to speak again,
write again, be a leader.
I want them to start thinking
for themselves.
And I want my privacy.
No, I meant what do you want?
Dog and a beer.
- Two.
- $7.
Okay, I understand you.
You should be entitled
to as much privacy as you want.
But why stop writing?
I haven't published a word in 17 years,
and still I have to endure lunatics like you.
What do you think would happen
if I suddenly came out with a new book?
They'd bleed me dry.
Go the distance.
What's the matter?
- You didn't see that?
- See what?
I'm sorry.
I guess you didn't have to be here.
What?
Whenever you want to go, we can go.
Fine. Let's go.
What is it you're not telling me?
I've already taken up
too much of your time.
I wish I had your passion.
Misdirected though it might be,
it is still a passion.
I used to feel that way about things, but...
- You got another message, didn't you?
- You'll think I'm crazy.
I already think you're crazy.
What did it say?
It said, "The man's done enough.
Leave him alone."
Moonlight Graham.
- You saw it.
- Saw what?
You saw it. New York Giants, 1922.
He played one game. He never got to bat.
- You saw it!
- What did I see?
Chisholm, Minnesota.
We were the only ones who saw it.
Did you hear the voice, too?
It's all right to admit it.
It's what told me to find you.
Did you hear it?
"Go the distance"?
- Yes. Do you know what it means?
- Yes.
What?
It means we're going to Minnesota
to find Moonlight Graham.
- We're going... We?
- I must be out of my mind.
- What do we do when we find him?
- How the hell am I supposed to know?
That's right. You're right.
- This is so bitchin'.
- I don't believe I'm doing this.
Hey, Annie, guess what?
I'm with Terence Mann.
Oh, my God. You kidnapped him.
No, I didn't. He wanted to.
I'm really sorry,
but I'm going to be a few days longer.
We're going to Minnesota.
I don't believe this. What's in Minnesota?
An old ballplayer.
I'll explain when I get home.
- How are things with you?
- Fine.
Great. Look, Ann, I got to go, okay?
Give Karin a hug for me, and I love you.
I love you, too.
Someday explain all this to me, okay?
I'll try. Bye-bye.
'Bye.
Why didn't you tell him?
You got no choice in the matter.
Half a dozen Grahams.
No Archibald. No Moonlight.
Follow me.
Hello.
Excuse me. Maybe you can help us.
We're looking for an ex-baseball player,
Archibald Graham.
- Oh, you mean Doc Graham.
- No, I think his nickname was "Moonlight."
- That's Dr. Graham.
- Dr. Graham?
His baseball career never amounted
to much, so he went back to school.
His father was a doctor.
- Do you know where we can find him?
- It's nothing bad. We're not from the IRS.
Doc Graham is dead. He died in 1972.
"At times children could not afford
eyeglasses or milk or clothing.
"Yet no child was ever denied
these essentials...
"...because, in the background,
there was always Dr. Graham.
"Without any fanfare or publicity,
the glasses or the milk...
"...or the ticket to the ball game
found their way into the child's pocket."
- You wrote that.
- The day he died.
Can I see that?
- You're a good writer.
- So are you.
Something's missing.
He sounds like he was a wonderful man.
Half the towns in North America
have a Doc Graham.
Why do we have to travel halfway
across the country to find this one...
...sixteen years after he died?
There's got to be more.
What else?
He always wore an overcoat...
...he had white hair,
and he always carried an umbrella.
What was the umbrella for?
I think it got to be a habit,
something to hang on to.
If you asked him, he said he used it
to beat away his lady admirers.
Tell me about his wife.
Alicia.
She moved to South Carolina
after Doc passed.
She passed a couple years later.
She always wore blue.
The shopkeepers in town
would stock blue hats...
...because they knew if Doc walked by,
he'd buy one.
When they cleaned out his office...
...they found boxes of blue hats...
...that he never got around to give her.
I'll bet you didn't know that.
No, I didn't.
No screwing, no drinking,
no opium, no midnight abortions.
No illegitimate children, no shady finances.
You sound disappointed.
Shoeless Joe had a problem.
That's why he needed you.
This guy doesn't need us.
Do you know you're missing?
Oh, God.
"His father, who lives in Baltimore,
notified police after receiving...
"...no answer to repeated telephone calls."
Shoot.
I better call him.
- You want me to...
- Thanks.
I'm taking a walk. Be back in a while.
What do I tell him?
"This year's"?
Dr. Graham?
My name's Ray Kinsella. I'm from Iowa.
Are you Moonlight Graham?
No one's called me Moonlight Graham
in 50 years.
I've come a very long way to see you.
I couldn't sleep tonight.
Usually I sleep like a baby.
I told Alicia I was going to take a walk.
Do you mind if I join you?
I'd like to talk to you.
Let's walk over to my office.
What do you want to talk to me about?
When you got to the majors,
you played only one inning of one game.
What happened with you?
It was the last day of the season.
Bottom of the eighth inning,
we were way ahead.
I'd been up with the club for three weeks,
but I hadn't seen any action.
Suddenly old John McGraw
points a bony finger in my direction...
...and he says, "Right field."
I jumped up like I was sitting on a spring.
Grabbed my glove, and ran out on the field.
Did you get to make a play?
They never hit the ball out of the infield.
The game ended. The season was over.
I knew they'd send me back down.
I couldn't bear the thought
of another year in the minors.
So I decided to hang them up.
- Go on. Sit down.
- Thank you.
So what was that like?
It was like coming this close
to your dreams...
...and then watching them brush past you,
like a stranger in a crowd.
At the time, you don't think much of it.
We don't recognize our most significant
moments while they're happening.
Back then I thought,
"Well, there'll be other days."
I didn't realize that was the only day.
And now, I want to ask you a question.
What's so interesting about half an inning
that would make you come from Iowa...
...to talk to me about it
50 years after it happened.
I didn't really know till just now...
...but I think it's to ask you,
if you could do anything you wanted...
...if you could have a wish...
And you're the kind of man
who could grant me that wish?
I don't know. I'm just asking.
You know,
I never got to bat in the major leagues.
I'd have liked to have had that chance,
just once...
...to stare down a big-league pitcher.
Stare him down,
then just as he goes into his windup, wink.
Make him think you know
something he doesn't.
That's what I wish for.
The chance to squint at a sky so blue
that it hurts your eyes to look at it.
To feel the tingle in your arms
as you connect with the ball.
To run the bases,
stretch a double into a triple...
...and flop face first into third.
Wrap your arms around the bag.
That's my wish.
Is there enough magic out there
in the moonlight...
...to make this dream come true?
- What would you say if I said yes?
- I think I'd actually believe you.
There's a place
where things like that happen...
...and if you want to go, I can take you.
This is my most special place
in all the world.
Once a place touches you like this,
the wind never blows so cold again.
You feel for it. Like it was your child.
I can't leave Chisholm.
I understand. I do.
But I really think
you're supposed to come with us.
No.
But your wish?
It'll have to stay a wish.
I was born here, I lived here,
I'll die here, but no regrets.
Fifty years ago, for five minutes,
you came this close.
It would kill some men to get that close
to their dream and not touch it.
They'd consider it a tragedy.
Son, if I'd only gotten to be a doctor
for five minutes...
...now that would have been a tragedy.
I better be getting home.
Alicia will think I got a girlfriend.
And he smiled.
And then I figured, maybe we're not
supposed to take him with us.
I don't know.
I don't know why in the hell
we were supposed to come here.
Maybe it's to find out
if one inning can change the world.
- Think it did?
- It did for these people.
If he'd gotten a hit,
he might have stayed in baseball.
I don't know.
Your wife called before.
She wants you to call her tonight.
I'm fine. I'm just so glad it's you.
Listen, I talked to the bank...
...and I asked them
if we could miss a payment or two...
...and they told me that they had just sold
the note on the farm...
...to Mark and his partners.
Right. So they own the paper now.
He says if we don't sell to them,
they're going to foreclose.
We don't have the money.
Look, I've got to take Mr. Mann
back to Boston first.
- No.
- Wait a second.
I'm going to Iowa with you.
We're coming home.
Hell, I can't quit now.
I got to see this ball park.
Not everyone can see it. You might not.
Give it a try.
I need all the karma I can get right now.
- Thanks. You're the first car by.
- How far you going?
- Iowa.
If it's okay, I'll just ride along a while.
I play baseball.
- Hop in.
- All right.
I'm looking for a place to play.
I heard that all through the Midwest,
they have towns with teams.
And in some places,
they'll even find you a day job...
...so you can play ball
nights and weekends.
This is your lucky day, kid.
We're going someplace kind of like that.
All right.
- I'm Ray Kinsella. This is Terence Mann.
- Hi.
I'm Archie Graham.
It's funny the way he described towns
finding you a job...
...so that you could play on their team.
They haven't done that for years.
My dad did that for a while,
but that was in the '20s.
What happened to your father?
He never made it as a ballplayer...
...so he tried to get his son
to make it for him.
By the time I was 10, playing baseball...
...got to be like eating vegetables
or taking out the garbage.
So when I was 14, I started to refuse.
Can you believe that?
American boy refusing to have a catch
with his father?
Why 14?
That's when I read The Boat Rocker
by Terence Mann.
God!
I never played catch with him again.
That's the kind of crap
people always lay on me.
It's not my fault
you wouldn't play catch with him.
I know.
Anyway, when I was 17...
...I packed my things,
said something awful, and left.
After a while, I wanted to come home,
but I didn't know how.
Made it back for the funeral, though.
What was the awful thing you said?
To your father?
I said I could never respect a man
whose hero was a criminal.
Who was his hero?
Shoeless Joe Jackson.
You knew he wasn't a criminal.
Then why did you say it?
I was 17.
The son of a bitch died
before I could take it back.
Before I could tell him...
...you know.
He never met my wife.
He never saw his granddaughter.
This is your penance.
I know. I can't bring my father back.
So the least you can do
is bring back his hero.
Well...
Now I know
what everybody's purpose here is.
Except mine.
- Daddy!
- Karin, come here.
Hi!
- We missed you. Are you okay?
- Yeah. This is Terence Mann.
Terry.
- Welcome.
- Thank you.
Hi, Terry.
And this young fellow is...
This is Archie Graham.
- Archie.
- He's come to practice with the team.
Yeah? He's going to be able to do
a lot more than that.
What does that mean?
- Welcome back.
- Thanks, Joe.
- Oh, my God.
- What?
That's Shoeless Joe Jackson!
Of course it is.
You mean you didn't believe me?
I thought I did, but... Oh, my God.
- Hi, Annie.
- Hi, Joe.
Good to see you. Terry,
I'd like you to meet Shoeless Joe Jackson.
Joe, Terry Mann.
- It's a pleasure meeting you.
- The pleasure's mine.
I hope you don't mind,
but we got tired of just having practices...
...so we brought another team out
so we could have some real games.
I don't mind. Where'd they come from?
Where did we come from?
You wouldn't believe
how many guys wanted to play.
We had to beat 'em off with a stick.
That's "Smokey" Joe Wood, and Mel Ott...
...and Gil Hodges!
Ty Cobb wanted to play.
We couldn't stand the son of a bitch
when we were alive...
...so we told him to stick it!
- Are you Graham?
- Yes, sir.
What are you doing on the sidelines?
You came to play ball, didn't you?
Yes, sir.
- All right. Well, go warm up.
- Yes, sir.
Rookies.
Unbelievable.
It's more than that.
It's perfect.
Safe!
Go, Graham! Go, kid!
Come on, Archie!
He looks like a baby next to those guys.
He is.
Let's go.
Watch it, boy!
Don't let him shake you up. Hang in there!
Knuckles, what did you throw
at the kid for?
- He winked at me.
- Don't wink, kid.
Good thing for you
he didn't throw the fastball.
Let's see that fastball.
Ball.
Hey! Come on. Give us a break!
Hey, ump.
- How about a warning?
- Sure. Watch out you don't get killed.
Time!
Those first two were high and tight.
So what do you think the next one will be?
Either low and away or in my ear.
He's not going to want to load the bases.
So look for low and away.
Right.
But watch out for in your ear.
- Come on, Archie!
- Let's go, kid!
Batter, batter, batter!
Come on, Arch. It just takes one.
- Yeah.
- That's deep enough.
Go! Go! Go home!
- Safe!
- Son of a...
Way to go, Arch! Way to go!
Attaboy, Arch!
This is the wave!
- Way to go, man!
- Yeah, Archie.
- All right.
- Archie, we need it.
- Way to go.
- Yeah. Way to go.
- What is this?
- What is this jerk doing?
Hi!
- Shit! Wreck him.
- Let me at him!
You're interrupting the game, Mark.
It's time to put away your little fantasies
and come down to Earth.
- It's not a fantasy. They're real.
- Who is real?
Shoeless Joe Jackson, the White Sox,
all of them.
- You mean?
- No. He can't see any of them.
Who is this, Elvis?
Ray.
As a matter of fact, it's Terence Mann.
How do you do? I'm the Easter Bunny.
- Let's settle this thing now.
- Look. I'm not selling.
You have no money.
You have a stack of bills!
Come fall, you got no crop to sell.
But, I have a deal
that allows you to stay on the land.
Daddy? We don't have to sell the farm.
- You'll live in the house rent-free.
- What about the team...
Do you realize how much
this land is worth?
Yeah. Yeah.
$2,200 an acre.
We can't keep a useless baseball diamond
in rich farmland.
Read my lips. We're staying, all right?
- We're staying.
- Ray, you're bankrupt!
I'm offering you a way to keep your home
because I love my sister.
My partners don't care
and are ready to foreclose right now.
Daddy, we don't have to sell the farm.
- Karin, please!
- Just wait! Wait!
People will come.
- What people, sweetheart?
- From all over.
They'll just decide to take a vacation, see?
And they'll come to Iowa City.
They'll think it's really boring.
So they'll want to pay us.
Like buying a ticket.
You're not seriously listening to this,
are you?
- Yes.
- Wait a minute.
Why would anybody
pay money to come here?
To watch the games.
It will be just like when they were kids,
a long time ago.
They'll watch the game
and remember what it was like.
- What the hell is she talking about?
- People will come.
All right. This is fascinating...
...but you don't have the money
to bring the mortgage up to date.
So, you're still going to have to sell.
I'm sorry, Ray. We got no choice.
People will come, Ray.
They'll come to Iowa
for reasons they can't even fathom.
They'll turn up your driveway,
not knowing for sure why they're doing it.
They'll arrive at your door
as innocent as children...
...longing for the past.
"Of course, we won't mind
if you look around," you'll say.
"It's only $20 per person."
They'll pass over the money
without even thinking about it.
For it is money they have
and peace they like.
Ray! Just sign the papers.
Then they'll walk off to the bleachers...
...and sit in their shirtsleeves
on a perfect afternoon.
They'll find they have reserved seats
somewhere along one of the baselines...
...where they sat when they were children
and cheered their heroes...
...and they'll watch the game...
...and it will be as if they dipped
themselves in magic waters.
The memories will be so thick...
...they'll have to brush them away
from their faces.
When the bank opens in the morning,
they'll foreclose.
People will come, Ray.
You're broke, Ray.
You sell now, or you lose everything.
The one constant through all the years,
Ray, has been baseball.
America has rolled by
like an army of steamrollers.
It's been erased like a blackboard,
rebuilt, and erased again.
But baseball has marked the time.
This field, this game.
It's a part of our past, Ray.
It reminds us of all that once was good...
...and it could be again.
People will come, Ray.
People will most definitely come.
Ray, you will lose everything.
You will be evicted.
Come on, Ray.
I'm not signing.
You're crazy! Absolutely nuts!
I can't do it, pal.
Ray, you build a baseball field
in the middle of nowhere...
...and you stare at nothing.
It's not nothing.
- Your daughter's turned into a space case.
- Get your hands off her!
Karin?
- Is she all right?
- I don't know.
- Is she breathing?
- Should I get the car?
I'm going to call emergency.
- Annie, wait.
- What?
Just wait.
- What have we got here?
- She fell.
- This child's choking to death.
- Get her up.
Hold her steady now.
Hot dog. Stuck in her throat.
She'll be all right.
She'll be turning handsprings
before you know it.
Thank you, Doc.
No, son. Thank you.
Oh, my God. You can't go back.
- You can't go back.
- It's all right.
- I'm sorry.
I best be getting on home...
...before Alicia begins to think
I got a girlfriend.
Hey, Doc.
Good work, Doc.
Nice going, Doc.
Going to miss you.
Win one for me one day, will you, boys?
- Okay, Doc.
- Yeah.
When did these ballplayers get here?
Hey, rookie!
You were good.
Do not sell this farm, Ray.
You got to keep this farm.
You've had a rough day.
- Go inside and get something cold to drink.
- Yeah.
That's a good idea.
Don't sell the farm, Ray.
Ray?
We're going to call it a day.
- See you tomorrow.
- Okay.
Do you want to come with us?
- You mean it?
- No, not you.
Him.
- Him?
- Come with you?
- Out there.
- What is out there?
Come and find out.
Wait a second. Why him? I built this field.
- You wouldn't be here if it weren't for me.
- I'm unattached. You have a family.
I want to know what's out there.
- I want to see it.
- But you're not invited.
"Not invited"?
What do you mean I'm not invited?
That's my corn out there.
You guys are guests in my corn.
I've done everything I've been asked to do.
I didn't understand, but I've done it.
I haven't once asked what's in it for me.
- What are you saying?
- I'm saying, "What's in it for me?"
Is that why you did this? For you?
I think you'd better stay here, Ray.
Why?
Ray. There's a reason they chose me...
...just as there's a reason
they chose you and this field.
I gave an interview.
What are you talking about?
The one about Ebbets Field,
the one that sent you to Boston to find me.
- You lied to me.
- You were kidnapping me at the time.
- You lied to me!
- You said your finger was a gun.
- That's a good point.
- Ray.
Listen to me, Ray. Listen to me.
There is something out there...
...and if I have the courage
to go through with this...
...what a story it'll make.
"Shoeless Joe Jackson comes to Iowa."
- Are you going to write about it?
- You bet I'll write about it.
- You're going to write about it.
- That's what I do.
Good.
Honey, where's he going?
Terry's been invited
to go out with the other players.
- How are you feeling, sweetheart?
- Stupid.
You mean "out"?
Yeah.
Out.
Far out.
I want a full description.
Take care of this family.
Be careful.
'Bye.
What?
What are you grinning at, you ghost?
"If you build it...
"...he will come."
- Oh, my God.
- What? What is it?
It's my father.
"Ease his pain."
"Go the distance."
It was you.
No, Ray. It was you.
My God.
I only saw him years later
when he was worn down by life.
Look at him.
He's got his whole life in front of him,
and I'm not even a glint in his eye.
What do I say to him?
Why don't you introduce him
to his granddaughter?
Hi.
I just wanted to thank you folks
for putting up this field...
...letting us play here.
I'm John Kinsella.
I'm Ray.
My wife Annie.
This is my daughter Karin.
Karin, this is my...
This is John.
Hi, John.
Hi, Karin.
Well, we're going to let you two talk.
If all these people are going to come,
we got a lot of work to do.
It was very nice meeting you.
Ma'am.
Come on.
You catch a good game.
Thank you.
It's so beautiful here.
For me...
For me, it's like a dream come true.
Can I ask you something?
Is this heaven?
It's Iowa.
- Iowa?
- Yeah.
I could have sworn it was heaven.
Is there a heaven?
Oh, yeah.
It's the place where dreams come true.
Maybe this is heaven.
Good night, Ray.
Good night, John.
Hey! Dad?
You want to have a catch?
I'd like that.
Subtitles by SOFTITLER