http://subscene.com/u/659433
Improved by: @Ivandrofly
"So, even though he wanted
to do a lot as President,"
"he died of pneumonia
after only 32 days."
"So, we can all learn
from William Henry Harrison"
"to wear our coats
and wash our hands,"
"so we have better
immune systems."
"The end."
(SHOES TAPPING RHYTHMICALLY)
(STUDENTS GROAN)
(SCATTERED APPLAUSE)
Good job, Annie.
Okay, Annie B., your turn.
You sure there's time?
I don't wanna keep anyone from vacation.
(STUDENTS LAUGH)
Just get up here.
Where's your essay? Up here.
And it's more
of a performance piece.
(STUDENTS LAUGH)
Here we go.
My president is Franklin
Delano Roosevelt.
He was elected in 1932,
when almost everyone was poor.
So, pretty much just like now,
but without the lnternet.
(STUDENTS LAUGH)
Everyone except the front
row, you be the poor people.
You're hungry and mad. So,
growl and stomp your feet.
(RHYTHMICALLY)
Grr! Grr-grr!
STUDENTS: (CHANTING)
Front row, good news,
you're the rich people.
Laugh and clap like you're
better than everybody.
(RHYTHMICALLY)
Ha-ha! Ha-ha-ha!
STUDENTS: (CHANTING)
(SYNCOPATED CHANTING)
But FDR didn't like it that everyone
was poor, so, he gave them all jobs.
He called it the New Deal.
Work hard, and you get rich.
So, when I tap you, you're rich.
He had people build
roads and got paid.
Cut down trees and got paid.
Made it easy to buy
a house, go to college.
Soon, the whole
country was happy.
But don't worry, rich people.
You're still better than everyone
because you get even richer!
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
TEACHER: Good job, Annie.
Have a good vacation, everyone!
(EXCITED CHATTER)
You gonna make it in time?
I always do.
We'll cover for you. Good luck.
Luck's for suckers.
(FAST-TEMPO DRUMBEAT BEGINS)
(JACKHAMMER DRILLING IN
RHYTHM WITH DRUMBEAT)
WOMAN: Tomorrow.
To-To-Tomorrow.
To-Tomorrow.
It's the hard-knock life for us
(DOORS SHUT, HORN HONKS TO RHYTHM)
(HORN HONKING WITH RHYTHM OF MELODY)
(BICYCLE BELL DINGING TO MELODY)
Excuse me!
Do you have any time left?
I have about 10 minutes.
I'll return it for you. Really?
Promise.
Thanks!
(SIREN WAILING)
SUBWAY ANNOUNCER: Stand clear
of the closing doors, please.
(ELECTRONIC BELL DINGS)
ROCK BAND SINGER: I think
I'm gonna like it
I'm sure I'm gonna like it
I think I'm gonna like it
I think I'm gonna like it here.
CROWD: Ten, nine,
eight, seven, six,
five, four, three, two, one.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Light it up!
How many of you guys want
some free Stacks phones, huh?
I can't hear you!
(CHEERING CONTINUES)
Any reservations for Bennett?
Honey, I told you.
If anyone I think could even remotely
be your parents walk in,
I'm gonna let you know.
And I mean remotely.
Name's Bennett, Senate,
Pomegranate, black, white, other.
I'll let you know.
I'm guessing you're
gonna wait anyway. Yep.
(CHUCKLES)
STACKS: Get your free Stacks phone.
Never drop a call.
Thanks, thanks. Cool.
Free Stacks phone. Okay?
Thank you. Thank you.
All right.
And there we are, ma'am. Free Stacks phone.
Never drop a call.
I'm totally gonna vote
for you for mayor now.
Yeah, well, you know what?
This isn't a campaign event.
(WHISPERS)
But I would totally love that.
Oh! (LAUGHS)
Mmm-mmm! Mmm-mmm!
Okay, that's it. We're done.
Thanks.
Hose me down. I feel
like I'm on fire.
Yeah.
You should clean your tongue.
You kissed a few babies. You
don't want to catch colic.
You know what? You're right.
Oh! Will!
You shake 500 hands, and you
tell me how you feel, huh?
Feel like a zookeeper.
WOMAN: Marry me, Will!
Okay, sure.
(PEOPLE TALKING QUIETLY)
Sorry.
It's okay. I just
come for the cannoli.
I'll see you next Friday?
You know it.
Hey, girl. How'd it go?
Nah. Eh.
Can I? Sure.
As long as you give
those to my lady.
Thanks.
(LADDER CREAKING)
(TV PLAYING QUIETLY)
(CLATTERING IN DISTANCE)
(THUMPING IN DISTANCE)
HANNIGAN: Freeze!
(GROANS)
I said freeze, you little rat.
I know you heard me.
Get over here.
These are from Lou.
They look like they're from Lou.
I'll tell him you loved them.
You think the world wants
a smart-mouthed little girl?
No, they don't, or you
wouldn't be here.
And the only reason you are here
is because I get $157
a week from the state.
Which, believe me,
is not worth it.
I should put a leash
on you, you little...
You're so pretty.
I used to be a bright star.
I was in the biggest
band in the world,
C+C Music Factory.
About to go
on Arsenio Hall Show.
September 16th, 1991.
But I was too good for them!
Fired me right before I went
out on stage.
You have a very pretty voice.
I will die with that secret!
Hey, you little monster, I wasn't
done with you! Get back here!
I haven't told you how I was almost
one of Hootie's Blowfish.
(GIRLS LAUGH)
How did I get here?
Did you find them?
Nah, but it's okay.
So sorry. Sorry, Annie.
Shh! The witch will hear us.
They're never gonna be
at that restaurant.
Be quiet, Pepper. Yes, they are.
You be quiet, Isabella.
Annie's never gonna find her family.
None of us are.
Don't say that.
Don't listen to her, Mia.
You're gonna get adopted.
I promise.
You keep saying that. I'm almost 13.
No one wants a teenager.
Yes, they do. We all have
families somewhere.
Can you read your note again?
Okay.
Oh, God. For the millionth time?
Yeah, read it, Annie.
But quietly.
ANNIE: They went to Domani's,
ordered two cannolis,
and wrote me this note.
"Please take care of our baby."
"Her name's Annie."
"We'll be back to get her soon."
"There's half a locket around her
neck, and we have the other half,"
"so when we come for her,
you'll know that she's our girl."
Can I see it?
They're gonna come back for all of us.
I promise.
(SNAPPING RHYTHMICALLY)
Maybe far away.
Or maybe real nearby.
He may be pouring her coffee.
She may be
straightening his tie!
Maybe in a house.
All hidden by a hill.
She's sitting playing piano.
He's sitting paying a bill!
Betcha they're young.
Betcha they're smart.
Bet they collect things
Like ashtrays, and art!
Betcha they're good.
Why shouldn't they be?
Their one mistake.
Was giving up me!
So maybe now it's time
(GIRLS HARMONIZING)
(GROANS)
And maybe when I wake.
They'll be there
calling me "baby"
- (YAWNS)
- ALL: Shh!
Maybe.
Betcha he reads.
Betcha he reads...
Betcha she sews.
Betcha she sews...
Maybe she's made me A
closet of clothes!
Maybe they're strict.
As straight as a line.
Don't really care.
As long as they're mine.
So maybe now this prayer's.
Maybe now this prayer...
The last one of its kind.
Won't you please come
get your "Baby".
Maybe
(DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE)
HANNIGAN: Wake up!
Wake up, rats.
(SHRIEKS)
Get out of bed!
It's so early.
And it's Saturday.
Thanks for the time and date. Now,
over to Stormy for the weather.
It's raining! (GROANS)
The city called. They're
coming to inspect.
You gotta go and clean
this whole place up!
Aren't they supposed to give
a couple days' notice?
Aren't I supposed to be
married to George Clooney?
Get out of bed
and start cleaning!
Who's George Clooney?
Exactly, girlfriend. Exactly.
No breakfast until this
place is spotless!
I hate her so much.
And if you find any loose change
over a nickel, it's mine.
I was having the best dream.
I was ice-skating
on real, live ice.
Save your dreams for good stuff.
Like shopping with an unlimited
credit card.
Or swimming in candy.
Or flying to the moon
in a rocket ship.
All things
that will never happen.
(SHRIEKS)
Now, clean like your life depends on it.
'Cause it does!
It's the hard-knock life.
(SWEEPING RHYTHMICALLY)
(MOPPING RHYTHMICALLY)
(MOP SQUEAKS TO RHYTHM)
(THUMPING RHYTHMICALLY)
It's the hard-knock life.
Wait. What does
"hard-knock life" mean?
It means our life sucks.
Oh. Then, yeah.
It's the hard-knock life for us!
'Steada treated.
We get tricked!
'Steada kisses.
We get kicked!
It's the hard-knock life.
Less singing and more cleaning!
And make sure
my bathroom shines!
But don't touch
my medicine cabinet!
It's the hard-knock life for us!
'Steada treated.
We get tricked!
'Steada kisses.
We get kicked!
It's the hard-knock life.
Don't it feel like the wind
is always howling?
Don't it seem
like there's never any light?
Once a day don't you wanna
throw the towel in?
It's easier than puttin'
up a fight.
No one's there when your
dreams at night get creepy!
No one cares if you
grow or if you shrink!
Empty belly life!
Rotten smelly life!
Full of sorrow life!
No tomorrow life!
(PLATE SHATTERS)
Santa Claus we never see
Santa Claus.
What's that? Who's he?
No one cares for you a bit.
When you're a foster kid!
It's the hard-knock life!
"Make my bathroom shine! But don't
touch my medicine cabinet!"
(GIRLS LAUGH)
Good one, Mia.
It's the hard-knock life for us.
Yank the whiskers from her chin.
Jab her with a safety pin.
'Steada treated, we get tricked.
Send her to the loony bin.
'Steada kisses, we get kicked.
Oh, I'm so sorry!
Toss me the broom! Incoming.
Plastic!
Paper! Can!
(GASPS)
(GIRLS LAUGH)
It's the hard-knock life for us.
Yank the whiskers from her chin.
Jab her with a safety pin.
No one cares for you a bit.
Send her to the loony bin.
When you're a foster kid!
It's the hard-knock life
I said no singing and dancing!
(WHISPERING)
It's the hard-knock life
(DOORBELL BUZZES)
The inspector's here.
Here, read a book.
Braid her hair. Blow on this.
Put this together.
It's a kitty cat.
What should I do? Pray.
I've tried. It hasn't worked yet.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Okay. Showtime! You guys
act well cared-for.
ALL: We love you, Miss Hannigan!
Take it down a thousand.
Nobody's gonna believe that.
(LAUGHTER)
(GROANS)
(MOUSE SQUEAKING)
Get under here.
(GRUNTS)
Well, hello there.
Are you Colleen Hannigan?
My maiden name. But I'm not married
to it, if you know what I mean.
No. Come on in. The girls
are just recreating.
(GIRLS CLAMORING)
(CLAMOR STOPS)
Uh, should we start
here in the bathroom?
Why, Mr. lnspector,
how forward you are.
But I'm right behind you.
What? What?
No, I'm asking you. This way.
Wait, what? (GAGS)
HANNIGAN: Oh, your
arms are so strong!
The dude dropped this.
This has all of our information.
Really?
You're kidding.
Damn. I've been in a lot
of homes.
TESSIE: This says
I've been in millions.
PEPPER: That's your Social
Security number, dummy.
What's a scoso curcurity murder?
It's what the government
uses to keep track of us.
Wait. This is what I need
to get my records.
And find my parents.
I'll copy it down.
Plan your exit.
Okay.
You know, people come
for the bathroom,
but they stay for the bedroom.
What? You know it.
Can I go to the library
to study?
Can we talk about this after
the handsome inspector with no
wedding ring is gone?
Okay.
Can I have some floss?
I think I have some nutritious
breakfast stuck in my teeth.
What?
Pretty sure I saw
some in the medicine cabinet.
Oh, right there?
You know, I just remembered.
We're out of floss.
Maybe you wanna pick
some up on your way to the library.
Thank you, Miss Hannigan.
Bye, Mr. lnspector.
Bye, now.
Seems like a great kid.
Yeah, she seems great.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
Oh-oh, I know that run.
How much you need, mija?
$43.55.
By when? Now?
Go rob Bank of America. Here,
I'll loan you my mask.
I'll work for it. Please, Lou.
That face.
Take the expired drinks from the cooler.
Go ahead.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
Whoa, what are you doing, girl?
This ain't no Whole Foods.
Don't throw them out.
Change the date.
STACKS: (OVER TV)
I believe in hard work.
I don't just settle for "okay."
"Great" is all I know.
I built my company to be
a worldwide leader.
And that's what I wanna do with the city.
I wanna make it great again.
REPORTER: You're 20
points down in the polls.
You've got billions to spend
and it's not working.
How are you gonna
change people's minds?
Everybody wants
to count my money, huh?
4.3 billion.
You know, I have feelings.
And I feel for people
that are out there...
Baba Booey! Baba Booey!
Yes. See.
That's probably one of my satisfied
customers right there.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
This is terrible.
Do you really think
a businessman can run the city?
At Stacks Mobile, I made a cell
network that never drops a call.
As mayor, I'm gonna
make a government
that never drops a citizen.
Yeah, as long as those citizens
live below 96th Street.
You're lucky you can't vote yet, mija.
Politicians are all liars.
What dates should
I change these to?
One week for the milk.
Two weeks for the juice.
GUY: You need to smile more.
You only smiled four times.
Is that right? Really?
Voters respond 23% more
favorably to full-teeth smiles.
Yeah. How about thumbs up, huh?
Uh, Sixteen percent better
if you give them a single.
Thirty-eight percent if you
shoot them the double.
Why do I get the feeling
like I'm wasting my time here?
Am I gonna win, or not?
'Cause this seems
like a waste of time.
You hired me to win.
You're gonna win.
Put this on. Why? I'm
already dressed.
How you doing? Here.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
I gotta feed the hobos?
Don't say "hobos." Say "bums."
For some crazy reason,
everybody thinks
you're a rich elitist that can't
relate to regular people.
Oh, so the girl from Oxford is trying
to tell me how to keep it real.
I'm telling you if you
want a chance at this,
you're gonna have to remember
where you came from.
Okay, Gatsby?
Compliment them on the food,
but not too much.
Oh, I ain't eating this food.
You're gonna eat the food.
And you're gonna like it,
but you're not gonna love it, okay?
We don't want to seem
like we're pandering.
I don't eat hobo food.
All right. That's good.
How we doing, folks? Starving?
How do you sleep at night?
Silk sheets and Ambien.
Look at all these
handsome faces!
There you go. All right.
And here we go. God bless.
Bet you never had mashed
potatoes, Mr. Stacks.
Are you kidding me?
Why, my grandmother made some of
the best mashed
potatoes in Queens.
You know, that's where I'm from.
Born and raised.
On the playground's where
I spent most of my days.
And look at this.
It's not amazing, but it ain't terrible.
Look at this, huh?
Mmm-mmm!
(PEOPLE EXCLAIM)
Went down the wrong pipe.
This is disgusting.
Look, it's terrible.
Oh, God. You're a child.
Well, how do you guys
think that went?
Nash, you saw it. Would you vote
for me if you didn't work for me?
No, sir.
Thank you for your honesty.
You're fired.
(CHUCKLES)
That didn't take long.
And there are already parodies.
Mashed potatoes Mashed potatoes...
(SPITTING IN RHYTHM)
Mashed potatoes, mashed
potatoes in Queens.
See, this is why China's winning.
Not really.
(SPITTING)
(GOOFY ELECTRONIC BLIPPING)
Maybe this is a blessing
in disguise.
Just because you can run for mayor,
doesn't mean that you should.
We already discussed this
is great for my profile.
It's going to grow the company.
Plus, the city needs me.
All right. Take it easy, Batman.
You let all your employees
talk to you like this?
The ones that make
me billions, I do.
You make me mayor, you can
say anything you want.
Hey! (HORN HONKS)
Oh, no. Not again.
Nash. Why we stopping?
Sorry, Mr. Stacks.
Uh, I'll fix it.
Next!
I'd like to get
my records please.
You'll need DOH
form number 4380...
BOTH: 7-8.
And $43 and...
55 cents.
And an application signed
by a parent or a...
Guardian. Bam.
It's all there.
Are you going to stare
at me the whole time?
Sorry.
Next! Can you read it?
I'm too nervous.
(SCOFFS)
"Annie Bennett. Abandoned
outside 26th Precinct."
"Age estimate at time
of abandonment, four years."
"Placed in state foster care.
No further data."
What does "no
further data" mean?
That's all there is to know about you.
Sorry, honey.
It's okay. I'll figure it out.
(DISTANT SIREN WAILING)
The sun'll come out tomorrow.
Bet your bottom
dollar that tomorrow.
There'll be sun (CHILD GIGGLING)
Just thinkin' about tomorrow.
Clears away the cobwebs
and the sorrow.
'Til there's none.
When I'm stuck with a day.
That's gray, and lonely
I just stick
out my chin and grin.
And say, oh.
CHILD: Faster, Daddy!
The sun'll come out tomorrow.
So you gotta hang
on 'til tomorrow.
Come what may
(CHILD GIGGLING)
Tomorrow, tomorrow
I love you, tomorrow.
You're always a day away!
(CHILD GIGGLING)
(CHILD LAUGHING)
When I'm stuck with a day.
That's gray, and lonely
I just stick
out my chin and grin.
And say, oh.
The sun'll come out tomorrow.
So you gotta hang
on 'til tomorrow.
Come what may.
Tomorrow, tomorrow
I love you, tomorrow.
You're always a day away!
Tomorrow, tomorrow
I love you, tomorrow.
You're always a day.
Away!
(DOG BARKING)
Get it! Get it!
Come on! Hey!
(BARKING)
Throw something at it!
BOY: Throw the can!
ANNIE: Hey! Stop!
Mind your own business!
What's going on?
I don't know. I'm not a chemist.
Jimmy Neutron here had me throw
this experimental engine in.
It shows that he cares
about the environment.
You know,
that he's forward-thinking.
Oh, great. Here they come
with the pictures.
We gotta distract her.
Something whimsical.
Let's get into a leaf fight!
Ma'am.
Okay, okay. I'm
gonna call a car.
Hey! I'm gonna go walk.
BOTH: What?
Where's he going?
I wanna be alone.
We don't really have time.
I know how to walk
down the street!
I'll text you directions!
Don't need them.
This is all your fault.
Take it easy, pantsuit.
And, you... I'm sorry.
MAN: Hey, Stacks!
Your phone
bill's killing me, bro!
BOY 2: Get it! Annie: I told you to stop!
(PANTING)
BOY: Try to hit it!
ANNIE: Leave it alone!
Hey!
(HORN BLARING)
(BARKING)
All right, kick it! Kick it!
Stop! Leave it alone!
See how scared it is!
Leave it... (GRUNTS)
(HORN HONKING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
MAN: Watch where you're going, kid!
Are you okay?
Let's get out of here! You
could've got run over.
Sorry. Don't be sorry.
You be careful.
Why're you running? Gets
me to places quicker.
Little kids. Kids with germs.
(BLENDER WHIRRING)
How was the library?
Educational.
Well, I have some more
education for you.
I told the inspector I don't
wanna foster you anymore.
As of next week, you're
somebody else's problem.
Did they say who?
Not a who, sweetie. A what.
Group home.
Okay.
Maybe that'll teach you
to stop running your mouth.
So, where
are we with our new phones?
Well, we've got the battery
up to 150 hours. That's not a week.
I said I need the charge to last
a week, Grace. Specifically.
At the moment, unfortunately, the phone
is burning up in people's hands.
What?
That's what I told Mom. And
she says to me, she...
(SCREAMS)
You burned me!
Don't worry. She signed a waiver.
(PHONE RINGS)
You burned me!
What up, Guy-O?
You're up. Five
points in the polls.
Really? They liked that he vomited
on a homeless man?
Uh, no, Grace. They
liked the fact that
he saved a little girl
from getting hit by a Van.
Some guy recorded it, put it
on the lnternet. Check it out.
"Oh, I'm a little girl who doesn't
see where I'm going."
"Well, look! I bumped
into the future"
"mayor of New York
who just saved my life!"
This is fantastic, Will.
I'm telling you. It's the most human
thing you've done
this entire campaign,
all due respect.
None taken.
You didn't tell me you
saved a little girl.
You didn't tell me anything.
Like Batman.
Hey, listen to me. You
gotta capitalize on this.
Of course we do. You
invite her to lunch.
No. See how she's doing.
Snap a few pics. The
press'll eat this up.
Do we know who she is?
That's the best part.
She's a foster kid from Harlem.
Hmm. Did you hear what I said?
Foster kid! Harlem!
Your undereye vein is bulging.
I'm gonna go get her. No. I'm
gonna let Grace go get her.
What? Why? What?
That's a terrible idea!
Do you actually
want 5-hour ENERGY
to go over there and scare
this little child?
I don't even know
what this is about.
Grace, please. For me, Grace.
Please.
Thank you. Will, let
me go to Harlem.
Please. Don't send her.
They will whoop
your ass in Harlem.
Don't shut me off. Thank you.
Don't shut me off!
(BUZZING)
HANNIGAN: (OVER SPEAKER)
Yeah.
Is that Colleen Hannigan?
(HANNIGAN SPEAKING IN SPANISH)
I was wanting to talk to you
about a girl in your care.
Annie.
(HANNIGAN GROANS DRAMATICALLY)
I work for William Stacks and he would love
to take Annie out for lunch.
Why?
They ran into each other yesterday.
She didn't tell you?
No.
We didn't have a chance to, uh,
have our girl-talk
jawbone last night.
Annie!
So you said he ran
into her, huh?
'Cause I noticed that her neck
did seem a little whiplash-y.
We are happy to make a donation
to the charity of your choice.
Gosh! There's so
many to choose from.
There is.
Let's see, Save
the Whales, of course.
And Clean Water,
but you can't have
whales without water. (GROANS)
Gosh. You know what? Just make it
out to "cash." I'll divvy it up.
Perfect. Annie!
You know, she's such an angel.
We don't inherit the Earth,
we borrow it from our children.
It's a lovely sentiment.
Oh! There she is.
Hi, Annie. I'm Grace.
I work for Mr. Stacks, the gentleman
that you ran into yesterday.
He'd like to invite
you to lunch.
I promise we won't
keep you long.
You can keep me
as long as you want.
No way! Is this for real?
This car's as big as a subway!
You're so lucky!
It's incredible.
Oh, my gosh. I want that!
Oh, my gosh!
Help yourself
to whatever you want.
No way. Really?
Sure.
Give me this! Give me this!
I want this!
Oh, my God!
I want that one! I want that!
This is crazy! My God!
Kids love candy, huh?
(GASPING)
Hey, Annie! Maybe
I should come with you
and make sure that everything's USDA
Grade A awesome, huh?
I'm good. Thanks.
Bye, Annie!
Bye! Later.
Thanks! Oh, my gosh.
Hey, gorgeous!
How does it feel
to have a famous kid?
What are you talking about?
It's Annie!
Your Annie!
Hey, you wanna go out tonight?
I got my dance pants on.
I haven't hit
that rock bottom yet.
I love it when you
throw me shade!
(SCOFFS)
Here, Lou. It's okay.
She likes me.
Oh, my God, this is so good.
Mr. Stacks would like to take some pictures
with you, if that's all right.
I guess so. Why?
People wanna know
that you're okay.
What people?
Everybody who saw that.
Whoa, my hair's gigantic.
We can listen
to whatever you like.
Can you put on talk radio?
Are you sure you don't
wanna listen to music?
I love talk radio. It calms me.
So do I. I loved it when
I was a little girl.
I used to think that they were
all my friends.
(CHUCKLES)
Sorry, that sounded very sad.
(LAUGHS)
Sorry.
I have a lot of friends,
so don't worry about me.
I mean, so I work a lot. I do. And
I could have some more friends.
But how many friends
do you really need?
I mean, if you were
my parents asking me,
"Are you fulfilled
and are you happy, Grace?"
That's a whole different
conversation, right?
But we're not having
that conversation.
And, frankly, it's really not your position
to ask me that at all. So...
Okay.
There she is. Our own
Little Orphan Annie.
Foster kid.
She's here.
Hey, this is the one, right?
All right. Let's get this.
Slow your roll.
Excuse me? Can we eat first?
It was a long drive.
(WHISPERING)
Yeah, yeah. Go, go.
Yeah, yeah, sure. Let's eat.
We got time for that.
All right.
So, how are you feeling
from yesterday?
So, what's the hustle?
What makes you think there's a hustle?
There's no hustle.
Come on, come on. Uh...
I'm 10. I'm not an idiot.
I never said you were...
An idiot. Or 10.
Truth of the matter is,
I don't know how old you are.
Ten. Well, now we know
that you're not an idiot.
But there are a lot of people
out there that are
and when they saw
that photo of us,
they thought that I would make
a great mayor.
Why?
Why? Because I'm a...
I'm a rich guy.
I saved an orphan.
I'm not an orphan,
I'm a foster kid.
And you didn't save me.
Oh, I didn't save you?
I didn't just
push you out of the way
of a Van?
Why don't I call that Van
back and have him
finish up what he...
(GUY CLEARING THROAT)
You know what?
The more we're seen together,
the better it is for my campaign.
Wait. That's how a mayor
gets elected?
Yes. Insane, isn't it?
I bet if I moved in with you,
you'd become president.
(COUGHING)
Move in with me?
This is not that kind of party.
That's it. That's it. That's it.
(BEATBOXING)
I think he wants
to tell you something.
Actually, that's not a bad idea.
Annie coming to live with you.
BOTH: (IN UNISON)
What?
From what I understand, it's very
crowded where you live.
How'd you like some more space?
Is that something
that you might like?
Living with the richest
guy in the world?
Yeah, that's something
I might like.
Great. Perfect.
Guy. What are you talking about?
Listen to me. It'll only be
for a few weeks.
Then she'll go back
to wherever she came from.
Taking in a foster kid, that's an automatic
15 point jump in the polls.
Guaranteed. You want
me to play Daddy?
It's easy. All I need
is a bed and meals.
You don't have to do
anything else.
And you get $157 a week.
(LAUGHS)
Do I look like I need
$157 a week?
Everybody needs
an extra $157 a week.
You're not really thinking
about doing this?
You want photos, right?
I'm sure there's easier
ways to get photos.
Not with me in them.
Smile.
Mr. Stacks!
Are you really doing this?
Yeah, won't even know
she's there.
It's like having a turtle.
I wonder if she has her shots.
How was your lunch?
What's your name?
Her name is Annie, and she'll be
staying with Mr. Stacks for awhile.
He's going to adopt you?
No, no, no. I have parents.
This is just temporary.
If he gets approved.
(LAUGHS)
What now? Next.
I need a temporary
guardian approval, please.
There is a six-week waiting period
and you need form NYS 84...
Sweet Lord.
Hi.
Bam.
You know, I don't normally
do the site visits,
but I've taken such
a liking to young Annie.
I forget sometimes, you
know, why I got into this.
(SHUTTER CLICKS)
It's for my files.
So, does the guardian have "adequate
income to provide basic shelter"?
I'm just gonna go ahead
and check that box.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
Come on in.
MALE REPORTER: (OVER TV)
about $95 per share in cash and stock.
FEMALE REPORTER: Detonated
an explosive while fire...
(VARIOUS NEWSCASTS CONTINUE INDISTINCTLY)
Whoa.
Oh, yeah, whoa.
Hey, is there
a co-temporary guardian?
No.
Would you like a co-temporary
guardian?
Why don't I take these
guys on a tour,
and you can get back to work.
Best idea of the day.
GUY: I'll come with you.
Will. Will, Will!
Okay, so the state says
that you must have at least
one water source in...
Check.
And a window that's... Okay.
And then at least
one chair per 10 persons.
And I think the Starship
Enterprise is gonna count.
I'm gonna check that box.
How does it do this?
It's a smart house.
So, it recognizes your voice
and then adjusts itself accordingly.
It's like a friend.
I consider it a friend. But I have
real friends that aren't robots.
Let's forget this conversation
and the previous conversation
and start afresh.
Got that? Great.
I'm gonna record your voice now,
Annie, and it'll be in the system.
So, just say
something into this.
What should I say?
Anything.
I think I'm gonna like it here.
(ELECTRONIC CHIMING)
Got it.
Great. It's all yours.
Have a go. And I'll be back.
Ma'am?
Excuse me. You are not
allowed to go in there.
MRS. KOVACEVIC: This is very nice.
Are those halogen bulbs?
GRACE: Ma'am.
MRS. KOVACEVIC: This sink
is bigger than my entire country.
(FAST-TEMPO RHYTHM BEGINS)
I think I'm gonna like it here.
I think I'm gonna like it
I'm sure I'm gonna like it
I think I'm gonna like it here.
So, think it and it shall appear
Because it knows just
what you wanna see.
Wait, I think it
and it comes to me?
Here's something grand
for you to play.
Wait, I couldn't
do that yesterday
I think I'm gonna like it here.
It's very hard not to, my dear.
Yes, yes, I think I'm
gonna like it here.
Think I'm gonna like it here
I think I'm gonna like it here.
Yes, yes, I think I'm
gonna like it here.
(GASPS)
Yes, yes, I think I'm gonna like it here.
Think I'm gonna like it here.
Look!
It knows the temp
you're comfy in.
That's great. Can it
teach me to swim?
GRACE: We'll get a coach,
no need to fear.
(MUFFLED)
I think I'm gonna like it here.
The water's cold!
Everything you've ever dreamed.
Is at your fingertips.
And if you haven't
dreamed it yet.
Add it to your wish list.
Is this Mr. Stacks' room?
No, Annie, this is your room.
Sweet Lord.
I think I'm gonna like it
I know I'm gonna like it
I know you're gonna like it.
Damn right, you're gonna like it
I think I'm gonna like it here!
Yes, yes, I think I'm
gonna like it here.
Think I'm gonna like it here
I think I'm gonna like it here.
Yes, yes, I think I'm
gonna like it here.
Think I'm gonna like it here.
Yes, yes!
(SIGHS HAPPILY)
The closet was so big, I thought
it was the living room.
Really? How big
was the living room?
I thought it was Connecticut.
Oh, my gosh.
Is he nice?
I think so.
He just doesn't know it yet.
We're gonna miss you, Annie.
I'm not. Finally can get
a little space in here.
Well, whenever you miss me,
all you gotta do is call.
Bam, bam. What? Are you serious?
Bam. Stacks phones?
Even one for you, Pepper. I know
you're gonna miss me. Bam.
No case, huh? This is janky.
Hey, Mr. Will Stacks.
Or should I say
Soon-To-Be-Mr.- Mayor?
No, thank you. We're
just waiting on someone.
I'm not looking for temporary
companionship.
Not judging you.
God has a path for us all.
Your path should be away
from the car. What?
Ma'am, wanna move away
from the car, please?
How dare you...
Oh, really, you're
gonna spray me?
You think you're better than me?
Is that what it is? You think
you're better than me?
I do. I do think I'm
better than you.
ANNIE: Hey, Miss Hannigan. What?
I just wanna thank you
for everything you've done for me.
You think your life
is a fairy tale?
There is no happily ever after.
And the worst thing
is to get a little taste
of something good
'cause it never lasts.
And then all you can taste
from then on out is
not that taste.
Huh?
Shh. Just let her talk when
she gets like this, remember?
Shut up!
Colleen Hannigan! H-bomb!
Like me on Facebook!
I don't like you in Harlem.
Why would I like you
on Facebook?
Come on, rats, let's go!
(GIRLS GASP)
lnside! Bye, Annie.
Bye.
What was that?
Don't worry about it.
All right, Nash,
we can take off.
I can't, there's a truck.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Bogey on your left, Nash,
bogey on your left. Steady.
No, thank you. I'm not
looking for companionship.
What is it with this neighborhood?
No, that's Lou.
You know her name? It's a he.
Hey, girl.
Hey. I got you something.
No, thanks. Those
things are evil.
They steal your private
information
so that big business can spy
on you and crush your soul.
Really?
I'm happy for you though, mija.
Getting off the block.
Take care.
Bye, Lou.
Stay warm, Mr. Stacks.
Sorry. He just doesn't like you.
A lot of people don't like me.
That's why we're doing this.
Don't worry, I got a game face.
Let's take some photos.
MAN: My opponent wants to be
mayor for two reasons.
To feed his ego, and bolster
his business interests.
And now he coincidentally takes
in a foster kid? Come on.
Don't pee in my ear
and tell me it's hot rain.
Are you saying Annie
is a political move?
I'm surprised he hasn't
gotten a dog yet.
Are you sure I can have one?
No. Yes.
GUY: Look, kids love dogs.
Come on, they see them on the street
and they all go, "Aw."
Am I right? Hello.
You know, women do
the same thing.
Hello. (BARKS TWICE)
Hello.
(BARKING)
What about that one?
She was separated from her pack too early.
She just needs a little love.
Don't pick that one,
it's licking its own hoo-hah.
Hey, girl, we found each other.
I'll never leave you
again, I promise.
FEMALE REPORTER: Annie,
what are you gonna name it?
She's like a hurricane.
Sandy. Her
name's gonna be Sandy.
I told you. Ow!
Annie, will you take
a picture with us?
Um, sure.
Thanks, Annie.
She really likes you.
(SANDY PANTING)
Look.
Hey.
Something wrong?
Couldn't sleep.
So quiet up here.
What you doing? I'm working.
This late?
Always.
When do you have fun?
This is fun.
I haven't been to Disneyland,
but I don't think they have
a paperwork ride.
Look, if you're hungry, there's not
a lot of food here. Only takeout.
Fridge.
Cool.
Knock yourself out.
You don't have a cook? Or
like a million servants?
Nope, I don't.
I like to be alone.
So why do you need
all this space?
'Cause I like to be alone
with a lot of space.
Look, I think people surround
themselves with other people
just so they can feel loved.
I don't believe in that.
I believe the people
that actually love you,
you can count them on one hand.
You know you're making a fist.
Whatever.
Where are your people?
Wow, you ask a lot of questions,
little one. My people aren't around.
You don't want new ones?
I'm good.
You know what? I am hungry.
I can make a meal
out of anything.
Pick five ingredients.
I don't want to. Come
on, this'll be fun.
Annie, listen,
I don't have time...
Not work, but almost as fun.
(SIGHS)
All right. Fusilli, pancetta,
steak, pomegranate,
truffle, sun-dried tomatoes.
I've only heard
of two of those things.
Google it.
Okay, where
are your pots and pans?
Pots and pans.
I know.
Cool. Cool.
Put some in there.
Eh...
Put in some carrot?
You're not gonna
chop that carrot?
You lactose-intolerant?
I'm kid-intolerant.
How's your cholesterol?
It's good right now.
I'm gonna go downstairs and get
some supplies. See you later.
Orange you glad I'm back?
The sixth ingredient
is my jokes.
Order up.
Are we really doing this?
Cheers.
(GROANS)
You gotta be kidding me.
Sorry, it's gross.
But you gotta learn to stop spitting.
You're not a camel.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Guy has this crazy idea
that I should take you
to a movie premiere
tomorrow night.
A movie premiere?
Yes.
Can I bring my friends?
There's more of you?
More photos. Click, click.
All right. More photos.
More photos.
It's worse the second time.
Yeah.
This is kind of like a bunk bed.
Morning, Annie.
Good morning, Nash.
I know this sounds
crazy, but do you guys
spy on people with your phones?
Why?
I really need to find
some people.
Come with me.
Come on, you got it.
There you go.
Stacks Mobile Control Center.
We can trace every call,
every data transmission
made on every carrier
over the past 20 years.
Whoa. Mmm-hmm.
People shouldn't be
scared of governments.
They should be scared
of cell phone companies.
Check for Bennett. Checking.
NASH: Whoa. That's a lot
of Bennetts.
Can you please go
back six years?
Around the 26th Precinct.
It'll take a bit,
but we'll let you know.
Thanks.
(GIRLS SQUEALING)
TESSIE: Oh, my God!
Did Hannigan catch you?
No, she's passed out.
Things that make
you go glug-glug.
WOMAN: Uh, Mr. Stacks,
who are you wearing?
Armani.
Annie, who are you wearing?
This is my friend lsabella's,
and this I think
I found somewhere.
MAN: Annie, how'd you
like the French toast
you had for breakfast
this morning?
Wait. How'd you know that?
You tweeted it. @annie4realz
I started you a Twitter account.
1.3 million followers so far.
You get it? "4realz."
Because she's "for reals."
(CHUCKLES)
All right.
You get it, right?
Hey! Stacks Phones!
Never drop a call.
And, uh, vote for me, too.
Things happen for a reason.
Says the boy who doesn't have to go
home to the moon every night.
Then don't go.
You know it's not my choice.
What the hell is happening?
Her moon tears are running out.
Of course they are.
MAN: (IN MOVIE)
Then I'll make it my choice.
Did you just grab yourself?
Shh. (CELL PHONE BUZZING)
MAN: (IN MOVIE)
You're buzzing.
It's your phone. Oh.
Hey, it's one of our phones.
It's time.
That cost us $500,000.
What?
Product placement.
It's the only thing
that's keeping the movie
business afloat.
Execute your orders
and return to the queendom.
You succeed, and your mother
will be set free.
If not...
(GROWLS)
(AUDIENCE SCREAMING)
(ANNIE LAUGHS)
We are ready down there.
Once the moon sets,
we will attack.
Thanks, Sakana.
What is going on?
The fish are going
to attack the moon.
But they should attack already.
There's not gonna be enough time
for Kyle and Saffron
to get away
from the Luna Monsters.
(PANTING)
(SQUEALS)
Attack, Sakana, attack!
AUDIENCE: Shh!
Quiet.
She's a fish and he's a boy.
Moonquake, Moonquake...
(SQUEALING)
Sakana, Sakana!
Sakana!
Sit down.
I can't believe
Sakana told on them.
Of course you can. You can't
trust the fish people.
Gwarklark warned them.
I think she was bluffing.
Nah, it was a warning. They
come back in the next movie.
There's a next movie?
There're four more.
BOTH: (IN UNISON)
Shut up!
Whoa! Cool!
(GROANS)
I gotta get back to work.
You can't stay for the party?
No. I haven't
worked in two hours
and three of my men
think I'm dead.
I'm alive.
You've worked enough.
If your building gets any taller
it's gonna hit the sun.
You got this crazy way
of turning a no into a yes.
How do you do that?
I think when people say no, they're
just really scared of saying yes.
Well, I'm not scared. No!
Please! No!
Please. Yes.
Yes! Come on!
(STAMMERS)
Uh... Uh. Uh, listen. I don't know.
- Well, okay.
- GRACE: This is amazing.
Mr. Stacks! Will!
I can't believe how long
you've been here.
We're gonna be late
for the Jets-Giants game.
You're doing
the ceremonial coin flip.
And remember, they're
both New York teams,
so, heads or tails, you gotta
be equally happy and sad.
You're right.
You go, I'll stay
here with the kids.
You sure? Yeah.
All right, come on, let's go.
What is that?
MIA: Look, Tessie!
- Can we make one more stop?
- TESSIE: Shh.
Sure. Don't wake up Hannigan.
GIRLS: Bye! Bye, girls!
You come here every Friday?
It's the only day
they serve cannoli.
And that's all you've got
to go on?
Do you think you'll remember
what they look like?
I think I'll just know.
(TV PLAYING INDISTINCTLY)
(GROANS)
(GIRLS SINGING ALONG TO
STEREO IN OTHER ROOM)
(CONTINUE SINGING)
What are you doing still up?
(MUSIC STOPS)
Where did you get
all of this stuff?
Where'd you get it?
We went with Annie to the movies,
and we got candy and soda,
and we went ice skating,
and Mr. Stacks is so cool,
and I got fish earrings.
Nice, Tessie.
I can't keep a secret.
I got fish earrings.
Pack it up. It's going back.
Why? Because you
don't deserve it.
Yes, we do.
It's from our friend.
She's not your friend. And
neither is Mr. Stacks.
They're all just a bunch of parasites
who suck the life out of you
and move on once
you're not the shiny
new object
in the Factory anymore.
You're being mean.
I'm being educational!
Now pack it up! You
look ridiculous.
(CLATTERING)
I didn't fall.
(LAUGHING)
reptile in the bathtub.
DOLL: Mama.
Mama.
Little girls, little girls.
Everywhere I turn
I can see them.
Ugh.
Little girls, little girls.
Night and day I eat,
sleep and breathe them.
Get out of here!
I should be anywhere but here.
Private planes,
on the stage and MTV.
But I find myself here
at the snot house.
Little shoes, little socks.
Please kill me. I'm
serious, please kill me.
I'm not singing, I'm asking.
Locked in a cage
with all the rats
I've slipped through the cracks.
And now I'm stuck
with the scraps.
And I can't seem
to find my way back.
Get me out, get me out of here.
LITTLE GIRLS: Oh, get her out
I'm ready for stardom
after all these years
I'm done with little girls
(GIGGLING)
I wanna be someone
in this world.
Little girls, little girls.
Everywhere I turn
I can see them.
Ugh.
Little girls, little girls.
Night and day I eat,
sleep and breathe them.
Get out of here!
Locked in a cage
with all the rats
I've slipped through the cracks.
And now I'm stuck
with the scraps.
And I can't seem
to find my way back.
Oh, get me out, get
me out of here.
Oh, throw me a rope
I'm ready for stardom
after all these years
I'm done with little girls
I wanna be someone
in this world.
Little girls, little girls
(GIRLS GIGGLING)
HANNIGAN: Ugh.
(SLOW, STEADY CLAPPING OUTSIDE)
LOU: Oh, my God.
(CONTINUES CLAPPING)
That was beautiful.
Your voice matches your beauty.
You sound like a church bell,
if it was stuck on top
of a beautiful woman,
or if a beautiful woman
was inside a church bell.
Not that you look like a church bell.
That's not what I'm saying.
If you looked like a church bell,
I'd go to church every day.
What?
I got you a T-shirt, and you're gonna
love it. Here, you ready? Here.
(GRUNTS)
LOU: What...
It's not your color? Not your size.
I got more in the store.
You know what I'm talking
about, the church bell, right?
(CHUCKLES)
Cannoli. One
for your pretty friend.
Thank you.
Sorry, kid. It's okay.
Can you not tell
Mr. Stacks about this?
I don't want to bother
him with it.
Sure.
MAN: (OVER TV) He's worked selflessly
his entire life for New York.
From his first job teaching
in inner-city schools,
to his 25 year stint
on the City Council...
Whose voice is that?
I don't know.
Endorsed by The New York
Times, the New York Post,
and me, Michael J. Fox.
Michael J. Fox? It's over.
We're finished.
If Michael J. Fox endorses
him, then I'll vote for him.
Listen to me, Michael J. Fox
is not as great
a guy as you think.
Oh, no, no. Come
on, he's a Saint.
I hear there's a tape. Forget it.
I don't wanna hear it.
You've plateaued.
Michael J. Fox.
Pay attention. Follow
the little green dot.
That's you there. I don't need
a pointer to read a graph.
Well, read this. Annie's taken
you as far as she can, okay?
But it's not over.
How bad do you want this?
I don't start
things I can't win.
Well, how far are you
willing to go?
Or should I say, how far
do you want me to go?
I pay you a lot of money
for you not to ask me
those types of questions.
Okay, Guy-O?
Rat-a-tat-tat, message
received, boss.
(SANDY WHIMPERS QUIETLY)
(WHIMPERS QUIETLY)
Good morning. Made
you breakfast.
You made me breakfast.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Hey, I was thinking maybe you would wanna
go in to work with me today.
Cool. That'd be cool?
I'll go make us drinks.
All right.
Don't let your food get cold.
Mmm!
(MOUTH FULL)
Okay. I won't. This is amazing.
Oh...
Annie, you really
outdid yourself.
Annie, this is a triumph, honey.
You got me eating this
thing up like a dog.
Oh! Mmm!
This is good. What is it?
Mmm, paprika, mmm, oregano.
What is... Mmm, mmm! What
is that, Gouda cheese?
You wanna know what's Gouda?
This breakfast.
Cool, a helicopter!
Yeah.
Oh! Make sure you duck! Why?
I don't know. They always
duck in the movies!
Hop on up.
All right. Here we go.
Do you get airsick?
Don't know. I've never
been in the air before.
Ah. I threw
up on the swings once.
Annie, we're gonna do
a cell tower check.
Make sure they're all working.
You do that yourself?
Yep, told you work was fun.
Gilbert, let's roll.
You'll be all right.
STACKS: You wanna know the secret
to "Never drop a call"?
Not really.
Yes, yes, I do. Desperately.
Good.
See, we have five times
as many cell towers
as the other guys.
But we hide them in plain sight.
Like right there. You see?
No.
It's in her crown.
Yeah!
(CHUCKLES)
ANNIE: That's so cool.
STACKS: It's beautiful,
isn't it?
How'd you do this? How'd you
become king of the world?
Well, I wouldn't say
king of the world.
But I work my butt off.
The harder I work, the more
opportunities I get.
See, you gotta play the cards
that you've been dealt,
no matter how bad the cards are.
What if you don't
have any cards?
Then you bluff.
See, that's what I love
about this city.
No matter who you
are or what you are,
you just gotta want it bad enough,
and work with what you got.
This is just the start
of your story.
If you got guts,
you'll get glory.
Anyone can make
their dreams come true.
In New York City.
And now's the time you
gotta stand tough.
'Cause if you work
hard, you can rise up.
Anyone can make it, even you.
In New York City.
Look at me, I'm
just blood pumpin'
You and me
are two hearts thumpin'
We are two souls
feeling the same beat.
So take it all,
the city's yours.
It's worth fighting for.
It's all yours.
So take it all.
The city's yours.
It's worth fighting for.
It's all mine.
It's all yours.
Why don't you go
above 96th Street?
No reason.
Gilbert, go uptown.
This is my New York City.
Where'd you live?
Everywhere.
- Oh, I see a cell tower!
- STACKS: Where?
See it? Right there.
Right under that devil bird.
STACKS: Good eyes.
You know, Annie, sometimes
what you're looking for
is right in front of your face.
In New York City.
So take it all.
The city's yours.
The city's mine.
Worth fighting for.
It's worth fighting for.
It's all mine.
So take it all.
The city's yours.
The city's mine.
Worth fighting for.
It's worth fighting for.
It's all mine.
It's all yours.
In New York City.
Grace. Hmm?
What's our presence
past 96th Street?
Um, well, we're
mostly focused below,
but I've been saying
for a while we should try...
No, but I had it this way.
Let me do this. I've got it.
I know what I'm doing.
Miss Farrell?
Oh. It arrived. Thanks.
What's that?
I bought a dress for Annie
to wear to the event tonight.
It's gorgeous. I just
need you to tie the bow
and make sure that the satin...
I tie the bow? Yeah.
I'm dressing her? You
just have to tie the bow.
No, I... (CLEARS THROAT)
What kind of bow?
It's just a simple bow.
Like a slipknot?
'Cause you know I didn't
take Boy Scouts.
It's very easy, Will.
And have the satin facing out.
The satin?
Yeah. I knew a girl named Satin.
I'm sure you did. You
don't need to elaborate.
Satin and bows is not
necessarily my...
You know what? I'll come over.
Yeah, I mean, either way. Great.
She's gonna look gorgeous.
Mmm-hmm.
Annie.
(CHUCKLES)
You did not...
You didn't see anything?
I didn't see anything.
Good. Good. 'Cause I... Well, I don't know.
I thought I saw you...
Nope! Here the whole time.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS) What were
you guys doing? Just hanging out?
Hi.
Evening.
Wow.
Uh, Grace, you look great.
Oh, please. You look
handsome, lovely.
STACKS: No. GRACE: Yes.
This is old. This is my grandmother's.
It's nothing.
Your grandmother is hot.
I mean, not that I've... I've never
seen your grandmother. I'm not...
I'm saying
that the dress is nice.
Well, you're sweet.
You look good.
So do you.
Let's go and get you dressed.
Let's go!
Oh, oh, her dressed.
I was already dressed.
Come on! Yes.
Come on.
Yeah. Get some...
(CHUCKLES)
ANNIE: Ready?
Yes. I'm very excited.
Oh, Annie, it's gorgeous.
You're just gorgeous.
I can't believe it.
All right, ladies, let's go. Let's go.
We're running late.
Annie! Wow.
I know, right? I've never
seen a bow this big.
Yes, and I noticed that you put
the satin on the outside of the bow.
That's a very
interesting choice.
You know what? Get out of here.
We're not done yet.
You know what? When did
this stop being my house?
ANNIE AND GRACE: Out!
Okay, fine.
You know what? You're
changing everything.
As a matter of fact, this
used to be a Basquiat.
Now it's a dog
and a deer in a Meadow.
Why is that combination so cute?
(BOTH LAUGH)
Come on. Let's do your hair.
Why aren't you
and Mr. Stacks together?
(LAUGHS)
That's a complicated question.
Not really. Do you like him?
Well, you know, I work for him.
You know,
liking him doesn't
really come into play.
Okay.
I mean, is he my friend? Yes.
Do I find him attractive? Sure.
And not just in the physical sense.
But he is very good-looking.
He's got lovely shoulders
and a great, chiseled face.
Lovely lips. Good hair.
I wouldn't bank
on the hair, sister.
Well, I'm far too
busy to be bothered
with anything
like that anyway, so...
That sounds like something
Mr. Stacks would say.
Yeah, it does, doesn't it?
When my friend Pepper
liked this boy at school,
she punched him in the face.
She got suspended, but they play
in the park together now.
Sometimes I'd like to punch
Mr. Stacks in the face.
I'm just meaning punching.
That's it.
I just want to punch him.
He's annoying.
(HORNS HONKING)
(REPORTERS CLAMORING)
(CAMERAS CLICKING)
Thanks for doing this, Will. Your
name's gonna look great up there.
Now, you sure the Guggenheims are okay
with me taking their name off?
You gave me 100
million reasons not to care.
(LAUGHS)
Did they find anything
on my parents?
No, not yet. And we dug real deep.
I'm sorry.
ANNIE: Thanks for trying.
Annie!
REPORTER: Annie, come on!
Annie, Annie!
(CLAMORING CONTINUES)
New Yorkers face challenges
every single day.
Challenges that seem
insurmountable.
We all tell ourselves
"no" a lot.
We say, "No, I won't
get that job,"
or, "No, I can't
afford college."
Unless it's you, Franklin,
coming from the mean streets
of Martha's Vineyard.
(LAUGHTER)
(ORCHESTRA PLAYS RIM SHOT)
Hey! Yeah.
STACKS: Let's change
those noes to yeses.
Because when we say no, we're
actually just scared to say yes.
So, let's start saying
yes to ourselves,
and let's say yes
to a brighter future.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Now, many of you know that I've had
a visitor staying with me recently.
She only knows
the word "yes." Annie?
Hmm?
Could you come up, please?
Go on. You'll be great. Go on, darling.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Swallow your shrimp, Annie.
STACKS: Now, Annie, I don't
wanna embarrass you.
I just want everyone to see
what the future of our city is all about.
Now, do you have
anything you want to say
to these good people that are just
oozing with liberal guilt?
Except for you, Senator.
I know you're trying
to build that fence.
(LAUGHTER)
I can't believe I'm here.
I'm in a dress
that feels like a cloud.
I'm standing in the middle
of a giant cinnamon roll.
(LAUGHTER)
With a band that has
little violins,
big violins... (ORCHESTRA
PLAYING SOFTLY)
one of those.
Oh, a piano.
Mr. Stacks has
taught me so much.
He's given me such
a big opportunity.
Under the glow of the very
bright lights
I turn my face
towards the warm night skies.
And I am not afraid
of a thousand eyes.
When they're
above five hundred smiles.
Oh, I used to think.
Oh, she used to think.
What wouldn't I give.
What wouldn't she give.
For a moment like this.
This moment, this gift.
Now look at me.
And this opportunity.
Is standing right
in front of me.
But one thing I know
It's only part luck and so
I'm putting on my best show.
Under the spotlight
I'm starting my life.
Big dreams becoming
real tonight.
So look at me
and this opportunity.
You're witnessing
my moment, you see?
My big opportunity.
Oh, I used to think.
Oh, she used to think.
What I wouldn't give.
What wouldn't she give.
For a moment like this.
This moment, this gift.
And now look at me.
And this opportunity.
Is standing right
in front of me.
But one thing I know
It's only part luck and so
I'm putting on my best show.
Under the spotlight
I'm starting my life.
Big dreams becoming
real tonight.
So look at me
and this opportunity.
You're witnessing
my moment, you see?
My big opportunity
I won't waste it
I guarantee.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Take a bow.
(LAUGHING)
That was great.
(QUIETLY)
Now read my speech. What?
That speech I wrote you. My speech.
It's right there.
Is everything all right?
I'll make it bigger for her.
There it is. "Thank
you, Mr. Stacks."
Hold on a second. No.
Annie, is everything okay?
Leave me alone.
(CROWD MURMURING)
Annie! Annie!
Annie?
(MICROPHONE FEEDBACK SQUEALS)
This is your big opportunity.
To vote for William Stacks
Annie.
Wait! Wait, wait, wait!
(HORNS HONKING)
Annie!
Hey! Wait, Annie. Slow down.
What are you doin'?
Annie. Wait, wait, wait.
I got it.
What's going on? It's nothing.
Young lady, you're
have to tell me
what's going on with you now!
No, I don't! You're not my dad.
Wow.
Well, I know that.
I know I'm not your dad.
But I would like to know
what's going on with you.
I can't read.
What do you mean you can't read?
I've watched you read, Annie.
Maybe you were just nervous.
Sorry I ruined
your shrimp event.
NASH: What happened?
I don't know. She freaked out.
Hey, what were you
two talking about earlier?
She asked me to help her find her
parents, but it was a dead end.
Even asked some of my old
buddies on the force.
There's nothing on that kid.
Her parents.
Genius.
(REPORTERS CLAMORING)
Annie, what's wrong?
Get back! Hey, hey, get back!
Grace! Get back!
Nash! Hey!
Hey, hey, hey, hey. Make room!
She's a kid. Get back.
She's a kid.
Come on.
Get back. She's a kid!
(DOORBELL BUZZES)
Who is it?
It's Guy Danlily.
I work for Will Stacks.
(SWEETLY)
Come in.
(LOCK RELEASE BUZZES)
(CLEARS THROAT)
(CLICKS TONGUE)
Hello there.
Uh, Colleen Hannigan?
That's my maiden name.
But I'm not married to it,
if you know what I mean.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
Can I buy you another drink?
So, if he wins, I get
paid a fortune.
More than anything I've ever
been paid combined.
Why so much?
It's like getting paid
long odds on a dark horse.
Do you know how hard it
is to get Will Stacks elected?
"Never drop a call." What
does that even mean?
Everybody texts now.
There have been worse
politicians than him.
I know. I got them elected.
Schwarzenegger, Kim Jong-Il,
that blood diamonds guy.
What? But I'm over it.
I'm tired of being the cockroach
everybody needs,
but treats like a...
Cockroach?
Exactly. Hmm.
This is my last
roll at the table.
Get paid and get out.
There's no such thing as a way out.
Trust me.
There's always a way out.
And in this particular case,
it's all about finding Annie's parents.
You know, I'm tired
of being the black hat.
Of running the show
down in the snake pit.
Are you singing to me?
So this is our chance
to get out of this place.
Is this really happening?
So come on, let's run for it to.
Easy street.
Where you sleep till noon.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
If Stacks reunites Annie
with her parents,
80% surge in the polls for sure.
We talked about this already.
They don't exist.
We'll make them exist.
Find a couple people
to pretend to be her parents.
They learn every detail
and miraculously show
up right before the election.
(CHUCKLES)
Add water, instant parents.
What's in it for me?
Same as for me. Ka-ching.
And no more being a cockroach.
Yeah, I'll be the girl
who's dripping in jewelry.
The crowds'll go
wild when I sing
I won't have to look
out on a fire escape.
Two.
The view will be
billboards of me.
On easy street On easy street.
Easy street Easy street.
To a way out.
Where we all get paid
Where we all get paid.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah
(CHEERING)
Move them feet to Move
them feet to.
Easy street Easy street.
When you get there
When you get there.
Stay Stay
I knew I liked you.
(CHUCKLES)
(GRUNTS)
Okay, we're not doing
that right now.
That's fine. YOLO, YOLO.
That's fine.
To easy street.
(SONG ENDS)
I've been telling her she can do
anything she wants
to do in this city,
and come to find
out she can't even read.
(SIGHS)
How does that happen?
A lot of kids get lost, Will.
A lot of people get lost.
Well, it's unacceptable.
We gotta get her a tutor.
For her, though, right?
Not just for the press.
Yeah. Yeah.
For her.
What? (CHUCKLES)
I can feel you smiling with those
Britisher-than-thou lips.
Your secret's safe
with me, Batman.
What secret? That
you care about her.
I care about the kids
that are in New York City.
And Annie.
Well, she lives in New York.
So, therefore, she's cared for.
It's a blanket... Mmm-hmm.
She's within the structure
of the whatever.
Annie? Where you going?
Thanks for everything. Sorry
I messed up last night.
Hope you can still be mayor.
What are you talking about?
Get back here.
It's okay. I'm
good at this part.
I've had a lot of practice
getting kicked out of places.
(SIGHING)
Oh, Annie.
Listen, put your bag down.
You're not going anywhere.
Sandy's gotta go.
Stop it.
You and Sandy are staying here,
and I don't care
what happened last night.
No, I mean Sandy's gotta go.
No, I mean... Oh, Sandy's gotta go.
Okay.
Well, is it, uh,
champagne or gelato?
What?
Is it Mountain Dew or is it
just plain old doo?
(CHUCKLES)
Is it lemonade
or chicken nuggets?
We should... I should go.
Now I wanna go
because my bladder's full.
Come on, let's go.
STACKS: I saw you
sign your name.
That's all you gotta
know how to do.
But what about your teachers?
How is this possible?
I'm good at hiding it.
Okay, at home. They
didn't catch it at home?
"At home"?
How come you didn't tell
anybody about this?
It's not like the whole world
wants a foster kid
to begin with.
And plus, it's embarrassing.
I didn't want anyone to know.
You know what?
I wanna show you something.
STACKS: This is good here.
ANNIE: Where are we? Queens.
Do I need my passport? (LAUGHS)
Truth is, Annie,
everybody's got something
that they don't want
anybody to know.
Including me.
For me, this is it.
This is my family.
Can you see them right now?
No, I don't. I see
them in my mind.
Like this part
of the track right here?
This is where my father
worked 20 hours a day.
Work, and work,
and work, and work.
And then, uh, he died.
I was 12 years old.
What was he like?
I don't know. I barely knew him.
He was always working.
And that's why I felt
like if I worked hard enough,
then that'd probably
bring me closer to him.
And that's why I developed this.
Well,
now, you got this.
Yeah, all right, Annie.
You know, this pollen
or something's got
my eyes all scratchy.
Let's walk this way.
We can see where the trains go.
MAN: It's so good to see
you after all these years!
PEPPER: Yo, suit. No cuts, no butts,
no coconuts. You gotta sign in.
For what? The auditions.
Audition?
Oh, my God!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, wait!
Oh! "We've been trying
so hard to find you!"
Where is she? Back there. Why?
Wait!
Hey! Stop! Stop!
That's an interesting choice.
"Oh, darling girl! It's so good
to see you after all these years!"
"We've been trying so
hard to find you,"
"and then we saw
pictures of you"
"with the nice man
running for mayor."
"Let's sing our special
song only us three know."
Locket!
(SINGING SCALES)
The sun will come out.
Pronto!
BOTH: Bet your sweet
bottom, fella, that.
Pronto! (BEATBOXING)
There'll be sun!
(IMITATES SCRATCHING)
What the hell is this?
A disaster.
You're garbage. You're pitchy.
Next! Come on.
I really like the script.
David Kramer says hello!
Out! That hack.
What are you doing?
You told me to find two people
to play her parents.
I meant some friends
or some neighborhood toughs.
Not open auditions.
These are callbacks.
I know, right?
And why are they singing?
People love musicals.
Bursting into song for no apparent reason.
It's magical!
There's a window There's a bed.
Here's a table
There's your head.
Okay. You're done.
I'll take care of finding the parents.
You don't do anything.
I'll call you when I need you.
But... No buts. We're
running out of time.
Oh!
(LAUGHING)
Touch the sign! I did it!
You ever see Casper
the Friendly Ghost throw up?
No.
(GAGGING)
(LAUGHING)
(PLAYFUL GROWLING)
Would you like a marshmallow?
Psych! How about a Graham cracker?
You son of a...
(MUFFLED TALKING)
(CHUCKLES)
You make me laugh.
(LAUGHING)
Hey, Grace. Uh, let
me ask you something.
(SIGHS)
Exactly how hard would it be
to become a foster parent?
And not temporarily either.
More like a...
Well, you know,
permanent situation.
You mean, adopt Annie?
Yeah, well, whatever
the word is.
That's the word, Will.
Then, uh...
Yeah.
Sandy.
We slept in the bed.
Which one do you prefer, Will?
Hmm? Uh, red.
It's been two hours.
I don't think
she's completely
learned to read yet.
Yeah, well, not
completely, but...
GUY: Will! Will!
We got our game changer.
Every election needs a game changer.
Stop saying "game changer."
Annie's parents.
They saw her picture, and they called us.
It's a miracle.
"Game changer." Apparently,
they've been looking for her for years,
but she's not in the system.
How do they know
she's their daughter?
Well, they know
everything about her.
They know about the locket,
the note,
and oh, yeah, I ran a DNA test.
Boom goes the dynamite.
DNA test.
(CLEARS THROAT)
All right, but don't tell her.
I wanna meet them
before Annie finds out.
I wouldn't have
it any other way.
I mean, you should
totally be the one.
(LOUDLY)
who tells Annie that we found her parents!
You found my parents?
Yes, honey, we did.
Well, we think so.
Really?
Uh, yeah. We're gonna meet them
at a place called the Domani.
That's where the note is from!
No way!
I knew they'd come for me.
Uh...
I'm happy for you, Annie. I know
this is what you always wanted.
And it's all because of you.
ANNIE: I can't believe I'm gonna see
my parents. I'm kind of freaking out.
(CROWD CLAMORING, CAMERAS CLICKING)
REPORTER: Annie! Annie!
Over here!
Are you happy? Are you happy?
Very happy for you.
Thanks.
Annie, The Reunion.
Annie. My girl.
(CHUCKLES)
Is it a match? Let's see, huh?
(GASPS)
It's a match.
MOM: We thought
we'd lost you forever.
Me, too.
DAD: We fell upon hard times.
We just felt it was best for someone
else to look after you.
I figured.
I've never forgiven
myself for it.
But when we got
back on our feet,
well, we just couldn't
find you, kid.
But the angels were looking out.
Where do you live? New Jersey.
Ooh. (CHUCKLES)
But we're moving
to Brazil for my job.
I think you're gonna
like it there.
ANNIE: Cool.
GUY: Okay, let's get started.
Everything is, uh, in order.
We have the DNA test
signed by the judge.
Now, we just need
signatures of the parents.
That's you guys. That's us.
MRS. KOVACEVIC: Ma'am,
sign right there.
Hey. Remember me from before?
You know what, I do.
That's right.
I didn't know that you
were Annie's foster mom.
Amongst other things. I know.
She said that you're
a very good singer.
What'd she say?
(WHINY) "Oh! She's a really
good singer."
No, she didn't do any of that.
She just said
you have a very nice
voice, and she liked it.
She did? Yep.
Said it made her feel
good about herself.
MRS. KOVACEVIC: Thank you, Rodney.
The guardian of record.
That's you, stretch. Come on.
Right here.
You sure about this?
That this is gonna win
you the election? Yeah.
No. Annie.
You don't pay me
to worry about her.
And the current temporary
guardian, William Stacks.
Mr. Stacks, we meet again.
That is a very big pen.
Thank you.
Okay. Well, according
to the State of New York,
you are officially reunited.
ANNIE: Yay! Great!
We'll pick you up at 4:00.
Great.
(CLAMORING)
All right.
REPORTER 2: What were they like?
Hey! Hey, hey, wait!
How did you do the DNA test?
You can do anything with money.
Well, who are those people,
and what's your plan with her, anyhow?
Don't worry about it.
She served her purpose.
What does that mean?
That they'll hold
her for a while
then dump her back in the system
till after the election.
No harm, no foul.
You can't do that to her. I mean,
she's still a little girl.
What do you care? Look, just go
home and keep your mouth shut.
Hey! You can't talk
to me like that.
I know things about you.
Well, if you know
what's good for you,
you'll go home, and keep
your mouth shut.
(ENGINE STARTS)
REPORTER 3: Mr. Stacks! Has
it helped you in the polls?
Hey, folks, Mr. Stacks is thrilled
for Annie and her family.
Never drop a citizen.
Vote Stacks for mayor.
REPORTER 4: Annie! Annie! Did you
enjoy seeing them? How was it?
(CLAMORING)
We're gonna miss you, Annie.
Yeah.
We can finally get those bubbles
out of the apartment. (CHUCKLES)
(SOFTLY)
Yeah.
(SIGHS)
Warm enough?
Yeah. Are you?
Yeah.
Is it dusty in here?
Nah.
NEWSCASTER: The New York
Post reports Will Stacks
reuniting Annie with her parents
has pushed him into a dead
heat in the race for mayor.
He was once trailing
by as much as 30 points.
Hey, baby. So, I haven't seen
you in here for a minute.
To what do I owe this pleasure?
Take it easy.
How you doing?
Not super awesome.
You want me to make you a sandwich?
(SCOFFS, GAGS)
How about if I make you a key?
(SIGHS)
You ever do anything
that you thought
was really a good
idea at the time,
but then after,
it's like you're not so sure.
Yeah. Putting up that key sign.
I don't know the first
thing about making keys.
What's the matter, sweetie?
What did you do?
'Cause, whatever it is, you
know I'm here to help.
Why are you so nice to me,
the way I treat you?
Because under all that bitter,
there's a sweet lady with a big heart.
She's just been gone for a while.
That's all.
Hmm.
Yeah.
Who am I, and what have
I become?
Do I stand for something
or for money?
Who am I, and where's my good
girl gone?
You know I had a good
heart once, you see.
Who am I now
that my armor's gone?
You gave me what I didn't
know I needed.
Who am I now
that my heart is won?
I didn't know I needed anyone.
But I've got today
I gotta make I gotta make.
The best I can of it
The best I can of it.
'Cause yesterday
'Cause yesterday.
Is dead and gone
Is dead and gone.
And me along with it
I want to start again
I want to start again.
So I look within So
I look within.
Remember what I wanted
Remember what I wanted.
'Cause I don't know
'Cause I don't know.
Who I've become Who I've become.
But I will trust in it
But I will trust in it.
Yeah, I will trust in it
Yeah, I will trust in it.
Who am I? I spent my life alone.
Forever looking
for some place to call home.
Who am I? About to meet myself.
This should feel right,
but something don't.
ALL: (IN UNISON)
I want to start again.
So I look within.
Remember what I wanted.
'Cause I don't know
who I've become.
But I will trust in it
I will trust in it.
Oh, I will trust in it
But today I gotta make.
The best I can of it.
'Cause yesterday
is dead and gone.
And me along with it
I wanna start again.
(SONG ENDS)
(SIGHS)
TESSIE: Cinderella
dressed in yellow.
Went upstairs to kiss her fella.
Made a mistake and kissed
a snake How many doctors...
Guys, I need your help.
Hey. Hey.
Gotta give this back to you.
It won't work in Brazil.
Yeah, we're not in Brazil yet.
We're in Ecuador,
Bolivia, Colombia...
Actually, Southern Colombia.
Now, Bogota,
that's a tough place
to penetrate.
Yeah, I've heard
that about Bogota.
Made you something.
Really?
That's me, that's Sandy,
and that's you.
I copied "Stacks" from my phone.
I'm gonna miss you.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
MOM: Annie. Hi.
You ready? We're gonna go
straight to the airport, kid.
ANNIE: Okay.
It's been great getting
to know you, Annie.
You're such a special
little girl.
You should punch
Mr. Stacks in the face
so you can go play
in the park together.
Then you'll have a real friend.
(LAUGHS)
That was between us!
Okay? Okay.
I'd like to help you out.
(CLEARS THROAT)
No, thank you. We don't
believe in handouts.
Only hand ups. And
you've already given us one.
Bye, Annie.
(WHISPERS)
Never slow your roll.
You neither.
(SANDY GROWLING, BARKING)
Whoa! (GASPS)
What a cute dog.
Come on. Bye.
(QUIETLY)
Bye.
Goodbye, Annie.
The press is eating this up.
We're gonna crush. (CHUCKLES)
Goodbye, Harold Gray, you
pathetic, nonprofit do-gooder.
Grace, where
are we with that phone battery?
What?
A full week on one charge,
where are we with that?
We're close. Close
is not good enough.
Well, we don't have the...
We've already
wasted enough time.
I'm gonna go call
the research department.
(REPORTERS CLAMORING, CAMERAS CLICKING)
Knock them dead, kid.
REPORTER: Bye, Annie!
Will? I hate seeing
you like this.
Grace, I'm fine. Let's just...
NASH: Mr. Stacks, I think
you're gonna wanna hear this.
TESSIE: Annie's in trouble.
What? Those weren't
her real parents.
What? What is happening?
Ignore her, 'cause
she's clearly insane.
Watch your mouth, chango.
Look, I did something terrible,
and I'm really sorry.
What do you mean those
aren't her real parents?
He had them take her somewhere.
I can't believe
I danced with you!
You danced with him?
I was desperate. He
was a little handsy.
Where is Annie?
What have you done?
Where's Annie?
ANNIE: Is it cold in Brazil?
(WHISPERING)
Just be cool.
She's asking questions.
(WHISPERING CONTINUES)
Do you collect ashtrays?
No.
Art? No.
Do you play piano? Just shut up.
Where are we going?
We're just taking you
someplace for a little bit.
Just relax.
You're not my real
parents, are you?
Sit back. Sit still.
DAD: What are you doing?
Stop that.
Let me go!
When Mr. Stacks finds
out about this...
Stacks doesn't need you anymore.
Why do you think
we're taking you?
You work for Mr. Stacks?
He wouldn't do this.
Yeah, well, I guess
he has enough photos.
Mr. Stacks did this?
Call my guy at the FBI.
I want to get everyone on it.
I got it.
I'm already on with the police.
I didn't think anything
like this could happen.
How could you not
know who has her?
I got a guy who takes care
of these kinds of things.
It keeps our hands clean.
Trust me.
I can't trust you.
You took Annie.
Hey!
Hey, look!
It's me! Annie!
Hey, girl! Help!
(CAMERA CLICKS)
Get her. Grab her.
Sit, sit, sit still.
Don't touch me! (SANDY BARKING)
Sit still! (TIRES SCREECHING)
(HORNS BLARING)
Everybody, listen up.
Check every call
within a 10-mile radius. On it.
I knew they could do that!
Someone just posted a picture
of Annie on Twitter.
Where? 54th and 6th.
(PHONE CHIMES) Another one on an Annie
blog. It looks like she's waving.
57th and 6th. Let's go.
Hey. You do this,
and everyone will know.
Forget about being mayor.
It'll destroy your whole business!
I don't care.
You're making a huge mistake.
Think about everything
you've worked for.
That everything means nothing.
You're fired.
You! Talk to him. Ow!
You're
the only one he'll listen to.
(GROANS)
It's not 'cause she likes you.
She's got these pointy little...
Oh!
Nice chopper! What
is this, a Bell 429?
What?
What, a guy like me can't
know about helicopters?
I don't know anything about helicopters!
It's written right here.
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
Gilbert, let's go.
GILBERT: Roger that.
Who's Roger? Who's Roger?
Is anyone else dizzy?
Look! It's Annie!
Help.
Another picture on lnstagram.
65th and 10th.
Head west, Gil.
(HANNIGAN GASPS, WHIMPERS)
(KIDS CLAMORING)
Hey, what are you doing? Hey!
Hold her still.
(TIRES SCREECHING, HORN BLARING)
We'll find her, Will.
(PHONE CHIMES)
Just posted on the George
Washington Bridge.
She's waving. She's doing
it on purpose!
Head uptown, Gil.
There she is!
STACKS: Don't lose them.
(HANNIGAN SCREAMING)
On an Annie blog! She's heading
to the State Park.
STACKS: They're
headed into the park.
Gilbert, don't make me come
up there and fly this helicopter.
There they are!
Annie! Annie! Annie!
I don't think she can hear you.
(SIREN WAILING)
What? It's the cops.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Oh, no. It's Stacks.
Why would he be following us?
(SIRENS WAILING)
Watch it! Whoa!
Watch out!
Annie! (WEAKLY)
Annie.
(RETCHING)
Gil, let's land this!
Cut them off.
(WEAKLY)
I really hope we find Annie soon.
No! (TIRES SCREECH)
Annie!
Get them!
OFFICER: NYPD, hold it!
STACKS: Annie!
Annie, are you okay?
I'm fine. We even now?
What? Want another photo?
(CAMERAS CLICKING)
It's not like that, honey.
It's exactly like that.
You don't care about me.
I was just an opportunity to you.
No, that's not true. It is true.
You did all this to me so
you could be stupid mayor!
No... Listen, you
gotta trust me!
I can't trust you.
I can't trust anybody!
No! Just let me go!
Listen, I'm sorry
for what happened to you.
I can't look you in the eye
and tell you that I didn't know
that something was going on.
But I did not know that those
people weren't your parents.
You gotta believe me.
This is you, Annie.
It's you.
REPORTER: Oh, wait, wait.
Sir! Sir. (CAMERAS CLICKING)
I officially withdraw
from this mayoral race.
I think that this city deserves
someone better than I am.
I wanna take time
out to concentrate
on things that really
matter to me the most,
and that's this amazing
little girl, Annie.
Because...
Oh, It's kind of dusty.
(SNIFFLES)
No, it's not dusty.
I'm crying.
(VOICE BREAKS)
That's my family.
Thank you.
(REPORTERS CLAMORING)
I need one more thing from you.
You are always on the hustle.
What is it now?
Stop playing games.
Oh, yeah, I got this.
You all right?
I'm fine.
Grace, listen, I've always
had a problem
with realizing what's right
in front of me,
and, well, I'm learning.
Would you like to go
out to dinner with me?
What?
I mean, without you,
I can't function.
That just doesn't
mean work either.
You're right about everything.
You're right about the phone,
you're right about Guy,
you're right about this
mayoral race,
right about the wind...
Oh, shut up!
Ooh! (GIRLS LAUGHING)
(LAUGHS)
Together at last!
Together forever!
We're tying a knot.
They never can sever!
I don't need sunshine now
To turn my skies to blue
I don't need anything but you!
You've wrapped me around.
That cute little finger.
You've made life a song.
You made me a singer, oh!
You're not warm and fuzzy.
And ain't the most shyest girl.
But nothing on Earth
But nothing on Earth.
Could ever divide us!
Today was terrible.
Today was a straight-up
nightmare.
But that was then
But that was then.
'Cause I was looking
for something.
Looking for my loose end
Looking for my loose end.
Now I don't need
anything but you.
But that was then
I was looking for something
I was looking for something.
Looking for my loose end
Looking for my loose end.
Now I don't need
anything but you.
But nothing on Earth
But nothing on Earth.
Could ever divide us!
But nothing on Earth
But nothing on Earth.
Could ever divide us!
But nothing on Earth
But nothing on Earth.
Could ever divide us!
But nothing on Earth
But nothing on Earth.
Could ever divide us!
Yeah, all right.
Everybody dance now.
No, no. It's their thing, mami.
Together at last!
Together forever!
We're tying a knot.
They never can sever!
You're two of a kind.
The happiest pair now.
Like bright shooting stars.
You're floating on air now.
And what's the title of the dream
that just came true?
I don't need anything.
Anything
I don't need anything but you.
Keeps singing
and dancing like that,
there's no way
he was ever gonna win.
ANNIE: "The city is full of opportunity.
It's yours to take."
"The sun will come
out tomorrow."
(CROWD CHEERING, MARCHING BAND PLAYING)
The sun'll come out tomorrow.
Bet your bottom
dollar that tomorrow.
There'll be sun.
Just thinkin' about tomorrow.
Clears away the cobwebs
and the sorrow.
'Til there's none.
When I'm stuck with a day.
That's gray, and lonely
I just stick
out my chin and grin.
And say.
The sun'll come out tomorrow.
So you gotta hang
on 'til tomorrow.
Come what may.
Tomorrow, tomorrow!
But nothing on Earth
I love you, tomorrow!
Could ever divide us.
You're always a day away!
But nothing on Earth.
Could ever divide us.
Tomorrow!
But nothing on Earth Tomorrow!
Could ever divide us
I love you, tomorrow.
You're always a day.
Away!
To-To-To-To-Tomorrow
Tomorrow is a day away.
(MUSIC STOPS)
Yeah!
(CHUCKLES)
ALL: Whoo!
Hey, America Let's turn it up.
Yeah, check out our style.
'Cause you know you're never
fully dressed without a smile.
Your clothes may
be Chanel, Gucci.
Your shoes crocodile.
But baby, you're never
fully dressed without a...
(SCATTING)
But if you stand for nothing,
you'll fall for it all.
We got all we need,
got love and more.
You're never fully
dressed without a smile.
And if you stand for something,
you can have it all.
'Cause if it's real,
you'll open every door.
You're never fully
dressed without a smile.
Oh.
You're never fully
dressed without a smile.
It's the hard-knock life for us!
'Steada treated We get tricked!
'Steada kisses We get kicked!
It's the hard-knock life.
Don't it feel like the wind
is always howling?
Don't it seem
like there's never any light?
Once a day don't you wanna
throw the towel in?
It's easier than puttin'
up a fight.
No one's there when your
dreams at night get creepy!
No one cares if you
grow or if you shrink!
Empty belly life!
Rotten smelly life!
Full of sorrow life!
No tomorrow life!
Santa Claus we never see
Santa Claus What's that?
Who's he?
No one cares for you a bit.
When you're a foster kid!
It's the hard-knock life!
It's the hard-knock life for us.
Yank the whiskers from her chin.
It's the hard-knock life for us
Jab her with a safety pin.
'Steada treated, we get tricked
Send her to the loony bin.
'Steada kisses, we get kicked.
It's the hard-knock life for us.
Yank the whiskers from her chin.
It's the hard-knock life for us
Jab her with a safety pin.
No one cares for you a bit
Send her to the loony bin.
When you're a foster kid!
It's the hard-knock life.
She's a fish and he's a boy.
Moonquake, moonquake
I want to take
a swim in Lake Moon.
Now I am awake, awake.
Since I dove into your blue.
Moonquake, moonquake
I want to take
a swim in Lake Moon.
Now I am awake, awake.
Since I dove into your blue.
She came from the Moon
ready to fight.
Nah-nah-nah-nah Nah-nah-nah.
With scales and a tail
and a fishy bite.
Nah-nah-nah-nah Nah-nah-nah.
Ready to destroy
all of humankind.
Nah-nah-nah-nah Nah-nah-nah.
Fierce and fighting
with a brook trout mind.
Nah-nah-nah-nah Nah-nah-nah.
He was born in above the earth.
Strong in legend,
my soul's in mirth.
Nah-nah-nah-nah Nah-nah-nah.
Son of a mom and a bee farmer.
With just a smile for a sweet...
Nah-nah-nah-nah Nah-nah-nah.
They were never meant to meet.
But fate didn't listen.
They were never meant to be.
Oh, it never does.
They were never meant to see.
It didn't listen.
They were never...
She's a fish and he's a boy.
Moonquake, moonquake
I want to take
a swim in Lake Moon.
Now I am awake, awake.
Since I dove into your blue.
Moonquake, moonquake
I want to catch you in my net.
Now I am awake, awake.
Like the day we never met.
They met one solstice
at a fishing hole.
Nah-nah-nah-nah Nah-nah-nah.
He was unsure casting his pole.
She swam right up to him
and took the bait.
Nah-nah-nah-nah Nah-nah-nah.
He reeled her
in and made it a date.
Nah-nah-nah-nah Nah-nah-nah.
When your words are worn
and you look inside.
Nah-nah-nah-nah Nah-nah-nah.
Fight the power,
stop the divide.
Nah-nah-nah-nah Nah-nah-nah.
Four eyes, two gills,
one human nose.
Nah-nah-nah-nah Nah-nah-nah.
Wrap your arms around me
and then lean in close.
Nah-nah-nah-nah Nah-nah-nah.
You'll have clothes.
Moonquake, moonquake
I want to take
a swim in Lake Moon.
Now I am awake, awake.
Since I dove into your blue.
Moonquake, moonquake
I want to catch you in my net.
Now I am awake, awake.
Like the day we never met.
Moonquake, moonquake.
Moonquake.
Nah-nah-nah-nah
Nah-nah-nah Moonquake...
(RASPY SCREECHING IN MOVIE)
You do you, Saffron! (CHUCKLES)
That's what I'm talking about.
Nah-nah-nah-nah Nah-nah-nah
http://subscene.com/u/659433
Improved by: @Ivandrofly