Okay, 118, I want ladders up, ventilation,
inch-and-three-quarter
hose line. Let's go!
Hoses out! Let's get that water flowing!
Ladders. Come on, let's go, let's go!
Let's do it!
My god! No!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa! Sir! Sir!
- My god!
My wife and my son, are they okay?
- How old is your son?
- He's 11 months old.
There's a nursery on the
second floor on the right.
Okay, we will get them
out of there. Officer.
Come here, sir.
Kinard, han, Wilson, double time!
We got people inside!
On it!
Let's go! Let's go!
Lafd! Can anyone hear me?
Upstairs! Let's go!
We can't wait for that hose line!
Ma'am?
Ma'am.
Hen, chim, get up here right now.
Ma'am, can you hear me?
Micah.
Micah? Where's Micah?
- The nursery.
- The nursery, okay.
Let's get her up and
let's get her out. Let's go.
- Where's that hose line?
- -It's on its way, cap.
We can't wait! Let's go, Tommy!
Cap, wait!
And this is north remembrance hall.
In addition to our
outdoor interment spaces,
we also have four mausoleum halls,
as well as three indoor columbaria.
We have several vaults available
in east hall, if you prefer,
but I've always liked the morning light
in here. The halls are
all climate controlled
and open to visitors
8:00 A.M. to 6:00 P.M.,
362 days a year.
- Mom?
- We offer a floral placement service.
Some families choose to
have their flowers placed
on birthdays or holidays,
others on a more frequent basis.
The families don't come themselves?
Some do, but life has a way of filling
all the nooks and
crannies of our calendars.
I just... Don't think it's right.
I don't think my husband
would want to be inside.
Appreciate your time, Mr. Powell,
but I think we need
to find someplace else.
Mom, it's been almost two weeks.
At some point, we're gonna
have to have a funeral.
Yeah, tell that to the federal,
state and local authorities.
They still haven't released his body.
But they will eventually,
and we have to be ready.
And we will be.
We just need... To find the right place.
Maybe this is them, now.
Hello?
Um, I'm sorry.
I'm going to need you to
explain that to me again.
No.
I did not authorize that.
Did the kids leave already?
They got a lift to school with the Martins.
I... Wanted to make you breakfast.
I mean, thank you.
It's your first day back at work.
A week earlier than your
doctor recommended.
It'll be light duty.
Don't worry, I'm not
looking to pop any stitches.
I can't believe they're asking you back
before Bobby's even... in the ground?
It just
- seems wrong.
- Everything about this is wrong.
So, take the extra five days.
The boys are all coming back today, too.
I have to be there.
Okay.
Hey, hey, guys?
Buck?
Hey.
Is-is chimney ready?
He said we would drive
in together this morning.
First day back.
No, he's not here.
- He's not?
- He left before I woke up,
and when I texted him,
he said there was something
that he had to do before work.
Wait, he didn't tell you?
No. I-I... Feel like
he's not been telling me
a lot of things lately.
I think he might be avoiding me.
Yeah, he's been avoiding everyone.
Did he tell you that he's started running,
like, as a hobby?
Really?
I thought he hated running.
Well, now it's like his
favorite thing to do.
He said that it helps clear his mind.
I think it helps him
avoid talking to anyone.
He's talking to the
counselors, though, right?
He's been doing his sessions.
I don't know that he's
actually been talking to them.
What about you?
Yeah, well, I've done a
lot of therapy at this point.
Pretty good at it.
Okay...
What's this for?
Because I love you,
and given recent events,
I feel like that's something
that I should start saying more.
Yeah.
I love you, too.
Did you do this?
- I got a call from downtown.
- Athena
apparently, one of
captain Nash's firefighters
has been burning up the lines,
complaining about why it's taken so long
to release his remains. Was it you?
Yeah, but, I mean... it was
not your place to interfere.
I was just trying to help.
I didn't think it was right
they were making you
wait so long to Bury him.
Right, because until he's in the ground,
nobody gets to move on.
They have to live yet another day
thinking about Bobby and how he died.
Athena, no one's ever
gonna forget about what cap
did that day, least of all me.
Athena...
Well, congratulations, it worked.
Funeral's next Tuesday.
- Sorry.
- You're fine.
I might've come in the wrong
door. Is there a right door?
Depends. Who are you looking for?
Captain Bobby Nash.
Why are you looking for captain Nash?
I was hoping he could help
me keep my sister out of prison.
There you go.
- Enjoy. -Thank you.
- Thank you.
I'm sorry about your husband.
I hadn't heard the news, otherwise
I wouldn't have shown up like that.
You said your sister was in jail.
Why was she arrested?
Stalking, breaking and
entering, attempted kidnapping.
Who was her intended victim?
Her dead son.
Who she has become convinced
is not dead, but living in Santa clarita.
My nephew Micah died
eight years ago in a house fire.
Leah was there when the fire broke out.
She couldn't get to him,
and by the time the firefighters got there,
it was too late.
My husband's fire company.
That's right.
After that, Leah's marriage fell apart.
She couldn't hold a job.
Some days, she could
barely get out of bed.
Basically, all the terrible things
you think would happen to someone
after the worst thing
imaginable happens to them.
So, I got her a job.
I own a catering company.
Found her a place to live, and
it took time, but slowly,
she began to put her life back together.
And then what happened?
A few weeks ago, we were on a job,
a birthday party for a nine-year-old boy.
He would've been the
same age as your nephew.
Same birthday.
Look, as soon as I realized,
I tried to send Leah
home, but she insisted
that I was being silly,
that she could handle it.
And four days later,
she's calling me from jail.
She has become convinced
that this boy is her son
and that he was stolen
from her by this other mother.
And I've tried to reason with her,
but she just says, "Gary,
you don't understand.
You weren't there that night."
So you went looking for someone
who was there that night.
I don't know what I expected him to do.
Maybe I'm just desperate.
She won't listen to me.
And I thought maybe, just maybe,
she would listen to him.
Do you think she might listen to me?
First, I'd like to start by
offering my condolences.
Words cannot express how sorry I am.
The lafd lost an exceptional firefighter,
and we all lost an exceptional person.
I'm not here to take
his place. No one can.
And I'm not gonna be
returning as your captain.
I'm just here to get you
through this difficult transition
until chief Simpson can
appoint a candidate more worthy.
My goal
is to keep things running
smoothly while I'm here
and to support you in this difficult time.
I know that whatever I say isn't
gonna make any of this better.
But I would like to say a
few words about captain Nash
and what he meant to me personally.
Right.
One of these.
I want co2 and a hand
line on that engine.
Buckley, kill the batteries,
stabilize the vehicles
and start extrication.
- Yeah.
- Wilson, you get her.
Han, you get... Him.
Thanks. That was getting annoying.
Lafd, sir. Is your seat belt jammed?
Yeah. This crazy lady
came out of nowhere.
That jerk blew through the red light.
Ma'am, were you unconscious?
No, but I might black out from rage.
Does your neck hurt at all?
Nope.
Sir, I need to check your pupils. Sir?
I bet she was on her phone.
Yeah, you can see here
where she totally smashed my grille.
Sir, I really need to examine you,
especially because
you seem very litigious.
Sir?
Here we are.
Wow, first he t-bones me, now he's tmz.
Smile. Tell the camera why you did it.
Excuse me? You're the one who hit me.
Let the record show
this was not my fault.
Are you kidding?
This is 100% your fault.
That's your car, that's her car
and that's a "t" that you boned.
This is all your fault.
Whoa.
So, if you'll kindly sit your ass down,
I can check you for a head injury,
make sure you don't bleed out and die.
Han, a word.
Yeah, that's right. Yeah.
What, you gonna give me
a lecture on comportment?
No, a chance to cool off.
You mean a time out. No, thanks!
I'll just scrub the crapper.
I know you're hurting. I am, too.
You know, you shouldn't even be here?
What right do you have to run
the 118? You are not half
the man that Bobby was.
Be that as it may, I am your captain.
Only because I killed our last one,
so I'd be very careful if I was you.
Hello, Leah.
Um... Thank you for
agreeing to talk to me.
My name is Athena.
Gary told me you were coming.
He said you're a police officer.
That's not why I'm here.
Gary said you're captain Nash's widow.
Yes.
I'm so sorry. He was a good man.
He was.
Leah, your brother, he's
very worried about you.
Well, he thinks I'm crazy. I'm not crazy.
I just did what any
mother would've done.
Probably went about
it the wrong way, but...
Can you tell me about this boy?
- Micah.
- The police report,
they say that his name
is Cameron Myers.
Well, of course the
police report says that
because that's what
she's been calling him,
but my son's name is Micah.
And why do you think
that this boy is your son?
I wasn't certain at first.
I mean, I kept telling myself,
"you must be imagining things."
Excuse me? Do you
have any more bags?
He looked so much like Micah.
I couldn't catch my breath for a moment.
And then I asked him his name.
What's your name?
I'm Cameron.
It's my little boy's birthday today, too.
How old is he?
Nine, just like you.
I would've chalked the whole thing up
to some crazy coincidence
until I handed him the bag
and I saw the birthmark.
This tiny little heart on
the inside of his wrist.
I kissed that birthmark every night
when I put Micah to bed.
I used to tell him it
connected his heart to mine,
and that it meant that,
no matter where he went,
he would always carry my love with him.
And that's when you knew for sure?
That's when I allowed for the possibility.
And I kept saying to
myself, "you're crazy."
"This can't be real.
I mean, you don't even
know these people."
But turns out I did.
You recognized her?
Prenatal yoga.
9:00 A.M., Tuesdays and Fridays.
You were in prenatal
yoga class together?
Yes, until she stopped attending.
I remember some of
the other mothers saying
they'd heard her
pregnancy ran into trouble
and that she'd lost the baby.
And that's when you began to think
that she went after yours.
I mean, I've heard stories of women
so desperate to have a baby
they'll even cut one
out of another woman.
So, how much easier...
wait till the baby's born,
steal him from his crib... Start a fire.
Exactly.
If you're desperate
enough, you'll do things
you never thought you
were capable of doing.
You got this!
Whoo! Come on, honey!
That's my son.
I'll race him, though you're
not coming back from that.
No recovery.
Cameron.
Hi.
I'm Leah.
Your mom asked me to pick you up.
Mom says I'm not supposed
to go with strangers.
Sweetie, I'm not a stranger.
I was at your birthday party, remember?
Yeah.
I'd love you to meet my son.
Come on.
- Excuse me! Cameron?
- Come on, honey.
- What are you doing?
- It's okay, honey.
Mom?
- Come here, sweetie.
- Cameron. Who are you?
It's Leah.
Okay, honey, stay here.
Your name is Micah.
Okay? You're my son,
- not hers.
- Mom, mom, what's she talking about?
Honey, I don't know. She's crazy.
- Help!
- You stole my son!
- Sir!
- Don't let her leave.
This psycho tried to abduct my child!
- Micah!
- I'm calling 911.
Don't be scared, baby. Don't be scared.
- Hey. Just calm down.
- She stole my son!
I know what I did was
reckless and stupid.
But I'm not wrong.
I thought I buried my son.
But I didn't.
He's alive.
You think I'm crazy?
No.
And I promise you this.
That if your son is alive,
I'll bring him back to you.
I swear it.
She posted every single day
until march 17.
And then, not again until may 9.
That's six weeks missing.
So... Maybe she did lose her baby,
but not before he was born.
Are you gonna start a podcast?
I think I almost got it figured out.
Something happened
to Heather's baby within these six weeks.
Her not posting things
on the Internet isn't quite
the evidentiary bombshell
that you seem to think it is.
Well, even after she
started posting again,
things were different.
The cute matching outfits were gone,
no more daily photo shoots
and she stopped showing his face.
Well, maybe she
realized that the Internet
was full of "creepy-ass stalkers."
I'm quoting you, -in
case you don't remember.
Look,
if you are not going to be helpful,
go haunt someone else. I'm busy.
Aren't you supposed to be
busy planning my funeral?
I heard it's gonna be big.
Yeah, a hero's burial.
That's what the chief calls it.
They already got a
template they can follow,
they don't need me.
But this woman does?
Helping her is so important
that you're hiding in here,
racking up 11 missed phone calls
and 42 unread texts?
You're the one who locked
himself in a lab to die.
You don't get to tell me
how to spend my time.
Ouch.
This woman, her loss,
it was important to you.
You would've helped her.
I'm doing it because you can't.
- How can you know that?
- I know you.
You knew me.
Past tense.
Hi.
Hey.
I don't see jee. What time is it?
She went down about half an hour ago.
Hey, you've been gone for a while.
Did you go for another run?
No.
I tried out that new yoga studio.
You know, they've got this
yoga for runners program.
Great. So, another hobby
that will keep you out of
the house for hours at a time.
That's not what I'm doing, Maddie.
You're shutting me out,
which is the one thing
that we promised each
other we would not do.
And please don't insult my intelligence
by pretending like that's
not what's happening.
- Running just...
- Helps me to... -not think?
Chim, that's the thing about running.
There's never gonna
be anywhere far enough.
You carry the pain with
you, and eventually, it...
Takes you down.
I think maybe it already did.
And I'm not trying to shut you out.
I'm just trying to figure out
how to get back up on my feet, that's all.
It's 8:07 A.M.,
and we are exhuming the
grave of Micah Hamilton
in order to obtain a DNA sample.
Okay, I'm going to go check on the doc.
You keep recording.
Got it, sergeant.
I got it. Gary, what are you doing here?
I came to put an end to this insanity.
- Wh...
- you're digging up a baby's grave?
Gary, it's the only way
that we can be sure.
No, I am sure.
My sister's crazy.
Clearly, it is contagious.
I'm gonna put an end to this.
Stop, stop. No, this
is my nephew's casket.
- Sir...
- I don't consent to this.
I'm very sorry for your loss
but I've been hired by the child's mother.
Please, let me do my job.
No, you don't understand
- what you're doing.
- Gary, you really
shouldn't be here for this part.
I can call you with the results.
There aren't going to be any results.
What?
The casket is... empty.
We didn't know how to tell my sister.
The fire, it just...
There was nothing left to Bury.
Are you okay?
Henrietta?
What the hell?
What are you doing
skulking around my house?
I'm checking on you, Athena.
I guess chimney asked you to do this?
You got to check up on the little widow.
Your kids, actually.
You haven't been
returning their phone calls,
their text messages.
The chief's office said that you haven't
finalized any of the plans for the funeral.
And then I come here and... And what?
I mean, should I start with
the air mattress in the corner and
or the wall of crazy over here?
I was helping this woman.
Leah.
She lost her baby in a
house fire eight years ago.
She thought that the
fire might have been
a cover for the real crime.
A kidnapping.
They stole her baby and
then set the house on fire?
I figured we start by
proving that the baby
that Leah buried wasn't hers,
so we exhumed the
grave, and it was empty.
Yeah, just some sandbags...
And a baby picture.
That is sad.
But not a huge surprise.
I mean, a fire so hot
and a... a baby so small?
I'm surprised the mother
didn't say something
before the exhumation.
She didn't know.
Her brother and her husband,
they decided without consulting her.
Because it would just
upset her even more.
So they decided,
because they knew best.
I mean, who does that?
If you love someone,
you're honest with them.
You respect them.
You trust that they can
make the hard decisions.
You don't just blindside
them and then take off!
You don't leave them to
deal with the-the-the mess!
Alone!
Athena... He's not
supposed to be dead, hen.
He stood here in this
kitchen that morning,
planning our future.
And then he just... Left?
He left me.
He didn't want to.
And he did anyway!
Hello?
Hi.
Is your mom home?
Mom, it's for you!
Gary said you exhumed the grave.
He was so mad I gave you permission.
It wasn't my son in there, was it?
No.
I knew it.
Leah?
There was nothing.
Just an empty casket.
With a photo of your beautiful baby.
Evidently, after the
fire, there was nothing
- left to Bury.
- No.
There was nothing there
because my son isn't dead.
He didn't die in a fire.
That woman has him.
I have DNA test results here.
There was a match.
A match to what?
You said there was nothing there.
Not to what we didn't
find in Micah's grave.
These are DNA results
from buccal swabs
taken from Cameron Myers
and his mother, Heather Myers.
I went to them, explained the situation,
and she agreed to it.
We tested Cameron, his DNA,
against your sample and hers.
Hers... Was a match.
That little boy is her son.
Micah... Is gone.
I'm so sorry.
But I was so sure.
When I saw him, I was
sure, I... I felt it, I felt him.
You think I imagined all of it.
I think that you were overcome by grief.
For a moment, you
let yourself believe that
miracles were possible.
I feel like I'm losing him all over again.
The district attorney,
he's willing to consider
a diversion program.
If you comply, your
charges could be dismissed.
And you could get back to your life.
What life?
Leah, you've lost a lot, but
you haven't lost everything.
I can see why he loved you.
I'm sorry he's gone.
He was a special person.
I want to say how
sorry I am for your loss.
I know how enormous the
pain of losing a child can be.
Really?
How many children have you lost?
Two.
- I'm sorry.
- You don't have to apologize.
I'm the man who was supposed
to save your son and I didn't.
You don't owe me anything.
What were their names?
Robert and brook.
11 and nine.
My baby was Micah.
That's a nice name, I will pray for him.
Thank you.
Can I ask you something?
Yeah, sure.
How do you keep going?
How... I.
I live in the belief that one
day I will see them again.
And you really believe it?
With all my heart.
I do.
Hello? Is someone there?
It's just us.
What are you doing here?
We bumped into Mrs.
Anderson at the grocery store.
And she asked us why no one
told her that we'd moved back in.
Yeah, but don't worry.
We covered for you.
Come here.
Now, what's for dinner?
Well...
We have breakfast.
And we also brought some sleeping bags
so we can stay with you.
Like the way we used to
camp out in the backyard.
You would do that?
Mom, we love you.
Even more than running water.
And I love you, too.
And, um... After dinner, I can,
I can show you some photos
of the place that I found for Bobby.
- You found a place?
- Yeah.
I think it's perfect.
Hey, it's not locked.
You know I'm not a
probie anymore, right?
Yeah.
Then why am I still picking
up your dry cleaning?
Because I had to go to the
airport and pick up this one.
Good to see you, rav.
It's great to see you, too, man.
I wish it were under
different circumstances.
Yeah.
We all do.
I should've been there.
Hey.
You're here now.
Help.
Hen?
The, purse.
Clutch.
- I don't know.
- Come here.
You're okay.
That looks good.
What is that?
I think it's a crumpet.
There's plenty. You want one?
Nah, I'd probably just end up wearing it.
You know, I've never
done one of these before.
I mean, you were in the military, too.
Guess you've done a lot of 'em?
Not like this.
Okay.
You ready?
As we'll ever be.
Hey, Maddie.
Yeah, yeah, no, that-that's fine.
I will.
Hey, Ravi, do you mind
driving Eddie to the church?
I'll meet you guys there.
- Everything okay?
- Yeah, I just,
I have to pick something
up for the service.
This is a private party, Buckley, go away.
I can't do that.
Made a promise to a pregnant lady.
Yeah? Well, I'm guessing
she's getting pretty used
to broken promises these days.
Come on, chim.
Put down the drink and let's go.
We're gonna be late.
To my own funeral?
No, wait.
Not my funeral.
Just should have been.
That's not fair.
No one blames you.
Hey.
I don't blame me, either.
I blame him.
Bobby had no right
to keep us in the dark.
He just decided for everyone
how things were gonna go.
And I kind of hate him for that.
You don't mean that.
Yeah, buck, I do.
He should have told us the truth.
It wouldn't have changed anything.
It might have.
There's always the third option, buck.
You know, when you're out
in the field and you only have
two bad options to choose
from, you do not accept that.
You do not let those be the only
two crappy options available.
You always find the third way.
You know who taught us that?
Yeah, Bobby did.
And we always did that,
time after time after time.
We never gave up.
We always found a third way.
And we always did it together.
And you think there was a third way?
I spent the last two
weeks thinking on it.
I came up with nothing.
Buck, he gave his life so I could live.
I'm just not sure what I'm
supposed to do with that.
I think you're just supposed to live.
Yeah.
Of all the days
this is the one you choose
to leave me to go it alone.
On this day, we gather here
to celebrate the life and legacy
of captain Robert Wade Nash.
A day filled with heaviness
that weighs on us all
as we gather in this sacred space.
A day marked by
gratitude for the life we lost
and the many lives saved.
As we reflect on his service,
we remember the
countless lives he touched,
the friendships he forged
and the sacrifices he made.
Captain Nash was
more than a firefighter.
He was a mentor.
A husband. A father.
And for so many of us, a beloved friend.
There are many
traditions in the fire service.
Among those traditions
is the sound of a bell.
It was the bell
that signaled the
beginning of that day's shift.
Each alarm was sounded by a bell
which summoned these brave
souls to put their lives on the line
for the good of others.
And when the alarm had
come to an end, it was a bell
that signaled the completion of that call.
When a firefighter
fell in the line of duty,
an officer would tap out a special signal:
Ten bells.
This signal would be
heard by all station houses,
notifying them of the
passing of one of their own.
It is customary and
fitting that the final alarm
be sounded for our brother,
captain Robert Wade Nash.
He has completed his
duties... a job well done
and has now returned home.
Uniformed personnel, please stand.
Atten-hut!
Present arms.
Order arms.
Rest easy.
You're home now, baby.
You're home.