I don't know if you can hear me.
I got to admit, you freaked me out before.
I didn't understand you...
...but I get it now.
Come on, man, talk to me.
I know everything about you.
I'm a fan.
Your name is James Patrick March.
You were born October 30th, 1895.
You're a Scorpio...
...which explains a lot.
You're the greatest serial killer
who's ever lived.
How do you know all this?
I Googled you.
That sounds obscene.
You were right, man.
Killing is awesome.
High five!
Good. You've found your calling.
Then you can appreciate
what I've built here.
Secret rooms, hinged walls,
acid pits, asphyxiation chambers.
Are you familiar with my black closet?
Yes.
There are places in my murder palace
that have sat in cold neglect for far too long.
You can put them to good use, old boy.
I'm listening.
Good.
Now--
- My God, look at this.
The whole floor needs to be torn out.
This space is perfect for my atelier.
It's gonna be sensational.
And wait until you see this room.
What are you doing here?
Visiting a friend.
I was told that nobody lives
on this floor.
You're a squatter.
Tristan, you clean up pretty well.
I barely recognized you.
Thank you, Claudia.
What happened to your cut?
Get your paws off.
I'm not here to be a deposit
in your spank bank.
Heh, heh. Owned, Dad.
Get out. I'll call the cops
if I see you in my hotel again.
Models.
Tear this floor out?
Where will I launder the linens?
He can't be allowed
to touch a single room.
Don't worry, dude.
I got this.
It's hard to believe now...
"but raising kids was nave: a part
of my hopes and dreams.
My friends with babies
only made me more resistant.
Their lives seemed kind of dreary,
to be honest.
I wanted 10 save kids...
mother people's kids.
h' Pm honest...
...being the best pediatrician possible
was my only real dream.
Okay,
We're gonna get you to the hospital...
...put you on a big fat IV of antibiotics.
Okay?
We just need his slippers
and his coat.
Wait, wait, wait. Hospital?
This kind of pneumonia,
the one we associate with the measles...
...is something we like to treat...
...aggressively.
I don't understand why you didn't call me
the second his fever went over 103.
I guess I just felt ashamed.
After our last conversation,
you made me feel pretty terrible.
Please just tell me
he's gonna be all right.
I hope so. Upstairs.
By the way, I'm not unaware
of the obvious cliche' here.
§ wanted to save kids
because I felt I needed saving.
Bu! in my case the cliche' is dead-on.
Suffice it to say,
mine was not a happy childhood.
Then Holden showed up.
It was a tectonic shift...
...where everything I thought
I knew about myself got rearranged.
It was like I finally fell in love for real.
All the cracks and missing pieces
came together.
I felt whole.
I'd found my sou! mate.
I couldn't stop smelling his head.
It made me feel drowsy and giddy.
Like we were in the middle of a lavender field
in the south of France.
The smell was real.
He truly smelled like fresh lavender.
It was and always will be my drug of choice.
I even wondered if I truly loved John...
...because my feelings for him were never
as powerful as my feelings for Holden.
And I've always felt guilty.
Because I never quite bonded
like that with Scarlett when she was a baby.
It was a special kind of love.
Maybe a once-in-a-lifetime thing.
And then he disappeared.
Holden!
Holden.
At first, every time you hear the phone,
you think they've found him.
Your hear! pounds.
Hello'?
Then after a month or so...
...the phone is just the phone.
You do whatever you need to do
to soldier on.
Because you tell yourself...
"lime is on your side,.
And then a year has gone by
and you understand...
...that the next year
will not be much different.
This feeling will never go away.
Because there is no getting over it.
There is no getting to the other side.
I do carry on.
Mostly for Scarlett.
But there are many days
when I don't really know why.
Same days are bearable.
Today is very hard.
Alex?
Are you with us?
We haven't heard a lot from you, Alex.
I don't know what to say.
I'm afraid the truth about how I'm feeling
wouldn't be very helpful.
This is the right place
for you to speak your truth.
And the right time.
Honestly, I'm angry.
I mean, I don'! understand, Scarlett.
It's like...
...you're trying to hurt me.
Us.
I don't have the sense
that Scarlett holds any ill will.
Her stories strike me as being more about
wanting to alleviate your pain.
Wanting the family whole again.
You're both wrong.
It's not about my mother or the family.
It's what happened.
Scarlett.
Tell us the story
exactly how you remember it.
Tell us everything.
Well, there's a room
where they all play Nintendo...
...and there are these big glass things
full of jelly beans.
That sounds like a fun place.
And he sleeps in the bottom...
...of a glass coffin.
In the bottom of an empty swimming pool.
That's when I first saw him.
He was just waking up.
And when you first saw him...
...what did he say exactly?
Does he talk about us?
No, he was different.
He didn't have normal feelings.
And he smelt like...
...lavender.
You know, like those candles
we have at home.
Yes, dear.
Yes, the change of scenery
was good for Will.
He was getting too stale in New York.
Yes, Jess.
I'm losing you.
Can you hear me?
Claudia, Claudia--
Jess.
We need to get Mario Testino out here
to do a shoot.
Did you hear that? Jess?
Oh, darn.
No! No!
Help me! No!
I got the guys checking on
Islamic terrorist groups active in the area.
You know...
...this could be another Charlie Heb-do thing.
This is a gossip site.
He stopped their tongues from wagging.
Thou shalt not bear false witness.
These people trafficked in lies.
They broke the commandment.
Have Ballistics run a check
on the casings at the scene...
- ...with casings from previous murders.
- All?
- Yeah, all of them.
- Gotcha.
There may be a commandment murder
we missed.
We'll cross-reference.
I'm not sure, but--
Help me.
Boo!
How the hell did you get in here?
I picked the lock.
When I was first starting out modeling,
I made extra scratch as a thief.
I'm not the waiting-tables type.
I did six months for breaking-and-entering.
Did you know that?
Look, I'm sorry about the show.
I'm clean now, I swear.
You and I used to get along great
when I was clean.
You thought I was hilarious.
Every beautiful young thing is hilarious.
And then you get old and you don't understand
why everyone isn't still laughing at your jokes.
How did they fix that scan'?
I'll show you mine if you show me yours.
What are those?
They're the original plans for the hotel.
They're the ones that are registered
with the city, but not the plans for this hotel.
How do you know?
Well, for one thing, there's that hallway
on three with no doors that goes nowhere.
And according to these plans, there's rooms
off of them and access to the stairwell.
So I think somebody submitted
these plans...
...to get through inspection
then just built how they wanted to.
Man, you smell good.
You know, that's actually the worst part
about being in jail.
It's not the food...
...or being locked up like a dog.
It's the smell.
Everyone smells like shit.
Doesn't stop you from doing stuff,
though, you know?
A man has needs, right?
What is this? What is happening?
What are you doing?
Stay.
Another time.
What?
Son of a--
Looking at an OD here?
You'd think, but everything's
telling me withdrawal.
I don't think he's had a needle in him
in a few days, at least.
The blood?
Not his.
Let's get him sedated.
No! Please! I'm sorry, I didn't mean it!
Wait. Wait.
Please. I'm sorry.
Why are you sorry?
Detective.
I didn't mean to kill her.
Wait. Who did you kill?
I thought it was the other one.
- The junkie whore.
- Sally? Sally?
She did this to me.
She lied to me. She said that I'd be free.
Okay, gotta go. Gotta go!
We're losing him.
I hear she checked out.
Who did?
That shit-don't-stink fashion editor.
Guess this place wasn't up to her standards.
Not everyone can appreciate it here.
All this lovely darkness.
You know what I mean.
No. I really don't.
Why don't you tell me about your friend.
Which one?
The one at St. Vincent's.
Junkie, covered in blood, not his.
Oh, well, junkies...
...you can't believe a word they say.
Who was he?
How the hell should I know?
Why are you wasting your time on junkies?
We only hurt ourselves.
It's not like breaking
one of the Ten Commandments.
What did you say?
What?
Didn't you go to Sunday school?
How about thou shalt not kill?
Hm.
Well, that commandment
is always translated wrong.
It should be,
thou shalt not commit murder.
Killing can be a righteous act.
You've been in my room.
No.
But if that's an invitation...
How about this for an invitation?
You're under arrest.
Goody.
I know you sent me that text.
I don't know how deeply you're involved...
...or if you're working with someone,
or maybe you're just starved for attention.
I am starving.
You're starving too.
I can taste it on you.
Come on, detective...
...show me right from wrong.
I wanna help you.
I wish you could.
You'll see.
You and I...
...we're meant to be.
Hey, Dons.
I've been waiting for you.
Look, you need any help packing?
I printed out some Craigslist ads
for apartments for us.
Some nice two-bedrooms.
And this one.
This is-- Get this. This is the building
in Santa Monica...
...where they captured Whitey Bulger.
Look at it. It's glamorous, right?
I will live with the addicts in shitter's alley.
In a box in MacArthur Park...
...covered in the piss and shit
of this horror of a city...
...before I even consider living
under the same roof as you again.
You're a drama queen.
Baby, this is our chance.
This is what we've been waiting for.
Listen--
Don't touch me.
She never loved you.
She was just using you.
I knew that cold snake would get bored.
Not because of you.
You know,
because that's just how snakes are.
You really have no idea
how much I hate you, do you?
And I get that you never wanted to take
any authentic interest in me or my needs.
I have worked so hard over the past few years
to get you to notice how much I despise you.
Now, you hold on a minute.
I gave my life to you.
You have no clue how hard it was for me
to raise you and the sacrifices that I made.
Name one.
One that didn't serve
your perverted view of yourself.
Your father.
You think it was an easy choice,
kicking him out?
Becoming a single mother at that time?
Nobody did that.
But I did, because he was nowhere near
man enough to raise you.
My father was the best thing in my life.
I once hid in the trunk. of his Buick
and he made it to Bakersfield...
...before he noticed and took me back home.
Imagine that.
He didn't even know his own son
was in the trunk of his car.
The guy was an asshole.
He was a moron.
Do you know, when you kicked him out...
...he sat me down and asked me to promise
that when I was old enough, I would run away?
I had a plan.
Oh, she had a plan.
I went to an AA meeting once.
After I stood up and shared about you,
people came up to me.
Hardcore addicts,
and they were like:
"Wow, man. No wonder you use."
Every choice you made was a disaster.
Dad.
That insane vegetarian cult.
The Breatharians were cutting-edge.
They were using food as medicine.
I had so much fiber in my diet,
I shit my pants at school.
Fine.
You make a list...
...of all the ways I have failed you.
And you know what I say to your list?
Shit on it.
Because my list beats yours.
Item one...
...I gave you life.
Item two, I saved your life.
I wanted to die!
Coke, crack, heroin,
none of them could do it.
So I decided death was my only way
away from you. I chose it.
You hated me like that?
And you let me stay here
looking after you?
A real mother would have
let her son die in peace.
She would have buried me.
And grieved.
What mother wouldn't have wanted
her son to live?
Wouldn't have done
everything possible to save him?
You didn't bring me back for me.
You brought me back
for you.
I'm leaving here.
Tonight.
But...
...what am I supposed to do?
I don't know who I am
if I'm not your mother.
Honestly...
...if that is really true...
...you should kill yourself.
You should do it even if it isn't.
Oh...
Listen to the girl
As she takes on half the world
Moving up and so alive
in he: honey dripping
Beehive
R's good, so good, ifs so good, so good
Are you having some car trouble?
Picked a pretty shitty place for it.
These streets can be dangerous.
Hey.
I didn't mean to just show up like this.
I tried calling...
...I kept getting your voice-mail.
Yeah.
The service in here is pretty much shit.
Scotch.
Soda POP-
Am I interrupting something?
You're fidgety.
No. I'm just a little preoccupied
with the case.
You look terrible.
When's the last time you slept?
I'm fine, Alex.
You should get a real drink.
It's obvious you need one.
Why would you say that to me?
You're not in AA.
You don'! have a problem.
You need to give up
this obsession with control.
I need to stay sharp.
Well, you might need one in a minute.
Why?
What is this?
I don't expect you
to sign them right away.
I know you're gonna
wanna look them over.
No.
Alex, not now.
John, we have to.
For each other,
for our daughter.
I think this is why Scarlett is telling these
wild stories, because we haven't moved on.
No, I don't want a divorce.
I don't want a divorce, I never did.
I love you.
I love you too.
But it's not enough,
not anymore.
It's been rough with me out of the house--
It hasn't been rough.
It hasn't been rough at all.
It's been great.
I didn't think that I could do it,
but I can.
I don't think
you should come back.
It will just make things harder for everyone,
in the end, this is what we need to do.
Please.
Please, please,
don't tear this family apart.
I'm not the one tearing our family apart.
Someone else did that when they stole our son.
John.
Stay. Stay.
Somethings wrong with me.
I think I'm going crazy.
I feel like I've been seeing things.
Let's get you back to your room, okay?
I'm so sorry.
That's clumsy of me.
You never need to apologize for pouring
a glass of Chateau Margaux.
I was afraid you'd think
this was too much.
Oh, you mean the dress?
The night out on the town?
This nightcap?
You know I'm gay.
I'm not stupid.
We're destined for something much more...
...intimate.
What if I {Old you...
...Will Drake had to die?
Then you know the truth.
The well is dry.
Just yesterday, I drew a pair
of Bermudas in cannabis print.
So much for the West Coast influence.
I happen to think you're a genius.
But you've been comfortable
for far too long.
You need to burn...
...so you can rise from the ashes.
Kill Will.
You're giving me dangerous thoughts.
All great ideas are deadly.
I feel the same way with you
right now as I did...
...when I kissed my first man.
How many times
have you been with a woman'?
A few.
But they all ended...
...unfulfilled.
No danger in that tonight.
What is this shit?
Where did you get the balls
to eat out of my dish, man?
I'll call you later.
By the way...
...you're hard.
Mom swam
So that's it?
It's just over between us?
Don't be such a child.
What am I supposed to think?
I don't even get it. All he has is money.
Then you do get it.
What? You're rich.
I used to be.
And then I met Bernie.
Madoff was very good at
separating people from their money...
"because he'd make you beg
to give it to him.
All my rich friends got richer,
20 percent return even; year,.
But he wouldn't take mine,
not until he could get it all.
The stocks, the bonds, the hotel.
Bernie went to prison...
...and I lost everything.
So that's why you didn't want me
to kill Drake?
Will Drake can't die until after...
...I marry him...
...and take every goddamn penny.
Jesus Christ.
It's no wonder you're in such a state,
sleeping five feet away from all this.
I don't do much
sleeping anymore.
Which is why you're gonna take these.
Drink them down.
You don't have a fever.
You just need some rest.
A few hour's sleep,
and everything will be clearer.
Okay?
I'm so sorry, Alex.
I'm sorry I couldn't keep
our family together.
I'm sorry...
...that I couldn't bring
your boy back home to you.
I know.
It's not your fault.
I know how much you loved him.
More than me.
More than Scarlett.
John.
It's okay.
I never minded.
That's how I love you.
Let's have another baby.
Oh, Jesus.
What am I doing?
We still love each other.
The divorce papers are here.
If you have any questions,
just call the lawyer.
Is this hell?
No. If this were hell, I'd be the one in that
awful Zara knockoff that you're wearing.
Holden?
Hi, Mommy.
Oh, God. Get the lead out,
will you?
I'm terrified of needles.
I just want this over with.
First, you need to tell me
why I should be doing you this kindness...
...when I could just push you
right out that window.
Even things up.
Oh, come on.
You're not gonna torment me now.
I think it would be good for you
to talk about why you wanna die.
Entertain me with your self-loathing.
It's not about why die.
It's about...
...why continue to live.
I can't think of a single reason.
I guess
I'm just not lovable.
Now,
what's to say?
My own son hates me.
He always has.
You know, I see people
laughing and smiling.
And I cannot for the life of me...
...understand why.
I just don't get the joke anymore.
I am the joke.
Hang on.
We are going total bye-bye, right?
You swear you don't have
any unfinished business here?
Because I am stuck in this place,
thanks to you.
So I wanna be 100 percent sure
that when I do this, I am done...
...with your miserable old ass.
In other words...
...don't haunt my hallways, bitch.
I want nothing more...
...than the dark silence of death itself.
You've come to the right girl.
How many junkies did you feed on,
Donovan'! Heh, heh.
You're no good to anyone in this condition.
So I'm gonna clean you up,
get that poison out of your blood.
And then we'll see
if you can be of any use to me.
Who the hell are you?
Now, that's the wrong question.
What you should be asking is...
...who was I?
Somebody order room service?
I was the queen of them all.
No. We ordered hookers.
Get on your knees.
- I don't get on my knees for no man.
- Cut.
Check the gate.
Ooh.
That looked good.
Ha-ha-ha.
I had come to Hollywood with barely
a high school education and no prospects.
It wasn't long before I was a star.
My pictures grossed 10, 15 times
what they cost to produce.
Somebody was making money.
It just wasn't me.
They call what we did B movies.
I wanted more.
A chance, Mr. Samuels.
That's all I'm asking.
Before you cast Jane Fonda,
just let me read.
The role of Sally Hyde is gonna require--
A white woman.
A serious actress.
I'm very serious.
I'll tell you what.
I've taken a room at the hotel.
Why don't you come up for a drink...
...and we can talk more about it.
Ramona Royale.
What an honor.
I've seen all your pictures.
You should go.
Now.
What did you just do?
Saved you from making
a humiliating mistake.
All she'd done was look at
that producer and he'd turn tail and run.
Now she was tasking at me.
But I didn't feel like running.
She was this rarified, timeless creature.
She knew everything
about art, literature, fashion.
This was the world I wanted to live in.
And she promised I could, forever.
It was glorious.
She taught me I could be a lady
and badass.
There was nothing I couldn't be...
...except hers forever.
Prophet Moses was in the vanguard
of those early, heady days.
Back when Tupac and Biggie
were making some noise.
But he hadn't broken through yet...
...which is why the record company put him up
at the Cortez and not the Four Seasons.
Mo was a poet.
And he was, without exception."...
the most beautiful man I had ever seen.
I always thought she was
the great love of my rife.
I was wrong,.
It was Mo.
And I aimed to be with him forever.
You ready, baby?
I'm ready.
It's sad.
He could have had a future.
Who the hell are you?
Mo, Mo. Don't. Don't.
She must have really loved you.
What she couldn't have was one
of her creations creating something else.
There can only be one queen,.
She took away from me the only thing
that I ever really cared about.
And I plan to do
the same thing to her.
You think by killing me,
you'll get your revenge?
Not you, fool.
Those babies she made.
But I need access.
Someone on the inside.
And that someone...
...is gonna be you.
She dumped me last Tuesday.
You can go.
I thought you'd left us for good.
It's a pretty humbling feeling
when you realize you have nowhere to go.
And what's out there for me?
I've got no money.
No friends I can crash with.
Pretty hard to explain away
a 20-year gap in my résumé.
And I've got a floppy appendage
between my legs...
...which keeps me
from wearing pencil skirts.
We all have our flaws, kitten.
I thought you were an actor.
You don't have to have a resume
to be beautiful or talent to be an actor.
Just ask Laurence Harvey.
I'm not an actor.
Four years of auditioning,
and I booked one...
...under five on The Colbys.
Aw.
You need moonshine.
I did get to work with Charlton Heston, though.
Not everyone can say that.
I don't even have a room at this hotel.
I have got nothing.
No one.
For eternity.
No pity party in my bar.
Especially when the guest of honor...
...can't see that he's the luckiest man
who ever checked into the Hotel Cortez.
You think you've tasted humility
out there on the streets...
...you ain't tasted shit,
young man.
I know...
...because I have.
You should be ashamed of yourself
for abusing your mother.
I abused her?
I do not den}; that that woman is horrible.
Horrible. But in the next hundred years
of living...
...you may find someone who treats you
better, who screws you better...
...who makes you laugh more than cry.
You'll never find anyone who loves you
as much as she does.
I'm not dead.
Jesus.
You're unbelievable. I gave you enough
to kill an entire marching band.
Plan B.
Jesus, Iris.
Shouldn't be long now.
Hey, Ma?
Ma.
Shit.
Ma, it's Dono.
Ma!
She's resting.
Come back later.
I need to talk with her.
You leave her alone.
She's finally at peace.
No.
Ma, no, no. What did you do?
I didn't do anything.
Nothing she didn't ask me to do.
No, no.
No.
She can't be dead.
She's all I've got.
Oh, come on,
man.
You told her you wanted her dead.
You bitch.
What are you doing?
No, don't do that.
Unh!
Come back, Ma.
Come back to me, Mommy.
Come back to me.
There you go.
Yeah. Yeah.
Now, there's some twisted poetic justice.