(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING IN DISTANCE)
♪ ♪
I don't know if you can hear me.
I got to admit,
you freaked me out before.
I didn't understand you, but...
I get it now.
Come on, man, talk to me.
I know everything about you.
I'm a fan.
Your name
is James Patrick March.
You were born October 30, 1895.
You're a Scorpio,
which explains a lot.
You're the greatest
serial killer who's ever lived.
How do you know all this?
I Googled you.
That sounds obscene.
You were right, man.
Killing
is awesome.
High five!
Good.
You've found your calling.
Then you can appreciate
what I've built here.
Secret rooms, hinged walls,
acid pits,
asphyxiation chambers.
Are you familiar
with my Black Closet?
(WHIMPERING)
(SCREAMING)
Yes.
There are places
in my murder palace
that have sat in cold neglect
for far too long.
You can put them to good use,
old boy.
I'm listening.
Good.
- Now...
- CLAUDIA: My God, look at this.
WILL: The whole floor
needs to be torn out.
This space is perfect
for my atelier.
It's gonna be sensational.
And wait
until you see this room.
What are you doing here?
Visiting a friend.
I was told that nobody lives
on this floor.
You're a squatter.
Tristan, you clean up
pretty well.
I barely recognized you.
Thank you, Claudia.
What happened to your cut?
Get your paws off.
I'm not here to be a deposit
in your spank bank.
(LACHLAN LAUGHS)
Owned, Dad.
Get out.
I'll call the cops if I
see you in my hotel again.
CLAUDIA: Models.
MS. EVERS: Tear this floor out?
Where will I launder the linens?
He can't be allowed
to touch a single room.
Don't worry, dude.
I got this.
Improved By: Fidel33
Sub Upload Date: October 22, 2015
ALEX: It's hard to believe now,
but raising kids was never
a part of my hopes and dreams.
My friends with babies
only made me more resistant.
Their lives seemed
kind of dreary, to be honest.
I wanted to save kids,
other people's kids.
If I'm honest?
Being the best pediatrician
possible
was my only real dream.
Okay.
We're going to get you
to the hospital
and put you on a big fat IV
of antibiotics.
Okay?
We just need his slippers
and his coat.
Wait, wait, wait, hospital?
This kind of pneumonia,
the one we associate with,
uh, the measles, is something
we like to treat, uh,
aggressively.
I don't understand why
you didn't you call me
the second his fever
went over a 103.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR) I... I guess I felt
ashamed after our last conversation.
You made me feel
pretty terrible.
Please just tell me
he's gonna be all right.
I hope so. Upstairs.
(MACHINES BEEPING RHYTHMICALLY)
ALEX: By the way, I'm not unaware
of the obvious cliché here--
I wanted to save kids
because I felt I needed saving.
But in my case
the cliché is dead on.
Suffice it to say,
mine was not a happy childhood.
(COINS CLATTER IN SLOT)
(INDISTINCT P.A ANNOUNCEMENT)
(WHIRRING, LIQUID POURING)
Then Holden showed up.
It was a tectonic shift
where everything I thought
I knew about myself
got rearranged.
It was like I finally
fell in love for real.
All the cracks and
missing pieces came together.
I felt whole.
I'd found my soul mate.
I couldn't stop
smelling his head.
It made me feel drowsy and giddy,
like we were in the middle
of a lavender field
in the south of France.
The smell was real.
He truly smelled
like fresh lavender.
It was and always will be
my drug of choice.
I even wondered
if I truly loved John,
because my feelings for him
were never as powerful
as my feelings for Holden.
And I've always felt guilty
because I never quite bonded
like that with Scarlett
when she was a baby.
It was a special kind of love.
Maybe a once
in a lifetime thing.
And then he disappeared.
JOHN: (SCREAMING) Holden!
Holden?
Holden!
♪ ♪
At first, every time
you hear the phone,
you think they've found him.
(PHONE BUZZING)
Your heart pounds.
Hello?
Then after a month or so,
- (PHONE BUZZING)
- the phone is just the phone.
You do whatever
you need to do to soldier on,
because, you tell yourself,
time is on your side.
(WATER RUNNING)
And then a year has gone by,
and you understand
that the next year
will not be much different.
This feeling will never
go away...
(WHINING)
...'cause there is no
getting over it,
there is no getting
to the other side.
I do carry on.
Mostly for Scarlett.
But there are many days
when I don't really know why.
Some days are bearable.
Today is very hard.
WOMAN: Alex?
You with us?
We haven't heard
a lot from you, Alex.
I don't know what to say.
I'm afraid the truth about
how I'm feeling
wouldn't be very helpful.
This is the right place
for you to speak your truth.
And the right time.
Honestly, I'm angry.
I mean,
I don't understand, Scarlett.
It's like
you're trying to hurt me.
Us.
WOMAN: I don't have the sense
that Scarlett holds any ill will.
Her stories strike me as being
more about wanting to
alleviate your pain,
wanting the family whole again.
You're both wrong.
It's not about my mother
or the family.
It's what happened.
Scarlett, tell us the story
exactly how you remember it.
Tell us everything.
Well, there's a room where
they all play Nintendo
and there are these big glass
things full of jelly beans.
That sounds like a fun place.
And he sleeps in the bottom
of a glass coffin
in the bottom of an
empty swimming pool.
That's when I first saw him.
He was just waking up.
And when you first saw him...
and what did he say exactly?
Does he talk about us?
No, he was different.
He didn't have normal feelings.
And he smelled like
lavender.
You know,
like those candles
we have at home.
- (DOOR OPENS)
- CLAUDIA: Yes, dear.
Yes, the change of scenery
was good for Will.
He was getting
too stale in New York.
Yes, Jess.
I'm losing you.
Can you hear me?
Claudia, Claudia...
Yes.
We need to get Mario Testino
out here to do a shoot.
Did you hear that? Jess?
Oh, darn.
(WATER DRIPPING)
(INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
(BUBBLING)
(GASPS)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
No!
(GRUNTING)
No! No!
Help me! No!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING ECHOES, FADES)
(DISTANT SIREN WAILING)
I got the guys checking
on Islamic terrorist groups
active in the area.
You know, this could be another
Charlie Hebdo thing.
This is a gossip site.
He stopped their tongues
from wagging.
Thou shalt not bear
false witness.
These people trafficked in lies.
They broke the commandment.
JOHN: Have ballistics run a check
on the casings at the scene
with casings from previous murders.
- Yeah, all of them.
- Gotcha.
There may be a previous
commandment murder
that we missed.
We'll cross-reference.
I'm not sure, but I think...
(GRUNTS)
(GASPING)
Help me.
(GASPING SHARPLY)
Boo!
(LAUGHS)
How the hell did
you get in here?
I picked the lock.
When I was first
starting out modeling,
I made extra scratch as a thief.
I'm not the waiting tables type.
I did six months for
breaking and entering.
Did you know that?
Look, I'm sorry about the show.
I'm clean now, I swear.
You and I used to get along
great when I was clean.
You thought I was hilarious.
Every beautiful young thing
is hilarious.
And then you get old
and you don't understand
why everyone isn't still
laughing at your jokes.
How did they fix that scar?
I'll show you mine
if you show me yours.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
What are those?
They're the original plans
for the hotel.
Well, they're the ones that
are registered with the city,
but they're not
the plans for this hotel.
How do you know?
Well, for one thing,
there's that hallway on three
with no doors that goes nowhere.
And, uh,
according to these plans,
there's rooms off of them
and access to the stairwell.
So I think somebody
submitted these plans
to get through inspection,
but then just built
how they wanted to.
Man, you smell good.
You know that's actually
the worst part
about being in jail?
It's not the food
or being locked up like a dog.
It's the smell.
Everyone smells like shit.
Doesn't stop you from doing
stuff, though, you know?
A man has needs, right?
What is happening?
Hmm?
What are you doing?
(MOANING)
Stay.
Stay...
Another time.
What...
(STAMMERS)
Looking at an
O.D. here?
You'd think so,
but everything's
telling me withdrawals.
I don't think this man's had
a needle in him in a few days.
At least.
The blood?
Not his.
(GASPS)
Let's get him sedated.
No! Please! I'm sorry!
I didn't mean it!
Wait! Wait! Wait!
Please. I'm sorry.
Wait, why are you sorry?
Detective.
I didn't mean to kill her.
Wait, wait,
who-who did you kill?
I thought it was the other one.
The junkie whore.
Sally? Sally?
She did this to me.
She lied to me.
She said that I'd be free.
Okay, got to go.
Got to go!
(GRUNTING)
We're losing him.
(RAPID BEEPING)
(FLAT LINE DRONES)
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
SALLY: I hear she checked out.
Who did?
That shit-don't-stink
fashion editor.
Guess this place wasn't up
to her standards.
Not everyone can
appreciate it here.
All this lovely darkness.
You know what I mean.
No.
I really don't.
Why don't you tell me
about your friend?
Which one?
The one at St. Vincent's.
Junkie, covered in blood,
not his.
Oh, well, junkies.
You can't believe
a word they say.
Who was he?
(LAUGHS)
How the hell should I know?
Why are you wasting
your time on junkies?
We only hurt ourselves.
It's not like breaking
one of the Ten Commandments.
What did you say?
What?
Didn't you go to Sunday school?
How about "Thou shalt not kill"?
Hmm.
Well, that commandment
is always translated wrong.
It should be
"Thou shalt not commit murder."
Killing can be a righteous act.
(GASPS)
You've been in my room.
No.
(WHISPERS)
But if that's an invitation...
How about this
for an invitation?
You're under arrest.
Goody.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
I know you sent me that text.
I don't know how deeply
you're involved,
or if you're working
with someone,
or maybe just starved
for attention.
I am starving.
You're starving, too.
I can taste it on you.
(UNZIPS)
Oh!
Come on, Detective,
show me right from wrong.
I wanna help you.
I wish you could.
You'll see.
You and I...
we're meant to be.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
Hey, Dono.
I've been waiting for you.
Look, you need any,
uh, help packing?
I, um, I printed out
some Craigslist ads
for apartments for us.
Some nice two-bedrooms.
And this one... this is...
Get this, this is the
building in Santa Monica
where they captured
Whitey Bulger.
Just look at it--
it's glamorous, right?
I will live with the addicts
in shitter's alley
in a box in MacArthur Park,
covered in the piss and shit
of this horror of a city
before I even consider
living under the same roof
as you again.
You're a drama queen.
Baby, this is our chance.
This is what
we've been waiting for.
Listen...
Don't touch me.
She never loved you.
She was just using you.
I knew that cold snake
would get bored.
Not because of you.
You know, because that's
just how snakes are.
- (ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
- (SCOFFS)
You really have no idea how
much I hate you, do you?
And I get that you
never wanted to take
any authentic interest
in me or my needs,
but I have worked so hard
over the past few years
to get you to notice
how much I despise you.
Now, you hold on a minute.
I gave my life to you.
You have no clue how hard
it was for me to raise you
and the sacrifices that I made.
Name one,
one that didn't serve your
perverted view of yourself.
Your father.
(ELEVATOR BUZZES)
You think it was an easy
choice, kicking him out?
Becoming a single
mother at that time?
Nobody did that, but I did,
because he was nowhere near
man enough to raise you.
My father was the best thing in my life.
I once hid out in the trunk of his Buick
and he made it all the way
to Bakersfield
before he noticed
and took me back home.
(CHUCKLES)
Imagine that.
He didn't even know his own son
was in the trunk of his car.
The guy was an asshole;
he was a moron.
Do you know,
when you kicked him out,
he sat me down
and asked me to promise
that when I was old enough
I would run away?
(SCOFFS)
I had a plan.
Oh, she had a plan.
I went to an AA meeting once,
and after I stood up
and shared about you,
people came up to me,
hardcore addicts,
and they were like,
"Wow, man, no wonder you use."
Every choice you made
was a disaster.
Dad...
that insane vegetarian cult.
The "Breatharaians"
were cutting-edge.
They were using food
as medicine.
I had so much fiber in my diet,
I shit my pants at school.
Fine, you make a list
of all the ways
I have failed you.
And you know what I say
to your list?
Shit on it.
Because my list beats yours.
Item one, I gave you life.
Item two, I saved your life.
I wanted to die!
Coke, crack, heroin--
none of them could do it,
so I decided death was my
only way away from you.
I chose it.
You hated me like that?
And you let me stay here
looking after you?
A real mother would have
let her son die in peace.
She would have buried me.
And grieved.
What mother wouldn't have
wanted her son to live?
Wouldn't have done everything
possible to save him?
You didn't bring me back for me.
You brought me back for you.
I'm leaving here.
Tonight.
(WHIMPERING)
But...
...what am I
supposed to do?
I don't know who I am
if I'm not your mother.
Honestly,
if that is really true,
you should kill yourself.
You should do it
even if it isn't.
♪ ♪
♪ Listen to the girl ♪
♪ As she takes on
half the world ♪
♪ Moving up and so alive ♪
♪ In her honey-dripping... ♪
♪ Eating up the scum ♪
♪ It's the hardest thing for ♪
- (CAR HORN BLARING)
- ♪ Me to do ♪
♪ ♪
(CAR HORN BLARING)
Hey, are you having
some car trouble?
Picked a pretty shitty
place for it.
♪ Just like honey... ♪
These streets can be dangerous.
Hey.
- (STUN GUN ZAPPING)
- (YELLS)
(GROANING)
(ENGINE STARTING)
ALEX: I didn't mean to
just show up like this.
I tried calling.
I kept getting your voice mail.
Yeah, the service in here
is pretty much shit.
LIZ: Scotch.
Soda pop.
♪ Dangerous religion ♪
(LIPS SMACKS)
♪ All we have left to learn... ♪
ALEX: Am I interrupting something?
You're fidgety.
No.
I'm just... I'm just a little
preoccupied with a case.
You look terrible.
When's the last time you slept?
I'm fine, Alex.
Maybe you should get
a real drink.
I mean, it's obvious
you need one.
Why would you say that to me?
You're not in AA-- you don't
have a drinking problem.
You need to give up this
obsession with control.
I need to stay sharp.
Well, you might need one
in a minute.
Why?
What is this?
I don't expect you to
sign them right away.
You may wanna look them over.
No...
Alex, not now.
John, we have to.
For each other,
for our daughter.
I think this is why Scarlett
is telling these wild stories,
'cause we haven't moved on.
I mean, a divorce?
I don't want a divorce,
I-I never did-- I-I love you.
And I love you, too.
But it's not enough,
not anymore.
I know it's been rough with me
out of the house, but...
It hasn't been rough.
It hasn't been rough at all--
in fact, it's been great.
I didn't think that I
could do it, but I can.
I don't think you
should come back.
It'll just make things
harder for everyone,
because, in the end, this
is what we need to do.
Please.
Please, please don't
tear this family apart.
I'm not the one tearing
our family apart.
Someone else did that
when they stole our son.
(JOHN SOBBING)
John.
(SOBBING)
Stay. Stay.
Something's wrong with me.
I-I think
I'm going crazy.
I feel like I'm seeing things.
Let's get you back
to your room, okay?
COUNTESS: I'm so sorry.
That's clumsy of me.
You never need to apologize
for pouring a glass
of Château Margaux.
I was afraid you'd think
this was too much.
Oh, you mean the dress?
The night out on the town?
This nightcap?
You know I'm gay.
I'm not stupid.
We're destined
for something much more...
intimate.
What if I told you...
Will Drake had to die?
Then you know the truth.
The well is dry.
So much for the West Coast influence.
I happen to think
you're a genius.
But you've been comfortable
for far too long.
You need to burn...
so you can rise from the ashes.
Kill Will.
(SIGHS) You're giving
me dangerous thoughts.
All great ideas are deadly.
I feel the same way
with you right now
as I did when I
kissed my first man.
How many times have you been
with a woman?
A few.
But they all ended...
(SIGHS) ...unfulfilled.
No danger in that tonight.
What is this shit?
Where did you get the balls
to eat out of my dish, man?
I'll call you later.
By the way,
you're hard.
(DOOR SLAMS)
So that's it.
It's just over between us?
Don't be such a child.
What am I suppose to think?
I mean, I don't even get it.
All he has is money.
Then you do get it.
What? You're rich.
I used to be.
And then I met Bernie.
Madoff was very good
at separating people
from their money,
because he'd make you beg
to give it to him.
All my rich friends got richer,
20% return every year.
But he wouldn't take mine,
not until he could get it all.
The stocks,
the bonds, the hotel.
Finally went to prison.
I lost everything.
So that's why you didn't
want me to kill Drake?
Will Drake can't die
until after I marry him
and take every goddamn penny.
(CHUCKLES)
ALEX: Jesus Christ.
It's no wonder
you're in such a state,
sleeping five feet
away from all this.
I don't do
much sleeping anymore.
Which is why
you're gonna take these.
Drink them down.
You don't have a fever.
You just need some rest.
A few hours sleep,
and everything will be clearer.
Okay?
I'm so sorry, Alex.
I'm sorry I couldn't keep
our family together.
I'm sorry...
I couldn't bring
your boy back home to you.
I know.
It's not your fault.
I know how much you loved him.
More than me,
more than Scarlett.
John.
It's okay.
I never minded.
That's how I love you.
Let's have another baby.
Oh, Jesus.
What am I doing?
We still love each other.
The divorce papers are here.
If you have any questions,
just call the lawyer.
(DOOR SLAMS)
Is this hell?
No.
If this were hell,
I'd be the one
in that awful Zara knockoff
that you're wearing.
(CLICKING TONGUE)
(BOY GIGGLING)
Holden?
Hi, Mommy.
- (SCOFFS)
- Get the lead out, will you?
I'm terrified of needles.
I just want this over with.
First, you need to tell me
why I should be doing
you this kindness,
when I could just push you
right out that window,
even things up.
Oh, come on.
You're not gonna torment me now.
I think it would be good for you
to talk about why
you want to die.
And to taint me with your self loathing.
It's not about why die.
It's about
why continue to live.
I can't think
of a single reason.
I guess I'm just not lovable.
Now, what's to say.
My own son hates me.
He always has.
You know, I see people
laughing and smiling
and I cannot for the life of me
understand why.
I just don't get
the joke anymore.
I am the joke.
(SIGHS)
Hang on.
We are going total bye-bye,
right?
You swear
you don't have
any unfinished business here?
Because I am stuck
in this place, thanks to you,
so I want to be one 100% sure
that when I do this,
I am done
with your miserable old ass.
In other words,
don't haunt my hallways, bitch.
I want nothing more
than the dark silence
of death itself.
Well, you've come
to the right girl.
(GROANS)
How many junkies
did you feed on, Donovan?
You're no good to anyone
in this condition.
So I am gonna get that
poison out of that blood.
And then we'll see
if you can be of any use to me.
Who the hell are you?
Now, that's the wrong question.
What you should be asking is
who was I?
Somebody order room service?
I was the queen of them all.
No, we ordered hookers.
- (GUN CLICKS)
- Get on your knees.
- (CHUCKLING)
- Yeah.
(CHUCKLES)
I don't get on my knees
for no man.
DIRECTOR: Cut!
- (BELL RINGING)
- Whoo.
Okay, guys.
That looked good.
(LAUGHS)
I had come to Hollywood
with barely
a high school education
and no prospects.
It wasn't long
before I was a star.
My pictures grossed ten,
15 times what they cost
to produce.
Somebody was making money.
It just wasn't me.
They call what we did B-movies.
I wanted more.
A chance, Mr. Samuels.
That's all I'm asking.
Before you cast Jane Fonda,
just let me read.
The role of Sally Hyde
is going to require...
A white woman.
A serious actress.
I'm very serious.
SAMUELS: I'll tell you what.
I've taken a room at the hotel.
Why don't you come
up for a drink,
and we can talk more about it.
Ramona Royale.
What an honor.
I've seen all your pictures.
You should go.
Now.
What did you just do?
Saved you from making a
humiliating mistake.
RAMONA: All she'd done
was look at that producer,
and he'd turn tail and run.
Now she was looking at me.
But I didn't feel like running.
She was this rarified,
timeless creature.
She knew everything
about art, literature, fashion.
This was the world
I wanted to live in,
and she promised I could--
forever.
♪ ♪
It was glorious.
She taught me I could be a lady
and badass.
There was nothing
I couldn't be...
...except hers forever.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
♪ ♪
Prophet Moses
was in the vanguard
of those early, heady days,
back when Tupac and Biggie
were making some noise.
But he hadn't
broken through yet.
Which is why the record company
put him up at the Cortez
and not the Four Seasons.
Mo was a poet.
And he was, without exception,
the most beautiful man
I had ever seen.
I always thought
she was the great love
of my life.
I was wrong.
It was Mo.
(HIP-HOP BEAT PLAYING)
And I aimed
to be with him forever.
You ready, baby?
I'm ready.
(GASPS)
(GROANS)
(MOANING)
(GASPS)
(CRYING)
It's sad.
He could have had a future.
Who the hell are you?
Mo, Mo!
No, don't.
She must have really loved you.
(RAMONA SCREAMING)
(SOBBING)
What she couldn't have,
was one of her creations
creating something else.
There can only be one queen.
She took away from me
the only thing
that I ever really cared about.
And I plan to do
the same thing to her.
You think by killing me
you'll get your revenge?
Not you, fool.
Those babies she made.
But I need access.
Someone on the inside.
And that someone
is gonna be you.
She dumped me last Tuesday.
You can go.
(SIGHS)
I thought you'd left us
for good.
(SCOFFS)
It's a pretty humbling feeling
when you realize
you have nowhere to go.
And what's out there for me?
I've got no money,
no friends I can crash with.
Pretty hard to explain away
a 20-year gap in my résumé.
And I've got a floppy
appendage between my legs
which keeps me from
wearing pencil skirts.
We all have our flaws, kitten.
I thought you were an actor.
You don't have to have a résumé
to be beautiful
or talent to be an actor.
Just ask Laurence Harvey.
DONOVAN: I'm not an actor.
Four years of auditioning
and I booked one
under five on The Colbys.
You need a little Moonshine.
***
though not everyone can say that.
I don't even have
a room at this hotel.
I have got nothing.
No one.
For eternity.
No pity party in my bar!
Especially when
the guest of honor
can't see that
he's the luckiest man
who ever checked
into the Hotel Cortez.
You think you've tasted humility
out there on the streets?
You ain't tasted shit,
young man.
I know,
because I have.
You should be ashamed
of yourself
for abusing your mother.
I abused her?
I do not deny that that woman
is horrible. Horrible.
But in the next hundred
years of living,
you may find someone
who treats you better,
who screws you better,
who makes you laugh
more than cry.
You'll never find anyone
who loves you
as much as she does.
(WEAKLY)
I'm not dead.
Jesus.
You're unbelievable.
I gave you enough to kill
an entire marching band.
Plan B.
Jesus, Iris.
Shouldn't be long now.
(WHEEZING)
DONOVAN: Hey, Ma?
(KNOCKING CONTINUES)
Ma?
Shit.
- Ma, it's Dono.
- (KNOCKING CONTINUES)
Hey, Ma!
She's resting.
Come back later.
I need to talk with her.
You leave her alone.
She's finally at peace.
No, Ma, no, no.
What did you do?
I didn't do anything.
Nothing she didn't ask me to do.
No, no.
No.
She...
She can't be dead.
She's all I've got.
Oh, come on, man.
You told her
you wanted her dead.
You bitch.
What are you doing?
No, don't do that.
(GROANS)
Come back, Ma.
Come back to me, Mommy.
Come back to me.
There you go, there you go.
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah. Yeah.
Now there's some twisted
poetic justice.