[music - charlie mole]
[chatter]
CHILD: Winnie!
MAN: Pity we haven't
got any honey.
WOMAN: Do you think
he'd prefer honey?
BOY: Winnie, that's
what they call her.
MAN: --real thing.
BOY: Yeah, Tommy,
come have a look here.
MAN: She likes honey
best, you know.
That's what they like.
WOMAN: Honey?
MAN: Yeah, that's
what they like to eat.
Winnie.
Winnie, over here!
Winnie!
WOMAN: That's enough, children.
Kindly pick that
up, young man.
You can't just litter
the place with sticky--
Gah!
Father, why do
they call her Winnie?
Well, I--
I don't know, really.
BOY: It's a funny
name for a bear.
Yes, I suppose it is.
I wonder how she got it.
Got what?
Her name, silly.
Yes, I wonder.
I'll bet it's quite a story.
[music playing]
[snuffling]
[gunshot]
[bear cub cry]
[music playing]
[cries]
Hey, bear.
Bear, you get down from there.
- [crying]
- Come on, get!
You won't get no
sympathy from me.
A bear's a bear.
Stop that, right now!
[train whistle]
[chatter]
CAPTAIN: All right,
no more bets.
No more bets.
You need [inaudible].
Give me one, Captain.
Oh, just one?
Just one, huh?
All right, there's mine too.
HARRY: All right, are we
playing cards here or what?
Are you playing cards?
SOLDIER: I'm in, Harry.
CAPTAIN: Who needs cards?
- Let's go.
Let's go.
[inaudible] Let's
play some poker, here.
- How about you?
- You know, playing cards--
Three.
--is a good way
to pass the time.
You're being
annoying again, Taylor.
Sorry, Harry.
Uh, Sir.
I guess we're in
the army now, eh?
That's right, Corporal.
We are in the army now.
$5 says it falls
in eight seconds. $5.
SOLDIER: I got it!
SOLDIER: Who's in?
SOLDIER: Captain's got it.
Corporal collects,
that means you.
All right, let's play in there.
Dougal, are you in there?
Put $5 in here.
CAPTAIN: Wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait.
HARRY: OK, OK.
TAYLOR: OK?
All right.
And one, two,
three, four, five--
Captain: Come on!
SOLDIERS: Six--
Fall!
Seven--
SOLDIERS: Eight--
Aah!
I can't believe it!
How did you call that?
Well, you know.
What am I going to say?
[MUSIC PLAYING - "THIS IS MY
FATHER'S WORLD"]
[train whistle]
CONDUCTOR [VOICEOVER]:
White River, 20 minute stop.
White River's next.
[train whistle]
[violin playing]
[chatter]
[horse whinnying]
WOMAN: Look out!
Go, get out of the way!
Get back!
[screaming]
- Easy!
- Get back!
SOLDIER: Easy!
All right, steady
up with you now.
[chatter]
MAN: Shoot him!
We got him.
MAN: Get that horse.
Whoa.
Whew.
[WHISPERING] Hey.
Shh.
[whistling softly]
Atta boy.
Shh.
Just spooked a little.
Walk him.
He'll be fine.
[blacksmith hammering]
[bear crying]
Hey there, baby cub.
Hey.
You're a bit worried, are we?
Not surprising, I suppose.
TANNER: Help you, soldier?
Cub fur good for anything?
It's not.
So why is she
tied up like this?
Hunter didn't have the guts
to do what has to be done.
I see.
What exactly is it
that had to be done?
Shoot it.
[yells]
[bear crying]
As if I didn't
have enough to do.
I'll tell you what.
I'll shoot her for
you, if you like.
I'm with the Veterinary
Corps, Winnipeg Section.
Cost you $35.
HARRY: Wait, now hold on.
You know, I thought I was
just doing you a favor.
What do you want him for?
I didn't say I
wanted anything.
I said I'd shoot her
for you, if you like.
Uh-huh.
$25, and you can wang
away till cows give beer.
[bugle call]
CONDUCTOR: Valcartier
train now departing.
All aboard!
Valcartier, train
leaving for Valcartier.
All aboard!
Excuse me, folks, I have
a little situation here.
I was wondering if you can--
Egads!
No, she's not dangerous.
She's just a little bit--
A regimental mascot, I'll bet.
Regimental?
No.
I've just been a tad impetuous.
Go give the Kaiser a good
kick in his royal Bosch behind.
Oh, George!
You shouldn't say that.
[crying]
Huh?
All right, all right.
I understand.
I'm not really a
bear sort of person,
and I have a train
to catch, which means
I'm going to have to find you--
That your bear?
[music playing]
You like bears?
Hmm?
You know that they make
wonderful pets, far better
than dogs.
Did you know that?
My dog died.
Oh, I'm sorry.
CONDUCTOR: All aboard!
You must be sad.
Hey, what's your name?
Timmy McMurray.
Well, I tell you
what, Timmy McMurray.
How would you like to have a
bear for your very own pet?
Huh?
TIMMY'S MOTHER: Timmy.
Get away from that man.
TIMMY: Can we have
the bear, Mommy?
Bears make good pets.
He said.
Don't be silly, dear.
Little children don't
have bears for pets.
Even big, brave
soldiers know that.
TIMMY: [crying]
What am I going
to do with you?
Hmm?
You're going to get me
in trouble, aren't you?
Aren't you?
[train whistle]
You're gonna get me in trouble.
Who's your friend, Harry?
She got a name?
[laughter]
SOLDIER: What were
you thinking, Harry?
SOLDIER: Captain's not
going to like this.
[chatter]
SOLDIER: I can't believe
you got a bear, Harry.
What's your
name, little fella?
SOLDIER: Aww, she's a sweetie.
SOLDIER: Have you
trained him yet?
SOLDIER: Is it a she?
Is it a she-bear?
Is this a she-bear?
SOLDIER: You bought her?
HARRY: I bought her.
SOLDIER: For how much?
20.
Holy smokes, Harry.
That-- That's a pair.
You got a pair, there.
- Yes, I do.
Yes, I do.
- Yes, you do.
[inaudible] a wild bear.
HARRY: Thank you, Taylor.
Wild bear on a train.
Harry, what are
you doing with that?
[cries]
HARRY: To tell you
the truth, Captain,
it's not really an ambition
of mine to own a bear,
but the circumstances were--
It's wild, sir.
A wild bear.
- I can see that.
- [cries]
Her mother was shot,
and she was next.
You know the rules.
Yes, I do.
He knows the rules.
CAPTAIN: Taylor.
TAYLOR: Sorry, Harry, Captain.
I'm, uh, just, uh--
You can't keep a pet.
Pet?
Is that what you think?
Well, whatever it
is, you can't keep it.
That's the rule, is it?
Afraid so.
And rules are rules.
CAPTAIN: There you have it.
BEAR: [cries]
Well, there's no rule
against having a mascot.
Mascot?
No rule against mascot.
Unit mascot, what
do you say, boys?
[cheering]
SOLDIER: This is an opportunity!
Mascot with no name?
Of course she's got a name.
CAPTAIN: Uh-huh?
SOLDIER: Come on, Harry.
SOLDIER: Come on!
Winnipeg.
SOLDIER: That's right!
Winnipeg?
[cries]
Is that a good
name for a bear?
Winnie for short.
SOLDIER: Winnie it is!
Winnie.
Yeah, I like that.
SOLDIER: Winnie.
SOLDIER: Winnipeg, all right.
SOLDIER: Hey, Winnie!
Winnie!
Come here, Winnie!
SOLDIER: We've got a mascot.
No bears on my train.
Oh, uh--
Well, hold on now, sir.
This is no ordinary bear, sir.
No exceptions.
CAPTAIN: He's the, uh--
Uh, she's.
She's the unit mascot.
I don't give a hoot if she's
the King's great-grandmother.
I won't have a bear
defecating all over my train.
She's not defecating.
Will be.
You can count on it.
You can count on that.
HARRY: Sir, we're all
with the Veterinary Corps.
We've all been trained
to deal with animals
of all shapes and sizes.
Look, sunshine.
Wild critters don't give two
hoots where they defecate,
and this here one
won't be defecating
where it's against the rules.
And that would be in
first-class coach.
You want to keep a bear?
You keep it in freight.
[cries]
[fart sound]
[laughter]
[train whistle]
[music playing]
Crawford.
Sir?
SOLDIER: Good morning, sir.
And what the devil do they
think they're doing with those?
Osbourn.
- Sir!
Pack my charger.
Absolute mess.
What do you think it is?
It's nothing but a mess.
And there's no drainage here.
Move the tents up the slope.
Yes, sir.
And for heaven's
sake, keep them in rows.
You can't have
tents helter-skelter
all over the place.
Order and discipline, lads.
That's what wins wars.
Yes, sir.
- Carry on.
- Sir!
[music playing]
[soldiers completing drill]
Crawford.
What do you make of that ragtag
bunch at the end of the ranks?
CRAWFORD: Veterinary Corps,
sir, Winnipeg Section.
Blasted cowboys.
Fetch, uh, what's his name?
That new man.
Come on, what's his name?
What's his name?
Colonel Barret, sir.
Barret, thank you.
Have him deal with it.
Yes, sir.
Canadian Army Veterinary
Corps, Winnipeg Section
reporting for duty, sir.
Prepare for inspection.
I'm Barret, Chief Veterinary
Officer and Director
of Veterinary Services.
I don't care who your father
is, what school you went to,
or any of that
high-brow baloney.
As of this moment you
represent your country
as part of the 1st
Division of the Canadian
Expeditionary Force.
From all the
information I can gather
and what I can see
with my own two eyes,
your military training
has been slight to nil.
[bear cry]
[cries]
TAYLOR: That's Winnie, sir.
Short for Winnipeg.
Our unit mascot, sir!
Get rid of it.
[crying]
SOLDIER: Eyes front!
I don't believe in
mascots, and you men
must close your picnic
hampers and begin
to harden your hearts.
What you are about
to face is more
vicious and terrifying
than anything
you can possibly imagine.
[bugle call]
Carry on.
You can't just leave
her in the woods.
There's wolves and
foxes and coyotes and--
Thank you, Corporal.
She wants you to, um--
Yes, I'm aware of that.
Yeah, it can't be this row.
It's got to be the next row.
Well, maybe another
regiment will take her.
I mean there's no regulation--
The order was
to get rid of her.
Well, you never
used to follow orders.
Yes, we're having
a lovely little war,
now though, aren't we?
- [cries]
Harry.
I think we found your billet.
Get up there!
Why are you being such a--
Oh.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Can we give you a hand?
No.
No, thank you.
I'm fine.
HARRY: I'm Harry Colebourn.
This is Captain Elliot.
Oh, oh yes, hello.
Uh, Ian Macray, former
Kings College scholar now
colonial fodder for a
pompous imperial empire.
Let me.
[cries]
We're tentmates, I think.
Oh.
Well.
As a man thinks, so he becomes.
Huh?
Harry, I have some news, and
you're not going to like it.
I-- I was tying her up right
here, and then I looked away.
And then I looked back, and
she-- she- she was gone.
CAPTAIN: Taylor!
All right, split up.
Let's go!
Wh-- wh-- who-- who's gone?
It's Winnie.
Who's Winnie?
It's our bear.
Oh.
[music playing]
Have you seen a black
bear cub through here?
SOLDIER: Is his mother around?
COOK: Here we go.
[chatter]
Anything?
No.
[chatter]
COOK: What's going on?
Bear!
COOK: Get back here!
Get out of my
kitchen, get out!
Get out!
Hold on!
Hey.
Enough, bear.
Back to the woods with you.
[cries]
Come here.
Ten-hut!
GENERAL HALLHOLLAND:
Fine thing, mascot.
Had one myself once
in South Africa.
Sir Hugo.
Supercilious old billy goat.
Took his last time with
us at Paardeberg Drift.
Stray flare caught the
munitions, and dear
old fellow burnt to a crisp in
the [inaudible] of [inaudible].
Yes, well, in any event he
was awfully good for morale.
They're noble creatures, bears.
You make sure you
look after him, Major.
It's Lieutenant, sir.
And move this tent!
It's a pig sty!
Do you know why we don't
have women in the army?
Actually, sir,
I've often wondered.
COLONEL BARRET: When
the shooting starts,
the men rush to protect.
To fight and live requires
a soldier's full attention.
Eye on the ball, not the bear.
Yes, sir, but
the general seems
quite adamant about
having a mascot as--
Yes, I understand
the situation.
You have a week or so.
Do what you need to do
to take care of your bear
before we leave for England.
Yes, sir.
[music - "reveille"]
So they have teeth, of
course, and the intestinal tract
of a carnivore.
But--
Come here.
Winnie.
Uh, but they, um, they're
opportunistic eaters and--
which makes them
omnivorous and explains
their fondness for ants.
She'd have to
eat a great number.
Yes, that would be
a factor, wouldn't it.
It says here their
olfactory sense--
that means you-- is
more acute than a dog's
by the power of seven.
Isn't that amazing?
Yeah, that's why
their noses are bigger.
Huh?
Oh!
Actually--
Winnie, come down from there.
Winnie!
Her-- her preferred foods are,
um, nuts, acorns, insects, uh--
Winnie bear.
- --succulent greens, and honey.
- Winnie!
And, um, and, uh, berries.
HARRY: Winnie!
Winnie!
[cries]
MACRAY: But, uh, but I think--
I think it's a little late in
the season for-- for berries.
Oh dear!
HARRY: Winnie bear!
[cries]
Oh!
You know a lot
about bears, do you?
Well, not much I don't
know about, really.
WINNIE: [crying]
- I thought so.
Yes.
I think what's important is
that she needs to learn how
to defend herself and
forage for herself
and, uh, and to sleep-- oh!
And to sleep alone.
Winnie!
MACRAY: Wonderful, isn't it?
Macray, no offense intended,
but what in the name of glory
are you doing in uniform?
Know everything, done nothing.
That's me in a nutshell.
[music playing]
What?
You hungry?
[groans]
[WHISPERING] Don't wake him up.
Don't wake him up.
Go back.
Come here.
Winnie!
[slurping sounds]
Taste good?
[music playing - "reveille"]
[music playing]
GENERAL HALLHOLLAND: Come
on, [inaudible] everybody.
Pull those tents
down!
[music playing]
[cries]
Up.
Good Winnie.
[cries]
Good.
Good Winnie.
Good bear.
[cries]
[snoring]
[whinnying]
[chatter]
Wha-- wha-- what's--
what are you-- that's-- no,
the-- the horse is--
This horse is old and sick.
What-- no, they
don't have to do that.
No, no.
She's contagious.
But no, it's not.
I've ruled it out.
It's not epizootic
lymphangitis, and it's
not glanders or farcy either.
- Really?
- Yes, really.
There's a swelling.
It's a-- a-- a-- ch--
perhaps a boil or
maybe a splinter.
A splinter?
MACRAY: Yes!
Sergeant Major.
Professor Macray here seems to
think old Zeb's fit and able.
This animal?
I can see he is sick.
Just give me a minute.
Easy.
[cries]
HARRY: Easy, Zeb.
Easy.
[WHISPERING] Hey, good boy.
Good.
Shh.
Oh.
It's all right.
Steady.
[whinnying]
Come here.
Atta boy.
Up, up, up.
Oh!
Easy.
Shh.
Atta boy.
Easy.
Good boy.
Shh.
Atta boy.
Easy, easy.
Good boy.
Shh.
Easy.
Good boy.
Come here.
Want some apple, huh?
[music playing]
WINNIE: [cries]
[cries]
[yells]
GENERAL HALLHOLLAND: Come
on, pull those tents down.
And move this tent!
Ready and pull!
[gunshot]
I said pull, you lummox.
Just slow and steady
effort, the way
you would remove
a burr from a cat.
Ready and pull!
[gunshot]
General, may I have a word?
General Hallholland, the
constant relocation of tents
robs the men of valuable
time for training--
I understand you graduated
top of your class at RMC.
Sir, the men need
practical training.
They have no idea what's
facing them in France
So you must be related to
the Montreal Barrets, huh?
Old Charlie Barret
and I, we played
rugby together at McGill.
My father was a miner,
barely spoke English,
and as far as I know he
never played any type
of game his entire life.
Oh.
We depart by convoy in 48 hours.
That will be all.
[snoring]
[music playing]
[cries]
[barking]
[whinnying]
[cries]
No, [inaudible].
SOLDIER: Stampede!
Come on, let's go.
Stampede!
Wake up!
WINNIE: [crying]
SOLDIER: Go, go!
[bugle call]
SOLDIER: Stampede
at the stables!
SOLDIER: Stampede!
They all went down that way.
Harry!
[crying]
TAYLOR: But there must have been
something that bothered them,
and, uh, it was dark.
It was night.
I just-- I wish I
could have seen.
What did you see?
See?
Well, I-- I didn't see.
What I mean is that it-- it
was dark, and it was quiet.
And then all of a
sudden, uh, you know,
they were kicking or-- or--
Harry!
Find it.
Yes, sir.
[cries]
[yelling]
Still some are missing.
Look down by the river.
WINNIE: [crying]
[speaking french]
Bear.
What you have done?
This is not good.
Unless you have any
pertinent remarks.
Sir, there's no evidence
that says that Winnie
caused that stampede.
She's wild.
That's all the
evidence necessary.
HARRY: Sir?
Respectfully, I decline on
the grounds of an oath which
each and every one of
us swore to uphold,
to use our skills for
the benefit of society
through the protection
of animal health
and the relief of
animal suffering, sir.
All right, Lieutenant.
TAYLOR: No!
Winnie didn't do it.
What happened was I saw that old
mongrel dog run past on the way
out of the stables, and--
Did you see it
enter the stables?
Well, I-- that-- that--
that's just the-- that's just
the thing, sir.
I-- I was, uh--
I must have--
Sir, I fell asleep
at my post, sir.
That's a court martial
offense, Corporal.
Lieutenant, we
strike camp at 0800.
We'll take care of it, sir.
I'm awful sorry, Harry.
I-- you know, I wouldn't
do anything to hurt--
I know.
I'm sorry.
[music playing]
WINNIE: [cries]
MACRAY: Easy.
HARRY: I'm going to set her
down over here in this clearing.
Oh, easy, girl!
Easy, girl.
That's it.
- [cries]
What d-- What does she want?
What does she want from me?
Look, there's some
raisins in my bag
down there, in the satchel.
- Girl, good girl.
- [crying]
No, she wants out.
I don't have the raisins, Harry.
We left the raisins.
You're doing great.
She's attacking.
I'm-- Hello.
Good.
Good Winnie.
I'm not sure if she
likes me or not.
I thought you
knew about bears!
MACRAY: [MUFFLED] [inaudible].
Winnie.
[inaudible]
WINNIE: [crying]
These berries?
Uh, bunchberries,
cornus canadensis.
They are very tasty
for bears, but sadly
dried up and out of season now.
Blueberries.
Yes, perfect.
Perfect.
Come on!
Come on, Winnie.
- Show her those.
- Come on.
Come on.
Look, see?
Berries!
Look, berries.
Good.
Good girl.
Shh.
Easy.
OK, go.
Go.
I can't help feeling
we're abandoning her.
Well, perhaps we
should think of it
as returning her to her rightful
place in the great chain of--
Macray.
Yes, well, she is
unusually clever,
an extraordinary bear, really, a
survivor if there ever was one.
Don't you think?
WINNIE: [crying]
[music playing]
Do you have any ideas?
You're the smart one.
Well, not like her.
OK, I'm going to put
her down right here.
WINNIE: [crying]
Let's go!
Move!
[music playing]
WINNIE: [crying]
HARRY: Can she get out of it?
I think, judging by
her past performance.
You're right.
Won't take you long,
will it, Winnie?
Hmm?
This is where you belong, girl.
You'll be fine here, OK?
[music playing]
Good-bye.
Good-bye, Winnie.
WINNIE: [crying]
Forgive my impertinence,
Harry, but you're not
Canadian-born, are you?
Or rather, I-- I mean I can
just detect a slight hint of--
My father died
when I was young.
Mother remarried.
I was sent out here at 14.
My uncle's with
the grain exchange.
That's interesting.
Is it?
No, no, no, no, no, no.
No, it's nothing really.
I just--
HARRY: Nothing?
If a simple veterinarian
from Winnipeg, Manitoba,
is interesting at all,
I want to know about it.
Well, it's simply that,
um, what I find interesting
is that--
well, your sensitivity towards
Winnie being abandoned when--
when you've experienced
something similar
yourself, in a manner of
speaking, more or less.
[music playing]
My good old dad came out here
with a piddling remittance.
You know, the black sheep of
the family, the feckless son who
just couldn't measure up,
and sent to the new world
to seek his fortune.
And unfortunately
his family was right.
[music playing]
And my mother, well, she taught
school, and she still does.
All of which I suppose
explains why I--
I can speak Latin, but I
can't swim or throw a ball.
[music playing]
[cries]
[MUSIC PLAYING - "NO MORE
SOLDIERING FOR ME"]
CHOIR [PHONOGRAPH]: [SINGING]
When this rotten war is over,
no more soldiering for me.
When I get my civvy clothes
on, oh, how happy I shall be.
No more church
parades on Sunday.
No more putting in for leave.
I shall miss that Sergeant
Major, how I'll miss him,
how he'll grieve.
When this rotten war is over,
no more soldiering for me.
When I get my civvy clothes
on, oh, how happy I shall be.
I shall sound my own reveille.
I shall make my own tattoo.
[crying]
[music playing]
[chatter]
[cries]
[music playing - "reveille"]
[music playing]
[chatter]
MACRAY: Now this, I must have.
I can't do without.
You know, it's al-- it's always
Dickens or-- or Longfellow.
Do you find?
[music playing]
[chatter]
I find that it--
No!
[cries]
HARRY: Winnie!
Where did you come from?
Winnie!
- [cries]
That's-- that's Winnie!
She-- She's here, but I
thought that you-- well,
it is good that she's here?
No, it's not.
It's not so good, but it's
certainly extraordinary.
Whoa, what are
you going to do?
Because I mean, she's
not so wild anymore.
She obviously likes people.
We can't leave her here.
MACRAY: We can't?
No.
Wh-- wh-- yeah, but we can't
take her with us, either.
We-- I mean, what
are you going to do?
Smuggle her in your--
in your haversack?
WINNIE: [cries]
This is not good.
[music playing - "reveille"]
I hope this works.
HARRY: Private.
Leonard, right?
Well, Leonard--
Let's-- let's go.
Over there.
We got this, Jake.
A big strapping
fellow such as yourself.
[inaudible]
OFFICER: Left.
Right.
Left.
In a few weeks you will stand
against the Prussian army,
the greatest, strongest, most
professional, well-trained
military machine in the world.
I suggest over the next week
you take a few moments to plan
how you intend to stay alive.
[music playing]
OFFICER: Left.
Right.
Left.
[music playing]
SOLDIER: Here,
have one of these.
SOLDIER: Oh, lovely.
[chatter]
[music playing]
Our-- our dressing stations
are well behind our lines,
so we're not going to
see any real action.
Technically we're still in range
of their guns so there's always
the off-chance--
One-ton shell might
blow us into next year.
Right.
But what are the odds?
What-- What do you think, Harry?
Wh-- What are the odds?
[cries]
I think I've made
a terrible blunder.
We can't take Winnie to war.
To the front line?
- No.
She'll end up
like old Sir Hugo.
MACRAY: Or worse.
You're right.
Harry.
What I'm trying to figure is,
if Zeb's back to his old self,
then there must be a reason why
you want to keep him inside.
Well, I don't think another
day or two of reprieve
would hurt.
Would it, Taylor?
Oh.
No, no, no.
Wait.
I-- I think I know.
It-- it's because
of her, isn't it?
Yes, it is.
It's-- it's because you don't
want Winnie getting lonely,
because boy oh boy,
if she gets lonely,
then the first thing she's
going to do is run to camp.
And then the Colonel
and everybody--
Thank you, Taylor.
WINNIE: [crying]
Sorry, Harry.
Just uh, just had to
work that out a bit, huh?
Just, just work it out.
The front is no place
for you either, is it?
Huh?
Old man.
Now you be a brave bear
and look after Taylor.
We'll be back as soon
as we can, all right?
WINNIE: [cries]
You know what to do
if the brass turns up.
Sure do.
[bell rings]
[cries]
TAYLOR: Girl.
HARRY: We should get
there in plenty of time.
MACRAY: Wait, wait,
wait a minute.
We never discussed we.
It was always you.
The situation's changed.
It needs to be we.
What?
In any event it will
be a walk in the park.
Harry, I'm afraid
I'm not terribly brave.
Haha, you'll get over that.
MACRAY: No, one does not
get over a firing squad.
Sir.
SOLDIER: Sir.
Excuse me, sir.
Sir.
Canadian Army, Veterinary
Corps, Winnipeg Section
ready for inspection, sir!
At ease, Corporal.
Where is she?
I have no idea
what you mean, sir.
No idea whatsoever?
Well, yes, sir.
Well, no, sir.
I-- no idea whatsoever, sir.
Very well.
I know she was on the boat.
I have evidence, and
I know she's here.
And when I get to the bottom of
all of this, the bunch of you
will be finding yourselves
facing disgrace, dishonor,
and a punishment so cruel
only English schoolboys
could have thought of it.
Do you understand?
Yes, sir.
Understand, sir.
No idea whatsoever, sir.
[music playing]
WINNIE: [cries]
[cries]
[music playing - "reveille"]
[SLURRED] Barret.
This is uh, this
is from Whitehall.
And uh, ha!
I don't know what--
I mean, what do they know.
I know they need the [inaudible]
because apparently it's
machine guns that are
going to win this war.
Listen.
"Each one replaces 80 rifles."
Codswallop, isn't it?
[LAUGHING] I mean, what--
and what if it jams?
Eh?
What then?
Well, no, sir.
Thank you very much.
I'll take the 80 rifles
and a crack cavalry.
It's horses that are
key to this fight.
And they always have been,
and they always will be.
What do you think, Colonel?
General, may I speak candidly?
GENERAL HALLHOLLAND: Crawford.
Sir!
General, I recommend you
lift your ban on alcohol
for our boys and
loosen the restrictions
you've imposed with regard
to leaving the base.
Impose?
I don't impose orders, boy.
I give 'em.
[liquid pouring]
And I expect them to be
followed by everyone.
Sir, the men need to let
off steam every now and then.
Yeah, and it's,
um, it's clean living
that keeps my lads sharp,
and that means no liquor.
And if they have to go
looking for it off-base,
well, they'll be shot.
Will that be all, Colonel?
Men prepared to sacrifice
their lives for their country
should not be
treated as children.
Don't you tell me
how to run my army.
General, the Canadian
Expeditionary Force
is not your private
army, and I will not
stand by while the
lives of 30,000 men
are compromised by
some vainglorious whim.
Who the hell do
you think you are?
Don't you dare talk
to me like that!
Do you know who I am?
Do you realize the
prime minister--
your father was a
nothing, a nobody,
and that's exactly
where you'll end up if I
have any say in the matter.
Sir, the sun is about
to set on your day to have
a say in anything that matters.
And as to your other point,
my father didn't need to wear
a uniform to be a man of honor.
Get off!
[music playing - "reveille"]
[cries]
SOLDIER: Morning, Colonel.
WINNIE: [cries]
[music playing]
I knew it.
WINNIE: [cries]
Come over here.
Come here, you.
[cries]
OK, don't-- don't--
don't do this to me, bear.
I don't-- we-- no, this
doesn't work with--
OK.
Oh, my goodness, you stink.
I know exactly
where you've been.
Come on, let's go.
Corporal, we need
to have a chat.
HARRY: Did you sleep well?
Hmm?
No problems last night?
No, sir--
Harry.
Are you all right?
Yeah, everything's fine.
Just another day in--
Gasoline, oil, and oxygen.
It's highly combustible.
That's what makes
the engine go.
Yes, I know, but, uh, what I'm
wondering is whether, uh, well,
between here and where we're
going, we-- we wouldn't be
in harm's way at all, would we?
[gunfire]
Harry, are you positive
this is the only way?
It's the only fence
that's not patrolled.
- Get down!
- [cries]
HARRY: Down!
Down!
That would be the reason why.
OFFICER: Cease fire!
You, there!
That's no way to
treat your weapon.
Sir?
This here Ross rifle's a
terrible piece of junk.
Heats up.
Jams up all the time.
Breech explodes.
Can't shoot straight,
even if I'm trying to-
It's a poor workman
who blames his tools!
Yes, sir!
All right, listen
up, everybody.
SOLDIER: Get down!
Now let me tell you the Ross
repeater is the most perfect
military rifle in the world.
I helped modify it.
This weapon is the most
accurate weapon ever fired.
Every single one of you
should be able to pink
his enemy every time.
[laughs]
[gunshot]
Come on.
Come on, let's go.
Let's go.
Harry, I must say I
feel rather exposed.
Here, take Winnie.
Not to worry, with
this little beaut
we will be there
and back in no time.
There's not a lot of room
there for me and the bear,
is it?
What's that?
24-hour pass for both of us--
MACRAY: What?
HARRY: --signed by--
Barret!
WINNIE: [cries]
Do-- do you have any
idea what just occurred?
I think I do.
[music playing]
[crying]
All right, Winnie.
It's time for you
to do your business.
Still have a fair ways to go.
We don't want you to be doing
your business in the sidecar
as there's not much room for a
bear's business in the sidecar.
Harry, I've been, uh--
Thinking?
Indeed.
About?
Well, should anything
unfortunate occur,
I would like my mother to, um--
you see, she wasn't for this.
It would be my honor.
Thank you.
But it won't come to that.
Oh, no?
Well, you haven't swallowed
that home by Christmas nonsense,
have you?
No.
Then?
Faith.
That's funny.
What?
I wouldn't have taken you
for a man of the church.
Faith in you.
[chatter]
[roar]
WOMAN: Henry, come
look and at this!
MAN: He's a beast, isn't he?
Ah, look at him.
She is, uh, clean, isn't she?
It doesn't do to,
uh, muck up a zoo
with some mangy,
flea-ridden creature.
[crying]
They spread disease, you know.
Bears have their own
diseases, of course,
but they affect other animals.
Had a cross-infection between
a giraffe and a beaver once.
Very nasty.
Well, here we are.
One of our larger, more
spacious enclosures.
As secure and reliable
as the Pope has penury.
Oh, now listen.
I shouldn't worry.
She'll soon accustom herself.
They all do.
HARRY: Winnie's used to a fair
bit of human companionship, Mr.
Protheroe.
MACRAY: She-- She's
been tamed, you see.
Yeah, completely tamed.
Yes, well, no animal is ever
completely tame, are they?
Winnie's different.
Look, I can't take risks, not
as far as the general public
is concerned.
We know her.
Intimately.
Uh, well, so-- so to speak.
She needs human contact.
Yes, well, she'll have
me and the underkeepers.
We're perfectly convivial.
WINNIE: [cries]
I don't think you
understand, Mr. Protheroe.
Believe me, Lieutenant.
I have worked with bears
for the past 20 years.
Yes, they can be beguiling.
They have a-- a knack of
amusing us and putting
us at our ease, so to speak.
But believe me when
I tell you this,
you can never lower
your guard, not
for an instant, not with bears.
[crying]
I don't think Winnie
knows she's a bear.
Yes, well, listen,
I've got to lock up,
so you, uh, say
your final goodbyes.
All right?
WINNIE: [cries]
Hey, we have to go
away for a while, Winnie.
OK?
No place for bears, so
you have to stay here.
You understand?
Mr. Protheroe's going
to look after you now.
Stop.
Winnie.
Winnie, play fair.
Play fair.
[crying]
You're an impossible
bear, you know that?
This is what we're going to do.
I'm going to come back,
and we'll get in a ship.
And we'll go back to Canada.
We'll go home together, promise.
[music playing]
[crying]
You take care.
You'll be fine here.
All right?
[crying]
MACRAY [VOICEOVER]: Harry?
I've got a bad feeling.
[metal creaking]
[crying]
Time to eat, Winnie.
Lovely bits of fresh fruit.
I cut it meself.
Come on, girl.
Any luck?
Same as every day, sir.
Won't touch nothing.
That was peculiar.
What, sir?
Oh, the way she
just looked at me.
I could have sworn--
Just curious, probably.
No, it was more than that.
It was her eyes.
It wasn't like an animal at all.
It was as if she could
see what I was thinking.
Whatever she is, sir,
she's gonna starve.
Yeah, well, I'm afraid it
may be past that point already.
Well, she's really not looking
very well at all, is she?
No.
I don't like the look of her.
You know, I think she's
missing the soldiers.
[chatter]
WOMAN: Is it not very well?
What's wrong with the bear?
[music playing]
MRS. MCGUINESS: Oh, excuse me.
PROTHEROE: Yes, madam?
Have you seen a child come by?
A little girl.
She's wearing a
blue dress, and--
it's a green dress
with, um, brocade.
She had a little gold locket.
Her name is Muriel.
- Muriel?
Muriel McGuiness.
Oh.
Hello.
[music playing]
Do you like biccies?
Here you are.
Ahh!
WINNIE: [crying]
Uhh.
Ohh.
[cries]
Oh.
WINNIE: [cries]
- Muriel!
- Your gun, sir.
Muriel, sweetheart!
[gun cocks]
Darling, come to me!
UNDERKEEPER: The bear's escaped!
PROTHEROE: Miss McGuiness!
Muriel!
Oh.
MRS. MCGUINESS:
[WHISPERING] Muriel.
MURIEL: A little bear.
HARRY: Prime minister impatient
with his eccentric ways.
Well, that's a surprise.
[motorcycle engine]
SOLDIER: Come on, let's move it!
SOLDIER: All right, all right.
[inaudible] to
the Eastern flank.
Battalion's falling back.
Where are they coming from?
Through [inaudible] Wood.
Oof!
My men are there!
[chatter]
MACRAY: Pass me that one.
Thanks.
Here you go, Zeb.
Huh?
Do you like that?
We're going to
get you home, Zeb.
OK?
[chatter]
All right, come on.
You're a handsome
old man, huh.
[rocket screaming]
[explosion]
[whinnying]
[explosions]
[whinny]
[rocket screaming]
[explosion]
Elliot?
PRUSSIAN SOLDIER:
[speaking german]
[whicker]
Macray!
PRUSSIAN SOLDIER:
[speaking german]
[whickering]
Macray, it's Harry.
[CRYING] They're all gone.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, old man.
Macray, we've got
to get out of here.
I-- I was wrong, Harry.
I was dead wrong.
About what?
A man doesn't
become what he thinks.
He becomes what he does.
Macray!
[yells]
[yelling]
[machine gun fire]
Quick.
Harry!
I know the way.
This way now.
DOCTOR: So why don't you
step inside, and then I--
I'll have another look at it.
Won't go outside.
Won't leave the room.
Most days he won't
even get off bed.
Just lies there.
Doesn't let any of it out.
What those poor boys
had to go through.
BARRET: How can I help him?
Does he speak?
NURSE: Little, not much.
BARRET: About?
His friend, mostly,
the one who was killed.
Macray.
And sometimes at night,
he whispers a name.
His mother or
girlfriend, I suppose.
Do you know her, sir?
Who's that?
Winnie.
[chatter]
WOMAN: What's that?
MAN: Look!
What the-- What's
that doing here?
Gah, keep it away!
Gracious!
You might as well--
WOMAN: What is it?
What on earth!
Visitor for you,
Captain Colebourn.
[music playing]
Winnie!
It's you.
Look at you.
You got so big.
[chatter]
Hey, Winnie.
Good girl.
Yeah, good girl.
Yeah?
It's a remarkable bear!
Wave for Harry?
[music playing]
Missed you so much.
[crying]
I missed you.
Good bear.
Shh.
There's a good bear.
It's all over.
It's hard to imagine.
- You can go home.
- Home.
Winnie too, but this
time, not in my trunk.
Thank you, sir.
BARRET: You did a job, Harry.
You all did.
Fine brave hearts,
every one of you.
Thank you, General.
Transfer's all
in order, Captain.
Inoculation jabs,
delousing, and so forth.
Oh, the blue one you have to
show to immigration in Canada.
Shouldn't be a problem,
though, should it?
Of course, she's a
Canadian citizen.
Thank you very
much, Mr. Protheroe.
I'm very grateful for
everything you've done.
Grateful?
[laughs] That's a [inaudible].
Grateful.
She's the most infamous
animal in our keep, sir.
A fair bit of human
companionship,
I think that's how you put it.
Do you remember?
[children talking]
PROTHEROE: Ha!
I mean, look at them.
They can't keep away from her.
Horrible little hatchlings.
Overrun the entire
area, they do.
They come in droves.
And on Sundays, well, it
taxes a Christian heart.
Need a herd dog
to get them away.
I love my zoo, understand.
It's just those pesky little--
yes, well--
WINNIE: [crying]
PROTHEROE: --it's not
an issue anymore, is it?
Mr. Protheroe, what
would you say if--
what I'm thinking
is Winnie seems
to have find herself a home.
Home?
Here, at the zoo.
You can see how she adores them.
Them?
What do you mean--
Oh no, no, no.
Oh, no.
No, no, no, no.
You can't go back on your word.
Besides, I've already
given you the--
the paper--
No bear could be better loved
nor have a greater purpose.
The bear is not the problem.
It's them.
They-- They drop
their sticky wrappers.
They-- They kick up a ruckus.
They-- They scare the monkeys.
Animals are one thing kept, but
those sticky, thankless vermin.
I'd better say goodbye.
Hey.
I guess this is
it, old girl, huh?
Hmm?
Huh?
You know I'll come back
and see you, don't you?
Hey.
No, I promise.
[sighs]
Why am I telling
you anything, huh?
You're just a bear.
Extraordinary bear.
You know that, don't you?
Huh?
Of course you do.
You know I love you.
Huh?
You'll be fine.
[music playing]
[snuffling]
[cheering]
Where do you think she
lived before she lived here?
Where do you think, my boy?
Well, I imagine in the woods.
FATHER: You're probably right.
SON: What did she eat?
Why don't you ask Edward?
He's not Edward.
He's not?
Not anymore.
No?
He's Winnie.
FATHER: Winnie?
Yes.
There once was a
bear name Winnie.
Who lived in the wood.
And who loved to eat honey.
Honey!
[crowd calling for winnie]
[music playing]