It was about 3 years ago. I was
the only kid in church that day.
The others were with Isaac
out at the cornfield.
I didn't get to go
'cause dad didn't like Isaac.
He was pretty smart, my dad.
After church we've been
to Hansen's, just like always.
Sarah was homesick with mom.
She'd turned down with a fever.
- Morning, Dave.
- Morning.
- How are your wife and Sarah?
- Dad was worried...
so he went to call mom
first thing.
- I'm gonna call your mom, ok?
- Okay!
- You want the usual?
- Yeah, strawberty shake.
That's when I saw Malachai
and the others.
I guess the meeting with Isaac
was over.
They were acting real creepy.
- There you go, Jobie.
- Thanks.
- How is she?
- I'm worried, Dave.
The fever's gone
from 101 to 104.
Sure.
Okay.
Good coffee.
Oh, my God!
No!
It happened everywhere
in Gatlin that day.
That's when Sarah started
drawing these pictures.
Happy birthday!
What are you doing?
C'mon!
Make a wish.
What did you wish for?
To live happily ever after.
- Is that a proposal?
- No, it's not.
Well, I guess I'll
give you this anyway.
What is it?
- That's nice!
- Turn it over.
In honor of this special occasion
we'll have a birthday serenade.
1, 2.
1, 2, 3, 4.
No more books and studies
Now I can stay all day
With my buddies
I can do the things I wanna do
'Cause all my exams are through
I can root for the Yankees
From the beaches
And don't have to worry
About teachers
And I'm so glad
That school is out
I could sing and shout
School is out
Everybody's gonna have some fun
Everybody's gonna jump and run
C'mon, people
Don't you be late
I just got time
To take my girl out today
You're whacko.
Holy cow!
We better get going now.
I got a lot of driving to do today.
Couldn't wejust say
the hell with it...
- and stay for a couple of hours?
- I wish.
Starting Monday I've got
fifty patients a day to look at
- I've some things you could look at.
- Is that right?
Hello?
Maid service.
We'll be out in a minute.
We gotta get going.
I'm gonna grab a quick shower
before we go, okay?
C'mon, honey! You're making
something out of nothing.
To me is something,
to you is nothing.
I'm just worried about this
internship, okay?
I've been working forthis
forfouryears.
I know.
I do understand.
Why do you have to be
such ajerk about it?
Welcome to Nebraska.
We weren't the only ones
who thought Isaac was weird.
One day Joseph told us
he was running away.
He said he couldn't
take it anymore.
He was pretty scared.
I wasn't.
- I'm scared.
- Me too.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
I said I'd come back foryou.
I promise.
- Can we go with you? Please!
- No.
I'd never make it with you two.
- But we don't like it here.
- I said you'll be alright!
As long as nobody finds
that pictures you've been drawing.
She can't help it.
That won't matter
to Isaac and Malachai
They'll take it as a sign.
Anyway, you now crayons
and drawings are forbidden.
- Just like that record player.
- But we like it.
Isaac doesn't let us do anything.
Youjust better mind
until I get back.
Or else, you know what happens.
- Are you going through the corn?
- I can't go no other way.
- What if...
- I said it'll be alright.
- Unless you tell anybody I'm gone.
- We won't.
Cross your heat? Hope to die,
stick a needle in your eye.
You know what that means now?
If you tell, you're gonna burn in
a lake of fire for all eternity.
Make sure nobody's looking.
- Okay. Go!
- Nobody's looking.
I spy...
something that begins
with the letter "C".
- Corn.
- Right.
So now we know...
back roads are even less
interesting than the highways.
Maybe they've discovered music...
Hallelujah!
There are many Lord's mansions...
but there's no room
for the fornicator!
- No room!
- No room...
- for the homosexual!
- No room!
No room
for the drugs user!
No room!
Amen.
Peanut butter and white bread!
There's no room
forthe college graduated!
No room for people
who watch public television.
- No room for commitments!
- Amen!
C'mon!
Here it is.
- I wonder how it got here.
- Not me.
It looks like this one
goes to Grand Island...
and this one
cuts up to the highway.
Where's this Gatlin that we've
been seeing the signs for?
- It's not on here.
- How come? It's gotta be.
Look out!
Hang on.
Let me check.
- Where? Right there?
- Yeah.
It was just a bump.
Just tty to relax.
That was an animal, right?
I gotta go back there, okay
Just stay here and tty to rest.
C'mon, buddy.
Oh God!
- Is he...
- Oh yeah.
- Oh God!
- Easy, easy. C'mon.
Easy.
Don't look at him.
Now listen to me.
There's something vety wrong here.
So I want you to go back to the car
and wait for me there. Understand?
- And keep the doors locked.
- Why? Where are you going?
I'll tell you when I get back.
Just do what I say.
Burt.
I'm so sorty.
- Vicky, c'mon.
- Burt!
- Easy. Calm down.
- I kneeled down next to him.
It's ok. Take it easy.
Take it easy and relax.
It's okay, understand?
You're okay.
Me and Sarah were playing in our
old house. We play there lots.
Malachai said it was forbidden.
But I think that's because nobody
ever asked him to play.
When I grow up, I'm gonna have
all the money in the world.
- Me too.
- You can't.
- Why not?
- 'Cause I'm gonna have it.
- I'll get it first.
- Will not.
- Will too.
- Oh yeah? How?
Seven.
One, two, three, four,
five, six...
seven.
Alright! See?
Two hundred dollars.
No, Jobie!
How much?
- Thirteen thousand hundred dollars.
- Thirteen thousand hundred dollars?
Okay, two thousand.
I thought so.
One hundred, two hundred, three...
I gotta a great idea.
Let's pretend this guy is Isaac
and we'll put him injail.
What if he gets to get out
ofjail with a free card?
What card?
You think it might've been some
accident with farm equipment?
Not like that.
His throat was cut deliberately.
He was already dead
when he stumbled down the road.
Whoever killed him,
do you think he saw us?
- I felt like we're being watched.
- Possible.
Blood starts to coagulate
in four minutes.
When I went to get the suitcase
it was still fresh.
- He could have been out there!
- I couldn'tjust leave it there.
What if it holds
some sort of clue?
- Let's open it.
- No.
Let's just get to a phone
or a house or some place.
Malachai took us
right to Isaac.
He'd finally convinced him
punishing us for being unbelievers.
Up to them, we've been forgiven
'cause we were in the corn...
the day that "He Who Walks Behind
the Rows" made himself known.
That bothered Malachai.
He had a lot of problems.
I found these two
in one of the old homes...
they had a game, music...
and this.
They come already.
You have the gift of sight.
- This is a blessing, my child.
- I've seen this car up on the road.
Go to the old man.
Make sure he tells them nothing.
What about these two?
Take them back
where they were.
But they had a game and music.
They're forbidden.
Question me not, Malachai.
I act according to His will.
It seems we are in the Moon.
We haven't even seen a truck.
We'll be in Gatlin soon.
Do you think he lived there?
We may never knowthat.
I really thing we should open it.
Okay.
Let's see if we can get
some news.
I'm getting tired of that crap.
What is it?
- Jesus Christ!
- Not in my Book.
- It looks like primitive folk art.
- I think it's repulsive.
Sarge, bring the number six.
Damn it!
You better give me the eight.
C'mon.
We haven't got all day.
Good boy.
We'll have that transmission fixed
in no time...
then, we'll get on the radiator.
Damn. This road is becoming
a bloody highway.
I think it's the third car
in a month.
We know what to do, don't we?
We better put that suitcase away.
I'll be right back.
- Hi, we got a...
- I ain't got no gas.
- I don't need gas.
- I ain't got no diesel.
- You don't understand. I need...
- lf you don't buy gas...
you can't use the rest room.
- I need to use your phone.
- Telephone?
I ain't got no telephone.
Sarge.
Sarge, you be still.
You have to go to Hemingford.
It's about 19 miles down there.
- What about Gatlin?
- There ain't nothing in Gatlin.
What do you mean:
"There ain't nothing in Gatlin."?
Folks in Gatlin got religious.
They don't like outsiders...
and they probably won't have
a phone there either.
I'd like to stay here and talk,
but I got a transmission to fix.
If you get on that road
you'll be in Hemingford in no time.
- Right.
- Sarge, sit! At ease!
Thanks a lot.
Sarge!
Eitherthat man is senile, or he's
being out in the Sun fortoo long.
Sarge!
Come back here.
Come back here!
Under the awning!
You hear me?
Come back here.
That's an order.
Who is it?
Is that you?
What do you want?
What are you doing there?
Well, there really isn't that much
stuff in here. Just kids' stuff.
Clothes, matches,
compass, pocket knife.
- I don't get it. Camping stuff?
- Yeah.
Oh, great!
This must be our day.
In the last sign we saw
Gatlin was 3 miles...
- and pointed that way?
- That's what I thought.
- Did I miss a turn?
- No, we've been going straight.
Somebody's been
messing with the signs.
Hemingford is gotta be
straight ahead.
Must have been the wind.
These latches ain't worth a damn.
Blow all for nothing.
I nevertold them nothing.
I swear it.
I kept our bargain
just like always.
Jesus Christ! Gatlin! What do they
have? Amonopoly on road signs?
What about Hemingford?
For people who don't like visitors
they sure do advertise enough.
Overthere.
Of course, it's the wind.
Why did you have to go
afterthem, Sarge?
You bastards!
You can't do this to me.
I know you're in here.
C'mon! C'mon!
I can smell you, you stinky
little skunks.
C'mon!
Murderers little devils!
- What was that?
- Probably my golf bag.
- Are you sure?
- What do you mean: "Am I sure."?
This isn't even a road.
- We'll never gotta get out of here.
- We'll too. Stop it.
Sorty.
- Just tell me where we are.
- I don't know.
We're back where we started from.
We never should have listen
to that old fool.
Hemingford is 19 miles,
Gatlin is only 3.
I don't care how much religious
they've got. We're going there.
Don't ever show up
in my emergency room, buddy.
Behold.
Adream did come to me in the
night. And the Lord show all to me.
Praise God!
Praise the Lord.
Atime of tribulation has come.
Atest is at hand.
- The final test.
- What has the Lord commanded?
In the dream...
the Lord did come to me
and he was a shape.
It was He Who Walks
Behind The Rows.
And I did fall on my knees
in terror and hide my eyes...
unless the fierceness of His face
struck me dead.
He told me all
that it since happened.
He said:"Joseph has taken his
things and fled this happy place...
because the worship of me
is no more upon him...
so take you his life
and spill his blood".
- He did?
- Yes.
"But let not the flesh
pollute the corn.
- Cast him instead upon the road."
- And so was done.
Joseph, the betrayer,
was cast out.
And He Who Walks
Behind the Rows did say...
"I will send outlanders
amongst you.
Aman and a woman.
And these outlanders...
will be unbelievers
and profaners of the holy".
- I thought Isaac never came here.
- But he's always been here.
Just like He Who Walks
Behind The Rows.
"And the man shall
sorely test you...
for He has great power. Even
greaterthan that of the blue man.
The blue man!
Yes, the blue man!
And just as the blue man
was offered upon to Him...
- so shall be the unbelievers!
- Make sacrifice unto Him.
Bring the blood
of the outlanders.
Praise God!
Praise The Lord!
Let's get out of here!
Praise God!
Praise The Lord!
It looks like a swinging place.
I guess nobody told them
we were coming.
I hope not.
I don't see anybody.
Town Hall.
Grocety store. Hansen's Cafe.
It seems they got a phone.
Unless a ghost is using it.
- What is it with this corn?
- You got me.
Is dead.
Just like evetything else here.
- A rat.
- Yeah. Just an ordinaty rat.
Now can we
get out of here, please?
Wait a minute!
Come back here!
C'mon, Vicky. Hurty up.
I don't wanna lose them.
What are you gonna do
if you catch them?
Ask where we can get help.
What else?
They just got off that way.
Damn!
Where did they go?
We're already in the car. Why
wouldn't wejust go to Hemingford?
- That would take us 20 minutes.
- We'd just found people.
Yeah, three kids
that tried to steal our car.
There's something
vety strange about this town.
We'd be better off
in a biggertown anyway.
- The size of Seattle.
- Yeah.
- Overthere!
- What?
- I just saw a door open and close.
- I didn't see anything.
- Let's check it out.
- Why? I thought we were going.
- Settle down.
- Don't patronize me.
I'm not patronizing you. I just
wanna see if there's someone there.
Hello?
Anybody home?
We've had an accident.
We need to use your phone.
Okay.
Now can we go?
- Burt, this is somebody's house.
- I know. I just want a phone.
Hello?
Gross.
I'll check out the back.
I found the phone.
Matches the decor.
This is three years old.
I don't understand
what's going on here.
Well, can we go?
Burt!
Hello?
Anybody here?
Don't be afraid.
We didn't mean to scare you.
Hi!
- What's your name?
- Sarah.
Sarah!
That's a beautiful name.
- This is Burt and I'm Vicky.
- Are you here alone, Sarah?
Do you live here?
Youjust come here to play?
- Are your mommy and daddy around?
- They're in the corn field.
- What are they doing there?
- All the grown ups are there.
Are they working there
or having a meeting?
No. Isaac put them there.
Who's Isaac?
- Sweetheart, tell us who Isaac is.
- Our leader.
Leader of what?
Evetybody.
Of course.
Listen,
could you take us to Isaac?
- Why not?
- He's scaty.
It's vety important we speak to
some grown ups as soon as possible.
- We're wasting ourtime, Vicky.
- Give her a chance.
I'm gonna go look
at the Town Hall.
Why?
Because we have a murder
to report...
and we're walking in circles,
wasting ourtime.
- Maybe she can help.
- Fine. You stay here with her.
Things aren't happening fast.
I'm gonna leave you the car.
I won't be gone vety long.
If anybody comes, honk. Okay?
Are we safe?
Yes. It's weird here,
but it's safe.
I'll be back.
So, it looks like it's just
you and me.
What were you doing here
by yourself? Just playing records?
Come on, you can tell me.
Drawing.
Drawing...
- what's so secret about drawing?
- I'm not supposed to.
You're not supposed to draw?
- Who says? Isaac?
- Malachai.
Malachai?
Why don't you draw me a picture
we won't tell Isaac...
or Malachai
or anybody?
- How's that sound?
- Okay.
- How's it coming?
- Fine.
- What did you draw?
- You.
You did?
Can I see?
What is this?
Burt?
Burt, is that you?
Somebody here?
Who are you?
What do you want?
We want to give you peace.
Seize her.
Come on! Get her!
Let's finish it!
No!
Burt!
- Are we safe?
- Yes, it's weird here, but it's safe.
Help me!
Where are you taking me?
Help!
Vicky!
Sarah, what happened here?
What happened?
Where's Vicky?
You've gotta think.
Think.
What happened to her?
Please!
Does He speak to you, Isaac?
He speaks to me always.
But today he's displeased.
He's displeased with you,
Malachai.
What have I done?
Question Him not in vain.
Do you not know you sacrificed
Joseph without an offering?
And did you not spill the blood
of the old man...
when his oil and gasoline
were still useful to us?
We have our own fuel now
from the corn.
Sow not your pride, Malachai.
We have not enough.
Maybe He's displeased
that we have not offered Him...
- Sarah and Jobe.
- Sarah has the gift of sight.
She warned us of the coming
of the interlopers.
Question not my judgment,
Malachai.
I am the giver of His word.
Go you and bring me the husband.
We must offerthem tonight
when Amos leaves.
Sarah, come on.
Tell me what happened to her.
Look at me!
Think!
- What?
- Malachai.
Who's Malachai?
What do you mean?
Vicky?
Kill! Kill! Kill!
Nowthe blood of Amos
will be shared.
Stop it!
Stop that!
Hold the outlander!
What the hell is going on here?
Are you crazy?
What do you think you're doing?
My passage.
It's my birthday.
You've got a pretty sick way
of celebrating it, pal.
Silence, interloper!
Your presence profanes
this holy place.
- He will wreck with you.
- Great. I don't know who He is.
Maybe He'd like to discuss
what's going on here with me.
- It says it should be...
- Amos!
- It says it is written.
- Speak no more to him!
He is an unbeliever.
Hurty, get Isaac!
No! Wait!
Bring Malachai.
What do you mean: "As it's
written? "Written where?
What? In this?
Are you rewriting the whole thing
orthe parts that suit your needs?
- Back off!
- Sit down!
What do we have here?
Nineteen, eighteen...
What is this?
- These people died so young!
- Not died.
We go to Him the first night
of our nineteenth year.
Who the hell is Him?
He Who Walks
Behind The Rows.
Malachai comes!
Seize him!
Back off!
Seize him.
Do not let him escape.
Where is he?
Come on!
There he is. Go get him!
You! Go that way!
I need your help!
Come on!
Come on, help me
Help me!
Outlander!
He's here.
- Got you.
- This isn't a game.
Back off!
Outlander!
Go get him!
Check the doors!
You guys go back to the alley.
You, overthere. You two follow me.
Shit!
Damn it!
Hey, mister!
I know a place to hide.
But we gotta hurty.
- Who are you?
- Jobe. Stop asking questions.
Come on!
Will you come on?
Careful.
Don't be a scared cat.
- Come on. It's only me and Sarah.
- Sarah?
Yes, my sister.
Isn't that nice?
My dad built it...
when the communists launched
theirfirst strike.
I don't think it's the communists
we have to worty about.
Don't worty.
Nobody knows about this place.
It's secret.
- Those guys are friends of yours?
- No way!
They listen to Isaac
and Malachai.
- Who are Isaac and Malachai?
- Isaac started the whole thing.
If he hadn't come,
this would never have happened.
When he was young,
he was a preacher...
so evetybody believed him.
They thought he had
a great spirit.
I thought he was weird.
We must sacrifice
them both tonight.
Amos will satisfy Him.
We need the woman.
- She'll bring the man to us.
- No.
He must be taken
without her.
We cannot remove her
from this place. It is holy.
We'll bring the Lord two
by using one.
Do not blaspheme, Malachai.
You know not the laws.
He speaks them only to me.
I think not, Isaac.
You are the one who's lost
favor with Him.
He's a God of blood
and sacrifice, not ceremonies.
Sacrilege!
Down on your knees, heretic!
Shut your mouth, Isaac!
You've grown proud farfrom us.
He Who Walks Behind The Rows
will decide yourfate.
Don't you sit there, seize him!
Punish him, cut him down.
I command you!
I am the word and the giver
of His laws.
Disobedience to me
is disobedience to Him.
Do it now oryour punishment
will be a thousand times...
a thousand deaths, each more
horrible than the last.
They're tired of yourtalk.
I've showed them what I can do.
Cut the woman down.
Put Isaac in her place.
We'll see howthe Lord
favors you.
Dare not to blaspheme.
He will punish you.
The God of hell will devouryou.
All of you!
No! No!
When my dad wouldn't get up
I ran from Hansen...
to get Officer Hodgekiss.
But it was too late.
Why?
What happened to him?
He got away at that time.
He went to the barn
after he talked to the minister.
Minister?
- What happened to the minister?
- Malachai.
Outlander!
You, overthere.
He's coming.
Outlander!
We have your woman.
She still lives.
Outlander!
Maybe you don't hear so well.
Her blood will spill
unless you give yourself up.
We won't wait much longer.
The night is coming.
Night is His time.
Outlander!
Come on!
Come on, outlander!
Are you looking forthat lady?
- Yes, you know where she is?
- They took her out to the clearing.
- What clearing? Where?
- In the corn field.
- Are you sure?
- Of course I'm sure.
I followed them,
just like I followed you.
Show me.
- Okay.
- Come on, let's go.
Okay.
Quiet.
Come on.
Follow me to the barn.
Careful.
I'm ready to celebrate
my birthday.
Malachai!
He will not forgive you.
None of you will be forgiven.
All of you shall feel His wrath!
We have a surprise foryou,
Amos.
Isaac is gonna keep you company.
I am the word
and the giver of His laws.
This is the end!
Come on.
Over here.
You can see evetything from here.
Okay, you two...
you stay here and wait for me.
All right?
But if anything happens to me...
you get to Hemingford
as fast as you can.
You get on that road
and don't get off it. Understand?
Go past the irrigation pump.
It's Him.
He's come for me.
He's come to welcome me.
I'm here, Lord.
I'm ready.
Take me now, Lord.
Your will, Lord.
My passage.
I did it right.
I swear it.
I did evetything You wanted!
No! No!
Stop!
Vicky, come on,
run to the barn!
He hit Malachai!
- Seize him.
- Take that.
Vicky, get out of here!
Was it like that with your
parents? Was it?
Just because some suck
proclaims himself a holy man...
and says God commands?
What kind of God tells children
to kill their parents?
Answer me that, buddy.
Did you hearthat
before Isaac? Did you?
I can't believe
you're this blind.
Maybe you've been listening
to this holy roller so long...
that all starts to sound the same.
But it's not!
Any religion without love
and compassion is false.
It's a lie!
Is he dead?
Is this what you want?
Is it what He commands?
I don't think so.
Get him!
Stop him!
Kill him!
Malachai!
He wants you too, Malachai.
He wants you too.
- Vicky?
- Burt? Over here!
- Are you okay?
- Yes.
Get down.
Get some help and get
those doors closed. Quick.
Rudolf, Robert, come on!
- What do we do?
- I don't know.
If I knew what it was,
I could tell you.
It's He Who Walks
Behind The Rows.
What if we tried to make it
to the road?
I think we're safer here,
for now.
Has anybody evertried
to hurt the monster?
Any of the adults, your parents
before they were killed?
The Blue Man!
Who is the Blue Man?
What did he do?
Officer Hodgekiss.
I told you.
He came down here
after he talked to the minister.
He was reading a page
torn out from the Bible...
and it was working
with distil.
What was he reading
at the Bible?
What was it?
Do you know?
You have it?
Hurty up. Where is it?
"And the devil
that deceived them...
was cast into the lake of fire
and sulphur.
Where the beast and the false
prophet shall be tormented...
day and night,
for ever and ever."
What's that supposed to mean?
What was the Blue Man
doing at the distil?
He hooked the hose
and he was ttying to roll it out.
- What stopped him?
- Malachai.
Lake of fire. Fire!
He was gonna burn the field.
Oh, yes.
The alcohol from the distil.
- How?
- Never mind, never mind.
Kids, you bring me as many hoses
as you can find. Quick!
Jobie and Sarah. Find me a bottle.
Aglass bottle.
Quick!
Move!
Vicky, come here!
Over here!
It doesn't fit.
There's gotta be a connector
here somewhere.
Tty this.
Get somebody
to hold this on tight.
- Okay.
- Hang on to it. You got one. Good!
Vicky, see if you can find me
a thick rag.
Jobie, come here.
Hey, this is not a rag.
Get them to hold on that tight.
Open it up when I get there.
All right?
All right.
Be careful.
I love you, Vicky.
What are you doing here?
Get back to the barn.
Hurty up!
Go on!
Move! Now!
Excuse me!
Get that valve. Quick.
Do you know howto run
this thing?
- Crank it!
- What?
Crank it.
Push the button at the top.
Now!
- Get the bottle!
- Okay!
Jobie!
Come back here!
Run, come on, run!
- Jobie!
- Here's the bottle!
Throw it!
It's the right time!
Burt!
Jobie!
- Vicky!
- Sarah!
Jobie!
Look!
Come on! Come on!
Let's go!
- Is he dead?
- I think so.
Then why are we still running?
- Just keep going!
- Where did you get this guy?
Hemingford is 19 miles
right?
- We'll walk?
- Sure.
Are you sure
you're strong enough?
I'm okay. And you?
Are you okay?
I'll make it.
I got a great doctor.
Jealous?
So what do we do with these
two little kids?
I don't know.
You guys wanna stay with us
for a couple of days?
How about a week?
Okay.
- How about a month?
- No.
All right. All right.
I'll grab the map.
- Interloper! No!
- God!
You must die!
Oh, boy!
She's out cold.
What are we gonna do now?
Send her a card from Seattle.
Let's get out of here.