Constable, a boat's blown in
with the storm.
God.
Come on!
Fletcher?
I went aboard, sir,
to see if anyone was alive.
And?
What's that?
Captain's log.
This log is a record
and a warning.
And if it finds you,
God help you,
as he has abandoned
the Demeter.
We tried to stop him.
If we didn't succeed,
God have mercy on your souls.
I can't go back, sir.
Come on.
Orginal Sub By ViKramJS
Resync By M_I_S
www.opensubtitles.org
Hey!
Hey, mister! Sit down!
It's your turn.
Come on, wake up.
Let's go back home.
Oppa!
Sixth of July,
made port in Varna, Bulgaria.
Don't wander far, Toby.
We're not staying long.
I won't, Grandpa. I promise.
Our crew was a few hands short.
Captain.
And I have tasked Mr. Wojchek
to remedy this
before we take on cargo.
The Demeter is looking for
hands all the way to England.
I fold.
Open your ears, men.
Demeter needs
three able-bodied seamen.
Bound for London.
We pay in gold.
I'm able.
And strong as an ox.
Who are you, boy?
Clemens.
You dress like an educated man.
Where did you go to school?
University of Cambridge.
I have a steady hand
with a needle, and, uh...
I have supplies if you're
in need of a ship doctor.
I-It's been a while,
but I-I do know
my way around a boat, if not.
Learning about boats ain't
the same as keeping one afloat.
What did the sailor
ever learn from a book
that did him an ounce of good
when he was lost at sea?
Astronomy, for one.
Can lose a chart.
You can lose a compass.
But you can't lose
the stars, can you?
Never met an Englishman in such
a hurry to return to England.
Be gone as soon as we reach it,
no doubt.
We need strong crew,
not passengers.
Me?
You.
No, never mind you.
What's he saying?
He says they cannot stay.
The hell they can't.
We need their hands
or we lose the tide.
He says they need to leave
before the sun sinks.
What kind of nonsense is that?
For your men.
We go now.
Men!
This is more than I paid
to bring the damn cargo here.
What did he spit at the end?
"Good leave"
or "good riddance"?
"Good luck."
Come on, pull!
Pull!
See, let go. Let go!
Toby!
Are you all right, boy?
Toby?
Mr. Wojchek, hold that man!
You never said
nothing about dragons.
I know this mark.
It is a bad omen.
You could have killed the boy.
I don't give a whore's ass
about dragons!
Keep your gold,
the devil's serpent.
God save you all.
May he save the ship.
May he save the crew.
Are you all right?
-You injured?
-Mm-mm.
-Thank you, Mr. Clemens.
-Yeah, sure.
We leave port within the hour.
You prove to be lying about
knowing your way around a boat,
I'll throw you off the boat
myself, astronomer.
Uh, th-thank you, sir.
Larsen, get this stinking bunch
of cockroaches underway.
You heard Mr. Wojchek.
Olgaren,
get those crates stowed.
Come on.
Good boy!
Cast off! Ready the headsails.
Pull in the moorings!
Be quick about it!
Pull!
-Pull! -WOJCHEK: Give me
a way to steer.
She moves like a fat pig
with all this weight.
Do you see that beam up there?
That's where they used to hang
pirates and mutineers.
Have you ever seen
a real dead man, Mr. Clemens?
I have.
-Really?
-Let me show you the ship.
Captain's cabin's
that big door.
There's lots of maps
and drawings in there,
but captain
doesn't like me fiddling.
This here is Huckleberry.
-Oh.
-But we just call him Huck.
Hello, Huck.
That's the cargo hold.
Everything there is
headed for London.
You knock on wood like this
if there's any trouble.
Or to signal a change of watch
or if the sky's looking fierce.
You can hear it
all the way from the bunks
to the captain's
on a clear night.
-I swear.
-Mm.
I've heard it.
Yes, I believe you have.
This is where we eat.
This used to be a lumber ship,
built the old way.
But now everyone wants
steam ships.
Captain says there's no joy
in metal ships.
Well, that's the thing
about progress, innit?
It cares not for joy,
your captain's or otherwise.
The Demeter's a fine boat.
No doubt.
Meet my crew, Mr. Clemens.
The faster we eat them,
the less crap
I have to clean up.
Mm.
Ah-ah, Huck.
You know the rules.
And up here is the galley.
-Joseph.
-Huh?
This here is Clemens.
He's a doctor. A real one.
We eat at six bells--
no sooner, no later.
You stay out of the galley.
And I won't serve any man who
takes the Lord's name in vain.
-He means that last one.
-I mean all of them.
Do you know
who Saint Nicholas is?
Patron saint of sailors.
Well, you're not a heathen.
Thank the Lord
for small favors.
Toby, show him to his quarters.
And get this mutt
out of my kitchen.
Huck!
On sixth July,
we finished taking in cargo--
Turkish cotton,
ten barrels of petroleum
and private crates
marked for London--
with nine hands.
Crew of five, one ship doctor,
two mates, cook
and myself, captain.
Fair wind.
Crew in high spirits.
♪ Oh, they call me
Hangin' Johnny... ♪
All is well, Captain.
Making about 12 knots
on the nor'easter.
Wheel's kicking a bit,
but she'll settle down.
12 knots?
We'll reach London
well before August the sixth.
Aye, sir.
For the crew's sake, we better.
Already finding ways
to spend the bonus pay.
♪ The holy family ♪
♪ So hang, boys, hang ♪
♪ They say
I hung my mother... ♪
I've decided this is to be
my final voyage, Mr. Wojchek.
I'm going to buy
a little cottage in Ireland.
Toby will enjoy
the countryside.
And I promised my daughter
I wouldn't let the sea air
bleach the future out of him.
I intend to keep that promise.
I will arrange for you
to be my successor
as captain of the Demeter
as soon as we reach London.
Sir, I...
You're a good seaman,
Mr. Wojchek.
The ship couldn't ask for a
better hand to guide her crew.
♪ Away, boys, away ♪
♪ They call me Hangin' Johnny ♪
♪ So hang, boys, hang. ♪
800 pounds eight ways,
and minus the captain
and first mate's share,
comes to round about...
75 each.
-75?
-Gonna get myself
a proper shave and one of them
waistcoats with the tails on.
Ooh, the English ladies
love them tails.
Almost... almost as much
as they love me.
If you put them
over your face, mm, maybe.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
You're the funny ones,
aren't you?
What are you lot
gonna do with yours?
"The generous soul
will be made rich,
and he who waters
will also be watered himself."
Although the Lord
might not mind
if I just simply
watered myself.
Oi! 75!
Do you know
what I will do this much?
The same thing
that you always do, Petrofsky.
Find the nearest brothel
and spend the next month
absolutely up to
your gills in...
Mr. Abrams, if you please.
Apologies, Captain.
- Forgot about the lad.
- I'm almost nine.
I know
what a brothel is, anyway.
Do you, now?
Yeah.
It's a place we pay women
to take off their knickers.
Ah, I love kids!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Well, isn't it?
Oh, close enough, lad.
Close enough.
Well, Mr. Clemens,
what about you?
-Sir?
-Our charter has agreed
to pay a sizable bonus
for timely arrival
of his cargo in London.
You're part of the crew,
which means you earn
a crewman's share.
How do you plan spending it?
A new petticoat, perhaps?
Well, everything I desire
in this life, unfortunately,
coin will be of no aid.
And what would that be, now?
To understand this world.
The more of it I see,
the less any of it makes sense.
The world cares little
for sense, Mr. Clemens.
Perhaps it is not meant
to be understood
but rather experienced
and accepted.
Perhaps.
But I need to get
to the heart of it.
And understand why
the world has so much goodness
inside it and yet...
Isn't that
what all men desire, mm?
Deep down.
Well, hell, he's right.
I'll have his share, then.
What the devil is that?
Toby. See to the livestock.
Toby?
What's gotten into them?
It's probably just the weather.
Hey, they can sense
a storm coming.
Toby, give me a hand with this.
That should put them to rest.
What was that, Mr. Clemens?
Fetch the captain, lad.
Tell him something fell
in the cargo hold.
Stay with me.
Come on.
-What in the seven hells?
-She was below deck.
A stowaway.
A stowaway who is going to die
if we don't administer
proper medical care.
You want to help her?
Who knows what kind of diseased
rat infections she has...
-Captain.
-What do you need?
Her body's infected.
I need to attempt
a transfusion.
-What are you babbling?
-A blood transfusion.
She needs blood
to fight the infection.
You're joking.
You are of aid to me or you are
in my way and need to leave.
In either case,
please make yourself apparent
and fulfill your purpose.
She'll make it the
night, but I need to continue
with the transfusions until
she has no more infected blood.
We've done all we can.
Then maybe she'll
wake up in time to see us
toss her to the waves.
We let Poseidon deal
with stowaways-- always have.
I didn't save this girl's life
only to watch you end it.
At least let us off
at the next port.
"Us," is it?
I see where your loyalty lies,
Mr. Clemens.
We stop, then we forfeit
the bonus wage.
And I ain't
forfeiting the bonus wage
for you or your diseased whore.
Mr. Wojchek, lower your voice.
Control your language.
I would prefer not to have
my final voyage
at the helm of the Demeter
marred by the death
of a young woman.
Stowaway or not.
We will repurpose
the carpenter shed
-as the young woman's quarters.
-Thank you, sir.
And you will be solely dividing
your own rations
with your patient, Mr. Clemens.
Toby.
-You'll look after her for me,
will you? -Mm-hmm.
Anyone tries to see her,
you come get me
-or the captain straightaway,
you understand? -Yeah.
All right, then. Go on.
That's a good lad.
You're making
all sorts of friends,
aren't you, Mr. Clemens?
Woman on the ship.
Bad omen. Hmm?
Bad luck.
Men won't be happy.
The men don't need to be happy,
do they, Mr. Olgaren?
They just need to get this boat
to London, huh?
I'm trying to help you, son.
Keep spouting words like that.
Maybe she'll make it
to London, but...
but I reckon
you'll be swimming.
Knock if you need me.
-Saves the pipes.
-Mm.
-Understand?
-Aye!
Islands and rocks
everywhere here.
So we're in the Aegean, yes?
It's the Mediterranean at dawn.
It's good time, innit?
Greece should be
to our starboard.
Mr. Olgaren?
Olgaren?
Jesus Christ!
Did you see it?
Did no one pass by?
See what?
There's no one on deck but us.
There is something out there.
Someone.
What the...
Oh, God, Huck.
All the livestock?
Any man with knowledge
of this heinous act
needs to step forward now or
find themselves in irons later.
The girl...
Was in no shape
to do anything of the sort,
and Mr. Wojchek can attest to
that, even if he'd rather not.
Aye.
He's right on this.
She didn't need to.
We all know.
Bad luck, woman on board.
Makes skies turn,
animals go mad.
The dog was ripped into.
Perhaps he went rabid
and was gored by
one of the larger livestock
as it attacked it.
You think Huck did this?
Ripped apart the animals?
No. He's a good dog.
You heard the man.
Rabies. Bad luck is all.
Push on through as we always do.
If this is an outbreak,
then we'll need to make port.
-Captain... -No. No. -No,
we won't make our bonus, then.
What are you talking about?
Then we lose the bonus wage.
We can't make port. No.
Mr. Clemens,
a malady of this sort,
could a human catch it?
No.
Rabies, it-it can't pass to
a human without it being bit.
Dispose of the meat.
Immediately.
I guess we say
the Lord's Prayer
over cabbage and potatoes
for the rest of our voyage.
Have you all been struck dumb?
It's not rabies that opened up
the livestock cages.
And there is only
two people on this boat
I have not sailed with fore now:
the cy in the toolshed
and this darky savage
pretending to be doctor.
Mm?
Say it again.
No man did this.
Evil is on board.
Powerful evil.
Anna.
That bloody reeks.
Toby?
Hey.
Huck was a good dog, son.
I'm sorry.
It wasn't just Huckleberry.
I promised the captain I--
It was my job
to look after them.
The animals, I mean.
I-I promised the captain.
Hmm.
Toby...
sometimes things go wrong,
no matter what we promise.
All right?
There are things in this world
that we can't control,
but we do our best. Hmm?
Yeah.
Thanks, Mr. Clemens.
Go on.
The skies are angry.
The skies
feel nothing, my friend.
It's precipitation
and air pressure,
as knowable as
the workings of this ship.
I saw something last night.
There is something unnatural
on board with us.
I'm afraid I don't believe
in superstitions, Mr. Olgaren.
I believe in science
and in nature.
And in Saint Nicholas,
since Joseph wouldn't
give me food otherwise.
Keep your science.
I saw your face
in the dark last night.
Your eyes.
You saw it, same as I.
16th of July.
Rough weather last three days
and all hands busy with sails.
Our ship's doctor continues
to administer regular
transfusions to our stowaway,
yet her condition
remains unchanged.
Food is running sparse,
men downcast,
and now past Cape Matapan,
we've more than two weeks
to travel.
Her name is Anna.
She told you that?
Has she been awake?
Mr. Olgaren taught me
some Romani.
She speaks some English
sometimes, too.
She didn't say this one
so much, but...
I don't think
she's having very nice dreams.
She repeats a word
over and over.
"Feed."
Can't sleep?
You noticed it, too, then.
The rats.
Still quiet.
I was checking the larder.
They're all gone.
Gone? What do you mean gone?
I mean what I say. Gone.
Always a dozen or so
in the woodwork,
screeching, scrabbling.
Well, if... if Huck went rabid,
perhaps, before the livestock,
he drove them off...
You could burn this ship
to the keel, Mr. Clemens,
and the rats would
just nest in the ashes.
Something drove them off.
A boat without rats,
such a thing is against nature.
Abrams?
Playing some kind
of fool's joke.
Idiots playing games, huh?
Abrams?
Where the hell
did you come from?
Petrofsky?
The knife was found here?
And the wheel was tied off?
Petrofsky must have been drunk.
Slipped on the deck
and fell overboard.
Right after he bled
all over the deck?
And what were you doing up
in the middle of the night?
You had his knife in your hand
when we found you.
Of course. I-I killed him.
And somehow managed
to keep myself
free of all the blood
you see staining the boards,
then I rang the signal bell
to report myself.
It's quite brilliant,
innit, Mr. Wojchek?
Open-and-shut case.
Captain, the dog's body,
I examined it.
It wasn't killed in the larder
like the other animals.
It had bite marks on its neck.
All the animals did.
What exactly are you
suggesting, Mr. Clemens?
I don't know, sir,
but their arteries were
ripped open, and then they...
He's here.
He is here.
We have to get off this boat.
Now!
All of us!
We have to get off this boat!
- Mr. Clemens, restrain
your patient. -
-Now! He will kill us all!
-Please! Anna, please!
-Anna, please! Please!
-Kill us all!
Get off the boat.
Captain will say a few words
from the good book,
and we'll get on with things.
There's not enough liquor
on board to get Petrofsky
-drunk enough to fall off...
-Mr. Abrams.
Are we not gonna listen to
the lass and what she just...
I'll spend no more time
discussing anything
but the state of this boat
and the weather.
Understood, Mr. Abrams?
Get to work.
18th of July.
Men reported in the morning
that one of the crew,
Petrofsky, was missing.
I had the men do
a thorough search of the ship.
This after Olgaren confided
that he had seen something
strange nights before.
These blood transfusions
should keep your infection
under control.
So, what were you trying
to tell us out there?
He is here on the ship.
He has been all along.
He?
Okay.
I can't help you
if you don't speak to me
and tell me what happened,
why we found you below deck.
It is spoken in my village
of an evil
that lives
in the mountains above.
A castle older than any of us.
-Evil?
-An evil that appears as a man
when it wants to hide
its true nature.
And at night, he feeds
on the blood of the innocent.
I have lived in the shadow
of that castle my whole life.
I knew that the elders, they...
they made bargains
for the safety of our people.
You were given to this man?
-It is not a man.
-Then an animal?
No, it is not
some mindless animal either.
Do not make that mistake.
We call him Dracula.
And you-you believe
that he brought you on board?
Why?
He brought me here to feed.
Dear God.
He is here, Mr. Clemens.
The thing that wears
the skin of a man.
In the night,
it drinks our blood,
and he is on this ship.
Which means
that we will never leave it.
The woman,
she seems harmless, but...
ever since she came on board,
I wonder if...
if we would have been better
just to let the ocean have her.
But then I think about
my daughter.
She's around her age and...
smart and-and pretty.
Olgaren?
What's wrong?
I heard your knock.
My knock?
Please, no!
Please, no.
Pull, you bastards!
Pull!
Abrams!
Where the devil is Larsen?!
-Larsen! Larsen!
-Olgaren!
-Larsen!
Larsen!
That's it.
Olgaren, where's Larsen?
Olgaren. Hey.
There he is.
Hold him!
Guys!
24th of July.
There seems some doom
over the ship,
already a hand short
entering the Bay of Biscay
with wild weather ahead.
And last night, a second man
lost and another man injured.
A strange injury.
Men all in a panic of fear.
We are 18 days at sea.
The closest port is England.
We must put our trust in God
and go forward.
He's cold as ice.
He makes noises and he moves,
but his eyes won't open.
Like he's unable to wake
from some dream.
But what happened to his neck?
And what was he doing
in the rigging?
Anything could have happened.
Perhaps some rigging
wrapped around his throat.
No. No, no, no.
This looks like a bite.
It looks like the same bites
we saw in the animals,
the same bites that ravaged the
girl in the carpenter's shed.
You think some devil did this?
Like she says?
I...
...do not.
-Good.
-But something did.
And that is real and on board,
whether we choose
to believe in it or not.
From now on,
I want two men
for every watch, armed.
No exceptions.
Search the ship, Mr. Wojchek.
Not just the hold.
Everywhere.
All right, Toby.
You have quite the task.
A captain...
is only as good as his spyglass.
Can I trust you
to shine it up for me?
If it's too much to...
No.
I mean, no, sir.
I can do it, I swear.
Good lad.
I'll be back soon.
Toby, lock the door.
I don't like this.
Sun's going down,
and he'll be coming.
Hello?
Mr. Olgaren, you're up.
Mister...?
Mr. Olgaren?
Mr. Olgaren,
will you please go away?
Please.
That's every mast.
Any other strokes of genius,
Mr. Clemens?
Do you hear that?
What?
Oh, my God.
Help!
Toby! Toby!
Olgaren?
Help!
Toby.
Toby?
- Toby.
- Open the door!
Toby, open the door.
Toby?
Open the door!
Open the door.
Toby?
Open the-- Toby! Toby!
Toby!
- Toby!
I can't reach the lock.
Toby!
-Toby!
Toby! Toby!
Move!
- Toby!
Toby!
Toby?
Toby. Toby.
Oh, my God.
You will be fine, my boy.
Everything will be fine.
Mr. Clemens
will take care of us.
August 1st.
We must be past
the Strait of Dover.
Still five days to London.
God seems to have deserted us,
and we are drifting
to some terrible doom.
Lord help us.
He's mad.
As if possessed.
Possessed by
that beast? -Oh, no, no.
Not in the way you mean,
at least.
It's like a poison or...
an infection.
Infection?
Not like any I've ever seen.
I can feel it.
Olgaren?
Can you hear me?
I can hear everything.
The sea.
The wind.
The blood pumping in your veins.
It burns.
Burn?
Maybe he needs some water.
It burns.
Olgaren?
Burns.
It burns! It burns!
It burns!
Oh, for God's sake.
Will someone say something?
What the hell happened to him?
I warned you.
I warned all you, didn't I?
It is a punishment
brought down for our sins.
Petrofsky, a criminal.
Olgaren, gypsy heathen.
A whoremonger, a lecher.
And from Gomorrah herself...
Oh, will you shut the hell up,
you bleedin' idiot!
Abrams, take the morning watch.
And, Joseph, you are
to relieve him when he's...
That child will be the next
to rise up from death.
Satan's black blood pumping
corruption through his veins.
God's anger has come upon
this vessel like Jonah...
Just shut it up!
See to the supplies.
Whatever was in Olgaren...
...it's fair to assume
it is in the boy.
He has all the same symptoms.
But your blood transfusions
saved the girl.
Not Toby.
He's smaller. He's weaker.
The wound was worse,
and the blood loss is greater.
Just...
I don't know. I think, uh...
I think we might
have to start discussing...
Go on.
Look him in the eye
when you do it.
That's not what I meant.
That is not what I meant.
It has to be hiding here.
If we can find it,
I think we might be able to
figure out a way to save him...
Are you sure the boy is
the one that's on your mind?
Get to your bunk.
We're running out of men
for the watch at this rate.
Anna.
You're going to open
the crates, aren't you?
Yes.
Go back to the shed
and bolt the door.
We are all trapped
on the same ship, Mr. Clemens.
Are you forgetting it needs
to feed because you saved me?
I'm coming with you.
This thing has killed
most the crew.
Then imagine what it will do
if we let it get to London.
Let's go.
If we do find your devil,
will bullets kill it?
He has controlled my village
for generations.
Do you think I have
any notion how to kill him?
I never liked guns.
I want you to have...
Let's see. Sixth of July.
Private cargo consigned
for Carfax Abbey in London.
Doesn't say the owner.
He told Jonah,
and he was spared.
He was spared.
"I cried out to the Lord
because of my affliction,
"and he answered me.
"Out of the belly of Sheol
I cried,
"and you heard my voice.
"For you cast me into the deep,
into the heart of the seas."
- Why London?
- Because in my country,
there is no one left
to feed on.
Let's start with this one.
Dirt.
It's nothing but dirt.
Nothing.
This one looks different.
Look.
We have found
where the devil sleeps.
"I cried,
and you heard my voice."
Oh, Lord...
Oh, Lord.
Oh, God.
Oh, God!
Hey!
The starboard lifeboat's gone!
Abrams, do you see it?
No. There's nothing here.
Nothing.
No.
Sir, not supposing you heard?
You would have made
a good captain, Mr. Wojchek.
If we had just seen London.
Mr. Wojchek.
How's Toby?
Shall I bring him some...
What the hell is happening
on this ship?!
Captain Eliot.
We've, uh...
we've wrapped Toby's body
in canvas, sir.
We're a doomed crew,
Mr. Clemens.
On a doomed ship.
We no longer plot our course.
The devil below does.
And we all know
where he plans to deliver us.
To hell, Mr. Clemens.
Each of us, one by one.
Captain?
Dear Lord...
...take this sweet boy.
May he never again be hungry,
never be cold...
...never be scared.
This world is
cruel and uncaring.
May Toby find his next home
to be a kinder one.
Amen.
Wait.
I saw him move. He's alive.
Captain Eliot, the boy
has no breath in his body.
He has no heartbeat. He's gone.
Uh...
Captain, you should sit.
I tell you, he's alive.
He moved.
Captain Eliot, please.
No!
Mr. Wojchek,
can I... can I speak with you?
We have a plan. If we can...
You seen what I seen
and you still want to plan.
This ain't Cambridge,
astronomer.
You can't think your way
out of this one.
I was one of
the first Black doctors
to graduate from Cambridge
with medical degree.
Have I told you that?
Well, that's very nice
for you...
I applied to all the best
hospitals in the country.
Immediately, I was told there
were no positions available.
I fought tooth and nail
for my education,
and yet no one
would let me practice it.
Finally, I was offered
a position by post.
Royal physician to King Carol
the First of Romania.
My name,
it reached them somehow.
But the color of my skin,
it would later seem, had not.
Captain Eliot once asked me
over dinner
what I most desired.
I told him I wanted
the world to make sense.
I need this world
to make sense, Mr. Wojchek.
This beast--
and mark my words,
it is a beast--
deep down,
I need it to make sense, too.
I need to know why
it is the way it is
and why it does what it does.
And then I will remind
the beast that it,
like the world,
has absolutely no hold over me.
And then?
And then I want to kill
the cursed thing.
If we barricade this cabin,
we are a day from London
with this wind.
Can't set more sail,
crew what it is.
What, you want us to
wait around, eyes in the dark,
served up and ready for dinner?
It ran
from our guns in the night.
It won't risk
an outright attack.
- Running?
- It's...
It was not running.
It was rationing.
Rationing?
One a night.
Once we had hit open waters
and could no longer make port.
It hid below deck,
sustaining off Anna until then.
But now it has us right where
it wants us, doesn't it?
Like he said,
London's only a day away.
It no longer needs us.
So we have to kill it
before it reaches the coast.
Kill it?
We can't even find it.
No, we can't.
It is why we're to set a trap.
We must sink the ship.
With him on it.
Scuttle the Demeter?
Have you gone mad?!
She's right.
We set up an ambush and
leave it on the sinking ship.
Then we can escape
on one of the lifeboats.
If the course is right, we
should be able to make shore.
This is my home.
And I won't tear her apart
for this fucking thing!
I grew up on a boat,
Mr. Wojchek.
Just like this one.
My father was a deckhand
his whole life.
He always told me that the...
the ship, the living part,
is the men on board.
The crews.
The stories.
Everything else is
just timber and nails.
No!
This is my home.
She's mine.
It's going to be me.
We barricade the hold,
so that he only has
one way out on deck.
As night falls,
Anna will be at the helm.
When it comes for her,
we'll have a clear shot
from the crow's nest.
We sink the ship
and send the wounded beast
to a watery grave.
21 July.
Fourth August.
It dare not touch--
You got to get Toby home.
1830...
Captain.
No, uh, people need to know.
Uh, logs.
There needs to be a record.
The Demet is lost, sir.
We're abandoning ship.
Abandoning ship?
Aye, sir.
Mr. Wojchek's below deck making
preparations as we speak.
We'll leave the beast
a sinking ship
as a farewell gift.
He comes to me.
He whispers to me
behind my own eyes.
He can bring Toby back.
He took him away.
He can bring him back.
Captain, come to your senses.
You know that's not possible.
Toby...
Toby.
I just need to bring
the Demeter to shore.
I'm sorry, Mr. Clemens.
No! -ANNA: Captain.
You have seen him as I have.
You know deep down
that is not all.
When I dream, sometimes...
I remember who I was.
Before him.
But most often, I think of
the box he kept me in.
How every time he came for me
and tore into my flesh,
drank his fill,
dirt would seep into
the fresh wound,
filling me up.
You cannot sink the Demeter.
Picture Toby's face.
His smile, his laugh.
And think of that dirt
filling him up, too,
because that's
what the devil does.
He takes what is good
and what you love, and he...
he uses it, and he twists it,
and he rots it from within.
Do not let him do that
to the memory of your boy.
I will...
I will sail the ship
out to sea.
And when she finally goes...
...the monster will never be
able to reach the home I knew.
That Toby knew.
Captain,
there's no need for you
to stay on board the Demeter.
Where would I go, Mr. Clemens?
Do you think this'll work?
It has to.
There she is.
The shores of England.
And looks like
there's a storm blowing in.
Keep your eyes on the deck.
I can't see a bloody thing.
Quiet.
You don't need to be here.
You could stay below deck
with Captain Eliot.
Stay safe.
We are connected,
the devil and I.
You are smart enough
to have noticed.
I can sense him.
Feel him somehow.
He feels it, too.
He will come for me.
And while he's focused on me,
you know what to do.
Where the bloody hell is it?
What is it?
He knows, Mr. Clemens.
Dear God. It has wings.
It's coming!
Please, Wojchek!
Wojchek, help me!
For God's sake, cut it!
Wojchek!
We're coming!
No! Get the lifeboat ready!
Go!
We have to hurry!
We're close to the shore!
We need Wojchek!
And the captain!
I'll find 'em!
Cut the ropes if you have to,
but get it free!
Forgive me.
Wojchek!
Where are you?
Wojchek.
Anna.
Captain.
Captain!
He's coming. He's coming!
Anna!
Captain!
Oh, my Lord.
I renounce you, devil!
I renounce you...
Captain.
Mr. Clemens.
Let them know, will you?
Let them know I was true...
to my trust.
I will, Captain. I promise.
You want them to believe
that you're a god!
You and I both know
that you're not!
You bleed like any of us!
You sleep in dirt!
You feed!
Above all else, you feed!
You want us to... to fear you!
Underneath, you're afraid!
You're afraid of
what lies on the other side
as any other living thing!
You are in my head.
In my blood.
You have damned me to hell!
You bastard!
Anna!
Anna, get to the boat.
I do not...
f-fear you.
You will.
Die, you devil!
Jesus.
- What's wrong?
- Run and fetch the constable.
Tell him there's a ship trying
to get through the breakers.
The coast...
so close.
It's close.
Mr. Clemens.
No.
No. No.
I have known for days now.
I'm sorry.
Another transfusion...
Would only delay
the inevitable.
We both know that.
But I can... I can...
-If I just...
-No.
I don't want to become...
My whole life...
...my people,
the devil,
they chose for me.
I choose this.
No one else.
You saved me.
And you me.
It's all about
the ghost ship at Whitby.
No survivors.
How about you, sir?
Would you like The Dailygraph?
Get your paper here,
only a cost of a tuppence.
It's all about the ghost ship
at Whitby.
No survivors.
I've arrived in London.
The creature hunts for blood
somewhere in the city,
but I know where it lays
to rest during the day.
Carfax Abbey?
You the new owner?
No, miss. Just looking for him.
Oh, well, it's a couple hours
to reach the abbey
in a carriage from here.
It gets dark on the moors.
If I was you,
I'd wait till morning.
You know, miss,
I was thinking the same thing.
I have finally seen
the true darkness
that dwells beneath
the surface of this world,
the evil that neither science
nor reason can explain.
Yet I have also seen its beauty
and those willing to give all
to protect it.
And so
I will pursue this foul beast.
And I swear by those
who have given their lives
that I will extinguish
this blight
and send it back to hell.