East Coast!West Coast!
East Coast!
How does if feel to be the centerfold for losers?
Not this year.Sharks all the way.
Yeah.
Just because you shanks go all the way...
What?
...doesn't mean your team will.
Boys.
One, two, three, four.
''J'' to the ''E'' to the ''T'' to the ''S''
jets kick ass from east to west
All you do is shake your butts Cheer 101 for stupid sluts
We're the West Coast Sharks And we got bite
We got what it takes to win this fight
jets, you stiff,you dull, you old
Your moves and motions leave us cold
Carson, captain of their team A loser even in her dreams
You said it all,except one hitch
She's a stuck-up, nasty,stupid little witch
You girls think that you're ahead
Our mascot's moves will knock you dead!
l am so psyched!
No, really. This time it wasn't a nightmare.
Busted.
Damn! We're gonna have some fun.
Fun? We're not here to have fun, Ruben.We're here to win.
Do you think East Coast is here to have fun?Hell, no! So, no fun.
Okay. l won't use the ''F'' word anymore.
Look, this year we're taking the title and going on the world tour.
Hell to the yeah!
Let's bust some East Coast attitude!
Reality check.The Jets have beat us three years in a row.
What's your problem,doom cookie?
No problem. Let the disemboweling begin!
Dibs on their entrails!
Cheer TV is live at the Hard Rock Hotel at Universal Orlando.
And l'm here with Pepper Driscoll and Vance Voorhees,
owners of the two rival cheer camps.
Pepper, can you tell us a little bit about
the All Star Cheer Camp Championships?
l'd love to. Well, this year is extra special,
because the winning squad will represent our great nation
on a Cheer Exhibition World Tour.
That's right.
And my teams will come in at least first and second place again.
Pepper's camp has both champion squads
that epitomize the clash in American cheer styles.
In fact, last year,one of her squads,
the East Coast jets,with their traditional cheer moves
narrowly defeated the West Coast Sharks,
another one of Pepper's squads shown here
with their new wave dance styling
inspired by music video choreography.
ln the cheer world,the controversy is brewing over
what exactly defines cheerleading,precision or flavor.
Speaking of controversy,Vance,
is the bad blood between your Camp Victory
and Pepper's Camp Spirit Thunder
related to your divorce?
Of course not.We're both professionals,
and we handle our craft seriously.
Which is why l can say that, this year,
a Camp Victory team will vanquish all comers.
By vanquish he means third again.
No, this year Camp Victory has a secret weapon.
Bulltwinkle, you do not.
We do, and l guess you're gonna have to wait and see.
Well, we'll all see in this Saturday's World Cheer Exhibition
right here on Cheer TV.
All right, after everybody unpacks,
we need to practice our home routine.
We just got here.
Yeah, and if we want to leave here winners,
it's going to take practice, practice and more practice.
And after that...
Oh, my God. Carson.
l'm, like, so glad you came back this year.
Hey, Brooke,of course we came back.
After losing to us three years in a row,it's, like, so brave.
Yo! Can we burn this Least Coast trash?
You know what?They're not even worth it, Aeysha.
Give it up, Brooke.We're not gonna play like that.
Oh, you mean like champions?
Yeah. Not really your thing, huh?
Practice in 10 minutes!
Ta-ta.
We're from the West Coast The mighty, mighty West Coast
We ain't got no fear We're the best,it's our year!
W-E-S-T,West Coast can't be beat!
l think it's time for a little guerilla warfare.
Brooke, where are we gonna find gorillas?
Just follow my lead.
All right, you guys,spread out. Give it flavor.
Five, six, seven, eight.
One, two, four,five and six,seven and eight.
One, two, and four,five and six, seven and eight.
One and two...lgnore them!
Six, seven, eight. Hey, girls.
Oh, hell, no.
Oh, shit.
She's gonna go throw down.
Yo, Paris Hilton.
lf you and this little purse dog of yours
ever pull that skanky East Coast mess again,
l will slice you like government cheese!
Aeysha, give it a rest.Give it a rest.
l swear to you l will...
l didn't know the government made cheese.
She better watch her back.
What?
You go, girl.
You know what?l need to rework that transition, anyway,
so free time until opening ceremonies.
Whoa.
Hey, are you okay?
l'm fine.
You kind of got skid marks.
Good. Now the police can track down the stroller.
Hey, why do l feel like l've met you before?
l don't know.Maybe in a prior life.
Well, l was thinking this one, but now that sounds whack.
So, where are you from?
California. A place called Eden Hills. You?
Nowhere and everywhere.
You know,l'm an army brat.
l guess l'm just a regular brat.
l've never been out of the country.
We just moved back from London.
Really?We're going there soon.
Oh, you're gonna love England.
You know me so well.Oh, no doubt.
Because, you know,in our prior life,
when we were guards at Buckingham Palace,
you were that hottie wearing that bearskin hat.
Of course, all the guards were trying to hook up with you.
Oh, right, let me guess.
You defended my honor.
No, l was trying to get at you, too.
Hey, you ever done the Double-Dragon?
What?
Right. l got to go.
Hey, hold up, skids.
What if l want to see you again?
Number?
916-555-0198.
Cool. Now, l got your number, skids.
lt's Carson.
lt's Penn.
lf you need help wiping that off...
Just so you know,l'm not mad anymore.
l MySpaced it all out of my system.
Now, hurry up,or we're gonna be late for the opening ceremony.
Why him? Why now?
Why who?
Aeysha,l met this guy.
What? l wasn't even sure you remember what guys were.
His name is Penn and he's so...
Carson, breathe.
He's awesome and smart,but in a good way.
And he's hot,caliente hot.
Aeysha, l want to lick his abs.
But you didn't, right?
No!
l need to stay focused,that means no cute boys.
Right now,beating the Jets is my top priority.
And you're doing the right thing.
l know.
So, can l have him?
Ooh, Penn looks hot.
Just don't.
What do you mean?
l like your hair that way, Chelsea.
Oh, it's this new gel.
My hair always looks better when there's something sticky in it.
All right.Who is she?
What?
The girl who's making you stupid.
All right.Check it out.l met her today
when l was running.Her name's...
Carson!Carson!
Right.Wrong.
She's a Shark.
She's the frigging captain of the Sharks.
And what did she say?What did she want?
Did she ask about our routines?
Yeah, right.
Cheering was the last thing we talked about.
Penn, she's like your sworn emeny.
l swear it.
Trust me.She's not my enemy.
Penn, you need to know.
Carson's a two-faced,back-biting,man-eating Shark!
Yeah. And guys hate biters.
Why are you guys busting on me?
Because you don't get it.
Yeah. l think l do.
Don't flatter yourself, Penn.
This is about our team,about winning.
So now what, Captain?
Are you gonna forbid me from seeing Carson?
l would never do that.
Good, 'cause it wouldn't work.
He can't date a Shark!
Duh, Chelsea.Watch and learn.
Thank you.Thank you.Thank you.
Hi, everybody.
Welcome to Camp Spirit Thunder.
This year,we're so proud to welcome
a new member to our family, okay.
l heard she's really tough.
Give a big Spirit welcome to our new choreographer,Chicago.
Come on up here, girl.
All right, all eyes on me.
Now, I want you all to remember this gorgeous face,
'cause it will haunt you in your sleep.
Now, I believe in hard work.
Winning knows no pain.
So, when I say jump,I wanna hear, ''How high?''
Now jump.
How high?
That's what I'm talking about.
Don't hate the player, baby.
Okay, seriously,Cheerzilla is a little scary.
What? l love her.
She's the kind of black woman gay men emulate.She's amazing.
Welcome your cheer-tastic 2008 Spirit Thunder instructors!
Come on, guys.
That was really great.
Yeah! Aren't they terrific?
Aren't they wonderful?
Yeah!
All right.
And now, as you know,we have a very special tradition here
at Camp Spirit Thunder.
This spirit stick was given to me
by the father of cheerleading himself,
Herkie Herkimer.
It embodies the heart and the soul of cheerleading,
and it brings the luck of the cheer spirits.
So, each team will be able to experience
its powerful aura for one night.
That's right.
And last year's winners of the Championships will have the honors first,
the East Coast jets.
Go get it.What?
Come on.You do it. Go.What?
just a warning.
Lose the stick and you will face the wrath of the cheer gods.
I once knew a cheerleader who misplaced the stick for just one day
and she broke her leg doing a simple toe touch.
Wait for it.
So guard it with your lives, people.
You will find good fortune while it's in your possession, jets.
Cheer smackdown.
Words, shorty.Use your words.
Him.
Abs Penn.
Go jets.
Oh, girl.You know a cheer Crip
can't be hitting it with a cheer Blood.
All right. Everybody have a fun and safe week here at Camp Spirit Thunder!
You're a Jet?
Yeah, that's a trip, huh?
Why didn't you tell me?
What, that l was a male cheerleader?
Sure. That's a real panty-dropper!
Look, l didn't mean any...
Did Brooke tell you to play me?
Sucks to be you, huh?
Carson, l didn't know you were a cheerleader.
Like...And what's the big deal?
l'm a Jet. So what?
So what?
l cannot have an inter-cheeracial relationship!
Hello?
Greetings,Camp Spirit Thunder.
just a friendly video postcard from Camp Victory.
Looking very forward to seeing you in the Championships.
We've got a secret weapon this year.
Say, Pepper, how many of your kids can throw
a roundoff, back handspring double-fold twist?
Oh, none?
Meet the new and improved Flamingos.
See you at the...
The Flamingos?
They can barely stand on one leg.
Everybody,it is all right.
Vance Voorhees is just trying to psyche us out.Okay?
And it didn't work last year, and it's not gonna work this year.
We always win.
Nothing's gonna stop us this week.
Except the Sharks.
Your little trick's not gonna work, Brooke.
Making sure l knew Penn was a Jet
makes it that much easier to resist him.
l'm no player,but l thought l had a little game.
Sorry, Penn,but l've only got one thing on my mind,
and that is crushing your squad.
Not even in your dreams, Carson.
We're done here.Let's go.
Hey, can you go on spiritaccessories.com
and see if they have the key chains that light up?
lf pink is the new black,what's the new pink?
Aeysha, l'm trying to work here.
l have to find a killer stunt that'll knock East Coast on their spanks.
Sorry.
lt doesn't matter.
l can't concentrate anyway.
Hey, you need to get serious, 'cause l don't care how cute he is,
we are here to win, right?
True that, sister, yo.
Girl, go to sleep.Tomorrow is gonna be fun.
Five, six, seven, eight.
Come on.My granny can jump higher than that from her grave.
...seven, eight, one.
Okay, Sarah,you're up.
Let's have a little spirit this time.
1st and 10,do it again. Go, go
All right, Ruben,you're up.
P-E-A-C-E.Peace to the Middle East Go, planet!
He can't do that,can he?
l mean, if he cheers for peace, then the terrorists win! Duh!
Showmanship.
That's what sells the performance.
So, I want everyone to give me big facials.
Because you have to remember
that points will be deducted for bad facials, okay?
All right. All right,you guys, now.
Any of those dance moves can be used in a cheer routine.
Since when is dance a part of cheerleading,anyway?
Since the world first started recognizing that cheerleading was real.
I mean, think about it, you guys.
If you've got some dope cheerleading,
you're throwing some hot dance moves
and you got some crazy tumbling.
What do you have?
You got a triple threat, right?
Triple threat right here.
Yo, I got this.
Okay. Okay.Bring it, boo.
Ain't like they can hang when a sister
gets to cracking and popping her collarbone.
You smell me?
What the hell are you doing?
l'm keeping it real,sister.
Keeping it real for who?
You need to just be you, okay, boo?Just be you.
I love it when we win
The only thing that's better is when it's twice as long
And I get a double-header
Your cart.
First of all, we're gonna start with happy,happy, happy.
We're so happy to be here. Good.
All right, now,surprise.
What just happened?l don't know but it was wonderful.
Uh-oh! Here comes the big wink for you in the back, judge.
Big wink.There we go.
Come on, girl. Sunshine,I have seen better facials at a funeral
and l'm talking about the corpses.
Oh, we like that,do we?
Well, let's just make that smile...
Oh, gosh.Okay, all right.
Well, the workshop is over.
Do just one facial.Come on.
lf you hate cheerleading so much,why do you do it?
For Satan.
That's a shiny nugget I did not need to know.
It's just like yoga, you know.
It is.
Satan is my car.
My parents promised me payments and insurance if I join the squad.
Well, my parents promised me a car if l stop cheerleading.
And if I nail a girl, I get my own apartment.
See, that was almost a facial.
Yeah, in Transylvania.
Step off, Brooke.
Who are you?Her fairy Goth-mother?
Brooke, get over yourself,and stop sweating my team.
Why would anyone listen to you?
You suck as a gymnast and a captain, too.
Cheer-off. Sharks!
Yeah.
Five, six, seven, eight.
It don't matter what we do
Music, baby, is our cue
Hands and shoulders,face so tight
All our moves will rock this fight
Our moves are tight,we lift with ease
The things we do will make you wheeze
So watch us strike our muscle pose
While you all prance and dosey-doe
That was cute,your pose was dull
But all of you have belly rolls
Once again we groove with flare
The moves we do,you wouldn't dare
So listen quick while your face gets cracked
One, two, three, you're wack
Your rhymes are fun, but we're still good
We still can stunt,you're from the hood
Hood rats, good rats,what are you called?
The moves you do won't win at all
So listen quick, oops
You said that rhyme One, two, three, our time
Motions, motions,hear them roar
No one's knocking at your door
With no rhythm and with no sass
All of you can kiss our ass
Dance, 10, looks, 3
The moves you do make us all pee
We laugh, we cry,we all say hi
'Cause when you dance,it's bye, bye, bye
Bye, bye
Bye.
Bye. Have fun.
Yo, that was shady,Brooke.
Please, you totally popped a chubber.
Hey, Brooke.
What?
You've got no clue,you're in the dark
Wake up call,it's the year of the...
Come on, babycakes.
If we all just imagine this world's a fabulous place, it'll happen.
I see children frolicking under a rainbow eating hormone-free treats.
A unicorn.
l see mutant turtles gnawing on festering human flesh.
da
They ate the unicorn.
You need Jesus.Or Prozac.
Thanks for trying to cheer me up, Ruben,
but I'm more mad at myself than Brooke.
I let her get to me.
That's why we lost the cheer-off.
Yeah, that bites.
You gonna finish that steak?
Spirit to you.
Hey, l heard you had kind of a rough day, huh?
But your luck's about to change.
Okay. All right.
Oh, West Coast Sharks,may the luck of Herkie
smile on you as it has for me.
Go Sharks
Okay, guys, we got to give props to the spirits,
but isn't this a little extreme?
You know how nasty some cheerleaders can be when they're alive.
Do you really want to risk the dead ones hating on you?
Then let's do this right.Look, off.
Fire, water, earth,air, spirit stick.
You know what this really needs to pop?
The blood of a virgin.
Okay. Why are you guys looking at me?
Come on, Carson, just a little pin prick.
lf she can take a little prick, she wouldn't be a virgin.
You coming?
Hell to the yeah.
Where?
You wouldn't be into it.
Cheer poker with the Prairie Dogs.
What's the buy-in?
Sarah, this is cheer poker.
Sounds like easy pickings. Wait.
Who's gonna guard the spirit stick?
You know what? You guys go.
l'm captain, l'll do stick duty.
Thanks.Thanks, boo.
What room is the poker game?
Dumpy Dogs have a suite.
Why can't I delete you?
Down here.
Penn, what are you doing?
Well, you don't answer my calls and texts,
so l had to do it old school and show up in person.
Don't make me serenade you.
Penn, you're a Jet. We can't...
I know. I know. Look,let's just do the rides.
No cheer talk.I promise.
The Double-Dragon?
Now you're talking.I'll meet you.
Cradle.
That was sick!
You had fun,didn't you?
Hey! l know how to play, bro.
Mmm-hmm.
What? l take cheering seriously.
You know,my team's counting on me.
l'm not gonna let them down.
Word on the street? It's just summer camp.
Yeah, maybe for you.
We worked our butts off just to get here.
So did we.
And we had to raise a lot of money.
You know, wet T-shirt car washes.
Trust me. l know.
Anyways, winning a competition like this,
it could really up my chance of getting a scholarship to college.
l even had to get a team scholarship just to get here.
Yeah, so did l.
You know, it's nothing to be ashamed of.
In my case, it is.
What do you mean?
Look, don't get all serious on me, skids.
Come on.
You fumbled on the flop We'll trick you on the turn
Now here comes the river and the P-Dog burn!
You Dogs think you can fool us Sharks at poker faces.
You are so bluffing,Prairie Dog. I call.
Trip cowboys.I beat that.
How about my three bullets shoot down your cowboys?
P-Dogs rule!
Oh, yeah? How about a Texas titty twister on the house?
Hey, what are you doing? Oh, no, what the...
Go, go. Oh, no, we got them.
We got his shorts.
Look, shark.
A world tour is no big deal to me.
l've been overseas my whole life.
Well, if you win again, you can get a cheer scholarship, too.
To West Point?
Okay, wait, why would you go there?
You're a musician and a dancer.
Yeah, well, my father is a son of immigrants,
and they came from nothing.
And after he made a career out of the military,
he had everything.
So, all his sons went to West Point.
There's five of us, and well, I'm the last one.
So, my parents, well, my father expects it.
Well, can't you talk to him?
I mean, won't he let you cheer somewhere else?
Wait. He doesn't know?
My dad would spew a colon.
I kind of told him I joined the tae kwon do team.
Can l tell you a secret,but just between us?
Sure.
What?
Even though my family has money, I took a team scholarship
because I didn't want him to find out about Cheer Camp.
Wow. Well, does your team know?
Weak, huh?
So, where does your dad think you are now?
Extreme Warrior Martial Arts Camp.
He watched me pack my nunchuks.
Whoa, you sharks do stick together.
Yeah, get it, get it.
Move it. Come on, honey.
Oh, go get Carson.
Honey, that girl can wear a thong.
Yeah, my girl needs to learn to hang.
But we need to take this show to my crib.
She's guarding the stick there.
Come on, you all, let's go. Let's go.
Yo, Carson dipped out.
And took the stick.
Where?
Maybe my girl learned to hang.
Come on, let's go find her.
You know, I should really get going.
I just told you my darkest secret.
Yeah, l know, but...
Look, when was the last time you just danced for fun?
Without being thrown in the air every few seconds?
A bar mitzvah three years ago.
So, Jet boy thinks he can handle West Coast moves?
l think Shark girl's asking the wrong question.
No, Carson wouldn't bring it here.
Too many haters.
Where else can we look?
I think I have an idea.
Carson!
Oh, no.
What?
I'm about to have a secret, too.
Carson!
What are you guys doing here?
Us? You need to check yourself.
We were just hanging out.
Carson, give us back the spirit stick.
You junk up its karma around here with all these civilians.
Ruben, it's in our room.
No, it's not.
Why do you think we're out here looking for you?
Somebody jacked it, and now we know for sure who.
Jets!
jets kick ass from east to west
And speaking of coincidence...
You lost the spirit stick.
Ooh! You Sharks are tuna.
Just give it back.
Carson, this isn't a Jets prank.
l wouldn't scam you like this.
Come on, Carson, it's just a big coincidence
how he got you out of your room
and then the spirit stick was stolen.
Seems wrong he didn't tell you he was a Jet when he met you.
That's right. This has cheer bitch's
skanky paw prints all over it!
Don't let them play us again, Carson.
It's our year, remember?
This is so whack.Look, Carson.
l'll help you look for the stupid stick, all right?
What?Stupid stick?
Yeah. l'll help you look, too.
Look, don't get all crazy about this, okay?
No, it's not okay.
How can l trust someone who lies to his own team?
Carson.
You know, he didn't need you guys
to raise travel money for the trip.
He was too scared to tell his dad about Cheer Camp.
She's a liar,right, Penn?
No, Brooke. l should have just believed you
when you said Sharks and Jets were sworn enemies.
Now l know why.
You showed your true colors, didn't you?
And you showed you're just a Jet.
Have fun being cursed, losers.
Hey, we sold candy bars for you, dude.
l'll pay you back the money, okay?
But those Butterfingers were heavy.
Hey, Pepper.
Heard the Sharks totally lost the spirit stick.
What?
Yeah, they're over there.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
See you.
Uh-oh.
So it's true. You lost my spirit stick.
Pepper, I'm sorry. Look, I got distracted...
Well, it was up to you to guard it with your lives.
We'll find it, Pepper.
Oh, you better.
Yeah, so, on the real, what happens if we don't?
Oh, who knows?
You remember that cheerleader I was telling you about?
Well, after she broke her leg,
her entire team got some kind of nasty stomach virus,
and they all vomited on the competition floor, all right?
And, needless to say,everyone was happy
to see them go home the next day,
including the judges.
Okay, stop! We are not cursed.
Not even the spirit stick gods
can take this victory away from us.
We are going to win, damn it.
Pyramid, seven, eight.
One, two, three and four, five, six...
Hey.
You guys, get up!
This is one fast-acting curse.
Hey!
Damn curse.
Are those the Sharks? Yeah.
Don't let them touch you.
Let the curse be with you!
This is all the money l've got on me right now.
So l can give you the rest as soon as l can, all right?
That's not what l care about.
So, what's your deal, Penn?
Do you want to be here or not?
At this minute, not so much.
l'm serious.
We want to win.
Now you know what kind of snakes those Sharks really are.
Yeah. They're like snarks.
The enemy.
Yeah, l get it, Chelsea.
Do you?
Look, l get it.You're not into me.Nothing's gonna happen.
But it will happen for this team.
And the only way it's gonna work is if we do this together.
Yeah.
So, you're like with us or what?
''j'' to the ''E'' to the ''T'' to the ''S''
jets kick ass from east to west!
You know they stole the stick.
lt don't matter who took it, we got to bust a cap in this curse.
Even Ruben thinks so now.
AEYSHA: You know what?l think it's time for Sarah to do her thing.
A cheer sacrifice?Has it really come to that?
Well, if it'll get us a win,we'll do it at midnight.
O mighty fallen cheer angels,
we summon thee from darkness.
We're sorry about your spirit stick,
but shouldn't you be cursing the skanky succubae that stole it?
Not us.
While you process our request,
will you please accept our sacrifices?
Go, spirits!
lt wouldn't hurt.
Girl! Your lucky strapless?
lf you love something, set it free.
Oh, my God.The cheer spirits are here.
They don't sound cheerful.
Maybe it was just the wind.
That's for trying to get us cursed, freaks!
Yeah, except that you don't deserve.
Like we need to steal the spirit stick to win.
You couldn't even beat me in a cheer-off, loser.
All right, that's it.You want a real battle?
Sharks and Jets,right now.
Fair fight. No contact.
Cheer rumble!
Let's go.
Yeah, let's go,you guys.Let's do this.
Come on, you guys,go around the corner.
Come on, guys, let's go.
Hey, snarks.
Bring it.
Jets!
Sharks!
Pyramid! Higher!
What happened tonight is an all-time,
an all-time low for Camp Spirit Thunder!
You've just ruined this camp's chances against Vance.
And, even worse,
you lost my spirit stick.
Brooke, give Pepper back her spirit stick.
Hey, loser,if l had the stick,
why would my team have gotten hurt?
Because your team started the rumble.
You don't even deserve...
Enough!
You kids have let down yourselves, your camp and your country.
Take a look around.
Neither of you have enough team members to compete now.
So in the morning, when you get up,
there'll be buses here waiting to take you all home.
Good night!
Tomorrow, we need to whip those little Prairie Dogs into shape.
Then girlfriend,you'd better pray for a miracle.
Let's just go home and pretend
this whole sorry trip never happened.
What a nightmare.
Where's the
spirit stick?
Brooke, l know
you have it.
You're still the rock star of stupid.
Why would l keep the stick and stay cursed?
Can we all just get over it?
Even Paris and Nicole settled their...
Shut up, Ruben!
Pepper?
Run! Flip! Jump high!You dissed the spirits,and die, die, die!
Pepper, let go!
What the hell?
Brooke didn't steal the spirit stick.
She would've given it back by now to get rid of the curse.
Whatever! She is still a sick individual.
Now, just go to sleep.l don't need any more drama tonight, okay?
But that means Penn had nothing to do with it, either.
You guys,we can't leave like this.
lt's like we're giving up.
l promised you guys a win,
and we're going to get one.
Pretty.
Brooke,l don't think you stole the spirit stick anymore.
Like l give a flying tuck what you think.
Well, l do think you want to win
Camp Championships as much as l do.
So what?
Well, if there was any chance to stay and compete,
you'd consider it, right?
Even if it meant coming together.
Ew! That's like cheer-cest!
Chelsea, l meant combining our teams.
Look, it's about not quitting.
Pepper wants her camp to win,l think she'll help us.
Brilliant plan, Carson.
Look, l think the Jets are already on the spirits' hit list.
Because of you.
Okay, well,if we leave now,we'll all stay cursed.
Come on, Brooke.
Boo that, freak!We're out of here.
Penn?
Look, l'm sorry for...
Well, it's kind of a long list.
Later, Carson.
You can call me skids!
What?
You wanted me to say yes to Hilary Duff light?
Strap on a pair, Penn.
Can l borrow yours?
Don't even try to out-bitch me.
Yeah. Brooke's like the Olym-bitch champion.
No doubt.
l just never pegged you for a quitter.
l'm not quitting, Penn.
l'm embracing my future.
Which is freaking bright!
Everyone says so.
They say a lot of other stuff about her, too, you know.
Shut up, Chelsea!
Okay, we're in.
Yes.
l'm captain, of course.
You two perform together?
ln what? A cheer death match?
No. We would be...
Co-captains.
Pepper, even with only half our squads,
we've still got the best cheerleaders in camp.
Hey, P-Dog! lt is only a jump if your feet come off the ground.
Okay, hon?Whatever.
Pep, l'm trying to tell you, these Prairie Dogs are so bad,
they can't even roll over.
Don't give up on them yet.
Come on, you all.One, two, three, four,five, six, seven, eight.
Two, two, three, four...
We are the Flamingos!We are the Flamingos!
Look. Please give us a second chance.
Sorry, don't believe in those, angel pants.So you all just...
We are the Flamingos!
We are the Flamingos!We are the Flamingos!
Damn.
No Flamingo could throw down like that last year.
Get out of my camp,Voorhees!
Hey, we're just passing through,ma'am.
Don't get your scort in a twist.
Wouldn't it be fun to,like, rip him a new one in Championships?
All right, you guys.We called you out here to tell you
that Pepper got us approved with the council.
And now all we need is a new name.
l was thinking the East-West Spirit?
Ain't that an Amtrak train?
Why can't we have a cool name,like TomKat or Bennifer?
How about the Jarks?
How about
the Sharts?
How about the Shets?
l mean, l don't see you guys coming up with something better.
All right.We're the Shets.
Mmm-mmm. Mmm-mmm.This ain't gonna work.
Remember what happened to Tupac and Biggie?
We'll make it work.
We're combining the best parts of both routines,
so get up!Get up. Up, guys.
Come on, you guys,positions. Get up!
Penn and Chelsea,get in the back.
l so don't do the back row.Tell her, Brooke.
Why doesn't Goth-a-sauraus step to the back?
Because Goth...
Sarah can dance her little ass off.
Now let's try this.Come on.
Chels, please.
Five, six, seven, eight.
One, two, three, four,five, six, seven and eight.
Ready? Try it.
Five, six, seven, eight.
One, two, three,four, five, six.Two more.
One, two, three,four, five, six...Last one.
One, two, three, four,five, six, seven and eight.
l got this.
All right, everybody,that was great.We got the fever.
Yeah, bite me.
You're doing great, honey.
Hey, Penn.
l...
l'll be back before next practice.
You know, l was hoping that we could talk.
And by talk l mean,
you know, l thought that maybe we could have a do-over.
Do-over? Carson,l think we're done.
Look, Penn, l'm sorry l accused you of stealing the spirit stick,
and, of course,embarrassing you
and telling everyone your darkest secret.
That was bad, but...
This could be going better.
Look, Carson,l'm gonna work my ass off to help our team win.
But you and me,
l think we should stick to our own coasts.
All right?
Seven, eight.
One, two, three, four,five, six, seven, eight.
Tight work.
Hey!
Pepper's lost her mind.
l think she put out an AMBER Alert, too.
Man, l'd love to know who took it.
l smell P-Dog.
No.
l bet it was the Flamingos.
Look, either way,let's just hope the curse is done.
We need all the help we can get.
You know what?You're right.
Let's practice our routine one more time.
What? You guys! Ow!
Get it, boy.You better work it.
Bet l can cheer you up.
Don't be a wad, Penn.
Go find Carson.
Excuse me?
Yeah, l know.
Never thought l'd say those words.
But, hey, if you're into a bony ass and cankles,then what the hell.
Knot up! Go get her, fool.
Yeah, but after she ratted me out
l can't make myself trust her, you know.
Why not?
Damn.
l must be insane.
Doesn't mean l have to be.
Do what you want, Penn.
But don't be a pendejo.
Brooke, thanks.
Whatever.
By the way,
your loss.
l'm double-jointed.
Five, six, seven, eight.One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
One, and two,and three, and four...Hey!
Ever heard of this new thing called counting?
Everybody stretch! Now!
Ever heard of team work?Shut up, Carson.
Yo, watch it, cuz.
Yo, stop fronting, cuz.
l heard you with Chicago.
You're not just an Oreo,Aeysha.
You're double-stuffed.
You're wrong, Brooke!
My girl, she been pulling drive-bys since she was a shorty.
Yo, she was drinking 40s off the nipple.
Carson?
So, don't be getting up on her Kool-Aid, biatch,
'cause l have seen what she's done
to fugly swamp donkeys like you, fo shizzle.
Carson, it's over.
Are you sure?
l cannot watch you ''fo shizzle'' ever again.
Good.
Look, you all. All this,''Girl, please'' and cursing,
it ain't me.
l mean, it isn't me.
l just did it to get your respect.
See, the real Aeysha got teased every day
in junior high for being an Oreo.
You know,black on the outside,white on the inside.
And l've been hood ratting it up ever since.
You're whiter than me.
Maybe so, but,that's who l am.
Just a black girl who enunciates.
Do you have something to say?
Hey, if you want respect that badly,
just be a bitch, like me.
Same respect,half the effort.
Guess the bitch is out of the bag.
Truth out!
l'm a virgin.
Technically.
l just act that way so guys will like me.
But it's really hard being slutty all the time.
l don't know how you do it, Brooke.
My parents aren't bribing me to be a cheerleader.
l do it because cheerleading is dark
and twisted.
Are you high?
No. Think about it.
We cheer for the other team's failure
just as much as we cheer for own team's victory.
That's so twisted.
Sarah?
Okay, l'm a little high.
Yo, this is like confession.
l'm out of here.
No, wait.
l have something to confess.
This should be good.
Miss USA has a secret.
Spill, Tara Connor.
l'm scared.
lt's okay, Carson.
You can do it.
No, that's it.
l'm scared.
You know, l act like the fearless captain
who's not afraid to go for it,
but, in reality,going for it is my biggest fear.
l'm so confused.
But don't let it stop you, l mean,it happens all the time.
Yeah. What l meant was,
l just wish l could believe in myself
as much as l believe in all of you.
l'm not gay.
l like girls
a lot.
Are you serious?
l'm straight.
You girls just assumed,
so once you started changing in front of me, l couldn't stop you.
And then, l was like committed.
Hold up.
There's no way this guy's not gay, and l'll prove it.
Okay.
He is not gay.
No, but he is dead.
Get him. Get him.
Hey, Mom. Hey, can l speak to the General?
All right.
Hello, sir.
No, everything's fine.
l'm fine.
No, l'm great.
Actually, l'm not at Warrior Camp exactly.
l'm at Cheer Camp.
Because l'm a cheerleader.
Yes, one of those.
Sir?
Dad?
Dad!
Listen.
This is the funny thing, when you hear the rest,
cheerleading is gonna sound like the good part.
About West Point...
Okay, that was traumatic but good, right?
l mean, now we can work as a team.
Yeah. A team of freaks.
We are not a team, okay?
We can't combine routines and this was a dumbass idea!
Tell them, Ruben. We can do this.
We blow. We cannot do this.
Because we're cursed, all of us.
Holy crap, Ruben, snap out of it!
What have you done with happy Ruben?
lt's weird, you know.
Now that l'm not gay anymore,
l'm not gay anymore.
Okay, we're freaks!
But let's make that work for us.
Come on, you guys. l mean, there has to be some way
that we can perform together.
We can start with couples.
l'll take the lead.
So, like, we're gonna copy them?
l'm gonna move to the right then to the left.
Okay.
Start up like that, all right?
Here we go.
Hey, you want to try this?
There you go.
Top again.
All right, top again. Here we go.
Give me a turn. There you go.
For real.
This could work.
And l'll prove it. Get over here.
All right, everybody ready? From the top.
Look, l'm cool about you coming out of the straight closet.
Please, you're just saying that so l'll try to catch you.
Try?
All right. Five, six, seven, eight.
That was tight. You know what?
l think we could actually win this.
Maybe we should make sure.
''Compare the opposing army so you may know where strength lies.''
Recon?
Hey, guys. We need to get some disguises.
They practice on stage 70A. Find it.
Cell phones ready?
Recon positions by texting only. Break!
Chels,
l'm right next to you.
Thank you.
Hey, Ron, get the gate for me.
Hello, Mr. Voorhees.
The Flamingos just started...
Listen, we have got to tighten up the security.
l need more time for my Flamingos...
Keep up the good work.
l guess your father would laugh at us, huh?
He's not big into laughter.
You know, l told him everything.
Really?
Then what'd he say about you being a cheerleader?
Well, that he laughed at.
Hey, covert cheer-ops.
Two-to-one pyramid.
All right, Ruben, Eric, Nick, you three in the corner, be the base.
Come on, guys, hurry up. Let's go.
Chelsea, watch out for the guard.
Brooke, first level. All right.
One, two, three.
All right. Now, Carson.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
l don't want to see any loose knees.
Jason, that's on the two. You're always late.
Wait, how did you guys get in here?
Seriously, that guy wasn't even a real guard.
''lf an enemy leaves the door open, you must rush in.''
Art of War.
Base, keep it together now.
l really want to see you attack the ground. Oh, yeah!
Oh, my gosh.
Welcome to cheer-topia.
State of the art everything.
ls that Letty Trotter?
Choreographer to the stars?
That look on your faces,
that's the same look l had after my divorce.
So sad to see a dream die.
Anyhoo, give my best to Pepper, would you?
Vance wasn't bluffing.
Their tumbling is amazing.
Those Flamingos are like...
Better than us.
We need to come up with something really good.
No, really?
l thought we'd come up with something bad
and see if we can win that way.
Sorry, it's a reflex.
What are we going to do?
Look, l don't know, okay? l can't believe it.
After all this, l just wanted to win Camp Championships once.
Don't freak out, Carson.
Yeah, easy for you to say. You've won.
Look, our dance routine is better than theirs.
We just need a triple threat.
Let's think. What would Sun Tzu do?
''Make use of concubines who are greedy for gold.''
l don't think Sun Tzu would be riding a rollercoaster, Carson.
You see how the red and blue rails loop?
Criss-cross and then corkscrew away?
Yeah, almost like a double helix.
That'll be the path of the two flyers.
Sweet! Sweet!
No one's ever done that before.
We're gonna need something new if we want to win.
lmagine if we pull it off. That would be sick!
lt'd be awesome. So cool!
But is it possible?
Yeah, it's gonna be really difficult for the flyers.
Who's gonna do it?
Five, six, seven, eight...
You okay?
Yeah. l'm fine.
All right, you guys, let's do it again.
One, two, three, four, five, six...
Hey, Aeysha, who taught you to sew?
Martha Stewart.
All right. One portable hot press.
Nice work. Where'd you find that?
Concierges can do anything all over the world.
You'll see for yourself when we win tomorrow.
Where in the world of competition sports
will you find two arch rivals,
forced by a dramatic twist of fate,
to join teams and combine their styles
to face a mysterious new challenger?
Well, right here at the All Star Cheer Camp Championships,
where one of these teams will win the title
and the right to represent the United States
in the World Cheer Exhibition Tour.
And who will that be?
Up next on Cheer TV, the most exciting cheerleading in the world!
All right. All right. All right. Ladies and gentlemen,
boys and girls, moms and dads,
welcome to the All Star Cheer Camp Championship!
You guys look great.
All right. Well, let's not waste any more time.
Let's bring out our first people, representing Camp Victory,
ladies and gentlemen, make a lot of noise for Sebring!
PEPPER.. Thank you, Prairie Dogs. Good luck in the competition.
Next up on the practice pad, the Flamingos.
...three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
Yeah.
Yeah!
Yeah! Good job.
All right. All right!
Great job, Sebring!
They really brought it, didn't they?
Another fantastic routine. Am I right?
Yeah! Are you ready for another?
All right! All the way from South Dakota,
give it up for the Prairie Dogs!
Don't forget your lock out.
All right, guys, let's run it. Five, six...
This is a cheer-saster.
A cheer-tastrophe.
A total cheer-clipse of the sun.
Not bad. Good one.
Yes.
Look, no, you guys are all wrong, okay.
We're still good. We just...
We want the crowd to be pumped up.
MAN.. Okay, all right. They were really good, right?
Sharks, Jets, Shets.
lt doesn't really matter what you call yourselves.
Oh, and you call yourselves the Flaming Hoes.
Yeah. That's a bad choice.
...introduce to you, the mighty Flamingos.
Hope you've been practicing your loser facials.
Oh, wait. l think you're on.
You are so on.
Shelby, come on!
Come on, you guys.
Let's go.
Flamingos, think pink!
Pink, pink, pink!
They're even better than l remembered.
And they're not even cursed.
Carson.
Okay, you've got to get over yourself and fast.
What? Stop psyching yourself out.
Look, l'm totally fine.
You're totally not, and they know that you're scared.
Look, what else do you want me to say?
You've been right about me all along.
l'm not a good leader, my skills are...
You idiot. This is not about skills.
This competition is about showmanship.
Your choreography is going to win it for us.
Don't you know you're more creative than me?
Why else would l bother to put you down?
Carson, you've got it. You always have.
But for the Shets' sake, now you gotta bring it.
Hey, it's your year, remember?
No, Brooke, it's our year.
All right, you guys, this is it.
Just stay tight and lock out.
Okay. On three.
One, two, three.
Shets!
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
Yeah. Hey.
Yeah! Great job!
And now for our last performance of the day,
from Camp Spirit Thunder, rising from the ashes of both coasts,
here are the Shets!
Don't worry, skids, l checked your marks.
Just catch me, okay.
Cradle.
All set, Penn.
Told you l'd catch you.
Yes, yes. Yes, yes!
We did it!
That's what l'm talking about. Give me some.
Some what?
Okay. All right. Yeah!
As always, Cheer Camp Championships deliver, huh? Let's hear you.
We'll have to wait for the judges to score
because this one's going to be close.
Too close. Yeah.
Now is a really bad time to be cursed.
You know what? Who cares if we're cursed?
Getting cursed may have been the best thing that's ever happened to us.
Without this curse, we would have never become this team,
and hit a stunt that's never been done before.
l mean, that was amazing.
I have the results right here.
I'll be reading third place, apparently.
In third place, representing South Dakota, the Prairie Dogs.
Way to go, Dogs.
Look, we all gave 100%, and we trust each other.
Who cares about some stupid old trophy and world tour?
Coming in at second place,
the Flamingos!
Oh, my God!
All right. So that means the winning squad
that will represent the United States
on a Cheer Exhibition World Tour
is the East-West Shets!
Brooke, l meant what l said. l know.
lt's just... We freaking won!
l know.
Pepper, got something for you.
My spirit stick.
Vance, l knew it was you all along.
But why? You don't even believe in it.
No, but you do.
Besides, the stupid stick didn't work in the first place.
Pepper. Maybe it did.
We broke the curse.
You sure did. Congratulations.
No more curse! No more curse!
No more curse!
Carson.
Boy walk in the spot, he's so fresh
He got what he needs to impressin'
just look at the way that he dressin'
Ain't no question chicks like oh
Girl walkin' the spot, she stop traffic
She's blowing your mind with her asset
So jessica Alba fantastic Instant classic boys like oh
Maybe I can see us moving like that
Maybe I can see us touching like that
Baby I can see us kissing like that
We don't need no more that he said she said
Maybe I can see us moving like that
Maybe I can see us touching like that
Baby I can see us kissing like that
We don't need no more that he said she said
He said girl you winnin' She said boy where you been at
Stop talking let's get with it just like that they
He said you're amazing She said then why ya waiting
No more deliberating What you doin' let's get to it
just like that they
Boy actin' as if there's no pressure
He'd do anything to get with her
He say anything to convince her
Money spent to diamonds send her
Girl playin' it cool but she's with it
She lovin' the fact that she's gifted
Everything he do she gets lifted
Feels so wicked lovin' like oh
Maybe I can see us moving like that
Maybe I can see us touching like that
Baby I can see us kissing like that
We don't need no more that he said she said
Maybe I can see us moving like that
Maybe I can see us touching like that
Baby I can see us kissing like that
We don't need no more that he said she said
He said girl you winnin' She said boy where you been at
Stop talking let's get with it just like that they
He said you're amazing She said then why ya waiting
No more deliberating What you doin' let's get to it
just like that they
One night with you boy just one night with you
All the things we could do Every day I think of
One night with you no one else but us two
All our dreams would come true If we'd just get together
Maybe I can see us moving like that
Maybe I can see us touching like that
Baby I can see us kissing like that
We don't need no more that he said she said
Maybe I can see us moving like that
Maybe I can see us touching like that
Baby I can see us kissing like that
We don't need no more that he said she said
Uh, what you waitin' for?
He said girl you winnin' She said boy where you been at
Stop talking let's get with it just like that they
He said you're amazing She said then why ya waiting
No more deliberating What you doin' let's get to it
just like that they
And it's only baby
You're gonna like it You're gonna want it
You're gonna like it
We don't need no more that he said she said
You're gonna like it You're gonna want it
You're gonna like it
We don't need no more that he said she said