(DISTANT RUMBLING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(MEN SPEAKING GERMAN)
While I'm very familiar
with you and your family,
I have no way of knowing
if you are familiar
with who I am .
Are you aware
of my existence?
Yes.
This is good .
Now, are you aware of
the job I've been ordered
to carry out in France?
Yes.
Please tell me
what you've heard .
I've heard
that the Führer has put you
in charge of rounding up
the Jews left in France
who are either hiding
or passing for Gentile .
The Führer couldn't have
said it better himself.
But the meaning
of your visit,
pleasant though it is,
is mysterious to me.
The Germans looked through
my house nine months ago
for hiding Jews
and found nothing .
I'm aware of that.
I've read the reports
of this area.
But like any enterprise,
when under new management,
there is always
a slight duplication
of efforts,
most of it being a complete
waste of time, but needs
to be done nevertheless.
I just have a few questions,
monsieur LaPadite .
If you can assist me
with answers,
my department can close
the file on your family.
Now,
before the occupation ,
there were four Jewish
families in this area,
all dairy farmers
like yourself.
Doleracs, Rollins,
the Loveitts
and the Dreyfuses.
Is that correct?
To my knowledge,
those were the Jewish families
among the dairy farmers.
Herr Colonel ,
would it disturb you
if I smoked my pipe?
(CH UCKLES) Please ,
monsieur LaPadite ,
this is your house,
make yourseIf comfortable.
Now, according
to these papers,
all the Jewish families
in this area have been
accounted for
except the Dreyfuses.
Somewhere in the last year
it would appear
they've vanished .
Which leads me
to the conclusion that they've
either made good their escape
or someone
is very successfully
hiding them .
What have you heard
about the Dreyfuses,
monsieur LaPadite?
Only rumors .
I love rumors !
Facts could be
so misleading ,
where rumors,
true or false,
are often revealing .
So , monsieur LaPadite ,
what rumors have you heard
regarding the Dreyfuses?
(CLEARS TH ROAT)
Again ,
this is just a rumor,
but we heard the Dreyfuses
had made their way into Spain .
(MATCHSTlCKS SCRAPING)
So , the rumors you've heard
have been of escape?
(AGREES IN FRENCH)
Yes.
Having never met
the Dreyfuses,
would you confirm for me
the exact members
of the household
and their names?
(CLEARS TH ROAT)
There were
five of them .
The father, Jacob .
Wife, Miram .
And her brother, Bob .
How old is Bob?
Thirty, 31 .
Continue .
And the children ,
Amos
and Shosanna.
Ages of the children?
(SIGHS)
Amos was nine or 1 0 .
And Shosanna?
And Shosanna was
18 or 19 .
I'm not really sure.
Well , I guess
that should do it.
(ZIPPER CLOSING)
However, before I go,
could I have another glass
of your delicious milk?
But of course.
Monsieur LaPadite ,
are you aware of the nickname
the people of France
have given me?
(SIGHS)
I have no interest
in such things.
But you are aware
of what they call me.
I'm aware.
What are you aware of?
(THAN KING
IN FRENCH)
That they call you
"The Jew H unter."
Precisely.
I understand
your trepidation
in repeating it.
Heydrich apparently
hates the moniker
the good people of Prague
have bestowed on him .
Actually, why he would hate
the name "the Hangman"
is baffling to me.
lt would appear he has
done everything in
his power to earn it.
Now I , on the other hand ,
love my unofficial title
precisely because
I've earned it.
The feature that makes me
such an effective hunter
of the Jews is,
as opposed to most
German soldiers ,
I can think like a Jew
where they can only
think like a German .
(CHUCKLING) More precisely,
a German soldier.
Now, if one were to determine
what attribute the German
people share with a beast,
it would be the cunning
and the predatory instinct
of a hawk.
But if one were to determine
what attributes the Jews share
with a beast,
it would be
that of the rat.
The Führer and Goebbels'
propaganda have said
pretty much the same thing .
But where our conclusions
differ,
is I don't consider
the comparison an insult.
Consider for a moment
the world a rat lives in .
It's a hostile world ,
indeed .
If a rat were to scamper
through your front door,
right now,
would you greet it
with hostility?
I suppose I would .
Has a rat ever done
anything to you
to create this animosity
you feel toward them?
Rats spread disease.
They bite people.
Rats were the cause
of the bubonic plague,
but that's some time ago.
I propose to you any disease
a rat could spread ,
a squirrel could
equally carry.
Would you agree?
(AGREES IN FRENCH)
Yet, I assume you don't
share the same animosity
with squirrels
that you do with rats,
do you?
No.
Yet, they're both rodents,
are they not?
And except for the tail ,
they even rather look alike,
don't they?
It's an interesting thought,
Herr Colonel .
However interesting
as the thought may be,
it makes not
one bit of difference
to how you feel .
If a rat were
to walk in here,
right now, as I'm talking
would you greet it
with a saucer
of your delicious milk?
Probably not.
I didn't think so.
You don't like them .
You don't really know
why you don't like them .
All you know is
you find them repulsive.
Consequently,
a German soldier
conducts a search
of a house suspected
of hiding Jews.
Where does the hawk look?
He looks in the barn ,
he looks in the attic,
he looks in the cellar,
he looks everywhere
he would hide.
But there are so many places
it would never occur
to a hawk to hide.
However, the reason
the Führer has brought me
off my Alps in Austria
and placed me in
French cow country today is
because it does occur to me.
Because I'm aware
what tremendous feats
human beings are capable of
once they abandon dignity.
May I smoke my pipe
as well?
Please , Herr Colonel ,
make yourseIf at home.
Now, my job dictates
that I must have my men
enter your home
and conduct
a thorough search
before I can officially
cross your family's name
off my list.
And if there are any
irregularities to be found ,
rest assured they will be.
That is unless you have
something to tell me
that makes the conducting
of a search unnecessary.
I might add , also,
that any information
that makes the performance
of my duty easier will not
be met with punishment.
Actually, quite the contrary.
It will be met with reward .
And that reward will be,
your family will cease
to be harassed in any way
by the German military
during the rest of our
occupation of your country.
You're sheltering enemies
of the state, are you not?
Yes.
You're sheltering them
underneath your floorboards,
aren't you?
Yes.
Point out to me the areas
where they're hiding .
Since I haven't heard
any disturbance,
I assume,
while they're listening ,
they don't speak English .
Yes.
I'm going to switch back
to French now, and I want you
to follow my masquerade.
ls that clear?
(SN I FFLES)
Yes.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SHUSHING)
It's the girl .
(SOBBING)
(EXCLAlMS)
(PANTING)
Au revoir, Shosanna !
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
ALDO: Ten-hut!
My name is
Lieutenant Aldo Raine.
And I'm putting together
a special team ,
and I need me eight soldiers.
Eight Jewish
American soldiers.
Now, you all might've
heard rumors about the
armada happening soon .
Well , we'll be leaving
a little earlier.
We're going to be
dropped into France
dressed as civilians.
Once we're
in enemy territory,
as a bushwhacking
guerrilla army,
we're going to be
doing one thing
and one thing only.
Killing Nazis.
I don't know
about you all ,
but I sure as hell didn't
come down from the goddamn
Smoky Mountains ,
cross 5 , 000 miles of water,
fight my way
through haIf of Sicily
and jump out of a fucking
airplane to teach the Nazis
lessons in humanity.
Nazi ain't got no humanity.
They're the foot soldiers
of a Jew-hating ,
mass-murdering maniac
and they need
to be destroyed .
That's why any and every
son of a bitch we find
wearing a Nazi uniform ,
they're going to die.
Now, I'm the direct descendent
of the mountain man
J im Bridger.
That means I got
a little lndian in me.
And our battle plan
will be that of
an Apache resistance.
We will be cruel
to the Germans .
And through our cruelty,
they will know who we are.
And they will find
the evidence of our cruelty
in the disemboweled ,
dismembered
and disfigured bodies
of their brothers
we leave behind us.
And the German won't be able
to help themselves
but imagine the cruelty
their brothers endured
at our hands,
and our boot heels
and the edge of our knives.
And the German
will be sickened by us.
will talk about us.
And the German
will fear us.
And when the German
closes their eyes at night
and they're tortured
by their subconscious
for the evil they have done,
it will be with thoughts of us
that they are tortured with .
Sound good?
ALL: Yes, sir!
That's what I like to hear.
But I got a word of warning
for all you would-be warriors.
When you join my command ,
you take on debit.
A debit you owe me,
personally.
Each and every man
under my command
owes me 1 00 Nazi scalps.
And I want my scalps.
And all y'all will get me
1 00 Nazi scalps taken from
the heads of 1 00 dead Nazis.
Or you will die trying !
(SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(INTERCOM BUZZING)
(KLIEST SPEAKING GERMAN
ON INTERCOM)
(KLIEST SPEAKING GERMAN)
(BUTZ SPEAKING GERMAN)
(BASTERDS LAUGHING)
Hey, Hirschberg .
Send that Kraut
sarge over.
HIRSCHBERG : You . Go .
Sergeant
Werner Rachtman .
Lieutenant Aldo Raine.
Pleased to meet you .
You know what
"sit down" means, Werner?
Yes.
Then sit down .
How is your English ,
Werner?
Because if need be,
we got a couple of
fellows who can translate.
Wicki here,
an Austrian-Jew,
got the fuck out of Munich
while the getting was good .
Became American , got drafted ,
come back to give y'all
what for.
Another one up there
you might be familiar with .
Sergeant Hugo Stiglitz.
Heard of him?
Everybody in the German Army
has heard of H ugo Stiglitz.
(BASTERDS LAUGHING)
MALE NARRATOR: The reason
for Hugo Stiglitz's celebrity
among German soldiers
is simple.
As a German-enlisted man ,
he killed 13 Gestapo officers.
Instead of putting him up
against a wall ,
the High Command
decided to send him
back to Berlin
to be made an example of.
Needless to say ,
once the Basterds
heard about him ,
he never got there.
(GASPING)
Sergeant H ugo Stiglitz?
Lieutenant Aldo Raine.
These are the Basterds.
Ever heard of us?
We just want to say
we're a big fan
of your work.
When it comes
to killing Nazis. . .
(MAN GROANING)
. . . I think you show
great talent.
And I pride myself
for having an eye
for that kind of talent.
But your status
as a Nazi killer
is stilI amateur.
We all come here to see
if you want to go pro.
(BASTERDS LAUGHING)
Can I assume
you know who we are?
You're Aldo the Apache.
(BASTERDS WHOOPING)
Werner,
if you heard of us,
you probably heard
we ain't in the
prisoner-taking business.
We in the killing Nazi
business, and , cousin ,
business is a-booming .
HIRSCHBERG :
(LAUGHING) Oh , yeah .
Now, that leaves two ways
we can play this out.
Either kill you
or let you go.
Whether or not you're going
to leave this ditch alive
depends entirely on you .
Up the road a piece,
there's an orchard .
Besides you , we know there's
another Kraut patrol fucking
around here somewhere.
If that patrol were
to have any crack shots,
that orchard would be
a goddamn sniper's delight.
So if you ever want to eat
a sauerkraut sandwich again ,
you got to show me on
this here map where they are.
You got to tell me
how many they are,
and you got to tell me
what kind of artillery
they're carrying with them .
(SCOFFING)
You can't expect me to divulge
information that would
put German lives in danger.
Well , now, Werner, that's
where you're wrong , because
that's exactly what I expect.
I need to know about
Germans hiding in trees .
And you need to tell me.
And you need to tell me
right now.
Now, just take that
finger of yours
and point out on this
here map where this
party is being held ,
how many is coming
and what they brought
to play with .
I respectfully refuse,
sir.
(BATTAPPING)
Hear that?
Yes.
That's Sergeant
Donny Donowitz.
You might know him better
by his nickname.
The Bear Jew.
Now, if you heard of Aldo
the Apache, you got to have
heard about The Bear Jew.
I heard of The Bear Jew.
What did you hear?
Beats German soldiers
with a club .
He bashes their brains in
with a baseball bat,
what he does.
And , Werner,
I'm going to ask you
one last goddamn time,
and if you still
respectfully refuse,
I'm calling
The Bear Jew over.
He's going to take
that big bat of his,
and he's going
to beat your ass
to death with it.
Now, take your
Wiener-schnitzel-licking
finger,
and point out on this map
what I want to know.
Fuck you .
And your Jew dogs.
(BASTERDS LAUGHING)
(BASTERDS APPLAU DING)
Actually, Werner,
we're all tickled
to hear you say that.
Quite frankly,
watching Donny beat
Nazis to death
is the closest we ever get
to going to the movies. Donny!
DON NY: Yeah?
Got us a German here
who wants to die
for country.
Oblige him .
(BAT TAPPING)
(CONTL NUESTAPPING)
(BASTERDS CHEERING)
Did you get that
for killing Jews?
Bravery.
(BASTERDS EXCLAIMING)
Yeah !
BASTERD 1 : Oh , no !
BASTERD 2: Oh , no !
Donny!
BASTERD: Yeah , Donny!
About now I'd be shitting
my pants if I was you .
(LAUGHING)
Teddy Fucking Williams
knocks it out of the park !
Fenway Park is on its feet
for Teddy Fucking Ballgame !
He went yard on that one,
on to fucking Lansdowne Street!
You !
Damn it,
Hirschberg !
Donny, bring that other one
over here. Alive !
Get the fuck up !
Batter up .
You're on deck !
Two hits. I hit you ,
you hit the ground .
English?
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
ALDO: Wicki .
Ask him
if he wants to live.
(BOTH SPEAKING GERMAN)
Tell him to point out
on this map
the German position .
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(BASTERDS LAUGHING)
Ask him how many Germans .
(BOTH SPEAKING GERMAN)
Around about 1 2.
What kind of artillery?
(BOTH SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Now, when you report
what happened here,
you can't tell them
you told us what you told us.
They'll shoot you .
They're going to want to know
why you so special ,
we let you live.
So tell them , we let you live
so you could spread
the word through the ranks
what's going to happen
to every Nazi we find .
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Now that you've survived
the war, when you get home,
what you going to do?
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
WlCKl : He's going
to hug his mother.
(SNIFFS)
Well , ain't that nice?
Ask if he's going
to take off his uniform .
(WlCKl SPEAKING GERMAN)
(BUTZ SPEAKING GERMAN)
WICKI : He's going
to burn it.
Yeah , that's
what we thought.
We don't like that.
See , we like
our Nazis in uniforms.
That way you can spot them .
Just like that.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
But you take off that uniform ,
ain't nobody going to know
you's a Nazi .
And that don't sit
well with us.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
So I'm going to give you
a little something
you can't take off.
You know, Lieutenant,
you're getting
pretty good at that.
You know how you
get to Carnegie Hall ,
don't you?
Practice.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(EXCLAIMS)
(LAUGHS)
(CLEARS THROAT)
(SIGHS)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(CH UCKLES EXCITEDLY)
(EXHALES)
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(LAUGHING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(CLEARS THROAT)
(LAUGHS EXClTEDLY)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(BOTH SPEAKING GERMAN)
(OFFLCER EXCLALMS)
(OFFlCERS CHATTERING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(CLEARS THROAT)
(EXHALES)
(CHUCKLES)
(LAUGHS)
(SAYING GOODBYE IN FRENCH)
(DRIVER SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(CAR APPROACHING)
(BRAKES SCREECH)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(LAUGHING)
(GOEBBELS LAUGHING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(GOEBBELS SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(FREDRICK LAUGHS)
(PANTING)
(BRAYING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(TRANSLATING IN FRENCH)
(TRANSLATOR
SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(COUG HS)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(TRANSLATOR
SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(TRANSLATES IN GERMAN)
(GOEBBELS SPEAKING GERMAN)
(TRANSLATING IN GERMAN)
(SCOFFS)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(CHUCKLES)
(LAUGHING)
(TRANSLATING IN FRENCH)
(FREDRlCK SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
HANS: Au revoir, Shosanna !
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(LAUGHING)
(HANS SPEAKING GERMAN)
(FREDRlCK SPEAKING GERMAN)
(GOEBBELS SPEAKING
GERMAN)
(HANS SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(CH UCKLES)
(GASPING)
(GOEBBELS SPEAKING GERMAN)
(LAUGHS)
(TRANSLATOR
SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SHOSAN NA
(GOEBBELS SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SCOFFS)
MALE NARRATOR:
At that time , 35 millimeter
nitrate film was so flammable
that you couldn't even
bring a reel onto a streetcar.
Hey, you can't
bring those here
on a public vehicle.
They're films,
ain't they?
Yes.
Then they're flammable.
Go on , hop off.
MALE NARRATOR: Because
nitrate film burns
three times faster than paper.
Shosanna has a collection
of over 350 nitrate
film prints.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
MAN : Right this way,
Lieutenant.
(CLEARS TH ROAT)
Lieutenant Archie H icox
reporting , sir.
General Ed Fenech .
At ease, H icox.
Drink?
If you offer me a scotch
and plain water, I could drink
a scotch and plain water.
That-a-boy, Lieutenant.
Make it yourseIf like
a good chap , will you?
The bar is in the globe.
Something for yourself,
sir?
Whiskey. Straight.
No junk in it.
lt says here that
you speak German fluently.
Like a Katzenjammer Kid .
And your occupation
before the war?
I'm a film critic.
List your accomplishments.
Well , sir,
such as they are,
I write reviews and articles
for a publication called
Films and Filmmakers,
and I've had
two books published .
Impressive.
Don't be modest, Lieutenant.
What are their titles?
The first book
was called
Art of the Eyes, the Heart
and the Mind: A Study of
German Cinema in the '20s.
And the second one was called
Twenty-Four Frame da Vinci.
It's a subtextual film
criticism study of the work
of German director G .W. Pabst.
What should we
drink to, sir?
Well . . .
Down with H itler.
All the way down , sir.
Yes.
Are you familiar
with German cinema
under the Third Reich?
Yes . Obviously, I haven't
seen any of the films made
in the last three years,
but I'm familiar with it.
Explain it to me.
Pardon , sir?
Well , this little escapade
of ours requires a knowledge
of the German film industry
under the Third Reich .
Explain to me U FA
under Goebbels .
Goebbels considers
the films he's making
to be the beginning
of a new era
in German cinema.
An alternative
to what he considers
the Jewish-German
intellectual cinema
of the '20s,
and the Jewish-controlled
dogma of Hollywood .
How's he doing?
Frightfully sorry, sir.
Once again?
You say he wants
to take on the Jews
at their own game.
Well , compared to,
say, Louis B . Mayer,
how's he doing?
Quite well , actually.
Since Goebbels
has taken over,
film attendance has steadily
risen in Germany over
the last eight years.
But Louis B . Mayer
wouldn't be Goebbels'
proper opposite number.
I believe Goebbels
sees himseIf closer
to David O . Selznick.
Brief him .
Lieutenant H icox, at this
point and time I'd like to
brief you on Operation Kino .
Three days from now
Joseph Goebbels is throwing
a gala premiere of one
of his new movies in Paris.
What film , sir?
The motion picture is
called Nation's Pride.
In attendance
at this joyous
Germatic occasion
will be Goebbels , Goring ,
Bormann , and most of
the German H igh Command
including all high ranking
officers of both
the SS and the Gestapo ,
as well as luminaries
of the Nazi propaganda
film industry.
The master race at play?
Basically, we have
all our rotten eggs
in one basket.
The objective
of Operation Kino ,
blow up the basket.
And like the snows
of yesteryear,
gone from this earth .
Jolly good , sir.
An American Secret Service
outfit that lives deep
behind enemy lines
will be your assist.
The Germans call them
the Basterds.
The Basterds.
Never heard of them .
Whole point of
the Secret Service , old boy,
you not hearing of them .
But the Jerries have heard
of them , because these Yanks
have been them the devil .
You'll be dropped into France,
about 24 kilometers outside
of Paris.
The Basterds
will be waiting for you .
First thing , you'll go
to a little village
called Nadine.
In Nadine,
there's a tavern
called La Louisiane.
There you'll rendezvous
with our double agent.
She'll take it from there .
She's the one who
is going to get you
into the premiere.
It'll be you , her,
and two German-born
members of the Basterds.
She's also made
all the other arrangements
you're going to need .
How will I know her?
I suspect
that won't be too much
trouble for you .
Your contact
is Bridget von Hammersmark.
Bridget von Hammersmark?
(CH UCKLING)
The German movie star
is working for England?
Yes, for the last
two years now.
One could even say
that Operation Kino
was her brainchild .
Indeed .
Got the gist?
I think so, sir.
Paris when it sizzles.
You didn't say
the goddamn rendezvous is
in a fucking basement.
l didn't know.
You said it was
in a tavern .
lt is a tavern .
Yeah , in a basement.
You know,
fighting in a basement
offers a lot of difficulties.
N umber one being ,
you're fighting
in a basement.
What if we go in there
and she's not even there?
We wait.
Don't worry.
She's a British spy.
She'll make the rendezvous .
Stiglitz, right?
That's right, sir.
l hear you're pretty good
with that.
You know, we're not looking
for trouble right now.
Simply making contact
with our agent.
Should be uneventful .
However,
the off chance I'm wrong ,
things prove eventful ,
I need to know
we can all remain calm .
I don't look calm to you?
(LAUGHS)
Well , now that
you put it like that,
l guess you do.
This Jerry of yours,
Stiglitz, not exactly
the loquacious type, is he?
ls that
the kind of man you need?
Loquacious type?
Fair point, Lieutenant.
So you all
get in trouble in there,
what are we supposed to do?
Make bets
on how it all comes out?
If we get into trouble,
we can handle it.
But if trouble does happen ,
we need you to make damn sure
no Germans , or French ,
for that matter,
escape from that basement.
If Frau von Hammersmark's
cover is compromised ,
the mission is kaput.
Speaking of Frau von
Hammersmark, whose idea was it
for the deathtrap rendezvous?
She chose the spot.
Isn't that just dandy?
Look, she's not
a military strategist.
She's just an actress .
You don't got to be Stonewall
Jackson to know you don't
want to fight in a basement.
She wasn't picking
a place to fight.
She was picking
a place isolated
and without Germans .
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(LAUGHING)
(ORDERING IN GERMAN
AN D FRENCH)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(ALL LAUGHING)
(MAN LAUGHING)
(FEMALE SERGEANT
SPEAKING GERMAN)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING FRENCH
AN D GERMAN)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
(SPEAKING GERMAN
SOFTLY)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(CORK POPPING)
Mmm .
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(ALL CH EERING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(ALL TOASTING IN GERMAN)
(STAMMERING)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(LAUGHING)
(THAN KING IN GERMAN)
(EXHALING)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(PHONOG RAPH CRACKLING)
(LAUGHING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(CH UCKLING)
(LAUGHING)
(SlG HS)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(H UMMING
EXOTlC MELODY)
(ROCK MUSlC PLAYING)
(WHl P CRACKING)
(G RU NTS)
(VON HAMMERSMARK LAUGHING)
(VON HAMMERSMARK AN D H lCOX
SPEAKING GERMAN)
(H lCOX SPEAKING GERMAN)
(LAUGHING)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(EXHALES)
(ERlC SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(EXCLAlMS)
(BOTH SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Well , if this is it,
old boy,
l hope you don't mind
if I go out
speaking the King's.
By all means,
Captain .
There's a special rung in hell
reserved for people who waste
good Scotch .
Seeing as I may be rapping
on the door momentarily,
l must say,
damn good stuff, sir.
Now, about this pickle
we find ourselves in .
lt would appear there's only
one thing left for you to do.
And what would that be?
Stiglitz.
Say auf Wiedersehen
to your Nazi balls.
(SCREAMING)
(PANTING)
(DOOR OPENING)
(G U N COCKING)
You outside.
Who are you?
British? American?
What?
ALDO: We're American .
What are you?
I'm a German , you idiot.
ALDO: Speak English
pretty good for a German .
l agree.
So let's talk.
Okay, talk.
I'm a father.
My baby was born today.
ln Frankfurt.
Five hours ago.
H is name is Max.
We were in here
drinking , celebrating .
They're the ones that came in
shooting and killing .
It's not my fault!
Okay!
lt wasn't your fault.
What's your name,
soldier?
Wilhelm .
Now, is there anybody alive
on our side?
No.
I'm alive !
(SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
ALDO: Who's that?
(G RU NTS)
ls the girl
on your side?
Which girl?
Who do you think?
Von Hammersmark.
Yeah , she's ours.
ls she okay?
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Wilhelm !
(SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
She's been shot.
But she's alive.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
ALDO: Okay, Wilhelm .
What do you say
we make us a deal?
What's your name?
Aldo.
Okay, Wilhelm ,
here's my deal .
You let me and one of my men
come down there
and take the girl away.
No guns. No guns me,
no guns you .
And we take the girl
and leave.
It's that simple, Willi .
You go your way,
we go ours.
And little Max gets
to grow up playing
catch with his daddy.
So what do you say, Willi?
We got us a deal?
Aldo.
I'm here, Willi .
l want to trust you .
But. . .
But how can l?
What choice you got,
son?
Okay, okay.
Aldo,
I'm going to trust you .
Come down .
(SN I FFLES)
Hey, Willi ,
what's with the machine gun?
l thought we had us a deal?
We still have a deal .
Now, get the girl and go.
Not so fast.
We only got a deal ,
we trust each other.
And a Mexican standoff
ain't trust.
You need guns on me
for it to be
a Mexican standoff.
You got guns on us.
You decide to shoot,
we're dead .
U p top , they got grenades.
They drop them down here,
you're dead .
That's a Mexican standoff,
and that was not the deal .
No trust,
no deal .
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
All right, Aldo.
Fine.
J ust take that
fucking traitor, and
get her out of my sight.
(VON HAMMERSMARK G ROANING)
Not so goddamn fast, doc.
Tell him to go
play with his dogs.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(DOGS BARKING)
Before we yank that slug
out you , you need to answer
a few questions.
Few questions
about what?
About I got three men
dead back there.
Why don't you try telling us
what the fuck happened?
The British officer
blew his German act and
the Gestapo major saw it.
Before we get into
who shot John ,
why'd you invite my men
to a rendezvous in a basement
with a bunch of Nazis?
l can see
since you didn't see
what happened inside,
that the Nazis being there
must look odd .
Yeah , we got a word
for that kind of odd
in English .
It's called suspicious.
(EXCLAIMING)
Everybody needs
to calm down .
You're letting
your imagination get
the better of you .
You met the sergeant
yourself. Willi .
You remember him ,
don't you?
Yeah , I remember him .
H is wife had
a baby tonight.
He had just become a. . .
He had just become
a father!
H is commanding officer
gave him and his mates
the night off to celebrate.
(GROANS)
The Germans being there
was either a trap set by me
or a tragic coincidence.
It couldn't be both .
(GRUNTING)
How'd the shooting start?
The Englishman
gave himseIf away.
How'd he do that?
He ordered three glasses.
We order three glasses.
That's the German three .
The other looks odd .
Germans would
and did notice it.
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
Okay, let's pretend
there were no Germans
and everything went exactly
the way it was supposed to.
What was the next step?
Tuxedos.
To get them into the premiere
wearing military uniforms
with all the military there
would've been suicide.
But going as members
of the German film industry,
they wear tuxedos
and fit in with
everybody else.
I arranged for the tailor
to fit three tuxedos tonight.
How'd you intend to get them
in that premiere?
Hand me my purse.
Lieutenant H icox
was going as my escort.
The other two were going
as a German cameraman
and his assistant.
You still get us
in that premiere?
You speak German
better than
your friends? No.
Have I been shot? Yes !
I don't see me tripping
the light fantastique up
a red carpet anytime soon .
Least of all ,
by tomorrow night.
However, there's something
you don't know.
There've been
two recent developments
regarding Operation Kino .
One , the venue has been
changed from The Ritz
to a much smaller venue.
Enormous change
at the last minute?
That's not very Germatic.
Why the hell is Goebbels
doing stuff so damn peculiar?
It probably has
something to do with
the second development.
Which is?
Der Fuhrer is attending
the premiere.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Fuck a duck !
What are you thinking?
I'm thinking getting
a whack at planting
old U ncle Adolf
makes this horse
a different color.
What is that
supposed to mean?
lt means you getting us
in that premiere.
I'm probably going
to end up losing this leg .
Bye-bye, acting career.
Fun while it lasted .
How do you expect me
to walk the red carpet?
(SNORTS)
Doggy doc's going
to dig that slug
out your gam .
He's going to wrap it up
in a cast,
and you got a good
how-l-broke-my-leg-
mountain-climbing story.
That's German , ain't it?
You all like climbing
mountains, don't you?
I don't. I like smoking ,
drinking and ordering
in restaurants.
But I see your point.
We fill you up
with morphine till it's
coming out your ears
and just limp
your little ass up
that reuge carpet.
I know this is
a silly question
before I ask it,
but can you Americans
speak any other language
than English?
We both speak
a little ltalian .
With an atrocious accent,
no doubt.
But that doesn't exactly
kill us in the crib .
Germans don't have
a good ear for ltalian .
So you mumble ltalian
and brazen through it.
Is that the plan?
That's about it.
That sounds good .
It sounds like shit.
What else are we going
to do? Go home?
No, that sounds good .
If you don't blow it,
with that, I can get
you in the building .
Who does what?
Well ,
I speak the most ltalian ,
so I'll be your escort.
Donowitz speaks second most,
so he'll be
your Italian cameraman .
Omar, third most.
He'll be Donny's assistant.
I don't speak ltalian .
Like I said , third best.
Just keep your
fucking mouth shut.
In fact,
why don't you start
practicing right now?
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(CHUCKLES)
(MOTORCYCLE ENG IN ES STARTING)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(KISSES)
(DRAMATIC ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Yes.
(MAN SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(LAUGHING)
(LAUGHING HYSTERICALLY)
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Gorlomi?
Gorlomi .
(SOFTLY) Gorlomi .
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Antonio Margheriti .
Margheriti .
HANS: Margheriti .
Dominick Decocco.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(ALL SAYING GOODBYE
l N ITALIAN)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(l N DlSTl NCT CHATTERING)
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(HANS SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
(USH ER CONTl N U ES
AN NOU NCING IN GERMAN)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(GASPS SOFTLY)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
What's that
American expression?
"If the shoe fits,
you must wear it."
(CH UCKLES)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(HANS EXCLAlMING)
(VON HAMMERSMARK G RU NTING)
(VON HAMMERSMARK SIGHS)
(HANS PANTING)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
ALDO: Fucking shithead .
Faggot fuck. Fuck you !
Bunch of shithead fuck.
Fuck you , too !
Goddamn Nazi farts ,
sons of bitches !
Get your hands off me .
You fucking
bratwurst-smelling . . .
Goddamn you ! Get off!
Hmm .
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
You Jerry-banging ,
Limburg-smelling . . .
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
As Stanley said
to Livingstone,
Lieutenant Aldo Raine,
I presume?
Hans Landa.
(TRUCK ENG IN E STARTING)
You've had
a nice long run , Aldo.
Alas, you're now
in the hands of the SS .
My hands to be exact.
And they've been waiting
a long time to touch you .
Caught you flinching .
ALDO: Touch me again ,
Kraut-burger.
Utivich?
Is that you ,
Lieutenant?
Yeah .
Do you know
what happened to Donny?
Omar?
The woman?
No, I do not.
Tell me, Aldo,
if I were sitting
where you're sitting ,
would you
show me mercy?
Nope.
What is that
English expression
about shoes and feet?
"Looks like the shoe is
on the other foot." Yeah ,
I was just thinking that.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
So you're Aldo the Apache .
So you're The Jew H unter.
I'm a detective.
A damn good detective.
Finding people
is my specialty,
so naturally,
I worked for the Nazis
finding people.
And , yes,
some of them were Jews.
But Jew H unter?
(SNORTS)
J ust a name that stuck.
Well , you do
have to admit,
it is catchy.
Do you control the nicknames
your enemies bestow on you?
Aldo the Apache
and the Little Man?
What do you mean
the Little Man?
Germans' nickname for you .
The Germans' nickname for me
is the Little Man?
And as if to make my point,
I'm a little surprised how
tall you were in real life.
l mean ,
you're a little fellow, but
not circus-midget little,
as your reputation
would suggest.
Where's my men?
Where's
Bridget von Hammersmark?
Well , let's just say,
she got what she deserved .
And when you purchase
friends like Bridget
von Hammersmark,
you get what you pay for.
Now as far as your paesanos,
Sergeant Donowitz
and Private Omar. . .
How you know our names?
Lieutenant Aldo,
if you don't think
I wouldn't interrogate
every single one of your
swastika-marked survivors,
we simply aren't
operating on the level of
mutual respect I assumed .
No, I guess not.
Well , back to
the whereabouts of your
two ltalian saboteurs.
As of this moment,
both Omar and Donowitz
should be sitting in the
very seats we left them in .
Double-zero 23
and double-zero 24 ,
if my memory serves.
Explosives
still around their ankles,
still ready to explode.
And your mission ,
some would call
a terrorist plot,
as of this moment,
is still a go.
That's a pretty
exciting story.
What's next? Eliza on lce?
However,
all I have to do is pick up
this phone right here,
inform the cinema,
and your plan is kaput.
If they're still here,
and if they're still alive,
and that's one big if,
there ain't no way
you're going
to take them boys
without setting off
them bombs.
I have no doubt.
And , yes,
some Germans will die .
Yes, it will ruin the evening .
And , yes , Goebbels will be
very, very, very mad at you
for what you've done
to his big night.
But you won't get H itler,
you won't get Goebbels ,
you won't get Goring ,
and you won't get Bormann .
And you need all four
to end the war.
But if I don't pick up
this phone right here,
you may very well
get all four.
And if you get all four,
you end the war
tonight.
So , gentlemen ,
let's discuss the prospect
of ending the war tonight.
So , the way I see it,
since H itler's death
or possible rescue rests
solely on my reaction ,
if I do nothing ,
it's as if
I'm causing his death
even more than yourselves.
Wouldn't you agree?
I guess so.
How about you ,
Utivich?
I guess so, too.
Gentlemen ,
l have no intention
of killing H itler and killing
Goebbels and killing Goring
and killing Bormann ,
not to mention winning
the war single-handedly
for the Allies,
only later
to find myseIf standing
before a Jewish tribunal .
If you want to win
the war tonight,
we have to make a deal .
What kind of deal?
The kind you wouldn't
have the authority to make.
However, I'm sure
this mission of yours has
a commanding officer.
A general .
I'm betting for. . .
OSS would be my guess .
(EXCLAlMS)
That's a bingo !
Is that the way you say it?
"That's a bingo."
You just say, "Bingo."
Bingo ! How fun .
But I digress.
Where were we?
Yeah ! Make a deal .
Over there is a very capable
two-way radio
and sitting behind it
is a more than capable
radio operator named Hermann .
Get me someone
on the other end
of that radio
with the power of the pen
to authorize my,
let's call it,
the terms of my
conditional surrender.
If that tastes better
going down .
You know,
where I'm from . . .
Yeah?
Where is that exactly?
Maynardville,
Tennessee.
I've done my share
of bootlegging .
U p there, if you engage
in what the federal government
calls illegal activity,
but what we call just a man
trying to make a living
for his family
selling moonshine liquor,
it behooves oneself
to keep his wits.
Long story short,
we hear a story
too good to be true,
it ain't.
Sitting in your chair,
l would probably
say the same thing ,
and 999 . 999 times
out of a million ,
you would be correct.
But in the pages of history,
every once in a while,
fate reaches out
and extends its hand .
What shall
the history books read?
(PEOPLE ON Fl LM SHOUTING)
(G UNFl RE)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SCREAMING)
MAN : I implore you .
We must destroy that tower.
Sarge , that tower. . .
MAN : The tower stands!
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Psst! Psst!
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(G UNFl RE)
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
HANS: So when
the military history
of this night is written ,
it will be recorded
that I was part
of Operation Kino
from the very beginning
as a double agent.
Anything I've done
in my guise
as an SS Colonel
was sanctioned by the OSS
as a necessary evil
to establish my cover
with the Germans .
And it was my placement
of Lieutenant Raine's
dynamite
in H itler and Goebbels'
opera box that
assured their demise.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
By the way,
that last part
is actually true.
I want my full
military pension and benefits
under my proper rank.
I want to receive
the Congressional
Medal of Honor
for my invaluable assistance
in the toppling
of the Third Reich .
In fact,
I want all the members
of Operation Kino
to receive the
Congressional Medal of Honor.
Full citizenship for myself.
Well , that goes
without saying .
And I would like
the U nited States of America
to purchase property for me
on Nantucket lsland
as a reward for all
the countless lives
I've saved
by bringing the tyranny
of the National
Socialist Party
to a swifter-than-imagined
end . Do you have
all that, sir?
l look forward to seeing you
face to face as well , sir.
Lieutenant Raine?
Right here.
Yes, sir.
GENERAL: Colonel Landa will
put you and Private Utivich
in a truck as prisoners.
Then he and his radio operator
will get in the truck
and drive to our lines.
Upon crossing our lines,
Colonel Landa and his man
will surrender to you .
You will then take over
driving of the truck
and bring them straight
to me for debriefing.
ls that clear, Lieutenant?
Yes, sir.
Over and out.
(GUNFIRE)
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(LAUGHING)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(CHIMING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SIGHS)
(GUNFIRE ON FILM)
(GROANS)
(MOANS)
(SCREAMS)
When I kill that guy,
you got 30 feet
to get to that guard .
Can you do it?
I have to.
(AU DIENCE CHEERING)
Champagne?
(GUNSHOT)
(SCREAMING)
(LAUGHING)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Who wants to send
a message to Germany?
I have a message
for Germany.
That you are
all going to die.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
And I want you to look deep
into the face of the Jew
who's going to do it!
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Marcel , burn it down .
Oui, Shosanna.
(LAUGHING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
My name
is Shosanna Dreyfus,
and this is the face
of Jewish vengeance.
(SHOSANNA LAUGHING)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
HANS: Hermann ,
uncuff them .
I'm officially surrendering
myseIf over to you ,
Lieutenant Raine.
We're your prisoners.
How about my knife?
(CHUCKLES)
Thank you very much ,
Colonel .
Utivich , cuff
the Colonel's hands
behind his back.
ls that really
necessary?
I'm a slave
to appearances.
(G U NSHOT)
Scalp Hermann .
Are you mad?
What have you done?
I made a deal
with your general
for that man's life !
Yeah , they made that deal .
But they don't give a fuck
about him . They need you .
You'll be shot for this !
Nah , I don't think so.
More like chewed out.
I've been chewed out before.
You know, Utivich and myself
heard that deal you made
with the brass.
End the war tonight?
I'd make that deal .
How about you , Utivich?
You make that deal?
I'd make that deal .
I don't blame you .
Damn good deal .
And that pretty little nest
you feathered for yourself.
Well , if you're
willing to barbecue
the whole H igh Command ,
l suppose that's worth
certain considerations.
But I do have
one question .
When you get
to your little place
on Nantucket lsland ,
l imagine you are going to
take off that handsome-looking
SS uniform of yours .
Ain't you?
That's what I thought.
Now, that I can't abide.
How about you , Utivich ,
can you abide it?
Not one damn bit, sir.
l mean ,
if I had my way,
you'd wear that
goddamn uniform for the rest
of your pecker-sucking life.
But I'm aware
that ain't practical .
I mean , at some point,
you're going to have
to take it off.
So ,
I'm going to give you
a little something
you can't take off.
(HANS SCREAMING)
You know something ,
Utivich?
I think this just might be
my masterpiece.