（接受）
I only came here out of respect for my parents who...我来这里 只是看在我父母
Knew your family.认识你家族的分上
Your father was more than just a friend to my family.令尊对我的家族而言 不只是一位朋友
That was a long time ago.那是很久以前的事了
Yes.是啊
A long time.很久以前的事了
Thomas Wayne believed in my father.汤玛士韦恩相信家父
He believed a man could bring order to a world of chaos.他相信人能让混乱的世界恢复秩序
And you, Bruce?布鲁斯 你呢？
I believe in Gotham city.我相信高谭市
- You try the vongole?   - Mm. Delicious.-尝过蛤蜊义大利面了吗？   -好吃
（法官办公室）
（当选人 哈维丹特）
Master Bruce. Happy Halloween.布鲁斯少爷 万圣节快乐
- Is there coffee?   - In the study, sir.- 有咖啡吗？   - 已经送到书房了 少爷
A miss Kyle telephoned.有位凯尔小姐打过电话
She said she was checking the number you gave her to make sure it's real.她说想确认你给的号码是真的
The gates are open. We haven't seen a trick-or-treater in years.大门都开了 好几年没看到讨糖的人了
We won't see one tonight.今晚不会看到了
Hardly worth the security risk, wouldn't you say?不值得冒险 对吧？
Respectfully, sir,恕我直言 少爷
if our security is dependent on $600 worth of iron alloy...如果我们的安全 依赖的是六百美元的铁合金…
This city is fallen, Alfred.这座城市已经跌入深渊 阿福
Then we must endeavor to lift it up again, Bruce.那我们得努力让它再站起来 布鲁斯
In the meantime, we live in obstinate hope.在此同时 我们拥有顽强的意志力
And an unlocked mansion.还有没上锁的豪宅
Anyway... It's an absurd holiday.无论如何 这是个荒谬的节日
Oh, yes. Putting on costumes and striking fear.是啊 换上奇装异服 搞得人心惶惶
Quite absurd.的确荒谬
Do you really think...你真的认为…
I hate when he does that.我讨厌他这样
James, babs! No running!詹姆斯 小芭 别跑来跑去
Come on, guys, slow down. You're gonna hurt yourselves.好了 别跑了 你们会受伤的
They're excited, Jim. Big night.他们很兴奋 吉姆 今晚很热闹
Yeah. All right. But we're taking the squad car.没错 但我们要开警车
Too many crazies out.外面太多疯子了
Sir!长官
Hang on.等等
Now, you're ready.你准备好了
All right, who wants to drive?好了 谁想开车？
Jim!吉姆
Just joking.开玩笑的
Hey, hey, hang on.嘿 等等
It could be a wrong number, or a crank call or...可能是打错电话 或恶作剧…
Gordon.高登
When?什么时候？
All right. I'm on my way.好 我马上过去
Your father's captain now.爸爸现在是队长了
The whole department's counting on him.整个警局都依赖他
Well, I was counting on him, too.我也很依赖他
I'll try and be quick.我会尽快回来
Hello?有人吗？
Gilda, there you are.你在这里啊 吉尔达
What?怎么了？
Harvey.哈维
- You're home.   - Better late than never.-你回来了   - 晚到总比不到好
Why are you hiding out here in the cold?你怎么躲在外面吹冷风？
I know. I'm sorry, I just...抱歉 我只是…
Mm, you started without me.你没等我就开始了
Did you have any kids?有小孩吗？
What?什么？
Trick-or-treaters.讨糖的小孩
Oh, no. I don't... no. I just...没有…我… 我只是…
I don't think I'm really up for all that tonight.我今晚没那个兴致
Answering the door every five minutes...每五分钟开一次门
Smiling.保持微笑
Yeah, I saw the bowl on the porch.嗯 我看到门廊上的碗了
It's okay. It's a ghost town out there.没关系 这座镇上没什么人
So to speak.对吧
We're gonna be eating that candy for a month.那碗糖我们会吃一个月
Or not.或者不会
You know I have a love-hate relationship with candy.你知道我对糖果又爱又恨
You have a love-hate relationship with everything.你对所有东西都又爱又恨
Let's just crawl into bed我们躺在床上
and watch an old black and white movie on...看部黑白电影…
Baby, I'm so sorry.亲爱的 很抱歉
You have to go.你要去忙了
Pick a movie. I'll be back soon.电影你选 我马上回来
I love you.我爱你
Does he always keep you waiting like this?他老是让你在这里等吗？
He'll be here.他会来的
I thought you quit.我以为你戒了
I have.我是戒了
Hmm. Don't worry, I won't tell Barbara.别担心 我不会告诉芭芭拉的
Gentlemen.两位
Ah. Good.太好了
This is district attorney Harvey d...我是地方检察官哈维丹…
Bats.蝙蝠侠
Dent.丹特
Okay.好的
What's happened?怎么回事？
Johnny viti was murdered tonight.强尼维提今晚遭到谋杀
Damn it!该死
The Roman's nephew.罗马人的侄子
He has a name.他有名字
It's carmine Falcone, not "the Roman."他叫卡麦法尔康尼 不叫罗马人…
Harvey, calm down.别激动 哈维
Where were your men, Jim? I've been working on viti for months!你的人呢 吉姆？ 我已经调查维提好几个月了
Nobody on your team thought he'd be vulnerable你队上就没半个人想到
the night before he's gonna turn state's evidence?他在转污点证人前一晚 会有危险吗？
22 caliber, taped handle, serial number filed off.点22口径 枪把包着胶带 序号磨掉了
Baby bottle nipple for a silencer. Odd, but effective.用奶瓶嘴当消音器 很怪 但很管用
And untraceable.而且无法追踪
Hard to tell if we're dealing with a professional.很难判断是否是职业杀手
Of course it was a professional! This was Falcone!当然是职业杀手 是法尔康尼干的
He found out viti was gonna betray the family,他发现维提要背叛家族
so he took him off the board!於是做掉他
Maybe.也许吧
We were so close.我们只差一步就能拿下他们了
We were so close, Jim.就差一步 吉姆
He was ready to sing.强尼本来决定要告发他们
And not just about carmine, the whole family was going away.不只卡麦 整个家族都会遭殃
We had a real opportunity to change things.我们本来有大好机会 能改变一切
We still do. It's just a setback.机会还在 目前只是遇到挫折
We'll find another way to take down Falcone.我们会找到方法击溃法尔康尼家族
Together.我们一起
Where's the Jack-o'-lantern?南瓜灯在哪里？
Excuse me?你说什么？
You think it's important?你觉得这很重要吗？
I don't know yet.还说不准
Look, Harvey's right.哈维说得对
This city's finally got a chance.高谭市好不容易有机会
And it's the three men standing here right now.就靠我们三个了
The Falcone crime family has to be taken down.必须击垮法尔康尼犯罪家族
So, I'm putting you two together.所以你们两个合作
District attorney dent will work in the light, and you...丹特检察官负责白天行动 而你
Will work the other side.负责夜晚
Bend the rules, but never break them.随机应变 但不要违法
And I'll do everything I can to protect you both.我会尽力保护你们两个
Understood.明白
He needs to hear you say it, bats.他必须得到你的承诺 蝙蝠侠
Two heads are better than one.人多力量大
Leads come my way pretty fast.线索来得很快
Keep your ears open.保持警戒
Then I guess we're up and...那我想我们准备好
Running.行动了
He does that a lot. I just...他常那样 我已经…
And I'm talking to myself.剩我自言自语
Godfather.教父
I'm so sorry to hear about your nephew.您侄子的事 请节哀
Grazie, amico.谢谢你 朋友
Carmine,卡麦
no disrespect but why are we sitting on our hands here, huh?无意冒犯 但为什么我们什么都不做？
He put two in Johnny's head!他对强尼开了两枪
Who did?谁干的？
Salvatore maroni! Who else?不是萨尔瓦多马洛尼还有谁
Ever since he took over that family, he's been gunning for us,自从他接掌他家 就一直想除掉我们
and tonight he found the target.今晚他找到了目标
It's a warning, for chrissakes!他是在警告我们
Perhaps.也许吧
But let us be clear.但先讲清楚
The man who pulled the trigger did not load the gun.开枪的人不是上膛的人
Maroni's ambition was in check until the law put a target on my back.在司法针对我以前 马洛尼不曾轻举妄动
Now, it's open season.现在是打猎季节
If anyone is responsible for my nephew's death,若要说是谁害死我侄子
it's that new son of a bitch in the da's office.就是地方检察署那个混蛋
Dent.丹特
- Mm-hmm. Yeah.   - Maybe he should sleep with the fishes.-没错   -也许该除掉他
Hell yes!没错
You just say the word, carmine, and I'll do dent myself!卡麦 只要你下令 我就亲自解决丹特
Settle, antoni.你先冷静 安东尼
At the right time, we'll hit back. Until then...等时机成熟 我们会报仇 在那之前…
The right time is now, carmine!就是现在 卡麦
Now! Any delay is only gonna make you look even weaker!再拖下去 只会让你看起来更懦弱
Thank you for your concern, antoni.多谢你关心 安东尼
No disrespect, carmine.无意冒犯 卡麦
It's "godfather."是“教父”
Milos. Come on!米洛斯 别这样
Please!求求你
Milos! No!米洛斯 不
Nol不
We have other business to discuss?还有别的事要谈吗？
Alberto?阿尔贝托？
Alberto!阿尔贝托
Business time.我们在谈正事
Take your crosswords for a walk.拿你的字谜游戏出去玩吧
They're... logic puzzles.这是…逻辑谜题
Thirty-two going on 13.32岁了还像13岁一样
Wayne is not gonna support any large-scale structuring effort.韦恩不会支援大型建案
So, for now, the assets will have to be moved to a more secure facility.所以现在得暂时把资产移到更安全的地方
Your equipment's weighing you down.你的装备拖垮了你
Why are you running?你为什么要跑？
Fun. You could use a little fun.好玩啊 你需要来点乐子
Give me your hand.手给我
Nah.不
Got you exactly where I want you.总算把你引来我要的地方
Falcone.法尔康尼
Walt till you see what's inside.等你看了里头的东西再说吧
Have you ever seen this kind of money?你见过这么多钱吗？
It's authentic.是真钞
So crisp and clean.如此乾净
Actually, it's incredibly dirty.其实是脏钱
Falcone's been having trouble laundering his cash for some time.法尔康尼最近洗钱不太顺利
We just didn't know where he was stockpiling it.我们只是不知道钱藏在哪
Thank you.谢谢
I'm happy to help.我很乐意帮忙
Why?为什么？
You could have kept it to yourself.你大可据为己有
You could have lived pretty well with all this.这些钱能让你过上好日子
Why hand it over?为什么要交出来？
To you?交给你？
Who knows?谁知道？
Get down!趴下
Take it from me, pal, around here, curiosity can get you killed.听我一句 朋友 在这里 好奇心会害死你
Let him go.放了他
What? Why?什么？为什么？
Because he's with me.我们是同夥
Also, because he's the da who put all your friends into arkham.就是这位检察官 把你朋友全送进阿卡汉的
We got room for one more.那里还有一间空房
Anyone follow us?有人跟来吗？
I could barely follow us.我都快跟不上了
Falcone imports has been doing quite a business.法尔康尼进口公司搞了一番大事业啊
You know, if we were any other men...你知道 如果我们像其他人…
We're not.我们不是
Yeah. No. Of course.当然不是
So, what now?现在怎么办？
We should call Gordon.应该叫高登来一趟
Have his men pick this up as evidence.请他的人把钱带回去当证据
Falcone owns the mayor and the entire city assembly.市长和市议会都听法尔康尼使唤
It'd be back in his coffers by tomorrow.明天这些钱就会回到他的金库
So, the only way to make an impact is to make it disappear.所以唯一有效的办法就是让钱消失
Yeah, but look at all this. Moving it could take days.没错 但看看这些钱 光是移动就要好几天
Well, who said anything about moving it?谁说要移动了？
Why are you trying to hurt Falcone?你为什么要惹法尔康尼？
Why are you?那你呢？
It's not personal, sweetheart. It's justice.无关私人恩怨 亲爱的 只是伸张正义
Justice can be personal, sweetie.正义也可以是私人恩怨 亲爱的
Give me a head start.我先走一步
I don't want to get caught anywhere near here.我可不想在这里被抓
I don't know.我不知道
Gordon says I'm supposed to work in the light.高登说我负责白天行动
Well, then, light it up.那就照亮这里吧
I owe you one.我欠你一次
You owe me, like... A billion-five.你欠我的次数…难以估计
I can't really be a lawyer and a criminal, can I?我不能既是律师又是罪犯 对吧？
I want to win.我想赢
But do I want to win like this?但我真的想靠这个赢吗？
I'm of two minds here.我无法决定
So, it's a coin flip.丢钱币决定
Yeah, I guess it is.只好这样了
Heads, we burn it down.人头 就全烧光
Okay.好
Call chen.把陈叫来
Firefighters on the scene here in the industrial district消防员来到工业区
working to contain the Blaze试图控制火势
before it can spread to nearby homes and businesses.以免波及邻近住家及店家
Now, at this time, Jackie,贾吉 目前
officials believe the Falcone imports warehouse,官方认为 恶名昭彰的法尔康尼犯罪家族
owned, of course, by the notorious Falcone crime family,所拥有的这间公司仓库
to be vacant...里头空无一人
"Two heads are better than one."“人多力量大”
Gilda?吉尔达？
Hey! You scared me.嘿 你吓到我了
I came home and I didn't know where you were.我回来找不到你
Did you hear me calling?有听到我叫你吗？
Please stay.求你留下来
I'm not going anywhere.我哪都不会去
I mean it. Don't leave me.我是说真的 别离开我
Baby, I know I haven't been around. And I'm sorry.亲爱的 我知道我最近很忙
But this job...很抱歉
It isn't forever.但这个工作只是暂时的
Hey, we caught a huge break tonight on this Falcone thing.法尔康尼的案子今晚大有斩获
Once I take him out, and I will take him out,等我击垮他 我会击垮他的
things are gonna be different.一切就会改变了
We can start a family.我们就能生孩子
You know I can't.你知道我不能
Of course you can. We can.你当然可以 我们可以的
We'll talk about options when you're ready,等你准备好 我们再来计划
but I need you to trust that we're still on track.但我需要你相信我们办得到
And that I love you.还有我很爱你
Now, are we still having movie night, or not?今晚的电影还算数吗？
No, don't even answer that. Come on.不 别回答 走吧
If we take 66th, we can cut them off at the westward bridge.走66街就能在西向大桥拦截他们
No. Maintain a safe distance for now.不 先保持安全距离
Good evening, sir. The Turkey is roasting,晚安 少爷 火鸡正在烤
the pies are cooling, and miss Kyle is en route.派已经凉了 凯尔小姐正在路上
Alfred, make a note to order a new windshield.阿福 记得订新的挡风玻璃
Bulletproof.要防弹的
Of course, sir, but if I may...好的 少爷 但容我…
Aah!（中国城）
I thought you didn't hurt people!我以为你不会伤人
You thought wrong.你误会了
You and your San ho hui buddies有人看到你和三合会同夥
were seen outside Harvey dent's house on Halloween.万圣节出现在哈维丹特家门外
We were trick-or-treating.我们是去讨糖
Having fun?好玩吗？
Not yet.还没开始呢
But any second now.马上就会好玩了
Yeah!去吧
Go. I'll keep an eye on your little friends.我会盯好这些小朋友
A "thank you" would be nice!这时应该说声“谢谢”
It is Thanksgiving.今天是感恩节
We can make this easy, Mickey.我们可以速战速决 米奇
Just tell me who hired you to kill dent.只要告诉我 是谁雇你去杀丹特
Go to hell, bat-freak!去死吧 死蝙蝠
Right now, the only difference between you and me现在 我俩唯一的不同是
is that I know what's down here.我知道这下面有什么
Grundy.格兰迪
He's mine.他是我的
Let him go.放了他
This is your place.这是你的地盘
Give him to me and I'll make sure he never sets foot down here again.把他交给我 我保证他不会再出现在这里
You can be alone.你可以一个人待在这里
Born on a Monday.星期一出生
One more for ya.又来一束花
My goodness.天啊
大家都对哈维很好
Oh, this one's not for your husband. It's for you.这不是给你先生的 是给你的
From a "Mr. Falcone."来自“法尔康尼先生”
I'm sorry, ma'am.抱歉 女士
It's none of my business...这不关我的事…
Isn't it time for his dinner?他的晚餐时间不是到了吗？
I don't wanna be here, Mick.我不想来这里 米奇
My wife's cooking Turkey with all the trimmings.我太太在忙着准备火鸡大餐
I love Turkey with all the trimmings.我喜欢火鸡大餐
So, just tell us what you know检察官家爆炸
about the bomb in the district attorney's house,你有什么内幕 和盘托出
then we can all go eat.我们就能去吃大餐了
I don't even know carmine Falcone.我根本不认识卡麦法尔康尼
The Roman contracted your triad to take out Harvey dent!罗马人雇了你的三合会 去解决哈维丹特
Your signature's all over it.完全是你的作案手法
Mickey, you gotta help me keep my friend here calm.米奇 你得帮我安抚我的朋友
Just give us something... Anything.只要告诉我们 任何线索都好
Someone's trying to frame me.有人想陷害我
I told you. I'm innocent.我说过了 我是清白的
Chairs are for suspects.椅子是给嫌犯坐的
This guy's innocent.这家伙是清白的
Hey. I thought we were just doing a thing.我以为只是要吓吓他
This little act doesn't get us anywhere if the guy gets hurt.要是这家伙受伤 我们就功亏一篑了
Maybe you guys should admit you have nothing on San ho hui.也许你们应该承认 你们没有三合会的把柄
If you had, you would've booked me already.否则早就逮捕我了
All right. That's it. Montoya!好了 够了 蒙托亚
Please, show our friend out.请带这位朋友出去
Maybe you should thank whoever planted that bomb.也许你该谢谢那位炸弹客
What did you say?你说什么？
You still haven't figured out who killed Johnny viti?你还不明白是谁杀了强尼维提吗？
Get him outta my sight.把他带走
You may be aces in a fistfight,你也许擅长拳脚功夫
but you've got a lot to learn about detective work.但查案你还有很多要学
I found him, didn't I?是我找到他的 不是吗？
It's not just about finding them.找到他们还不够
You gotta know how they're gonna help your case.你得知道怎么利用他们破案
Mickey chen is a small fish protected by Falcone.陈米奇背後有法尔康尼罩着
We were never going to get a confession.我们永远拿不到自白
We needed to make friends and, in time, flip him.我们应该跟他们交朋友 最後劝他们当污点证人
Keep talking like that, they'll make you da.继续说下去 有人会找你当检察官
Harvey isn't dead yet.哈维还没死
And he isn't a killer, either.他也不是凶手
No matter what that scumbag thinks.无论那个人渣怎么想
He's never even owned a gun.他连枪都没有
Falcone fits.法尔康尼有
The Roman killed viti and ordered the hit on dent.罗马人杀了维提 然後买凶杀害丹特
Occam's razor.奥坎剃刀法则
The simplest explanation is usually the right one.最简单的解释通常是正确的
All right. If I leave now, I might just make dinner.好吧 我现在走 可能赶得上晚餐
You should be with your people, too.你也应该跟家人团聚
Fine.好吧
Good night.晚安
Happy Thanksgiving, Mrs. dent.感恩节快乐 丹特太太
Now, I'm sure the missus is running out to pick up some real food,夫人一定是去外面享用餐点
but I guarantee you, you have never had pumpkin pie like...但我向你保证 这南瓜派你绝对没…
Uh, Mr. dent?丹特先生？
I just, you know, wanna get out of the city, I hate this place.我只是想离开这座城市 我讨厌这里
Nice.很好
The secret is the basil.秘诀在罗勒
You want only the youngest leaves from the youngest plant,只能用最嫩的叶子
otherwise, it's like mint.否则就像薄荷叶
Overpowers everything.喧宾夺主
We have a lot to be thankful for, Alberto.我们有很多事要感恩 阿尔贝托
Such as?例如？
Health. Family.健康、家人
What's left of it.仅剩的家人
If you are referring to your cousin Johnny,如果你指的是你表哥强尼
that is being handled.那件事已经处理好了
By Mickey chen.陈米奇办好了
And who do you think hired him?你以为是谁雇用他的？
Of course.当然
Is there something you wish to say?你想说什么吗？
No, poppa.没有 父亲
Except to point out that Harvey dent is still alive.我只是想说 哈维丹特还活着
Because I allow it.是我允许他活着的
For now.暂时活着
This...这就是…
This is what I keep talking about.这就是我一直在说的
This is Oxford.都是牛津大学害的
That place polluted your mind, Alberto.那个地方污染了你的脑袋 阿尔贝托
You used to know your place. Now?你以前很安分守己 现在呢？
I should have never sent you there.当初不该送你去的
The dangers of independent thought.独立思考的危险
When have you had one independent thought你有过任何想法
that actually benefited this family?是真正对这个家有帮助的吗？
Maybe when I sent flowers to dent's hospital room我以法尔康尼的名义送花到医院
in the Falcone name.给丹特的时候
You did what?你做了什么？
I sent flowers.我送花过去
I thought it would take suspicion off of us如果我们关心他的复原状况
if we looked like we care about his recovery.就能摆脱嫌疑
Now, I suppose you'll say it was a sloppy move.我想你会说这是草率的行为
I can forgive sloppy.我可以原谅草率的行为
What I will not tolerate,我不能忍受的是
is you presuming to speak on behalf of this family.你自作主张 代表这个家发声
Let me be perfectly clear.让我再跟你
Again.说清楚
Any notion you may hold about being next in line若你指望
to take over our business interests接掌整个家族事业
is a pathetic delusion.不用痴心妄想
You are weak.你真懦弱
Your weakness is my liability.你的懦弱只会扯我後腿
You are to have zero contact with Mr. or Mrs. Harvey dent.不准你再去找丹特夫妇
End of discussion.我说完了
Harvey!哈维
Hello.嗨
I got a call that you went missing from the hospital.我接到电话说你在医院失踪
How did I know I'd find you here?谁想得到你会在这里
Couldn't stand being cooped up anymore.我不想再被关在那里了
Thought I'd stretch my legs.想出来动一动
Yeah.嗯
Listen, why don't you hop in? I'll take you back.上车吧 我载你回去
Oh, no. No. No. No. No. I like it out here.不 我喜欢待在这里
I'm on my way home for Thanksgiving dinner.我正要回家吃感恩节晚餐
You should come along. Barbara always makes a ton.一起来吧 芭芭拉老是煮一堆
I'm not hungry.我不饿
Harvey, what are we doing here?哈维 我们在这里做什么？
I don't know. Maybe I wasn't ready for this yet.不知道 也许我还没准备好
I think I'm gonna go back now.我想我该回去了
Don't you worry about Harvey.别担心哈维
All right, counselor.好吧 律师
As far as I'm concerned, you don't have this.对我来说 你没有这把枪
The falcones are dangerous people and, to them, you're the bad guy.法尔康尼家族是危险分子 他们视你为眼中钉
Protect your family.保护好家人
So, I made him an offer, you know.所以我开了个条件给他
To the family.敬家人
Those dearly departed...敬离开我们的挚爱…
And those whom we are fortunate to have beside us here today.以及有幸还在身边的家人
Let us be thankful for the time we still have together让我们感恩能在此团聚
and for the many blessings bestowed upon us.并拥有许多祝福
- Alla salute!   - Salute!-乾杯   -乾杯
Ah, yes.没错
- Oh, look.   - Oh, come here!-你看   -快过来
- Oh-ho!   - Yeah!好耶
- I told you I'd walk.   - Very good. Very good.-就说我会出来的   -很好
Yeah!太好了
Welcome back.欢迎回来
Barbara?芭芭拉？
Solomon grundy...所罗门格兰迪…
Born on a Monday...星期一出生
Believe me, I told him where he could stick the cape.相信我 我教他怎么钉住披风
Even Gordon laughed.连高登都笑了
That's when they let me go.他们就放我走了
（感恩节）
You don't need me for this. I should be out hunting.你不需要找我来 我应该在外面调查才对
We've got it covered.我们都处理好了
All of Gotham pd will be deployed throughout town by midnight.所有警察午夜前会布署在全城
One way or another, when holiday comes calling, we'll be ready.无论如何 假日杀手一出现 警方会准备好
You know, this was all you.你知道 这都是因为你
I wanted them in Gotham penitentiary.我原本想把他们关进高谭市监狱
This was Harvey. And he was right.这是哈维的主意 他是对的
Calendar man.日历人
So...所以…
A killer who only works on holidays.只在假日下手的杀手
And it's December 24th.今天是平安夜
I was wondering when you'd get to me.我还在想 你们何时才会来
We don't have much time, day.我们没多少时间 戴伊
Who killed Johnny viti on Halloween?谁在万圣节杀了强尼维提？
The same person who killed Mickey chen and his crew on Thanksgiving.凶手也在感恩节 杀了陈米奇和他的同夥
We need a better answer than that.你得回答得再详细点
Viti was the Roman's nephew.维提是罗马人的侄子
The Roman was chen's employer.罗马人是陈的雇主
First suspect is, therefore, the Roman.因此 头号嫌犯就是罗马人
But since sneaking around isn't really Falcone's style,但鬼鬼祟祟不是法尔康尼的作风
we move on to the second suspect.还有第二位嫌疑犯
Someone hoping for the fall of the Roman empire.一个希望罗马帝国毁灭的人
Like sal maroni.例如 萨尔马洛尼
He's as good a guess as any of the others.他跟其他人一样有嫌疑
What "others"?其他人是谁？
You're down a man.你们少一个人
This is a waste of time.这是在浪费时间
I told you to bring Mr. dent.我叫你带丹特先生来
He isn't safe out there.他在外头不安全
The da who put you all in arkham?让你们进阿卡汉的检察官？
Half the patients here would kill him on sight,半数的病患看到他就会杀了他
so, I'd say out there is the only place he is safe.我倒觉得他在外面才安全
Perhaps.也许吧
Or perhaps he doesn't know you're here.也许他不知道你在这里
Perhaps...也许…
The district attorney...检察官
Is a suspect.就是嫌犯？
Well, of course. Intelligent, calculating,当然了 聪明 工於心计
with a mission to take down carmine Falcone.打算击溃卡麦法尔康尼
It all fits.全都符合
Harvey dent is not a killer.哈维丹特不是凶手
Unless he's leading a double life.除非他过着双重生活
Like your caped crusader, here.就像这位披风战士
Why did you ask for me?你为什么找我来？
So you could see for yourself.这样你就能亲眼看到
I don't have time for your crazy.我没空听你发疯
You really don't.没这个必要
There's lots of crazy out there these days.近来外头疯子可多了
And just when you thought you'd cleaned it all up.你以为将他们清乾净了
What a...真是
Joke.可笑
Happy holiday.假期愉快
Open it!开门
（丹特检察官 哈哈哈）
He had somebody get to my kid!他派人去对付我的小孩
If... if I didn't help him.如果…如果我不帮他
I'm sorry.对不起
Harvey isn't safe.哈维不安全
Go!去吧
"Tis the season to be jolly令人愉快的季节
Outside it's an awful chiller外面冷得要死
Boy, this holiday's a killer老天 这个假期真迷人
Gilda? Is that you?吉尔达？是你吗？
"Gilda"!“吉尔达”
She looked like a gilda.她看起来像吉尔达
在找这个吗？
Relax, lollipop!别紧张 甜心
Police issue.这是警方该管的
Where's my wife?我太太呢？
She's just where I left her, last-minute shopping.我看到她在做最後的采买
Spoiler alert. It's socks.透露一下 她要送你袜子
What do you want?你想要什么？
Aww, I thought I was playing santi claus!我以为是我扮圣诞老人
Oh, all right.好吧
I want a fire engine and a football and...我要消防车、橄榄球 还要
To deliver a message.送你一则讯息
Put the gun down and we'll talk.把枪放下之後再谈
Sure!好啊
Your suspicions were correct.您怀疑得没错
A Santa clown has reportedly terrorized three families today.据说圣诞小丑今天已经恐吓了三个家庭
Sir, they were all named "dent."少爷 他们都姓丹特
Where did you get that?你怎么会有那个？
Why? Ya missin' one?怎么？你的不见了吗？
You could use some cheering up!你需要打打气
Have ya heard the one about the murderous clown that escaped the asylum有没有听过一个杀人小丑逃出精神病院
and showed up at the home of the da who put him there?跑去把他关进精神病院的检察官家里？
See, there's a persistent rumor round these parts最近一直有传言 丹特检察官本人
that da dent is more than he appears to be.并不是外界看到的那样
But there's only room for one homicidal maniac in this town.但这座城市只容得下一个杀人狂
And if I hear that happy Harvey dent is steppin' out,只要我听到快乐哈维丹特出门
I'll make sure little gilda doesn't have to clothes-shop我就让小吉尔达从此不用再采买
for hubby-wubby ever again.老公的衣服
You call that a joke?你以为很好笑吗？
But you haven't even heard the punchline!我还没说到最精采的地方
It goes like this!就是这个
Harvey.哈维
Harvey, can you hear me?哈维 听得见吗？
Any idea where he was heading?你知道他跑去哪里吗？
Maroni...马洛尼
Mangia.蒙日
What happened to your friend's face, maroni?你朋友的脸怎么了 马洛尼？
Nothin'. What happened to yours?没什么 那你的脸呢？
Oh, you mother...你这混…
Tell me everything he said.告诉我他说过的话
If you get off of my neck.只要你松开我
He was inside before we got there.我们到的时候 他就在里面了
Took out the whole staff, poisoned the fagioli.他杀了所有人 在豆汤里下毒
I wasn't hungry, but, uh, Freddy, here...我当时并不饿 但弗雷迪…
I don't know. Guess I'm lucky.不知道 我大概是走运吧
No. He let you live. Why?不 他留你活口 为什么？
Do I look like I know?我看起来像知道的样子吗？
He put a gun in my face and told me that this is his turf他拿枪指着我的脸 说这里是他的地盘
and that he's cracking down on interlopers.他会除掉干涉他的人
Maybe I should thank him.也许我应该感谢他
I don't know where you get off.我不知道你是怎么想的
Freaks like this clown used to play way out on the fringe,像小丑这种怪胎 以前只游走在法律边缘
but once you showed up...但你出现後…
Relax, pal.别紧张 朋友
Ya know, things used to run smooth in this town.你知道 以前这座城市很安宁
Now, we got killer crocs and moths and sewer zombies,现在有杀手鳄 杀手蛾和下水道殭屍
not to mention a homicidal maniac更别提还有个杀人狂
skulking around the holidays hittin' made men.专挑节日出没 干掉黑帮成员
What's the common thread? Huh.共同点是什么？
（小丑）
Where is he?他在哪里？
Who knows? He's a nutjob.谁知道？他是个疯子
But if he's the guy killin' Falcone's men,但如果是他杀了法尔康尼的手下
it's only a matter of time till he gets to old carmine himself.那他迟早会去对付卡麦
Maybe start there.你该从那里查起
Not really much of a detective, are ya?你不擅长当侦探 对吧？
Hello.嗨
Navy, Navy, charcoal, black.藏青色、藏青色、深灰色、黑色
Really, carm, is a splash of color too much to ask?拜托 卡麦 试试不同颜色会怎样吗？
Stop clowning around. If you're gonna kill me, just do it.少耍猴戏 要杀我就快动手
Is this the face of a killer?这是杀手的脸吗？
I guess it is!我想是的
Oh, relax, polpetto, I'm not going to kill you.别紧张 小家伙 我不会杀了你
Not tonight, anyway.今晚不会
It's Christmas!今天是圣诞节
But...不过…
Someone will die tonight.今晚会有人死
Probably someone close to you.也许是你亲近的人
Don't you want to know who's pulling the trigger?你难道不想知道开枪的会是谁吗？
Anyhoo, I just popped in to say,总之 我只是来说一声
if you hear any news about the holiday investigation,如果你有假日杀手案的调查情报
I'd like you to pass it my way.希望你通知我一声
As a professional courtesy.基於职业礼貌
Here's my card!这是我的名片
Buon natale!圣诞快乐
Buon natale.圣诞快乐
I kill me.我真幽默
What the hell?搞什么？
Missed me!没打中
You know what I forgot?知道我忘了什么吗？
Whoa! That was close.哇 好险
（圣诞节）
I would remind you, sir,少爷 容我提醒您
of Mr. Falcone's annual benefit for the Gotham children's clinic.法尔康尼先生为高谭儿童医院举办的年度义卖会
It would be advisable to show your face at least one year.建议您至少去露一次面
Your father built that hospital.那间医院是令尊盖的
He helped the Roman build it.他帮罗马人盖的
Still, a good cause.也算是做善事
And, frankly, a night on a yacht could do you some good.坦白说 参加游艇晚宴对您有益
Miss Kyle will be there.凯尔小姐也会出席
Three murders on three holidays.三个节日谋杀案
Each of the victims a Falcone associate.被害者都跟法尔康尼有关
All shot with the same type of untraceable gun.凶器都是无法追踪的同一款枪
No withesses.没有目击者
Suspects?嫌疑犯呢？
Salvatore maroni.萨尔瓦多马洛尼
His family's always been second to the Roman.他的家族一直都不如罗马人
He's notoriously ambitious.他是个野心勃勃的家伙
But he's killed Falcone's men in broad daylight.但他在光天化日之下 杀了法尔康尼的手下
Why the cloak-and-dagger holiday business?为什么要搞奇怪的假日杀人戏码？
Carla viti, Falcone's sister.卡拉维提 法尔康尼的妹妹
Runs their Chicago operation.负责他们的芝加哥据点
She could be making a play for control of the family.她有可能为了掌控家族 搞了这一出
By killing her only son on Halloween?在万圣节杀了独子？
She is a criminal.她是罪犯
And he is a homicidal maniac.他是杀人狂
The guard testified that he escaped before the first murder.狱警作证 他在首起谋杀案前就逃了
The Roman himself.罗马人自己杀的
Johnny viti was about to flip强尼维提本来打算叛变
and Mickey chen could testify that Falcone ordered dent's murder.陈米奇有可能作证 是法尔康尼雇他去杀丹特
He had motive to silence them both.他有杀他们两人的动机
But why kill his own bodyguard?但为什么要杀自己的保镳？
May I ask why you're keeping the fifth suspect off the board?可以问您 为什么不怀疑第五位嫌疑犯吗？
Because I don't like it.因为我不喜欢
But it fits. Doesn't it?但符合 不是吗？
Obsessed with taking down Falcone.他一心一意想击溃法尔康尼
More than boss maroni and every ambitious made man in town.完全不把黑帮老大马洛尼和城里其他帮派放在眼里
He was turned down for a gun license last year,他去年的枪枝使用申请没过
when the psych eval showed some wild aberrations.因为心理评估报告指出 他有严重的精神错乱
Or is it someone else entirely?或根本另有其人？
Someone we haven't even considered.一个我们从未考虑的人
I thought this would be about sweeping criminals off the street,我本来以为是要扫除街上的罪犯
maybe scaring them straight.把他们吓到改邪归正
I never thought that Batman was going to have to be a detective.没想到蝙蝠侠有一天还得当侦探
A good one.优秀的侦探
What if I can't save them, Alfred?要是我无法救他们呢 阿福？
I've seen these growing pains before, sir,我以前就见过这些痛苦 少爷
and I am confident that, in the end,我有信心 到了最後
the Batman will be what the world needs him to be.蝙蝠侠会成为世人心目中的模样
The same, I believe, should be said of Bruce Wayne.这也能套用在布鲁斯韦恩身上
My distinguished guests,各位嘉宾
it is my honor to welcome you here tonight.欢迎各位今晚莅临
I see a lot of familiar faces. Mayor.我看见许多熟面孔 市长
Your eminence.主教阁下
No, I was talking to sal maroni.不 我说的是萨尔马洛尼
Sal maroni. On my yacht.萨尔马洛尼在我的船上
It's like my father always said, "keep your enemies close...正如家父常说的 “靠近你的敌人
And a loaded gun closer."并随身携带手枪”
Thirty years ago, a small group of concerned gothamites30年前 一群热心的高谭小子
joined together to build something携手打造一个
the politicians squabbling in the halls of government could not.市政厅里唇枪舌战的政客盖不了的东西
Dr. Thomas Wayne and I built the children's clinic to protect families.汤玛士韦恩医生和我盖了儿童医院 保护众多家庭
And if you know me,如果各位了解我
you know there is nothing more important to me than family.就知道我最看重家人
So, buon anno!新年快乐
Thank you all for being here and for your generosity.感谢各位莅临及慷慨解囊
Let's beat last year's total.让我们打破去年的纪录
Remember, cash only, please.记住 只收现金
Also, I would like to thank our corporate sponsors,我也想感谢企业赞助商
kord omniversal, soder cola,柯德寰宇、索德可乐
and, for the 10th year running, Gotham broadcasting company.以及成立十周年的高谭广播公司
I'm so sorry!抱歉
Here, let me.我扶你
No, thank you.不 谢谢你
One more thing, and then I promise I'll let you enjoy the party.再说一件事 我保证就让各位享受派对
I would like to acknowledge someone.我想感谢一个人
As I said, nothing is more important to me than family.正如我所说的 我最看重家人
And, perhaps, my one regret我很後悔
is making this man feel like he is not a part of this family.让这个人觉得 自己不是这个家的一分子
We have not always agreed on details.在细节上 我们有时意见分歧
But we agree on the most important things.但我们都赞同几个重要的观念
We believe in family.我们相信家人
We believe in business.相信事业
And, like all of you here tonight,像今晚莅临的所有嘉宾一样
we believe in Gotham city.我们都相信高谭市
Ladies and gentlemen, the son I never had...各位先生女士 他就是我视如己出的
Mr. Bruce Wayne.布鲁斯韦恩先生
- I think I see them!   - Wh-what?-我好像看到他们了   -什么？
As if it matters. I hardly ever see you, anyway.说得好像很重要一样 我几乎都见不到你了
I'm just saying, there's no need to...我只是说 没必要…
Hey, Harvey!嗨 哈维
Shouldn't you be working, captain?你不是在值勤吗 队长？
I am.我在值勤啊
This is the largest police presence this city's ever seen.这是高谭市史上 最大规模的警察集结
We got caught with our pants down on Christmas,我们圣诞节遭遇挫折
but heaven help holiday if he tries anything here tonight.但假日杀手如果今晚想出手 只能自求多福了
Always on duty.无时无刻都在值勤
Always.无时无刻
You didn't bring the kids?你没带孩子出来？
They're sleeping over at my mother's tonight.他们今晚在我母亲家过夜
We should try and hire you to sit next time, gilda.下次应该请你帮忙带孩子 吉尔达
I bet you're great with kids.你一定很会带小孩
I haven't worked as a sitter in years.我很多年没当保母了
It paid her way through law school.她当保母赚钱念完法学院
I didn't know you're a lawyer.我不知道你是律师
I was.曾经是
Now, I'm not anything.现在我什么都不是
Dead pilot? Check.飞行员死了？确认
Ground crew? Check.地勤人员？确认
Poison gas? Check.毒气？确认
Time to ring in the new year.是时候迎接新年了
Ladies and gentlemen, please fasten your seatbelts,各位先生女士 请系好安全带
as I have no idea how to fly this thing!因为我不知道怎么驾驶这玩意儿
Looks like a real party.看起来像真正的派对
So, what the hell are we doing here?我们到底在这里干嘛？
I don't know.不知道
Something tells me this is where I need to be tonight.我的直觉告诉我 今晚非来不可
We...我们…
Look, we haven't talked, and I think we should.我们没好好谈过 我们应该谈谈
I feel like whatever this is...我觉得无论问题在哪…
Whatever we've tried to be to one another is... unraveling.无论我们想为对方做什么 都失败了
And we both know why.我们都清楚为什么
We've never spoken of it,我们从不谈这件事
but the truth is that you and I are two different people.但事实是 我俩差别很大
It was fun to try...尝试的过程很有趣
But I don't think we're ever gonna be able to put it all together.但我们可能永远无法结合
I guess we're just not cut out for...我想我们就是无法变成
Whatever this is.心目中的彼此
Was.都过去了
Don't worry, though. I'll see you on the other side.不过别担心 回头见了
When did you do it?你什么时候做的？
Do what?做什么？
You took my watch without me noticing.趁我不注意时拿走我的表
So, when did you do it? I'm curious.你什么时候做的？我很好奇
Take it from me, Bruce,听我一句 布鲁斯
around here, curiosity can get you killed.在这里 好奇心会害死你
Not now.现在没空
What?什么？
Where?哪里？
I just want to have a normal night. Can we just have a normal night?我只想过个平凡的夜晚 我们能过个平凡的夜晚吗？
I don't even know what that is anymore.我都不知道什么叫平凡了
I am alone here.我在这里好孤单
I told myself it was okay because it would get better, but it hasn't.我告诉自己没关系 一切都会好转 但没有
You don't have to be alone.你不需要一个人
We've talked about having a baby.我们谈过生小孩的事
I can't! You know that I can't!我没办法 你知道我没办法
Maybe not the old-fashioned way,也许不用传统的方式
but that doesn't mean that we can't try something...那不代表我们不能试…
I don't want it.我不想生孩子
I don't want it because I can't and I can't because I don't want it.我不想 因为我不能生 我不能生 因为我不想生
Can we please talk about this in private?我们可以私下谈吗？
Jesus, why can't you be more like...天啊 你为什么不能变得像…
More like who?像谁？
I'm only one man.我只是一个普通人
I can't do this.我做不到
Not now.我现在不想谈
Excuse us.我们先失陪了
Jim, did you know they're having these kinds of problems?吉姆 你知道他们有这些问题吗？
Jim?吉姆？
Yeah. I see it now.嗯 我看到了
What's going on?怎么回事？
Crappy new year!新年不快乐
Hey.嘿
Should all offenses be forgot and never brought to trial...所有罪行是否该被遗忘 而且不用审判…
Oh, silly me. The safety. Ha!噢 我真蠢 安全阀 哈
Ooh, pretty.太好了
Well, shit.该死
Economy class ain't what she used to be. Ha!经济舱跟以前不一样了
This area needs to be clear!撤离这一区
- Everyone remain calm.   - This way!-大家保持冷静   -这边
- Pearce!   - Captain, sir!-皮尔斯   -队长
I need to get my wife out of here.带我太太离开这里
Yes, sir! Follow me, ma'am.好的 长官 请跟我来 夫人
What are you trying to prove with this stunt, joker?你想用这些噱头证明什么 小丑？
Prove? Stunt? Joker?证明？噱头？小丑？
No, wait, that one's right.不 最後一个是对的
- Why did you kill Johnny viti?   - What?-你为什么要杀强尼维提？   -什么？
And Mickey chen and milos grappa?还有陈米奇跟米洛斯葛莱帕？
You think I'm holiday?你以为我是假日杀手？
Oh, poppet, I didn't know you cared.宝贝 我不知道你这么关心我
Of course I'm not holiday!我当然不是假日杀手
If I were him, why would I be trying to kill him?我如果是他 怎么还会想杀他？
Kill him?杀他？
He's the competition!他是竞争对手啊
And, like the corn kernel always says,就像玉米罐头上说的
"I won't be number two."“我只当最好的”
If it's holiday you want dead...如果你想杀了假日杀手…
Then why gas everyone in Gotham square?干嘛对整个高谭广场释放毒气？
Half the city's down there,全市一半的人都在下面
which means holiday either is, or isn't!表示假日杀手要嘛在里面 要嘛不在
I have a 50-50 chance.我有一半的机率成功
And if I fail, well, at least I've killed a lot of innocent people.如果失败了 至少我杀了很多无辜的人
No, don't kill me! Not before I find out who holiday is!不 别杀我 先等我找到假日杀手
Why do you care?你何必在乎？
Oh, you adorable fool!你这个小笨蛋
Don't you know by now? I'm just like youl!你还不懂吗？我就跟你一样啊
We both love a good puzzle.我们都喜欢谜团
So, when the clock strikes 12:00,等12点的钟声响起
do I get a little kiss?我能得到一个吻吗？
Whoop! Taking that as a "no."这是不要的意思吧
There goes my resolution.我的愿望泡汤了
out of the way. Now! Move!让开 快点 快让开
Alberto, right?你是阿尔贝托吧？
Selina.我是赛琳娜
Can I ask you a question?能问一个问题吗？
I'm trying to imagine what it's like to grow up around all this.我试着想像 在这样的环境成长是什么感觉
I wouldn't know.我也不知道
"Mr. family" had me in boarding schools overseas before I could walk.在我学走路前 “家族先生”就把我送到海外寄宿学校
Which is fine. I would have never fit in here, anyway.这没关系 反正我也不能融入这里
I'm an Oxford graduate who's learned more about business我毕业於牛津大学 我对商业的了解程度
than my father could ever hope to understand, yet...是家父永远也无法想像的 但是…
You don't get a seat at the table.你无法成为核心成员
Because I'm "weak." I fell in love.因为我懦弱 我爱上了一个人
How is that weak?那怎么会懦弱呢？
She was the wrong woman. Wrong for the family.她不是正确的对象 对家族没有益处
Wrong for him.对他没有益处
And, back then, I was so desperate for his approval.我当时很渴望得到他的认可
What happened to her?她後来怎么了？
Terrible things.很惨
I let him scare her away from me.我让他把她吓跑
Which, ironically, only proved that he was right about me in the first place.讽刺的是 这证明了他一开始就没看错我
Weak. An embarrassment.懦弱 丢人现眼
I'm sorry, I don't mean to...抱歉 我不是有意…
Why do I feel like I can talk to you?为什么我觉得能跟你聊？
Uh, I, um...我…
I just...我只是…
Oh, no. No, I'm sorry, I...不 抱歉 我…
I can't... we can't.我不行…我们不能这样
Get away from her.离她远一点
Bruce!布鲁斯
Wait. Bruce? Wayne?等等 布鲁斯？韦恩？
Bruce Wayne is the Batman?布鲁斯韦恩是蝙蝠侠？
And Alberto Falcone is holiday.阿尔贝托法尔康尼是假日杀手
Surprises all around.每天都有惊喜
Me? You've been fed some bad clues, Bruce.我？你被错的线索误导了 布鲁斯
But I still solved the puzzle.但我还是解开了谜题
The rejected son, born to inherit an empire, but cast aside.不被接受的儿子 本来能继承帝国 却被排除在外
You're wrong.你错了
You knew you'd never be handed the keys to the kingdom,你明白你永远得不到王国的钥匙
so you manufactured a crisis that targets the family business.於是制造了危机 要破坏家族事业
What?什么？
With potential successors dropping like flies,可能的继任者陆续遇害後
poppa tightened the circle to family only,父亲只将事业交由家族管理
and, for the first time, you were on the inside.於是你首次进入了核心
I don't want control of the family!我不想管理这个家
I never did!我从没想过
Ten! Nine! Eight! Seven! Six! Five!十 九 八 七 六 五
Four! Three!四 三
I would happily trade that for a normal life!我很乐意拿这个身分 交换普通的人生
To spend my days as far away from Gotham as possible.离开高谭 到远方过日子
Two! One! Happy new year!二 一 新年快乐
To get married, and have a child with...结婚生子…
Oh, my god!天啊
You couldn't know. You're missing so many pieces.你不可能懂的 你遗漏了太多线索
（新年）
Come on.走吧
Jim, what the hell are we doing?吉姆 我们到底在干什么？
The divers will be fishing out parts of Alberto Falcone for days.潜水员会花几天打捞 阿尔贝托法尔康尼剩下的遗体
Five-bladed prop on its slowest speed.五叶螺旋桨以最慢速运行 这样卷进去
Hell of a way to go.死法真惨烈
That isn't how he went.那不是他的死因
He was shot by holiday before going overboard.他在落水前就被假日杀手枪杀了
Hang on. Alberto wasn't holiday?等等 阿尔贝托不是假日杀手？
I thought he was.我原本以为他是
It was occam's razor, Jim, the simplest solution.这是奥坎剃刀原则 吉姆 最简单的解决方法
But it was wrong.但那是错的
I went there for Alberto Falcone.我去船上找阿尔贝托法尔康尼
I thought I was supposed to stop him,我以为我要阻止他
but I was supposed to save him.但我应该是要救他才对
He was innocent. And now he's dead.他是清白的 但现在他死了
I needed to be better.我必须再谨慎点
We all did.我们都是
All of us.所有人都是
You have to put a protective detail on carmine Falcone.你必须派维安人员保护卡麦法尔康尼
If he'll even let you.如果他肯让你这么做的话
Do you realize we started out trying to take down the Roman,你知道我们起初是要击垮罗马人
and, now, we're trying to save him?现在却是要救他吗？
When did that happen?什么时候变成这样的？
I have a better question.我有更好的问题
If Alberto Falcone wasn't holiday... Then who is?如果阿尔贝托法尔康尼不是假日杀手 那谁才是？
And who's next?他的下个目标是谁？
（谨以本片纪念娜娅里维拉）
Grant that our brother may sleep here in peace until you awaken him to glory,愿我们的兄弟长眠於此 直到蒙主召唤
for you are the resurrection and the life.因为您代表复活与生命
Then he will see you face to face届时他将与您面对面
and in your light will see light您让他看见光辉
and know the splendor of god.明白上帝的璀璨之处
Amen.阿门
Bruce.布鲁斯
A word.借一步说话
Carmine. If there's anything I can do.卡麦 需要我帮忙的地方尽管说
You know what I want you to do but, time and time again, you refuse me.你知道我要你帮什么忙 你却一再拒绝我
The Wayne foundation isn't a money-laundering outfit for the mob.韦恩基金会不是让黑帮洗钱的地方
And it won't be, so long as I'm in control.永远都不是 只要我还是主席
Of course.当然
Oh, how rude of me.我真失礼
I don't believe you've met my associate.我想你还没见过我的合夥人
Charmed.幸会