Tell me this never has to end.
All things wither, Bruce,
but if we're lucky... not for a long time.
Aren't you forgetting something?
Again?
I can't resist you.
No man can.
You've been a good boy.
The foundation
was such a burden to you,
to us... just like
the rest of the company.
You know what you have to do
so we can be together.
Mr. Wayne, I think you've
over fed your philodendron.
Stop!
This isn't you, Bruce.
She's controlling you somehow.
Oh, hell. Sorry!
Oh.
How did you know?
Well, you haven't exactly
been discreet.
Appearing with Ivy in public and
signing assets over to the Roman.
I'll wake the lawyers, sir.
Police will be here any minute.
Tell them everything you
remember and then get to bed.
You look awful.
I told you
I don't want a partner.
You sure wanted one
these past three months.
Three months?
It took a while to catch the jolly
green jezebel with her guard down.
- And holiday?
- Still at large.
Gilda, I'm sorry.
We'll make the late movie.
I'm looking forward to it.
I think I'd like to go home.
Why? We can...
Yeah. Yeah, okay.
Jesus!
Harvey...
You were right.
Chong's been supplying holiday
with his guns.
You should have listened to me,
Jim, moved on this guy sooner.
We might have learned something.
The holiday killer's
covering his tracks.
Mother's day.
This one snuck up on us.
Sure did.
Where's our friend?
Who helped you escape?
Give me a name or I'll...
It was my mother.
That's who helped me.
I strangled the old witch
years ago,
but I think she still watches
over handsome little jonny.
Happy mother's day.
Mother.
Through here.
Sweetheart,
I don't know if this is the...
Take what you want.
Don't hurt us.
Is he okay?
I don't care. Let's go.
Bruce, what are you doing?
Mother?
We have to get you home.
Bruce!
Where... where is she, Alfred?
- She?
- My... my mother.
I was with my mother.
Up we go.
Gotham police
are searching for two inmates
that escaped
from arkham asylum last night.
One of them, Dr. Jonathan
crane, aka the scarecrow,
stole one of arkham's horses
from the grounds.
He's considered
extremely dangerous.
Anyone with knowledge
of his whereabouts
needs to call the Gotham pd
hotline right away.
Again, he's considered
highly dangerous.
Wait.
I packed your lunch.
Thanks. I gotta go.
I've come to see my father.
It's a tie.
And, yes,
my parole officer knows I'm here.
Sofia, my little girl.
Heat give you
any trouble downstairs?
There's more cops here than I ever
saw in ten years on the inside.
"Holiday detail." For my
protection, or so they tell me.
- Listen, I'm very busy, so...
- That's why I need to talk to you.
Poppa, I want to be in the room.
Sofia, we have
already discussed...
I executed the crane escape
like you ordered.
And this foolish war
with sal maroni, I think...
Basta!
Things... are strained.
Half our top earners have been taken
out by either holiday or maroni.
We had a chance with Wayne, but now
that he's out, we have to restructure.
That is exactly why you need me.
I do not.
Sofia, if I bring you in now, our new earners
will think I am lining up a successor.
And that will make me
look old... and weak.
You are neither.
Nevertheless.
Good. End of discussion.
Now go buy something.
Big, flashy. A dress, a car. I don't care.
Just make sure everybody sees it.
Happy father's day, poppa.
Awful business at first Gotham.
How do you know
it was the scarecrow?
Crane recently fled arkham.
Gases all of his victims with a
fear-inducing neurotoxin, so...
Yeah, you can't really miss him.
- Look, so, Mr. Wayne...
- It's Bruce.
Can I get you anything?
Alfred makes a terrific Mai Tai.
It's 8:30 in the mor...
No... no, thank you.
We have some questions
about new year's Eve.
The night Alberto Falcone
was murdered.
Harvey here was updating
the files.
And it seems that you were the
only passenger on that yacht
who didn't give us a statement.
Afraid I'm not much help.
I left the party before all
the commotion in a dinghy.
You probably noticed
it was missing.
Of course, I'd have given you
a statement anyway,
except that it would have been
a matter of public record
and could place my name next to that
of the young lady I went to meet.
I don't think her husband
likes me very much.
That's very convenient.
Well, not for her husband.
Here's what
I'm trying to understand.
You recently signed over
significant areas of your business
- to carmine Falcone.
- That's all been reversed.
And I was drugged and manipulated,
if that's what you mean.
Was your father drugged
and manipulated
when he went into business
with the Roman?
You know everything
that monster is today
was born of the legitimacy
handed him by the name Wayne...
Harvey.
It's all right. Yes,
my father built hospitals with Falcone...
But the only influence
he was under
was an overwhelming desire
to save innocent lives.
And how many other innocent lives
did he end up trading for it?
Two... that I know of.
Please help my son.
I have nowhere else to go.
- This way! Over here.
- Onto the desk.
Looks like four...
No, five bullet wounds to the chest.
You shouldn't have come here.
Your son needs to be in a hospital.
Where Luigi maroni could
find him and finish the job?
No, Dr. Wayne, please.
Carmine is my only son.
I'll do what I can.
- Alfred, get my bag.
- Right away, sir.
He's stable, but I don't want
to move him yet.
Grazie. I can never repay you.
He isn't out of the woods.
Come on,
we have to let him rest.
You shouldn't be here.
It's okay.
Do you know who my father is?
The Roman?
Smart kid.
So you know who I'm going to be?
The Roman.
Very smart.
You remind me of my boy.
Your pop saved my life.
I guess that makes us family.
It fell out of your pocket.
My insurance policy.
There's a lot of bad people
out there.
Criminals.
And everybody knows criminals
are superstitious.
Sometimes all it takes to get out of a
bad situation is a good flip of the coin.
It didn't work for you tonight?
Yeah.
Still, two heads
are better than one.
No?
Keep it, kid.
All we get is all we take.
I was eight when Dr. Thomas Wayne
pulled Luigi maroni's bullets
out of Falcone's chest.
My father was dead by a
mobster's hand within a year.
Any connection between my family
and the Roman died then, too.
Thank you for stopping by.
If there's nothing else...
Gentlemen,
these are the names and addresses
for those who can account for master Wayne's
whereabouts on the night in question.
A lot of names on here.
Must have been quite a night.
Yes, well, a man was murdered.
Let us hope your respective
offices can deliver for him
the justice still denied
Thomas and Martha Wayne.
What happened to them
was a tragedy.
And all the more reason why your boss
should stay away from men like Falcone.
Will there ever be a time
when the sins of fathers
don't fall to their sons
for redemption?
Good day.
They're going to be watching my every move
today to confirm that I'm not the killer.
Then you'll be staying in?
No, just pay off
some more alibis.
I have to go to work.
Sit tight.
If he knew about us,
it would kill him.
I'll be right here, love.
Your favorite cannolis.
Cannoli. Cannolo for one,
cannoli for a box.
Your Italian is sterco.
I know, poppa. I'm sorry.
Yeah. You bring cannoli
on father's day, I forgive.
Sit.
So...
This war with Falcone.
It's killing us, pop.
Carmine thinks we've got something
to do with this... this holiday jerk.
Sciocchezze.
Carmine's paranoia is not to do
with holiday but with the new da.
Unless these two are one
and the same.
Dent's a crusader but I can't
see him getting his hands dirty.
More likely the bat.
You want advice? Win or lose,
the only thing that ends war
is peace.
Make peace with carmine?
Poppa...
I don't know.
I don't...
Poppa!
Sal!
I heard a gunshot.
Are you okay?
What happened?
Strange place to do business.
Guessing it's the last spot the
pigs leave you alone these days.
Working late?
How the hell
did you get through security?
You were with him, right?
I needed to put an end to the
stupid war with the falcones.
My father's last words to me were that
I should make peace with my enemy.
At first I thought
he meant carmine,
but Luigi maroni
would have never wanted that.
There's only one other thing
he could have meant, so...
I'm here to make peace with the law.
Cut a deal.
You want Falcone
and I got plenty on him.
Enough to put him away for good.
In exchange for...
Dropping all outstanding
warrants against me and my men.
You want Falcone?
That's the deal.
Take it or leave it.
Tell you what.
Heads, I'll take it.
I expected a low turnout
after the new year's fiasco.
- But this is really pathetic.
- Fine by me.
The more people stay home,
the easier my job gets.
Speaking of jobs getting easier,
is it true you got maroni?
It's not a done deal.
My office is working out
the details now.
But if ol' sal tells a judge
what he's told me...
Let's just say today's
a good day for the Roman
to celebrate
what's left of his freedom.
Speak of the devil.
I'm surprised to find you
outdoors on a holiday.
- Dent.
- Falcone.
Actually, I was speaking
to your wife... Mrs. Dent.
Don't touch her.
I never took you
for a patriot, carmine.
Oh, I wouldn't miss fireworks
like this for all the world.
Good evening,
Mrs. Dent, captain.
Evening.
I tell you, harv, if I could, I'd have
every cop in the city here tonight.
See you on the other side.
Utter
inanity proved his insanity
while he rattled
a couple of bones.
I've been thinking about it
and maybe you're right.
Uh, about what?
Having kids.
Stay down.
Get to Gordon. I'll be back.
Harvey, no. Harvey!
Get out of here.
Not till I know why this
scumbag is trying to kill me.
If I was trying to kill you,
you'd would be dead already.
Then what are you...
That's enough.
Someone's trying
to provoke you, dent.
Into doing what?
Good question...
Get up.
The walrus and the carpenter
were walking close at hand.
They wept like anything
to see such quantities of sand.
"If seven maids with seven mops
swept it for half a year,
"do you suppose," the walrus said,
"that they could get it clear?"
Huh... I doubt it.
There...
That's the drop.
As for the bat,
delivering him
wasn't part of the deal.
So we can do
whatever we want with him.
What fun.
Twinkle, twinkle little bat...
How I wonder what you're...
Your business with the Roman
ends tonight.
No.
Poor little thing.
Such a tiny little thing.
No.
- Down here.
- What do you got?
Run!
Motive means opportunity.
Dent. All right,
let me be clear,
this freak is done
terrorizing my family. Done!
You expect us to believe that
a respected public servant...
- I don't know why you watch that garbage.
- Is it true?
You believe this bs?
Is that why you want a divorce?
I never said that.
I have been talking about therapy.
Maybe divorce isn't so bad,
now that you can't go back to him...
Ungrateful bitch.
I'm... I'm sorry.
I don't know why I said that.
I'm going to be late for court.
You left the basement door
open again.
I haven't been
in the basement today.
Mr. Dent?
Mr. Dent,
are you ready to proceed?
Uh, yes.
Yes, your honor. Thank you.
Murderer.
What?
I asked if you're ready,
Mr. Dent.
Yes, of course.
Mr. Maroni, you have
confessed to 19 counts...
Confess.
What the hell is he...
He's here, captain. The roof.
Mr. District attorney,
we are all waiting.
Uh, yes, yes. Sorry, your honor.
Rooftop really necessary?
I thought you'd want privacy.
Harvey's starting
to lose it down there.
I think all this holiday speculation
in the press is finally getting to...
Privacy? Why?
Where'd you find them?
You're not going to like it.
Uh, yeah.
I hit Frankie gazzo
and his brother Lenny.
Tossed their bodies
in the Gotham river.
Lots of wise guys you're
looking for are in there.
Maybe that's why I got an ulcer.
You know, from drinking the water?
And didn't you commit
these murders and felonies
under direct orders from
carmine "the Roman" Falcone?
Felonies? Nah, guy's a Saint.
- Now.
You okay, dent?
What is it, heartburn?
Happy to share.
Now, Mr. Maroni,
may I remind you
that your immunity
is contingent upon your truthful
testimony during these proceedings.
And I told you the truth.
Falcone is clean as a whistle.
Sal, what are you doing?
What I'm told.
Okay.
- Um, your honor, in light of the witness's...
- Double cross!
Change of heart,
I need to request a continuance.
Continuance? Uh. What is that?
Like, uh, a holiday?
- What?
- Holiday.
You know, like father's day.
Luigi maroni sends his regards.
Go.
Bailiff, detain the witness!
You're dead, holiday!
You hear me, dent?
That stuff will
eat through concrete!
- Harvey!
- My god. Call an ambulance!
Idiots. They think it's you.
Who are you?
You know who I am.
No, I...
You sound tired.
Why not let me take the wheel?
I don't know what's happening.
I'm sorry no one told you, harv.
Told me what?
You're dead.
I have to take this.
Yeah.
Now?
No, it's the perfect time.
The doctor says he'll be fine
in a few days. Don't worry.
Oh, my god, he's gone.
Secure the exits.
He couldn't have gotten far. Let's go!
Well, where is...
Let me guess.
You're not coming after all.
Afraid not.
Yeah. You're not really
one to get your hands dirty.
You know nothing about me.
I know you're a liar,
a thief, a murderer.
A father.
- A coward.
- Goodbye, dent.
Fine.
He wants to talk to you.
Come on, come on.
Really?
It's not personal.
It's business.
Happy birthday, poppa!
All right, here we go.
What a wonderful night.
Thank you.
This year has been a trying one.
And while we have
yet to fully dismantle
the vicious machine
the law has set against us,
you might say
we put a dent in it.
To Sofia Falcone,
for brokering the peace with maroni.
Mille grazie.
And my beautiful sister, Carla.
Where is she? Carla?
Probably more TV interviews.
Now, now.
Those interviews helped.
I think she's got a future.
Sorry to startle you.
Shouldn't you be
looking for Harvey?
I'm narrowing down his location
by interviewing known associates.
Known associ... oh...
Well, you're wasting your time.
The man's a mystery.
Or so it would seem.
Did you notice any recent
changes in his behavior?
Mood swings?
Is that so strange
when you deal with people
like Falcone every day?
Harvey never mentioned
he went to Oxford.
Is it important?
Maybe.
This doesn't feel
like just a job for you.
It's personal. Why?
He's my friend,
and he needs help.
Dinner time already?
Solomon grundy
born on a Monday.
Christened on a Tuesday,
married on a Wednesday,
ill on Thursday,
worse on Friday.
Died on Saturday.
Buried on Sunday.
That was the end.
Born on a Monday.
Reborn, resurrected.
On a Monday.
Is that what happened to you?
Did you die and come back?
Can a man live two lives?
Born on a Monday.
Thirty days hath September.
But today's the one
that troubles you the most.
Where is he?
It's been months.
I've missed you.
The da who was attacked and maimed
before vanishing from the hospital.
Hm, he does that.
Later that night, Carla viti, who'd
publicly accused dent of being holiday,
was killed on her way to her
brother's birthday party.
I know. Wasn't that terrible?
I think she was right.
Of course you do.
It seems everyone who comes
after dent winds up dead.
We need to find Harvey
before he kills again.
What do you know?
Gordon and his men have been here
day after day asking the same thing.
I'll tell you
what I told the captain.
Let me walk out of here
and I'll stop the killing.
We're done.
It's labor day.
And, if the pattern holds,
I believe you have
something holiday wants.
Head north on atwell.
- Sir, the penitentiary is south...
- I know where it is.
This is the longest goddamn
prisoner transfer I've ever seen.
Guess you guys
just can't get enough of me.
Dent! You're alive?
He's no longer
running this operation.
All right... that's enough.
Relax, Jim, I'm not
here to kill maroni.
I'm here to thank him
for giving me a new... outlook.
Oh, my god. Harvey...
I have to tell you, jimbo,
your gun has come in handy.
I know it was meant for Harvey,
but possession is nine-tenths.
If you're not Harvey,
then, who are you?
Holiday?
We found the guns
in your basement.
You found the guns
in my basement?
Of course.
We know everything.
We just wanna
take you to get help.
I think Thomas Wayne
was onto something.
You can't beat 'em, jimbo,
not your way.
Join 'em first.
Then beat 'em
on their own terms.
Heads, you die.
It is up to you, Harvey.
You and I know that both sides
of that coin are heads.
How the hell could you...
Oh, nice outfit, bats.
I suppose this little trap
was your idea.
Drop the gun, now!
No!
Come on, grundy, move your ass.
I think we're
back to square one.
Ah, you're up early.
Hm?
Oh, no, I just got in.
Of course. Then I suppose
it's off to bed with you.
- Is there something I can help...
- How did it happen, Alfred?
Were they forced into
business with the falcones?
Or were they so set
on building a legacy
that they'd work
with the devil himself?
Your parents believed that there are
two ways to look at everything...
And everyone.
Only two?
They were young.
Two exceptionally good people
living in
an exceptionally bad place,
trying to make it better.
But Falcone?
Didn't they know that
by legitimizing him,
they were helping
to make a monster?
They made difficult choices
and more than a few mistakes.
But they were willing
to pay for them.
I've always told myself that I'm
doing what I do to honor them.
What does it mean if deep down,
I'm really doing it to redeem them?
I think it means
your parents would be proud...
Of their real legacy.
This is absurd.
Sorry for the inconvenience,
ma'am, but it's Halloween.
- Mr. Dent is still at large.
- And captain Gordon ordered us to be here.
So, you're stuck with us.
You've blocked in my car.
We're more than happy to drive
you anywhere you need to go.
Though you'll be making our jobs a
lot easier if you remain indoors.
There's no way to know where or
when your husband will show up.
My husband is dead.
I'm sorry, ma'am,
but that's not true.
Yes, it is.
Wake up, Julian.
You know what today is.
It's all hallows' Eve...
The 31st day of the tenth month,
and the 305th
of this miserable leap year.
And...
Taco Tuesday.
Muy bueno.
What the hell?
Trick or treat.
Attacking us like that
out in the open...
It didn't fit the profile.
So it was a hired gun.
We see dent and holiday in the
same place at the same time,
and, just like that, the da
has got himself an alibi.
Did Harvey study at Oxford?
Like Falcone's boy?
I see where you're going but
don't let Harvey hear you say it.
He's a Gotham u man.
A dyed-in-the-wool nighthawk.
Don't get hung up on it.
Not every lead checks out.
And we already have
what we need to make our case.
It's hard to believe the man
who stood on this roof
and made that promise, that bond with
each of us, would cross the line.
Can you honestly say that man and the
one we met in the alley were the same?
There are deep scars there...
And I'm not talking about his face.
If you think we're wrong,
find the evidence.
But, for now, the best way
to save lives,
including Harvey's,
is to bring him in.
Do you know what my people
call this past year?
The long Halloween.
My nephew,
my son, my sister,
half my men...
Why?
Why would dent kill your son?
I wish I had the chance to be
a better father to my boy.
We will never
see each other again.
For that,
I am so...
So sorry.
There is a rule among my kind.
We leave the wives out of it,
but dent does not play
by our rules.
And when that happens,
he will die.
Whose wives?
I guess justice really is blind.
Poppa.
Everything is fine, Sofia.
I just stumbled.
That wasn't necessary.
Maybe not.
Are you going to tell me why
you're so obsessed with them?
I never thanked you
for finding me
and getting me home that night.
You thought I was your mother.
Scarecrow's fear toxin.
Where you found me
is where I lost her.
I don't even know
my mother's name.
But I think there's someone
who can tell me.
Your father.
Are you sure?
When the time comes,
I'm not sure
I'll have it in me to ask.
Is there even such a thing
as a normal family in this city?
Maybe not...
For people like us.
What the hell is that?
Oh, shit!
All units,
10-33 at the corner of 6th and Mason.
All available units respond.
No, captain said we don't leave
for anything, not tonight.
♪ Pop goes the weasel ♪
Keep coming, boys.
Everyone's invited to this party.
Not everyone.
Head. I meant heads!
Sofia, please.
It was nothing.
Stop treating me
like an old man.
You're not old.
Maybe I am...
Too old for this business,
at least.
Have you...
Heard from your mother?
She loves you.
Just not this place.
This place is me.
I know you think that
and maybe at one time it was.
But things have changed,
so much...
So fast.
Haven't I changed with them?
Yes, you have.
But when you were coming up
when mama was here,
you wouldn't have thought to hire
freaks like poison Ivy and scarecrow.
These... people,
they're not stable, poppa.
Times change.
Boss!
Something's wrong downstairs.
The cops took off
and we can't get any
of our guys on the comm.
Maron...
Sofia, no!
Come on, you mother...
Sofia!
What is this?
Judgment day.
We lost them in the sewers.
You're right.
This was meant to distract us.
Yeah, but distract us from what?
I really
owe it all to you, carmine.
You've taught me
that all men are guilty...
And innocent.
Which makes justice nothing more
than the flip of a coin.
The outcome unpredictable.
That is, of course...
Unless the system is corrupted,
rigged in a man's favor.
Legit businessman/philanthropist
by day.
Criminal racketeer,
murderer by night.
You've rigged every game
you've ever played
in your business
and your family.
It's really the most minor
of adjustments,
a small change of outlook
that decides if you live...
Or not.
Just pull the fucking trigger.
You haven't listened.
If you had, you'd understand
that for the first time,
carmine,
it really isn't up to me.
Good luck.
No!
En garde,
you sanctimonious shit...
Ow!
Nancy, hold all my calls.
I have to terminate someone.
Harvey, don't!
Alone at last.
Now let's get you
out of all this.
Stay back.
Harvey.
You don't have to do this.
Harvey, Harvey, Harvey.
Can't you see
I'm a new man, bats?
I'm finally awake.
And, unlike Harvey dent,
I'm not beholden
to petty motives like revenge,
or, worse, career advancement.
A weight has been lifted.
I don't have to decide
who's innocent
and who's guilty anymore.
All I have to do
is... execute.
- Guilty.
- No!
No!
Poppa.
Sofia, no!
Two bullets only.
Sorry, gorgeous.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Sofia.
I can't... I can't hold on.
Louisa?
Louisa.
Selina.
- Selina?
- Let me help you.
No.
All we get is all we take.
Do you still believe?
Yes...
I do.
Good.
Harvey?
Not anymore.
It had to be done.
You will never
convince me of that.
There won't be
any judges to be bribed.
No witnesses to disappear.
The Roman is dead
and two-face killed him.
The long Halloween...
Is over.
We'll get you help.
You're the ones who're gonna
need help from now on.
Harvey...
Two-face... whatever.
You betrayed everything
you believe in.
Not everything.
Arrest me, jimbo.
I'm responsible.
Not just for Falcone,
but all the holiday killings.
I have to face judgment.
The cost.
The promise we made
right here, one year ago
to take down the Roman.
In the end... was it worth it?
He's asking
if the good guys won.
Yes, the good guys won.
But we won't know
for a very long time
if it was worth it.
Gilda.
It had to be done.
You know that.
The same way you knew Harvey
never went to Oxford.
That was me.
Well,
me and...
Alberto Falcone.
If you could see
how in love we were then.
I was pregnant.
He didn't hesitate.
We were married that same day.
He was heir to the Roman empire.
And his father could never
welcome into the family
a child
conceived out of wedlock.
I tried to fight.
But what chance
did I have opposite
the godfather of Gotham?
Against my will,
our marriage was annulled
and our child
ripped from my womb.
What they did to me...
The way it was done...
Left me broken.
You wanted revenge.
I wanted justice.
I came to Gotham and married
the man I thought
had the best chance
of delivering it.
Oh... Harvey and I
were so much alike,
only what was inside him
hadn't yet been ripped out.
That was... useful.
And...
Even fun for a time.
But then he became so busy
wrestling his own demon,
I was left to take down mine
all by myself.
One holiday, one twisted family
snapshot at a time.
I have no regrets about
what I did to the Roman,
or his son,
or anyone else in that
godforsaken family.
But Harvey,
in the end, I loved him.
But not all of him.
So...
Are you going to
take me away or just...
Stand there in judgment?
I need to know
that holiday is done.
Not done...
Finished.
I wonder... how long
did he know about me?
Is that how you figured it out?
Did Harvey tip you off?
He didn't give you up.
Not knowingly.
But after maroni was killed,
the way he protected holiday,
he must have known then.
He was my friend.
He believed in me.
I should have saved him.
What will you do now?
Tell Gordon?
Alfred.
Really?
I know it's late, sir,
but you never know.
It doesn't matter
how late it is.
We don't get trick-or-treaters.
Not all Gotham families
share your obstinate hope.
It's going to take
a lot more good people
trying to make things better
before we see real change.
If you say so, sir.
You're cute when you're wrong.
Trick or treat.
It's for you, sir.