Your friend from the Pentagon
Special Intelligence Unit came to see me.
Poundstone?
Yeah, Poundstone.
Poundstone's unit pushed all that WMD
intel you've been chasing your tail on.
What? You mean Magellan?
Who is Magellan?
Have you ever met him?
No.
Poundstone's got him
locked up tight.
That's why we gotta find out
what's going on.
Here's the deal.
We checked the notebook.
It's a list of addresses around Baghdad,
mostly Adhamiya.
It's a Sunni stronghold,
very sympathetic to the army.
More than likely,
that's where Al Rawi is.
The notebook's probably his line
to his battalion commanders.
We all set?
Not yet. We're waiting
on military support.
Push them hard. I want to
get every address in that book.
So, what do you think
that meeting was about?
What would you be talking about
if you just got invaded?
You think Al Rawi
wants to fight?
If we don't make him
an offer, he will.
What? You're going
to cut a deal?
You're going to cut a deal
with the Jack of Clubs?
What do you think
you're doing here, Miller?
You're off reservation
for a reason. What is it?
Well, I came to find weapons
and save lives.
And I didn't find shit.
I want to know why.
There are no easy answers. If you
want that, go work with Poundstone.
All we got is hard choices.
You want to know what
happened to the weapons?
We gotta find Al Rawi
and bring him in.
He'll give us
the truth about WMD
and give us a shot at standing this
country up without a bloodbath.
Do you want the job or not?
Yeah, I want it.
Good.
Hamza's being held at the high-value
target wing at Camp Cropper.
Poundstone's unit
have him under wraps.
So, how are you going
to get to him?
I'm not. You are.
Here's a pass.
We've got another prisoner there
we can use to get you in.
Low-level Republican Guard,
way below their radar.
Use him as an excuse
to get to Hamza.
Here's a million
dollars in cash.
Tell Hamza the money's his
if he gives us what we need.
You tell him if
he gives Al Rawi to me,
keeps his mouth shut
over there until I bring him in,
I'll have him and his family out of
the country by the end of the week.
You want me to tell him to not
talk to the American interrogators?
That's right.
I thought we were
all on the same side.
Don't be naive.
Miller.
Pentagon just
revoked your transfer.
You're being released back to your unit,
effective immediately.
You chose the wrong side.
Follow me, Freddy.
We gotta move fast.
Where do you think you're going?
Let us through.
Step aside, please.
What the hell are you playing at?
Get me Langley.
You are required
to hand over all information.
White House authorization.
I want the book.
DC's got too much riding on this to have you
and some Ba'athist generals fuck it up.
Martin.
Langley confirms.
I've got it!
Let's go.
Stay out of this, Marty.
You all right here?
Yeah.
Use local assets.
It's high priority.
Stay close to me, Freddy.
Put him down.
OGA.
I'm here to see a prisoner.
Heads up, Sarge.
Hey, Sergeant.
Hello, sir.
I'm here to see
Abdullah Ferat.
I'm gonna have
to search your bag.
What's up with Hajji?
He's my translator.
Arms up, legs apart.
Check it out.
What's that in your pocket?
It's my cigarettes.
Good to go.
Here you go, sir.
Go ahead and take
them back to IR-1.
Right here.
That's not necessary, Sergeant.
Standard procedure, sir.
Sergeant, I have to have a classified
conversation with the prisoner.
You can go on
and step outside.
Roger, sir.
Be right outside.
Do you know why
they brought him here?
He's here because he's in
the Republican Guard, Freddy.
Hey, Sergeant.
Hey, listen, this guy just gave us
a piece of intel.
You apparently have a prisoner in your
HVT wing here named Seyyed Hamza.
He can ID him for me.
I gotta get him down here
and ID him real quick.
You're going to need
an EJ-75 for that, man.
Guys, I got a live op going.
I got a team in place ready to move on
a target. I gotta do this now.
How long will it take?
2 minutes.
Just 2 minutes?
That's it. 2 minutes. Come on.
All right. Good, let's go.
Hey, Freddy.
Put those bags
on their heads.
OGA coming in
for an ID check.
Hey, Hamza.
Get up.
Shit.
Get a medic!
I said, get a medic!
Hey, get the medics on the phone.
We've got a situation here.
He say, "Why did you
do this to me?"
He say the general did everything
you ask of him in the meeting.
What do you...
What meeting?
He just say Jordan.
Clear the way!
What is going on here, Miller?
Coming through! Okay.
What does he mean, "Jordan"?
We gotta stop the bleeding.
His pulse is weak.
I need to talk to you
about Magellan.
I'm going to call you
right back.
What you got?
I read your articles.
You said an Iraqi WMD source
named Magellan
met with US officials
prior to the war.
I need to know
about that meeting.
No. Come on, Miller.
I can't discuss my sources with you.
Well, did you ever meet the guy?
Do you know who he is?
Of course I didn't meet him.
He's an Iraqi internal, for Christ's sake.
Then how do you know
what he's saying is true?
Because I made contact through
a reliable intermediary.
Reliable?
Yes.
Have you ever even been to
any of Magellan's sites?
You ever been
to Diwaniya? Tikrit?
No.
There's nothing there.
Magellan's intel
is bullshit.
Who's the intermediary?
No. I'm not discussing
sources, Miller.
Jesus Christ!
This is the reason we went to war!
All right, then at least tell me
how it happened.
How does this happen?
How does somebody like you
write something that's not true?
Tell me!
What do you know?
Look, I got a phone call one day
from a senior official in DC.
He says,
"I've got a story for you.
"The truth about
Saddam's WMD programs."
So I go to meet him.
He puts the source
report in my hands.
Magellan's product,
the raw intel.
But when do you
check the story?
He was a senior official,
for Christ's sake.
He had access
to Magellan's debrief.
All he asked was that I not disclose
the location of the meeting.
The location.
Yes, in case I'd
compromise the source.
It was Jordan, wasn't it?
The meeting was in Jordan.
Yes.
You can keep
your million dollars.
Al Rawi's Magellan.
They're debriefing Magellan.
They've got him held tight.
Supposing they don't?
John, take care of the money.
Hamza said Al Rawi
met US officials in Jordan.
Now Dayne said
the same thing about Magellan.
That's more
than a coincidence.
Maybe. It doesn't
make any sense.
If Poundstone met Al Rawi in Jordan,
what's he hiding?
Well, what if he told him something
he didn't wanna hear?
What if he told him
there were no WMD?
I want Al Rawi's
movements outside Iraq.
January, February, 2003.
Anything you got.
I'm on it.
It all makes sense.
The bad intel.
Why our teams came up
empty at those sites.
Maybe we're looking at this thing
the wrong way around.
It's a theory.
You've got no proof.
Don't be naive.
Sir, Mohammed Al Rawi was in Amman,
Jordan on February 5th, 2003.
That's 3 days before
Magellan came online.
Give me Clark Poundstone's
movements, same period.
Sir, we've got a DOD
Gulfstream on the same date.
Passenger Clark Poundstone routed
Washington, DC to Amman, Jordan.
Martin, we're getting reports of
an attack on an Al Rawi safe house.
South Adhamiya.
Poundstone's hunting Al Rawi.
He doesn't want the truth to get out.
I need to know where the next
safe house is.
All clear, Chief.
Send Freddy!
Yes, sir!
Freddy, on the move.
Freddy, I need you
to translate.
Tell him I need to get a message
to General Al Rawi.
Tell him I need
to meet Al Rawi tonight.
Chief Miller on the
phone for you, sir.
Yeah?
I got him.
Tahir al-Malik, one of Al Rawi's
battalion commanders.
Where is he?
I let him go.
Look, I told him to get
a message to Al Rawi.
I told him I'd meet him
at the Adhamiya bus station tonight.
If I can bring him in alive,
then we'll have our proof.
If he talks, then we'll get
the truth about WMD.
All right, if you get in front of Al Rawi,
offer him whatever you have to.
If you pull this off,
there's still a chance we can
hold this place together.
I'm headed there now.
You are serious to do a deal
with Mohammed Al Rawi?
You know what already
he do to this country?
We're just trying
to save lives, Freddy.
There are people who think
he can stop an insurgency.
All right, listen up,
we're going to Adhamiya.
But look, we're going alone,
so weapons check, comms check.
Make sure you're 100%.
We got no support.
Hooah?
Hooah!
You okay?
Sergeant P, can I get a radio check?
Go to 1.
Miller, what you are doing?
Channel 1.
Roger that.
Look at what's happening.
I just need you to do
your job tonight, Freddy.
Let's roll!
Thank you all very much.
Admiral Kelly, Captain Card,
officers and sailors
of the USS Abraham Lincoln,
my fellow Americans.
Major combat operations
in Iraq have ended.
In the battle of Iraq,
the United States and
our allies have prevailed.
All right!
Yeah?
This is Briggs.
We got a problem.
My local assets are down.
I got a report saying it was US Army
took them out and nobody called it in.
Where's Miller?
Stand by.
All right, listen up. I need
everybody on a Blue Force Tracker.
Met-Delta 85th, XTF.
Sir.
He's moving northwest
towards Adhamiya.
ETA?
12 minutes, sir.
ETA, 12 minutes.
He's meeting with Al Rawi.
Son of a bitch.
He's on his way there right now.
All right, what do
you want me to do?
Follow Miller.
He'll lead you right to him.
And when you find Al Rawi,
you take that son of a bitch out.
What about Miller?
He's off reservation.
Miller can't bring in Al Rawi.
Don't let him
get in the way.
I want to make
that announcement.
Now?
Just make it happen!
This is Vanguard 6
on the airborne command.
I need a C-2 bird
with eyes over Adhamiya.
I want an ISO
on all military radio
and cell phone transmissions
for a 3-mile radius.
Alpha 1, this is Vanguard 6.
Vanguard 6,
this is Alpha 1.
Alpha 1, I need you to divert
to Adhamiya Central immediately.
We have a high-value target identified,
Mohammed Al Rawi.
This is a kill,
no capture mission.
Roger that.
Here they are.
Yeah, I'll tell him.
We're on our way.
Poundstone's just called
a press briefing downstairs.
It's something big, Marty.
This is the bus station.
It's just over there.
Stagger 2 teams.
I'm going to move
across to the kiosk.
You give me 30 seconds
to get across, then follow.
Someone just showed up.
I'm going to follow.
2 minutes, people.
2 minutes to the announcement.
He's going out
the central alley, west.
Thank you all for coming
at such short notice.
We have a major announcement.
This follows in lockstep
with our commitment
to eliminate the tyranny
of Saddam Hussein
and expeditiously transform Iraq into
a modern, functioning democracy.
Ambassador Bremer
has just signed an order
immediately disbanding Iraq's
remaining military forces.
The Coalition Provisional
Authority hereby dissolves
the entirety of Iraq's military
and paramilitary forces,
ministries of defense,
information, military affairs,
intelligence and national security.
All officers,
soldiers, conscripts
and other military figures
are relieved of duty.
All military ranks, titles
and status are canceled.
In addition, Iraq's ruling Ba'ath Party
is dissolved with immediate effect.
Party members will be summarily fired from
central and local government offices,
hospitals, universities, schools
and other public institutions.
This is the dawn of new leadership in Iraq,
and let the world take note,
change is coming to
the Middle East at last.
Still moving southwest.
Southwest.
Copy that.
You got him?
Yeah, I see him.
I lost contact.
Fuck!
Get an angle!
Fuck, he's in the vehicle.
God damn it!
Stay on Chief!
Where the fuck did they go?
Did he get in the vehicle?
Let's go! Let's go!
This is MET Team "D."
We need help.
American soldier kidnapped!
We need help down here!
All units, we need help
in the Adhamiya district.
Copy that, MET Team.
This is Vanguard 6 and TF221.
What's your position
and status?
Vanguard 6, we're 5 blocks south
of the Adhamiya bus station.
Kidnappers heading
east in 2 small cars.
Roger that.
Met-D, I am en route.
I need you to return to your vehicles
and await further instructions.
Falcon 16,
this is Vanguard 6.
We have a US soldier abducted.
We need eyes on those vehicles now!
Vanguard 6,
this is Falcon 16.
Currently 2 klicks
northeast of Adhamiya.
Establishing an area of perimeter
and sweeping Adhamiya.
AOR 87, Alpha Tango.
We gotta get him out of there.
Get me Chief Miller now.
They've taken him.
God damn it! They've taken him.
Vanguard 6,
this is Falcon 16.
I've got your 2 vehicles
moving rapidly.
The 2 vehicles
just entered a garage.
There's a large water tower
on top of the building.
Grid Kilo-Zulu-8732-6428.
Alpha 1, I'm going in on foot.
Continue to target. Acknowledge.
This is Alpha 1.
We're 3 klicks from target area.
All right, put us down.
Find an LZ a klick from here.
Who are you?
General, my name's
Roy Miller.
I'm a chief warrant
officer with the US Army.
What do you want?
I came here to bring you in.
General, I'm aware that you had
contact with a US official
in the weeks
leading up to the war.
I know you were ready to tell them
everything about Iraq's WMD programs.
What programs?
There are no programs.
I told your official.
We dismantled
everything after '91.
He told my government that you confirmed
that the programs were still active.
He lied about what you said.
That's why we're here.
Did anyone verify
his story?
No.
Your government wanted
to hear the lie, Mr. Miller.
They wanted Saddam out, and they
did exactly what they had to do.
This is why you are here.
Go.
Alpha 1, this is Vanguard 6.
Give me your location.
Vanguard 6,
this is Alpha 1.
We're half a klick away.
Split up.
Alpha team,
take the west side,
Bravo team, take the east side
of the objective.
I got north-south. Move to
assault positions. Wait for my go.
Roger that.
So, do you have
a message for me?
General, if you
come in with me,
there are still people in Washington
who will work with you.
People who understand
that we still need the Iraqi army
to hold this place together.
Then why is your government
disbanding the Army?
Making us outlaws.
Why take Iraq apart
piece by piece?
Why?
I risked my life
to tell you the truth
about WMD.
"Tell the truth and you'll have a place
in the new Iraq," they said.
So where is my place,
Mr. Miller?
On a deck of cards?
Why are you
really here, Miller?
You were supposed
to lead me into a trap.
You will tell me now how
they are planning to take me.
Everybody in position?
Vanguard Bravo in position.
Vanguard 6, this is Bravo 1.
We're ready.
Vanguard 6, this is Alpha 1.
We're in position.
You have to come
in with me, General.
You will get nothing
if you fight us.
You have to come in now
before it's too late.
You think the war is over
just because you are in Baghdad?
You will see.
It has only just begun.
Let's go.
Grenade!
Go! Go!
Come on! Move!
Let's go. Let's go.
Man down!
Hit the rooftop!
Go!
Clear! Stack on Dutch!
"B" Team, go left.
Last guy with me. Let's go!
I've got something.
Sir, I've got 2 hostiles
headed east.
Sir, I got one more.
There's one friendly in pursuit.
Hold!
Vanguard 6, this is Falcon 16.
2 hostiles and one friendly
have exited target site
and are now moving through alley
northeast of your location.
Keep the area clear.
I'm activating
my transponder.
Bring me in.
I want to cut them off.
Down, get down!
Get the fuck down!
Vanguard 6,
this is Falcon 16.
The targets have lost the friendly.
Targets are now moving north.
Turn 45 degrees to your left,
maintain intercepting course.
Turn! Turn!
I've lost visual contact.
I've got them!
Vanguard 6,
this is Falcon 16.
Keep going
your current direction.
The target is crossing
open ground, headed north.
RPG!
Shit!
Walk over.
Stop there.
You sure this is what they want
back in Washington?
Put that weapon down!
Now, Freddy!
What the fuck did you do?
It is not for you to decide
what happens here.
Get out of here,
Freddy. Go home.
We're gonna be
locking this area down.
There are gonna be
soldiers everywhere.
Go home now,
while you can.
Do you think you can form a successful
government without Sunni involvement?
This is a new beginning for Iraq.
This is the end of tyranny and the
beginning of freedom.
How long will
US forces be in Iraq?
As long as they are needed.
Thank you. That's it.
Clark.
Mr. Zubaidi.
It's a great day.
Indeed, indeed.
Good to see you.
Welcome. Welcome.
How are you, gentlemen?
How are you? Good, good.
So, does this mean there's
going to be an election soon?
There's been
a democracy deficit.
Can you comment about the action
last night in Adhamiya?
Chief Miller.
It's a copy of my intel report.
I wanted to give it to you personally.
Thank you.
Is this Al Rawi?
Yeah.
Yeah, I heard about this.
There's some pretty
strong language here.
But what's the point, Miller?
Do you think anybody's
going to listen to you?
I know what you did.
What did you say?
You made him up
to get what you needed.
Magellan.
You made him up.
I don't know what
you're talking about, Miller.
When you peddled that shit in DC,
did they know it was a lie?
Or did they just
never bother to ask?
Okay, okay.
Come on, none of this matters anymore.
WMD? This doesn't matter.
What the fuck are you talking about?
Of course, it fucking matters.
The reasons we go to war
always matter!
It's all that fucking matters.
It fucking matters.
At ease, soldier.
Do you have any idea
what you've done here?
What's going to happen next time
we need people to trust us?
Clark!
We're not turning
back, Miller.
We won.
Clark!
Son of a bitch. What?