Stop.
Controlling
then the anti villain Lee
can't catch this.
Woo.
work
The math for the legendary Zodiac Stone,
we will become the most powerful
villains in the world.
OK, let's get a move on.
We leave for agent tonight.
I'm in.
Hello beautiful.
Thinking.
What?
Hello.
Yes, those Zodiac school.
Boom, the problem
is unstoppable.
This will be ours.
All that crying out loud.
Hurry up, I got a bunch
of deadly toxins on my family.
I cut the stove.
Old man, but this is heaven
new yeah Joe just got way.
Hold on I started this group will it team?
Where's your loyalty?
Oh please, we're villains
there's no such thing
for the next generation.
MINIONS
RISE OF GRU
And needs.
Why it down class people people?
So why do you want to be
when you grow up?
You want to be a doctor?
Wonderful, really.
I want to be a teacher now.
You do not.
I want to be fireman.
Who's the president
and also drive race cars
exciting.
And what about you bro?
Grow.
Me, I want to be.
Supervillain
Brad.
Alabama.
90 relatives
guys come on.
I've got the damage to Apple here.
right
OK, are you guys for the movie?
Let's go.
And I've been.
Hate me.
Sweet
sweet sweet quick
quick quick quick.
OK
I don't know.
Jason, Jason Jason.
Don't tease me bro.
So creamy.
Valerie
magazine
listen each green staff.
Woo.
Won't look like a bully.
Come again.
Hello Mr brew.
We've received your application to the world's
best supervillain team,
the vicious, since a recent opening has become available
and
your interview is tomorrow at noon.
Please go to 417
Main St.
The password is you're no good.
You're no good now get up.
Because this imitation is going
slow, baby it's gross.
Mom.
man
Mom, who is this wedding guy
you stinking up your house?
I thought you were cooking
cabbage.
He's my new.
Hello, weird buddies, they better
stop pulling their weight around here
or I'm kicking them out.
They are killing
my mellow vibes.
Yeah, yeah.
I heard that.
Come on, let's go tell
the truth the good news.
Who the basement?
People.
This is.
Looks great guys.
Most points.
Well, you gotta break a few eggs.
Am I right?
Good job.
Great job.
Never mind.
And did not look as good.
Open city.
No help the family.
OK.
Bundle your overalls, hold
on their goggles divisions.
6 wants to meet me tomorrow.
Not many.
Please stop calling me that
and also they haven't accepted me yet.
Look at what?
Although blood is it.
2nd.
Yes.
OK, you know it would be fun.
Let's play the quiet game.
Anyway, thanks for the hard work today
everyone.
I gotta go get some rest.
Tomorrow is the biggest
day of my life.
The world.
Of these guys, so the person
can't believe it.
bus
Really, people don't know.
Yeah, I get it, but I need
a good night's sleep to get out.
OK fine fine because you had the nightmare
but just tonight.
I'm not buying the nightmare story though.
This goes on.
Really, you too get in.
You're good now,
goodnight, yes goodnight.
Stop.
Little kids sleep.
Breaking news the vicious 6 is ready to rewrite
the rules of villainy,
feelings of the world.
In three days when the clock strikes midnight
and the Chinese New Year begins,
this bad boys power
is going to be unleashed.
With the power of the Zodiac,
we're going to take out
the anti villain league.
And the vicious 6 will be
the most powerful villains on the planet.
Digging.
Why do I dig it?
I don't dig it.
There's nothing to dig.
They thought they could leave me
for dead, huh?
Kick me to the curb
like a piece of old meat.
Why do what's coming?
Wanna make that stuff up?
Ohboy, Mr.
Knuckles.
Why we just wanted to make sure
we be getting paid this week?
What a mouth on you
not paying you with knowledge.
You are
less than one.
Always be prepared.
Listen to the Belgian.
Those things that lesson 3.
Haircut
that's worth all the money
in the world.
Hey guys, forget about it.
You're going to get paid,
but first we got to get my phone back.
Bad group.
I see I'm feeling on his way.
I'm going now in the room with five year olds
and coming.
They're gonna love
because I'm the best.
Do.
Don't mess up tonight.
You're going to join the vision.
Here is the bad crew
and did I guys.
Dude.
Oh, you want to come?
yes
Right,
OK?
When you guys tracked me down
and responded to my help wanted that.
I was like hold out of this.
I think they're they're thoughts
and where did they get so much there them?
And you're just wasn't quit.
I like
come on in.
We've had some great times since then,
but The thing is, the vicious sex
didn't the big leagues and you guys.
Or
Gray.
And so the champion did in Delaware.
A plus.
It's just what I was thinking
is that there are a lot
of other villains in the world.
Now.
OK,
never mind work, I think I
just need to fly solo.
People gonna go.
Getting backlash.
yes
No.
You know that.
I did.
let
No.
cool
Here we go.
excuse
son
wondering if you're.
No.
well
My mistake.
Ohh
sorry I didn't mean to scare you.
I was just trying out
this new invention of mine.
Our cool it get your fingers
or smart good.
I haven't quite landed on the name yet.
Algeria.
I overheard you were looking
for something.
Special.
I yes, I was hoping
you're no good.
I think you'll enjoy
listening in Booth 3.
Right this way.
yeah
This isn't mums.
The word keep it down.
Good luck.
Let her have it, son.
Thanks Mr Mayor fario.
right doctor nefario
hey.
If you ever get famous, remember
who gave you your first gadget.
OK.
Go.
Sisters
really.
Hello.
Everybody hears what they.
Me too.
So what do you guys
got going on later?
Are you up to no good?
Then you gonna get it?
Within the first one there,
they're ready to.
Oh, good good.
This danglish village.
My name is crew.
I feel like I'm talking too loud,
even though our proximity
doesn't require this kind of volume.
If you told me when I was ten,
if I would have the chance
to fill the shoes of my favorite filling ever,
why don't merkels?
I would say you got
the rocks in your head,
but now that I'm 11 and 3/4
it makes a lot more sense.
All right, who let the kid in?
I thought he was this tiny man.
What's wrong with you?
Really think a puny little child
can be a villain.
Pretty despicable,
you don't want to cross me.
Evil is for adults
who steal powerful ancient stones
and wreak havoc,
and not for tubby little pups
who should be at school learning
taking a recess.
Suck, I can't stop.
Come back when you've done
something to impress me.
Who's that?
I am with man,
the next fever of the vicious 6.
Behold, the power of flight, Sir.
Alright, so.
one
right
OK, that's this.
Call
building.
I did nothing here.
Your breathing comes alive
nice Joyce.
Hello.
Just keep walking.
Deserve a kid.
Guys.
What are you doing here?
Just get that.
A little rain.
Huh?
That didn't.
We'll take the phone back
to the lair.
I'll distract them.
No, come on.
Enjoy the rest of the start.
We're coming for you.
More.
i
Again, wouldn't be
a real villain.
This guys just those happening
from
villains in the.
When I bring it back to them,
they're going to say.
It's terrible to stake.
Please join us.
Please crew
and I will say.
I will be the newest member
of the vicious say.
Is Apple where is Arthur?
No, that's not
don't look gourmet.
He needs to come now.
That is.
Is this are you pulling
on my legs right now though?
Where's this done this good?
They call it boom.
What about you?
Come up.
Piano.
The physical is not.
Did you just trade my future?
For a, that's not.
OK,
where was this birthday party?
I don't remember.
Is that the ball acceptable?
I told you guys that you weren't
ready for the big leagues
and you have proven me correct.
You guys messed everything up.
Up
wow.
My mom was right.
You do not belong here,
you're fired.
I'm going to find that stop
when I get home you open the record.
Close your yapper.
see
I'll say goodbye.
No one ever cared if I should leave.
Let them on.
Kevin, no, I will be better
off on my own.
Live with that.
I just can't see.
So.
move
Those.
It's a boy.
I'm sorry I thought to be impressed
and I just speak to Bell bottom.
Good.
Why isn't that cool?
We're alive.
Wow, my favorite villain
is also my kidnapper.
This could be a great opportunity
if you don't kill me,
shut up
and give me this stone.
Ohh this this stuff.
Here's the thing about that.
It's kind of a funny story.
Give it to him.
Going to go South very quickly.
Well done, heck is this.
You're at.
Where is it going?
I don't have it,
I don't have it.
I know you're hiding
it somewhere.
Stick a needle in my eye.
Don't actually do that though.
Somebody bring me a phone.
Call home it's ransom time.
Probably pay you the kidney.
Move one full.
Not getting.
Hello, like I said, who is this?
Kevin lay what?
Didn't you got engagement?
The end of them.
Listen, you bring your stone them
in San Francisco 6830 Green
St got it now you got two days
where you are never going to see
your little boss again.
That's not done.
I don't care.
So now.
I don't know.
We grew up though.
Oh no, no.
What's up?
OK, Google.
Stone.
But it was.
It's more his style.
Oh
I told you I don't know where
you went you stupid Twinkies.
OK.
Bully.
Not cool man.
Thank God I did something like that.
But
San Francisco.
I don't know.
What kind of weather?
Come in, get out.
Let's rock and roll time
to get our stone back.
We're coming for you, Mr grew.
Murder.
Are you?
yeah
For some fun.
San Francisco OK,
How will you be paying?
final
Oh great, you know if you have any hairballs
we can upgrade you to 1st class
get out.
I got a better.
And I had to turn back
at LaGuardia.
Hey Dolly.
i
yes
There was like.
Hello
yes please.
goodnight
yes
you
I don't know.
yeah
For that, right?
Yeah.
I know.
You got real moxie kid,
stealing from the vicious 6.
I got Moxy really did I just
receive a compliment?
Right now, well, it's about
to become your nightmare.
Welcome to my newest torture
device and disco inferno.
Your minions better get it
by sundown tomorrow
because in 48 hours of discount
on kill you the blade will.
So that.
All that.
Go go go.
no
Grew.
yeah
Honey.
Next up brain St.
Who does like any?
Yeah.
Minivan.
Do I?
No no no no OK OK?
We're going to go back.
Go go.
Wait a minute.
Hello.
service
burger.
OK, now you might feel
a little pinch.
Time to bring some fun.
Any plans for the weekend?
25 deep breaths.
You like picking
on little guys, huh?
Don't take a nap, old lady.
Lady.
i
Ancient Shaolin art
of Kung Fu.
No.
Get lost.
If you come back to our place,
you're dead.
Come in.
Thank you, thank you.
You can thank me
by going away, I'm working.
computer
you want to learn Kung Fu?
You didn't.
Fu
my teaching days are over.
This is my life now.
look
I have my level,
you just come through.
But I see that.
If a boy.
I.
I will teach you.
Hey,
those are not for you.
The name of the game
is sell, sell, sell.
LA
Where is groom?
How should I know what's
with the costumes?
Halloween was four months ago.
You look stupid.
That's off shoe.
I'm getting my meat tenderizer.
Let me help you with that, dearie.
Yeah, where's the boy?
I didn't mean to scare you.
Don't worry,
we're not mad at him.
We just want to
hire him.
Where is it?
Why not go live
and working with the kid?
We're going to San Francisco.
You had better be paying for my roof.
Pretty groovy high.
What?
We begin with a basic kick.
How do you?
OK, no kick.
This is a melon hammer.
It's a weapon.
This is Fred.
He is a dummy.
Never underestimate a dummy.
No attack.
My time.
Don't tell to me
I cannot break this wood.
But doubt exists
only in the mind.
You know what I say
to my mind.
Now you gay.
kevin kevin kenny
Looks like I can.
OK, clearly we are not ready
for philosophy.
Let's just trade.
Oh
OK OK OK yeah.
Yeah.
Hello.
Rest up tomorrow's going
to be even worse.
Why you're quitting?
I told you what I get, that stone?
We're going to be unstoppable.
I have had enough.
There's nothing sadder
than an aging village.
Guys, come on, we're a team.
Hope you like it.
Is this?
I just had to fire
my henchman, you know why?
Because they weren't getting
the job done.
OK, I'm just gonna untie you now because I
I I I need you to do some stuff
for me around the house.
You know, kind of nice to have
a little company around here,
yeah?
Just throwing some jars.
Well, those are kind of trouble.
We could get them though.
What's that?
That's your evil chuckle, obviously.
Well, it stinks.
You sound like a clown
who swallowed a kazoo really well?
You look like a wizard going
through an end of life crisis.
Vehicles.
Who's done rickles?
oh
Dude.
I thought we lost you
there for a minute.
Trying to swim.
Hey soul brother,
we're getting off to.
Let's go back to Frisco Frisco.
It's so lucky day chick
I'm heading up the coast.
I could drop you off on the way.
People.
look
Start with the pool.
This place you going to be
sticking spared.
What are you doing?
You look like the overcooked Turkey.
My mom makes some Thanksgiving.
Oh yeah, I forgot to mention,
the pool is filled
with my pet crocodiles.
Yeah, well doesn't scare me.
Be careful I can't have you losing all
because they need you to change
some light bulbs after this, yeah.
I'm sorry how it's done.
Knock it off.
Google.
However, no, no no.
no
Wow.
goodnight
I got there.
I thought that you.
Take my hand.
Cool.
You gonna run well,
you were you didn't I told you?
My favorite.
World I could not let you could even
by crocodiles.
Even though that would have been
kind of cool to watch.
So, so you want to be
a great villain, huh?
That's all I ever wanted.
You want I don't know you want me.
Do you have any teacher thing or two?
Many
how did I become a great master?
Even the smallest of us are capable
of great things.
You just dig down deep,
find, join the please and.
doesn't
Now you try.
Find your.
Stop this.
We have a lot more work to do.
Coach
Kevin Stuart and Bob
you are ready.
Ready for you?
4 chievement badges.
They're dead.
First rule of ice.
Always stay in character,
Grandpa.
See.
My boy Dexter here can't hold it
in till we get home.
Bank of.
It's Showtime kid.
Follow my lead and don't forget
your cube.
Hello I I just need to cash this oh wow
is that way what The Big Bang?
How many security guards
are in here?
Who's this little guy?
Well that's my grandson who still has not learned
that children should be seen and not heard.
It's actually have a son of my own.
Yeah, you look so weird.
Your son is very
cute.
Help I'm seeing you like Ellen,
I'm coming for you.
Hello, I'm Carmen for you ohh help
help.
Said nothing helped him.
This is the big one.
You're here.
This is the sweet
sound of angels.
Something my life
is flashing before my eyes.
The other way, the other way.
all
Stand back.
Wait a minute, wait.
Don't give up on me now, buddy.
You have a.
Clear.
so
Did we do the high?
Well said the darkest day.
You've done this.
Hey not bad.
Not bad at all.
We make a good team.
Oh yeah, hey,
we got to keep fighting
when did you see what I'm
going to teach you next?
OK, do you want to do it?
Love hair fan out
and find them.
Something big is going
down in Frisco.
Daddy
put it down.
It's been one heck
of a ride, little man.
You know I'm going to miss you.
Hey so welcome good luck.
My friend, you're not going
to learn from the old school.
Umm?
No.
I can't believe they did this to me.
I've looked up everything they know.
We were a team.
Umm?
I give up.
Hey.
You are a great bad guy.
They are stupid idiots.
Only dream I ever had
was doing bad stuff
with my buddies.
Now look at me old long.
Well, you are old.
But you're not alone.
All right, listen up, Buster.
We are starting a new thing
and it's going to be called
the terrible twos.
We can find a better name later,
but right now we are going
to find that stone
and show everybody that you still got it.
It's just a little kid,
it's all over.
Go home, what do you said?
You found this stall.
You
we don't have much time.
We got to get this to wild levels.
Long time no see.
Like that?
Billy, you are under arrest.
Everybody, could you forget
what time it is?
no
No no.
And now.
What do you think you're going
you stole from us?
God.
Being torn apart.
Honey.
Guys,
why don't we make this a fair fight?
Serious.
Come on Raiders.
Remember Mary?
You can leave me for dead.
You destroy everything I own,
but I will not let you her test it.
So you're going to save the kid.
Yeah, you and what army?
Oh good, this army.
Ohh
ah.
Dig down deep.
Please.
Hmm.
Come in.
Get away from him.
Destroy the kid.
Hello.
How does it feel to be beaten
by the happy little bug?
You guys were amazing.
The Kung Fu,
where did that come from?
Obviously you guys are really high.
cool
No well beckles.
Brew.
Hey.
You're gonna be OK, right?
Don't worry about big kid.
Fine.
Finally.
You are going away
for a long, long time.
Yeah, well, I wouldn't bet on it.
No.
See you soon kiddo.
Knuckles
was my favorite villain.
We didn't have much time together,
but the time we did have.
I'm so grateful for
I've been thinking about how you
won't see me grow up or be there
for all the terrible things
that I'm going to do, but we've.
But I'm going to make you proud.
I'm going to be the best feeling
ever because of you.
Because you taught me what matters,
you can't do anything alone.
Find your tribe.
And never ever let them go.
Auto.
Videos.
thought
to give back that.
But I like it OK.
You better stay out of trouble,
kid.
Good and honest life.
Why?
You have to blow my mind.
How could you do that?
I cannot wait to fake my own death
to avoid the authorities.
Choose for the mode.
Girls.
It's.
No, I am done with villainy
off the happier horizon.
Goodbye little chap.
Apple.
Ohhh alright alright fine stop
with a face I'm in.
Wanna see something cool?
I like that.
yeah