They figured out
we're not aid workers.
Three klicks from the ridge.
Two cars in pursuit. Possible RPG.
Don't let them line up a shot!
Moving into position now.
In position.
I have visual. Spider?
I have a shot.
Let her rip. We are ready to boogie.
What was that?
It's a trap! Shooters on the ridge!
Hit the other driver!
They're lining up the shot!
Shoot the truck!
Let's go
before the others come.
The truck is empty.
Driver's dead.
Other guy is gone.
Grab the gun.
I'll look around.
Come on, work!
Parker, do you copy?
- We are approaching the vehicle.
- Parker?
Parker, we are approaching the vehicle.
What's your status?
I'm sorry, Nick.
- I volunteered to tell the family.
- I'll come with.
No, I got it.
- Adam, no!
Parker!
What are you doing?!
Hey! Stop it!
Enough! Parker!
It's over! It's over!
Unbelievable.
He won't even get a slap on the wrist.
You can't solve
every problem with a knife.
Should I just have let him
murder assets?
How does he think
we're going to get information from them
if he keeps killing them all? Hmm?
I don't think the boy thinks.
♪ Pull it out push it in... ♪
Adam requested that you be
transferred out of the unit.
How do you know?
♪ I'm not scared
Do I need to force her to change... ♪
- You hacked his email.
- I did not.
- You're gonna get caught.
- I'm not gonna get caught.
You are gonna get caught.
I deleted the request.
"Thank you, Spider!"
"You're so welcome, Parker."
Hmm. That's how that should've gone.
You read my emails?
- No, I do not read your emails.
- Mm-hmm.
But that's only because you need to learn
to unsubscribe from some shit.
- Now, you have too much spam, girl.
You got more spam
than a Hawaiian middle school in there.
Yo, what's that?
That picture. Who is that?
My prom date.
-  [Parker] Jesse?
Hey, Parker. How you doing?
Hey, um, it's not really a great time.
Yeah, sorry about that.
So...
Listen, there was a cave-in
at the mine last night.
And your dad got caught underneath it.
And by the time we found him,
it was too late.
Hi.
I'm just, uh...
I'm just trying
to wrap my head around all of this.
I've been thinking that maybe there's
some kind of poetry or something
in the fact that he was swallowed up
in his favorite place.
He loved that damn cave.
What's that?
Found it on his desk
in the bedroom.
Well, it's a letter. Why is it evidence?
Well, I'm wondering if it, uh...
if it could have been on purpose.
The cave-in, I mean.
You think this is a suicide note?
This is... It's just a letter.
I mean, we would write
each other sometimes. It's not a--
It's not evidence for anything.
It's just a letter.
All right. Uh... How did he sound
the last time you two spoke?
Lonely? I don't know.
He missed me.
We... We missed each other.
We always miss each other.
He's not that guy.
I mean, it was an old mine,
a really old mine,
and old mines have cave-ins all the time.
Right. No. You... You...
You're right. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Hands are sweating. I... I don't know.
It's fine. It's...
Um...
Can I give you a ride home?
- Yeah, I... I need a ride.
- Yeah, I'm gonna give you a ride home. Um...
Let me grab my keys.
If you want to protect
our America, vote for Senator Swann.
I'm Senator Ezekiel Swann,
and I approve this message.
How's your dad's
re-election campaign going?
Uh, uh, it's going.
Think one of your dad's rich donor friends
would be interested in buying Maria's?
Seriously?
Yeah.
But Harry built Maria's for you.
You don't want to stay and run the bar?
I can't stay.
I'm gonna leave after the funeral.
It just doesn't feel like home
without Pops here.
You want me to help you
take these upstairs?
Oh, no, it's... it's fine. I'm okay.
All right.
- Thanks.
- Yeah, I'll, uh...
I'll let you get settled in, then.
Okay.
You need me, just holler. Okay?
Thanks.
Cheers, Pops.
Oh jeez! I'm here to feed the lizard!
Please don't kill me!
Mikey?
Parker?
Ugh.
Jesus.
You all right?
No! No, I almost shit myself.
Sorry about that.
No, it's good to see you.
Now, uh, where's that lizard?
Uh, Andy, come on out, buddy.
It's dinnertime.
Does he usually come
when you call?
No.
Hmm.
Uh, Harry was really proud of you.
He always talked about it.
How you... were killing terrorists,
doing spy shit.
I don't know, whatever you're doing.
Do you know where they found him?
I found him, actually.
Oh man. Mikey, I'm sorry.
Will you show me?
Is that a camera?
Yeah, yeah.
Harry, uh, stepped up security lately.
He actually got real cameras this time.
Not like the fake ones in the bar.
So I saw a lot of dust
coming out of the mine.
Uh...
It was crazy. It was so thick that I could
barely see my hand in front of my face.
Couldn't find him anywhere.
I was, uh... I was worried,
really worried something happened to him.
He'd just been spending
so much more time down here.
Why?
I don't know.
This knife
protected your abuelo.
It got me through Vietnam.
It's part of our legacy.
Look at how tall you've gotten.
It's done.
I need you to sharpen this
when we go back.
Never carry a knife without...
Without sharpening it.
Hey.
- Parker.
Huh?
It's over here.
It took me like an hour
to feel my way over here.
At first, I... I was worried
he was trapped on the other side.
So I was... I was yelling for him,
and then, uh--
And then I saw the... the blood.
I didn't know rocks
could come down like that. Scary shit.
You okay?
Yeah, it's just...
What is that?
Did Pops mention
opening the tunnel more?
I don't... I don't know.
Why?
Huh.
Look at these pockmarks.
Uh, yeah, what about it?
Think you can, uh, do something
about the power?
Uh, yeah, let me see what I can do.
Okay.
This place is incredible.
Imagine people come in,
getting some of our family's recipes.
Sitting with your neighbors,
enjoying each other.
- What name should we give it?
- We should name it after Grandma.
Maria's.
All right, boss.
Maria's it is.
So, uh, guess you're
my new boss now, right?
- Till I sell the place, yeah.
- Oh.
Figured you were taking it over.
You know, he always talked about it.
Nah. I gotta get back to work.
Well, if you're interested in keeping it,
you know I could always run it for you.
We could turn a profit.
- Not a big one, but--
- Cover your ears!
- Why? Is that the grenade?
Parker...
...what the hell was that about?
- I have a question, Mike.
Yeah.
I believe that that mine collapse happened
because of one of these grenades.
- Okay.
- See the pockmarks in the rocks? The same.
But my father was a Green Beret,
and he knew how to handle explosives.
So what happened?
Uh, I don't know.
Maybe he forgot he pulled the pin.
That's not possible.
It... It might be.
Okay? He was, uh...
he was getting forgetful.
What do you mean forgetful?
Like, you know,
he was... he was getting old.
He was just forgetting shit.
Pops never mentioned it.
Well, he's probably
just trying not to worry you.
Plus, we all take care of each other here.
Like, when this place was hit,
people were here
in like 30 minutes boarding it up.
Well, I'm gonna get another.
Do you want one?
Yeah. Here, twist my arm.
Okay.
Oh.
Mo!
Hey, Parker.
I'm getting a refill.
- Help yourself.
Thank you.
Yo, Mo.
Yo!
- Can we get another round over here?
Yes, sir, just give me one second.
♪ We got a knockdown band... ♪
- Thank you.
- Thank you for your service. I got you.
Appreciate it, ma'am.
♪ They got guitar, fiddle, bass
And drums... ♪
Whoo!
♪ They're all plugged in
And the night is young... ♪
Haji!
Elvis Swann is here.
Haji! Another Bud.
Name's Mo, Elvis.
- Yeah, I know your fuckin' name.
It's a joke.
Cheers.
♪ They're the rockin-est band around... ♪
Do my eyes deceive me?
Jesse said you were back.
Elvis.
You two fucking again or what?
How about I buy you a drink?
We can toast to Harry.
- Looks like you've already had enough.
Let's let bygones be bygones, shall we?
I was a dick to you when I was younger.
Hey, hey, I'm sorry.
No girl was ever good enough
for my brother.
I do think you guys would have
some really cute mixed babies though.
- Ow!
- You don't get to touch me.
- Okay.
- You understand?
- Mm-hmm.
Such a flirt.
Hold up.
What? It's a busted up car.
Jesse ever arrest the people
that knocked over this place?
No difference. Some assholes
robbed Frank's trailer last week.
Gas station got hit a month ago.
Hmm.
Got people staring at us.
People can suck it.
- How do you like that? That was...
- That was pretty. Yeah.
- That was smooth as hell.
- Oh man.
Mike, let's sit for a sec.
I just want to keep an eye on that truck.
It's... stolen.
Truck you were looking in?
Mm-hmm.
Okay, well, if it's stolen, you want me
to call Jesse? He'll take care of it.
Not yet.
- Start the car.
Up next,
an old favorite, here on KWIO.
Could you slow down?
Get off their ass!
Leave one car distance
between us and them, okay?
Fuck, okay, it feels weird.
You know, what if they just drive
a busted-up car?
And now we're... we're being Karens,
we're following them.
We are not being Karens.
They had a machine gun
in the back of their car.
A machine gun?
Where would you even get a machine gun?
It's not easy.
Holy shit.
Yup.
Now, my friend, you can call Jesse.
Okay, I'm going to call--
Where are you going? Parker!
What the hell are you doing?! Shit.
Any other cash in here?
You got a safe? Huh?
Hey, yo, yo, see if there's a safe.
Come on! Let's go.
They held me at gunpoint
and took it right off my wrist.
You know, my dad gave me this watch
when I graduated high school.
I can't believe you found it.
And you remembered
it was mine after all these years?
Yeah.
I'm sorry about Harry,
but I'm glad you're home, kid.
Huh.
Maybe this'll work.
Whoa!
One more! Load it up.
Elvis Swann.
Yeah!
You little rat.
Ah. Load me up.
Count me down, baby!
- All right. Three, two, one! Fire!
- This is the one.
- Yeah!
Whoa!
Fuck the money, man.
Let's keep it!
Where the hell did you get that?
Are they just giving out
military weapons now?
- Hey.
- Hey. Is this a bad time?
Nah, for you, never.
No, I'm just walking to the car.
You know, they got me over at Langley,
stroking a few keys for a few weeks.
How's home?
You know, home.
What do you know about Cirrus Securities?
Small-time cloud storage
used by a lot of CCTV providers.
Think you can break into it?
Who are you talking to?
Of course I can break into it. Why?
I found a link to it
with some of my dad's stuff.
He installed a bunch of new cameras
on the property, so--
Uh-huh. Should we, uh,
I don't know, take a look-see?
- Yes, please.
- You know the deal. Shoot me that link.
I already did.
All right. I am in.
Really?
Well, your pop's password
was one, two, three, four.
Jesus, Pops.
Yeah, now I see where you get
all your chaotic storage vibes from.
I mean, it's a lot of footage here, P,
but no organizational system.
Can you go to the day he died?
- It's two Thursdays ago.
- I mean, that's gonna be a minute.
It's a lot of footage, and I gotta go
file by file, check every single one.
Let me see if I can get an intern
to write a program for you. Hold up. Okay.
I see, uh, some footage of a monster truck
with some flames on the side.
- Any idea who that could be?
- Is it black?
- That's the one.
- Yeah.
Elvis Swann, two n's.
He's a total dipshit.
His dad is a senator.
I actually caught him messing around
with an RPG on my property earlier.
- Any idea why he'd be in the mine?
- Pops had it set up like a living room.
He had a stash there.
Booze, old records, movies.
Oh shit. Your pops
had an actual man cave in a real cave?
Yeah.
-   Mmm.
- Oh, other hobbies.
Your boy Elvis watches a lot of porn.
Uh, looks like
he's on the dark web a lot too.
Really? Doing what?
It looks like selling some M16s,
Sig Sauers, MK13s.
All this stuff's still active service.
I mean, they've got to be stolen.
Any mention of grenades?
Don't see any grenades.
It's probably a hard sell these days.
I swear, if he had anything
to do with that cave-in, I will kill him.
Hey, P, get proof first.
Trail him a bit. Track him.
I'll call you when I have something.
You good otherwise?
I'm always good.
Shit.
Hey.
- Oh, what's up, fool?
Parker?
Oh, what a treat!
Hey.
Oh, I'm so happy to see you!
Don't mind the hands.
I'm getting a bird ready.
- No worries.
- Do you want a beer?
- Of course I do.
- All I've got's light.
Yeah, I'll take a beer too, please.
Sorry, you're out.
Mom, you didn't get beer?
So, Georgia, since you
kind of have your ear to the ground,
what have you heard
about Elvis other than,
you know, being a piece of shit?
He's the same old entitled you-know-what,
selling drugs to Allen's kids,
riding around Quinnie's lot drunk.
Still hanging with, uh, Beck and Mickey?
Mm-hmm.
Wow, those guys haven't been arrested yet.
Well, who's gonna arrest him, Parker?
Jesse? I mean, come on.
Touché.
Elvis got them jobs at the Army depot.
I can't imagine
what they're doing there though.
Not making this town any safer.
You hear anything
about Elvis and guns, Mikey?
Uh, I don't know.
Um...
Matter of fact, yeah. He tried to sell
an AK, uh, to my buddy Trench.
- Tried to trade him for his dirt bike.
- No.
- Yeah.
- Where'd he get an AK from?
- Uh... Walmart.
Mmm.
- Think they're having a sale.
- Funny.
'Sup, hot stuff?
Your boy Elvis has an exchange
set for this afternoon at his place.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
And I assume you've snuck into
a window or two in your youth.
Your assumptions are correct.
I wonder what you think
about that, Senator Swann.
I've never felt
more unsafe in my own country.
In an effort to be progressive,
Washington has stopped protecting us.
When I'm re-elected,
I will continue to fight for our values.
Freedom, family, and faith.
I am Creation through and through.
Swann residence.
We're here to see Elvis.
Come on in, boys.
I couldn't agree more,
Senator Swann.
Thank you, and God bless.
God bless America.
A little more party, huh?
A little more party.
Okay, boys.
I got this one right here.
Since day one, baby!
Yeah, I'll take all of these.
Great, great.
Rumor has it you might have access
to something a little bigger.
How much bigger
are we talking about?
I'm looking for RPGs.
Ah... I'll have to talk
to my connect about that.
See what I can, uh... See what I can do.
You get me five RPGs,
and I'll have half a mil
in your bank account
by the end of next week.
Yeah, I think we can figure something out.
Anybody can defend America
against foreign threats.
Oh really?
Mm-hmm.
But how many people can defend
Quinnie's new herd from meth heads?
- I think you should quit.
Move back home, come on as my deputy.
I think you just miss me.
You think?
Yeah.
- Hey, Parker.
Hey, Dad.
Senator.
I see you two old lovebirds.
How is being back?
Um...
- Good.
- Yeah?
I see your campaign is, uh, going well.
You're on all the billboards,
and I hear your ads on the radio.
Mm-hmm.
- Very passionate.
Nah, that's some bullshit.
Power over policy, right?
That's what people want, Parker.
We have got to have her over the house
one of these nights, huh?
Catch up, right?
I mean, I would get
drips and drabs from my son here.
Sure.
Yeah?
Well, how about this weekend?
You'll come too, Jesse.
Anyway, I gotta get back to the office.
It's good to see you.
Have fun.
God, I feel like
I've been shot back to high school,
like I should be
worried about sneaking off
before Harry's done with last call.
Remember that time
I tried sneaking out the window,
and he was in the parking lot
with his friends?
And he said, "Jesse, what've you been
doing these days, other than my daughter?"
Yeah.
I thought I was dead,
till he started laughing.
He liked you.
He liked messing with me.
Same thing.
He didn't kill himself, Jesse.
You know that, right?
Well, he hadn't been himself lately.
You know, he was...
getting more and more confused.
It's not like any of us were worried
about him being home alone or anything.
It was just that sometimes he would...
...you know.
I know. Mike told me.
So you think he killed himself
because he was forgetful?
That's not a thing.
When are you gonna release the body?
Uh, tomorrow.
I told them to prepare him for cremation
so you can have the funeral.
And we're ruling it an accident.
Good, because it was.
It was an accident.
Is there anything I can do?
I wanna help.
That's very generous of you.
It's Roberto.
He's gonna make me go
back to AA, I guess.
Better than getting a divorce.
Ugh.
Everyone in town knows
I'm not racist.
Hmm.
In fact, my great-grandfather
was a Native American.
Oh really?
Yeah.
- What tribe?
Yeah, I don't know.
But it's where I get
my lactose intolerance from.
You're funny.
You know, people see a white guy
spouting conservative talking points
in this climate and they shut down.
Never mind that most Latinos
are conservative.
You know, people like you
around here, Parker.
They like Harry, or liked him.
- If I could get an endorsement from you--
Oh, hey, careful, Dad.
You blow her ego up too much,
she's gonna end up running against you.
Now there's a question
I wanted to ask you. Uh...
How am I supposed to say that, that, uh...
that "Latinx"?
How do I say it? Is it Latinx or...
It's great.
The way you're saying it, it's great.
- Oh, is that right?
Mm-hmm.
Well, can I be honest with you?
Please.
I don't understand it at all.
Latinx.
- I gotta go.
You can't stay for a minute?
No, no. It's a... It's a work emergency.
Let's do this again.
That's a shitload of rocks.
Going to be clearing them all night.
The Swanns need to pay us
for this shit.
How long before she's back?
Wow, I guess this spic
really loved Chuck Norris.
We should take those back with us.
This is my favorite part.
Come on, Elvis, get up.
This is your mess.
Mm-hmm.
Get out of his chair!
- Oh shit!
- You did it, didn't you? Didn't you?
- What?
- Help!
Elvis?
Shit!
Walk. Now!
Do what she says. Go!
Go on, go! Come on, get to it!
- Shit. No! Oh.
Hey, hey.
- I didn't kill Harry, okay?
- I don't want to hear it!
What do you think's gonna happen?
My brother's gonna come and arrest me? Ah!
Ow, don't do that!
What makes you think
he doesn't already know I'm here?
Huh?
Oh God, Maria's!
No! Stop!
Please, stop!
Fucking bitch!
Mickey, stop!
Come back here!
Come out here, bitch!
Come on, Elvis, get in.
Get it goin'! Come on!
Elvis!
Oh shit!
Let's go. Come on!
The tires are flat.
What the fuck?
You killed Pops.
- You killed him, didn't you?
- Hey, get off him.
You smuggled guns through the tunnels,
and he caught you.
I said get the hell off him!
Parker, stop it!
Get off him! You're gonna kill him!
Admit it! Admit it, Elvis!
Calm down,
or I'm gonna have to arrest you.
He murdered Pops!
I'm gonna kill him!
You told me you stopped.
Right. Oh...
You don't know how much they were offering
for just a couple of these missiles, so...
Who are these people?
I don't know. They're...
They're people from the fucking Internet.
Fucking motherfucker!
- Boys! Come on, quit it. Quit it!
You're the worst thing
that's happened to this place.
You know that?
Selling goddamn stolen guns
on the dark web,
drawing every type
of nasty person to our town!
All this crime is a win.
It's a win!
You're the sheriff of the town.
You get to play hero.
Dad looks generous.
It's saving his fucking career, man.
I mean, you guys should be thanking me.
Goddamn it.
If you'd just kept her at the dinner,
none of this shit would've happened.
Everything would've been fine. She would
be having a nice meal, enjoying herself
while we cleared out the cave
and got the fucking missiles!
You could've at least told me
what the goddamn plan was.
- Supposed to tell you everything?
- You're supposed to--
Enough!
How much does Parker know about this?
Too much.
You gotta clean this up.
I got good news for you.
My dad found a buyer
for the five acres around Maria's.
They're willing to give you
three million for it, as is.
Five million.
Just take the money
and go back to your life.
How... involved are you?
Was our whole thing
supposed to be... a distraction?
No. No.
You let me think he killed himself.
What are you doing?
There's footage of their bullshit.
The best thing you can do
is turn yourself and them in.
The cameras in the bar are fake.
He put real ones outside.
I'll need to see them, then.
Oh really?
Not before my lawyer does.
Thanks for coming out all this way.
Anything for Spider.
- Luis Torres.
- Parker.
- Pleasure to meet you, Parker.
- You too.
Can you, uh, excuse us?
Yeah, I'll be in my office.
You're being held
for assaulting Elvis,
but they also found a body at Maria's.
Sheriff.
Wonder if I could ask a few questions.
- Yeah, sure. Sit.
Thank you.
Sheriff, the men Parker caught
robbing the feed store last week,
they're still in the hospital, yes?
Mm-hmm. Are they relevant to all this?
No, just doing my due diligence.
Your brother, Elvis,
he's employed by your father, yes?
- In a limited capacity.
- Which is what?
I stay out of it.
All right.
Well, that's all I got for right now.
Thank you for your hospitality.
Sheriff?
Oh, don't you want to be
done with this, Parker?
Come on.
Just give us the security tapes.
You know, if you, uh... if you
pivot on that back foot,
you won't punch like such a little bitch.
Maybe she's full of shit.
There is no security footage.
Harry had no fucking idea
what he was talking about half the time.
Fucking--
Parker, please.
You can make this stop.
So could you.
Why don't you
just tell us what's on the tape,
and then we'll give you
a little water and some food,
and you know,
take those little cuffs off for a while.
- No, I'm good. I'm good. I like it here.
Yeah?
You wanna know
what really happened to Harry?
Dad.
Look, I'm working with the hand I got.
Let's make a trade.
Okay.
It's with a friend of mine.
I need to call
and tell him where to send it.
Come on.
What?
If you tell her too much now,
it fucks everything.
Well, we can keep busting her ass.
- I mean, either way it's on her.
You've gotta call this off.
The fuck?
Who are these people?
If you try anything...
you understand
what's gonna happen to you, yes?
What's his number?
202...
555-1227.
Tell him it's Parker,
and call back on this number.
Good girl.
Hey.
Hey, Spider.
I'm gonna need
another favor from you, my friend.
I'm, uh, here with Senator Swann
and, uh, his sons.
They're torturing me.
Shoot her, Jesse!
Shoot her!
- Gun down. Down.
Do what she says, boys.
Get in the cell.
- She's not gonna kill you.
- No, Parker!
In the cell, now.
Get on the ground!
- Shit.
- Now!
Okay.
Stay down!
Calling all cars.
Be on the lookout
for a Swann County Sheriff's patrol SUV.
Driver is a woman, Hispanic, 30s.