Downloaded from
YTS.MX
BETA FILM presents
Official YIFY movies site:
YTS.MX
In 972, the Fatimids founded Al-Azhar,
to make it a center for Islamic knowledge.
The Great Imam
is the highest authority in Sunni Islam.
For centuries the rulers of Egypt
have tried to control Al-Azhar.
So far they have not succeeded.
TOFIK BARKHOM
FARES FARES
Film on TARIK SALEH
Señor Dios
Come on, wake up!
Good day!
It's for you.
Open it.
'You have been accepted to Al-Azhar University.
Congratulations!
Come on!
God has blessed you with a gift.
You used to come here every day to read.
Al-Azhar is the greatest Islamic institution in the world.
And they chose you.
Come on!
Yes, father?
Give me a hand.
You smell like tobacco.
Everyone, put your hands up!
What are you doing?
Hush, you're going to wake up dad.
What is this?
I received a scholarship.
- Can not be!
For Cairo? -Yes.
What will you say to dad?
I don't know.
You know what he is like. He will understand.
What do you want? Go to sleep!
God gave you a brain
who thinks more than necessary.
You are like your mother.
She was always curious, peace be upon her.
She sent you to school
so that you don't become a fisherman like me!
I had your brother read the letter to me.
If God wants you to go to Cairo,
no one should hinder Him.
Even your father.
On your way!
Thank you.
I will miss you.
Take care of yourself, Adam.
Will you take care of dad?
Do you promise?
Look at me.
You know how much I love you.
Yes, father.
Don't forget where you're from.
- No, Dad.
Good bye.
Goodbye, father.
Oh! Al-Azhar!
This is the elite!
God bless you with knowledge!
What is your name? - Adam, sir.
What a nice name!
If God said, by completing your studies,
you will become Sheikh Adam!
Here it is.
Goodbye.
The third floor, the corridor on the right,
the district office.
Thank you.
- Good luck!
Excuse me.
Hello.
It seems to me that you are in my bed.
No, this is mine.
Is that so?
Is this bed available?
Do you snore? - No.
Are you sure?
Then it is free.
Are you new here?
Yes, I just arrived.
Welcome.
Will you put out if you love?
This life is just a game
fun
bragging and competition
for material wealth.
Like the rain
to make the grass be pleased
with itself because it grows.
It will then dry out
it will turn yellow
and it will turn to dust and rubbish.
The afterlife is eternal. And there
Only God's forgiveness matters.
What are you doing?
Am I? I am creating a new brand of cigarettes.
My own brand.
Listen, Adam.
It doesn't matter who you are,
but who you want to be.
We're running late.
Calm down, Sardine.
God has rewarded you with a sure hand.
You don't tremble.
In the name of the merciful God,
Al-Azhar is the guiding light
of the Islamic world.
And on the day
in which you will leave Al-Azhar
and you will return to your villages,
and you will become bearers
of this knowledge.
Are you all right, Sheikh*?
Make way!
Shout the doctors!
The Grand Imam's condition
is still critical.
What does he say?
Let's pray for the great imam.
We wish him a speedy recovery!
Good day. I have a meeting
with the general.
Okay, sir. Park in tomorrow.
Open the door.
Who will take over the situation?
Colonel Ibrahim, sir.
Sednete.
As you all know
the great imam died yesterday.
Rest in peace.
Now it is necessary
our candidate to become
the new grand imam.
Of course, sir.
Who are our insiders?
We have eyes and ears,
but it's complicated.
It is very difficult.
Idiots changed the constitution.
Now the grand imam is appointed for life.
It is not a matter of issuing
minor religious prescriptions.
The choice of a great imam
is a matter of national security.
No one should hold a post for life,
except our president!
We don't want that!
It is unacceptable for usto have
two pharaohs in the country!
Sheikh Durrani is close
to the Muslim Brotherhood.
He supports terrorists!
Slepiya Sheikh
is one of the most popular
imams in Egypt.
And it is not known to be biased.
President
iska Beblavi.
His views coincide with
those of the president.
Make sure they choose it.
Consider the task accomplished.
Do you have a prayer rug?
Ahmed, bring the general a prayer rug!
Stay away until they choose
the new grand imam.
Until they choose you.
Please!
Don't get involved.
Who does the council want?
The majority wants the Blind Sheikh.
We want another.
I was exposed. You must release me.
Do you know what the sentence
is for traitors?
Name me new "angel
Unattached Freshman.
Don't worry.
Close your eyes
to see the truth.
Need is blind
until she becomes conscious.
And freedom is a conscious necessity.
Do you know who said it?
Jewish philosopher Karl Marx.
Furthermore, he said that religion
is proof of the mental impotence of man
in the face of what he cannot understand.
Life is not a game.
Hello
Where are you from?
Fire Manzala.
ribar?
I am Sheikh Negm's assistant.
If you need help...
Blagodary.
Tell me which doctrine does
Sheikh Negm follow?
The truth.
What is the truth?
Truth on Sheikh Negm.
Do you want to pray?
Are you going to the center yet?
I will go tonight. Do you want to come?
dobre.
This is halal.
Drink!
'I found a replacement.
Son of a fisherman."
What?
she.
Your soul is still pure.
What?
But every single moment in this
place will corrupt her.
Wait here.
This morning
One of our students was found dead.
Colonel Ibrahim is here,
to investigate this tragedy.
God help him.
to discover the truth.
Excuse me for intruding on such
a delicate moment.
We can end our investigation
until a new grand imam is elected.
Can you tell me when this
will be announced?
The question is purely technical.
We have our own rules and we follow them.
May God guide you.
Who was his teacher?
He was an assistant in my department.
What else can you tell me about him?
Nothing you don't already know.
Why is State Security investigating this?
The deceased has foreign citizenship.
President Nasser tried to turn Al-Azhar
into a state institution.
Sadat tried to corrupt him.
And Mrs. Suzanne Mubarak tried
to change the laws of God,
to please the Americans
and the women around her.
So tell us, Colonel,
What are your instructions?
I just want to know why the boy is dead.
osamat
Where are you from?
From Alexandria.
Ahmed of Giza.
me?
Adam Taha.
Where are you from Adam? - From Manzala.
A fisherman? - Yes.
You are free.
Forget about the legs.
After sunset, go out through
the exit that Zizo showed you.
Then take a bus to the center.
Descent of Mohandesin
to the Arab League.
There is an American cafe there.
I'll meet you there.
Order something
and sit at a table next to me.
Take out your phone
It's like you're talking to someone.
Did you order something?
I'm not hungry, sir.
If you don't order, they'll kick you out.
I have no money.
Order a cinnamon latte and brownies
with cream.
Duck with cinnamon
and brownies with cream.
Save them until our next meeting.
Don't you have relatives in Cairo?
I don't have any.
Well, what happened?
On the way back from the mosque
men were waiting for us.
what?
Men with knives.
Officially, your friend died
in an accident.
But as you saw, he was killed.
We will find out who did it.
And they will pay for it.
We want you to help us.
Sir, all I know.
Wij, Adam
I only ask you to attend the dawn prayer.
Shall I pray?
Praying and observing who else is praying.
Remember their faces, learn their names.
Adam? - Yes it's me.
Someone asked me to do something.
I am not sure if this
is acceptable or a sin.
A right is a right, a sin is a sin.
God will guide you.
Prayer is better than sleep.
God is great. There is no other God.
Straight line, upright posture.
No distance between you.
We will all die, my children.
Who complains
of life's accidents and God's outline,
he will weaken his faith.
Now go.
Please pray for your brother
and pray to God to have mercy on him
and forgive his sins.
Do you have the names? - No.
Your father has gallstones.
That's why it hurts.
If left untreated, he will die.
We have a hospital in Dhakalia.
I will arrange the operation.
He won't know you helped him.
We do not forget those who work for us.
But I have to ask you.
Don't call your village imam anymore.
And I want you to know who prays
at dawn in the mosque.
Sharia is not Islamic law.
It is rather a divine right.
Fiqh is the human interpretation
of this right.
There are five principles in Sharia:
care for religion, soul, material goods
generation and reason.
Declare yourself!
Bro...
I have a study group for those who wish
to improve their recitation.
Come on in.
Aslam.
Asfur.
Harun.
Nazim.
God bless you!
Bravo.
You're okay, bro.
He sings, Sheikh!
Leave it.
He is new here.
He doesn't know that we don't sing here.
It is forbidden to sing the Koran.
STATE SECURITY
Enter!
Honorable Sheikh!
Come in, sir
How can I help you?
I have come to confess.
Admit it?
I killed him.
Please, I can't believe it!
Sit down, please.
- Why?
Because I'm blind?
No, but you are a respected scientist.
Do you have another suspect?
No, but we are still investigating the case.
We"? Which "we"?
I'm talking about State Security.
Who do you work for?
For the president?
Correct.
My president is Almighty God.
Very good, Sheikh.
How could you be so reckless?
Recruiting a foreign informant?
And what's more, the assistant
of the Blind Sheikh!
What were you thinking?
I never planned for him to die, sir.
Stop the sarcasm, man.
I know, every morning in front
of the mirror you say to yourself
Why am I not the boss?
You are older than me.
You've worked here much longer.
Do you know why they didn't promote you?
- No, sir.
But I have a feeling that you know
and are getting ready to tell me.
I swear to you
if it blows up in our face,
It's over with you, not with me!
Clear? - Yes.
listen.
You leave me no choice.
Arrest him!
Good day.
Aslam Aslan, Nazim bin Syed...
Nazim bin Saeed?
Sounds like a foreign name.
He is from Algeria.
I hear your father's surgery went well.
I am eternally grateful to you.
You don't need to thank me.
Your work is important to us.
I will tell you a secret.
We believe that the Muslim Brotherhood
infiltrated Al-Azhar.
And they ordered the murder of your friend.
Do you know this book?
This is a guide to modern jihad.
But it is forbidden, sir.
Let Nazim see you with her.
Don't be afraid.
How are you? - Okay.
The infidels who are in power
They treat true Muslims as terrorists.
We invite you to tea with us.
Blagodary.
Do you like to read forbidden books?
Adam, we are family here.
You can trust us.
Not the books condemned by God
or idolatrous books.
The books that scare tyrants
and the kings.
It is time for every Muslim
to make a choice.
Children are being killed in Palestine.
In Syria and Iraq, they rape our women.
China built extermination concentration camps
of the Muslims.
Yet our leaders turn a blind eye
and take their money.
In Burma they kill us.
And what does the so-called
"civilized" world say?
They give the Nobel Peace Prize
of the leader of the criminal gangs
that kill us.
There is no need to look further.
Al-Azhar!
The guiding ray of Islam in the world.
What does Al-Azhar say about all this?
Nothing.
And speaking of that,
Do you know what happened
to the Blind Sheikh?
I heard he was sick.
State security arrested him.
They will keep him until the grand imam
they want is elected heh.
They think they can scare the Council
and for him to choose their puppet candidate.
But they will fail.
The corrupt leaders
on this side
try to prevent God's will.
And they use snakes
to penetrate among us.
Your friend Zizo.
Some say I killed him.
Seriously bros?
Why do you think they say that?
Do you know what I think?
He was killed by State Security.
bro
Want to do more than just read?
Soliman thinks you have arrested
the Blind Sheikh,
to force the Council to select
your candidate.
He says you will fail, sir.
Am I going to fail?
That's what he said, sir.
You said it, Adam.
No, he said it, not me.
He doesn't trust you. He's using you
as a courier.
You have to earn his trust.
- How?
Do you share his views?
I'm taking that as a yes
Does it matter what I believe, sir?
Yes, of course. For him.
Like Satan
penetrating pious minds?
Welcome to the dark side.
Shut up.
"The establishment of the kingdom of God
on earth, the destruction of human,
the struggle with the power of the usurpers
and its return to God,
the supremacy of divine law alone,
the abolition of human laws
and to all those who do not follow
the instructions..."
Raed, please!
The point of importance" by Said Kutb.
Bro?
Why are you hanging around
Soliman and his gang?
This is a study group only.
- A group of which he is the leader.
You know they hate me, right?
Idiot!
Not a word about the book!
- I will be silent.
Will you take part in the recitation
competition on Friday?
Against your new friends.
Are you sure? - Yes always.
Don't come crying to me
when you lose on Friday.
Come on, let's go.
Why don't you like Sol Iman?
I just don't like it.
Because of how he behaves with
your friend Raed?
He is not my friend.
Is that so?
Does he suspect you?
Don't worry.
I'll shut him up.
Why do you care?
He's not your friend, is he?
Tariq Ibn Ziyad burned his boats
when he arrived in Spain.
He said to his men: "The sea is behind us,
the enemy is before us."
Do I have to burn your father's
boat to motivate you?
Gained Soliman's trust.
How is dad?
Has anyone visited you?
Niko?
Sorry, I can't talk anymore.
I miss you.
spri
Stop it, Asfur.
Forget "they persisted."
They persevered and looked proud.
And now the two finalists remain!
The winner is Raed Abdelmajid!
Congratulations, son!
What do you want?
Informant! - What have I done?
Is it because I won?
What is this?
They are not mine.
Dirty rat!
Adam...
What have you gotten yourself into?
You did the right thing, brother.
God punishes the unbelievers.
God bless you.
Bravo.
Adam...
Who gave you "Important Points"?
You know this book is forbidden.
Who gave you your copy? - My uncle.
There is also a book stall.
Seriously? - Yes.
He sells books, God bless him.
Here it is.
Put it on speaker.
Hello?
Hello uncle, how are you?
Hi Adam, how are you?
We miss you.
I'm fine.
I just wanted
to thank you.
About the book you gave me.
What? I do not understand.
The book I took from you.
The book.
Don't you remember?
I really don't understand.
Is there a problem?
No, uncle.
S.O.S
Who are you writing to?
Give me your phone.
Watch it.
Disappear!
Who do you work for?
I don't understand.
Damn stairs!
Look down.
How many meters are they to the ground?
Maybe 13.
Your body will be unrecognizable.
Who do you take orders from, boy?
By Sheikh Durrani, Sir!
Are you sure you want to play
games with me?
I carry out orders that I receive
over the phone.
You are resigning today.
And you will tell Sheikh Durrani
that Adam will replace you.
Then you told the university that you
wanted to pursue something else.
Tourism, maybe.
I hear he's picking up speed again.
The sphinx smiles again.
Yes, sir.
Coffee.
Can you make coffee?
Today my assistant resigned.
He was like the son I never had.
I recommended you as my deputy.
I told him not to worry.
Go to the pharmacy.
Get me paracetamol for children.
And a rubber comb for babies.
It's for the child.
- Of course.
Congratulations.
It's for my son's son, idiot!
I'm a grandfather.
Congratulations on your new job.
How do I karash?
Do you already have a girlfriend?
Was there anything else, sir?
Are you into anything in particular?
Answer me, boy!
No, sir.
You're up for something special,
aren't you?
Do you think you have a gift?
Is that why you got this scholarship?
You are nothing!
Have you ever wondered why we are
looking for people like you?
We helped you so you could help us.
Maybe your friend
The village imam helped us find you.
No, you are not better than others.
I took a big risk to get rid of your skin.
Give me something.
Whatever.
Today he asked me to buy baby things
for his son to his son.
He has no son.
Tonight you have to go downtown.
I want McDonald's.
Everyone says the meat in their
burgers is halal.
Take me two Big Macs
with fries and ketchup extra.
If someone sees you, say they are for you.
He just wants me to buy him McDonald's.
I will drive you.
Let's go.
We just passed McDonald's.
Gospodine...
Good evening. Colonel Ibrahim, I called you.
Get in, Colonel.
Command, sir.
Welcome. Enter.
Enter the living room.
Welcome.
Um Reem is Sheikh Durrani's housekeeper.
Sit down.
May God protect him, he is a man of God,
he gives us everything we need.
What will you drink?
We will not hold back.
- Hibiscus or Pepsi?
I don't have to deal with it.
- Good.
Welcome.
There, sir.
How are you, Rome?
My name is Ibrahim.
Can I hold it?
His diapers need to be changed.
You are very cute!
God bless him!
What a beautiful baby!
We need to talk to your daughter.
I will leave you.
God bless you.
Who is the father, Rome?
Please don't ask me about that!
Don't be afraid.
Nobody will harm you.
Sheikh Durrani is a great man.
He is like a father to me,
I don't miss anything.
It's my fault.
Will they take it?
Listen, Rome.
If you keep quiet, no one will
pick up on it.
Did you understand?
Let's go.
Goodbye, Rome.
What's up?
I don't believe what she said.
How can she be sure that Durrani
is the father?
He took her virginity.
How do you know?
Thanks to you.
You discovered his secret.
After seeing you, I did some research.
I found you were right.
Sheikh Durrani has no son.
There are only girls.
He has secretly married Rome.
He bought her that apartment.
Do you think he did it out of kindness?
Why are you telling me all this?
Make sure Durrani doesn't become
the next Grand Imam.
Just a moment.
This world is in decline.
The signs of the Last Judgment are visible.
Ignorance of religion has spread,
the denial of religious precepts
and attacks on the Prophet's way of life.
The spread of obscenity
usury and bank interest
alcohol consumption and entertainment...
The House of Islam has caught
fire and is burning!
Muslim brotherhood
Salafis...
You give...
They all aim to burn the home
of Islam to the ground.
And women appear
purely naked on the streets.
And outsiders have more trust
of the hypocrites than
of the true believers,
who are falsely accused
and criticism of customs!
Good night.
- You too.
Come in!
Good evening, respected Sheikh.
Aren't you Sheikh Durrani's
new assistant?
I have something to share with you.
I don't like gossip, boy.
He got a girl pregnant.
A girl the age of his children.
The next great imam - father
of an illegitimate child?
If your statement is true,
this will destroy Al-Azhar's reputation.
I refuse to blame Sheikh Durrani.
I will, sir.
you?
Who are you? Who will listen to you?
He would listen to me.
Who do you work for?
For Sheikh Durrani, sir.
Sheikh Durrani.
Good evening.
Damn it
All the applause, clever man!
Zizo was your informant, wasn't he?
That's why he's dead.
They killed him.
Did you kill him?
Tariq Ibn Ziyad never burned boats.
This is a myth propagated by his enemies.
Actually, he had no boats.
He borrowed them from
a Spanish nobleman.
His men would not have won
if they were afraid.
They fought because they
believed in victory.
I want guarantees.
Of course.
I guarantee that if you fail,
You'll wish what happened
to Zizo happened to you.
Reverend Sheikh.
You are next in line for the post
of grand imam.
Some don't want that to happen.
Why are you taking the blame
for the case?
The will of the president..
The President of the Republic
he would announce himself as the next
great imam if he could.
Zizo was your informant, wasn't he?
It wasn't an accident.
On Judgment Day
the killer will carry his victim
on his back forever.
19TH INTERNATIONAL ISLAMIC FORUM
We follow the procedure.
We are not in a hurry.
Can you tell us if Sheikh Negm
is still alive?
Internet rumors claim that
State Security arrested him,
to prevent him from becoming
the next great imam.
Only rumours!
This is a religious conference.
Religious conference!
Rumors have no place here.
What is your question?
I have a question about secret marriage.
Ask your question.
If a young woman
let's call it Rome
has a child from a married man
with an impeccable reputation
my question is, can we have trust
of a man who has a secret marriage
and also a child
that his legal family doesn't know about?
What Islam says
for such a person?
Excellent question.
Who on the Council wants to answer him?
Sheikh Durrani?
Will you answer?
Okay.
Sheikh Abdel Kader
has written extensively
on the clandestine marriage.
Thank you, Sheikh.
It depends on the circumstances.
A little while ago
Did the girl's guardian approve
of the marriage?
Yes.
does the man have the resources
to get married
in some other way?
Third
did they get married
before or after
the conception of the child?
Some people
in the parliament they want..
Al-Sheikh Omar Al-Beblawi.
Blessed be the presidency.
Thank God!
It's not really about me.
This goes much further.
The main thing is that religion
and the state work side by side.
What is good for Al-Azhar
is good for the state.
And vice versa.
Holy water from Zamzam. May we drink
it together in Mecca.
I see a very bright future for you.
Come in.
Leave this.
Major General Sobhi, head
of State Security, greeted.
Adam is a model of the ideal student.
I'm trying, sir.
I will unpack the books after your meeting.
No, no.
No more unpacking books.
Another student will do it.
You will stand behind me
at the prayer on Friday.
Did you understand?
Yes, thanks.
Adam, have we met before?
God created 40 doppelgängers
of everyone, sir.
At the moment
anywhere on the Internet
there are calls for demonstrations
against the government
for greater freedom.
My take on this is,
that the civil war
is something more serious than murder.
Please, sir.
There is no need.
Greetings, sir.
The president is very pleased.
- Thank goodness.
What is this?
- The report, sir.
No, it won't work like that.
The blind sheikh cannot be the murderer.
He is blind!
- But he admitted.
What does he want?
- I'm not sure.
Shouldn't we notify the general?
No, it's not something important.
Is there anything else? -Yes.
Your "angel"
We don't need it anymore. Get rid of him.
Sir, that's a bit too much.
Too much?
You know very well
that we don't like unfinished business.
Get him to admit that he killed Zizo.
Then we will hang him.
Bring it.
Where is your mother? - Sleep.
Did you do your homework?
What are we going to eat when she sleeps?
You accomplished your mission perfectly.
I have come to arrest you.
Will I see my family again?
I can't believe it.
We do not decide our destiny.
God chose you.
You chose me.
Let the university go.
Only 3 weeks of classes left.
Go home.
And forget you ever met me.
Major General Sobhi?
Sorry to bother you so late.
My informant disappeared.
I assure you it is.
I only know his first name
- Raed.
I know it's amazing
but so it happened, sir.
Of course, sir.
Very good. Goodbye.
'Sardine, can we meet? Raed"
See you in the evening.
Good evening.
Don't be afraid.
Let's not complicate this.
You killed Zizo.
Clear?
Some think.
That they can be silent.
We pull out their nails.
But they still don't talk.
Do you know when they talk?
When we bring their fathers...
to watch the torture.
An ugly sight!
Open it
Is your father at home?
Father!
What's up?
Someone has come to talk to you.
Which one?
- I do not know.
Get inside
What's up, Osman?
- You must come with us.
It's a little late.
Okay, enter.
Should I bring food?
No, there is no need.
I found it.
Your "angel"
Calm down.
Only a hair falls from his head,
and I will kill you!
He is still alive.
Damn you!
Lord, forgive me.
Damn you, Sobhi!
I don't understand.
Why do you care about him?
We still need him.
For what?
Is nothing.
You sent your men to kill Zizo!
Why?
He was compromised. There should be
no connection between us.
Why wasn't I notified?
For your own good, fool!
The Blind Sheikh knows that Zizo
was my informant!
He also knows that we killed him!
He confessed to the crime to convict us!
We will kill him too.
The Blind Sheikh?
Are you crazy?
You need permission from the general.
What the hell am I doing here?
Sir, we killed Zizo Albizri.
Sir, I tried to tell him...
- Shut your mouth!
Sir, I know this is a politically
sensitive decision.
But the Blind Sheikh forced
us to arrest him
for the murder of Zizo.
Did he force us?
And where is he now?
Knock, sir.
In the building?
May God have mercy on us all!
What if he's gone? Forever!
You want me to become an accomplice
to murder
of one of the country's greatest
religious leaders?
No, sir.
Sir...
The boy helped us choose a great imam.
It could convince the Blind Sheikh
to retract his confession.
And we will write it as an accident.
Please let us.
Sit down.
Do you know that the Blind Sheikh?
did he confess to the murder
of the foreign student?
He didn't do it.
State security killed him, sir.
He was their informant,
but he wanted to leave.
But why the Blind Sheikh
to confess to a crime he did not commit?
To tell the process the truth
to the whole world.
He could turn to the media.
But he knows who controls the media.
Could the son of a fisherman
make him change his mind?
Could try sir.
Why should he do it?
Al-Azhar and the state should
never be in conflict.
This could lead to civil war.
I need your advice Sheikh.
They made me confess to killing Zizo.
And I will be hanged for it.
A true believer is not afraid of death.
I know that.
I am a believer.
But I'm afraid.
I'm afraid for my father.
He will lose his son.
My brothers will lose me like
we lost my mother.
If your faith is strong
and your heart is pure, one day
you will meet her in heaven.
And if you confess to a murder
you didn't commit?
Are you going to heaven?
If the intention is to reveal the truth,
the intention is good.
I thought that God created us
to fulfill his wishes.
Not to change them.
I run from the destiny given to me
by God to fulfill his wishes.
When Omar Ibn Al Khattab was told
that the Prophet Muhammad had died,
he drew his sword.
I will kill anyone who says Muhammad
is dead!"
But Abu Bakr replied: Whoever
bows to Muhammad
he knows that Muhammad is dead.
He who worships God knows
that God is immortal.
Who exactly are you?
I am your student.
You are no longer a student.
You don't need anyone to teach you
your religion.
Tell the people outside
that I withdraw my confession.
Power is a double-edged sword.
He can easily cut your hand.
Welcome home.
- How are you?
I'm fine. What's new?
Hello, Dad.
- Welcome home, son.
I wish your mother was here to see you!
You're back!
Congratulations.
Welcome home.
Glory be to God.
Glory be to God..
What did you learn?