I'll give my heart just to one man
The greatest love since time began
He'll come my way and he'll be strong
And he will sing me love's sweet song...
- What happened Mr. Höfgen?
- Who call you?
I don't need you now!
Go to hell!
We're invited to a boring banquet.
Sorry, but we have to leave now.
Can't you sit with us just some minutes, Dora?
No, we're much too late.
Sorry, good evening.
I just wanted to say you were marvelous tonight.
It was fantastic. Thank God I saw it.
You liar! You didn't even see the show.
Never mind, I`ve hear you're talented.
Me? Talented?
Say it louder, please.
Yes, you're very talented, Herr Höfgen.
I'm sure you'll soon be able to show
just how talented you are.
I must be going, goodbye.
- Böck, seven marks.
- But Hendrik,
if you need money
I can lend you fifty marks.
This is men's business.
Böck likes giving money. There we go.
Good evening, Miklas.
Thank you.
Right!
If it was for Dr. Kroge,
I`ll die of hunger.
Höfgen, you old sinner!
Take a seat.
Well, Director,
how'd you like the show?
What's getting you down, Hendrik?
That I'm a provincial actor.
Is that all? Nothing else?
Good day.
You're late.
One day, I'll come to fetch you.
Don't you dread that, Heinz?
- Please don't call me Heinz.
- Why not? That's your name.
I dislike it. Understand?
I understand all, Heinz.
You can't even drink a beer
like a man who feels like drinking one.
Shall we start?
What was that about beer?
It's not your style,
simply to call for a beer.
"A beer, please" sounds phony when you say it.
You know I don't drink, Juliette.
I know, Heinz. Take your shoes off.
What is it?
Don`t stand there like you`ve stained your pants.
One, two...
One, two, three, four...
On one.
Don't fall down now.
Faster!
Show me what you can do.
You want to be an actor
and show off for money, too?
You comical picture of misery.
That`s it!
Oh God!
If you liked the music,
you wouldn't get tired.
You always laugh at me, Juliette.
Always!
I can't cry.
Would you love me if I could cry?
I love you anyway.
You only love yourself, Heinz,
and even then not enough.
Keep talking.
I like hearing you.
You never listen to me.
Your only concern is your face
being devoid of human expression.
It's a mask, you hear?
I, too, have skin and bones and body weight,
and eyebrows and fingernails,
just like you.
I, too, feel the cold.
I can be hungry and thirsty.
I, too, think of my mother.
And I know there are Philistines and Communists.
But my eyes are not my eyes.
My legs are not my legs!
My face is not my face!
My name is not my name,
because I am an actor!
Do you know what it means to be an actor?
An actor is a mask...
among human beings.
Come! Come!
Juliette!
Ladies and gentlemen,
I have the honor
of welcoming you
to the first reading of the play.
But before that, may I introduce our guest,
Nicoletta von Niebuhr,
who will play the female lead
in this production.
Do you mind if my friend watches the rehearsal?
I have no objection.
- Two cognacs and one absinte.
- Yes, Mr. Director.
Coming up right away, Director.
- Three beers, please.
- Right.
There you go,
two cognacs and one absinte.
Thank you.
To a good collaboration.
Now, please excuse me.
- A beer?
- Yes, a beer please.
Right.
The old Hansemann...
Hendrik, will we look lovely in this play?
We are lovely.
May I introduce my best friend,
Barbara Bruckner?
Nice to meet you.
What?
There's a nice smell of lavender about you.
Can you smell the lavender, too?
How shocking, on a man.
But I need it like my daily bread.
A little on the temples
is as good as a night's sleep.
Sleep would be better,
but there's no time.
A beer and a mineral water.
We'll hear what the old man has to say,
use the good bits, then play it our way.
He's good, but old-fashioned.
The future of Hamburg Art Theater is me.
I mean the two of us, naturally.
But most of the plays here
are shallow bourgeois stuff.
But Otto and I visualize theater
that will involve everyone,
like the workers, the dockers.
Where will you perform this theater?
It doesn't matter.
In the docks, in the factories, in cellars.
Hendrik, they asked me about the play.
We promised it for last week.
Let's get this opening night over first.
To prove that theater has a
political responsability is difficult.
Before it can be political or revolutionary,
it first has to be good.
Which actors will be in this sort of theater?
All who think like us. Even workers.
It's what we say, not how we say it.
But I've no qualms if Hendrik stages our plays.
Why are you looking at me?
Am I not allowed to?
If it pleases you, go ahead.
Without you, I'll be finished, Barbara.
There's too much evil in me.
Alone, I'm too weak to overcome it,
but you could help me to fortify my good side.
I can't talk anymore.
So many thoughts are just parts I've played.
I love you, Barbara.
I'm in love. With a woman.
Juliette, am I a good looking man?
I've never seen you on stage.
Maybe you're handsome,
but frankly,
I've never found you good looking,
but sometimes your cold cheating eyes
are those of a sad child.
You do it well.
Who have you fallen for?
- A girl.
- Great!
You falling in love...
One day you may just learn how to walk,
not just dance.
Love the girl, Heinz,
and don't tell me anything about her.
- Do we keep in touch?
- Yes.
You know what? I'm coming with you.
I have nothing to lose, Heinz.
Are you crazy?
See a psychiatrist, Heinz.
Though I'm sure
you wouldn't dare talk about yourself.
Go, Heinz. We'll meet soon anyway...
even if you don't want to.
Excuse me grandmother, have you a moment?
- I'd like to introduce...
- Your fiancé.
I have to take a closer look
at my new grandson.
Not bad at all.
My mother send her apologies,
she will be here shortly.
I assume you know, my dear Höfgen,
that loving mothers rarely want
their only sons to leave the nest.
Good day, Sebastian.
That is Sebastian.
Mom.
Yes.
I'm pleased.
I'm really pleased.
Barbara, my dear child.
I'm Nicoletta von Niebuhr,
the adoptive daughter of the house,
the bride's best friend,
almost her sister.
Often, the bridegroom's mistress.
Only on stage, of course.
May I call you Aunt Bella?
But of course, Nicoletta.
Come Höfgen,
let us leave the ladies to themselves.
I'd like to show you my garden.
I'd love to see it.
Have you unsettling memories?
You know, Barbara, memories that give you the creeps
when you think about them?
When I was about twelve,
I got into our school choir.
I was overjoyed.
I thought I could sing better than the other boys.
We had to sing in church at some wedding.
I wanted to show off.
I was so proud of my soprano voice.
I had a great idea.
I sang one octave higher than the others.
As I stood there, proudly singing,
the music teacher looked at me
more in disgust than disapproval,
and he said softly,
"Just keep quiet."
Do you understand?
Softly and dryly he said,
"Just keep quiet."
When I felt I was singing like an angel.
Do you have such memories?
No.
You've never felt ashamed in your life.
I often have. That was the first time.
I often have to feel awfully ashamed of myself.
So ashamed, I could sink down into hell.
Do you understand me?
This is the basement room.
The window faces the street.
Here's a lamp post and here, too.
Behind it the bakery,
- with workers' wives lined up.
- Stop!
Prima!
Ms. Schult, you come up past the window.
Barbara, can you put a lamp post here,
with a light to dazzle the audience?
You come here and begin with the widow`s monologue:
"I'm widow Queck who hasn't paid the rent."
Barbara, we could have several more
lamp posts in the middle of the auditorium,
so people feel they're really in their filthy street.
We'll have posters, recent political slogans,
all jumbled up.
At the back, a grocer's shop,
with nothing to sell, of course.
Everything in the hall
must express what we talk about!
And two policemen can patrol the rows
and stare at the audience.
An end to passive watching,
actors and public isolated from each other.
The public must play an active part.
The days of the peepshow are over!
The actor with is text,
is only one element of the performance,
not it's focal point.
The hall, lights, walls, movements, sounds,
all must blend into a whole!
Only then shall we have real theater.
The workers need total theater!
One that shocks and arouses!
I am the widow Queck, who cannot pay the rent.
My husband died and I am a servant of the baker,
the owner of this house.
It's the only way I can feed
my seven hungry children.
Wait! Wait!
The half-hour has to be paid for.
At your orders,
we've been waiting half an hour.
Here reigns logic and hunger.
Yes, I already owe you 31 marks and 25 pfennigs.
I've had nothing.
In these last days, I couldn`t even...
Silly goose!
Sabotaging our work!
Do you think I don't know why?
Miklas or one of his damn party friends
has put you up to it!
- What do you want from me?
- Why don't you prompt her?!
Never mind! Revolutionary Theatre
can't be staged with provincials.
With amateurs, you can't create any sort of theatre.
Even revolutions need professionals!
I'll buy you a drink to celebrate
the failure of the Revolutionary Theater.
You're beside yourself with joy.
Good day.
Two stiff ones, Hansemann.
How about another rebellious evening?
I'd like to invite you to dinner.
What, me?
- Good morning.
- Morning.
You're still half asleep.
I'm awake.
I've even phoned our grocer,
he's a bit impatient over our large bill.
I'm sorry. I don't present a picture
of early morning freshness.
If I, too, went riding every morning,
I'd probably look more attractive.
But in our circles,
such noble sport is not customary.
The offended husband, as in Moliére.
Oh, be quiet!
It's not customary to sit all night
at a National Socialist thug's table.
- Miklas is not a thug.
- All National Socialists are thugs!
You must avoid their company.
Their dirt rubs off on you.
It`s a pity you can't understand.
It's your family's well known liberalism.
No political beliefs, just curiosity.
For you ideologies are psychological quirks.
I feel sorry for Miklas.
He gets small parts and earns very little.
You all treat him very badly.
He's at a loss, that's why he's with them.
So much understanding for that lousy brat.
How do you think they'd treat us
if they came to power?
God forbid!
And yet you sit and chat with him, Barbara.
It's your bourgeois tolerance.
This understanding of one's enemy.
I'm sure you could even excuse Fascist terrorism.
Your liberalism might even get used to dictatorship.
No, thank you.
May I remark, my love,
it's common practice to eat an egg
from its shell and with salt.
I know, in the Bruckner household
you eat it from a glass
with six spices, and that's very original,
but no need to make fun
of those unaccustomed to such originality.
- Who's juvenile lead in Halberstadt?
- Herbert Boltz.
Where's Ms. Türkheim-Gawernitz now?
Strangely in Heidelberg.
- And Hannelore Kühn.
- In Mannheim.
- And who's Othello there?
- Max Krause.
- And Iago?
- Johannes Fiedler.
- And Desdemona in Leipzig?
- Kathe Müttel.
Who's the ingénue in Jena?
A stupid cow called Lotte Lindenthal.
Why is Lotte Lindenthal a stupid cow?
I don't know, but she is.
I know why you insult her.
She's the friend of a National Socialist leader.
I'm only moderately interested
in the names and titles of her lovers.
Must be quite a long list...
Watch your tongue, Höfgen!
I don´t allow you insult a lady
because she's in the Nazi German worker's party,
and the friend of a German hero.
You won't stand for it?
My, my...
Stop it! You're drunk!
I'm not. On the contrary.
Apparently I'm the only one here
with a spark of honor left.
Nobody in this Jew-ridden business cares
if a lady is insulted!
Let go of me!
No!
- Hans, calm yourself.
- Leave me!
I'll gladly believe you're not drunk.
So you won't make that an excuse, then.
As for this Jew-ridden business you're in,
you won't suffer it much longer.
That I promise you.
Perhaps you're right.
I agree, the fellow's behavior was intolerable,
but I can't just fire a poor,
sick man like that.
Sick? He's not sick at all.
Why this indecision and compromise?
It's just like our government parties.
Excuse me, Barbara.
We must show this murderous pack
it can't get away with it.
I beg you, don't insist
that he be sacked on the spot.
It's punishment enough
that he won't be hired for the next season.
He has no idea what he said last night,
he just went wild.
I'm amazed, Otto.
I'm really amazed that you,
of all people, should say that.
I don't want him made a martyr.
- In the political situation...
- Excuse me if I interrupt.
This interesting but theoretical discussion is useless.
The case is simple, it`s him or me.
Either Miklas leaves the theater...
or I do.
Don`t say nonsense.
Don`t worry Höfgen, we will dismiss him.
Higher, higher!
Enough! This isn't a funeral march!
Again.
Lights!
Sorry to interrupt.
Dr. Kroge asks you to approve the poster
for the next premiere.
I must take it to the printer.
Can't I get my name spelled correctly
even in this theatre?
My name is not Henrik, but Hendrik!
Hendrik Höfgen.
One day they'll all have to mark my name.
Try to understand, Dr. Kroge.
I can't and won't tie myself down.
It's a great strain to stay under contract.
I must be free. Free!
I can't be a provincial matinee idol.
No, no, I don't want to be that.
You want to leave Hamburg for good?
I don't know yet.
The Professor invited me to a Berlin guest appearance.
One never knows.
By the way, Dora Martin will be my partner.
Good. Then accept the offer.
Thank you.
Berlin!
Thank you, ladies. Till tomorrow.
Goodbye.
So you are Höfgen.
You have friends here.
Some of them, who understand theater,
have recommended you.
Your father-in-law, too,
when we met at the ministry of culture.
And now also Dora Martin, as well.
In real life I may seem a bit nondescript,
but not, I hope, on stage.
My father-in-law once aptly described
my ability to transform myself.
Well, we'll give you a try.
Don't expect too much.
I'm not offering anything big.
You are probably used
to a reasonable income in Hamburg.
Here you'll have less.
Have you expensive tastes?
Money doesn't interest me.
My needs are modest.
All I need every day is a clean shirt
and a drop of cologne.
Discuss the details with Miss Bernhardt.
Please give my regards to your father-in-law.
- Hendrik Höfgen.
- Oh, yes. Bernhardt.
Here's your contract.
Thank you.
- May I?
- Please.
700 marks a month, less tax.
You agree to play as cast.
So...
Please give these flowers...
and this card to Ms. Martin.
Will you?
THANKS!
Well, Hendrik Höfgen.
Now you're a beginner again.
Hamburg's fame, routine and security
all lie behind you.
Now you must summon up all your strength.
And we'll work off that blubber.
- Who is that?
- Dora Martin's Hamburg actor lover.
- No, Miss Bernhardt's.
- You're misinformed, dear.
So glad you were able to come,
despite all your work.
May I introduce some of your admirers?
Mr. Davidson of the London Times.
Caser von Muck, Mr. Müller-Andrea.
Mind you aren't influenced by the prevailing
culture Bolshevism which reins in Kurfürstendamm.
What do you mean?
German culture can only be renewed
if it returns to its national roots,
to its essence of blood and soil.
Russian ravings or French farces
are alien to the spirit the nation needs.
Lenie!
Have you met Mr. Höfgen?
Berlin's new star,
according to tomorrow's London Times.
I've seen you on stage.
You danced, didn't you?
Yes, I like dancing.
I had a good teacher.
You`ve an outstanding head.
I'd like to model it.
No necktie and no gold we've got
We're just a very shabby lot
At which the bourgeois spits
The bourgeois with polished boots
And medals on morning suits
And every morning he ablutes
for church, or for the Ritz
Where does the bourgeois get it all?
His guns, his celebration ball?
He steals it where he can
He makes it hard for us to rob
Takes it all, the greedy slob
Exploits the poor and wrecks the job
of every working man
Oh, if so wealthy I could be,
Commit like him grand larceny
All honored since my birth
If then I met someone I knew,
You filthy lot, I'd spit at you
That's all you dogs are worth!
Out! Out of here!
You jewish pig!
- Go away!
- Alright!
They are completely drunk.
Now one of the most famous State Theater actors,
Hendrik Höfgen.
Forget State Theater and fame.
I am your comrade Hendrik Höfgen.
What does the proletariat want?
That nobody should rule!
Nobody shall give orders
Nobody shall be a slave
Freedom, equality for all souls
I'll dictate. Headline:
Actor Höfgen wins Berlin workers' hearts overnight.
New paragraph.
- Hendrik?
- Hello.
I went to an antique dealer in Woltersdorf.
I bought this picture at some other things.
- You don't mind?
- Why should I mind?
I going to change, then you can admire it.
I love you, Barbara.
Not only your father and grandmother.
I love you... I, Hendrik Höfgen.
Welcome to my home, my dear Sebastian.
Unfortunately, the theater awaits me,
but when I came back, we can talk...
The three of us!
Up!
Two!
Three!
Four!
Five!
Six!
Führer!
We are our people's strength!
We shall create a new world!
- What's your father's job?
- Road digger!
- And your father's?
- Farmer!
- And yours?
- Teacher. He educates us!
- And your father?
- Baker. He bakes our bread!
Mine's a miller. He grinds our grain!
A doctor. He makes us healthy!
Bricklayer. He builds our houses!
- Conductor!
- Electrician!
We are the sons of one people,
we all have the same goal!
Unity and strength!
We follow the Führer!
No. That's not convincing enough.
Say it like this...
We are the sons of one people,
we all have the same goal!
Unity and strength!
We follow the Führer!
- Again... one, two, three.
- Unity and strength!
Again!
Unity and strength!
- Louder! Again!
- Unity and strength!
We follow the Führer!
Blood is a very special juice...
let us in depths of sensuousness
assuage our burning passions.
No bounds and goals are set for you.
You find your pleasure.
A fleeing treasure.
May you enjoy the prize you get.
Help yourself and don't be coy.
But listen, it's not a question of joy.
To knowledge I'm devoted,
most painful gratification.
Most hateful love,
most vexing stimulation.
Believe me, who a thousand years
on this hard nourishment has fed.
That from cradle to the grave,
no human can digest so stale a bread.
Believe me, worlds celestial and infernal
for one divinity were made.
He exists in eternal light.
But us, into the darkness conveyed,
there's day and night alone.
Yet I want that!
That's well worth hearing.
But there's one thing I fear.
For time is short, but art is long.
If I thought you sought more teaching,
cultivate a poet fond of preaching.
Let his thoughts wander.
And every noble quality
upon your brow let him bestow,
the lion's courage,
the buck's swiftness.
The Italian's fiery blood,
the north's enduring pluck.
He'll teach you the secret vile
of magnanimity steeped in guile.
May his youthful drives uncover
to make of you an ardent lover.
I'd like to meet a scholar of such fame,
to Microcosm I'd change his name.
So what am I, if it's not possible
the paragon of humanity to attain,
towards all my senses strain?
You're in the end just what you are.
Put on the wigs of a million curls.
Put your feet in elevating socks.
You'll stay for ever what you are!
Bravo!
Wonderful!
You were fantastic, Hendrik.
You were born to play Mephisto.
You say that with a touch of malice, Dora.
Not true, I don't detest people
for what they are.
- Anyway, thank you for coming.
- Let's skip the cliches.
- What's your next project?
- I'm learning English.
English? Why?
- I'll be working in America.
- In America? But why?
Here the curtain's descending.
Haven't you noticed?
You're at the top here, hit after hit.
Thousands adore you. So why go?
The love of thousands!
Soon they'll be raving about others.
Dora, there'll always be theater,
no matter what happens in Germany.
No matter what happens in Germany?
You really mean that?
Well, all the best, Hendrik.
You`ll not see me for a long time.
I'm leaving in a few days.
In a few days?
I don't want to wait till it's too late.
But you'll always do well,
Hendrik Höfgen,
no matter what happens in Germany.
It's open.
Mephisto, I never lock the door.
Need neither bolts nor life insurance.
- I bet you've already made one.
- I need no life insurance.
Sit down, sir, in my new home.
You could have gotten me a nicer flat.
- Have you registered?
- Yes, sir.
What did the landlord say?
Nothing. He was drunk, humming a song...
"No neckties, no gold..."
He gave me the key and I moved in.
I've been longing to see you.
- And how's your wife?
- She's with her father, thank God.
They're worried about the Republic.
In Hamburg, the foreigners
were also very worried about Germany,
about German culture,
whose Number-One-Parrot you are.
As if a peril threatened it.
What are the Jews planning against Germany?
Everyone talks about them.
Even the whores wonder,
and they don't care about the pant color
as long as it has a fly.
Barbara understands politics, doesn't she?
Is she keeping an eye on you?
No. Mostly her opinions
are the opposite of mine.
- Have you told her so?
- No. What point would there be?
Words don't say everything.
I'd like very much to sleep with you.
Shall I make up the bed?
Yes!
Hendrik! Hendrik!
Hendrik, wake up! Get up!
You're here already?
I came on the early train,
because of you.
- What's the matter?
- When did you go to bed?
I'm tired. I was tossing all night.
Why?
The National Socialists have won the elections.
You know who became Chancellor?
No.
Do you hear that?
That Bohemian corporal has become Chancellor?
Here, read it!
I thought there was nothing to fear
from the National Socialists.
- Remember that business with Miklas?
- I don`t have friends between them.
That could have unpleasant consequences.
What do we do now?
Keep a clear mind and don't panic.
So, the Austrian clown has become Reichs-Chancellor.
But there still is the opposition, no?
Communists and Social Democrats.
They'll make sure
he doesn't get too big for his boots.
Perhaps there'll even be armed resistance.
And even if the National Socialists stay in power,
why should it concern me?
I'm from the Rhineland.
So are my parents.
What can happen to us?
On top of that, I'm an actor. No?
I go to the theater, play my parts and well,
then go back home. That's all!
But some people can see the consequences,
and are leaving the country,
where a career in the arts is now impossible.
People will think you don't care
about anything beyond the limelight?
There were elections in a democratic state.
One party won, that's all.
I've never been interested in politics,
so why now?
Don't you realize what's happening here?
Don't answer it. I'm not here, I'm sick!
Say what you want.
Hendrik, is that the solution?
To lock yourself in, to hide, not be at home?
To run!
To not answer the phone?
Is that all you can think of,
instead of taking a definite stand?
Definite? Definite?
This is my answer!
- No, I don`t accept that.
- Hamlet! Shakespeare!
Either we take a stand or go,
if our freedom is in danger!
This is the only form of freedom for me,
for an actor.
You can't hide behind Shakespeare,
on the stage!
Barbara, I'm an actor!
An actor in Germany at all times.
You can go away.
Your father is a famous writer.
You can design sets anywhere,
or buy antiques.
But I need the German language!
I need the motherland, don't you see?
- Who's there?
- Otto.
- Who?
- I must talk to you.
- You want some coffee?
- No, thanks.
- Tea?
Act with us again. It's the only reply
we can give to these events.
An appearance by all of us,
a common front.
So we don't lose our future.
You just want to divide the audience?
We must work out our tactics.
Tactics will force us to our knees.
We must fight this crushing demagogy.
It's our job to tell the hesitators:
Now is the time to resist dictatorship!
Otto, in the first place, we're actors...
No, not a protest on the street.
I'm talking about the stage.
Still, I think we should wait a few days.
We must do something immediately.
Tonight.
Otto, I'd rather stay with the reserves.
Thank God I've no performance today.
GERMAN REICHS-MAIL
Film contract, locations in Budapest...
leading role.
Production Manager Altenburger.
She really is a beauty.
She's sitting by the side altar.
Cut! Very good.
The second one.
Now the scene where the officials
follow her to the Fishermen's Bastion.
What it is?
What's going on?
Are we done for today?
Can we go home?
- The Reichstag was burned down!
- What?
They say the communists set fire to it.
Your wife wants you to join her in Paris.
She didn't dare phone you from Berlin.
Don't go back to Berlin.
I`m moving to Vienna myself.
Many of your Berlin friends have vanished lately.
Otto Ulrichs is one.
We must be prepared for anything.
I fear we'll never be able to return.
For years the Nazis have blacklists.
The Professor, his father-in-law,
your wife and you are on them.
Please, never go back to Berlin.
Hendrik, promise me that.
Please!
Cheers, and a thousand thanks!
- Cheers!
- I make the toast with water.
To the most beautiful actress in Europe!
When are you going home?
I'll stay a few more days in Budapest.
It´s a beautiful city.
Then I'm going to see
about a contract in Vienna.
I understand you, Hendrik.
I'll tell you now,
I'm not going back to Germany, either.
I signed you for this part,
so you, too, could slip away,
if you want to.
The film studio gave me
your address in Budapest.
I hope my letter reaches you.
I'm in Berlin now.
I've landed a part in a comedy.
During the shoot I met the actress
Lotte Lindenthal.
She's friendly with a National Socialist
officer pilot who's very powerful now.
She's wonderful.
She never flaunts what great influence she has.
I told her you were abroad and didn't dare return,
for certain reasons.
"What's the man afraid of?", she said,
"He is an eminent artist."
She said she saw Mephisto several times.
"We need such actors", she said,
and she promised to speak to her friend.
This morning she said:
"No matter what silly things Höfgen has done,
when it's an eminent actor,
they are tolerant."
Her friend has promised
that nothing will happen to you if you return.
Hendrik, Berlin awaits you.
You have nothing to fear.
No one can replace you in the the theater.
I know that and also those who rule now our lives.
The theater is a shelter for me
and people like me,
in which we all feel safe
and have nothing to fear.
It would be that for you, too, Hendrik.
Theater is a mission.
In true friendship, yours,
Angelika Siebert.
Name?
- Hendrik Höfgen.
- Profession?
Actor.
Where?
At the State Theater in Berlin.
- Is something wrong?
- No, no.
Please.
Thank you.
I don't know if you'll feel
at home again here, Höfgen.
The spirit is different
from that you were accustomed to.
Cultural Bolshevism is over.
There will no longer be a chance
to perform your friend's plays,
or those popular French farces
you like so much.
We perform German art now.
Frankly, I saw no great reason
to recall you from abroad.
But Lotte Lindenthal wants you as her partner
in her comedy debut here.
I didn't want to displease her.
The role of elegant friend and seducer
shouldn't cause you any difficulty.
I'm so cold.
I'll warm you up.
Your room isn't heated
in this dreadful weather?
Is this how you anticipated my visit?
Very nice of you!
There's a warm room over there.
Come.
No, I'm in a great hurry today.
It would warm us up.
No, there's no point in this cold flat.
My new maid doesn't know her duties yet.
You should have told her
your visitor needed warmth.
But I've only just returned home.
You should have returned earlier!
I knew you`d come.
I'm someone you must wait for, impatiently.
If I want to meet someone in passing,
I have my husband. And besides...
Where did you get this new maid?
She's far too pretty!
It's an honor to act with you.
It's so nice to hear a warm voice again.
I'm happy to hear you say that,
I know you're no flatterer.
Me, a flatterer?
I'm notorious for telling people the truth.
I like honest people.
If she turns, everything will be fine.
If she waves, I've scored a triumph.
I`ve live 10 years in Hamburg.
After the Reichstag fire, I had to leave the theatre.
Bonetti went in uniform to the essay.
Before being fire,
he threw me out of the canteen.
He said:
"We've got you now, Böck. Out!"
They almost beat me up,
my landlady threw me out.
I had to leave Hamburg.
Are you upset that I've come?
When I heard you were in Berlin,
I found new hope and I thought:
"Maybe God will help me."
So, I just came.
- Are you angry with me?
- I'm not angry with you, Böck.
Live here till things settle down,
but don't tell anyone.
Just simply disappear without a word.
You know, if I were in your position,
I might well commit suicide.
I'll buy you a radio,
so you'll know what's happening outside.
Don`t leave here
and don`t speak with neighbors.
I've got nobody else in the world but you.
- Is Budapest beautiful?
- I don't know!
Yes, quite nice.
I could have gone there.
Barbara wasn't with you.
They wouldn't have let you cross the border.
I'm a German citizen, too. My father was pure German.
Why can't I go out?
If you can't understand why,
we'll both be in trouble.
You're horrible!
You look like a caretaker!
- You're an idiot!
- Go to hell you... you actor!
Dear Lotte, may I ask a great favor?
I have to play Mephisto. I have.
I'll see what I can do.
I look forward to seeing you again as Mephisto.
Between us, it's thanks to me
you'll be playing Mephisto again.
Certain ministerial circles feared
you might revive your old Faust spirit.
The spirit of cultural Bolshevism,
as it was called.
Well, I succeeded in overcoming those fears.
Cesar, thank you, thank you very much.
THANK YOU!
Please give these flowers...
to Miss Lindenthal.
Ready.
- Good morning!
- Good morning.
Morning, Mr. Höfgen.
Mr. Miklas!
Are you still around?
- Morning.
- Fine.
I've only been here a short space,
I come with a humility to this place...
to find a teacher of vocation
who's held by all in veneration.
How pleasant is your courtesy,
but I`m a common man.
Have you looked around?
Take me as your student.
I come with courage and my young blood.
My mother tried to stop me.
I want to study with all my heart.
You've come to the right place.
I feel like going home I fear.
In that great hall
I won't like it at all.
You see no grass, you see no trees.
And in the classes we are taught,
I lose my hearing, sight and thought.
It all depends on habit.
Seeing the breast,
a child might accept the gift unwillingly.
But soon it sucks in delight.
So will you, on wisdom's breast,
enjoy it daily with more zest.
Around her neck I'll cling with pleasure,
but tell me how can I find this treasure?
When you continue on your way,
which faculty will make your day?
Is this where the cut comes?
The art of medicine is not hard, you know.
You study the world, big and small.
And in the end you let them go
when God demands it.
You'll try in vain to learn all science.
Each man just learns what he can.
But he who grasps every chance,
he is the worthy man.
You are still of pleasing build,
with self-confidence at last instilled,
others will have confidence in you.
Especially learn the women to enthrall.
Eternal moans, a thousand ills.
There's just one place to cure them.
If you've honor to some degree,
one may allow some shared intimacy.
A title helps to make her certain
your art exceeds that of your peers.
And may grant you a glimpse of which
another schemes for many years.
Her pulse you must learn to feel.
And burning looks you then must steal.
Her slender hips are then embraced,
to see how tightly she is laced.
That's what I could care for.
Gray, my friend is all theory.
And green the golden tree of life.
That's the way.
I greet the learned gentleman!
You made me to sweat profusely.
- What is your name?
- The question's odd,
for someone who idle talk despises.
Who, far removed from worldly show
seeks only academic prizes.
With you, one knows your game
generally by your very name.
It's evident, Sire, if one's called a liar.
Who are you?
I'm a part of that force
that always craves evil
and always creates good.
What is this riddle?
I'm the spirit who negates.
And rightly so, for all creation
is worthy of annihilation.
So it were better nothing were created.
And so everything you've stated
is sin, destruction, devilment.
Remains my actual element.
Good evening, Herr Höfgen.
The Prime Minister invites you to his box.
Yes.
It's all going like clockwork.
May I introduce you
to my distinguished colleague Hendrik Höfgen?
Ah, our Mephistoles.
Congratulations.
That mask is perfect, it's evil itself.
It's sacred evil.
Yet, your eyes are so kind,
your handshake so soft. It's strange...
it seems the secret of acting is to portray strength,
yet one is weak.
I imagine you've prepared for this role
for a long time.
All my life, Prime Minister.
That's the only way.
That is the secret of greatness.
Good luck.
Carry on the good work, Mephistoles.
Höfgen residence.
Lotte Lindenthal!
- Höfgen.
- Hendrik?
- What`ll do after tonight's performance?
- Nothing.
Would you like to come afterwards?
There'll be just a few friends here.
With pleasure.
Yes, thank you.
- See you then. Bye.
- Thank you.
Böck! Just a few friends will be there,
just a few!
Am I not an incredible villain?
Why a villain?
You're just successful, Mr. Höfgen.
To the renewal of German culture,
ladies and gentlemen.
Long live the actors.
Long live! Long live! Long live!
Our theater has many elements
that have nothing to do with Germany.
We must set up a customs control of the mind
for culture smugglers...
to stop foreign elements poisoning
German literature and theater.
This can't be left entirely
to our frontier guards.
Everyone must cooperate in this control.
- Am I understood?
- Yes, General.
There are many who don't understand.
Look at this painting, my Mephisto.
A masterpiece of German romanticism.
Where did I find it?
At an art dealer with an foreign accent.
I had it restored.
No, no...
the future of painting
doesn't belong to the Liebermanns.
Your Mephisto occupies my mind.
You've brought him alive.
He's a hell of a guy.
Isn't there a little of him in all of us?
I mean, isn't there a bit of Mephisto
in every German?
Wouldn't our enemies love it
if we had nothing but the soul of Faust?
No, Mephisto is also a German national hero.
It's just something we mustn't tell people.
I must go now.
Come to my office at 10:30,
the day after tomorrow.
I`m expecting some foreign journalists.
French, english, americans.
They want to know what 'Germany' means today,
above all the German culture.
I'll tell them. You can elaborate
on what I say about theater, for example.
About painting, architecture, sculpture,
they`ll have plenty to write about.
I want them to be informed by experts.
Tell me, why do you have
such a limp handshake?
Good day.
So, we meet again. How time flies!
You were wonderful as Mephisto.
Now you act him more forcefully.
But I liked the other one, too.
I sensed it in the seed of what
can now be unfolded to the full.
I also liked you in the play
with Lotte Lindenthal.
Lotte Lindenthal is the ideal actress
to portray the ideal German woman.
What are we doing here?
Why is he wasting his time with foreigners?
Do you know what it is?
He said they're interested in German culture.
They'll ask a few questions.
- I see. You spoke to him?
- Yes.
How are you?
Nice to meet you again.
The Prime Minister sent for me.
I hope this doesn't last too long.
Always problems with the old statues.
Shall we tear them down or not?
As if that were important for our future.
I'd like to sculpt a bust of you, Höfgen.
What sort of man are you?
Your own face differs amazingly from Mephisto.
In private you don`t look devilish,
but rather shy.
I'll do a bust of you,
but in clay or in bronze?
- What is your face made of?
- Perhaps a mixture.
I very much enjoyed your Mephisto.
I only had eyes for you.
I'm preparing an exhibition.
The General wants a preview.
Try to come.
- Here's my number.
- Thank you.
If you have time,
give me a ring and come to my studio.
You can relax while I model you.
How strange your face is.
A German face yet it changes every moment.
That's acting.
The rest is humility and hard work.
I've discovered your secret, Mephisto.
It's the surprise effect, right?
The unexpected.
I've been watching the way you appear on stage.
Always different.
Sometimes quick, erratic.
Then slow, suddenly,
when the audience is lulled.
But always surprising and unpredictable.
Thus you create the feeling of something original,
even if the spectator knows your lines by heart.
That is you secret.
And your glib tongue,
your deliberate pauses, your precise emphasis.
I think I'm learning from you.
It's important to be unpredictable.
The spectators needn't know
what my next step is or where I'm going.
- They're not prepared and can`t defend themselves.
- Exactly.
Yet it was only a change of pace,
or a slightly longer pause.
In the theater it's the others
who make the king a king.
Building the role is all important;
pianissimo alternating with fortissimo.
Naturally, you need a certain flair,
artistic talent,
and as I usually say,
a high degree of culture.
When I hear the word culture,
I reach for my revolver.
Bourgeois nonsense!
Bolsheviks preach it to win over school teachers.
To say nothing of artists.
Isn't that so?
I wasn't untouched by Bolshevik trends, either.
And I must admit that for a while
I flirted with the left.
Well, anyone can get involved in some folly.
Those were troubled times.
Let's have a drink.
General, other deserving artists
committed the follies I did.
I can't forget those paying for sins
for which I've been generously pardoned.
I'm pleading for a certain person,
for a friend.
I guarantee he's reformed.
General, I'm pleading for Otto Ulrichs.
Otto Ulrichs? Who's he?
He ran the communist cabaret,
'The Storm-Bird'.
Well... he must be a pretty bad fellow.
No, he's not bad.
A bit rash, I admit.
A bit thoughtless, but not bad.
If anything, he's too decent.
Once he gives his word, he keeps it.
I'm back at the State Theater!
The funny thing is,
I simply can't believe it.
Just as I can't believe
I'm here with you by the window.
I know it's reality, but I don't feel it.
- Great art.
- Magnificent, really.
A German work of art.
Not every German artist is capable of such work.
It is a courageous work.
Come, Mephisto.
You sign, too.
What did I prophesy?
The exhibition is a success.
Thank you very much.
You rascal, so you make secret visits here.
If I may add something personal,
it is a courageous work.
Courageous, because it captures our time,
the beauty of strength without bourgeois snobbery.
Contrasting the degenerate taste
of the loud-mouths of culture.
We see muscles and clear-cut features
mankind wants to see.
Strong and beautiful in his strength.
Warrior-like and victorious in his struggle.
Good day Hendrik Höfgen.
- That was a wonderful speech.
- Nicoletta! You`re here?
- You know each other?
- Very well!
You're in Berlin? Since when?
I'm only here because I want to dine with you.
I haven't seen you for so long,
but I read all about you.
So where will we go?
Your choice. How's Hamburg?
Surviving without me?
I'm in Berlin to have dinner with you.
Hamburg is history.
You're out of touch.
Kroge's in Switzerland. He just vanished.
Didn't even tell his girl. Simply went.
Kroge is a traitor.
Why must you appear with them?
Because they asked me to.
They ask others, too. You needn't go.
You can't refuse, none of us can.
If anyone says they do, they're lying!
Besides, the General's a nice chap
and he knows a lot about the theater.
He's not so closed minded as most others.
A well behaved boy who wants to enjoy
the rewards for good behavior.
- Yes, I like to be well behaved.
- Because you're afraid.
- I like it.
- Then you should.
It will be difficult to stay with me
and maintain good behavior.
Damned black woman, right?
I can't help being different
from what's allowed here.
And is visible.
People can spit in my face in the street.
Even if I wanted,
I can't do anything about it.
My nose, my hair remain the same
even if I`m ashame.
Yet, I'm German, a German Negro.
German is my mother tongue.
What am I supposed to do?
Where should I go?
I don't know.
I don't even know what will become of me.
You think only of yourself!
And like an idiot,
I dreamt of us having a child!
- That's all we need.
- Why?
Is the child to be to blame,
for she might ruin her father's career?
That's enough now!
- Now it`s enough!
- Now it`s enough?
Enough...
I can see why your wife
couldn't stand living with you.
Here... I pinched a photo of you once.
Look at it!
Do you recognize yourself?
Hello, I must speak to you.
To tell me what you've said behind my back?
I don't know what you mean.
Hendrik Höfgen has no scruples.
Didn't you say that?
I won't dispute that I dislike you.
- What do you want?
- I want you to sign this.
My signature? What for?
You want a raise?
Or do you collect signatures
because theater safety regulations
are a bit unsafe?
From a moral standpoint much seems unsafe.
And I don't mean the theater.
What do you protest against?
Against a leadership that disregards our rights.
But you are in the Nazi party,
since back when you were in Hamburg.
I'm leaving the party.
That's your business.
I'd like to ask you to read our protest
and sign it.
Regardless of my opinion,
you are today's leading German actor.
Let me say that I won't even read this thing.
Be careful not to get yourself and others
into real trouble.
Miklas, you can go to hell.
I won't let a dirty pig like you provoke me.
Dear God!
Congratulations, my dear Höfgen!
You put it precisely.
There are some you only can send them to hell.
If you were a soldier, I'd promote you.
I'm very pleased.
By the way, you needn't be afraid.
For the fun of it, I checked your horoscope.
It's excellent.
- Best of luck, Höfgen.
- Thank you.
Did something happen?
Good morning.
Quick!
Start walking!
We regret to inform the colleagues that the actor
Hans Miklas has died in a car accident.
How awful, such a young fellow.
But, frankly,
there was something disquieting about him,
don't you think, Hendrik?
Disquieting...
That was no car accident.
He must have come to you, too,
with that protest.
Are you insane?
How can you talk such nonsense?
Why shouldn't it have been a car accident?
Do you think the government
would stage a car accident,
all for some unknown actor?
We're not in some tenth-rate melodrama.
People shouldn't cross roads in heavy traffic.
I've great plans for you.
You can refuse and remain an actor.
But then you can't do
as much for our cause as you could.
Your speech was good.
I realized you're not only an actor.
You put the essence into words.
Write your own biography, Hendrik.
Submit it to me, as soon as possible.
Höfgen...
you will manage the Prussian State Theater.
Your task is easy:
A full house and a wildly enthusiastic
audience for you.
Do you understand?
No need to enlarge upon your past in Hamburg.
Nor need we mention the Revolutionary Theater.
Just mention some of your roles there.
What did you really imagine in Hamburg?
How could you have conceived...
promoting Russian Bolshevism?
You, a German. Incredible!
- Where is your wife now?
- In Paris, I believe.
No, she's in Amsterdam,
working against her Motherland.
They're publishing a newspaper.
You don't correspond with her?
We have no contact at all.
You'll get a divorce easily.
I'll see to that.
German citizens who have left Germany
couldn't wipe us out,
so they signed their own death sentence.
Where weakness perishes,
humanity becomes healthy.
Politics, like theater, is a fight.
Just as every rebuild is the start of a new war.
But we're not talking about this now.
Hamburg...
In a harbor town by the river...
Lots of foreigners, night clubs, bars.
I understand you perfectly.
But in the Reich's capital?
No offense, we're men, but...
What's this Hamburg souvenir doing here?
Juliette Martens.
Is she kept by you?
You once, rightfully, said...
"Professor Bruckner
was not a man of the future."
And, even more rightly,
you parted from his daughter.
If you have such a good instinct for a healthy,
clean attitude...
what's this Negro-woman doing in Berlin?
Mephisto...
it defies racial purity.
Don't even keep her picture at home.
General...
Wait, I haven't finished.
I hope you completely understood me.
- Yes.
- So?
- She's not to come to any harm.
- Leave that to me.
I'd like to request, Prime Minister,
that she'd be allowed to leave Germany unharmed.
Agreed.
She'll be taken to the frontier and good-bye.
Forget this part of our conversation.
You'll hold a press conference,
giving information about the theater.
The repertoire, plans and your performances.
In October there'll be a big cultural event
in our Paris embassy.
I'd like you to attend it.
Böck!
I bet they know about him, too.
Böck! Böck! My note-book.
Böck stays.
- Here it is.
- Give it to me.
I have to call friends.
I urgently need a friend.
- Find me a friend.
- But you've so many friends.
Friends...
Call Miss Nicoletta von Niebuhr.
Find the number and call her.
Shall I make coffee, or tea?
Shall I become manager?
Yes or no?
Can I? May I? Must I?
Is it my duty?
Can I make myself useful?
I mean, can I help anyone?
And if so, should I?
Or shall I look at it as a new role?
Or shall I emigrate to America?
I can earn as much in films as Dora Martin.
If I accept such an office of this government,
then...
Do I want to, at all?
They need me.
I was about to emigrate,
and now the Prussian Minister
asks me to rescue his theater.
Tomorrow morning I must give him an answer.
Heaven evidently has great plans for me.
Then you've won.
Would you help me?
I'd be proud of you.
Yes, I'll help you, Hendrik.
If only one could live for ever.
Here's your passport for France.
You have five minutes to pack.
Yes, but why?
We're waiting. Hurry up.
You needn't thank me for this raise.
I made it a condition for taking over this job.
Everything's covered with dust!
If you don't clean the dressing rooms
as well as all the others,
you may have to look for another job,
outside the Prussian State Theater.
I hope we'll get along.
If you have any problems, come to me.
I would like to treat you all to coffee.
Allow me to give you the money.
I'm sorry I can't come with you.
Mr. Joachim would like to speak to you.
Send him in.
Wait, Hannelore!
So, now he can enter.
Please, consider decent roles for me.
With you I can talk.
You're not like the other managers.
You're an actor yourself.
You understand.
I must act as if he's saying something important.
When you talk to actors, you must put them at ease.
That goes for me, too.
No, I don't like Premieres.
All night one has to wear a big, frozen smile.
I hate that!
You think it's a good costume?
I don't! I think it's terrible!
Good morning, Mr. Kappelmüller.
How are you?
- Good.
- How's the family?
So your daughter graduated as a hairdresser.
Maybe we can use her.
See you later. Continue.
Good morning!
Haven't you noticed?
New suit, new shoes, new manager, no? Well.
"Ex-Bolshevik Höfgen,
manager of the Prussian State Theater,
is letting his former comrade
appear in his production of Hamlet."
Hannelore?
Has the cast list for Hamlet already been posted?
Not yet.
Good. Let's wait another two days.
Thank you.
I must offer them more than old comrades.
You must cultivate connections.
That's the essence of the system.
Let me tell you,
yesterday I went to the Prussian State Theater,
it was Faust and the name
of some white-faced clown was Mephisto.
What a joke!
And Mephisto by some man called Höfgen, it was terrible!
I'd rather go to the Bavarian People's Theater.
Goodbye then.
Why am I doing all this?
Because I enjoy it.
I must enjoy amateur plays
and use actors that are blonde, not talented.
Most are totally untalented.
A Frankfurt audience applauded Marquis Posa's
'Give us freedom of thought'.
Performance stopped, play withdrawn.
In Munich, 'The Robbers', withdrawn.
Schiller, our national poet!
They want to produce plays by German authors.
But what authors?
Those who haven't emigrated
aren't allowed to write, or won't.
It's simply impossible
to offer theater worthy of the name.
Unless I dig up a couple of old farces.
All Rococco wigs and white faces.
The joke is that the regime
now sees Shakespeare as one of our own.
Let's do 'As You Like It',
'Where the Banished Return.'
Show the opponents of dictatorship
that the will for freedom still lives.
I didn't hear that!
I can't possibly have heard that!
Am I not an incredible villain?
Isn't what I'm doing insane?
"Fürst and Niklisch,
both on the staff of your theater,
on grounds of German racial purity...
dismiss them."
- Good morning.
- Well, how are you?
- Fine.
- And you?
- Everything all right.
- I don`t want to interrupt.
- See you later.
The stage-hands that are concerned,
Fürst and Niklisch...
are indispensable...
and the loss of their services...
would jeopardize the theater's work.
Date. Heil! Signature.
Germans!
Don't tolerate Nazi oppression!
Embassy of the German Reich
Did you bring me anything from Germany?
A leather coat, at least?
- A leather coat?
- Yes.
Those who took me to the frontier had them.
It's the fashion for men.
Your eyes are so dead,
how do they look?
- Empty?
- No, dazed.
Yes, that's how I felt these past days.
You see? You were never like that.
I've thought a lot about you.
I believe I should be grateful.
Without you, I'd be in a concentration camp,
or already dead.
If you still like being with me,
then stay here.
I'll look after you.
You needn't leave the house, not at first.
Then I`ll find you a job.
You're so gifted.
- I could have gone to America.
- There you go.
Yes, I think I am gifted.
But also a terrible coward.
What do I do elsewhere?
Be an extra, a stage-hand, a technician?
Do you think these hands
were made for manual labor?
I'll provide for you.
What else do you want?
Success.
Hendrik Höfgen, just imagine...
you'd belong to me.
Juliette, I have to go now.
- Shall I see you again?
- I don't know.
- Can I see you off at the station?
- No, you don't fit into the picture.
All right, forget the station.
Just do what you want.
I do.
That's why I'm here.
Juliette, don't write anymore.
It's no good.
There aren't many people in this café.
Would you prefer to sit in the sun?
You like that.
No. Though I haven't had much sunshine lately.
May I ask you something?
Do you still live alone?
No, I've got friends. And you?
Friends? In times like these?
It's difficult.
How can you still live in Berlin?
You know what`s going on.
- What keeps you there?
- Barbara, I live in the theater.
And that is in Berlin?
I don't think you can judge from Paris.
You're more than an actor now.
You took an oath. You're a manager.
I didn't take the oath,
I just moved my lips.
Someone has to save our values
for a better world.
I'm playing Hamlet,
whether those in power like Shakespeare or not.
Shakespeare is their ornament to prove
"we're not as bad as you think."
You can't stay in Berlin.
I have a family in Berlin.
You know I'm married to the theater.
I can help people who are having a hard time.
If I leave, nothing better will replace me.
Words!
It's always the same with you.
Your method of self-deception is still intact.
Don't you see? Whoever you save,
it's only a gesture to your friends.
You're a show-case.
By legalizing those people, you participate.
You`ll never get rid of the guilt.
We can't choose when and where we're born.
An entire people can't emigrate.
As an actor I'm obliged to live in my country,
to observe and portray it.
And I can tell you,
there are decent people among them.
I hate coffee shop intellectuals
and I hate such resistance-fighters, too.
The really valuable,
such as theater and art can rise above everything.
That's my conviction.
Why did you want to meet me?
Well, I don't really know why.
It might even be dangerous for you.
Tell me, Barbara, did you ever...
really love me?
Why did I come here today?
If you'd been listening, you wouldn't ask that.
If you don't accept what's happening in Germany,
why do you still live there?
What does freedom mean for you?
Do you need it to live?
Or do you just need to be successful and loved?
I'm satisfied with success.
It means many love me.
And the fury of the envious does me good.
Babara, don't make me responsible
for the impotence of your friends.
- Mr. Höfgen.
- Mr. Davidson, this is a surprise!
The check...
L'addition, s'il vous plait.
Have I come too early?
Farewell, Barbara.
May I pay?
What could I do here?
Freedom...
What for?
Oberon and Titania!
Congratulations!
I greet our wonderful and truly tantalizing
German bride and groom.
Two young, yet mature people,
of purest race and noblest blood,
who have enchanted us
and who serve our new society!
- Thank you very much.
- All the best.
Thank you.
Marietta, what joy!
Thank you all!
General, nice of you to come.
They can say what they want.
For me, the world is Grünewald!
Thank you for coming.
I'll remain a German artist and patriot,
no matter who may rule my land.
Grünewald is my favorite place,
and what other country brews such good beer?
Cesar!
- Thank you for coming.
- Sic itur ad astra
You can hold your rehearsals in this villa, Hendrik.
We're very proud of the way
you spoke in Paris.
The way you simply answered
all the questions...
and said quite frankly and honestly
what it's like here.
Carry on dancing.
Good evening.
Now, that's a surprise!
I won't say no to that.
- Congratulations, my Mephisto!
- Thank you.
Now, as old Admiral Tirpitz said:
"Target sighted! Full speed ahead!"
I'm looking forward to your Hamlet, my Mephisto.
Me too.
Your interview in Paris
made a good impression on all of us.
My dear.
Congratulations!
And lots of healthy German boys!
Thank you.
Madam?
Beautiful.
Yes, very much to my taste.
Very lovely.
Thank you, Madam.
Cheers!
We have no working hours, just work.
I'm sorry, I must go now.
Be happy together... Hamlet.
Nicoletta, lately I've been wondering
whether we actually deserve all this.
If I'm forced to answer,
then I must say "Yes."
If not we,
who represent individuality and art...
who else should, can and must rise
above all that happens in the world?
That's why we're an example
and encouragement to others.
No matter how filthy the world is,
true art always remains pure and true,
doesn't it?
I'm married to the theater.
And so are you.
I try to call Otto Ulrichs about the raise
and to sign the contract,
but I didn`t find him.
I sent a messenger to his flat,
but he was told that two men
took him away two days ago.
Call the Prime Minister and connect me with him.
If he's not there,
ask for an appointment as soon as possible.
- Hello?
- Give it to me.
Höfgen.
Yes, I`ll would like to talk
with the Prime Minister.
Good day.
- Good day.
- Do come in.
Good day.
Well, what's going on?
Excellency, recently you helped me,
on behalf of a colleague.
Now I have to ask again for help.
The thing is...
Otto Ulrichs was taken from his apartment
a few days ago.
- Is this why you've come?
- Yes, Excellency.
I'm fed up with you, Höfgen.
These matters are outside your competence.
Keep your nose out of this affair.
I'll give you some good advice:
Stop meddling.
You'd do better minding your own business,
so you won't get crushed like a bug!
Think you matter?
Ulrichs was involved in dirty work.
My State Theater manager ought not show
such interest in a traitor.
Now go.
I told you to go.
Get out, actor!
I know how much I and the theater
owe to the General.
I also know that to a great extent
we owe it to you.
Dear Lotte, that's why I ask you
to intervene for Otto Ulrichs.
- I'm so worried.
- Worried? But he's dead.
Didn't you know?
As far as I know, he committed suicide.
Suicide.
He knew the risks he ran.
I think he's more to be envied.
The Prince of Denmark renounces rank,
youth and love.
He is the savior of the North.
The lonely knight with lofty ideals,
the ideal of purity of blood and race.
Hamlet is a complex character, too.
A great and simple man.
Despite repeating myself so soon:
He is a nordic man.
He kills.
And in his self-destructing battle...
he shows us the way to the future.
He commands us to lead a pure life.
That is his bequest to us today.
He is not weak,
yet actors have often portrayed him as neurotic,
a pathological revolutionary,
thus as a decadent type.
I disagree.
Hamlet is a hard man.
You will see him as an energetic,
resolute hero.
He is also a hazard for the Germans.
We constantly analyze too much.
For the hour demands actions,
not only thoughts.
Least of all corruptive reflection.
Hamlet is the tragic conflict
between action and inaction.
Between hesitating, thinking and doing.
And we, the bearers of German culture,
know what to make of that.
Hamlet is a populist drama.
Neither religious, nor aristocratic, nor bourgeois,
but a work like the Greek tragedies.
So we'll abolish the barrier between audience and actor.
Space, light, movements, sounds are everything,
and even the spectators merge into one great,
common effect.
We must bring about total theater.
A theater that shocks and mobilizes.
It has cost 60,000 marks
to decorate the theater for tonight,
and it will be closed for 5 days.
A nice birthday party!
And we have to participate in this circus.
- Good evening.
Good night, Director.
The only place you will find
a party like this is in Berlin.
Very kind.
Good night.
Dearest Bella, we haven't met in ages!
Are you well?
No homesickness from Ulm?
I'm sure you're fantastically well
and your great son is flourishing.
- Dear Höfgen, how are you?
- Very well, thank you.
- How is the party going?
- People seem to enjoy it.
Your Hamlet was magnificent.
The boss was quite taken.
After the premiere
he spoke only of you and the theater.
I envy you.
Success is strange.
Sometimes you have it, sometimes not.
No, dear Höfgen, you give people something,
you create.
Believe me.
Here they come!
- How are you, Mephisto?
- Very well, Your Excellency.
I haven't told you,
how wonderful your Hamlet was.
I'm very glad.
Allow me to say a few words.
Mr. Prime Minister, Madam,
ladies and gentlemen.
We are proud to be able to celebrate this day
with you in this theater.
Since I have the honor
of greeting you on behalf of everyone present,
I salute the statesman and soldier,
friend and generous patron of the arts.
We admire him as our role model,
love him as our friend,
obey him as our master,
for without patrons,
art is a bird with broken wings.
As the poet says:
"May the gods protect you
and may the heart of Rome beat for your aims."
The Prime Minister wishes to speak to you, herr Höfgen.
He`s waiting in his car. Follow me.
You alone.
Nicoletta will take you home.
I won't be long.
Well, Mephisto,
what power is looking down on you here.
Do you feel it?
This is theater! Look at this arena.
It's almost ready. Wonderful, isn't it?
This is where I'd stage a performance.
Don't blink, Hendrik, look history in the eye.
What an echo!
Hendrik Höfgen!
We shall rule Europe and the world.
A thousand-year Reich!
Hendrik Höfgen!
Go! Get going!
Into the middle!
Hendrik...
Höfgen!
Well, how do you enjoy this limelight?
This is the real light, isn't it?
What do they want of me?
What?
I'm only an actor.