I'll give my heart just to one man
The greatest love since time began
He'll come my way and he'll be strong
And he will sing me love's sweet song
- What happened, Mr. Höfgen?
- What do you want?
I don't need you now!
Go to hell!
We're invited to a boring banquet.
Sorry, but we have to leave now.
Can't you sit with us, Dora?
No, we're much too late.
Sorry, good evening.
I wanted to say you were
marvelous tonight.
It was fantastic. Thank God I saw it.
You fraud, you didn't see the show.
Never mind, you're talented.
Me? Talented? Say it louder.
Yes, you're very talented,
Herr Höfgen.
I'm sure you'll soon be able to show
just how talented you are.
I must be going, goodbye.
- Böck. Seven marks.
- But Hendrik...
...if you need money
I can lend you fifty marks.
This is men's business.
Böck likes giving money.
Good evening, Miklas.
Thank you.
So...
...Doctor Kroge lets me starve.
Höfgen, you old sinner!
Take a seat.
Well, Director,
how'd you like the show?
What's getting you down, Hendrik?
That I'm a provincial actor.
Is that all? Nothing else?
Hello.
You're late.
One day, I'll come to fetch you.
Don't you dread that, Heinz?
- Please don't call me Heinz.
- Why not? That's your name.
I dislike it. Understand?
Perfectly, Heinz.
You can't even drink a beer like
a man who feels like drinking one.
Shall we start?
What was that about beer?
It's not your style,
simply to call for a beer.
"A beer, please" sounds
phony when you say it.
I don't drink, Juliette.
I know, Heinz. Take your shoes off.
Come on...
One, two...
...one, two, three, four...
On one...
Don't fall down now.
Faster!
Show me what you can do.
You want to be an actor
and show off for money, too?
You comical picture of misery.
If you liked this music,
you wouldn't get tired.
You always laugh at me, Juliette.
I can't cry. Would you
love me if I could cry?
I love you anyway.
You only love yourself, Heinz,
and even then not enough.
Keep talking.
What you say is very nice.
Your only concern is your face
being devoid of human expression.
It's a mask, you hear?
I, too, have skin and bones
and body weight...
...and eyebrows and fingernails,
just like you.
I, too, feel the cold.
I can be hungry and thirsty.
I, too, think of my mother.
And I know there are
Philistines and Communists.
But my eyes are not my eyes.
My legs are not mine,
my face is not mine.
My name is not my name,
because I am an actor!
Do you know what it
means to be an actor?
An actor is a mask...
...among human beings.
Juliette...
Ladies and gentlemen,
I have the honor...
...of welcoming you to
the first reading of the play.
May I introduce our guest,
Nicoletta von Niebuhr...
...who will play the female
lead in this production.
Do you mind if my friend
watches the rehearsal?
I have no objection.
- Two cognacs, please.
- Yes, director.
Coming up right away.
Three beers, please.
There you go.
Please excuse me.
Father Hansemann...
Hendrik, will we look
lovely in this play?
We are lovely.
May I introduce my best friend,
Barbara Bruckner?
Nice to meet you.
What?
There's a nice smell of
lavender about you.
Can you smell the lavender, too?
How shocking, on a man.
But I need it like my daily bread.
A little on the temples is
as good as a night's sleep.
Sleep would be better,
but there's no time.
A beer and a mineral water.
We'll hear what he has to say...
...use the good bits,
then play it our way.
He's good, but old-fashioned.
The future of Hamburg
Art Theater is me.
I mean the two of us.
Most of the plays here
are shallow bourgeois stuff.
But we visualize theater
that will involve everyone...
...the workers, the dockers.
Where will you perform this theater?
It doesn't matter.
In the docks, factories, cellars.
They asked me about the play.
We promised it for last week.
Let's get this opening night over first.
We must prove that theater
has a political function.
Before it can be political or
revolutionary, it first has to be good.
Which actors will be in
this sort of theater?
All who think like us. Even workers.
It's what we say, not how we say it.
But I've no qualms if
Hendrik stages our plays.
Go on. Why are you looking at me?
Am I not allowed to?
If it pleases you, go ahead.
Without you, I'll be finished, Barbara.
There's too much evil in me.
Alone, I'm too weak to overcome it,
but you could help me.
I can't talk anymore. So many
thoughts are just parts I've played.
I love you, Barbara.
I'm in love. With a woman.
Juliette, am I a good looking man?
I've never seen you on stage.
Maybe you're handsome, but...
...frankly, I've never found
you good looking, but...
...sometimes your cold cheating eyes
are those of a sad child.
You do it well.
Who have you fallen for?
- A girl.
- Great.
You falling in love...
One day you may just learn
how to walk, not just dance.
Love the girl, Heinz, and don't
tell me anything about her.
- Do we keep in touch?
- Yes.
You know what? I'm coming with you.
I have nothing to lose, Heinz.
Are you crazy?
See a psychiatrist.
Though I'm sure you wouldn't
dare talk about yourself.
Go, Heinz. We'll meet soon anyway...
...even if I don't want to.
Grandmother, have you a moment?
- I'd like to introduce...
- Your fiancé.
I have to take a closer look
at my new grandson.
Not bad at all.
Excuse my mother please,
she will be here shortly.
I assume you know,
my dear Höfgen...
...that loving mothers rarely want
their only sons to leave the nest.
Hello, Sebastian.
That is Sebastian.
Mom.
I'm really pleased.
Barbara, my dear child.
And I'm Nicoletta von Niebuhr...
...the bride's best friend,
almost her sister.
Often, the bridegroom's mistress.
Only on stage, of course.
May I call you Aunt Bella?
But of course, Nicoletta.
Let us leave the ladies to themselves.
I'd like to show you my garden.
I'd love to see it.
Have you unsettling memories, too?
You know, Barbara,
memories that give you the creeps?
When I was about twelve,
I got into our school choir.
I was overjoyed. I thought I could
sing better than the other boys.
We had to sing in church
at some wedding.
I wanted to show off.
I was so proud of my soprano voice.
I had a great idea. I sang
one octave higher than the others.
As I stood there, proudly singing...
...the music teacher looked at me
more in disgust than disapproval...
...and he said softly,
"Just keep quiet".
Do you understand?
Softly and dryly he said,
"Just keep quiet".
When I felt I was singing
like an angel.
Do you have such memories?
No.
You've never felt
ashamed in your life.
I often have. That was the first time.
I often have to feel awfully
ashamed of myself.
So ashamed,
I could sink down into hell.
Do you understand me?
This is the basement room.
The window faces the street.
Here's a lamp post and here, too.
Behind it the bakery...
- ...with workers' wives lined up.
- Stop!
Great.
Ms. Schult, you come up
past the window.
Barbara, can you put a
lamp post here...
...with a light to dazzle the audience?
Then you come here. "I'm Widow
Queck who hasn't paid the rent".
We could have several more
lamp posts in the auditorium...
...so people feel they're
really in their filthy street.
We'll have posters, recent political
slogans, all jumbled up.
At the back, a grocer's shop,
with nothing to sell, of course.
Everything in the hall must
express what we talk about.
Two policemen can patrol the rows
and stare at the audience.
An end to passive watching, actors
and public isolated from each other.
The public must play an active part.
The days of the peepshow are over.
The actor is only one element
of the performance...
...not it's focal point.
The hall, lights, walls, movements,
sounds, all must blend into a whole.
Only then shall we have real theater.
The workers need total theater.
One that shocks and arouses.
I am the widow Queck, who cannot
pay the rent. I work for the baker.
It's the only way I can feed
my seven hungry children.
The half-hour has to be paid for.
We've been waiting half an hour.
Here reigns logic and hunger.
I already owe you 31 marks
and 25 pfennigs.
I've had nothing these past few days.
Silly goose!
Sabotaging our work!
Do you think I don't know why?
Miklas or one of his damn party
friends has put you up to it!
- What do you want from me?
- Why don't you prompt her?!
Never mind! Revolutionary Theatre
can't be staged with provincial hams.
With amateurs, you can't
create any sort of theatre.
Even revolutions need professionals!
I'll buy you a drink to celebrate.
Revolutionary Theater is a big flop.
You're beside yourself with joy.
Hello.
Two stiff ones, Hansemann.
How about another
rebellious evening?
I'd like to invite you to dinner.
What, me?
- Good morning.
- Morning.
You're still half asleep.
I'm awake.
I've even phoned our grocer, he's
a bit impatient over our large bill.
I'm sorry. I don't present a picture
of early morning freshness.
If I, too, went riding every morning
I'd probably look more attractive.
But in our circles,
such noble sport is not customary.
The offended husband, as in Molière.
Oh, be quiet.
It's not customary to sit all night
at a Nazi thug's table.
- Miklas is not a thug.
- All Nazis are thugs.
You must a void their company.
Their dirt rubs off on you.
But you can't understand. It's your
family's well known liberalism.
No political beliefs, just curiosity.
Ideologies are psychological quirks.
I feel sorry for Miklas. He gets
small parts and earns very little.
You all treat him very badly. He's
at a loss, that's why he's with them.
So much understanding
for that lousy brat.
How do you think they'd treat us
if they came to power?
God forbid.
And yet you sit and chat with him.
It's you bourgeois tolerance.
This understanding of one's enemy.
I'm sure you could even
excuse Fascist terrorism.
Your liberalism might even
get used to dictatorship.
No, thank you.
May I remark...
...it's common practice to eat an egg
from its shell and with salt.
I know, in the Bruckner household
you eat it from a glass...
...with six spices,
and that's very original...
...but no need to make fun of those
unaccustomed to such originality.
- Who's juvenile lead in Halberstadt?
- Herbert Boltz.
Where's
Ms. Türkheim-Gawernitz now?
In Heidelberg.
- And Hannelore Kühn.
- Mannheim.
- And who's Othello there?
- Max Krause.
- And Iago?
- Johannes Fiedler.
- And Desdemona in Leipzig?
- Käthe Müttel.
Who's the ingénue in Jena?
A stupid cow called Lotte Lindenthal.
Why is Lotte Lindenthal a stupid cow?
I don't know, but she is.
I know why you insult her.
She's the friend of
a National Socialist leader.
I'm only moderately interested
in the names and titles of her lovers.
Must be quite a long list...
Watch your tongue, Höfgen!
You won't insult a lady because she's
in the Nazi German worker's party...
...and the friend of a German hero.
You won't stand for it?
My, my...
Stop it, you're drunk.
I'm not. On the contrary.
Apparently I'm the only one here
with a spark of honor left.
Nobody in this Jew-ridden business
cares if a lady is insulted.
Let me!
No!
Go away!
I'll gladly believe you're not drunk.
You won't make that an excuse, then.
As for this Jew-ridden
business you're in...
...you won't suffer it much longer.
That I promise you.
Perhaps you're right.
I agree, the fellow's behavior
was intolerable...
...but I can't just fire a poor,
sick man like that.
Sick? He's not sick at all.
Why this indecision and compromise?
It's just like our government parties.
Excuse me, Barbara.
We must show this murderous
pack it can't get away with it.
I beg you, don't insist that
he be sacked on the spot.
It's punishment enough that he
won't be hired for next season.
He has no idea what he said
last night, he just went wild.
I'm amazed, Otto.
I'm really amazed that you,
of all people, should say that.
I don't want him made a martyr.
- In the political situation...
- Excuse me if I interrupt.
This conversation is quite pointless.
The case is simple.
Either Miklas leaves the theater...
...or I do.
That's nonsense.
Higher, higher!
Enough! This isn't a funeral march!
Again.
Lights!
Sorry, to interrupt.
Dr. Kroge asks you to
approve the next poster.
I must take it to the printer.
Can't I get my name spelled
correctly even in this theatre?
My name is not Henrik, but Hendrik!
Hendrik Höfgen.
One day they'll all
have to mark my name.
Try to understand, doctor.
I can't and won't tie myself down.
It's a great strain
to stay under contract.
I must be free. Free.
I can't be a provincial matinee idol.
No, no, I don't want to be that.
You want to leave Hamburg for good?
I don't know yet.
The Professor invited me to a Berlin
guest appearance. One never knows.
By the way, Dora Martin
will be my partner.
Good. Then accept the offer.
Thank you.
Berlin.
Thank you, ladies. Till tomorrow.
Goodbye.
So you are Höfgen.
You have friends here.
Some of them, who understand
theater, recommended you to me.
Your father-in-law, too,
when we met at the ministry.
And Dora Martin, as well.
In real life I may seem a bit
nondescript, but not, I hope on stage.
My father-in-law once aptly described
my ability to transform myself.
Well, we'll give you a try.
Don't expect too much.
I'm not offering anything big.
You are probably used to a
reasonable income in Hamburg.
Here you'll have less.
Have you expensive tastes?
Money doesn't interest me.
My needs are modest.
All I need every day is a clean shirt
and a drop of cologne.
Discuss the details with
Miss Bernhardt.
Please give my regards
to your father-in-law.
- Hendrik Höfgen.
- Oh, yes. Bernhardt.
Here's your contract.
Thank you.
- May I?
- Please.
700 marks a month, less tax.
You agree to play as cast.
Please give these flowers...
...and this card to Ms. Martin, will you?
THANKS!
Well, Hendrik Höfgen.
Now you're a beginner again.
Hamburg's fame, routine and
security all lie behind you.
Now you must summon
up all your strength.
And we'll work off that blubber.
- Who is that?
- Dora Martin's Hamburg actor lover.
- No, Miss Bernhardt's.
- You're misinformed, dear.
So glad you were able to come,
despite all your work.
May I introduce some
of your admirers?
Mr. Davidson of the London Times.
Cäser von Muck, Mr. Müller-Andreä.
Mind you aren't influenced by
the prevailing culture Bolshevism.
What do you mean?
German culture can only be renewed
if it returns to its national roots...
...to its essence of blood and soil.
Russian ravings or French farces are
alien to the spirit the nation needs.
Have you met Mr. Höfgen?
Berlin's new star, according to
tomorrow's London Times.
I've seen you on stage.
You danced, didn't you?
Yes, I like dancing.
I had a good teacher.
I'd like to model your head.
No neck-tie and no gold we've got
We're just a very shabby lot
At which the bourgeois spits
The bourgeois with polished boots
And medals on morning suits
And every morning he ablutes
for church, or for the Ritz
Where does the bourgeois get it all?
His guns his celebration ball?
He steals it where he can
He makes it hard for us to rob
Takes it all, the greedy slob
Exploits the poor and wrecks the job
of every working man
Oh, if so wealthy I could be,
Commit like him grand larceny
All honored since my birth
If then I met someone I knew,
You filthy lot, I'd spit at you
That's all you dogs are worth!
Get the Jews out of here!
They are completely drunk.
Now one of the most famous
State Theater actors, Hendrik Höfgen.
Forget State Theater and fame.
I am your comrade Hendrik Höfgen.
What does the proletariat want?
That nobody should rule!
Nobody shall give orders
Nobody shall be a slave
Freedom, equality for all souls
I'll dictate. Headline:
Actor Höfgen wins
Berlin workers' hearts overnight.
New paragraph.
- Hendrik?
- Hello.
I bought this picture at the
antique dealer. You don't mind?
Why should I mind?
You can admire it
while I go and change.
I love you, Barbara. Not only
your father and grandmother.
I love you... I, Hendrik Höfgen.
Welcome to my home,
dear Sebastian.
The theater awaits me.
Up!
Two!
Three!
Four!
Five!
Six!
Führer!
We are our people's strength!
We shall create a new world!
- What's your father's job?
- Road digger!
- And your father's?
- Farmer!
- And yours?
- Teacher. He educates us!
- And your father?
- Baker. He bakes our bread!
Mine's a miller. He grinds our grain!
A doctor. He makes us healthy!
Bricklayer. He builds our houses!
- Conductor!
- Electrician!
We are the sons of one people,
we all have the same goal!
Unity and strength!
We follow the Führer!
No. That's not convincing enough.
Say it like this...
- Again... one, two, three.
- Unity and strength!
Again!
Unity and strength!
- Louder! Again!
- Unity and strength!
We follow the Führer!
Blood is a very special juice...
...let us in depths of sensuousness
assuage our burning passions.
No bounds and goals are set for you.
You find your pleasure.
A fleeing treasure.
May you enjoy the prize you get.
Help yourself and don't be coy.
But listen, it's not a question of joy.
To knowledge I'm devoted,
most painful gratification.
Most hateful love,
most vexing stimulation.
Believe me, who countless years
on this hard nourishment has fed.
That from cradle to the grave, no
human can digest so stale a bread.
Believe me, worlds
celestial and infernal...
...for one divinity were made.
He exists in eternal light.
But us, into the darkness, has
conveyed there's day and night alone.
Yet I want that!
That's well worth hearing.
But there's one thing I fear.
For time is short, but art is long.
If I thought you sought more teaching,
cultivate a poet fond of preaching.
Let his thoughts wander.
And every noble quality upon
your brow let him bestow...
...the lion's courage,
the buck's swiftness.
The Italian's fiery blood,
the north's enduring pluck.
He'll teach you the secret vile
of magnanimity steeped in guile.
May his youthful drives uncover
to make of you an ardent lover.
I'd like to meet a scholar of such fame
to Microcosm I'd change his name.
So what am I, if it's not possible
the paragon of humanity to attain...
...towards all my senses strain?
You're in the end just what you are.
Put on the wigs of a million curls.
Put your feet in elevating socks.
You'll stay forever what you are!
Bravo!
Wonderful!
You were fantastic, Hendrik.
You were born to play Mephisto.
You say that with a
touch of malice, Dora.
Not true, I don't detest
people for what they are.
- Anyway, thank you for coming.
- Let's skip the clichés.
- What's your next project?
- I'm learning English.
English? Why?
- I'll be working in America.
- But why?
Here the curtain's descending.
Haven't you noticed?
You're at the top here, hit after hit.
Thousands adore you. So why go?
Thousands! Soon they'll be
raving about others.
There'll always be theater,
no matter what happens in Germany.
No matter what happens in Germany?
You really mean that?
Well, all the best.
I'm leaving in a few days.
In a few days?
I don't want to wait till it's too late.
But you'll always do well, Hendrik...
...no matter what happens
in Germany.
It's open.
Mephisto, I never lock the door.
Need neither bolts nor life insurance.
- I bet you've taken one out.
- I need no life insurance.
Sit down, sir, in my new home.
You could have
gotten me a nicer flat.
- Have you registered with the police?
- Yes, sir.
What did the landlord say?
Nothing. He was drunk,
humming a song...
No neck-ties, no gold we've got...
He gave me the key and I moved in.
I've been longing to see you.
- And how's your wife?
- She's with her father, thank God.
They're worried about the Republic.
In Hamburg, the foreigners were also
very worried about Germany...
...about German culture,
whose Number-One-Parrot you are.
As if a peril threatened it. What are
the Jews planning against Germany?
Even the whores wonder...
...and they don't care about
the pant color as long as it has a fly.
Barbara understands politics,
doesn't she?
Is she keeping an eye on you?
No. Mostly her opinions
are the opposite of mine.
- Have you told her so?
- No. What point would there be?
Words don't say everything.
I'd like very much to sleep with you.
Shall I make up the bed?
Yes!
Hendrik! Hendrik!
Hendrik, wake up! Didn't you here?
You're here already?
I came on the early train,
because of you.
- What's the matter?
- When did you go to bed?
I'm tired. I was tossing all night.
Why?
The Nazis have won the elections.
You know who became Chancellor?
No.
Do you hear that?
That Bohemian corporal has
become Chancellor?
Here, read it.
I thought there was nothing
to fear from the Nazis.
Remember that business with Miklas?
That could have unpleasant
consequences. What do we do now?
Keep a clear head and don't panic.
So, the Austrian clown has
become Reichs-Chancellor.
But there still is the opposition, no?
Communists and Social Democrats.
They'll make sure he doesn't
get too big for his boots.
Perhaps there'll even
be armed resistance.
And even if the Nazis stay in power,
why should it concern me?
I'm from the Rhineland.
So are my parents.
What can happen to us?
On top of that, I'm an actor. No?
I go to the theater, play my parts,
then go back home. That's all.
Some people are leaving a country...
...where a career in the arts
is now impossible.
People will think you don't care
about anything beyond the limelight?
There were elections in a democratic
state. One party won, that's all.
I've never been interested
in politics, so why now?
Don't you realize
what's happening here?
Don't answer it. I'm not here,
I'm sick. Say what you want.
Is that any solution? To lock
yourself in, to hide, not be at home?
Is that all you can think of,
instead of taking a definite stand?
Definite... this is my answer!
Hamlet! Shakespeare!
Either we take a stand or go,
if our freedom is in danger.
This is the only form of freedom
for me, for an actor.
You can't hide behind Shakespeare,
on the stage.
Barbara, I'm an actor.
An actor in Germany at all times.
You can go away.
Your father is a famous writer.
You can design sets anywhere,
or buy antiques.
But I need the German language!
I need the motherland, don't you see?
- Who's there?
- Otto.
- Who?
- I must talk to you.
- You want some coffee?
- No, thanks.
- Tea?
Act with us again. It's the only reply
we can give to these events.
An appearance by all of us,
a common front.
So we don't lose our future.
You just want to divide the audience?
We must work out our tactics.
Tactics will force us to our knees.
We must fight this
crushing demagogy.
It's our job to tell the hesitators:
Now is the time to resist dictatorship!
Otto, in the first place, we're actors...
No, not a protest on the street.
I'm talking about the stage.
Still, I think we should
wait a few days.
We must do something
immediately. Tonight.
Otto, I'd rather stay
with the reserves.
Thank God
I've no performance today.
GERMAN REICHS-MAIL
Film contract, locations in Budapest...
...leading role.
Production Manager Altenburger.
She really is a beauty.
She's sitting by the side altar.
Cut! Very good!
The second one.
Now the scene where they follow her
to the Fishermen's Bastion.
What's going on?
Are we done for today?
Can we go?
- The Reichstag was burned down.
- What?
They say the communists set fire to it.
Your wife wants you
to join her in Paris.
She didn't dare phone you. Don't go
back to Berlin. I'm moving to Vienna.
Many of your Berlin friends have
vanished lately. Otto Ulrichs is one.
We must be prepared for anything.
I fear we'll never be able to return.
The Nazis have blacklists.
Your wife and you are on them.
Please, never go back to Berlin.
Hendrik, promise me that.
Please!
Cheers, and many thanks!
Cheers!
To the most beautiful
actress in Europe!
When are you going home?
I'll stay a few more days in Budapest.
Then I'm going to see about
a contract in Vienna.
I understand you, Hendrik.
I'll tell you now, I'm not going
back to Germany, either.
I signed you for this part...
...so you, too, could slip away,
if you want to.
The film studio gave me your
address in Budapest.
I hope my letter reaches you.
I'm in Berlin now.
I've landed a part in a comedy.
During the shoot I met the
actress Lotte Lindenthal.
She's friendly with a National
Socialist who's very powerful now.
She's wonderful. She never flaunts
what great influence she has.
I told her you were abroad and didn't
dare return, for certain reasons.
What's the man afraid of?
She said you were an eminent artist
and saw Mephisto several times.
"We need such actors", she said, and
she promised to speak to her friend.
This morning she said: "No matter
what silly things Höfgen has done...
...when it's an eminent actor,
people are tolerant".
Her friend has promised that nothing
will happen to you if you return.
Hendrik, Berlin awaits you.
You have nothing to fear.
No one can replace you.
Those who rule our lives...
...know that the theater is a shelter
for me and people like me...
...in which we all feel safe
and have nothing to fear.
It would be that for you, too.
Theater is a mission.
In true friendship,
yours, Angelika Siebert.
Name?
- Hendrik Höfgen.
- Profession?
Actor.
Where?
At the State Theater in Berlin.
- Is something wrong?
- No, no.
Thank you.
I don't know if you'll
feel at home again here.
The spirit is different from
that you were accustomed to.
Cultural Bolshevism is over.
There will no longer be a chance to
appear in your friend's plays...
...or those popular French farces.
We perform German art now.
Frankly, I saw no great reason
to recall you from abroad.
But Lotte Lindenthal wants you as
her partner in her comedy début here.
I didn't want to displease her.
The role of elegant friend and seducer
shouldn't cause you any difficulty.
I'm so cold.
I'll warm you up.
Your room isn't heated
in this dreadful weather?
Is this how you anticipated my visit?
Very nice of you!
There's a warm room over there.
Come.
No, I'm in a great hurry today.
It would warm us up.
No, there's no point in this cold flat.
My new maid doesn't
know her duties yet.
You should have told her
your visitor needed warmth.
But I've only just returned home.
You should have returned earlier.
I'm someone you must
wait for, impatiently.
If I want to meet someone in passing,
I have my husband. And besides...
Where did you get this new maid?
She's far too pretty.
It's an honor to act with you.
It's so nice to hear
a warm voice again.
I'm happy to hear you say that,
I know you're no flatterer.
Me, a flatterer? I'm notorious
for telling people the truth.
I like honest people.
If she turns, everything will be fine.
If she waves, I've scored a triumph.
After the Reichstag fire,
I had to leave Hamburg.
Bonetti wears a uniform now.
He threw me out of the canteen.
"We've got you now, Böck!" he said.
They almost beat me up,
my landlady threw me out.
I had to leave Hamburg.
Are you upset that I've come?
When I heard you were in Berlin,
I found new hope...
...and I just came.
Are you angry with me?
I'm not angry with you.
Live here till things settle down,
but don't tell anyone.
Just simply disappear without a word.
If I were in your position,
I might well commit suicide.
I'll buy you a radio, so you'll know
what's happening outside.
I've got nobody else
in the world but you.
- Is Budapest beautiful?
- I don't know...
Yes, quite nice.
I could have gone there.
Barbara wasn't with you.
They wouldn't have let you
cross the border.
I'm a German citizen, too. My father
was pure German. Why can't I go out?
If you can't understand why,
we'll both be in trouble.
- You're horrible.
- You're an idiot!
Go to hell you... you actor!
Dear Lotte, may I ask a great favor?
I have to play Mephisto.
I'll see what I can do.
I look forward to seeing
you again as Mephisto.
It's thanks to me you're
playing Mephisto again.
Certain ministerial circles feared
you might revive your old Faust spirit.
The spirit of cultural Bolshevism,
as it was called.
Well, I succeeded in
overcoming those fears.
Cäsar, thank you,
thank you very much.
THANK YOU!
Please give these flowers...
...to Miss Lindenthal.
- Good morning!
- Good morning.
Morning, Mr. Höfgen.
Mr. Miklas! Are you still around?
- Morning.
- Fine.
I've only been here a short space,
I come with a humility to this place...
...to find a teacher of vocation
who's held by all in veneration.
How pleasant is your courtesy!
A man like many more you see.
Have you looked around?
Take me as your student.
I come with courage and my youth.
I want to study with all my heart.
You've come to the right place.
I feel like going home I fear.
In that great hall
I won't like it at all.
You see no grass, you see no tree.
And in the classes we are taught
I lose my hearing, sight and thought.
It all depends on habit.
Seeing the breast, a child
might accept the gift unwillingly.
But soon it sucks in delight.
So will you, on wisdom's breast,
enjoy it daily with more zest.
Around her neck I'll
cling with pleasure...
...but tell me how can I
find this treasure?
When you continue on your way,
which faculty will make your day?
Is this where the cut comes?
The art of medicine
is not hard, you know.
You study the world, big and small.
And in the end you let them go
when God demands it.
You'll try in vain to learn all science.
Each man just learns what he can.
But he who grasps every chance
he is the worthy man.
You are still of pleasing build
with self-confidence at last instilled...
...others will have confidence in you.
Especially learn
the women to enthrall.
Eternal moans, a thousand ills.
There's just one place to cure them.
If you've honor to some degree
one may allow some shared intimacy.
A title helps to make her certain
your art exceeds that of your peers.
And may grant you a glimpse of which
another schemes for many years.
Her pulse you must learn to feel.
And burning looks you
then must steal.
Her slender hips are then embraced
to see how tightly she is laced.
That's what I could care for.
Gray, my friend is all theory.
And green the golden tree of life.
That's the way.
I greet the learned gentleman!
You made me to sweat profusely.
- What is your name?
- The question's odd...
...for someone who idle talk despises.
Who, far removed from worldly show
seeks only academic prizes.
With you, one knows your game
generally by your very name.
It's evident, Sire
if one's called a liar.
Who are you?
I'm a part of that force...
...that always craves evil
and always creates good.
What is this riddle?
I'm the spirit who negates.
And rightly so, for all creation
is worthy of annihilation.
So it were better,
nothing were created.
And so everything you've stated
is sin, destruction, devilment.
Remains my actual element.
Good evening. The Prime Minister
invites you to his box.
Yes.
It's all going like clockwork.
May I introduce you to
my distinguished colleague?
Ah, our Mephistoles.
Congratulations.
That mask is perfect, it's evil itself.
It's sacred evil.
Yet, your eyes are so kind,
your handshake so soft. It's strange...
...it seems the secret of acting is
to portray strength, yet one is weak.
I imagine you've prepared
for this role for a long time.
All my life, Prime Minister.
That's the only way.
That is the secret of greatness.
Break a leg.
Carry on the good work, Mephistoles.
Höfgen residence.
Lotte Lindenthal.
Höfgen.
- Hendrik?
- Yes.
Will you come to us
after tonight's performance?
There'll be just a few friends here.
With pleasure. Thank you very much.
Böck!
Just a few friends will be there.
Am I not an incredible villain?
Why a villain?
You're just successful, Mr. Höfgen.
To the renewal of German culture.
Long live the actors.
Our theater has many elements that
have nothing to do with Germany.
We must set up a customs control
of the mind for culture smugglers...
...to stop foreign elements poisoning
German literature and theater.
This can't be left entirely
to our frontier guards.
Everyone must cooperate
in this control.
- Am I understood?
- Yes, General.
There are many who
don't understand.
Look at this painting, my Mephisto.
A masterpiece of
German romanticism.
Where did I find it? At an art dealer
with an foreign accent.
I had it restored. No, no...
...the future of painting doesn't
belong to the Liebermanns.
Your Mephisto occupies my mind.
You've brought him alive.
He's a hell of a guy.
Isn't there a little of him in all of us?
I mean, isn't there a bit of Mephisto
in every German?
Wouldn't our enemies love it if we
had nothing but the soul of Faust?
No, Mephisto is also
a German national hero.
It's just something we
mustn't tell people.
I must go now.
Come to my office at 10:30,
the day after tomorrow.
Some foreign journalists
want to know many things.
Above all, what 'Germany' means
today, and the German culture.
I'll tell them. You can elaborate on
what I say about theater, for example.
Painting, architecture, sculpture,
plenty to write about.
I want them to be
informed by experts.
Tell me, why do you have
such a limp handshake?
So, we meet again. How time flies!
You were wonderful as Mephisto.
Now you act him more forcefully.
But I liked the other one, too.
I sensed it in the seed of what
can now be unfolded to the full.
I also liked you in the play
with Lotte Lindenthal.
The ideal actress to portray
the ideal German woman.
What are we doing here? Why is
he wasting his time with foreigners?
He said they're interested in German
culture. They'll ask a few questions.
- I see. You spoke to him?
- Yes.
How are you?
Nice to meet you again.
The Prime Minister sent for me.
I hope this doesn't last too long.
Always problems with the old statues.
Shall we tear them down or not?
As if that were important
for our future.
I'd like to sculpt
a bust of you, Höfgen.
What sort of man are you? Your own
face differs amazingly from Mephisto.
In private life, you look rather shy.
I'll do a bust of you,
but in clay or in bronze?
- What is your face made of?
- Perhaps a mixture.
I very much enjoyed your Mephisto.
I only had eyes for you.
I'm preparing an exhibition.
The General wants a pre view.
Try to come. Here's my number.
If you have time, give me a ring
and come to my studio.
You can relax while I model you.
How strange your face is.
A German face yet it
changes every moment.
That's acting.
The rest is humility and hard work.
I've discovered your secret.
It's the surprise effect, right?
The unexpected.
I've been watching the way you
appear on stage. Always different.
Sometimes quick, erratic.
Then slow, suddenly,
when the audience is lulled.
But always surprising
and unpredictable.
Thus you create the feeling
of something original...
...even if the spectator
knows your lines by heart.
And your glib tongue, your deliberate
pa uses, your precise emphasis.
I think I'm learning from you.
It's important to be unpredictable.
Spectators needn't know what
my next step is or where I'm going.
- They're not prepared, it's a shock.
- Exactly.
Yet it was only a change of pace,
or a slightly longer pa use.
In the theater it's the others
who make the king a king.
Building the role is all important;
pianissimo alternating with fortissimo.
Naturally, you need a
certain flair, artistic talent...
...and as I usually say,
a high degree of culture.
When I hear the word culture,
I reach for my revolver.
Bourgeois nonsense! Bolsheviks
preach it to win over school teachers.
To say nothing of artists.
Isn't that so?
I wasn't untouched by
Bolshevik trends, either.
And I must admit that for a while
I flirted with the left.
Well, anyone can get
involved in some folly.
Those were troubled times.
Let's have a drink.
General, other deserving artists
committed the follies I did.
I don't forget those paying for sins for
which I've been generously pardoned.
I'm pleading for a certain person,
for a friend.
I guarantee he's reformed.
I'm pleading for Otto Ulrichs.
Otto Ulrichs? Who's he?
He ran the communist cabaret,
'The Storm-Bird'.
Well... he must be
a pretty bad fellow.
No, he's not bad.
A bit rash, I admit.
A bit thoughtless, but not bad.
If anything, he's too decent.
Once he gives his word, he keeps it.
I'm back at the State Theater.
The funny thing is,
I simply can't believe it.
Just as I can't believe
I'm here with you by the window.
I know it's reality, but I don't feel it.
- Great.
- Magnificent, really.
A German work of art.
Not every German artist is
capable of such work.
It is a courageous work.
Come, Mephisto.
You sign, too.
What did I prophesy?
The exhibition is a success.
You rascal, so you make
secret visits here.
If I may add something personal,
it is a courageous work.
Courageous,
because it captures our time...
...the beauty of strength
without bourgeois snobbery.
Contrasting the degenerate taste...
...of the loud-mouths of culture.
We see muscles and clear-cut
features mankind wants to see.
Strong and beautiful in his strength.
Warrior-like and victorious
in his struggle.
Hello Hendrik.
That was a wonderful speech.
- You know each other?
- Very well.
You're in Berlin? Since when?
I'm here because
I want to dine with you.
I haven't seen you for so long.
So where will we go?
Your choice. How's Hamburg?
Surviving without me?
I'm in Berlin to have dinner with you.
Hamburg is history.
You're out of touch. Kroge's in
Switzerland. He just vanished.
Didn't even tell his girl. Simply went.
Kroge is a traitor.
Why must you appear with them?
Because they asked me to.
They ask others, too. You needn't go.
You can't refuse, none of us can.
If anyone says they do, they're lying.
Besides, the General's a nice chap
and he knows a lot about the theater.
He's not so closed minded
as most others.
A well behaved boy who wants to
enjoy the rewards for good behavior.
- Yes, I like to be well behaved.
- Because you're afraid.
- I like it.
- Then you should.
It will be difficult to stay with me
and maintain good behavior.
Damned black woman, right?
I can't help being different
from what's allowed here.
People can spit in my face
in the street.
Only I can't do anything about it.
My nose, my hair remain the same
even if I want something else.
Yet, I'm German, a German Negro.
German is my mother tongue.
What am I supposed to do?
Where should I go?
I don't know. I don't even know
what will become of me.
You think only of yourself.
And like an idiot,
I dreamt of us having a child.
That's all we need.
Is the child to be to blame, for she
might ruin her father's career?
That's enough now!
- That's enough of that now!
- Now it is enough?
I can see why your wife
couldn't stand living with you.
Here... I pinched a photo
of you once. Look at it!
Do you recognize yourself?
I must speak to you.
To tell me what you've said
behind my back?
I don't know what you mean.
Höfgen would bury his mother alive.
Didn't you say that?
I won't dispute that I dislike you.
- What do you want?
- I want you to sign this.
My signature? What for?
You want a raise?
Or do you collect signatures...
...because theater safety
regulations are a bit unsafe?
From a moral standpoint much seems
unsafe. And I don't mean the theater.
What do you protest against?
Against a leadership that
disregards our rights.
But you were in the Nazi party,
back when you were in Hamburg.
I'm leaving the party.
That's your business.
I'd like to ask you to
read our protest and sign it.
Regardless of my opinion, you are
today's leading German actor.
Let me say that
I won't even read this thing.
Be careful not to get yourself
and others into real trouble.
Miklas, you can go to hell.
I won't let a dirty pig like you
provoke me.
Dear God.
Congratulations, my dear Höfgen.
You put it precisely.
Some elements must go to the devil.
If you were a soldier,
I'd promote you. I'm very pleased.
By the way, you needn't be afraid.
For the fun of it, I checked
your horoscope. It's excellent.
- Best of luck, Höfgen.
- Thank you.
Did something happen?
Good morning.
Get walking!
The management regrets that Hans
Miklas has died in a car accident.
How awful, such a young fellow.
But, frankly, there was something
disquieting about him...
...don't you think?
Disquieting...
That was no car accident.
He must have come to you, too,
with that protest.
Are you insane?
How can you talk such nonsense?
Why shouldn't it have
been a car accident?
The government would stage
a car accident...
...all for some unknown actor?
We're not in some
tenth-rate melodrama.
People shouldn't cross
roads in heavy traffic.
I've great plans for you. We're alone.
You can refuse and remain an actor.
But then you can't do as much
for our cause as you could.
Your speech was good.
I realized you're not only an actor.
You put the essence into words.
Write your own biography, Hendrik.
Submit it to me, as soon as possible.
Höfgen...
...you will manage the Prussian
State Theater. Your task is easy:
A full house and a wildly
enthusiastic, audience for you.
Do you understand?
No need to enlarge upon
those matters in Hamburg.
Nor need we mention
the Revolutionary Theater.
Just mention some of
your roles there.
What did you really imagine
in Hamburg?
How could you have conceived...
...promoting Russian Bolshevism?
You, a German. Incredible!
- Where is your wife now?
- In Paris, I believe.
No, she's in Amsterdam,
working against her Motherland.
They're publishing a newspaper.
You don't correspond with her?
We have no contact at all.
You'll get a divorce easily.
I'll see to that.
German citizens
who have left Germany...
...couldn't wipe us out, so they
signed their own death sentence.
Where weakness perishes,
humanity becomes healthy.
Politics, like theater, is a fight.
Just as every rebuild
is the start of a new war.
But we're not talking about this now.
Hamburg...
"In a harbor town by the river..."
Lots of foreigners, night clubs, bars.
I understand you perfectly.
But in the Reich's capital?
No offense, we're men, but...
What's this Hamburg souvenir
doing here? Juliette Martens.
Is she kept by you?
You once, rightfully, said...
...Professor Bruckner was
not a man of the future.
And, even more rightly,
you parted from his daughter.
If you have such a good instinct
for a healthy, clean attitude...
...what's this Negro-woman
doing in Berlin?
Mephisto...
...it defies racial purity.
Don't even keep her picture at home.
General...
Wait, I haven't finished.
I hope you completely
understood me.
- Yes.
- So?
- She's not to come to any harm.
- Leave that to me.
I'd like to request, Prime Minister...
...that she'd be allowed
to leave Germany unharmed.
Agreed. She'll be taken to the frontier
and good-bye. That's what we'll do.
And you'll hold a press conference,
giving information about the theater.
The repertoire, plans
and your performances.
In October there'll be a big cultural
e vent in our Paris embassy.
I'd like you to attend it.
Böck. I bet they know about him, too.
Böck, Böck, my note-book.
Böck stays.
- Here it is.
- Give it to me.
I have to call friends.
I urgently need a friend.
- Find me a friend.
- But you've so many friends.
Friends...
Call Miss Nicoletta von Niebuhr.
Find the number and call her.
Shall I make coffee, or tea?
Shall I become manager? Yes or no?
Can I? May I? Must I?
Is it my duty?
Can I make myself useful?
I mean, can I help anyone?
And if so, should I?
Or shall I look at it as a new role?
Or shall I emigrate to America?
I can earn as much in films
as Dora Martin.
If I accept such an office
of this government, then...
Do I want to, at all?
They need me.
I was about to emigrate...
...and the Prussian Minister
asks me to rescue his theater.
Tomorrow morning I must
give him an answer.
Heaven evidently has
great plans for me.
Then you've won.
Would you help me?
I'd be proud of you.
Yes, I'll help you Hendrik.
If only one could live forever.
Here's your passport for France.
You have five minutes to pack.
Yes, but why?
We're waiting. Hurry up.
You needn't thank me for this raise.
I made it a condition for
taking over this job.
Everything's covered with dust.
If you don't clean the dressing rooms
as well as all the others...
...you may have to look
for another job.
I hope we'll get along. If you have
any problems, come to me.
I would like to treat you all to coffee.
Allow me to give you the money.
I'm sorry I can't come with you.
Joachim would like to speak to you.
Wait, Hannelore!
So, now he can enter.
Please consider decent roles for me.
You're not like the other managers.
You're an actor yourself.
You understand.
I must act as if he's
saying something important.
When you talk to actors, you must put
them at ease. That goes for me, too.
No, I don't like Premières. All night
one has to wear a big, frozen smile.
I hate that.
You think it's a good costume?
I don't! I think it's terrible!
Good morning, Mr. Kappelmüller.
How are you?
- Good.
- How's the family?
So your daughter graduated as
a hairdresser. Maybe we can use her.
Good morning.
Haven't you noticed? New suit,
new shoes, new manager, no? Well.
...ex-Bolshevik Höfgen, manager of
the Prussian State Theater...
...is letting his former comrade
appear in his production of Hamlet.
Hannelore! Was the cast list
for Hamlet posted yet?
Not yet.
Good. Let's wait another two days.
Thank you.
I must offer them more
than old comrades.
You must cultivate connections.
That's the essence of the system.
Let me tell you, yesterday I went to
the Prussian State Theater...
...it was Faust and the name of some
white-faced clown was Mephisto.
What a joke! And Mephisto by some
man called Höfgen, it was terrible!
I'd rather go to the Bavarian
People's Theater. Goodbye then.
Why am I doing all this?
Because I enjoy it.
I must enjoy amateur plays and use
actors that are blonde not talented.
Most are totally untalented.
A Frankfurt audience
applauded Marquis Posa's...
...'Give us freedom of thought'.
Performance stopped, play withdrawn.
In Munich, 'The Robbers', withdrawn.
Schiller, our national poet!
They want to produce plays by
German authors. But what authors?
Those who haven't emigrated
aren't allowed to write, or won't.
It's simply impossible to offer
theater worthy of the name.
Unless I dig up a couple of old farces.
All Rococo wigs and white faces.
The joke is that the regime now sees
Shakespeare as one of our own.
Let's do 'As You Like It',
'Where the Banished Return.'
Show the opponents of dictatorship
that the will for freedom still lives.
I didn't hear that!
I can't possibly have heard that!
Am I not an incredible villain?
Isn't what I'm doing insane?
"Fürst and Niklisch, both on
the staff of your theater...
...on grounds of German
racial purity... dismiss them."
- Good morning.
- Well, how are you?
- Fine.
- And you?
- Everything all right.
The stage-hands that are concerned,
Fürst and Niklisch...
...are indispensable...
...and the loss of their services...
...would jeopardize the theater's
work. Date. Heil! Signature.
Germans!
Don't tolerate Nazi oppression.
Embassy of the German Reich
Did you bring me anything from
Germany? A leather coat, at least?
- Leather coat?
- Yes.
It's the fashion for men. Those who
took me to the frontier had them.
Your eyes are so dead,
how do they look?
- Empty?
- No, dazed.
Yes, that's how I felt these past days.
You see? You were never like that.
I've thought a lot about you.
I believe I should be grateful.
Without you, I'd be in a
concentration camp, or already dead.
If you still like being with me,
then stay here.
I'll look after you. You needn't
leave the house, not at first.
Then we'll find jobs. You're so gifted.
- I could have gone to America.
- There you go.
I think I really was gifted.
But also a terrible coward.
What do I do elsewhere? Be an extra,
a stage-hand, a technician?
Do you think these hands
were made for manual labor?
I'll provide for you.
What else do you want?
Success.
Hendrik Höfgen, just imagine...
you'd belong to me.
Juliette, I have to go now.
- Shall I see you again?
- I don't know.
- Can I see you off at the station?
- No, you don't fit into the picture.
All right, forget the station.
Just do what you want.
I do.
That's why I'm here.
Juliette, don't write anymore.
It's no good.
There aren't many people in this café.
Would you prefer to sit in the sun?
You like that.
No. Though I haven't had
much sunshine lately.
May I ask you something?
Do you still live alone?
No, I've got friends. And you?
Friends... in times like these?
It's difficult.
How can you still live in Berlin?
What keeps you there?
Barbara, I live in the theater.
And that is in Berlin?
I don't think you can judge
from Paris.
You're more than an actor now.
You took an oath. You're a manager.
I didn't take the oath,
I just moved my lips.
Someone has to save our
values for a better world.
I'm playing Hamlet, whether those
in power like Shakespeare or not.
Shakespeare is their ornament to
prove "we're not as bad as you think".
You can't stay in Berlin.
I have a family in Berlin.
You know I'm married to the theater.
I can help people who are
having a hard time.
If I leave, nothing better
will replace me.
Words!
It's always the same with you.
Your method of self-deception
is still intact.
Don't you see? Whoever you save,
it's only a gesture to your friends.
You're in a show-case, legalizing
these people will be attached to you.
We can't choose when
and where we're born.
An entire people can't emigrate.
As an actor I'm obliged to live in
my country, to observe and portray it.
And I can tell you, there are
decent people among them.
I hate coffee shop intellectuals and
I hate such resistance-fighters, too.
The really valuable, such as theater
and art can rise above everything.
That's my conviction.
Why did you want to meet me?
Well, I don't really know why.
It might even be dangerous for you.
Tell me, Barbara, did you ever...
...really love me?
Why did I come here today? If you'd
been listening, you wouldn't ask that.
If you don't accept what's
happening in Germany...
...why do you still live there?
What does freedom mean for you?
Do you need it to live? Or do you just
need to be successful and loved?
I'm satisfied with success.
It means many love me.
And the fury of the envious
does me good.
Don't make me responsible
for the impotence of your friends.
- Mr. Höfgen.
- Mr. Davidson, this is a surprise.
The check, please.
Have I come too early?
Farewell, Barbara.
May I pa y?
What could I do here?
Freedom...
What for?
Oberon and Titania.
Congratulations!
I greet our wonderful and truly
tantalizing German bride and groom.
Two young, yet mature people...
...of purest race and noblest blood,
who have enchanted us...
...and who serve our new society!
- Thank you.
- All the best.
General, nice of you to come.
They can say what they want.
For me, the world is Grunewald.
I'll remain a German artist and patriot,
no matter who may rule my land.
Grunewald is my favorite place...
...and what other country
brews such good beer?
Cäsar, nice to see you.
You can hold your rehearsals
in this villa.
We're very proud of the way
you spoke in Paris.
The way you simply answered
all the questions...
...and said quite frankly and
honestly what it's like here.
Carry on dancing.
Good evening.
Now, that's a surprise!
I won't say no to that.
- Congratulations, my Mephisto.
- Thank you.
Now, as old Admiral Tirpitz said:
"Target sighted! Full speed ahead!"
I'm looking forward to
your Hamlet, my Mephisto.
Your interview in Paris made a
good impression on all of us.
Congratulations!
And lots of healthy German boys!
Thank you.
Madam?
Beautiful.
Yes, very much to my taste.
Very lovely.
Thank you, Madam.
Cheers!
We have no working hours, just work.
I'm sorry, I must go now.
Be happy together... Hamlet.
Lately I've been wondering whether
we actually deserve all this.
If I'm forced to answer,
then I must say "Yes."
If not we, who represent
individuality and art...
...who else should, can and must rise
above all that happens in the world?
That's why we're an example
and encouragement to others.
No matter how filthy the world is...
...true art always remains pure
and true, doesn't it?
I'm married to the theater.
And so are you.
I can't contact Otto Ulrichs.
I sent a messenger to his flat...
...but he was told that two men
took Ulrichs away two days ago.
Call the Prime Minister and
connect me with him.
If he's not there, ask for an
appointment as soon as possible.
- Hello?
- Give it to me.
Höfgen.
- Hello.
- Do come in.
Well, what's going on?
Recently you helped me, on
behalf of a colleague.
Now I have to ask again for help.
The thing is...
...a few days ago, Otto Ulrichs
was taken from his apartment.
- Is this why you've come?
- Yes, Excellency.
I'm fed up with you, Höfgen. These
matters are outside your jurisdiction.
Keep your nose out of this affair.
I'll give you some good advice:
Stop meddling.
You'd do better minding
your own business...
...so you won't get crushed
like a bug! Think you matter?
Ulrichs was involved in dirty work.
My State Theater manager ought
not show such interest in a traitor.
Now go.
I told you to go.
Get out, actor!
I know how much I and the theater
owe to the General.
I also know that to a great
extent we owe it to you.
Dear Lotte, that's why I ask you
to intervene for Ulrichs.
- I'm so worried.
- Worried? But he's dead.
Didn't you know? As far as I know,
he committed suicide.
Suicide.
He knew the risks he ran.
I think he's more to be envied.
The Prince of Denmark
renounces rank, youth and love.
He is the savior of the North.
The lonely knight with lofty ideals,
the ideal of purity of blood and race.
Hamlet is a complex character, too.
A great and simple man.
Despite repeating myself so soon:
He is a man of the North.
He kills. And in his
self-destructing battle...
...he shows us the way to the future.
He commands us to lead a pure life.
That is his bequest to us today.
He is not weak, yet actors have
often portrayed him as neurotic...
...a pathological revolutionary,
thus as a decadent type.
Hamlet is a hard man.
You will see him as an
energetic, resolute hero.
He is also a hazard for the Germans.
We constantly analyze too much.
For the hour demands actions,
not only thoughts.
Least of all corruptive reflection.
Hamlet is the tragic conflict
between action and inaction.
Between hesitating,
thinking and doing.
And we, the bearers
of German culture...
...know what to make of that.
Hamlet is a populist drama.
Neither religious,
aristocratic, nor bourgeois...
...but a work like the Greek tragedies.
So we'll abolish the barrier
between audience and actor.
Space, light, movements,
sounds are everything...
...and even the spectators merge
into one great, common effect.
We must bring about total theater.
A theater that shocks and mobilizes.
It cost 60,000 marks to decorate
the theater for tonight...
...and five days loss of takings.
A nice birthday party. And we have
to participate in this circus.
- Good evening.
The only place you will find a
party like this is in Berlin.
Dearest Bella,
we haven't met in ages.
Are you well? Not homesick?
I'm sure you're fantastically well
and your great son is flourishing.
Dear Höfgen, how are you?
How is the party going?
People seem to enjoy it.
Your Hamlet was magnificent.
The boss was quite taken.
After the première he spoke
only of you and the theater.
Success is strange. Sometimes
you have it, sometimes not.
No, dear Höfgen, you give
people something, you create.
Here they come.
- How are you, Mephisto?
- Very well, Your Excellency.
I haven't told you, how wonderful
your Hamlet was.
I'm very glad.
Allow me to say a few words.
Mr. Prime Minister, Madam,
ladies and gentlemen.
We are proud to be able to celebrate
this day with you in this theater.
Since I have the honor...
...of greeting you on behalf
of everyone present...
...I salute the statesman and soldier...
...friend and generous
patron of the arts.
We admire him as our role model,
love him as our friend...
...obey him as our master...
...for without patrons,
art is a bird with broken wings.
As the poet says:
"May the gods protect you...
...and may the heart of Rome
beat for your aims".
The Prime Minister wishes to
speak to you outside, in his car.
You alone.
Nicoletta will take you home.
I won't be long.
Well, Mephisto, what power is
looking down on you here.
Do you feel it?
This is theater! Look at this arena.
It's almost ready. Wonderful, isn't it?
This is where
I'd stage a performance.
Don't blink, Hendrik, look history
in the eye. What an echo.
Hendrik Höfgen!
We shall rule Europe and the world.
A thousand-year empire.
Hendrik Höfgen!
Go! Get going!
Into the middle!
Well, how do you
enjoy this limelight?
This is the real light, isn't it?
What do they want of me? After all...
...I'm only an actor.