Witchfinder General - Vincent Price
Horror 1968 [H264-mp4] English
"Things I heard, as it were, the voice
of much people in heaven, saying,."
"Hallelujah."
"Salvation and glory and power
is to our God."
"For true and just are his judgments,"
"who hath judged the great harlot
which corrupted..."
"with her fornication,"
"and hath revenged the blood
of his servants, at her hands."
"Come, gather yourselves together
to the great supper of God."
"That you may eat the flesh of kings,
and the flesh of tribunes,"
"and the flesh of mighty men,
and the flesh of horses,"
"and of them that sit on them,
and the flesh of all freemen and bondmen,"
"and of little and of great."
"And I saw the beast,
and the kings of the earth,"
"and their armies gathered together
to make war with him"
"that sat upon the horse..."
Bring on some water!
"And the beast was taken,
and with him the false prophet,"
"who wrought signs before him,"
"wherewith he seduced them
who received the character of the beast,"
"and who adored his image."
"These two were cast alive into
the pool of fire, burning with brimstone."
"And the rest were slain by the sword
of him that sitteth upon the horse..."
"and all the birds were filled
with their flesh."
The year is 1645.
England is in the grip of bloody civil war.
On the one side stand the Royalist party
of King Charles,
on the other, Cromwell's Parliamentary
party, the Round-heads.
The structure of law and order
has collapsed.
Local magistrates indulge
their individual whims,
justice and injustice are dispensed
in more or less equal quantities
and without opposition,
an atmosphere in which
the unscrupulous revel
and the likes of Matthew Hopkins
take full advantage of the situation.
In a time where the superstitions of
country folk are still a powerful factor,
Hopkins preys upon them,
torturing and killing in a supposed drive
to eliminate witchcraft from the country
and doing so with the full blessing
of what law there is.
However, his influence is confined largely
to the eastern sector of the country,
East Anglia, which is held firmly
in Cromwell's grasp,
but not so firmly that
the Round-head cavalry patrols
have everything their own way,
for there still exists
an ever-present threat
from the remnants of the Royalist armies,
desperately foraging
for food, horses and supplies.
- Stop that, Richard.
- What?
- What you're thinking.
- What am I thinking?
Ungodly thoughts of your Sara,
that's my guess.
Thoughts of Sara, yes. Ungodly?
Depends on how you look at it.
And you, a supporter of Cromwell...
- Hold your talking, you two.
- Yes, sir. Of course, sir.
We'll be stopping in a few minutes
to give the horses a rest.
You can gabble all you want then.
Fifteen minutes
and we'll be on our way again.
Get down. Royalist snipers.
Probably only a few of them
after food and horses.
We'll flush the bastards out in no time.
Marshall, you stop behind
to keep an eye on the nags.
The rest of you follow me
and keep spread out.
Captain, look! There's one!
I see him! Follow!
Harcourt, this way.
Robert?
Captain?
Captain Gordon, is that you?
We're here, trooper Marshall.
It's quite all right.
- Getting a bit nervous, were you, lad?
- Aye, just a bit, sir.
Well, no need to worry.
We got them all, I reckon...
Not quite all. One of them got away, sir,
though I put my sword in him first.
We'd better move on
out of this wood, then.
If he has got away,
he could still be dangerous.
Swallow, bury Brace's body
as soon as you can.
Look out, sir!
- Thank you, trooper Marshall.
- He was trying to kill you, sir.
- I gather that, trooper.
- It was a lucky shot, sir.
Yes.
Nevertheless, it could have
ended my career for good.
Right, we move out.
Swallow, join us as soon as
you've finished your business here.
Harcourt, give him a hand
to remove the bodies.
Yes, sir.
So, you granted young Richard
here leave, did you, Captain?
- I did.
- Aye, two days.
Then you'll be away to see your girl,
I suppose. And how will she greet you?
Just promoted cornet
for killing King's men.
She knows my reasons for fighting
and it's only while the trouble lasts.
What are you laughing at?
Leave him be, Robert.
Can't you see he's in love?
Aye, I'm not ashamed of it, either.
A toast, lads,
to the lovely women of Suffolk.
And may they keep their beds warm
for General Cromwell's gallant men.
Come on, boy. Nearly home.
Well!
Master Marshall, welcome.
I trust you're well, sir.
My body is as strong as ever,
but the war continues?
- Aye, we still fight.
- And why...
Well, my company's recruiting.
I have two days' leave.
- Then you must eat with us this evening.
- I thank you, sir.
We still have good food
for all you soldiers take it from us.
And ale. Come, we shall drink together.
After your experience,
it is likely our village has grown
a little smaller for you, eh, Richard?
Not so much smaller
as lacking in promise, perhaps.
In Ipswich or Cambridge,
a man might find better opportunities.
Richard, if you took Sara to wife...
You mean, you'd give us your blessing?
You would take her away from here?
You honor me, sir,
but I only have a small farm
that belonged to my father
and my soldier's pay, which is...
I am little concerned
with your ill kept lands.
And still less for the silver you get
for killing good Christians.
Well, forgive me. That was unjust.
But there is trouble coming to this village
and I want Sara far away
before it arrives.
Surely Suffolk should be free
from the King's armies.
It's not only the King's armies
which bring death this year.
A lack of order in the land
encourages strange ideas.
You mean more rebellion?
I'm sorry,
you have worries enough already.
But give me your word that
you will soon take Sara away from here
and you shall ask her consent tonight.
- You have my word on that, sir.
- Good, Richard. Good.
That's right, my dear.
Master Richard Marshall.
Farm boy into soldier.
Welcome back, Master Marshall.
I'm glad to be back, Mistress Sara.
By the way, Sara,
I expect the meal at the usual time.
Yes, Uncle.
Your uncle has agreed to our marriage.
Richard.
Oh, the army has taught you
rough manners.
Sara, why is he frightened?
There have been threats to us
since you were last here.
- Threats? Why?
- We've been called papists and idolaters,
and filth chalked up on the walls.
They say we're King's creatures
and should be pilloried and worse.
Who says these things?
We've become outcasts in our own village.
Rest easy.
Now, no one shall harm you.
I put my oath to that.
Have you arranged a day
for the wedding, Richard?
No, sir.
Much depends on how the armies move.
Remember, it must be soon.
But how certain are your fears
of this danger?
Perhaps just an old man's bad dream,
and being an old man,
I must early to my bed.
- Good night, my dear.
- Good night, Uncle.
Oh, and Sara, remember to see
the doors are well bolted.
Yes, Uncle.
And Richard,
don't keep Mistress Sara up too late.
Country women need full eight hours
in their beds
if they're to be proper wives and mothers.
- Goodnight, Cornet.
- Goodnight, sir.
And will you make a proper wife
and mother, Sara?
I still have much to learn, Richard.
I'll teach you.
Now, didn't your uncle just say
you must early to bed?
- He did.
- And isn't he a wise man?
- He is.
- Right.
How much further, Matthew?
You will not call me Matthew.
I'm not one of your drinking cronies,
carousing and wenching in the taverns.
Aye, you're not that, sir.
Remember, John Stearne, you ride with
me only because you help me in my work.
- Oh, you call it work?
- It's the Lord's work, a noble thing...
And a profitable one.
The Good Lord paying in silver
for every hanging.
That is blasphemy, Stearne.
Hold your tongue.
I'm merely an honest man
who helps you get your confessions.
The law has prescribed due methods
of interrogation.
And I have been blessed with the skills
to carry them out.
Oh, stop your gabbling.
We have work to do in Brandeston.
Who is it this time?
- The message tells of a priest.
- A priest?
One who gives worship to Satan
and calls him Lord.
Oh, with the priest himself a witch, there'll
be others corrupted, too, I'm thinking.
You enjoy torture, don't you, Stearne?
And you, sir?
Goodbye, sir.
God be with you, Richard.
- Goodbye, Richard.
- Goodbye, Sara. I'll see you again soon.
Given up ale for star-gazing, Tom Salter?
Not star-gazing, Master Marshall. Waiting.
What for?
Matthew Hopkins, a lawyer.
Must be important,
that you wait after dark.
- It is, that.
- Aye.
Well, if I see a lawyer on the road,
I'll tell him you're here.
How far is it to Brandeston, friend?
- About three miles.
- Thank you.
- Are you the lawyer?
- Aye.
- Name of Hopkins?
- Aye, Matthew Hopkins.
- And this is my assistant, John Stearne.
- Why do you want to know, soldier?
There's some men from the village
back there, waiting for you.
Aye, they sent for us.
What would a lawyer want in Brandeston?
A man who may not be
what he seems to be. Come Stearne.
- John Lowes is his name.
- An evil man.
- A papist.
- Yeah, burning candles and all.
That is no proof of witchcraft in itself.
Dressed himself in devil's garments,
he did.
- And made unholy signs.
- Yeah, he did. I saw him.
I will find out the truth for you.
Have no fear, friends.
Yes?
John Lowes?
So, it has come to this.
You accuse me, a priest,
of working with the Devil.
We can only judge by the evidence.
And there's a lot of that, old man.
I reject your accusations totally.
He's going to give us trouble.
A simple confession, priest,
that's all we ask.
Help us.
We've got a lot of work to do
in Brandeston.
Leave my house, the pair of you.
I told you he was going to be difficult.
I reject your foul suggestions!
Leave here at once!
All you reject is the true God!
Take him, Stearne.
Look for the Devil's marks upon him.
Right. Help us, you two.
- Look, he still prays to Satan.
- Get on with your task.
If the Devil made you a priest, he's going
to have hidden his mark with a lot of care.
To what purpose is this?
When the Devil buys a soul, he marks
the person's flesh, so we will know him.
If such a mark is pricked,
no blood will flow, nor pain be felt.
Mistress Sara? Mistress Sara?
They've come for him.
Seems Satan has hidden
his mark well, Matthew.
Set him to running.
Quick, then, you two, around the table.
And keep him moving.
You would be his niece.
- Your name, child?
- Sara.
I am Matthew Hopkins, Witchfinder.
Being his niece,
you, too, may be corrupted by Satan.
No, not his niece.
A foundling,
taken in by him and his housekeeper.
- Are you telling me the truth, child?
- Yes, yes, of course.
When she died, I became his servant.
And you've remained innocent
all of these years?
Yes, sir, entirely.
- I trust you know the old man?
- Better than anyone.
In private talk, we may shed some light
on his innocence.
Private?
Yes, away from the distraction
of the crowd.
Perhaps in the quiet of your room tonight,
you might be able to help me
prove him guiltless.
Would you release him now?
You might be convinced tonight
that this is all needless.
And you will make every effort to present
the facts to me?
- You may come to my room tonight, sir.
- At what hour?
At 8:00, if you'll release him now.
All right. He can sleep in the jail,
and we'll be rid of him.
Come on!
Get up, you papist bastard!
- Has he confessed yet?
- Not a word.
- Well, then stop this.
- But he hasn't confessed.
Take him to the jail. We'll continue
the interrogation tomorrow.
Jail... You heard what he said.
Quiet down, you animal.
You know what, Marston? There
were these couple of right filthy girls,
filthy they were!
Horrible to behold, horrible!
- Witches?
- Yes, both of them.
We hanged them, Matthew and me.
Matthew. You know Matthew,
he's my partner.
Did it take you long to get
a confession out of them, John?
Well, a couple of days with one of them,
the other one...
Do you want more ale, sir?
Go on, then? Come on.
What about the other one?
Tell us about her.
Oh, yeah, the other one.
Now, she was a real strange one, she was.
Loved us for it,
like she wanted to get strung up.
Reckon that was the only bit
of excitement she ever had.
Well, go on, then, Mr. Stearne.
Go on.
Sara, I've come to question you.
You came here for a purpose, sir.
I came here to get your evidence
about the priest.
He's been kind to me.
Perhaps he had a motive.
Men sometimes have strange motives
for the things they do.
I know.
My motive in coming here was
to find the truth.
How about the priest, Master Hopkins?
We'll have done with him in a day or two.
Have no fear, child.
- He's been good to me in his way.
- He is an idolater.
He must confess and die.
Stearne will see to that.
Oh, no, please!
Don't let him be harmed, please!
You seek to protect a witch
from rightful justice?
Oh, no, not that,
but couldn't he be kept in a cell?
He could do no harm from a prison cell.
Oh, please!
But justice must be done, my dear.
Grant me this.
Please, Matthew.
Past noon,
you unkempt lout. Get up!
Get away!
I need air.
- Where's the priest?
- Where you put him, in the jail.
We'll get him out
and start questioning him, then, eh?
- No.
- What?
- He stays where he is.
- But we have no confession at all.
I said we'll leave him in the cell.
All right, then. All right.
What about the women? When are
we going to start interrogating them?
I hear tell they've a good few witches
around this place.
- When you're in fit condition.
- I'm fighting-fit as it is.
Oh, and where were you
last night, Matthew?
- I hear tell you've been a-wandering.
- You hear tell too much, man.
You, there, old man.
Master Hopkins, the Witchfinder,
he says you're to be kept here,
interrogated no further.
- Where are you off to, John?
- I'm going for a walk.
By myself.
Tell me! Tell me! Tell me!
Tell me that! Come on! Tell me!
Confess, witch!
- Tell us your foul iniquities!
- No!
Your familiars, woman. Confess!
Stop. For God's sake, stop.
Quiet, old man, and be thankful
you're not getting the same.
How many of them? A dog? A ferret?
Come on, tell them!
John. The Witchfinder, he's coming.
I trust you are using
the prescribed methods, Stearne?
Naturally.
Has she confessed?
Well, give me time.
She's only been here an hour.
Continue with the interrogation.
I shall be gone for a while.
You're always going off somewhere, sir,
aren't you?
- What do you mean?
- Nothing.
I've been called over the hill
to the next village.
I shall be back by tomorrow.
You will remain in charge here.
Carry on your work
while you're away, aye, sir?
Indeed.
- And the priest?
- I said to leave him be.
What do you want?
- You.
- Where's Master Hopkins?
- Gone.
- Gone?
- Where?
- Just gone.
He's left me in charge.
No! No!
No!
And don't think I don't know
why the old priest is being spared, eh?
Stearne, the priest.
I've changed my mind.
Confess!
Confess.
He confessed. You heard him.
I've heard nothing yet, Master Hopkins.
Refresh Master Salter's memory, Stearne.
You heard him.
You did, too.
Yes, Master Hopkins.
Witnesses.
Get up, you blasted witch! Get up!
Come on!
You are, all of you, confessed idolaters.
However, these proceedings shall be
carried out through due process of law.
What law demands, we shall satisfy.
You will each be tied in a prescribed
fashion, and cast into the moat.
Should you then sink, we will know
that your confessions are false.
If on the other hand
you are seen to swim or float,
then your confessions of witchcraft
are proven beyond a doubt
in the sight of God.
And you will be withdrawn from the water
and hanged by the neck
until you are dead.
You can't hang me. The law forbids it!
I'm with child.
And who would want
to make you pregnant, witch?
Quiet. Stearne, go on with your task.
Oh, God, help me!
- No!
No! Help me...
Hey, look! One of them is gone already.
They swim.
The mark of Satan is upon them.
Give us a hand here! Come on!
They must hang.
She was innocent.
God forgive you, Matthew Hopkins.
Jailer,
take them to the tree.
The money from the magistrate,
nine guineas in silver.
Good. Now we can leave.
- Good morning, soldier.
- Good morning.
What'll you be after in the way
of horses, then, aye?
A dozen or so for General Cromwell's
armies up north.
Well, lost a few, have you?
Aye, at Cheriton Wood.
That's a pretty sorry looking bunch
of old nags you got in there, friend.
- The best we could find.
- Then they'll have to do.
- A dozen you say, eh?
- Aye.
We'll be back in Suffolk soon where,
thank God, they still breed strong horses.
Oh, I doubt you'll find much better there.
I'm just back from those parts.
The mounts up there are much like these.
Have you been through
Brandeston at all, man?
Brandeston? Aye.
And a fine commotion
they're stirring up there.
What, over you taking their horses?
No, nothing like that. A mass hanging.
- Who?
- Witches, I heard.
Two women and a priest.
- Where was the priest from, man?
- Brandeston, I suppose.
A brave old boy for all his white hairs.
Was he a friend of yours?
Two troopers, Gifford and Harcourt,
will be here directly.
Have them take these horses here
back to the regiment
and report that I'm delayed.
I'll join them further north.
Do you understand?
Yes, but where will you be going to?
Anything else?
Sara!
Sara?
Sara.
Sara!
They took him and killed him.
They said he was an idolater.
I know, I heard.
- Sara...
- One of them, the Witchfinder,
he...
He...
I didn't want to...
I thought I could save him.
I thought they'd have pity.
We kneel before thee, oh, Lord, in humility
to ask for a blessing on our union.
We ask for forgiveness of our sins
and strength to lead righteous lives
as man and wife.
We pray also for the soul of thy servant,
John Lowes.
May he know eternal peace.
And it is in thy sight, oh, Lord,
that I hereby swear.
I shall not rest from
the pursuit of his murderers
till they stand before thee,
ready to answer to thee for their sins.
Take this money and whatever you need
from the rectory and go to Lavenham.
- You'll be safer there.
- I will, Richard.
Find lodgings and stay there.
I'll come to you.
I love you very much.
Oh, Richard!
Shepherd, I seek two men.
Witchfinders, they call themselves.
They were said to be headed this way.
- Matthew Hopkins and his assistant?
- Aye.
I've heard they're in Hoxne, about
four miles yonder, but I can't be sure.
Thank you, Shepherd.
Get out!
Oh, come on, Johnny, give us a kiss.
- Oh, get away from me.
- Stop it, you dirty rascal!
Stop it!
Here, I'll bet you two pennies.
- Ale, soldier?
- Aye, to wash the dust from my throat.
- Another one for you?
- Aye, get a move on with it.
She's got a powerful thirst still.
Landlord, I'm looking for a man
called Hopkins.
- I heard he was coming this way.
- Matthew Hopkins?
- Would you know where he is, friend?
- Aye, he's gone to Cambridge today.
But you got an accusation to make,
I'll get your confession for you.
I do the pricking, you know, not Matthew.
I'm your man, friend.
John Stearne, they call me.
I'm husband to Sara Lowes.
- You all right, friend?
- Yeah.
- You better get out of here.
- Yeah, I'm going, don't worry.
As for you, soldier, you are coming down
to see the magistrate.
Am I? Not with you.
Quick, Matthew!
For God's sake, Stearne,
what have you done? Who was that?
- Richard Marshall.
- Who?
He's married to the girl, Sara.
- How did he find you?
- He was looking for you.
He found out about Brandeston.
We're going to have to separate.
I won't run from him.
We have work to do down south
in Lavenham.
Not me. He's after our blood.
Seems to me he's already had
some of yours.
Well, he's not going to have any more,
you understand?
You're forgetting our powers.
He could be a witch.
He's a man who's out to kill both of us.
Then it appears to me that we should
take steps to see to his death first.
Come. We travel to Lavenham.
I full well understand
your feelings, Cornet,
but you're an officer of the army,
a soldier,
and desertion is punishable by death.
However, in this case,
there are two factors
which will stay me from subjecting you
to a full court-martial.
One, we are grouped here at Naseby
in preparation for a major assault
on the Royalist armies.
We need every man we can get.
And you're a pretty good soldier,
most of the time.
Thank you, sir.
Secondly, I would sleep ill
if I had to send to the gallows
a man who had saved my life.
But, Cornet, remember this.
If you should leave your command again,
I will have no alternative but to throw
the whole weight of military law
against you.
- Understand?
- Yes, sir.
Dismissed, Cornet.
And may God help you in your search,
Cornet Marshall.
Robert, hello.
- Richard, you're back.
- Aye.
- What happened with the Captain?
- Nothing.
I heard about Brandeston, Richard.
Hopkins and Stearne.
- I'll find them somewhere.
- But what can you do?
What proof have you
that they committed any crime?
- I've got Sara's word on it.
- Is that enough for the magistrates?
- There'll be no magistrates involved.
- What do you mean?
We'll talk more later, Richard.
We must be on our way.
We're after horses for this skirmish
that's coming up.
- All right.
- Come on.
Parliament men,
comrades of friend Marshall.
There's some good ones
coming now, look.
- Hey!
- Let's make a run for it, shall we,
- while we can.
- Be calm.
Yeah, but if they find out
who we are, they'll...
They won't. Come on.
That's a fine horse you've got there, friend.
The army needs mounts of such caliber.
I am not selling.
But you will get your money
when the war's over.
You don't appear to understand.
I am not selling.
Oh, but you are selling, friend.
And we'll take that one, there, too.
So you filthy soldiers can
butcher my mare?
Sergeant, he thinks we're filthy soldiers.
Do you hear?
Aye, I heard.
You can't go saying
things like that, friend.
What he needs is a little army discipline.
I hear you need more pikemen
in your platoon, Sergeant.
You'll pay for this!
Good horse you had, there.
Cost a pretty penny, I reckon.
We robbed the canteen mint.
A right jester, he is.
Yeah, well, a day's fighting in Cromwell's
army will soon cure your wit, my lad.
I am not doing any fighting,
neither for the King
or your precious Cromwell, either.
- You mark that well, soldier.
- Yeah, you coward.
Just like your friend.
- Matthew Hopkins is no friend of mine.
- Hopkins?
The fancy boy who just made a fool
of your cavalry, comrade.
- You rode with him.
- I had reasons.
- He pays you?
- We were partners.
- In what business?
- Extermination.
- Eh?
- And what does that mean?
Now,
Matthew Hopkins, sir.
- Adequate, very adequate.
- We did our best, sir.
Lavenham has served me well,
Master Webb.
Now I must find out how I can serve you.
They're all women, sir.
Strange, isn't it, how much iniquity
the Lord vested in the female?
Pardon, sir?
- Who makes the accusations?
- Myself, sir. I'm representing the town.
- How many?
- Three, sir.
And what age?
Well, two are young, sir,
Elizabeth Clark and Mary Reynolds.
The other's worn and old.
Fetch the young pair here to me.
What of the other hag?
Well, the old ones are more sensible.
It's the young ones who are stubborn.
They require time.
Oh, I see.
- Sir?
- Yes, man?
Your assistant, sir. We were told
he, too, would be coming to Lavenham.
He's engaged elsewhere.
He's fighting for the Parliamentary cause.
Oh. He will be joining you here, sir?
I really can't say.
- You can manage without him?
- Of course.
- I apologize...
- No.
Not only can I manage without him,
but I intend to instigate
a new method of execution,
and you, Master Webb,
you shall aid me in carrying it out.
- What's that, sir?
- You'll see.
It's a fitting end for the foul ungodliness
in womankind.
Yes, sir.
Now, fetch that young pair here.
Sir.
An excellent meal, gentlemen.
There is little I find so satisfying
as good food after a well-earned victory.
- Wouldn't you agree?
- Entirely, General.
The conflict at Naseby, sir, will go down
as a triumph of your strategy.
Perhaps.
I would rather that it went down as
a triumph for the forces of true godliness.
Nevertheless, your name will symbolize
the victory, sir.
Whether I like it or not, eh, Captain?
That cornet you so highly recommended
to me, is he to join us?
He's coming now, General Cromwell.
Good.
Amongst the most pleasurable aspects
of victory, gentlemen,
is the opportunity it affords
to reward valor.
It ranks almost with good food.
- Cornet Marshall, sir.
- All right. Rest, Cornet.
Your captain has told me about you.
- He says you're a good soldier.
- Thank you, sir.
He recommends that
I promote you to captain.
I thank you, sir.
I have a special mission for you, Captain.
Take three men
and ride back into East Anglia.
The King has escaped us and is rumored
to be making for the Norfolk coast.
If that is the case, find and apprehend him
before he can escape to the continent.
- It's an honor, sir.
- Pick your men. Start at once.
If you find the King,
you will escort him then to Norwich.
If not, join us in the west.
Good luck, Captain.
Shall we rest up for the night, Richard?
We've got a job to do.
We'll go on till we've done it.
Do you mean looking for the King?
Or finding Hopkins and Stearne?
Both.
Richard, you can't go off and desert again.
I don't plan to desert!
But supposing you do find out
where they are?
Then I shall take temporary leave again.
For God's sake, Richard,
I know how you feel,
but to risk court-martial
to kill Parliament's own appointees,
you'll be hanged yourself.
Robert! I've taken an oath.
I won't break it!
- It's madness!
- It's justice!
It's my justice.
And what about one of them, sir?
You won't find better horseflesh
in the whole of Suffolk.
So, how much you going to try
to drag out of me if I take that one?
- He's yours for a couple of guineas, sir.
- A guinea.
A guinea and a half for getting me
out of bed at this hour of the morning.
- One guinea.
- And a quarter?
I'll quarter you.
- You drive a hard bargain, sir.
- Yeah.
And where would you be heading
that you need a horse in such a hurry?
- To find my partner.
- Your partner, eh?
And what line of business
might you be in?
God's business, witch-finding.
Witch-finding. Oh, that's nice.
That's very nice.
You wouldn't make it a guinea
and a quarter, would you?
Do you know a man
called Matthew Hopkins?
- You know where he is?
- I heard tell of such a man down south.
Lavenham, I believe.
What's he doing in Lavenham?
Extracting confessions, I don't doubt.
You let me have
that four-legged cripple now!
This happened three days ago.
Why didn't you report it
to the militia then?
How should we know
it was the King himself?
A stranger, obviously a townsman,
tries to hire a boat to cross to France
- and you suspect nothing?
- When the country's torn by civil war?
I didn't know there was a war on
till you gentlemen told me so.
Oh, come on, Richard.
We'd better go back.
Aye, I suppose so. I want to pass through
Lavenham and see how Sara is.
- Lavenham?
- Aye, how far is it from here?
About two days ride, I reckon.
They got more excitement over there
than any of your city folk's wars.
- What do you mean?
- They're burning witches there, I hear.
- Some such rigmarole.
- They're in Lavenham!
Richard!
Elizabeth! Elizabeth!
Oh, God!
- All is ready, Master Hopkins?
- Aye.
Proceed with the executions, then.
Bring forth Elizabeth Clark.
Right. Siegel, fetch the rope.
Get the rope.
Oh, come on, you little bitch!
No! Help!
No!
- Lower away.
- Slowly, now. Keep her slow.
Elizabeth!
Master Hopkins,
there are two more to be burned.
Yes, Magistrate. Master Webb, the others!
Here you are, 12 guineas in silver.
To be spent in the service
of our Lord, Magistrate.
We must thank you for your good work,
Master Witchfinder.
Thank you, Magistrate, for your aid.
- Witchfinder!
- Greetings, Stearne.
Is that all you've got to say after
leaving me there with Cromwell's men?
Well, I provided us both
with the opportunity to escape.
Only you did and I was captured.
Fortunes of war, Stearne.
You know me well enough to know that
I wouldn't hesitate to fire and kill you.
Aye, you would that.
I hold all human life dearly, Stearne,
especially my own.
Oh, come now.
- You've escaped and all is well.
- Maybe.
I even saved your share of the pay
even though I did all of the work myself.
Now, are you going to be sensible
or do I kill you?
By the way, do you know
what they call me now?
What?
Witchfinder General.
There are those who think that I should be
appointed such for all of England,
appointed by Parliament.
Here! Look.
- Sara. She's here.
- Very nice, eh, Matthew?
No, you fool.
Don't you realize that if she's here,
that trooper must be around, too?
- But he's away fighting.
- Suppose he got leave after Naseby.
Where do you think he'd go?
To see her, of course.
- We better move along then, eh?
- No.
That man, Marshall,
is not going to give up.
He's proved that to us already.
Then we have to get him
before he gets us, right?
We have the power to do it, legally.
- Prove him a witch, huh?
- Exactly.
- He'd never confess, not that one.
- On his own, no.
But if we had him and the girl?
Yeah, she's the niece of a man
we executed for witchcraft.
And Marshall is her husband.
I owe that jumped-up plowboy
a seeing-to.
Go out and ask around.
Find out if he's been seen.
If not, we'll tarry here a while
until he does arrive.
Who is it?
Sara, open the door. It's me.
Richard?
They were here, Hopkins and Stearne.
I didn't know what to do.
I saw them in the street.
- I didn't know if they saw me or not.
- I know.
I know.
Well, I'll be in the tavern
with the others, then.
He's here, Matthew! Just arrived.
- Where's he gone?
- To see the girl.
- Alone?
- Yeah. The three others are in the tavern.
Go and get us an extra man to help.
Where are we going to take them,
Matthew?
Up to the castle.
The magistrate here is very helpful.
That's where you interrogated the others,
is it?
Yes.
Now, hurry to it, man.
What are you going to do?
You say Hopkins arrived two days ago.
Yes, and then he was with the other one
in the street today.
And they haven't left yet?
I'm not sure. I've been
too scared to leave.
Come on! Open up in there!
Drop that sword, soldier.
This man accuses you, Sara Lowes,
and you, Richard Marshall,
of consorting with the Devil.
- Is that not so, Master Webb?
- It is that, sir.
Will you describe your evidence to us?
I observed the accused talking
with their familiars
and making the signs of Satan, sir.
And what were these familiars
to which you refer?
Black cat and a stoat, sir.
You're a very observing citizen,
Master Webb.
Well, Sara, do you confess?
And what do you have to say, soldier?
I'm going to kill you, Hopkins.
I don't think you'll find that easy.
The law is with me, remember?
And what are you? An accused witch.
They must be submitted to the test.
Take them, Stearne.
Hopkins!
A Royalist sympathizer,
evidently.
But what are we going to do with him?
Leave him. I'll inform
the magistrate later.
We have more important work to do.
Come on.
Get moving.
Orders from the magistrate.
Suspected witches.
Yes, sir. Sorry, sir.
I heard them.
Where are they taking them?
To the castle to test them.
Test them?
They're accused of witchcraft.
- Harcourt, you come with me.
- Yes, sir.
- Shall I look after him, sir?
- Yes, try and find him a physician.
I've heard much of how
Hopkins conducts his interrogations.
Come on, Harcourt.
All right, Stearne.
No!
Well, Captain Marshall,
do you now confess?
Keep at it, Stearne.
You're doing God's work.
Put her over here.
And you, Master Webb, help him.
Master Hopkins and his assistants,
are they here, man?
- That they are, sir.
- Well, let us pass, then.
You're here to help the Witchfinder?
- We're here to find him, yes.
- Have you a signed pass?
Sara, I'm going to place this iron
on your back.
Should you faint or cry out,
we can only take it that Satan has
intervened to spare you your agony.
However, I could show mercy if...
If Captain Marshall were to confess
to witchcraft first.
But will you do it, sir?
I shall kill you.
So, you have no
proper authorization, then.
What do you mean?
- From the magistrate. Authorization.
- Not here with us, no.
Well, we'll go back and get one then.
All right. Then I'll let you pass.
Master Webb,
go and see what is the matter.
Yes, Master Hopkins.
What do we do, Matthew?
We shall carry on with God's work
as before, man.
And fetch Captain Marshall over here.
He shall kneel before his wife
and watch her suffer.
- But Matthew...
- Go do it, man!
Oh, God!
You took him away from me.
You took him from me.
You took him from me!
May God have mercy on us all.