How do you do that?
Hey, Daddy, look at me!
I'm not wearing any underwear.
Are you going to be able to concentrate?
Not if you aren't here.
I'm on my way.
We hit some weather in Washington,
so I just got off the plane.
I don't think I'll make curtain,
but I won't miss your entrance.
Have I ever missed?
What's wrong?
Today is the last show.
Aw. Are you sad for us or for the show?
For us.
Oh, I'm touched.
Hold on.
Hang on, Victor.
- Hey, what's up?
- Client doesn't like London now.
- Is Paris set up?
- Yeah.
- I just have to talk to Brian.
- Already did, he's fine with it.
Looking forward to seeing us
in New York for a champagne toast.
I said,
'Friday would be okay?'
Sounds fine.
I'll call you later, okay?
Russell?
- Sorry, baby.
- That your husband?
Uh-huh.
Now where were we?
Oh yeah, my underwear.
Look, I didn't want to tell you
this over the phone, but.
I've fallen in love with you.
Shit, hold on.
What is it, Victor?
I am counting on you for dinner, you know.
Why?
What do you mean, why?
George is dawdling on this thing.
He desires you and I think he can
close it tonight, that's why.
You know, I don't think I can make it.
But I'll try to make dessert, okay?
Don't wait for me.
George?
Thanks for holding.
Listen, 9:00 might be better
if it's not too late.
Good.
- Russell?
- Yes.
We had a deal, remember?
So you're just going to have to deal
with me pining and moaning over
what we might've had together.
You didn't hang up.
Not yet.
So what does that mean?
I can't do this.
If you're going to bail,
you'd best do it now.
Sweet.
But you didn't scare her away.
Sounded too much like you meant it.
I did.
10 minutes till curtain everyone.
Here we go, folks.
Last night.
Well, then I feel like Cupid.
Please, don't hurt her
if that's what this is about.
Do you believe in God?
Yes, I do.
Life's a walking shadow,
a poor player, that struts
and frets his hour upon the stage
then is heard no more.
It's a tale told by an idiot
full of sound and fury
signifying.
nothing.
If you move or speak,
this blows.
It's very sensitive.
For the next few moments
you're going to be closer to your God
than you've ever been.
Don't waste it.
Early curtain tonight, everyone.
Let's get going.
Help.
What, motherfucker?
Jeez,
say something, fool.
Hey, Dwayne,
how's the salmonella business?
Hey, Papa Chulo.
I got kosher, man.
I got turkey,
100% beef, you know,
and all that good stuff.
- What, no vegetarian?
- I got vegan, best on the market.
Can't tell the difference.
Forget it.
Me, I'm going to go all the way.
- 100% beef.
- And lips.
It's true. What do you think
they do with the lips, man?
Anus and spleen and all that stuff.
It's all 100% cow.
Very funny.
I'll see you next week.
Give my regards to your boss.
Russell?
Has anyone seen Russell?
Did you lose my little darling again?
He told me he'd be back by now.
Have you seen him?
In the carnal sense?
No, not yet.
Hey, find the ice queen
rich bitch and you'll find him.
- Russell.
- Help.
Russell?
Please don't do this to me again.
Russell you will personally
be responsible for my heart attack.
Five minutes, everyone.
She's still not in her seat?
He left a message on my cell 10 minutes ago
saying he would be here 10 minutes ago.
Shit. Okay,
five more minutes, everyone.
- Should I be getting dressed?
- Fuck off.
Okay.
I'll get dressed anyway,
just in case.
So you want to spot me another gram?
- It's the weekend.
- Can't do that, Mel.
I got a big day, bro'.
Look, I'm going to tell you something, man.
My boss is a mean son of a bitch, all right?
I got kids, you know?
A hundred. I'll give you
the rest Monday. end of day.
Don't be waving that shit around here, man.
Jesus.
- Hey.
- I swear.
- You the man, Dwayne.
- Whatever.
Hello, Dwayne.
Hey!
- Has it been a week already?
- Yeah.
Last performance tonight.
We're having a big party.
Yeah?
Well, they got some big numbers
coming in from New York next.
- Oh, yeah.
- Yeah.
Big deal.
Oh.
Wow.
You take care of yourself, huh?
Got a good thing going on,
you and me, huh?
Liberty Wallace.
Nice to meet you,
- My name's Joe.
- What could I do for you, Joe?
Stand still.
Excuse me?
I'll need you to pay attention.
Look, I'm late for a play.
Who is this?
You mean you're late for your weekly fuck?
Asshole.
Look, asshole, whoever you are,
if you call one more time.
I didn't expect to like Russell.
But then again, I guess you
didn't expect to like him either.
About a half hour?
Dwayne had to take a whiz.
. so he needs you to step in.
What do you want?
Calm.
Walk over to the hot dog stand.
You need to be closer.
You need to know I've locked a signal
onto your cell number.
There's a bomb,
a really big bomb,
in that hot dog stand.
I'll shoot innocent people.
We've got a bit of ground to cover,
so I don't want to have to kill you.
Walk closer
to the stand.
If your cell phone goes dead
or you touch the mute button
for any reason, it'll blow.
It's irreversible translation.
No off switch.
There's enough explosive in there
to take out the whole block.
So.
you have a little problem on your hands.
Now take a breath.
Liberty, could please check your battery?
'Cause we need to know how much time we have.
It's half charged.
That gives us about 80 minutes.
There's a pair of cuffs hanging on the cart.
You've got quite a decision to make.
Tell me what you want.
Your soul.
Fine, name a price.
Do you really think
I'd go through all this trouble
for cash?
You're going to have put on that ankle cuff.
Then we're going to have a talk.
Do it.
- Do it.
- No!
Okay, okay.
No.
On your ankle, please.
Tug.
Show me it's secure.
Good.
Okay, now I'll make an honest man of myself.
Open the top left door of the cart.
Jesus.
I'm guessing you know what that is.
I take it you have some political affiliations.
No.
That's the problem.
I need yours.
Look, we could just cut to the chase here.
I'm guessing you have a 223.
It's sophisticated.
- You mean expensive.
- That too.
- Which means you're connected.
- Yeah.
All right, you've got me
standing still. What's next?
Easy.
I get to decide how this goes down.
I know it's not Russell,
because he's backstage
thinking about your future.
He's wondering whether you
put your panties back on
and are making a run for it.
I'm sure you're wondering
if I'm working for your husband.
I'm not.
If he knew about Russell he'd take it hard
and he's a very violent man.
Hey, is Dwayne around?
No, he stepped away.
Is he going to be back soon?
Did he leave anything for Frank?
Tell him something,
he looks desperate.
- No.
- What?
No, I don't eat meat.
Thank you.
He thinks you warned him about the cops.
You having fun, Joe?
Yes.
But not like you think.
How much do you want?
Nothing.
It's not about cash.
It's about you.
You have two choices.
First, you die an American hero.
Second.
you die still working for the fat man.
Look, I have accounts all over the world.
I have unlimited resources.
Tell me how much you want.
Is it all champagne inside that pretty head?
I don't see where this is going.
Ah, Liberty.
Memory lane.
The former you.
Life before the Bulgari handbag.
What happened?
- You know my husband.
- Can't pin this on him.
He's just a thug working on any side of the law
that'll give out a check.
By the medals he earned during
his stint with the military,
some would say he's a hero.
And what would you say,
Liberty?
I don't think this is about
what I think of my husband's track record.
Do heroes pray for war so that
they can sell their bullets?
We never discuss our business.
Okay, Liberty.
You're in my sightline,
you're standing next to a bomb,
and you're not at liberty to discuss
that you and your husband manufacture guns
and sell them to any fucking country,
or street asshole,
or all-American kid who'll pay you the cash.
Hooray for the American dream.
If you want something,
ask for it,
otherwise,
I'm just going to hang up.
Go ahead.
Is this about the sale to Poland?
- Serbia.
- Poland.
Denial is a curious thing.
The shipment never made it to Poland.
Serbians, Croats.
kids on both sides.
all died.
What's the fucking difference?
So you were there?
Go on, honey.
Hot dog, please.
Sure. Sure.
No mustard.
I said no mustard.
Cute. Don't make me pull the trigger.
- He's just a kid.
- I have nothing to lose, Liberty.
Or haven't you figured that out yet?
Go.
You know,
you know a lot about me.
What I'm thinking,
who I'm fucking.
just amazing, Joe.
And I'm your only friend at this moment.
- My final confessor.
- That too.
So you whacking off right now, baby, hmm?
Working out some domination bullshit?
Tread carefully,
dear heart.
Why? In this game of yours,
the way I see it,
I die either way.
May as well have some fun.
VP Marketing, McCloud,
standard in American weaponry.
Kind of like Beretta is to the Italians.
Ah, so that's what this is about.
Your dilemma is.
when to pull the plug.
pull the plug.
Who are you going to take with you?
And who are you going to take with you?
Aah!
What was that?
Now.
you've just been shot at
by your best-selling rifle.
How does it feel?
How's it supposed to feel?
Real.
Fine, I'm terrified.
Is that what you want me to say?
Well, it's a start.
And you've got a little over an hour
to sound like you really mean it.
You want to know what makes me
so twisted?
Crazy?
The whyof it all?
It's kind of funny.
Right now I feel absolutely sane.
But I know what it's like
to be twisted and crazy.
Something I don't think
that you've ever experienced.
Well, I've had my moments.
Don't compete.
You're right, you're probably
crazier than I've ever been.
I'll take a long walk,
and then you'll know.
I mean, I don't have to.
Good God, he sucks.
I can't go out there.
So, you're quite a shot.
Yeah. I started with BBs and squirrels.
You're a pretty crack shot yourself.
Well, you know, my father wanted
a competition kid,
so I went for the medals.
You know what he did to me
the first time he took me
out in the bush?
He shot this deer.
The deer had a fawn.
You know what he made me do?
He made me shoot it.
Close range.
And you pulled the trigger.
I hated him for making me do it.
- I had nightmares.
- How ironic.
Yeah.
Come on, let's get back to the point.
Why are you doing this, Joe?
You must meet all kinds in your business.
- Why do they?
- Come on, I sell corporately.
It's not like I deal with every asshole
who wants to wave a big dick at something.
So it's about my dick?
What if Russell slit his wrists?
We should call the police.
Slit his wrists?
Russell's the happiest man I've ever met.
Happiness is the best cover
for clinical depression.
What? Did he tell you he was depressed?
The man is dating a barracuda.
What's not to be depressed about?
You know, we're in a bit of a time jam here.
This guessing game's getting a bit tiring.
Why don't you just tell me what's going on?
Fair enough.
I want you to understand loss.
You lost someone.
to a gun accident?
No accident.
A willful act.
Premeditated.
Your wife?
Son?
Your daughter.
Look, I'm really sorry for you and your family,
but is this how she'd want you to act?
She's not alive to ask.
Why would you want more blood on your hands?
Misery needs company.
The blood is going to spill into your hands,
where it belongs,
Liberty.
There's hundreds of people who trade weapons.
I'm just one tiny speck in all of this.
That's all it takes.
Presidents and three-year-olds die
all in the name of the Constitution.
They have metal detectors and cops in schools.
Is that what makes America great?
Okay,
I get where this is going.
I'll denounce my involvement in weapons,
I'll denounce the industry, fuck,
I'll denounce death in general, okay?
We'll get the press here,
we'll cause a big scene.
Is that what you want?!
You're so full of shit.
Look, I know you must be dying inside,
but I'm standing next to a goddamn bomb,
and it's going to cause some serious damage.
So if you want coverage,
Come on, let's get it going.
What were your father's last words?
He has nothing to do with this.
Yeah, I guess blowing your brains out is.
is about as much as anyone person can ever say.
You seem to know a lot
about me and my family, Joe.
It's personal.
And I get to atone for the sins
of every cheap-suit fucking gun salesman?
Yeah, and your father.
He has nothing to do with this. Fuck you!
This has nothing to do with my father.
This is about you going postal!
He's part of the family legacy.
Bullshit!
He is not.
- He is not!
- You were an impressionable kid.
His money bought you into a society
on both sides of the law.
He's definitely a part of this.
No he isn't.
Try that $5,000 watch you're wearing.
- Fine.
- Oh, better yet,
that $25, 000 wedding ring.
You got it.
Say, honey.
Where's Dwayne,
Ms. Liberty Wallace?
Oh, he had to step away.
I'm watching the stand.
You doing this for a reason?
You tell him,
I shoot him.
It's hot today.
His life is in your hands, Liberty.
Put your clothes on.
Yeah! I'll take whatever you're selling.
Beat it.
A hot dog for the road.
Oops.
- Good for sales.
- I said beat it!
All right.
Whatever you're on, lady,
get more of it.
You're pissing me off.
I'll be right back.
Uh-huh.
You're signing his death warrant.
Is that what you want?
It's show time.
Your actions have consequences.
You shot him?
God, you shot him.
He's dying as we speak.
Tell me what you want.
For one,
your company just made
a deal worth several million dollars.
You're not going to deliver.
Officer,
are you all right?
Oh my God.
Hello?
Yeah, there's an officer here.
He's bleeding.
I don't know, I think
the corner of 9th and Grace?
Fuck him he was a bad cop.
That dick did it on the take.
My name?
It's George.
McCannister.
I'm just standing here,
I don't really want.
Yeah, I'll wait.
I guess.
A fucking lot of people are about to arrive.
This is your window of opportunity, Liberty.
- Let's call your husband.
- No, don't.
- I'll three-way you.
- Don't!
McCloud Industries,
Victor Wallace's office.
- Yes, is he there, please?
- May I say who's calling?
- Liberty.
- Ex cuse me?
His wife.
I'm calling for his wife,
who asked me to call
because she's in a bit of a jam right now.
Please hold.
Make a copy and distribute it
to code red level security.
Mr. Wallace,
your wife is on the line, sir.
- What's up, Lib?
- She's on the other line.
We're conferenced.
And who is this?
I'm Joe. Your wife's cuffed
to a bomb wired to blow
if the cell phone dies.
I've also got one of your rifles pointed at her
so I can shoot her
or anyone else I figure isn't working out.
Liberty?
Oops. Is he always that sympathetic?
He probably thinks you're a terrorist.
Terrorist?
Why is that?
Because of the deals
you cut with Senator Tollman?
Government involvement is classified.
Hey, they're on their way, all right?
Just hold on a second.
Your husband just hung up on you.
That's because he thought he was protecting me.
We signed a no-deals policy
so we wouldn't be vulnerable
to every...
every fucking terrorist.
It was a condition for the military.
Oh, please.
What does signing a contract
really have to do with it?
Don't answer.
- Liberty?
- Hey, it's me.
It's for real. I'm at the corner
of 9th and Grace.
I have about 45 minutes left on my battery.
Liberty, talk to me.
Any idea who we're dealing with?
No.
He said something about us bailing on a deal.
I don't know what he's talking about.
The only one big enough
is the one going through Paris.
- Nothing more specific?
- No!
I don't get it.
How did you leave it with Washington?
Done.
The money's wired.
What does he want?
Hijack the shipment?
I don't know what he wants!
He won't tell me.
- This could be goodbye.
- Don't get dramatic.
If they wanted you dead,
you would be.
I'm hanging up now.
I'm on it.
- I don't fucking believe you.
- If you do that again.
I'll shoot innocent people on your behalf.
Oh, he didn't even say goodbye, did he?
Well, he's got a lot at stake.
International arms dealing is tricky business.
No loyalties.
Call Brian.
- I already did.
- Oh, good boy.
Very good boy.
This is a hostage situation.
Your hands are tied.
What am I supposed to do now,
go and sip tea in a safehouse
while my wife is chained to a bomb?
Calm down.
You're a target too.
She knows the drill.
You both signed the security agreement.
- The machinery just kicked in.
- I'm calm. I'm very calm.
Shit.
Step away.
Did you see what happened here?
I didn't see anything.
1986 request backup.
Request immediate backup.
Shots fired, officer down,
possibly dead.
Oh my God.
He's barely got a pulse.
Do you have an open marriage,
or is it all just pretend from the beginning?
I'm sure this isn't about our marriage.
But I'm the last person you're
going to speak to on this Earth,
so might as well tell me everything.
- He'll hunt you down.
- He might hunt you down.
You just became a security risk.
You know, they took out JFK
over the price of oil,
so I'd say your chances
of being a military target
are pretty high.
Like you said,
the stakes are high.
This is all more important than an individual.
Am I right? Is that what
you tell yourself every day?
I'm only a cog
in the great wheel of misfortune.
That's the way it is.
How did you end up here?
How the fuck did that happen?
I can make a deal or break one.
I have my own connections.
Get back to your little theater gig,
backstage every Thursday.
body guards, off limits,
of course.
Do you pretend,
it's passion,
or is it like taking Prozac?
Leave Russell out of this.
He better be dead, or I swear
to God I'm going to kill him.
Call his publicist.
She'll know where he's hiding.
You're on, folks.
Name your terms, Joe.
This is about dignity.
My daughter's death robbed her of hers,
You're going to dredge up whatever
little nobility you have left.
and give the world a little of what she had.
Can't believe she'd want this.
She was a fighter.
Unlike you,
I wasn't.
I had to make a choice.
Jump out the window,
or live by the rules that she died by.
What happened to her?
A boy in her school.
Armed and fucked up.
Headlines that make every
mommy and daddy in America
cross their fingers.
Ah, but for the grace of God go I.
So.
now I'm using the same right
to bear arms that he had.
It's an all-in package,
I was told.
And you can't fuck with freedom.
to quote a phrase.
How do you know that?
What?
Your father's last words.
Ah. Brilliant.
Brilliant way to go out,
I thought.
In fact, it's.
it was what made me choose
you as the spokesperson.
Nobody knew what my dad's note said.
Just fucking shoot me.
Get it over with,
I'm sick of your bullshit.
How do you know so much about me?
I'm good with details.
Nobody knew what was in that note, Joe.
Only the cops,
it was a long time ago,
the files are filed.
Unless you're a cop.
Is that it?
What makes you think you should do this?
You don't have kids,
so you don't know.
God.
Bless America,
Just give us a minute,
stay there.
What do you make of that?
Stand beside her.
Psych ward.
She may have seen something.
I'll check it out.
Hey, get back here.
I don't want them getting any closer.
What do you got your hands in the air for?
Don't come any closer.
Looks like your husband sent some goons
to protect you and your relationships.
He has Washington,
the Middle East,
the Mayor's office,
the police, the mob.
You guys work on all sides of the fence.
Must be hard to keep track.
Did you see what happened over there?
This is really about Victor.
You're a package.
What?
Now it's time to make your deal with God.
- You all right?
- Say no.
His walkie signal is a bad thing
for sensitive explosives detonators.
Get back!
There's a bomb in here.
Did she say bomb?
So.
The chick's a looney.
Now what?
Well, thank you,
for getting the ball rolling
but improvise again and everything goes boom.
She said there's a bomb.
Let's call the Henry guys,
just in case.
Dispatch 11, 1986,
requesting Henry unit
into the alley of 10th and Grace, ASAP.
Request DLT traffic control
between 7th and 12th,
Olive and Bay.
Henry unit on its way.
It's gang turf. Could be something
he stuck his nose into.
RTO 1986 Henry Car returning.
Code three, responding
from Valencia to downtown.
All right, copy, Dispatch.
Should we clear the area?
1986, stay with officer.
wait for H unit and supervisor.
Paramedic, ETA,
seven minutes.
Copy.
Gentlemen, you're in a bit
of a grizzly situation here.
Bill,
you're here early.
Give us some space,
all right?
You know I'm always on the hunt for that Emmy.
Yeah. We've got nothing for you, yet.
Family hasn't been informed,
no names yet.
What happened?
Bill, we've been here five minutes.
Just back off, you'll be
the first to know, I promise.
Okay. Yeah.
Promises, promises.
One Adam 97,
respond.
Repeat. One Adam 97,
please respond.
Bill Tollman.
Look at the hotdog stand.
She can tell you the story.
No cameras yet.
Stay on the phone.
I want to know who you are
before I get any deeper into this.
You were happy to get a tip 20 minutes ago.
Why all the sudden the change of heart?
Because a cop is down.
Then you can help.
You're the onlyone I'll let her talk to.
She saw it all.
One Adam 18,
Alameda and 11th.
ETA, 12 minutes.
Bill!
Jesus Christ Bill.
Get back here.
The bomb squad's on the way.
I got a guy on the cell phone,
tells me she's got the whole story.
Son of a bitch.
Wait until he gets back here.
No one. not you, not us.
goes over there.
I swear to God I'll take you down, Bill.
Now get back here.
Joe: Welcome to our party.
We're conferenced.
A-team, Liberty Wallace,
please let me introduce you to Bill Tollman.
We're lucky to have Bill join us.
He's ambitious, smart,
and for the most part.
honest.
I'm sorry.
And you are?
I'm Joe.
I'm out for vengeance.
Liberty needs forgiveness.
And we both need publicity.
Why me?
Your lucky day.
Why don't you bring him up to speed, Liberty?
He's got a military-issue,
sniper rifle pointed right at you.
He's an ex cellent shot.
There's a bomb in the hot dog cart.
It's set to blow, if my cell phone
battery dies, for any reason.
The bomb's big enough
to blow up this entire block.
Think Oklahoma.
That theater's going to let out
in less than an hour.
I have less than an hour left on my battery.
I die either way.
Unless you get out of here soon, so do you.
Aren't you the Liberty Wallace of...
Yes.
Any demands?
He wants.
He wants somebody to pay
for the death of his daughter.
Almost right.
Joe's daughter, died.
from a fucked up kid with a gun.
It was a gun manufactured by my company.
He wants me to die,
knowing I have blood on my hands.
Joe, you've got to rethink here.
This is crazy.
There's a real gun pointed at you.
What I mean is,
there are other ways,
Uh-huh.
That's where you come in, Bill.
You want me to use
my influence as a journalist,
to debate the right to bear arms with you,
because you've got a gun pointed at me?
I'm standing next to a bomb
that's on final countdown.
Yeah.
What happens when all this is over?
I blow my brains out.
This becomes my journalistic moment of truth.
Your Emmy.
And your quest.
I'm sorry, Joe.
What do you want me to say here?
Say yes.
No. Say that you're accountable.
There are plenty of causes, Joe.
Bill, look at Liberty.
She's going to die.
It's her choice when,
it's my choice how.
You have a similar dilemma.
Now,
Iook around.
Jesus, shit.
He shot me.
I'll do whatever he wants.
He's going to die in your arms, Liberty.
Get ready.
Watching someone die.
changes you forever.
19-86.
to Dispatch.
We have a female with a gun.
I'm not dying.
His father is Senator Robert Tollman.
He's also a constitutional lawyer.
He lobbied for the NRA,
so we know which side his bread is buttered on.
He's proud of his son.
And now like me,
has every reason to switch sides.
Hey.
How many times do I have to tell you?
Turn that fucking thing off.
Just hang on.
Help's coming.
No. It's not.
- Camera. Fucking asshole.
- Sue me.
Get him out of here.
Can't buy this kind of press.
10:00 news, buddy.
Call my father for me.
Why are you doing this?
Why?
Tell me.
Your dick is the size of
the little trigger on that gun.
That makes you nothing, Joe.
You're less than nothing.
You probably didn't even have a daughter,
if you did,
she's better off dead.
I'll forgive you for that,
given the circumstances.
Just kill me.
- Get it over with.
- Shut up.
I'm not the one shooting.
I can't take anymore.
I'm going to hang up.
That asshole's shooting with a 9 millimeter,
He hasn't got a hope
of hitting you from that distance.
Ah, Victor.
You have made my day.
Hello.
It's kind of ironic,
me saving your life.
They're here.
The officer went down over there.
The lady with the bomb is across the street.
It's time to do something.
Bill has a tape recorder,
in his suit pocket.
Name names,
Liberty.
Blow the lobbies wide open.
Payoffs are always good news breakers.
You're an amateur, Joe.
No. No. No. Don't tell me that
you're worried about the fallout.
Your husband, or someone he works for,
has or dered the CIA thugs
to put a bullet in you.
Is that the world you want to live in?
What do you think you can accomplish
by me babbling about Senator-this
and Senator-that?
That's not going to do anything.
It's a start.
It's an end, Joe.
Let me do what I can really do.
Let me work from the inside.
I can.
I can do something.
So that's what you tell yourself every morning?
Joe, I can really change things.
I promise you I'll do it.
I promise.
Police.
Put them down.
Come on.
We can always count on our nation's
finest to serve and protect.
Shots fired. I've got
a civilian down possibly dead.
Looks like a shooter.
Senator Libby
took at least three payments in cash.
Senator Lipton, Crick,
Congressmen Gomez.
Check Geneva bank accounts,
Swiss Union bank accounts,
Cayman Islands, Bahamas.
My husband.
Victor Wallace is fucking the president's wife,
among others.
Presidents.
or wives?
Humph.
What do you want me to do?
Nothing.
You're on a roll.
Keep it going.
You're already on the news.
Victor's mobilized
every senator I've just mentioned.
The police chief is in his back pocket.
He supplies the gang that controls
this corner, for Christ's sake.
He?
Okay. I.
We.
I.
I'm in this, okay?
Is that what you want me to say, 'I'm in it'?
Yes.
Now, who are you going to trust?
Nobody.
- Keep talking.
- No.
I'll name names,
I'll bury everyone who deserves it,
but you have to shut this bomb off.
Uhh. can't.
Then I can't.
Fair enough.
You've done your job anyway.
Now we can depend on Bill's dad, the senator,
and his newfound quest.
He'll go down as a hero for the cause.
It was a life well spent.
In the big picture.
Have a hot dog.
You don't want to go out on an empty stomach.
Let them take him away.
Ma'am.
Come with me, ma'am.
Over here.
Every Thursday,
they meet backstage,
go into Russell's dressing room,
and lock the door.
They order in.
Bastard changed the lock.
Fuck.
Yeah, she slinks out sometime during the night,
and we don't see Russell again
until the next performance.
Oh. Ex cept for tonight.
He's probably in there,
fucked to death.
Uh-oh.
Time to call a locksmith.
Back up's coming in from 53.
Look's like we've got ourselves a sniper.
There's no I.D.
on the woman,
no trace on her cell phone yet.
If she's chained to the stand.
She told officers there was a bomb, all right?
We believe she's working with the sniper.
The man on the ground out there,
is a reporter with KNBS.
Bill Tollman,
the senator's son.
We believe shot.
We have a confirmed fatality
in a parking structure back here.
We don't have enough information on that yet,
but we can't rule out terrorists,
militia, or just a basic nutcase.
We're going to block
5th to 10th, Olive to Berry.
We've got at least 20 buildings to evacuate.
We're thin on manpower.
Use uniforms to back you up.
All right?
Be safe, gentlemen. Let's go.
Captain.
We've got no location on the shooter,
no I.D. on the woman.
We've got backup coming in.
We're set up in the garage back here.
Somebody shut them down.
Jesus.
Clear the media back, please.
We are live.
The drama continues in downtown LA,
where we apparently have
a fatal shooting of an officer,
here at the corner of Grace and 9th.
Is your wife going to be tuning in?
No.
But I guarantee your husband's watching.
Back to you, Dennis.
My husband.
My husband's on the way to the airport by now.
He will be unreachable for comment.
Why'd you marry him?
I thought he could save my father's company.
It was a bad idea.
I even thought I loved him.
Should we do a shield rescue
for the guy on the ground?
No. It's too risky until
we find out where the shooter is.
Poor bastard's gonna bleed out.
I want all traffic locked down
from 5th to 9th.
Yeah, that's done already.
Who's the negotiator on call?
John's going to be here in 10 minutes, Captain.
Joe, more death isn't going
to make the guns disappear,
it's not going to bring your daughter back.
I'm begging you.
Oh. Liberty.
Tiananmen Square boiled down to one man,
standing in front of a tank,
that couldn't move or shoot.
Because human dignity was stronger
than steel or bullets.
It changed a nation.
That was a completely different situation.
What's the difference?
We've got gated communities,
security systems, and kids
carrying combat weapons,
all because most people
haven't even read the 2nd amendment.
So,
our freedom of speech,
is protected,
as long as we don't piss off a guy with a gun.
I'm not brave enough
to take a bullet for my country.
You underestimate yourself.
The one thing that guarantees our freedom,
and independence,
is responsibility.
We lost that somewhere between
Vietnam and presidential blowjobs.
Many of the Fathers of the Constitution.
had slaves,
but they wrote a document,
about freedom.
Go figure.
So you see,
things are meant to change.
We're all grown up now.
So are you, Liberty.
I think you've figured out
there's no such thing
as a politically correct gun.
I'll say all that to the press.
But please turn this bomb off, Joe.
I don't know what to do next.
It feels like this whole thing was a dream.
I should have told you before, but I.
What do we do now?
Huh.
The cops have.
G-36's.
Did you make that deal too?
It was more of a donation.
I'll bet that you were a hero.
We got a big luncheon,
key to the city,
mayor in my pocket,
- You make it sound so easy.
- If you've got the cash flow,
a little planning goes a long way.
Did they know
you had just sold 26 stripped down
P-99's that went straight to the streets?
I guess it was one of those
an-eye-for-an-eye deals.
It's easy to get lost in a deal.
I know it's not an excuse.
This is a perfect fucking nightmare.
127 locations for an asshole with a gun.
We've got a cell phone we can't bust into,
and a bomb next to a theater.
Anybody picking up in there yet?
- Just voicemail.
- Fucking voicemail.
Well.
the shooter is back.
Who's he work for?
Your husband or the CIA?
Whoever's got the cash.
Who's the cowboy in the chopper?
Get him higher,
he's surveillance.
I don't want him
landing on the fucking rooftop.
Okay, you guys,
let's get in here.
Let's get into the theater.
I should have told you before, but I.
What do we do now?
It's up to you.
Do you still love me?
Of course I do.
How about you?
Of course.
It won't make a bit of difference.
How full is the theater?
It's the last performance.
I figure 10 to clear the building,
Copy that.
No one exits the front door.
Hold until we've cleared all rear exits.
Senator Tollman's son was just shot,
by the same guy who's got Liberty.
I'm calling your husband.
Why?
Yeah.
Who called the militia?
I want to talk to Liberty.
Touching.
It's not one of yours?
That's not good,
Victor.
Liberty are you there?
Such a sweet name,
don't you think?
Her parents were Republican.
I want to talk to my wife.
I'm here.
Alive.
And on TV.
I. uh.
I know, you're doing what you have to do.
You know who's calling the shots?
The president's wife?
Come on.
No, of course not.
If it were, you'd be standing here.
I'm doing what I can, but.
You know the rules, right?
Aw, honey,
fuck you.
Joe, hang up.
No, what she meant is,
why don't you let her die with some dignity?
Get the car.
- Mr. Wallace is leaving.
- Yes, sir.
Right through here.
Right this way.
Through here.
How do you know Victor?
Classified.
Keep moving this way.
Come on, let's go!
- Copy that.
- Who the fuck is she?
We just I.D.'d her,
Liberty Wallace.
the VP of McCloud,
married to the CEO,
connections up the wazoo.
Jesus Christ.
I know him. Victor.
Yeah, we're trying to track him down right now.
Then there's no way she's
with the shooter, she's a hostage.
So I'm bait.
No, more like.
more like a showpiece.
I like your reckless side.
You travel without your body guard,
five hours every week and sometimes twice.
You're a little bit more
accessible and predictable
than the president's wife.
So, who's pissed off at Victor, the president?
No.
It's all me this time.
I was a dad.
I'm not anymore.
Somebody's pulling your string.
Who is it?
No one.
Not now.
Never thought my skills from
my former life would ever payoff.
CIA?
Well.
that too.
Come on,
if I'm gonna die
I have the right to know
my assassin a little better.
I worked covert.
covert operations for the CIA.
I was in China during Tiananmen Square,
Cuba, Panama,
and I was in Columbia.
when my daughter was killed.
This is Captain Hank Wilford.
Could you tell us what this is about?
I don't want anyone else to die
because they're talking to me.
So, what's it gonna be?
Huh-uh-uh.
It's your show, baby.
Just leave me out of this for now.
There's a bomb in the hot dog cart!
It's set to blow when my cell phone dies.
In about 15 minutes.
I'm chained to the cart.
What are the demands?
A public debate of the 2nd amendment.
- Hmm.
- Heard of it?
Go, girl.
I'd like to understand,
are there any other demands?
Can I come closer?
Any other demands?
No.
No!
Liberty,
I will kill anyone who comes close.
We have no confirmation yet,
but it appears that KNBS reporter, Bill Tollman
has been seriously hurt.
And that Liberty Wallace of McCloud Guns
is demanding a public debate
about the constitution,
and its role in our violent times.
She's grandstanding,
got to be militia.
Sir.
Yeah.
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir, Liberty Wallace.
You were good under the pressure.
And the whole world will applaud you.
Or laugh at me.
The press is the least
of my concerns at this point.
I'll try to move them back, but.
Yes, sir.
I'll move them back right away.
Thank you, sir.
Get rid of the press.
Tell them it's a safety issue.
Uptown doesn't want this thing
under a microscope.
They're gonna make a move, Joe.
They'll never disarm that bomb.
They probably already guessed that.
You won't be alone in the final moment.
Status on the theater?
Somebody welded all the side exits shut.
We've got an entering team coming in,
- But the fire department.
- Is stuck in traffic.
- All exits?
- Yeah, our cutters won't work.
The only exit is onto the street,
and through the front door.
So in effect they're hostages.
Tell me about your daughter again.
A boy at school put a gun to her head,
and asked her
if she believed in God.
What did she say?
I don't know.
Is that robot ready to go?
It'll be here in 15.
What about the bomb truck?
We've got one coming in from the 48.
ETA. 30 minutes.
General evacuation?
We've got a full retreat going.
We'll find this son of a bitch.
It'll just take a little time.
Tell me about your father.
My father.
He was my hero.
He was.
After he...
you know.
I had to leave school to earn a living.
One thing led to the next.
I found myself working in the family business
that was no longer family-owned.
Captain, I've only got 10 guys.
We should be fine once the 53 squad shows up.
That should be another 10 or 12 minutes.
We're not gonna make it.
It's all I knew.
Along came Victor,
he was brilliant, thought he could
save my father's company.
Our first big deal was with the Saudis.
But the Iraqis were shooting
us with our own guns.
What do people think the government
does with all those used weapons?
Melt them down?
Make little sculptures out of them?
Once we took the company international,
suddenly we were in a different league.
It got complicated.
Here I am.
And Russell made you feel human again.
And anonymous.
You know,
my great-great-grandfather,
he designed the gun that changed
the outcome of the Civil War.
I grew up thinking that's
what we were still doing.
We are securing the building.
I'm really sorry about your daughter.
Joe.
One less breathing to help us tell our story.
We've got the shooter
on the roof of a building at 8.
I don't care if it looks like the Russians,
or the Pakistanis,
or the Girl Scouts,
that guy's voice is American.
This is an internal thing,
get on it.
I want to know who the fuck else
is shooting at my wife.
Yeah.
Where are you going?
Why?
The bereaved husband.
When are you gonna stop screwing around
and tell me what this is all about?
You're doing it by the book:
go on a business trip:
be unavailable for comment:
touch down in Washington
for a little face time with the client:
check the temperature.
I don't really have a whole lot
of choice, now do I?
Joe.
We know each other don't we?
Victor: Don't we?
You do any time in South America?
Well, who didn't?
None of us really came through that
with our mental health intact,
did we?
God knows,
it took me a while
to pull my shit together when I got back.
Yeah.
Yeah,
it's a mental health thing.
You talk like a company man.
Or at least, well,
you were a company man,
because they'd never go for
this kind of theatrical bullshit.
What is your beef with me?
That you'd run away and let them take Liberty.
That you're not man enough
to stand up for your wife.
Hope you're impressed with your life.
Grace and 9th.
- Sure about that, sir?
- Grace and 9th!
You've got it.
- Shooter's still out here.
- Shit, take cover fast.
The sniper is shooting
at our guys on the ground.
How many down?
No report yet.
Luke, it's Mac. We have the shooter.
We've got the guyon the roof.
Nobody moves until we get
more information. Understood?
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee,
blessed art thou amongst women,
blessed is the fruit of thy womb Jesus.
Looks like we've got a problem up here.
It's not the sniper.
Well, who the fuck is he?
Why is he shooting?
No report yet.
...pray for us sinners,
now and at the hour of our death.
Amen.
Chuck says he's talking
the gold star clearance.
CIA?
Jesus, get him down here
if he's still breathing.
Joe,
what is enough?
Are you begging for lives?
Yes.
Where are the shots coming from?
My guys are thinking the brick,
maybe the concrete.
I'm thinking higher than the.
Way too much information.
Status on backup?
It's probably a hoax.
I think it has something
to do with her husband.
Russell's been playing with fire.
Now, don't be jealous, dear.
Oh, fuck off.
Victor knew your voice.
Is this some kind of setup?
Come on, now think hard
and you'll get it all figured out.
What the fuck do you mean, think?
Come on, come clean.
You've taken my life,
you owe me that much.
If I'm CIA or FBl,
then I went through all of this
because someone very high up
wants a lot of visibility.
Okay, okay,
it was a stupid thought.
Look, you can't write this off
to be some big conspiracy.
That's gonna confuse
the fuck out of all of them.
Think. Think about how
you're doing on the scoreboard.
It's not like I woke up one day and said,
'Wow, it's great to be
in the lethal weapons business.'
It's like the guy on the corner
who sells newspapers,
it's what I do.
- What else am I gonna do?
- Be the boss!
It's your life, isn't it?
If the idea was for me to see God,
you've achieved it.
I mean, I prayed, for Christ's sake.
To the parking garage.
Let's assemble in there. Let's go!
When my daughter was killed,
my wife came apart.
We met the parents of the kid who did it.
His father...
cried.
And he told us that he had taught his son
how to use a gun safely.
Never saw it coming.
I wanted to kill that kid.
Then I wanted to kill the father.
But.
here I am instead.
I like you.
This is no way to die.
For us there's no other wayout.
I thought about this for a long time.
Bomb squad wants us to move further back.
Captain, it's Victor Wallace on the line.
Nobody move.
Victor, Hank here.
Hank?
Jesus Christ.
Do you know what this is about?
I was hoping you'd tell me.
I don't believe you.
We found a guyon the roof
shooting at her. He looked CIA.
- Did you get him?
- No, somebody else shot him.
The guy we've got is not the sniper
or maybe he's one of them.
My ass is hanging out here, Victor.
I need you to tell me what's going on.
What's going on?
We're dealing with a nutcase.
That's what's going on.
Yeah, or terrorists buying time.
It's only been half an hour
and the press is still stacking up.
I'm five minutes away.
This action may be connected
to the recent lawsuit
filed by seven of the largest gunmakers,
alleging that efforts by government to impose
gun safety measures,
amounts to a conspiracy
that violates constitutional
guarantees of free trade.
Wallace's company, McCloud Guns,
is at the center of this controversy
by refusing to become signatory
to any government proposal
that legislates more controls.
Thanks for that breaking news.
Now on the international.
31 cities and countries
have brought charges against
manufacturers claiming they're not doing enough
to keep guns out of the
hands of children and criminals.
Apparently, Wallace is
staging a high-stakes protest
against the very industry
that made her family famous in America.
Back to you, Dennis.
We're in the final stretch, Liberty.
So,
what's your plan?
I don't want to die.
I don't want anyone else
to die because of me, Joe.
Me neither.
You know,
the NRA is just gonna
spin this and say it's because
of people like you that we need to be armed.
Well, I was an honest law-abiding citizen.
By that definition I deserve to be armed.
And I was acting out against the oppression
of our freedom.
There it is.
You know,
I first saw you in Jerusalem.
About three years ago.
You must have made a hell of a deal.
'Cause they were kissing your ass.
- Did I meet you?
- Nope.
I did business with Victor, though.
On behalf of the Saudis.
It seems he likes to sell on all sides.
We met in our early days.
Seriously flawed mission to Columbia.
I saved his life.
How funny.
I saved the life of the man
that killed my daughter.
Joe.
Thanks, Barry.
I don't feel good about this.
Death isn't as ex citing
as I thought it would be.
Excuse me, please.
Excuse me.
Excuse me,
I'm Victor Wallace.
Sir, you can't come through here.
I'm the husband,
you fucking moron.
Sir, just one question!
Don't talk to me.
Has this played into McCloud's position
on gun safety legislation?
This has absolutely nothing to do
with McCloud Industries.
These are the actions of an insane man.
And my wife is a wonderful woman.
She's a wonderful woman.
- Victor, you can't go out there.
- I just want to let her see me.
Why?
'Cause I think I know who this guy is.
And I think I can get her out of this.
Whatever you're thinking,
- I can't let...
- This is my problem.
Don't make me make problems for you.
Be good to the car.
I said the car.
Liberty!
Victor.
Hey, Alex.
Well, here we are again,
in the kill zone.
What can I do for you?
I remember the day you wept like a baby
while I promised not to let you die.
Okay, okay,
you saved my life, yeah.
Wasn't I thankful enough then?
Well, thanks again.
I mean it.
- Victor.
- But I have a feeling that.
what's really expected of me
is some sort of big,
public confession.
Am I right?
What am I supposed to say?
Joe, don't do it.
That.
that really shiny one
that I have is actually for.
for leading a bunch of men to their death?
Is that what I'm supposed to say?
Come on.
Alex, it's a war.
That's the kind of stuff that happens.
You think I'm proud of it?
I didn't ask for the medal.
Your death is gonna mean something.
But my daughter's...
won't.
Joe, don't do it.
Don't do it!
- Don't!
- Christ, he's been hit.
Get him out of here!
Get him inside fast!
Come on, pick him up!
Move!
Let's go! Let's go!
Don't!
Liberty.
Liberty!
- It's time.
- What?
Time for you to go.
The keys for your cuffs
is in a box taped to the underside
of the cart near the corner.
Okay, guys, it's got to be this one
right here, 7th and Alvarado.
Move on it!
7th and Alvarado!
Aah!
Bring the chopper into the back,
or this guy will blow it out of the sky.
Must be some kind of shooter
if he's holed up that far.
In the theater,
officer needs backup.
There's people panicking.
Smoke everywhere.
A fire's been set or something.
Hey!
Stop! Get away!
There's a bomb!
Guys, all eyes out for the Wallace woman.
Run! Run!
There's a bomb!
Run!
Liberty,
it's up to you now.
Time to choose.
Everybody, move!
Video attachment is streaming.
Senator Libby took at least
three payments in cash.
Senator Lipton, Crick,
Congressman Gomez,
check Geneva bank accounts.
You'll all be able to return to your cars,
once we secure the area.
Where's Russell?
- Where's Russell?
- I haven't seen him.
Russell!
Get out of here!
Don't!
There's a bomb!
Get out! Run!
Get out of here!
The file with the video
attachment has been sent.
As you can see,
the area has been contained.
The situation is under control.
Now, if you'll ex cuse me.
All right,
everybody into the alley, now!
All right, get the fire hose.
Find that motherfucker!
No, sir.
No other civilian casualties
from the explosion.
We've had a fire reported
in the back of the theater, sir.
No damage. No casualties.
All noise and smoke.
He made me shoot it.
Close range.
- Who are you?
- I was looking for my wife's purse.
It's not safe in here.
Get out of here.
My great-great-grandfather,
he designed the gun that changed
the outcome of the Civil War.
Where exactly were you when
the first explosion took place?
Umm. that's funny that you would ask.
Excuse me.
Mr. Perry! Mr. Perry!
I grew up thinking
that's what we were still doing.
On the other side!
I'm really sorry about your daughter.
My father.
he was my hero.
He was.
Let me do what I can really do.
Let me work from the inside.
I can.
I can do something.
Joe,
I can really change things.
I promise you I'll do it.
I promise.