Downloaded from
YTS.MX
[sinister music playing]
Official YIFY movies site:
YTS.MX
[Fay whimpering]
[tense music playing]
[chains rattling]
[footsteps approaching]
[Fay grunts]
Going live in five, four,
three, two, one.
[revolver spinning]
[gunshot]
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen,
and welcome to Russian Roulette.
You'll remember Ms. Green here,
real name Fay.
Now she was the loser
of our historic first-ever game.
Sandman52 from Germany.
Congratulations.
Your wager of 124K
is our highest correct guess.
And we all know what that means.
You and you alone get to choose.
So what's
on the trolley tonight?
[trolley rolling]
Now will it be finesse...
[Fay grunting]
...force,
[laughing]
or simple good old fashion fun?
[chainsaw buzzing]
Sandman 52, the choice is yours.
Have 30 seconds to ponder on me.
[Fay whimpering]
Any last words
while we wait, Ms. Green?
[whimpering]
Please.
Please, please, don't do this.
I'm begging you.
Please, please just let me go.
[voice breaking]
Can anyone help me?
I like to think
that my last words
would be a little more poetic
than that but to each their own.
-There must be something--
-[alarm ringing]
Sandman52, your time is up,
please ping your punishment.
[computer chimes]
Ah, the first round
of Russian Roulette
comes to an end,
ladies and gentlemen.
Not in this case with a bang,
but with a [roaring].
[chainsaw buzzing]
[screaming] No!
No, please!
[Fay shrieking]
-[loud bang]
-[Ben] Move!
[all] Police! Police! Police!
[indistinct chatter over radio]
[suspenseful music playing]
[Ben] I got eyes on him.
Stop right there.
Sam and Linda Anderson. We have a warrant
to search this property.
Hands where we can see them!
[indistinct chatter over radio]
[ominous music building]
Drop it!
[dog barking]
[suspenseful music intensifying]
-[gunshots]
-Shoot!
[police siren wailing]
Quick!
[siren wailing in the distance]
I need a medic!
[helicopter whirring]
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
[helicopter whirring]
You'll be okay.
[reporter] Two brothers,
Harry and Charlie Madden
missing for two weeks were found
overnight during a police raid
at a remote property
in North Plains
in an operation led by detectives
Benjamin Jacobs and Cathy Burnett.
The police have yet to comment
and reports
have yet to be substantiated.
But we believe both of
the children were found alive.
And we understand they have
been reunited with their parents
in a secure facility while
receiving medical attention.
We'll have more on this story
as it breaks.
[gentle melody playing]
[whispering] Hey.
Mm.
-Hey.
-How you doing?
[chuckling] Napping.
[Lisa sighs]
-I saw the news.
-Hm.
-Hey, you did good.
[Lisa] Hm.
-Hey, hey, hey.
-[gasps]
-Wow.
-[chuckles] Yeah.
[gasps] You're kicking
for Daddy, sweetheart?
Not long now...
and you'll be out in this big,
beautiful world...
with men like Daddy...
[suspenseful music playing]
to watch over us.
Keep us safe.
[sighs]
[phone vibrating]
[grunts] Yeah?
[Captain Larson]
Ben, you're needed.
We found free Randall.
-We got free Randall?
-Yes and no.
Sit down.
[tense music playing]
Ladies and gentlemen,
boys and girls,
beggars and thieves.
Welcome to the very first game
of our very first season.
What is this?
Cybercrimes came across it
yesterday after a routine sweep.
Passed it on to us immediately.
Only one bullet in a regular
game of Russian Roulette
so there can ultimately be
only one winner
in our game
of Russian Roulette.
Please get involved.
Post your comments
and keep those bets coming.
-Bets?
-A game I can confidently say
that everybody knows
only with one added
deadly double R spin.
Rock, paper, scissors.
[audience gasping]
Who the fuck is this joker?
He's no joker, Ben.
Rock, paper, scissors.
Who's she looking at?
She keeps looking that way.
Three, two, one.
[The Presenter laughing]
Best of three.
The winner lives
to fight another day
and the loser, well, loses.
Are we ready? Three, two, one.
Now, oh.
[fingers snapping]
-[cattle prod buzzing]
-[both screaming]
[Fay shrieking]
Do we know
where this is coming from?
Could be anywhere.
Cyber's on it right now,
trying to hack the feed.
Shall we try that again?
Three, two, one.
First blood.
That's more like it.
Ready for round two.
Three, two, one.
[counter buzzing]
[laughing] Oh!
We know what that means.
Just love me a decider.
Three, two, one.
-[counter buzzing]
-Oh, my God.
You could not
[indistinct] this.
The tension, I can taste it.
Actually, I can smell it.
Did one of you
just poop yourself?
Let's keep focus, here we go.
Three, two, one.
Guys...
we have a paying crowd.
A paying, paying crowd.
Let's not let them down.
Three, two, one.
-[counter buzzing]
-[bell dings]
[tense music playing]
I'm sorry.
Tune in tonight
for a results show.
You will not want to miss.
The live results show,
do you know when it is?
This was captured yesterday,
Ben.
So, we're assuming
it was yesterday too.
-But we have the feed.
-Cyber's on it.
-Who at Cyber?
-Parker Green.
-New kid?
-Mm-hmm.
[thrilling music playing]
The feed's proxy hosted
on the dark web,
their index
will have been shredded through
at least
30 levels of code refraction.
Idiot's guide.
The chances of locating
the source of the feed
from the feed itself
are in the region of one
in 7 trillion.
So we can't identify
who's running the show.
We can't find out
who's watching it either.
-So he's got us.
-For now.
We're doing everything we can,
detectives,
including echo-bouncing
the messages they sent out.
They sent out messages?
On the dark web, yeah.
How else
will they find an audience?
By now,
their computers may well know
we've got ours trying
to crack their code.
They won't know it's us.
We're just one of the many systems out
there policing the waves, uh,
but their computers
are constantly changing the code
before anyone works out
how to break it.
Basically, it's a race.
A race we win.
Most times, yeah.
Uh, really good to meet you,
Detective Jacobs.
Your stories, something else.
Win the race, Green.
[thrilling music playing]
As we know, Fay disappeared two weeks
ago after taking a walk.
No cameras in the park.
This was the last image of her.
And the other guy?
Guy one?
Trolling for a match
from missing persons.
[phone chimes]
They've got the results show.
The first round
of Russian Roulette
comes to an end,
ladies and gentlemen.
Not in this case with a bang,
but with a [roaring].
[chainsaw buzzing]
[Fay screaming] No!
No, please, no!
-[Fay shrieking]
-[chainsaw buzzing]
[blood splattering]
Oh, she was a bleeder.
And the fun
doesn't stop there, folks.
Look out
for a brand new contestant
coming soon
to a screen screen near you.
[tense music playing]
This went out last night?
Seven, our time.
Look, I don't wanna be
that guy, but...
is this real?
Is this some
fucking deep fake shit...
or is it real?
There's ways we can check.
Um, pixel of lineman,
lighting anomalies.
-Priority.
-Understood.
[cars honking]
[lighter flickering]
"Brand new contestant."
That's what he said.
Someone he's got,
someone he's gonna get.
[grunts]
We're just gonna let him
take someone off the street.
We do what we can, Ben.
And how many more free Randalls
in the meantime?
[ethereal music playing]
Very good, Lev.
Doesn't Mama look professional?
She looks funny.
Funny?
[chuckles] Well,
I guess
you've never seen your mom
looking like this before.
But the thing is,
I've forgotten to.
This is your first step back
into the job market.
Remember this.
You can do this, Katia.
You can do anything.
You left that abusive piece of--
you left that piece of work
and you brought your son
all the way over here
for a better life.
That's the woman you are.
Don't forget it.
Okay, mom.
Be good to your grandma,
okay, Lev?
-Okay?
-[whispers] Okay.
I love you, my little kotik.
I love you too.
[Katia] Aw.
[dramatic music playing]
-And any problems, just ask.
-Okay, I will.
-Good luck.
-Thanks.
That's what matters most,
what you're doing right there.
Nice big smile.
Oh, if it's that easy,
I'm gonna nail it.
-[both chuckling]
-I'm Sofia.
I'm Katia.
Jane says you've worked
in this kind of retail before.
Yes, I did.
In Moscow a few years ago now.
-Then you've got this.
-I hope so.
-[both laughing]
-[doorbell ringing]
That's for you.
[Katia chuckles]
[Katia] Hello.
-[guest] Hello.
-Welcome, welcome.
[sinister music playing]
We adjusted brightness,
screen color, gradient,
four others, plus Sam,
the rock-paper-scissors guy.
Is it good enough
for a match or what?
Two so far.
They're all wearing
color-coded armbands.
Sam Clark, Mr. Yellow.
The rock-paper-scissor guy
went missing six nights ago
after leaving
a downtown nightclub.
Witnesses say he was drunk.
Friends say he's teetotal.
Sasha Morgan, Mr. Blue.
OTH, discharged from the army
six months ago.
Possession of drugs.
Pretty much
disappeared off the system.
We're guessing homeless
or drifting
between temporary addresses
so he could have been abducted
at any time.
This is not a deep fake, Ben.
This is real.
We're doing acoustic analysis
of the audio.
It can tell us
the size of the room,
maybe even the layout, and, uh,
background noises
can give some suggestion
to the site's location, um...
about hacking the feed though,
I-- I--
I wanted to suggest something.
-What?
-Um, well, someone.
If there's one person
who stands a chance
of breaking this IP wide open...
-its [indistinct] Larch.
-Are you out of your mind?
Which is why
I decided not to bullshit,
detective,
and say it like it is.
I studied Larch's case
for my major.
The guy's in a league
of his own.
And you're the one
who got him, so.
His lawyers reached out to us
last year on the Bowler case,
-offering his help.
-He offers his help every year.
Well, maybe this time
you should say yes.
So you're admitting
you're not up to it.
I'm admitting--
-What?
-We need a specialist.
[tense music playing]
So, how was it?
Good. I think.
I hope.
Sofia was such a great help.
Well, I liked what I saw.
Well done.
See you tomorrow.
Someone deserves a drink.
A tradition
at the end of your first day
to celebrate
joining our happy little family.
I probably shouldn't.
Wouldn't want to break
a tradition on your first day.
Okay, why not? [chuckles]
[suspenseful music playing]
[Sofia] Didn't make an American
degenerate out of you yet?
America, yes.
But degenerate, no, not so much.
[laughs]
-The American dream.
-Now you're talking.
We have to drink to that.
[light jazz playing]
[both giggling]
-[both slurping]
-Mm.
Do you have a husband?
No, not anymore luckily.
But I have my true love.
This is Lev, my little kotik.
Kotik, what's that? Oh!
That's what I call my son.
Lev means lion.
Kotik means little cat.
Sweet. And who's with him now?
-My mom.
-Ah, she moved here as well.
Yeah, that's what
family's all about, right?
Yes.
We have to drink to that too.
[both giggling]
[suspenseful music playing]
[man breathing heavily]
[suspenseful music intensifying]
[footsteps approaching]
[both struggling]
[Katia grunting]
Help!
[Katia screaming]
[Katia grunting]
Help!
[Katia whimpering]
[suspenseful music intensifying]
[Katia groaning]
[Katia grunting]
[suspenseful music fading]
[suspenseful melody playing]
[Sasha] Hey.
Hey.
I know you're scared...
but try not to make a sound.
Don't move.
We're not allowed to talk.
We think
the cameras are above us...
so we can communicate a little
if we lie like this.
No movement. Just whispers.
My name is Sasha.
Katia.
Where are we?
We don't know.
What do they want?
[metal creaking]
[Sasha] Hey, hey, hey, hey.
It's okay, Katia.
You can do this.
They're going to be watching now
as you've just come in,
so we need to lay low
for a while.
But Katia, keep your mind clear.
Keep strong.
We're going to need
everyone's strength
to get out of here.
Because that's what
we're gonna do.
Understand?
[thrilling music playing]
[Katia screams]
[Katia screaming]
[Katia grunting]
Did you think for a second
she might get away,
ladies and gentlemen?
Just playing with you.
Don't forget to tune in
tomorrow
to meet
our wonderful new contestant,
the second Ms. Green.
All road signs and identifying
markers have been blurred,
but we have enough
other information to go on.
Looks like here.
Looks like Portland.
On our fucking watch.
[mysterious music playing]
Is he all good
or is this one getting to him?
This is what he does, okay?
He finds missing people.
We all know what happened.
Thinking about
what Parker suggested?
No.
We need Larch.
[indistinct shouting]
[door buzzes]
How are you, detective?
The dark web.
Hm.
Rinsed and shredded, no doubt.
But there's always a way.
You would know.
[chuckles] Oh gosh.
The market changes rapidly, Ben.
Haven't been here three years. What I know
is prehistoric by now.
So I'm wasting my time.
He's going live
with some of these?
[suspenseful music playing]
Yeah.
Within the closed network?
-I think so.
-No social media?
Nothing we can see.
As much protection
as he gives himself,
going live in any way,
that's the weak link.
Proxies have to engage
at some point.
Think of it
like a secret ducting pipe
that eventually
has to meet the outside wall.
They join there, one vulnerable screw, one
nut, one spigot,
that's where you're looking for.
Who you got?
Cybercrimes?
Well, good luck with that.
Will you let me watch
one of the feeds?
-No.
-Aw.
I could help so much more
if you let me watch
-one of the feeds.
-No.
All those nuances
that otherwise--
Read my lips.
Describe it to me then.
You got pictures.
Oh, a few pictures
is not the whole picture.
Come on,
talk me through it, Ben.
He made them play
rock-paper-scissors.
If they didn't cooperate,
they were electrocuted
with a cattle prod.
[gasps]
The loser was assassinated
in a live show later on.
Assassinated how?
-Chainsaw.
-[gasps]
The viewer
had a choice of three weapons.
-What were the other two?
-Why do you wanna know?
Full picture, Ben.
Baseball bat
and a lethal injection.
Wipe that fucking smile
off your face.
My hands are tied.
What else
am I gonna do for pleasure?
Look, I did what I did
on my dark web network
for my entertainment.
This guy, well, he's doing it
for everyone else's.
He's a showman, that's for sure.
-I wouldn't call him that.
-He would.
So I won't.
-You wanna provoke him?
-No.
-I wanna kill him.
-Oh.
I think you'll have to play
his game a little longer.
No.
-That's your ego talking.
-Fuck you.
Oh, and now it's shouting.
You wanna go over like you did
with me, full-on attack mode?
I'm a coward, Ben,
that's why it worked.
But this guy,
I think you'll have to go under
to even get through.
But the question is,
are you the man to do that?
We're not talking about me.
We're talking about the feed.
It won't help you to keep thinking of him
as a killer or evil incarnate.
He's a showman.
And that's not a job title,
it's a psychological need.
[sucking teeth]
Christ,
I'm giving you gold here,
but without a life fee there's not
much more I can tell you.
You're looking good, Ben.
Actually, why did I say that?
That's a total lie.
You're looking haunted.
You know when I killed one
it wasn't enough.
Two, yeah, kinda maybe,
but still not enough.
No number was enough,
would ever be enough.
Some things
just can't be satiated, but you know that.
Me killing, you saving,
it's the same problem, right?
Never enough
to scratch that itch
so it goes away for good.
[laughing]
Two reports
of the same missing person.
One from the store
where she works,
-one from her mother.
-The new contestant.
Katia Volkova, Russian.
Arrived here a year ago.
Last night,
the night she was taken,
that was her first day working at the
Campbell's Landing jewelry store.
We spoke with her boss there and the last
person to see her before the abduction,
a colleague, Sofia Romana.
They went for a few
first-day celebration drinks.
Where?
Little joint
on 21st and Bay Tree.
All right, pull security footage
from the bar in the local area.
What about the mother?
Thought you and me
could handle that.
Okay.
[The Presenter] Ms. Green
to the diary room, please.
[tense music playing]
[Katia screaming]
[Katia] Ah, no!
[Ben] Mrs. Volkova,
we have information
about your daughter.
She is alive.
We can't say
who has her or where,
but she is alive.
Oh, thank you.
Oh, oh, thank you.
Thank God.
Could you tell us
about any of her friends?
This is first time
she been out in months.
I-- I was happy for her.
I was hoping it was a young man.
So she talked about a young man.
No, no,
I just want her to be happy.
I want her to be happy.
[somber music playing]
Oh, my darling.
[sobbing]
[Cathy] I feel sick
knowing what we know.
[Ben] Better she doesn't.
This look familiar to you?
[suspenseful music playing]
This is it.
I'll get forensics down here.
It's a long shot,
but maybe they were sloppy.
[Katia] Ah!
[The Presenter] Settle
yourself in, welcome.
Katia.
A genuine Russian
joining our lovely game.
How are you feeling?
How do you think I feel?
I know a little fearful,
a little cautious.
Maybe, though, there's a thrill of
excitement
that you wouldn't wanna admit to.
What's your favorite color?
What?
We wanna get to know you.
It would pay to answer.
[breathing heavily]
Red.
As in blood?
[breathing heavily]
In the sunset.
Ah.
Favorite place?
Home.
Favorite smell?
[somber music playing]
Home.
Tell me,
why is your life worth living?
[sniffling]
My son...
doesn't know his father.
I want him to know his mom.
I want him to know
how to be happy.
Thank you, Katia.
[sorrowful melody playing]
Now's as good a time as any.
[door creaks open]
What?
[suspenseful music playing]
No.
[Katia grunting]
Ah!
[Katia breathing heavily]
No!
[screaming]
[sobbing]
[Katia grunting in agony]
The smell will go away
along with the pain.
Just in time for the show.
[whimpering quietly]
[Katia breathing heavily]
[Katia sobbing]
[Cathy] So what do we know
so far?
Katia Volkova.
32. Born in Russia.
Came to the US last year
with her son Lev, now six.
Lives at an East Portland address
registered to her mother, Inga.
Started a new job at the Campbell's
Landing jewelry store two days ago.
Blue, Sasha Morgan,
who we also know that we know
nothing about his disappearance
or his movements before that.
White, Alex Chambers,
delivery driver.
Taken on the night of the 11th.
Red, Chloe Demaine,
substitute teacher.
Recently qualified.
Taken two nights after Alex.
Last seen
at her weekly dance class.
And Brown, William Elise,
security guard
at the Harold Mall.
-Anything connecting?
-Not that we know of so far.
We know they're all local,
so they aren't searching
too far field for their target victims.
And we don't think
that this is money-motivated.
None of the captives
are particularly wealthy.
So anyone could be
the next target.
I don't want the media
getting their hands on this.
If the full details
of this goes public,
that'll play
right into his game plan.
[footsteps approaching]
They're going live in ten.
-How do we not know about this?
-There's a schedule.
His viewing figures
are already up.
Up how? More subscribers?
No, no. A-- anyone
with a fucking laptop.
[thrilling music playing]
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen.
Welcome to Russian Roulette.
Another unlucky loser
on the way.
Two guns, two chambers,
one bullet each.
But where?
And when?
Greetings, blood-hungry
brawlers, bastards, and bitches.
How's life?
About to end
for one of this lot.
With the contestants
at either end
that's Mr. Blue and Mr. Yellow,
please pick up a pistol,
take a shot,
and pass the weapon along.
Assuming you're still standing,
of course.
[breathing heavily]
[The Presenter exhales]
So predictable.
-[cattle prod buzzing]
-[both groaning]
[Sasha breathing heavily]
[The Presenter] Pistols, please.
Or believe me,
next time, throats get cut.
Thank you.
Music please.
Contestants,
when it stops,
pull that trigger.
[upbeat music playing]
[The Presenter chuckles]
I won't allow anyone to accuse me of
not milking this for all it's worth.
Jesus fucking Christ.
[suspenseful music intensifying]
[music stops]
[gun cocks]
[Sasha laughing maniacally]
[vomiting]
[The Presenter] Pass the pistols
along, please.
Ms. Red and Mr. Brown,
you know what to do.
Music, please.
[upbeat music playing]
[whimpering]
Keep those bets coming in,
people.
[keyboard clacking]
-Anything?
-Nothing.
-Even the bets aren't hackable?
-Encrypted on the dark web.
Same as the feed.
So we're just gonna
fucking watch this happen?
[upbeat music playing]
You've gotta see this.
That's not real...
is it?
[upbeat music stops]
-[gun cocks]
-[whimpering]
[gun fires]
[tense music playing]
Oh, my God, don't you see that?
[laughing]
Don't worry
about the floor, folks.
We use Easycare paint.
Just wipes away like a dream.
Fresh gone, please.
One final pass.
Ms. Green, Mr. White.
Oh, just one second.
It's better.
And raise the guns.
Wait for the music.
[upbeat music playing]
[tense music intensifying]
-[music stops]
-[gun cocks]
[sobbing]
Explain.
Sniffling a little.
Oh, you can smell the fear, folks.
Adult diapers next time.
You know what to do, Mr. White.
[tense music intensifying]
[gun cocks]
And there it is,
ladies and gentlemen, bastards and tramps.
We have our unlucky loser,
Mr. White.
And when you see what's in store
for this poor soul,
you'll agree that the guy
who blew his brains out was the lucky one.
Thank you once again,
boys and girls, for joining us.
See you again real soon
for results show.
You will not wanna miss.
One minute the IP is in Canada. The
next, India, the next, Sweden, I can't--
Fuck! Fuck!
[elevator pings]
[tense music playing]
Gentlemen.
I don't change diapers.
Just saying.
Work him hard.
Okay.
[thrilling music playing]
Why don't you make yourself useful and
get me a coffee, huh?
[inaudible conversation]
[inaudible speaking]
You okay?
Talk to me.
What do you want me
to talk about?
The evil inside of us?
'Cause...
that is what
I'm faced with.
Yeah. But not all of us.
Enough of us.
Not you, Ben.
[phone chimes]
[Lisa] Don't.
Please.
Ben--
Ben!
[suspenseful music plays]
[eerie music plays
over phone]
[phone buzzes]
Yeah. I got the email.
That shithead's sending out
fucking emails now?
-I knew he would.
-Let him.
Because the good news is,
we're in.
-You hacked it?
-Mr. Larch hacked it.
You're welcome, Ben.
-How?
-The email was a leaky nut.
Just rolled on
right past the gatekeepers.
-We're undetected?
-Of course, man.
My God,
what do you take me for?
How do you know for sure?
This is the exclusive members list.
These are the guys
who place bets and gamble.
238 members are online
and active right now, hmm?
[Ben] But there's
no sign of us.
238 sick people who will get
their reckoning one day.
[laughs] Is that how
you seriously talk for real?
-It's just like the movies--
-Shut the up fuck up, Larch.
What have we got
on the feed?
Clear view of the prisoners.
Contestants.
It's a game.
They're getting
ready for broadcast.
[eerie music plays]
Ahoy there!
As you, my fine friends
will recall,
Mr. White here...
Alex lost the last round.
He dodged... [groans]
...the bullet, literally.
But in doing so,
he missed the point...
[imitates death rattle]
...fatally.
[audience
and The Presenter sigh]
[laughs] Now,
before the main event,
I would like to welcome
our new viewers.
It's great to
have you with us, folks.
Please enjoy the show.
It's gonna be a blast.
Ha!
What's he talking about?
-Us?
-You.
How does he know
we're watching?
Not from the IP.
We're invisible.
You said
we were undetectable.
I told you
he'd be expecting this.
Either that
or the setup is seriously,
admirably way more sophisticated
than you thought.
How the fuck
are we not able
to shut this whole
fucking shit show down?
More importantly,
Happy Dan
from the good old US of A
was the winner
with a pledge of 300K.
Well done to you, Happy Dan,
or Happier Dan now,
I should imagine.
So without further ado,
what's on the trolley tonight?
-[trolley rumbles]
-[The Presenter cackles]
-Going out with a bang.
-[gunshot booms]
[The Presenter laughs]
Missing the point. [laughs]
Or celebrating with fizz.
Who writes these lines?
Oh, actually I do. [laughs]
Happy Dan, you have
30 seconds to make your mind up.
As usual,
we ask our plucky loser
to say a few final words.
Please. Please!
[sighs] We got to get 'em
to work on their final words.
This is good television.
We're missing a trick.
-We really are.
-[Larch] Impressive.
He's gaining confidence.
You notice that?
-[alarm rings]
- Happy Dan... ...your time is up.
Please ping your punishment.
[computer chimes]
[laughs] I'm so glad
you chose that one.
The chateau bleach.
A most excellent choice.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
Oh, my God.
I finally get to see
what drain cleaner does
to the insides
of a terrified man.
[chuckles] I've been wondering
since I was 12.
This is fucking insane.
Mr. White, it's been
a pleasure to have you with us.
But as-- who was it?
Oh, someone once said,
all good things
must come to an end.
Bad things too.
I don't think
he wants it, folks.
I'm killing
that motherfucker.
Careful what
you wish for, Ben.
[Alex] Please.
I'm begging. Please.
I know, but see,
this is all about
giving the audience
what they signed up for.
I think we're just gonna
have to make this a little more watchable.
[Alex grunts]
-[Alex groans]
-[The Presenter cackles]
That's more like it.
Shall we begin?
Alex, how are ya?
Yeah, I'm--
I'm good. [laughs]
That's good.
[both laugh]
-Would you like a drink?
-Yeah.
See, you look like you could do
with a little refreshment.
Yeah. [groans]
Okay. You sure?
-Yeah.
-Okay.
[tense music intensifies]
[chokes, gags]
[whimpering]
[laughs maniacally]
And there it is,
my viewing vultures.
Another unlucky loser
on Russian Roulette.
Look out
for a brand new contestant
coming soon
to a screen screen near you.
[computer chimes]
[Captain Larson] Now we got
this shit to deal with.
Just great.
Those goddamn news boys, man.
[office din]
[reporter 1 on TV]
Is it true the FBI
will be taking over the case?
[reporter 2]
Do you concede Portland PD
have failed
the people of this city?
[reporter 3]
Why didn't you inform the public
that a killer
was on the loose?
[reporter 4]
Do you have any suspects?
[reporter 5] How many
have been killed so far?
-Two.
-[reporter 5] Who are they?
We're not yet releasing
that information.
[reporter 3]
Are they demanding a ransom?
[thrilling music plays]
[Ben] The feds?
-Working with us, not taking over.
-Same thing, boss.
We need to do whatever it takes to shut
this motherfucker down.
So quite frankly, I don't give
two shits who the boss is.
-But--
-[agent] Officers.
Captain Larson.
[indistinct]
[The Presenter over PA]
Miss Red and Mr. Yellow, exercise time.
Are these prisoner's IDed?
It's all on the file.
-Anything connecting them?
-They're just randoms.
He's picking them up
off the street.
Random?
Like spinning a wheel?
Potluck who gets picked?
[computer whirring]
[whispers] Always the same one
carries the keys.
Whoever stands
in that corner...
if we can overpower them,
we have a chance.
[suspenseful music booms]
Is it true
[indistinct name] Larch?
You pulled him in to help?
[scoffs] You're inviting
trouble there, detective.
I figured
we weren't enough as it was.
You're the one
who put him away, right?
So you're
the Barry Bailey guy.
They're done.
[chains jangle]
[lock clicks]
How do we overpower
four guards?
Timing's the key.
It's the only thing
we have on our side...
during exercise
or during the game.
I'm in.
'Cause we're dying
here anyway.
We need to work on some signals,
so we know when to act.
[The Presenter over PA]
Miss Green, Diary Room.
What have I done?
Hmm.
Chatty little bitch.
But don't worry,
I'm not talking about you.
Please. [yelps]
Do you know
the soles of your feet contain
over 200,000 nerve endings?
[prisoner whimpers]
[prisoner screams]
[The Presenter over PA]
See, you, you're new.
You don't know better.
But Miss Red does.
We miss something?
Is this one of the games?
No. This one
he's just doing 'cause he can.
We've seen cases
like this before.
There's normally
a sexual element to his actions,
even though
he is not showing it now.
Likelihood is
he was traumatized as a child.
I'll start profiling.
Help us work out
his next steps.
Yeah, it's classic,
but it's not the rule.
-All right?
-Sick fuck.
[Larch] He's wrong.
There's no sexual element
to this whatsoever.
Basing that on what?
I know how sexually sadistic
desires manifest.
I lived it for, what,
six years.
His are nothing alike. It's a waste of
time and money going down that alley.
A sadist, yes.
And narcissists too with histrionic
tendencies thrown in.
But the biggest thing
to consider here is power.
Power over people.
I don't mean his captives.
No, that's cheap.
I mean those enabling him, his members,
subscribers, those men in the room,
I'm assuming
they're all men.
Certainly.
They'll be volunteers
because what they really want
is to be him.
Hmm. So they live out
their fantasies
through him
and his fantasies.
He delivers what they need.
And what does he need?
Have you forgotten already?
-A Showman.
-Showman.
Ratings.
That's what he needs.
He wants that audience.
And now he's got it,
he's not gonna wanna lose it.
He'll keep
going bigger and better.
Your task
is to wait for the mistake.
You got that kinda patience?
Well, you're feeling
threatened.
-By what?
-The FBI.
I just want what's best.
Well, you haven't got it
with the FBI
and their sexual obsessions,
that's for sure.
Would you have done
all this...
if you could?
Are you taking
an interest in me,
Detective Jacobs?
I was all about the meat.
He's all sizzle.
Would you kill like him?
You ever seen him
get his hands dirty?
It's not about the killing.
It really isn't.
He knows you're watching.
We know he knows.
Use that. Go public.
Oh, he'd love that.
Tempting and taunting you
to the edge of catching him
make for great television.
-Play right into it.
-No.
He would.
Has an ex-con
ever joined the force?
Asking for a friend.
You're not an ex-con.
[laughs]
Oh, it's always nice
spending time with you, Ben.
[door buzzes]
Be careful though.
You come down
to his level...
you might not find
your way back.
I can confirm
that the Bureau is now in charge
of this investigation
and we will bring
the killer to justice.
Beyond that, I won't be
commenting on the specifics
of the investigation
at this time.
-Thank you.
-[reporter 1] What makes you think
that the FBI can succeed
where the Portland PD failed?
The entire resources
at the Bureau
are being brought to bear
on this case.
[reporter 2] What
can you share with us?
The prisoners are all local
to the Portland area,
and so far we have
no reason to suspect
they are
in any way connected.
[reporter 3]
So anyone could be next.
[agent 2] We won't let it
come to that.
[reporter 1] And what do you say
to all the people sharing
these clips
of the Russian Roulette games
-on social media?
-That they really shouldn't be.
It is only a matter of time
before we find him
and justice
takes its course.
Is it really?
-[keyboard clacking]
-[computer chimes]
[soft music plays]
It's a girl.
We're having a daughter.
Did you forget?
-Or just not care?
-I care.
Hey.
I care.
Two contestants are required,
my ennobled enablers.
But, and here's
the special bit, you get to choose.
So who's not going home
tonight?
Let's take a look.
Will it be possible
contestant number one,
the mysterious man
from the [indistinct]?
Or perhaps
you prefer the delights
of this possible contestant,
a sweet commuter.
Or this wonderful woman
from the world of business.
And finally,
what about this little cutie,
our last possible contestant?
No, not the baby, silly.
It's not that kind of a show.
The choice, ladies and gentlemen
of the jury, is yours.
-Okay. So this is good.
-What?
We can work this
to our advantage.
This is our chance
to trap him.
Yeah, but
if we can identify them,
then we can find them,
then we can make them safe.
-Or we can catch him in the act.
-And risk a kidnapping?
We're on it, detective.
Ladies and gentlemen, the FBI.
-They're on it.
-[agent] Fuck you.
Believe this fucking guy?
You don't trust them one bit.
Something you learn, buddy.
Something you learn.
[thrilling music plays]
[inaudible conversation]
-Two have been taken.
-What?
-Which ones?
-None of the ones he trailed.
-What?
-Two others entirely.
Fuck!
-Detective Jacobs, any comments?
-Not today.
Reports say seven people
were taken last night.
Don't believe
everything you read.
You are saying
there weren't any kidnappings.
I'm saying we're on it.
If you're on it,
why were there any kidnappings?
How many were taken,
detective?
I'm not discussing
the case any further.
It's become public now.
It's all over the news.
You don't think
the terrified people
of this city
deserved to know?
I think you just
wanna scare them more.
Are you the best officer to be
on this case given past events?
Would you say your own experiences make
you the perfect candidate?
Wouldn't you like to know
more from the police
when your mother
and sister were abducted?
[reporter groans]
[suspenseful music]
[keys clacking]
[computer chimes]
Ah!
Gotcha.
Oh, that's beautiful.
Yeah.
[mutters]
[prisoner screams, sobs]
I know this.
I know where I am.
I watched it.
I don't wanna
play this game.
[sobs] Please.
Go on, you fucking coward!
Do it!
Give the new Mr. White
his due.
[grunting]
[hits landing]
A special treat for those of you
hanging out with us
in our downtime,
ladies and gentlemen.
Don't say
we don't treat you nice.
[Katia] Just breathe.
Don't fight the restraints.
That's it.
We're not allowed to talk.
We think
the cameras are above us.
No head movements,
only whispers.
My name is Katia.
We're gonna get through this.
You want my badge?
[scoffs]
Have I asked?
He's calling it an assault.
We're calling it
obstructing a police officer
during an emergency.
Detective Jacobs,
he knows who you are.
He read up on you after he watched
your title fight back there.
Great fucking job, detective.
I need to call Lisa.
We can send
some officers to watch.
Or you can spend
some time at home, Ben.
Which, under
the circumstances...
might be wise.
-You need anybody with you?
-I'm good.
If something happens,
I'll call.
-Be safe out there.
-Count on it.
[somber music plays]
-Hey, honey.
-Hey.
How's it going?
Good. Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
-It's going. It's going.
-It looks good.
[laughs] Where did you, uh,
where did you order this one?
-Seriously.
-Stop it.
They should rewrite
their instructions for sure.
[phone chimes]
Miss Orange,
diary room, please.
Amy, this is you.
Amy.
[sobbing] Oh, no, please.
-No!
-Amy, it's okay. [cattle prod buzzes]
[whimpers]
[Amy sobs]
No!
Please! [panting]
Please!
Listen to me.
I am. I'm listening.
And you're live.
I know the show.
-[laughs] You said.
-I watched it.
I figured because you said
you knew the show, right?
Please, I just wanna go home.
Quiet, Amy.
Can I call you Amy?
I can call you Amy. [laughs]
-Favorite color?
-What?
Ah, favorite place?
I don't know.
And why is your life
worth living really?
-I wanted to-- I just--
-[computer chimes]
Let me just show you this.
Just in
from Japanese Jelly Maker.
Now, I don't know
if they're really Japanese
or if they're even making jelly.
[laughs] I just love
that name.
This is what
Japanese Jelly Maker wrote just now.
Do you know what Japanese Jelly Maker
is referring to there, Amy?
So, then,
without further ado, guys.
[screams, sobs]
Show will go live in six.
Okay, I want
this location found, guys.
Tonight, this session.
Nobody goes home
till we have an address.
There.
[eerie music plays]
My tribe, my base.
Welcome, welcome, welcome.
Time to find ourselves
another loser.
For tonight we present...
-dodgeball.
-[audience cheers]
Now the rules
of our very special
deadly dodgeball--
Uh, wait.
Do I really need to
explain the rules?
How about
we just jump straight in
and pick
the first contestant.
Mr. Yellow, you'll be playing
to dodgeball
the shit out of...
[man groaning]
Miss Green.
Now, I want a good,
clean fight.
The only balls of yours touching this
little beauty are the ones we give you.
Are we understood?
Keep those bets coming
thick and fast, folks.
And remember,
the lucky winner gets to choose.
[grunts]
Guys, you are making me
look bad.
Where's the conviction? Huh?
Where's the knowledge that your very lives
depend on this?
Huh? Or do I have to
give it some...
[imitates electric buzz]
So let's give it 100%.
You know what I'm saying?
You just can't get [indistinct].
Okay. Let's play.
[both grunt]
[Katia screams]
[both exclaim]
[sobs]
[The Presenter] And play.
[whimpers]
I lose.
This is
your last warning, Mr. White.
I didn't say
I wouldn't play.
I said I lose.
You are a brave old man,
Ray Callahan.
An ancient warrior.
And a fool.
Have we got
a results show lined up
for you,
ladies and gentlefolk?
Look out for the alert.
You do not wanna miss this.
[keyboard clacking]
-[computer chimes]
-Guys.
[laughs] I fucking have it.
Okay.
Okay. Listen up, boys and girls.
We have a location.
Great news. Trading estate,
30 minutes west of here.
Two strike teams
are prepping to go.
[thrilling music]
-[tires screech]
-[sirens wailing]
20 minutes out.
[officer over radio]
The results show has started.
I repeat.
The results show is live.
Copy that.
[The Presenter] You again?
Welcome. Welcome.
To the results edition
of Russian Roulette.
Let's remind ourselves
of why we are here.
I didn't say I wouldn't play.
I said I lose.
You gotta hand it
to Mr. White there.
That was bold, ballsy.
Made me rethink things.
And I want to honor him
for the samurai he is.
No, not Samurai, exactly.
Kamikaze would be more apt.
[tense music plays]
So my preening public,
we have two lucky losers.
I know. Two.
How entertaining is that?
[laughs]
But who's it gonna be?
Is it gonna be
Mr. White or Miss Red?
[computer chimes]
And it seems
you can't decide either.
And I don't blame you.
They're equally killable.
[chuckles] I'll tell you what.
Why don't we ask
our friend at the Portland PD,
seeing as you
and your fed pals
are so keen to get involved
in our little project here?
Let's get you involved.
Are you watching,
Detective Ben Jacobs?
Portland's very own short fuse,
ladies and gentlemen,
with a trigger all his own,
his beloved mother and sister.
Are you there, Ben?
[phone buzzing]
Cathy.
I don't think you should be
in here for this, Lisa.
Well, I don't know
how long we can hang around.
I-- hang around.
[The Presenter
and audience laughs]
[imitates choking]
Am I good or am I good,
huh? [laughs]
Okay. Good to go.
I'm engaging.
Affirmative.
[computer chimes]
[The Presenter]
Ah, there you are.
Of course, you are. I mean, you wouldn't
wanna miss this either, would you?
I mean,
what else is there to watch?
[laughs] Ben.
Sergeant Benjamin Andrew Jacobs,
I have a gift for you.
The gift of a choice.
White or red? Red or white.
-What the fuck?
-The choice is yours.
Think of yourself lucky
you didn't have to bid for the privilege.
Strike teams, are you there?
Five minutes out.
Five fucking minutes.
Don't be shy now.
If you don't choose,
I'll choose.
And I'll choose
to kill 'em both.
It would, after all,
be the only fair thing to do.
This is so fucked up.
You can't do this, Ben.
-You can't kill one.
-I'm saving one.
Jesus.
-Ben--
-What do you want me to do?
You want me to let both die?
Wait.
The strike teams
are on their way.
He's bluffing.
-This guy does not bluff.
-Let it play out.
-Cathy-- Cathy--
-Ben--
I'm gonna have to put
a clock on you, Ben.
You see, my viewers, they don't like
no awkward silences.
-Strike teams, are you there?
-Two minutes out.
We don't
fucking have two minutes.
[sirens wailing]
Going dark.
If we cannot rely on you
to make a moral choice,
who can we rely on?
[laughs] The likes of me.
[tires screech]
[officer 1] Breech her up.
[officer 2] Breeching.
Alpha team, go!
On your six.
Alpha [indistinct] Charlie.
Gonna have to push you
for an answer, Ben.
Talk to me.
Alpha team,
there's nothing here.
Fucking Christ!
Strike team two.
The whole fucking
warehouse is empty.
Ben, come on now.
This is a matter of civic duty.
In five, four, three, two, one.
And there it is.
You've chosen to save Ms. Red
and kill the old warrior.
It means a lot.
[suspenseful music plays]
[breathing shakily]
Whoops.
[gasping for breath]
[wheezing, sobbing]
Fuck! Fuck!
[somber music plays]
You fucking animal.
[sobbing]
Oh, by the way, I hope your,
um, colleagues enjoyed
that little excursion. [laughs]
I really must send you
into town next time.
Pick up my dry cleaning.
See you tomorrow,
ladies and gentlemen,
for another blood rendition
of Russian Roulette.
Wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
These-- these viewing figures.
Oh, my. [laughs]
I-I-I don't know what to say.
I mean... [sighs]
...my-- my heart is full.
No, you complete me.
You do. I do this for you.
I love you all. I do.
But listen,
I do have some bad news
for all concerned.
The next episode
will be our last.
-[audience exclaim]
-I know.
The season finale,
ladies and gentlemen.
Need I say more?
You will wanna be right here.
[imitates kiss smacks]
It should have been me.
Should have been me.
[somber music building]
[chilling music plays]
[ominous chords play]
[phone chimes, buzzes]
[breathing heavily]
[ominous music plays]
Ray.
Ray!
No! Ray!
Help!
[sobbing] Help!
[sobbing, whimpering]
Put the cameras on him.
Leave him there a while.
Be a nice surprise
for all our viewers.
-Hey.
-[Lisa] Hmm?
There's a package for you.
What is it?
I don't remember
ordering anything.
-Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
-What is it?
Put it down.
-Hey.
-Go to the kitchen.
-Ben.
Ben, what is it?
Cap, I want those officers
out here right now.
He sent a Russian doll
to my fucking house.
I heard what happened.
He crossed the fucking line.
[Captain Larson] Season finale.
That's what he said.
We go back over everything.
No matter how many times
we've already gone over it.
Every lead, every piece of video footage,
every episode.
Clock's ticking.
We all know what it might mean.
Let's get to work.
Ben, I want you to--
[chains rattle]
[tense music plays]
Do you think I should give you
all the last diary?
No.
I think maybe I should.
A chance to say something
to your little kotik.
See.
I do have a heart.
[office din]
[indistinct chatter]
Katia.
We have to do this.
Whatever the games,
we have to do this tonight.
He was talking to the police.
If they're watching,
we can talk to them too.
And say what?
[The Presenter over PA]
Ms. Green, diary room, please.
He said I'd have a chance to say
something to my little kotik.
-Who?
-Exactly.
I've never told any of you
and I've never told him.
How did he know?
[footsteps approaching]
[chains rattles]
[The Presenter]
Ms. Green, you're live.
So let's try
to keep this interesting.
Ray, Mr. White,
his death,
how did that make you feel?
[scoffs]
How does it make you feel?
[The Presenter sighs]
Save me the trouble, I guess.
Could you do that to yourself?
See, I've been wondering whether
there's an entire episode
and watching
one of you kill yourself...
could be powerful television.
Seminole.
That said, where's the tension?
Where's the 50/50
Benning peril, you know?
Tell me how it feels
to be afraid.
Familiar.
That so?
I've met monsters before.
Have you now?
But those ones you escape.
Tell me why.
-Why what?
-Why do you do this?
That's a very interesting
question, Ms. Green.
Maybe let me
turn it on its head.
What do you feel...
when you see one of your
fellow contestants breath their last?
I'm thinking about what I miss.
What do you miss?
I miss my family. My mom.
I miss my work colleagues too.
But mostly I miss my son.
So you are afraid of death.
Not anymore.
Well, it's my job
to make sure you are.
Thank you for lighting a fire
under my butt.
I'm gonna have to get
more creative.
Don't forget,
ladies and gentlemen,
the season finale tonight.
Be there and beware.
You look good on camera, Katia.
The people like you.
I expect your death
to top the ratings.
[dramatic music plays]
[groans softly]
Why you look so sad?
I miss my family. My mom.
I miss my work colleagues too.
But mostly I miss my son.
I miss my family, my mom.
I miss my work colleagues too.
But mostly I miss my son.
I miss my family. My mom.
I miss my work colleagues too.
Cathy.
I miss my family. My mom.
I miss my work colleagues too.
She was at work for just
one day before she was taken.
Before that,
she was a stay-at-home mom.
[Katia]
I miss my work colleagues, too.
How do you miss someone
you've only just met?
[thrilling music plays]
Hi. Ms. Romano,
we have some more questions.
Please, come with me.
[suspenseful music plays]
I wanna ask you
about Katia Volkova.
How long did it take you
to walk from here to The Embar?
We stopped a few times
along the way,
so, that's hard to remember.
Stopped where?
We were window-shopping.
Where?
She said
she needed a winter coat.
She said that would be
her treat from her first payday.
All right, well, uh,
thank you so much for your time.
[keyboard clacking]
[tense chord plays]
[The Presenter]
Oh, uh, hey, there.
Wasn't expecting you.
Not. [laughs]
Welcome,
whores and hounds everywhere.
Tonight's episode is going to be
very special indeed.
Guaranteed to pack a punch.
Just look at those
viewing figures.
You-- you guys are gluttons
for somebody else's punishment.
Cathy, I've got a location,
Shannon Industrial Park.
-I'm heading there now.
-I'll get back up.
No.
I don't want anything
to blow it this time.
Let me check it out.
I'll call it in.
Roger that.
The live show started.
Hopefully, that means
he's looking the other way.
Mr. Blue and Mr. Yellow,
I expect a dirty fight.
You know
what you're fighting for?
You're fighting to win.
And to win, you gotta destroy!
You with me? Okay.
Let's play!
[groans]
[suspenseful music plays]
[both grunting]
[both groan in pain]
Come on.
[both yelling in pain]
[fight din]
[thrilling music plays]
[both panting]
[yelling aggressively]
[grunting in pain]
[screaming]
[loud thuds]
[screams]
[grunting in pain]
-[cattle prod buzzing]
-[man screaming]
They're gonna
get themselves killed.
[loud thudding]
[gunshot bangs]
Sasha!
[suspenseful music plays]
[phone buzzing faintly]
-Yeah?
-[Cathy] Ben.
-They're trying to escape.
-What?
[grunting in effort]
[cattle prod buzzing]
[Sasha] Katia, behind you.
[gunshot bangs]
[Katia grunts]
The guns only have one round.
Come on!
Let's go!
[breathing heavily]
Amy!
-Amy!
-[gunshot bangs]
Let's go!
[suspenseful music plays]
Go, go.
[man screaming]
[blows landing]
[Katia screams, grunts]
No!
[yells in pain]
[Katia panting]
Sasha!
Cathy, we need backup.
[thrilling music plays]
[muffled scream]
Katia, run! Run!
[Katia panting, grunting]
Help!
[screaming in pain]
Please, help.
Help. Help.
Portland police.
-All right, stand back.
-Okay.
[gunshot pops]
-Katia?
-Yes.
Is he down there? The Presenter?
Yes. And two of his men.
Go. Help's on its way.
All right.
[thrilling music plays]
-Police!
-[repeated gunfire]
[gunshots banging]
[panting]
[thud]
[rapid gunshots]
Hold it!
[dynamic music plays]
Oh, shit.
[indistinct
police radio chatter]
[Katia sobbing]
[ominous music plays]
Drop the weapon!
Ms. Green was the clever one.
She was talking to you,
wasn't she?
Do not move!
If move, I will shoot you.
She asked me why.
You see that, Ben? Why?
Because life's nothing more
than a game of Russian roulette.
That's why.
All things considered,
this is quite a moment for you,
isn't detective?
A real victory.
The question is
what do you do next?
Well, the other officers arrive.
You take me in
and you're the hero.
But if you shoot me,
you're still the hero.
Killing me will feel like you're-- you're
killing your demons.
[laughs]
Killing good old Barry Bailey.
That has its own obvious appeal.
Not a choice for you, Ben.
But this is a big one.
The size, big one.
Well, we all have these moments
of choice along life's journey.
And your little sis.
You chose to take a walk
on that fateful night,
chose the root that put her
straight into the Bailey's path.
He chose to follow her home,
chose to introduce himself
to her and your mom, to abduct them...
to gut them.
And, well,
you have your choice now too.
[groans] I have made mine.
[thrilling music intensifies]
[rapid gunshots]
No! No!
No!
No! Hey, come on.
[The Presenter]
Well, I don't know about you,
ladies and gentlemen,
but I think
that's the game to beat.
-[Ben] I've made mine.
-[rapid gunshots]
[The Presenter]
So, let's give respect
to our final contestant.
He exceeded expectations.
Oh, he really did.
No! No!
-[Ben] I've made mine.
-[rapid gunshots]
[eerie music plays
[indistinct chatter]
[somber music building]
[indistinct chatter over radio]
[quiet music plays]
[tense music building]
[The Presenter] Well done you.
[car engine revs]
-Mummy!
-[Katia gasps]
-Katia!
-Mama!
[sobbing]
So my wicked wanderers.
For the next thrilling season
of Russian Roulette,
please help me pick a theme.
Will it be jungle,
desert, island, or cave?
You choose.
[computer pinging]
[thrilling music plays]