My name is F. Gary Gray.
I'm the director of Straight' Outta Compton.
And I want to first start off
by thanking my team-
my producing partners Ice Cube,
Dr. Dre,
Scott Bernstein.
There's a whole host of other people
that should be involved,
but since we have
a short amount of time,
I want to start with those guys
and thank everybody else who's involved.
Also want to thank Universal,
Donna Langley
and the entire Universal family
for really being
the best home for this movie.
This movie would not
have been as successful,
it wouldn't have been executed
in the way that it's been executed
without the Universal family
and without everyone.
I'm sure I'm forgetting a ton of people.
But I want to thank everybody involved
with making this movie.
One of the big themes
in this movie is brotherhood.
We serve the theme with the group
and the brotherhood between the guys.
I love this because it just shows
how smart Eazy-E is.
He pulls up into this drug deal
with what we used to call a bucket-
a old, beat-up car.
Basically, he's not showing his hand.
He's playing chess.
He has a ton of drugs
that he's selling,
but he's not gonna let anybody know
that he has money.
This is just a way to define quickly
who this guy is.
He's very, very smart.
That's what you see
when you see the contrast
between that really fancy car
and his old, beat-up car.
It's just defining Eazy-E immediately.
I love what my production designer did
with this crack house.
Because you really, really feel
that you're in Compton
and you really feel like
you're in a dangerous situation.
You can smell the beer
and the smoke and the drugs.
And the danger is just visceral.
My DP, Matty Libatique, did an amazing job
at capturing this entire film.
But this scene in particular,
because it's a way
to show that it's natural,
it's raw, it's dangerous.
It's not slick.
It doesn't feel like Hollywood.
It just feels raw, not unlike the group
and not unlike their music.
This is one of my favorite moments
because it just doesn't feel staged.
The two women you see
are actual models.
Natascha, she's a stuntwoman,
but basically she's a very beautiful woman.
She's a model.
And that's Zee James.
She's a model as well,
and I made her take out- cut her hair,
take it all out
and play a crack addict.
I do that from time to time
to play the opposites.
I did that with Friday,
with the Felisha character.
She was a beautiful comedian
who I turned into a crack addict.
I just have fun with casting
in that way.
She was a beautiful comedian
who I turned into a crack addict.
I just have fun with casting
in that way.
This, of course,
is the introduction to Jason Mitchell,
who is an amazing young, new actor
who carries this film
and does an incredible job.
You'll see, as the movie unfolds,
that this guy gives
a world-class performance.
It's partly because he studies,
but I think it's partly because
he's just real and authentic.
He comes from the streets
of New Orleans.
I think he draws on his experiences
from the past
to give us one of the best performances,
I think, of the year.
Now, this is important because
instead of giving you this long,
drawn-out montage
of images from the '80s
to show you that you're
in a period piece-
following this group circa 1985, 1986-
I wanted to do it by showing
what was going on
but also showing the battering ram.
People called it the batterram
back in the day.
For those who know,
the batterram really marks the time.
If you were living in Los Angeles
in the 1980s,
people were afraid to get
their houses ripped apart,
by this- essentially, by this military tank
that would come and completely
rip the guts out of your house.
This was just a way
to mark the era
without doing some corny montage.
Chic Daniel, our police consultant,
did a great job at helping us
do everything technically right with this scene.
He used to actually drive
that vehicle in the '80s,
which is kind of a coincidence.
So, finding the vehicle was hard,
but finding the original driver
was just as interesting.
And to put all these elements together
really, I think, gives the audience
a good sense of what was going on.
It completely immerses you
into the time immediately.
That's what I wanted to do.
Matty Libatique came up with this great filter
that gives you these sun ﬂares
that is kind of a metaphor
for being in California.
It's sunny, and the music is warm.
But at the same time,
there's this contrast with the danger
and all the stuff that happens outside of
the warm, sunny Southern California days.
We wanted to create
some sort of visual signature
to let you know you're in
Straight Outta Compton and nowhere else.
This is something that is just
kind of a signature of the movie
that we carry on throughout.
Matty Libatique, I think, is a genius
for coming up with that.
I really like this moment
because it's one of those moments
where I get the chance
to illustrate my childhood
and some of my childhood inﬂuences.
I love all the music
that he's listening to
because that's the music
I listened to when I grew up
and that my mom passed on to me.
When you see Roy Ayers
and Parliament and James Brown,
these are all artists that I grew up to
and my mom grew up to.
Of course, this is Corey Hawkins,
who is an amazing young artist
from the East Coast who plays Dr. Dre.
He was trained at Juilliard.
He actually performed on Broadway.
He never thought that he
could pull off playing Dr. Dre
because his personality is so opposite
of where Dre is from
and how Dre really acts in real life.
But this guy is such a talented actor
that he can transform,
and I think that's what he did.
I used this time to really set up
the relationship
between Dre and his family.
Although that was
a hell of a slap right there,
you could really tell
that his mom loves him.
She wants to send him
in the right direction.
Maybe a questionable approach,
but, definitely, there's love there.
Also establishing the love
between Dre and his brother,
which, as the story evolves,
you get a sense
of how much he loves his brother.
I just want to make sure
people get the point.
Focusing on controversial lyrics
and some of the mistakes
that we all know that these guys made,
or we all make
because we're all human,
is not the point.
The point is you can start from anywhere
with absolutely nothing
and make a transition
and transform your life.
That's what these guys did.
When you start off in Compton
with the gang violence
and all of the shit
that you're surrounded by-
the drug dealing, the drug abuse,
all of the things that really influence
everything that happens around you-
and you have the strength
to turn that around
and create
and to raise a healthy family
and to create prosperous businesses,
I think that there's something there.
I don't want that point
to be missed on the viewer.
Because there's a lot of criticism
that these guys experienced along the way.
I'm sure, when people watch the movie,
there are things that people would want to see
that probably they missed.
The one thing that's interesting about N.W.A
is they pissed a lot of people off.
But in a strange way,
they inspired people as well.
You don't hear a lot of the stories
about how they inspired people.
When you live in an environment
where you're discouraged,
you're disempowered,
all these things
that work against you,
and you still stand up and say,
“You know what? Fuck that.
I'm going to be my own man.
I'm not gonna serve polite society.
I'm going to speak my mind.
I'm going to do things
that feel good to me,
and I don't give a shit
if you judge me or not”-
There's something inspiring about that
to guys who grew up in my neighborhood.
O'Shea Jackson, Jr., who plays Ice Cube,
this guy worked the hardest
to get this role.
It took him two years,
a lot of acting coaches
and callbacks and chemistry tests.
I think he did an amazing job.
So we go from the Valley
of the privileged
into South Central LA,
which is not far from Compton.
This is a very, very dangerous place,
as you'll see very soon.
This is what Ice Cube writes about.
He says, “I saw how they lived
on the other side,
and I see how we live,
and this is unfair.
I'm gonna write about it.”
That's where you get a little bit
of that anger and a lot of passion
from Ice Cube as an artist.
This is one of my favorite moments
in the movie
because it feels so raw
and so real.
Growing up in Los Angeles
in the '80s
with all of the gang violence
and the dangers,
it's a very specific moment in time.
And you feel exactly where you are
immediately
when Michael Taylor-
that's his name-
His street name is Compton Menace.
You feel how dangerous Los Angeles is
just in this moment.
That's how it was,
and this guy is very real.
He's from Compton,
and he's had a street life.
That's the reason why I cast him.
Because I wanted the audience
to really feel the fear
and understand
that, at a moment's notice,
you could be in the sun,
enjoying a trip home on a school bus,
and, the next moment,
you could be killed.
That's how unpredictable
Los Angeles was at the time.
This is another thing
that motivated the lyrics
and the songs that N.W.A created.
So instead of talking about it,
I wanted the audience to feel it.
When you're a 16-year-old kid,
and someone pulls a gun to your head,
that's very traumatic.
They say that people
in these environments
suffer from post-traumatic stress disorder.
And when people criticize
gangster rap specifically,
they don't realize where it comes from.
That's one of the moments
that motivates this genre of music.
This is one of my favorite shots
in the movie.
My DP, Matty Libatique,
was so gracious in figuring it out.
I told him I wanted to do a great 12 o'clock
Boys motorcycle moment in the movie.
When you have a set of young guys
who stand up for what they believe in,
whether you agree with it or not,
I think there's a certain strength in that.
And when you grow up
in an environment
where you have all of these antagonistic
elements working against you
to disempower you, to discourage you,
I think there's something strong
in standing up and saying,
“I don't care what you think.”
I love this moment because
this shows how talented Dre is,
and it shows how you don't have to have
a lot of money or a lot of resources,
but you can just create.
That's what's so cool about this moment.
It's quintessential hip-hop.
But you can just create.
That's what's so cool about this moment.
It's quintessential hip-hop.
It's like, “I am going to create.”
it's just two turntables
on an ironing board.
This guy is making music
with instruments they essentially created.
I love that about this moment.
It's very, very raw
and very inventive.
This is Jinx's bedroom.
Jinx is played by Cleavon McClendon.
This guy is really funny.
He's kind of comic relief.
I really liked him.
He did a great job in the audition.
He has little moments in the movie,
but they're really funny
and really potent.
Another reason why I love this moment
is because this is where it starts.
Dre has the music,
Cube has the lyrics.
This is where it all starts- in the bedroom
with two turntables on an ironing board.
You know, it's funny.
It wasn't called gangster rap back then.
The media coined that term.
They called it reality rap.
They wanted to talk about the things
that were going on in the neighborhood
and put it to music.
That's why Dre is saying,
“Listen, I want the hard-core stuff.
I want to really feel it.”
Of course, Cube has that stuff,
and you know why.
You see what motivates him.
One big thing
is what just happened on the bus.
And another little funny moment
is when he said,
“Hey. He gave a motivational speech.”
I thought that was really funny.
This is another moment
that motivates Cube
and his writing.
This is a scene
where he gets harassed by the cops
for no reason whatsoever.
He just walks out of the house.
It's the same thing
with most of these kids out here.
They're being harassed.
They didn't do anything.
This is something
the LAPD would do constantly.
In the '80s, they would
call it gang sweeps.
They would come,
and they would search you
to see if you had any contraband,
any weapons,
any drugs or anything on you.
They would come sweep the neighborhood
and see who they could pick up and arrest.
The fact that his mom
is essentially violated in this scene
and his dad violated and humiliated
is another moment
where you really understand
what motivates Ice Cube
to write the lyrics that he writes,
especially for the song “Fuck tha Police.”
When you experience these things
time and time again,
over and over again,
you can't help but be inﬂuenced
by these moments.
It's sad to say that
it happened a lot back then.
It's happening now.
And it was important to show
that this kid didn't just wake up
in the suburbs
and decide to write these lyrics.
He was inﬂuenced by the things
that happened on the bus,
the things that happened
in his neighborhood,
and he was really passionate about it.
That's the reason why
people felt the music.
Because it was real.
It wasn't just made up.
This is the introduction of MC Ren,
who's played by Aldis Hodge.
Really, really good actor.
He had the most experience
out of all the guys in the group.
Worked on the television show Leverage.
This is the friendship between two guys
that we're establishing as well.
I think they were associated
with the Crips back in the '80s,
and they're in Doo-To's,
which is a Blood club.
If you don't know anything about gangs,
they're mortal enemies.
So, the fact that Eazy-E and MC Ren's
walking into a Blood club
is really crazy.
Here's the introduction of DJ Yella,
who's played by Neil Brown, Jr.
He, again, is so fun to work with.
He's also comic relief
throughout the movie.
You'll see that as the movie unfolds.
That's another thing I love
about the structure of the movie
and how we define the characters.
Everyone has
their own different personalities.
Of course, we introduce Lonzo Williams,
who's played by Corey Reynolds.
This guy's really, really talented.
He's funny too.
You see the dynamic
between Dre and Lonzo.
There's this beef that's happening
between the two of them.
Because Lonzo wants him to do
the World Class Wreckin' Cru group,
which is, you know, the satin jackets
and the kind of Prince
and almost kind of Michael Jackson wear,
and Dre's not really with that.
You'll see how that story unfolds
as it unfolds,
but there's definitely static
between the two.
This is the do-or-die moment
for Ice Cube.
He's gonna get up on stage
with a hostile crowd,
and he's either gonna sink or swim.
It's the equivalent
of performing at the Apollo.
At first, the crowd is kind of questioning
who he is, where he's from.
What is he talking about?
See the guy folds his arms.
He's like, “Who is this dude?”
But then, when Cube keeps it real,
he's like, “lf you don't like how I'm livin',
well, fuck you.”
Then in a weird, strange way,
he wins the crowd over with his confidence.
And this song is “Gangsta Gangsta.”
And the track underneath
is “Weak at the Knees.”
This is the song that Dre sampled.
I love the original song.
I love “Gangsta Gangsta.”
I love what O'Shea Jackson, Jr.
did with this moment,
'cause he feels really confident
on stage.
And we established that
what Dre had envisioned actually works.
And of course, Eazy-E got a chance
to experience a little bit of that.
DJ Yella the same.
We also see that Dre is a hardhead.
He's not gonna listen to Lonzo
or anyone else, for that matter.
Now he's about to get his ass chewed out
by Lonzo for that very reason.
This is a funny moment because Lonzo's
tending to that Jheri curl of his.
And you can't take him serious.
You just can't take him serious.
Between the satin jacket and the Jheri curl,
it's a funny moment for me.
I just really liked it.
You see that shirt that he's wearing?
Lonzo is just a real caricature
of the real Lonzo.
But it's a fun moment.
With storytelling,
you deal a lot in motivations.
This is one of the motivations,
besides being broke.
He's motivated
to get out of this environment.
He doesn't want to continue
to do this old school music
and in this environment
with Lonzo's pressure.
So, you get a sense of why Dre
really wants to start his own thing.
He doesn't have a lot of money.
Of course, he's sleeping on his aunt's couch.
He comes up with this brilliant idea
to ask Eazy, “Hey, listen.
You're in the streets.
Of course, it's dangerous.
It's not gonna last.
Why don't you consider
getting into this music thing?”
This is where it all comes together,
or, at least, this is where you see Dre
pitching his heart out.
Because he's really done
with this whole Wreckin' Cru,
pink satin jackets
and the drama of being under Lonzo.
Dre wants to make changes.
And he wants to see if he can
convince Eazy to make changes.
Again, that's where we get a sense
of their relationship.
Now he's gotta go back to Lonzo.
This is one of those moments
where I wish I had a little more time
to make it perfect.
We didn't have a lot of time
to shoot this scene,
so I didn't get all the shots
that I wanted to get.
But again, you get a real sense
of how much Dre loves his brother.
He just came out of nowhere
to defend his brother,
and his brother wasn't necessarily
even doing the right thing.
He was just causing trouble
in the parking lot.
Now LAPD shows up,
and they didn't see the punch.
Again, this happens a lot.
They walk into this environment
or they drive into this environment
and feel like they're runnin' the show.
And Dre is not havin' it.
He's like, “I am at home.
You can't just drive up
and basically tell us what to do.”
He stands his ground.
Dre's like that to this day.
Of course, you get
the relationship with law enforcement,
which is the same
as what just happened with Ice Cube.
You understand why these guys
feel the way they feel.
Which is the same
as what just happened with Ice Cube.
You understand why these guys
feel the way they feel.
Now we establish Eazy-E's '62 Impala.
This is the really expensive car
that he wouldn't drive to a drug deal.
He's in Compton
at the Compton courthouse,
and this is a really interesting moment
because they're right in front
of the Martin Luther King monument
in Compton.
It's a very, very popular spot,
very famous spot.
They're in front of the Martin Luther King
monument in Compton.
It's a very, very popular spot,
very famous spot.
I wanted to really show
that we were in Compton,
and this was one of the best ways
to show that.
This moment, of course,
is really uncomfortable for Eazy
because there are a lot of cops around.
He doesn't want to be there.
But in serving the theme of brotherhood,
he's gonna be there for Dre
to pick him up, to bail him out.
Where Lonzo is not there for Dre.
Again, the theme of brotherhood
is served.
I wanted to do that
so that people could understand
that it's not just about street toughs
and people out there
doing dangerous things.
This is about love,
and these guys have love for each other.
It pays off a little later on,
but I wanted to have a little levity
and a little fun and a little humor,
which I think they handled really well.
I wanted to do it in Compton.
Look at that guy.
It's just a great smile.
He has a great smile.
Jason is very-
He just has a magnetic personality,
which really works.
Because when you're dealing
with this genre of music
and a dangerous environment,
I really wanted to cast someone
who you could really root for,
especially given all the stuff they end up doing
and they're involved with.
But Jason is just magnetic,
and you can see that in his smile.
This moment's important because this is Dre
being the consummate businessman.
“Let's start a record label.
And let's do it on our own.”
You know, I think most people realize
that that was a great approach for Dre,
because now he's a billionaire.
That's where it all started.
The moment between H.B.O.-
Home Boys Only-
which is the group from New York.
It was a group that Dre wanted
to manage and put out.
They were supposed to do
“Boys-N-The-Hood” first.
Ultimately, it didn't work out.
I wonder where those guys are today.
I'm wondering if they know
that if they had done the song,
maybe they would be
just as famous as N.W.A.
But they decided not to.
And this serves as one of
the more funny moments in the movie.
And kinda crazy.
They really wanted to put Compton
on the map
because most of hip-hop was just about
what was going on in New York.
And you can see a little tension
between the guys from New York
and the guys from LA.
And you get a sense of the genesis
of West Coast hip-hop
because it was really
dominated by New York.
And rightfully so,
because it came from New York.
But Eazy was really proud of Compton.
And no one had heard of Compton.
These guys really wanted to say,
“Listen, we respect New York,
but we are not from New York.
We're from Compton,
and we want to put Compton on the map.”
And they stood their ground.
That's why most people around the world
know Compton.
It's because of what happened
in this very moment.
Eazy-E wasn't a rapper.
He was a businessman.
He didn't really care about
being an artist.
He just wanted to make money,
and I think he wanted to socialize.
You know, just like
any other young guy.
And so-
This is a funny line about
“I'm the Berry Gordy of the group.”
He just wanted to be the boss.
“I'm the boss.
You guys do that creative stuff
and let me know when you're done.”
Of course, Dre's genius
is displayed in this scene
where he's like, “Listen, we can't use Cube
'cause he's a part of a group.
And you already paid for this studio time,
so why don't you just do it yourself?”
I'm glad he pushed,
because we wouldn't have this movie
if Dre didn't push in this very moment.
They convince Eazy
to get in the studio.
Now, if you don't understand art
or how artists work,
this is a huge moment.
You have a guy who is
essentially from the streets,
who deals drugs.
He's not into all of this type of stuff.
And Dre has it in his mind
that he's gonna make the leap
from street businessman
to rapper?
That's a huge leap.
And it's one of the funniest moments
in the movie.
You think about the fact that
Eazy just couldn't get it right.
And the average person would've-
They would've given up on him and said,
“You know what? This is not gonna work.
I'm gonna go find another group.”
But Dre is like a dog with a bone.
He just will not let go.
He's like that to this day.
If he feels something-
And he's very intuitive.
If he feels something,
he's gonna fight for it. And he did.
And he did it with every single line
in this song to create this moment.
You talk about motivation.
Between what Lonzo did
and having to leave home,
this is a do-or-die moment for Dre.
And he's gonna make it work,
come hell or high water.
And he did.
This is another moment
where we actually just improvised.
I have a lot of these moments where
you just feel like the script is good.
Jonathan Herman, who was one of the writers,
did a really good job with the script.
And of course Ice Cube and Scott Bernstein,
who's one of our producers-
we all worked a lot on the script.
But on the day when we're shooting,
I'm always going to look
to elevate the material.
And so I would allow
the actors to improvise
to make sure the moment
feels real and organic.
This is one of those moments where I just
let them go off and do their thing,
and it ended up extremely funny,
very natural.
And that's a testament
to the skill level of the artists
and the actors that I hired.
That's part of the thing.
That's part of what my job is-
to make sure I hire people
that not only can rehearse
and memorize their lines,
but who could make contributions.
And I think they're invested even more
when they feel like
they can make a contribution.
Now, this is obviously a famous moment
where we get that famous line,
“Cruisin' down the street in my 6-4.”
Which is quintessential N.W.A,
quintessential Eazy-E.
Everybody loves this song
and loves that particular track
and the opening of that track.
And to capture that on film,
it just felt good.
'Cause I remember when I was younger
and I heard it, I remember where I was,
and it was just great to be able
to capture that with a little humor
and to show that Dre is a genius
and Eazy is a risk taker.
And one of my favorite songs of all time,
to be able to capture that on film
was just a lot of fun.
Now we go back to the brotherhood.
These guys aren't hurting anyone.
They're just creating.
And you see the smiles
and the laughter
and how it's just a bunch of fun.
They are in an old, dusty garage
talking about their environment,
and you could just feel
the love in the room.
These guys just-
it was important for me
to really, really establish
that it's not about thuggery,
it's not about danger, all this stuff.
It's about these guys creating
in an environment that's warm,
and there's a connection between them.
Because later on,
you get a sense of what happened.
I want the audience to root for these guys
and root for their friendship
and root for the brotherhood
so that later on, when they're challenged
and the group disbands,
you wish for and hope for the days
that they were together.
This is one of those moments
where I subtly lead the audience and say,
“Listen, you should like these guys
and like who they are
when they're together
and they're firing on all cylinders.”
So when it's not that way,
you feel the loss.
And of course Lonzo is hatin'.
That was one of the funniest moments
in the movie,
And of course Lonzo is hatin'.
That was one of the funniest moments
in the movie,
where he's like, “No, you got it!”
I remember when he did it,
we busted up laughing so loud.
Corey Reynolds
has great comedic instincts,
and again, it's just funny moments
and brotherhood.
The love in this room
is what you want to protect.
But of course,
as the story unfolds,
they run into their challenges.
But I love this moment.
This is the guys at their happiest.
You know?
With Tyree, the younger brother,
with the girls and the fun
and the brotherhood.
We, of course, have to do a montage
because we can't squeeze
all of that time into a short movie.
So we show that
they press up the album
and experience local success
in Los Angeles.
We show that Eazy, of course,
is using cash from his street money
to fund this whole thing.
Who's that hack?
Who's that guy?
That's my Hitchcock moment.
I wish I was a better actor,
but you guys have to suffer through it.
I'll apologize later.
This is an important moment
because we introduce Paul Giamatti,
who plays Jerry Heller.
This is one of the most talented actors
I've ever worked with ever.
I was there, I believe, somewhere
in the beginning of his career.
We worked a long time ago
on my third motion picture,
The Negotiator,
with Kevin Spacey and Sam Jackson.
He played this character, Rudy.
He was so talented then.
He's incredibly talented now.
I was so lucky to get him because-
As a director, you have a person in mind
when you read the script initially.
You know, you have your first choice.
And you don't always
get your first choice.
Sometimes they are busy,
you have scheduling conﬂicts
or they didn't respond to the material-
for whatever reason.
But Paul Giamatti was my first choice.
And I was lucky enough
to get my first choice.
But what was strange about it was
we didn't make the deal with Paul
until two days before
we started shooting this scene.
This was his first day of shooting.
And we had to put everything
together so quickly
with his wardrobe and his wig-
That's a wig, by the way.
Andrea Jackson did a pretty good job.
But that was a bad hair day for him.
First day, the wig's all over the place.
It was kinda funny, but he weathered it
and did a pretty damn good job.
But he's- Paul is so good.
There were times where
I would forget I was directing.
I would get lost in his performance
and forget to say “Cut.”
I'm like, “Okay. Cut, cut. Cut it. My bad.”
And I think that Paul,
as an anchor to the movie,
really motivated
and helped the younger guys.
Because this is a new cast,
with Jason and Shea.
Neil worked a little bit,
and of course Aldis had some experience.
But when you work with
a veteran like Paul,
it only makes you better.
And I think that's what he did.
He was the anchor of the cast.
And such a good personality
and a good attitude about everything.
'Cause the script- We did a lot of changing.
He didn't mind improvising.
And he just did a great job.
Now, Kelli Jones-
she's our costume designer,
our wardrobe person.
She did a great job as well.
If you look at that velour suit,
anybody from the '80s knows
that that suit, believe it or not,
was popular at one time.
Look at the suit,
the way it hangs on him.
That's his version of cool.
You'll see later on, when he starts
to make a little money,
that it's gonna change a little bit.
But right now he's working
in this record shop- Macola Records-
and as Cube would put it,
he wasn't doing the greatest.
He was managing groups and things
like that, but basicallyjust hustling.
This is where they meet
and he convinces Eazy that,
“You know what? I can make you legit.”
And after watching that first scene,
you understand why Eazy's motivated
to want to be legit.
And of course a little eye candy.
I want to thank Bone, our consultant,
'cause he did a good job at helping us
find authentic people,
gave us details of things
that really happened back in the day.
He did a really good job
at making things happen for us.
I want to definitely give a shout-out to Bone.
Skateland USA is in Compton-
or was in Compton.
And this is how it was.
I get a lot of people from Compton that said,
“You really, really captured that.
I was there for that particular concert
with Eazy-E and N.W.A,
and it felt perfect.”
I love to hear that.
You get a sense
of where the all-black comes from.
The Raiders gear,
the Kings gear.
And of course Yella didn't do
what he was supposed to do.
And of course Eazy-E's on top of it,
being the leader that he is.
This is a moment that's, again,
serving the individuality of Eazy-E
as a character.
Dre's about the creativity,
Cube is about the writing
and kinda the politics
because everyone's passed
on this music.
No one's really biting.
So if you don't really perform now,
this could be the end of it.
And that's not in the theatrical.
But I love the fact that he comes in
and just kind of raises the stakes.
This is a moment that's, again,
serving the individuality of Eazy-E
as a character.
Dre's about the creativity,
Cube is about the writing
and kinda the politics
and Eazy-E is about the money.
And you see that when he says,
“Listen, you know what?
Let's show them who we are
and let's go get this money.”
This is a defining moment for him.
“Dopeman” was extremely popular.
I remember when I first heard this song,
I was thinking,
“Wow, did they really say that
on a record?”
it's a crazy song,
and it's so cinematic.
And that's what I loved
about Cube's writing.
You can draw a straight line
from a song like this
that feels almost like a movie.
You can see everything
that he's saying
and you can draw a straight line
to Cube as a filmmaker,
as a writer, as a director,
as a producer.
And this is a young guy
who visualizes things
and writes about them.
So there's a direct connection
to movies.
And you see that.
And of course it's a great moment
for O'Shea Jackson, Jr.,
because he's rocking the crowd.
He's got full control,
he's very confident,
and that's exactly what I wanted.
But more important than that,
this is the first time
the group performs together
and the first time
the actors performed together onstage.
And so, psychologically,
this was a very important moment,
not only in the story for the group,
but for my actors.
If they got this right, then the rest
of the shoot would go well for us.
But if they ran into any hiccups
or did something wrong
where it challenged their confidence,
it could have been disastrous
for the movie.
But they jumped out there
with the help of Dub-C William Calhoun,
who was a rap consultant.
He helped them all through the details
of performing West Coast-style
and all the little behavioral cues
and physical cues.
And DJ Robshot helped Corey
with the deejaying.
And also DJ Yella,
who is Neil Brown, Jr.
And so it all came together
in this one moment.
And you could see these guys
really rock the crowd.
And it felt real.
As a director,
you couldn't ask for a better
first performance out of your cast.
People have no idea
how challenging that is
to have to learn your lines,
wear a wig,
pretend like you're in the '80s
and rap for the first time.
This is what a lot of these guys
were doing,
And also DJ Yella,
who is Neil Brown, Jr.
And so it all came together
in this one moment.
As a director, you couldn't ask
for a better first performance
out of your cast.
And again, shout-out to Dub-C.
He did such a great job at making those guys
feel comfortable on stage.
This scene is a moment
where the guys are young
and to a certain extent
just celebrating and innocent, you know.
The brotherhood theme is served.
And of course we have
the introduction of Suge Knight,
who's played by Marcos Taylor.
Now, the story behind Marcos
is that he's not an actor.
He's a stuntman,
and more than that,
he's actually an MMA fighter.
I had such a hard time
finding a Suge Knight character,
because everybody
is so familiar with who he is
that I had to go
the unconventional route.
And at the last minute-
we call it midnight casting-
my stunt coordinator, Lin Oeding,
he brought Marcos Taylor
to the table and said,
“I have a guy who looks like Suge.
He's not an actor.
But maybe you could work with him.”
And when he came to the set,
when we were shooting
the battering ram scene,
I saw his guy and I'm like,
“Wow, he really does look like him.”
He auditioned with a couple other guys
while we were shooting.
And I said, “Although he's not an actor-
he's just used to fighting-
there may be something there.”
And there were some challenges because,
again, you're working with someone
there may be something there.”
And I think that Marcos
did a great job as well.
And there were some challenges because,
again, you're working with someone
who's not used
to the rhythm of making movies.
But, all in all, this guy stepped up
and really delivered.
And, of course, we introduce Bryan Turner,
who is played by Tate Ellington.
This is another good moment,
I think, for Dr. Dre,
because you show that he definitely
needs to make a choice,
especially given
the financial situation that he's in.
But he's not just gonna settle.
So he challenges Bryan.
He's like, “Hey, listen. Who's on your label?
We never heard of you.”
And I'm sure Jerry's thinking,
“What the fuck are you doing?
The only guy who's interested
in representing you guys
and signing you guys
is about to give you a deal,
and you're questioning that?”
That's just Dre.
He wants it to be right.
And that's a theme that really
runs with his character,
because he's not gonna do it
just to do it- he wants it to be right.
This is the first time you see that.
So far, the collaboration
between Jerry and Eazy is working.
They get a record deal,
and now they move
from Lonzo's dusty garage
to Audio Achievements.
Now this is really serious for Dr. Dre,
and he wanted to let everybody know
this is our lives, this is our creativity,
and we'd better do
the best we possibly can.
And he makes it clear.
In this montage, you get a chance
to listen to the different songs.
I love it.
This montage helps a lot,
because MC Ren doesn't get
a ton of time in the movie
and you really get a chance to see
how talented he is and hear his song.
You also get a chance
to see Dre on the mike,
because Dre wasn't really
rapping that much back then.
Showing a little bit of “Express Yourself'
really had to help show
that each one of these guys
had a very specific talent
and they all contributed to the album
Straight Outta Compton.
This montage also showed better times-
the brotherhood with the guys
and the fun times and the smiles.
It's not about threats
or danger or drama.
It's really just about the love
that these guys have for their art,
their creativity and for each other.
And of course later on
it gets challenging.
But these are the good times,
and you really feel that.
Our deal with Priority Records is done.
This is Jerry doing his job.
He gets out there.
He brokers the deal with Bryan Turner
and Priority Records,
and this is where you get a sense
that Cube is not necessarily happy
with everything that's going on.
It's a funny moment with the straws.
But really the definition of the scene is,
“Hey, listen, what's going on
with our contracts?”
Because Cube, as you'll find out,
never had a contract with N.W.A.
He was part of the group,
he wrote a lot of the songs,
but he did not have a contract.
And you got a sense of his doubt.
Keep an eye on that hamburger right there.
It pays off in the next scene.
This is another thing
that motivates Dr. Dre.
His baby's mom is really, really incensed.
She hates the fact that
they're sleeping at his aunt's house.
She packed up all of his kid's things,
all of her things
and moved out of Jinx's house.
She's had it.
She's done with it.
She thinks he's out screwing around,
just playing around
and not taking care of his responsibility,
and she just drives off
with his kid and everything.
And this is something that-
You feel a little bad for Dre.
You feel like, wow,
this guy is actually trying,
and nothing's going right.
Now, to add on to this moment
where he essentially loses his woman
and close contact with his child,
here comes the Torrance police.
This actor who plays the black cop,
his name is lnny Clemons.
Very talented actor
who, actually, I hired the night before.
What's strange is,
he assisted me on this movie.
He's a part of
the midnight casting as well.
We wanted to put a black officer in
so that the relationship with law enforcement
wouldn't be just racial.
It wasn't just white and black.
It was, hey, this is just about abuse of power.
Doesn't matter what color you are.
If you have power and you're abusing it,
we wanted to really show
that it came from all sides.
And he did a great job.
I think it's one of the strongest,
more potent moments in the movie.
I always get chills
when I watch this scene
because you see the guys on the ground
for absolutely no reason.
And I created a shot
where you really
define the relationship
between these particular cops
and N.W.A.
They really treat them like trash.
You see that shot right there?
There's boots and garbage
next to their faces.
And I just wanted to give the audience
a sense of how the guys felt.
They felt like trash.
And they're next to the boots
of these officers
while they're having
a casual conversation with Jerry
about the merits of what's happening.
And that's a violation.
And you really feel that.
It's not something you have
to intellectualize. You feel that.
That's part of the reason why it's one
of the stronger moments in the movie.
Because these guys were just artists
doing their thing.
They didn't break the law.
But they're being treated like trash.
And as an American citizen-
Not to get too preachy,
but that's fucked up.
But let me be clear.
This is not an anti-cop movie.
This movie is about a music group
that made history.
There are a lot of
little sub-story lines,
and their relationship with law enforcement
was part of that.
The point is,
any form of excessive force
is wrong.
And that's what this scene represented.
And I think that's what the song
that they're about to sing represents.
But I wanna be clear-
there are good cops out there
and there are cops
that overstep their boundaries.
And we hope that everyone
gets a sense
of what it feels like to be violated.
And maybe it changes the culture
in which this happens.
And that's what we're hoping for.
What I liked about the last scene
is Jerry takes up for the guys.
You get a good sense of why
he has a relationship with Eazy.
He's there,
he's defending the guys,
and he even gets a sense
of how abusive law enforcement
can be with the guys.
And you really get a sense of
how they all come together-
not just the brothers,
but Jerry as well.
The song “Fuck tha Police”
is obviously a reaction
to all of the moments
that led up to this,
but this is part of the montage
of making Straight Outta Compton.
And you get a sense
of the guys coming together,
how much fun it was
just being in the studio
with no supervision,
just everybody
really fully expressing themselves
and just being happy about it.
Eazy gets off on the mike.
Cube gets off on the mike.
Dre gets off on the mike.
Ren gets off on the mike.
And you see the fruits of their labor.
They're all happy
that the album was made.
They're all happy that not only
did they experience local success,
but they experience national success.
Now, Crenshaw Boulevard-
this is the strip.
I remember cruising Crenshaw Boulevard
in the '80s, and that was so much fun.
There's a movie called American Grafifi/
where they have a strip
where Ron Howard and his friends
kinda hang out,
and you get a sense of how much fun
they had with all the custom cars.
This is the equivalent of that,
but the black version.
Crenshaw was so much fun.
I loved shooting that scene
because you got a sense of how creative
everyone was in that environment-
In the hood, without a lot of resources,
they're customizing all these cars,
with the Suzuki Samurais,
with the El Caminos and the lowriders.
It's just a great moment.
This particular scene didn't make it
in the theatrical cut,
but I thought it was really funny.
They actually put it in the trailers,
but it didn't make it in the theatrical cut
for time purposes.
But Eazy was always strapped.
He was known for having
this semi-automatic or-
I'm not really sure.
It could have been a machine gun.
But it had a big silencer on it.
I talked to my prop guy,
Mike Sexton,
and I really wanted him to make sure
he got the gun right.
And instead of kind of creating
a dangerous moment,
the two times we show that gun,
it's actually really funny,
and this is one of them.
And of course, we start the tour.
This is the only tour I believe N.W.A.
went on, at least with Ice Cube,
and we start in Houston, Texas.
I went to the Cannes Film Festival
for another film that I produced,
and Matthew McConaughey told me
he went to this concert.
He had this whole story
about how he was the only white guy
with his friend in this concert
and he had a blast.
That's what I love about N.W.A.
No matter who you run into,
they have an N.W.A. story,
whether it's something
that they experienced on the tour,
or at least they knew where they were
when they first heard the group.
That's why I believe this movie
is so universally loved.
It's because the group was universally loved.
They had their haters,
but there was a lot of people who
loved them because they were honest,
and it touched a lot of people
outside of Los Angeles
and even outside of the States.
We shot that in the daytime.
We just digitally effected that.
This is a scene that did not make it
in the theatrical release.
I thought it was one of the funnier moments.
But again, of course, we can't have
a three-hour theatrical movie,
so we had to cut it out.
But Neil Brown, Jr. is so matter-of-fact
about watching porn
on the bus with these guys.
It just shows how funny it is
and how they had a lot of fun
with each other,
and they're just a bunch of kids.
People took them so serious.
They were labeled
the world's most dangerous group.
But when you watch the movie,
you realize they weren't as dangerous
as people said.
They were just a bunch of young guys
who wanted to have fun
and express themselves.
And they made history.
But that was just one of the funnier moments.
This is a funny moment as well.
But we start this scene off
with Dre talking to his brother,
really showing that he's concerned
and really showing that,
“Hey, listen, although I'm in the midst of all
this fun, I love you. How's Mom doing?”
And showing that he really cares
about his family.
You don't get that with the records.
A lot of times, people just associate
negativity with what they're talking about,
but the point of the movie is they're
human beings beyond the music
and beyond the genre of music.
They have their good days and bad days.
You show how much Dre loves his family,
and it really humanizes these guys.
That's part of the point as well.
These two guys are really from the streets.
That's why the movie feels so real.
I really wanted to cast guys
who you really felt the danger.
This one shot was so hard to get
because it takes place in two rooms
and a hallway.
Matty Libatique did such a great job
at creating moments like this
and helping me create moments like this
that didn't feel like the average coverage.
Everyone had to get everything right
and the timing had to be perfect.
This is one of my favorite moments, too,
where Jason is like,
“She's just sucking dick.”
I'm sorry. it's funny because you see
where his priorities are.
Then he lifts up this bed
and pulls out a shotgun.
It just shows how these young guys
are, one moment, partying
and the next moment ready to go to war.
Again, you see how
the brothers come together,
and there's nothing that can challenge them.
I thought this was a really clever line
that Jason came up with.
You really, really get a sense
that this group is impenetrable.
That's what I wanted to set up,
so you really felt it when things
start to go wrong.
You really don't want this group of guys
in this hallway to break up.
You just know they're gonna
be together forever.
Now this moment right here with Felicia
and the “Bye, Felicia” moment,
that was improvised.
Most people think we set that up.
No one could have wrote it.
Shea came up with that line,
and it's an homage
to my first movie, Friday,
which obviously I did with his dad,
Ice Cube.
The audience goes nuts when they see
that “Bye, Felicia” moment.
I still to this day don't know
why it's a phenomenon,
but “Bye, Felicia” lives on.
“Gangsta Gangsta” has to be
one of my favorite N.W.A. songs.
I love the way he captures this,
because he's just into it.
He just really, really gets into it.
It's such a vivid, visual song.
Again, it's a testament to Ice Cube
and his talent.
He's just really, really good.
You feel like you're in the scene
when you listen to those moments.
Now you start to feel the pressure
from outside forces.
It starts with law enforcement
and their reaction
to the album Straight Outta Compton.
And more specifically, “Fuck tha Police.”
Again, it's a testament to Ice Cube
and his talent.
Now you start to feel the pressure
from outside forces.
It starts with law enforcement
and their reaction
to the album Straight Outta Compton.
And more specifically, “Fuck tha Police.”
This scene really sets up the fact
that it goes well beyond LAPD.
Now the FBI is getting involved.
And Ice Cube's point,
and the group's point, for that matter,
is why is it
that it's in our Constitution
that we have the right of freedom of speech
but we can't really speak our mind
in our records?
This is a testament to Eazy's genius,
where he says, “You know what?
If we're going to be challenged
by the government,
then we're gonna make money off of it.
We're gonna create publicity to surround
what is clearly an illegal push
to silence us and to censor us.”
For Eazy to be so young
but to be so savvy,
it really shows how street knowledge
really kicks in.
You don't necessarily have to have an MBA
to understand business and to be savvy.
And Eazy was extremely savvy.
This is one of those moments that really-
it was a pivotal moment.
It changed the course of history,
especially for the group.
They used it.
They didn't cower,
and they didn't shy away from the challenge.
I don't know how Jerry Heller
felt about it, but-
He seemed to not want
to go down this road.
He seemed a little hesitant, to say the least.
I can understand why he would,
but you have a bunch of young guys
that are really passionate.
And Cube always says,
“We didn't really give a shit about the FBI
'cause we didn't know
to what extent they had power.
We just thought it was just a letter.
A letter can't hurt us.
If it was the LAPD-
which, you know,
we've been at the other end of a billy club-
we'd be worried.
But this is the FBI.
We just see those guys dressed in suits
and walking around offices on television.”
So they weren't really that...
fazed.
They just kept going.
Of course, there was the controversy.
There are people around the nation
that love the guys,
but there are some people
who really did not feel it.
They felt like some of the lyrics
were misogynistic.
They felt like the lyrics were really negative.
And we represented that
in that one little moment
where everyone wasn't in love with the group.
You start to see that all the fun
that led up to this moment
is starting to really change.
This moment is a lot of fun.
We shot this in 1O minutes.
My production designer wasn't in love with
the fact that we trashed that bus with beer.
But it's N.W.A.
What do you expect?
They're on tour.
We have a “war on drugs” moment
with Nancy Reagan.
That's something for those
who are a little political
and understand what that means.
Again, a moment where the group
starts to splinter.
More specifically, Ice Cube.
He brings up the contracts earlier
before the Torrance moment with the cops,
and now he's bringing it up again.
This time, he's a little angry.
He sees that these guys are having lobster.
They're eating Fatburger.
And there's just this disparity
between how they're living-
being Eazy and Jerry-
and how the group's living.
And it doesn't feel right.
On top of that,
he's doing all this work,
he's not really getting paid what he deserves,
and he's standing up for himself.
It takes a lot of balls for a young guy
without pretty much any money at all,
who lives at home with his mom and dad,
to challenge his bosses.
Because that's essentially who they are.
They run the show.
But he has a sense that something's wrong,
and, at every turn
he's gonna challenge them.
I actually respected that.
Another really good moment
for O'Shea Jackson, Jr.
This guy really showed up
and really performed.
And he's in there with a heavyweight.
Paul Giamatti is really great at what he does
and you really feel the weight of that moment.
I love how expressive Jerry is, his eyes.
You always know there's subtext there.
It's one thing for him to say something,
but you always know there's something
else going on behind his eyes,
and that's the brilliance of Paul Giamatti.
Now Cube is really trying to figure out
if everyone has a chance.
More specifically,
does Dre know what's going on.
Do you see what I see?
Dre is like, “Listen, man,
I have too much going on.
I want this to work.”
This moment is a great moment,
and it really draws on
what Corey Hawkins is good at.
All of that training at Juilliard
and his dramatic training
really pays off in this scene.
Because it's really hard for a young man-
especially a young black man
from DC and from the streets-
to tap into his emotions.
Or at least I've found that,
in dealing with people
who are acting or who attempt to act,
to really tap into their vulnerable side
or to show any vulnerability at all.
And the training really helped.
Because I was always nervous
about shooting scenes like this
because you're so used to not going there
that when you do, it feels false.
That's been my experience
with younger talent.
That when you do, it feels false.
That's been my experience
with younger talent.
They just have a hard time going there
and making it feel real.
But when someone's trained,
you can just press a button
and they'll get there.
This moment between the guys is one
of the most important moments
because the theme of brotherhood
is really captured in this sequence
when Dre's brother dies.
They all come together.
You normally don't associate a lot of emotion
with this genre of music.
You just don't.
Or vulnerability. You just don't.
This is where you see all of these guys
really show another side.
This moment between the guys is one
of the most important moments
because the theme of brotherhood
is really captured in this sequence
when Dre's brother dies.
They all come together.
You normally don't associate a lot of emotion
with this genre of music.
You just don't.
Or vulnerability. You just don't.
This is where you see all of these guys
really show another side.
And to show that,
“Hey, Dre, you are important to us.
You're important to me.
I love you.
I love you as a brother
and you'll never lose me.
And we know this is challenging.
It's probably the most challenging time
of your life, and we have your back.”
Another great moment with Lisa Renee Pitts.
She's just so solid and grounded.
And, you know,
to get this relationship with Dre
and his mom is so important.
Because the group is always attacked
about their relationship to women
and how they don't care
and how negative it could be sometimes.
It was important for me to show
that that's not their relationship
in real life with women.
And I love that moment
between Dre and his mom.
This is one of my favorite shots in the movie
because it's family.
Now for the Detroit police sequence.
This was a really fun, fun sequence to shoot.
That's Greg Collins, the cop.
He's a really good actor,
and all of the cops next to him
are actually real.
They're from LAPD.
They're on-duty cops.
They actually had a good attitude
about us shooting this sequence
after hearing the song “Fuck tha Police”
over and over and over again
over the course of three days.
I think they had
just a good attitude about it.
I like this sequence because,
when you're being bullied,
sometimes you have to stand up.
That's what this sequence represents.
Freedom of speech
applies to everyone in this country.
It's a constitutional right, and that's what
these guys are basically saying.
You cannot bully us,
we can say what we want,
we can feel what we want to feel,
and as long as we're not breaking the law,
you have no right to tell us what to do
and/or say.
This is somewhat of a bittersweet moment.
This is one of their best songs.
This is one of the best sequences
in terms of performance
that my actors gave.
But at the same time, it's really heavily
politicized by a lot of Americans
and also by some politicians.
It's bittersweet
because it's such a good moment
where you feel that these characters
are standing up to bullies,
and you understand why.
But at the same time,
there's death and destruction
that's happening in the streets of America,
and it's wrong on both sides.
We don't advocate violence
against American civilians
and certainly don't advocate violence
against law enforcement.
People have taken this song
and they've taken parts of this movie
and tried to politicize it,
and I think it's unfair.
So it's a bittersweet moment for me
because it's necessary.
But at the same time,
it's specific to the moment in time
when it was performed,
when it was created,
and I don't want any of these moments
to be taken out of context.
This cable cam shot was very hard
to not only achieve and execute,
but just even the design,
it was crazy.
Because it went from way back there
in the wide shot
all the way to wrap around
a close-up of his finger.
My line producer, Adam Merims,
did a great job at really making that happen.
That's one of those mountain requests
that you make.
“L want you to move this mountain.
Make it happen.”
He made it happen.
Now one of my favorite shots happens
right coming up about here.
I just love, like, how all three of them
just emphatically started the song.
Because it's just, again,
the synergy with all the guys.
You just knew they were all together,
and there's no one who could challenge them.
It's just a great moment.
It's a great moment in the film.
It's a great moment in music.
It's a great moment in history.
It says, “Listen, you should stand up.
You stand up for what you believe
regardless of who's challenging you.”
And I love it.
I love this performance because
this is the biggest concert scene
we had to shoot, at the Joe Louis Arena.
Of course, it was the LA Sports Arena.
I loved what the group delivered.
I loved what my actors delivered.
They did a great job at performing both songs,
“Straight Outta Compton,”
and more specifically, “Fuck tha Police.”
it's a great song.
It's a great moment in the film.
But the song is a response
to excessive force,
and it was necessary,
and that's the end of it.
There should be a change in law enforcement
in terms of the culture.
On the ﬂip side to that,
we're not advocating violence against police.
Because at the end of the day, we need
law enforcement to protect us as well.
So we fight against anyone
who feels like it's okay
to violate or hurt
innocent citizens of this country.
Peﬂod.
It doesn't matter if you're from the hood
or if you're in law enforcement.
We want to be clear about that.
I love this shot right here.
And I love this shot right here.
Big shout-out to my camera operator
Colin Hudson.
He was so great at doing what he does.
He's a drummer,
and I liken all art to music,
or at least I think that all art
is somehow connected to rhythm.
When you have a camera operator
that's a drummer, they just get it.
It's all rhythm and timing.
And he just did an amazing job.
He, along with Matty Libatique.
You couldn't get any better camera operator.
They knew where to be,
what shot to create in the moment
because I did a lot of handheld shots.
And they knew exactly
how to capture the moment
and where to be
and the rhythm of the scene.
I love those guys.
They are A1, top, top-notch.
Now the riot, we shot this in Los Angeles
at the LA Sports Arena,
my old stomping grounds when I was a kid.
And a lot of people showed up
from a radio contest.
A lot of those extras are extras
that showed up in a radio contest
and they were really fully into it.
I love this moment too. These guys get
arrested and thrown in a paddy wagon,
and they laugh their way through it.
Which, in a strange way,
although they're being arrested,
they're still celebrating like it was a win.
It's like, “You know what?
We defied the cops. We don't give a shit.
We won because we didn't let them
tell us what to do.”
it was just a fun moment for them.
It was a fun moment in the movie as well.
I want the audience
to really get a sense of the “Why?”
Meaning, why would these young guys
write these lyrics?
Why would they do these songs?
You hear about a lot of negativity
on the surface, but why would you do it?
We touch a little bit on that in this scene.
When you grow up in an environment
that changes so drastically
when there's this inﬂux of not only cocaine-
crack cocaine-
but military weapons,
it changes the whole environment.
And the whole gangster lifestyle
is fueled not only by the lack of education,
but the inﬂux of drugs and weapons.
This is what these guys wrote about.
Now, in no stretch of imagination am I
suggesting they were freedom fighters
or that they live on the level
of Martin Luther King.
But I will say that they just wrote
about what they saw,
what they experienced.
In the last scene,
they talked about the fact that,
“Hey, we don't have passports,
but we have access
to Russian machine guns.
We don't have passports,
but we have metric tons of cocaine
being shipped into our neighborhoods.
Now who's doing that,
and why?”
So when you start to judge the music,
dig a little deeper and figure out
why the environment's like that.
Because they wouldn't write about it
if it wasn't like that.
But dig a little deeper.
In the last scene, they mention
that this is just a reﬂection of our reality.
You don't necessarily
have to love the music,
you don't even necessarily
have to agree with it,
but you have to, at the very least,
examine it.
I like that last scene
because it touches on something
a little deeper than just music.
On a side note,
remember that velour sweat suit
that Jerry wore in the first scene?
This is where he gets a little ﬂy.
This reminds me of Al Pacino in Scarf ace.
He's got the ﬂy hairstyle,
he's got the Don Johnson, Miami Vice
sports coat on,
and so you can tell
he's making a little money
and getting a little ﬂy.
Cube notices that too.
But the heart of this scene is really about
the fact that he does not understand
these contracts,
and he needs to take it to someone else,
and he feels like something's
really fishy here.
I gotta say, when I was that age,
I wouldn't have challenged that.
If someone held up a check for $75,000
and told me to sign it-
Probably if they held up that check today,
I'd probably sign it.
But definitely as a teenager,
I would have just signed it and went with it.
But Cube was smart enough
to say, “Listen.
If I can't get this examined,
I do not want to sign it.”
That should inspire people
to just do their due diligence
and really serve good business.
That's a pickup shot with the bus
that's filled with beer smells.
We did that later.
This is Suge Knight and Big Dave.
Big Dave's actually a real guy.
We gave him a couple lines in the movie
because, again,
he just really is an authentic dude.
Really from the streets of Compton.
This scene is really-
it represents the beginning of the end.
You see how the group was together
for the first half of the movie,
and now, even visually,
you start to see the group splinter.
D.O.C goes his own way,
Eazy goes his own way with Jerry,
and as you'll see coming up,
even Cube goes his own separate way.
So it seems like what was
a group of brothers-
After the tour, after the drama,
after the losses and the pain
and the contracts,
the group starts to splinter.
I wanted to show that
not only intellectually.
I wanted you to see it visually.
Everybody goes their own separate way.
And it's never the same after this moment.
We shot this in Leimert Park.
I went to elementary school in this area.
So it's a special place,
'cause I love bringing production
back to places where I grew up.
I moved around quite a bit,
but this is a special place for me.
This is South Central LA,
Leimert Park.
It's a block away from Crenshaw,
and I love this place.
- Take care of yourself, Dre.
- Peace.
This digs into the relationships with women.
More specifically, Dre and his mom.
You show that he really loves his mom.
Regardless of what happened earlier,
he wants to be there to support her,
especially after the loss of
his little brother and her son.
That wasn't in the theatrical release,
but it was something that was
important to me.
We now introduce
Ice Cube's wife, Kim.
She's Kim Jackson now, of course.
She's played by Alexandra Shipp,
and she did a really good job.
I actually think that Shea
was pretty fond of her.
You can understand that.
But he was a little distracted sometimes.
But he did a good job in this scene.
He strikes a deal with Bryan Turner
and goes on to make what I consider
one of the best hip-hop albums of all time-
Amer/KKKate Most Wanted.
That album was absolutely crazy.
llovedit
To this day, it's still one of the top
hip-hop albums, period.
He went to New York and worked
with The Bomb Squad and Chuck D.
We showed Chuck D a little more.
You see the guy with the P hat?
That's Chuck D.
You see some of his inﬂuences in this scene
and how he went from West Coast
and Dr. Dre,
went straight to the East Coast
and had The Bomb Squad
do this crazy, different approach to music
with a West Coast lyricist
but with an East Coast ﬂavor.
I think that's part of the reason why-
When you bring the two together,
history is made.
I love West Coast music,
and I love East Coast music,
but when you bring them together, it's crazy.
That album really represented that.
As you can tell, Dre even loved the album,
even though Cube is not
a part of N.W.A. anymore.
And by the way, that car is worth $110,000,
'cause there's not a screw
that wasn't touched on it,
and it's a beautiful car.
Now here we are at the Eazy-E
“Wet and Wild” party.
This is where they had
the most notorious parties
that LA has probably ever seen.
I love this moment because you see
that everybody is having fun,
but they're all separate.
You have Yella and Ren over here.
You have Dre over with the women by himself.
Then you see Eazy with Jerry.
So something that's different about this
is ordinarily when they're having fun,
they're together.
But once Cube left the group,
you start to feel this disconnect
with the guys.
While on the surface
it feels like they're having a good time,
you start to see that the group is splintering.
I wanted to do that visually
to give you a sense
that while it seems
okay on the surface,
things aren't really
as good as they may seem.
Let's sit down for two seconds.
- Look, we need to keep Dre happy.
- Yeah.
In this scene- besides the fact that
Eazy really wants to participate in the party-
he sees that Dre may be
the next one to go.
Jerry really wants him to focus on business.
Eazy wants to focus on pussy
and making sure his group
doesn't fall apart.
You see where his priorities are.
It's kind of interesting,
at least in the movie.
The serious part
about this scene is that
this is where Suge
starts to poach Dr. Dre.
You can see the concern on Jerry's face,
and the fact that he started
with D.O.C. and was successful.
He's not really sure,
but he looks like he's starting on Dr. Dre.
You see that look?
You also quickly see D.O.C.
give that kind of same
suspicious look right there.
Dre tells me all these stories
about what was going on.
He said that's what would happen,
and it's pretty crazy.
This is a really cool moment,
because I remember
when this actually happened.
I got a phone call from a friend saying,
“Cube just went nuts
and tore up Priority Records.”
And this is the moment that
sets up that moment where he's saying,
“Listen. I've been through this once before,
and I'm not going through this shit again.”
I remember Priority Records
was on Sunset Boulevard.
The fact that Cube
didn't get arrested
for tearing up
an office in Hollywood
with a bunch of his goons
and baseball bats
is so amazing to me,
especially with their relationship
with the police.
He could have- He could still be in jail
right now for what he did.
But you see, in this particular cut,
he looks at all of the platinum albums
and the gold albums.
And enough is enough.
We know what's about to happen right now.
You see the baseball bat.
People actually ask me,
“Did that really happen?”
'Cause it seems like a dramatic moment
that a director would put in a movie
but it really didn't happen.
And it really did happen.
Cube ripped this office apart.
I wouldn't suggest anyone do this now,
but it actually worked.
He got his check.
It probably wouldn't work today,
but it worked back in the day.
If you look at this one shot,
you see, just to the left, the ice cube-
where we go from
the last smashing of the table,
and we rack focus to the ice cube
on Bryan Turner's desk,
showing Ice Cube has been here.
He came, he saw and he conquered.
Now we set up that the group
was splintering at the party.
Now all of the fun that we set up
in the earlier recording sessions-
when they were recording
Straight' Outta Compton-
now it's just not the same.
You see everybody is sitting around,
the energy's low, no one's having any fun,
everyone seems somewhat either distracted-
it just doesn't seem like the brotherhood
is the same as it was before,
now that Cube left.
I think that's one of the reasons
why it's so important to establish
how much fun it was
when they were a group.
Now it just feels like work.
Even the happiest guy in the group-
DJ Yella's kind of sitting back going,
“This is not fun at all.”
This is also a moment that happened
where Dre gets a call
about D.O.C. being in a car accident.
This was a big story back in the day
when we all heard
that one of the best West Coast MCs-
although he was from Houston,
he was still considered part of the west-
lost his ability to speak,
or, at the very least, his ability to rap.
That was tragic because he was so good.
He had so much potential.
Where your people?
Where Eazy and Jerry?
How the fuck should I know?
And of course,
this is where Suge,
kind of rightfully so, says,
“Listen, man. This could be you.
Something's going on with your business,
and I want to help you with this.”
As Dre telIs it,
this is kind of where
they start to kind of investigate
what their agreements were with Ruthless.
You could see right here,
Corey Hawkins is doing such a good job
at splitting his attention
between his friend, who's injured,
and the business at hand.
The seeds of doubt have been planted.
Right now, Suge's getting a foothold
into the Ruthless camp.
This is a moment that did not
make it into the theatrical release.
I hated that it didn't,
because I wanted to show
that Tomica Woods-Wright,
who is Eazy's widow-
really had a relationship with him
beyond the average groupie.
This scene kind of defines that.
She's played by Carra Patterson,
who's from New York,
who did such a great job.
But it shows Eazy's vulnerable side.
It shows that in the midst of partying
with all these groupies
and doing all this stuff on tour,
that he's a little vulnerable with her.
You could see in his eyes,
and see that this girl's a little different.
She works in the record industry.
She's an executive assistant.
So she has a little bit of something
going for her.
You could feel a different connection
between the two.
Now his office has been
completely remodeled
because of the damage
that Ice Cube inflicted.
And again, to this day,
I don't understand
how he didn't get into any trouble.
But he stood up for what he thought
was right, and he got his money.
Now the plot thickens.
I remember when this song came out
and was thinking,
“Whoa. That was pretty harsh.”
“Benedict Arnold.”
That was pretty harsh.
But there's nothing more harsh
than what I consider
one of the best dis tracks
in the history of all of music.
Not just hip-hop, but all of music.
“No Vaseline” has to be
one of the most passionate,
venomous dis tracks
to ever be recorded to this day.
It wasn't in the original script.
But I called Cube up one day
and said, “Listen.
You cannot make an N.W.A movie
without putting 'No Vaseline' in the movie.”
You just can't do it.
It's not possible.
It's such a popular song
that never had a music video.
So in a strange way,
obviously it serves the narrative
for Straight Outta Compton.
But it's also, in a strange way,
the music video for “No Vaseline.”
I've never had a response
from a sequence like this
in the history of my career.
We dropped a Brink's truck
in the Italian Job.
We blew people up in LawAb/d/ng Cit/zen.
I've had some pretty good moments
in cinema history,
but people damn near stood up
and cheered after listening to this song
and experiencing the reaction
of the guys in the group.
It's Ice Cube at his best.
The young lady right here, Maria Sten,
is Miss Denmark 2007.
Very beautiful woman.
Very, very cool. A good actor as well.
Cube said that he was heavily inﬂuenced
by Richard Pryor and Muhammad Ali.
When you listen to “No Vaseline,”
you could really hear the inﬂuences,
especially Muhammad Ali-
the rhyming, the humor, the venom.
He just torpedoed the group.
I really don't think the group
was the same after that.
That shit's kind of funny.
Neil Brown, Jr. is so funny.
Just comic relief when you need it,
especially with something so harsh
with the lyrics
and how they responded to the song.
His comedic timing is just perfect.
Who the fuck does he think he is?
Un-fucking-believable.
That kind of fucking bullshit.
Jew-bashing bullshit.
MC Ren is incensed.
Paul Giamatti, who plays Jerry Heller,
is super pissed off.
Eazy-E
is really starting to see
his team fall apart.
And you can feel that.
I don't think Cube planned
for it to have that type of effect,
but after talking to the group,
they really said
nothing was the same after that.
They acknowledged that
Cube won that battle,
and he clearly did.
And hip-hop-
You hear these battles
going back and forth and stuff like that,
but it's not the way it used to be.
These guys really went back and forth,
and it was crazy.
Cube clearly got the upper hand,
especially with this song.
If looks could kill-
look at that look.
You got to love Jason.
He's just so on point.
That felt like a real moment.
Like a really real moment.
He didn't seem like he was acting.
He really looked like he was pissed off.
I guess that's the goal.
But he just really sank
into this particular character.
Again, people ask me,
did this really happen?
There was a New Music Seminar
where there was a group called
Above the Law,
and they got into a brawl
with Cube and Da Lench Mob.
This is what happened.
This kind of goes beyond hip-hop.
You should keep it on wax
when you have these beefs,
but it got so crazy that it became physical.
Of course, this is the infamous
Rodney King beating.
And it's juxtaposed to what you would
consider black-on-black crime.
You have black guys
beating up black guys.
Now you have white guys
It's just a weird feeling to see
all of this violence.
I was hoping that people would
watch this moment and say,
“You know what? This is all silly.”
it's kind of ridiculous
to actually war with each other,
when clearly, people are warring with us.
And now we're in the studio yet again,
and it's not fun at all.
All those fun moments when they
were recording Straight Outta Compton,
all the montages where the guys were having
a great time, laughing and smiling-
none of that.
I think that really affected Dre's creativity.
He was creating under duress.
One of the surprise moments
was this moment
by an ex-NFL football player,
who went to the Super Bowl
and the Pro Bowl-
Thomas Jones,
who really is a superb athlete.
But he comes off as one of
the hardest thugs
and scariest thugs you've ever seen on film.
When he says, “Is this your house?”
I don't think any man alive
wouldn't think twice
about answering that question.
That look left and right
was one of the most
awkward moments in the movie.
Because you don't know if
this guy is going to shoot Jerry,
stab him or skin him alive and scalp him.
He's so comfortable in this
passive-aggressive threat,
that it just sends shivers
down the spine of the audience.
I love this moment.
And he just walks away
like nothing happened.
This scene here is one of the more
pivotal moments in the movie.
We obviously experience
Ice Cube leaving the group.
But this is a moment
that's really, really emotional
for Dr. Dre in real life.
He told me that-
He assumed when he brought
the contracts to Eazy,
that it was a foregone conclusion
that he was going to say, “Okay,
I see that things don't seem right
or, you know, it doesn't add up.
So, I'm going to rock with my boy,
and we're good.
We're just going to find
a new path to business.”
When Eazy decided to actually
go with Jerry versus Dre-
I remember having
my first meeting with him.
He paused because I think
he still felt a certain way about it.
It was very painful for him, because
he had such a great relationship-
or so he thought- with Eazy.
Eazy's not here to speak for himself.
I'm assuming that it was just a mistake.
But this is something
that Dre took to heart.
He was very surprised.
He was taken aback.
It was very, very painful for him.
I think this is one of Corey's
strongest moments as well.
This is a really interesting moment,
because Eazy can't even
look him in the eye.
He just can't.
When you have a movie that deals
with this genre of music,
again, you just don't associate emotion,
this level of emotion or vulnerability
with this genre of music.
I think that's part of what
makes these guys special.
Because they're true leading men.
Their performances are top-notch.
Because they're not only capable
of giving you
that masculine, macho,
street-guy thing,
but they're also capable
of being vulnerable.
Which is a great balance.
This is a great, balanced performance.
I always said-
Not to compare them to these guys,
but if you look at a Humphrey Bogart
or if you look at a Marlon Brando-
You look at A Streetcar Named Desire.
These guys really, really were tough guys.
Or Casablanca
or anything that Bogart did.
They give you this tough-guy image,
but they're also able to be vulnerable.
That's what makes a classic performance.
I think these guys really delivered that,
especially Dre and by Eazy.
This is the turning point for Dre.
He's now in bed with Suge Knight.
They started the company Death Row.
“Deep Cover,” which is a crazy track.
I love this song.
Dre's feeling like, “Hey, listen.
I can make good music,
but I'm still under contract.”
Marcos is very, very comfortable
in playing this role.
You can tell.
This is actually a moment
that really was kind of funny.
If you know anything
about the streets of Los Angeles,
there's a Crip and Blood dynamic
that's very, very interesting.
It's actually very dangerous.
And so Keith Stanfield,
who plays Snoop,
walks into this room filled with Bloods
and he's a Crip.
This guy is probably 110 pounds soaking wet.
He walks into this room with these goons
that are 300 pounds apiece-
all muscle, all murder.
He doesn't give a fuck about
what they think about where he's from.
He's like, “I'm from Long Beach.”
He's got a blue rag in his back pocket
in a red room
with a room full of Bloods.
He just doesn't give a shit.
Look how he moves his hand.
He's like, “I'll just listen to the music.”
This guy can get his neck
broken at any moment.
He just doesn't care.
It's kind of how Snoop was, you know.
He was a thin guy,
but he had a lot of heart.
We captured that moment, I think.
Keith was great.
He sounds like Snoop.
He doesn't look like Snoop as much,
but he definitely captured Snoop's
essence and kind of looked like him.
It's a funny moment. if you look at that stare
that Suge gave him- it's fucking crazy.
He looked like he could kill
Snoop and Dre in that moment.
And back to Rodney King.
I wanted to show this common-
this thread that was
going through the stories.
Just the thread of law enforcement
but also the hints of black-on-black crime.
These things are running parallel
in the movie.
It's pretty sad.
Hopefully when the viewer
watches this movie,
they can get a sense of how idiotic
it is to be so destructive.
You see it on the tapes with Rodney King.
You see it with the scene
that's coming up next,
where there's this violence that happens.
I can't judge anyone else,
but I do feel like there are better ways
and better solutions to solve
some of the problems we deal with today.
And better solutions to solve
You see the juxtaposition of
law enforcement and gangs,
and sometimes I don't see the difference.
Like, who's right and who's wrong?
You know?
That's a Malinois dog,
and I hope I pronounced it right.
He looks like a German shepherd,
but he's like a turbo German shepherd.
They're extremely dangerous.
My understanding is that
Suge used to have a dog
that was from Holland or from Germany,
and he spoke German.
And the dog was extremely dangerous.
On command,
this dog would attack anyone.
I've met the trainer for this dog,
and he was so on point with these dogs.
You could give them
a German command,
and they would destroy
anything in front of them.
Then they would just chill out.
I was told stories about this dog,
and he was kind of infamous.
Because while you see
all these big guys in the room,
kind of not afraid of anything,
they were afraid of that damn dog.
This is another great moment.
Although Eazy is being
jumped by these guys,
he still had heart, you know.
Eazy didn't strike me as a guy
who was fearful or would back down.
You experienced that moment
in the beginning of the movie
when he was in the dope house
with the Crips in Compton.
He was like, “Hey, listen.
Do what you got to do.”
Even now, he doesn't give a shit.
That was the lion heart of Eazy-E,
and I wanted to capture that.
I think Jason- A part of Jason's
personality is like that too.
This guy is fearless.
You get a sense of that.
There's no acting there.
I think that was part of
Eazy's approach to life as well.
The guy was fearless.
I think that's the reason why you get
such a great performance from Jason.
This guy is fearless.
You get a sense of that.
There's no acting there.
I think that was part of Eazy's
approach to life as well.
The guy was fearless.
I think that's the reason why you get
such a great performance from Jason.
This is a moment that I think serves
the brotherhood theme as well.
And although this dynamic is not
necessarily brother and brother,
what I wanted to create
was more of a father-son dynamic.
Because based on my research,
I think that Jerry had more of
a father-son relationship with him,
and that's the reason why Eazy trusted him
and that's the reason
why he confided in him
and they had a deeper relationship
than just business.
And there was a lot of trust there.
When Eazy got into this issue,
he went to Jerry to confide in him
and to let him know and warn him,
“Hey, listen, things are about to get thick,
and I'm gonna do what you would
ordinarily do on the street
because it has to happen.”
And Jerry, being this father figure,
basically says, “No, you're not gonna do that.
I care about you.
You have to do this the right way
because it's a zero-sum game.
If you hit back it's gonna end, and it's not
necessarily end in your favor.”
And what I like about that is
you really get a sense
of why Eazy would trust Jerry.
Because- There's part of me that feels
like Jerry really did care about this guy.
Otherwise it probably,
at least in the storytelling,
would make Eazy look kind of crazy
to just go with a guy
who just comes off as untrustworthy.
I think they had a great relationship
and a deeper relationship
than just business,
and that's the reason why things got
uncomfortable or twisted towards the end.
This shot did not make it
in the theatrical release because of time,
but I loved the moment.
Because Eazy really has to figure out
his next move,
and he confides in his woman, Tomica.
You know, he goes to Jerry first,
which he has this father-son relationship,
and then he goes to his woman.
And I wanted to have a little more with
all the relationships with the women.
I wanted to deepen the relationships.
And it's unfortunate that the cut was
so long that I had to cut these things out.
But you can see how much
she cares about this guy
and the pain he's going through because
he can't hit back the way he wants.
And there's something that feels
changed about him and different.
And Tomica Wright told me,
when this actually happened,
he came home and it seemed
like he was just never the same
after that evening.
And I think Jason did an amazing job and
restrained himself from going over the top,
but you could see it in his eyes.
So then when we check in with Dr. Dre,
he, on the surface, looks cool,
especially to his friends and family,
but he told me he was broke.
He had maybe $20,000, $30,000
in the bank,
this huge house with absolutely
no furniture,
and he just didn't have
any real motivation.
He was distraught,
and that was pretty interesting
because a lot of people felt like,
“You're Dr. Dre. You're doing well.”
This particular scene did not make it
into the theatrical release.
And it's kind of interesting
because everybody knows
about the chronic.
It's just a funny moment with Snoop
offering him the chronic,
and then he goes on and embarks
on the chronicjourney.
I don't think that's really
what happened in real life.
It was someone else
who actually did that,
but we took a little dramatic license.
Because everyone knows
Snoop's relationship with marijuana,
and Dre really didn't smoke a ton
before that time.
And the rest is history.
The Chronic is a classic album.
And that's the reason why things got
uncomfortable or twisted towards the end.
This is one of Dre's best songs,
“G Thang,”
and it's one of my favorite moments
in the movie
because Keith Stanfield does such
a great job at playing Snoop.
The track is incredible.
It's quintessential Dr. Dre,
California, LA life.
And it's also pretty funny
because you have this guy
making a classic
in a big, empty mansion.
And it really captures
exactly what was going on
with the drama and the creativity
and the rawness of The Chronic album.
And it's just a lot of fun, man,
and I think Keith did a great job.
And Corey is really into it.
Harvey Mason Jr.,
who actually set this up for us,
did a great job
at reverse engineering the song.
They're in this big
Tony Montana house.
It's just a fun moment.
Now you check in with Ice Cube,
who says that although
he experienced a lot of success
with Amer/KKKate Most Wanted
and with Death Ce/T/'ficate,
this is one of the most challenging
moments in his life.
He got a lot of ﬂack for a lot of things
he said on Death Certificate.
He had to defend himself,
and this is one of those moments.
Cube has always been
a pretty clever guy, really funny.
He told me that he was inspired
by Richard Pryor
and by Muhammed Ali.
And you can hear that in his lyrics.
You can also kind of see
a little bit of that in this scene
where he challenges the reporter
and tells him about
his point of view on everything.
And it's not only kind of
a strong approach
to illustrating and letting a person
know what your philosophy is,
but it's also pretty damn funny.
This is one of the biggest laughs
that we have in the movie,
and Shea Jr. is absolutely on point
when he delivers this last line-
“Eat a dick and get the fuck out of my house.”
This is something-
that Cube would have said
back in the day.
It's a really funny moment,
but it was also one of the more challenging
moments in Cube's career.
I'm glad he let us put that out there
and kind of show
that it wasn't always easy.
If you think Eazy-E had wild parties
with the “Wet and Wild” parties,
there was no party like a Dr. Dre
summertime party circa early '90s.
Trust me. I went to one,
and it was absolutely crazy.
This shot was one of my favorite shots
and we had to cut it out
of the theatrical movie,
but it's kind of an homage
to Scorsese.
I loved it because it starts on
the second floor with the menage a trois
and we follow the weed and the joint
to the deejay,
and then we go down
to the first ﬂoor
and then down even farther
into the pool.
We pick up Nicole,
who is now Dre's wife,
but in the movie,
he's never met her before.
So we have to go through the water,
follow her- as you can see her
in the left frame-
reveal Dre and, of course,
a little booty,
and then we see Dre see Nicole,
and he's awestruck.
I gotta tell you, it took over 2O takes
just to get that one shot.
It was one of the hardest shots
I'd ever, not only designed,
but ever had to execute.
Because between the girls
bumping the camera,
the beach ball hitting the camera,
my grips bumping the camera,
water getting on the camera,
I can't describe to you the level
of engineering it took
to actually get that one shot.
I got to say I was a little disappointed
we couldn't put it in the theatrical.
But I saved it for you guys,
so I hope you enjoyed it.
Because it took an entire day
to do that one shot.
And there's nothing wrong
with having a few pretty women around,
so anybody who wants to complain
about that, e-mail me.
This scene is an interesting scene
because, while it wasn't written
in the script,
I always wanted to show
a father-son relationship.
So you see Jerry
bringing Eazy sandwiches
and he's serving him food,
and he's always
somewhat nurturing Eazy.
And so, again, just psychologically,
you get a sense that he has a different
relationship with Jerry
than he does with the guys.
He has to be a leader,
he has to be a street tough
and all the things that you would expect
from Eazy-E- he's from the street.
But, basically,
you serve the father-son relationship
between the two in the blocking.
And, of course, this is where
we meet Jimmy lovine,
who is, to this day,
Dr. Dre's business partner.
This is the beginning.
This is where it all happens.
And if you do a little homework,
you'll see that they've gone on
to not only work with each other with
Death Row Records and lnterscope,
but with Aftermath and then, of course,
on to one of their bigger ventures,
which is Beats headphones,
which they went on to sell to Apple.
Which was one of the biggest deals
in Apple's history.
Not only that, but one of the biggest deals
to ever happen to a hip-hop artist.
To not only work with each other with
Death Row Records and lnterscope,
but with Aftermath and then, of course,
on to one of their bigger ventures,
which is Beats headphones,
which they went on to sell to Apple.
Which was one of the biggest deals
in Apple's history.
Not only that, but one of the biggest deals
to ever happen to a hip-hop artist.
And this is where it all begins.
Mark Sherman plays Jimmy lovine.
Again, this is one of those cases
of midnight casting.
This guy walked in.
He had the attitude.
He knew what he was talking about,
and he held his own.
I really like what he did.
This is a moment that Dre explained
to me happened quite a bit.
There was things that escalated
unnecessarily at Death Row,
and it started to shift the way he felt
about his decision to leave Ruthless.
It's like almostjumping
from the frying pan and into the fire.
We obviously couldn't put all of the things
that happened in Death Row into the movie,
but this is one of the moments
that we captured
to show that this was not the place
that he thought it was going to be.
This was not the company
that he wanted to build,
and this was just the beginning.
This moment here was a huge moment
for everybody involved-
the verdict of the Rodney King trial.
It surprised everyone,
and the city of Los Angeles burned.
This was really, really important
because Cube and the group
really tried to warn everybody.
“Listen, this is really going on.
And I know you guys don't believe us.”
In a strange way, they felt really sad
that the riots happened in the way that it did,
but almost vindicated at the same time.
Which is kind of this strange dichotomy,
because there was a warning.
“We told you people will rise up
if this continues to happen.”
And we all experienced
the death, the destruction
and this reaction-
this emotional reaction to police brutality.
And this reaction-
And it's really sad
that it's still happening to this day.
I thought that this moment
was really important in the film.
Because this is part of what motivates
some of these artists
to write what they write.
And this moment in particular
was important,
because it's really time for these
young guys to come together
and do something positive
and stop killing each other.
The red rag and the blue rag
and the senseless violence
is something that was extremely
important for me to convey.
And I hope when these young guys
who are involved with gangs see this,
at least they think twice
about the senseless violence
that goes on in the streets
of LA, Chicago, New York, Baltimore,
so on and so forth.
It goes beyond N.W.A.
It goes beyond the music.
It goes beyond hip-hop.
It's just important.
It's senseless,
and it needs to change.
All this weed
is for your Ruthless artists?
Yeah. Shit, I'm tryin' to take care
of these little money problems.
They can smoke it, sell it,
throw a party on it.
Eazy-E is really in a bad way now.
Dre experienced a certain level
of success with his company.
Cube is going off
to start doing movies.
And Eazy is really starting
to wonder what's going on.
He's not where he used to be.
He's not the artist that he used to be.
He's having financial troubles
and he's gotta revert back to things
he did in the beginning of the movie,
which is sell drugs.
His journey's almost come full circle.
I don't know if you noticed that,
but you see in this scene
that was the first cough.
And we all know that Eazy-E,
unfortunately, died of AIDS.
I didn't want to just lay it all out there.
I wanted to kind of slowly reveal
that this guy was sick,
and we buried it in this scene.
And we also showed that this
is really the beginning
of the downfall of Eazy-E.
And especially, not only with the group-
or what's left of the group-
but what's left of his relationship
with Jerry Heller.
You can see
they're starting to go at it.
I like this moment 'cause you can really tell
that MC Ren and DJ Yella
really care about Eazy-E.
You see his house
being packed up.
He lived this great life in this big
mansion, almost like Scarf ace,
and now he needs protection
and he's losing money
and things are changing.
Cut to Ice Cube.
He's not only experienced
a lot of success writing music,
now he's writing
his first motion picture, Friday.
Which is, coincidentally,
my first movie.
I should be somewhere on the phone
giving him notes in the movie,
it's kind of a fun moment because you have
O'Shea Jackson, Jr. playing his dad,
watching his dad in the first music video
that they made.
It's kind of an interesting moment.
Cut to Eazy-E, who can't
escape Dr. Dre's success.
The Chronic went on to be one of
the biggest hip-hop albums of all time,
a classic,
and you can tell that he's starting
to realize that he made a mistake.
That Tower Records building
is actually a digital building.
It used to look like that.
But, obviously, nowadays
Sunset Boulevard is completely different,
so we had to put
that building in digitally.
But you could see Eazy
passing Tower Records
and seeing, “Hey, maybe I made a mistake
with going the route that I took.”
I like this moment because Tomica Woods,
she actually told me that this moment
happened quite a bit,
where she would kind of kick back
and smoke a little weed
and have these very interesting
conversations with Eazy,
kind of heart-to-hearts.
And it's great to put these type
of moments in a movie,
especially when you have so much,
I don't know, just tough-guy stuff going on.
And we've all been there.
We have our tough exterior,
and then you end up hanging out
with a girl that you really feel,
and you turn into another guy.
He was a tough guy,
but he was actually pretty passionate.
So I like the fact that Jason
was able to loosen up
and show that he was vulnerable
and not just a guy
who can spew controversy.
This scene right here wasn't
in the theatrical release,
and I like it because, again,
you see the father-son dynamic
between Jerry and Eazy.
But you can start to feel that Eazy's
kind of not having it.
He comes over with this kung pao chicken,
he's fixing him a plate,
he's got a little iced tea, and he's like,
“Listen, I'm gonna take care of you.”
And he's like, “Get the fuck
out of here with that.”
Look at that look.
If looks could kill.
“Get the fuck out of here.”
And I love Paul
because Paul's so expressive.
He's kind of like trying to check to see
if Tomica is a problem
or, you know, is she just
kind of a groupie.
And he wants him to sign these checks.
It's just a really interesting moment.
He grabs a bite of food,
pacifies him,
and you can just see the look
on his face.
He just really realizes that,
“Our relationship is really changing,
and I'm not really sure
where it's coming from.
Maybe it's Tomica,
maybe it's someone else,
but something's just not right.”
Yet another scene that didn't
make the theatrical release.
I loved working
with the women in this movie
because you got a real sense
that these guys,
as tough as they sound on wax,
they really love the women
in their lives.
Dre, to this day,
is married to Nicole.
He's got a great family.
And he's been married
for 20-something years to this woman.
So when you get these complaints about
misogyny and all this type of stuff-
These guys- Even Ice Cube
has been married for over 2O years.
You gotta be able to really
kind of separate
the art, and the choices they make in art,
and real life.
Now, I'm sure they've been through
some tough things
because you got a real sense
that these guys,
as tough as they sound on wax,
they really love the women
in their lives.
Dre, to this day,
is married to Nicole.
He's got a great family.
And he's been married
for 20-something years to this woman.
So when you get these complaints
about misogyny and all this type of stuff-
These guys- Even Ice Cube
has been married for over 2O years.
You gotta be able to really
kind of separate
the art, and the choices they make in art,
and real life.
Now, I'm sure they've been through
some tough things
and the stuff that you would expect,
but, at the same time,
from what I know of these guys,
it's really an inspiration.
If you want to change your life,
and you grow up
in a really dangerous environment,
this movie should inspire you not to just
go on and make a ton of money
and do well in business,
but to inspire you to understand
that you can change your reality
and create what you want.
And these guys did that.
What I like about this scene is
we get a chance to get a sense
of what Death Row felt like
back in the day.
But we also get a chance to get
a real small snippet of Tupac,
who's played by Marco Rose.
I remember meeting this guy
for the first time,
and I was ﬂoored
by his likeness to Tupac.
I worked with Pac before in the '90s.
I actually directed a music video
with Cube, Dre and Tupac,
and it was just uncanny,
the resemblance to Tupac.
It was crazy.
It was hard for me to even direct him
because you would just sit there
and stare at this guy and go, “Wow!”
This guy is really embodying
who this guy is,
and we haven't seen him in a long time.
And you just almost feel
like you saw a ghost.
This is one of my favorite collaborations
between Dre and Tupac.
One of the famous collaborations
in hip-hop, “California Love,”
and, of course,
it's interrupted by the drama.
By the way, that's my nephew
in the background, Tyrell,
who's by that couch.
Now, he walks into Babylon-
the equivalent of Babylon.
It's this huge lounge
at Death Row
where this guy is being essentially
tortured like he's in Guanténamo Bay
by a guy with a huge bull mastiff.
And, as Dre would put it,
it's a fuckin' circus.
This is a place
that doesn't feel like a company.
It feels more like a prison.
And this is not what
he had envisioned for himself.
And you can see the contrast
between how much fun the guys
had in the beginning of the movie
when they were recording
“Boyz-N-The-Hood”
and the smiles and the brotherhood.
And now it feels like- although
he has a Ferrari and a pretty girl
and all this money
and he's selling all these albums-
that all that glitters is not gold.
And you kind of learn this lesson.
It's like sometimes
when you gain material success,
it's not necessarily
the best thing in the world,
or it doesn't necessarily add up
to success in life.
This is something that he was really
passionate about putting in the movie.
And I think it not only helps
with Dre's character,
but it really helps define
where he is in life,
even with all this material success,
but also helps you understand
what motivates him to leave
a little later on in the movie.
This my motherfuckin' name
on the wall, man!
And y'all in here actin' like
y'all on motherfuckin' vacation.
I got Pac in the next motherfuckin' room.
Grindin', man. Workin'.
You see the crown
next to Suge Knight.
I really wanted to show
that he's ruling his kingdom.
This is an important moment
where we show the police there,
because now Dr. Dre feels like,
“I can't go anywhere.
Everyplace I go feels corrupt.
I can't deal with my friends.
I can't go to my company.
I'm getting screwed over.
We've already had a challenging
relationship with the police,
and now they're in
on this criminal activity.
This is really strange.”
And so he's gotta get out of here
because this is-
and I quote-
“the straw that breaks the camel's back.”
He jumps into his Testarossa
after having left Babylon,
and now he gets into this high-speed
car chase with the police.
He just left Death Row
with the police there,
so now he's like, “I don't give a shit
about being chased by the cops
because I don't know who's real,
I don't know who's fake,
I don't know who's corrupt.”
And so that's part of the reason
why he just runs.
He's fed up.
He has no faith in the system.
He almost just loses faith in humanity.
And he admits, listen,
along the way, he made mistakes.
He wasn't an angel.
But at the same time, this is the moment
that changed his life.
Because when he was arrested
and he went to jail for I believe it was
120 days or something like that,
he had a lot of time to think
and think about
all the choices he made
and all the mistakes
that he made,
and realized that he wasn't really
surrounded by friends.
He had to change his life, otherwise
something extreme was gonna happen.
And this is where he gets arrested.
From that point on,
Dr. Dre's life completely changed.
Now this takes place in New York
at a club called the Tunnel,
a famous hip-hop club
that all of the famous rappers
would go and hang out.
This is a meeting that Cube
would always describe,
which is his last meeting with Eazy-E.
I thought it was actually
pretty humble of Eazy
to walk into what is
essentially Cube's lair.
Cube is surrounded by Da Lench Mob.
He's got his crew with him.
You know half those guys are strapped.
And the last interaction he had with Eazy-
or at the very least his goons-
was at the New Music Seminar.
So at any moment, a brawl, a war
or a gunfight could break out.
We wanted that tension there.
But at the end of the day,
when you have love for somebody,
a lot of times, if you are mature enough,
you get over it.
That's what this moment is for me,
and I think it was for Cube.
It does seem a little easy
that after all the drama
and “No Vaseline” and the big brawl,
that it may feel a little easy
that they just bury the hatchet.
But as Cube telIs it, you know what,
he didn't really have a beef with Eazy.
Eazy is the guy who helped him
start his career.
He just wanted
to keep the drama on wax.
He feels like the physicality
and all of the street shit is not hip-hop.
It's just a great message to everyone
who loves hip-hop.
If it has to be physical,
it's not really hip-hop.
If you have skill, put it on wax.
Anything beyond that, you're just a thug,
and there's nothing really cool
about taking it there.
I like that message.
Part of my job is to create an environment
that's comfortable
so my actors can really get out there
and create.
And I really have
a really great relationship with-
I call 'em my team.
This is my team.
You know. The N.W.A team-
Shea, Jason, Aldis, Neil and Corey.
I put 'em through a lot.
But we're all like family now.
The movie's been released. it's done well.
But we talk often
and we went through a lot
to make this movie.
I really wanted to create an environment
for them to ﬂourish-
because a lot of these guys are new at this-
and they did.
But the love you see there
between these two guys-
By the end of the shoot-
'Cause this was towards the end.
A lot of that was real, man.
A lot of that was real.
That concern was real.
That's the second cough, by the way.
You can see that Eazy is slowly
starting to deteriorate.
His eyes are glassy and red.
You can start to see that somethings
not right with him physically.
But they buried it,
and it's water under the bridge.
Now we want the group
to get back together.
She is a very talented actress.
Her name is Carra Patterson,
out of New York.
She's playing Tomica.
And for the short amount of screen time-
I think most all of the women
did a great job, really connecting,
just to counter all of the testosterone
in this movie and in the music.
She did a great job
catching Jason's back.
There was good chemistry there.
This is the moment where he finds out
that the counting is a little off,
or a lot off.
More importantly, he really knows for sure
that something is just not right.
If you look really close, you'll see
I made some choices visually.
I'm not gonna give that up.
When I see you next,
we can talk about it.
But there's something I did visually
in this scene
to really capture
what these guys represent.
I'll just leave it at that.
I believe this is one of Jason's
stronger moments as well.
It should be. it's the end of the movie.
He's dealing with a heavyweight
in Paul Giamatti.
In rehearsals, I would tell the guys,
“We are a family.
It's really important
that we support each other.
So if you're off-camera
and you have to do a scene
and you're not on-camera,
you'd better give it,
you'd better bring it,
so that the other actor has the ability
to actually perform.”
But on this day,
I said, “You guys are enemies.”
I told them that separately.
More importantly, I told Jason that.
'Cause I didn't want him to walk into
this loving environment
and have this father figure
that he's essentially going to fire.
I think that Jason and Paul
have great chemistry.
Again, it's not just about a male-female thing.
When you're an artist-
it's almost like music.
You have a jam session
and you're working with great artists,
they all can get into the same rhythm.
Although these guys are opposing
each other in this scene,
the chemistry is amazing.
You can see there that Jerry
really cares about this guy.
You can also see that Eazy's really in pain.
But the chemistry is there.
You can feel it.
It's just magnetic.
When you have actors
that make these strong choices,
you don't have to do anything.
All you have to do is set up the camera
and let them do their thing.
It's all in the eyes. Just watch.
Jerry/Paul- watch his eyes.
Watch Jason and his eyes.
It's all underneath.
This is one of those scenes where you
don't have to listen to the dialogue.
You can see everything in their eyes.
That's really a great sign
of an amazing performer.
I believe them
and I believe the relationship
and I believe the pain and the hurt.
I loved working with these guys, man.
I know I'm having a moment,
but these guys are amazing.
But I didn't start this.
I didn't fuck it up.
You did!
No.
You did.
You fired, Jerry.
With Jason, it's so interesting,
you can tell that he's really accessing
something different
than just kind of actory choices.
He's been through a lot.
He's been on the streets of New Orleans.
He's accessing real life.
That's the reason why he feels so real.
And with Paul, he's just, again,
one of the best actors around alive.
And to really show the chemistry
between a guy
from the opposite end of the spectrum
and another guy the same-
There are days I can't wait to see them
come together and perform
because you end up
with a scene like that.
I think they were both great.
This is another one of those moments
that served the theme of brotherhood.
You have Eazy who calls Dre.
This is one of the more vulnerable moments
for a guy from the streets
who has to basically say,
“Hey, I was wrong. I got love for you.
I want to do this over again.
Will you forgive me?”
And while those aren't necessarily
the words that he used,
that's the sentiment.
That's what makes Jason,
who plays Eazy, so endearing.
You look in his eyes and you could tell-
“Man, I made a mistake.”
A lot of us sometimes, especially
coming from where we come from,
we need to get over ourselves.
There are times where you let your pride
get in the way,
especially in situations where you shouldn't.
And to be the bigger man,
you gotta make the phone call.
I love this moment.
You can see Corey, who plays Dre,
just lighten up and brighten up.
In the midst of all the street shit
and Death Row and the tough guy stuff,
these guys are just young dudes
who want to create
and they want to get back to basics-
the love of creating
and the love of their brothers.
And if you don't take anything
away from this movie,
you should understand that if you have
people in your life that you love,
love 'em while they're here, man.
Because there's just no guarantee
for tomorrow.
Again, I don't want to be preachy,
but that's what a lot of this means.
It's not just about hip-hop.
It's not just about gangster rap.
It's not just about Los Angeles
and N.W.A.
This movie is so much bigger
than N.W.A.
That's a quote from Ice Cube.
You experience the coughing,
which is worse,
and you're really, really hoping
these guys get back together.
If you freeze the frame,
coming up really soon,
I kind of indicate that the end is near.
I do that with a freeze frame
of a painting
right over Eazy's shoulder.
It happens right about now.
You see the gun to his head.
You see the microphone.
It's almost like
the success of the music business
is what also led to his demise.
I can't be sure if that's what happened, but-
I worked with my art director
and my production designer
to build in some of these Easter eggs.
So that for the people
who love movies like this,
you get a chance to see things
you didn't see the first time around.
After the collapse and-
Kind of cutting to Cedars-Sinai.
This is one of the toughest moments
of our shoot.
It's not only because,
obviously, it's a challenge
to shoot Eazy-E in the hospital
and the revelation that he has AIDS,
but this is the end of our production schedule.
Everyone at this point developed
great and close relationships.
So when Shea or Aldis
or Neil or Corey
would show up
and see Jason in the bed,
they would have a real emotional response
to seeing their cast-mate sick.
Although he was acting,
these guys developed a love
for each other so much so
that it was really hard for them
to see him in the hospital bed because
they really developed
a relationship with him.
Jason did such an amazing job
capturing not only
the surprise of finding out
he was essentially
sentenced to death-
But again, this is another
one of those moments
where he tapped into something very real.
I remember when-
I made sure the set was really quiet.
I wanted him to really, really deliver
in this moment
and deliver truth in this moment.
Tears started to roll down his eyes,
and you started to really understand
that this is not acting.
There is something that happens
when you're not allowed to express yourself,
you're not allowed to cry.
And this moment right here,
I think, is very personal to Jason.
All of the moments
that led up to this film-
living on the streets,
being from the streets,
having the pain of having to be
a black man in America-
I think he tapped into that
and he just let 'em go.
He let the tears go.
This is a real moment.
Our cast, they really had a hard time
seeing him in this position
because they knew there was
a lot of truth in those tears.
When you have to express
such a range of emotion in a movie
and you nail it
in the way that he did it,
that's world-class.
This scene wasn't in the theatrical release.
I hate that it wasn't, honestly,
because this is where
he decides to marry Tomica.
There was a lot of controversy
surrounding this moment.
But what I loved about it
is this is where Jason goes deeper
with his level of vulnerability,
where he really shows that “I care.”
When you have to express
such a range of emotion in a movie
and you nail it
in the way that he did it,
that's world-class.
You see that in those performances
like De Niro in Raging Bull.
I can list the performances where an actor
has to really show a full range.
Jason just really naiIs it.
It was pretty emotional for me as well
because I felt like these guys
are my little brothers
and I had to shepherd them along
and teach them some things.
This moment right here
with Neil Brown, Jr.,
those tears are real.
As a matter of fact, when I cut,
I had to console him
because it was really hard for him
to see Jason in this condition.
We all knew Jason tapped into
something very real.
It's a testament to all these guys
and not only their ability to perform
but their ability to open up
and love each other.
You don't experience that
much on movies.
As hard as it was to see that,
I think we all grew personally.
And you want that, hopefully,
after the end
of an experience like this
where you spend a few years of your life
trying to make history
and put an amazing story like this
on the screen.
You grow professionally,
but you also grow personally.
I think we all did.
Corey kind of reminds me
of Denzel Washington in this scene,
'cause he has such restraint.
But the emotion and how he just covers-
or tries to cover his emotion, but it's-
He's trying to hold those tears back.
It's so emotional and so real.
I love- This is one of my favorite
moments with Corey.
People are surprised
when they see this level of emotion
in a movie called Straight' Outta Compton.
They think they're gonna get
just the thugs
and the drama and the danger
and the gangster rap, but-
There's a lot of emotion and pain
and vulnerable moments
between these guys.
I think these moments really show
the humanity behind the icons.
You think about Ice Cube, think about
Dr. Dre and MC Ren and Yella.
You think about the icons.
Sometimes you don't take the time
to think about the human beings.
This whole section of the movie
just shows you that
they have feelings,
contrary to popular belief.
And while- We all grow.
We all make mistakes.
They'll be the first to admit all the stuff
they did wasn't overly positive.
Some of it was, some of it wasn't,
but they grew up on wax.
You understand that they're people.
I think the cast really delivered
just a full range.
And they offered up something
that I think surprises people.
Because you feel like,
“I can identify with these guys.”
A lot of people going
into the theaters felt like,
“Yeah, I'm gonna watch the N.W.A. movie,
but I don't know if I can identify
with a gangster rapper.”
But in a strange way,
based on the reaction,
a lot of people did
and they do.
Again, I think
that's a testament to my cast
and their ability to perform.
I remember outside of Cedars-Sinai,
there were thousands of people.
A lot of people loved Eazy-E
and were really surprised when he passed.
This moment
didn't make it into the theatrical cut.
But I like it,
'cause there's this closure here.
You see Cube, who started off
as the teenager in the group.
Now he's a grown man
with a family.
The same family to this day.
His wife and his kids.
Eazy won't have that opportunity
to live out his life with his family.
I wanted to touch on that,
because it's sad
to know that he could have.
It's just a sad moment.
We wrap up the movie
with the great smile.
I think this is one of the great images
of Jason, who plays Eazy.
You get a sense of the man
behind the music
and the man behind the glasses.
That smile just says it all.
Dre going to Death Row,
with the goons.
And the determination to say,
“You know what? Enough is enough.”
I'm out of Death Row.
I don't know how many people you know
that would walk away
from a successful company,
$50 million
and all of the artists
and all of the hard work.
But Dre just felt like,
“You know what?
There's another life for me.”
He had the courage to walk away
from all the material gain
and had enough faith in himself
to actually do something different.
When I talk to him, he says,
“I will always bet on myself.”
And that's inspiring.
It really is inspiring.
For a guy who comes from Compton,
who comes from poverty,
to make it in a capitalistic society,
on top of the world, at least financially-
He just went with his heart.
Now the guy's a billionaire.
I think it was a smart move.
People ask me,
“What do you want people to take away
from the experience of watching this movie?”
The truth is, I just want you to be inspired.
You can always change your reality.
You can come from nowhere.
You can come from less than nothing.
You can always create something better.
These guys are a living testament to that.
I want to thank my producers
Ice Cube, Dr. Dre, Scott Bernstein,
Matt Alvarez, Tomica Woods.
They worked really, really hard on
providing me with what I needed
in order to make this movie great.
I want to give a shout-out to Chic Daniel,
our police consultant
and all-around good guy.
This guy connected us with the police.
They really had such great attitude
about helping us make this movie.
I want to thank DJ Yella, MC Ren,
Dr. Dre and Ice Cube
for allowing me to tell their story.
I definitely want to especially thank Eazy-E
and his family
for allowing us to tell this story.
I really want to thank my crew.
It's too many names to list,
but you couldn't ask for a better crew.
My crew was off the chain,
and I love you guys for helping me make
what I consider my best film.
Thank you so much.
Thanks for listening.