Do you know Professor Wahl?
I'm sorry, sir?
Professor Wahl, the sculptor.
l know he lives in a windmill
Is it far?
Other side -
near the stone women
What?
We call it
the Mill of the Stone Women
Is that it?
No, further on
Past the cemetery of Veeze
He wants the Mill of the Stone Women
We're off...
- Thanks
- You're welcome
Who's there?
Van Harnim. Hans van Harnim
Can l help you?
Professor Wahl, please?
Come in
Wait here, please
Sir...the Professor wants you
to wait in his studio
But...
This way, please
Please, sir
Hans van Harnim?
Professor Gregorius Wahl
l didn't expect you
It's a long way from Rotterdam
Professor Caran sent me.
I’m his assistant
He said you'd be expecting me
l didn't reply yet.
Why such haste?
The book's publisher
is putting pressure on
The monograph should be ready
for the centenary
Of course...l didn't think of that
The first of February,
it will be 100 years...
...since my great grandfather
first opened the windmill
So, when can you start?
Tomorrow, if that's all right.
Professor Caran has given me 10 days
Since you're here, why not start now?.
I'm afraid
l have very little time to spare
Follow me...
Conrad, check the brakes.
We don't want an accident
Yes, Professor. l'm just doing it now.
Careful, this floor is very cluttered
Here are the gears.
They use to run the mill,
now they give life to the statues
- Are they still the original statues?
- Most of them, yes.
- Some of them I had to duplicate myself.
You saw a few in my studio.
They certainly very impresive.
And you did finishing too?
I did everything by myself.
This way, please.
Here you are.
You can do your work in here.
Very peacefull little room.
I've got some documents ready for you
All the history of the windmill
Everything you need should be here
- Can l take them away?
- No...!
I'd prefer they remain here
Then l can help you with your work
l shall take some days' holiday
I’m afraid l have to go now
The last ferry leaves in three hours
Be sure you don't miss it
Don't worry
One final thing,
you must finish in six days
I’m sure that's enough
I'll leave you to it
Shelma!
Shelma...
No. no. The line is too heavy.
Try a lighter touch here
Thank you, Professor
Hey, Annelore, Annelore...
Don't distract me.
l can't even get two lines right today
You've been like that
ever since Hans turned up
Nonsense, Raab
You've really got your head
in the clouds today
What's wrong?
Nothing. I’m just a little tired
- Professor?
- Yes
Did a Mr Van Harnim
come to see you?
Do you know him?
Since we were children
Ah, childhood friends
He seems like
a serious young man
I’m sure he'll do good work
Right, that's it for today.
Class dismissed
l must cancel the class for Tuesday.
We'll meet next Friday for sculpture
Four days off...what bliss
What'll you do?
Go to Danzen with Hans.
That's our home town
Carpe Diem, Liselotte
It's time he settled down
before he gets too old
I’m sure this time he'll come with me
Come on, hurry up!
Hans will go if we keep him waiting
Excuse me, do you have a light?
Of course
l asked for a light...?
Oh yes, sorry
Thank you, Mr...?
Van Harnim...Hans van Harnim
Bolem...Doctor Bolem
Goodnight
Goodnight...
Excuse me
My legs are very pretty
And spiritual
There's none in this city
That look so well
They're made just for dancing
Olay! Olah!
And if l want to show them off
Well, what's the harm?
The rhythm of the dance
Excites you all
And now it's your chance
To join the ball
You cry in gay abandon
You lose your head
Forget about your troubles
And dance instead
And if my little ditty
Should make you warm
You think it's very witty
And full of charm
l give it all I’ve got
And then some more
To give you all some ideas
Behind closed doors!
Hey! You look happy
l got a job at the Globe in Paris.
Top billing
- So...I’ll never see you again?
- I’ll send you a postcard, Raab
The best of luck, Annelore!
Liselotte!
What're you doing?
Me? Nothing...
just getting a free show
You'll catch cold
When l found you'd gone,
l was worried
Unlike you, to worry about me
All right, I’m sorry
But your damn Professor
made me work late
Satisfied? No?
Alright then, I’ll buy you dinner
Come on
Happy faces to brighten up
my gloomy world
What's wrong?
l should have studied dance
rather than fine art
And what have you been up to today?
Oh...Playing bowIs
with Professor Wahl
Like to order?
How was Wahl?
He gave me six days to finish
and said l had to work there all day
Do you know him well?
Does he have a daughter?
A daughter?
l heard something...
l believe her mother died
in childbirth
And she has a strange name.
Elfy, or something
Elfy, that's right. What's she like?
No idea. No-one ever saw her
She's must be so ugly,
he keeps her locked away
Strange...very strange
Why?
Because she's pretty - very pretty
Don't you get it, Raab?
You know her?
No - but l do know...
...you!
Are you trying to annoy her?
No...she's right
But l didn't mean it like that
Do me a favor, Raab.
Have a word with her
Here we go again!
l am Elfy
Hans...Hans van Harnim
Come in...
Sit down
No. l can't stay, Hans.
l must go soon.
Someone's watching me.
There always is
l can't explain right now, Hans...
But l must speak to you
This evening
This evening...but where?
Here...
In the mill
But someone might see us
Is it really so urgent?
Yes. It’s really urgent
11 o'clock tonight.
They will all be asleep
No-one will know
Take this key.
It unlocks the door to the mill
Please...be careful
I’ll be waiting
l am tired
l must rest now
Let me accompany you
Good night, father
Good night, my dear
My compliments, Elfy
l never saw you play
with such passion before
It wasn't for you, Bolem
l realize that
But never forget I’m the only one
who really knows you
And you have no right
to love any other
Stop it, Bolem
Good night
Elfy!
Hans!
You scared me
Didn't you hear me come in?
l was asleep
I’m sorry if l woke you
You seemed so keen to speak me
But when l came in
you were so strangely still
l was dreaming of you
How you were coming to see me
from so far away
l was waiting for you to arrive
and l was so happy
It was strange
to feel such happiness
And when l felt you there beside me
l wanted to go on sleeping
l was so afraid...
l was so afraid to wake up
l didn't want the dream to end
It was a dangerous dream, Elfy
Who knows where it might have ended
What's wrong?
Don't you want me?
Of course, Elfy. But afterwards...
Who cares about that?
What matters is that l want you now
Come and kiss me
Two friends of yours
are waiting downstairs
Who?
l don't know.
A young lady and a gentleman
Thanks
Hello, Raab.
l guessed it was you
But she said there were two people...
- Oh, Liselotte!
- l came to tell you off
Good. l need to hear that
Well, l think I’ll go off
and see these statues
How long have we known each other?
l don't know- forever
And you always loved me?
Yes. And you?
Well...l didn't know that l loved you
It’s only now l realize it
Now that l know what real love is
Your love
But l don't deserve it,
Liselotte
Why not?
I’m ashamed to say
Then don't
Can you forgive me?
Everything?
Of course, Hans...l love you
They scare me!
The Poisoner of Poitiers
Stop! Stop!
What is it?
A young woman's fallen ill
Miss Liselotte...!
So what happened?
l don't know.
l don't understand
Now wait a second.
l think l have something...
Here...
Get her to breathe this
She'll soon be alright,
you'll see
This sort of thing often happens here
How do you feel, Lotti?
Better, thanks.
But please let's go
Help her outside
Oh...
Wait a second...
It must have been your hat pin
Don't worry,
it's only a small cut
That's better.
Now you can go and get some fresh air
I’m sorry to be so much trouble
No, please, don't apologize
It wasn't your fault
Take care of yourself.
I’ll see you in class next Friday
Hans, l would like a word
before you go
Yes, Professor
See you soon, Raab.
And thanks...
Well done, Lotti.
You did it
Of course
Professor...?
Please, come in
It will probably seem strange to you
that I’m going to talk about things
to do with my family
But l have my reasons
l have a young daughter
whom l love
Elfy
She is very ill
As was her poor mother
Science is powerless to help
All we can do is watch and wait
That's why Dr Bolem lives here
He never leaves us - day or night
Always ready to act
should a crisis occur
and her life be in danger
Is she aware how serious it is?
She really understands very little
Or why she can't live
like other girls
It is essential that she avoids
all strong emotions
or her life will be in danger
l believe you to be honest
and trustworthy
l really hope you understand
why l have spoken to you of Elfy
It’s a request and a warning...
The next attack could kill her
You can count on me
You are a good boy
and l thank you
And now...
Back to work
l was waiting, Hans.
l knew you'd come
You didn't give me much choice
Forgive me.
l was desperate
l don't know why...
...but l had a sudden fear
you no longer wanted me
That you'd never come back
l thought of giving your letter
to your father
But that seemed rather unkind
Now l feel I’ve betrayed him
After he trusted me
So you would betray me?
Because my father trusted you...
That's not the only reason.
We made a mistake, Elfy
We were foolish,
but it must not continue
But l love you, Hans
l love only you.
Don't you understand?
Others have abused my trust;
taken advantage of my loneliness
l know you blame me for that.
That's why you reject me
But if only you knew
how horrible my life is
All day locked up in this place
l do understand, Elfy.
l don't blame you
But...l don't want to mislead you.
Elfy - l don't love you
So what? You can grow to love me.
l just want to be with you always
Take me away from here, Hans.
From this sad existence
l will go wherever you go, Hans
Please, don't talk so.
You know it's impossible
You have to stay here
We must forget
everything that happened
Hans! Don't lie to me
It’s because of that girl
Yes, l saw you
But l swear to you she won't
take you from me
and if she does,
I’ll kill you...
Elfy, stop this nonsense.
Are you crazy?
Yes...yes...
And that's why l want you...
My...my...
Dead...!
Good morning, Mr Hans
I’m sorry l kept you waiting.
l was just clearing up
What can l do for you?
What can I do for you?
l must speak to Professor Wahl.
Urgently
l haven't called him yet.
It’s still very early
l realize it's inconvenient,
but l really must see him
l can't call him now, Mr Hans.
It’s not even 7 o'clock
Can't you wait just a little while?
Yes?
What is it?
I’m sorry, sir.
l didn't know you were there
I’ll come back
Wait, Shelma...
Yes, sir?
Come in
Has anyone been here
since yesterday evening?
No-one ever comes in here
Did you put this rose here?
I’m far too busy
to collect flowers
That's all right, Shelma
Professor Wahl wants to see you
I’ll go now
What's wrong? Are you in pain?
No, it's nothing
I’m not so sure.
Do you have a fever?
You cut yourself...
l told you, it's nothing.
I’m all right!
You can't see the Professor
in this state
However urgent it is
I’m sorry, I’m a little tired
Well, let me see...
What can l give you...?
Yes, a tranquilizer.
That's just what you need
Two of these
and you'll feel a lot better
Go on, drink it
Soon you'll feel much better
Murderer!
You're a coward and a murderer!!
No...You must believe me
That's why l came here
To talk to you...
to tell you the truth...
Words! Just worthless words!
Pathetic excuses
You took advantage of my hospitality
l trusted you.
Talked to you like a son
You knew how frail my Elfy was,
but that didn't stop you
You killed her.
Murderer!
It’s not true...it's not true!
I’ll hear no more.
What use are mere words
No-one...no-one
can bring my daughter back
Elfy is dead
Elfy is dead and buried
May she rest in peace
Let no-one disturb her sleep
Let her rest in the grave
Whatever happens,
no-one must know the truth
No-one!
Elfy is in her tomb
in the cemetery at Veeze
Nothing shall sully her memory
Let her sleep in eternal peace
What...?
You are ill...Very ill
But, there was blood...there
Blood?
Why?
Elfy!
It’s not possible...!
It was there!
Mr Van Harnim,
what are doing here at this hour?
What's going on here?
l don't understand
l want to see Professor Wahl!
Calm down
Who's that woman?
What woman?
Tied up in there!
l don't know
what you're talking about...
There - take a look if you want
Where is Professor Wahl?
l want to see him now
You're in a state.
Calm down
Out of my way
Professor Wahl!
Who's there?
Hold on!
Conrad...Conrad,
it's all right
So, what is it?
Professor, l must talk to you
More lights
Talk to me?
It’s one in the morning...
l was trying to tell him,
but he's in such a state
Something's going on here.
You must explain...
Mr Van Harnim...
l think it's you
who owes me an explanation
Earlier today l saw you...
...and you forbade me
to ever mention Elfy again
Elfy...
What are you saying?
Who talked to you about her?
And what do you thinks’ going on?
Can you really not remember?
Or do you not want to...
Now l begin to understand
You want me to think l was dreaming
No! You can't blame me
It was not my fault!
l think you've gone mad.
What was not your fault?
Typical schizophrenic hallucinations
No...You want me to believe
that l saw Elfy alive
But what about the bracelet?
It was there on the table...
Then...
Then, Elfy was wearing it
in her coffin
Elfy! Elfy in her coffin?
What are you talking about?
At the cemetery of Veeze...
You told me yourself, Professor
l saw her...In her coffin.
Dead...Dead...
As you know!
Hans!
What's going on here?
Why all the shouting?
It’s nothing serious, miss
Go back to bed.
Don't worry, Elfy
Bolem, go with her
Conrad!
Listen...
I’m no doctor, but l can tell
you are in a disturbed state...
...that could be dangerous to me
and my daughter
l won't have it
Yes, Professor?
Get the carriage
to take Mr Van Harnim into town
Yes, sir
And you...come with me
Don't be ridiculous, Bolem.
Hans is not mad
You stopped him seeing me
Elfy, you must forget all about him
Never...
Hans means life to me
No. Hans for you is certain death
And l...
l am your life
Your salvation
You are bound to me forever
Bound to a monster like you?
You're mad
And what would your Hans say
if he found out what you really are?
l know what a rat you are Bolem.
You'd never talk
You're too scared to tell the truth
Now go
Bolem, we've done it
My plan has worked
l have to admit, it does seem to have
The drug you gave him
destroyed all sense of reality
lf he ever talks about it
They'll think him mad
Maybe...but l still think
the other solution was better
No. It would been too dangerous
to kill him
Too many people saw him here
So long as he lives,
he is a threat
Your daughter
will try to see him again
She will forget him in time
And after tonight's experiences,
he is unlikely ever to return
Indeed. But there is one fact
we can't escape...
What?
Elfy died tonight
So..?
He held her in his arms.
He will have known she was dead
Just another hallucination
Don't forget,
there's nothing to prove what he saw
l hope you're right
l shudder to think
he might see your daughter again
lf he asks her questions,
he'll discover the truth...
...that she died
and came back to life again
And if he discovers how...
it's the end for us
...and for your daughter
lf that does happen, we'll be forced
to try your solution
Elfy!
Another attack
Quick, Bolem!
Yes, yes. l will save you, Elfy.
Trust me, my darling
Once again l will save you
Get everything ready, Bolem.
I’ll fetch her
Help me, Professor!
Professor, l beg you...!
Untie me...
Of course, Annelore...
I’ll set you free
You won't suffer anymore, l swear it
Just be patient.
I’ll set you free soon...
Very...very soon...
Everything's ready, Professor
Give me that
See, Elfy.
Your bad blood is being drawn away
It'll be gone...
In just a few seconds
Ready, doctor
Now!
Yes, Professor
How is he, doctor?
Medically speaking, he is well.
He needs to rest
Just four or five days
l really thought we'd lost him
It was a sort of
nervous breakdown
A breakdown? How strange...
He was in such good health before
It is indeed strange.
l can't explain it
What caused it?
l have no idea.
You're his friends, you know him best
What can we do now?.
Nothing special
Just lift his spirits
and keep him amused
You're young,
that should be easy!
Thanks doctor
I’ll show you the way down
So, what did the doctor say?
Is it all over for me,
or is there a glimmer of hope?
It’s bad news, Hans.
You're almost well again
Now you will be able to escape
from me
l know how much you loved
playing the nurse
Especially with me lying here
all defenseless
That's right. And l loved it
when you called my name
You'd say:
Liselotte, l don't feel well...
Liselotte, don't leave me...
Liselotte, hold my hand
l must have been really sick
Go ahead and make fun of me
l don't mind now
Why not?
Because you let it out
when you were sick
Now l know you love me
You know that?
And do you know when l can get up?
In about three days
That's too late
Hans, what are you doing?
l have urgent business tomorrow.
l must go to Danzen...
To ask the parents
of a certain person...
if they will accept me
as a son in law
Hans, really?
l think you should help me this time
For three years l refused
and l still do
l am a doctor,
not a mummifier of women
Fine scruples for a man
kicked out of the medical council
Who spent many years of his life
hiding from the law
And you seem to forget
that these statues keep you safe
l still refuse to be a part
of this macabre carousel
l am here for one reason only:
to save your daughter's life
l could say l do it for science,
but that wouldn't be strictly true
l have no interest in your motives
l ask only one thing of you:
that you keep Elfy alive
Professor Wahl
What is it?
While you play with death,
l have conquered it
As you know...
l have created a serum
that will protect the red blood cells
But it was not permanent
l needed to find an exact match
for your daughter's blood group
It was very rare...
but now l have found it
Elfy can soon live like other girls
But who is it?
Liselotte Cornaim!
52 steps...we could have called her
from the ground floor
Liselotte
Probably still asleep
Who's there?
What do you want?
Oh, Mr Hans...
Are you looking for Miss Liselotte?
I’m sorry, but she's not there
Not there?
But she was expecting us...
She might have been
What's going on?
Well...l don't know if l should say
Please do
The young lady has not been back
since yesterday evening
Didn't she say anything?
leave a message for me?
Nothing at all,
or l would have told you
Maybe there's a note in her room
Maybe...
l could let you in
Why has she left her bag?
Maybe she took another one
She's also left her papers
and her money
What's going on?
There could be any number of reasons
Hey...What's up?
This girl?
Yes...
She's a red-head?
Yes, that's right. So what?
It’s her...
It has to be her that l saw
What do you mean?
You must have seen her in the bar
l never saw her before that night
But how can that be,
if it was all an hallucination?
Will this nightmare never end?
Listen Hans, l tried to question you
when you were ill
You wouldn't talk about it
and l gave up
Now we're getting somewhere
That girl with the red hair
was a model called Annelore
You said you saw her.
But where?
In the basement...tied up
What basement?
At the windmill
Hold on a second, let's think...
Annelore said
she was leaving for Paris
She never came back to the art class
And now you - who never saw her -
recognized her photograph...
and knew that she had red hair
So it was no hallucination;
you must have seen her at the mill
So then...it might all be true
All what?
This is serious, Hans
Tell me...
Tell me everything that happened
The blood has not degenerated.
We can operate on Elfy tonight
Are you sure of this?
There's no risk to Elfy?
No risk at all
Then we must not hesitate.
We'll do it tonight
We must prepare at once.
Please help me
Tell Conrad to put this statue
in the carousel today
He knows what to do
Of course
We need some physical proof
that your story is true
Of course - the cemetery...
The cemetery at Veeze
Just like you said
The coffin is empty.
What can that mean?
Well...
It was a dummy
you saw in the coffin
A wax dummy
The thunder scares me
When l was small l used to hide
under the bed
But you...you were never afraid
of anything
Because you were never alone like me
This mill was so full of shadows
Did you already know Hans then?
Did he comfort you in his arms?...
How wonderfully exciting
it must have been...
...to tremble in Hans' arms
But that's all over now, Liselotte
Hans will love me,
because you won't be here anymore
And your life will be mine
There, in this tube,
is your daughter's life
Three years of meticulous work,
Wahl...
During the transfusion,
the serum will be introduced here
Where it will be mixed
with the new blood
The serum is essential.
Without it the red cells couldn't grow
They would be destroyed
in a few months
Like a cancer...
We will have to anaesthetize
your daughter
The process may cause
a painful reaction in her
Apart from that,
it will be quite straightforward
Good work. l congratulate you, Bolem.
You've thought of everything
Almost everything
You sure about this, Hans?
No turning back now
Where to now?.
To the basement
We need light
There, by the doorway
Stop it! Quickly...
It’s a body...A mummified corpse
It looks like...
...Annelore!
Liselotte!
- She's down there
- What can we do?
Move this, quick!
Come on
Ready, Professor
Good - get to work
Wait a second, Professor Wahl
What it is?
Tonight will be the last time
that Elfy has need of this
And so?
You realize...l have spent years
saving her from death
I’ve committed crimes for her
and this evening,
l will be giving her new life
Your point?
l should be recompensed
l never quibbled about money
Who mentioned money?
Then what do you want?
Your daughter, Wahl
Do you know what you're saying?
Yes...l have loved Elfy for years
lf she lives, it's only thanks to me
Now l want her for my wife
Your wife!
You think l would give Elfy
to a creature like you?
A vile monster, barely worthy
to draw breath?!
lf not for me, you'd have been
locked up years ago
Be careful Wahl.
Remember that l have the power now
l always wanted her
and now l will have her
Are you crazy, Bolem?
l will never allow it
You will never have Elfy.
Her life will never belong to you
She will never be soiled
by a foul creature like you
For me you were nothing
but an instrument
Enough!
Now l no longer need you, Bolem
This is the end for you
The only face my daughter will see
when she awakens...
...will be mine!
Killing me...
you've killed your own daughter...
Killed her...
It’s hopeless
Quick! Through Wahl's studio
Elfy, tonight it will all be over.
l will cure you forever
Down here
Quickly!
Where's the serum?
Where...?
Bolem, you dog! Where is it?
No...l don't believe it!
It’s broken
Quick Raab, this way!
She's still alive
Untie her quickly
Dead...
Dead...!
You killed her, damn you!
You will all die...! All of you!
Go on!
It’s all on fire!
Go through the house
Be still!....Be still, damn you!