In a far corner of the Earth
is a South American wilderness.
These extreme landscapes
are home to strange
and wonderful animals.
GENTLE ROAR
From the rugged peaks of The Andes...
..across the scorched
desert steppe...
..to coasts battered by some of
the roughest seas on the planet.
Living here takes guts
and determination.
There are incredible opportunities
for some.
For others, it's a battle to survive.
The pioneering spirit unites them all
under the spell...
..of Patagonia.
Patagonia is a land of two extremes.
The west is a lush wonderland.
But the east is a different story.
A world battered by the wind.
Then baked by the sun.
This is a journey that
blows from the Andes mountains
to the Atlantic coast.
Through Patagonia's
increasingly tough desert,
where life copes by reinventing
itself in weird and unique ways.
An Andean condor.
One of the heaviest
flying birds in the world.
Held aloft on huge wings.
Three metres from tip to tip.
Making the most of Patagonia's
powerful winds.
Winds borne far out to sea.
Driving across
thousands of miles of ocean.
Laden with moisture,
they race towards Patagonia.
And crash into a formidable barrier.
The Andes mountains.
WIND GUSTS
These high peaks strip the clouds
of virtually all their moisture.
Over three trillion tonnes of fresh
water locked up in glaciers...
..going nowhere.
The winds still blow,
but now they're freezing cold
and very dry.
They sweep eastwards
from the Andes...
..on a journey towards
the Atlantic coast.
WIND GUSTS
The winds blow so fiercely
that those who live here
call them La Escoba de Dios -
The Broom of God.
In the foothills, the world
they create is like no other.
Open moorlands bustling with life.
And unexpected wandering herds.
A male guanaco,
wild ancestor of the llama.
At this time of the year,
his main concern
is keeping an eye on his harem.
Young bachelors are intent
on stealing his females.
GUANACO BLEATS
On the edge of the herd,
one female has concerns of her own.
Giving birth to a calf
with legs nearly a metre long.
GENTLE BLEATING
Whist Dad is preoccupied
with the bachelors,
a grey fox is taking an interest.
Mum takes no chances.
The new addition takes
its first faltering steps.
Joining the family herd.
Even Dad is curious.
After giving birth,
the females quickly become fertile.
They must mate again soon -
and the bachelors know it.
The male's entire harem
is now at stake.
One bachelor makes his move.
The female spits her disapproval.
The male leaps into action.
FIERCE BLEATING
Using razor-sharp teeth...
..he aims for
his challenger's testicles.
An emasculating bite.
Necks are protected by
specially thickened skin.
These fights have no rules.
The battles are exhausting.
The challenger is driven off.
His masculinity intact, the male
enjoys the rewards whilst he can.
As the wind barrels
across the slopes,
it is twisted into ephemeral spirals.
Spinning Patagonia's
mysterious flying saucers -
lenticular clouds constantly whipped
by the swirling winds.
On the ground below, the challenge
is how to cheat the wind.
The stunted vegetation
is sculpted and armoured.
BIRDSONG
But under its protection,
delicate flowers bloom,
hidden from the shredding blasts.
This is gavilea,
a southern specialist.
An Andean sweet pea,
its fragile petals
saved from the wind.
And the porcelain orchid,
named after the delicate cracks
that adorn its petals.
It relishes these cold conditions.
These spirited blooms each exploit
a chink in the hostile climate.
And it's not just the flowers
that are keeping their heads down.
BIRDSONG
On the edge of this lake,
one bush looks a little different.
Darwin's rhea -
Patagonia's largest bird.
Like the bushes around,
it's hunkered down to avoid
the worst of the icy wind...
..keeping something precious warm.
A clutch of up to 50 eggs,
each ten times the size
of a hen's egg.
But this isn't Mum -
this is a dedicated father.
These eggs were laid by many mothers,
but they all have a single father,
and he's now incubating them alone.
For 40 days, he will barely eat
or drink as his clutch develops.
When dads can finally
stretch their legs,
they stride out with family in tow.
Four rhea chicks, all sporting
a mint humbug camouflage.
In a rhea's world,
it's all about growing up fast.
Building up fat reserves
to insulate against the cruel winds.
Plants, insects
and even lizards are all snapped up.
They'll grow to Dad's three-feet
height in just over eight months.
Whilst the chicks can hardly see
over the grass...
..Dad's long neck allows him
to keep an eye out for danger.
With Dad on the lookout,
the chicks can get back to
eating their way through
the Patagonian scrub.
A flightless single father
is unusual for a bird.
But in Patagonia, those that survive
often find unexpected solutions
to the challenges they face.
Small pools dot the foothills,
formed from the meagre winter snow.
They provide a refuge
for an unlikely wanderer.
Chilean flamingos.
Flamboyant and seemingly fragile,
they are, in fact, hardy nomads,
living over 50 years.
After a freezing night,
ice has formed on the water.
Soon, they won't be able to feed,
so they must leave
before they become trapped.
Flamingos can travel over 300 miles
in a day, looking for a new lake.
But as they head east,
away from the mountains,
not any old lake will do.
It must be shallow.
Salty, but not too much.
Ideally warm, getting lots of sun.
Then, like this lake,
it will be teeming with the tiny
crustaceans the flamingos eat...
..which give their feathers
such dramatic colour.
Their tongues pump vast quantities
of water through their bills,
sieving out the microscopic food.
Filtering the lake
as fast as they can.
It's essential, as they can't bank on
where they'll find their next meal.
The winds are still blowing,
but now the powers of the wind
and the sun combine.
Together,
they start to strangle the lake.
As it evaporates,
its chemistry changes,
gradually killing off
the flamingos' food.
Tempers begin to flare.
Once again, they must leave
and resume their search
for the next perfect lake,
racing the power of the sun.
Ahead of the flamingos,
everything changes.
The foothills give way
to the Patagonian Steppe.
A vast landscape
nearly 300,000 square miles,
three times the size of Britain.
East of here, the wind is warmer
and the sun hotter,
and the more difficult life becomes.
The soils here are too dry for trees.
Instead,
another plant has the upper hand.
This is the kingdom of grasses.
Over 50 species.
Tough, shiny leaves
defy the bone-dry wind.
The first Europeans to see this land
weren't so impressed.
Even Charles Darwin said it was
"wretched and useless".
But this land is very good
for something.
These grasslands produce
some of the finest wool in the world,
from some of the finest sheep
in the world.
The merino.
Patagonia's dry air
keeps the sheep cleaner.
Their whiter fleeces are prized
by the fashion houses of Europe.
Once a year, Patagonia's
eight million sheep are rounded up.
SHEEP BLEAT
SHEEPDOG BARKS
It's been said that the culture
and economy here
is built on a sheep's back.
As the gauchos bring in the sheep...
..the shearers are on their way.
They travel the Steppe,
living, sleeping
and eating together
for months on end.
Cesar Gueide has been shearing sheep
for 25 years.
TRANSLATION:
DOG BARKS
The flock gathers.
The shearers are ready.
TRANSLATION:
FAINT SINGING AND WHISTLING
WIND WHISTLES
Making a living in these rolling
grasslands is all about
being part of a community.
They all seek a home out of the wind.
The architect of all this
is the big, hairy armadillo.
ARMADILLO SNIFFS
He scratches a living
searching for grubs
and beetle larvae hidden underground.
His sense of smell is acute.
He can detect food buried
under 50 centimetres of soil.
Inside his nose are special filters
to keep out the dust.
He can breathe
where others would suffocate.
He works his way around the Steppe...
..excavating as he goes.
While he does, others are taking
advantage of his tunnelling skills.
A burrowing owl.
And his mate.
With no trees for shelter, the Steppe
wind drives them underground.
So an old armadillo burrow
makes for a snug home.
They have a strong, lifelong bond.
But their domestic bliss
is threatened
by nightmare neighbours.
Maras.
Perhaps Patagonia's oddest animal.
It's like a guinea pig on stilts.
Patagonia's answer to an antelope.
She's also looking for a burrow.
But they're in short supply -
so the maras take them by force.
That doesn't go down well
with the owls.
They're only eight inches tall,
but don't give up without a fight.
There's a lot at stake
for the mara, too.
She needs the armadillo's burrow
just as much -
for her pups.
This one's only a day old.
He was born eyes wide open
and fully furred.
He'll share this nursery
with up to 40 others.
Burrows are vital to his survival.
Whilst his parents
can sprint from danger,
his only defence
is to dive underground.
Today,
the community's a hive of activity.
The maras graze,
the armadillos trundle about...
..and the owls...well,
they take it easy.
And for the newborn,
it's time to play.
HIGH-PITCHED SQUEAL
Before long, the pups are hungry.
Each mother only feeds her own.
Their smell is unique,
so she sniffs each one.
But the others still try their luck.
So every female
is harassed by hungry mouths.
HIGH-PITCHED SQUEAL
The newborn joins in -
but he's in for a shock.
He tries again and again.
But female after female
drives him away.
HIGH-PITCHED SQUEAL
Desperate for a meal,
he tries one last time.
And his courage is rewarded.
This is HIS mother.
This community's success goes to show
that with a little help,
you can make a home in the Steppe.
These rugged landscapes have,
over the years,
attracted people seeking freedom
and a fresh start.
The original Patagonians were nomads,
but the new settlers
wanted to put down roots.
In 1865, Welsh pioneers set up
a new homeland along the rivers.
This was to be a Welsh utopia,
far from English influence.
By pulling together,
this fledgling community, 153 strong,
made farmsteads from the wilderness.
Life was tough,
but they had a lifeline that kept
their remote settlements together.
It still does today.
TRAIN WHISTLE
La Trochita - The Little Gauge.
Better known
as the Patagonian Express -
a steam train in miniature.
TRAIN WHISTLE
La Trochita was built
to open up the Steppe.
A vital link,
transporting settlers in
and wool and livestock
out to the coast.
It's still going strong,
lovingly maintained by Carlos Kmet
and his team.
TRANSLATION:
Even with La Trochita,
the Steppe remains one of the most
sparsely populated places on Earth.
Carlos relishes his link
to Patagonia's past.
TRAIN WHISTLE
La Trochita survived,
but the unpredictable climate
really tested new settlers.
In 1902, the famous bank robbers
Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid
escaped here to invest their loot.
Butch declared, "This part of
the country looks so good,
"I like the place better every day".
But life proved too tough.
After just five years,
they packed it in -
only to die in a Bolivian shootout.
Monuments to failed ventures
still haunt the Steppe today.
Halfway across the Steppe,
the winds begin to lose their power.
The sun takes control.
Success in the stifling heat
depends on the ability
to seize the day.
One creature is determined
not to miss his chance.
Patagonia's male wandering tarantulas
are searching for love.
This male's spent four years
reaching maturity.
But in two months, he'll be dead.
He's in a serious hurry.
He'll barely eat or sleep.
This is what he's looking for.
Silken threads left by a female.
Impregnated with her pheromones,
chemical love letters
advertising her availability.
They lead him to her lair.
She can live for 30 years.
She's seen many suitors in the past.
He taps a seductive rhythm
to tempt her out.
She replies.
For him,
this is a very dangerous liaison.
He eyes her up.
If he's not her type, she'll eat him.
But this male
has a talent for seduction.
He tenderly stokes her body.
She relaxes, opening her fangs,
allowing him to move closer.
He carefully delivers
his packet of sperm.
During mating, the female
falls into a trance-like state.
She stays like this
for several minutes.
He has to make a quick getaway
before it wears off.
For tarantulas, lingering goodbyes
are generally fatal.
The winds are coming to
the end of their journey,
reaching the edge of the continent.
Yet here,
Patagonia is at its most brutal.
This is a true desert,
and also Patagonia's
most mysterious landscape.
For most of the year,
there's not a drop of rain.
It's so hot and arid
little can survive here today.
But this was once a lush forest.
It's littered with tree trunks
now long dead.
Over millions of years,
they've been petrified.
Turned to stone.
They're evidence that the steppe
was once far wetter.
But that changed catastrophically.
Seven million years ago,
the rising Andes mountains
reached their full height.
The mountain stole the rain,
transforming Patagonia's climate
for ever.
A reminder that entire worlds
can be snuffed out
when the elemental forces of nature
collide.
Within touching distance
of the Atlantic,
Patagonia's desert
is at its most extreme.
Yet life triumphs even here.
Not a mirage -
a penguin.
She's on a mission,
walking deeper into the desert.
Her lifelong mate is waiting for her.
Just one couple in the largest
penguin colony in South America.
Magellanic penguins,
over half a million of them.
So the competition for burrows
often boils over.
Magellanics have short fuses.
They aim for bare patches of skin
where blood vessels
are closest to the surface.
The damage looks worse than it is,
but he'll think twice
before stealing another's burrow.
This couple have come to the desert
for one reason -
the dry air.
Their new chicks are covered
in a fluffy layer of down.
Despite the searing day,
nights are cold,
so the down is essential for warmth.
But if it gets wet,
the chicks will chill and die.
So everyone suffers in the heat.
Each day, their parents take turns
trudging to the sea
across a mile of desert.
Dad's feet are leathery -
protection from the burning sand.
Finally.
The ocean is a welcome relief.
He'll swim miles out to sea,
fishing tirelessly
for over eight hours.
Back at the burrow,
it's tough for Mum.
With her thick feathers
and a layer of fat,
she's in danger of overheating.
But, despite the heat,
she can't doze off.
The colony is not safe.
Kelp gulls.
They skulk around the colony
searching every burrow
looking for unattended chicks.
They won't try anything
with Mum around.
The gulls keep her on her toes,
but the main threat to her chicks
is the desert itself.
Their only source of water's
within the food
their parents bring back
from the sea.
Around them, the gulls are making
the most of early casualties.
But these chicks are lucky.
Dad emerges from the dust,
his stomach full of fish and squid.
Food and drink in one gulp.
For this couple,
100 days of trudging the desert
lie ahead,
before their chicks are old enough
to leave the colony,
heading out to spend winter at sea,
saying goodbye to Patagonia
for another year.
The theft of rains by the Andes
mountains may have destroyed a world,
but, in doing so,
it has created a new one.
A windswept land to the east...
..an arid world of plucky
and adaptable survivors...
..pioneers who take on a punishing
combination of elements
and, against all the odds,
they triumph.
Patagonia has a rugged beauty,
and the jewel in its crown
is Torres del Paine,
famous for its iconic granite towers.
It's where the Patagonia team
have come to film two creatures
during the brief spring.
Their aim is to capture
the birth of a wanako
and a rhea father with
his newly-hatched chicks
and, to do so, they turn to
the people who know Torres best,
Chilean film-makers
Christian Munoz-Donoso
and his son Christiaan Munoz Salas,
also known as Doco.
They would each take on
one of these challenges.
With Doco is director Hannah Hawe.
Their mission was the rhea family.
Rheas are massive.
They're Patagonia's biggest birds.
I just didn't think it would be
that hard to find them.
But I hadn't really banked
on the scale of the landscape.
It's just vast, and rheas
are incredibly well-camouflaged.
They just vanish.
From a distance,
every rock looks like a rhea.
They needed extra help,
so local rancher Juan led them
to the spots he knew.
So, Juan is just going to check
the route ahead for us.
There's a bit of a, er...
Well, from here,
it looks like a bit of a cliff.
He's just going to check
if there's a route down.
It's his land, so...
..whatever he says goes.
It's not his car, however.
Ooh!
CAR DOOR SLAMS
BIRDSONG
Finally, a rhea.
But too far away.
And not stopping.
Rheas run at nearly 40mph.
BIRDSONG
But if the rheas
were proving difficult,
the guanaco team seemed
to have the harder mission -
to film a mother giving birth.
Very soon, they saw a welcome sight.
Getting close wasn't the problem.
But they'd missed the birth,
and only by minutes.
But for the rhea team, Patagonia
had unleashed its powerful winds.
They're called the Broom of God.
Gusting over 100mph...
..and making filming impossible.
WIND ROARS
I can't...
I genuinely can't stand up!
HE LAUGHS
WIND ROARS AND WHISTLES
HE EXHALES DEEPLY
CAR ENGINE WHIRS
The next day, the wind dropped.
The rhea team had a new lead.
But Christiaan had a word of warning
before they went their separate ways.
HE CHUCKLES
Like any father, Christiaan
was concerned for their safety.
If we encounter pumas, what...
What's the protocol?
THEY LAUGH
OK.
Bye.
Off we go.
Puma country.
Hyunh!
I'm sticking with you, Doco.
SHE CHUCKLES
Here is...
..the first sign I've got
that we are...
definitely in puma country.
Not much left of that.
I guess that was a guanaco.
Finally, a rhea that was staying put.
But as soon as we found the rhea,
I forgot about the pumas.
It was the closest
we'd managed to get to one.
He was sitting on a nest
and he wasn't going anywhere.
He just sat tight on that nest.
And we just had to do the same.
BIRDSONG
They needed this dad to have
chicks beneath those feathers.
After five hours, he stood,
only to reveal that
there were no chicks, just eggs.
And rheas can sit on their eggs
for five weeks before they hatch.
It was disappointing.
We just didn't have time to sit
with him and wait for them to hatch.
It was really gutting.
But we had to move on.
Down the road, for the guanaco team,
it was all kicking off.
Suddenly, there were chulengos
appearing all over the place.
The guanaco mission was complete.
But the rhea team
were running out of options.
They had one last tip
they could check out.
We'd been told about a lake
where rheas are often seen.
It was called Lake Nandu, which is
the local Spanish word for 'rhea',
which I thought was a good omen.
After a couple of tense hours
scouring the horizon...
I've just seen a rhea
with his chicks.
He's just come over the big hill.
His chicks were just a few days old.
BIRDSONG
And this time, Doco managed to get
the shots that he needed
that helped us tell that story of
our dad with his little chicks.
It was a huge relief.
Sometimes, it's the things that you
think are going to be easy
that take you by surprise
and prove to be the most difficult.
It just goes to show that you can
never second-guess Patagonia.
BIRDSONG
Next time, we travel
along Patagonia's coastline,
from the turbulent,
freezing waters of Cape Horn...
..forging northwards
over 1,000 miles...
..where rich ocean currents favour
those who dare to be different.
SEALS BARK AND SNARL