The heat wave continues.
It's 109 degrees in Los Angeles.
As drought-ridden Los Angeles
swelters in agonizing heat,
drug lords wage bloody
warfare in the streets.
Yet another open conflict...
Fuck this! Get me out of here!
We're in a war zone, Dave, two
motorcycle officers
horribly wounded
in a deadly crossfire,
the police seemingly
unable to rescue them
in spite of several desperate,
heroic attempts.
It's completely out of
control down here.
My beautiful cantina, everything
I own, they shot it to pieces.
My microwave, my automatic
steamer, my grill...
You fucking pendejos!
Fuck you!
Tony Pope, live with Hard Core,
on the scene and in your face.
It's like Dante's hell
down here.
Smoke, fire, oppressive heat,
as Colombian and Jamaican
drug fiends once again
transform the streets of
LA into a slaughterhouse.
Who the hell's in charge down here?
The cops?
They're outmanned,
outgunned and incompetent.
Mr. Mayor, on vacation
in your home in Lake Tahoe,
get off your butt, get down
here and declare martial law!
Okay, don't keep me
in suspense, Danny boy!
It has not been a nice day!
Two motors pulled over a truck, stumbled
right in the middle of a narc stakeout.
You know, ten Colombians and
Scorpios armed to fuck all.
They're trying to get
inside their headquarters.
We're keeping them pinned down, but
those officers are bleeding to death.
Fuck! They're dying, man.
Where the hell is
Special Weapons?
They're still tied up in that
shootout in San Pedro
getting their ass kicked
by the Jamaicans.
They shot down
one of our choppers.
And Mills and Johnson won't
last much longer out there.
We need an assault
vehicle to go get 'em.
I'm gonna chat
with these assholes.
Okay, when I give a signal,
give me some cover!
Got it!
Too small.
Right.
Come on! Come on!
Get 'em out of here! Now!
Get 'em out! Get 'em out!
Hey, assholes!
Mike, are you okay?
Yeah. Let's get
the rest of them.
We can't. Just got orders
from Chief Heinemann.
He says secure perimeter,
surround building and wait.
- Wait for what?
- I don't know!
Some bullshit special unit.
The feds, the DEA.
If we let those bastards
get dug in now, we'll have to
level the building
to get 'em out!
Come and get it.
El Scorpio is ready.
Sarge, any of your
people in the building?
No.
Let's go.
Hey, can't let you in there.
Heinemann's on his way.
Heinemann can kiss
my sweet ass! Come on!
Goddamn it.
Go with him.
Three, two, one...
Go!
Get back, back, back. Back.
Next door over.
Take this room!
First floor, officer down.
We need backup.
Freeze!
I said hold it!
Now, lay your guns down.
It's over.
You can walk down or fly,
it's your choice.
I said put it down, asshole!
No!
Let's do it now!
Take it easy.
Damn, it's hot.
Must be losing it.
Mike!
Spread out.
Secure the roof.
Just take it easy.
I'm right here.
All clear here.
All clear on the site.
Danny boy.
I gotta get down from here.
Shit.
Okay, search the roof.
Work your way down.
Check every floor.
Maybe someone else...
Seal it off.
No one leaves.
Danny, come and get me
off this damn roof.
You get the rest of them?
Somebody beat us to it.
Leona.
Shit.
So, what happened to El Scorpio?
He's out front having lunch.
What the hell is this?
I don't know.
They've been cut to pieces.
Must be the Jamaicans.
Their style but where
the hell did they go?
Okay, nobody gets in here until
Forensic arrives. Nobody.
Okay, you know the drill.
Mike.
Up there.
He must have been killed out
here, and then someone...
That's about 35, 40 feet.
No rope, no ladder.
The guy weighs
about 190, 195 pounds.
You couldn't carry him up there.
Lieutenant?
Deputy Chief Heinemann's
downstairs.
He wants you and your people
out of the building now.
Son of a bitch.
What the fuck is going on?
This is not good,
Mike. Not good at all.
I want a real name
on this joker, okay?
You got it.
Mike.
Phil, this is quite a surprise. What
brings you down from the palace?
You let me down, Mike.
You're making me look bad.
I thought we had
an understanding.
I put my ass on the line
to get you here,
and all I expect is
a little cooperation!
Now, you were told that
this was a federal matter.
Yet you disobeyed a direct order
to stay out of the building.
Don't let this get out, Phil, but
it's a fucking war down here.
You are a soldier and
you take orders. Don't push it!
I'll push it as far as I can every day, Phil,
'cause we're fighting for our lives here,
while you're downtown pushing
pencils and kissing ass!
I don't roll over for
anybody, especially the feds,
without a goddamn
good explanation!
Take this equipment up to the third
floor now. Come on, let's move!
- Let's go.
- Excuse me, sir! Sir!
Hey, what the hell is
going on here, Heinemann?
Insubordination. Disregard for direct
orders from a supervising officer.
Now get back to
your cage at Alvarado.
I'll show you insubordination,
you son of a bitch!
No, no, no!
Where you running to?
Come here! Come on.
You don't need this, Mike.
It's not worth it.
Relax.
Fuck!
I have an update for you.
Now, get this.
In a midst of shootout, five
members of one Colombian drug gang
were apparently ambushed by their bloody
rivals, the Jamaican Voodoo Posse,
who escaped without a trace.
Again making total fools of...
- What've you got?
- A detective is here to see you.
Back there.
Listen, lady, you got a backed-up toilet.
Call a plumber, not the cops.
This license has expired.
Bullshit! I paid that
fee six months ago.
- I'll kick your ass!
- Sit down! Right now!
- Move! Get your ass movin'!
- Just calm the fuck down!
What you lookin' at?
And all you got to do
is tee it high and let it fly.
Dead solid perfect.
Now, remember, for distance you gotta
gently but firmly grip the club.
Lieutenant Harrigan! Detective
Lambert, Rampart Division.
Hey, kid, just have a seat.
I'll be right with you.
- Hey, Cap.
- Don't start with me, Mike.
Heinemann's already been up my ass so far
I won't be able to sit down for a week.
We're not winning this war.
As much as it's gonna piss you off, you're
gonna have to play the game on this one.
"Effective immediately,
"a federal task force under the
direction of Special Agent Peter Keyes
"will be investigating
criminal activities involving
"the trafficking and distribution
of controlled substances."
And you will extend him
your full cooperation.
Which means you're cutting off my
dick and shoving it up my ass.
God damn it, Mike, the feds are calling
the shots on this. My hands are tied!
- Yeah?
- Captain Pilgrim, Peter Keyes.
- It's good to meet you.
- Nice to meet you, sir.
Lieutenant Mike Harrigan.
Special Agent Peter Keyes, DEA.
Heard a lot about you.
I'm sorry for this
jurisdictional intrusion.
Don't mean to be
stepping on your toes.
But we want to prevent
King Willie's voodoo gangs
from taking over and controlling
the entire West Coast.
I wish I could tell you more.
But we have a large number of
deep-cover operatives involved.
You know how it is.
We all have a job to do.
Now, I'm sure we can respect each
other's situation and act responsibly.
Well, cooperation
is my middle name.
I'll see you around.
Lieutenant Harrigan,
- I'm the new transfer, Jerry Lambert.
- Like I said, have a seat.
I'll be right with you.
- Who is this dude?
- Yeah, what an asshole.
All right, Danny boy,
what we got?
What have we got? Five lowlife
Scorpions make it into the building.
The next minute,
they're all shish kebab.
Not one bullet wound.
Well, it wasn't drugs or money. There's
a shit load of that for the taking.
Maybe King Willie brought in some outside
talent. He's making his big move.
A pro would have split the
moment he heard the action.
More than one,
we would have seen them.
Whoever did this waited
until the last minute,
and then took out four men armed
with machine guns by hand!
And then got by us.
Maybe we should give him a job.
Let's put him on the payroll.
So me and my partner bolt up the stairs,
somebody is screaming bloody murder...
- You gotta... You gotta hear this.
- What?
Hey. Hey,
I forgot to tell you.
See that guy there?
That's Ferris's replacement.
This guy's Jerry Lambert. The
Lone Ranger from Rampart station.
That's the Lone Ranger?
I thought he was here
to fix the air conditioning.
I said "Lady, you are under
arrest." And she said "Why?"
I said "Because your husband is dead.
You killed him."
And you know what she said
without missing a beat?
No.
She said, "I stabbed that son
of a bitch plenty of times.
"He never died
on me before."
Looks like he's putting
the moves to Leona.
- His first big mistake.
I have heard about you.
- Yeah? All right.
- Yeah!
Like your last partner got shot.
What?
Well...
You try that cowboy
shit with me, fucker,
you can kiss these goodbye.
- Got it?
- Yeah, I got it.
Well, well, I see that
the three of you have met.
Lambert, if you're
feeling up to it,
why don't you limp your way in and go see
the lieutenant. He wants to talk to you.
Yeah.
- You're a bad girl.
- I like that.
No, no, no!
Goddamn, is that bitch
on the rag or what?
This is what I call
"the speech," kid.
It's the only one I've got and I
only give it once, so pay attention.
Until now, it's all been fun and games,
cops and robbers, Dunkin' Donuts.
But you're in the shit now.
Metro Command is a war zone.
Lieutenant, I've paid my dues.
I had to bust my ass
to get my transfer.
And that scares
the shit out of me, kid.
No one requests to come down here unless
they're looking for a reputation.
There's no room for showboats,
anyone looking to prove themselves.
I won't stand for it.
Now, don't get me wrong.
We need good cops down here, and
they say you're good at what you do.
But the team comes first.
You live by that, and you'll be okay.
And we'll all be there for you.
Remember, the door
swings both ways.
That's it.
Hey, kid.
Welcome to the war.
No!
Okay, guys. This
has gone too far now, huh?
Hey, hey, guys.
I know you're trying
to scare me, huh?
Well, you did
a pretty good job, man.
I'm scared now.
Stop it now.
I can pay you.
$2 million, man. In cash.
Right now!
This is not about money.
This is about power!
There's a new king
in the streets.
This is a message
he has for your people.
You are history.
Fucking history, goddamn puto.
What the fuck are
you doing now, man?
You're crazy!
King Willie says,
not only do I have to kill you,
but I have to take your soul.
Voodoo magic.
Fucking voodoo magic, man.
But you know what?
I tell you what I believe.
Shit happens.
Shoot it!
Fucker!
Shit happens.
I'm standing just outside a
penthouse complex in San Pedro...
...involving as many as 20 people.
It's uncertain just who they were.
But, at least one report indicates it might
be the feared Jamaican Voodoo Posse.
So I go in for
my physical, right,
and the doctor says "I need a
semen, stool and urine sample."
I say "Gee, doc, I'm in a big hurry.
Can I just leave my underwear?"
Oh, God.
Word is there may be as many as
50 more dead bodies up there.
Oh, man, it's Pope.
That parasite
must live in his car.
I'll handle it.
PR is my specialty.
Feds just sent word they want
your ass off the job.
- Tony, my man!
- Who the hell are you?
Your biggest fan, Tony! Catch
your show all the time.
Well, I got a job to do!
Your job is to root for your
garbage somewhere else.
- Been inside?
- Yeah, I did.
We were gonna go
in there with our guys,
but we were told on
a radio transmission
nobody goes in there under
any circumstances at all.
All units responding
to San Pedro and 5th Avenue, be advised.
Federal officers
will handle investigation.
- We didn't hear that. Let's go.
- You're the boss.
This is Cheryl Tyer
reporting live...
Hey, nice flashlight.
Mind if I borrow it?
Okay.
Damn!
Look familiar?
Fuck.
Oh, God.
Ramon Vega, the crack king.
Biggest operator in East LA.
100 keys a week.
Why isn't he skinned?
And who are these assholes?
They're Jamaicans.
King Willie's boys.
That doesn't make sense.
This was a voodoo ritual. I've seen it
all before. They took his heart out.
What for?
Terror tactics, man.
You know, to scare the shit
out of their enemies.
King Willie.
Who the hell is King Willie?
King Willie, voodoo
priest of the LA posses.
Ran the terror gangs
for Edward Seaga in Jamaica
till he got too powerful.
The Jamaican chiefs won't make
a move without his approval.
So what the fuck happened?
Shit!
Hey, we got a survivor!
What's she saying?
I don't know. She's
not making any sense.
She keeps saying "El diablo vino por ellos.
" The devil came for them.
Shit, if the Colombians did all this,
then why'd they leave their boss Ramon
over there hanging and his
girlfriend naked on the floor?
It wasn't the Colombians.
Our friend from the armory.
Right.
We got a new player in town.
Come over here, Mike.
Check this out.
What is that?
Looks like
a spear tip or something.
This is a restricted area.
I want it cleared immediately.
You're walking on
physical evidence.
- We'll take care of her.
- She's with me. Just back off!
Lieutenant, I'd like a word
with you in private, please.
They say that persistence is one of
your most outstanding qualities.
Hey, look, I know
this is your show...
You're not listening to me!
You got a big nose and you're
sticking it too far in my business.
Maybe you can hear this.
The next time you cross me,
you're gonna turn up missing.
Garber, the man with the camera.
Get him. Right now.
Yes, sir.
- All right. Come on, let's go.
- Stay away.
Hey, fuck you, man!
Give me my camera!
Shut the fuck up.
Hey, wait a minute! I got my rights!
I'm a journalist.
Harrigan!
Shut up. Let's go.
Smells like a cover-up.
The press has a right to know!
- Take him out of the building. Search him.
- Scum ball.
Now you get
the hell out of here.
Who the hell are you, Keyes?
The last person in the world
you wanna fuck with.
Wanna make me proud, kid?
Take your bag of tricks, stay with
them, find out where they take her.
Meet me later at La Cita's. And be careful.
These guys are good.
Hey, don't worry, Lieutenant!
Surveillance is my specialty.
Okay, then.
Just get going.
Go get 'em, Lone Ranger.
Hey, Danny, look here.
We gotta take this real cool.
These guys sure aren't the DEA,
but it's still Keyes's party.
You stick around, stay out of sight.
I'll meet you at 1:00.
We'll take a good look at that room, okay?
Hey, wait for me.
Danny boy,
no hero stuff, understand?
Danny boy.
Watch your ass, Danny boy.
She never made it.
The feds were waiting.
Hustled her off in a chopper.
Let me guess.
A silver Alouette?
That very one.
And guess what. Your pal Keyes was running
the whole show. And his butt boys.
Son of a bitch.
You done real good, kid.
Now tomorrow,
start a tail on Keyes.
Everything he does,
everywhere he goes.
Who knows?
You might just get lucky.
Lieutenant!
Luck is my specialty.
Yeah. I bet it is.
Now, if you'll
excuse me, Lieutenant,
I got some serious
police work to attend to.
Come to Papa.
Hey!
- Hey, are your balls okay?
- Fine.
How are yours?
- Hey, do you mind? It's my sister.
- Say what?
You're not my sister, are you?
Son of a bitch. Who are you
really chasing, Keyes?
Time to go to work.
Shit.
Danny boy.
Mike?
Oh, God!
No. No. Oh, God!
Mother of God!
Please, no!
Lieutenant Michael R Harrigan.
Violence prone,
obsessive%compulsive personality,
a history of excessive
physical force
throughout his 18 years as a
Los Angeles police officer.
Also responsible for the destruction
of 11 patrol cars, a city bus...
What about ten
commendations for valor,
and the best felony arrest record
in the history of this department?
That and my intervention on your
behalf are the only reasons
you still have a job, Harrigan.
If it were up to the chief,
he'd charge you with Detective
Archuleta's death and suspend you.
As it is,
he left it in my hands.
Now, this John Wayne attitude and flagrant
disregard for policy is gonna end now.
'Cause no one under my command is gonna impede
the progress of this federal task force
headed by Agent Keyes.
No one.
That's it.
Dismissed.
Mike, you're too close to this.
Stay out of it.
It's a police matter. They can't
keep the department out of it.
We'll find Danny's killer.
Captain, Danny and I
came up together.
Fifteen years on
the fucking street!
Whoever killed him is gonna pay.
I'm gonna finish it.
Hey!
Hey, come on.
What is this?
Listen, shithead.
I don't give a fuck who you really are
or what you want with this asshole
because now it's personal.
And he's a dead man.
The concept of what you're dealing with
is over your head. I'm warning you...
You! You don't know
what you're dealing with.
And I'm warning you.
Stay the fuck out of my way!
I'll take care of him.
No.
Let him go.
We're too close.
...claiming as his,
turf already controlled by
the bloodthirsty Jamaican
and Colombian drug lords.
Watch as we continue our report.
Yes, the word is out,
LA is up for grabs,
the spoils of our once fine
city going to the ruthless scum
who can spread the most carnage
and blood in our streets.
The latest update
on the scoreboard,
five assorted trash
and one good cop,
one of the best on our force.
Who's next you say? Where's the mayor?
He's not even in the city...
Forget it. It's over.
Mike, goddamn it.
This ain't your personal
little war, you know.
I loved Danny, too.
Hey, you told me, Lieutenant, the only way you
survive down here is because you're a team.
The door swings
both ways. Remember?
All right.
We'll do it together.
Come on. Talk to me about Keyes.
He's been everywhere. We've been
on him for the last three days.
And they're not looking
for drug dealers.
Yeah. They've been setting up these
weird radar sensors all over downtown.
I mean, I used my whole
repertory to keep up with them.
I had scanners on them,
but they scrambled my shit up.
Man, they had equipment
I can't begin to touch.
And then this morning
I lost 'em.
We lost them.
- Lost them where?
- Vernon and Industry.
I mean, like,
they fucking disappeared!
The slaughterhouse district?
Yeah, and in this heat!
I mean, BO and barbecue!
Whatever Keyes is looking for, he's
found it, or damn close to it.
Leona, I want to
meet with King Willie.
Willie and I seem to have
the same problem.
In the meantime,
you come with me.
Mike, it's impossible!
Just do it.
Fuck!
Omega 1, this is Control.
This is Omega 1.
Okay, we've only got 22 minutes
remaining on safe window of operation.
Yes, sir.
Verify that
final telemetry check.
Start your test now.
Scan track three, two, one,
mark.
Number six,
power up on the UV banks.
We're complete on the
lower UV banks. Ready for testing.
Second level, check for
ambient temperature variations.
You got two minutes.
Now get going.
To all units. All units,
you have approximately 20 minutes
to finish your task.
- Roger.
- Increase this UV.
Up 42 per cent.
Your friend's death was the result
of a massive intrusion in the chest cavity
by an edged weapon that nearly
cleaved the heart in two.
Death was instantaneous.
He was boned like a fish. I've
never seen anything like this.
Please, do not touch anything.
Doctor, what about
the other victims?
Anything there?
The federal team brought in
their own forensic examiners.
I am the medical examiner and the
chief pathologist in the city,
and they've cut
me out completely.
Any way you can get a look at any of
the evidence the feds have collected?
I mean, they must
have run tests.
It won't be easy.
Doctor...
I pried this from Danny's hands. This
is what took him up into the rafters.
It has almost no weight.
But it cuts like steel.
Let me see.
We are now at 150,000 times
normal magnification.
Astonishing. This material
doesn't correspond to anything
on the periodic table.
Lieutenant, what the
hell is that thing?
I don't know. But you don't
buy it in a hardware store.
- Military?
- Good guess.
Either something that got away from
us or something they want real bad.
Keyes. We're getting
closer now to what happened...
- Look out!
- Hey, no!
Easy, kid.
Put your gun away.
King Willie will see you now.
It's okay.
Don't you want me
to go with you?
I'll call you later.
You want me to follow you?
I'll call you later!
You want some ganja, man?
License plate number.
1-8-8...
No, no. 1-8-8-3...
Fuck!
The door swings
both ways, my ass.
This door swings both ways.
Thanks for the ride.
You know,
you guys really
ought to cut down.
They say you want to talk to me.
They say you offering me favors.
Tell me why, Babylon.
Mr. Policeman.
I want some information.
Information.
About the one that's
doing all the killing?
He killed your people.
Now mine.
I think you know who he is.
I want him.
I don't know who he is.
But I know where he is.
The other side.
What are you talking about?
The spirit world, man.
You see,
it's always the same.
There's no stopping
what can't be stopped.
No killing what can't be killed.
Hey, make sense, man.
This thing that's killing
your people and mine
is from the other side.
I can feel him all around.
You can't see
the eyes of the demon
until him come calling.
This is dread, man.
Truly dread.
Nothing else for
you here, policeman.
Time to go.
Prepare yourself.
"His foundation lie
in the holy mountain."
"Selah."
This is Tony Pope live from LA,
the city of fear.
The psycho-vigilante killer continues
his daily diet for murder.
Bodies strung out,
bodies with the skins ripped off,
the hearts torn from the cadavers.
And just recently,
King Willie, the drug lord,
the vicious drug lord found in
an alley just around the corner
with his head cut off and his
spinal column torn from the body.
A fitting demise to
the Prince of Powder.
First Danny, then King Willie.
And you were right there!
He's playing with you, Mike.
You've gotta be careful.
Yeah. We all gotta be careful.
What about Keyes?
Anything there?
There's definitely something
slippery about our brother Keyes.
Seems there's
a Peter J. Keyes.
PhD physical sciences, Cornell.
Hot out of college and right into
bed with the Strategic Defense Institute.
Then two years later commissioned as
a captain in Air Force Intelligence.
Mike, this is a dead end.
We're way out of our league!
Look, I don't care how big
this is or who's involved.
This guy killed Danny
and he's going to fall!
Now, what about the good doctor?
Yes, I'm here, Lieutenant.
The federal authorities erased everything
from the computer file except for this.
Part of a chemical test on a
fragment of wood from the penthouse.
And it contained traces
of cattle blood and heavy
traces of steroids.
I believe that whoever killed
Detective Archuleta
had recently been
in a slaughterhouse.
Slaughterhouse. That's where I
lost Keyes the first time, Lieutenant.
Yeah. That's where
we'll find him.
Take the metro, Long Beach line. I'll
pick you up at Vernon station in an hour.
Just because you don't see Keyes's
boys doesn't mean they're not around.
I just want you to
stay in the car. Okay?
Your mom and I won't be very long. You sit
still. We'll be back in a few minutes.
All right?
Come on, honey.
Yes, dear.
Which way was it?
Down here to the right.
Take that, you scum-sucking dog.
Want some candy?
Brian?
- You come here right this minute.
- Mommy, I saw a ghost.
Want some candy?
Rest.
Danny's necklace.
God, I hate
the subway at rush hour.
You know, it's hard
enough to find a seat,
and if you find one, someone's either
pissed in it or thrown up all over it.
This damn heat
is killing me, man.
Hey, it's me!
- I look great!
- Shut up.
No autographs, Pop.
Hey, look. There's two seats right there.
I told you...
Don't touch me!
Get off! Hey!
This shit never ends.
- After you.
- Asshole!
- Excuse me. Police business.
- Get out of my way!
Hey, baby.
Bésame mucho. Come on!
You look like
a sympathetic dude.
My partner here
needs an operation.
But we're a little short of
cash, if you know what I mean?
No need for that.
Money.
Get the hell away from me!
- I know how to use this thing! Don't make me use this thing!
- He got a cap gun.
Bet mine's bigger than yours!
I'll take that.
Hold it. Police!
We're in trouble now.
Nobody move!
Okay, everybody just take a deep
breath, loosen your sphincters.
We don't need any
rush-hour Rambo's there.
Tú también, motherfucking baby!
Drop it and sit down!
Siéntate!
What the hell is that?
Leona, you okay?
This is it! He's in the train!
Get these people out of here!
Jerry!
What's happening?
Get down! Get down!
Come on, come on,
come on, get out of the way!
Jerry!
Leona!
Leona, get 'em out! Go! Go!
Now!
I can't see...
Jerry!
Now, Leona, do it!
Now!
Hey! Over here!
Yeah, that's right.
Come and get it.
Come on! Move it! Move it!
Let's go, let's go! Vamos!
What is that?
Yeah.
Move it! Don't panic,
just go! Go! Apúrense, vamos!
Jesus Christ.
What the fuck are you?
Wait!
Vamos! Ven, ven, vamos!
Come on!
Keep walking! Come on, you too!
Vàmonos!
Come on, motherfucker!
Want some candy?
Let's dance!
Move it. Come on, get out of the way!
Come on.
Get out of the way!
Out, come on!
Come on,
out! Out! Out!
Come on, move it!
That way! That way!
Towards the light! The light!
Come on! Get out!
Come on.
Oh, God.
Jerry.
God, not again.
Okay, move your ass!
Move out the way!
Watch out! What's happening? What's
happening? What's happening?
It's a fucking slaughter
down there, Lieutenant.
Oh, God!
Hey, Jerry!
Oh, Leona! Leona!
Please. Leona.
How's she doing?
Deep shock, but she's alive.
Picking up fetal heart sounds.
This woman is pregnant.
Let's move.
LA County. Stat!
Stand back.
On three. One, two,
three. Load up.
Out of my way!
Move out the way!
Move it! Move it!
Man!
Wait a minute.
Let me see.
Where's Jerry?
I don't know.
We found his badge.
Who got hit this time?
Five gang members,
bunch of commuters.
Doesn't make sense.
They were all armed.
- What do you mean?
- It's the chief.
Wait here. Yeah?
What the hell's
going on down there?
It's a damn nightmare.
Civilians this time.
- All killed?
- Yeah. Just like the others.
Damn!
Jerry!
Hey!
Holy shit! What the
hell is going on here?
Hey, guys, get the camera on! Get
the camera on this right now!
Get that goddamn thing on film!
What's going on?
Hey! Hey!
Hey, Harrigan!
More victims.
More mutilations.
- Fuck you!
- Pope!
Pope? Are you there, Pope?
Pope, what's going on?
Sir, the cop is back.
Goddamn.
Harrigan! Don't you show up
in the damnedest places.
Come here, Lieutenant. I got something
you might find interesting.
What is this?
How many times do I have to tell you? You
don't know what you're dealing with.
There's your killer.
Wonderful, isn't it?
Pheromone signature left by his body.
These are scent molecules.
Punch up three.
Ten years ago one of his
kind stalked and eliminated
an elite Special Forces
crew in Central America.
There were two survivors.
They indicated that,
when trapped,
the creature activated
a self-destruct device
that destroyed enough rainforest
to cover 300 city blocks.
Remarkable weaponry.
That's right, Lieutenant.
Other-world life forms.
A fucking alien!
Iwo Jima, Cambodia, Beirut.
Drawn by heat and conflict.
He's on safari. Lions.
The tigers. The bears.
Oh, my!
Trophies. That's the
game, isn't it, Keyes?
You're the lion.
This is his jungle.
So why can't we see him?
Defensive adaptations
are astounding.
It's somehow able to bend
light. Perfect camouflage.
You admire the son of a bitch.
Not what he does, Lieutenant.
For what he is.
For what he can give us.
A new era of
scientific technology.
I've waited a lifetime for this, and
I'm not going to miss the chance.
Mr. Garber, we're picking up
something on the pheromone scanners.
Target one is on the roof.
It's taken us over two weeks
to learn his patterns.
He comes here every
two days to feed.
Seems he has a taste for beef.
I didn't think
he was vegetarian.
Well, we've prepared a little
trap for this predator.
We are certain that this being can
see in only one spectrum of light,
- infrared.
- Infrared?
He hunts by seeing our heat.
Block the heat and he's blind.
These suits insulate all body heat, making
the team invisible to the creature.
We've flooded the packing
house with radioactive dust.
We've also installed powerful
ultraviolet lighting everywhere.
The dust adheres to his body,
making him visible.
Liquid nitrogen. You're not gonna kill
this asshole. You're gonna freeze him.
Well, we have to capture him.
He's moving.
Finally.
Grab a seat. Enjoy the show.
This is history.
Capture and isolation
is our objective.
Defensive action
only on my orders.
Power up. Lights on.
Let's get him!
We're in.
Switch to ultraviolet.
Radio silence. Out.
Engage ultraviolet units
A through J.
What's all this interference?
Correcting the problem, sir.
They're moving
to the second level.
Target's still moving, heading
towards the number two stairwell.
Playing right into it.
Wait a minute.
It's stopped.
It's moving back
against the wall.
It's backing up.
It's moving away from them.
He sees them, Garber.
Your boys have been made.
Sir, it's circling
around behind them.
Get 'em out, Garber! They're
walking into a trap! Get 'em out.
Keyes, he's right behind you. Third
floor structure. Right there!
Who is this?
Clear the line.
He sees the damn lights. Turn 'em off!
Turn 'em off! Shit!
Stop him!
Door. Open it.
Go fuck yourself.
Okay. Okay.
The door.
- Yes, sir.
- You don't know what you're doing, Harrigan.
It's open.
You'll ruin everything!
Fuck yourself!
Defensive formation one.
Nitrogen guns, safeties off.
Everyone else, lie still.
This is it.
He's moving down on your
position from the right.
Garber, where is he?
I can't see him.
He's right there!
God damn it! Where is he? Well,
give me a coordinate! Where is he?
Watch out!
My God.
Watch your crossfire!
What...
I'm losing my pressure.
Keyes, you all right?
Keyes, it's over here!
Come on,
damn it! Switch over!
Shit! I can't see!
They're gone.
They're all dead.
You want me? Here I am!
You are one
ugly mother...
Motherfucker!
Guess who's back.
Too late to go home now.
Get out of here, Harrigan.
I'm gonna save your ass.
This is between me and him!
God...
Birds.
Damn birds.
Okay, pussyface.
It's your move.
Shit happens.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
That's all I need is birds.
You can do it.
I can do it. I can do it.
It's like falling off a log.
Like a 30-story log.
Damn!
Yeah. Maybe I'll
get lucky and fall.
Damn it.
The final
Jeopardy answer is this,
Berengaria, who never set foot in
England, was its queen for eight years
after marrying
this king on Cyprus.
Good luck.
Herb?
Herb, wake up! There's
somebody in the bathroom.
Herb!
It's all right.
I'm a cop.
I don't think he gives a shit.
Shit!
Get back inside!
Holy Moses.
Not again. Shit!
Son of a bitch.
Oh, God.
Why can't this guy
stay on the ground?
Come on, come on.
Come on, come on!
Come to Papa.
Stop! Stop the elevator!
Stop it!
Now where the hell am I?
Where are you?
Jesus Christ.
That's right, asshole!
Shit happens!
Okay. Who's next?
Take it.
"1715."
Harrigan! What the fuck
happened in there, huh?
Goddamn it.
We came so close!
Don't worry, asshole.
You'll get another chance.