Subtitles By deity
Formatted By tangseng @ 23.976ps, 1CD, 01:51:28
Senators, consider
the opportunities
for the Empire.
At last, the destinies
of the planets
Romulus and Remus
will be united.
Shinzon of Remus is offering us
a chance
to make ourselves stronger
than ever before.
lt would be madness
to reject it.
l beg you not to let
prejudice or politics
interfere with this Alliance.
By joining Shinzon's
forces with ours,
not even the Federation will
be able to stand in our way.
That's enough!
The decision has been made.
The military does not
dictate policy on Romulus.
The Senate has considered
Shinzon's proposal
and rejected it.
He and his followers will be met
with all deliberate force
and sent back
to that black rock
they came from.
Do l make myself clear?
Yes, sir.
lf you will excuse me,
Praetor,
l have an appointment
with the Tholian Ambassador.
Of course.
Senators, are there
any others who wish to speak?
Then l call for a vote
on the motion
to open trade negotiations
with Celes ll.
As you know, the Reman mines
have not been
filling their quotas
for months now.
l hope you will all
bear in mind
the Trade Committee's findings.
As much as we don't want...
Would someone alert Security?
Bring back Senator Tal'aura.
Duty.
A starship captain's life
is filled with solemn duty.
l have commanded men in battle.
l have negotiated peace treaties
between implacable enemies.
l have represented
the Federation
in First Contact
with 27 alien species.
But none of this compares
with my solemn duty today...
as best man.
Now, l know
on an occasion such as this,
it is expected
that l be gracious
and fulsome in my praise
on the wonders
of this blessed union.
But have the two
of you considered
what you are doing to me?!
Of course, you're happy,
but what about my needs?
This is all
a damned inconvenience.
l mean, while you are happily
settling in on the Titan,
l will be training
my new First Officer.
You all know him.
He's a tyrannical martinet
who will never, ever allow me
to go on away missions.
That is the regulation, sir.
Starfleet Code Section 12,
Paragraph Four...
Mr. Data?
Sir?
Shut up.
Yes, sir.
15 years l've been waiting
to say that.
No, seriously.
Will, Deanna,
there's still time
to reconsider.
Yes?
-No.
No?
Oh, very well, then.
Will Riker, you have been
my trusted right arm
for 15 years.
You have kept my course true
and steady.
Deanna Troi,
you've been my guide
and my conscience.
You have helped me recognize
the better parts of myself.
You are my family.
And in best maritime tradition,
l wish you both clear horizons.
My good friends...
make it so.
The bride and groom!
To the bride and groom.
You ever think
about getting married again?
No.
23 was my limit.
Worf?
Are you all right?
Romulan ale should be illegal.
lt is.
That was a lovely toast.
lt was from the heart.
And you needn't worry.
l'm going to brief
your new Counselor
on everything she needs to know.
Oh, like hell you are.
You already know
too much about me.
But l take it that there will be
no speeches during the ceremony
on Betazed.
No, no speeches and no clothes.
Ladies and gentlemen,
and invited
Tran gendered species...
in my study of Terran
and Betazoid conjugal rites,
l have discovered
it is traditional
to present the happy couple
with a gift.
Given Commander Riker's
affection
for archaic musical forms,
l have elected to present
the following as my gift
in honor of their conjugation.
Conjugation!
Never saw the sun
Shining so bright
Never saw things
Going so right
Noticing the days
Hurrying by
When you're in love
My, how they fly
Oh, blue skies
Smiling at me
lrving Berlin...
Nothing but blue skies
Do l see...
lt's tradition, Worf.
You, of all people,
should appreciate that.
l will not do it!
Won't do what, Mr. Worf?
Captain, l do not think
it is appropriate
for a Starfleet officer
to appear... naked.
Oh, come now.
A big, handsome,
strapping fellow like you?
What can you be afraid of?
Captain, l am picking up
an unusual
electromagnetic signature
from the Kolarun system.
What sort of signature?
Positronic.
lt's very faint,
but l've isolated it
to the third planet
in the Kolarun system.
What do we know about it?
Uncharted.
We'll have to get closer
for a more detailed scan.
Theories?
Since positronic signatures
have only been known to emanate
from androids such as myself,
it is logical to theorize
there is an android
on Kolarus lll.
Just what l was afraid of.
Captain? Diverting
to the Kolarus system
takes us awfully close
to the Romulan Neutral Zone.
lt's still well on our side.
l think, uh...
l think it's worth
taking a look.
Don't worry, Number One.
We'll still have you to Betazed
with plenty of time to spare.
Thank you, sir.
Where we will all honor
the Betazoid tradition.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
l'll be in the gym.
Mr. Branson, lay in a course
for the Kolarun system.
Warp five.
What do you think, Data?
A long-lost relative?
l'm reading six distinct
positronic signatures spread out
over a few kilometers
on the planet's surface.
What do we know
about the population
on Kolarus lll?
lsolated pockets of humanoids.
lt appears to be
a prewarp civilization
at an early stage
of industrial development.
Captain, l wouldn't recommend
using the transporter.
That ion storm doesn't
look very neighborly.
lt could head in our direction
without much warning.
Understood.
Data, Mr. Worf.
You're with me.
Captain, l don't have
to remind you...
l appreciate
your concern, Number One.
But, uh, l've been
itching to try the Argo.
l'll bet.
Captain's prerogative.
There's no foreseeable danger.
And your wife would
never forgive me
if anything were
to happen to you.
You have the Bridge...
Mr. Troi.
l will always be puzzled
by the human predilection
for piloting vehicles
at unsafe velocities.
Over that rise, sir.
Half a kilometer.
The radiant
electromagnetic field
is interfering
with my tricorder
but we are within a few meters
of the signal.
Fan out.
Let's search around.
lt appears to be a robotic arm.
Very astute.
Mr. Worf, bring it
to the vehicle.
This doesn't feel right.
The final signature
is approximately
100 meters to the north, sir.
lt's you.
The resemblance is striking.
-Fascinating.
To the vehicle.
l think it's time
to try some unsafe velocities.
Why do you have a shiny head?
This is not the appropriate time
for a conversation.
Why?
Because the Captain
has to concentrate
on piloting the vehicle.
Why?
-Because...
-Data!
Sorry, sir.
Have l said something wrong?
Data.
Valve transfer initiated.
You know, all things
considered, Data
l think you have nicer eyes.
Our eyes are identical, Doctor.
So what have we got, Geordi?
Well, l'd say he has
the same internal mechanics
as Data
but not as much
positronic development.
The neural pathways
aren't nearly as sophisticated.
l'd say he's a prototype.
Something Dr. Soong
created prior to Data.
Do you have a name, sir?
l am... B-4.
B-4. Dr. Soong's penchant
for whimsical names
seems to have no end.
Can you tell us
how you came to be
on the planet
where we found you?
l do not know.
Do you remember anything
of your life
before you were on the planet?
No.
Why does the tall man
have a furry face?
Number One, keep me informed
and, uh, Geordi, reassemble him.
Aye, sir.
B-4, do you know who l am?
You are me.
No.
My name is Data.
l am your brother.
Tea, Earl Grey, hot.
Captain, you have
an alpha priority communication
from Starfleet Command.
Acknowledged.
Admiral Janeway,
how good to see you again.
Jean-Luc, how'd you like
a trip to Romulus?
With or without
the rest of the fleet?
A diplomatic mission.
We've been invited,
believe it or not.
Seems there's been
some kind of internal
political shakeup.
The new Praetor,
someone called Shinzon
has requested
a Federation envoy.
New Praetor?
There's more.
He's Reman.
Believe me, we don't
understand it either.
You're the closest ship,
so l want you to go
and hear what he has to say.
Get the lay of the land.
lf the Empire becomes unstable,
it could mean trouble
for the entire Quadrant.
Understood.
We're sending you
all the intelligence
we have, but it's not much.
l don't need to tell you
to watch your back, Jean-Luc.
Hardly.
The Son'a, the Borg,
the Romulans--
you seem to get
all the easy assignments.
Just lucky, Admiral.
Let's hope that luck holds.
Janeway out.
Helmsman, lay in a new course.
Take us to Romulus,
warp eight.
Aye, aye, sir.
Course plotted and laid in.
Romulus?
l'm afraid the Opal Sea
will have to wait, Number One.
Engage.
As you can see, one side
of Remus always faces the sun.
Due to the extreme temperatures
on that half of their world,
the Remans live on the dark side
of the planet.
Almost nothing is known
of the Reman homeworld
although lntelligence scans
have proven the existence
of dilithium mining
and heavy weapons construction.
The Remans themselves are
considered an undesirable caste
in the hierarchy of the Empire.
But they also have
a reputation for being
formidable warriors.
ln the Dominion War,
Reman troops were used
as assault forces
in the most violent
encounters.
Cannon fodder.
Yeah, but how did a Reman
get to be Praetor?
l don't get it.
We have to assume he had
Romulan collaborators.
Coup d'etat?
Praetor's power has always been
the Romulan fleet.
They must have been
behind Shinzon
for him to have overthrown
the Senate.
What have we learned
about Shinzon?
Starfleet lntelligence
was only able
to provide a partial account
of his military record.
We can infer
he is relatively young
and a capable commander.
He fought 12 major engagements
in the war, all successful.
Beyond that, we know nothing.
Well, it seems as though we are
truly sailing into the unknown.
Keep at it.
Anything you can give me
will be appreciated.
Dismissed.
l still can't believe
the Captain went along
with the memory download.
Captain Picard agrees that
the B-4 was probably designed
with the same self-actualization
parameters as myself.
lf my memory engrams
are successfully integrated
into his positronic matrix,
he should have all my abilities.
Yeah, but he would also have
all of your memories as well.
You feel comfortable with that?
l feel nothing, Geordi.
lt is my belief
that with my memory engrams,
he will be able to function
as a more complete individual.
An individual more like you,
you mean.
Yes.
Maybe he's not supposed
to be like you, Data.
Maybe he's supposed
to be exactly the way he is.
That might be so,
but l believe he should have
the opportunity
to explore his potential.
Hmm.
Okay, we're done.
B-4, do you know where you are?
l am in a room with lights.
Can you remember our father?
Our father?
Yes, Dr. Soong.
No.
Do you know the name
of the Captain of this vessel?
Captain...
No.
Data, he's assimilating
a lot of programming.
Remember, he's a prototype,
a lot less sophisticated
than you are.
We just don't know if his matrix
will be able to adapt.
We really need
to give him some time.
Geordi, what purpose
does this serve?
What?
This.
That's a redundant memory port.
Maybe the provisional
memory storage
is in case his neural
pathways overload.
Do you mind if l keep
him here for a while
run a few diagnostics?
No, l do not mind.
Data.
No.
You must remain
with Commander La Forge.
He is going
to try to help you.
Captain's Log, Stardate 56844.9.
The Enterprise
has arrived at Romulus
and is waiting
at the designated coordinates.
All our hails
have gone unanswered.
We've been waiting for 1 7 hours.
Counselor?
They're out there, sir.
Captain, l recommend
we raise shields.
Not yet, Mr. Worf.
Captain, with all due respect
to diplomatic protocol,
the Federation Council
isn't sitting out here;
we are.
Patience.
Diplomacy is
a very exacting occupation.
We will wait.
Captain...
Raising shields.
-No!
-Captain...
Tactical analysis, Mr. Worf.
52 disruptor banks,
27 photon torpedo bays
primary and secondary
shields.
She's a predator.
We are being hailed.
On screen.
Enterprise, we are
the Reman Warbird Scimitar.
Praetor Shinzon, l'm pleased...
l am not Shinzon.
l am his Viceroy.
We are sending
transport coordinates.
Not very chatty.
Away team to Transporter Room 4.
l hope you'll forgive
the darkness.
We are not comfortable
in the light.
Praetor Shinzon?
Captain Picard.
Jean-Luc Picard.
l'd always imagined you
a little taller.
lsn't that odd?
You may scan me without
subterfuge, Commander Data.
You are not as we imagined you.
No?
You are human.
Why have you asked
us to come here?
Praetor?
l've never met
a human woman before.
l'm only half human.
Deanna Troi...
of Betazed.
Empathic and telepathic
abilities, Ship's Counselor--
all this l knew, but l
never knew you were so...
beautiful.
You seem quite familiar
with our personnel.
Oh, l am, Commander Riker.
May l touch your hair?
We came to Romulus
on a matter we were assured
was of great importance.
lf you have anything
to say to us as representatives
of the Federation,
l suggest you do it now.
Yes.
l'm sorry, Captain.
There is so much
we need to talk about.
l would be interested to know
what we are talking about.
Unity, Captain.
Tearing down the walls
between us,
to recognize that we are one.
l'm talking of the thing
that makes us the same--
peace.
We want peace.
Right now, you're thinking,
''This all sounds
too good to be true.''
But you're also thinking
that the chance for peace
is too promising to ignore.
Am l right?
Yes.
Then perhaps it's time
to add some illumination
to our discussion.
Computer, raise the lighting
four levels.
When l was very young,
l was stricken
with an odd disease.
l developed
a hypersensitivity to sound.
Even the slightest whisper
caused me agony.
No one could do
anything about it.
Finally, l was taken to a doctor
who had some experience
of Terran illnesses
and he diagnosed me
with Shalaft's syndrome.
Do you know of it, Captain?
Yes.
Then you know
it's a very rare syndrome.
Genetic.
Apparently, all the male members
of a family have it.
Eventually, l was treated,
and now l can hear
as well as you can, Captain.
l can see as well as you can.
l can feel...
everything you feel.
ln fact, l feel exactly
what you feel...
don't l, Jean-Luc?
Come to dinner--
tomorrow on Romulus,
just the two of us.
Or should l say...
just the one of us?
l think you'll be wanting this.
Till tomorrow then, Captain.
We have much to discuss.
Computer, return lighting
to previous level.
There's no doubt, Captain--
right down to your aggressive
strain of Shalaft's syndrome.
He's a clone.
They probably used a hair
follicle or a skin cell.
Why?
l intend to find out,
Number One.
lnform Starfleet
of the situation.
l need to know
where the hell he came from.
Counselor.
We supported you, Shinzon,
when you assassinated
the Senate.
You told us
the timing was perfect
for an attack
on the Federation.
l don't understand
why now, you delay.
You don't have to understand.
And bringing
the Enterprise here--
What possible purpose
could that serve?
l have a purpose.
Then perhaps
you'll enlighten us.
Silence from you!
You really must learn patience,
Commander.
Spend 18 hours every day
under the lash
of a Romulan guard, and you'll
soon understand patience.
Now go.
Commander Donatra.
Please, remain.
There's a word
l want you to consider:
allegiance.
lt's something l demand
from those who serve me.
Do l serve you?
Yes.
And l think, faithfully.
Commander Suran,
on the other hand...
gives me pause.
Here's another word, Praetor:
trust.
Do you trust me?
How far does that trust extend?
How...
deep does it go?
What must a Commander do
to prove herself
faithful to you?
What must a woman do?
You... are not a woman.
You are a Romulan.
Serve me faithfully,
and you will be rewarded.
Keep those lovely eyes
on Commander Suran.
And at the first sign
of treachery...
Dispose of him.
Then you will have
proven yourself.
Now go.
And, Commander...
if you ever touch me again...
l'll kill you.
The Romulans had somehow
gained possession of your DNA
and l had been created.
And when l was ready,
they were going
to replace you with me...
put a Romulan agent
at the heart of Starfleet.
lt was a bold plan.
What happened?
As happens frequently
here on Romulus...
a new government came to power.
They decided
to abandon the plan.
They were afraid that l
might be discovered,
that it would lead to war.
Not quite the face you remember.
Not quite.
A lifetime of violence
will do that.
They broke my nose
my jaw...
but so much is the same.
The eyes...
Surely you recognize the eyes.
Yes.
Our eyes reflect our lives,
don't they?
And yours are so confident.
So l'm not as tall
as you expected.
Well, l had always hoped
l might hit two meters.
As had l.
How did you end up on Remus?
They sent me there to die.
How could a mere human
survive the dilithium mines?
Not that it mattered,
as l was no longer
part of their plans
against the Federation.
ln those terrible depths
lived only the damned.
Together with the Reman slaves,
l was condemned
to an existence of unceasing
labor and starvation
under the brutal heel
of the Romulan guards.
Only the very strongest
had any hope of survival.
l was only a child
when they took me.
Then l didn't see the sun
or the stars again
for nearly ten years.
The only thing
the Romulan guards
hated more than the Remans
was me.
But one man took pity on me.
The man that became my Viceroy.
He protected me
from the cruelty of the guards
and taught me how to survive.
And in that dark place where
there was nothing of myself
l found my Reman brothers.
They showed me the only true
kindness l have ever known.
You're doing this
to liberate the Remans?
That is the single thought
behind everything l have done--
from building the Scimitar
at a secret base
to assembling my army
finally coming to Romulus
in force.
l knew they would never
give us our freedom.
l would have to take it.
And how many Romulans died
for your freedom?
Too many.
But the point is, that finally
the Empire is realizing
that there is a better way.
And that way is peace.
You don't trust me.
l have no reason to.
You have every reason.
lf you had lived my life
and experienced
the suffering of my people
you would be standing
where l am.
And if you had lived my life,
you would understand
my responsibility
to the Federation.
l cannot allow
my personal feelings
to unduly influence
my decisions.
All l have are
my personal feelings.
l want to know
what it means to be human.
The Remans have given me
a future, but you can tell me
about my past.
l can tell you about my past.
Were we Picards always warriors?
l think of myself
as an explorer.
Well, were we always explorers?
l was the first Picard
to leave our solar system.
lt caused quite a stir
in the family.
But...
l'd spent my youth...
Looking up at the stars dreaming
about what was up there.
About...
New worlds.
l'm trying to believe you,
Shinzon.
lf there is one ideal
that the Federation
holds most dear
it is that all men...
all races can be united.
What better example
than a Starfleet captain
standing in the Romulan Senate.
Nothing would make me more proud
than to take your hand
in friendship...
in time... when that trust
has been earned.
Captain, we have had
an unauthorized access
into the main computer.
Source?
lt's going to take some time
to figure that out, Captain.
The data stream was rerouted
through substations
all over the ship.
What programs were accessed?
Well...
that's what l can't figure out.
lt's mostly just
basic stellar cartography.
Star charts, communications
protocols, some uplinks
from colony tracking stations.
lt's not even
restricted material.
Nevertheless,
we must learn the source.
Keep me informed.
Captain, there's something else.
l was reviewing the sensor logs.
Look at this.
When the Scimitar de-cloaked
there was a momentary spike
in the tertiary EM band.
There.
You're not going
to believe this.
lt's thalaron.
l thought thalaron radiation
was theoretical.
Which is why our initial
scans didn't pick it up,
but he's got it, Captain.
Thalaron research
was banned in the Federation
because of its biogenic
properties.
lt has the ability
to consume organic material
at the subatomic level.
l can't overestimate the danger
of thalaron radiation, Jean-Luc.
A microscopic amount
could kill every
living thing on this ship
in a matter of seconds.
l understand.
Keep on it.
l want to know what he has
and how we can neutralize
any threat.
l need options.
This was a mistake.
We're wasting time.
My time.
And l shall spend it
how l choose.
Do not forget our mission,
Shinzon.
We must act now.
We'll return to the Scimitar.
l was merely curious about him.
Come.
Beverly, come in.
Remember him?
He was a bit cocky as l recall.
He was a damned fool.
Selfish, ambitious
very much in need of seasoning.
He turned out all right.
l really wanted
to believe Shinzon.
But this thalaron radiation
just can't be explained away.
Whatever he's after,
it isn't peace.
ls he very much
the way you were?
Oh, yes.
Data to Captain Picard.
Go ahead, Data.
Captain, Geordi and l
have identified the source
of the unauthorized
computer access
and l believe we have found
a way to gain
a tactical advantage.
On my way.
Will...
as Ship's Counselor,
l recommend you get some sleep.
Some honeymoon.
Come to bed.
Imzadi.
No.
He can never know you as l can.
He can never touch you
as l can.
This isn't real.
Feel my lips.
l'm with you, Imzadi.
l'll always be with you now.
No!
-This isn't real.
-Deanna...
what's the matter?
-No.
-Deanna.
Deanna.
Deanna!
No!
The bond has been broken.
Find her again.
Praetor, we've received
the transponder signal.
lt's accelerating.
You have no more time for games.
Have the doctors prepare.
Transport.
Begin the download.
Tea.
Hot.
Aside from slightly
elevated levels of adrenaline
and serotonin,
you're perfectly normal.
Deanna...
can you describe it?
lt was a...
lt was a violation.
Shinzon's Viceroy seems to have
the ability to reach
into my thoughts.
l've become a liability.
l request to be
relieved of my duties.
Permission denied.
lf you can endure
more of these assaults,
l need you at my side,
now more than ever.
The Enterprise is far
from Federation space and...
Worf! Shields up!
Hello, Jean-Luc.
Why am l here?
Why have you done this?
l was lonely.
What are you going to do?
l need a sample of your blood.
What is it
your Borg friends say?
''Resistance is futile.''
Oh, yes-- the android.
The bait you couldn't refuse.
All of this
so you could capture me.
Don't be so vain.
After we found it,
we had to make
a few modifications.
An extra memory port,
a hidden transponder.
l've now gained access
to Starfleet's
communications protocol.
l now know the exact location
of your entire fleet.
You may go.
Where?
Out of my sight.
What is all this about?
lt's about destiny, Picard.
lt's about a Reman outcast.
You're not Reman.
And l'm not quite human.
So what am l?
My life is meaningless
as long as you're still alive.
What am l while you exist?
A shadow?
An echo?
lf your issues are with me,
then deal with me.
This has nothing to do
with my ship--
nothing to do
with the Federation.
Oh, but it does.
We will no longer bow
before anyone as slaves
not the Romulans
and not your mighty Federation.
We are a race bred for war
and conquest.
Are you ready to plunge
the entire Quadrant into war
to satisfy
your own personal demons?
lt amazes me
how little you know yourself.
l'm incapable of such an act!
You are me.
The same noble Picard blood
runs through our veins.
Had you lived my life,
you'd be doing exactly as l am.
So look in the mirror.
See yourself.
Consider that, Captain.
l can think of no greater
torment for you.
Shinzon.
l'm a mirror for you as well.
Not for long, Captain.
l'm afraid you won't survive
to witness the victory
of the echo over the voice.
His cloak is perfect.
No tachyon emissions,
no residual antiprotons.
Keep at it, Geordi.
Find a way in.
Praetor Shinzon
needs the prisoner.
About time, Mr. Data.
My mission was a success, sir.
l have located the source
of the radiation.
This entire ship is essentially
a thalaron generator.
lts power relays lead
to an activation matrix
on the Bridge.
lt's a weapon.
lt would appear so.
What about the download?
Shinzon believes he has
our communication protocols
but they will give him
inaccurate locations
for all Starfleet vessels.
Good work.
Sir.
Geordi supplied me
with a prototype
of the emergency transport unit.
l recommend you use this, sir,
to return to the Enterprise.
lt will only work for one of us.
Yes, sir.
We'll find a way off together.
lt is time for the procedure.
Move, puny human animal.
A bit less florid, Data.
Kill him.
This way, sir.
There is a shuttlebay 94 meters
from our current position.
There it is, sir.
Go!
Data!
lt appears to have
an encrypted security system.
Alacrity will be
appreciated, Commander!
Reman is a most complex
language, with pictographs
representing
certain verb roots...
While l find that fascinating,
Data, we really need
that door open!
According to the ship's manifest
they are Scorpion-class
attack flyers.
Data, what do you imagine
this is?
Port thruster, sir.
Would you like me to drive, sir?
Data, can you open
the shuttlebay doors?
Negative, sir.
They have erected
a force field around
the external portals.
Well, then, only one way to go.
Do you think this is
a wise course of action, sir?
We're about to find out, Data.
Power up the disruptors.
Ready, Captain.
Fire.
Tractor beam, now!
Worf, lock on transporters.
l have them, sir.
This has gone far enough.
l thought we
discussed patience, Commander.
Mine is wearing thin.
We supported you
because you promised action,
and yet, you delay.
The Enterprise is immaterial.
lt won't even make it
out of the Neutral Zone.
And in two days,
the Federation will be crippled
beyond repair.
Does that satisfy you?
For the moment.
And when l return, you and l
shall have a little talk
about showing proper respect.
What's happening to his face?
Commander, a moment.
Are you truly prepared to have
your hands drenched in blood?
He's not planning
to defeat Earth.
He's planning its annihilation.
And his sins will mark us
and our children
for generations.
The more l studied his DNA,
the more confusing it got.
Finally, l could come
to only one conclusion.
Shinzon was created
with temporal RNA sequencing.
He was designed so that, at a
certain point, his aging process
could be accelerated
to reach your age more quickly.
He was engineered to skip
30 years of his life.
But when the temporal sequencing
wasn't activated,
his cellular structure
started breaking down.
He's dying.
Dying?
Can anything be done for him?
Nothing except
a complete transfusion
from the only donor
with compatible DNA-- you.
How long does he have?
l can't say for sure
but the rate of decay
seems to be accelerating.
Then he'll come for me.
Brother, l... cannot move.
No. l have only activated
your cognitive
and communication subroutines.
Why?
Because you are dangerous.
You have been programmed
to gather information
that can be used
against this ship.
l... do not understand.
l know.
Do you know anything
about Shinzon's plans
against the Federation?
No.
Do you have any knowledge
of the tactical
abilities of his ship?
No.
Can l move now?
What are you doing?
l must deactivate you.
For how long?
lndefinitely.
How long is tha...?
A long time, brother.
lt's called
a Cascading Biogenic Pulse.
The unique properties
of thalaron radiation
allow the energy beam
to expand almost without limit.
Depending on its radiant
intensity,
it could encompass a ship...
or a planet.
He would only have built
a weapon of such scope
for one reason.
He's going after Earth.
How can you be certain?
l know how he thinks.
Destroy humanity,
you cripple the Federation.
The Romulans invade.
No way of penetrating his cloak?
No.
So he could pass
within ten meters
of every ship in Starfleet
and they'd never know.
We do have one advantage,
though.
He needs your blood to live.
He might come after you first.
l'm counting on it.
We've been ordered
to sector 1045.
Our fleet has been diverted
to meet us there.
Strength in numbers.
Yes. At least,
that's what we hope.
He must not be allowed
to use that weapon.
All other concerns
are secondary.
You understand me?
Yes, sir.
All hands... battle stations.
lnitiate the force field.
Captain's Personal Log,
supplemental.
We're heading toward Federation
space at maximum warp.
The crew has responded
with the dedication
l've come to expect of them.
And like a thousand
other commanders
on a thousand
other battlefields,
l wait for the dawn.
How long?
A matter of hours.
We must begin the procedure now.
How long until we reach
the Rift?
Seven minutes.
Data, what's
our current position?
How soon until we reach
the fleet?
At our current velocity,
we will arrive at sector 1045
in approximately 40 minutes,
sir.
''For now we see
but through a glass darkly.''
Sir?
He said he is a mirror.
Of you, sir?
Yes.
l do not agree.
Although you share
the same genetic structure,
the events of your life
have created
a unique individual.
lf l had lived his life,
is it possible that l would've
rejected my humanity?
The B-4 is physically identical
to me, although
his neural pathways
are not as advanced.
But even if they were,
he would not be me.
How can you be sure?
l aspire, sir,
to be better than l am.
B-4 does not...
nor does Shinzon.
We are passing through
the Bassen Rift, sir.
The projection will return
when we have cleared it.
lt's interfering with our uplink
from Starfleet cartography?
The Rift affects
all long-range communica...
Commander Riker,
evasive maneuvers.
Target weapon systems
and shields.
l don't want the Enterprise
destroyed.
Can you learn to see
in the dark, Captain?
Report.
He's firing through the cloak.
We can't get a lock.
He disabled our warp drive
with his first shot.
We only have impulse, Captain.
Mr. Worf, prepare
a full phaser spread.
Zero elevation.
All banks on my mark.
Scan for shield impact.
Stand by, photon torpedoes.
Aye, sir.
Fire.
You're too slow, old man.
Attack pattern Shinzon Theta.
We are losing dorsal shields!
Full axis rotation to port.
Fire all ventral phasers.
Minimal damage to the Scimitar.
Defensive pattern Kirk Epsilon.
Get the shields on line,
Geordi.
l'm already on it.
Counselor Troi,
report to the Bridge.
Captain...
we are being hailed.
On screen.
Captain Picard...
will you join me
in your ready room?
You can't trace my holographic
emitters, Captain,
so don't bother.
And you can't
contact Starfleet.
lt's just the two of us now,
Jean-Luc.
As it should be.
Why are you here?
To accept your surrender.
l can clearly destroy you
at any time.
Lower your shields
and allow me to transport you
to my ship.
And the Enterprise?
l have little interest
in your quaint vessel, Captain.
Look at me, Shinzon.
Your heart, your hands...
your eyes
are the same as mine.
The blood pumping within you--
the raw material is the same.
We have the same potential.
That's the past, Captain.
lt can be the future.
Buried deep within you,
beneath all the years
of pain and anger,
there is something that
has never been nurtured.
The potential
to make yourself a better man.
And that is what it is
to be human.
To make yourself
more than you are.
Oh, yes.
l know you.
There was a time
you looked at the stars
and dreamed of what might be.
Childish dreams, Captain,
lost in the dilithium
mines of Remus.
l am what you see now.
l see more than that.
l see what you could be.
The man who is Shinzon of Remus
and Jean-Luc Picard
could never exterminate the
population of an entire planet.
He's better than that.
He is what his life
has made him.
Then, what will you do
with that life?
Waste it in a blaze of hatred?
There is a better way.
lt's too late.
Never, never.
You still have a choice.
Make the right one now.
l can't fight what l am.
Yes, you can.
l'll show you my true nature.
Our nature.
And as Earth dies,
remember, l will always
forever be Shinzon
of Remus.
And my voice shall echo
through time
long after yours has faded
to a dim memory.
Two ships de-cloaking, sir.
Romulan.
Captain.
Just when l thought
this couldn't get any worse.
We are being hailed.
On screen.
Captain Picard,
Commander Donatra
of the Warbird Valdore.
Might we be of assistance?
Assistance?
The Empire considers this
a matter of internal security.
We regret
you've become involved.
Commander, when this is over,
l owe you a drink.
Romulan ale, Captain.
Let's get to work.
You heard the lady.
Let's go to work.
Mr. Worf, coordinate our attack
with the Valdore
Tactical Officer.
Triangulate all fire
on any shield impact.
Aye, sir.
Aft shields down to 40 percent.
Keep our bow on the Scimitar.
Auxiliary power
to forward shields.
Aye, sir.
Target the flanking warbird.
All forward disruptor banks
on my mark.
Forward shields
down to 10 percent.
Bring us about.
Drop cloak
on the aft port quadrant.
Prepare for full emergency stop.
What?
You heard me.
He's losing his cloak.
Stand by all forward
disruptor banks.
She's almost on us.
Not yet.
Praetor!
Full stop!
Fire!
Restore the aft cloak
and bring us about.
l'm afraid that drink
will have to wait, Captain.
Do you have life support?
For the moment.
But we're dead in the water.
Understood.
We are losing
structural integrity on decks 12
through 1 7, sections
four through ten.
Emergency force fields
are holding.
Evacuate those decks
and reroute field power
to forward shields.
Captain...
l think l may have a way
to find them.
Prepare for a lateral run.
All starboard disruptors.
What is it?
She's here.
He's resisting me.
No!
Remember me.
Now!
Fire at will.
Prepare a boarding party.
Bring me Picard.
You.
Get the cloak back!
Target all shield coordinates,
beta three.
All disruptors, fire.
Captain, we've lost
central shielding on deck 29.
Divert all power and compensate.
lntruder alert.
Number One.
Let's go.
Security detail to deck 29.
The Romulans fought with honor.
Yes, they did, Mr. Worf.
Worf, cover me.
Medical team to the Bridge.
...functioning
on reserve power only.
Did you check the system status?
Report.
We have exhausted our complement
of photon torpedoes.
Phaser banks
are down to four percent, sir.
What if we targeted
all our phasers
in a concentrated pattern?
The Scimitar's shields
are still at 70 percent.
lt would make
no difference, Captain.
We have damage on all decks.
What's he doing?
He wants to look me in the eye.
We've got him.
He thinks he knows exactly
what l am going to do.
Geordi, divert all power
to the engines.
Take it from life support,
if you have to.
Give me everything you've got.
Ready, Captain.
We are being hailed, sir.
Deanna, stand by.
Open a channel.
l hope you're still alive,
Jean-Luc.
Oh, yes, l am.
Don't you think it's time
to surrender?
Why should the rest of your crew
have to die?
Shinzon, l don't think
l ever told you...
about my first
Academy evaluation.
ln particular, l was thought
to be extremely...
...overconfident.
Captain, as much as l enjoy
listening to you talk,
l really think...
On my mark, Deanna.
All hands, brace for impact.
Engage.
Hard to port!
Divert all power to the engines.
Full reverse.
No!
Reconfiguring now.
Computer, stand by auto-destruct
sequence Omega.
Recognize voice pattern
Jean-Luc Picard.
Authorization:
Alpha-Alpha-3-0-5.
Auto-destruct is off-line.
Disruptors are not functional,
sir.
Deploy the weapon.
Kill everything on that ship.
Then set a course for Earth.
We must complete our mission.
Matrix initiated.
Sequencing procedure
for thalaron radiation
transfer...
activated.
Some ideals are worth dying for,
aren't they, Jean-Luc?
Thalaron intermix procedure
initiated.
Deployment of targeting arms
commencing.
How long until he can fire?
The targeting sequence
should take
about seven minutes, Captain.
When the targeting arms
are fully deployed,
the matrix on the Bridge
will relay
the thalaron radiation
to the firing points
at their tips.
No one on the Enterprise
will survive.
How can he?
He'll kill you.
lt's not about me anymore.
Prepare
for a site-to-site transport.
Captain, l don't think
that the transpor...
That's an order, Commander.
Sir, allow me to go.
Data, this is something
l have to do.
-Sir...
-Data.
You have the Bridge, Commander.
Try and put some distance
between you and the Scimitar.
Now, Mr. La Forge.
Aye, sir.
That's it.
Transporters are down.
The system is fused.
Counselor Troi,
please assume command.
Geordi, come with me.
Thalaron intermix level...
30 percent.
Four minutes to firing sequence.
Thalaron intermix level,
50 percent.
Three minutes
to firing sequence.
Thalaron intermix level,
60 percent.
Two minutes to firing sequence.
Thalaron intermix level,
80 percent.
l'm glad we're together now.
Our destiny's complete.
One minute to firing sequence.
Thalaron intermix level
completed.
30 seconds to firing sequence.
Good-bye.
Ten, nine, eight, seven,
six, five, four, three...
Data?
Captain...
lt's Data.
Captain, we're being hailed.
On screen.
Open a channel.
This is Commander Donatra
of the Valdore.
We're dispatching shuttles with
medical personnel and supplies.
Thank you, Commander.
You've earned a friend
in the Romulan Empire today,
Captain.
l hope the first of many.
Valdore out.
Geordi, prepare the shuttlebay
for arrivals.
They, uh, they don't
know our procedures.
Just open the doors.
l'll take care of it, Captain.
You have the Bridge, Number One.
Thank you.
To absent friends.
To family.
First time l saw Data,
he was leaning against a tree
in the holodeck
trying to whistle.
Funniest thing l ever saw.
No matter what he did,
he couldn't get
the tune right.
What was that song?
Can't remember the song.
Come.
Will.
Permission to disembark, sir.
Granted.
So... where's the Titan
off to?
The Neutral Zone.
We're heading up
the new task force.
Apparently the Romulans
are interested in talking.
Well, l can't think of
a better man for the job.
lf l may, just a word of advice
about your first command?
Anything.
When your First Officer
insists that you can't
go on away missions...
lgnore him.
l intend to.
Serving with you
has been an honor.
The honor was mine, Captain.
l don't know if all this
has made any sense,
but l wanted you to know
what kind of man he was.
ln his quest to be more like us
he helped us to see
what it means to be human.
My...
my brother was not human?
No, he wasn't.
But his wonder,
his curiosity about every facet
of human nature
allowed all of us
to see the best parts
of ourselves.
He evolved.
He embraced change
because he always wanted to be
better than he was.
l...
l do not understand.
Well, l hope someday you will.
Captain, the warp engines
are ready to go on line.
l'm on my way.
Please inform
Commander La Forge.
We'll talk later.
Never saw the sun
Shining so bright...
Shining so bright
Never saw things...
Going so right.
Going so right...