Those schoolgirl days of telling tales and biting nails are gone, yeah
But in my mind I know that they live on and on
But how do you thank someone, who has taken you from crayons to perfume?
It isn't easy, but I'll try,
If you wanted the sky
I would write across the sky in letters
That would soar a thousand feet high
To sir, with love
The time has come
For closing books and long last looks must end,
And as I leave,
I know that I am leaving my best friend,
A friend who taught me right from wrong,
And weak from strong,
That's a lot to learn,
What, what can I give you in return?
If you wanted the moon I would try to make a start,
But I, would rather you let me give my heart,
To Sir, with Love