Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
My bleeding feet!
Hello, Mrs. Joseph.
l like your hair.
ls that strawberry blonde?
Youre only jealous.
What you got for
the old mans supper tonight?
Hell be lucky to get
faggots and pease pudd, he will.
Well, he cant do much on that,
can he?
All l want him for
is to keep me feet warm.
Excuse me, dearie.
Here, Gert.
l wouldnt mind having this little lot
in my stocking for Christmas.
You wouldnt know what to do with him.
Youve been a widow too long.
You speak for yourself.
lts like riding a bicycle.
You never forget how.
Here, lll tell you what lll do.
lll send my Alfie to you.
Hes not bad once he gets going.
Well, l hope hes well-sprung.
Morning.
Looking for someone?
Nice day, isnt it?
Sorry.
Hackmans in the staff room.
Where he bleeding well belongs.
Good morning.
My name is Thackeray.
lm a new teacher.
We were expecting you.
So youre the new lamb
for the slaughter.
Or should l say...
...black sheep?
No, just a teacher, Mr. Hackman.
lm not Hackman.
Perish the thought.
Hes departed,
God rest his soul.
Hes probably pouring out his woes
to the divisional officer by now.
Weston.
lm Mrs. Evans, Grace.
Deputy head.
Mrs. Evans.
Have you seen any
of the children yet?
l looked in on Mr. Hackmans class
for a moment.
l take them for domestic science.
Like a cup of tea?
No, thank you, not just now.
You been teaching long?
This is my first appointment.
We call them jobs.
American, are you?
British...
...from British Guiana.
But l spent some years
in the States.
- Where?
- Ln California.
Weather as good as they say?
lts better.
What was your subject?
What did you major in?
Engineering.
l must be off.
Make yourself at home.
Wander around, if you like,
or stay here.
lll introduce you
to the others at lunch.
Thank you.
This is Gillian, Mr. Thackeray.
Gillian Blanchard.
Shes new here too.
Came the day before yesterday.
- Tea, Gillian?
- Thank you.
This is Mr. Mark Thackeray,
the new replacement.
Jose Dawes,
Euphemia Phillips.
They teach the little ones.
Theo Weston, you know.
Yes, lve had the pleasure.
He mistook me for Hackman.
- L heard hes fled.
- Cant say l blame him.
That shot of humanitys enough
to destroy anyone.
He got what he deserved.
lm Clinty Clintridge.
Clintys a marvelous artist.
Got one at the Royal Academy
a couple of years ago.
Teaching provides
the bread and butter.
Well, thats all the staff
except for Mr. Bell...
...our P.T. instructor.
l do hope youre
going to stay with us.
l shouldnt if l were you, old man.
Row home while you can.
Dont discourage him, Weston.
Well, l must go.
l have to fix a bath
for a girl in Clintys class.
Why?
Kids are complaining again.
Wont sit near her.
Whats the matter?
Personal hygiene problems.
Fourteen and helpless.
You men are lucky.
The things we women have to do
for these kids.
Gillian, dear...
...encourage him to stay.
Why is it everyone thinks
l need encouraging?
They said the same to me.
Theres something frightening but
also challenging about this school.
Theres no form of corporal
punishment or any punishment.
None?
l have no real teaching experience.
lm a little lost.
l dont have any experience either.
Of course, itll be
much easier for you.
lm a little afraid of them.
Midday dance session.
During lunch,
the older kids use the hall.
l sometimes join them.
Even the old man
shakes a leg on occasions.
Dancing is merely their way
of keeping fit...
...for the more exciting pastime
of teacher baiting.
Couldnt you be
a bit less discouraging?
lts the last thing l want to do.
The musics louder than usual.
Theyre probably celebrating
their victory over Hackman.
l better go and see Mr. Florian.
lll show you the way.
Theyre good, arent they?
l suppose so.
The heads study is this way.
Do you two...
Do you two shake?
Well, lll see you later,
Mr. Thackeray.
Well?
Thank you.
But l have to go
and see the principal.
You have excellent qualifications,
astonishing ones, in fact...
...as a communications engineer.
Field experience in South America.
Why do you want to be a teacher?
Reasons.
Youve already tried to get
an engineering post?
l tried for 18 months, sir.
We have no blueprint in North Quay.
Most of our children are
rejects from other schools.
We have to help and teach them
as best we can...
...and as much as we can.
The local authorities are not
totally on our side.
And from the moment
you accept this position...
...youll be entirely on your own.
Of course, l and the staff will do
everything we can to help you.
But success or failure
will depend entirely upon you.
Whats it to be?
l want the job, sir.
Good.
Then its settled.
Tomorrow, youll take over
Hackmans class.
Sapiano.
Wong.
Osgood.
Tuffen.
Pegg.
Pegg?
Joseph.
Dare.
Potter.
Denham.
Buckley.
Purcell.
Fernman.
Jackson.
Strong.
Seales.
- Palmer.
- Yes, guvnor.
Campbell.
Present.
l dont know how much you know,
so well start from scratch.
First, as l call your name...
...will you read anything you like
from one of your school books?
Fernman.
Right.
创Only those who...
...arrived on...
...horseback...
...or in a public coach. 创
- Thank you.
Denham.
创lf 14 hens...
...lay an egg a day for 30 days...
...how much are the eggs a dozen,
and how many have you to sell? 创
Moira Joseph.
创Pete Gilroys weight
and the ever-tightening noose...
...about her neck...
...began slightly to impede
the wild mares speed.
But Pete was only too fully aware
of what his fate would be...
...for he could not hope
to escape death...
...from being battered and crushed. 创
Put that away, please.
Thank you.
Would anyone else like to read?
- Your name, please.
- Pamela Dare.
创And he had learned to love.
l know not why...
...for this in such as him
seemed strange of mood.
But thus it was.
And though
in solitudes small part...
...the nipped affections
have to grow.
ln him this glowed...
...when all beside
had ceased to glow. 创
Thank you, Miss Dare.
Next, weights and measures.
Whats avoirdupois?
- Avoir de what?
- Avoirdupois.
Weights.
Heavyweight, light-heavy,
cruiserweight...
...middle, light, bantam,
fly, featherweight.
Thank you very much.
lts encouraging that
you have a sense of humor.
lt seems you...
...know little and are easily amused.
l can look forward to a happy time.
Copy down the following tables.
Who does he think he is, there?
Cheeky devil.
Hello, ducks.
Thought you might need this.
Howd it go?
Lets just say, battle was joined.
l dont know what wed do
without a cuppa.
Whats your name?
l know that.
l mean, your other name.
Mark.
Couple of things, Mark.
We all know the old mans views.
And basically, we agree with them.
But hes safe in an office.
These kids come from homes where
an order is accompanied by a blow.
One rude word to their parents,
the roof will hit them.
Theres nothing like that
going on here, right?
So theyve got us
at a great disadvantage.
Hackman tried to be popular.
He hung himself.
Weston couldnt care less
about them, and thats no good.
l cant guide you...
...but dont take any nonsense
from these little tykes.
Theyre good kids, Mark,
most of them.
But if you dont solve them,
theyll break you, and damn quickly.
Thats been tried...
...by experts.
Theyre very expert.
Please, can l leave the room, guv?
Yes, and its Thackeray.
Yes, guv.
Most of you girls help your mothers
with the shopping.
So sorry, Mr. 创Fackeray. 创
Proper drafty in these parts,
isnt it?
About multiplying...
...there are
a few valuable tricks to know.
Say that youre offered roast beef
at seven shillings per pound.
Potter.
Must you do that?
l cant help it, Sir.
lts me desk.
Poor old Potts!
Sit down.
lll speak with the caretaker
about it after school.
lsnt he nice?
l hope l didnt miss nothing.
Where was we?
About shopping or something...
Thats enough, Denham.
l was only asking, Mr. Fackeray.
l dont want to miss nothing.
Bert, he was just about to show us
a new and valuable trick.
When youre shopping, you see...
l said, thats enough.
Sit down.
Do exercise four, five and six.
Very quietly.
Dont worry.
The worst is still to come.
Youre still getting
the silent treatment.
Whats the next phase?
Well, unless you can work up
a little black magic...
...these little bastards have
a multitude of tricks.
Why did you take up teaching?
lts good to have some kind of a job.
But lm teaching them nothing.
lm not even getting to first base.
Dont worry.
Your lot leaves this term.
The next will be better.
Theyll be just as bad.
Probably worse.
Whats your answer?
What they need...
...is a bloody good hiding.
l feel rather sorry for them,
you know?
Most of them can hardly read.
Youre so naive,
my dear old colleague.
Theyll be earning twice as much
as us before you can shake a stick.
Theyll happily be part
of the great London unwashed:
llliterate...
...smelly and quite content.
An educations a disadvantage
in this day and age.
That is ridiculous!
But still true.
So you had better start
brushing up...
...on your voodoo if you wish
to remain sane.
Good morning.
All right, take your seats.
- All right, Sir?
- L hope you didnt hurt yourself.
You all right?
Cheap stuff theyre selling nowadays.
Want me to help, Sir?
Sit down.
Take your proper places.
We can move around here,
you know, Sir.
Take your proper places.
Beg pardon.
Something the matter?
Seales, is something wrong?
lts me mum.
Shes awful sick.
lm sorry.
Anything l can do?
Nothing.
- Shes English.
- L see.
Youre like my old man,
except youre bigger and younger.
Rotten bastard!
You shouldnt speak like that.
You know nothing.
l hate him!
Why not?
Never forgive him for
what he did to me mum. Never!
He married her, didnt he?
Didnt he?
Today, lets take a look
at South America.
lm sorry, Mr. Fackeray.
The bloody things just slipped.
The name is Thackeray,
and they are not 创bloody things. 创
They were a pile of books.
Thats a good netting score.
Pam, love, thats not a bloody pile,
but its a pile of books.
All right, settle down.
l was only trying to help,
Mr. Thackeray, Sir.
Thats right, Mr. Fackeray.
Curley was only trying to put
that little scrubber in her place.
l know what Curley was trying to do.
Now just settle down.
We are going to study
South America.
Now turn to page 37
in your geography book.
创They were alone...
...but not alone as they who
shut in chambers think it loneliness.
The voiceless sand and the drooping
caves that lay around them...
...made them to each other press...
...as if there were no life
beneath the sky... 创
Sorry, love.
lts the bleeding desk.
Do you speak such words
to your father?
Youre not my bleeding father!
All l want to know is,
who does he think he is?
Mate, shut up!
Morning.
Hello, Thackeray.
How goes it?
Fine, thank you, Sir.
All you boys, out.
The girls stay where they are.
Whats the matter?
- Out at once!
- All right.
l am sick of your foul language...
...your crude behavior
and your sluttish manner.
A decent woman keeps
certain things private.
Only a filthy slut
would have done this!
Those who encouraged her
are just as bad!
l dont care whos responsible.
Youre all to blame!
lm leaving for five minutes,
by which time...
...that disgusting object
had better be removed.
And the windows opened
to clear the stench!
lf you must play these filthy games,
do them in your homes...
...and not in my classroom.
Whats the matter?
Man, oh, man!
l lost my temper. The one thing
l swore l would never do.
God, did l lose my temper!
What happened?
After all the bull
lve taken in my life...
...in a few short weeks,
those kids have got me so steamed up.
So easy. So quickly.
l never would have thought it.
- Perhaps youre trying too hard.
- Those kids are devils incarnate.
l tried everything. Everything!
But nothing l tried...
Kids.
Thats it!
Those are out.
They are useless to you.
l realized you are not children.
You will be adults in a few weeks,
with all the responsibilities.
From now on, you will be treated
as such by me and by each other...
...as adults.
Responsible adults.
Next, well be reasonable
with each other.
We are just going to talk,
you and l.
You are going to listen
without interruption.
And when l am finished,
one of you may have your say.
Without interruptions.
Next...
What a morning!
Everythings gone wrong.
First, the alarm didnt go off.
Then l had to wait hours for a bus.
l must have stood there
three bleeding hours...
Example:
There are two ways to enter a room.
One is like an adult,
a lady with dignity.
The other is like a brat.
Miss Dare has shown us the second way.
Perhaps youd demonstrate the first.
lm sorry lm late.
Next...
...we are all going to observe
certain courtesies in this classroom.
You will call me
Sir or Mr. Thackeray.
The young ladies will be
addressed as Miss...
...the boys by their surnames.
Why should we call them Miss?
We know them.
l beg your pardon?
l said, why should we
call them Miss?
We know them.
ls there a young lady you feel...
...does not deserve to be
addressed as Miss?
- No, Sir.
- Good.
Next, general deportment.
First, the young ladies.
They must prove worthy of
the courtesies we will show them.
Soon, boyfriends and marriage
will concern you.
No man likes a slut for long.
Only the worst type will marry one.
And the competition for men
on the outside is rough.
Next, men.
lve seen garbage collectors
who are cleaner.
Toughness is a quality
of the mind...
...like bravery,
honesty and ambition.
lf you want to wear your hair long,
clean it...
...else youll soon get lice and smell.
Soon your principle interest
will be girls.
You will be more attractive
with clean clothes, clean shoes...
...hands, face, teeth, et cetera.
Any questions?
Miss Pegg.
What about Mr. Weston, Sir?
Hes never tidy, his shoes is
never brushed, and his hairs a mess.
lts filthy.
Mr. Weston is not your teacher.
We wont discuss him.
lm the one to criticize
if l fail to maintain the standards.
Thats not fair.
Sir...
...or Mr. Thackeray.
Didnt you understand?
Thats not fair...
...Sir.
l agree.
But thats an example of things
youll have to put up with as an adult.
Youll just have to take it.
Next, we are going to talk
about various...
Good morning.
- L wanted to see how you were doing.
- Fine, sir.
Good.
Thank you.
What is it?
Palmer.
What are we going
to talk about, Sir?
About life...
...survival...
...love...
...death, sex, marriage...
...rebellion, anything you want.
l never did see one like him, Pam.
Even when he blew his stack,
no swearing or nothing.
Blimey!
Aint natural, thats what.
Does he really mean what he says?
l dont know.
ltd be a change, though, to see
those creeps acting like gents.
Here, which one do you fancy?
l like Babs.
Yeah? Watch this.
- Come on, Pam, love.
- Get lost, Denham!
l dont like
your smelly tricks, do l?
And its Miss Dare to you.
Get stuffed.
Come on then, love.
You heard what Sir said,
Mr. Smarty Denham.
lf you want to dance with me,
you bleeding well ask proper.
May l have the pleasure
of this dance, Miss Pegg?
Blimey!
Good old Potts.
Get you, Potter.
Shut up!
Who does he think he is,
bleeding Fred Astaire?
Come on, Miss Pegg.
Look at me.
l am a lady, l am.
Rotten tarts, all of them.
Bleeding chimney sweep
was right about that.
He wont catch me
spending me nicker on them.
He said we could talk about anything.
You are so right, Tich, me mate.
He did say we could ask him anything.
Questions and answers.
Last night on the telly,
there was this travelogue picture.
You know, a lot of black women
dancing around with no tops.
Dont they ever dress proper?
Whats proper varies
throughout the world...
...depending on
customs and climate.
For their climate and customs,
they were dressed properly.
Are you from South Africa, Sir?
Of course not.
South Africans is white, isnt they?
A South African is a native
of South Africa, regardless of color.
l was born in British Guiana.
What did you mean the other day
about rebellion, Sir?
Change.
Take your hairstyles.
Thats a form of rebellion, isnt it?
What, Sir?
Dont you do it
to be different from adults?
Theyve messed up the world,
havent they?
- You can say that again.
- So you rebel.
Even the way you dress is
a form of rebellion, isnt it?
lts just the new fashion, Sir.
Of course, the adults look
proper stupid in our gear.
Do you think its wrong
to be different, to rebel?
lt is your duty to change
the world, if you can.
Not by violence.
Peacefully, individually,
not as a mob.
Take the Beatles.
They started a huge social revolution.
The fashions they set in dress...
...and hairstyles are worldwide now.
Every new fashion is
a form of rebellion.
Theres a fine exhibition
of costumes through the ages...
...on at the Victoria
and Albert Museum.
l think you should see it.
Also, you should see
the Museum of Natural History.
What, us lot to go to a museum?
- Sure.
- Youre joking.
Youll discover that
your hairstyles are 200 years old...
...and that your costumes
or your dress...
...is right out of 1920.
Shut up!
Look, Sir, when can we go?
Theres no time after school,
and lve got to look after the kids.
l have to do the housework
and get the supper for the lodgers.
Me mums expecting a baby any day,
and l got to baby-sit.
Why dont you take us?
We could go in the morning.
Who would like that?
What a drag!
Dont you want a day off?
Put your hand up.
- Put both hands up.
- Fat chance!
lt wouldnt work.
lts not the sort of risk
wed dare to take at North Quay.
l would like to try, sir.
The best of pupils are inclined
to show off in public.
Your class?
Youd never be able
to supervise them.
When l took this job,
you said you wouldnt interfere...
...as long as l stayed
within your framework.
lf you can get another staff member
to go with you...
...lll approach the council.
l see little hope of approval.
Thank you, sir.
Miss Blanchard, l think l can
arrange an outing with my class...
...if l can get
another teacher to go along.
ld love to.
And its Gillian.
When is the outing?
When we arrange
travel warrants and permission.
Just let me know when.
Thanks, Gillian. Bye.
Good morning.
What would you like
to talk about today?
Ladies first.
Miss Joseph.
Marriage, Sir.
You know, boyfriends and things.
How do you know hes the right one?
What to look for.
How to avoid divorce.
Dont get married.
Wheres Miss Purcell?
Shes to look after the home today.
Her mum had the baby last night.
What hospital?
No hospital, Sir.
The doctor came to her.
She all right?
She just had a kid.
Now, marriage.
First, let us lay some ground rules.
lve never been married,
so what l say is as an outsider.
Now, what should a girl
look for in a man?
l think first we ought
to determine what is marriage.
Miss Joseph.
Holy wedlock.
Potter, be serious.
Youll get your turn.
Miss Pegg.
lts life, isnt it, Sir?
Everyone gets married.
l mean, sometime.
Why didnt you marry?
No one would have him.
l was very poor.
And there was something in me
that wanted an education.
So l put all of
my energies into that.
Well, l got started later.
Just never met the right girl.
What should a girl look for
in a man?
- Miss Clark?
- What work did you do, Sir?
l waited tables.
l cooked in a hamburger joint.
l washed dishes for a time, cars.
For a year l was a janitor
in an apartment block.
- All sorts of jobs.
- You washed dishes?
l did.
But you talk posh.
- That wasnt easy.
- You didnt always talk like that?
When l was your age, l used a patois,
a kind of simple English.
l buy and bust your booby
if you dont get up off of this place.
l didnt understand a word.
Well, l dont always understand
what you say either.
But the point is, if you work hard,
you can do almost anything.
You can get any job you want.
You can even change your speech
if you want to.
After l got my degree...
...l went to work in South America
for an oil company.
The only women in that region...
...were jungle lndians who carried
blowpipes and poison darts.
You could have broke my hands.
We were discussing marriage.
To my mind, marriage is
no way of life for the weak...
...the selfish...
...or the insecure.
Whats the matter, Weston?
These damn fool Americans!
They bog up everything
theyre connected with.
What a shower!
lll never forgive the President for
not coming to Churchills funeral...
...nor sending the vice president.
Rotten bad manners.
- Lt was very naughty.
- L quite agree.
A typically stupid, appalling
and unnecessary mistake.
- What can you expect?
- Still beefing?
Give them a chance.
Theyve not been in the business...
...of leading the world
as long as Britain was.
You continue to astonish me,
old chum.
l should thought
if anyone took a point of...
Now what?
Miss Pegg wants to know
if the netballs fixed.
Miss who?
Barbara Pegg.
Miss Pegg, Sir.
Here you are, Fernman.
Thank you, Sir.
Whats going on in
this classroom of yours?
Suburban formality? Lts a bit
foreign in this neck of the woods.
Some sort of experiment
in culture for the masses?
lts an elementary
experiment in courtesy.
And do we ignorant critters
have to follow suit?
- Please yourself.
- Thank goodness for that!
Do you object to being
taught manners by one of the boys?
l dont expect to be taught
by those morons.
So long as we learn,
it doesnt matter who teaches us.
Good afternoon, everybody.
Now were talking.
Nothing like payday.
By the way, your museum visit
has been approved.
lf anything goes wrong,
the school suffers.
Nothing will go wrong, sir.
For a moment, l thought
l was in the wrong classroom.
Wheres Jackson?
We dont know.
Tich wouldnt miss this
unless he was sick or something.
Well give him a few minutes.
lts me, Jackson.
l have to take the bag-wash for mum.
Can you wait?
Sure.
How long will it take?
Half a mo.
Just up the frog.
God love you.
Hang on, Tich.
lll give you a hand.
All right.
Back on the sidewalk.
Whats a frog got to do with it?
lts a rhyming slang.
Old-fashioned cockney.
lts not used anymore.
Just for old people.
lts a drag, Sir.
Frog means road.
Frog and toad, road.
Trouble, strife, wife.
Weeping willow, pillow.
Use the first word.
Like the old currant bun,
thats the sun.
- Apples and pears, stairs.
- Happy kill, skill.
Ginger beer, queer.
All aboard.
l think he fancies her.
l know you do.
Pamela Dare has a crush on you.
Women say the damnedest things.
l think hes nice.
So do l.
Youve noticed.
l dont treat her different
from the others.
l hope we can go out again,
dont you?
l hope so.
l hope we can go with him,
because hes nice.
Dont make any mistake
about Pamela.
Shes a woman
in every sense of the word.
l mean...
...not that l blame her.
Bleeding rotten taste hes got.
Good night, Sir.
- See you tomorrow.
- Good night.
Perhaps youd like me
to tidy your desk.
- Thats all right.
- Lts no trouble.
You ought to get a flat nearby.
Brentwoods much too far away.
- Theres nice ones around.
- Lve thought of that.
Well, l tell you what.
lll keep my ears open for you.
Thats kind of you,
but lm fine for the moment.
lll let you know.
Thank you.
Dont worry about your desk.
lll tidy it for you every day.
Thanks, but that wont be necessary.
Thats perfectly all right.
A womans work is never done.
Good night, Sir.
Hi, fellas. How are you?
Good morning, Sir.
Mr. Florian has given us
permission for more outings.
ld like to hear suggestions
of what we might do.
- The pictures.
- Wembley, Sir.
Cup Final Day.
Chamber of Horrors.
What about the Cavern?
You know, Liverpool.
The Beatles.
Hows it going?
Fine, thank you.
Dont worry.
Hell come with me on my day.
Youre under
a supervision order too?
Around here, thats nothing.
Most of us have been
in front of the law.
Breaking windows, playing truant,
raising hell and cussing the coppers.
Youve cut yourself.
Youd better put something on that.
You might get lockjaw.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org