"Shaolin Monastery"
One
Two
Three
Four
Five
Six
Seven
Eight
Stop!
Brother Zhi Shan,
the Abbot would like to see you
Greetings to Abbot
Zhi Shan, you've been a monk
since you were a kid
How long have you been in this monastery?
I came here since I was six,
it's been twenty years
For years, monks in this monastery
have practised martial art to resist Qing
but we are short of weapons
The Qings forbid
the possession of weapons by people
that's why we have to make them ourselves
I'm now ordering you to
go to the Wen Shu Temple
Go and meet Priest Wu Chen
to get the blueprints of gunmaking
and steelwelding
Do you think you can manage this task?
I'll do my best
Good
Wu Chen was an exMing general
He's very good at kung fu
You can stay and learn from him
I will!
Brother Zhi Shan
We students from Shaolin
aren't allowed to leave freely
This time Abbot ordered you
to the Er Mei Mount
You're lucky to have the chance
to move around
to get some experience
People in the martial arts world
are crafty
There are pitfalls everywhere,
you must be very careful
Brother Fei Wen is right
but man is by nature kind
Otherwise,
Buddha wouldn't have come to save us
Do you have Abbot's letter with you?
Yes!
Brother, please!
Take care
Goodbye
Master, haven't seen you around here
at Mt. Er Mei
May I ask where you are from
and where you're headed?
I am from Shaolin Monastery at Song Shan
and have to go to Wen Shu Temple
to see Priest Wu Chen
What a coincidence.
Wu Chen happens to be my uncle
Across this mountain is the Wen Shu Temple
Thank you Madam! Please!
I don't know you,
and this path is precarious
I must be on my guard
against your sudden attacks
I know abbot's requirements
The weapons drawings he wants
would take at least 3 months to compile
You stay here first.
I'll get it done as soon as I can
Thank you!
What else did the abbot want you to do?
He said you excel at martial arts
and wants me to learn from you
That's laudable
I'll take you as my student
Teacher, my respects!
Good!
Dao de
Yes
Take Zhi Shan to the guest room
Yes!
Since the Shaolin Monastery
is dedicated to
expel the Manchurians
its kung fu must be extraordinary!
Everyone in the monastery
is busy practising
How many years have you practised?
I joined at six and am twenty six now
So you have practised for twenty years
You must be peerless
May I venture to match blows with you?
Brother Feng, why did you
use such a fatal maneuver?
That's what I've learnt
You'll recover after a month's rest
I admit I've not mastered kung fu
Some day
I'll meet him again
Brother, it's your own fault
I saw you used a devastating technique
to attack him
He hurt you only out of selfdefense
It wasn't intentional, please excuse me
Zhi Shan, don't blame yourself
This is my younger brother Bai Mei
whojust returned from his tour
He got some Shaolin news from the court
which may interest you
The Court has found out about Shaolin
secretly indulging in martial arts
and making weapons
Those from Shaolin
have been classified as rebels
and yet you have retained
a Shaolin monk here
I don't think it's right
What do you mean?
Shaolin is committed to expel Manchurians
That is a heroic act
we should all contribute our part
If you want to be friends with rebels
I have nothing to say
Brother, to each his own
From this day we go separate ways
There must be some truth in this news
from brother Bai Mei
I'll inform Shaolin Monastery
For the meantime
concentrate on your kung fu
Yes!
You have practised kung fu at Shaolin
for years
what are your specialties?
DragonVanquishing Palm
Iron head
And SingleFinger Meditation
You have been practising
hard style kung fu
but now you should
work on your inner powers;
This transcends all kung fu
For Chopping, exhale from the abdomen
Strength is exercised from the palm
Once you master it
you can break the jars
For Iron Head,
practise neck strength first
Exhale and focus all strength
towards the head
Guang Yuan
Yes!
Dan Tian Gang
Yue Ying Qi
Yes!
Monks in the Shaolin Monastery
are conspiring to rebel
What have you found out about it?
We have sent someone inside,
posing as workers
it's confirmed they are practising
kung fu in secret
and have treacherous intentions
Why haven't you wiped them out?
There are underground secret chambers
We must not arouse their suspicion
I order you to wipe them out in 3 months
failing which you'll be beheaded
Troops of He Nan are at your disposal
Yes
I'm grateful for your instructions
in this half year, sir
You've assimilated everything well
and have made remarkable progress
Keep on practising after your return
Yes!
Keep well the
weapons drawing
Yes. Please go back, I'll take your leave
Zhi Shan must pass here
on his way to Shaolin today
When he does so, I'll teach him a lesson
Brother Zhi Shan is a gentleman
it's your fault too that day
Why are you doing this?
I don't want the master to blame us
Go away if you're afraid
Uncle Bai Mei has said
we are free to kill Zhi Shan
What a coincidence we meet here
Brother Feng, I am returning to Shaolin
So you have learnt our Er Mei kung fu
and want to return to Shaolin to show off
Why do you say this?
Teacher said learning kung fu
is just for defense
this is the only purpose
I want to see if you could defend yourself
Shaolin Monastery is full of
secret tunnels and cells
you've sketched it well
Thank you, Mr Li
We have two spies staying in Shaolin
for half a year
Until today we've found out
the layout of the monastery
I hear their rules are strict
and monks are not allowed to leave
Yes, I was instructed to buy
foodstuff today
that's why I could come here
Mr Li
Yes!
Tell them to prepare dynamite
and hide it all inside the food
Let them bring back to the Monastery
Yes!
Pick out 400 elite for this duty
after eradicating Shaolin,
they'll be promoted
Yes!
Return to Shaolin first to help us there
Go back, hurry!
Yes
Some men are here
May I ask why are you here
at this late hour?
By the order of His Majesty
Tibet's Lama is here,
ask your abbot to welcome him
Since Bodhidharma travelled south
our Monastery honoured the Zen sect
We have no connection with
Tibet's esoteric doctrine
Please go back
You dare disobey an imperial order?
Shaolin will be eliminated
for disobedience
Come on, men!
Attack!
Kill them!
The Manchurian troops are here...
Guard the monastery's gate, quick!
Guard the monastery's gate,
I'll protect the Abbot
Hurry
Abbot, the Manchurian troops
are attacking us
Order everyone to resist
Come with me to fight, hurry!
Those monks are all in the secret cells
Let's go!
It's in the front
The secret cell is underneath the well
Great, those monks are hiding in the cell
We will use dynamite to block the tunnel
They are all trapped
None of them can get away
Throw it down!
Hurry! Let's rush out and kill the Tartars
You protect the Abbot
Yes!
Spare my life!
Blow them up!
Abbot... run!
Where's the Abbot?
Abbot! He's in the secret cell
Abbot! Abbot!
Zhi Shan!
What happened to you?
You are back
Run! Hurry and run!
Use the dynamite to blow up the Monastery
Yes!
Let's go!
Abbot!
I can't make it,
you better run for your life!
No, Abbot. How can I leave you behind
Did you get what I ordered you to get?
Yes
But what's the use?
Yes, the Shaolin Monastery is destroyed
It's your duty to rebuild it
Do you understand?
Yes, I'll risk my life
to have the Shaolin Monastery rebuilt
Go to the south
The people there have an unbending spirit
Go and solicit offerings
and look for heroic men
to rebuild the Shaolin Monastery
Yes!
Guang Dong and Fujin have famous mountains
South Shaolin must be rebuilt
Yes, Abbot, I will take up
this responsibility
I'm relieved
South Shaolin must be rebuilt
Even though I've to beg every penny of it
Shaolin Monastery must be rebuilt
in the South
"Guang Dong"
Sir, please offer me a vegetarian diet
and allow me to stay for a night
Nonsense. I'm running a business,
not doing charity
Without money, even gods are unwelcome
Go away...
Master, please stay
His lodging and boarding
will be on me
Yes Sir!
Master, have a seat!
Thank you, Sir!
Li Ba Shan, are you sure
the information is correct?
Shaolin has been destroyed
and Zhi Shan fled?
Teacher, this is absolutely true
A relative of mine just came back
from Guang Dong
He saw a monk who begged alms
claimed that he would rebuild Shaolin
in the South
Good aspiration I'd say,
but it's not that easy
to rebuild the Shaolin Monastery
all by himself
Dao de
Why are you so dejected?
I just returned from the Wen Shu Temple
A general with an imperial appointment
for my teacher, honoring him as
a Taoist Chief
Teacher insisted on turning it down
Wu Chen has no respect for His Majesty
When I tried to persuade him,
he thundered with rage
and said that
if I ever brought this up again
he'll evict me
With your fame and kung fu
you are no worse than teacher
You can earn the title unreservedly
Of course
but so far there's no imperial order
An imperial decree is here
You are Taoist Bai Mei?
It's my honor to meet you today
This is an imperial envoy
General Yue Ying Qi
General Yue
By imperial order
you are appointed as Taoist Chief
Please accept the imperial mandate
On your knees
I accept the imperial order
The imperial mandate reads:
Honouring Priest Bai Mei of Er Mei today,
I decree that
he be named as Head of Taoism
and spiritual leader
Dao de, what's the time now?
It's already the fifth watch,
please take your medicine
Is there any news from Zhi Shan?
I hear he's gone south
to rebuild the Shaolin Monastery
Since he has the will,
he will succeed
Go and rest
Yes!
The medicine...
You...
Teacher...
Why have you done this?
I'm under imperial order
to suppress the rebels
Teacher!
Wu Mei, go down south and find Zhi Shan
Rush to Guang Dong
to capture Zhi Shan alive
Hold it there!
If you want money, just take it
but don't hurt anyone
Let's go!
Silence him
Go away!
Let's go...
Thanks for your help
Fate has brought us together again
My home is just three miles from here
Please go there to have a rest
Thank you!
Please...
Sir, your kung fu is great
The best in Guang Dong
Of course
Uncle!
Jin Lun, since you like martial arts
I've invited a Shaolin martial artist here
Go and meet him in the sitting room
Uncle, in the martial arts world
many claim to be Shaolin kung fu experts
but they are mere imposters
Don't be taken in
How can you say such things?
When I was robbed on the road
he rescued me
You are naive
How do you know
he wasn't their accomplice?
Ah Fu!
Yes!
Bring the monk here
and I'll teach him a lesson
to see if he dares to cheat any more
Hurry and go!
Yes!
Jin Lun, you...
Sir, Master is here
Please!
Master!
Master... please
Let me introduce,
this is my nephew Jin Lun
Monk, did you knock down
several robbers on the road?
Yes!
So you also know kung fu
Only a smattering of it
Monk, how should one start
when learning kung fu?
One should start with breath control;
However, a young and
impulsive youth like you
should start with taking stances
That is the basis of all kung fu
Master, have a seat!
Thank you, sir.
But my sole purpose here is
to raise funds for rebuilding Shaolin
If you can sit firmly, we'll offer half of
our 20 silk shops in Guang Zhou
Deal
Hurry
Young Master...
Teacher, if you agree to take me
as your student
I'd rather give you all the 20 silk shops
Half is enough
Have you done what I've instructed you?
Don't worry!
Don't lie to me
They say, Master Zhi Shan
is an expert in kung fu
Master Zhi Shan's kung fu is fascinating
My nephew Jin Lun used to be haughty
But now
He has been totally overwhelmed by Master
You are too naive
to have given away
ten silk shops like that
In case he's a worldly monk
you'll have made a fool of yourself!
He's from Shaolin Monastery
It's impossible
I've got ways to find out
by testing him
If you find out he's honorable
you ought to
contribute more to
rebuild the Shaolin Monastery
No problem... everyone
We are all willing to contribute
but you can't let him know now
Of course
Good, deal
Bring the monk to my home tomorrow
I've an idea
Come... let me introduce
This is my good friend
He's Ling Ho,
a rich merchant from Guang Zhou
Meet Master Zhi Shan of Shaolin
An honour indeed to have you here
My mother maintains
quite close ties with Buddha
When she heard that
Master is in Guang Zhou
she insisted on your staying here
for a few days
and performing praying for her,
if it's okay with you
Since you are devout, I must accept
Great. Ah Gui
prepare some vegetarian food for Master
Yes!
Master, please come with me to the shrine
Please!
This way!
Hurry... put it down, hurry
Lift it up!
Miss Jinbao, Master is waiting for you
Follow me!
She's here!
Masters, sorry to keep you waiting
Jinbao, remember what I've told you
Don't worry, unless he isn't a man
I'll make him yield to my temptation
even if he's a Buddha
We'll count on you. Make good preparations
Just count on me
Master, please!
You must tired, please take a rest
Thank you!
Help! Help! Master, help!
Who is it?
Help!
Miss, what happened?
My stomach ache recurs,
it can only be cured by a man's belly
pressed against mine
Master, please help me!
How can there be such a disease?
It's not appropriate for you to stay here
It really hurts!
You are a monk, you should be merciful
How can you not help me? It hurts!
If you don't go away, I'll leave
Wait!
Thanks for your help
A small token of my appreciation
Madam
I saw this monk last night
he was really unmoved by beauty
but his greed got the better of him
Jinbao left a bag ofjewels last night
and he kept it
This shows he is not too respectable
Don't blame him. A monk is also human
Coveting small gains is inevitable
Right!
Were it you or me,
we mightn't even have been able to
resist Jinbao too, not to mention
the lure of money
Correct
Sir, Master is here
Please!
Good morning!
I picked this bag up
in the backyard last night
it contains valuable jewellery
It must be yours, so
I have come to return it
I admire you for not being greedy
but a monk shouldn't lie
You said you picked this up
from the backyard
I fear that's not the whole truth
You've reprimanded me well,
but as the origin of the jewelry
is questionable,
I'd rather not reveal the truth
or it may ruin someone's reputation
I'll take my leave
Master, wait
Your noble character is commendable
I'll contribute my share
for the rebuilding of
the Shaolin Monastery
What about you, gentlemen?
I've two mountains in Fujin
best suited for
building the Shaolin Monastery
You can take one
I'll donate half of
my profit in my business
for your disposal
I have 300 acres farmland
I'll donate them to Master
Thank you all!
Get lost!
Come out
Priest, what do you mean by this?
I just want some donation
No problem. Give him twenty coppers
Bull shit
Keep it for a beggar!
Then how much do you want?
I heard you promised
a Shaolin monk
that all your money would be given
for his disposal
Is it true?
I don't want much
Just fill up this tripod with silver
and I'll leave
Get lost!
Go in and get the silver
Listen, I'll sleep before the door
and whoever approaches, gets it
Priest
Scram!
Excuse me, it's him
May I know your Buddhist name please?
I'm here to solicit offerings. Go away
This is not solicitation, it's blackmail
So what?
How is Wu Chen related to you?
I don't know him
How are you related to Bai Mei?
None of your business
Thank you Master!
Please come to Jing Chan Temple for a chat
Sister
Brother Zhi Shan
So you too have come to Guang Zhou
I saw what happened just now
That crook is called Lee Ba Shan
a student of Bai Mei
Bai Mei defected to the Qing regime
and killed teacher
Now they are after you
Master Wu Chen is killed!
I'll stay here for the time being
come to me if need be
How are you getting on with fund raising?
Guang Dong people are charitable
I have got enough money
I got a mountain site too
But I'd like to get more supporters
before going to Fujin
to build the Monastery
Make way, let me handle it
Try harder...
Make way
Where's that monk?
That way, to the south suburbs
Let's go!
Mr Lin, your knife is ready
Good! Gong Qian Jin, you are not bad
Thank you!
Don't mention it
Mr Lin, thirty coppers for it
Alright... thirty coppers
Give it to me!
I'm sorry, business isn't good
I will pay you tomorrow
No...
I won't be here tomorrow,
you must pay today
Well, I'll give you a piece of pork
Sauteed meat to go with wine
Alright! Give it to me
Gong Qian Jin, it's worth seventy coppers
I owe you thirty
Give me the change for forty coppers
I won't have it even for seven coppers
Take it back! And pay me back thirty
Did you see our rule here?
For goods once sold, there'll be no refund
You've taken the meat, give me the change
Damn you, pay me!
Are you paying or not?
Great, you've torn my clothes
My clothes are worth eighty coppers
So you have to pay me 110
Trying to evade payment?
How is it? Not bad
My pig's feet are not bad either
Are you trying to ruin my chances?
Are you blind?
This is the toilet
not a place for fighting
Smells good?
It stinks!
You bastard, don't run!
You two are good at kung fu
Don't hurt each other
for anger at the spur of the moment
You know nothing, monk
Go away!
Punches and kicks have no eyes
we don't want to hurt you
Damn monk, beat him up!
Butcher, we should fight him
Why are you hitting me?
The damn monk was behind us
Can't move any more?
Not bad
Don't move!
You are so obedient
I can take you as my students
Damn monk, I'll teach you a lesson
Beat him up
Teacher!
Teacher! I'm looking for you everywhere
Who did you fight with?
A priest with white eyebrows
He hit me with a duster
Priest Bai Mei
He has come to Guang Dong!
Seems he is making trouble here!
Let's go back first
Let's go and beg him to teach us kung fu
Right
Follow him!
Teacher!
Leave...
The magistrate is here
Greetings to Your Honour
Everyone please be seated
Anything we can do for you, sir?
You are all business magnates
in Guang Dong
and are well respected
But I can't cover up
any rebellion among you
Your Honour, what do you mean by this?
Are you keeping a Shaolin monk
at your home?
Our family are devout Buddhists
It's no surprise that
there are monks staying with us
Did you donate
half of your assets to that monk
to rebuild the Shaolin Monastery?
Charity is part of our humanity
If you hand over that monk to the Court
you'll get a title, what do you think?
I can't, I'm leaving
Mr Li
You'll be killed for
providing shelter to a rebel
You must hand over Zhi Shan in three days
or else you'll all be like him
Open the door! Jin Lun!
Open the door! Open up!
Uncle Wang, what's going on?
Jin Lun,
your uncle has already been killed by
Yue Ying Qi who was sent by the Court
The troops will be here anytime,
you'd better run!
Teacher! Hurry and leave!
You leave with Mr Wang first
Alright! Go!
This is the monk, capture him
Let's go!
Go and find Hong Xi Guan
Buy a casserole!
Sir, buy a casserole!
Hong Xi Guan, come over...
What is it? Why are you so nervous?
Li Jin Lun's home was sealed
Where could
Jin Lun and Master Zhi Shan be?
I want to fight with that monk and he left
Gui Jue Qi, come here!
Go and gather information
about them
We'll be at the Min Xiang Teahouse, go
Yes!
You wait for me at the Min Xiang Teahouse
I'll be there after I've packed up
Alright! Go!
Everyone, I'm sorry, I'm closing up
I am so sorry
Gui Jue Qi, hurry!
He's coming!
What is it?
What news have you got?
Li Jin Lun's uncle was killed by the Court
There's no trace of Zhi Shan and Jin Lun
Li Jin Lun is our brother
We can't stand by without helping him
Master Zhi Shan is wanted by the Court
We as his students
can't wash our hands off the matter
Zhi Shan is your teacher,
but I'm not convinced
I must fight with him
A monk won't count for much
I can break his ribs right away
Brother! Let me warn you
If you want to fight with my teacher
you'd better be prepared to suffer
We are not afraid
Let's split up and find out
and contact each other if there's any news
Don't go
I've no money today
who pays the bill?
None of our business, let's go
You're in bad luck!
Master Zhi Shan
When you have settled down
please let me know
I will, no need to see me off, goodbye!
Zhi Shan, you are hiding here
You've killed Master Wu Chen
Aren't you ashamed?
To kill rebels is a common thing
in the martial arts world,
what's the big deal?
That's exactly what I intend to do
Let's go!
This is the home of
my good friend Hong Xi Guan
He's a casserole vendor in town
Stay here to recuperate,
no one will find out
Take Sister Wu Mei inside and have a rest
After taking the herbs,
she'll recuperate soon
Does your friend practise kung fu also?
Yes, he's been practising the post
for three years
He has mastered the light skill
One with his perseverance must be good
I may recruit him in rebuilding
the Shaolin Monastery
But he's one of those
who think highly of themselves
and it's not easy to convince him
Alright, I'd like to test him
when he's back
Seeing is believing
You are Master Zhi Shan?
Yes, I am
He's my good friend
I've long heard of your excellent kung fu
I'd like to spar with you
I'm only a rowdy. Don't be pedantic
I never depart from punches and kicks
Great, we have much in common
In that case
could we have a match at the posts
Whoever falls
will have to kowtow three times
and greet the other as 'teacher'
Deal
Yes, it's a deal, please!
Wait!
Your posts are fixed
I'm not used to it
Let me hold up a few special ones
What do you think?
As you please
Casserole posts
Come up!
Great!
You're not bad with the fixed posts
but you need to practice on movable ones
Master, I have never in my life
kowtowed to anyone
Now... I
Arise...
Hong Xi Guan!
Master, I admit defeat
Please take me as your student
Hong Xi Guan, we have now become brothers
From now on, we are family
Teacher
Just now we saw a Tibetan Lama
drinking with several Qing officials
It's heard that
this lama came from the capital
with orders to capture you alive
Jin Lun, you hide with your teacher here
We'll go and find out
what kind of Hercules
this lama is!
Let's go!
Sir, please! Have a seat here!
Just sit here
Sit...
Over there, that's him
Ah Zhing, I think this monk
is quite good in kung fu
I'm only afraid of his staff
You cope with him, I'll go out for a while
The wine is here
What did you say to the lama?
I know the lama since from Tibet
Of course I was speaking to him in Tibetan
It seems that he didn't understand
what you said
Of course he did
Take it
This lama is terrific
Keep fighting with him
Double kicks, Three stars with the Moon
Gin Wa kick
Damn you, want to attack my behind?
Cannon Position. HeartPiercing Leopard
Carrying the sedan
The troops are here, run!
Lama
Where do you think these rogues are from?
They are riffraff
with uncouth skills
They are a disorganized gang
I think Zhi Shan's students did this
Magistrate!
Yes!
Enforce martial law and search
every household
We must trace Zhi Shan by all means!
Yes! Yes!
Come in at once!
Everything is now ready
Shaolin Monastery must be rebuilt
in three months' time
therefore we must go to Fujin
as soon as possible
But Bai Mei has ordered a curfew
It's hard for us
to get out of Guang Zhou
Where there is a will, there is a way
Make all the necessary preparations today
we'll charge out of the city tomorrow
Your Honour!
Stand still!
Open the coffin!
Attack!
Let's go
Run! Hurry and run!
Teacher, sea and land routes both
in Guang Zhou
are heavily guarded,
don't go out in the open
You'd better hide beside the pier ahead
We'll try and find a boat
When we have found one, we'll contact you
Alright!
Go!
There's no boat anywhere,
what should we do?
Let's split up to find one
Alright!
It was this priest!
Great
I'm sure the six of us can get rid of him
Dao de, capture him!
Yes!
He's practised Golden Armour before,
everyone watch out
Attack!
I have practised the Golden Armour
all my pressure points are closed
Zhi Shan, you must remember
There are six critical pressure points
in a human body
that cannot be totally closed
even with protection of the Golden Armour;
There must be at least one vulnerable spot
Sail it over here
Teacher!
A boat is coming, Teacher!
Sail it over
Come on...