Obsolete.
Irrelevant.
In an age when desire
has become amplified,
but where lust can be
sated electronically,
we need something more
than just a wooden box.
There is a mechanism.
The house is ready,
we can adapt.
Technology may have advanced
but sin remains unchanged.
Pure. Greed.
Lust. Lies. Betrayal.
This new millennium
hurtles forward.
Faith is lost.
Mankind has become a
vacuum without morality.
So many souls seeking new
and darkened experiences.
Degradation upon degradation,
sin after sin.
So then those are the souls
we shall seek out first.
"Mr. Watkins,
"we know, we understand,
and we can help.
"But you must come.
"Come now before it's too late.
"Come to 55 Ludovico Place.
"Alone. Now.
A sympathetic friend".
Ah, Mr. Watkins.
So good of you to come.
We have such sights
to show you.
Please, step inside.
Mr. Watkins.
The fuck is going on?
Who the fuck are you?
What are you doing to me?
That's all-all valid questions.
What the fuck is going on?!
Mr. Watkins, please.
Please assist your situation.
Look at your environment.
For now, you are merely captive
sitting tied to a chair.
If we wanted you killed,
you would be.
We have simply invited
you here to talk.
To hear your
thoughts and desires.
Furthermore, if they're as
interesting and illuminating
as I believe them to be,
then your reward will be
beyond your belief.
A reward?
A reward tailored for a man of
your particular tastes and desires.
You know about me?
You know the things I've done?
It was that resume of
yours that led us to you
and in turn, you to us.
Who are you?
Yes. Perhaps a
little illumination.
Please, try not to be too alarmed.
Oh, Jesus Christ!
Heavens, no.
Same city, completely
different zip code.
What is going on here?
What-where am I?
Mr. Watkins, we really
must begin your interview.
So many people for you to see.
So, let's just
dive in, shall we?
August 18th, 2001...
you lured little
Courtney Rettison to your car.
Why?
I-I-I never...how do you know...?
Please.
Let's save ourself the time
and you the considerable pain
by answering
the questions honestly.
Clearly, this is a place
where the rules of your
world do not apply.
And obviously, I am
a man for whom pain
is nothing more
than a common currency.
I will spend some on you...
if you like.
I'd...seen her at the uh,
the playground before.
I couldn't help myself.
Oh, I understand.
I was just tryin' to help.
Yes, yes.
She had blonde hair.
Long and... it was in a ponytail.
Never seen so much blood
from a little creature.
My, my, quite the busy bee
with you, Mr. Watkins?
What about my reward?
First of all, you will
meet with the Assessor.
He will look over your pages,
pass on his findings to the Jury,
and we'll go from there.
The Assessor will be
with you shortly.
Tears...
of children.
What?
Serves you right,
you sick fuck!
Ladies, your verdict?
Guilty.
The Jury has deliberated,
and a guilty verdict
has been given.
What?
You'll be taken from
here to be cleaned
and then to the Surgeon.
What about my reward?
Your note said you understood.
It said you were a friend.
I do understand.
This is your reward.
This is what you're
deserving of, my friend.
No!
Please!
I'll be better!
I'll be good!
What? Who is it?
Who is it?
Fuck.
Please, help me.
Please, help me, please.
No! Please!
Help! What the fuck are you
doing to me? Stop!
You must be cleaned...
on the inside, too.
Help!
Uber Black, my ass!
You're just a...
piece of shit!
What the hell?
Josh?
Are you in my apartment again?
I told you that you need
to give me my key back.
Okay? This late-night
booty call shit is over.
Although, I could...
probably go for...
a quickie for...
old times' sake.
Josh...
Okay, I'm drying up
real fast here.
This...weirdo-in-the-dark thing
is only a turn on for like
a few minutes.
And-And where's my dog?
Baby?
Fuck this.
Seriously, what the fuck
have you done with the lights?
What do you want?
To make a lesson out of you.
You look like shit.
What'd you do last night?
Wonderful. Yeah.
I had a great time last
night, thank you for asking.
You're gonna take a left
two blocks up the way
on Taylor.
Victim is one Crystal Lanning,
21 years old.
Building super found
her this afternoon.
Went out with a girl
called Crystal.
It speaks!
What was that like?
The Tale of Two Cities.
The what?
Charles Dickens.
Right.
Like anyone reads
that shit anymore.
It's the most popular
fictional book on the planet.
So why is this Crystal chick
like the book?
Read it.
We're here.
Good.
worship this little guy.
The place has been
cleared, locked down.
Everyone's been told to hold
back until we make our pass.
In case it's him.
worship this little guy.
I worship this little guy.
-I worship this little guy.
-Nice.
I worship this little guy.
It's him.
It's definitely him.
You think?
Doesn't this seem a bit basic
for the Preceptor?
The fuck are you?
What are you doing creeping around
a murder scene at night time?
You wanna end up dead?
Detectives Carter and Carter.
Brothers in arms...
literally.
Detective Egerton.
I've been assigned to
this case with you.
-You got her?
-I got her.
Detective Christine Egerton.
Do you mind?
Why are you here?
Who thinks we need
help with this?
Like I was saying,
isn't this just a bit basic
for the Preceptor?
I mean, I was under the
impression that he liked to shock,
appall, teach.
And that?
"I am a jealous God
thou shalt have no
others unto me?"
It's one of the
remaining commandments.
and is part of his M-O.
I think that it's just a--
-What was that?
-Jesus Christ!
What the fuck is that?
Has anyone seen
the dog in the video?
Fuck.
It's okay.
Baby.
The dog was her baby.
So he put it into her womb.
I'll call it in.
Alison's birthday. Shit.
Nice.
It's a very 1940s
detective agency.
Do we still smoke stogies and
have Scotch for breakfast?
What we're investigating,
it's very dark.
Fluorescents give me a migraine.
Look, I know that me coming
in here must be a bit of a shock.
Detective teams are a tight
knit at the best of times
but I do know this job.
So, I can help
if you let me.
I've gotta go.
It's my wife's birthday
and I'm late.
We'll do this tomorrow.
Nine a.m.
Uh-huh.
He takes it personal.
Well, he shouldn't.
I was assigned.
Not you.
The killings.
That won't last in here.
Plastic.
Thrives in all climates.
Happy birthday to me.
I'll take care of that.
I don't even like carnations.
I'm going to bed.
The previous commandment
prior to the Lanning was...
"Thou shall not lie".
This is a Catholic family.
Jessica and Steven,
both lawyers.
The Preceptor cut out
both of their tongues
with an electric turkey knife.
Let them bleed out in front
of their only son, Michael.
What'd he do with the tongues?
Put 'em in a blender,
force-fed 'em to the son
laced with bleach, of course.
Donut?
Now why would he feed
the tongues to the son?
He said they were feeding
lies to everyone,
so he fed their
lies to their son.
How you guys know all this?
He's quite the letter writer.
We have copies, obviously.
-I'll get you some.
-Speakin' of which...
this came from the M.E.'s
office this morning.
Got it out of Lanning's abdomen.
"The irony of this killing
"is that when people
see what I've done,
"their reaction will be...
"'Oh, poor dog'
with no consideration for
the vacuous vessel in which
I chose to store it".
Nice.
Forensics has been
over the letters?
Local and Langley.
Came up with nothing.
Letter was typed in a
old manual typewriter.
Common ink.
No prints, oils, residue,
glue, particulates. Nothin'.
The name Preceptor.
That's a masonic term.
Has that avenue
been checked out?
It's used by Freemasons,
but it's older than that.
A precept is a teacher...
responsible to uphold
law or tradition.
In this case, the
Ten Commandments.
-Shall I?
-Just one second.
How many victims are we
talking about in total now?
Fourteen.
-Two commandments left.
-"Thou shalt not steal".
"Thou shalt not covet".
Can I ask you, what exactly
is your background?
Why are you on this case?
Of course. You can
ask me anything.
Can we go through the cases
in order, top to bottom?
You worked Forensics two years...
before you became a detective.
Did it take a lot
of detective work
to find out about
another detective?
Someone higher up think
we're screwing this up?
Someone higher up wants
this guy caught,
and it's as simple as that.
Okay. Let's do this.
Okay.
"And upholds all things
by the word of his power,
"when he had made
purification of sins
"and he sat down at the right
hand of the Majesty on high."
"I am speaking in human terms
"because of the weakness
of your flesh.
"For just as you presented
your members as slaves...
"to impurity and to lawlessness,
resulting in further lawlessness,
"so now present your members
as slaves to righteousness,
resulting in sanctification."
You all right?
Let her go.
Who do you think they are?
Uniforms are going door to door
checking CCTVs.
Fuck me.
Eye for an eye,
tooth for a tooth.
Tiffany Nardico, age 12,
Emily Cartwright, 13.
Susan Allison, 14,
and Nicole Panna, 15.
They all have records,
but it's just like petty theft.
You okay?
Yeah.
I just got off the
phone with Hodges.
The medical examiner.
The preliminary for the
hair, teeth, and eyes
were a match with the hands.
Same with the blood in the jar.
So it's just the four victims.
The killer injected some
kind of epoxy into the hands
to keep them into position.
-Anything else?
-Yes.
No coagulation
in the fingertips.
Shit.
What?
He cut their hands off while
they were still alive.
Jesus.
-Are those them?
-Yeah.
-What name is that?
-Nicole Panna.
Does that mean anything to you?
No, why? Should it?
Just a second.
Carl Watkins.
Who?
Local perp.
Flasher. Kiddie porn peddler.
We picked him up a
couple of times,
but he always pled out...
or made a deal informing.
So, what does he have
to do with this?
All of these girls went to
Chase Terrace Academy.
Terrace put a restraining
order against him
after he was caught
a few times
loitering and jerking off
to the girls in gym class.
That's a real stretch, David.
Guess who also went to
Terrace a few years back?
Crystal Lanning.
Exactly.
Seriously?
Do we have an address on him?
He's not in.
That cocksucker owes
me two months' rent.
He hasn't been here
for a couple of days.
Think he'd be
hiding out inside?
Well, if he is, he's freezing
his ass off in the dark.
I cut his power yesterday.
Seriously?
No windows?
Honey, with what those
boys are doing in there,
no windows ain't a bad thing.
Shut the door when you leave.
"What an incredible smell
you've discovered."
This shouldn't take long.
This guy seems to have
quite the right arm.
Doesn't really seem like
the Preceptor type.
Speak of the devil.
Looks like it's typed on
an old manual typewriter.
-Let's get that back to the lab.
-Mm-hmm.
Put out an ATL on Watkins.
In the meantime,
let's hit the usual suspects.
You go with David.
Anything?
Nope.
You done for the day?
Yeah.
I'm gonna swing by Watkin's
apartment on the way home.
What's up?
Somethin's been
buggin' me about it.
Give our regards to that
sweet-mouth landlady for me.
I'll give her your number.
Thanks for turning the power on.
Excuse me.
Detective Sean Carter.
Mr. Carter?
Mr. Carter. You're a man
of some interest to us.
-What do you want to know?
-Excuse me?
You obviously have questions.
Why would you say that?
'Cause if you wanted me
dead, I'd be dead already.
That's very true. What else?
If I had to guess,
I stumbled into a
painful, possibly fatal situation--
the agenda of which
you'll soon tell me.
What can you tell me
about Carl Watkins?
A man of impeccable
taste, apparently.
And what can you tell me
about the Preceptor?
I was about to ask you
the same question.
What are those?
Well, since you've been good
enough not to waste our time
with the usual drudgery of
"Who are you" and
"Save me", etcetera,
perhaps a reward is in order.
Dear God.
Where am I?
You wanted to know about these?
They are... a linking
mechanism between
our world and yours.
They are judgment and redemption
to those who open them.
They are sensation...
rebirth... death...
love... hate...
all manner of emotions.
They are a conduit
to the unimaginable.
In a wooden box.
You'll be amazed what
they can do when opened.
What on Earth is this place?
It isn't.
So, now what?
This is the beginning
of a process.
An interview.
An audit of sorts.
And you want honest answers.
Absolutely.
So, then let's just
get on with it.
Tempus fugit, after all.
Tell me...
when was the first time
you hurt something?
Be honest, Mr. Carter.
The sooner you tell the truth,
the sooner you will be free.
Four.
We had a pet dog.
I hit it.
Should I go on?
March 31st... 2004.
I was 25.
The bullet hit him in the throat.
I saw a fist-sized chunk...
blown out the back of his neck.
I stood over him
and watched him die.
And after that?
Two kids.
Grenade.
It was the first time I'd ever
seen a body blown to pieces.
Skin stripped from muscle.
Flesh stripped from bone.
You... were a man
protecting his country.
You were permitted
to carry out these acts.
But what were you
permitted to feel?
-What did you feel?
-What did I feel?
How the hell was I
supposed to feel?
You have killed
a great many people.
I was doing my job.
"You will have purged
from yourselves
"the guilt of shedding
innocent blood.
For you have done what is right
in the eyes of the Lord."
Only God can judge me.
"And God will judge both the
righteous man and the wicked man."
Ecclesiastes 3:17.
Deuteronomy 21:9.
Ha!
I... would like to
dig a little deeper.
What choice do I have?
None.
During my second tour,
our convoy hit--and I...
There is still more.
"It is a terrible,
ponderous chain
you are making, Scrooge".
Charles Dickens.
Now what?
Next you will meet the Assessor.
And my...
what a meal he has
ahead of him.
What have you done?
You will be taken to be cleaned.
And then to the Surgeon.
No, it can't be!
I hate this place.
The stench, the decor.
The seedy games and indulgences
we allow you to play as
part of the arrangement
-Why are you here?
-Let him go.
He has no business here.
I don't understand.
Well... just because
it falls into your web
does not make it
prey for a spider.
Catch and release,
do you understand?
What about the Assessor?
Clerical error, quite literally.
-I've never heard of this--
-I don't care.
The Jury never passed
their verdict.
You let him go,
do you understand?
Not really, no.
Well, do you understand
who is in charge?
Just let him go.
Do not give me a reason
to come back here.
You must be cleaned...
on the inside, too.
No!
Uh, a moment of your time.
A candidate...
I need your assistance,
with your...guidance.
Why?
His answers
choked the Assessor.
Froze the Jury and...
summoned Jophiel.
Innocent?
Where is he now?
I sent him to be cleaned.
He's gone!
Escaped with one of the boxes.
The pages.
Take.
Eat this in remembrance
of my body.
You must go after him.
Bring him back.
You must dig deeper.
We must find out why
Jophiel wants him released.
There's no need to go after him.
He'll be back.
It's 2:30 in the morning.
You got-You got any flashlight?
-Yeah, why?
-I'll drive.
Why, what's up?
Huh?
What's going on?
You wanna call this in?
What are we doing here?
Hey.
What the fuck
are we doing here?
So?
Come on, man!
It's nice. Nice place.
You put an offer in yet?
-Or are you in escrow?
-Fuck.
Hey!
What is going on?
You drag my ass out here in
the middle of the fucking night
with no explanation?
You barely talk to me
anymore, man.
Alison is worried about you.
Oh, you'd know that.
Man, we're all worried
about you, Sean.
I'll drive you back to your car.
They are a conduit
to the unimaginable.
Sensation, rebirth,
death, lust, hate.
Hey, hey, hey...
It's just a dream.
You're okay.
It's okay.
Come here, come here.
Shh.
Shh. It's okay.
I don't know what's
going on anymore.
This case... it's destroying you.
I can't get it out of my head.
Shh.
Sean!
What?
What is going on?
What are you doing?
What?
Judgment and redemption
to those who open the box.
Thank you.
Almond milk.
Thanks.
So, what's on your mind?
Your brother?
I'm just curious.
You've been here
for a couple of days.
What do you see?
I see two people mired
in a pretty dark case.
One of whom is
probably internalizing
a little bit too much of it.
Honestly, I don't know
that I would be any different.
Yeah, he's not running right.
Have you talked to
somebody about that?
Not official, but I do
talk to his wife.
Alison.
Yeah.
How'd you know that?
Did he ever suffer from any
PTSD when he came back?
Not that I know of.
But he's never really talked
about what went on over there.
Drinking, drugs?
None of that?
He drank for a little while
but he's sober now.
Just lately he's been distant.
I think maybe it's starting
to have an effect on him.
I...
What?
Look, I was assigned
to this case for two reasons.
One of them is to expedite the
catching of the Preceptor...
and the other is because
there are some concerns
about Sean's behavior.
So I am here, first and foremost
to help you with the case
but also to evaluate.
We've been working our
ass off in this case.
And it's not about that.
This is genuine concern for
someone who might be in too deep.
It's Alison.
Hey, you.
What?
He is?
Don't worry about it.
I'll come by and pick him up.
You take Sara to school.
Okay.
His car broke down.
I have to go pick him up.
He didn't call you?
I gotta go.
Hey.
Sean!
I'll uh... I'll go take a shower.
Ah, wait a second, please.
You gotta straighten up.
Just in case, Egerton has...
other motivations
for being with us.
Meaning what?
Think about it.
How long have you
been drinking again?
Alison and I got
in a bit of a fight.
I had a few drinks,
caught up to me.
I got this.
Go get cleaned up.
Sean...
no one is judging you.
Like I told somebody else,
only God can judge me.
God will judge both the righteous
man and the wicked man.
"It was the best of times,
it was the worst of times".
If I had a relationship
like that...
Hello.
Hey.
Take a look at this.
This is the first letter
from the Preceptor.
Read here.
"There is no accountability.
"I will bring back
the wrath of the Almighty.
"I will be the plague of retribution.
It will be the season of darkness
and winter of despair."
And?
And I just found this
at Sean's house.
Dickens.
He didn't tell you about this?
He mentioned the book,
but he didn't mention this.
Well, maybe he just
put it together.
Then why didn't he say anything?
I don't know,
you should've asked him.
Where is he?
He's on his way.
I thought he had some
kind of car trouble?
He did not have car trouble.
He was drunk
and I had to go help him.
You said he was sober.
He was. He is.
David, what the
fuck is going on?
I don't know.
That's why I came to you.
I'm gonna have to talk to him.
Talk to who?
You--what happened to your face?
About what?
Hello.
Yes, this is Carter.
Yes, that Carter.
He did.
What exactly?
Phone?
Where?
We'll be there.
Medical examiner.
Found Crystal Lanning's
cell phone...
wedged down her throat.
-You're kidding me.
-He wants us there.
Okay.
You and I go.
David stays here and goes
through some of that evidence.
-Okay.
Shit.
Forgot my phone.
Just give me a sec.
Forgot you cell phone?
I need you to do me a favor.
Take a quick look around
See if you find
anything unusual.
I'm not investigating
my brother.
I'm not asking you to.
Take a look.
For his sake.
-Okay.
Well, it seems to be
running okay now.
What?
The car.
David said you had some
car trouble this morning.
Marriage trouble.
Well, at least you're honest.
Can I ask you something?
Honestly?
Do you think you're
too close to this case?
Probably, but it's my work.
Yeah, but if it's tearing
your world apart...
What can I do?
There's only one
commandment left.
Gotta finish it all the way
to the end, right?
I get that.
And I think it's
really admirable, but...
this is not a tour of duty.
It is for me.
Well, I was reading through
the notes from the Preceptor.
I notice that a lot of the
turn of phrase is very poetic.
Almost reads like literature.
You know, David mentioned
you read a lot, so
I thought I'd ask if anything
struck a chord with you.
Not really.
I mean, there were a
couple of lines...
lifted from A Tale of
Two Cities by Dickens, but
nothing else comes to mind.
Did you bring that up
in the investigation?
It didn't seem relevant.
After all, it is the most
popular book on the planet.
Yeah.
I guess it is.
Hodges.
-Hodges.
-Hey.
So.
Let's see...
Yeah.
I thought you said you
found a cell phone.
Yeah, we did, in her throat.
We found that
in her mouth first.
Silver?
Born with a silver
spoon in her mouth.
She certainly died that way.
We found this in her esophagus.
Way down in there.
Damn shame.
Yeah, she was only 21.
Yeah, yeah, absolutely.
I mean that's an iPhone 7.
I still got a 4.
Thanks, Hodges.
Thanks for the information.
It still works.
-What?
-The phone.
Yeah, one of the kids
here has the same model,
so we managed to
power the thing up.
And we did, turns out she
was using a GPS app.
The location on it
wasn't her apartment?
No, we checked.
She wasn't killed at
the apartment, either.
What he did took time and uh...
would've been quite the mess.
Yeah, especially with the dog.
No, he took her somewhere
alive, prepped her, killed her.
Luckily, if you can say that,
her phone died with her.
So it stored her last location.
Serial killer caught
by a smartphone.
Do you have the address?
You know, I haven't seen
you around here before.
Yeah, I was just
assigned to the case.
Single?
You're kidding, right?
I'll call it in.
Yeah, this is
Detective Sean Carter.
We're on the scene of a
possibly compromised location.
Requesting uniform backup.
Address is 12437 Gladstone.
It looks like a fisherman's
warehouse of some kind.
Okay, copy that.
I think this is
pretty locked up.
Yeah.
I guess we'll be waiting.
I don't know, I hear a
struggle of some kind,
destruction of evidence.
I don't hear anything.
Well, if you did, we wouldn't
have to wait for a warrant.
-You wanna catch this guy, right?
-Of course, I do.
Well, then we hear a struggle.
Over here.
Look at this.
It's him.
Holy shit!
Drop it.
Fuck!
Backup's on the way.
No, they're not.
But someone is.
Now move to the fucking
center of the room.
How did you find out?
You told me.
What was it you said?
"Only God can judge me".
"God will judge the righteous".
"God will judge both
the righteous man...
"and the wicked man".
"Ecclesiastes is one of
24 books of the Tanakh...
"or Hebrew Bible".
"The title Ecclesiastes is
a Latin transliteration
"of the Greek translation...
"traditionally translated as 'Teacher'...
"or 'Preacher'...
"or 'Preceptor'".
Preceptor.
Shit!
When I didn't hear
back from Egerton...
I called Hodges
to get the address.
Quite the detective.
Why are you doing this?
Like I've always told you,
you should read more,
starting with the Bible.
Sean?
You wouldn't call backup
on you own brother.
Not until you knew for sure.
So I called someone else.
In here.
I came as fast as I could.
Shit!
Sean, what are you doing?
Sean?
What is this?
What's going on?
Come on in, sweetheart.
Come stand next to
my dear brother.
No, no, no, no.
Go stand next to David.
I didn't say touch her!
I have so much more planned
for the two of you!
That Lanning bitch's cell phone
fucked things up!
I don't understand.
You don't?
Look around.
Look at what I've done.
This is the love of God,
that we keep his commandments.
And his commandments
are not burdensome.
Where is Egerton?
Oh!
-Jesus Christ!
-Oh!
Sean, no, no.
Wait, wait.
We... We...
This whore cheated on me
with some guy she met online...
two weeks after I left
for my first tour.
I'm sorry.
Thou shall not covet
another man's wife.
So I cut his eyelids off
and burned him alive
in his own car.
I wasn't surprised with her.
But I expected more of you.
Sean, I'm...
What a plague of
smartphone junkies.
I... loathe the modern world.
I loathe the populace.
If I had the means and ways,
I would incinerate them all.
Rain down fire and sulfur.
Now.
I want you to sit down
in front of each other.
Just do it!
What are you gonna do?
Open that.
What?
What the fuck is this?
Open it, both of you.
Now. Together.
What?
What is this?
What's happening?
Judgment.
I knew you would find
your way here eventually.
After all...
evil seeks evil.
I knew someone
would come for me.
So I thought I'd save you
the time and offer you a deal.
There is no deal to be made.
Them for me.
Adulterers.
They open the box.
And they will be
dealt with accordingly.
It is a separate faction
who has want of you
and there is no
bargaining to be done.
Ah, Mr. Carter.
So good to see you again.
And you brought friends.
I brought them to trade for me.
That is not how it works.
I don't want to go
back in that room.
Mr. Carter, please.
That won't work for you now.
You have been found
guilty by the Jury.
You will be taken to be cleaned.
Again.
And then to the Surgeon.
Not me!
The pages of your
audit was so rancid,
this clear essence of your guilt,
they made even the
Assessor choke.
When the Surgeon and the
Butcher are finished with you,
you will be reborn
in an eternity of agony.
What the fuck is going on?
Silence!
Your pitiful adultery
is beneath me.
Bow your head to the catalog
of filth you brother has created.
Amateurs.
But still we will afford
them an experience
beyond the limits
in your name.
Get away from him.
Ah, Jophiel. Eden's doorman.
Once upon a time.
And then, what was it?
Watching over the ark builders'
incestuous offspring.
And now?
Monitoring this
basement's misfits.
He was found guilty.
Let him go.
There are matters at play here
that are part of a bigger plan
and he is a part of it.
You want him out
there on Earth...
or rather he wants
him out there.
He wants his flock
afraid of the wolf
so that they look
toward the light.
You're not as foolish
as you look.
But what about the
things he has done,
the-the innocents he has killed?
Acceptable losses.
Good cannot exist without evil.
When we discovered long ago
that in order to
control the evil,
we had to be the ones
implementing it.
Sin ordained by Heaven.
Send him back.
Continue your work,
Preceptor.
With our blessing.
And the Lord saw that the sin
of man was great on the earth,
and that all the thoughts
of his heart were evil.
There is process...
order to what we do.
Send him back!
Or?
There'll be hell to pay.
Hell. To pay.
Don't test me.
Very well.
Now get me the fuck out of here.
I've been forgiven.
Not forgiven.
What?
You're a murderer.
A twisted sadist.
For now, your actions
work in our favor.
But there will be judgment
for you eventually.
And we will be waiting.
Fuck you!
Send him back.
With pleasure.
I'm back.
"It is a far, far--"
We have an officer down
at 12437 Gladstone.
Send assistance.
This is Egerton.
We have the Preceptor.
Get me a fucking ambulance.
You knew that would happen.
You know nothing
of human behavior.
There will be retaliation.
You will suffer.
Suffer?
Me?
How dare you use such a word.
You know nothing of suffering.
I welcome its warm embrace.
I exist only
to share its meaning.
Sin and suffering
are my dominion.
Perhaps it's time
you learned a little
of the matters
you seek to manage.
What are you doing?
Do you know who I am?
I care not.
Irony.
Are you the way?
Do your worst.
You forget my first
task for Him.
That my order's already
been sanctioned.
Look at me.
I'm already in Hell.
Forged in agony and pain.
I welcome an
eternity of anguish.
See you, Pinhead...
Here endeth the lesson.
Jesus wept!
Probably should not
have done that.
I have nothing to fear.
Did you forget?
She is the angel who banished
them from the Garden of Eden.
Perhaps there is a torture
we cannot endure.
Banishment.
Exile.
Back to the mortal world.
Banishment.
The sweet suffering.
No!
Two.
Pfff.
And it isn't even a Tuesday.
Subs by enwansix