[Butcher] With great power
comes the absolute certainty
that you'll turn
into a right cunt.
We got everything under control.
[reporter] An explosion
rocked Midtown Manhattan.
[Mother's Milk] Soldier Boy.
[Butcher] And what you gonna do
when you find him?
You need us.
[Starlight] You shot up
an untested drug from Vought.
[Frenchie] Nina.
[Little Nina] Our classified
lab destroyed...
My powers are gone!
[Little Nina] ...three
of my contacts disappeared,
so you're the one
who pays the debt.
Black lives matter!
Supe lives matter,
fucking ingrates!
Stop!
[doctor] Nathan
will never walk away.
- What the fuck?
- [Butcher] Crimson Countess.
Your lover boy's
on his way here.
How much did the Russians
pay you?
- They didn't.
- I loved you.
I hated you. We all did.
[explosion]
You're teaming up
with a murderer.
Please don't go.
[inhales]
[sighs] Past few days have
got me feeling a little, um...
well, philosophical.
Uh, these Supervillain attacks,
they've affected everyone.
Doesn't matter who you are,
where you're from.
We're all in this together.
And together, we can imagine
a better world.
[chuckles]
♪ Imagine there's no heaven ♪
♪ It's easy if you try ♪
♪ No hell below us ♪
♪ Above us, only sky ♪
[both] ♪ Imagine
all the people ♪
♪ Living for today ♪
♪ Ah, ah, ah-ah-ah ♪
♪ You may say I'm a dreamer ♪
♪ But I'm not the only one ♪
♪ I hope someday
you will join us ♪♪
[explosion]
Stop.
Deep. [sighs]
Is there anyone else that can
operate this thing? Seriously.
Ashley thought we should
get rid of most of them.
- What? You fired them.
- Here, I found it. I found it.
Okay.
Stop.
Zoom in.
Soldier Boy.
[Deep] No, that's impossible.
He died, like,
- 40 years ago.
- Someone's cosplaying?
Look at his face. It's him.
- Or maybe CGI.
- It is not CGI.
You don't even know
what CGI stands for.
[Deep] It stands for "blow me."
[Ashley] I don't understand.
Where has he been?
Why did he kill
Crimson Countess?
I mean, the two
were, like, fucking
Kurt and Goldie.
All right, you know what?
This is fine. This is fine.
We dominate the news cycle.
I will call Haberman.
We'll message that we got
Soldier Boy
totally under control.
Shut up.
You want to tell the world
that Soldier Boy,
hero of heroes,
is back from the fucking dead
and blowing up Midtown?
Before me, he was Vought.
His statue's in front
of the fucking building, Ashley.
Oh, my God,
if this gets out...
company's fucked. I'm fucked.
Oh, God. If the company falls,
I fall.
Oh, fuck.
Oh, God. Why is this
happening to me?
This isn't fair.
This is so fucking unfair.
Okay.
I'll handle this.
I'm gonna find him and kill him.
You bury it. All of it.
The footage, no one sees it.
He fucks it up, it's your head.
Noir.
[sighs]
Why would he kill
Crimson Countess?
He was your team leader,
you have any idea?
[sighs]
I'm really glad to have you
with me on this one, pal.
[sighs] Seriously. You're
the only one I can count on.
[elevator bell dings]
[screams]
- Uh... thank you.
- [elevator bell dings]
[whimpers]
[Hughie] What the hell?
Where's the Chop Socky
Oriental Sauce?
They don't have that anymore.
Why the fuck not?
Uh, many... many good reasons.
Did you get the other shit?
Here you go, guv.
Oh.
Man, I missed bennies.
It's how we won D-Day, you know.
We were wired
to the fucking gills.
[Butcher] Listen,
let's have a little chat
about this team-up, yeah?
Yeah, what the hell
do I need a team for?
The last one handed me
to the Reds.
And we got you out
of that little pickle.
We wrapped up Crimson Countess
and delivered her like
a fucking Christmas turkey,
and I even sorted
Gunpowder for you.
[Soldier Boy] Why am I supposed
to be impressed with that?
That's like killing
Emmanuel Lewis. [chuckles]
[snorts]
[Butcher] Yeah, well, he grew up
a bit since you last saw him.
- [sighs]
- Hands off the fucking shield.
- Mm.
- [Butcher] Anyway,
you want payback on Payback,
don't you?
Well, it just so happens
that we
are experts at exterminating
shitbag Supes.
You see, it's a whole different
world out there now, son.
We're here to help you
find your way.
Well, I can find them on my own.
Uh, are you sure?
I mean, do you know
what a GPS is?
Or-or Bluetooth? Or, I mean...
[chuckles] ...the internet?
You made those words up.
No. No. No,
those are real words, um,
and-and you need those
to find them.
All right? You need us.
Kid's right.
And all we ask in return
is that you add
one more name to the list.
Who?
A right cunt named Homelander.
I've seen pictures.
Who is he?
He's the new you.
No one's the new me, pal.
But why him?
Let's just say you're not
the only one wants payback.
Hm. Hm.
All right.
You help me find
the rest of my team,
and I'll help you
with this Homelander.
[grunts]
[snorts]
[indistinct P.A. announcement]
♪ ♪
[chatter, laughter]
[both grunting]
[grunts]
[Starlight] So, you think
that Soldier Boy
is going after
the rest of Payback?
Countess wasn't strong enough
to fuck him over on her own.
She had help.
Soldier Boy's
just getting started.
[Starlight] Do you know
where any of them are?
[Mother's Milk] Those
shady-ass TNT Twins
got an address in Vermont.
- Okay. Does Butcher have it?
- No,
but he'll get it.
I think Soldier Boy
is bulletproof.
This ain't for Soldier Boy.
Look, I'm pissed
at those guys, too,
but we have to keep
our heads on.
Why? Why do I always
have to take the high road?
You know, when
white folks get mad,
y'all motherfuckers go berserk,
but I got to turn
the other cheek?
Fuck the high road,
fuck Butcher, and fuck Hughie.
Hughie is not himself right now.
Hughie is a grown-ass man
that's made his own choices.
M.M.!
Please. Soldier Boy
is gonna kill more people.
I mean, fuck.
Kimiko is in the hospital.
She lost her powers.
Frenchie isn't answering,
Alex is dead,
and Maeve...
We're all we've got.
It's up to us.
[cell phone ringing]
- Shit.
- [cell phone clicks]
This is Starlight.
Yeah, of course, Ashley.
I'll be right there.
I got to go up
to the Tower for a little bit.
Now?
If I don't go, they're
gonna know something's up.
I'll be one hour.
Do I need to worry about you?
Okay.
[door opens]
[narrator] Even the
greatest trees
must grow from a single seed.
Follow one proud
Black man's journey
to the root of his roots,
as he takes the
A-Train to Africa.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Hey.
It looks great.
Man, there's so much strength
in dignity.
What are you doing
about Blue Hawk?
Okay, first of all,
everyone at Vought
is just heartbroken over
your brother's tragic accident.
It wasn't an accident.
Blue Hawk went apeshit
for no reason.
Well, he said
he felt threatened.
- Threatened?
- Mm-hmm.
By what, a room
full of Black people
with no superpowers?
Look, I've scheduled him
for 12 weeks
of sensitivity training.
Fuck that.
I want charges brought.
Okay, A-Train,
persecuting Blue Hawk
will only make things worse.
This is a time for healing.
I don't give a shit.
I thought we got rid
of the Nazis around here.
[sighs] Vought rejects racism
- and Nazism
unequivocally. Okay?
- Hmm.
Now, uh, can we talk
about this later?
I have a lot going on today.
Thank you.
You know, whatever.
I don't need you.
I'll just ping his chip,
go get his ass myself.
No. Homelander wants
everyone to present
a united front right now.
My brother is paralyzed.
I want some fucking justice.
Seriously? Justice?
- Yeah.
- You want justice?
- [grunts]
Oh, fuck.
I have spent over 100 hours
in crisis management meetings
specifically figuring out
how to cover up your bullshit--
including all three
of your straight-up murders--
while you were out
in the club with your crew,
or getting your toe sucked
by Popclaw,
who, let's not forget,
you also murdered.
Yeah, that's right.
I know about that.
You did not give a shit
about all the collateral
you caused then.
Now, all of a sudden, you care
because it happened to you?
Go fuck yourself.
Yeah, that's right.
I said that.
Out loud.
- [door closes]
- [Deep] Homelander.
- What?
- Couple things. Uh...
Noir, he's, uh, he's gone.
What do you mean, he's gone?
He cut out his tracking chip.
No, he-he-he...
He-he wouldn't. Not Noir.
He wouldn't run.
Well...
He wouldn't do that to me.
He w... he wouldn't run.
Tell him...
what we figured out.
Right.
We think Crimson Countess
was just the start.
We think... he's going after
his whole team, including Noir.
The good news is,
that means we know
where he's probably headed next.
The twins. TNT.
They're the closest. Vermont.
Okay.
Okay? Really?
Homelander, thank you so much.
Shh, shh, shh.
You go there,
and you check it out.
- Yeah.
- And if Soldier Boy
does show up,
then, uh...
- you call me.
- [Deep] Yeah.
Uh...
- what should I tell the twins?
- I don't give a fuck.
Got it.
Babe, that was amazing.
Yeah, but, you know, I didn't
need you to jump in there
like that.
I had the whole thing.
Hey, hey. [scoffs]
I'm just trying to help. Okay?
We're in this together, right?
Okay. Right.
Right. [chuckles]
[Deep sighs]
Why the long face, tiger?
What if I can't handle him?
I mean, if Noir ran...
Oh, you can handle him.
You're the top
of the food chain.
Hey, hey.
When we were kids,
alone in the bad room,
I got us through it, right?
Don't I always?
- Always.
- No matter what.
No matter what.
And now,
I'll get us through this.
Just as long as you and me
stick together.
But... what if Edgar's right?
What if it was a mistake
to take over Vought?
And-and...
and I am just talent,
and they all know I'm a fraud.
What do you care what
a bunch of mud people think?
[stammers]
Come on.
Tell me the real reason.
I want to hear you say it.
- Say it!
- I want them to love me.
Yahtzee!
Only it never seems
to work out, does it?
Madelyn, Maeve, Stormfront,
even your own son.
So why do you keep
running headfirst
into the same brick wall?
I don't know.
Pants on fire. You know.
It's because, deep down,
there's a part of you
that is still...
human.
- No.
- Mm-hmm. Part of you is.
- Mm-mm.
- A dirty, shriveled,
anemic little part of you
that still mewls
for approval, and love,
and a mommy, and a daddy,
and a boo-hoo-hoo.
Look at me, tiger.
Look at me.
We got to cut that part
of you out like a cancer.
And then, well,
then, my boy, you can finally be
who you were always meant to be.
Pure. Clean.
Like marble.
[grunts]
These people would rather die
than be Soviet slaves.
It's too late.
Afghanistan is ours.
Wrong. It's free.
And I'll stand by our mujahideen
brothers until the end.
You know what else I'll do?
What?
I'll distract you.
[both] TNT! Detonate!
[screams]
[Soldier Boy] These
fucking twins.
You know they couldn't hit
their fucking marks?
Fucking unprofessionals
is what they are.
Hey, uh, yeah,
Butcher's gonna find them.
Why don't you, uh,
why don't you get some sleep?
Mm, no. I've slept enough.
[sighs]
- [upbeat jingle playing]
- [announcer] Dads. We know
you love taking
your babies everywhere.
No matter where you go,
Starlight Diapers...
Do men really walk
around like that?
Yeah. I mean, dads do.
Okay, well... [chuckles]
Bill Cosby
is America's dad, and,
tell you one thing,
he wouldn't be caught dead
in that pussy gear.
Lot to unpack there. Uh...
The Cos. That's a real man.
[chuckles] Holy shit,
did he make some strong drinks.
[whispers] Holy fucking shit.
But, seriously,
what passes as a man today?
Christ on a cross.
I read that we were ass up
in Afghanistan.
The fuck is up with that?
Those were the good guys.
- I mean, when I left,
it was, uh...
- Yeah, you know...
I mean, goddamn it. We-we were
ten and one, you know?
I lead the 116th
onto Omaha Beach.
I was in the fucking
Eagle's Nest.
I fought for this country.
[Geiger counter crackling]
And what did I get for it?
Forgotten.
Left to rot by my own team.
[chuckles]
You know, I wanted
some rug rats of my own,
with Countess. Yeah.
Ain't that a bitch.
You know, couple of little boys.
Raise them up
to be men.
Now... [smacks lips]
...now I got nothing.
Hey, um,
can I ask you something?
What happened in Midtown?
I don't know.
I mean, your team wasn't there,
so did someone do anything,
or say something...
- I said I don't know.
- Okay. Okay, yeah.
♪ ♪
I blacked out.
About ten minutes.
When I came to,
the damage was done.
I didn't mean to hurt
those people.
I'm not a bad guy.
But that won't happen again...
right?
Only if they got it coming.
[door opens]
Oi, oi.
You're bleeding.
Not mine. Got an address.
We're off to Vermont.
[Tommy] Lord of the Seven Seas.
Wow.
My man, I'm such
an incredible fan.
Jesus, Tommy. Slather his balls
in peanut butter, why don't you?
Sorry. My sister's
a goddamn bitch.
And, uh, TNT.
Right. I'm a big fan
of yours, too.
Cool outfits.
Always felt you got railroaded
with that Starlight thing,
by the way.
You know, like, what,
nowadays, you can't even
pay a lady a compliment.
- I know, right?
- You're disgusting.
Anyway, we are just
so pleased, you know,
have a big star such as yourself
grace our humble soiree.
You guys having a party?
[dance music playing
in distance]
[chatter, laughter]
Wait, is this...?
This is Herogasm.
[moaning]
[Starlight sighs,
clears throat]
I'm really glad you're here.
I missed you.
- Who's joining us?
- They didn't tell you?
Hey, there.
[chuckles] Hey, lady.
[bell rings]
The mayor can say
anything she wants,
but Homelander
is the one working
- to catch the guy.
- Mm.
We're about to turn
a corner here.
Absolutely, we are.
- Thank you, honey.
- Of course, sweetheart.
- That's reassuring.
- [chuckles]
But there are 19 dead
and dozens wounded.
Congresswoman Neuman,
what do you say to the Americans
who are watching right now
- and feeling scared?
- Yeah, look,
it's understandable...
What kind of
a-a nasty question is that?
Oh, no, it's fine.
I'm happy to answer...
Starlight just said,
and I keep saying,
this is not a problem. [sighs]
I'm sorry, sir, I didn't mean...
[Homelander] I don't have time
for your mediocre ambush.
Your job is to report facts,
not attack us when we sit here
and tell you the truth.
The American people, they know.
They know when someone's
telling them facts,
and they know when the media
is lying to them.
There is no problem.
It is safe to go out. Period.
You know what? We're done here.
[whispers] Stupid fucking hack.
Up next, Chuck makes empanadas
with Rachel Ray.
We'll be right back.
- [woman] And we're clear.
- [bell rings]
[Ashley] You fucking amateur.
The next report
you're gonna be doing
is inside my fucking asshole,
you piece of shit.
Hey, uh, you free
for a little catch-up?
You know what? I'm-I'm
a little slammed right now.
Oh, come on.
Ten minutes won't kill you.
Hey, so, uh, where's Hughie?
Oh, he's just camping
with his dad
for a couple of days.
[laughs] Okay. Okay, good.
Oh, great. I thought
he was avoiding me
- or something, you know...
- No, no.
...'cause he was scared
I was gonna pop his head.
[swallows]
Hmm?
Come on, Annie.
Put them away.
I'm not gonna hurt you
or Hughie or your families.
Besides, you'd lose.
Then why are you here?
Because I want to help you.
Huh. Help.
From the psycho
who blew up Congress.
Look, most of those guys
passed around deepfakes of me
on the House floor
blowing bin Laden,
so I'm not exactly overwhelmed
with sympathy.
Annie, you need me.
You're all alone.
I mean, come on,
that "hashtag Homelight" shit?
That looks like you're in
a hostage video.
Blink twice if I'm wrong.
And, what, you got to play nice
with the guy
that throat-fucked you
on your first day of work.
And Maeve, they say Maeve
is in rehab,
but you and I both know
she's probably dead.
I'm all you got.
Come on, Annie,
you and I were friends.
None of that
has changed for me.
Are you ever gonna get
to the point?
You have 193 million
Instagram followers.
Lend me your influence,
and I'll lend you mine.
I can protect you
from Homelander.
You'll finally
be team captain for real.
And in return, you help me
goose my numbers.
I can finally get
my education reform bill passed.
We can make things
better, Annie.
For my daughter,
for a lot of daughters.
Come on, what do you say?
You're right.
This whole place.
I'm so fucking tired...
...of listening
to people tell me
I need to be shitty
in order to win.
Fuck you.
And fuck Homelander,
and fuck Vought
and this
"whatever it takes" crap.
You're just gonna end up
sitting on top
of the steaming pile of shit
that you built.
I'm done.
I'm fucking done.
I'm not doing it anymore.
You're not gonna be
doing anything
if Homelander kills you.
Yeah, maybe.
But then I'll know I'm not
working with a fucking nutjob.
So, either pop my head
or get the hell out.
Hey, keep this between us?
It'd be really tough to take out
America's sweetheart,
but not impossible.
[door opens]
[door closes]
I'm so sorry.
[Frenchie] No.
[grunting]
[panting] No. S'il vous plait,
no. Don't do this.
His body is a masterpiece, no?
[inhales]
Do you know the story
behind this one? [exhales]
Oh, years ago, my cousin Kolya
went State's witness, so
I send my Serge. Not even three
bullets could stop
my attack dog.
Bar fight on the Basque coast.
He started it.
Oh, my beast.
This is my favorite.
When Serge was
14 years old,
he dropped a glass.
His father told him
to kneel in the shards
and not move until he said so.
Little Serge
did not shift an inch,
not even after his father left
to get drunk
and pass out in the whorehouse.
Oh, please, don't cry for Serge.
He likes to be told what to do.
And he loves to be punished
when he's bad.
Makes him hard.
No.
So... Cherie...
- No.
- [Little Nina] ...or Kimiko?
[Frenchie] No, don't do it.
Don't do this! Nina!
[Little Nina] You must
choose, Serge.
If not, I will kill
both of them,
and when you've finished
screaming, crying,
I will kill you, too.
[speaking French]
- Choose.
- No.
- [gunshot]
- [screams]
- Fuck.
- [gasps]
- [gunfire]
- [Frenchie shouts]
[grunts]
[panting]
No.
[screams]
[grunts]
- [screams]
- [coughs]
[gasps]
[grunts]
[Frenchie] Kimiko, run!
[Frenchie] Kimiko!
No!
[grunts]
[grunts, gasps]
[pants]
[gasping]
Oh, fuck! [screams]
Fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck!
- [panting]
- [Frenchie] Mon coeur.
Mon coeur.
She's gone.
[panting] Nina's gone.
It's over.
- [sighs]
- [Frenchie] It's over.
Have you always had that?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
[sighs] I grew up in Harlem,
brownstone filled with family.
Grandparents, uncles,
aunts, cousins.
One night,
there was a ruckus outside.
I looked out the window,
and it was Soldier Boy.
He had pulled up on some kids
that were trying
to boost a Benz, and so I run
and wake up my granddad.
"Grandpa, Grandpa.
It's Soldier Boy. Come look."
Soldier Boy takes the Benz,
and he hurls it
through our house,
like a fucking freight train.
It missed me
by about six inches.
And my grandpa...
One minute he was there...
...and then he wasn't.
And I woke him up.
I put him in that spot.
That is not your fault.
[Mother's Milk] That's when
this whole OCD shit started.
I mean, I don't understand it.
All I know is that
if I didn't check the burners
three times a night,
Soldier Boy would come back
and kill the rest of us.
And I'm still that kid.
Still getting up
in the middle of the night,
checking the burners.
'Cause if I don't,
Soldier Boy's gonna come back,
and he's gonna kill my family.
I got to get this motherfucker
out of my head,
and end this.
Or it'll end me.
- [gasps] Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
- Oh, hell nah.
- [Starlight] Oh, my God.
- Invitation?
I got your invitation
right here.
Hey.
Starlight. I did not
even recognize you.
Come in. You are
more than welcome to party.
- Party?
- [Love Sausage] Yeah.
The 70th anniversary
of Herogasm.
- Fuck me.
- Oh.
- Oh, shit.
- Fuck.
You seem familiar.
You about to get familiar
with these hands
if you don't get this
motherfucking love sausage
away from my goddamn face.
Okay, okay, okay.
You are not Supe.
I'm with her.
For the fuck party.
Yeah. Um, mm-hmm.
No, he's very good
at cunnilingus.
Yeah, his tongue
- is just... Yeah.
- Oh, yeah?
He just gobbles
that vagina right up.
Nom, nom, nom, nom, nom,
nom, nom, nom. [chuckles]
- Mm-hmm.
- Love Sausage, huh?
This is good name for me.
I like it. Come on in.
[moaning]
Oh, my God.
Oh...
All right, so once a year,
a bunch of C-listers
get together
at one of their places
- to get they wicks wet.
- [moaning]
- [grunts]
- Stop.
- Herogasm.
- Mm-hmm.
- I get it.
- Holy ass-ramming.
Ew.
Aw, stop!
Holy ass-ramming.
- [screams]
- [moaning]
[female Supe] Come on.
Come on my hump.
That's it.
- [grunting]
- [electricity buzzing]
Poor Frenchie.
He's always wanted to see this.
He's gonna be heartbroken.
[Mother's Milk] You know
what's fucked up?
- Hmm?
- [Mother's Milk] It's that it's
real fucking sex workers here
getting banged up,
and not in the good way.
[screams]
[Mother's Milk] Not that
these Supes give a shit.
When Soldier Boy gets here,
it's gonna be a slaughter.
We have to get these people out.
What up, bro?
What the fuck
did this motherfucker
- put on my jacket?
- Oh, my God. Okay. Um...
It's my favorite fucking jacket.
- Let's go find a bathroom.
- Some nasty-ass shit.
- This shit is sticky.
Let's go clean it up. Let's go.
- What the fuck is this shit?
- Yellowtail sashimi?
No. No, not in the mood
for that. Thanks.
- Goddamn it.
- [male Supe] Throwing ropes.
[gasps, screams]
[male Supe] Oh, shit.
Lick it up,
you yummy brown bear.
[door closes]
I can't.
I need a bathroom.
Right now.
[Hughie] Oh, okay.
So, this-this is an actual orgy.
That's what this is.
[Butcher] Fucking Herogasm.
Still a thing, eh?
It's my thing. I founded it
in '52.
Me and this other Supe, Liberty.
Man, was she a firecracker.
[Soldier Boy chuckles]
Frenchie's gonna be heartbroken
he missed this.
There are a lot
of people in there.
Well, as long as they stay out
of my way, they'll be fine.
Okay, all right. Just, uh,
give me three minutes.
I'll jump in,
I'll jump back out.
I'll tell you exactly where
to find the twins.
Nobody else in your way.
Three minutes.
[Blue Hawk] Soldier Boy?
Nah, he's dead as dog shit.
No, he's not.
I swear,
this is really happening.
Please, you need to help me
get people out of here, now.
Starlight, come on.
Do not let them do this to you.
- [sighs]
- This... this fear.
You heard what Homelander said.
Lamestream media's
making a fucking mountain
out of a molehill.
- Do the research.
- Oh, my God.
This is real.
These attacks are real.
Soldier Boy is real.
Well, I just think
you could stand to be
a little better informed.
Homelander's gonna
take care of it, okay?
I'm gonna go find
a salad to toss.
Excuse me.
[moaning in distance]
[panting]
[male Supe 2] You melted
my cock ring.
- [loud moaning]
- [woman] Oh, Jesus,
your stretching powers!
[Deep] Oh, my God,
your mouth is amazing.
It's like a velvet vacuum
draining my balls.
[Deep] Oh, yeah.
You are so fucking hot.
Oh...
God, your legs go on for days.
- [grunts]
- [squishing]
Ooh. Ooh. Oh, my God.
- What the fuck?
- Shit.
It's not what it looks like.
What are you doing here?
Nothing. I'm not doing anything.
Why would you even...
This octopus was sick.
Why would you ask that?
- Homelander is gonna love this.
- No, no, no. Wait, wait, wait.
Please, please, please. Stop.
Stop, stop, stop. No.
Okay. Okay, okay, okay. Look.
That's why I'm here.
It's his idea.
What's his idea?
I said no cameras
in the toilets, Tommy.
- Give it back.
- You're pathetic.
[Tessa] You know what?
Let's see how everyone feels
about close-ups
of their assholes
without consent!
Fuck you. I'm done.
[distant] I never want
to see you again.
Oh. That's so sweet.
Uh, just, I got to give
my asshole a breather.
You know?
[Tessa] Then say goodbye
to that Westfield mall opening
next week in Poughkeepsie,
'cause nobody
is coming to see you without me.
[Tommy] I fucking hate you.
I hate your mouth.
I hate the way your jaw pops
when you chew.
And I hated every second I spent
holding that clammy hand.
I should've killed you
in the womb.
Ah, fuck you!
Fuck you!
Fuck you, Tommy!
- [both grunt]
- Sorry.
Ah.
Hey, I know you like
fucking Supes,
but I'm off the table.
That's not why I'm here, okay?
You're here, too, you know.
Whatever, Pornhub.
I don't have time
for you right now.
Hey.
You never said you were sorry.
What?
For Robin.
You never apologized for Robin.
Jesus, you want
to do this right now?
[Hughie] Yeah, I do.
You just get away
with everything, don't you?
Just running past all the broken
people you leave behind.
All right, you know what?
What?
♪ ♪
I'm sorry.
♪ Let me see you
shit the floor...
Is that what you want to hear?
'Cause I am.
Okay?
It's fucked up,
seeing somebody that you love
get hurt like that.
I'm sorry.
I'm fucking sorry, Hughie.
[Hughie panting]
- Hughie. Hughie.
- How did you do that?
- Stop, stop!
- No. No, no, no.
How the fuck did you do that?
- I'll show you again!
- No.
That is not going to happen.
A-Train, get out of here.
Not that you deserve
the warning.
Come on. Come on.
Come on, come on.
- [panting]
- Is he here?
He's only here for the twins,
all right?
Nobody else has to get hurt.
You don't get to decide
who to serve up
on a platter here, okay?
These are real people.
We need to clear the house now.
This is about to be
a fucking bloodbath.
No, it won't. I made Soldier Boy
promise not to do anything...
Hughie, stop it. Listen to me.
Homelander is coming.
The Deep told me.
When those two start fighting...
Please. Help me.
- You have to go.
- No. I need to stop him.
Annie. No, Annie.
Annie!
[gasps]
Oh, my God... You teleported me?
What the fuck?
I saved you, Annie.
Jesus Christ.
All I want is to save you.
You keep saying that,
but I don't need you to save me.
Right, God forbid I help you,
because I always have to be
the weak one,
- the one you have to rescue.
- No.
You always have to be
the strong one.
so much stronger than me.
I thought that you
didn't care about that.
I mean, on our first date,
you said that
it didn't bother you.
I know.
But it does.
Sometimes.
A little.
I thought the drugs had
fucked you up, Hughie, but...
...this is you.
This is all you.
[inhales]
Halothane.
What'd you think
you were gonna do with that?
You killed my family.
Which one?
[Butcher] Oi.
Not him.
Twins are out there.
[sighs]
[panting]
So you get Homelander,
but I can't get Soldier Boy?
You're a fucking hypocrite,
Butcher. Now move.
I can't let you do it, M.
It'd be suicide.
[grunting]
[grunts, panting]
Oh, come off it.
What you gonna do with it?
Move!
You're such a fucking idiot.
Can't even work
the TiVo without me.
[cackling]
And there it is, sick fuck.
Hiya, kids.
That poop chute's had
a workout, huh?
Looks like the Lincoln Tunnel.
[Tessa] Ben.
You fucked me, you selfish
piece of shit!
That's enough.
[wood clatters]
- Nicaragua wasn't our fault.
- Yeah, swear to God.
Then whose fault was it?
If you tell me,
maybe I'll let you go.
I-it was Noir.
It was Noir's idea,
top to bottom.
He gave you
to the Russians. Please.
- Noir?
- Uh-huh.
- Yeah.
- Noir wouldn't take a shit
without Vought's say-so.
Please? It's the truth.
[Russian pop song playing]
[Love Sausage speaking Russian]
[Russian song playing]
[grunts]
- Give me your hand.
- It's been years.
Do you want to die?
[both] TNT detonate!
[screams]
[distant explosion]
- I got to go.
- [Hughie] Annie, wait.
Annie, Annie, Annie, just...
You can't go.
I can't?
I'm not gonna let you.
[groans]
[screaming]
[people screaming]
Oh, shit.
No. No.
I don't want
to hear it right now.
[tires screeching]
[woman screams]
[engine starts]
[tires screeching]
Blue Hawk!
- What?
- We got to talk.
Jesus Christ, not right now.
There's a psycho back there.
[grunts]
The fuck?
Get your fucking hands off me.
You hurt a lot of people.
You hurt my brother.
You're not gonna
get away with it.
Not this time.
- [screams]
- Fuck!
[Blue Hawk screaming]
[heart beating rapidly]
[A-Train grunting]
[heart beating faster]
God.
[exhales]
[birds chirping]
- [people screaming]
- Help me.
S-someone please help...
[grunts softly]
[distant screaming]
[panting]
Huh.
[footsteps approaching]
[grunts]
Sorted?
What happened?
William Butcher and Soldier Boy.
Of course.
You are behind this.
This whole thing.
It really is all about me.
William, we made a deal
to fight to the death,
you and me.
This is cheating.
Deal's off.
You were my hero growing up.
I watched all your movies,
hundreds of times.
You were the only one that was
nearly as strong as me.
Buddy, you think
you look strong?
You're wearing a cape.
You're just
a cheap fucking knockoff.
Oh, no, no, no.
I'm the upgrade.
[gun clicks]
[Starlight] M.M.
M.M.
M.M., M.M., please, I need you.
People are hurt.
M.M.! M.M. Please.
He doesn't control you.
We have to help these people.
It's up to us.
[shouts]
You really had me
going for a minute there.
Oi.
What the fuck?
What have you done?
Scorched earth.
[yelling]
[growls]
[grunting]
Do it!
Hughie!
Get out of here!
No fucking way.
[straining]
[shouts]
[all panting]
Let's see?
[siren wailing in distance]
Hey.
I'm sorry.
Hey, please, no. Easy.
We need a doctor
to resew these stitches.
It was always me.
What do you mean?
I blamed the V
for making me a monster
but...
that's not true.
It is just who I am.
No.
You are not a monster.
It seems no matter
how much we try to run,
we cannot escape
our old lives, huh?
I suppose no one
can run that fast.
Those things
Little Nina said about you
are NOT true.
[laughs softly] Yeah.
♪ ♪
[indistinct radio chatter]
This is a bad idea.
Homelander helped make me
America's sweetheart.
He's gonna regret that.
- You ready?
- Mm-hmm.
I'm in Montpelier, Vermont.
Twelve heroes
and civilians are dead,
a lot more are wounded.
Now, Homelander and Vought
are going to tell you
that it was the Supervillain
and that they have it handled.
They don't.
It was Soldier Boy.
I know I sound insane, but...
Soldier Boy doesn't care
about protecting Americans,
and he probably never has.
Most heroes
don't care about you.
They only care about
their image, and...
Homelander is the worst of them.
He's hurt people.
He's done something to Maeve.
I don't know what they're gonna
do to me for telling the truth,
but I'm going to keep doing it,
and I should've done it sooner.
I'm sorry.
And one more thing.
I'm not Starlight anymore.
My name is Annie January...
...and I fucking quit.
♪ ♪