AL
>> HELLO EVERYONE.
HELLO AND HELLO, NEW MEXICO.
BY FAR, MY FAVORITE MEXICO.
SO GREAT TO BE HERE IN THE GREAT
CITY OF ALBACORE.
TUNA CAPITAL OF THE UNITED STATES.
I CAME BACK FOR A SURPRISE RALLY
BECAUSE I HEARD THEY'RE BUILDING
A WALL.
ON THE BORDER OF COLORADO.
TO KEEP THE NEW MEXICANS OUT.
CAN WE BRING OUT THE MAP,
PLEASE?
AS YOU CAN SEE, MOST OF AMERICA
IS GOOD.
EXCEPT FOR THE PARTS THAT ARE
BAD OR LAKES.
I MEAN, WHAT IF WE HAD PUT
CALIFORNIA IN THE OCEAN?
THANK YOU, RAQUEL.
RAQUEL IS A FORMER MISS TEEN USA
AND OUR CURRENT SECRETARY OF
ENERGY.
AS YOU KNOW, MY LYING
IMPEACHMENT INQUIRY CONTINUES.
AND WHAT IS IT REALLY, FOLKS?
>> A WITCH HUNT!
>> AND THERE WAS ABSOLUTELY NO?
>> NO COLLUSION.
>> NO NO, THE NEW ONE.
THERE WAS NO ‐‐
>> QUID PRO QUO.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
NO QUID BRO CODE.
THESE DEMOCRATS LED BY ADAM
SHIFTY‐SCHIFT,
HE'S A REAL
SCHIFF‐HEAD, IT'S A DEEP‐STATE
CONSPIRACY,
AND TONIGHT I'D
LIKE TO BRING UP SOME OF MY LOYAL FOLLOWERS
TO EXPLAIN
WHAT'S REALLY HAPPENING IN THIS
COUNTRY.
FIRST UP, WE HAVE CHRISTINE FROM
LAS CRUCES.
>> YES, I AM!
AND I AM PROUD THAT YOU
ASKED ME UP HERE!
>> UH, I THINK YOU'VE GOT A COUPLE OF
TYPOS ON THAT SHIRT.
>> NOPE, THIS WAS TAKEN VERBATIM
FROM ONE OF YOUR TWEETS,
THEREFORE IT'S CORRECT.
THE WORDS NEED TO CHANGE,
BECAUSE YOU SAID SO, SIR!
>> OKAY, WELL EXPLAIN TO EVERYONE
WHAT THE DEMS ARE DOING WITH
THIS IMPEACHMENT.
>> THIS MAN IS UNDER ATTACK!
IT'S DEEP STATE LIZARD
CONSPIRACY.
AND EVERYONE'S IN ON IT!
THE CIA, THE FBI!
THE M-I-C, THE K-E-Y,
AND THE M-O-U-S-E!
>> OKAY, THANK YOU.
>> NO, THANK YOU, SIR!
WHO'S NEXT?
>> I AM, SIR.
I'M WITH BIKERS FOR TRUMP.
AND IF THEY TRY TO GET RID OF
YOU, THEN ALL OF US BIKERS, WE'RE
GOING TO RIDE.
>> WHAT IF THEY DON'T TRY TO GET
RID OF ME?
>> WE'RE GOING TO RIDE.
KIND OF THE ONLY THING WE DO.
>> RIGHT.
AND DO YOU KNOW WHY THEY'RE
DOING THIS TO ME?
>> I DO, SIR, BECAUSE I WATCHED
IT IN A NEWS MACHINE.
ALL THIS MAN DID WAS SHAKE DOWN
A FOREIGN GOVERNMENT TO GET DIRT
ON HIS POLITICAL ENEMY.
I MEAN, IS THAT WRONG?
>> YES!
>> NO, NO, NO, THE ANSWER IS NO.
>> SORRY, NO!
>> I FORGIVE YOU.
I FORGIVE YOU.
HERE ARE SOME SNICKERS AND JUUL
PODS.
>> YOU'RE WELCOME.
>> SIR, I LOVE YOU, AND I DON'T
CARE WHAT THEY SAY, I KNOW IT'S
BIG.
>> LET'S GIVE ANOTHER PERSON UP
HERE, PLEASE.
>> YES.
YES, HELLO.
I LOVE YOU.
AND I WORSHIP YOU AS THE ONE
TRUE WHITE LORD!
>> THANK YOU.
WHAT KIND OF REAL NEWS HAVE YOU
HEARD OUT THERE?
>> OH, YEAH, WELL, I HEARD THAT
IF YOU READ THE TITLE OF
MICHELLE OBAMA'S "BECOMING" BACKWARDS
IT SPELLS,
GNI MOC EB
WHICH I LOOKED UP IN A
WITCH TH-- THESAURUS,
AND IT'S A
SYNONYM FOR ANOTHER WITCH WORD
SNART.
AND IF YOU SPELL SNART BACKWARDS
THAT SPELLS "TRANS"
SO YEAH,
THEY'RE COMING FOR US!
>> OKAY. OKAY, THAT'S
A VERY SMART POINT.
YOU SEE MY FOLLOWERS LOVE BOOKS.
EXCEPT THE NEW ONE ANONYMOUS BOOK
ABOUT ME CALLED, "A WARNING"
MY LAWYERS TOLD ME NOT TO SAY
THIS, BUT IF I FIND OUT WHO THE AUTHOR IS,
I'M GOING TO SHOOT THEM
IN THE FACE ON FIFTH AVENUE.
>> OH YEAH. AND I'D BE HONORED IF YOU
USED MY GUN.
>> NO, NO, NO. WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
JUST KEEP THAT GUN, OKAY?
OKAY, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THANK YOU FOR COMING.
>> OKAY. WELL, THE EARTH IS FLAT AND
BEYONCE IS WHITE!
>> OKAY, WHO'S NEXT?
YOU, SIR, PLEASE.
>> SO GREAT TO SEE A YOUNG TRUMP
SUPPORTER.
>> OH, THANK YOU.
THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT.
THANK YOU.
>> AND WHERE ARE YOU FROM?
NEW MEXICO?
>> ISIS!
YEAH, I WAS A PRISONER IN SYRIA
UNTIL LAST WEEK WHEN YOU FREED ME,
SO, I JUST WANTED TO SAY,
THANK YOU FOR BRINGING JOBS
BACK.
TO ISIS.
AND I PROMISE THAT I WILL MAKE
ISIS GREAT AGAIN!
>> TERRIFIC.
WHAT A GREAT GUY.
ISIS IS BACK IN A BIG, BIG WAY,
FOLKS.
AND WE LOVE THAT, DON'T WE?
OKAY.
BUT, WAIT, WHO'S COMING UP NOW?
DID SECURITY VET THIS GUY?
>> MR. PRESIDENT, YOU KNOW ME.
I'M LINDSEY GRAHAM.
>> LINDSEY, I'M SO SORRY,
I THOUGHT YOU WERE A SCOOP OF ICE
CREAM MELTING INTO A SUIT.
>> THAT'S CAUSE I'M SWEATING PROFUSELY
ALL THE TIME.
EVEN MY BODILY FLUIDS ARE TRYING
TO DISTANCE THEMSELVES FROM ME.
>> I HAVE TO THANK YOU AND THE
REPUBLICANS FOR ALWAYS DEFENDING
ME.
>> WELL, I AM A TRUE SOUTHERNER
AND I STANDS BY MY MANS.
>> WELL, THANK YOU FOR COMING.
SIR?
>> MAY I DO A QUICK SOLILOQUY
FROM A TENNESSEE PLA--
>> SURE.
KNOCK YOURSELF OUT.
>> OKAY.
I WAS ALWAYS A SHY CHILD.
I KEPT TO MYSELF MOSTLY.
MY ONLY FRIENDS WERE MY GLASS
ANIMALS.
MAMMA SAID, GO TO TYPING
SCHOOL LAURA,
SO YOU CAN CATCH
YOURSELF A GOOD HUSBAND,
BUT I'M
JUST TOO TERRIBLY SHY.
EXCEPT WITH MY GLASS ANIMALS.
>> THANK YOU, LINDSEY.
THIS IS RARE AT MY RALLIES.
WE'VE GOT SOMEONE FROM THE TECH
WORLD, TOO
IN CONGRESS, IN THESE CONGRESSIONAL HEARINGS,
HE GOT
HIS ASS COMPLETELY OWNED BY AOC,
WHICH MEANS HE'S ONE OF US NOW.
PLEASE WELCOME MARK ZUCKERBERG.
>> HELLO.
PROJECT.
EYE CONTACT.
FRIENDLY LAUGH.
>> MARK, I WANT TO THANK
FACEBOOK FOR RUNNING OUR RUSSIAN
CAMPAIGN FOR US.
FACEBOOK ISN'T PRO‐RUSSIA, IT'S
JUST NOT ANTI‐RUSSIA.
>> I'M SURE THAT NUANCE WILL
REALLY REGISTER WITH THE PEOPLE.
>> LOOK, FACEBOOK ONLY CARES
ABOUT THE TRUTH.
THAT'S WHY WE'VE CREATED AN
INDEPENDENT FACT‐CHECKING REVIEW
BOARD THAT'S EXTREMELY RIGOROUS.
>> OH, YEAH, I'M ON THAT.
IT'S DOPE.
I LET EVERYTHING THROUGH.
>> THANK YOU, ZUCKMAN!
>> ANGRY DAB!
>> AND THIS GENTLEMEN HAS BEEN
WAITING PATIENTLY, ALL NIGHT TO
SAY SOMETHING.
YES, YOU SIR, PLEASE COME UP HERE.
YES, HELLO, AMERICA.
>> BILL CLINTON, EVERYBODY!
WHY ARE YOU ‐‐ BILL, WHY ARE YOU
AT A TRUMP RALLY?
>> IS THAT WHAT THIS IS?
I JUST FOLLOWED THE PARTY.
BUT, MAN, I WISH I WOULD HAVE
KNOWN THAT A PRESIDENT COULD BE
ON THE ROAD LIKE THIS, DOING
RALLIES.
CAN YOU IMAGINE?
OH, MY LORD, I WOULD NEVER COME
HOME.
>> BUT, BILL, YOU KNOW I'M
GETTING IMPEACHED, RIGHT?
>> YOU ARE?
YOU DIRTY DOG.
>> NO, NO, IT'S NOT FOR THAT.
THEY DON'T MIND WHEN I DO THAT,
TRUST ME.
>> WELL, THAT IS PROGRESS.
OKAY, THANKS, BILL.
I WANT TO BRING UP A NEW FRIEND
OF MINE.
PRESIDENT ERDOGAN OF TURKEY.
HELLO
>> IT'S SO GREAT TO SEE YOU,
DONALD.
COME ON, GIVE THIS TURKEY SOME
GRAVY.
DON'T WORRY, WE'RE TREATING THE
KURDS REALLY WELL.
>> GREAT STUFF.
ERDOGAN AND I ARE SUCH GOOD
FRIENDS NOW.
>> YES, IT'S LIKE WHEN FRANCO
AND MUSSOLINI WOULD TAKE
VACATIONS TOGETHER.
>> OF COURSE.
SOME PEOPLE LIKE OUR GENERALS OR
VA-GENERALS, AS I CALL THEM,
ARE MAD THAT WE PULLED OUT OF
SYRIA.
>> USUALLY PEOPLE ARE MAD WHEN
YOU DON'T PULL OUT.
>> THIS GUY'S INCREDIBLE.
BUT, AGAIN, I HAVE NOTHING TO
GAIN FINANCIALLY FROM THIS
DECISION.
>> NOW, HOW WOULD HE PROFIT FROM
THIS?
HE'S A TERRIBLE BUSINESSMAN AND
VERY POOR.
>> WELL, NO, ACTUALLY, I'M-- I'M RICH.
>> YEAH, RIGHT, YOU ONLY HAVE
WHAT, 100 BILLION?
>> WELL, NOT EXACTLY, BUT IT'S
DEFINITELY BILLIONS.
>> HE'S BEING MODEST.
I'M SURE IT'S MORE THAN THAT.
SHOW THEM YOUR TAX RETURNS.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR
STOPPING BY.
>> AND WE'RE STILL WORKING ON
GETTING THAT DIRT ON BIDEN,
BUT
I WANTED TO THROW OUT THAT WE
COULD JUST MAKE HIM DISAPPEAR.
>> NO, NO, WE DON'T WANT TO DO
THAT.
>> ARE YOU SURE?
IT'S NO BIG DEAL, WE DO IT ALL
THE TIME.
>> NO, NO, NO, BUT IT'S SO NICE
OF YOU TO OFFER, REALLY.
>> OKAY, WELL THEN, TURN THE OVEN
OFF, BECAUSE THIS TURKEY'S DONE.
>> All: And live from New York, it's
Saturday night!
HOST AND MUSICAL GUEST,
CHANCE THE RAPPER.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN, CHANCE THE
RAPPER.
>> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
I'M CHANCE THE RAPPER AND IT IS
SO GREAT TO BE BACK HERE AT
SNL.
IF YOU DON'T REMEMBER THE LAST
TIME I WAS HERE, I GAVE $1
MILLION TO CHICAGO PUBLIC
SCHOOLS.
AND I'M HAPPY TO SAY, IT
COMPLETELY FIXED EVERYTHING.
NO, HONESTLY, TO THE TEACHERS IN
CHICAGO, I KNOW YOU GUYS ARE ON
STRIKE RIGHT NOW,
I FULLY SUPPORT YOU.
I JUST WISH THAT WHEN I WAS IN
SCHOOL, MY TEACHERS HAD GONE ON
A STRIKE.
LIKE, FOR REAL, THOUGH.
BUT IT'S GREAT TO BE BACK.
AND TO HONOR MY HOMETOWN, I'M
GOING TO DO A SONG ABOUT
CHICAGO, THE SECOND CITY.
OKAY, OKAY, HERE WE GO.
♪ NOW, I LOVE CHICAGO, THE CITY
THAT FATHERED ME,
CALLED THE
SECOND CITY, BUT THAT DOESN'T
BOTHER ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOTTA TELL YOU
I THINK IT'S THE REVERSE
SOMETIMES THE SECOND BEST
IS BETTER THAN THE FIRST
LIKE, I DON'T LIKE GOOGLE
I USE BING ♪
♪ I LIKE FRENCH FRIES
FROM BURGER KING
WHEN IT COMES TO HARRY POTTER
PEOPLE GIVE ME GRIEF ♪
♪ BECAUSE I PREFER
PERCY JACKSON LIGHTNING THIEF
I ONLY DRINK PEPSI
NEVER COCA‐COLA ♪
♪ JIMMY KIMMEL IS FINE
BUT I LOVE ADAM COROLLA
AND ROBIN GIBB
FAVORITE BEE GEE ♪
♪ I HATE MARIO, LOVE LUIGI
BECAUSE I'M THE KIND OF GUY
THAT LIKES THE SECOND BEST
BETTER ♪
♪ I'M THE KIND OF GUY
THAT LIKES THE SECOND BEST
ONE
I LIKE DMC BETTER THAN RUN ♪
♪ BECAUSE I'M THE KIND
OF GUY THAT LIKES
THE SECOND BEST SON ♪
HEY, KYLE MOONEY!
>> HEY, CHANCE.
I WAS JUST LISTENING TO YOUR
SONG AND I CAN TOTALLY RELATE.
YOU SEE, I'M FROM SAN DIEGO,
SORT OF THE SECOND CITY OF
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA.
>> DO PEOPLE CALL IT THAT?
>> THEY DO, YEAH, ALL THE TIME.
>> BECAUSE I'VE NEVER HEARD
ANYONE CALL IT THAT.
>> WELL, THEY DO, OKAY?
NOW, LET ME RAP.
>> OKAY.
>> HERE WE GO.
KYLE MOONEY RAPPING.
♪ NOW ME AND CHANCE
WE LIVE THAT THUG LIFE
BECAUSE
WE LIKE ANTZ MORE THAN BUG'S
LIFE ♪
♪ SENSE AND SENSIBILITY
WAS BETTER THAN PRIDE AND
PREJUDICE
NEVER HAD NINTENDO ♪
♪ BUT I ROCKED
A SEGA GENESIS
YOU KNOW I LIKE SCRAPPY
MORE THAN SCOOBY‐DOO ♪
♪ I DON'T LIKE CHILI'S
BUT I LOVE CHILI'S TOO
I LIKE THE CLIPPERS
THE NETS AND MY WHITE SOX ♪
♪ I DON'T HAVE NETFLIX, I LIKE
REDBOX ♪
>> I USE DHL FOR MY OVERNIGHT
SHIPPING ♪
♪ MY FAVORITE BULLS PLAYER
IS SCOTTIE PIPPIN
I LIKE HANUKKAHS
MORE THAN CHRISMASES ♪
♪ I DON'T LOVE ISLANDS
BUT I LOVE ISTHMUSES ♪
>> WHAT'S AN ISTHMUS?
>> IT'S A NARROW STRIP OF LAND
CONNECTING TWO BIGGER PIECES OF
LAND.
>> AND THAT'S SECOND BEST TO
ISLANDS?
>> FOR THE PURPOSES OF THE SONG,
YES.
JUST KEEP GOING, OKAY?
>> OKAY.
♪ INSTEAD OF STARBUCKS
YOU KNOW WHAT I DO
I GO TO COFFEE BEAN AND
TEA LEAF OR CARIBOU
♪ LUNCHTIME I DON'T HAVE TO
THINK IT OVER
I SKIP CHIPOTLE
HEAD TO QDOBA ♪
♪ SOME PEOPLE LIKE MA$E
MORE THAN PUFFY
I LIKE THE SHOW ANGEL
BETTER THAN BUFFY ♪
♪ MY FAVORITE SHOW ABOUT '90s TEENS
WASN'T
SAVED BY THE BELL
IT WAS CALIFORNIA DREAM ♪
>> I WAS WONDERING, DO YOU THINK
I COULD BE ON YOUR NEXT ALBUM?
>> NO.
>> THAT MAKES SENSE, ALL RIGHT.
TAKE IT AWAY.
>> OKAY.
HERE WE GO.
BIG‐TIME.
♪ YEAH, I'M THE KIND OF GUY THAT
LIKES THE SECOND BEST BEST ♪
♪ I THINK CHICAGO IS BETTER THAN
THE REST ♪
♪ I TAKE SECONDS AT DINNER AND
SECOND GLANCES ♪
♪ I BELIEVE IN SECOND CHANCES ♪
♪ I LOVE MY WIFE AND
MY FAMILY IS TRUE
♪ A MONTH AGO WE WELCOMED
DAUGHTER NUMBER TWO ♪
♪ NOW I'M IN NEW YORK, IT'S
GREAT TO BE ALIVE ♪
♪ I'M BACK FOR THE SECOND TIME ♪
♪ HOSTING "SATURDAY NIGHT
LIVE" ♪♪
WE GOT A GREAT SHOW FOR YOU
HERE TONIGHT. I AM HERE
SO STICK AROUND AND
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK!
>>> LEAGUE OF LEGENDS WORLD
CHAMPIONSHIPS ONLY ON MSG.
>> Announcer: WELCOME BACK TO
MSG'S E SPORTS COVERAGE OF THE
LEAGUE OF LEGENDS WORLD
CHAMPIONSHIPS.
DOUG MILLER ALONGSIDE MARK
LARAMIE.
AND WHAT A TOURNAMENT IT HAS
BEEN.
>>> INCREDIBLE.
TAKE A LOOK AT THIS.
MOMENTS AGO, SHADOW GAMING
ELIMINATED TOP‐RANKED TEAM ECHO,
CLAIMING THEIR NEXUS IN ONLY 32
MINUTES.
>> WHOO!
DID NOT SEE THAT COMING.
WOW!
OUR REGULAR E‐SPORTS REPORTER
JAKE SUSSMAN IS OUT TODAY,
TAKING THE PSATs.
>> GOOD LUCK, JAKE.
>> YEAH.
>> FILLING IN FOR HIM IS LAZLO HOLMES,
WHO USUALLY COVERS THE
KNICKS FOR US HERE AT MSG.
HOW YOU FEELING DOWN THERE, LAZ?
>> UH, CONFUSED.
TO BE HONEST, WHEN THEY ASKED ME
TO COVER A LEAGUE OF LEGENDS TOURNAMENT,
I ASSUMED IT WAS A
BASKETBALL GAME WITH NBA
LEGENDS.
THIS IS NOT THAT.
UH...IT IS A COMPUTER GAME CONTEST.
>> YEAH, A LITTLE DIFFERENT.
>> UH, YES.
I BROUGHT A BASKETBALL TO GET
SIGNED AND SOMEONE IN THE CROWD
HERE ASKED ME WHAT THIS WAS.
SO VERY DIFFERENT THAN THE KNICKS GAMES,
BUT WE'RE HAVING
FUN DOWN HERE.
I'M NOT.
BUT THE CROWD IS.
LAZLO HOLMES, LIVE AT THE
LEAGUE OF LEGOS.
>> HEY LAZ, WALK US THROUGH THAT
LAST MATCH.
>> NO THANKS.
I'M JUST PLAYING.
IN A NUTSHELL, THERE WERE TEN NERDY DUDES
SITTING DOWN AT COMPUTERS WITH HEADSETS ON
WHILE 20,000
PEOPLE SCREAMED LIKE THEY WERE
WATCHING THE BEATLES.
I DID NOT KNOW THIS WAS A THING.
I GUESS E‐SPORTS IS WHAT WHITE
AND ASIAN KIDS HAVE BEEN DOING
WHILE
BLACK KIDS WERE INVENTING HIP
HOP.
NAH, I'M JUST KIDDING, THOUGH.
BUT YOU KNOW HOW THEY DO IN
E‐SPORTS.
READY, SET, SIT DOWN.
>> NOW, WE'VE GOT LOTS TO UNPACK
HERE.
>> WELL, DON'T LET ME STOP YOU.
THIS IS LAZLO HOLMES, SIGNING
OFF.
>> NOW, HOLD ON, LAZ.
I'M SURE YOU HAVE THOUGHTS ON
TEAM ECHO'S ATTACK STRATEGY.
>> I DO NOT.
>> WELL, HERE'S THE MOMENT
EVERYONE IS TALKING ABOUT.
LAZ, WHAT DO YOU MAKE OF THIS?
>> WELL, TO ME, THIS GAME LOOKS
LIKE HOW A SEIZURE FEELS.
BUT I THINK IF YOU KNOW WHAT'S
HAPPENING IN THIS CLIP
YOU NEED
TO GET OUT OF THE HOUSE MORE.
NO, I'M JUST KIDDING.
THAT'S ME KEEPING IT LIGHT.
BUT IN TERMS OF WHAT'S HAPPENING
IN THIS CLIP, I DON'T KNOW.
>> YOU CAN SAY THAT AGAIN!
ECHO TRYING TO DEFEND THEIR
NEXUS WITH TWO HEROES ON RESPAWN!
AND ALL THEIR CC ON COOLDOWN!
>> THAT'S WHAT'S UP.
>> WELL, THEY'RE TAKING THE LOSS
IN STRIDE.
LAZ, YOU'RE GONNA LIKE THIS.
ECHO'S CAPTAIN D-DOUBLEPUMP JUST TWEETED,
CONGRATS SHADOW GAMING.
CAN I BORROW SOME XP?
THAT MEANS NOTHING TO ME.
>> LAZ, WE'RE HEARING THAT THE
CAPTAIN OF SHADOW GAMING IS ON
THE FLOOR.
MAYBE YOU CAN GET A QUESTION IN.
>> UH, LET'S DO THAT.
I AM HERE WITH ‐‐ TURN AROUND
FOR ME.
>> YEAH, I'M NOT GOING TO SAY
THAT.
SO, HOMEY, EVERYBODY WANTS TO
KNOW, HOW YOU GOING TO WIN THAT
LEAGUE OF LEGOS TODAY?
>> UH, WE GOT SOME EARLY KILLS
TOP-LANE, VULCAN IN THAT TWO-V-TWO
IN THE BACK LANE
GOT LUCKY ON TURRETS,
AND THAT FIVE-V-FIVE SIEGE FOR
THE BEACON.
>> THAT'S WHAT'S UP.
>> OH, I AM SO SORRY TO BOTHER
YOU, BUT I LOVE YOU SO MUCH!
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND, I'M
LIKE SHAKING RIGHT NOW!
>> FROM MEETING HIM?
>> DO YOU WANT TO GO BACKSTAGE?
>> OH, MY GOD, YES!
CAN MY FRIENDS COME?
THEY LOVE YOU, TOO!
>> WHAT?!
>> OKAY.
THANK YOU.
>> LAZ?
LAZ, DID WE LOSE YOU?
>> NO, SORRY, WHAT I JUST SAW WAS
SO UNEXPECTED
THAT MY BRAIN WENT
INTO A TOM HANKS IN "SAVING
PRIVATE RYAN" MODE.
LAZLO HOLMES COMING AT YOU LIVE
FROM THE UPSIDE DOWN.
>> THANK YOU, LAZ!
>> WHEN WE RETURN, THE QUARTER
FINALS BEGIN.
>> AND WE'LL BE ONE STEP CLOSER
TO SEEING WHICH TEAM WILL TAKE
HOME THE $7 MILLION GRAND PRIZE.
>> $7 MILLION?
>> STAY WITH US.
HE TAKES
nonsense
AND HE TAKES NO MORE THAN TEN
SECONDS TO REACH A VERDICT.
HE'S JUDGE BARRY AND THIS IS
FIRST IMPRESSIONS COURT.
>> ALL RISE.
THE HONORABLE JUDGE BARRY
PRESIDING.
>> ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU.
BE SEATED.
>> YOUR HONOR, THIS IS CASE
NUMBER 18 ON THE DOCKET.
>> 26‐YEAR‐OLD PATRICIA JONES IS
SUING HER FORMER FRIEND FOR $2,700
AFTER SHE ALLEGES HE
STOLE HER CAR WHILE SHE WAS
ASLEEP AND STILL HASN'T RETURNED
IT.
THE DEFENDANT, 53‐YEAR‐OLD
TREVOR FRISBY SAYS THAT HE ‐‐
>> GUILTY.
HE DID IT!
NEXT CASE.
>> HOLD ON, NOW.
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT, YOUR MAJESTY,
YOU AIN'T EVEN
HEARD MY SIDE OF THE STORY YET,
MAN.
>> SIR, I'VE BEEN A CHICAGO
JUDGE FOR 31 YEARS.
I DON'T HAVE TO HEAR YOUR SIDE.
I'M LOOKING AT THAT RIDICULOUS HIGHLIGHTER SUIT
AND I KNOW
FOR A FACT THAT YOU'RE GUILTY
OF SOMETHING.
>> THANK YOU, YOUR HONOR.
>> WELL, NOW, NOW, WAIT A MINUTE.
YOUR MAJESTY, PLEASE, NOW COME ON.
JUST LET ME EXPLAIN.
>> YOU'VE GOT TEN SECONDS.
>> WELL, I THANK YOU FOR THAT.
OKAY, NOW, FIRST OF ALL, THE ONLY
REASON I'M UP IN HERE
IS BECAUSE
THIS WOMAN IS TRYING TO HAVE
SEXUAL PENETRATIONS ON ME, MAN.
>> EXCUSE ME?!
>> YOU KNOW I GOT THAT MAGIC
STICK, BABY.
>> YOU'RE DISGUSTING.
>> GET HIM OUT OF HERE!
JUDGMENT IS FOR THE PLAINTIFF.
NEXT CASE.
>> PLAINTIFF JUDITH BAKER SAYS
SHE IS OWED $325
AFTER THE
DEFENDANT, HER EX‐BOYFRIEND,
29‐YEAR‐OLD LADENZEL JENKINS.
>> HOLD ON.
YOUR NAME IS LADENZEL?
OH, YOU DEFINITELY GUILTY.
>> THANK YOU, YOUR HONOR.
>> BUT YOU AIN'T EVEN HEAR MY
STORY!
>> WHATEVER IT IS.
YOU DID IT, MAN.
LOOK AT HOW YOU CAME TO COURT.
>> LOOK, YOUR HIGHNESS, ME AND
THIS WOMAN AIN'T NEVER EVEN
DATED.
>> YES, WE DID.
WE HAVE A SON TOGETHER.
>> THAT IS A LIE!
YOU CAN'T GET PREGNANT ON THE
FIRST TIME.
EVERYBODY KNOW THAT!
>> GUILTY.
JUST PAY THE LADY.
LET'S KEEP THIS THING MOVING.
NEXT CASE.
>> THE PLAINTIFF ‐‐
>> GUILTY.
HE'S GUILTY.
>> BUT I'M THE PLAINTIFF.
>> PLAINTIFF, DEFENDANT, I DON'T
CARE.
I JUST KNOW THAT YOU'RE GUILTY.
>> BUT I HAVE A SPECIAL SURPRISE
WITNESS.
>> LET ME GUESS, IT'S THE PUPPET?
>> ALL RIGHT, I'M GOING TO GO.
>> YEAH, WISE CHOICE.
NEXT CASE!
>> A MALE EXOTIC DANCER ‐‐
>> NEXT CASE!
GUILTY.
>> YUP.
>> ALL RIGHT.
CAN WE DO ONE WITH NORMAL
PEOPLE?
>> ANDREW WILSON IS SUING HIS
FORMER TENANT AND COWORKER, JOANNE McCORMACK
FOR A BROKEN
LEASE, STOLEN FURNITURE AND
APPLIANCES AMOUNTING TO $5,000.
>> OKAY.
OKAY.
THIS IS A TOUGH ONE.
>> YOUR HONOR, THIS LADY MAY LOOK INNOCENT,
BUT SHE IS A CON
ARTIST, A LIAR, AND A THIEF.
>> INTERESTING.
MA'AM?
>> OKAY, FIRST OF ALL, THAT'S A
DANG LIE.
HE JUST MAD CAUSE HE
WANNA DO CUNNILINGO WITH ME!
>> GUILTY.
HE WINS.
YOU ALMOST HAD ME.
ALL RIGHT
LET'S DO ONE MORE.
I GOT NIGHT CHURCH IN AN HOUR.
>> GLADYS FELDMAN IS SUING HER
FORMER LIVE‐IN NURSE,
APOLLO
BENZ ‐‐
‐‐ FOR STOLEN CASH.
>> NOW, LISTEN, YOUR HOMBRE.
I SEE THE WAY YOU'RE LOOKING AT
ME RIGHT NOW
AND I KNOW WHAT YOU'RE THINKING.
>> THAT YOU BANG OLD LADIES AND
THEN STEAL THEIR MONEY?
>> THAT MAY BE SO.
BUT I'M NOT JUST SOME DUMB GIGOLO,
I'M ALSO A CERTIFIED
PARAPLEGIC ‐‐ LEGAL.
SO I UNDERSTAND THE LAW.
>> YOUR HONOR, THIS MAN IS A
THIEF.
>> EXCUSE ME!
SHE STOLE FROM ME FIRST.
>> OH, REALLY, WHAT DID SHE
STEAL?
>> MY HEART.
>> YOU KNOW WHAT, YOU GAVE ME
THE BIGGEST AND BEST Os OF MY
LIFE.
BUT I STILL WANT MY MONEY AND MY
CHANDELIER EARRINGS.
THEY'VE BEEN IN MY FAMILY FOR
GENERATIONS.
>> SIR, DO YOU HAVE THIS WOMAN'S
EARRINGS, TOO?
>> WAIT, THESE?
BUT THEY WERE A GIFT.
>> GUILTY! ALRIGHT,
I NEED A NEW BOY BREAK.
LET'S TAKE A QUICK RECESS.
>> IT'S "FIRST IMPRESSIONS
COURT" WITH JUDGE BARRY.
>>> I'M STARVING.
YEAH, I NEED A SNACK PRONTO.
>> YEAH, GOT ANYTHING GOOD TO
EAT JASON?
>> I DON'T KNOW, LET'S FIND OUT.
LET'S SEE, WE'VE GOT CHIPS, POPCORN,
COOKIES, FRUIT SNACKS.
>> AWESOME!
>> CHOCOLATE SNAPS, CRISPY
CAKES.
NUT FUDGIES.
>> SNACKALICIOUS!
PRETZEL RODS.
CHEDDAR CHUNKIES.
>> ANY OF THOSE SOUND AWESOME.
>> GUMMY TUMMIES.
CHOCKO RINGS.
>> THAT'S A LOT OF SNACKS.
>> CORN NUGGETS.
CHEESE BALLS.
>> MAYBE TOO MANY SNACKS.
>> DINGEL DOODLES.
CANDY BEANS.
>> YOUR PARENTS BUY YOU ALL
THAT?
>> YEP.
FIG TWISTIES, BANARAMAS...
>> I THOUGHT YOUR PARENTS WERE
LIKE SUPER STRICT?
>> THEY USED TO BE.
NOT ANYMORE.
>> DON'T THEY MAKE YOU GO TO
CHURCH LIKE TWICE A DAY?
>> NOT ANYMORE.
BUT WE'VE GOT LEMON SOURS, LIME
SOURS.
CEREAL BARS.
>> WHERE ARE YOUR PARENTS?
>> ON VACATION.
ROASTY TOASTIES.
>> WITHOUT YOU?
>> YEP.
>> S'MORES SNACKS.
WINGO DINGOES.
PRUNE POPPERS, MINI MUFFINS,
PIZZA PIECES,
YUMMY CRUNCHERS
RAZZIE TASSIES.
TOPSY TURVYS, JOLLY JAMMERS
LA TOSTADA, MUNCH MIX.
LIL BIDDIES, CORN CRISPIES. IOS
COCOA NIBS.
ROUGH AND PUFFIES.
>> SMELLS KIND OF WEIRD IN HERE,
RIGHT?
>> NO.
CRUNCHY CAKES. LITTLE NOM NOMS.
>> IT'S COMING FROM THE FRIDGE.
>> NO, IT'S NOT.
HI HOS, WACKY TACKY TANGOES.
>> WHY IS THERE DUCT TAPE AROUND
YOUR FRIDGE DOOR, JASON?
>> MANGO MUNCHERS.
CHERRY BERRY BARS.
>> WHAT'S IN THE FRIDGE, JASON?
>> NOBODY IS.
STERS
>> WHAT DO YOU MEAN, "NOBODY"?
>> WHAT DID YOU DO TO YOUR
PARENTS?!
>> TASTY TOASTER TARTS.
>> AWESOME!
>> TASTY TOASTER TARTS ARE THE
TREAT KIDS CRAVE.
>> JASON'S HOUSE IS THE BEST.
>> GOT ANYTHING TO DRINK?
>> NO!
>> TASTY TOASTER TARTS.
KEEPS KIDS HAPPY.
>>> BABY, THIS IS TOO SPOOKY.
LET'S JUST GO BACK TO THE PARTY.
>> COME ON, IT'S HALLOWEEN.
WE'VE GOT TO HOOK UP IN A GRAVE
YARD.
>> DO WE, THOUGH?
TYLER?
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
♪ ON HALLOWEEN, YOUR BREATH IS
TAKEN ♪
♪ FOR TONIGHT, THE DEAD AWAKEN ♪
♪ LISTEN WELL OUR LIVING FRIENDS
AND HEAR HOW WE
ALL MET OUR ENDS ♪
>> OH, MY GOD, TYLER, THEY'RE
GOING TO SING ABOUT HOW THEY
DIED.
>> I KNOW, I'M SCARED!
♪ I WAS A CAPTAIN AT MY SHIP'S
WHEEL ♪
♪ A HEART OF GOLD AND NERVES OF
STEEL ♪
♪ I FELL OVERBOARD ONE NIGHT SO
DARK ♪
♪ AND I SWAM JUST FINE, BUT SO DID
THE SHARK ♪
♪ I WAS A DEBUTANTE, THE BELL OF
THE BALL ♪
♪ MEN WOULD CHASE ME FROM SPRING
TO FALL ♪
♪ I NEVER MET A FLAME THAT I
COULDN'T HANDLE ♪
♪ UNTIL MY GOWN MET A CANDLE ♪
>> WE CAN SKIP ME.
HAPPY HALLOWEEN!
>> IS THAT ALL HE'S GOING TO DO?
>> YEAH, I WAS WONDERING THE
SAME.
THAT WAS IT?
>> YES, SKIP ME.
>> OKAY, I'LL GO, THEN.
NOBODY HAS EVER SKIPPED BEFORE.
I'M SORRY.
♪ I WAS A MINER, DIGGING FOR
GOLD ♪
♪ THEN ONE DAY, I HIT THE MOTHER
LODE ♪
♪ I GRABBED A CIGAR, GAVE IT A
LIGHT ♪
♪ TURNED OUT MY STOGIE WAS
DYNAMITE ♪
>> WOW.
EVERYONE DID GREAT.
AND I THINK WE'RE DONE HERE, RIGHT?
>> NO!
UH‐HUH.
IT'S THE DIDDY OF THE DAMNED.
ALL FOUR OF US HAVE A TALE TO
TELL ABOUT DEATHS BEFORE WE CAN
GO BACK TO OUR GRAVES.
THAT'S HOW IT WORKS.
SO COME ON.
>> WELL, HERE'S THE THING, MY
DEATH WAS A REAL "YOU HAD TO BE
THERE" SITUATION.
IT NEEDS A LOT OF CONTEXT, I
DON'T WANT TO WASTE ANYBODY'S
TIME.
>> SING NOW!
>> OH, MY GOD.
FINE.
I'LL GO.
READY?
♪ ONE DARK NIGHT WITH THE MOON
SO RED ♪
♪ WHAT KILLED ME HAPPENED AND NOW I'M
DEAD ♪
HAPPY HALLOWEEN!
>> WAIT.
BUT LIKE, HOW DID YOU DIE?
>> HOW?
A GHOST NEVER TELLS.
>> THEY DO, THOUGH.
THAT'S WHAT THIS WHOLE SONG IS
ABOUT.
>> IS HE ALLOWED TO BE VAGUE
LIKE THAT?
>> HE IS NOT!
>> ALL RIGHT.
IT'S GOING TO SOUND WAY WORSE
THAN IT ACTUALLY IS.
YOU GUYS KNOW WHAT A 9‐VOLT
BATTERY IS, RIGHT?
IT'S IMPORTANT FOR THE SONG.
♪ AT 12 YEARS OLD, I SAT ON A
9‐VOLT ♪
♪ IT GAVE MY HEINIE A QUICK
LITTLE JOLT ♪
♪ I LIKED HOW IT FELT, SO I DID
IT A LOT ♪
♪ BUT I BUILT UP A TOLERANCE TO A
LOWER WATT ♪
♪ THEN REALIZED THERE'S NO HIGHER VOLT
THAN THE ONE THAT
COMES FROM A LIGHTNING BOLT ♪
♪ SO ONE STORMY NIGHT I WENT TO MY ROOF
AND I PUT A METAL POLE IN
MY ASS ♪
YO, WHY Y'ALL ‐‐
I CAN'T DO THIS RIGHT NOW.
Y'ALL ARE LOOKING AT ME LIKE I'M
SOME SORT OF FREAK OR SOMETHING.
>> NO ONE IS JUDGING YOU.
>> YES, YOU ARE.
LOOK AT THAT OWL.
>> FORGET ABOUT THE OWL AND JUST
FINISH THE SONG.
>> OKAY, GOD.
ALL RIGHT, EVERYBODY REMEMBER
WHERE WE LEFT OFF?
>> YES.
YOU'RE ON THE ROOF WITH A POLE
IN YOUR ASS.
I'VE DONE THE SAME THING MYSELF.
>> REALLY?
>> NO, MAN!
IT'S WEIRD AS HELL!
JUST GO!
>> WHATEVER.
♪ LIKE BENJAMIN FRANKLIN WITH
HIS KEY AND KITE ♪
♪ THAT LIGHTNING HIT MY POLE
THAT NIGHT ♪
♪ I SQUEALED WITH DELIGHT, BUT I
QUITELY STOPPED
WHEN MY INSIDES
FRIED AND MY COLON POPPED ♪
♪ AND MY ASS BURNT OFF AND MY
THING CAUGHT ON FIRE
AND MY FACE
CAUGHT ON FIRE AND I WENT IN MY
PANTS ♪
HAPPY HALLOWEEN!
>> WHAT THE HELL IS WRONG WITH
YOU, MAN?
>> NOTHING.
I WAS A KID, MAN.
KIDS DO WEIRD STUFF.
>> YOU DIED IN YOUR 20s.
>> WHATEVER!
LET'S JUST FINISH THE SONG.
♪ LISTEN TO THE DEAD AND THE
VOICES OF THE PAST ♪
♪ AND LIVE EVERY DAY LIKE IT'S
YOUR LAST ♪
♪ HAPPY HALLOWEEN ♪♪
>>> LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
CHANCE THE RAPPER.
Zanies and Fools
♪ BUT THE WORLD IS FULL OF
ZANIES AND FOOLS ♪
♪ WHO DON'T BELIEVE WHAT
SENSIBLE PEOPLE SAY ♪
♪ IMPOSSIBLE THINGS ARE
HAPPENING EVERY DAY ♪
♪ ONCE UPON A TIME
I WASN'T SURE OF MYSELF
I WOULD ALWAYS CLAIM
I NEVER HAD NO HELP ♪
♪ LOOK INTO THE MIRROR
THE MOST UNFAIR OF ALL
HIT THE PLAYER'S BALL
IT WAS UNBEARABLE ♪
♪ ANOTHER BIG BIRTHDAY
ANOTHER MILESTONE
TO MAKE YOUR BIRTHSTONE
FEEL LIKE RHINESTONE ♪
♪ THE CATERPILLARS THAT HAD
BURROWED INSIDE MY BELLY
STARTED TO FLUTTER BEFORE
I LEARNED HOW TO FLY ♪
♪ I HAD A BUNCH
OF MIDLIFE CRISES
BEFORE I TURNED 25 ♪
♪ THE TEACHERS
PUT ME IN THE BACK
WHERE I WAS
LEARNING TO HIDE ♪
♪ BECAUSE WHEN THE TEACHERS
CALL YOU SPECIAL
THAT'S A PERFECT DISGUISE ♪
♪ I HAD TO BURY
ALL THE DANCING
THAT WOULD BURGEON INSIDE ♪
♪ I GOT QUIET
THOUGHT THE SILENCE
WAS THE PERFECT REPLY ♪
♪ I TURN TO CASPER
ANY TIME A
TURN ON THE SLIDE ♪
♪ UNTIL I TURNED UP
AT THE TALENT SHOW
A PERMANENT HIGH ♪
♪ I HAD JESUS
BEHIND THE WHEEL BEFORE
I LEARNED HOW TO DRIVE
♪ IT'S POSSIBLE
SNL!
♪ ONCE UPON A TIME
A LADY WHO TRIED TWICE
AT BEING A GOOD WIFE
AND GIVING A GOOD LIFE ♪
♪ TO BOTH OF HER LIL
GIRLS WITH BALLERINA TIGHTS
SHE CALLED UP THE RE/MAX
AND OPENED HER OWN SITE ♪
♪ CLOSING OPEN HOUSES
HIRED HER OWN TYPE
ALIMONY IS PHONY SHE
PAID FOR HER OWN FLIGHTS ♪
♪ CRAZY OFFICE PARTIES
SHE'S THROWING THEM INSIDE
AND MY MAMA SEALED MY FATE
WHEN SHE OPENED THE INVITE ♪
♪ THE LADY HAD A PLAN
SHE KNEW IT ALL IN ADVANCE
THE PARTY WAS A GOOD MIXTURE
OF EMPLOYEES AND FRIENDS ♪
♪ SHE TOLD THE PEOPLE
COMING TO MAKE SURE
THEY BRING THEIR KIDS ♪
♪ YEAH BRING SOME FOOD
BUT JUST MAKE SURE
YOU BRING YOUR KIDS ♪
♪ AFTER WE ARRIVED
AND AFTER STANDING AROUND
THE LADY TAKE THE GLASS
AND TOLD US GATHER AROUND ♪
♪ FOR A SPECIAL PERFORMANCE
FROM HER DAUGHTERS
SHE SAID IT PROUD ♪
♪ BUT TONIGHT
THEY NOT MY DAUGHTERS
TONIGHT THEY
DESTINY'S CHILD ♪
♪ OUT FROM THE BACK
CAME THREE LIL SURVIVORS
IN FORMATION
CHOREO TIGHTER ♪
♪ ONE ON THE LEFT
I THINK I MIGHT LIKE HER
ONE ON THE LEFT
I THINK I MIGHT LOVE HER ♪
♪ LADY JUST FOLDS HER ARMS
RUBS HER HANDS
ALL OF THE MOMENTS
LEARN HOW TO DANCE ♪
♪ ALL OF THESE MOMENTS
LEFT UP TO CHANCE
EVERYTHING WILL GO
RIGHT AS IT CAN ♪
♪ IT'S POSSIBLE ♪
♪ ONCE UPON A TIME
I HAD CARATS SUPPLIED
TO A PAIR OF FAIR RINGS I
WOULD SHARE WITH THE BRIDE ♪
♪ EVERY KISS BEGINS WITH
CLEAR CUT CLARITY SIZE ♪
♪ THEY WERE FOREVER
BUT MARRIAGE HAD
AN APPARENT DECLINE ♪
♪ NOW WE LIVE IN FEAR
OF DOING WHAT OUR
PARENTS WAS TRYING ♪
♪ SO EVERY RAPUNZEL
DON'T GOT THE KIND
OF HAIR YOU CAN CLIMB ♪
♪ EVERY SINCE
THEY LOST A SLIPPER
EVERY PAIR THAT THEY FIND ♪
♪ THEY SAY THESE BOOTS
WERE MADE FOR DANCING
LIKE MARY J. BLIGE ♪
♪ WE LIVE A LIFE APART
LIFE SO HARD
LIFE'LL NEVER REALLY
END UP LIKE THE START ♪
♪ WE LEARN TOGETHER
HOW THE BACK DOOR FEELS
AND WE WAS JUMPING OVER
BROOMS IN TOBACCO FIELDS ♪
♪ WE WAS THE SAME
ALL BLACK FOLKS STILL
UNTIL
THE WHITE MAN FOUND OUT BLACK
VOTES STEAL ELECTIONS ♪
♪ SO THEY LEGITIMIZED US
BUT BEHIND US
IT'S STILL BLACK FOLKS
AT THE BACK DOOR STILL ♪
♪ FOR EVERY SMALL INCREMENT
LIBERATED OUR WOMEN WAITED
AND ALL THEY
PRIVACY BEEN INVADED ♪
♪ ALMOST EVERY TRAIT
I GOT THROUGH THE SLAVE OWNER
DARK SKIN BROWN NOSE ROUND
BUT THE BENNETT MADE IT ♪
♪ NOW I WANNA GIVE IT TO HER
SIERRA LEONE SERENADE
SOMETIMES LOVE COME
WITH ITS OWN BARRICADE ♪
♪ SOMETIMES LOVE JUST
GOTTA HOLD MARINATE
LET IT HOLD LET IT WAIT
HERE IT GO HERE IT GO ♪
Well, we must be some zanies and fools
To take a gamble on this love just like we do
♪ IT'S A CRAZY THING TO DO
IT'S POSSIBLE
IT'S POSSIBLE ♪
>>> IT'S "WEEKEND UPDATE" WITH
COLIN JOST AND MICHAEL CHE.
>> THANK YOU.
GOOD EVENING, EVERYONE.
>> WELCOME TO "WEEKEND UPDATE."
I'M MICHAEL CHE.
>> AND I'M COLIN JOST.
>> WELL, IT'S BEEN ANOTHER
LESS‐THAN‐IDEAL WEEK FOR
PRESIDENT TRUMP.
A TOP DIPLOMAT CONFIRMED THE
QUID PRO QUO WITH UKRAINE.
PUBLIC SUPPORT FOR IMPEACHMENT
ROSE TO OVER HALF THE COUNTRY.
AND THEY EVEN TOOK TRUMP'S NAME
OFF HIS OWN SKATING RINKS IN NEW
YORK.
YOU KNOW YOU'RE LOSING SUPPORT
AMONG WHITE VOTERS WHEN YOU
CAN'T EVEN APPEAL TO ICE
SKATERS.
BUT EARLIER TODAY, TRUMP FIRED
BACK AT ALL OF HIS CRITICS WITH
THIS TWEET.
FOUR DOTS.
THAT WAS THE WHOLE TWEET.
AND WHILE YOU MIGHT THINK IT'S A
MISTAKE, IT'S STILL UP ON HIS
ACCOUNT AND IT'S GOT 41,000
LIKES.
FOUR DOTS IS MAYBE THE MOST
OMINOUS THINK YOU COULD POSSIBLY
TWEET WHEN YOU'RE PRESIDENT,
EXCEPT WHAT HE TWEETED JUST AN
HOUR AGO, WHICH WAS,
"SOMETHING
VERY BIG HAS JUST HAPPENED,"
WITH NO FURTHER EXPLANATION.
WHICH WITH TRUMP COULD EITHER MEAN, WE
JUST INVADED MEXICO
OR THE McRIB IS BACK.
BUT STILL, TRUMP HAS HIS SUPPORTERS,
A GROUP OF HOUSE
REPUBLICANS LED BY LIVE‐ACTION QUAGMIRE MATT GAETZ
STORMED INTO
A HEARING ROOM DURING TESTIMONY
DURING THE IMPEACHMENT INQUIRY,
AND THESE REPUBLICANS WERE NOT
HAPPY WITH HOW TRUMP WAS BEING
TREATED.
>> IF A GOVERNMENT CAN DO THIS
TO THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES,
THEY CAN DO IT TO YOU AS
WELL.
YOU NEED TO BE SCARED.
YOU NEED TO BE VERY SCARED.
>> YEAH, SOMEHOW, NOT SCARED.
I JUST DON'T THINK THAT THE
AVERAGE AMERICAN IS SCARED THAT
THEY'RE GOING TO LOSE THEIR JOB
FOR WITHHOLDING MILITARY AID FOR
UKRAINE.
THIS PROTEST WAS SO LAME THAT
HALFWAY THROUGH, THE REPUBLICANS
ORDERED A PIZZA.
AND A REPORTER TOOK THIS PHOTO
AND MY FAVORITE PART IS THIS
STAFF MEMBER'S REACTION WHEN
SHE SAW THE PIZZAS.
IT'S THE KIND OF EXPRESSION THAT
SAYS, OH, SOMETHING VERY BIG
HAS JUST HAPPENED.
>> NBC NEWS REPORTER
ACCIDENTALLY GOT A BUTT DIALED
VOICE MAIL FROM RUDY GIULIANI,
IN WHICH HE TALKED ABOUT
OVERSEAS DEALS, JOE BIDEN,
AND
THEN ASKED FOR A FEW HUNDRED
THOUSAND DOLLARS.
MAN, WHAT THE HELL HAPPENED TO
RUDY GIULIANI?
I'M A NEW YORKER.
I REMEMBER GIULIANI COMING OUT ON TV DURING 9/11,
SO CALM AND
MEASURED AND HE TOLD US NOT TO
WORRY.
AND NOW I WATCH HIM ON TV AND
I'M LIKE, WAIT, DID THIS GUY
EVEN UNDERSTAND WHAT WAS GOING ON THEN
OR WAS HE LIKE FORREST
GUMP IN VIETNAM?
SOMEHOW GIULIANI WENT FROM THE
MAYOR OF 9/11 TO THE 9/11 OF
MAYORS.
>> SENATOR AND GHOST POINTING TO
WHERE THE MURDER HAPPENED,
MITCH McCONNELL
DENIED A CLAIM THAT HE
REFERRED TO THE UKRAINE CALL AS PERFECT,
BECAUSE THE ONLY TIME
MITCH McCONNELL HAS EVER SAID
SOMETHING WAS PERFECT
IS WHEN HE
SAW A CHILD DROP HER ICE CREAM
CONE AND LOSE HER BALLOON AT THE
SAME TIME.
>>> REPRESENTATIVE ALEXANDRIA
OCASIO‐CORTEZ HAS ENDORSED
BERNIE SANDERS FOR PRESIDENT.
DAMN, ANOTHER YOUNG WOMAN
TURNING TO AN OLDER MAN
PROMISING TO PAY FOR COLLEGE.
YOU HATE TO SEE IT, COLIN, YOU
REALLY DO.
THAT'S 0 FOR 2?
>> BERNIE SANDERS ANNOUNCED HIS
PLAN TO LEGALIZE MARIJUANA ON
THURSDAY AT 4:20.
BECAUSE HE LIKES HIS VOTERS LIKE
HE LIKES HIS TAXES, HIGH AS
HELL.
HILLARY CLINTON INDICATED ON A
RECENT PODCAST THAT SHE BELIEVES
PRESIDENTIAL CANDIDATE TULSI GABBARD
IS BEING GROOMED
BY RUSSIAN INTELLIGENCE.
WHILE BERNIE SANDERS IS BEING
GROOMED BY A LEAF BLOWER.
>>> THIS WEEK, PRESIDENT TRUMP'S
ELDEST SONS ATTACKED HUNTER BIDEN IN THE MEDIA
FOR ALLEGEDLY
PROFITING FROM HIS FATHER'S
POLITICAL INFLUENCE.
HERE WITH MORE, FIRST SONS, ERIC
AND DON TRUMP JR..
>> HEY, COLIN.
NICE BERNIE JOKES.
CAN YOU BELIEVE IT, THEY
ACTUALLY MADE FUN OF A DEMOCRAT.
>> DO YOU LIKE THAT, ERIC?
>> I DON'T GET IT!
>> NOW ERIC, YOU WERE RECENTLY
INTERVIEWED ON FOX NEWS?
>> ALL BY MYSELF.
>> YEAH, YOU WERE.
GOD, I WAS SO PROUD OF HIM.
OUR LITTLE BOY IS GROWING UP,
COLIN.
TODAY HE SAT THROUGH AN ENTIRE
MEETING WITHOUT DOING THE
PEE‐PEE DANCE.
>> AND I HAD TO GO.
>> HE'S TRANSITIONING FROM BATHS
TO SHOWERS.
>> I STILL LAY DOWN.
>> AND HE EVEN HAS A CRUSH ON A
GIRL.
>> MY WIFE!
LARA TRUMP, YOUR WIFE.
>> CONGRATS, ERIC.
WELL, YOU'VE BOTH BEEN ACCUSING HUNTER BIDEN
OF BENEFITING
FROM HIS FATHER'S POLITICAL CONNECTIONS,
BUT HAVEN'T YOU TWO
BEEN DOING THE EXACT SAME THING?
>> COLIN, WE'D BE RUNNING THE
TRUMP ORGANIZATION EVEN IF
DONALD TRUMP WASN'T OUR FATHER.
>> YEAH, I DON'T KNOW ABOUT
THAT.
>> WELL, BUT HUNTER BIDEN,
YOU KNOW, COLIN, THERE'S A WORD FOR
WHEN YOU GET A JOB BECAUSE OF
WHO YOUR FAMILY IS.
NIPPLE TEASIN'.
>> NO.
IT'S NEPOTISM, BUD.
IT'S NOT NIPPLE TEASIN', RIGHT?
NEPOTISM.
>> DO YOU WANT TO TRY SAYING
NEPOTISM?
NEPOTISM.
ALL RIGHT.
LOOK, IF THE DEMS WANT A WITCH
HUNT, THEY SHOULD GO AFTER THE
REAL WITCH, OKAY?
JOE ‐‐
>> HERMIONE ‐‐
>> BIDEN.
>> ‐‐ GRANGER.
>> NOT REAL, BUDDY.
LOOK...
LOOK, ALL OF THESE ATTACKS ON
OUR FAMILY, COLIN, ARE JUST
DISTRACTIONS.
THE DEMS KNOW THIS PRIMARY'S A
DISASTER.
AND NO ONE CAN BEAT OUR FATHER
IN THE GENERAL.
AND THE WORST IS THIS KAMALA
HARRIS.
OH, MY GOD.
MY DAD CAN'T STAND HER.
BECAUSE HARRIS IS ‐‐
>> A WOMAN!
>> NO.
NO, THAT'S NOT WHY.
HARRIS IS ‐‐
>> BLACK.
>> NO.
ERIC, SHE'S A BIG TALKER.
BUT IT'S CLEAR SHE'S ALL BARK
AND NO ‐‐
>> WHITE!
>> NO, NO.
ERIC, YOU KNOW SOMETHING, BUDDY,
DO YOU WANT TO PLAY WITH YOUR
NEW PIN TOY?
>> GOT THIS AT FAO SCHWARTZ,
RIGHT?
THE BOTTOM LINE, COLIN ‐‐
LOOK, YOU KNOW HOW THIS WORKS.
YOU PUT THINGS IN IT LIKE ‐‐ OH,
>> COLIN!
>> OH, NO.
>> LOOK, I'M GOING TO TALK TO
COLIN RIGHT NOW, OKAY?
LOOK, COLIN, I'LL MAKE THIS
SIMPLE.
ALL THE LIES, WITCH HUNTS, AND
IMPEACHMENT INQUIRIES IN THE WORLD
WON'T HELP THE DEMS'
CHANCES IN THIS 2020 ELECTION.
THE TRUMPS ARE HERE TO STAY.
AND NOW THE MESSAGE FOR THE
DEMS, DO WE LOOK LIKE PEOPLE WHO
LOSE?
>> NO COMMENT.
THE TRUMP BROTHERS, EVERYONE.
>> I DISAPPEARED!
>> THANK YOU, THANK YOU.
>>> RAPPER KANYE WEST RELEASED
HIS NEW GOSPEL ALBUM, "JESUS IS KING" YESTERDAY,
AND IT'S ALSO
BEEN REPORTED THAT KANYE WILL BE
ALTERING HIS OLD HITS WITH MORE
G‐RATED LYRICS.
SO, YAY.
AT FIRST, I THOUGHT KANYE WAS
LOSING HIS MIND,
AND NOW I FEEL
LIKE, HE'S FINE, HE'S JUST
TURNING INTO AN OLD WHITE LADY.
HE USED TO BE ONE OF THE COOLEST
BLACK DUDES ON EARTH,
NOW HE'S
SHOWING UP TO EVENTS IN SWEAT
PANTS AND ORTHOPEDIC SNEAKERS
LOOKING LIKE KENNY G. AND TRYING
TO GET BLACK PEOPLE TO LIKE TRUMP.
IT'S LIKE, HOW LONG BEFORE THIS
GUY CHANGES HIS NAME TO
KATHY?
YOU MIGHT THINK THAT I'M CRAZY, BUT
ABOUT FIVE YEARS AGO,
THERE WAS A FELLOW NAMED BRUCE JENNER,
AND
HE MOVED TO CALABASAS.
>> PRETTY MUCH ENDED.
YEAH, THAT'S GREAT.
TWO WOMEN ON THE INTERNATIONAL
SPACE STATION MADE HISTORY
WITH
THE FIRST ALL‐FEMALE SPACEWALK
WHICH WAS MARKED BY LIVE
TELEVISION COVERAGE
AND A MALE
ASTRONAUT INSIDE THE SPACE
STATION YELLING, "KISS"!
>>> A NEW POLL SHOWS THAT THE
BEST‐KNOWN SUPREME COURT JUSTICE
IS NOW BRETT KAVANAUGH.
SORT OF IN THE SAME WAY THAT THE
BEST‐KNOWN SANDWICH MASCOT IS
JARED FOGLE.
>> ALL RIGHT.
NAME ANOTHER ONE.
>>> LAWMAKERS IN BOSTON ARE
CONSIDERING A NEW LAW THAT WOULD
MAKE IT ILLEGAL TO CALL SOMEONE
A BITCH.
UNLESS, OF COURSE, THAT PERSON
IS WEARING A YANKEES' HAT.
>>> TO CELEBRATE THE 400th
ANNIVERSARY OF "THE MAYFLOWER,"
A SOLAR‐POWERED BOAT WILL CROSS
THE ATLANTIC.
PERSONALLY, I'M NOT CELEBRATING
ANY SHIP THAT CROSSED THE
ATLANTIC 400 YEARS AGO.
FOOL ME TWICE, SHAME ON ME.
>>> AN ART STUDENT IN NORWAY HAS
TRAINED HER PET RAT TO MAKE TINY
PAINTINGS WITH HIS FEET.
CRITICS CALL THE PAINTINGS BAD,
EVEN BY RAT STANDARDS.
>>> POLICE IN FLORIDA ARRESTED A
MAN IN A LOCAL TARGET FOR
MASTURBATING WITH AN OLAF DOLL.
WORSE, HE LET IT GO.
NOW, I THINK IT'S WEIRD TO USE
AN OLAF DOLL,
BECAUSE MOST
PEOPLE JUST USE THEIR HANS.
>> For "Weekend Update," I'm
Colin Jost.
>> I'm Michael Che!
Good night!
>>> COME ON, JENNIFER.
CHEER UP.
I HATE TO SEE YOU SO DEPRESSED.
>> I'M SORRY.
I KNOW IT'S NOT VERY 2019 TO BE
DOWN ABOUT A GUY, BUT I STILL
MISS HIM
>> OH, OF COURSE YOU DO!
YOU WERE TOGETHER A LONG TIME.
>> LET'S JUST GET MORE DRINKS
AND I'LL WRITE DOWN MY ADDRESS
FOR WHEN I PASS OUT.
>> WELL, THIS NIGHT'S GOING TO
BE BAD.
>> ACTUALLY, JENNIFER, THERE'S A
GUY AT THE BAR AND HE'S STARING
AT YOU.
>> HE'S LOOKING AT ME?
THAT HAS TO BE A MISTAKE.
>> GIRL, HE'S COMING OVER HERE!
>> HELLO.
MY NAME IS WILLIAM.
I'M NICE, BUT I'M ALSO SHY.
>> I'VE HEARD THAT BEFORE,
RIGHT, LADIES?
>> OKAY, GIVE HIM A CHANCE,
JENNIFER.
>> I COULD TELL YOU LOOKED SAD.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO DANCE?
>> DO THEY HAVE DANCING HERE?
>> I DON'T CARE.
IF THEY DON'T LIKE IT, THEY CAN
KILL US.
>> HEY, BUDDY, WE DON'T REALLY
HAVE ROOM FOR DANCING HERE.
>> WELL, WE ARE GOING TO DANCE.
AND IF YOU DON'T LIKE IT, I
SUGGEST YOU KILL US.
>> WOW, I NEVER MET ANYONE SO
CONFIDENT.
>> AND I'VE NEVER MET ANYONE SO
BEAUTIFUL.
>> OH, MY GOSH!
DID YOU HEAR THAT?
HE KNOWS JUST WHAT TO SAY.
>> I KNOW.
I MEAN, EVEN IF HE'S A PSYCHO,
IT'S NICE TO HEAR YOU'RE
PRETTY.
>> I KNOW, EVEN FROM A CRAZY
PERSON.
IT'S 100.
>> AND HE'S DRESSED WELL.
>> HE IS DRESSED WELL.
SO CUTE.
>> HEY, DO YOU BELIEVE IN LOVE
AT FIRST SIGHT?
>> I THINK I'M STARTING TO.
THIS IS CRAZY.
>> WHAT'S CRAZY IS HOW YOU FEEL
IN MY ARMS.
>> I FEEL LIKE I'M FLOATING.
>> HEY, ARE JENNIFER AND HER NEW
FRIEND FLYING RIGHT NOW?
>> OH, MY GOD.
I WOULDN'T CALL IT FLYING, BUT
IT'S DEFINITELY A LOW HOVER.
>> IS THIS WHAT TRUE LOVE IS
SUPPOSED TO FEEL LIKE?
>> I WOULDN'T HAVE IT ANY OTHER
WAY.
DO YOU WANT TO SEE IF WE CAN
MOVE AROUND?
>> SURE.
LEAD THE WAY.
>> HERE WE GO.
GUYS, BE CAREFUL.
>> YOU GUYS DON'T HAVE A LOT OF
CLEARANCE.
>> YEAH, WHICH MAKES ME THINK
THEY'RE NOT THAT MUCH IN LOVE.
>> DON'T LISTEN TO THEM.
THEY'RE JUST JEALOUS OF ME.
>> AND ME, TOO.
>> SURE.
HEY, HAVE YOUR HAD CHAMPAGNE?
>> NO, WHAT IS IT?
>> YOU'LL SEE.
LET'S FLY TO THE BAR.
HERE WE GO!
THIS WILL DO NICELY.
>> I'LL GET THE GLASSES.
I FEEL LIKE
I'M FLYING AMONG
THE STARS.
>> UH, YOU'RE NOT.
YOU'RE LIKE THREE FEET, TOPS.
I DON'T CARE, WE'RE IN LOVE!
AND WITH LOVE, THERE ARE NO
RULES!
WE'RE IN LOVE!
LOOKING RIGHT UP YOUR SKIRT,
HONEY!
>> I AM SO HAPPY FOR JENNIFER.
I JUST HOPE SHE DOESN'T GET
HURT.
>> YEAH, YOU MEAN PHYSICALLY,
RIGHT?
>> YEAH, WITH ALL THE CRASHING
AND ‐‐
>> GUYS, I DON'T WANT THIS NIGHT
TO EVER END.
>> WHO ORDERED A SEAFOOD
PLATTER?
>> OOH YES!
>> THANK YOU.
THAT WAS SO EASY TO MAKE.
>> THIS IS THE BEST NIGHT OF MY
LIFE, AND WE HAVEN'T EVEN
KISSED.
>> LET'S CHANGE THAT.
>> OH, WAIT.
WAIT, WHY ARE YOU SINKING?
WAS MY KISS WEIRD?
>> NAH, IT WAS GOOD.
>> WELL, THEN, COME BACK UP
HERE, WHERE ALL THE LOVE IS.
>> PLEASE DON'T PULL MY ARM.
>> I WANT YOU UP HERE WITH ME.
>> YEAH, I'M JUST GOING TO GO TO
THE BATHROOM.
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
HEY, THIS WAS FUN.
>> SO DO YOU WANT TO CLOSE UP OR
WHAT?
>> YEAH, SURE, LET ME ‐‐ I'LL
GET MY PURSE.
>> JENNIFER, DON'T BE SAD.
YOU KNOW, MAYBE I WAS MEANT TO
BE ALONE.
>> NO, YOU'LL FIND SOMEONE ELSE
SOONER OR LATER.
>> YEAH, I THINK IT'S GONNA
BE SOONER.
>> YOU?
>> YES, ME!
>> JENNIFER MAYBE NOT THE BARTENDER,
>> BUT THERE'S JUST ONE WAY TO FIND
OUT.
KISS ME!
>> WE'RE IN LOVE!
>> Announcer: FROM THE PRODUCERS
WHO ENJOYED "APOLLO 13,"
"AD ASTRA," "GRAVITY" AND "THE MARTIAN"
COMES
ANOTHER FILM ABOUT THE DANGERS
OF SPACE.
>> DADDY, WHY DO YOU HAVE TO GO
TO SPACE AGAIN?
>> BECAUSE THAT'S WHERE I WORK,
SON.
>> PROMISE YOU WON'T MAKE A
MISTAKE UP THERE.
>> I PROMISE.
BECAUSE THAT WOULD BE THE WORST
PLACE TO MAKE ONE.
>> YOU SAID LAST TIME WAS THE
LAST TIME.
>> BABY, WHAT ARE YOU SO WORRIED
ABOUT?
>> I'M WORRIED YOU'LL MAKE A
MISTAKE!
YOU COULD CRACK YOUR HELMET,
SPIN TOO FAST,
PUSH THE WRONG
THING AND THE TOP COMES OFF.
YOUR TUBE COULD POP.
THE WINDOW COULD KABOOM!
>> GOING TO SPACE TODAY.
YOU GUYS EXCITED?
>> I AM.
JUST HOPE WE DON'T MAKE ANY
MISTAKES UP THERE.
>> WELL, YOU KNOW WHAT THEY SAY?
IN SPACE, NO ONE CAN HEAR YOU
MAKE A MISTAKE.
>> NICE.
>> OKAY, NOW.
TEN, NINE, EIGHT ‐‐
REMEMBER, NO OOPSIES.
>> GOT IT!
>> SEVEN, SIX ‐‐
I MEAN IT!
EVERYTHING HAS TO GO PERFECT.
>> WE PROMISE!
>> FIVE ‐‐
>> DUDE, SEAT BELTS!
>> OH, MY BAD.
NICE CATCH!
>> FOUR.
>> IT'S NOT WORKING!
>> SEAT BELT FIRST, THEN GLOVES.
>> I FORGOT!
>> TWO ‐‐
>> WHAT DID YOU DO?!
>> ONE.
>> I MADE A MISTAKE.
>> SPACE MISTAKES.
>> WHAT HAPPENED?
>> MURPHY, HE MADE A MISTAKE,
AND BECAUSE IT HAPPENED IN
SPACE, HE EXPLODED.
>> DAMMIT!
>> SIR, HE BURST.
>> A FILM THAT ASKS THE QUESTION,
WHAT IF YOU MESSED UP
AT WORK, BUT YOUR WORK WAS
SPACE.
>> OH, NO.
>> OH, CRAP.
>> I DONE BOOFED IT.
>> I DROPPED IT!
>> NO, A MISTAKE!
>> WHAT'S THIS BUTTON DO?
>> MISTAKE, MISTAKE, MISTAKE.
>> LEFTY RIGHTY, TIGHTY LOOSY.
NO, NO, NO!
>> MA'AM, IT'S YOUR HUSBAND.
HE MADE A MISTAKE.
>> WHERE?
>> IN SPACE.
>> NO!
>> "SPACE MISTAKES," SEE IT IN
IMAX OR ON A PLANE.
NOTHING IN BETWEEN.
>>> HI, I'M EVELYN MACINTOSH.
>> AND I'M DIANA KRILL.
>> AND WE'RE THE PROUD OWNERS OF
DAZZLE DESIGNS,
YOUR PREMIERE
SOURCE FOR SHOW CHOIR ATTIRE.
>> AS DIRECTORS OF A TEAM SHOW
CHOIR, WE WEAR MANY HATS,
CONDUCTOR, PIANIST, COMING OUT
SOUNDING BOARD AND FASHION
DESIGNER.
>> WHEN YOUR GROUP OF 60 TEENS
IS STANDING ON RISERS FOR SIX HOURS IN THE BASKETORIUM,
THEY
SHOULD LOOK EXACTLY AS GOOD AS
THEY SOUND.
WHETHER YOU'RE DOING A MESSIAH
OR AN ILL ADVISED AFRICAN TUNE,
WE'VE GOT YOU COVERED.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT SOME OF OUR
DESIGNS.
THIS COOL TEEN DRESS HAS AN AIR
OF ELEGANCE,
BEST DESCRIBED AS
AMISH BAT MITZVAH.
GUARANTEED TO HAVE YOUR TEEN
DAUGHTER LOOKING LIKE THE
FIANCEE OF AN IMPORTANT NAZI.
♪ MOON RIVER ♪
HERE TO HELP MODEL OUR MENSWEAR LOOKS
ARE THE MOST TALENTED AND ONLY
BOYS IN OUR CHOIR, THE TREVORS.
>> HI.
>> I'M A BASS.
>> I'M A TENOR.
>> AND I'M A BULLY.
>> OH, BOYS, YOU'RE PERFECT.
NOW, SHOW THEM WHAT YOU'RE
WEARING.
>> LOOK LIKE YOU'RE GOING TO A
PROM, WHERE THE THEME IS
VIRGINITY.
RENT THEM PRE‐STINKY FROM YOUR SCHOOL
AND PAIR THEM WITH YOUR DEAD
UNCLE'S DRESS SHOES.
>> THE BUTTONS LET YOU KNOW IT'S
VELCRO!
>> THEY'RE MADE FOR DANCING,
AND BY DANCING, I MEAN A TERRIFIED
THIS.
>> MMM NOW, LET'S SEE SOME DARING
ENSEMBLES.
CHILDREN ARE GIFTS.
PUT THEM IN A BAG.
WIDE SHOULDER, EVERYBODY BOAT
NECK.
AS A CHOIR DIRECTOR, YOU'LL LOVE
HOW THE SHININESS OF THESE OUTFITS
DISTRACTS THE AUDIENCE
FROM YOUR BOUNCING ASS.
>> NOW, THIS IS A SPUNKY LOOK
BECAUSE OF THE SEXUAL HAT.
AND IT'S GOOD THAT IT LANDS AT
THE WIDEST, WORST PART OF EVERY GIRL'S
LEG.
CAN'T YOU PICTURE HER SINGING A
MODERN HIT FROM THE RADIO.
♪ I DON'T WANT ♪
♪ A PLACE TO STAY ♪
♪ GET YOUR BOOTY ON THE FLOOR ♪
♪ MAKE MY DAY ♪
>> ALL RIGHT, LET'S SEE OUR
FINAL AND BEST LOOK ON THE BOYS.
>> COMPLEMENT YOUR FOUR‐PART
HARMONIES WITH A 22‐PIECE TUXEDO
ENSEMBLE.
COMPLETE WITH POCKETS, BUTTONS,
AND NO REAR VENT.
THOSE FARTS ARE COMING OUT OF
YOUR MOUTH.
>> WE GOT THESE FROM A MAGICIAN SUPPLY WAREHOUSE,
SO SOME OF THE
POCKETS STILL HAVE DEAD DOVES IN
THEM.
>> WANT TO KNOW MORE?
VISIT OUR WEBSITE,
PRINT IT OUT,
FAX THE PRINTOUT TO OUR SON.
HE'LL MAIL YOU A PHONE NUMBER
WHICH IS A WEBSITE.
>> WE ACCEPT ALL MAJOR CREDIT
CARDS, VISA, DISNEY, AND KOHL'S.
>> SO DAZZLE TODAY!
>>> ONCE AGAIN,
CHANCE THE RAPPER.
Handsome
>> "SNL," MAKE SOME NOISE!
♪ BABY I LOOK GOOD
I LOOK HANDSOME
SOMEBODY GON TAKE
ME FOR RANSOM ♪
♪ EVERYBODY ROUND ME
WAS DANCING
AIN'T NOBODY ROUND ME
COULD HAVE NONE ♪
♪ BABY YOU LOOK GOOD
YOU LOOK PRETTY
I KNOW WHY YOU
STOPPED WITH ME ♪
♪ IT'S A LOT OF BOMB
IN THE CITY
BUT YOU KNOW NOBODY
COULD GET YOU ♪
♪ IT'S A HOTTIE IT'S A BODY
WE AIN'T MISSING NO MEALS
I RIDE SHOTTY SHE LIKE FIVE
SOME BUT SIX IN THEM HEELS ♪
♪ I'M A DUCATI
YOU GONNA DO
90 DOWN 290 HUH ♪
♪ KNOW WHERE YOU GOING
KNOW WHERE TO FIND ME
KNOW WHERE TO FIND ME HUH ♪
♪ BIG THUMB ROTISSERIE
BIG TONGUE
MAKE IT SLIPPERY HUH ♪
♪ I GIVE YOU A SEC
I'LL LET YOU
SHAKE IT OUT HUH ♪
♪ NOW LET'S RUN IT BACK
THIS TIME DON'T
MAKE A SOUND
♪ MAKE IT WALK UH
CLIMB UP TO THE TOP
AND DO A SPLIT
AND MAKE IT DROP ♪
♪ YOU LOOK GOOD NAKED
LOOK GOOD PREGNANT
ANYTHING YOU MAKE IT POP ♪
♪ YOU OUT HERE BAKING
HOT LIKE MEGAN ON MY BACON
WHEN IT POP
♪ BABY YOU LOOK GOOD
YOU LOOK GORGEOUS
THIS RIGHT HERE YOUR CITY
I'M A TOURIST ♪
♪ I KNOW I'M A CATCH
I'M A SWORDFISH
GOT ME ON YOUR HOOK, ON YOUR
CHORUS ♪
♪ BABY YOU LOOK GOOD
I LOOK HANDSOME
SOMEBODY GON TAKE
ME FOR RANSOM
♪ EVERYBODY ROUND ME
WAS DANCING
YOU KNOW THAT MY MOMMA
WANT A GRANDSON ♪
♪ BABY YOU LOOK GOOD
YOU LOOK PRETTY
I KNOW WHY YOU
STOPPED WITH ME ♪
♪ IT'S A LOT OF BOMB
IN THE CITY ♪
STALLION
♪ WELL KNOWN
ACROSS THE GLOBE
FROM MY PLAYER WAYS
AND MY SKIMPY CLOTHES ♪
♪ HOUSTON HOTTIE
WITH A MODEL BODY
I'M A BUST IT OPEN
LIKE A CENTERFOLD ♪
♪ BAD CHICK WITH A LOT
OF OPTIONS YEAH
AFTER ME IT'S REALLY HARD
TO TOP IT HEY ♪
♪ SHE DON'T LIKE TO RIDE IT
SHE DON'T ‐‐
SHE DON'T LICK THIS
SHE AIN'T REALLY WIFEY ♪
♪ ALL THAT TALKING
YOU KNOW THAT EXCITE ME
♪ AND I KNOW THAT MEAN
YOU LOVE ME WHEN
YOU TELL ME YOU
DON'T LIKE ME AY ♪
♪ AND I KNOW YOU NEED SOME
WHEN YOU ARGUE AND WE FIGHTIN
DON'T ‐‐ KEEP YOU POPPIN ♪
♪ BABY YOU LOOK GOOD
YOU LOOK HANDSOME HANDSOME
RICH PUT THAT ‐‐ UP
FOR SOME RANSOM ♪
♪ BEFORE I LET YOU GO
I HAD TO HAVE SOME
♪ RICH SO YOU KNOW
I GOT MY BANDS UP AHH ♪
♪ BABY I LOOK GOOD
I LOOK HANDSOME
SOMEBODY GON TAKE
ME FOR RANSOM
♪ EVERYBODY ROUND ME
WAS DANCING
YOU KNOW THAT MY MAMA NEED A
GRANDSON.
♪ BABY YOU LOOK GOOD
YOU LOOK PRETTY
I KNOW WHY YOU
STOPPED WITH ME ♪
♪ IT'S A LOT OF BOMB
IN THE CITY
BUT YOU KNOW NOBODY
COULD GET ♪
DANCE
>>> ALL RIGHT, GOOD EVENING,
DANCERS!
THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR GIVING
UP YOUR HALLOWEEN TO REHEARSE.
AS I UNDERSTAND IT, YOU GUYS
WERE PICKED BY EARTH, WIND, AND FIRE THEMSELVES
FOR THEIR BIG
HALLOWEEN BOOGIE SPECTACULAR.
YOU ARE THE BEST, OR AT LEAST EARTH,
WIND, AND FIRE THINKS SO.
DO YOU ALL KNOW THE OGRAPHY?
>> YES!
>> WELL, THEN, SHOW IT!
BOOGIE WONDERLAND.
MAKE IT SIZZLE AND STANK! GO!
COME ON.
GIVE IT, GIVE IT!
WHERE'S THE STANK?
WHERE'S THE STANK?!
AND THE WONDER.
WHERE IS THE WONDER?
THE MOON!
I MUST CLOSE THE DRAPES!
THE DRAPES!
I MUST CLOSE THEM.
THE DAMN BACKS!
PLEASE, RELEASE THE DRAPES!
>> THAT WAS WEIRD.
WEIRD GOOD OR WEIRD BAD?
>> I THINK BAD.
YEAH.
IT KIND OF BACKS UP THE SECRET I
HEARD.
>> CAN YOU TELL US, BRAD?
>> HERE'S WHAT I CAN SAY.
A, IT'S DARK.
AND B, IT'S ABOUT TONY SOLIS.
>> ALRIGHT, SORRY, SORRY, DANCERS.
I HAD TO TAKE AN IMPORTANT PHONE
CALL FROM FRED FAKE McMADEITUP.
>> TONY, ARE YOU OKAY?
>> I'M BETTER THAN OKAY. I'M TONY SOLIS,
LET'S TAKE IT FROM THE TOP.
AND FILL TO THE BRIM WITH FLAVOR AND
FUNK.
GO!
COME ON, POP THE FUNK!
POP THE FUNK,
GRIND THE WIND.
FEEL THE '70s.
OOOH, THE MOON!
THE VENETIAN BLINDS!
I MUST DRAW THEM SHUT!
OH, THE MOON!
THE VENETIANS.
CLOSE BABABA!
I MUST FIGHT BACK THE BEAST!
OH, NO!
WRONG WAY!
CAN'T LET THE DANCERS KNOW WHAT
CREATURE LURKS WITHIN ME.
FIGHT THE CURSE TONY.
>> HEY, GUYS, I'M CURIOUS, DID
ANY OF YOU GET A FAX LAST NIGHT?
>> OH, YOU'RE RICH.
>> YEAH!
BRAG ABOUT YOUR FAX MACHINE
MORE!
>> WELL, I DID.
AND IT SAID, "ATTENTION, DANCERS.
IS THERE A FULL MOON?"
FOLLOWED BY, "FORGET WHAT I JUST
FAXED.
I'LL BE FINE."
>> I AM SORRY.
I HAD ANOTHER BUSINESS CALL FROM
DONNY DANE McDIDN'THAPPEN.
>> GUYS, I'M BEGINNING TO THINK
THESE CALLS AREN'T REAL.
TONY, WHAT'S UP?
>> WHATEVER DO YOU MEAN? I'M TOTALLY FINE ‐‐
OH, THE
MOON!
THE ROMAN SHADES!
WHERE IS THE CORD?!
WHERE IS THE LITTLE PULLEY CORD?
DAMMIT, WHY DO ALL OF THESE
WINDOWS HAVE TO BE DIFFERENT
DRESSINGS?!
WHO STYLED THIS DANCE STUDIO?
OH, I DID!
OH, DAMN ME.
THIS IS MY STUDIO!
THIS IS TONY SOLIS' DANCE STUDIO
SLASH WEREWOLF'S HOUSE!
>> YOU GUYS, TONY SOLIS IS A WEREWOLF.
>> WAIT A MINUTE, DID YOU HEAR
THAT FROM ME?
>> NO, THE DUDE LOOKS LIKE A
WOLF!
>> AND HIS FACE IS COVERED IN
FUR.
>> AND HE HAS SOME KIND OF BEEF
WITH THE MOON.
>> AS LONG AS WE ALL KNOW I
DIDN'T BLAB.
>> ALL RIGHT.
ENOUGH WITH THE CHITCHAT!
Y'ALL ARE HERE TO DANCE!
SO LET'S DO IT!
COME ON.
WRONG STEP.
WRONG STEP!
ABSOLUTELY, GHASTLY!
AND WHO HIRED YOU?
>> I'M GETTING OUT OF HERE!
>> HE JUST KILLED TRISH!
>> SUIT YOURSELF.
>> I'M STAYING.
I'M NOT BLOWING THIS GIG.
>> THAT WAS YOUR WIFE, MAN!
>> YO, THANK YOU TO ALEC
BALDWIN, FRED ARMISEN,
DARRELL
HAMMOND.
JASON MAMOA, MEG THEE STALLION
JASON, LORNE, EVERYBODY ELSE,
JESUS CHRIST IS LORD, YOU
KNOW HOW WE'RE GETTING DOWN!
IT'S CHANCE THE RAPPER BABY!
TWO TIMES!
translate