金矿
GOLD
美国 剧情 / 惊悚 / 冒险
We were a real business
That's what you got to understand
We were goddamn industry...
the kind that's the backbone of this country
Don't take my word for it
Go in the parking lot and look on the license
of that brand-new Mercedes 450 of yours
Hey Are you seeing this?
That's furnace creek
This, uh, picture's over 100 years old
Hmm
And you see this handsome devil right here?
Uh-huh
He's a Wells
Okay, so, um, I know you're a mining company
- mm-hmm  - But I pictured...
Well, I don't know what I pictured exactly
I guess little... little carts
going down little...Little train tracks
- Right -I mean, what is it that you do here?
Wh-what we do is we look for the metals
and the minerals, all right?
There's exploration over there
there's engineering and there's production, right?
We're prospectors
Not yet?
- Okay, how about this?  - Yeah...
Um... so let's say that this...
Is the earth
My handbag?
Your handbag is mother earth
with all of her deep-filled mysteries
and goodies on the inside that she does not want to give up
Me, I'm man
and I'm damn curious about what she's got inside
So, I send down what's called an exploratory drill
I go down inside and dig around
come across something
I pull it out It's nickel
Now, nickel's actually 75% copper and 25% nickel
but there's a whole lot of nickel in the world
and the world needs nickels
I'm back down there getting my second core sample
and I happen to pull up, say...
Silver
Now, the thing is, when you find a little bit of this
that means there could be a whole hell of a lot of it
So we start raising money
We raise enough money to open a mine
like the one in that picture right here
Then...
We dig it all up
Now, sometimes...Not that often, but sometimes...
The prospecting gods are having a party at the pearly gates
and we get real, real really lucky
And we dig down in there
then we find a little metal called...
Gold
- Yes  - Kenny
You like it?
I love you
Old man wants to see you
Afternoon, Marianne
Hey, pop Heard you want to see me
Yeah, Kenny
Get your ass in here, would you?
Would you, uh, run through this
Pershing county strategy again for me?
Right, um...
It's about this Southern part of this Newmont property
right here
Now, Newmont just started drilling 140 meters
and they're finding a whole lot of magnesite
If you remember, we still own the option on relief Canyon
which is next door We're not finding squat, why?
We're not drilling deep enough
Let's get back in there Drill deeper
Go to 140 if we need to,and we got a damn good chance
of getting relief back in production
What about Jerritt Canyon?
Well, that's your baby
You know a hell of a lot more about it than I do
But the assays look promising
Could be fucking huge
I want you to run point on this
All in
Scale it up
Make it yours
Yes, sir
Clive Coleman's on board
Those boys will ride with you
God, we work hard in this business
Sometimes for nothing
I wake up every morning I tell myself
"I don't have to do this
I get to do this"
And then it's just blue skies
Blue skies, baby
My old man...
A legend
That was the last time I saw him alive
A little eye-opener, Kenny?
God bless you, Roy
Here we are
- Boys, to the mother lode  - Mother lode
Today be the day
The geological reports on this are highly encouraging
We are taking a very aggressive approach
Prospectus? Of course I can have my secretary send you one right out
But I got to tell you, this offering
it's already over-subscribed
You know, we can always try and get you in on the next one
No, no Yea, I understand
Shit
Watching the time? It's 11:15, Kenny
Oh, Christ
Where would I be without you?
Mr. Wells?
- Yes  - Lloyd Stanton
- Hello, Lloyd Kenny Wells  - Hi
This is my colleague, Henry Andrews
- Pleased to meet you  - Hey
- Come on back   - Absolutely
Thank you
So, what can we do for ya?
Well, why don't we wait for Clive?
Oh, uh, Mr. Coleman got tied up in a meeting
No offense, boys
but I'm supposed to be meeting with Clive
None taken, but if you were supposed to be
meeting with Clive, you would be meeting with Clive
All right Here is what we have
We are developing some very exciting properties
that are spot-on for your investor profile
Low buy-in with a sizable upside
- Mm-hmm  - And the beautiful part is
they are all only 12 to 18 months and cash positive
Manitoba?
Yeah, We picked up an option on a skip claim at an auction
Right, but it's a 90-day option
Yes, the window is narrow
but if you have a look at the Geo
you'll see a very promising shale formation
that hasn't been tapped yet
Mr. Wells, Washoe has a practical value
hovering just above zero
Your debt load is untenable
and you bring us, uh, raw land with no infrastructure
- no fungible assets  - I mean
you can't possibly expect us to underwrite this
Yeah I'm talking about a small offering here
As I said in the beginning, a low buy-in
Now, if you'll take a second look at the Geo
you will see what I see
And that's money
Not our money
See, the... the thing is
that the whole economy had turned
particularly for commodities
Close of the day
Washoe was trading at four cents a share
if it was trading at all
Washoe mining There's this great little land lease
'Cause this is a once in a lifetime opportunity
Right Washoe Washoe mining
You know, carrying the... Carrying on the business
You know, there's still minerals out there
We just got to find them, right?
Yeah, all right, all right, thank... thank you for your time Bye
I could...
12 to 18 months...
Cash positive
A deal...
Goddamn, I am calling you
Fuck whatever time it is
Washoe mining
the company that my grandfather
literally scratched out of the side of a Nevada mountain
the company that my father made into a real player
was almost gone
Almost
I'd already, uh, lost my house
and I was, uh... I was living with Kay
And, uh, we-we were about to lose that, too
I had a half gallon of Seagram's in me
Shit, most people would have been dead, but not me No
Instead...
I had a dream
I mean, I mean, I mean, literally, I...
Indonesia
Gold
Now, I'd been to Indonesia five or six years earlier
I still had a little money in my pocket
You know, Indonesia was booming
and I was looking for a way to get in
Back then, if you wanted
to put a hole in the ground in Indonesia
you wanted Mike Acosta
telling you where to dig
He's what they called a river Walker
Yeah, a real hands-on geologist
The real deal
Oxford college, Mit
His mom was Venezuelan
His dad was English
Now, you see, he'd just discovered the largest copper strike in southeast Asia
and everybody wanted a piece of him, including me
You got the Nazca plate, the pacific plate
Juan de Fuca, north American, south American
Aleutian, Marianas, Tonga
The plates rubbing and grinding up on each other
Six trillion kilobytes of pressure
10,000 degrees Celsius kicking up geothermic hot spots
all along the pacific rim
He called it the, uh, the ring of fire theory
And he definitely had everyone's attention
That's how I found the copper
And that's why I'll find the gold
You're up early
Hey
You want to talk about yesterday
No I gotta go right now, babe I've gotta plan Gotta plan
- Oh, wait, Kenny, Kenny, listen   - Hmm?
Carl had an idea
- American home Carl?  - Uh-huh
He said he could, uh, get you on for a while
- if you wanted    - Right, right, right, right
Yeah, I don't think that's going to be necessary, babe
Yeah, but it'd just be temporary
till the market turns
We could fool around in the warehouse
You know, I tell you...
When I get done with this trip, all right?
Shouldn't take more than a week
- All right  - What? Where you going?
- If it doesn't work out, I'll give Carl a call - Baby...
- I'll call you from the airport  - Wait Wait, wait...Kenny!
It was like I was being called, you know?
It was the gold calling
That may sound crazy to you
but if you... If you knew that feeling
well, you'd know
Kenny Wells I'm down here in the, uh
the lobby of the, uh, Jakarta palace
Uh... yeah, listen
we must've got the times mixed up
Um... let me know I'm down here
I'm in the brown suit, I'm on the green couch
I'm the good-looking guy, okay?
All right, We'll make it happen, Cap'n
All right
Wells?
Mike
Good to see you again
I know a local place, a bit more color
What, they're not pouring here?
- Good
So
what are we talking about here, Wells?
Ring of fire, Mike
Ring of fire
You're playing my greatest hits
Fire's gone out of that one
Well, what are you talking about?
It's the opinion of my fellow esteemed geologists
that the whole thing... I'm quoting here...
Is a crock of shit
Well, what the hell, you know?
You called it wrong
What are you going to do?
There's no right or wrong in this business
There's only hits and misses
There's gold here
I'm glad you said that, Mike
I truly am, 'cause I...
believe you
I hate to dash your hopes, but don't you think
others have come along before you with the same thought
and, from the looks of it, deeper pockets?
Ring of fire is real, Mike
I knew it the first time I heard
It struck me like a fucking lightning bolt
and I never forgot it
Go ahead, laugh I get that all the time
But hear this
I don't just believe
I know
- No, you don't  - I've seen it
You don't understand
- No one will back me  - I will
You tell me where you want to dig, Mikey
and I'll make goddamn sure the bills are paid
No offense, Wells, but...
You look like you had to rob someone just to get here, man
You know nothing about me
You know it's still out there
I know that
I can see it in your eyes You still believe
I get it, and I was born on the side of the mountain, too
My-my father scratched everything he ever owned
out of a fucking rock All right?
Died with dirt under his fingernails
and I intend to do the same
This business...
Wrote me off years ago
All right, maybe you're not running the hottest
in your career right now either
so let's prove them wrong
You and me
Let's prove them all fucking wrong
And you know why?
You do know why, because the ring of fire
is right, Mike You called it
You just haven't found it yet
Tell me I'm crazy
I'll be on the next plane
You're crazy
You have a hat, Wells?
Yeah, I got a hat
Why, we going somewhere?
Up river
What river is that, Mike?
You're late
The only one that matters
The Dayak have been panning this river
for over 5,000 years
That's how it got its name
Daya Kensana
What's it mean?
"Daya" means "upstream"
"Kensana" means "gold"
You got to be shitting me
Wells
We're here
So, listen, the Dayak are warrior people
probably best known for Ngayau
headhunting
But it doesn't happen much anymore
They might be thinking we're some traders
or someone's mother-in-law
How long?
This jungle will... will test you
It will hold you up, weigh you
and decide your worth within an ounce
Do you always talk like this, Mike?
Like a book on tape?
I suppose I do
Where are we going?
Up
Take a look
Oh, my god
It's my dream
There have been a few folks up here
tapping over the years
but have all focused on the foothills far to the south
But what interests me is the other way
That small depression
like a giant left a footprint walking away
Something happened there, Wells
Something hot and angry
That's where we'll find the tasty bits
My dream...
is out there
Damn right it is
Look, if it's the big boys
that you're thinking about investing in us...
You know, the Harvard endowment
or some... Some pension fund, right?
I am not your guy
But the little guys, right
guys that you don't even know about
the, uh, the hustlers, the scrappers
the make-it-happen motherfuckers
those are my guys
How much do we need?
Seven Seven-fifty to start
Okay
How much do we need?
It isn't just a lease
We're in Indonesia
That means getting a permit and lining pockets
Equipment, You don't just do this
with a couple of shovels and a pickax
I'll get the money
Whatever it takes
- What's that?  - It's a contract
Read it
Sign it
Keep it
I could feel it in my bones
I was selling something that I believed in
20-k minimum buy-in, right
and the shares are fucking flying off the shelf
I mean, no risk, no gain, right?
No, 'cause it's coming in right now
No, Acosta Michael Acosta
It's the largest copper strike in history
and that's the guy that we got
Kay, get those shoes shined for dancing, baby
We don't even have the exploration permits
What are they selling?
What are we selling?
Mikey, we're selling the story
And right now, the story is you
Speaking of which, what the fuck are you doing right now?
I'm down in Kupang city looking at coring equipment
Acosta's in Kupang city
looking at coring equipment
He's in Kupang city as we speak
It-it's a fucking...
Kupang city We're getting the coring equipment...
You're magic, Mike You're fucking magic
You there, Mike?
Two hundred and sixty-seven thousand
four hundred and thirty-four...
Dollars
That's not exactly the number I had in mind, Wells
Well, look, I may be able to borrow a little bit
against it, but, you know...
No, you know what? Truth, Mike?
Th…that's it for now
Th-that's it Can you make it work? Hmm?
I can make anything work
You work out of a bar, Wells?
Keeping a lid on expenses, Mike
Making the dollar holler
- We're in!
Record player That's classy
Am I paying for that, Mikey?
Six-man crews
12-hour shifts around the clock
Tomorrow we'll start looking at our core samples
Then we'll send the most promising
down river to the assay lab
The mother lode, Mike
You're out there, baby
The man that invented the hamburger was smart, Mike
The man who invented the cheeseburger
now, that's the genius
Don't ask where the meat came from Hmm?
Have you ever read Christopher Columbus' journals?
Of course not
In his petition to the queen of Spain
he promised the conversion
to her holy faith of a great number of peoples
And he went on and mentioned god 26 times
Gold, on the other hand
he mentioned 114 times
Smart dago
I've been wanting to ask you something, Wells
Fire away, Mike
What's the meaning of the tattoo on your arm?
Oh, it's a bird
It's from a poem I read when I was a kid
Bird with no feet...
Sleeps in the wind
Assay!
Assay! Assay!
Mike, Mike!
Hey These things, they look worse every time we get one
Do you remember what I told you about Patience?
Yeah, you-you remember what I told you about money?
- Yeah  - Huh?
- You said that it wasn't a problem  - Well, it...
It's a fucking problem now!
Hey!
Hey...
Hey, wait!
Stay! Stay! Stay! Stay!
Hey!
Stay...
Hey! Stay
Stay!
On top of everything else
I... I got a bad case of malaria
which kills like something like a million people a year
something like that
Suddenly, I was on the list
Maybe... maybe we were pushing them too hard
Maybe we should just take it easy, you know?
Cut them in
You know, give them some ownership
Maybe they'll come back, you know?
Let them know that they got something at the end
you know, when it all works out
Give them a piece of the pie, you know?
Get up
Come on, get up
I'm freezing, Mike
Don't let me die and have nothing, okay?
Get some rest now
I'm pulling the plug
No
No, no, no, no, no
Don't pull the plug, Mike
No, no, You can't do that, Mikey
Let's get you out of here, Wells
What's the plan, Mikey?
Hmm?
Now, I know you got a plan, Mike, hmm?
I know you got a plan
What's the plan, hmm?
What's the plan?
They need clean water
If we get filter systems up here
I think they might come back
I got about $1,800 on this visa right there
Close to 500 on this diner's club
Use it all, hmm?
Use it all, Mikey
Damned if he didn't go
to every single place
that every one of our workers lived
Streams that had no name
All feeding the great Kensana river
Whoa!
But you know what?
The workers came back
I spent the next few weeks in a malarial haze
Should've been dead
But Mike kept it all going
What day is it?
No idea
- Month?  - August
You been sitting there this whole time?
Let's not get carried away
What'd the report say?  What's the news?
We pulled 17 more cores
What?
- No good?  - No good
Mm
More in the vicinity of great
Fuck you, Mike Don't mess with me, man
Eighth of an ounce per ton
Eighth... eighth of an ounce per what?
What... what are you... What are you saying, Mike?
We got a strike in
We got a gold mine?
- We got a gold mine?  - We got a gold mine
We got a gold mine, Mike!
- We got a gold mine  - We got a goddamn gold mine!
We got a gold mine!
We got a goddamn gold mine!
We got a goddamn...
Gold mine!
We got a gold mine!
I knew it, I knew it
I knew it, I knew it, I knew it
We got a goddamn gold mine!
Fuck you, mosquitoes!
That moment...
There's no way I could possibly describe the feeling
It's amazing how a little gold dust
can just change everything
Now, for better or worse, the ride had begun
and what a goddamn ride
Okay, okay
Oh, thank god
- To the best goddamn team in the business -Fucking-a
You're a stand-up guy, Kenny
- Sharing the wealth  - Crazy, huh?
To the mother lode
The mother lode
All right, baby Do me a favor
Close your eyes, will ya?
- All right  - Cover them with your hands
Keep 'em closed
- Okay
- I got you I got you I got you -Oh Okay
One, two, three
It's gonna be our place
Away from it all, above it all, just like we always wanted
You like it?
- Huh?  - Yes, of... yes
Okay, look... the house... Right here, all right?
The kitchen, facing there, The great room over here
- Two fireplaces  - No...
Can we afford this?
Almost, baby Almost We're almost there
All right, look at this Couple bedrooms on that end
- Couple bedrooms on that end  - Okay
Look at this playground for the kids, huh?
How many kids you want to have?
Kitchen has to stay over here
We gotta put it over here
- to get the morning light  - Yes!
And a second kitchen over on this side
- A third one across the creek
A fourth one up there with the elk
- Kenny, Kenny  - Mm?
- This is Walt Kealer,he publishes gold digger magazine - Mm
We reach half a million subscribers
and they'd all love to know
what you got cooking over there in Indonesia
If you have a minute, I'll buy you a drink
He's all yours, Walt
Hell, I read gold digger magazine
Come on over
They say you bring this in, you'll get the golden pickaxe
- Aw, shut up  - What do you say about that?
I'd say you probably just jinxed it
- How many ounces you guessing?  - Hmm
Millions, Walt Absolutely millions
Placer mining?
No, Hard rock, This is varsity ball
How's the infrastructure?
Building it from the ground up
Any message you'd like to give
to the readers of gold digger magazine?
The last card you turn over is the only one that matters
- Kenny, it's good to see you  - Good morning, Beverly
Clive, how are you?
- There he is  - Good to see you, sir
- It's good to see you, son  - Mm-hmm
You know, your father and I
we started together in this business
Hell, I mean, he put me in the business
I don't have to tell you that
He always spoke very highly of you, Clive
He's one of the best men I ever knew
- Yeah  - Now!
You have gone from four to 23 cents
on your first assay results
And you pulled in two more to confirm those findings?
Three more
- Three more?  - Mm-hmm
Well, that's fantastic
Well, I would like to underwrite
a private placement of Washoe stock
And I believe that we can raise
anywhere between $8 million and $10 million
Well, capital is definitely
at the top of our agenda
right now
Well, yes, it is
And a lot of people are going to want to make this deal
but history is on our side
Mm-hmm
But I just wish you'd brought this to me sooner
- I could have helped you from the get-go -Hey
- Well, here we are  - Here we are
Lloyd...
Top that off for me, will you?
Straight black with a spicer chaser
Mr. Wells, uh, coffee
There we are, Lloyd Thank you
Stanton, Mr. Wells has agreed
to give us his business on one condition
Lloyd, I want you
to personally handle my account
I-I need you to be
available to me 24/7
365, as you will be riding shotgun in my jockstrap
Absolutely Yes Thank you
Well, let's quit standing around here
and go make some goddamn money, huh?
That sounds good to me
Kenny? Kenny?
Kenny, did you read the last report?
Yeah... No, I'm looking at them right now, Holy shit!
Holy shit is right, my friend
No, it's unbelievable
Holy shit
Bobby, I can hear your wife
smiling from here
Right back where you belong, Kenny
Yeah, there's a lot of ghosts in this building, boys
Oh, nice work, Todd!
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
All right, men
Now, this stock is going to start cooking
Make sure you put a little bit away
Sell some Just the long way Just in case
- Especially you  - What?
- Put a little bit away  - I...
For the first time in your life
think rainy day, Bobby, okay?
- Of… of course, Of course  - Hey
- What?  - Okay?
- Okay  - Okay
Oh, we're going to be so fucking rich
At least look like you're working, man
Yeah?
What do you got?
Wildcatters, basically
This Mike Acosta has had some success Copper
Got taken over by Freeport Mac
- It's all in there  - Yeah I've heard of Acosta
- I like this  - But I think we start
with the good news, which is that we are, uh
50% allocated and, uh, we want to set aside, uh
30 of the remaining 50 for you boys...
There's more food here, Don't drink through lunch
All right?
Or just eat something as well
-	Hey, Kay!  - Phone!
- What?  - Phone, please
- That one, Thank you  - You want me to answer it?
Hello
Uh, Washoe mining, How may I direct your call?
- Hi,Uh,Kenneth Wells, please  - Please hold
Kenny, you got a call!
- Thank you, dear  - Love you, baby
All right
Kenny Wells
This is Brian Woolf at brown, Thomas in New York
I'm with the minerals and oil group
No shit
Uh-huh
Well, that sounds outstanding, Brian
And let me tell you something
I'm looking forward to it
All right
They're fucking flying me out
Come on!
Yeah, the way I see it
what banks do... who knows?
But what made this country is not tight asses in suits...
No offense... Taking the easy way down
but guys like me and Mike who jump
What we have
is a private placement in play here
Already over 50% subscribed
Now, if the numbers keep coming in good
which... They're fucking going to
the sky is the limit on this thing
You don't have to sell us We've done the math
We believe you're sitting on
the largest gold find of the decade
May I speak plainly, Mr. Wells?
Of course, Brian That's the only way to speak
Our clients are going to want to see a serious plan
to turn lab results in a volatile region
into an investment we can all stake our reputations on
It's not going to be a problem
No, it's not a problem, per se
but the fact remains that neither of you have taken
a find of this magnitude through production
Wait just a minute there, Brian
We-we found it, we can dig it up
- It's not that complicated  - Actually
historically, we found it could be quite complicated
and we'd like the opportunity
to help you formulate how you present the operation side
Wh-what-what exactly does that mean?
I'd like you both to consider
bringing on a strategic partner
Oh
All right
Have any of you ever
set one of your... Your handmade loafers
down in the hole in the side of a mountain?
- No  - No We have
Washoe has history
We've done a fairly thorough analysis of Washoe
Mr. Wells, and we feel like you need strategic help
No, No way, No, This is a new day, all right?
And Indonesia is goddamn different
We can help you get off the side of that mountain
I don't need any help getting off the side of the goddamn mountain
I can land this plane
I can!
Wells came and found me
I was at a low point, I have to admit
It happens in this business, ups and downs
But he backed me with his last cent
and more than that, he risked his life
almost lost it, actually
It was touch and go there for a bit
And now we have the bull by its horns
And, boys, they're big fucking horns
I've worked with the best
and I can tell you Kenny Wells is up there with them
We're not by any stretch of the imagination
suggesting at this moment that anybody take a backseat
- Just be open to strategic alliances  - No fucking...
Way!
It's a dime out of every one of my dollars
not your dollars!
I said no a second ago
You want to invest? We got the gold
- We can talk about it
Don't need a fucking partner, I know that
You know, there's something about...
Finding gold...
That is so difficult to put into words
It's real difficult
Taste of it on your tongue
The feel of it between your fingers
it's... it's electric
It's like a drug
'cause it hooks you
And it's precisely what you're missing here in the city
It's what makes it so hard for us to have this conversation
because you have never felt it
So I have a proposal for you
Put together your institutional players
the guys who rep the big money
Whoever needs to kick the tires on this thing
I will take them on a little trip up the river
So... it was Acosta
who proposed the-the junket in Kensana?
Or did you cook that up together?
Oh, Jennings, you're... You're not getting it
Look, we-we didn't feel like we had to cook up anything
I mean, I had people coming at me from all sides
My-my neighbor, hart Hubbard
he's a lawn care professional
Usually only worried about Kay's mulberry tree
leaning over the back of his fence
but now he's dropping mining terms
"Hey, Kenny, how's the grade purity over there at Kensana?
I hear it's great How about the core frequency?"
Hart fucking Hubbard He mows grass for a living
- We interviewed Mr. Hubbard  - What I'm saying is we didn't
think we needed to cook up anything
Everybody wanted in
So it was Acosta who proposed the banker junket?
Yes
It was a genius move
Now, you get outside
stick close to me and hang on to your wallets
Come on, come on No, no, no, no, no, no, no
Back, back, back, back, back, back, back, back, back
There he is
Gentlemen, Mike Acosta
Glen
Acosta
- Bobby  - Acosta
Jeff Jackson
If any one of you wants to turn back
this is your chance
What's that?
He's just messing with you Welcome to Indo, boys
When we got the hit
we stepped out in a radiating pattern
and we kept going until we had the definitive picture
We're mapping the underlying geology
The cores are cut into sections, and then crushed
They are then bagged and sealed
This cage is guarded 24/7
Under guard, the samples are sent down river
to independent labs in Kalimantan
If a seal is broken or damaged in any way
the lab, by law, has to discard the entire sample
Every safeguard has been put in place
to assure the security of the process
Diamond-tipped saw blades, rock crushers
Core samples being ripped from the guts of the earth
It all sounds great, but...
you boys want to see some gold
No one's going to believe this shit
So, what do you think?
Not sure What about you?
Acosta seems to know what he's talking about
but, uh, I don't know
Hey Hey
Come here, come here
I think I... I think I got something
See this?
Few more like this
you can pave wall street
When Jackson pulled that nugget out
we had 'em
Brown, Thomas is proud
to announce the public offering of 27 million shares
of class a common stock
and the initial listing of Washoe mining
on the New York stock exchange!
We're all going to make a lot of fucking money!
Welcome to the Waldorf Astoria, ma'am
We'll get your bags right upstairs
Kenny?
Are you here?
Ah
Oh, my goodness
You surprised?
Yeah
It's your favorite flower, right?
Babe
You look beautiful, Kay
Come here
I have missed you so much
You have no idea
Are these the softest sheets you've ever felt?
- Yeah, you know, I think they are  - Yeah
- You want to get under 'em?  - Yeah
Oh, hello, men
Everyone, meet the lovely Kay
- Brian – Hi  - Nice to meet you
- Hollis Kay  - Hi
- Pleasure  - Nice to meet you
- Stanton, you know  - Hey
The only man in this business that sweats as much as I do
All right, let's do this, huh?
Ah, there he is
Mike Acosta, the one and only
Mike, meet Kay
Two of my favorite people in the world
You know this one stole my watch to go meet you
- You stole her watch?  - Oh, no, no, no -No...
- I'm just teasing   - She's just teasing
- No, you're not  - No, she's not
- No, I'm not
I didn't know what time it... I got to go
It's so good to meet you, Mike
- You must be very proud  - Never doubted for a second
Here we go!
Five!
Four! Three!
Two! One!
- Yeah... baby!
I'm ringing the bell, baby!
In the story we've been following very closely
Washoe mining
may be the stock of the year
On their first day
on the New York stock exchange, Washoe mining
turned into a rocket ship today
- Hi Great to meet you  - Kenny Mike Come
Oh
No, I'm okay Thank you
This and the money are in the genes
How are you? Kenny Wells Good to meet you
True fucking story
Who at this table wants to know the secret
to winning bets at pro football?
- What's that?  - Take the east coast team
every fucking time, You know why?
The west coast team... to them, they're playing after midnight
- Rachel hill  - Mm
- Giants fan  - Kenny Wells, Rachel
So, what do you do, Rachel hill?
- Investor relations  - Mm
Brown, Thomas, On the team
Cheers to that You got to be the best-looking one
on the team, I'll tell you that
It's like a drunk raccoon
got a hold of the hope diamond
You don't want to get too close
but you're not going to let it get away either
- It's your raccoon  - Mm
You let it run a multi-billion-dollar company?
What, and lose you as a client
and half the rest of my business?
There's risks and there's risks
Still, it was a good fucking day
Now, who wants to buy me a drink?
Three double shots of Jack
So tell me, to go out into the wilderness
with your bare hands
and discover something that everybody wants...
how does that feel?
I, uh... propose a toast
Hear, hear
To a small creature, often misunderstood
To the raccoon
Well, fuck me
River of gold
The thing is, if you don't watch it
gold will grow on you
- I can see that now  - Mm
- I don't want to talk about it  - What did...
I wasn't doing anything
I said I don't want to talk about it!
Well, what the fuck should I have done, huh?
Just bend her over the table right there
and fucking banged her in front of everybody?
You are too drunk to get it up anyway
I'll take that challenge, baby
I don't care about you flirting with miss pneumatic 1988
You think I haven't seen that shit before, Kenny?
She had tiny little fucking titties
You don't think they were real?
No, none of this is real None of it
Why are you fucking...
We made it!
- Shit  - Baby, what the fuck?!
You know what your problem is, Kay?
- No Why don't you tell me  - You've got no vision
Right? Fucking vision
Your vision starts right here, and it goes to right here
Right here is the fucking kitchen sink
and right here's the goddamn parking lot
at the furniture store
- Come on  - You mean an actual job
that would support a person in the place they live?
You mean that vision?
You know what? Fuck you
- Ah, Kay, fuck me  - Fuck you
Fuck you Fuck... Wh-wh-what, what?
Don't you see what's happening here?
Oh, great Go... yeah, yeah
Pack your shit, run back to your shitty life, huh?
- You know what? I like my shitty life  - Christ
- It's mine  - Fucking giving this up
You always wanted a broken bird, didn't you?
Said the right things, but in here
you never fucking believed in me, did you?
You never believed in me, did you, Kay?
Hmm? You like me losing, don't you?
- How can you even say that?  - It makes you feel comfortable
doesn't it?  Does it feel comfortable, Kay?
These people are using you
- They don't care about you  - I don't fucking...
And they certainly don't believe in you
- Yeah, but, Kay, I found gold  - -Goddamn...
Now we're winning, babe
Would you just let me have the win?
We're winning!
It ever occur to you that I know what I'm doing?
I hope you do
Huh?
I do
- I love what's in there...
- Mm
More than you'll ever know
These guys are going to tear you up
Mm
Don't ask me to watch what happens next
I know what I'm doing, Kay
I know what I'm fucking doing
What'd you do next, Wells?
What did I do?
I rode it
I rode it, Jennings
Another double Seagram's on the rocks
Yes, sir
And I'll have the same
Oh, goddamn, You don't have to impress me
Reminds me of my childhood
So how is everything
in the very enchanted world of Kenny Wells?
I feel like a million bucks
only a few hundred times better
That must be a very nice feeling
Yeah It looks like there's a...
A few other people around here with a similar feeling
Mm, maybe
Maybe not
How does someone like yourself end up, uh, here?
I know tom
Tom is a friend
- Oh, I bet he is  - Now, now
I stay with his cousin, Timmy, down the Lane
Timmy's really quite a character
if you get to know him
I don't know Timmy
I don't really feel like talking
Let's just feel things
Wells
- Kenny Wells?  - Uh-huh
Mark Hancock
Seems I've caught you at a bit of a disadvantage, Mr. Wells
Depends on how you look at it
Kenny goddamn Wells, mark
This is Rachel
Oh, I know the lovely Rachel
You know, this son of a bitch here
he controls more gold than anybody on the goddamn planet
With the possible exception now of Mr. Wells
This is how it happens, huh?
This is how it happens
Goddamn
What can I tell you?
- Kenny, it's a generous offer  - It's a fucking joke!
This isn't a deal, Brian This is a goddamn rape
- Listen... listen to me  - No, no, this is mine!
It's mine! I-I found it!
Me and Mike We were the ones up to our ass
in the mud and the shit and the malaria
And this little prick offers a minority partnership?
Kenny, let's keep some perspective here, okay?
Whenever anybody offers this amount of money
it's a good day
You may say yes, you may say no
but it's not like anybody's trying to offend you
Well, mission goddamn not accomplished
Hancock and Newport holdings have the expertise
and the experience to bring this home
- This was always there as a contingency  - No, no
- You know that  - No, no, no
This is when Washoe mining becomes a player
right here, right fucking now
Not mark fucking Hancock and Newport holdings
I don't even see our name on here, Brian
You took our fucking name...
You took my name off it
But if we take a step back here
wouldn't it not be terrible
to sit back and enjoy your success?
"Wouldn't it not be terrible"?
What the fuck kind of way of talking is that, Brian?
W-w-wouldn't it not be terrible
if I bend over and grab my ankles
so you could fuck me up the ass?
You think you can buy me out and take my name?
Or just throw Kenny Wells to the fucking cornfield?
Fuck you, Brian
If we hit pause for a second
and consider, without emotion
I think you'll realize
that this is one of those very rare moments
where, with a stroke of a pen, no one in your family...
I'm talking your children's grandchildren...
Will ever have to worry about money again
You see these hands, Brian?
These are my father's hands
I have scratched and clawed through the hot earth
with these hands
and I will bury you with these hands
Now, you go tell that silky sable, mark Hancock...
He works for Kenny Wells
My fucking day
My day!
You know, I almost respect this guy
That was a pretty foolish
business decision, wasn't it?
You're a foot away from living in your car
You turned down $300 million?
Over naming rights?
Yeah, I did
Because Kensana would become a Newport mine, right?
And mark fucking Hancock's Midas touch continues
Me, Kenny Wells
the-the lucky bastard who fell down drunk
and woke up in a pile of cash, No
It was my dream
I dreamed it
You sell your dream...
What do you have left?
Good morning, Stacy How are you today?
- Good  - How's Ronnie? Good?
- Thank you  - Okay Mm - Kenny
- Mike, hang on Kenny...Kenny's here - Come on!
- It's Mike  - It's a fucking shit-storm  - Mm
Mikey, what's up?
They're locking us out
- They're what?  - They're locking us out!
The military's here
They're taking over the mine
What happened at your meeting with Hancock?
What happened at the meeting, Kenny?!
Listen, Mike, they-they were trying to push us out
Push us out? Wha-what do you mean, push us out?
They took... they took our names off it, Mike
Mine and yours They took our fucking names off
Aw, you fucking moron!
They can't... can't just revoke the-the permit, all right?
They can't just steal it away
Kenny, what?  What the fuck is going on?
Of course they can revoke the permit!
Suharto can do whatever the fuck he wants!
Hey! Hey!
- Mike! - Kenny, what's going on?
- What the fuck is going on? - Shh!
- Mike Mike  - Kenny, we lost the site
I told you, man
You knew exactly who we were dealing with
These people are killers
Hancock first among them
I told you, Kenny
- Now it's gone  - Uh...
So it turns out that in addition
to having, um, longstanding ties
with Suharto...
Newport holdings actually had on its board
a certain ex-president of the United States
Who was also...
In one of Suharto's weddings...
As a groomsman
So you see, that whole time they're telling me
how rich my grandkids are gonna be
they got a backup plan
They're gonna pick my pocket and steal it all away
Washoe stock was off nearly 50 points
at the opening bell this morning
on news of the Suharto government's revocation
of Washoe's exploration rights
President and CEO, Kenny Wells, has not...
All fucking con men They stole it's what they did
They goddamn stole it
Mm
You're gonna need to go home, Kenny
Just pour me a goddamn drink, Roy
Go home, Kenny
This is us
We can't get to the phone...
Wrong number
This is us
We can't get to the phone right now
You know what to do
Hey, hey, Kay
It's me Uh...
I-I-I-I guess you're not home
you know, right now
I was... And I was just calling...
Honey, I really... I want to hear your voice
I s... I-I screwed up, Kay
I want... I wanted to build something
Something real that would last...
Last for you and me and...
For dad
That's all I wanted to do
But you were right, you know?
You were right
Again
I love you, Kay
Mm, I'm gonna... I'm gonna stop now
I'm-I'm not gonna call...
I'm not gonna call you anymore
Oh, my god, is that him?
Yeah, that's Acosta
He looks different in person
Isn't he supposed to be in Indonesia?
Where is he?
Here you are
Get up!
You don't own my fucking company just 'cause you...
Quit fucking kicking me
I didn't know who it was till I heard the cocky fucking talk
- Ah?  - Fucking moron
Oh, yeah?  You're gonna fight?
Yeah? Yeah? Yeah?  Yeah, you want to fight?
Yeah, you want to fight now?
After losing my fucking company?
You want to fight now?  Yeah, you want to fight?
Yeah? Yeah?
You know what they say?
That you're a drunk
A clown
Out of your league
Yeah, well, fuck them
Yeah, fuck them
You know what? Fuck you, too
You think I want to hear from the fucking golden boy
standing there in his golden glow
telling me how messed up everything is? Huh?
No, go fucking back to your perch
at the Jakarta palace, huh?
Huh? You can use that instinct of yours
to find some new strike with some new people
Is that what you think?
I know you, man You're Mike fucking Acosta
Prick
Okay
Let me tell you what really happened
We're in north Sulawesi
Monsoon season
It's 1980
Yeah
The famous copper strike
Only we was looking for bauxite
On my way to... Where I'm planning to drill
I get us stuck
Five feet of mud
We're just sitting in the rain day after day
watching the metal rust
What'd you do?
Under the theory that it's better
to do something than nothing, I...
Reported... this was the spot
Nowhere became somewhere
The place you got stuck
I got lucky
I fucking love that
You went looking for bauxite, and you found copper
I went looking for gold and...
Found a friend
That is the single hokiest thing
I've ever heard in my life
So, you got a plan?
Don't you?
So, get this
Turns out Suharto had a son
his youngest, Darmadi
aka Danny
Bit of a screw-up, real problem for the old man
Mm, safe to say we understood each other
So, Suharto had been trying to get Danny set up for years
all right, but everything Danny touched turned to shit
Now, I figure if we can bring Danny on board
as a partner, maybe he could get daddy
to change his mind and swing things back our way
Now, it was a hail Mary from our own one-yard line
but it was all we had
But it also didn't hurt
that Danny had been regularly ignored
by a certain ex-president of the United States
who was a groomsman at his father's third wedding
and also happened to sit on the board at Newport holdings
So, this guy goes to a Cadillac dealership
Right? Dealer comes out and he says, "sir
are you thinking about buying a Cadillac?"
He says, "no I'm definitely buying a Cadillac
"What I'm thinking about...
Is pussy"
Pussy
Mm Oh, shit
Cadillac is...
Pussy magnet
You like Cadillacs
Yeah!
Hey! Heads up, right there Oh!
Ah...
I gotta ride shotgun
President Gerald Ford
- a tall man  - Mm-hmm
George hW Bush...
A very tall man
Mm-hmm
Mark Hancock...
Also tall man
My father...
Small man
Small in stature
But... he loves his family
Mine, too
Yeah
Died in the driveway bringing in the groceries for my mother
His heart
Fuck, well, it makes sense, huh?
To father of Wells
85/15 split
if you have the balls
50/50, and I might consider it
That's a fucking deal
That's a deal if you have the balls
No balls, no deal
Kenny...
do you have balls?
- You asking me if I got fucking balls? -Yeah
Fuck, he has balls
- Go in there?  - Mm-hmm
- Fucking 85/15 fucking split?  - Mm-hmm
No balls...
No deal
Open it
I'm touching a tiger
I'll pull my cock out, we go 60/40
Ah, fuck you
Mike, I'm touching a tiger right between the eyes
Hollis, what's going on?
You haven't heard?
Wells cut a deal
A deal?  What are you talking about?
Who cut a deal with him?
Suharto The Indonesian government
- What?  - Washoe retains 15% of the find
The other 85 goes to a company of Suharto's choosing
which just so happen to be owned by his son
- Wells cut us off at the knees  - What about Hancock?
He's out, Can't compete at that number
Deal's done, Brian
Wells and Acosta are now the only outside partners
in the biggest gold strike in history
We represent exactly none of it
- 15% is a terrible deal  - Is it?
What's 15% of $30 billion?
I can explain You met him
You'll be fine, Brian
You'll land on your feet
I was afraid you'd come home with a bone in your nose
- or some such shit  - How are we doing?
- Good, man  - Hey, where's Kay?
- You didn't hear?  - Hear what?
She quit
She got a promotion  out at the store
- Assistant manager  - Hey, Roy, turn that up
Kenny Wells, right there!
It's on the news, man!
Massive gold strike
fending off a takeover
by Newport holdings
Washoe shares are soaring...
- Oh, yeah!
Soaring! Soaring!
Kenny!
Can I see you a minute?
What you got, Clive?
I just got a call
The national association of prospectors
is gonna honor you with the golden pickaxe
- You shittin' me?  - No, I'm not
You are now the best miner in the world
And I'm sure somewhere your daddy is smiling
Well, goddamn, if he's not, I can smile for the both of us
Ah...
Where are you going?
Got to find someone
Yeah?
Mike I didn't think you could make it
Okay
A thousand monkeys, thousand horses...
Uh...
And across and around...
I'm nervous
You're gonna be okay
"Every last one of us
"who calls the great state of Nevada home...
"Arrived here...
"With a dream
"It was my great granddad who came out here on a wagon
"He had a horse and he had two mules...
"When they finally stopped moving
"and said...
'This is the place'"
too much?
That's good
- Yeah
Our own Kenny Wells!
Get up here, Kenny!
Thank you, Um...
My great granddad...
Was one of us
He came out here in a wagon with two horses and a mule
and, you know, he crossed six states
before he slowed down, and it was...
It was when he got here
that he finally pulled those reins back and said...
"This is the place"
What is a prospector?
No, no, I'm...
Seriously, what...
What is a prospector?
It's someone who believes...
It's out there
Who wakes up every morning
again and again, again and again...
believing it's out there
- And then it's not
- Right? It's not  - Mm-hmm -Mm-hmm
And he's standing on the edge of the desert
staring a...
New day's sunrise right in the eye, and...
And he hears that little voice
a little voice that says...
"Go ahead
Keep walking"
And the sun gets higher and higher
and it's shining down on him, and he's really hot
and he doesn't have any water to drink
and everybody that came with him wants to turn back
and eventually, they do turn back
and there he is
And he's all alone
With the belief...
that it's out there, man
It's out there
That's a prospector
Really great speech, son Just great Great
- To your daddy  - To Mr. Wells!
Mm
Yeah?
What?
Say-say again?
No, I-i don't understand
Wait… wait
Kenny, what's going on?
Kenny... what happened?
I don't know
I'm going to find out
I don't know any more than...
You're not gonna get away with this!
Back the fuck off!
Kenny, please fix this!
What happened, huh?  What happened?
The independent assayer
They couldn't reproduce Mike's findings
There's no gold
Kenny, there's no goddamn gold, There never was
That's not possible
The image on the left is the type of gold
found in the Washoe samples, This is river gold
Notice how the edges are rounded
worn smooth by the erosion of water
What we should have found is flake gold
the sample on the right
pulled directly from the rock, rough-edged and angular
That's a pretty darn big detail to overlook
wouldn't you say?
It's a big detail, but... You have to understand
everything else about the Washoe samples was right
But the gold was wrong
It's called salting... It literally means when someone
sprinkles gold dust into a rock sample
like you... salt your steak
It is the oldest trick in the book
Oldest trick in the book?
And yet major mining corporations
investment banks, the auditors
everyone was fooled
We weren't fooled
We just didn't look
By all appearances
Washoe's security protocol
were ironclad
But... when the person
administering the security is fraudulent
the whole system goes down
Right Did he say...
Wh-wh-where-where he was going?
Did he mention Jakarta?
I'll call you back
The New York stock exchange just suspended trading
They've taken Washoe off the board
You sold some, right?
Yeah
Of course
Bobby
I thought...
I thought it was just gonna
keep going up
Damn it, Bobby, I told you from the beginning
just put some away, save a little bit just in case
How many times did I tell you that?
Kenny, did you know?
Did you know, Kenny?
Did I know?
I can't believe you would ask me that
I'm asking you that Did you know?
No, I goddamn didn't know, Bobby
Kenny
- Kenny  - What?
I don't even know how to tell you this
Just look
Acosta was dumping stock
- Mm  - Shell companies
Banks in the Philippines, the fucking Azores
Gibraltar
Multiple layers, all offshore
How much?
- $164 million
Okay, uh...
What are we gonna do?
I don't fucking believe this Hmm?
This is the FBI!
Step away from your desks!
Take two big steps away from your desks!
Do not touch anything!
How much money was lost in the fraud
- that we know of?  - Oh, billions
Large institutional investors
- lost billions of dollars  - So one or maybe both of them
two outsiders, took everybody on wall street for a ride?
Yeah, it really looks like they did
- Yeah  - And Acosta has vanished?
With hundreds of millions of dollars
Kenny Wells has always maintained his innocence
that he was duped along with everyone else
Given that, what do you make of this?
Kenny Wells, a fool or a mastermind?
It's a very good question, Roger
Um...
Mike-Mike Acosta was my friend and, uh, my partner
and he-he betrayed me
I-I know as CEO of Washoe mining
it's my responsibility to know
everything that's going on, and I... I didn't
It's not an excuse
All right?  I sincerely apologize
to everybody and anybody that lost on their investments
Come on, Mike
Mikey, come on in, man
All right?
What happened, huh?
- Howard  - I saw you on TV
- Hey, man, can I talk to you for a minute, please?  - No
Look, I just want to know where my money went
- Come on! -Don't know anything about it, okay? -Mr. Wells
Mr. Wells, exactly when will you be departing?
Uh, later A few days or so I'll let you know
- We just need to talk about your bill, sir  - I'll be down
We'll settle it up
Do I need a lawyer?
Do you need a lawyer?
Right answer
How'd you meet Michael Acosta?
The, uh, first time or the second time?
How'd you meet him, Wells?
It was April... of '88
Yeah, I was on the balls of my ass
Scrambling
Not exactly uncharted waters for me, but...
I was in deep
I think it's pretty unlikely
we'll ever see your partner again
- What are you talking about?  - A lot of very powerful people
are very angry at Michael Acosta
Well, what happened?
What happened?
$17 billion of value disappeared overnight
Mike Acosta waves good-bye to you
in the ballroom downstairs and goes back to Indonesia
on a jet chartered with Washoe funds
And then he does a disappearing act
But this you know
First, he's locked out of the assay lab in Kalimantan
by the minister of the interior
- So he goes back to Jakarta...
- Mr. Acosta
please walk with with me
Where he's immediately detained
by the Indonesian military
And they hold him
while they try to reproduce for themselves
the lab results claimed by Washoe
Which, of course, they are unable to do
Now, at this point
either he's being transferred to an actual prison, or...
He's bribed one of the officers
Either way
he's on a military helicopter
They fly north, loosely tracking the Kensana river
A thousand feet up, over the Kensana...
Mike Acosta takes a header
No way
No fucking way
He either faked it
or he paid to have this-this bullshit story
you're telling put out
$164 million goes a long way in Indonesia
They found a body
Hands and face were eaten away
probably by wild pigs
Sure this is him?
I'm not sure of anything...
Except Mike Acosta traded water filters for river gold
But now
the Indonesian government
have gone unusually quiet
on the subject
There was an autopsy
corroborating the identity of the body
They then sealed the report...
cremated the remains
Interestingly, Danny Suharto, your friend...
Dumped a lot of stock as well
So the Suhartos are even richer now
Mike Acosta is ostensibly dead and buried, and...
$164 million is still missing
And the only question...
I'm left with is...
Whether or not you were in on it
I...
- I can't believe it  - Can't believe what?
No, look, th-this business...
Had written Mike off years ago, all right?
They called his theories crap
But...
There's no way
He wouldn't, he fucking couldn't
let this be the last word on him
- No fucking way  - You talking about Acosta or yourself?
All right, look We-we-we were running out of money, right?
And I was practically dying from malaria
I gave Mike the last dollar to my name
And I made him promise me something, I said, "Mike...
Don't let me die out here for nothing"
A few weeks later, I came to, and...
Mike was there
He said, "we got...
"We got a strike, Kenny
We got a goddamn gold mine"
And th-there's no way that he set out to swindle anyone
He just needed to buy a little more time
And he didn't want to let me down
You're fuckin' lyin'
- Levine, sit down!
You want to talk about the truth?
All right, let's talk about the truth
The only truth here is, when everybody's getting rich
nobody gives a shit about the truth
Come the fuck on All anyone had to do was look
open their eyes
Man, the-the gold was wrong, the find was too good
There were red flags everywhere
Why did no one look?
'Cause no one wanted to fucking know
We all wanted to believe
Me, you, fucking everybody Why?
Because we were all making so much fucking money, man
That's the truth
That's been going on for fucking centuries!
Oh, fuck...
Were you aware Mike Acosta was salting
- the Washoe core samples?  - No
You had no knowledge
Mike Acosta
was perpetrating a fraud?
- No  - You were not in collusion
with Mike Acosta on the Kensana gold strike?
No, man, I fucking thought I won the lottery
Did you profit from the Kensana fraud?
- No -Did anyone close to you profit?
My friends lost money
My neighbors lost money
Me...
I lost everything
You know what the truth of it is?
I never really cared about money
I cared about gold
And it's different, Jennings
It's fucking different
Interview terminated with Kenny Wells...
6:45 AM
October 17, 1988
Interview conducted by myself
Paul k Jennings, special agent
Also present, agents Levine and banks
federal bureau of investigation
district of Nevada, Reno
Mr. Kenny Wells...
you are free to go
Well, lookee there
Somebody believes me
I wouldn't go overboard
In fact, I wouldn't leave the state
or start buying new stuff or chartering
- any more jets  - I gotta sneak by the guy
at the front desk 'cause I can't pay the hotel bill
I can't be a party
to that information
Good luck, Mr. Wells
We'll be keeping an eye on you
What are you gonna do now, Wells?
Hey, Kenny
I-I'm still worried about that mulberry
- over the back fence  - Yeah I know, hart
It's good to see you
Good to see you, too, Kenny
Can I come in?
- You want coffee?  - Yeah, sure
This place looks great
So do you, Kay
I made curtains
From that fabric
Hmm
Some stuff came for you, some mail
What?
What is it?