The Japanese ambassador just arrived.
He should be up shortly.
Thank you.
The Japanese are stalling, Henry.
You know that.
When Nomura took over as ambassador...
...I had some hopes of settling
our differences.
But our meetings so far
have been unproductive.
He brings me proposals,
I offer compromises.
He brings me counterproposals,
and so on.
I tell you, Henry,
Nomura was sent here to buy time.
That's what he's doing,
at our expense.
The president thinks he's...
...a man we can trust and deal with.
Mr. Ambassador, we meet again.
It is always a pleasure.
I assume you know Mr. Stimson,
the head of our War Department.
Oh, yes, of course.
Mr. Ambassador.
I do hope, Mr. Stimson...
...your presence here
doesn't indicate anything ominous.
Of course not, Mr. Nomura.
Mr. Nomura, won't you please sit down?
Thank you.
Well, since our last talk
a week ago...
...I have received a certain...
...shall we say...
...question from my government...
...to put to you
to clarify certain matters.
There it is.
This machine lets us intercept
every word between Tokyo...
...and all Japanese embassies.
The coded material is fed
into that machine.
It goes round and round in there...
...and comes out here,
decoded in Japanese.
All we have to do is translate it.
We decode this quicker than
the Japanese embassy...
...right here in Washington.
No wonder you decided to call it
"Operation Magic."
- The latest intercept, sir.
- Thank you.
Things are getting a little
hotter in the Pacific.
As long as we're sharing
this assignment...
...take a look at this.
Behold the 1 2 apostles.
The chosen few are authorized
to see the magic intercepts.
Hap Arnold, Chief of the Air Corps,
isn't on the list.
No, and not one of our
overseas commanders.
Stand by.
Execute.
Look at that entrance to the harbor.
Sink one good-sized ship in the channel
and you've bottled up our whole fleet.
You know as well as I do,
this harbor is a mousetrap.
Fleet should have stayed
in San Diego where it belongs.
I made the mistake to point
that out to Roosevelt.
We're expected to obey orders.
We're also expected to exercise
our own good judgment.
I didn't ask for the job.
Sorry, Kim, but this was my command,
and it's become habit...
...to worry about the security
of the fleet.
The British, flying some
old biplanes...
...torpedoed and sank three Italian
battleships at Taranto.
Harbor very much like this one.
I share your concern, but CNO
doesn't think it can happen here.
Why not?
A torpedo dropped
from a plane plunges...
...to a depth of 75 feet or more
before it levels off.
I know, and Pearl is only
40 feet deep.
I'm still worried, Kim.
Ten-hut!
Do the planes have to be
parked like that?
Way at the edge of the field.
Standard dispersal procedure, general.
In case of enemy air attack.
There are 130,000 Japanese
on this island.
Our main problem is sabotage.
It'd be too easy for enemies
to sneak in at night...
...and blow up every one of them
if they're left out there.
Make a note, Fielder,
we'll have to make changes.
Ten-hut.
Admiral Halsey's here to see you.
Send him in, please.
Blast me, break me, court marshal me,
draw and quarter me...
...if you think they're gonna
send my ships...
...on convoy duty in the Atlantic.
Kim, I think they've
gone nuts in Washington.
How will I fight
a task force if they send...
...my ships to the Atlantic?
That damn ocean is a swimming hole
compared to the Pacific.
What are we, a fighting fleet
or these toy boats here...
...so the Japs
can buy them at Christmas?
All right, Bill, now ease it off.
It's not just you.
They asked for some
of our tankers too.
How do they expect to feed
these wagons...
...parked out here on
this land-locked duck pond?
You're still planning on rotating
half of them at sea?
I was.
Look, Kim, you've got to make them
understand what's going on out here.
I'm gonna do everything I can, Bill.
Even go to the president.
By God, I knew there was
at least one man...
...in this man's Navy
who hadn't gone nuts.
And we go on to say,
"It should be noted that Japan...
...has never preceded hostile action
by a declaration of war.
We believe it possible
that a fast-rated...
...Japanese carrier force may arrive
in Hawaii with no prior warning...
...from our intelligence service.
The most favorable time
to the enemy would be dawn.
He probably would employ
a maximum of six carriers...
...strike on a weekend.
- We recommend that the Air Corps..."
- I read it.
Yes, sir.
I appreciate the work that you
and General Martin have put in.
These reports are very useful
to General Short and myself.
General Martin, you don't pull
any punches do you?
"We recommend that the Air Corps...
...maintain a thorough
360-degree search...
...of the Hawaiian area
during daylight.
This will require a force of
180 B-17 airplanes."
We can't search the sea approaches...
...unless we have the planes, sir.
One hundred and eighty B-17s?
For God's sakes, that's more than
the number existing in the States.
It looks fine on paper, but that's
not a paper fleet out there.
Squadron from the Enterprise.
Bill Halsey's working
the tails off his men.
Wish we had more like him.
Makes the most of what he's got.
Doesn't keep asking for the moon.
Well, not one bomb anywhere in
the target for the past hour.
Your pilots can see it, I suppose.
- Who's next?
- It's Anderson, sir.
Now, that's more like it.
- Maybe your boys finally get it.
- I hope so, sir.
Who's next?
Lieutenant Dickenson.
Tell Lieutenant Dickenson for me...
...he couldn't hit a bull
in the butt with a bass fiddle.
Yes, sir.
Ten-hut.
- Carry on.
This it?
Yes, sir. Our new radar.
It's a remarkable
scientific achievement...
...capable of spotting an intruder
on the sea or in the air...
...and at quite a range.
Now, listen colonel, as you know,
we're short on patrol planes.
We're gonna have to rely on this...
...thing to detect the enemy.
General, radar should do the job.
What's it doing here, not set up?
We're about to truck it up
that mountain.
That peak up there is the ideal spot
to put our main radar post.
At that height, we'd be clear
of all interference.
Obviously.
But, sir, we can't get permission
to put her up there.
Permission?
From the National Park Service
Department of Interior.
See, all of this belongs
to the Hawaiian National Park.
The Hawaiian National Park?
Yes, sir. The Wildlife Preservation
Society is raising hell too.
And we can't get permission?
No, sir.
Not unless we want to fight them.
Fight them? You're damn right
we're gonna fight them.
- Now you make a note of that, Fielder.
- Yes, sir.
Wildlife Preservation Society.
It's no use, Hal.
I spoke to General Miles.
He took it up with General Marshall.
The order stands.
The president is off the ultra list.
Incredible.
Withholding information
from the president.
Security found a copy of an intercept
in a waste basket at the White House.
Truth is, the brass don't trust some
men close to the president.
Does anyone trust anyone anymore?
- Do you even trust your own wife?
- Do you?
Come to think of it, I believe I do.
Part two of No. 1390, colonel.
Tokyo to embassies
in Washington and Berlin.
Thank you, Miss Cave.
The Japanese are moving south
to occupy French Indo-China.
- This is big trouble.
- Yeah.
Well, ultra list or not...
...someone has to tell
the president about this one.
"Therefore, we will impose
a full embargo...
...on all trade with Japan.
We do not anticipate immediate
hostile action by Japan...
...but you get this information...
...so you may take appropriate
precautionary measures."
"Appropriate precautionary measures."
What the hell does that mean?
Now, this is signed jointly
by General Marshall and Admiral Stark.
Until we know how the Japanese will
react, we're not gonna take chances.
- We go on full alert.
- Yes, sir.
Stark says they don't anticipate
hostile action.
Why send a warning at all?
Damn it.
Damn it, why can't Washington
give us the full inside story?
I'd sooner form my own opinion.
"Don't anticipate hostile action."
Well, all right, we'll go ahead.
Increase air and sub patrols,
alert senior commanders.
Maybe out of this we can find out
how well we can function.
Kaminsky.
This is Captain Earle.
Going on full alert.
Yes, captain.
We're going on full alert.
Notify all ship, sub and air patrols.
What the hell is going on here?
What are you doing?
Carrying out orders.
General Short's concern is sabotage.
All aircraft not ready
for flight from now on...
...will be parked in the center...
...so they can be kept under guard.
Suppose there's an air raid.
They hit one plane, and it all
goes up in flames.
I'm sorry. General's orders.
It's not an ideal radar sight,
but at least we got a permit.
Let's get the other units working.
Easier said than done.
What do you mean?
We have to get all six units adjusted
and link them by phone to headquarters.
That means training men to operate
an information center...
...so they know what to do
with the information.
Take it easy, Murph.
- You'll figure it out.
- Yeah, I'll figure it out.
Don't just stand there.
You know how to operate this thing.
We know the theory.
Let's put that theory into practice.
- Switch on.
- Yes, sir.
Stay put and keep watching the screen.
In two hours, close down.
I'll send a truck to pick you up.
Excuse me, sir,
but what are we watching for?
Anything unusual.
Any large blip coming from the sea.
Colonel, if we do spot something,
what do we do?
Report it to headquarters, damn it.
- How, sir?
- What?
We haven't got a telephone, sir.
There's a gas station
a mile down the road.
They must have a phone.
We got 183 combat planes
on this base, general.
The way they're parked now, a one-eyed
monkey hanging from a balloon...
...could scatter them to hell
with one hand grenade.
Don't blame me.
General Short gave the order.
Come in.
- Sir, Lieutenants Taylor and Welch.
- Okay, send them in.
You two men get in your planes
and fly over to Haleiwa.
Yes, sir.
What are our orders when we get there?
Just sit tight.
Listen for the phone. That's all.
Yes, sir.
Haleiwa is one
of the subsidiary fields.
We send those two up there,
two more here.
Only way I know to disperse
a few of the planes.
If I'd get away with it, I'd send
all to the neighbor islands.
- You know why we're being transferred.
- Them poker games.
Been winning too often.
Some sucker loses his shirt,
so he bitches to the general.
Nomura has offered
his resignation several times.
But Tokyo won't let him quit.
Instead they're sending a second
ambassador, Kurusu, to help him out.
Do you really think
this Kurusu can do any good?
Well, I doubt it, Frank.
He's hardly the most tactful choice.
When he was ambassador in Berlin...
...he signed the Axis Pact
on behalf of Japan.
- You sick or something?
- No.
I've been piecing together this
batch of new intercepts.
A frightening picture is taking shape.
Ambassadors Nomura and Kurusu
asked their government...
...to extend a deadline for suspending
negotiation between Japan and America.
- You remember that?
- Yeah.
Now, according to this latest
intercept...
...Tokyo wants to conclude
negotiations with us...
...no later than November 29...
...after which, and I quote...
..."Things are automatically
going to happen."
Look at this intelligence report
from the British.
Five Japanese troop transports
with naval escort...
...were sighted off Formosa,
heading south.
We've been monitoring their fleet.
Most of it seems to be on home waters.
I'm not so sure.
I'm betting they're
going to attack us.
Japan is going to attack us.
The 29th is only four days off.
The 30th is on a Sunday.
We're gonna be attacked on Sunday,
the 30th of November.
The pieces fit together.
But can you prove it?
No. But I'm convinced I'm right.
Miss Cave? Get me General Marshall.
General Marshall's
at Fort Benning, sir.
Then get me the secretary of war.
I've got the evidence, Al.
And I'm gonna make the brass
around here admit I'm right.
Bratton's analysis makes sense.
His facts are undeniable.
Henry, I'm washing my hands
of the whole matter.
From now on, it's in your hands...
...and in those
of the Navy department.
I'll call the president.
A message declaring a full alert
will be sent out.
General Marshall anticipated
an emergency like this.
Before he left to attend maneuvers...
...he made out this alert order.
Read this back to me.
"Japanese future action unpredictable.
But hostile action possible
at any moment.
If hostilities cannot be avoided...
...the United States desires that
Japan commit the first overt act."
Read that again.
"If hostilities cannot be avoided,
the United States desires...
...that Japan commit
the first overt act.
This shouldn't be construed
as restricting you...
...to a course of action
jeopardizing your defense.
Prior to hostile Japanese action...
...you are directed to undertake
reconnaissance...
...and other measures
as you deem necessary.
These measures should be
carried out...
...so as not to alarm
the civil population...
...or disclose intent. By order
of General George C. Marshall."
Not to alarm the civil population.
What do you make of it?
If you ask me, sir, it's double talk.
But the chief of staff doesn't go in
for double talk.
- We're going on alert.
- Again?
But the men are confused.
So many alerts.
- Damn it, unconfuse them.
- Yes, sir.
"Japanese forces may attack
the Philippines...
...Thailand, the Kra Peninsula
and Borneo.
This dispatch is to be considered
a war warning."
Well, there it is, gentlemen.
You now have
as much information as I do.
That's the second warning
in three days.
"Japanese forces may attack
the Philippines...
...Thailand, the Kra Peninsula
and Borneo."
They don't mention us.
That's correct. I think it should be
considered significant.
Well, gentlemen...
...we have a job to do.
Washington wants us to send
a squadron of fighters to Midway.
And another squadron to Wake.
When can you sail?
Well, the Enterprise can sail
tomorrow morning.
I'll need a day or two. We're just
completing repairs on the Lexington.
Hurry things along, John.
I want you out there to probe.
I want planes up in the air
morning and afternoon.
I want a report on any sign
of hostile ships.
Understood.
Do you want battleships along?
Hell, no. They're too slow.
If we're gonna probe, let's probe.
We don't want anything holding us up.
You're right, but I'm not ready
to commit them myself.
Not until I know when and where.
Do you plan to keep half the fleet
at sea while the carriers are gone?
No, it's too risky.
I'll have to keep the fleet
here at Pearl while you're away.
Get out. Get back as soon as you can.
I don't like the idea of having my
battleships without air cover.
- Let's get going.
- Yes, sir.
Kimmel.
Level with me.
I want a clear directive.
If I run into a Jap ship,
what action do I take?
Use your common sense.
That's the best damn order I ever had.
If I see so much as a sampan there...
...I'll blow it out of the water.
What is it this time,
getting me over here?
Tokyo has alerted their embassy
to stand by...
...for a very long message
in 14 parts.
Look, Rufe, you scared me
and everybody else last week.
We're not doing that again, are we?
You should see this.
It's the latest report on those
Japanese troop transports.
Remember those troop ships?
They're still heading south
with an escort...
...only 14 hours
from the coast of Malaya.
What about their aircraft carriers?
We don't know.
Intelligence was keeping track
of them until recently.
Now we've lost them.
Look, Rufe, try to put yourself
in their minds.
Where do you think I have been
the past week, night and day?
I am still convinced they're
going to attack us.
What can we do that we
aren't doing already?
I don't know about you,
but I know what I'm gonna do.
Where is everybody?
Oh, it's past 1 2, sir.
They've already gone.
- Get them back.
- On the weekend?
Yes, on the weekend.
This completes 13 parts?
Yes, Tokyo is holding
the final part till morning.
I wonder why.
It's almost 9.
Harry, I'm going to make the
rounds with what we have here.
Thank God the president's
back on the list.
Have Brotherhood call me
when the missing part is in.
Right.
You're late.
- Well, I was...
- Please, take me to the White House.
If you told me we were invited to the
White House, I would've dressed.
You know Mrs. Roosevelt.
She's informal personally,
but a stickler for protocol...
Darling, will you shut up and drive?
Well?
Captain Wilkinson's.
Did you see the president?
No, I saw Harry Hopkins.
And did he read the, whatever it is?
No, he doesn't have the key.
I gave the pouch to our Naval aide,
Lt. Schulz.
He took it in to the president.
And the president has a key,
I suppose?
Of course he has.
And did Lieutenant Schulz
say anything?
He said, "Thank you."
Darling, step on it, will you?
Admiral Stark can't be reached.
Should I take it to chief of staff?
It's after 10, General Marshall
always retires early.
I see no reason to disturb Marshall
with something that's incomplete.
- Wait till you have the final part.
- Yes, sir.
If you're so concerned...
...why don't we call chief of war
plans, Admiral Turner?
His telephone doesn't answer, sir.
- You don't happen to know where he is?
- No idea.
The president has already
discussed it with me.
He sent a personal message
to the emperor.
But when the final part of this
comes in, I'd like to see it then.
- Good night, commander.
- Good night, sir.
I was starved. I'll bet you are.
Oh, thank you, dear.
Can't you tell me anything?
Even a hint?
You'd think the world
was falling apart.
Admiral Stark talked to the president.
What did the president say?
He sent a personal message
to the emperor.
Gordy.
We got those B-17s coming in
from California in the morning.
Honolulu radio will stay on
the air all night...
...so the planes can home in.
You and I had better be in that
control tower at 7:30 sharp.
Yes, sir.
- Tyler, I've got a job for you.
- Sir.
Report to the new radar center
at Fort Shafter at 0400.
At 4:00 in the morning?
From 4 to 7 a.m.
Our marvel of science
only operates for three hours.
Lucky boy. Lucky boy!
Captain, how's it feel?
First command, first patrol.
Just fine, Mr. Young.
In fact, I think I'll
turn in for a while.
- Good night, sir.
- Good night.
Here you are.
Kramer.
Al, listen to this.
The fourteenth part.
"Will the ambassadors please
submit our reply...
...to the United States government
at precisely 1 p. M...
...December 7th, your time."
1 p. M?
"Precisely 1 p.m., your time."
I'll be right over.
Look at the president's message.
I should have had it hours ago.
As you know, communications
have been delayed...
...and frequently garbled lately.
Or deliberately interfered with.
Gene, call the foreign minister.
Tell him I want an immediate
audience with the emperor.
"After deciphering...
...part 14...
...destroy at once...
...your cipher machine...
...all codes...
...and secret documents."
Translate this immediately.
- Give a copy to Kramer when he comes.
- Yes, sir.
I've got to get the hell out of here.
Hey, look at this.
Finally got one.
Communication center.
It even works.
That's great.
Opana Point, communications check.
Are you reading us?
Coming in loud and clear.
Where's the general?
It's Sunday, sir.
This is Colonel Bratton.
Connect me with Chief of Staff,
General Marshall.
Yes, at his quarters, Fort Myer.
Chief of staff's quarters,
Sergeant Aguirre speaking.
Yes, Colonel Bratton.
I'm sorry, sir,
the general isn't here.
Where he always is
this time Sunday morning.
- Where's Colonel Bratton?
- Gone to see General Marshall.
He left this for you, sir.
The 14th part of this
intercept Kramer...
...just delivered indicates to me
the Japanese are going to attack.
We know war is coming.
We know they have
an expeditionary force heading south.
Sir, as hostilities seem imminent...
...I recommend you telephone
Admiral Kimmel...
...in Hawaii.
No.
I better call the president first.
Now, if you'll all please excuse me?
- Yes, sir.
- Thanks.
"The Japanese government regrets
to have to notify...
...the American government...
...that, in view of the attitude
of the American government...
...it is impossible to reach...
...an agreement
through negotiations."
- There are supplemental messages.
- Thank you.
Gentlemen, I am convinced
the Japanese intend to attack...
...at or shortly after 1:00 today.
- I'll alert all Pacific commands.
- Yes, sir.
Colonel Bratton, just a minute.
Take this to communications center.
Come in.
Captain, can you come to the bridge?
Very well.
Sub contact, Mr. Goepner?
- We're not sure.
- What ship?
The Navy tug Antares.
Look astern of her, captain.
She's towing a target raft.
Look between the ship
and the raft, sir.
That, Mr. Goepner, is a submarine.
She's sneaking through the net
into the harbor. General Quarters.
- Sound General Quarters.
- All engines ahead, full.
- Come left, 15 degrees.
- Come left 15 degrees, sir.
- Tell Antares we're attacking.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Flags, tell Antares we're attacking.
- Mount one, commence firing.
- Stand by to roll depth charges.
- Roll one.
- Roll two.
Notify Com-14 we dropped depth charges
on a sub in our security zone.
Aye, aye, sir.
Captain Earle speaking.
- We have a message from the ward.
- All right, read it to me.
"Have dropped depth charges on sub
operating in our security zone."
We've had so many of these
false sightings, Kaminsky.
But this is the real thing, sir.
Closer than any previous sighting.
Just off the harbor entrance.
You and I know the skipper
of that destroyer is a green kid.
I'll pass it to Admiral Block.
With all do respect, sir, I think
we should alert all commanders.
Confirmation, Kaminsky.
I want confirmation.
This is hot.
General Marshall wants it sent to
all commanders by the fastest route.
Right.
The general's handwriting:
It's hard to read.
You're gonna have to help me
with it, Rufe.
Major, I picked up
some great music from Honolulu.
That's fine, pipe it through.
Where's the damn chow truck?
Shut the thing down, George.
It's already after 7.
Hey, Joe, come here.
What do you make of that?
I've been watching it for minutes.
It's moving in, fast.
I've never seen anything that big.
- Looks like two main pulses.
- Hey, Joe, I got it.
I make that about 140 miles north,
three degrees east.
Don't make sense,
we got no planes out that far.
We gotta contact
the information center.
Our problem is over at 7:00.
The center might make
some sense out of it.
Okay, suit yourself.
Information center.
I don't know, Mac,
we're all closed down here.
Is that right? Hang on a minute.
Lieutenant, sir.
Lieutenant Tyler.
Sir, this is Private Elliot,
Opana Point.
There's a large formation
of planes coming in...
...140 miles, three degrees east.
Well, don't worry about it.
The boys at Opana Point must have
picked up the B-17s...
...coming in from the mainland.
- He said not to worry about it.
- Come on, let's go eat.
General, I sent this to Manila,
the canal zone and San Francisco...
...but the direct channel
to Hawaii is out.
Atmospherics again?
Yes, sir, it's real bad today.
We could give it to the Navy.
What makes you think
their atmospherics are better?
- Send it as a telegram.
- Yes, sir.
Do you mean a submarine was
cited over half an hour ago...
...and that it's taken
this long to report it to me?
I don't care if it
still hasn't been confirmed.
I should've been informed after
the ward radioed a first report.
A submarine that close is a serious
matter. A very serious matter.
Get the confirmation
or reports to my office.
I mean, right now.
Have my driver get the car.
Aye, aye, sir. Oh, sir...
...should I tell General Short
you'll miss the golf date?
No, damn it, get my car.
A message for the general
at Fort Shafter.
- Is it marked urgent?
- No.
It's a little bumpy, Davey...
...but you have to fly
in all kinds of weather.
Sure, Miss Fort.
Don't let the nose drop.
That's better.
You're doing just fine.
I'm taking over, Davey.
Stand by.
Execute.
Get his number.
I'll report him for safety violations.
Come on!
Alert all commands:
"Air raid. Pearl Harbor.
This is no drill."
General Quarters.
Man your stations.
Sir.
Battle stations. Battle stations.
Fire your gun. Fire at will.
That bastard!
Station six, man your pump.
Plane to starboard.
Pearl Harbor is being attacked.
- Pearl Harbor?
- Pearl Harbor is being bombed.
Pearl Harbor's being attacked.
Go back to your quarters.
What in the hell is going on?
Why wasn't the Army notified?
Did anyone think to inform Washington?
I thought so.
- General.
- Put all units on a full war footing.
Alert the territorial guard.
Open a command post
at Aliamanu Crater.
- Yes, sir.
- I'll be right down.
Oh, my God.
The island's under attack.
Those bastards will kill us all.
Men, get to the armory.
Get guns, ammunition.
- You too, lieutenant.
- Yes, sir.
- Operator.
- Duarte airfield.
All the phone lines are jammed.
Well, try the radio again.
Hose down that plane.
Run for it.
Run, run!
There's Hickam.
Major, I heard something
funny on the Honolulu radio.
What kind of traffic control is this?
The radio said
something about an attack.
They're Japs, sir.
What a way to fly into a war.
Unarmed and out of gas.
Oboe leader to Oboe flight.
We've flown into the middle of a war.
Get out fast.
Anywhere. If you can't make
Hickam, try Bellows or Wheeler.
We've been hit.
Nothing serious.
They shot one circuit box.
The landing light isn't working.
Better use the hand crank. Hurry.
- Major.
- Yeah.
One wheel is stuck.
Well, jolt it loose. We're going in.
- I tried.
- Try again!
Here they come. Fire!
Tell them to stop shooting at us!
We're Americans.
Major, no go, sir.
Like I said, it's a hell of a way
to fly into a war.
- Run for it!
- Hurry up!
Tower to B-17,
there's a Jap on your tail.
Goose your engine and get out.
Have damage control report
all damages.
Sir, if we stay here we're gonna fry.
Okay, sergeant,
let's get the men down.
All right, you guys, let's go.
Where the hell are our fighters?
Captain, the main fuel tanks
are fractured.
Lower deck's flooded,
we're listing 8 degrees.
Counter flood, counter flood.
You wanted confirmation, captain?
Take a look.
There's your confirmation!
"Oklahoma, capsized.
Nevada 's taken a torpedo forward
and is down to the head.
West Virginia, subjected to six
torpedo hits and several deck fires.
Raleigh and Helena
damaged and listing."
The California, two torpedoes, fires
all around, temporarily abandoned.
I've just come from her.
It's spent, sir.
Would've been merciful
had it killed me.
Mr. Secretary.
"Air raid. Pearl Harbor.
This is no drill."
No, this can't be true.
They must mean the Philippines.
No, sir. It's Pearl.
Get me the White House,
the direct line.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Ambassador, Mr. Hull will see you
in a moment. Please be seated.
Mr. President,
has this been confirmed?
Then, sir
I'd like you to have it confirmed...
...before I receive Nomura and Kurusu.
They're waiting outside.
Operator. Operator.
Get me Haleiwa field. Fast.
George, get ahold of a car,
a truck, anything.
I'm calling Haleiwa. I'll get them
to start our planes. Go.
Recommend course 2- 3-0, sir.
- Very well. Stay at 2- 3-0.
- Stay at 2- 3-0, sir.
Take cover!
More hose! More hose!
More water.
Abandon ship! Abandon ship!
- Abandon ship! Abandon Ship!
- Over the side!
Can't get through
the outer channel in this shape.
She goes down here,
she'll block the south channel.
We'll have to beach her
there so she's clear.
File these.
G-5.
I need five copies each.
Messenger.
- Take this to General Short's office.
- Right.
File these.
Corporal.
This has to be decoded
for the general.
Take it to the decoding room.
Ask them to send it back soon.
Run for it!
Drop the hose
and get the ladders and axes.
What are you waiting for?
- We got no water.
- Why? What's wrong?
It's the Arizona.
She cut the pipes in the mains.
The tanker in the ocean there
is full of aviation fuel.
If it goes, we'll blow up the harbor.
Hey, look out!
In all my 50 years
of public service...
...I have never seen a document so
crowded with infamous falsehoods...
...and distortions...
...on a scale so huge...
...that I never imagined
until today...
...that any government
on this planet...
...was capable of uttering them.
Mr. Hull.
Go.
Yes, all right.
This came from the decoding room,
a cablegram from the War Department.
Get a copy to Admiral Kimmel.
Pardon me, admiral.
- From Washington.
- Thank you.
Gentlemen.
"The Japanese are presenting
at 1 p. M...
...Eastern Standard Time today...
...what amounts to an ultimatum.
Just what significance the hour set
may have, we do not know...
...but be on alert accordingly."
Signed...
...George C. Marshall,
chief of staff.
My God.
This leaves the Navy with only two
combat groups in the Central Pacific.
Ours and the Lexington.
We don't want to get caught
like they did.
I don't intend to.
When can you be ready for sea again?
We can fuel and provision
and be on the way before dawn.
Good. That's good.
Subtitles by
Gelula/SDI
[ENGLISH]