[lightly edgy music]
♪
- I wasn't sure if you were
going to show up or not.
I almost gave up.
- I almost didn't,
but I couldn't help myself.
- [laughs]
I get it.
It feels wrong
for guys like you.
Don't fight it.
I want to make you
feel so good.
[slicing sound]
Uhh--[gasping]
[choking]
[tense chords]
[indistinct chatter]
- See you, T.
- Hey.
Church on a weekday.
I'm impressed.
- Yeah, well, not exactly.
It's a memorial service
for my father.
He passed a year ago today.
- Oh, I'm sor--I didn't know.
Are you okay?
- No, I'm good.
My mom passed
two years before him,
so I kind of got
this grief thing on lock.
- Okay, but you know
if you ever need to talk...
- Oh, thanks, but I'm good.
I know talking
about our personal lives
is not really our thing.
- It isn't?
- No.
- Oh, come on, since when?
- Since we met.
- What? We talk.
We're talking--isn't that
what we're doing right now?
- Sure.
[phone rings]
Oh, wait.
Oh, we just got a case.
Jubal wants us to head
straight to crime scene.
[dog barks]
[overlapping chatter]
Um, I'll liaison with ERT
if you want to get an update.
- I'm Sergeant Mitchell.
You the ones
taking the handle on this?
- Affirmative. Agent Scola.
My partner over there
is Agent Wallace.
What do you know so far?
- Not much.
Witness who called it in
is a nature photographer.
Thought he'd tripped over
a fallen tree limb.
Called 911 when he realized
it was a partially buried arm.
I've already
taken his statement
which I can forward to you.
- Any chance he's involved?
- No. Based on
the composition of the dirt,
the body was buried
sometime early this morning,
and he just flew in
on assignment
from Nat Geo a few hours ago.
- No excess blood around
the body or in the soil.
I think he was killed
somewhere else.
- Gonna be honest here,
we've never dealt with
something like this before.
- Any luck identifying
the victim?
- No. I went through
his pockets,
found a few condoms
and some cash but no ID.
- Kay. Hopefully DNA and prints
will give us some answers.
- Scola, you got to see this.
- What do you got?
- Four more graves.
♪
- Dog alerted on all of them?
- Yeah.
Looks like our killer's been
putting in some serious work.
♪
- Take a good look, folks.
DNA is in and our recently
discovered serial killer
appears to have a type--
young, black, and homeless.
Most of these young men
had prior drug
or prostitution charges
in and around the West Village.
All were stabbed in the neck.
None, and this saddens me
to say--
had been reported missing
by friends or relatives, so...
let's dig in extra hard, huh?
Since nobody else
really seemed to care.
Go to work.
- Do we have any
security footage we can scrub
from the park or the roads?
- None to speak of yet.
- Hey, Jubal.
- Yeah?
- I think we got something.
This is from a nature cam
that was installed
three days ago
to monitor animal crossings.
Good news for us
is that it gives us
a clear view of the road
less than a half mile
from the burial site.
The only vehicle
that was captured
was this blue cargo van
with no plates.
Time stamp has it leaving
the park early this morning.
- Can we get a facial rec hit
on the driver?
- I've tried. Angle's bad.
- All right so blue cargo van,
no plates.
That help anybody?
Well, we'll work
with what we've got,
which admittedly is not
a whole hell of a lot.
What can we ascertain about
the guy's physical attributes?
Elise, you want to help me out?
- Based on the height
of the van,
specs on the interior,
estimate the seated subject
is about 5'10".
Hoodie is form-fitting.
The guy is obviously fit
so he probably weighs
about 170 pounds.
- Meaning he's probably
a lefty based on
the dominant use
of that hand on
the steering wheel.
- Somebody talk to me
about the most recent victim,
Rob Holden.
- 20 years old.
Born in Hazard, Kentucky.
He's got three priors
for solicitation.
Two in the West Village.
Reports indicate that he picked
up his johns at local clubs.
- O--okay so we need to
start pulling
security footage from
bars in the West Village.
Ian, you want to--
- Sir?
Yeah.
- Hey, do we know when
the first victim was killed?
- ME's office says it was
about two weeks ago.
- So this guy
is striking every few days.
Let's dig in and get this guy
before he strikes again.
- NYPD seems to think
they found
the killer's vehicle
in Brooklyn.
- Any sign of the suspect?
- Uh, negative.
They're sitting on it
until ERT gets there.
- All right, you two,
grab Maggie and OA.
Get some answers fast.
- Stolen three weeks ago
over in Queens.
No security cams or witnesses
to the theft.
- Okay, can you arrange
for the owner of the vehicle
to come down, check the front,
see if there's anything
in there that doesn't
belong to him?
- Not a problem.
Lot of blood in that van.
- All right, we need
a thorough sweep of the van.
If there's a shred of DNA
from our suspect in there,
we're counting on you guys
to find it.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Okay, we'll take
the east side of the block.
You guys want to canvass
the west?
- Copy that.
We'll radio you
if we find something.
- Okay, we'll do the same.
- Excuse me.
- You guys asking about
that van the cops were
messing with down the street?
- Yeah, did you see
anyone by it?
- Sure did.
Saw a suspicious looking guy
climb out of the back of it
when I opened up this morning.
Had a shovel and
some other stuff in his hands.
Figured he was up to no good.
- Did he get in a car,
or he walk off by foot?
- He walked
straight into that warehouse
at the far end of the block.
Been abandoned for years.
Haven't seen him walk out,
so maybe he's still in there.
You didn't hear that from me.
- Uh, thanks,
but doesn't work that way.
We'll be back to chat
after we check it out.
- Maybe we should wait
for backup.
- Eh, we got this.
Radio Maggie, OA,
have them meet us over there.
♪
[metallic clattering]
[man, indistinct]
- You hear that?
- Yeah. You go that way.
I got this.
- Yeah.
- There we go.
- Easy, easy, easy, easy.
- FBI!
Hands where I can see them.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- Let's go, on your stomachs.
On your stomachs now.
- Oh, easy, oh...
Okay, man, okay!
- [scream]
- [groan]
[dramatic music]
♪
- Hey--
- Yeah, go, I got this.
[man panting, whimpering]
- Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa--
- Stop.
- Let go--up!
Put your hands
behind your back.
Hands behind your back!
- Clean bill of health?
- Yeah.
I mean, just a little sore.
My shoulder
took most of the hit.
- Look, you were probably
right.
Maybe we should've waited
for backup.
- So those teens--
they were a couple of runaways.
What about the guy
with the shovel?
- Currently homeless.
Just got out of jail
two days ago.
Definitely not our guy.
- Why was he in the van?
- Found it unlocked.
Rifling through,
looking for stuff to sell.
- Hey.
Just spoke to the owner
of the stolen van.
The shovel isn't his.
- So we're gonna send it
to the lab for analysis.
Hopefully we can get
some prints or some DNA.
- Doesn't look that old.
- Maybe the JOC can run down
where it's sold.
We'll get lucky.
- Profile's starting
to take shape.
- Killer's persistent
if not sophisticated.
- Five bodies in 14 days?
He's got an itch
that he can't scratch.
- The behavioral analysis unit
thinks it's probably
somebody who's struggling
with their own sexuality.
Maybe somebody new in the area
who finds that kind of
open community exciting but
triggering at the same time.
- And the method of killing--
stabbing in the neck
to watch them bleed out--that
is all about anger and rage.
- Yeah, if he stays on pattern,
he's going to
strike again soon.
We need to find this guy fast.
Kelly, where are we
on the shovel?
- Uh, the only DNA recovered
was from Agent Scola
and the homeless guy
who punched him.
- Well, damn, suspect
must've been wearing gloves
the entire time he handled it.
- But the dirt samples
taken from it did match
the New York
National Park soil.
- Okay, so the shovel
is the killer's.
Where are we on its purchase?
- Lots of places
in New York sell it.
We're putting together a list,
trying to narrow down
time and date sold.
- Grab the corresponding
security footage as well.
- Okay, good, so the shovel
is a promising lead,
but let's--let's not
rely on that alone
to dig us out of this hole.
See what I did there?
It's called a pun.
[clears throat]
- I might have something.
Been scrubbing video footage
from last night
around the Christopher Street
area like you asked.
Building security cam footage
shows the latest victim,
Rob Holden, leaving the club.
- Eyes up.
- Now time stamp on that video
is 3:45 in the morning.
- Okay, so to get
from this club
to the New York
National Park,
that takes an hour and 15 yeah?
- So shortly after this footage
was shot, Rob was killed
and driven upstate
in this blue van.
Do we have a facial ID on
the bouncer he was talking to?
- Yup. Guy's name
is Greg Robinson.
- All right.
- We don't have
any security cameras.
I keep asking them
to put some in,
but the boss thinks
it's intrusive.
- Well, this man's name
is Rob Holden.
He was killed last night
shortly after
this video was taken.
- Wow, for real?
- What did you two talk about?
- I can't remember.
It's like a circus
at closing time,
like trying to herd cats
out the door.
That is, if the cats
were all drunk dudes
trying to hook up
with each other.
- This was less than
24 hours ago.
- I'm trying to remember
but...
I think he was just, uh,
another party guy, you know?
Bouncing around, dancing,
talking to 20 different dudes
at once looking to get
a free vodka tonic.
You know what I mean?
- What about a different guy?
Medium build,
wearing a black hoodie,
driving a blue van
at some point.
You remember somebody
like that?
- Um, I want to help,
I really do,
but I don't be looking
at these dudes
and the clothes
they be wearing.
You know what I'm saying?
- Sure.
- Not that it's a big deal
or anything.
One life, one love right?
- Okay, well, if you remember
anything, just give us a call.
I'm gonna get Kelly to pull
the club's credit card records
from last night.
- Yeah, especially since
Holden would talk
to anybody
who'd buy him a drink.
Guy definitely wanted us
to know he was not gay.
- Yeah, that mindset is still
prevalent in my community,
especially with the men.
- Where you going?
- Oh, to the outreach center
down the block.
- For what?
- Well, my cousin works there.
He's a pastor.
Might know something.
- Worth a shot.
- Yeah, I've seen a few
of these guys before.
Never counseled any of them
one on one, though.
Wish I had...maybe that
would've changed their outcome.
- Come on,
let's not do this again, okay?
These kids were targeted
because of one man's
self-hatred
and not because
they didn't have
enough Jesus in their lives.
- I know.
I just wish I could've helped.
Find a way to get them out
of this lifestyle, you know.
These guys are sellin' drugs,
turning tricks, you name it--
just so they can get
their next meal.
- Terrence,
like I've always told you
you cannot save everybody.
Okay?
- What about the people
you have counseled?
Any whispers about anyone new
or dangerous
in the neighborhood?
- There's always someone
preying on these young men.
Most of them are runaways,
out of work.
Makes them ripe
for exploitation.
- These murders are
pretty recent, so the person
we're looking for probably
just showed up on the scene.
Guessing he's aggressive.
Probably hookin' up sexually
with these young men...
before he kills them, that is.
- There's a guy named Isaac.
He extorts a lot
of the homeless
making them pay for protection,
using violence if they refuse.
As you can imagine,
they're broke so...
- So they turn tricks.
- You know if anyone's ever
reported him to the cops?
- These men
don't trust the police.
Plus, this Isaac dude's
pretty scary.
I've seen him a few times.
He carries a knife on his belt.
He isn't shy
about using it either.
- All right, what else do
we know about Mr. Jones here?
Aside from the fact
that he has a penchant
for cheap neck tattoos.
- Has a long history
of robbery and assault.
Currently has an arrest warrant
in the system
for the latest one.
- Good.
Means you can drag
his ass in for questioning
whether he likes it or not.
Do we have
a last known address?
- He's got a small house
in Brownsville.
67th and Foster,
the rough part.
- The really rough part.
I made some arrests
in that area back in the day.
- You never told me
you worked that beat.
- You never asked.
- Well, since Tiff
is apparently familiar
with the area, you want us
to go pick Isaac up?
- Uh, you guys have already
been
on the wrong side
of a fight today.
- Yeah, Maggie and OA
are still in the field.
They can handle it.
- Isaac Jones.
- Yeah.
- FBI.
- Is everything all right?
- Just need to
have a word with you.
[dramatic music]
♪
[whispering]
- FBI, go, go.
- Hey, come on, man.
- You take left.
I'll take right.
♪
- Hey.
Are you good?
- Yeah, thanks.
- What the hell are these?
- You know exactly
what these are.
Their pictures
of your victims.
- You think I killed
these people?
You out of your damn mind.
- It doesn't matter
what we think, Isaac.
It matters what we can prove.
- I'm not guilty,
so how you gonna prove that?
- Right now the knife
you tried to filet me with
is in the crime lab.
What are the odds
that it is a match
to the murder weapon
used to kill these men?
- Zero.
I don't kill people.
I protect them.
- You mean you extort them.
You shake them down
for money or else.
Is this what happens to
the people who don't pay you?
- Come on, I'm a businessman
just like every other
security firm.
I offer my services
for a fee.
If somebody don't need it,
that's cool.
I got enough clients as it is.
Killers like this,
putting dudes in the dirt,
it's good for business.
Then the other day
there was this one guy,
they call him Crabtree--
he almost got grabbed up.
Got away and told all
his friends.
Now they really trippin'.
Gonna have to pay me double.
- What do you mean
he almost got grabbed up?
By who?
- I don't know, some guy.
Tried to throw him in the back
of the van and he got away.
And like I said, business
has been good ever since.
[buzzer]
- Hey, guys.
Lab just called.
Isaac's knife is not a match.
- So he's got more than one.
- Yeah, likely.
But, uh, we scrubbed some
building security footage
across the street
from where he lives.
Found time-stamped video
of him at his house
when Holden was killed,
so he's not our killer.
- Well, it might not
be a complete waste of time.
Isaac might've just given us
a witness.
He said some guy named Crabtree
almost got abducted
the other day.
- Really? Crab--Crabtree?
- Street name.
- Right.
- Yeah I--I know the name.
Sells dope, hustles older men.
Picks some pockets too.
Whatever it takes
to make a buck.
- Don't suppose you know
his full name?
- Um, no--not
off the top of my head,
but I take
pretty detailed notes
of all the people I counsel.
I can check my files.
Uh, I tried putting
him into programs,
but he just keeps
going back to the life.
- Um, thanks so much
for helping out, cuz.
We really appreciate it.
- Yeah, of course.
- Take a lot of photos too.
Wow, you weren't kidding
about these notes.
This is impressive.
- Please don't do that.
These people deserve
their privacy.
There's a lot of personal
information in here.
- I apologize.
- Crabtree's full name
is on the back.
Please let him know I'm here
to help if he wants it.
- All right, so
Phillip Johnson, aka Crabtree,
how do we find this guy?
What do we know?
- Uh, not much.
No permanent address.
Hustler, runs at night.
- Which means he fits
the profile
of the other victims.
- He has six solicitation
arrests too.
- But the last three were
in a four block radius
of Christopher Street.
- Okay, yeah.
Let's set up over there
and see if we can't find
Mr. Crabtree.
- Is that him?
- Yeah.
Hey, Crabtree, FBI.
We just want to ask you
a few questions.
- What's going on?
I--I didn't do nothing.
- You're not in trouble,
okay, like she said,
we just have a few questions.
- Okay. About what?
- Couple days ago, a guy
in a van tried to grab you.
Is that true?
- Yeah. What about it?
- What color was it?
- Blue.
- Can you tell us
what he looked like?
- No. It was dark in the spot
where he pulled up.
And he was wearing gloves
and a hoodie pulled low
over his face.
- Did he try to talk to you?
Like as a customer, a john?
Is that how
he got close to you?
- No, it wasn't anything
like that.
To be honest, I thought
it was this preacher I know
from the church.
He drives a blue van
just like that.
So I went over to say hey,
but this dude jumped out
and tried to grab me.
- Was he medium build?
Did you see a knife?
- Look, I don't know.
- Well, come on.
You gotta remember something
that can help us out.
- Look, hand to God, I swear
I didn't--I didn't see no face.
I don't know how big he was,
but he was Black for sure.
I saw a little bit of his arm
when he tried to grab me.
[sirens wailing]
- Come on.
- FBI, what's going on?
- Busboy taking out the trash
called it in.
[dramatic music]
♪
- Listen up--bad news is
our killer has struck again,
which means he is not
afraid of the cops.
In fact, the thrill
of the kill seems to be
accelerating his activity.
So let's revisit
what we know so far--
he is Black, medium build,
carries a knife,
and used to drive a blue van.
- And we have his shovel.
- Yep, and we have his shovel,
though we don't know who bought
it or from where.
Not yet anyway.
Any update, Elise?
- Not yet.
I've got over 100 people
on video buying
that exact shovel
from various stores
throughout New York.
Knowing the suspect is Black
is helpful.
I can narrow the search
even more.
- Once you get facial rec hits
on the buyers,
make sure you prioritize those
with a violent criminal
history.
- No, no, no that's right.
Look.
- Hi.
- What's up?
- So I just finished scrubbing
some new security video
from a street cam down
the block from Don John's.
Captures
the club's side entrance.
- Did you get Holden
talking to anybody?
- No, Holden was not
in any of the footage
but Tiff's cousin,
Terrence, was.
- The pastor?
- He was at Don John's
the night that Holden
was murdered,
and it did not look like he was
on official church business.
- Okay, that's weird
that a pastor would party,
but it doesn't prove anything.
- No, but it's more than that.
Think about it, okay?
Terrence is familiar
with the type of victims this
type of killer is targeting.
I saw his files.
Lots of long lens shots
like he's stalking these guys.
And he drives a light blue van
as part of the outreach.
- We already got
the killer's van.
- I know, but it's the same
type used by the church.
Could be the reason
the victims got inside.
If Terrence is the killer,
okay,
and I'm not saying
that he is,
stealing the same type of van
that he drives for the church,
that's a clever move.
- I mean it's possible but--
- It could just be
a weird coincidence.
Look bottom line
is that Terrence knew
that Holden was at Don John's
the night that he was killed,
but Terrence never mentioned
that he was there too.
- That is weird.
Did you run it by Tiff?
- No.
I get it, okay? I know.
I just wanted to bounce it off
you guys first
to make sure
I'm even clear-eyed on this.
- What do you think?
- It seems valid to me.
♪
- There's no way
Terrence is involved in this.
I mean, I don't know why
he was at that club
but--but I can talk to him
about that.
- No. Not until we dig deeper.
- Jubal's pulling
Terrence's phone's GPS
to see if he was at the park
the night of Holden's murder.
- This is crazy.
Why the hell didn't you tell me
about this first?
Look, I know my cousin.
He--he's a pastor for a reason.
He doesn't have a violent bone
in his body.
- Hey I ju--just got the return
on Terrence's phone records.
- And...
- His phone is shut off
every night around 9 p.m.,
so there's no way to track him
during the time of the murders.
- So what?
That doesn't make him a killer.
- No, but it creates questions
that we need answers to.
- Okay, fine.
I'll get them for you.
- No. Let's have Maggie and OA
bring him in for questioning.
- Bring him in?
Is that really necessary?
- If he has an alibi
we can confirm,
it's gonna be
a short interview.
If not. we're gonna take
a deeper dive into your cousin.
Listen, I know
that neither of these scenarios
are ideal for you.
Which is exactly why
you need to recuse yourself.
Stand down until we know more.
Am I clear?
- Yes, ma'am.
No heads up, for real?
- Tiff, I just wanted to
make sure that--
- We're trying to help you,
Terrence.
But if you're telling us
that nobody can confirm
your whereabouts at the times
of the murders--
I mean, you're making our job
a lot harder.
- [huffs] This is crazy.
I--I help people like this.
I don't kill them.
Where's Tiff?
- Well you can talk to her
in a bit,
but first we need to know
about your cell phone.
- Okay. What about it?
- Um, why do you turn it off
every night?
- I--I work outreach.
Most of the people
that I deal with
are--are night owls, bipolar,
or--or drug addicts.
They've lost their way.
You--you have to set boundaries
with people like that.
So for peace of mind,
and--and, you know,
time to study the scripture,
I shut my phone off at night.
- Well, two nights ago
there was a kid, Rob Holden,
who was seen outside a club,
Don John's,
shortly before being killed.
- Yeah, yeah, I know.
Tiff told me.
- Right.
- Did you talk to him there?
- [laughs] What?
[laughing] No!
I wasn't there at the club.
Why would I go there?
- Why lie to the FBI
about that?
I mean, I know he's a preacher
and all, but it's 2021.
Times have changed.
- Not for everyone.
- So, um, for the record,
you're saying this isn't you?
- No, that's--
That's not me.
I mean, sure, uh, same height,
same build but--
Look, I--I was definitely
not at that club.
[uneasy music]
♪
- Do you own a black hoodie?
- Yeah, and so do a thousand
other New Yorkers.
Hey, do I need a lawyer?
[phone rings]
- What the hell is going on?
Terrence wouldn't hurt a fly.
- I know, but there's
some things he has to explain,
and once he does,
he'll be free to leave.
- What things?
Why do they suspect
my son of these murders?
- I can't go into detail
on that, Unc. I'm sorry.
- I am family, Tiff.
What do you mean
you can't go into detail?
- It's a criminal
investigation.
I--I want to tell you
everything, but I can't.
- This is your cousin
we're talking about.
You grew up together,
for Christ's sake.
This is insane.
- I know but my hands are tied.
- I have seen the news.
They think it's a gay man
killing those kids.
A gay man.
People gonna run their mouths,
think that Terrence is like--
i-is like that.
That he's a freak.
It'll ruin his reputation,
all because of you.
And this damn job.
- All right, so we haven't been
able to alibi out Terrence,
but we're holding him
pending further investigation.
We need to search
his apartment.
Look for a hoodie,
the murder weapon,
trophies from the victims,
anything that either
implicates this guy
or proves his innocence.
- What about Tiff?
- I don't want her involved
in any evidence collection
to play it safe.
- Okay, but we don't think
that she's--
- No, I don't,
but if we were to gather
some crucial piece of evidence
and she was present,
the defense
would leverage that.
- Good. Kay.
You okay?
- Yeah.
I just feel bad.
I didn't mean to--
I wasn't trying to
go behind Tiff's back.
- Hey, Terrence lied
about going to the club.
That's not on you.
[tense music]
♪
[buzz]
- Okay, there's no cameras
recording us.
You can talk to me
about any of this.
- Where have you been?
- I'm related to you.
They won't let me be involved.
- Why?
I didn't do anything wrong.
- You lied about
being at that club.
- I wasn't there.
- Terrence!
Okay, now I love you,
but I can't help you
if you keep making bad choices.
And lying to me about this
is the king of bad choices.
Now talk to me off the record
if you have to
but just tell me the truth.
- O--okay I--I was there.
- Yeah, I know,
but why did you lie about it?
- It's a gay club.
I'm a Baptist pastor.
You do the math.
- So you're gay?
- I--I'm not sure.
Maybe.
- T, that's okay.
If--if that's who you are,
that's how you feel,
there's absolutely nothing
to be ashamed of here.
- I know but, uh--
Some people in the community,
they--
- To hell with them.
Now look, I need you to tell me
everything about that night.
I mean, is--is there anybody
that can alibi you out?
Did--did you talk to somebody
or go home with somebody?
- No, I didn't. I didn't.
And I don't want you tellin'
any of your people my business.
I mean that.
- Nobody here's gonna care, T.
- I don't give a damn about
what they think.
I care about what goes
in that report.
If it's documented,
the church will find out,
and it will ruin everything
that I've worked for.
So this needs to stay
between you and me.
Promise me.
- If I can't go in the field,
I can at least help out here.
Um, Elise, where are we at
with the shovel?
- I've got it narrowed down to
at least 12 potential suspects
but I still need to run
criminal histories
on most of them.
- I know this guy.
Okay, I can't go into detail
but my cousin isn't good
for these murders.
You're just gonna have to
trust me on this.
The real killer
is still out there,
and I think I know who he is.
The man buying a shovel
in this photo is Greg Robinson.
He's a bouncer at Don John's
and he was seen
talking to Holden
just before he was murdered.
- All right, it's worth chasing
but it still doesn't
alibi out your cousin--
at least not yet.
- Terrence is gay.
Or at least he suspects
that he might be.
That's why he lied.
He was afraid that the church
would find out
and fire him
and he would lose everything.
- I understand,
but suppressed sexuality
fits perfectly
with our killer's profile.
- Hey, we ran
Robinson's cell phone GPS.
He was near
New York National Park
the night of Holden's murder.
- Near the park or at the park?
- Near. Cell phone tower
coverage in that area
is spotty and no way
to pinpoint the exact location.
- So all we have against him
is circumstantial evidence.
- He was seen buying the same
shovel that the killer used.
He's good for this.
- OA's over at Don John's.
Greg Robinson's not on shift,
but his cell in pinging
in that area.
- Because he's looking
for his next victim.
- All right have OA stay there.
See if Robinson circles back.
The rest of them can start
a grid search on foot.
Wait not you.
Listen I want him to be
the killer as much as you do,
but until we know for sure
you need to step aside
and let the others handle this.
- Okay, phone's pinging
into this building.
I think we should split up.
Cover more ground.
I'm going to take
the east side.
- All right, I'll go west.
[dramatic music]
Entering the back
of the building now.
- The street's clear.
I'm heading down the alley.
- Oh, easy. Up you go.
- [wheezing]
- Hey, hey, hey,
look at me, kid.
You're gonna be okay.
I'm FBI, all right?
We got a man down
in the west alley.
I need an ambulance
to 8th and Hudson asap.
- Scola, I'm on my way.
- Hey, can you tell me
who did this to you?
Which way he went?
♪
[man wheezing, gasping]
[gunshot]
- Suspect down.
Roll a second ambulance.
- I'll cover.
- Hey, can you hear me?
- [gasping]
- Just stay with me, okay?
- Hey, hey, hey, hey,
stay with me.
Come on.
- [gagging]
[exhales]
- He's dead.
You went into the field
after I specifically
ordered you not to.
- I know and I'm sorry.
Whatever punishment you decide
upon, I won't contest it.
- Scola also told me how
you saved his life out there.
Which is why I don't think
this needs to be
anything more than
a verbal reprimand.
- Thank you.
I really appreciate that.
- Have a seat.
Unfortunately, when it comes
to your cousin,
I cannot offer him
the same leniency.
- What do you mean?
- The ADIC has weighed in.
She says there has to be
consequences
for people who lie
to the FBI.
- I only held back
because I was afraid.
I didn't want to--
- I know.
I get it.
But your lies prevented us
from doing our job.
Terrence, if you had
told the truth...
that last victim,
he'd be alive right now.
Two people were killed tonight,
T, you get that, right?
I just wish you had told me.
I wish you would've been honest
from the beginning because...
lying to an agent--
that's a felony.
And now my hands are tied.
[buzz]
I'm sorry.
- Tiff--
- Can you just, uh, please.
- Tiff.
- You got to stand up, T.
Hands behind your back.
You going to be all right, T.
All right?
Okay?
I'll be with you
every step of the way.
Just like always.
All right?
- [sighs]
- I know that you're upset.
But I was just trying
to protect you.
- You know, if you would've
come to me first--
if you would've told me
what you were thinking,
I could've gone in there
and gotten answers
before Terrence had a chance
to lie to Maggie and OA.
- You were too close to it.
If Terrence had been the killer
you could've said something
or done something.
I just wanted to
keep you out of it, Tiff.
'Til we knew for sure
what was going on.
- You know,
if you really knew me...
I mean, as a person...
you'd know I'd never do
anything to compromise a case.
Even if family was involved.
And that's the real problem
with this partnership
is that we don't talk.
Like real talk.
You can't expect me
to reveal things about my life
when you stay so damn
buttoned up all the time
just to project this idiotic
of quiet toughness.
- You're right.
Maybe it is time...
to have some
real conversations.
Not just small talk.
- I'm down for that.
[wolf howls]