[Narrator] This is James Henry Trotter.
He lived with his mother and father in a cozy little house by the sea.
- Hey, I 've got ya! - [ Giggling ]
Happy birthday, darling. Now, quickly, blow them out before the wind does.
Make a wish first.
[Narrator] It was a wonderful life.
Theyhad each other, and theyhad their dreams.
Look!
That cloud looks like a camel.
And that one over there looks like a train engine.
Can you see the tallest building in the world?.
I can't find it.
Try looking at it anotherway.
[James] Isee it!
That's wherewe're going--
on the great ship thatwill take us across the ocean,
and we'll go right to the top ofthat building.
The three ofus... on top oftheworld.
Are there any kids there like me?.
Hundreds ofthem. It's a wonderful place,James.
A citywhere dreams come true.
[Narrator] Then one day, a terrible thing happened.
[ Thundering]
An angry rhinoceros appeared out ofnowhere...
and gobbled up his poor mother and father.
Their troubles-- ifthey had any at all--
were over in 35 seconds flat.
[ Roari ng ]
- ButJames's troubles werejust beginning, - [ Gaspi ng ]
for now he lives here with Aunt Sponge...
Get up, you lazy little bug!
- andAunt Spiker. - You've already wasted four minutes of daylight.
Look at him, lollygagging in dreamland,
when there's so much work to do.
[Aunt Sponge ] Weeds to pull, wood to chop.
[ Together ] Work, work, work, work, work!
Eww. Wouldn't want one of those nesting in your knickers.
I look and smell-- [ Sniffs ]
I do declare-- as lovely as a rose.
Just feastyour eyes upon my face.
Observe my shapely nose.
Beholdmyheavenly, silkylocks.
And If I take off both my socks,
you'll see my dainty toes. [ Giggles ]
But don't forget, my dearest Sponge,
how much your tummy shows!
- [ Snickering ] - [ Flustered Gasping ]
You lazybug! Who toldyou to stop working?
I finished the wood.
A travel book?. How dare you even dream ofleaving?.
This is the only home you'll ever have.
No one else would tolerate a worthless little nothing likeyou.
Where did you get this?. Where?.
Father gave it to me. He said we're to go there one day.
Stupid, foolish man!
[Aunt Sponge]Foolish man, always dreaming. That's what got him killed.
- And your mother. - Had his head in the clouds...
instead of looking where he was going.
[ Aunt Spiker ] He never even saw that rhino coming.
That rhino!
And the beast will getyou too ifyou don't behave.
Now get these stupid dreams out ofyour head...
[Together] and get back towork!
[Wind Gusting ]
-~~[Man Singing On Radio] - Careful, Spongy. Wouldn'twant to ruin that girlish figure.
Oh, shut up!
- Yes?. - I finished all ofthe chores.
What a coincidence! We finished all the dinner.
Oh, Sponge, you're such a tease.
There's something special waiting foryou in the oven.
[Chuckling]
- [Insect Buzzing] - [ Disgusted Grunt ]
[ Gulps ] Oh, do let me guess: They're not good enough for him.
What doyou think this is, Buckingham Palace?.
- Yuck! - [Buzzing Continues]
-[Aunt Sponge] Get out ofoursight! - Go on!
Go on!
[ Burps ]
Hello, there. Where did you come from?.
You know, you probably shouldn't build yourweb up here in the window.
Spiker and Sponge might seeyou, and they hate spiders.
I'll beyourfriend, though.
~ My name is James ~
~That's what Mother called me ~
~So it's always been ~
~Sometimes I forget ~
~When I'm lonely or afraid ~
~ And I'll go inside my head ~
~ And lookforJames ~
Here's something I've never shown anyone.
~There's a city that I dreamed of~
~Veryfarfrom here ~
~Very, veryfar awayfrom here ~
~Veryfar away ~
~There are people in the city ~
~ And they're kind to me ~
~ But it's very, veryfar away you know ~
~Veryfar ~
~They'll say,James ~
~James,James ~
~ How areya ~
~ Isn'ta lovelyday~
~James,James,James ~
~We're so glad you came here ~
~Wherewe are ~
~ From sovery, very veryfar ~
~ My name is James ~
~James ~
~James ~~
Good night. Pleasant dreams.
[AuntSpikerScreaming] Aah! Spider! Vermin!
Oh, beast! [ Gasping ]
No, wait!
- Sponge! - Wait, I'll get it! I'll get it.
Kill it! Kill it! Kill it!
- Where is it?. Whoo! - Aah!
[ Both Grunting ]
- Get it! Get it! Aah! - [ Breathlessly] Kill it.
-Aah! Get it, get it! - Kill it!
Get it! Aah!
You hit me in the face. You hit me in the face!
[AuntSpiker] Oh, doshut up!
[ Panting ]
Go on, get out ofhere. Get as far away from this place as you possibly can.
Oh, I wish I could.
- What's stoppingyou? - [ Gasps ]
Oh, don't be frightened,James. I meanyou no harm.
- How'd you know my name?. - [ Soft Chuckle ]
I know more than just your name.
What wouldyou say ifl were to tellyou...
that the answer to all your troubles is right here...
- inside this little bag?. - Hey, that's my--
Ofcourse it is! Go on,James.
Have a look.
There's more magic in them things than in all the rest ofthe world put together.
But... what are they?.
- Crocodile tongues. - Tongues?.
One thousand long, slimy crocodile tongues,
boiledin the skull ofa dead witch for 20 days and 20 nights.
Add the fingers of a young monkey, the gizzard of a pig,
the beak of a parrot and three spoonfuls of sugar.
Stew for a week, and then let the moon...
- [ Gasps ] - do the rest.
Have 'em,
and marvelous things will happen; things even you never dreamt of.
- Like what?. - Well, like...
you'll neverbe miserable again.
Andyou are miserable, aren'tyou,James?
You weren't meant to be, you know?
And that place you're dreaming of--
I t's not as far away as you think.
[James ] New York City!
And it'll be that much closer once you take the first step.
But how?. This doesn't make any sense.
Not up here it doesn't. The answers are in here,
and the magic is in here.
So,James, what'll it be?.
Now listen to me,James. Don't let them get away, because ifthey do...
they'll work theirmagic on whoever or whatever theymeet first.
Understand?
- [ Wind Blasting ] - Good.
[Aunt Spiker] What's going on out here?
- Uuh! Oh! No, wait! - [ Tongues Squealing ]
Wait! No! No, wait!
Wait, just a--
- Wait. - [Aunt Sponge ] Here he is.
Get up, you little worm! We sentyou out here to kill a spider!
- Not to laze about. - I wasn't lazing about. I tripped.
- How dareyou disagree with us! - Beat him, Sponge.
[ Sighs ] It's too early.
Well, that makes you the luckiest boy alive.
Now come inside and get dressed!
[Yawns ]
Spiker, look! A peach!
- Awhat?. - A peach!There, on that branch.
[Aunt Spiker] Why, that old tree's never hadso much as a blossom on it, let alone a--
Well, I'll be blowed. There really is a peach there.
A nice, big one too.
How can we get it?.
- The boy! Now, you be a good little boy... - The boy!
and climb up there and get that peach foryour dear aunties.
- Can we eat it?. - Of course we can. We'll share it.
Me and your Aunt Spiker! Now start climbing.
- Wait! - [Aunt Sponge] What?
- What, what? - It's-- It's growing.
- The boy?. - No, the peach, you idiot!
[Aunt Spiker] Look.
Oh! Come down!
- But I won't get hurt. - Climb down!
What a peach. What a peach!
Look, Spiker, it's still growing!
I'm not blind, you dolt. I can see for myself.
- Ohh! - Ohh!
Look at it go! It's a miracle.
It's coming down! Stand back!
[ Aunt Sponge Whimpering ]
[Aunt Spiker] Oh, myheavens! My--[Gasps]
Marvelous things will happen, just like he said.
Shut up, you little grub.
This has nothing to dowith you, sojust keep awayfrom it.
Oh! [Sniffing] Canyousmell that, Spikey?
- It smells delicious. - No!
It smells like... money.
[Children Chattering]
[Aunt Sponge ] Roll up, roll up. See the giant peach.
The Eighth Wonder ofWorld.
Have your money ready, ladies and gentlemen. Chance of a lifetime.
Ten bob only!
No peeking at the peach! Haveyour money ready, ladies and gentlemen.
Inyougo.
- Can we touch it?. - Touch it?. You want to touch it?.
Huh! She'll be wanting to taste it next.
Admission refused. This child has too many cheeky ideas. Go away!
- [Aunt Sponge] Quite right! - Ooh, Sponge.
- [Aunt Spiker Giggling] - [Aunt Sponge ]A photographer.
- [ Shutter Clicking ] - And another.
- Best side. - [Shutter Clicking]
- Move on in. - No cameras allowed.
Don't dawdle! Come along, ladies andgentlemen. Sorry, Father, it'll costyou double.
- May God forgive you. - Thankyou, Father.
[Aunt Sponge, Voice Echoing] Come along, children. Last chance ofthe day.
[Singsong Voice ] Yoo-hoo! Come down here.
Yes, Auntie Sponge?.
Oo-ooh, you're all spiffed up.
I was hoping to play with the children.
- Aww! - Aww! The children have gone.
Butyou can play with their garbage.
Heh, heh, heh! Garbage! Heh, heh, heh!
[Aunt Spiker Chuckling] And don't even think ofgoing near ourpeach.
'Cause ifyou do-- You know, they never did catch that rhino.
[ Both Chuckling ]
[ Sighing ]
- [ Tongue Squealing ] - [ Gasps ]
No! Wait a moment! Wait!
[ Disappointed Sigh ]
[ Sniffing ] Ahh.
Mmm. Mmm.
[ Gasping ]
[Female Voice]'Ere, now. Where doyou thinkyou're goin', Yank?
[Male Voice #1 ] I'm goin'stir-crazy. I gotta take a look around.
- Plan our escape from Spiker and Sponge. - [ Male Voice #2 ] Escape?
To where? We'll all be squashed... swatted... smooshed!
No one's goi ng to " smoosh" you, my dear boy.
- You're six feet long now. - Bigger target.
Let the biddies come. I'll take 'em both on.
I'm "indefeatable." I'm indivisible. I'm...
- Whoa! - in trouble!
- [ All Grunting, Screaming ] - It's Spiker and Sponge!
They've foundus!
- Hel-lo! - Oof! Uuh!
No, no, no. It's the lad from the house. What's his name?.
- Miserable Tick. - I thought it was Rotten Little Grub.
- No, that's what those horrible aunts call him. - [James Shrieks ]
His real name is-- Well, it's, eh, eh--
- It's James. - Aaah!
Lookwhatyou've done now, miss. Scared him to death.
Please! Don't eat me!
- Eat you?. - [ Laughing ]
Hey, Glowworm, turn upyour lights.
- [ Electrical Crackling ] - Ahh!
- I'm a vegetarian. - I eat dirt.
No onewill be eating you, James.
Yeah, she'll just punctureyour head and suck out the brains.
- That I am saving foryou. - Whoa! Prettyfast, long legs.
- [ Hissing ] - Oh-oo-oo!
Oh, such rude behavior. There's no need to be frightened, dearie.
Butyou're enormous bugs!
- Fascinating, isn't it?. - We've all changed...
- and so haveyou,James. - [ Gasps ]
The old man-- the one who gave me the green things--
He said marvelous things will happen.
Did he say, " Marvelous pigs in satin"?.
No, dear lady. " Marvelous things will happen."
Poor Glowworm. She's a little deaf.
I, however, have exquisite hearing.
- Yeah?. Well, listen to this. - [ Flatulent Noises ]
- Let's get outta here! - Waa-aa!
You mean leave the hill?. I can't. The rhino will get me.
Rhino?.
[ Chuckles ] I say, dear boy, I've lived on this miserable hill for decades.
- There are no rhinoceri here. - Except for Sponge.
- She's twice as big as a rhino, eh, kid?. [ Chuckles ] - [ Giggles ]
And twice as dangerous. My life hangs by a thread every day.
I've had to send all 300 of me children to safer pastures.
Hah! You think hiding in solid rock is fun?.
I can't even remember what fun is.
Well, it's just 'causeyou've been stuck here too long. Listen to me, kid.
I know a place that'll refresh your memory.
~ Bright lights Big city ~
~That's wherewe gotta go ~
~Where the food is great and the bugs are so pretty ~
~ I'd like to get my arms around a hundred or so ~
~ I'd hug 'em, squeeze 'em hold 'em tight ~
~Sleep all day Dance all night ~
~ I want the bright lights and the big city ~
~That's the life for me,yeah ~
~That's the life for-- ~~
~You little maggot Haveyou never seen the moon ~
~Gliding 'cross thewestern sky ~
~ A dead oaktree bythewaterside ~
~ Putrid vapors rising ~~
[ Coughing ] That sounds lovely, dear. I'm surewe'd all agree.
~ But I preferthe sunshine ~
~ A little park right in the center ofthe town ~
- ~ La-la ~ - ~ Flowers everywhere Children all around me ~
~ I'd love it Landing on a baby's cheek sowarm ~
- ~ It's wonderful, wonderful ~ - [ Sniffing ]
- ~That's the life for me ~ - ~ Ah-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha ~
~That's the life That's the life for me ~~
~ Elegant conversation ~
- ~ Bright lights, big city ~ - ~ An elevated point ofview ~
- ~That's where I'd go ~ - ~ Intellectual stimulation ~
- Yeah, maybe foryou. - ~ And someoneyou love to share itwith you ~
[All ] ~ Itwould bewonderful, wonderful ~
- ~That's the life for me ~ - You call that a life?.
- ~That's the life for me ~ - It's no pile ofdirt!
~That's the life That's the life ~
- ~ For-- ~~ - [AuntSponge] Where areyouhiding, boy?
Hup! Time to go make a pest of myself. Heh-heh!
Look at this place. It's still filthy.
[Aunt Spiker] Where areyou,you detestable worm?
- Aah! - Not you! Me!
You better not be near our peach!
Oh, please! Don't let them spray us!
Spray us?. They'll see the Yank up there and come after us with a shovel.
- It happened to my brother. - How awful.
Split him right down the middle. Now I have two half-brothers.
Shh! They'll hear us.
[Aunt Spiker] Yoo-hoo! Where areyou, boy?
I think I hear a rhino out here!
Ahh! This'll be a snap.
[Sawing Sound]
Shh! I really do hear something.
[ Whispering ] Timber.
[ Crashing, Rumbling ]
- What's that?. - Fasten your seat belts, kids!
- Aaah! The car! - Aaah! The car!
- We're turning! - Wha-Wha-Wha-- What haveyou done?.
[ Screaming ]
- Start, start, you piece ofjunk! - [ Engine Sputtering ]
- Oh! - Oh!
Aaah!
It's the peach! Our peach! We'll be killed!
- Whoa-oa-oa! - Oh! Ouch! Oh!
Aaah!
[ Centipede] Here, stomach! Here, stomach! Here, stomach!
[ Clucking ]
[ Crowing ]
[ Frightened Moaning ]
- I'm gonna be sick! - Yee!
- Our peach! - Our peach!
[Crashing]
[James] Where are we?
[ Earthworm ] Ow! Somebody pinched me!
Sorry. I thought you were the Spider.
- [ Indignant Gasp ] - Ouch! What was that?.
Excuse. I thought you were the Centipede.
Hey, Glowworm, how about some light?.
I can't hearyou, dear. I'll have to put my light on.
- Oh! Oh! This is so un-ladybug-like! - [ Electrical Crackling ]
- Don'tworry. I'll haveyou right-side up in no time. - Oh!
Thankyou,James. Where areyou going?.
To see where we've landed.
[ Sea Gulls Cawing ]
Whoa!
Oh, my!
Oh, my, my!
Oh, my achin' back!
Ohh! Fascinating, isn't it?.
[ Earthworm ] What?. What's fascinating, tell me?. Don't leave me dangling.
We're in the middle ofthe-- How doyou say?. The big puddle.
- The biggest puddle ofthem all, angel fangs: - [ Smacks Lips Contemptuously]
- the Atlantic Ocean. - Technically, the Pacific is larger.
Well... that goes without saying.
- But there is land in sight?. - Nothing but blue skies and clearwaters.
Uuuh! This is all yourfault!
Hey! Wasn't for me, we'd all be Spiked and Sponged by now!
This old man with his green things-- did he happen to speak towherewe are going?.
No. All he said was the answers would be right here.
Huh?. Mytravel book!
And look! It's the peach!
We'regoing to New York City!
- [ Coughs ] NewYork?. They love me there! - Wonderful! They've got...
- a whole park full ofleaves foryou, Miss Ladybug. - Oh!
- Central Park! - And loads of dark hiding places.
- Nightclubs! - And museums and concerts.
- Not to mention Yankee Stadium. - What about me?.
- Why, they've got miles and miles ofunderground tunnels! - The subway!
Myfather says it's the place where dreams come true.
- ~That's the life for me ~ - ~That's the life for me ~
- ~That's the life ~ - ~That's the life ~
~That's the life That's the life ~
~ For me ~~
NewYork it is then. Now, how dowe get there?.
- I'll get us there. - You?.
Sure! I've sailed all the five seas:
from the sun-drenched wreaths of Bora Bora...
to the icy shores ofTripoli.
- Oh! - Commodore Centipede,
- [ Yawns ] - they used to call me.
- Seven. - Huh?.
There are seven seas.
And Tripoli is in the subtropics... Commodore.
- Trim the sails! - There are no sails.
- Stoke the engines! - There are no engines.
I can't work with this miserable crew.
Great! We're stuck here until we shrivel up and die.
- Highly improbable. - That's a relief.
- We're far more likelyto drown. - [ Gasps ]
- [Ladybug] Oh, no! - [ Cawing ]
I know! We could--
No, it's a stupid idea.
- Compared towhat?. - Hey!
Well, we could fly out.
- Mm-mm. - He's right. It's stupid.
- [ Grunting ] - How would you do it,James?.
With the sea gulls. But we'll need string.
Oh, well, I'll just go to the stationer's and pick up some paper clips while I'm at it!
I have string. Miles ofstring.
Andwe'llneedbait; birdbait.
Bird bait?. Where doyou expect we're gonna find bird bait out here in the middle ofthe--
- [ Clanging ] -The-- Oh, no.
No, no! Haveyou lostyour minds?. Aah!
They've lost their minds! Anything but birds!
[Whispering ] Don'tworry, I'm right here.
- Nowwiggle. - No!
- But theywon't come ifyou don'twiggle. - Exactly, and you can't make me.
- Oh, yeah?. [ Babbling, Chuckling ] - Stop! Ah-ha-ha!
[ Laughing ] Oh! Hey, no fair! Mockingbirds munched me mother!
Here comes the first one. Get readyto pull down there.
Mysisters wereswallowedbyswallows! [Laughing Continues ]
- Pull! - [ Earthworm ] Whoo!
[ Whimpering Screech ]
It worked! I got one!
Shh! I hear teeth. Great, big, gnashing teeth!
- [ Low Rumbling ] - Sounds like a rhinoceros!
In the ocean?. Uh, scientifically impossible.
I hear something too.
It's a school ofTuna.
They're being sucked into some sort ofmachine.
- What doyou mean?. - Take a look.
[ Shrieking ]
[James] It's a giantshark!
[ Alarm Blaring ]
- It seems to have spotted us! - [ Gasps ]
What do we do?. What do we do?.
The sea gulls! It's our only chance.
It would take the whole flock and then some. We'll never do it in time.
We'll use Miss Spider's web for a net. Hurry!
Throw it here, dearie!
Wiggle, Mr. Earthworm! Our lives depend on it!
- I can't! I'm all wiggled out! - Aw!
[ Both Grunting ]
- Here, let me helpyou. - [ Frightened Gasping ]
- [ Screaming ] - Come and get it! Getyourfresh, hotwienie!
- Yaaah! Uugh! - Come on, baby!
[ Grunts ]
I got 'em! Hand me the loops!
- Hurry! - Shake a leg there!
Keepyour pants on! I've only got 1 2 hands.
[ Rumbling ]
It's getting closer!
[ Centipede Grunts ] Sea gulls away!
[All Squawking ]
- [ Both Gasping ] - Oh, no!
- Oh, dear! - [ MachineryStraining ]
Huh-huh-ho! Daah! Uuh!
[ Groaning ]
- Yow! - Oh! - Arf, arf, arf!
[ Straining ]
- Arf! - They're getting away!
Hop on,James!
Now nab them!
[ All Screeching ]
- [ Bellowing ] - [ Barking ]
- Help! - Help!
[Ladybug] Hooligans! Ruffians!
Degenerates!
Uuh! Uhh!
- Come on, sea gulls! - Putyour backs into it!
Shakeyour bloomin' tail feathers!
[ Nervously] Good sharky. Nice sharky.
- [Machinery Booms ] - Oh! Sharky!
- [ Grunts ] - [ Yelling ]
- [Machine Winch Cranking] - [ Exhausted Sigh ]
- Oof! - Gaah!
[ Screaming ]
- Aah! - Oh! Uuh!
[ Machinery Straining ]
[ All Cheering ]
All right!
Teach ya to mess with me, ya overgrown sardine! I'm from Brooklyn!
Oh, ho-ho! Pure twaddle!
Everybug on boarddisplayed extraordinary courage.
Why, did you see Miss Ladybug risk life and wing...
- to bash those brutes on the snoot?. - Ooh!
Well, theywere being very rude. I can't abide rudeness.
We are all forgetting something.
Everything we did was part ofthe brilliant plan ofJames.
It really did work, didn't it?.
Isay, three cheers forJames!
- Hip-hip! - Hooray!
New York...
here... we... co-ome!
- Ooh-ooh! - Whoeveryou are, keep away from me! Keep away!
- Earthworm! It's me! - Wha-Wha-Wha--
Oh,James. Oh, thank goodness.
- You mustn't frighten yourself like this all the time. - Why not?.
You'll makeyourselfsick.
When I had a problem, my mum and dad would tell me to lookat it anotherway.
How?. First I was bird bait, then I was shark bait.
I suppose. Or, you could say you gave us wings to fly,
and defeated a giant shark single-handedly.
No-handedly.
Exactly. You're a hero.
I am?. I'm... WonderWorm!
You are!
Want... food.
Food.
[ Groaning ]
Yousureyou know where we're going?
I don't see howyou can navigate without a compass.
- [ Sighing ] - [Cork Popping]
Huh?.
It's very hot up here. I'm roasted.
[ Shuddering ] Huh?.
[ Screeching To Clucking ]
[ Giggling ]
- Unhand that bird! - Aah-aah!
But I'm dyin' ofhunger!
Oh, perhaps I have a bit ofsoda bread in here somewhere.
- Food?. - It's not much, but it's--
- Not so fast! - Hey! - You?.
I need this food. I have a much higher metabolism.
- Bite me! - What?. - Haveyou two gone mad?.
[Centipede] Let go ofit, Gramps! Give it! Give it to me!
- Let go of my coat! - Give it to me!
- Ow! My lower thorax! - I'll rip you apart!
- I tell you, it's mine! - Give... it... back!
[ Growling, Together] Now lookwhatyou've done!
We're going to starve. Waste away. And not quickly.
Oh, no, that wouldbe the easy way out. We'll linger.
- [ Grunting, Groaning ] - Slowly. Miserably. Painfully.
- Nobody's going to starve. - Eh?.
Don't you see?. We have enough food here for five voyages.
- Food?. Where?. What are you talkin' about?. - Is there really food?.
- Ourwhole ship is made offood! - Oh, such a clever little boy.
- Takes after me. - Afteryou there is nothing left to take.
- It's delectable. Mmm-mmm! - Betterthan aphids.
Mm, betterthan ladybugs.
- What?. - Excuse.
It's not dirt... but it's not bad.
Not bad?. It's the best thing I've ever tasted,
and I have tasted a lot.
~ I've eaten manystrange and scrumptious dishes in my time ~
~ Like chili bugs and curried slugs ~
~ And earwigs cooked in slime ~
~ And mice with rice is very nice ~
~When they're roasted in their prime ~
~ But don't forget tosprinkle them~
~With just a pinch of grime ~
~ I'm crazy about mosquitos on a piece ofbuttered toast ~
~ And pickled spines of porcupines And then a great big roast ~
~ And dragon's flesh quite old not fresh, it costs a buck at most ~
Does it come with gravy?.
~ It comes toyou in barrels ifyou order it by post ~
[ Together] ~ It comes toyou in barrels ifyou order it by post ~
~ For dinner on my birthday ~
~Shall I tell you what I chose ~
~ Hot noodles made ofpoodles on a slice of garden hose ~
~ And a rather smellyjelly ~
~ Made ofarmadillos toes ~
~Thejelly is delicious ~
~ Butyou have to hold your nose ~
-~Peach, peach, peach ~ - ~ Peach, peach ~
~ Peach, peach, peach, peach Peach, peach, peach, peach ~
~ I crave the tasty tentacles of octopi for tea ~
~ I like hot dogs but I love hot frogs and surelyyou'll agree ~
~ A plate of soil with engine oil's a super recipe ~
[ Together] ~ Recipe ~
~ I hardly need to mention that it's practicallyfree ~
~ Peach, peach, peach, peach Peach, peach, peach, peach~
- ~ Peach, peach, peach, peach Peach, peach, peach, peach ~ - ~ Ahh-ahh ~
[ Together] ~We hardly need to mention that it's practically free ~
~ Now comes my fellow travelers the burden of my speech ~
- You show-off! - ~These foods are rare beyond compare ~
~ And some right out of reach ~
- Nice aim, Commodore. - ~ But there's no doubt I'd go without ~
~ A million plates of each ~
Out ofmyface!.
- ~ For one small mite ~ - ~One small mite ~
-~One tiny bite ~ -~Tiny bite ofthis ~
~ Fantastic~
~ Peach~
- ~ Peach, peach, peach, peach Peach, peach, peach, peach ~ - Stop! Stop!
- ~ Peach, peach, peach, peach Peach, peach, peach, peach ~ - Oh!
- [ All Chattering ] - Watch this!
~This fantastic peach ~~
[Snoring, Mumbling]
[ Snoring ]
[ Snoring, Hooting ]
[ Loud Snoring ]
[Yawning] You keep toyourself, don'tyou?
I prefer to be alone.
I was alone for a long time once.
I think it's much nicer to have friends, don'tyou?
I would not know.
Theywould beyour friends too. The others, I mean, ifyou'd just let them.
No, it is in their nature to have fear ofme. This I cannot change.
You'revery kind to me.
Maybe this is because you are kind to me first.
- You were the spider in mywindow. - Mm-hmm.
You were my first friend.
I mean, since I went to live with my aunts. They hated me!
Shh. Do not think ofthem now.
Butwhat iftheyfind us?
What ifwe don't make it to NewYork?
I'll die ifl have to go backto theway I was! They can't make me.
Nobody can makeyou do anything,James,
ifyou do not let them.
You are a brave boy.
Now to sleep.
You have had a very "tired-making" day.
[ Blows ]
[Yawns ]
- [Rumbling] - [ Gasps ]
[ CarSqueaking, Engine Rattling ]
Look, the little maggot's stuffing his facewith our peach!
- Get him, Sponge! - [ Screams ]
You can't crawl away from us!
[ Smoke Hissing ]
[Aunts Chanting] The rhino will getyou. The rhino will getyou.
The rhino will getyou. The rhino will getyou.
The rhino will getyou. The rhino will getyou. The rhino will getyou.
[ Groaning ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Shivering ]
- [ Wind Howling ] - Whoa.
- [ Birds Crying ] - [ Grasshopper] This is an outrage!
You are a disgrace toyourphylum, class, order, genus andspecies!
- Say it in English! - You, sir, are an ass!
Where are we? What's going on?
- I found this dime-store timmy asleep at the helm. - [ Gasps ]
- Now we're lost. - We are not lost!
- Then where are we? - Somewhere north, or possiblyvery, very far south.
What's your latitude? What's your longitude?
Hey, hey, hey! That's personal, bub.
You said you could navigate!
- You said you traveled the world. - You said you'd been to Bora Bora.
Well, not Bora Bora, per se, uh--
What about the shores ofTripoli?
Did I say "Tripoli"? [ Chuckles ] I meant the Halls of Montezuma.
- That's whatyou said. - Never have I heard such mendacity!
- Charlatan! - Wait!
Ifhe says he's seen the world, then he's seen the world. Right, Mr. Centipede?
- Right? - Well...
I did used to live between two pages ofa National Geographic.
Huh?
- [ Gasps ] - Veryinformative magazine, National Geographic. Wonderful pictures.
You incompetent, blithering nitwit!
All right, hoppy! Them's fightin' words.
Put 'em up! Put 'em up! Come on!
Gimmeyour best shot. [ Groans ]
Whoa. Good shot.
[ Spits ] Did you seewhat he did to me?
Hmph! Serves ya right.
What dowe do now? Which way dowe go?
Oh, it's simple, really. All we need to do is determine our coordinates,
then use triangulation to chart a direct route to NewYork.
- Then there's hope. - Don't be ridiculous. There's no hope at all!
We don't have a compass.
We'll never reach New York.
We're gonna be stuck here forever. We're gonna be frozen like living statues.
- Dead living statues. - [ Gasps ]
[Spider] No dark hidingplaces.
[Ladybug] No cozyleafin the park.
- [ Crying ] - [James ] No city where dreams come true.
Don't ships have compasses?
No doubt. But to brave those icy waters...
would mean certain death.
- [ Gulps ] - Onlya fool would do it.
Uh-huh.
Geronimo!
- What? What was that? - The Centipede jumped in!
- [ Gasps ] - Good heavens! He's committed pesticide.
Oh, this is all my doing.
Don't take all the credit. I helped too.
- I have to go after him! - Not on your life. You'll catch your death of cold.
-But he's myfriend. -James is right. Centipede is one ofus.
Get on my back. I'm going with you.
- You had bettertake good care ofhim. - This I promise.
Stay bythe line, and when you feel two tugs, pull us up.
[ CentipedeWhistling ]
A skellington?
Hmm?
Jackpot! A genuine compass!
- [ Squeaking ] - Sounds likeyou need a little oil, Captain.
Thankyou, sir! I'll be shovin' offnow.
- [ Growling ] - [ Screams ] I should'veworn a belt!
[ Gasping, Grunts ]
- [ Roaring ] - Holy shipwreck!
- [ Groans ] - [ Chuckles ]
[Centipede Groaning]
- [ Both Gasp ] - Listen, fellas,
I got a long history ofback problems, and I don't need it to get any longer!
[ Screaming ]
Aaah! Aah!
- [ Bones Cracking ] - Aah! Hey, that one felt pretty good.
- [Rumbling] - [ Growls ]
It's Paul Bunyan coming to cut me some slack. Whoa!
Whoa! Hey, pal, you're aimin'a little low. He's gonna cut me in half!
Hey, sailors! Looking for some kicks?
Oooh! Cut me loose!
[ Growling ]
Get the com pass!
[ Grum bl i ng ] Ah!
- Have got it! - " Ubutu!" [ Grunts ]
[ Warlike Grunts ]
Whoa-oo!
- [ Groans ] - [ Growls ]
- Gotcha! - [ Squawks ]
- Polly want a smacker? - [ Grunts ]
- Look out! - [ Duck Quacks ]
[ Groans ]
- Sounds like big trouble. - Get ready to pull.
[ Captain Growling ]
I got a good one forya.
- Why don't skeletons play music in church? - Oh!
- [ Grunting ] - 'Cause theygot no organs!
- [Bell Ringing] - A-ha-ha!
[ Screaming ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Both ] Noo-oo!
Oh, thank goodness! You're all right!
- What happened to Centipede? - He found a compass for us.
- And a shipload of pirates! - Hold this. I am going back.
Do be careful, Miss Spider.
[ Gasps ] Ohh.
[ Sniffles ]
Poor Centipede.
He saved our lives down there.
- Look out! - Miss Spider!
[ Gasps ]
- [ Laughing ] - Centipede!
How am I lookin', kid?
Centipede, I do not know whether to kill you or... kiss you.
- [ Grunting ] - [Centipede Chuckling]
- I'm so sorry. - Hey, I'm sorry.
- My sincere apologies. - I just wanna apologize.
- I just wanted to say-- - What I'm tryin' to say--
That's enough chitchat! I'm freezin'!
Hello? The compass is ready!
Mr. Centipede, would you please do us the honor of navigating us out ofthis icebox?
- Itwould be my pleasure. - I believe our position puts us very close--
I admireyour bravery, Miss Spider. I really do.
Why... thankyou, Mrs. Ladybug.
All right, boys. Coffee break's over.
- [ Squawking ] - [ Grunting Softly]
I'm looking forward to a hopping good time...
in the Big Apple, Mr. Centipede.
[ Centipede ] You said it, Mr. Grasshopper.
[Yawns ]
Oh, boy, what I wouldn't do for a cup of coffee.
[ Grunting ]
[ Groaning ] Cup ofjoe.
I say, old sport, came to relieveyou ofyour duties.
I said I'd steer the peach. Have to steer the peach.
[ Yawns ] Can't quit... now.
Good show, old boy.
[ Snores, Grunts ]
Thanks... Mr. Grasshopper. [ Snoring ]
~~ [Violin ]
[ Centipede Snoring]
- That music! - Oh, SirJames! Did I disturbyou?
So sorry. [ Stammering ] I'll put this away.
No, no. I like it.
I usedto hearit at myaunt's house before I went tosleep.
That was you, wasn't it? Or do all grasshoppers play music?
All grasshoppers... try.
I'm sureyou've heard this.
- [ Legs Chirping ] - Mm-hmm.
Ghastly, isn't it? Cricket stuff.
Music should be thevoice ofthe soul.
- What does that mean? - It means thatwhen I'm happy,
my music sounds like this.
~~ [ Classical, Upbeat]
- [ Groans ] -~~[Stops]
When I'm sad, it's like this.
~~ [ Classical, Slow]
-~~[Stops] -When I was sad, I used to climb in bed with my mom and dad.
But thatwas a long time ago.
I'm sure they'd be very proud ofyou,James.
I knowwe are.
[Yawning ]
~Take a little time Just lookatwherewe are ~
~We've comevery, veryfar together ~
-~ And ifl might say so ~ -~ And ifl might say so too ~
[Together] ~Wewouldn't have got anywhere ~
~ Ifitweren't foryou, boy ~
~ Love... is thesweetest thing~
~ Love... never comes justwhen you think itwill ~
~ Love... is the way we feel foryou ~
~We're family ~
[ Together] ~We're family ~
- ~We're family ~ - ~ All ofus ~
~ And you ~
- ~Thinkofwherewe'd be ifwewere on our own ~ - We'd be dead.
~You'rewhat holds us all together ~
- I am? - ~ And ifl might say so ~
~ And ifwe might say so too ~
~We never could love anyone ~
~ As much as we loveyou ~
- ~ Love ~ - ~ Is the strangest thing ~
- ~ Love ~ - ~ Does exactlywhat itwants to do ~
- ~ Lo-o-ove ~ - ~ Boy, ya know it's true ~
~We're family ~
~ Me, me, me, me, me And you ~
~ Ashes to ashes ~
~ And dust to dust ~
~Withoutyou there'd be no us ~
~ Love... is the sweetest thing ~
~ Love... does exactly what it wants to do ~
~ Lo-o-ove... is the waywe feel foryou ~
~We're family ~
~ Me ~
~ And... you ~~
We'll always be together, won'twe?
kid, you're stuck with us for life.
[Foghorn Sounding]
- Look, everybody, we made it! - We did?
- [Spider] New York City. - [ Grasshopper] Breathtaking!
- Stunning! - Glorious. - Look at the park.
- [ Centipede ] It's fabulous! - We have made it!
What a wonderful sight! There's Lady Liberty!
[ Sniffs ] I can almost smell the lovely dirt.
- Is it not beautiful? - [James ] The Empire State Building.
- See those lights! - [ Chuckling ]
Wa-hoo! Yippee! Atta boy,Jimmy!
Good show,James. The city awaits us.
Now remember,James, first impression is very important.
[WindBlowing]
[ Sea Gulls Squawking ]
[ Grunting ]
- Oh, no! - [Grasshopper] We'll be blown offcourse.
- We'll wind up in Jersey! - [Thunderclap ]
- Could it be-- - No, it couldn't be.
- [Roaring] - It's the rhino!
Oh,James, do something.
- [ Roaring ] - [ Thunderclap ]
Everyone, climb up into the rigging!
Hurry!
[ Shuddering ]
James, areyou not coming with us?
No!
- It got my mum and dad! Itwon't get myfriends! - [Thunderclap]
Come out and showyourface, you stupid beast!
[ Ferocious Roaring ]
[ Gasps ]
Good God Almighty!
[Thunderclap]
- Rememberwhat your parents said,James! - [Roaring]
"Try looking at it anotherway!"
You're not even a real rhino!
- [ Roaring ] - You'rejust a lot ofsmoke andnoise!
I'm not afraid ofyou!
[ Snarling ]
[ Roaring ]
I'm not afraid ofyou!
[ All Screaming ] Ja--James!
Noo-oo!
[ Crash ]
- [ Coughing ] - [ Squeaking ]
[ Groans ]
Miss Spider?
Mr. Grasshopper?
Hello? Is anyone there?
- [ Gasps ] - [Horns Honking]
This isn't right.
Where's the Empire State Building?
[Horns Honking]
[ Gasping ]
What the--
Officer! There's a boyup there!
What? A boy?
[ Panting ] Mabel, we got us a huge unidentified object here!
- What's it look like? - Round, fuzzy. It looks sorta like a giant fruit or something.
- Well, what is it? - I don't knowwhat it is!
Just send us the biggest crane in NewYork!
[People Chattering]
- Please, sir. How do I get to the Empire State Building? - You're on top ofit, kid?
We made it!
[ Solemnly] Well, I made it.
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
- Hang on. - [Crane Hoisting]
Haveyou seen any big bugs tonight?
- Big bugs? How big? - [Siren Wailing]
I hope they're all right.
[ Crowd Chattering ]
[Truck Horn Honks ]
[ Honks ]
Let's go. Let's go. Stay back. Stay back.
[ Chattering Continues ]
Don't worry, kid. You'll be all right.
Come on, sonny. Don't be afraid now. I got you.
[ Cop ] Stayawayfrom those trucks!
[Reporter] What is this thing?
- Where you from? - Whyyou here?
- Who? What? Where? When? Why? - Holdyour fire, fellas!
He's just a kid, for Pete's sake. Here, I got you.
It's okay, little guy. Nobody's gonna hurt you.
[Horn Honking]
[ Car Approaching]
[ Engine Sputtering ]
[ Rattling, Air Hissing ]
[ Crowd Gasping ]
[ Groans ]
[ Gasps ] No.
[ Sighs ]
- [ Crunching] - [ Gasps ]
Oh! Aaah!
Hello. [ Chuckles ]
Little angel.
- So kindofyou to look after ourlittle lost lamb. - Oh.
- Who are you? - We are the boy's legal guardians.
We've missed him so much.
So we'lljust take him home now.
And the peach, of course. We're taking that as well.
Well, wait a minute. Back up.
You mean to tell me that this thing is a peach?
- It's not a peach. It's our peach. - Our peach.
- Show him, Spongy. - Yes.
[ Panting ]
[ Gasps ]
- Looks like it's theirpeach all right. - Yes!
- Yes. We're very proud of it. - We're going to be in the record books.
It's not their peach. The old man gave the green things to me.
- That's what made it grow. - How dareyou disagree with us!
Patience, sister. Remember his... condition.
- His condition? - He's a chronic liar.
Sad, really. He needs his treatment.
Well, that's whywe're here; to bring him home.
So, you come here with us, hey, lovey!
I'm not the one who's lying. They are!
As you can see, Officer, it is urgent thatyou release him to us immediately.
Let the boy speak!
[ Crowd Murmuring Agreement ]
All right, all right, all right! Let's get to the bottom ofthis!
This thing is a peach.
Now, all right. I'll buythat.
Now, does somebodywanna tell me how it got here?
We attached it to a hundred sea gulls.
Sea gulls? [ Laughing ]
That's what happened! Me and Miss Spider and the Centipede and the Old Green Grasshopper.
- [CrowdLaughing] - I think he's gone mad. [Laughing]
This is all something he dreamed up.
Well, maybe it started that way, as a dream, but doesn't everything?
Those buildings,
these lights, this whole city!
Somebody had to dream about it first, and maybe that's what I did.
I dreamedabout coming here, but then I didit!
- The poor boy needs his medicine. - Yes.
- So we'll just take him. - And the peach.
Back to our cozy little house on the hill.
- Come along. You're going home with us. - No, I'm not.
- [ Skin Cracking ] - What did you say?
I said... no... I'm... not!
I hate that house and that cold room and how I was always hungry.
All right, that's enough!
- And how you beat me! - [ Gasps ] He's lying!
- [ Crowd Gasping ] - And told me I was nothing!
- Shut up! - Shut up! Shut up!
No, not this time! [ Panting ]
I flew the giant peach across the ocean.
I landed on top of the tallest building in theworld.
I made it! I'm not the one who's nothing. You are!
AndI'm nevergoingback withyou! Not me andnot thepeach.
How dareyou speak to us this way.
- [ Aunts ] Aaah! - [Crowd Gasping]
[ Screaming ]
[Whistle Blowing]
[ Grasshopper] James! Up here.
[ Glowworm ] Hello, we're here.
- [ Centipede ] Hey, buddy! - What are they?
- [ Glowworm ] Young James. - Hey,J immy.
- Bugs! - [ Centipede ] Need a little help down there?
- Giant bugs! - [ Gasps ]
Hey, you old biddies! [ Raspberry]
- [ Screams ] - Help us!
- Whoo-ee! Here we are, dear. - Hello,James!
I told you theywere real.
- Hello, old boy. - Requesting clearance to land.
[Sea Gulls Squawking]
[ Gasping, Screaming ]
Miss Spider, throw me a string!
- [ Gasping ] - Okay, pull them up.
[Aunt Sponge ] Help! [Screams ]
Where are we going?
[ Hysterical Screaming ]
- Spin them around! - You little--
[ Gasping, Screaming ]
Wrap them tightly!
[ Screaming Continues ]
Tighter! Tighter!
Well, I'll be a--
- The kid was tellin' the truth. - [ Muffled Shouts ]
Get those two creeps outta here!
[ Muffled Screams ]
[ Crowd Chattering ]
Stop the presses. I got a new front page. " Big Bugs In The Big Apple."
In big bold print: " Little Lindy Flies Giant Peach."
" Half-Pint Hero And His Peach Pit Pals."
[CrowdCheering]
Everyone,
these are myfriends; the ones I've been tellingyou about.
- Mr. Centipede! - Hi.
- Old Green Grasshopper! - My pleasure.
- Earthworm! Mrs. Ladybug! - Charmed.
- Miss Spider! - [ Chuckles ]
- And the Glowworm! - God bless the colonies!
Could we eat some ofyour peach?
- It won't keep forever. - Go ahead.
[ Crowd Cheering ]
Hey! What was your name?
It's James!
[ Cheering Continues ]
[ Old Man Narrating] They ate that peach all the way down to the pit.
Andset it up in Central Park as a permanent home.
AndJames Henry Trotter,
who once was the saddest and loneliest little boyyou could find,
now had a loving new family...
and all the friends in the world.
-J ames, di nner is ready. - Hi, Miss Spider.
All right. Nearly finished.
And-- And then-- And then the sea gulls--
[ Old Man ]AndsinceJames's visitors beggedhim again andagain...
to hear the story ofhis adventure with the giant peach,
he wished for a way to share it with everyone.
And that is exactly...
what you have just seen.
~ Once upon a time there was a vulture and a hog~
~ Livin'in a house up on a hill~
~ Had this little boy who lived with them, they worked him like a dog~
~ With any luck they'd have him up there still ~
~ Along came a magic man with a magic bag ~
~ Full ofnasty little green things in a funky old rag ~
~ He said, "Boy, you may not know it but this here's salvation you see ~
~ Son, you're going down in history" ~
~ Good news is blowin' in your window ~
~ Good news is knockin' on your door ~
~ Good news is comin' 'round the corner ~
~ Good news is rollin' aroundyour floor ~
~ Where can all my troubles be ~
~ Must be good news chasin'me ~
~ Good enough to set everybody free ~
~ Good news, good news Good news ~
- ~ Good news ~ - ~ There were bugs in the garden ~
~ Didn't have a clue ~
~ But everyday their life was on the line ~
~ They wanted to get out ofthere but they didn't know what to do ~
~ Their little brains was working overtime ~
~ That all changed one sunny day ~
~ That little boy dropped by to say ~
~ "Ifwe all work together we'll make out okay"~
- ~ We will ~ - ~ Good news ~
~ Good news Good news ~
~ So they rolled down the mountain Flew over the sea ~
~ Facing death and danger on their way ~
~ But together they have made it They're where they wanna be ~
~ They love each other more and more each day ~
~ They care about each other ~
~ Good news is sweepin' 'cross the country ~
~ Good news is spreadin' all around~
~ Good news is hittin' in the city ~
~ Good news has sprung up in the town ~
~ The things that used to hurt before ~
~ They don't hurt 'em anymore ~
~ 'Cause they know there's somethin'good in store ~
- ~ Good news, good news ~ - ~ Good news, good news ~
~ Good news ~
- ~ Good news ~ - ~ Comin' down the chimney ~
- ~ Good news ~ - ~ Knockin' on my door ~
- ~ Good news ~ - ~ Beamin' through the window ~
- ~ Good news ~ - ~ Can't take no more ~
- ~ Good news ~ - ~ Spreadin' o'er the country ~
- ~ Good news ~ - ~ For the young and old~
- ~ Good news ~ - ~ Goin' 'round the world now ~
- ~ Good news ~ - ~ Too hot to hold back ~
- ~ Comin' down the chimney ~ - ~ Good news ~
- ~ Knockin' on the door ~ - ~ Good news ~
- ~ Beamin' through the window ~ - ~ Good news ~
- ~ Ooh, can't take no more ~ - ~ Good news ~
- ~ Spreadin' o'er the country ~ - ~ Good news ~
- ~ For the young and old~ - ~ Good news ~
- ~ Goin'round the world~ - ~ Good news ~
- ~ Good news, good news ~ - ~ Good news, good news ~
- ~ Good news, good news ~ - ~ Good news ~
~ Good news ~
- ~ Good news ~ - ~ Good news ~
[ Bell Dings ]
- [ Bell Dings ] - [ Bell Ringing ]
[ Buzzer Sounding ]