I used to think this was
the beginning of your story.
Memory is a strange thing.
It does not work like I thought it did.
We are so bound by time.
By its order.
It's okay. Come back to me.
Come back to me.
Stick em up!
You are the sheriff in this here town?
My tickle guns are gonna get you!
You want me to chase you? You better run.
I remember moments in the middle.
I love you.
I hate you!
And this was the end.
Come back to me.
Baby, come back to me.
And now Im not so sure I believe in
beginnings and endings.
There are days that define
your story beyond your life.
Like the day they arrived.
Good Morning.
Where is everyone?
Ok... Well let's get started.
Today, we're talking about Portuguese
and why it sounds so different
from the other Romance languages.
The story of Portuguese begins
in the Kingdom of Galicia...
In the Middle Ages...
when a language was seen
as an expression of art.
Any news you want to share?
Dr. Banks can turn you turn the TV to
the news channel?
But police have already
set up a perimeter around the area
As you can see, we got just
about as close as we can...
but unfortunately, Montana right now,
is on complete lock down.
The object apparently touched down...
40 minutes ago,
just north of ****** 04.
We are waiting to hear if this is perhaps
an experimental vessel or...
Hold on...
Im learning that more objects like this
Have landed in as many as eight other
locations around the world
Yes? Henry?
This is from a site in Hokkaido.
This is worldwide and is
happening right now.
Okay... um...
Class is dismissed.
The Pentagon is simply asking
for cooperation
while authorities assess the object.
You are saying its not ours?
- Do you even know if its from Earth?
- We are collecting information.
We're coordinating with other countries.
We are not the only ones to
have one of these in our backyard.
If this is some kind of
peaceful first contact,
why send twelve? Why not just one?
I do not know, Mom.
Im watching the same news you are.
Mom... mom, please don't bother
with that channel.
How many times I have to say that
those people are idiots?
Do I sound nervous?
Ok, exactly... so...
Yeah, me? You know me. Im about the same
Mom, I'm fine.
Ok, I'll call you later - bye.
And in around eight hours after landing,
Theres still no signs of what
might be called "first contact."
The objects measuring
at least 1500ft tall...
Two more have reported to
have penetrated Russian airspace.
One in Siberia and the other
on the coast of the Black Sea...
above the ocean.
So far there are 12
unidentified objects
spread across the globe...
there is no obvious logic
to their locations
And no evidence that the
ships are even occ...
entertain the idea that
if it is a kind of vessel,
it may be unmanned.
Regardless, we have a protocol
for scenarios like this.
LIVE FROM VENEZUELA
After two days' of extraordinary events,
the President this morning, has declared
a state of emergency
With as many as 5,000 National Guard being
deployed to the state of Montana, alone.
Borders are closed and flights have been
grounded, stranding millions of travelers.
Purchase of gas, water and food
continues to escalate
and federal authorities
have temporarily lifted
the overtime limit on law enforcement.
The ATF has put a temporary
ban on new gun licenses,
forcing many independent suppliers
of hunting equipment and firearms
to close their doors to the public.
48 hours later and no
further development...
Two days.
And the public now expects us
to know all the answers.
I'm Colonel G.T. Weber.
We havn't formally met,
but two years ago,
You did a Farsi translation
for the Intellengy?
And you made quick work
with those insurgents.
You're on top...
on everyone's list
when it comes to translations.
And yet youve been two years in the SSBI.
So, you still have top secret clearance.
So thats why I'm in your office
and not in Berkeley.
Okay?
I have something I need you
to translate for me.
Why are you here?
Can you understand us?
Where did you come from?
Now you heard...
what you make of it?
- Is that...?
- Yes.
- How many?
- How many what?
How many were speaking?
Two.
They were speaking at the same time.
Are you sure they had mouths...
How would you approach translating this?
You hear any words? Phrases?
I do not... I do not know.
So what can you tell?
I can tell you that it is impossible to
translate an audio file.
I would need to be there
to interact with them.
You did not need that
for Farsi translation.
I did not need because I already
knew the language, but this is...
I know what you're doing.
- Tell me what Im doing.
- I'll not take you to Montana.
Its all I can do to
keep it turning into a
tourist site for everybody
who has a clearance.
Im just telling you what it would take
to do this job.
It is not a negotiation.
If I leave here... your chance is gone.
Good day.
Colonel...
You mentioned Berkeley.
Are you going to ask Danvers next?
Maybe.
Before you commit to him...
ask him the Sanskrit word for "war"
and its translation.
An agreement on sharing
scientific discoveries
Was closer tonight as Russia and China
***** at the United Nations.
Meanwhile, financial markets
across the world are in crisis
with the Dow Jones industrial average
fell 2,000 points...
- Good Morning.
- Colonel?
Gavisti.
He says that means discussion.
- What you say means?
- A desire for more cows.
Pack your bags.
- All right, give me 20 minutes.
- Take only 10!
Dr. Banks! This way, please.
- Are you alright?
- Yes.
Thanks.
Sorry. Couldn't hear what you were saying.
"Language is the foundation
of civilization...
It is the glue that holds
the people together...
It is the first weapon
drawn in a conflict."
Louise, esse Ian Donnelly.
Louise Banks, Ian Donnelly.
- Quite a reading!
- Yeah... you wrote it.
Yeah.
It's the kind of thing
you write as a preface.
Dabbled with the basics.
It's great. Even if its wrong.
- Its wrong?
- The cornerstone of civilization
isn't language - its science.
Ian is a theoretical physicist
at Los Alamos.
You'll report to me, but will be working
with him when you are in the shop.
Thats what they are calling the UFO?
Priority One. What do they want,
Where are they from?
Beyond that, how did they get here?
Are they capable of faster
than light travel?
I made a list of questions ranging from
handshakes to binary sequences...
How about we just talk to them
before we start throwing problem at them?
That's why you both are here.
I'll bring the coffee.
Coffee with some aliens.
- Take them to Dr. Kettler.
- Yes sir.
The procedure takes just a few minutes,
then we'll start.
Alright.
They will take care of your bags...
and cell phones.
Follow me.
Put this on and wear them all times.
Sir, they're here.
Louise Banks, Ian Donnelly.
When was your last meal?
- Last night.
- Same.
When was the last time
you did something stressful?
Does now count?
- Just saying.
- Who's being...
Carted off in a med-bag?
Not everyone is able to process
experiences like this.
Im gonna take some bllod from you.
And give you an immunization doze to
cover you against bacterial threats.
Can you sign this please?
Before we can start.
- Are any of you claustrophobic?
- No.
Are taking any medication, any allergies?
Pregnant?
The boost doze may give
a kick to your systems,
so you may experience side effects:
like nausea, dizziness, headaches.
Or even a ringing in your ears.
In exactly 112 minutes and 19 seconds
gravity starts to shift
and fall out of the room.
Have you found a scientific explanation
for it?
- Like is it for them?
- No, I think it is for us.
There seems to circulate air inside
the chamber, so...
After two hours, you run out of oxygen.
It doesn't take you 18 hours to pump
fresh air into a room?
Atmosphere.
- Excuse me?
- If their atmosphere
is different from earth,
It would take hours to balance
the concentration of air
and the pressure everytime
we open their door.
Are you saying that could suffocate us
if they wanted to?
This is Agent David Halpern, the CIA.
- Let me take you to your stations.
- Yes sir.
We need the answers as soon as possible.
What they want, where they came from.
Why you are here, this is the priority.
Everyone.
This is Dr. Ian Donnelly,
he will lead the team.
Have they responded to anything?
Shapes, patterns,
numbers, Fibonacci?
We can't tell what they were saying,
but they responded to "hello", so...
Ok that is all.
What have you figured out?
We're just getting started.
Good Morning.
This is Dr Louise Banks.
- She will be heading your team.
- Dr. Banks, its a pleasure
Dr. Banks is taking over the mission
from Dr. Waller.
The 15 minute alarm.
What kind of radiation are we walking into?
No, this is just for safety.
So is there any physical contact...
with them?
I'm the only one using the word: aliens?
It has a wall made of glass,
we do not make contact.
What they look like?
You'll see soon enough. Hurry up.
The suits are clumsy at first.
But you'll get used to them.
All personnel in the second vehicle.
We get there in a few minutes.
Make sure you hold onto something.
Every 18 hours... the door
opens at the bottom.
Thats when we go in.
Yeah, that has happened.
Alright, lets move. Time is wasting.
You ready?
It's okay, sir.
- You can proceed.
- Stand by
Okay, bring it up.
You okay?
Yeah.
Dr. Banks.
You can do it. C'mon.
I... I think...
Grab her.
Dr. Donnelly, you cool?
Yeah!
Holy fuck!
We go down in there,
You can start your job.
- Ok.
- Everybody, move up.
- Alpha Team in position.
We're on the move.
Setting up equipment...
What happens now?
They'll arrive.
Dr. Banks?
You can start.
Wait... Just a minute.
I'm fired?
You were better than the last guy.
That does not make me feel any better.
You have till 0200 hours
to think something up.
And what happens then?
You go back in.
Violence continues to spread across the US
today due to 2 bombings.
The President has declared
a mandatory dusk to dawn curfew
after the crack down by the National Guard
Failed to prevent a third night
of looting across the country.
In North Dakota, 144 members of
the St. Lawrence Pentecostal occult
Are feared dead after they
set their compound ablaze.
Their website claims, the arrival of aliens
Set in motion a prophecy that 12...
Uh.. we're up in 15...
You got any new intel?
Yeah. We've been playing back
some of their sounds...
And where has that got you?
When they play audio back at us.
Its from an unseen source
What are you up with?
Conversations from inside the
room. Branches of dialogue.
We have nothing.
- Whats that for?
- Visual aid.
Look, I'm never going to
be able to speak their words,
if they aren't talking.
But they might have some sort of
written language
or basis for visual communication.
Ok. Let's start.
Human.
I'm human.
And you?
Human.
- Oh my God.
- Are you recording this?
Yes sir. I have sent this to base.
Louise, its incredible!
Human.
Okay... Slow down Louise.
I don't want to take
away from your success,
but Dr. Banks,
is it really the right approach?
Try to teach them
how to speak and read?
- Thats gonna take long.
- You're wrong!
Its faster.
Everything you do here,
I have to explain to a
room full of men,
whose first and last question
Is how can this be used against us.
So you'll have to give me more than that!
Kangaroo.
What is that?
In 1770,
Captain James Cook's ship ran aground
off the coast of Australia and led a party,
where they found the aboriginal people.
One of the sailors pointed to the animals
that hop around and
put their babies in their pouch,
And he asked what they were.
The Aborigines said "kangaroo".
And your point is?
It wasn't until later that they learned
that "kangaroo" means
"I don't understand". So...
I need this so that
we don't misinterpret things in there,
otherwise it is going to take 10 times
as long.
I can sell that for now.
But I need you to submit
your vocabulary of words
before the next session.
Remember what happened to the Aborigines.
A more advanced race,
nearly wiped them out.
- Its a good story.
- Thanks.
Its not true, but it proves my point.
HUMAN?
I think we can present some
prime numbers here.
- It's something.
- Congratulations, you're a parrot.
Its a lot more than that,
you cheeky bastard. Dont you see?
They can't seem to follow our algebra.
But complex behaviours - that clears.
That does not make any sense, does it?
Problem is, not everyone shares
our policy of being open with the aliens.
That is Gen. Shang.
It is gathering strength in Shanghai
and at least four other nations
would follow him.
- Louise, we need get ground today.
- Ok.
You're gonna teach them your name
and Ian's?
Yes, so that we can learn their names,
if they have names,
and then introduce pronouns later.
These are grade school words.
Eating, walking.
Help me understand.
No no no! Not the top!
Ok, this is where you
want to get to, right?
- That is the question.
- Right.
So, first we need to make sure that
they understand what a question is.
The nature of our request for information
on the response.
Then we need to clarify
the difference between a specific "you"...
and a collective "you".
We don't want to know why
a 'Joe' alien is here,
we want to know why they all landed.
A purpose requires an understanding
of intent.
We need to find out do they make
conscious choices,
or is the motivation so instinctive
that they don't understand
any why "?" question at all.
And biggest of all we need to have
enough vocabulary with them,
that we understand their answer.
Yeah.
Stick to your list.
Just...
Don't add anything to it.
Let's get started.
Louise.
Louise, I'm Louise.
What is that?
Is that a new symbol?
I can't tell.
I don't know,
I think its the symbol for "human" again.
But with a curl at the end.
Maybe they indicate a question.
I don't know.
I do not know, Louise,
I think they are confused.
Dr. Banks, move to the next word.
Dr. Banks!
- Its okay.
- Whats going on?
What are you doing?
- Im fine.
- Are you crazy?
They need to see me.
She's taking off protection.
Dr. Banks!
Are you ok?
You are at risk of contamination.
- They need to see me.
- Dr. Banks.
- She's going upto the screen.
Should we abort?
Go back to your stations.
Now that's a proper introduction.
Louise.
I'm Louise.
Ian, you want to introduce yourself?
I...
Louise.
Fuck you.
Everyone dies one day, right?
Sir, Donnelly is taking off his suit too.
Permission to abort?
Continue with the session.
Ian.
Louise.
You?
Who are you?
I think those are their names.
They have names.
So what are we gonna call them?
I do not know.
I was thinking of Abbott and Costello.
Yeah.
I like it.
Vehicle One, exit your vehicles
and proceed to the decontamination camp.
Do not take off the masks until they enter.
Do not remove their masks,
and adhere to the decontamination room.
- How do you feel?
- Overworked.
Like I said, I need to tell you,
you put yourself at risk.
There is no signs of radiation poisoning...
yet.
I'll check your blood.
- For now, Im gonna give you another boost.
- Ok.
- No radiation?
- Nothing else we can detect either.
But I will still give her a strong
cocktail, regardless.
It was the first time we made
significant progress.
Alright. We'll take the risk.
- Honey... honey.
- What's going on?
- Can you tell me something?
- No.
- You are worried.
- How can I not worry?
Calm down.
Becky asked if the monsters
are going to kill Dad.
Honey, its not gonna happen.
- Come soon, please.
- No need to worry.
I'm so scared.
Here are some of the many things
we don't know about the heptopodes.
Greek: Hepta seven. Pod foot.
Seven feet. Hept치pode.
Who are they?
Trying to answer this in any meaningful
way is hampered by the fact that,
outside of being able to see them
and hear them,
They have deposited
absolutely no footprint.
The chemical composition of their
spaceship is unknown.
The Shell emits no waste,
no gas, no radiation.
Assuming that the ships
communicate with each other,
they do so without detection.
The air between the shells is controlled
by sonic emissions or light waves.
They are scientists or tourists?
If scientists,
they don't seem to ask a lot of questions.
Why they land in these places?
The world's most decorated experts
can not figure that out.
The most plausible theory is that
they chose places on earth
With the lowest incidences of
lightning strikes.
But there are exceptions.
The second most plausible theory
is that Sheena Easton
Had a hit song in each of
these sites in 1980.
So... we just don't know.
How do they communicate?
Here, Louise has brought us all to shame.
The first breakthrough was discovering
that there is no co-relation
between what a hept치pode says,
and what a hept치pode writes.
IAN YOU
Unlike all human written language,
their writing is semasiogr치fica.
It conveyes meaning,
it does not represent sound.
Perhaps they view our form of writing
as a wasted oppurtunity,
Passing every second
communication's channel.
We have our friends in Pakistan to thank
For their study on how the
hept치podes write.
Because unlike speech,
a hologram is free of time.
Like their ship or their bodies.
Their written language has no form
or no direction.
Linguists call this nonlinear orthography.
Which raises the question:
"Is this how they think?"
Imagine you wanted to write a sentence
using 2 hands, starting from either side.
You have to know each word
you wanted to use,
as well as how much space they will occupy.
A hept치pode can write a complex sentence
in two seconds effortlessly.
It took us a month to make
the simplest vocabulary.
Next, explain the vocabulary.
Louise thinks it will easily take
another month to get ready for that.
Hey.
- Hi.
- Weber's looking for you.
Why do you think I'm hiding out here?
C'mon up.
- Nice out here, huh?
- Yeah, it's a nice view.
Away from the noise.
You know, I was just thinking about you.
You approach language like a
mathematician. You know that right?
I will take that as a compliment.
But it is.
And... I want you to
Steer us around these communication traps
that I did not even know existed.
What...?
I guess this is why I'm still single.
Trust me, you can understand communication
and still end up single.
I feel like everything
that happens there...
It comes down to the 2 of us.
It's a good thing, alright? You and I?
See those jokers that
we are working with?
Thank God, I got you.
ALIEN CRISIS | DAY 25 VENEZUELA
UNITED KINGDOM SAVE OUR SPECIES!
Tonight, the first photo of the aliens
goes viral.
Biological contamination is a
major risk factor
At the Montana site. So say environmental
pressure groups.
800,000 march on Washington
to protest the government's handling
on the crisis.
All this and more, special coverage.
First contact was inside that thing.
Who's in charge? The government, of course.
The same government who ruined our
backyard and bankrupted our military.
Look at these people.
Most of them don't even have guns.
We could be facing a full scale
invasion invasion.
Our President is willing to sit back,
and let them overtake the country.
We are falling asleep at the wheel, people!
You know what Im talking about!
The smartest thing to do right now,
would be a show of force.
I'm talking about a shot across the brow.
I want to know what you think
about all this.
Whats this word?
Green Planet...
The Earth is a planet.
Want to see my project
for Miss. Garrett's class?
Of course, little nose.
We had to make up our own TV show.
If we had one.
- Who are those two people?
- Thats you and Dad.
The show is called: "Mommy and Daddy
talk to animals."
Its lovely.
Ok.
It's okay to be sad
that your dad and I...
I know. I'm not.
We both love you very much.
I know. It's just a drawing - not real.
Louise?
Are you alright?
Yes I'm fine.
I not sure if it's something...
I can explain.
Would you like a checkup
with Dr. Kevin?
I am ok.
It's fine, I'm ok.
How are you feeling?
I need some sleep, but...
I am fine.
Yeah?
I've been doing a bit of reading
about this idea that...
What if you emmerse yourself into
a foreign language...
- You can actually rewire your brain.
- It is a hypothesis.
It is a theory that...
It is the theory that...
The language you speak
determines how you think.
Yes, it affects how you see everything...
I'm curious. Are you dreaming
in their language?
I've had some dreams.
I don't think that makes me
unfit to do this job.
- Did you sleep?
- A little.
Know Mandarin?
The voice you're about to hear
belongs to the Chinese military chief.
General Shang.
Put it on.
We also have a live feed,
if you want to look.
Rewind.
Stop.
He is saying each of the 12
is offering advanced technology.
Go back again... play.
The scientific team is attempting
to decode the sense...
"sense"?
I dont know what that means.
Something that will manage.
Suits, honor and flowers. I don't...
- I don't know, that's all.
- I don't know what it means either.
An hour ago, China mobilized forces...
and now Russia is following suit.
Shang is about to start something.
All same suits... Suits...
suits, honor, flowers...
Colonel, those are all parts of Mahjong.
God... are they...?
They are using a game to communicate
with the Hept璥odes?
Maybe... why?
Lets say I taught them
chess instead of English.
Every conversation would be a game,
every idea expressed through opposition.
Victory... defeat. You see the problem?
If all I ever gave you was a hammer...
Everythings a nail.
We need to ask the big question.
Ready or not.
Hept치podes purpose.
Purpose of hept치pode.
Earth. What is your purpose?
Do we only have Costello?
Ok. There you are.
What is he saying?
Offer weapon.
You saw what they wrote. Using a word that
they don't fully understand.
Enough!
Louise.
We don't know if they understand
the difference between a weapon and a tool.
Our language like a culture is messy,
and sometimes one can be both.
I think it's quite possible that they are
asking us or them for something.
Not the other way round.
Like the first part of trade.
So how do we clarify their intentions
beyond these two words?
I go back in.. right
away we go back in... we clear this out..
- It's more complicated than that.
- How is it more complicated than that?
Col., the Secretary of Defense
is on the line for you.
We need to sit on this information
till we know what it means.
So we aren't sharing it with our enemies.
We have to consider the idea
that our visitors are prodding us
to fight among ourselves,
till only one faction prevails.
- There is no evidence for that.
- Sure there is.
Just grab a history book.
British in India, Germans with Rwanda.
They even got a name for it in Hungary.
We are a world with no single leader.
Its impossible to deal with just one of us.
We have the word weapon now...
Yes general.
What did they say?
China and Russia are off the grid.
They aren't speaking very well.
What they learnt in the last session
has them spooked.
Yes sir.
We have orders to do the same.
- Wait these are our allies!
- Put your radio on silence!
- Do it.
- We received a message from the hept치...
Damn it!
We need to be talking to each other!
Find out what this means.
This cam is now offline...
We've never re-entered the session before.
Louise, trust me ok? We got time.
Just gotta step on it, alright?
"USE WEAPON"
This is the alien message sent to provoke
the Chinese government
to withdraw their
scientists from the
international mission today.
In a statement, General Shang said:
"China no longer trusts the aliens
who wants to divide us.
Humanity must be protected."
China has asked for immediate
talks at the UN.
Alpha 1-9, this is Condor. Over.
Alpha 1-9, this is Condor. Come in. Over.
Captain Marks, Condor, not
receiving a transmission.
Let me know if you are listening.
Capt. Marks, all escorts are
ordered to cease all activites...
No, no, no...
Dr. Banks you can't go in there.
- Just need to ask one question.
- Dr. Banks!
The session is closed.
You can't go back in, it's dangerous...
We just need 5 minutes. No sweat.
Morris, Let him go.
Hey, Abbott.
So, what are calling our session?
Session 37?
- No 36 Part 2
- Ok.
Why are you alone?
Been attempting to call Capt. Marks.
- The escorts not responding.
- Why not?
Send security.
Offer a weapon... question mark.
They are offering us something.
Technology, device, method...
See this? This is a different word.
This... this segment is a lot busier.
Give... technology...
Now.
Whats he doing?
Capt. ****** check.
Security team coming, sir.
4 minutes remain.
We must see this through.
Come on. Download weapons.
- Fire *******.
- Understood.
We will open shooting soon.
To be no casualties.
Abbott wants me to write on the barrier.
I don't know.
I can't do it with both hands.
Louise.
What is that?
Hey... Hey... Hey... Take it easy.
You suffered a concussion.
Just lay back.
How you feeling?
- How is Ian?
- Well, same as you. He is ok.
- Who...
- Who did this?
- Some soldiers.
Been watching too much TV.
- What is that?
- Take it easy... take it easy
The place is no longer secure.
We're on standby to evacuate.
Where is Ian?
Weber came and got him
maybe 10 minutes ago.
He wouldn't leave till
he knew you were okay.
The whole tent is on the clock to figure
out whatever it is you were given up there.
This is all of it?
The feed wasn't interrupted
by the explosion.
Thats right.
- You see something?
- I don't know yet.
I need my team get together
with Louise's team.
- I need everyone working on this.
- We can not leave.
- Glad to see you awake.
- We need to go back in there
and explain to them that
this wasn't our fault.
- We can't go back inside.
- We have to!
What happened in there was an attack.
We can hope for the best,
but we have to prepare for retaliation.
We may have to evacuate...
Thats a wrong move.
As long as they stay, we have to stay.
Well, they are not leaving.
Why does it feel worse?
China is on the offensive.
They are positioning their military to blow
the alien vessel right out of the sky.
If this happens, we can't sit
and wait for their retaliation.
So get prepared.
The Air Force and Infantry are standing by.
BREAKING NEWS
Tonight, China becomes
the first world power
To declare war against the aliens.
Following the failure of the diplomatic
efforts of the United Nations,
China confirmed that its language experts
tonight...
delivered an ultimatum
at the Shanghai site.
In a televised statement,
Gen. Shang, chairman of the
People's Liberation Army,
Said the aliens have 24 hours to
leave Chinese territory,
or face destruction.
And he urged all other world leaders
to unite with China and
take a similar stance.
With a huge build up of forces
at their landing sites,
Pakistan, Russia and Sudan
Are thought to be following China's lead.
It can't be random.
Its going to take us years.
Whats this term here?
Mum.
- Mother?
- Hm?
- Sweetie?
- Whats this term for that thing...
Like a technical term...
When we make a deal and we
both get something out of it?
- A compromise?
- No...
Like it's competition,
But both sides end up happy.
And win-win?
More sciency than that.
If you want science, call your father.
Thank you.
Sorry.
Its okay.
What time is it?
Its time to open the bottle
you've been hiding.
You cracked something, didn't you?
Yeah. Come here.
Take a look at this section.
It seems to be talking about time.
You see the symbol of "time" - everywhere.
So what is this?
A formula for faster than light travel?
Who can tell?
It has too many gaps.
Its not complete.
Then it dawned on me.
Right here.
Stop focussing on the "1"s.
Look at the "0"s.
How much of it is data and
how much of it is negative space?
So I measured it.
0.0833 recurring.
Perhaps you'd like to add
that as a fraction.
1/12.
What is saying right here, is that,
this is one of twelfth.
- We are part of a larger hole.
- Or 1 of 12 contestants for the prize.
- Why do we have to talk to him?
- We all working together here.
We need to talk to the other
sites, We need to help
them with what they got
from the other Hept치podes.
In case you don't remember,
we're blacked out.
China just threatened to destroy
their Shell. We are on our own.
But it says that all the pieces fit in.
And I'm telling you that no one else cares.
Two hours ago we pulled this audio off
a secured channel in Russia.
Someone from their science team
was broadcasting live.
In their final session,
the alien said:
"There's no time. Many become one..."
I feel we have all the given weapons.
If anyone is receiving this...
Please...
Well, I mean...
There are a lot of ways you can
interpret what he said.
I don't need an interpreter to
know what this means.
Russia just executed one of their own
experts to keep their secret.
"Many become one"
can be their way of saying
Some only required.
Why hand it out to us in pieces?
Why not give it all?
What better way to force us
to work together for once?
Even if I did believe you,
How in the world are you
going to get anyone
else to play along, and
give out their data?
- We offer ours in return.
- Yeah?
- What, trade?
- Its a non zero sum game.
Non zero sum game.
Thats it. Thanks.
9 local completely isolated.
Only way to reach them is
to physically drive and
yell at the border guards
which we are doing.
But it won't be fast enough.
There must be a way to get the message.
To our allies, maybe. But at this stage,
it's little too late.
What we need is to get all the
other nations online...
before we start a war and theres
no way for us to reach them
Wait. Hold on a second.
Louise.
Its right above us.
Thats problematic for us right now.
The Pentagon is convinced
that our Shell will retaliate.
I'd guess its orders say that we leave
within the hour.
Look they are not our enemy.
They meant no act of aggression towards us.
Maybe thats their way of being aggressive.
- Its not the question.
- Then what is the question?
How do we get you back in that room
thats half a mile straight up?
I think our work here is done.
Its in the hands of our superiors now.
What the hell is she doing?
Costello?
Where is Abbott?
"ABBOTT IS DEATH PROCESS"
I'm sorry.
We're sorry.
I need you to...
I need you to... to send a message...
to the other sites.
LOUISE HAS WEAPON
"USE WEAPON"
I don't... I don't understand.
What is your purpose here?
"WE HELP HUMANITY"
"IN THREE THOUSAND YEARS"
"WE NEED HUMANITY HELP"
How can you know the future?
I don't...
I don't understand. Who is this child?
The program is called
"Mommy and Daddy talk to animals."
"LOUISE SEES FUTURE"
"WEAPON OPENS TIME"
Wait... No! Wait!
- Dr. Banks!
- Louise!
Are you alright?
- You alright?
- Yeah.
Come here.
I tried to understand. But they...
It doesn't matter now.
We have orders to evacuate.
- Why?
- Russia and Sudan
will follow suit.
Ian... I do not understand why...?
Help me, Mama.
Louise...
Mom!
Momma!
Sorry, honey.
What day is it, do you know baby?
Sunday.
Are you gonna leave me like Daddy did?
Oh, Hannah, honey,
your daddy didn't leave you.
You're gonna see him... this weekend.
He never look me anymore.
Its my fault.
I told him something that
he wasn't ready to hear.
What?
Well...
Believe it or not...
I know something thats going to happen.
I can not explain how I know it,
I just do.
And when I told your daddy, he
got really mad.
He said I made the wrong choice.
What? Whats going to happen?
It has to do with a...
A very rare disease.
And its unstoppable.
Kind of like you are.
You're so amazing
And your poetry and all the other amazing
things that you share with the world.
- I'm unstoppable?
- Yeah.
I got you...
I got you.
Louise.
I just realized why my husband left me.
My husband left me.
You have been married?
Let's get out of here.
- Mamma.
- Yeah?
Why my name is Hannah?
Your name is very special.
Because it is a palindrome.
It reads the same word from backwards.
- Turn it off.
- That goes back.
"UNIVERSAL LANGUAGE"
"TO HANNAH"
Hey!
We're done here.
Let's take this with us.
"UNIVERSAL LANGUAGE BY LOUISE BANKS"
TRANSLATING HEPT츓ODES
I can read it.
- I know what it is.
- What?
It's not a weapon. It's a gift.
The weapon is their language.
They gave it all to us.
So we can learn Hept치pode?
If you learn it... really learn it,
you get to perceive time the way they do.
So you get to see whats to happen.
But time, it isn't the same for them.
- It is not linear.
- Look...
We did our best but it wasn't enough.
The captain will lift off in 5 minutes.
Ian, Louise... It was an honor
to work with you.
Good luck.
Colonel...
I'll find out where we are going.
Wake up, Mummy.
Dr. Banks...
Its a pleasure.
General Shang, the pleasure is mine.
Your president said...
It was an honor to host me in celebration.
- Of course.
- I confess...
The only reason why I am here is...
To meet you in person.
Well, Im flattered. Thank you.
18 months ago, you did
something remarkable.
Something not even my superior has done.
- What's that?
- You changed my mind.
You are the reason for this unification.
All because you reached out to
me on my private number.
Your private number? General I do
not know your private number...
Now you know.
I claimed to know how your mind works,
but...
I believe it was important
for you to see that.
I called you tonight?
Yes, you did.
Louise...
Alright, let's shut down the system.
Sir... there's a satelite
here dialling China.
Here? What do you mean here?
Come on, answer.
Whose phone is it?
It's your phone, sir.
Search base camp now.
Find out who is using that phone.
- Hold on to those co-ordinates.
- Yes sir.
C'mon... What am I saying?
What am I saying?
Okay.
I never forget what you said.
You told me my wife's dying words.
We found the source of the phone call.
It is in decontamination.
Waiting for instructions.
Louise... What are you doing?
- What are you doing?
- Changing his opinion.
Buy us 20 seconds.
- We do not have time.
- Trust me.
- 20 seconds. Do you trust me?
- Now? It's all right.
Dr. Banks...
Drop the phone, or we shoot.
- Drop it!
- Im sorry!
This is an act of treason!
- Drop it!
- Its done.
I got it.
The communications blackout
from all 12 landing sites...
continues this evening...
Hold on... We are just hearing.
We are going to cut
this report to tell you.
Latest news.
China has called an emergency
press conference...
General Shang, chief of the
People's Liberation Army...
Has announced in an emergency press
conference that China is standing down.
China is stating that all the intelligence
they have received...
Will be shared immediately...
The world is entering a new era...
The Russian army are now revealing
information they acquired
from both their landing sites...
So, Hannah...
This is where your story begins.
The day they departed.
Are you alright?
Despite knowing the journey...
and where it leads...
I embrace it.
And I welcome every moment of it.
H-A-N-N-A-H.
Now backwards.
Hannah.
You ready, baby?
- Hey.
- It's okay?
- Yes you can go.
Daddy!
Are you ok?
I'll just roll over you.
Are you ready?
Guess what... All star stuff.
- Ian.
- Yeah.
If you see your whole life,
from start to finish...
Would you change things?
Maybe I...
I say what I feel more often. I don't know.
I've had my head tilted up to the stars
for as long as I can remember.
But you know what surprised me?
It was not meeting them.
It was meeting you.
I'd forgotten how good it felt
to be held by you.
Do you want to make a baby?
Yes... yeah!