Madeleine?
Madeleine!
Oh. No, no.
Mama.
Mama. Mama. Mama!
Mama!
Is Mr. White home?
-No. He's gone.
My name
is Lyutsifer Safin.
Your husband killed my family.
I told you, he's gone.
I know.
This will hurt him more.
You okay?
Yes.
Let's go.
How's the view?
It's growing on me.
Can you go faster?
We don't need to go faster.
We have all the time
in the world.
You can't help
looking over your shoulder.
-What?
-No one is coming.
I wasn't looking
over my shoulder.
-Yes, you were.
-No.
Are we gonna
have a row about this?
What are they burning?
Secrets. Wishes.
Letting go of the past.
Getting rid of old things,
in come the new.
Where did you go to?
Today, by the water. Hmm?
Tell me.
I'll tell you
if you tell me about Vesper.
Is that why we're here?
She's buried at the acropolis.
I know where she's buried.
Can you forgive her? For us?
I left her behind
a long time ago.
As long as we're looking
over our shoulder,
the past is not dead.
You have to let her go,
even if it's hard.
You mean, um,
if we're to have a future?
Mm-hmm.
So, I do this, and then...
I'll tell you all my secrets.
Okay.
I'm going to go
and do this,
and then I'm going
to come back for breakfast.
Thank you.
And then
you're going to tell me
where we're going next.
Home.
I miss you.
What...
Madeleine?
Blofeld sends his regards.
You know...
Madeleine,
she is a daughter of Spectre.
She's a daughter of Spectre.
Your baggage
is already down, Mr. Bond.
As your wife requested.
You were right.
Letting go is hard.
James.
What happened?
-What happened?
-How did they know I was here?
-What are you talking about?
-Madeleine,
how did they know I was here?
-I have no idea what you're--
-Spectre. How did they know?
What are you talking about?
James!
I didn't do anything.
-I didn't do anything.
We're leaving.
There is something
I need to tell you.
I bet there is.
James!
Pick it up. Pick it up!
It's Blofeld, my love.
Your father
would be so proud of you.
Your sacrifice
will be our glory.
-I don't understand.
-Bravo.
James, why?
Why would I betray you?
We all have our secrets,
we just didn't
get to yours yet.
James. James, listen to me.
I'd rather die
than you think I'm--
James!
Do something. James!
Say something, James!
Please.
Okay.
Come on.
So, this is it?
This is it.
How will I know
that you're okay?
You won't.
You'll never see me again.
We're in.
-Proceed.
Please
remember to back up
all data by00 p.m.
this evening
due to planned
server maintenance.
You okay?
You know the, uh, SL5,
the weaponized smallpox
I was using this morning?
Have you seen it?
I... I put it in the bloody...
Valdo, you haven't seen a tub
of smallpox, have you?
This was a good soup.
Now it is waste,
even if it is joke.
There is more complexity
in my tomato soup
than in both
of your brains combined.
Valdo, that is so unkind.
It's so...
One day
I will put Ebola in your tea.
And then I will watch
as your faces sweat blood...
-...and I will be laughing.
-Nice. Keep your hair on.
-Wow.
He's got a terrifying
imagination, hasn't he?
Dr. Obruchev.
They are coming.
-Who?
-Spectre.
-Safin.
-Do not try to stop them.
This is what
we've been waiting for.
They will ask you to enter
Bio Security Level Four fridge
and remove the weapon.
No one must see
what you are doing.
They will not kill you.
They think they need you.
-They will not kill me?
Transferring the files
as we speak.
Now... Now it's done.
What do I do with it?
Swallow it. Goodbye.
-Swallow the...
Yes, I like animals!
Bye-bye.
Danger,
illegal access detected.
Secure all biohazardous
materials immediately.
Move! Follow!
-No! No!
-Caution.
Unauthorized personnel
located in this sector.
Please,
we're scientists,
we're unarmed.
We're unarmed.
What do you want?
Valdo Obruchev.
Hello.
Open the Bio Security
Level Four fridge.
-And, uh...
-Give me the weapon.
The weap-- What weapon?
We have, uh...
Heracles.
It requires
double authentication.
Which one?
Him.
Hardy. Hardy! Don't let them.
Don't let them.
Don't let them, please.
-Oh.
Warning,
facility lockdown in progress.
-All exits are now sealed.
Warning,
facility lockdown in progress.
All exits are now sealed.
Oh, what is, uh...
It's a safety belt? This?
Wow.
I... I cannot!
There is no elevator!
Magnets.
Sir, I've just received
the most unusual--
I've seen it.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Sir, what's
the Heracles project?
-This lab isn't on the books.
No, it's not.
-There were casualties.
-It was a gas leak.
Shall I alert the PM?
It was a gas leak.
I'll handle it.
Moneypenny.
Where's 007?
Well,
isn't this a surprise, Felix?
James.
Who's the blond?
Logan Ash, State Department.
It's really nice to meet you.
I've heard a lot about you.
I mean, I'm a huge fan.
-Babylon.
-Police boy.
I need a favor, brother.
You didn't get the memo?
I'm retired.
I wouldn't ask
if you were still
in Her Majesty's Service.
And what does that mean?
Our elected leaders aren't
playing nice in the sandbox.
James.
Is there somewhere quiet
where we can talk in private?
Quiet? Yeah.
I was hoping
you could pick up
a package.
-Five.
-Four.
Where's the package?
Short trip. Cuba.
You love it there.
Oh, I love it there?
Hey. Valdo Obruchev.
You're gonna say
you never heard of him.
-Never heard of him. Two.
-Three.
Ah... It's a good life.
You never heard of him?
Didn't he defect
during your tenure at MI6?
Obruchev was kidnapped
three days ago
from a secret MI6 lab
in London.
Two days ago, his mug pinged
on a facial-recognition sweep
in Santiago de Cuba.
He's leaving out
the best part.
Spectre.
I have a contact there,
says they're gathering.
Coincidence?
Come on.
It'll be like old times.
-Three.
-Two.
You're really
the only guy for the job.
-You're the guy.
-It's my round.
Hi.
-Scotch.
-Yeah, man.
Where'd you find
the Book of Mormon?
Political appointee.
Not my choice.
Seems intelligence
isn't central anymore.
He smiles too much.
Help us get this
into the right hands.
Oh, what,
and you're the right hands?
I'm not just a pretty face.
I stopped trusting
pretty faces
a long time ago, Felix.
Yeah, I heard. Bad luck.
-Bad judgment.
-Yeah.
Harder to tell
the good from bad,
villains from heroes
these days.
I need you, James.
You're the only one
I trust with this.
I'm not screwing around.
I wanna get back to my family,
tell them
I saved the world again.
Don't you?
Nice to see you again, Felix.
-At least take my number.
-I've got your number.
In trouble?
Constantly.
Need a ride?
Sure. Why not?
Hold on.
-What's your name?
-Nomi.
-Yours?
-James. Call me James.
-What do you do, Nomi?
-I'm a diver.
-What do you dive for?
-I have a thing for old wrecks.
-Well, then you've
come to the right place.
After you.
Hmm...
Nice house.
Thank you.
Is that the bedroom?
Yes, it is.
Well,
that's not the first thing
I thought you'd take off,
but, uh...
Yeah.
You seem like a man
who's gagging
-for some action, Mr. Bond.
-Shall we cut to the chase?
I'm here
as a professional courtesy.
Well, you're not very
courteous, are you?
You've broken my car...
It's Commander Bond,
but you know that.
-Double-0?
-Two years.
-Very young.
-High achiever.
-Oh, Jesus Christ.
-The world's moved on
since you retired,
Commander Bond.
-Perhaps you didn't notice.
-No, can't say I had.
And in my humble opinion,
the world
doesn't change very much.
You would say that.
Look,
this all seems like heaven,
this little bubble,
or whatever.
-But it's so obvious
you're a man
who only has time to kill,
nothing to live for.
So Valdo Obruchev
is off-limits.
You get in my way, I will put
a bullet in your knee.
The one that works.
You need to ask yourself
a few more questions.
MI6, CIA
chasing after the same man,
not communicating
with each other, that...
-That's not good.
-Hmm.
You know what?
Tell M hello, but...
I don't work for him anymore.
Tell him yourself.
By the way,
I'm not just any old double-0.
I'm 007.
You probably
thought they'd retire it.
-It's just a number.
Yeah.
See you in Cuba?
How's it going, Q?
Several large files seem
to have been wiped
from Obruchev's hard drive.
He was working on some
pretty advanced algorithm...
-Can you retrieve the files?
-Trying.
Get me everything you can
and then destroy the drive.
If I knew more about
what this was, I could...
-Thank you, Q. That's all.
Yes. One minute.
The PM is calling again.
007.
Tell them something. Anything.
-007.
-M, darling.
Couple of things.
-Bond.
-I met your new 007.
She's a disarming young woman.
So, Obruchev.
You kept him
on the payroll, didn't you?
Stay out of it.
This has nothing
to do with you.
It does. It's Spectre.
Mallory, what have you done?
-Double-0 trouble?
-The CIA have the advantage.
Get me Blofeld.
Sir, he only speaks
to his psychiatrist.
I know.
The live feed's what I want.
They stay
straight in the middle.
And then they bring him up.
He's like this every day,
mad as a bag of bees.
-It's crowning day.
-Good.
-What is it?
-It's nothing.
It's clean as can be.
Everyone just wants a party.
Yeah, I want them both
to hear me.
Be a surprise.
Felix, I'm in.
He's in.
There's a young lady
in Santiago I want you to meet.
Paloma?
-You're late. Vamos.
-I...
Uh, something about a hat?
Paris, uh...
Huh? What hat?
I forget things
when I get nervous.
This is the biggest job
I've ever had.
This your room?
It's a wine cellar.
Okay, come here.
Don't you think we ought
to get to know each other
just a little bit
before we, um...
Oh...
No, no, no, no.
Um, no, I'm sorry.
Um...
-All right.
-You do it.
Thank you.
Do you mind, uh...
-This is gonna go brilliantly.
-I know.
I've done
three weeks' training.
-Let's get a drink.
Good idea.
Two vodka martinis,
shaken, not stirred.
Si, senor.
-So I can hear you.
What shall we drink to?
-Felix?
-To Felix.
Remind me to get him a cigar.
Vamos?
-Sure.
-Okay.
Will this sample
be enough for you?
If he has used it, yes.
It is now progressing.
Oops. Sorry.
Terrible, terrible gloves.
So slippery.
Forgive me.
How much longer?
A-ha.
To happy new future
for Spectre.
Now, it is ready.
You go that way.
I'll go this way.
What is this?
Spectre bunga-bunga?
You ever been
to a party like this?
How do you think
I got this job?
Don't get distracted, now.
Remember, we're looking
for our Russian scientist.
I'm seeing
a lot of Spectre agents.
Yes.
And it looks like all of them.
Wow.
Friend of yours?
Cyclops. We ran
into each other in Italy.
That was
an eye-opening experience.
They're wearing earpieces.
Scanning.
It'll be clean.
It's good.
It's as good as can be.
-It's my party.
-Ah. Found it.
Celebrate me,
my birthday,
my crowning day.
Who's the birthday boy?
Um...
-Ernst Stavro Blofeld.
-Is he here?
No, he's...
Make your way.
Follow the music.
He's in London in prison.
How do you know for sure?
Because I put him there.
...feel my warm embrace.
Experience
a delicious surprise.
Let us shepherd humanity
with our new power.
I've spotted him,
our little Russian scientist.
-Have you got him?
-I'm here.
-I got him.
-Stay with him.
But I see you
from my little eye,
and my little eye says hi.
Now, see, now,
we emerge from the shadows
as gods on Mount Olympus.
Here's to the end
of our pariah.
Oh, my burden, my brother...
James Bond.
Goodbye, James.
You're popular tonight.
You can't run.
-It's too late.
It's already crawling
under your skin.
Don't be alarmed,
it's harmless to us.
-Just to him. So delicious.
Sir!
It is working.
Only Spectre are dying.
Hello.
Are you for my, uh, esco...
-Hmm?
-No? Oh.
Go!
-Thank you. I'll take this.
-No!
-What was that?
-Get him!
Time to go. Let's go!
It's clear.
May I cut in?
Go get him.
I'll hold them off.
Cover the exits!
Paloma.
Don't let them
get away!
Have you got them?
Nearly.
No!
Down!
Get them!
Don't let them get away!
Paloma,
I know you're busy,
but the curtain's about
to come down on this one.
I can get a car.
Where do you need it?
I'll be right there.
Stay down!
Move!
Huh?
Come on!
Three weeks' training,
really?
More or less.
We're still gonna
need that car.
-Salud!
Where are you taking me?
I'm taking you back
to Mother, darling.
Mother? Oh, no, no, no.
Huh. There you are.
No!
-Stay there!
-You okay?
-I'm great.
I'm gonna borrow
your plane. Sorry.
It's a shortcut.
This is my stop. Goodbye.
-You were excellent.
-You too.
-Next time, stay longer.
-I will.
-Hey, a cigar for Felix.
-Thank you. Come on.
-Ciao.
Come on, let's go.
No, no, no, sir,
I am not getting on that.
Well, that's a shame
because we don't have a choice.
Let's go. Come on.
Okay, okay,
what have we got here?
Sir, I just saved
your life, okay?
Please remember that.
So, could you please tell me
what the hell is going on?
Where are you taking me?
Somewhere safe.
At least make it look hard.
Thanks, Felix,
you walked me into a trap.
Get in.
-What trap?
-Spectre's dead. Sit.
-Who's dead?
-All of them.
Good.
What is this?
Explain it to me.
I don't have the words
to describe
to someone like you.
Try one.
It's perfect.
A perfect what?
What? Assassin.
Thank you, Bond,
your mission's done.
-Why didn't it kill me?
-You don't have to answer
-those questions. Bond!
-Why Spectre?
-Bond, please stop
asking these questions.
-Quiet!
Speak up.
Because you were never
the intended target.
He was a target? Why?
I changed the DNA
like we decided.
Now the plan is complete
-and I'm confused.
-Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Who is "we"?
Did M make you build this?
He is out of line here, Felix.
Did M order you
to kill Spectre?
-Don't answer that!
-Is M behind this?
-He is out of line!
-Felix!
Ash, shut your mouth!
M.
M helped me build it.
But please,
he does not have the vision
-for how to use it.
-Well, who does? Who does?
Blofeld? How did he know
I was going to be there?
Oh!
I'm with Safin.
You understand?
Yes. I am Dr. Obruchev.
I know who you are.
I don't know about you,
but I got a feeling in my gut
Ash might not be on our side.
We need to have a conversation
about the company you keep.
I'm with you.
That's a lot of blood.
So,
where are we going?
Get in the plane, Doctor.
This might be my last mission.
-What do you think?
-I think you're just looking
for an excuse
not to help me.
-There you go.
Paloma, she gave me a cigar
for you to smoke,
and you are gonna smoke it.
Nice, but maybe you should
hold on to that for now.
You just stay put.
Keep the pressure on that.
I'm gonna find us a way out.
I'll be over here.
You know, Felix, we really
need to stop meeting--
-Ooh.
-Okay.
I was such
a big fan of his.
Felix!
This doesn't look good.
Come on, Felix,
we've been in worse
than this. Let's go.
It's like back when I was
a kid on that shrimp boat.
You're from Milwaukee.
Am I?
I thought I made that up.
-He got me.
Just let me go.
Let me go.
You got this?
Yeah. Yeah.
Make it worth it.
James,
it's a good life, isn't it?
The best.
Felix.
Felix. Felix.
-Name?
-Bond.
James Bond.
How's retirement?
Quiet.
Hi. Where's Obruchev?
I thought you two
would get along.
-Report, 007.
-Thank you.
00... 7.
That must bother you.
Where is he?
He left me for somebody else.
It's, uh...
-So, you lost him?
-You can go in.
-Thank you.
-Thank y...
Alone, I'm afraid.
Oh, does that bother you?
I get why you shot him.
Yeah, well,
everyone tries at least once.
Has this desk got bigger?
Or have you got smaller?
I can't pretend there
weren't some sorry faces
when you left us, Bond,
but you fell
so far off the grid
that we thought
you must be dead.
Now, learning that you
were, in fact,
alive and well, and...
working for the CIA, well...
Well, that really was a blow.
Well,
they just asked so nicely.
It's a shame that you
haven't lost your touch.
We wouldn't be in this mess.
This is your mess.
Blofeld tried to kill me
in Cuba,
but someone hijacked his plan.
And whoever stole your weapon
used it
to wipe out Spectre instead.
Now your weapon is on the run
and nobody seems
to know who has it.
So you can imagine
why I've come back to play.
We're looking into it.
I can identify
the man that took Obruchev.
And what do you want
in return, Bond?
Blofeld.
Impossible. He's in Belmarsh.
Yes. He ran a Spectre meeting
in Cuba from Belmarsh.
-How?
-No.
How?
No one has access. No one.
Why didn't you shut it down?
Why didn't you
shut Heracles down?
I answer to the interests
of my country, not you.
-And to Felix Leiter?
-I certainly don't answer
to Felix Leiter.
Perhaps because he's dead.
I'm sorry.
I had a lot of respect
for Leiter.
Look, if you have information,
I'd be happy to receive it.
-Get me into Belmarsh.
-No.
Blofeld's the only member
of Spectre still breathing,
-I can't risk that.
-Oh, but you will
risk developing
a DNA-targeting weapon
with a corrupt scientist
for ten years?
There was nothing
to suggest that Obruchev
was working for anyone else.
I had him--
My God,
you're thirsty at the moment.
You have no right
to speak to me that way.
You have no right to make
insinuations about my judgment.
If you've nothing left
to give, you are irrelevant.
You've done your bit
and we thank you
for your service,
again. Goodbye.
-Moneypenny, send in 007.
You can go, Bond.
It's definitely the same desk.
-Thank you.
-Mm-hmm.
-Go to Belmarsh.
I want everything
that Blofeld listens to,
looks at and touches scanned.
Scan every corner
of that cell.
Scan the whole prison.
In fact,
scan the whole damn man.
Sir. I'll bring my gloves.
James...
Uh...
What are you doing for dinner?
-So, you're not dead?
-Hello, Q. I've missed you.
Mm!
That smells great.
-Were you expecting somebody?
Um... No. What...
Excuse me.
Oh.
This is the first time I've...
He'll be here in 20 minutes,
I can't take my focus off...
I need you to tell me
what's on that.
No, I need to lay the table.
You know,
they come with fur these days.
I want to be very clear
that I am not authorized
to help you.
-And I have sworn...
-It's to do with Heracles.
I presume M doesn't know
that this is happening.
No, but there's something
going on, Q.
We need to find out
what it is.
Well, it's never
- 00 to- 00, is it?
Thank you.
-Um, Bond?
-Yes?
Do you know
where this has been?
Everywhere, I should imagine.
Into the sandbox.
Oh. Thank you.
-Um, it's a database.
Don't touch that, please.
What's the data?
It's DNA.
Multiple individuals.
What was M working on?
Something he should have
shut down years ago.
-Oh, hello.
-What?
There's more.
Hidden files.
I was asked to recover
what I could
from Obruchev's hard drive
just after the explosion,
and I have
a pretty good feeling that...
this is what was missing.
Yeah. A complete disk.
So, Obruchev is working
for someone
who managed
to kill all of Spectre?
Not all of them.
Blofeld.
Can you show me
the other files?
Mm-hmm.
Wait,
this can't just be Spectre.
Oh, my God.
There are thousands.
Who are they?
They're in categories.
I'm gonna need
more time to organize...
There have been, uh, breaches
round the world of databases
holding DNA information.
-We've been tracking them.
-Ours?
I can't imagine
they're leaving us out,
whoever they are.
Well, Blofeld
will know who they are.
Q, you need to get me
into Belmarsh.
Well, there's only one person
he'll speak to.
Who? M says no one has access.
-Really?
-Did he?
What's that?
Can I just have
one nice evening, please,
before the world explodes?
Who has access? Who?
-Morning.
New patient.
He's weird.
You can't say that.
I'm sorry I'm late.
I wasn't expecting
a new patient.
Sorry if I surprised you.
No. I like surprises.
You're very attractive
for a psychotherapist.
Must be dangerous
for your clients.
They are usually more
of a danger to themselves.
Foxgloves.
Beautiful.
-Did you choose them?
-Yes.
I found them friendly.
You know if you eat them
they can cause your heart
to just...
stop.
Then I'll make sure not to.
Do you know a lot
about flowers?
My father had a garden.
He taught me.
He died when I was young,
but my interest remained.
It's difficult
to lose a parent.
Especially at a young age.
Yes,
death has
a particular effect
on children,
doesn't it?
What effect
did it have on you?
Profound.
But I saved a life once.
I think that had
more of an effect.
Why is that?
Saving someone's life
connects you
to them forever,
the same as taking it.
They belong to you.
I'm not very good
at talking about myself,
so I brought a memory box.
I thought
it might interest you.
Sometimes objects
can be more evocative
than memories.
I never forgot your eyes
under the ice.
They needed me.
It is a shock to see them
so many years later.
They still need me.
I am rather taken by them.
-What do you want?
-Just a favor.
You owe me.
You murdered my mother.
And your father
killed my entire family.
Parents.
I need you to visit
someone for me,
wearing this.
It's harmless to you.
You are the only one
who can do it.
No.
Why would I do
anything for you?
Because I am a man
willing to kill
the person you love most.
I've already lost everyone
I've ever loved.
There is nothing
you can threaten me with.
That is very sad to hear,
Madeleine.
But it is not true...
is it?
Madeleine Swann, really?
Well, yes. We took
your information seriously,
but that was five years ago.
Nothing came up.
Well, she's very smart
and very good
at hiding things.
She's a useful asset.
She's the only psychiatrist
he agreed to speak to.
I had to exercise
my judgment...
Your judgment is the problem.
That weapon was designed
to save lives
and to eradicate
collateral damage
for our agents.
A clean,
accurate shot every time.
But it had to be off the books.
There are enough holes
in our national security.
If the world knows
what this can do...
-They'd kill for it.
-Mm.
Look...
If it's an error,
it's on my shoulders,
fair and square.
I've dedicated my life
to defending this country.
I believe in defending
the principles of this...
Of this.
But we used to be able to get
into a room with the enemy,
we could look him in the eye.
And now the...
The enemy
is just floating in the ether.
We don't even know
what they're after.
Blofeld.
We managed to access
a database of their targets.
"We"?
Oh, for fuck's sake.
I see.
And after Blofeld,
what do they want?
Well, it's hard to say.
I mean,
I would imagine world leaders,
innocent civilians, freedom,
you know, that sort of thing.
Oh, good,
well, just the usual.
Just the usual.
Blofeld was communicating
with his agents in Cuba
through a bionic eye
which we've now retrieved.
You're welcome.
Spectre's destruction's going
to have huge consequences.
Whoever did this is going
to be very dangerous
and very powerful.
We need all the information
that we can gather.
Sir.
Bond.
So the rumors are true.
You look well.
Tanner.
Sir,
there's been a development.
They were
just dropping,
one right after the other.
It was disturbing,
to say the least.
Wait till you see
what it looks like up close.
-Uh, Bond's in the office.
-What?
Oh, Bond. My God,
I haven't seen you in,
in, uh...
-How is your retirement?
-Shut up, Q.
I know he's staying with you.
And you're not
in the clear either.
-What happened?
-He's been reinstated
as a double-0.
-Double-0 what?
-What have you got?
Q has studied
the blood samples I gathered
from the victims
of the funeral.
Just look at this.
-What are we looking at?
This is the funeral
of one of the dead
Spectre agents from Cuba.
And here are
the members of their family
who made physical contact
with the corpse.
We found Heracles
in the blood samples
of all of them.
Now,
that's some good work, Nomi.
Thank you, sir. Double-0 what?
-What are they?
-They're... They're nanobots.
Right.
Microscopic bio-robots
that can enter your system
by the slightest contact
with your skin.
Programmed with DNA
to target specific individuals.
Heracles was...
It was designed to be
the most efficient weapon
in our arsenal.
Passing through
people harmlessly
before reaching
its intended target.
But Obruchev
modified the nanobots
so that they can kill anyone
related to the target.
-Anyone?
-Well, since it's DNA-based,
with further modifications,
yes.
Families,
certain genetic traits.
Single-nucleotide variants
and polymorphisms
that could target a range
from individuals to...
whole ethnicities.
You infect enough people...
And the people
become the weapon.
It was never intended to be
a weapon of mass destruction.
It was...
I need to call
the Prime Minister.
Tanner, quarantine
the families from the funeral.
-Yes, sir.
-And, Q,
hack into Blofeld's bionic eye,
see what you can find.
-You've got your wish.
Go to Blofeld and see
what you can get out of him.
And find
that cockroach Obruchev.
Sir.
We don't have a trail.
Logan Ash. State Department.
Ex-State Department.
Find him,
you'll find Obruchev.
Um...
Good luck.
Thanks.
I'll be outside
when you're done
with your important
preparation.
I'll be just a moment.
It's fine.
Blofeld's eyeball unlocked.
Accessing
received media stream.
I know you
and she have a history,
but we've kept a close eye
on her over the years.
She's been very compliant.
If Bond does
anything weird in there,
you'll be doing me
a huge favor,
so don't make it too easy
for him, okay?
Okay.
He's the most valuable asset
this country has.
I know you and he
have a history,
but don't let him get
in your head.
If you feel yourself
losing control...
Oh, Tanner, relax.
I'm not gonna lose...
control.
Dr. Swann, good afternoon.
Mr. Bond.
007.
Six-seven.
Special cell two
now locked off.
Segregation unit secure.
This is where we leave you.
Good luck.
Just get us a name.
Must be nice to catch up
with an old friend
so regularly.
-We're closer than ever.
Oh, that was awkward.
Does he have that effect
on all women?
Fifty-fifty.
-It's unpredictable.
-Huh.
Isolated in HSU.
You're shaking.
It's not an ideal situation.
Open the door.
Open the door!
-Don't.
-What is it?
James,
you don't know what this is.
Don't make me do this.
Please.
Right. Open the doors.
-Open the door.
-Open it.
What...
Where are you going?
Home.
-I'll get her.
-Wait.
-He won't talk without her.
-Just wait.
Special delivery.
James.
Hello, Blofeld.
Perhaps you can help me.
Cuba was quite the party.
-Happy birthday, by the way.
-Thank you.
I'm trying to piece together
what happened.
I mean, there you were,
or here you were,
with the world's
most powerful people,
your friends, all in one room,
a noose around my neck,
and your hands on the most
valuable weapon in existence.
It's like a...
It was like a testimony
to your greatness.
A celebration of all
that is Ernst Stavro Blofeld.
-Yeah, James.
Yeah.
But then it all went wrong,
didn't it?
My sweet James,
what do you want?
Your enemies
are closing in, Blofeld.
And the biggest twist here
is that if you tell me
who they are,
I could save your life.
Mm, my avenging angel.
My chaser of lost causes.
Now you even chase mine.
But you're asking
the wrong question.
Yeah,
Cuba was a disappointment,
but we all cry on our birthday.
You need to ask yourself,
why are we here?
Accessing media file 472.
Hmm. Looking sharp, Bond.
473.
474.
475.
476, 477, 478.
479.
Logan Ash.
A pleasure to meet you.
Oh, my God, that's him.
I am sorry
for your loss.
I believe you know
who I represent and work for?
We have an opportunity for you.
You keep
coming back to me.
I thought
I'd never see you again,
but fate draws
us back together.
Yes. Q's got eyes on Logan Ash.
-Go.
-Yep.
Let me know what happens.
Now your enemy
is my enemy.
How did that happen?
Well, you live long enough...
-Yeah. Look at us.
Two old men in a hole
trying to work out
who's playing tricks on us.
She still loves you.
Did you know that?
And you broke her heart.
And she betrayed you.
She is irrelevant.
Mm, I wouldn't be
so quick to dismiss.
You said it yourself,
she's very good
at hiding things.
And when her secret
finds its way out,
and it will,
it'll be the death of you.
Just give me a name.
-Madeleine.
Please, just...
Please, no games.
Madeleine.
Oh, do you know what?
The two of you
should come see me.
A little couples therapy.
I simply have to see your face
when she tells you the truth.
Just tell me
who they are, Blofeld...
and then I'll leave.
I'll leave you on your own.
No, I don't want you to leave.
We're just getting
reacquainted.
Hmm. All right. Come.
You were unusually patient.
I need to give you something
so that you didn't have to make
all this way for nothing. Come.
Careful, Bond.
It was me.
-You destroyed Spectre?
-No.
Vesper's grave.
Madeleine didn't do a thing.
It was all me.
I knew you'd come visit it,
I just needed to wait
for the bon moment.
She led you straight there
from the goodness
of her heart.
And then you left her, for me.
-It doesn't matter.
-Oh, but it does.
She still does, doesn't she?
My poor little cuckoo.
You were always so very,
very sensitive.
This isn't working.
Keep going.
All this wasted time,
the life you could have had.
And the reason all of this
is so beautiful,
so exquisitely beautiful,
is that you're coming
to me looking for answers,
whereas the one person
who knows it all is she.
It's Madeleine. She holds
the secrets you need.
All of them.
I didn't need to kill you.
I'd already broken you.
I wanted to give you
an empty world...
like the one you gave me.
It's enough
to almost make me regret it.
Eh, almost.
Die.
Hmm?
-Die, Blofeld. Die.
Jesus. Open the door.
-Bond! Bond! Bond!
-Open the door. Bond!
-Cuckoo.
What the hell
are you thinking?
Yes, yes, yes, I know how
to interrogate an asset.
-This interrogation is over.
-Tanner, don't lecture me!
Bond, you have violated
the most important rule
in the whole bloody playbook.
Don't move.
I'm... I'm gonna need those,
I'm afraid.
He's dead.
It's a good thing
you're not actually related,
or you'd be dead too.
-How do I get this off?
-Oh, you don't. You can't.
Nanobots aren't just
for Christmas.
Once Heracles
is in your system,
it's there forever.
Did they find the car?
We traced it,
but she abandoned it.
They searched her flat,
she hasn't been home.
-Is she one of them?
-I don't know.
James, do you have any idea
where she might have gone?
No. I don't know her at all.
Is that for me?
No.
Then why did you come?
Because you told me to.
I didn't think you
would remember.
I remember everything.
You need to tell me
who gave you
the poison, Madeleine.
Is he dead?
Yes, he's dead.
Good.
He told me
you didn't betray me.
I understand you're not built
to trust people.
-Neither are you.
-Then we were fools
for trying.
I wanted to.
I don't know if you wanted me
to come here,
or why you tried
to kill Blofeld,
or who gave you
the poison to do it,
or how long you've been
working for them,
but I do know...
that for what felt
like five minutes of my life
I wanted everything with you.
And it's not
because I didn't trust.
It was just that feeling.
I know I've come here
to find out who gave you
the poison.
But I'm not going to leave here
without you knowing
that I have loved you,
and I will love you,
and I do not regret
a single moment of my life
that led me to you.
Except when I put you
on that train.
Do you know
the worst thing about you?
My timing?
Don't.
My sense of humor?
-What?
-You look...
You look incredible.
This is Mathilde.
Um...
Hello. I'm James.
Sir, we've located Logan Ash.
007 wants a word.
-Well done, 007.
-Thank you, sir.
Permission
for a capture or kill.
Have we cleared this
with the Americans?
Granted.
And thank you for asking.
By the book, sir.
Well, your predecessor
was less deferential.
To be fair,
Commander Bond
gave me the lead.
Well, I'm glad to see you two
getting along.
-Sir.
Have you located Dr. Swann?
Nothing, I'm afraid, sir.
Thank you.
She's not yours.
But, um, the...
Okay, the blue eyes, the...
She's not yours.
Okay.
I have something to show you.
Another child?
What is it
with your dad
and secret rooms?
Talk to me.
I wanted
to bring you here before.
To tell you everything.
Blofeld ordered my father
to assassinate this family.
The boy survived.
His name is Lyutsifer Safin.
When I was a little girl,
he came here
to kill my father.
But he found me
and my mother instead.
He spared my life.
And now he's back.
-And what does he want?
-Revenge.
Me.
-Who were they?
-Spectre's poisoners.
My father held
a banquet for them,
used their own recipe
in the dessert.
Dioxin.
They would have
suffered horribly.
Scarred him for life.
The family had an island.
They called it
the Poison Garden.
Oh, so...
Blofeld took it from them,
and kept running it,
and now this Safin
has taken it back.
Q, find one Lyutsifer Safin.
Whereabouts unknown
and no recent photographs,
but I'm gonna send you
some images of him as a boy.
And a picture of an island.
So, you know, do your best.
And I'm gonna need a plane
to get there, a big one.
I'll send you
my location shortly.
You're going to find him?
There are a thousand reasons
why we need to find this man.
You just gave me a reason
to kill him.
How is it?
Excuse me.
-Yes?
-Bond.
Did you find the island?
Yes, it's part of a chain
in disputed waters
between Japan and Russia.
There's a chemical plant
dating back
to the Second World War,
seems to have had
quite a history.
Sir, Japanese intelligence
have reported suspicious
activity on the island.
Q, bring up
the satellite images
I just sent through.
These were taken
over the last few days.
-If that is Safin there...
-Then Heracles is there too.
Where do you need
this plane, Bond?
Hang on, Q. Did 007 manage
to locate Logan Ash?
She's closing in on him.
I'll send you her location.
I thought she
was following Logan Ash,
not me.
What? She is.
James, where are you?
Put her in the back.
There you are.
In here. Watch your head.
Q, I am gonna
need that plane, quickly.
I'm near Orland NATO base.
You think
you can get it to me?
Right. Right, yes.
We'll be there.
-Thank you.
-Mama.
James.
-Mathilde!
They're above us!
Get out of here! James!
You stay here.
I'll be back soon.
Anybody comes through
that door, you shoot them.
Unless it's me.
You be quiet, okay?
Stay really quiet.
Hey!
Go! Go!
There! Run him over!
Nice moves, Bond.
You won't be able
to stop him...
...so why don't you help
me out, brother?
I had a brother.
His name was Felix Leiter.
Need a ride?
Where have you been?
Chasing after your lead.
-Ash?
-Dead.
They took Dr. Swann.
And her daughter.
I... I didn't know
she had a daughter.
Did M get my plane?
Our plane.
I'm coming with you.
Thank you, 007.
-Hello, Q.
-Bond.
Sorry to get you
out of bed.
The objectives
of this mission are threefold.
Confirm the presence
of Heracles.
Kill Obruchev and Safin.
Get Dr. Swann and her daughter
off the island.
And, Bond,
I hope they're there.
-Thank you, sir.
-Sir.
Permission for Commander Bond
to be redesignated as 007.
It's just a number.
Very well. Agreed.
Good luck.
Bond, your watch.
It contains a limited-radius
electromagnetic pulse.
It'll short any circuit
in a hardwired network
-if you get close enough.
-Mm-hmm.
And how strong is it?
It's fairly strong.
"Fairly strong,"
what's that mean?
We haven't had the chance
to test it properly,
just be careful.
Right, this is Q-DAR.
It will map the space
as you move through it.
Don't touch that.
And smart blood
will track you...
Whoops. And your vitals.
Bond, you don't mind
a shot or two
whilst at work?
-Shall we?
-Well, I haven't had a drink
for three or four hou...
-Hours.
-Wow.
Doesn't sound like you.
-Ow!
-Good.
I assume you know
how the stealthy bird works.
No, no idea.
Gravity.
Welcome back, Mr. Safin.
Welcome to your family.
How are you progressing?
So, so good, Mr. Safin.
So, so good.
-My request?
-Svetlana?
Continue.
-What is that?
-Insurance.
A simple hair falls
from your head
and now I have your life
in my hands.
And yours.
How damaged you must be
to threaten a little girl.
You're any less damaged?
You love a killer.
You bore his child
despite his rejection.
You've hidden
and lied your whole life.
You will do anything...
To survive.
You understand me
the same way I understand you.
Move.
My father's garden.
It was his toxic treasure.
Let me show her.
-Give her to me.
-No.
I can protect her.
Mathilde.
It's a poison garden...
but it's perfectly safe.
My father made this.
He loved his plants so much,
he would sing to them.
I want to show you
one of my favorites.
Some of these plants
are very dangerous,
but not all of them
are for hurting people.
I have plants that can do
all sorts of things.
Mathilde!
No.
This one makes you do
as you're told,
so you never misbehave,
and you're always good.
You mustn't misbehave,
Mathilde.
And neither must your mother.
Ever.
-Do you like it here?
-No.
Well, you will learn to.
I grew up here,
and you will too.
Such a beautiful child.
Perhaps we should
have some tea.
-No.
-Make her see the light.
No,
you can't separate us!
-Mathilde!
-Mama!
Don't worry.
You have me.
As soon as you have
a line of sight on the island,
drop altitude,
stay below radar.
You ever flown
one of these things before?
Nope.
Don't forget
to release the chute,
and open the wings.
Gravity isn't always
your friend.
Look for a concrete structure
on the west side
of the island.
That's your best bet
for getting in.
Coming up for air, Q.
Right, good.
You should be entering
a World War II-era sub pen.
Doesn't seem
to get much activity,
but look out
for cameras anyway.
Use your watch, Bond.
Okay. Ah, there you go.
-Sir, they're in.
-Yes, we have it.
You should be able
to see the chemical plant's
architecture.
-Which one's Bond?
-He's the... He's the psi.
-He's the trident thingy.
-Give us the layout.
Right.
You're at the edge
of a toxic merry-go-round.
The main activity should
be towards the central hub,
which is directly above you.
Bond.
Bond, there's something...
There's something
big up ahead,
I can't work out what it is.
It's...
These walls
must be thick.
Bond.
Bond? 007, do you read me?
We've lost them.
They've entered
a blind spot, sir.
I can't work out what it is
they've walked into.
Well, just get them back.
Well,
will you look at those doors.
This was a missile silo.
Right.
Let's go.
Everybody, over there!
In the corner! Now!
-What? How?
-Move!
Move! On the ground!
Alarm.
Down, boy.
What... What are you doing?
You cannot explode
laboratory, please.
This is suicide mission.
Come on.
You will never leave
this island alive.
That was the farm.
And this is the factory.
They're mass-producing it.
Nomi, come and look at this.
Well, look,
you cannot stop it, mister.
We have big plan, you know.
-We have big numbers.
-What is it?
It's a simulation.
They're not
just attacking individuals.
They're going to kill millions.
It will not fit
in a suitcase this time, lady.
He's really getting
on my nerves.
Well, shut him up.
Ow!
My nose.
We have
to destroy this whole facility.
There is no need for violence.
Mr. Safin,
they use explosives.
-Shut up.
-Mr. Bond,
you have something of mine
and I have something of yours.
Why don't you come up
and we can talk about it?
Like adults.
Safin, where is he?
If I don't come back,
blow it all to shit.
We don't have enough
explosives for that.
Yeah, but they don't know that.
Huh.
He said you must drink.
-For your health.
-Do you trust him?
He made me kill
your last master.
Why do you think
he let you join him?
I think he wants you to drink.
I want him to give me
my daughter back.
He said if you behave,
you'll see her. Drink.
Do you know
what this flower does?
It makes you blind.
Just a drop of this
in your eye,
and you'll never see again.
Losing one eye is a tragedy.
Losing two...
-No games.
-This is not a game.
Welcome.
On the floor.
Your sidearm.
Careful.
-She is light as a feather.
-All right!
Please, sit.
It's going to be all right.
Promise you,
it's going to be all right.
James Bond.
History of violence.
License to kill.
Vendetta with Ernst Blofeld.
In love with Madeleine Swann.
I could be speaking
to my own reflection.
We've made
slightly different choices.
No. We've just developed
different methods
for the same goal.
Only your skills die
with your body.
Mine will survive
long after I'm gone.
And life is all about
leaving something behind.
Isn't it?
Doesn't have to be ugly.
You leave my baby alone,
I leave yours.
What do you think?
I think you're right.
Thank you.
I think we are the same.
We both know
what it feels like
to have everything
taken from us
before we're even
in the fight.
It would have been nice
to have a chance,
you know, don't you think?
Just...
we all should get a chance.
But this thing
that you're building,
it puts everyone,
the whole world
on a battlefield.
Nobody gets a chance.
The thing
that no one wants to admit
is that most people want things
to happen to them.
We tell each other lies
about the fight for free will
and independence,
but we don't really want that.
We want to be told how to live,
and then die
when we are not looking.
People want oblivion,
and a few of us are born
to build it for them.
So, here I am,
their invisible god...
sneaking under their skin.
You know that history
isn't kind
to those who play God.
And you don't?
We both eradicate people
to make the world
a better place.
I just want to be
a little... tidier.
Without collateral.
I want the world to evolve,
yet you want it
to stay the same.
Let's face it...
-I've made you redundant.
-No.
Not as long
as there are people
like you in the world.
And with all due respect
to the enormity of your...
tidy achievements,
all you're really doing is
standing in a very long line
of angry little men.
I'm not angry,
just passionate.
Disable your explosives,
get off my island,
and you can take this precious
little angel with you.
And Madeleine?
-She stays.
-You know I can't do that.
That is a shame.
She really hoped you would.
She knows
it's her only path to survive.
No, you have her tell me that.
What mother wouldn't sacrifice
herself for her own child?
Is that what happened to yours?
My mother lay at my feet
as I watched her die.
Wait! Wait. Wait.
I'll do whatever you want.
Yes, you will.
I... I apologize.
I'm sorry.
Simple choices, Mr. Bond.
Like do you want to die
in front of your daughter?
Or do you want your daughter
to die in front of you?
No. No. No. No. No.
I am sorry.
I'm sorry.
Look at your father, Mathilde.
This is power.
I'm sorry.
I'm truly, truly sorry.
James!
-Where is she?
The first shipment
is on the dock,
-ready for pickup, Doctor.
-Very good.
Hmm...
If you don't want
my protection, then...
off you go.
Move.
Our first buyers are arriving.
Sir, I've just detected
some suspicious activity.
Several high-speed transports
are headed towards the island.
Origin unknown.
Still no sign of 007.
Come on, Bond.
Where the hell are you?
This is hopeless situation,
lady. Please.
Bond.
-Bond.
The party is larger
than the reservation.
Look, lady,
please, please just let me go.
I... There was never
gonna be a way out.
Stop this nonsense.
You don't have a chance,
anyways.
Hey. Hey, I have a good vial
for your people,
good for West African diaspora.
It can be a good thing.
You know,
I do not need laboratory
to exterminate your entire race
from the face of the Earth.
-Do you know what time it is?
-What?
Time to die.
No!
Move! Move!
They dropped down
to a lower level.
There has to be
a stairwell down.
Mama?
Mathilde. Mathilde.
We should go.
It's Q. Do you read me?
Come in, 007, it's Q.
Traffic. We have traffic.
-I think we just got buzzed.
-Those are two Russian MiGs.
Traffic. TCAS,
you have control.
I understand, and I'm doing
the best that I can.
Just please wait.
Sir, I've got the Navy,
the Japanese, the Russians,
all breathing down my neck,
demanding to know why
we've got a C-17
circling a disputed island.
Don't tell them
anything just yet.
-Ah, just in time.
-Nomi, you know...
Madeleine, Mathilde,
they're my, uh...
-Hey.
-Hi.
Family?
Q. Q, are you there?
Yes. Bond.
Do we have
any Royal Naval vessels
-in the immediate vicinity?
-Uh, yes. Why?
We are gonna need
an immediate strike
on this location.
This whole island,
it's a manufacturing plant
for Heracles.
We don't have clearance
for missile strikes, do we?
Mm-mm.
Bond, there's something
else you should know.
Several unidentified ships
are headed your way.
They're coming after Heracles.
How far out?
Uh, 20 minutes.
Q, patch me through.
-007.
-M.
Our operation
is attracting a lot
of international attention.
We're seeing what we can do.
Come on.
Let's go. Come on.
It's going to get
very cold out there, so...
I want you to have this.
That'll keep you warm.
I have to finish this. For us.
I know.
I'll just be a minute.
I've got them.
This might come in handy.
Thank you.
Q, talk to me.
Um, our uninvited guests
are 15 minutes away.
Bond, M here. The situation
is diplomatically complex.
We don't have a choice.
Fire on my mark.
If we launch,
the Russians, the Japanese
and even the Americans
will want answers.
Well, don't give them any.
Rational minds, Bond.
I'm trying to save this from
escalating to all-out war.
Mallory, if we don't do this,
there will be nothing
left to save.
Fire on my mark.
007,
there's another problem.
-That room you were just in.
-Yes, I know, I know.
I've got
to open the blast doors.
Otherwise our missiles
will bounce off it
like they've hit a trampoline.
Yes, I know, I know.
Find the control room.
It should be in a tower
just above the blast doors.
The missiles will take about
nine minutes from launch.
Do you think you can do it
before the ships arrive?
Plenty of time,
plenty of time.
Bond.
Bond, do you read me?
Yeah.
Yeah, Q.
I read you.
Sounds like
you're in a rugby scrum.
I just showed someone
your watch.
Really blew their mind.
Right, good.
Now, did you find
the control room?
Well, my Russian
is a little rusty,
but I think so, yeah.
Okay, Q.
Uh,
I've done some research.
-Old schematics...
-Q, I am gonna need some...
Yes?
Bond?
-Hello?
-Power.
-Power?
Right, the infrastructure
must go back to the 1950s,
so it's going to be
an overly complicated
and intricate
switching system.
Now, the order
in which you engage it
will need to be
extremely precise.
You're looking
for a control panel.
There should be
a counterweight clutch.
So, listen very carefully, 007.
The first thing
you need to do...
Got it.
I think.
Yep, that's it.
Launch the missiles.
Not until you're clear.
Q, tell M
to launch the missiles now.
Okay. Okay, okay.
Understood.
M, Bond says fire.
HMS Dragon here.
-Admiral.
-Sir.
-M here.
-What are my instructions?
You have permission to launch.
Roger. Launching the strike.
Missiles airborne.
Nine minutes out.
No.
No. No, no!
Quite a mess you've made.
Like an animal.
Now we are both poisoned
with heartbreak.
Two heroes in a tragedy
of our own making.
Anyone we touch,
we are their curse.
A stroke to their cheek,
a kiss...
would kill them instantly.
Yes...
Madeleine.
Yes, Mathilde.
You made me do this,
you see?
This was your choice.
Q. Q, are you there?
Bond, there you are.
Are they safe, Q?
Yes, they're safe.
Bond,
have you left the island?
There's a slight problem
with the blast doors.
Won't take a sec.
No, no, no. Bond, the missiles
have already launched.
Just get out of there.
Q, how do I, uh...
How do I destroy this?
If the silo doors are open,
the missiles
will deal with it.
No. No, no, no.
If you get it on you,
how do...
How do you get it off?
You know as well as I do
that you can't.
It's... It's permanent.
It's eternal. Which is why
we have to destroy it.
For Christ's sake, James,
just get off the island.
It's harmless unless
you're near to the target.
Yeah.
Well, that's not gonna work.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
It's for Madeleine.
It's all right, Q.
It's all all right.
Would you put
Madeleine on, please?
Yes, of course.
How stupid of me.
Nomi, come in.
Can you put Madeleine on?
Madeleine.
-James.
-Madeleine.
I'm here.
Where are you?
Is it done?
-James?
-Yes.
Yes, he's... He's dead.
-Are you both there?
-Yes.
Good. You're safe.
That's good.
Have you left?
No. Um...
I'm not gonna make it.
What?
-Madeleine. Madeleine.
-You promised.
Just get off that island.
I know you can do this.
Everything's good now.
There's no one left
to hurt us.
Madeleine...
you have made...
the most beautiful thing
I have ever seen.
She's perfect.
Because she came from you.
Oh, God. The vial.
You've been poisoned.
Yes.
There must be a way.
We just need more time.
If we only had more time.
You have all the time
in the world.
I love you.
I love you too.
She does have your eyes.
I know.
Very hard to know
what to say,
but I thought we should gather
and remember.
And I...
I thought
this was appropriate.
"The function of man
is to live, not to exist.
I shall not waste my days
trying to prolong them.
I shall use my time."
To James.
-James.
James.
Right, back to work.
Mathilde.
I'm going to tell you
a story...
about a man.
His name was Bond.
James Bond.