INSPIRED BY REAL EVENTS
Kim!
Kim?
Kim! No!
Kim!
THE EVIL NEXT DOOR
What are you thinking about?
You.
And how great this is going to be for us.
- Maybe we should see the place first.
- Yeah, obviously, but...
- I just know it's right. I can feel it.
- Me too.
Daddy. My ship is full of dragons.
All right, then my ship
is full of... dragons... spaceships!
My ship is full of spuds.
It's your turn. Come on.
Okay. My ship is full of... cars.
- No. You're out.
- What? Why?
Your word has to start with the last one.
The last what?
The last letter. He said "spuds,"
so that gives you S.
Okay, I'll start over.
My ship is full of... screws.
- My ship is full of stew!
- My ship is full of...
water!
If you and my dad buy the house...
does that make you my new mommy?
No, I mean...
It's actually more like...
Does that mean you're going to die, too?
I was on P, right?
My ship is full of... poop!
That sounds like a gross ship!
I don't want to sail on that.
I think I'll catch a flight, thanks.
- Hey there!
- Hello.
- Hi!
- Erik.
- I'm Shirin.
- Nice to meet you. Welcome!
- So this is it.
- It's great.
- And you've brought the little guy. Hi!
- This is Lucas.
Great.
I'll just unlock the door
and you guys can have a look around.
Check it out. Wow. It's awesome.
- I didn't realize it was a duplex.
- Me neither. Let's go.
Excuse me?
Is there no one living next door?
No, the house is unoccupied.
Lucas?
The previous owners renovated the place
and knocked down a wall here to make
the kitchen and living room open plan.
So you get tons of amazing natural light.
In my opinion,
you can't go wrong with an open layout.
Hello?
There you are!
- Check this out.
- What a great room.
A child lives in here.
A child probably used to live here, yeah.
We'll see,
maybe this can be your room now.
- So, we're buying the house, right?
- Yeah, let's do it.
We're buying a house.
FRIDAY, 26 SEPTEMBER 2014
Go on, take that inside.
He's a huge help. He carried a teddy bear.
Great.
- Take these boxes.
- Okay.
This looks like old baby stuff.
Yeah, we don't need it anymore.
- There's no hole there. How do I...
- Daddy!
Yikes, buddy!
I thought you were going to help me
put this stuff together. You promised.
Do you know what happens when...
Hey...
Just be careful, you've got this.
Do you want me to help?
Yes.
Come here.
There we go. I'll put it here.
Take a sip, so you don't spill.
Cheers!
Hey! I'm great, how are you?
Wow! Yeah, totally.
The only thing is that we just moved away.
Hi.
Hey? Can you come down here?
I need to talk to you about something.
Okay.
I'd have to spend weeknights away
for a while, leaving you two alone here,
and leaving you to look after the house
and Lucas... I don't know.
You have to take the job. We'll be fine.
- Are you sure?
- Daddy?
- Yes, I'm sure.
- Come here, Daddy!
Lucas, just a second! I'll be right there.
Tell them yes.
Okay, I will.
- Daddy!
- All right, I'm coming!
- Where are you going to be?
- I have to be at work.
But Shirin is going to be here,
so you'll have an awesome time.
Okay? Good.
Now, let's get some sleep, shall we?
Scoot over.
- Can you sing Mommy's song?
- Mommy's song? Of course.
Good night, Lucas.
- Good thing that I have you, my sweet
- Good thing that we have us, my sweet
- We make each other complete
- Every day we get to meet
And be together, you and me...
SUNDAY, 5 OCTOBER 2014
- See you, buddy.
- Bye, Daddy.
See you in a few days.
- Bye.
Drive safe, okay?
Hello?
Yes, I want to play.
No, I wasn't scared.
He's not here right now.
No, I'm alone.
Do you live in there?
Lucas?
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
Okay, but it's time for bed.
Can I sleep in the big bed?
We all agreed that you should sleep
in your own room, remember?
- Please?
- No.
- Good night.
Sleep tight.
Hey.
Can a dead person come back?
Well, some believe that people
keep existing even after they die,
but, like, in a different place.
No, that's not what I mean.
I mean, can they come back here?
To us?
No.
No, they can't.
Is this about your mom?
No.
- Hi.
- Hi!
- Everything okay?
- Sure.
Is something wrong?
No. Nothing's wrong. It's just...
- It's just what?
- Lucas, he...
He talked about his mom.
- Okay.
- And...
I'm just struggling a little
with all of this.
I don't feel like...
Okay.
I don't know if I can... if I...
Babe, everything's going to be okay.
We all just need time to adjust.
You know what? You're right.
Everything is going to be okay.
I just need time to adjust.
Okay. I have to go, babe.
I'll talk to you later. Kisses.
Kisses.
TUESDAY, 7 OCTOBER 2014
This is Shirin.
Hi.
Damn it.
- Hi!
- Hi.
- I'm so sorry I'm late.
- It's okay.
Lucas had a great day.
It was his turn to tell a story.
Okay.
And he told everyone about his new friend.
Oh?
Yeah, the kid next door.
Hi, Lucas.
I'm sorry I'm late.
- Can we play a game?
- No, it's time for bed.
Just for a little while?
Go brush your teeth.
I'll be up in a minute.
Lucas?
Hello?
What are you up to?
Stop it. Just come out.
Lucas!
Yes?
Jesus, you scared me!
What are you doing?
We're playing.
Okay.
Come on. Brush your teeth.
"And all the animals gathered
in the clearing for a celebration,
because they thought
the troll was finally gone for good."
But was it, do you think?
To be continued.
Can you sing me the song?
No, I... I don't know that song.
And I think that should be something
special for just you and your dad.
Good night.
THURSDAY, 9 OCTOBER 2014
Watch out! I'm coming to get you!
- Hi!
- Hi.
Where do they get their energy from?
Sit down on the swing, Tilda.
So are you new to the neighborhood?
Yeah, we are. We just moved in.
- Oh...
- Mom, push me higher!
- Higher!
- Okay.
Are you ready to go?
I lost my shoes!
I lost my shoes! No!
One...
two...
three... four...
five...
six... seven...
eight... nine...
ten! Ready or not, here I come!
- What's going on?
- Nothing.
You know there's no boy
living next door, right?
- Yes, there is!
- No, there isn't.
He comes over to play.
You are mean.
- Lucas, listen to me. There's no...
- You're not my mother!
One... two...
three... four...
five... six...
seven... eight...
nine... ten!
Ready or not, here I come!
Where are you?
Are you in here?
Are you up there?
Where are you? Are you in here?
Lucas?
Oh, Lucas, what happened?
Lucas, did something happen?
Okay, calm down. Come here.
It's okay. The door just slammed shut.
There's nothing to be scared of.
He's coming!
It's him.
The bogeyman.
- No.
- Yeah, nothing.
- Hi! Are you okay?
- Yeah.
- Hi!
- Hi.
There are no signs of a break-in
and no response when we knock.
- Have you lived here long?
- No.
Houses make all sorts of noises
for all sorts of reasons.
- So there's no one in there?
- No.
But I saw a child in there.
Well, the place is empty now,
so there's nothing more we can do. Okay?
He's freezing.
Why doesn't he have a coat on?
- Up here?
- Yeah, right there.
I mean... maybe he was right.
It's a house with noisy plumbing.
It could just be the house settling.
No, someone was knocking!
And I saw someone in there.
Some kids probably just snuck in,
or it was just dark
and you were a little worked up.
Listen, I'll take tomorrow off and stay.
And then it'll be the weekend.
- No, you don't have to do that.
- I want to.
I don't want you to be afraid.
Oh, God! Watch out or I'll eat you.
Oh, no!
Oh, wow, you scared me!
Hey, I just folded all this laundry.
You're making the clothes all wrinkly.
Come on, six!
- Hey! What are you doing?
- Nothing.
- Are you trying to cheat?
- No, I just stroked Lucas's face.
Are you two in cahoots?
- No.
- What's that behind your back?
- Air?
- I know you've got something there!
- No, I don't!
- I don't have anything!
- What kind of example are you setting?
The example of a dad who cheats at games!
- Here.
- No!
- Every day we get to meet
- And be together, you and me
- Because...
I just wanted to say good night.
- Good night.
- Because no one, I said no one
- Wants to be alone
Good night.
Maybe we'll get a juice box.
Hold it! Are you licensed
to operate this thing?
You need a wheelbarrow license, see.
Hey, there's a speed limit here!
Hey! You little rascal!
Come here!
- Hi.
- Hi!
- How are things?
- Good.
I'm actually having a great time.
Julia, would you move your car
to let us out?
- Sure. By the way, this is...
- Shirin.
- Hi, I'm Sofie.
- They bought Peter and Jenny's house.
You know what happened there, right?
Actually, you and I don't know either,
so... See you around.
What do you mean? What happened?
Well, they had only just moved in,
and then their child went missing.
- Missing?
- Julia?
MONDAY, 13 OCTOBER 2014
Listen, you can stay with me tonight,
in the big bed.
Now spit.
Wake up.
Okay, Lucas, I'm coming.
Please, help me.
Help me...
Lucas!
Lucas? What happened?
He tried to take me.
TUESDAY, 14 OCTOBER 2014
- You're not even listening to me.
- I am listening.
I just don't get it.
Why did you leave Lucas on his own?
This is messed up.
Someone broke in and hurt him.
It wasn't some random intruder!
That's what I'm trying to tell you.
Something is seriously fucked up here.
Hey, buddy. Come here.
Come to Daddy.
Are you okay?
Let me see. Is your arm okay?
SIX-YEAR-OLD MISSING
I'm going out for a bit.
Okay, but tell me who hurt you.
Buddy?
Can you please tell me
what really happened?
Is Shirin nice to you?
- Hello. Can I help you?
- I'm looking for Peter Lindwall.
You found him.
- We bought the house from you.
- Okay?
And...
Well, I heard what happened to you.
Ever since we moved in,
strange things have been happening.
So, what do you want?
I think it could have something to do
with what happened to Kim.
What happened was that my wife
became mentally ill.
She had these crazy notions...
about the house next door,
saying it was...
it was...
What did she say about the house?
She said there was something
in that house that wanted Kim.
I have to talk to her.
Can you please ask her to call me?
Please.
- Hey. Where were you?
- Hey.
I went to see the guy
we bought the house from.
Things happened to the family
that lived here before us, too.
I talked to Robban
and I quit the project.
They can find someone else.
I just need to go back
to tie up some loose ends.
I'll be home tomorrow.
Okay, I'll call you later.
You know the little boy
that you play with...
is his name Kim?
What does he want, Lucas? Do you know?
He wants to play.
And he's nice.
Okay.
But he's afraid of the bogeyman.
He doesn't want
the bogeyman to get me, too.
Come here.
Look at me.
No one is going to hurt you.
Please, help me.
Stay here.
Kim?
He...
is...
here!
Lucas!
There you are.
Oh, sweetie! What the hell?
Let me see. Come here.
What the hell happened? Let me see.
What the fuck did you do?
Oh, sweetheart.
- Lucas?
- That's us.
Follow me.
WEDNESDAY, 15 OCTOBER 2014
Lucas...
- Your dad doesn't believe us.
- Stop it.
Don't leave him on his own!
Something is coming for him.
- What the fuck is wrong with you?
- Fredrik, please...
You're scaring him.
You have to believe me!
I know it sounds crazy, but...
No, you sound crazy!
You're the one who's been hurting him.
This is Shirin.
Hello?
Hello. Come on in.
I think I know why you're here.
Do you have kids?
Lucas. He's five.
Kim...
was about to turn six, when...
There's...
there's something in that house.
That something took my daughter.
Kim.
Then who's the little boy who...
That's him.
The one who takes the children.
Fredrik!
- What do you want?
- Where's Lucas?
He's sleeping.
Do you want to play with me?
Come play with me...
Lucas!
Lucas?
That's not him!
Fredrik!
Help!
Lucas! No!
Lucas?
Sleep...
No!
Go to sleep.
Leave him alone.
He belongs to me.
I am not afraid of you.
He already has a mother.
You have never cared about him.
He belongs to me!
It's time for you to go to sleep, too.
Lucas belongs to me.
He's mine. I love him!
You'll never have him!
He's mine!
Lucas?
Lucas! Lucas?
Lucas...
Oh, God!
I'm sorry! I'm so sorry!
Good thing that I have you, my sweet
Good thing that we have us, my sweet
We make each other complete
Every day we get to meet
And be together, you and me
Because no one, I said no one
Wants to be alone
Lucas?
I knew you'd come.