Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
Mon Mon Mon Monsters
Where's the money
Staright A's doesn't mean you can steal
Good skill
Smarty pants my ass
Ｗatch out for me
Ms. Li, please don't expel Lin
Everyone makes mistakes
The important thing is to repent
So let's make him sing a song
Don't look at me
Where's the money?
Ms. Li, I didn't steal it
If you didn't do it
Why is this envelope in your backpack?
I seriously don't know, I didn't do it
Ms. Li, I know
The money must be...
In his shoes
Yes! In his shoes
Take them off
Shoes off
This is your only chance to clear your name
So take off your shoes, quickly
I got it
The money must be in his anus
Pants off
Lin is ridiculous. What a fraud
I don't want to sit next to him
Impressive. What a thief
Lin is in this chat group, right?
Hi thief
Anus wunderkind
Kick him out
I know you didn't steal the money
Everyone
was just
messing with you
Shut up
Who asked you to talk
I just
Hope you don't turn out like me
Piss off!
No one will be like you
Get out!
Fuck off!
Boss, look
Thief
What are you doing here?
You guys are just ridiculous
If the school finds out
All of you will be expelled
The pool has been abandoned for decades
One man's trash, another man's treasure
Why did you guys steal the class fees?
When exactly did you see us steal it?
I knew it
You knew?
You must be a psychic aren't you
Aren't you?
I don't care if you guys steal
Why frame me?
Framed you?
What about now?
What a pervert, Lin
You're a thief and a boobies lover
I'm not
GOT CHA
Hang in there
Don't die on us, Lin
You know why we steal the money?
Cause I want to tune my bike
And I want to gas it up
You only think of yourself
If we didn't steal the money
We couldn't prank you
And you wouldn't be able
to touch my girl's boobs
What a shame
Lin
Hear me out
No one comes here since
they say it's spooked
But we've been smoking here for 2 years
I can't see no fucking ghosts here
Can I bury you alive here later?
If you can
Come haunt me as a ghost
Please do your best
You have to turn into a ghost and find me
I freaking want to see a ghost
Dying to see one
Please turn into a ghost
Come haunt my ass
Oh you know what?
Just turn into a Pokemon ghost
I'll get your ass again in my phone
Find out how high your CP is
I don't know
what happened between you guys
But something must've happened
Now that your snitching behind their backs
If your classmates find out
They will be very unhappy
Have you ever thought about that?
This is how karma works
But I didn't do anything wrong
Lin, in addition to studying at school
Relationships are important too
I know it's difficult
But have you ever wondered
Why it's you instead of someone else?
But they almost poked my eye out
Stop looking
Look at your test sheet
What are you looking at?
Start looking at your books
You said you didn't steal the money
Then do you have proof that they stole it?
This is a recording without video
Maybe you were the one to hit them first
Maybe you appeared to be taunting them
I think they deserve a chance
to explain themselves
Or would you like to seize this opportunity to
make things better with them?
(Boobies-lover)
Class
After Lin stole the class fees last time
He has been self-reflecting
So I would like to give him a chance
to redeem himself
Anyone want to help him complete
community service assignment?
Ren-hao
Yes
Guo-feng
Wei-zhu
You three are quite the celebrities
Complete this assignment with him
I think it will be extra meaningful
Far out! Ms. Li
How do you know I'm so kind-hearted?
Return to your seat
(Boobies-lover)
Keep up
Hurry
Boobies-lover
Hurry up
Go faster
Boobies-lover, hurry up
Welcome to the gang
What are you doing?
-What the hell -Let me do it
Uh-uh
Won't you all have bad karma for doing this?
We're going to be old too
We just have to die before we're old
GO
(Gaara)
Assignment time
Li Rong-feng
Time to eat
Rong-feng
Fuck! It stinks
Let's clean this shit up
It's so freaking dirty
Let's clean it out first
You're so into it
Boss
Switch
NRA's 29th Army Broadswords
A Broadsword
That's sick
Check out my broadsword skills
Thanks broadsword boss
So what if he's killed
Heros eventually turn into old farts
What's that?
Boss, check it out
I've heard that old veterans brought
a lot of gold
when they came from China
Stop it
Old vet, where are the keys?
Keys
Where are the keys? Old man
Where are they?
Give me the keys...
I think that safe must have bars of gold
Let's steal it
But it has a thick chain
I have hydraulic shears
Hydraulic shears to chop off your penis
Do you have a welding torch?
I have to check
Let's assmeble at 1:30 am
Let's make it 2, right here
Bring the stuff
Okay
What for?
Just shut up and come
You talk too much
Keep your mouth shut
2 am
What was that?
Dogs
You sure?
Yes, shut up
Boss
I really want to fart
Shut the fuck up
Guo-feng
I told you to bring hydraulic shears
What's with the shovel?
Digging your own grave?
Might come in handy
Lin
Didn't you say you had a welding torch?
I said that I had to look around
Idiot
I gave you a chance to step up and be a pal
I got it
A blowtorch
I was just going to say...
That's a blowlamp for barbeques
Isn't it a welding torch?
How did I end up with you three idiots
Wait up
What's up
What?
Go
Hurry
Fuck! Old fart
Never mind him! Move
Boobies-lover, watch the door
Watch the door
Move your ass
C'mon, let's go
Boss, want me to burn
it with the welding torch?
That's a blowlamp for barbeques
not a welding torch
What the hell?
Idiot, let me do it
Keep it down
Don't take pictures
What if we get a ghost on photo?
We won't
Boss, don't saw it open
Saw it right here
Hurry up
Li Rong-feng
Dumbass
Have an orange
You old fart
Come to the orange
Here, eat your orange
Come here
Have an orange
C'mon, have an orange
Li Rong-feng
You sure there's gold in here? It's real heavy
Let's settle things later
It'll suck if those aren't gold bars
Shut the fuck up
Should we split the earnings by 3 or 4?
I told you we'll talk later
By 4! I'm part of this too
Quiet we'll settle things later
Wait a sec
What is it
Did you hear that?
It's the sound of
my heart beat
-WTF -You retard
Wait a sec
Now what
I heard something
What
Run
Why is it still on?
I can't mute this shit
Switch hands
It's really heavy
Switch
Fuck! What the hell?
This is a kid, right?
Should we call the cops?
Idiot we're not calling the cops
What do we do?
Let's get out of here
Let's bounce
We can't
Fuck
Boss
Should we electrocute it?
Electrocute with what exactly?
You really are an idiot aren't you?
Hey boss
What the hell are we doing?
Why did we bring this thing here?
Idiot
If we left it there
The cops would bust
us using the security footage
If it dies, we bury the body
We didn't kill it anyways
You are right
But that swing of yours
What swing?
Do you want to get hit by a car?
I can dig one hole here
And I can dig two
Did you see that?
See what?
I think it's afraid of light
Yeah! Lights
Afraid of light
What?
Our Father! Show your powers!
Fuck. For real?
Give me that
Life doesn't have to be that long
Class, you may nap as long as you want
Napping is good
Napping is great
Anyone wants
to know the answer to this question?
You want to know?
Are you messing with me?
All you do is sleep in class
What are you really up to?
I give up
This is what you call a kidnap
Bingo! It is a kidnap!
Kidnapping
But boss, she doesn't look hungry
Idiot, can't you see
She eats humans, not lunch boxes
Humans
Wei-zhu
You guys are sick
Why capture this thing?
Owning a monster is awesome
It's not a human being
We do whatever we want
But how long will we keep it locked up here?
Until
I know what to do with it
Don't be afraid
They'll let you go once they're finished
Boobies-lover, are you ready?
Quickly
Hold on
Here, let's give you an upgrade
You're more used to be bullied, aren't you?
Hang on
Fuck
That's some dark blood
Will it grow back if we yank it?
Monsters' bodies can regenerate all the time
Like in the movies
If it grows back
We'll yank it again
And again
And
AGAIN
Quick, give me a bottle
I'm going to use them as beads
Do whatever you like with it
The Wall that rises, the sands that flow
Are what help me grow
Though the road is long
All I do is go
I'm just a Chinese camel
Broadswords
29th Army
Squad leader
Li Rong-feng
Foul beast
Name and rank
Jesus Chris
People have gone missing
They say this place is haunted!
Haunted!
You old vet, why are you still awake?
Singing some dead-old song
Talking about camels
Camels! What about camels?
Go to the fucking zoo
Where are your morals?
Who the heck you want to scare
with that big old knife
You old prick with Alzheimer's
Give us a break will you?
Heaven and Earth
Doesn't work
If a man find a damsel
That is a virgin
Which is not betrothed
and lay hold on her, and lie with her...
He that is wounded in the stones
or hath his privy member cut off
Shall not enter into
the congregation of the LORD
You suck
It's not afraid of silver
the bible or my middle finger
It's not an vampire
It isn't a zombie
It isn't human, either
You should thank this thing
Why's that?
If we didn't capture it
You would be up there
Me? But it's tied in scripture
You'll be tied in pornos, right?
Anyways, if it were you instead of it
I'll definitely be more creative
C'mon show your appreciation
Thank you
Fuck! For real?
We caught it together
You have 1/4 of the shares
I mean 1/5
Let me see
Why can't I see any red blood cells
That's because
There aren't any red blood cells
Those black dots
look like eggs
Eggs?
Eggs or spores perhaps
What are these?
(Center for Missing Persons)
(Lin Shiu-jen)
(Double homicide)
(Voodoo Master Dies Tragically)
(Voodoo Master)
(Conjuring poisons to kill for money)
(Conjuring them within female bodies)
(and extracting during menstruation)
What are you trying to say?
It's a girl!
What was this thing before
I don't know
But now
She's a monster
Boss, does this make us more cruel
than Cersei Lannister?
Who's Cersei Lannister?
The queen who killed her sons
Which son?
All of them
So why did we capture her?
Don't know if those Yankees at NASA
are into this stuff
Or are they just into ETs
Please! We're only high schoolers
We can' t be the only ones
who caught a monster like this
There must be plenty in America
Who knows
If boobies-lover's research is real
It's a Chinese monster
Poisoned by voodoos
FBI might not have any
So we should sell it to the FBI
We can't sell it, okay?
Why are we doing this?
Eventually she'll starve to death
True, if she doesn't eat any humans
She will die soon
Then who will we feed her
Yeah, who?
Yeah, who should be the one?
Let's vote and see
Okay, voting sounds good
Very democratic
Fine
Hello students
This is nurse Angela
Today,let's learn how to draw blood
Where is this from?
It looks so dodgy
Was it home-made?
It looks fine
This has the highest views
Totally trust-worthy
Why do I have to feed her?
Because you're the most caring person
Unless you want to see her starve to death
With that much blood in you
Draw some out is healthy
Exactly
I read on the internet
People who donate blood
have better metabolism
If you want to treat her well
Then take action
Stop moving
I didn't move
Don't move, I'm aiming
Stay still, or you do it yourself
Fine, I'll do it myself
No! Let me do it
I've always wanted to be Doctor Black Jack
I've never been afraid of blood
No! Please let me do it
I've never been able to do anything right
Please give me this chance
Let me
Move it
I'm developing my hobby
Lunch Time
Drink slowly now
I feel dizzy
If we find another voodoo master
or some person that knows magic
Can we get the voodoo out from you?
Or is it too late
for you to become human again?
What are you doing?
I understand how pitiful all of this is
But if I just let you go
They will kill me
They really will kill me
You've seen what they can do
But be patient
I'll think of a way to get you out
You know
I am helping you, right?
I'm not them
We're different
I'm not like them
What's this?
Blue
Blue, how much is it?
One thousand dollars
Don't take it
Tell the customers that there's no change
No change
Yes, no change, don't take it, remember that
This one here
One hundred dollars
Stop playing with that. Focus
I know what to do
If you see the red one just take it
Tell them to find change themselves
Let them find change themselves
I'll find change
Take what? What will you do with it?
Tell them to take it themselves
I know what to do
Put that back
Or pay for it
Go away
Put it back
Stand up
Attention
Bow
Good morning, Ms.Li
Sit down
Okay
Quiet down
Ren-hao
Yes, Ms. Li
You beat my son this badly
Where are your parents?
Apologize now
Apologize for what?
How will you pay for my son's injuries?
Ren-hao
You're just a piece of shit
Tell your parents to
take responsibility for this
Ren-hao, I don't know
what has gotten into you recently?
But that's okay
It's probably tests from Gods
Here, let me help you
Hands together
Namo Amoghasiddhi
Samantabhadra
Bhaishajyaguru
Amitabha
I know that's Buddha
Watch over disciple Ren-hao
To rid the karma from this life and the past
To rid thousands and Millions of Kalpa
You're funny, Ms. Li
Don't disrespect Buddha
You disrespect the Venerates
and Buddha now
You will go to hell tongue-less
Which hell?
Tounge-less in hell
Stop joking
Stand straight
So disrespectful
Gautama Buddha
Sounds impressive
Samantabhadra
Samanta~
Bhaishajyaguru
Bhaisha~
Stop with the jokes
Stop giggling and stand upright
Samantabhadra
Bhaishajyaguru
Repeat after me
I told you to repeat after me
Did you hear me? Samantabhadra
You better take me seriously
Ren-hao
Tell your dad to meet me tomorrow
I'm going to question him
How he taught a son like this
Who doesn't respect his teachers
With no respect of himself
You piece of crap
Say that again
Ren-hao
I suddenly remembered something
I should apologize to you
It's my bad
Your father can't come
to school tomorrow, yes?
Here's the thing
It's written in his family information
His father is still serving time in prison
I forgot what he was charged with
Drug abuse or robbery?
Or both?
You really can't blame Ren-hao
For becoming a scum like this
It's because of his father
is also a crime-committing social scum
If you really think about it
Maybe he is not his biological father
It's hard to say
Because his mother's occupation is “special”
Which one of those druggies
made her mother pregnant
No one really knows for sure
Ren-hao wasn't taught any manners
He is
Manner-less
Fuck
Bitch
I'm gonna
fucking
kill you
Fuck
Why does everyone have to pour some?
Just asking
What's gonna happen?
Idiot, we won't find out unless we pour it in
That's why we're pouring it in
Don't you want to be a pioneer?
Then let's try it with something else
How about we experiment with you?
Is it going to be like the movies?
If she drinks the monster's blood, she'll...
She'll what?
Turn into a monster
She better turn into a monster
Pei-fen, let's go catch a movie after work
There's a really spicy movie in theaters now
You mean "special"
Yeah, it's a really special movie
The movie's basically about falling in love
Boss
I wanted to
thank you
For what?
For backing me up
Relax, from this day forward,
only I can beat you
I'll beat up
whoever hit you
Why beat me then?
What for?
Because it's fun
It's got the coolest zombies
Werewolves and vampires
I'm going to a monastery
That way we can worship the gods together
And then go to the movies
You don't worship at a monastery
You meditate
Recently when I talked to that
group of students
I almost lost control of them
What a bunch of unspiritual kids
Do you think I should go meditate with you?
Let me take you to the health center
Thank you
Jackpot
Send her to the health center
Get a close up of this
Ms. Li
Buddha
is my BFF
What are you all doing?
Help her
Calm down everyone
HELP HER
What you are seeing now
is an incident at
Tung-Shih Senior High School
A teacher spontaneously combusted
and began massive bleeding
during a school basketball game
she then shortly burned to death
The cause of the fire has yet to be confirmed
Worth noting that all the student witnesses…
What happens when we add some
She better turns into a monster
In the end
We'll turn whoever
we want
into monsters
Capture them all
And pull their teeth out
Shu-wei
You're finally here
To Ms. Li who turned to Burning man
Burning man
Why won't you drink
I don't like drinking
Didn't you drink some last Halloween?
I don't like drinking from cans
I like the bottled kind
You want a bottle?
I have a bottle right here
I mean
Bottled red wine
Here, I got a bottle red wine
There's a bottle
right here
Just a bit left
Drink up
I can't, my parents will kill me if they find out
Brush your teeth then
What? I didn't bring my toothbrush
There's one in the bathroom
There is toothbrush?
It's classy
I don't have any toothpaste
Wait, you want Darlie or Sensodyne?
I don't use any of these
Are you going to drink or what
You think I'm going to burn you up?
I can kill you with a million ways
Why poison you?
Why bring him into all this?
I don't get it
Probably because I have blood
I didn't force you to provide blood
I'd be happy
He'd be happy
to watch her starve to death
You're the one that said no
What you looking at?
If you want to let her go, do it then
Let her go and let her eat you up
You want to be the good guy
You don't have the guts
What are you then?
Find change yourself
100 dollars. Find change yourself
100 dollars
Don't you know I'm scamming you?
Why do you believe in people so easily?
Let me tell you
There are no good people here,
only bad people
Or retards like you
-100 dollars -You
You retard, don't you understand
100 dollars find change yourself
Don't you understand
Find change yourself
100 dollars
You retard
100 dollars, find change yourself
The money's on the floor
I heard dogs chewed out this body all night
This is the seventh time this month
You guys always talk about another monster
She probably saw the news
and found out her partner's missing
Thinks one of the school's students did it
So what?
The monster doesn't know who exactly
kidnapped her companion
Am I right?
Okay
Have you guys had enough?
Burn her up already
Boobies-lover has a lot of blood
We'll burn her when he is out of blood
(Multiple Tong-Shih High School
Students Dismembered)
(Suspect Still At Bay)
I'm the one who sent you the note
at cram school
You said don't jerk-off in class
I was very pissed
Because I really was jerking off
But I swear I didn't finish
Because it would smell
I'm not a pervert after all
Because I love you
What do you want to drink?
I want a cup of watermelon juice
Extra large
What the fuck?
Bloody hell, crazy motherfucker
Hey what do you want?
Ma'am, one extra large cup
of watermelon juice
What the hell do you want?
S-I-S-T-E-R
Ready?
That monster
Will definitely go back
to where they were separated
Anything?
Yes
She responded
You two
Take this path
Boobies-lover
Take this one
I'll take this one
Which ever route she takes
The little one's blood will draw her here
Right here
We'll kill her right here
She must be able to smell
Therefore we can't douse the little one
in gas first
Put the gasoline in the water tank
Wei-zhu, you hide in there
Signal us when the monster comes
Seal off all the exits
Make her come through here
Boobies-lover
Lock the door once she's in there
Guo-feng
You'll open the water tank
And pour the gasoline in
And the boss will light it up
Boom
“Like shooting shrimp in a barrel”
What if
She doesn't show up
She will
I'm the slowest one here
What if I don't close the door quick enough
If so then the monster will kill you
I think the fastest person should
close the door
Let's vote then
Raise your hand if you want me to do it
Those who want boobies-lover
raise your hand
What if
the monster happens to
see me first?
What do I do?
Then you're so doomed
I'm sure that you know
What we've done these few days
I've got this
After your sister unchains you
You can jump out from here
You should know
I've been such a loser
But
I want to get this last thing right
(15 minutes to sunset)
Fuck! You've got balls
The boss called it
The bigger monster
would go back to where she lost the little one
(The app says daybreaks in 15 minutes)
Wei-zhu
What
Can I switch with you?
Didn't we vote on this?
Go back
When I was running back and forth
I happened to sprain my ankle
I want to switch with you
Can't you see I'll freak out too
Stop messing around
Aren't we friends?
Will you send your friend to hell?
What do you want?
Back then
Why framed me for stealing the class fees?
What's the point of talking about this
Just for fun
(She is here)
C'mon
Show yourself
Open the door
This was not the plan
Of course this wasn't the plan
We are not friends at all
We are friends! We're bros
Bullshit
You guys will torture me to death one day
Then why help the monster?
That thing eats people
So what if she eats people?
Bullying the monster
Won't make us saints
It will only make us worse
Open the door
You can kill me in a hundred ways
Now
Is my only shot to kill you
You know that you and me
we're on the same side
You'll tell your sister not to kill me right?
You know
Tell me that you know
I'm not like them
I am here to save your sister
Otherwise she would've died
I'm not like them
I fed her blood
I'm the good guy
Save me
100 dollars. Find change yourself
Find change yourself
You're not like us