child
come to me
come to mom
hurry up
come to me
baby come to me
everyone sing
Love each other, friends, don't hate friends
only one life
Let's go on a voyage
love it friend
be happy, my friend
Is the tape stuck?
Do you want me to unravel it for you?
no need
I'll do it in a while
Or use MP3
Who still listens to the Walkman now?
It's all going to be broken by you.
try this
delicious
good to eat
that
what did you do last night
why are you sleeping
Hey
Did you sleep with Jae Hyun last night?
is not it
what to say
I was right
say no
look in my eyes
definitely did
do not talk
I know I won't say it
happy
all night - really
I really don't talk
really don't say
don't care don't
That guy has been like that since the beginning
that pervert
where is this
my neck
Have you gone the wrong way - where is this?
where is this
It doesn't feel like it's here
Nothing at all
Is the director here?
The sightseeing bus fell under the bridge
Bodies found one after another in damaged bus
The windows have been shattered and there are luggage and vehicle wreckage everywhere
The condition of the damaged vehicle can be seen at the time of the accident
A bus that fell from a twenty-one-meter-high cliff
It's been damaged beyond recognition
Thirty-six employees of the group building of the company were in the car
When the bus goes downhill
Hit the guardrail and fell into the river
This is because the slope of the slope is too steep
woke up too early
do not be afraid
nothing will happen
my my child
I have a baby in my belly
I know
is a girl
This kid will have a brother
will be twins
The twins will also have numerous siblings
we will make it
what do you mean
Girl it looks like you really don't know who you are
Or are you pretending it?
It's ok
you may not know
we are with you
Auntie lives in a good place
really not bad
what is that
Where did that come from?
It's like this when you come to the old lady's house
general manager
The view here is really great
How did you find this place
I should have come over more often to say hello
I shouldn't have seen you for so long
You must be busy with so many new jobs
It's ok
I drew so many pictures
This is all drawn by you, the chief executive, right?
Why don't you have a solo exhibition?
It's a pity to leave ashes like that.
I heard there was an accident in the lab
Yes this morning
You speak too candidly
Could it be something wrong with the headquarters?
Yes
Something went wrong at the lab headquarters
no
not a small problem
It was the headquarters that was breached
Talking about these headaches to you who are taking a back seat
It's really inappropriate
but you used to be in charge
Some things still need to be known
who will do it
It won't be related to the problems of the previous generation, right?
how do you know
Chief, your bad taste is still the same as always.
you are right
After this group of garbage destroyed the laboratory, it was scattered all over the place.
Chief, aren't you curious about that?
who put those dolls out
what's their purpose
Only a few people inside the consortium know about the existence of the laboratory
There are only two organizations I can think of right now
transhumanist organization
And the alliance
so not on our side
It's on your side, the chief executive.
right
Anyone who investigates will find out right away.
no
We don't have time to take a slow look at our current situation
Although broken
But from our standpoint
It is broken from the inside, not from the outside
what do you mean
Yes
that child is lost
Not abandoned but lost?
yes lost
went out by himself
it's over
what's the matter with you
where are you going
Want to give you a ride
Why don't you answer when you ask questions?
What are you doing, get in the car
what are you doing
what are you gonna do
She has nothing to do with this, why bring her
are you a humanitarian
Now is not the time to worry about others
We might bury you
how to leave witnesses
We are very strict
How can she be so virtuous
Is the blood on her real?
Brother seems to be blood
what is she doing
Stop playing and let her go
she sees nothing
you are so noisy
she saw the car
I must have seen the license plate number.
stop bullshitting
Can you see it instead?
Not always
41 River 0115
did you really see it
how did you see
what else did you see
010－7562－3905
No. 702, Building 309, Zhushi Building
It doesn't matter, big brother, this is a set car
who are you
live here
The stinky boy asks you something
what are you doing
Stop playing and let her go
Shut up, stinky lady
Visit MovieHAB.com
you bastards
Don't bully innocent children
Smelly lady shut up and give me some peace
what the hell are you doing
how is this virtuous
Be honest with me, little brat
open
what the hell is this girl doing
Not the lunatic who lives here
Dude seems really crazy
right
Is she wearing a mental hospital outfit?
let me go
don't want
stop
do not do that
no more
Hello, this is 119, what help do you need?
please speak
Hey
Is there a problem
please speak
Hey
Hello
We'll send someone over, please don't hang up
follow me
uh uncle
Just a short walk from there
An ambulance passed in front of me just now
It's not that way, it's the second way
Hmm, that seems to be the one
wait a minute i'm out
uncle
It's not Kyung Hee, who did this?
Is Long Dou that bastard again?
Uncle, we have to hurry up, hurry up, hurry up
walk
But who is she
that
Seems to be seriously injured
nosebleed
that that
child
i really am
uncle fast
what is this
are you okay
Get in the car now
well
Really are
Kyunghee
Um
how are you feeling
I'm fine
But Long Dou is a bastard
Now blatantly killing people
That bastard should have a grudge
How long has your dad been dead?
Haven't taken that land yet
Resort bid is already in sight
words like that
Competitors are also to those shareholders
No face in front of them
how is that kid
That's what she said
It's that kind of weird
It doesn't feel so strange
what
Shouldn't it be fine?
No matter how amateur this uncle is
I used to be the one who flew all over the street.
I used this hand to save your dad many times when I was a kid
But don't you need to call the police?
Her wounds are also unusual
I always feel like a girl with a story
So I'm more afraid of calling the police
That's true
It doesn't do us any good to have dealings with the police.
And it's hard to explain
During this time, I will take care of her until her injury improves.
Well just do that
Captain, are you all right?
Why are there gunshots again?
Gan scare me this bastard
I can hear you speak softly
How many times have you said that you dog Keiko
How good are the headphones now?
I'm smoking now
Call the cleaners in and clean up
not captain
do you do this every time
Acting alone like this will really kill you
do you want to die
why didn't you wait for me
Do you have to act alone without backup every time?
Then you can't hurry up, kid
Shouldn't it be dealt with before the regular believers come?
what
Isn't that the gathering time you gave, Captain?
Shut up and drive your car
No, this bastard is so noisy
what to say
Are you scolding me now
Are you scolding me, why are you suddenly using Korean?
What's wrong with Koreans speaking Korean?
didn't say anything just said you were noisy
Why are you still holding that manual?
Where's the tablet I bought for you?
Never mind I like the analog age
I don't like front-end stuff
Then give that back to me if you don't need it
That's the latest
this bastard really is
You are so childish, you gave it to me, and I want to go back
And I am using
Where is it used I haven't seen you use it
What happened to Netflix when lying down before going to bed?
Use such an expensive thing to brush Netflix
Is it okay to use it for his purpose?
Shut up and go, asshole
I can't believe this dog is really
did you do it on purpose
dog Keiko
Is that dirty talk?
swear words
yes it's dirty words
scold me again
Yet again
Gan slams on the accelerator again
You're such a dirty talker
Hey I told you don't drink it to your mouth
what to do with the cup
It should be used when my sister is drinking.
kid
why do you look like this
Is it that boy Long Dou?
it doesn't matter
He is my brother brother brother
no problem, no problem
don't do that
let go of my boy
you boy
It looks fine
But who is she
It's my sister, the sister I know
Will be staying at our house soon
How long have you been in Korea
Have you met a sister so soon?
I didn't realize that you were a social cow.
It's just a social cow
Did the boy eat?
prepare dinner for you too
rude boy
Going to prepare dinner
what's wrong?
It's not that I don't have an appetite, it's not delicious
This kid is really
Then don't eat it, boy
Even if it doesn't taste good, you still put the food in your mouth.
Is it because of the taste?
just eat hard to survive
I'm really this kid
pain
Of course it hurts you to beat your boy
You kid has been to your sister recently
talk back boy
step on the nose
I said it hurts don't do this
do not do that
why not
Can't you say bad food?
Just warm up the quick meal
Soup is also bought in the supermarket
you need to be cleaned up today
you rude boy
don't talk back boy
don't do this what are you doing
let go boy
I said don't do it
you are now
did you just push me
I asked if you had pounced on your sister
really annoying
what
When did you say you hate this house and run out?
came back after my father died
What do you say every day, sister
you know how funny you are
Obviously you said you hated running away from this house
I said I didn't want to see my father and left.
our dad's place
When did you care so much about dad?
When did this start to be your home?
This is the room where I lived as a child
you live
Visit MovieHAB.com to support us
should be about the same
you wear it
Put on comfortable clothes and sleep
then rest
Let me know if you need it
that
i forgot to thank you
Thank you
I survived thanks to you
have a rest
rest
Subject's official name is Laboratory Data Point
On the record, it is written as ADP for convenience
is going to be an advancement for more than 40 years
Benchmarks for this project for kids
That's what my sister and the transhumanists wanted
full model
Those who successfully recovered the body they were looking for a long time ago
Separate the crystals that grow in the body
try to copy
One of them is this kid
What is Goo Ja Yoon's whereabouts still unknown?
I only know that after leaving here
Appeared in the last lab last month
The manager let go of the child he found
It actually surprised me a bit
She is stronger than I expected
But Zi Yun was also traumatized here.
So it should be impossible to act for a while
And she has weaknesses
Her brain needs to be drug dependent
She alone can't do us much power
But this kid is different, right?
I don't know what kind of monster
This is always overflowing in this world
must be removed
If this agency knew
Either the manager or I will be screwed
Probably will break our brains apart
used as experimental base
understand what you mean
Just use this to pay off my 10-year-old debt.
I'm leaving
Just in case there are chips implanted in lab kids
brain state
There is also a location
will help you find her
But this one seems broken
how to use
would you use this
what
That's almost broken
stop licking
dirty
Captain but can we do this
I mean
The performance is not good, and he still engages in non-formal activities
And that thing seems to be the main asset of the company
what's wrong
No
then you go home
Oh, why are you so disgusted? Don't you worry?
Did you hear what Mr. Bai just said?
And the kids in the lab
I contacted 10 years ago I know
they are cruel monsters
not even that
Do not talk nonsense
Grab them, they're getting in the way
right they are
Follow us since we came to Korea
so what
catch it now
Wait a moment
what's the situation
Seems to be a local dignitary
First everyone calm down
don't make trouble
I didn't know you were employees here
Let's talk first
look at me hello nice to meet you
what to say
Oops, this greeting is a bit harsh.
does it have to be like this
Enough is enough
I told your boss to let him come see me
There is a bus card, there is a bus stop in front of it
Let's go back
If you want to say something, just say it
But does our captain know their boss?
very cooked
Is that the boss before the captain?
Yes
As of ten years ago
it was a long time ago
fortunately
yes luckily
But why do you say that all of a sudden
Um
That's right
why
don't you like men
Yes
So I
what you bastard
bastard
you scold me again
Too much swearing in Korean
Gan, don't always sneak around and don't use honorifics with me
me
yes it's you
no absolutely no
It should be the reason why you are in a bad mood, Captain.
so where are we going now
Wait for this signal
open until signal
wow really original
Do you know how big this island is?
Do not you know
heard clearly
The area alone is 1833.2 square kilometers
It's like looking for a needle in a haystack, you know?
Are you listening to me now?
child
come to mom
hurry up
The smell of cow dung
Gotta get this down asap
Oh, is that Kyunghee?
long time no see
I'm Uncle Long Dou
remember me
stand there and don't move
hello that
Is it the gun your dad used to hunt with?
you should keep it at the police station
Can't just leave it at home
that's illegal
By the way, you are from America.
America
Anyway, that's where guns are rife, isn't it?
But where did everyone else go?
Why are you the only one holding that thing up your throat?
What are you talking about?
what to wear
My four men are now semi-crippled
life is in danger
My subordinates are clamoring to call the police
It's uncle, I managed to stop it
Hey, are Kyunghee and us outsiders?
Family matters have to be settled between the family
Can't involve outsiders
That can't be done, you know?
say
your amazing dad
Didn't I teach you this?
I'm asking you
Alright alright
Okay now that we've said that
So let's talk a little bit of a heartfelt thing today.
say what
I have nothing to say to you
hey, you have that style
To shut up
But have you ever shot someone?
let's go
do not come
I tell you not to come
Did you hear me
gan scare me
Tian - bring it here
let go of me asshole
- be honest - let me go
I ask you to let me go
scares me
Gan you gang of dogs Keizi
Gangou Keiko
who is this kid
Who are you, stinky boy - Daji
get off the bastard
don't hit my brother
Dog Keiko
hello
what kind of baseball player are you
don't hit him
don't touch my brother
no one in there brother
what really nobody
Ouch
It seems that we, Kyunghee, really didn't take my uncle seriously.
You just rely on this gun
Did you get all those bastards out?
What the hell have you been talking about?
okay
After all, I am very loyal to Brother Zhehao.
It's like nothing happened between our kids
It's all in the past anyway, what can I do?
So just obediently sign the contract.
or by handprint
Not what the hell are you trying to do here
Whether to raise cattle or sheep
Besides, did I let you give it to me for nothing?
I will give you a little more than the market price
Just take this money and go to Seoul
How about going for a walk and talking about love?
Then have a good life with the younger brothers
Parents are gone now
You have to take good care of your brother from now on, don't you?
Zhao family
I won't give it to you even if I die
How many times do you want me to say
Hey
I told you so much
Why don't you give a sincere answer?
why are you so bold
your dad is dead
But what's going on now
are you denying reality
I know
my dad is dead
didn't you kill it?
You killed my dad dog Keiko
I endure you for a while, but I keep my mouth shut
seal her mouth to me
Looks like she's going to be beaten
Gan tell the truth
As long as her fingerprints are intact
Don't hit you puppies
Gan let me go
Dog Keiko
good luck
no no no
- Good luck - Gan
stand up brat
come over come come over
come over
brat
This stinky boy is really on fire
Do you have to be beaten to cheer up?
Say it - don't move brat
what are you talking about, sir
where are you looking
Gan scared me to death
who is she
it's dangerous
down
come down be careful
feed down
how did she get up
Why are kids so daring lately?
hey hey - crazy woman
Dangerous fall
what is she doing
Why are you holding her back for a while?
hey hey come down
what's the situation
acrobatics?
what are you doing
did you just see
what is that...
Gan, are you here to visit?
Think of a way now, scumbags
don't come
do not come
go away
go away go away
never mind
Forget it
I'm all right
so stop fighting
move
don't come again
Do you understand
I cheer you up
Take your men to the hospital now
cheer up brat
ok i'll cheer up
hurry up
Get out, get out
Does it hurt or not, are you alright?
sister
who is she
what did i just see
calm down
Actually, she doesn't know.
look at her
what
Is she really an alien?
really not covered
Wasn't that just a scene from a movie?
how did you know her
Gan is great
It's amazing
how long will she stay in our house
can i talk to her
Do you want to shoot a video and send it to youtube?
sure to make money
what are you doing
not you
No. . . are you alright
Are you sure you're all right, brat
pain
this is how many
what are you doing
answer me brat
Sister, don't do this
Can you introduce her to me again?
You really have to get along with that kind of person.
Gan is awesome
oh who is this
Isn't this our Sergeant Zhao?
haven't seen you for a long time
This is pretty decent
I thought it was thrown somewhere
Seems to have some conscience
Is it because of faith?
Well, because I also have faith
And you can't just throw it away
It will pollute the environment
we should love the earth
Your face is still as good as ever
Still so handsome
You also know that this kind of thing is innate
you are still handsome
Still looking so sharp
Forget about the past years
what
okay
then don't mention it
Okay, say something else
why did you come back suddenly
I thought you would never come back
You know what to ask
Of course I know it was Mr. Bai who called you back.
But why did you come back
how
Is it because of that thing
Director Bai, that big Ting
Since it has been relegated to the second line
Then just wait
Why are you doing this?
Could it be that something is wrong?
Is that Da Ting
Are you doubting me?
Gan really speechless
How dare this goddamn hag doubt me
Feed that stinky girl
The last person to find is Director Bai, right?
After that, it silently evaporated
do you think that's all
Goo Ja-yoon ransacked Hoffen Glass and Bangkok laboratory
Before coming to Jeju Island
In the end, they also ransacked the Shanghai laboratory, you should know that
Advanced Experiments there
The dolls are all gone
Plus this time the lab headquarters was stolen
How dare you doubt that I am for real
Hey, just get out of the way
If you have anything to do with that Dating
no good for you
I don't care about the group of that company
how to fight behind the scenes
I'll figure it out, don't get in my way
If I keep looking for people to follow me, if it gets in my way
Then I won't sit back and watch
Oh, you are really
Saying it savagely
let's go let's not meet again
Now they really go their separate ways
hello zhao xian
hey stinky girl
It's been ten years since we met
Are you really going to leave like this?
Otherwise, what do you want to do?
Is it possible to talk about what happened ten years ago?
don't go slow
Be careful on the road and let them turn the car around
This shit is really
soy Mujer
Is it almost there?
Is it near there?
Well, it's almost a little bit soon
This island is not as small as I thought
ah so boring
hey look at this too
Korean shows are funny and interesting
you look at it more
How do you know to watch that all day long?
What's the matter, the stinky lady is going to die, isn't she?
Take good care of your mouth, be careful I tear up your stinky mouth
hey kidding
I won't argue with her anymore
come on
Come and see who wins
Oops what's the matter?
I played a game when I was a kid
Was that childhood?
what do you say?
fight
that... that he
how did he live
The brain was obviously hit by a bullet.
How did you survive until now?
Logically speaking, this level should be completely dead.
Yup?
Do you think I made a mistake?
No no absolutely no!
How can something go wrong, eldest sister?
I did not mean that
I mean
A small fresh meat
For the sake of your cuteness, I'll spare you
That's right
It should be completely cut off.
wait
Come and eat, let's eat
oh so cute
Is it tasty
fell to the ground
What about Embi?
Come
what's the situation
no
not what are you doing
hello quack
stinky old man
are you still seeing a doctor
You are cruelty to animals
and also
Did I say that if you dare to see the underground trade
Say it and drop your hand
did not say did not say
Really lately
Only treat cats and dogs
And it's just medicine
I can't have surgery now
yes?
Then your hands will be useless
dragon fight
Not Boss Zhao
Why do you suddenly do this to me
I won't speak out
really won't tell
be quiet
To shut up
you should have something to say to me
say what
The little one that Kyung Hee brought
The story about that girl
You must have something to say to me alone
Right
Probably the one who is wanted.
looks like yes
Who is the continuous gold lord
have you contacted
Yes, brother got the message
wow interesting
It's so exciting
that's what you see
This is the tubing
they upload videos of eating
keep uploading
If someone clicks in to watch
and has a considerable number of views
then you can get an ad
If you get an advertisement
money will come
If there are many fans
I can earn hundreds of thousands of won every month
hey are you listening
are you listening
Anyway, they make money just by eating.
You only need to completely subvert once
Then we're sure to make a fortune
what is this
Which is this?
noodles
Is it tasty
delicious
shall we eat this
ok let's eat
Aren't you listening carefully to me?
what is this
which
ah hot dog
Next to the pizza
Is it tasty
hey are you listening to me
will we eat this too
I'll buy you a hot dog
I'll give you some pizza later
I asked if you were listening to me
what is this
are you a foodie
why so greedy
Don't fix it, don't fix it
Forget it, don't fix it
stop it
Let's try abalone porridge
discount today
This is a bit hot
Please enjoy
Be careful, eat slowly
hello that. . .
she's finished
gone
Hey
hey hey hey
hey wait
hello uncle
sorry i will do it asap
What a shame, don't eat it
Do you have aliens in your belly?
They say I can eat whatever I want
You can eat it, but you have to eat it in moderation.
Is your planet run like this?
oh, where's my sister
GAMOR Tian
Feeding my sister at Dr. Kar's Uncle's Animal Hospital
Uncle got hurt
sorry i was in a hurry
Let's have dinner first
I'll be there asap
do you want water
Although it's useless now
But it's enough to stick
Kyunghee
I said that kid
Just let it go, not with that kid
While Long Dou hasn't caused any trouble
let the kid out
You have to hand over that land and house, okay?
go back
Daji should be waiting for you
what
Hi
who are you
don't be so scared
chat with us
I'm going really
Where did I say so much?
He can really fly and throw the car out with his bare hands
I'm going really
is a girl
what
I don't know, you guy
about seventeen eighteen
I'm going to do you know her age
Are you going to have a blind date with her?
didn't I say
Just that one girl
okay
I went and bought a few guns
Hey
Visit MovieHAB.com to support us
what's up with this call
Hey
I went to that is a new phone
close the door
But who are you
Who is it?
It's you who contacted us
Ah, that girl in the group is the one
Although it's a bit messy here, you should sit first
let's chat
where is that girl now
If I said you would kill me, wouldn't you?
Do not
isn't it?
If you don't say it, it will kill you
But hurry up, I won't torture you, just kill you
I was going to be like him
Allows you to observe the organs in your body slowly and in detail
kill you again
Haven't you seen your own heart?
right
hmm, haven't seen it
I'm not a heart surgeon
no need to look at those
I couldn't see those
But that
I should be able to make some use of it
there should be
It would be a shame to kill
I don't eat rice
after chatting
should be able to figure out our stakes
isn't it?
tell me
I'll give you a gift
here here here
this this this this
Did you see it? Did you see it?
She is the country girl Goo Ja-yoon
In fact, it's not the song that made it popular with this image
In my opinion, you are not playing on YouTube
Why don't we have this show too?
As long as you go, you should be able to explode like that Gu Ziyun
Hey, you can't eat rice
You eat a lot, don't you?
But I never sang
hey you really
Just go to the karaoke hall and practice hard for a few days.
than this
Except for picking people's joints and throwing the car out
what else would you do
as gentle as her
do something
I'll get you some pizza
It's a different size from the previous one
large?
Can I order fried chicken as a side dish?
I'll give you some pasta
pasta
are you special?
not so funny
laugh so much
what is this
no no feed
stop laughing
what to do
Not that kind
Does that want to be like this?
are you kidding me
right
hey don't do that
let me have a good look
try you try again
Do it well, let me see, let me see
you try
what
i go i go big hair
you are amazing
how did you do it
hey wait a minute
Can't unplug that antenna
Can't pull out the antenna
want to watch tv
put it down, put it down
I go
crazy
very impressive
Did you destroy that star just now?
crazy is it possible?
Ah that's not
But where did you learn that
you are very talented
what what what
It's really that kid
what are you looking at
She's a monster who doesn't know when to mutate
If you don't want your brother to die
Just listen to what I say
Time for everyone to watch
Fireworks are about 30 minutes
If it is not handled well during this period
The movement will attract the attention of the police or ordinary people
things will get bigger
Walk
But the captain
If only take her brother out
will that girl feel weird
What if she catches her running away?
I can only pray that she doesn't find out even for a few minutes
why don't you go
i want to cover the captain
bullshit
Who is covering whom?
there's no need for you to go
team leader
Captain, wait for me to go with you
Put sticky rice balls on top of rice and gulp
What is that
really
so funny
Did she find the captain?
Didn't I say don't talk into my ear?
curse again
curse
I'm going really
I really want to kill you
yes fireworks fireworks
fireworks festival today
what time is it now
it's time
Let's go, let's go take up the land
fireworks?
so pretty
Don't you know that your planet doesn't have one?
Go check it out first, it's really nice
Sister, are you not going?
good luck
What's wrong
let go of her hand
coming out soon ready
When you see them coming out, find a good distance and shoot
is the captain
what's wrong with you sister
run away
What did you say so suddenly
sorry
run away
I go
what are those guys doing
Captain look behind
They're from the Shanghai research lab, right?
who are you
Didn't I tell you not to come here again? Why are you here again?
Oh, yes
We Kyunghee took out that long pole again.
But we also have
Can you see what's inside
she's going to the roof
But the boy was with her too
I go
keep distance
come soon
hey can you see there
There is the main road
Can you run there in one go?
go go go
I'm going to my sister, then you go
hello that
will you come back
Come back when things get better
We're going to the karaoke hall
I'll give you pizza every day
we must see you again
where is that girl
Who, what girl
nonsense woman
what
go die
sister sister
sister sister can't
sister sister sister
did you find anything
nothing without captain
Will it be blown up by two missiles?
isn't there either?
no no
but
but what
there are other things
sister sister sister
I'm going I'm so fed up with your family
If there are so many, there will be that kind of child who insists on getting along with me
I'll go to the dragon fight you goddamn bastard
I'm going I'm going to kill you damn bastard with my own hands
why am i sorry for you
did i kill your father
hey do you know why your dad died
He was going to kill me but he died
do you know
I go I have been loyal for 15 years
Did you know that I won these lands with my body?
You do not know
What am I talking about to a little boy?
Okay, let's go with your sister too
hey pain rascal
Get out of here before I get angry
It's not your turn on this occasion
what
as you like
How can you decide for yourself
Why are you ruining my interest?
I went to the captain, did you see it?
She's not in the rank with those before her
hurry up and shoot you guy
I go
dying
Hey
run away
go fast
where the hell
don't make me upset
Captain again
this is new
I'm going really
That's how you keep telling me to cover me
go
This is new
Hey
wow it's you
it's wired
I must have smashed your head into pieces
how did you survive
I'll take your neck off this time
team leader
how are the kids
what are you gonna do
he is normal
good luck
Scared me
I saw
Aren't you scared to pee?
I go to those monsters
quite unexpected
Is it different from before?
That's also a bad breed
one more
you guy
it really hurts
but what use are these to us
what's the situation
She ignores us
really alive
but
Whether it was then or now
She doesn't look that great anyway
is she
where is amazing
you monster
you
finally come
haven't seen you for a long time
don't bother
But did you already know each other?
I understand
how did you meet
She was born living alone at the lab headquarters
she is my sister
I asked you to release my sister
who told you to kill her
Zi Yun
ah they?
I asked them to find you
from Shanghai, China
I was hurt a little
I can't handle it if you mess up
So I'll ask them
But I wasn't sure at first that it was you
you have been bullied by them
My sister can't be like that
So I don't think you're going to go
but here
feel you
Feeling a little rusty all of a sudden
It's also when we're only together when we're in mother's womb
separated at birth
Did you just let me out?
Um
why
because i need you
you need me too
so why
want to see mom
who i heard said
Your consciousness and mother are connected
Mom has been looking for you
she doesn't find me
go with sister
You are too indifferent to your sister you haven't seen for a long time, right?
do you hurt
do you know what that feels like
i want to save them
can also do
But you can't save both
you choose
It's just that no one can be an ordinary human being
Is it okay
Wouldn't it be better to die as a human?
Let's go to mom's place with my sister
Those kids meet after all
Coming soon to find their mother
how to draw like
Then let's get ready
Don't go away! Easter eggs at the end
almost suffocated
they are gone
gone away
team leader
Captain, they're gone
captain captain
Captain wake up
can captain hear me
team leader
What if you die like this?
I go
Hear your voice, those monsters have to come to us
The children were also taken away
what to do
lift me up
let's go
hurry up chasing them
give me your phone
You have memorized my cell phone number
what's wrong
Don't you mean we'll never see you again?
when did you start there
You don't care when I'm here, get to the point
Yes
I never wanted to see you again
But the situation does not allow please support us
Why should I help you don't you doubt me?
really stingy
Are you still calculating these things?
That should also be understood.
So what do you want me to do?
I'm going really
Are you going to keep chatting like this?
Don't hurry up and catch those people.
My phone is new
don’t worry
I know where they're going