In the criminal justice system,
sexually-based offenses
are considered especially heinous
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives who investigate
these vicious felonies are members
of an elite squad known
as The Special Victims Unit.
These are their stories.
My name's Ed
and I'm here to listen to
your problems with empathy,
without judgment or advise.
Go away.
I care about you,
- and I'm sure many others do, too.
- Please leave me alone!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Take it easy.
There's got to be a lot of
folks that would miss you.
No, no one.
What about the baby's father?
You don't understand.
I was raped!
- Name?
- We never got that far.
Is this her room?
No, she came in here
when the maid was cleaning.
I don't even think
she was staying here.
I need everybody out now.
It's cold out here.
I brought you something to drink.
- I can't drink coffee.
- It's just cocoa, okay?
Why don't you take it?
It'll warm up your hands.
I'm just gonna put it
right there, okay?
Here you go.
Thanks.
I'm Olivia.
April.
What's going on, April?
April, have you picked out
a name for your baby?
Sarah.
Sarah was my mom's name.
She died last year.
Breast cancer.
The security guard told you?
Yes.
That's why I'm here.
I'm from the special victims unit.
What if I can't love my baby?
- My baby...
- You chose to keep your baby.
You gave her a beautiful name.
You already love your baby.
- I can't, I can't do this alone.
- Well, you don't have to.
I want you to listen to me.
I'm gonna help you.
I promise you,
I will help you. / How?
We're gonna figure it out together.
Now, will you give me your hand?
No!
It's okay. It's okay.
No.
자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)
싱크편집
윤선영(seedyun@nate.com)
한글번역
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)
크리스 멜로니
(엘리엇 스테이블러 형사 役)
마리스카 하기테이
(올리비아 벤슨 형사 役)
리차드 벨저
(존 먼치 형사 役)
다이안 닐
(케이시 노박 검사 役)
아이스-티
(오다핀 핀 튜튜올라 형사 役)
B.D. 왕
(FBI 정신분석의 조지 황 役)
타마라 튜니
(멜린다 워너 검시관 役)
댄 플로렉
(돈 크레이건 경감 役)
Law & Order SVU
7x02 Design(1)
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON NBC: 2005/09/27
DVD sync by JEREMY 2009
Patient presented as depressed
and tearful upon arrival.
Her name's April. April Troost.
Ran a tox screen on her as well as
a blood alcohol. Both negative.
What about the pregnancy?
She's approximately 35 weeks.
No sign of distress or malnutrition.
- She's good to go.
- You mean give birth.
No. I mean I'm releasing her.
Uh, maybe you missed the part
where she was gonna take a swan dive
off a 20-story building.
Her suicidal ideation has passed,
and she has no history
of prior attempts.
Well, can you guarantee that
she's not gonna climb out
on the ledge tomorrow?
No, of course not.
Then put her on a psych hold
until the baby is born.
I can't do that.
She's not acutely psychotic
or a danger to herself or others.
Hey. Hey!
The baby, baby doesn't count?
Look, she agreed
to outpatient counseling.
My job's done.
I thought I was dealing with the rape.
Until yesterday.
I just snapped.
That happens.
You're not the first person
to go through this.
Everywhere I look,
I see his face.
- Even when I close my eyes.
- Why don't you tell me about him.
We met at a bar
and talked all night.
He offered to walk me home,
and I thought...
finally, a gentleman.
Went to my apartment.
And I remember praying,
"please kiss me good night."
It'd been so long.
That's when he shoved me in
and locked the door.
Why didn't you call the police?
I was a fool.
I actually believed
that he was interested in me.
A nurse's aide.
I barely have my GED.
April, what happened to you
wasn't your fault.
Facing him is gonna help you
deal with this.
I can't.
You gotta be strong for little Sarah.
You're all she has.
And I promise I will help you.
How?
By arresting the man that raped you.
Tell me his name.
Barclay Pallister.
Pallister Labs
43 West 37th Street
Wednesday, March 2
You expect me to remember a woman
I met in a bar eight months ago.
You drank, you laughed,
one thing led to another.
Maybe I'd remember if we'd had sex.
You did, and she's calling it rape.
Yeah, by the way, congratulations.
You're the daddy.
The hell I am.
I didn't have sex with anybody.
I certainly didn't rape anyone.
I'm happily married.
Happy enough for the wife
to alibi you?
I was probably here.
I spend more time in the lab
than I do at home.
No alibi.
Well, maybe she saw my photo
in Forbes or Fortune.
Thought I was an easy target.
All those NBA players out there
and she picked you.
Look, I don't mean to brag but,
women have been crawling
out of the woodwork
ever since my company went public.
What's up with the stiffs?
They're my gold mine.
I invented an eco-friendly method
of turning these cadavers into dust
without ever lighting a match.
My flash-freeze method will
revolutionize mortuary science.
And that gets you laid
like a rock star.
I'd never be unfaithful to my wife.
She stood by me one
failed experiment after another.
So you have no problem
taking a paternity test.
If it's necessary.
But I'm telling you,
the kid isn't mine.
DNA proves it. April Troost's kid
is definitely yours.
But that's impossible.
I didn't touch her.
Immaculate conception's
not gonna hold up in court,
- so why don't you try again?
- All right.
Mr. Pallister admits that
he met the defendant at a bar.
They had drinks,
but he does not remember
having sexual relations with her.
Okay, so you had one too many, you
didn't know what your body was doing.
Intox defense.
That's better.
- I'd know if I raped her.
- You did.
And April Troost has
a swollen belly to prove it.
In light of the DNA results,
we'll stipulate to paternity.
But the sex was consensual.
There was no rape.
Trial Part 15
Tuesday, March 22
I begged him to stop.
But he wouldn't listen.
This was after he bolted the door.
Yes.
He threw me on the floor,
and he pinned me.
I couldn't move.
- Did you scream?
- At the top of my lungs.
But then he covered my mouth
with his hand.
- And I could barely breathe.
- Did you fight him?
I think I scratched his face.
But then he got more violent,
and he put his hands around my neck
like this, and he choked me.
And I thought if I stopped
screaming, then maybe...
maybe he wouldn't kill me.
What happened next?
He raped me.
He raped me over and over and over.
Do we really want to put that
poor woman through any more pain?
What are you offering?
Probation, no jail time,
you and I take the rest
of the afternoon off.
I'd rather work.
15 years. He does it all.
He's a contributing member of society,
and she belongs in a psych ward.
Your own detectives
tried to commit her.
You can't use that.
I can in a custody hearing.
First he denies having sex with her,
now he wants to be father of the year?
It's his baby too.
He'll fight her for it.
Unless she agrees to a plea.
Ready?
- I can't face him again.
- You're already halfway there.
All you have to do
is keep your eyes on me.
Thank you.
Why did you wait eight months
to report the alleged rape?
I was scared.
Confused. Humiliated.
Would you say suicidal?
I wanted to end my life. Yes.
And your baby's?
No.
That's why I couldn't hurt myself.
I love my baby too much.
A love so strong, you're willing to charge
the baby's father with rape?
It's the right thing to do.
And nothing will change your mind?
No.
How about half a million dollars?
You called my office this morning
and said you wanted to settle.
What the hell were you thinking?
That lawyer told me if I lose,
Barclay will take the baby.
He was lying to you.
- I didn't know.
- You sandbagged me.
Now the jury sees you as
a gold digger, not a rape victim.
- I'm sorry. I made a mistake.
- Why didn't you just call me?
Because you'd be mad at me.
You are.
- I can see it in your eyes.
- I'm not mad.
I'm, I'm, I'm disappointed.
How bad is it?
Our only choice is to put you back
on the stand to turn down the settlement.
I'll recall you tomorrow,
and you can testify again.
I will do anything
to set things right.
Trial Part 15
Wednesday, March 23
My court starts at 9 sharp, Ms. Novak.
Where's your witness?
I'm sure she's just delayed, your honor.
We've been waiting 40 minutes.
She's made her decision.
She wants to settle.
She had every intention
of testifying today.
If I could just have
a brief continuance.
Miss Troost has obviously
changed her mind.
I'm not gonna keep that jury
waiting any longer.
Your honor, I have
detective Stabler on the line.
Highway police just found miss Troost.
She was traveling eastbound,
missed the curve,
- and ran off the cliff right here.
- No guardrail?
I bet they'll find
the money for one after this.
The gas tank burst
into flames on impact.
No survivors.
What time?
Fire department got the call
around 5 this morning.
They said it'd been burning
for quite a while.
She probably fell asleep at the wheel.
I think you'll find
it's a suicide.
Liv, there's nothing
you could've done.
I was angry, and I let it show.
You got pissed off
because she lied to you.
She needed somebody to believe in her.
The trial can still go on
without April, can't it?
What's the point?
I'm offering Barclay a deal.
He raped her and
he left her with a child.
The jury knows that he did it.
The jury's going to acquit.
Last two words they heard
were cash settlement.
Which she was about to turn down.
Unless she says so on the stand,
it's inadmissible.
So we just let Barclay walk?
Find me some evidence she was
gonna turn down the settlement,
and I'll use it to bluff
Barclay into a plea.
Apartment of April Troost
104 East 16th Street
Wednesday, March 23
There's no suicide note, no diary.
Nothing on her email.
No documents relating to the settlement.
Just bills.
Sofa's wet.
What's with the white crust?
Hydrogen peroxide.
Foams up when it comes
into contact with blood cells.
Bubbles dry and leaves
this white crust.
Well, check out the wall.
See these smears?
Tried to wipe off the blood.
And on the floor.
No body, but this is
definitely a crime scene.
I'd say we have a homicide.
Perp kills April here,
stuffs her body in the car,
and sends it over the cliff.
I figured out how
the crash was rigged.
- Looks like a paint mixing can.
- Similar.
But these are used
to store chemicals in labs.
- Like Barclay Pallister's.
- It was thrown from the car on impact.
See the angle of these dents?
They're consistent with the pail
being wedged under the dash
when the pedal's to the metal.
I found more evidence up there.
See these tire marks in the pavement?
Wheels spun in place.
He wedged in the can,
and revved the engine.
Shift the car into drive,
it takes off like a rocket.
Kills April in her apartment,
stages the crash here.
With her history, Barclay
knew we'd rule it a suicide.
Her body burns up so no one ever
knows what he did to her.
I sent everything from the car's
interior over to the morgue.
Maybe Warner can piece together
how she died.
This is all that survived the fire.
Not very much.
Fire marshal says
an accelerant was used,
probably gasoline,
to enhance the burn.
Smart guy, he wanted to make sure
we didn't find a body.
I didn't.
You mean it was incinerated?
No, I mean, there wasn't
one in that car.
Body burns, you always find something.
Partial long bones, dental fillings.
Son of a bitch used
his technology to vaporize her.
He had to have access
to her home and her car.
Maybe, maybe somebody
saw him with her.
April keep her car in a garage?
She parks it on the street.
Poor Ms. Troost.
She's such a sweet lady.
- Were you the doorman last night?
- Until 11.
- Who relieved you?
- No one.
After I leave, visitors
have to be buzzed in.
Well, how about security cameras,
surveillance video?
Management's too cheap.
When I retire in August,
won't even be a day guy
on the door anymore.
When is the last time
you saw April Troost?
Well, she came home
from a dinner date around 10.
You sure it was a date?
She was all dolled up.
She went to Luigi's,
which is kinda romantic.
How do you know what restaurant?
She brought me a doggie bag.
Nice T-bone for my rottweiler.
Of course I remember her.
She special ordered.
No garlic because of the baby.
Maybe she was hoping
for a good night kiss.
I don't think so.
They barely spoke the whole meal.
- What did he look like?
- Tall.
And from his black American
express card, very rich.
You get a copy of the receipt?
Should be behind the bar somewhere.
Uh, how was she acting?
Pretty upset.
Before dessert, she yelled
at him and stormed out.
Do you know why?
I figured it was the hormones.
Here it is.
Barclay Pallister.
Pallister Residence
135 East 84th Street
Thursday, March 24
This is sour grapes.
You had to dismiss the rape case,
so you're trying to pin
a homicide on an innocent man.
The only reason that we lost
the rape case is,
because your client killed
April Troost.
Kind of hard to kill someone
in a crowded restaurant.
But easy at her apartment.
I never went to her apartment.
- Where'd you go after Luigi's?
- Straight home.
Will your wife vouch for that?
She left me after you
charged me with rape.
Well, if the screw fits.
My client met Ms. Troost in a neutral
location with plenty of witnesses.
- No law was broken.
- What about witness tampering?
She invited him.
So what do a victim and a rapist
talk about over a plate of pasta?
Money.
She had me by the balls,
so I gave her half a million in cash.
You walked through this city
carrying $500,000
and just handed it over to her.
Yeah.
Then why did she leave crying?
Because she's crazy.
I was happy to pay her just
to get her out of my life.
She left with the money,
and I never saw her again.
The problem is neither has anyone else.
We're through here.
Charge my client or leave.
By the way, your cleanup job
at the apartment sucked.
You should've let April
burn up in that car.
You've made an awful
lot of mistakes,
and I promise they're gonna
catch up to you.
Every piece of evidence points
to Barclay Pallister.
CSU checked his lab.
Same chemical cans, same industrial
strength hydrogen peroxide.
Which you could find in any lab.
It's still circumstantial.
Well, look, the blood
on the sofa, walls, floor,
they're a DNA match to April.
We don't have a body.
Captain, we got a nosy
neighbor off the canvass.
Said she complained to April
about loud music the night she died.
April apologized and said
she'd tell her friend to turn it down.
Did the neighbor get
a look at this friend?
- She just said him.
- I may know who.
April's LUDs, four incoming calls
to her cell phone after dinner,
- all from the same number.
- Barclay Pallister.
No. A Roger Mason.
Lives on East 82nd.
April didn't answer the phone.
I was worried about the baby,
so I kept calling.
That's what friends do.
Most female homicide victims
are killed by a man they know.
That's another thing friends do.
You think I killed her?
You got impatient,
because she didn't return your calls.
Went over to her apartment,
got in a fight, and killed her.
I'd never hurt my baby.
Your baby?
Our baby.
We were going to adopt
her unborn child.
April never mentioned that.
We agreed to pay for the costs and
the fees of the pregnancy and delivery.
How much does a bouncing
baby girl go for these days?
$50,000. / Sounds like you
were buying a baby.
April didn't want to keep the baby.
This was best for everyone.
Now do you understand?
We could never hurt April.
Then what was so urgent that night?
April was depressed.
She'd been through a lot.
Her husband died.
She lost her job,
got behind in the rent.
We had been giving her extra cash.
But then two days ago
she stopped returning our calls.
April sure made a bundle
off of that rape.
Talk about making a silk purse
out of a sow's ear.
Half a million from Barclay Pallister,
and 50 grand for selling the baby.
Not exactly the poor, fragile victim
we thought she was.
You have no idea.
Meet the Ramseys,
the Harts, the Fritzlers.
All expectant parents.
All paid 50 grand
to adopt April Troost's baby.
There could be dozens of marks
we don't even know about.
She used the rape and pregnancy
to turn a quick buck.
And everybody she scammed
has motive to kill her.
Excuse me, I'm looking
for captain Cragen.
I'm captain Cragen.
Lorraine Dillon.
I'm April Troost's mother.
April said that her mother's
name was Sarah.
I've had six husbands
and as many last names.
But I've always been Lorraine.
Your daughter also said
that you died of cancer last year.
She always had a problem
with the truth.
When she was a child,
she'd run away.
And when I brought her back home,
she'd make all these crazy allegations
against my former husbands.
When's the last time you saw her?
It was about four years ago.
We had a fight.
She stole several very expensive
pieces of jewelry,
including my grandmother's diamond
and ruby necklace.
Did you call the police?
She was my daughter.
Maybe if I'd had, she'd,
she would still be alive.
Do you have any idea who did this?
Mrs. Dillon, we think April was
mixed up in some illegal activity.
- There are quite a few suspects.
- What did she do?
She took a lot of money
from a lot of people.
April always had a way
of hiding things.
I remember once she said something
about a safe deposit box.
- Take all the time you need.
- Thank you.
Any jewelry in there?
No. Headshots.
Those are very handsome men.
And well known.
He's a musician.
This one owns the hottest
restaurant in New York.
This is that new third basemen
that just came up from AAA.
These guys are a lot more
than just good looking.
How about this guy?
Barclay Pallister.
The man who raped my daughter?
April was stalking Barclay Pallister.
And dozens of other men.
All handsome, rich, talented,
at the top of their professions.
I know this guy.
J.J. Price.
I've got his CD.
It's quite a gene pool
she's got here.
April was looking for a champion breeder.
Barclay was the winner.
Some ho tricked me into fatherhood,
I'd be pretty worked up.
And paying child support
for the next 18 years.
17.5% of your income before taxes.
With April and the baby dead,
Barclay dodges that bullet.
Not for the murder charge.
If he did it.
He's only one of the men
April was stalking.
Let's find out who else she burned.
Oh, that crazy chick?
- What'd she say I did?
- So you know her?
Yeah, I really wish I didn't.
You two have sex?
Most likely, yeah.
You forget a hottie like that?
You must get a lot of action.
Dude, you don't know
the half of it, man.
I remember her face.
I just don't remember the name.
The whole night was kinda fuzzy.
- Where'd you meet her?
- At my restaurant.
Every man with a pulse
checked her out.
But she only had eyes for you?
And my wallet.
But a body like that
is worth every penny.
- How much she cost you?
- Nothing.
She bought me a beer.
- Bet that happens a lot.
- Well, they usually expect me to pay,
especially after signing
my last big contract but,
she was different.
She knew everything about me,
down to my stats.
What'd you do after the drink?
Think we went back to my crib.
You think?
That's all you remember?
Dude, I remember porcelain, man.
Up close and personal.
How many drinks did she buy you?
Just one, which never
gives me a hangover.
I was sick as a dog.
Groggy, nauseous?
Both. I thought I had the flu.
- Did you see a doctor?
- Didn't have to.
Pulled a random drug test
the next morning.
- I failed.
- What'd you take?
Nothing.
She doped me.
All right. What'd they find?
Rohypnol.
What are you doing here?
Just need to ask you some questions.
- Get the hell away from me.
- Hear me out.
The rape charge was dropped.
I don't need to talk to you.
Please, just listen to me.
Now, the first time that you met April,
she bought you a drink.
Yeah, so?
What's the next thing you remember?
Waking up in my own bed, alone.
Loss of memory. Headache?
Nausea.
She put something in my drink?
Rohypnol.
I told you I didn't rape her.
I know.
But if she slipped me a roofie...
how did I get it up?
The only explanation is a technique
called electro ejaculation.
I don't like the sound of that.
Nothing to it.
Insert this end in the rectum,
an electric shock causes
an involuntary ejaculation.
Love used to be simpler.
The first procedure
was done back in the '70s
on a teenager who died
in a motorcycle accident.
His parents wanted grandchildren.
It's called posthumous reproduction.
The sperm from a corpse is viable?
If harvested within 30 hours.
Will this thing work
if the guy's not dead?
They've recently started
using this technique
on paraplegics and coma victims.
If your guys were drugged,
they never knew it happened.
And this is legal?
No state law provides clear guidance
on how to retrieve sperm from
a man who's incapacitated or dead.
And you talked to all the men
that April stalked?
34 guys, same story.
April buys them a drink.
Next thing they know,
it's morning, she's gone,
they're sick puppies.
Any nightmares about cattle prods?
Oh, they never knew what hit them.
I thought I heard of every sex crime.
Damn, who thinks this stuff up?
Okay, so we know that  April used
Barclay Pallister's
sperm to impregnate herself.
What did she do with the rest?
A lot of women out there
would pay big money
to have one of these guys
father their children.
Sperm banks make big bucks
off genius sperm.
We have seven sperm banks
in New York city.
Let's split them up
and hit them all.
McManus Institute
114 East 57th Street
Friday, March 25
Welcome to the institute.
Please have a seat
and fill this out.
We're not interested in your services.
Do you know this woman?
April. She used to work here.
What was her job?
Collections.
She was our accountant.
You lying son of a bitch.
You're a fraud.
Listen to that crap.
Excuse me?
- Who are you?
- The police.
- What's going on in here?
- That quack tricked me.
I did nothing of the sort.
- I want my money back.
- Okay, stop.
Now, what exactly is the problem?
He said my baby
would be playing Mozart.
I told you there were no guarantees.
She can't even play chopsticks!
All she does is bang on the damn keys!
All right, what exactly
did you promise her? / Nothing.
I inseminated her with the life juice
of a renowned musician.
A genius in his field
who will remain nameless.
Then why am I stuck with her?
You provided 50%
of her genetic material.
Perhaps she inherited your traits.
Okay, how much did you pay
for this super sperm?
$20,000. / I want this woman arrested
for trespassing.
What are you doing?
I'm arresting you.
For, for what?
Stealing sperm.
What?
This is absurd.
You obviously don't understand
the magnitude of my work.
I'm saving the human race.
By stealing sperm.
I didn't steal anything.
You conspired with April Troost
to forcibly obtain the mother lodes.
Nobody was forced.
She explained my mission
to the gentlemen,
and persuaded them to donate.
Yeah, with a cattle prod.
I had no idea.
I'm sorry if people were hurt.
But their suffering will benefit
the greater good.
And how's that?
The intelligence of the world's
population is rapidly declining.
Poor, less educated people
are reproducing at higher rates
than bright, successful ones.
I have four kids.
Yes.
My work will reverse mankind's
inevitable demise
by spreading the seeds of world class
scientists, musicians, athletes.
You're nothing but a Nazi trying
to engineer a master race.
He's a nut job.
A lot of researchers think
he's Nobel prize material.
Who, the Dr. Mengele fan club?
Almost everyone in genetic engineering.
His work in pre-implantation
genetic diagnosis
allows us to screen embryos
for severe disorders
like Tay-sachs, cystic fibrosis,
down syndrome.
He's legit.
And controversial.
He just invented a technique for couples
to select their own baby's sex.
And he's researching ways of manipulating
inherited characteristics
- like height, eye color, intelligence...
- Making designer babies.
He can't do it yet.
But in our lifetime,
wealthy couples are gonna be
able to custom-order a baby.
- And the couples who can't afford it?
- There'll be two races.
The enhanced and the average,
driving a bigger wedge
between the rich and the poor.
Looks like McManus' research is on ice.
What happened?
His clinic's broke.
He makes hundreds of thousands
selling genius sperm.
But his research is expensive.
It's a temporary setback.
Dr. Frankenstein had a backup plan.
What's that?
April's life insurance policy
naming you as the sole beneficiary.
$5 million?
You just went from zero to rich
faster than it takes to drive off a cliff.
How could I know April was gonna
have a tragic accident?
Well, she didn't.
You murdered her.
That's preposterous.
It's more like ingenious.
You recognize that?
It's a chemical storage can.
We found it at the scene
at April's car crash.
It's just like the one
you use at your lab.
Know what else we found at your lab?
Hydrogen peroxide.
Same concentrate that was used to clean
up April's blood in her apartment.
Hundreds of labs use these things.
But I bet yours was the only one
who took out an insurance policy
on the one person who could blow
the whistle on where you got your sperm.
She suckered you, too, didn't she?
She blackmailed you
so nobody would find out?
That's why you were so broke.
And if your clinic closes down,
you're not saving the world.
So you murdered her
for the insurance money.
No. I loved her.
Oh, so you were sleeping with her too.
That's disgusting.
She's my daughter.
I didn't kill her.
And I can prove it.
Who told you?
Your father.
Mother always said never trust a man.
Where's the baby, April?
It was stillborn.
You're a liar.
What, you didn't need it anymore,
so you killed it?
That's not a very nice thing
to say to someone in mourning.
Cut the act, April!
I'm sick of your crap.
You were my friend.
You promised to protect me.
When you were a rape victim,
not a rapist.
You sexually assaulted three dozen men.
Really?
- Did they tell you I assaulted them?
- We've got you on extortion and fraud.
Not to mention ripping off
childless couples.
And extorting half a million dollars
from Barclay Pallister.
It was a settlement.
There's nothing illegal about being paid
for my pain and suffering.
Faking your own murder
for the insurance money is.
Gotta hand it to you.
Smearing your own blood on the walls?
- That was good.
- You have a sick imagination.
On my best day, I couldn't
make this stuff up.
I'm the victim here.
None of this is my fault.
April Troost, you are
under arrest for fraud.
You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say can...
You're only charging April
with fraud and extortion?
She's a walking crime spree.
My hands are tied.
Three dozen of her victims don't
even have a memory of being raped.
What about the baby?
No hospitals in the tri-state area
even have a record that she delivered one.
Casey, trust me, she did.
And then she sold it
or she drowned it or who knows.
But that evil bitch did
something terrible with that baby.
You know, for all we know,
it really was stillborn,
- and that's not a crime.
- No, it's a con!
April has been scamming us
since day one.
She never had any intention
of jumping off that ledge.
She played you, so now you're pissed.
Yes, I'm pissed.
But we still have to find that baby.
Not to mention ruining
Barclay Pallister's life.
That's not our fault.
That's April's.
And knowing her, she will find
someone else to blame.
Her mother.
April was raised without
any moral values whatsoever.
So she's a sociopath.
April's well aware
of right and wrong,
but she believes
the law doesn't apply to her.
That's how she was brought up.
My mother told me that
storks bring babies and
that Santa came down the chimney.
But you know what,
you grow up and you realize
that some of the things your
parents told you aren't true.
Not if you're brainwashed.
April Troost is like a suicide bomber,
indoctrinated from birth.
She lives her life
by the lies her mother told her.
Ignorance of the law is no defense.
Mental defect is.
Your shrink will agree,
April wasn't responsible for her actions.
Mother had me running scams
from the day I was born.
I saved her thousands in hospital bills.
She conned her doctor?
She took him for everything he had.
He was husband number two.
Do you find tricking people amusing?
Absolutely.
Mother always said
if you're too stupid to see the wool
being pulled over your eyes,
you deserve what you get.
So it's okay to rip people off,
to break the law?
I know there are rules.
But they don't apply to me.
- How did that go over in school?
- I didn't go to school.
Mother didn't want me picking up
any bad habits.
- Like what?
- Feeling sorry for people.
What mother called "getting soft."
She taught me to stay alert.
- Be on the lookout.
- For what?
There are always people who want
to take advantage of me.
That's why I have to take
advantage of them first.
Survival of the fittest.
Screw or get screwed.
Mother drilled that into me.
She taught me everything
she knew about people.
Men in particular.
She went through six husbands
and their fortunes.
What about your father, Dr. McManus?
Husband number one.
She left him right after I was born.
He was brilliant but broke.
I didn't meet him until a year ago.
He was thrilled to find
the daughter he never knew.
And how did you feel?
It was the opportunity of a lifetime.
I needed a job,
and he paid me well to bring him
the best genetic material.
Barclay Pallister.
April, don't you think that he
deserves to know where his baby is?
Only if I get a sweet deal.
Why should you get a break?
I'm too beautiful for prison.
I had no idea
how sick she really is.
April fooled everybody.
She's quite an actress.
I bailed her out,
and this is the thanks I get.
All of her problems are my fault.
Can she do this?
Can she tell all these lies in court?
I can make sure
the jury hears the truth.
- You can testify.
- No.
Let her say what
she wants about me.
I'm on my way
back to Florida tonight.
Hi, mom.
How could you do this
to your own mother?
Oh, some mother. You led the cops right
to my safe deposit box.
Too bad the money wasn't there.
This is not about the money.
Just tell them where the baby is.
Are you kidding?
I'm through with you.
No way I'm letting April walk.
Well, if we don't give her
some kind of plea,
we may never find the baby.
How do we know it's alive?
I'm sure of it.
It's her only bargaining chip.
We checked out all the couples
who had contracts to buy April's baby.
None of them have the child.
Hotel clerk says
she checked in alone.
She was not pregnant.
There are no leads off her LUDs.
That baby could be anywhere.
Black market in newborns?
That's booming.
She's a cold-hearted bitch.
But is she crazy?
No.
She's amoral.
She knows what she's doing is wrong.
The jury will see it
as just another con job.
Take her to trial,
you're never gonna find the kid.
Wherever the baby is, it's
better off than being with April.
Unless she sold the kid
to a pedophile.
You have to find my baby.
Mr. Pallister.
You must make April
tell you where the baby is.
She won't. Unless we let her off,
and I can't do that.
You have to.
She's a dangerous woman.
You owe me.
Do we have any other leverage on her?
Rikers Island
Tuesday, March 29
You're wrong about April.
She's a sweet girl.
If anyone's to blame,
it's her mother.
I never should've chosen Lorraine.
For what?
My first experiment.
I was looking for the perfect woman.
Bright, beautiful, accomplished.
Lorraine was ideal.
I married her,
and we had April.
She was a beautiful baby.
Smart.
170 IQ.
Great, but what happened
to your experiment?
I thought I'd picked the ultimate mate,
but Lorraine wanted to be rich.
I wasn't.
I didn't see April
till she found me last year.
I was just so happy
to have my daughter back.
Your daughter's using you to scam
rich and powerful men.
She meant no harm.
She was just trying to help me.
By claiming Barclay Pallister raped her
and then having his child to prove it?
She knew it was wrong.
And she came to me.
And she said that she had to die
to fix this mess she made.
Right, and you'd collect
on her insurance.
No, no, I was, I was
gonna give April all the money
so she and the baby
could start a new life.
Except that new life
doesn't include the baby.
- What do you mean?
- April doesn't have the child.
And she won't tell us where it is.
She'll tell me.
April, you're confused.
You're not thinking about
what's best for the baby.
I'm not confused. I'm thinking about
what's best for me.
- No one else will.
- I will.
Yeah, right.
They offer you a deal
if you got me to give up the kid?
No, I'm just trying to help you.
Why?
I'm your father.
I love you, April.
Love is for suckers.
That baby's my ticket out of here.
I want my deal.
I can't give you one.
Well, then I can't give you my baby.
Please.
Take this baby away from her
before she destroys it.
Fine, you have your deal.
No jail.
Now, where's the baby?
Nice doing business with you.
- Novak let you off, didn't she?
- Yeah.
I'm glad.
Why?
Because you don't deserve
to be a mother.
And I'm gonna make sure
that you never see that child again.
Good.
Maybe the kid'll have a chance.
You poor thing.
They stole your purse at the funeral?
Yes.
My credit cards, my ID, my cash.
My daughter is dead, and I just want to
get my grandbaby back to Florida.
Well, here's a voucher
for a train ticket to Miami.
- Thank you.
- You're not going anywhere.
Detectives.
Oh, man, you are a piece of work.
Just curious.
How did you track me down?
Your daughter gave you up.
You two have been
working together all along.
That was quite a performance
you gave at our squadroom.
Well, that's my girl.
I taught her everything she knows.
Well, you won't be teaching
that child a damn thing.
I can't prove that you broke
the law this time but, lady...
I am gonna get you.
Olivia.
How's the baby?
Sarah's fine.
Not that April
or her mother give a damn.
I bet you they're in a bar
right now laughing at us.
- Let it go.
- I can't.
They scammed everyone,
and we just let them walk.
- We got the baby.
- I know.
But we haven't seen the last of them.
They will never stop
playing their sick games.
Okay, she's medically cleared.
You can take her.
Hi.
Liv, you gotta stop
beating yourself up.
The baby matters more.
Now she'll bloved.
I was up all night preparing her room.
Because Sarah deserves the best.
Well, she's certainly got it.
- You take care.
- Thank you.
I hear April's IQ is 170.
That's what Dr. McManus says, yeah.
Yes, I've read up on him.
He's brilliant.
And she has good genes
on my side, too.
She's perfect.
번역수정
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)
한글교정
자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)
www.tvsubtitles.net