Charlie?
Charlie, come on.
Not going to the funeral?
No, didn't know her, really.
Is that on credit?
Unfortunately.
Makes you think, though.
Certainly does.
Wonder what he'll say at my funeral.
Something nice, I'm sure.
There you are.
Sorry.
Good boy.
That's it.
Come on.
Here we go.
No! No! Charlie, no!
Oh, no.
Oh, you bloody bugger.
Want some juice?
How much did that cost?
I don't know.
A few bucks.
Yeah? Used every
fucking cent we got, Dale.
Well, I'll put it on my card, Ron.
No.
They can trace after us.
Give me the cash.
Let's do a runner.
They've seen the car, Ron.
Now give me the cash...
and I'll sort it out.
It's only a few bucks.
Listen, you either pay me
the right money...
or I'll call the cops.
It's $4.50.
Fine.
Look, I hate to put you
in this situation.
Is there anything I could do...
that might square things up?
You'd be all right until about nightfall.
Here we go.
Jesus, Ron!
Are you out of your fucking mind?
He was calling the cops!
You gave him a blow job?
What was that back there?
What the fuck were you thinking?
What is Joey doing
in the boot of the car?
What'd you want me to do with him...
leave him in the fucking car park, Dale?
I'm trying to get you
out of that life, Dale...
and the first chance you get,
you're giving a blow
to some servo attendant for 4.50!
It was a fucking handjob, Ron.
Pardon me.
Same difference.
It's a big fucking difference.
One's with the hand,
and one's with the mouth.
Shit. Shit, Ron.
- Fucking turn off! Turn off!
- Just sit still and stay calm, all right?
Don't shoot anybody, Ron.
- Don't fucking shoot any...
- Shut up!
All right, we're gonna dump the car.
It's okay, baby.
It's okay.
That's nice.
We should be able to hot-wire it.
Maybe the keys are in the house.
Come on.
Hey, Ron.
What...
what are you doing here?
- No!
- Ron, no!
- Please don't hurt me.
- Shut up!
What's your name, asshole?
- Andrew.
- Andrew?
Asshole.
I was close, wasn't I?
Give me your wallet.
Get it out!
That's it?
Where are your car keys?
In the box on the table over there.
Get them, babe.
Here, hold that.
Get on your stomach.
Come on!
- You alone?
- Yes.
All right?
Look for some cash
or something.
All right.
Shit.
Oh, my God.
Yeah!
Yes.
Hurry up, Dale!
We're out of here!
Here's the plan, and...
You're gonna drive us up North.
Dale is going to be in the boot
until we get out of Bowral...
and I'm going to be
right behind you...
with my shotty sticking
straight up your ass.
When we get to Queensland...
you're going to pull
over to an auto teller...
and you're going to withdraw
up to your limit.
Now, I'm doing this
because, you see...
my girlfriend,
she's got a soft heart.
But if it was up to me...
you'd be dead already.
Am I getting through to you, Andy?
I can't.
No, really, you can.
No, you don't understand, I'm...
No, you don't understand.
So?
What do you think?
Women.
We need cash, Dale.
There isn't none.
God, you are fucking killing me.
No, please no!
I can't go outside! Please!
No! Please!
I'm afraid of open spaces.
I can't go outside!
Yeah? Well, I'm afraid...
of enclosed spaces, like jail!
Please!
No!
Get out!
Get up!
You're being
a very bad hostage.
Come on!
Get up now.
Fuck!
Coppers!
Get back.
Come back inside, Andy.
Come back
in the house, Andy!
Come in the house, Andy!
Come on, Andy.
Pills.
- My pills.
- What the fuck?
Bathroom... bathroom drawer.
Shit.
Servos, jumpers...
We've got it.
- What the fuck is the matter with him?
- He's agoraphobic.
Agora what?
I don't know,
he says he can't go outside.
No, no!
No!
Please!
He said he can't go outside.
He's outside now!
Bloody human boomerang.
Shit.
All right...
We just keep our heads down for a bit.
A day or so, they'll call it off...
and then we can get
the hell out of here.
Ron?
Where's the remote?
Where is it?
Fuck!
They got my face.
If we just done a runner,
when I said so...
we'd be halfway there...
but no, you got to sort it out.
Well, we're fucking sorted now,
aren't we?
Dead guy at the service station...
and our hostage is going
to go the same way.
No, he's not.
You're never killing him.
You're right.
It's about time you did
your own dirty work.
You know how I promised, remember?
I'm not doing that.
Bet you're not, you lazy bitch.
I'm not lazy.
I'm not the only one
that says so, all right?
I am not lazy.
Come on, stop it.
Don't touch me.
Oh, babe, come on.
Go then!
Fucking hell.
I won't forget this, you prick.
Dale!
I'm sorry.
I'm not fucking lazy, Ron.
I might be a pig, all right?
I'm a fucking pig...
that loves you.
I just like you the way you are.
Not dressed up like a champion.
Bitch.
You know?
I want to do some nasty,
nasty shit to you.
You're not wearing any undies.
You don't wear undies
in a dress like this.
You're bloody so fucking hot.
Yeah? Do you want me to fuck you?
Yeah.
You got a death wish?
Because I can grant it, dickhead.
No worries at all.
I've thought of a way...
I can get you $40,000.00.
Say that again.
I can get you $40,000.00...
in two days.
What are you doing?
Our friend Andy
just made a proposition.
This better be good.
It's a trust fund
that my mother set up.
That must be nice.
And this just tops up every fortnight.
Bullshit!
Look, all we have to do
is take the first check...
to the bank tomorrow...
and they will give you $20,000.00
Then when the account
is topped up overnight,
you take the second
check in on the Tuesday.
Look, the local bank
knows about my condition...
and they will call here
for a password.
Once I speak to them,
they will pay out in full...
and you will have
$40,000.00 in your hand.
Who does this for you normally?
Lilly, my housekeeper.
As if they're going
to give us 20 grand in cash!
They will if...
If you become my fiancée.
- I don't look nothing like her.
- Let him finish.
When I walked in that first time...
when I saw you standing there...
I'm not doing it.
You were so just like...
Look, Gabrielle's only been
to Bowral a couple of times.
If you were to dye
your hair blonde...
- Where is this fiancée?
- She's overseas.
- She's...
- Ron!
Babe!
Is your fiancée really
as pretty as my Dale here?
That dress is a perfect fit, isn't it?
I'm not doing it, I'll get caught!
Why am I the only one that
has to take a risk, huh?
This is typical of you.
Can't do a bloody thing.
Just take a look at me.
Now look around you.
I could never be her.
Ron, I really don't think...
that's the way to talk to her.
Andy, I really don't think...
that's the way to talk to Ron.
Dale?
Hey, you.
I'm scared.
I know you are, babe.
I'm scared, too.
Shit.
Ferrari 360.
He's a fantastic character, too...
Grow up, Andy.
So what's she like, this chick?
Does she talk like you?
I suppose so.
You can look at me, Andy.
You never been to a strip club?
No, I haven't.
So how long has she been away?
Six months.
You don't worry she got her legs...
wrapped around
some other guy by now?
- No. She's not like that.
- Like what?
Normal?
Like you.
Let me tell you something, Andy.
They're all like me.
Well! What do you know?
Another rainbow!
Where's my gun?
Fuck!
I knew it!
Pot of gold!
If you even wink at these pricks...
- you're fucked!
- What's going on?
Cops are at the door.
Oh, fuck!
Say anything you want.
Just get rid of him.
I've killed two people.
I got nothing to lose.
Mr. Shepard?
Yes?
How can I help you?
I'm Sergeant Widdens,
this is Constable Blarney.
We're with the Bowral Police.
Your housekeeper got in touch with us.
She reckons she hasn't
been able to raise you.
Oh...
- You all right, Mr. Shepard?
- Yes, I'm fine.
Would you prefer if we came inside?
I've been overdoing it a bit.
My fiancée rang a few days ago.
She's met someone else.
She's coming here
to pick up her things.
Yeah, well...
I know how these things
can get on top of you...
but if you could call her,
I'd appreciate it.
I'm really sorry to have troubled you.
You did it.
The cop car hasn't started.
The boss reckons
they're up North by now.
Yeah.
Oh, well.
He's the boss.
Hello?
Yes, hello, Lilly?
It's Andrew.
Yes, I'm sorry,
but thanks for your concern.
No, I was actually really touched.
No, I should have called.
Listen.
I... If you...
I don't want you to come in tomorrow
if that's all right.
No, next Tuesday will be fine.
You know, the usual...
personal things, Lilly.
All right, then, well, next week.
Okay.
Thank you.
Bye-bye now. Bye!
You did good.
You know, you could make
a very good crim.
You have earned yourself a shower.
Frittata!
How are you going to live in Thailand
if you can't eat real food?
I've had Thai, okay?
This is just an omelet for wankers!
I reckon he's a poofter.
Haven't you noticed?
He likes it when I tie him up.
Take me hostage.
What?
You're so cute
when you're an idiot.
Don't call me cute all right?
Kittens are cute.
There's hair dye in the cabinet.
The bathroom is free now
if you need it.
I'm done.
Take out the belly button ring.
What?
You're beautiful.
Yeah?
Well, just keep
your hands to yourself.
You are perfect.
A spot-on upper-class bitch.
...has been linked
to the abduction...
Shit.
He disappeared from
outside his club...
in the early hours
of Sunday morning.
Police believe
he has been wounded...
and may be in a serious condition.
In a tragic twist...
service station attendant
Terrance Gilmore...
was apparently murdered
yesterday afternoon.
Police have released
this photo of a man...
wanted for questioning
in relation to both matters.
He is 28-year-old
Ronald Jason Beron.
He is described
as armed and dangerous.
Beron is believed
to be traveling with a woman...
described as a brunette,
and in her early twenties.
Police believe the couple
may still be in the area.
In other news,
Prime Minister John Howard...
is meeting with cabinet today.
They think your dickhead boss
is alive.
That's why the choppers.
I can't go out there.
All right, that didn't look like you,
you're fine.
They're looking for a blue ute...
that we are not driving anymore.
Don't make me do it.
Babe, they're looking
for a brunette...
and you have blonde hair.
They're looking for a couple.
You're going to be on your own.
It's just shit that they
put out just to rattle us.
That's all.
Can't I go tomorrow?
Listen, if you do not go today...
and tomorrow...
we have to stay here
for another two weeks.
I can't go out there.
Well, I can't do it, can I?
You're doing it.
If you don't do this...
you might as well kiss
our future good-bye.
And don't cry.
That's my father
and that's Heather.
- Gold.
- Gold, Andy, gold!
You didn't tell anyone?
Not for a couple of years,
and when the list came up...
I bought it.
I never looked back.
- Your father, the rogue.
- Trust me...
You don't want to see that.
Your dad's an Aussie?
What the bloody hell
happened to you?
Your father's a rogue.
Wasn't that it?
It was perfect.
Gabrielle doesn't smoke, though.
Yeah, well, I do.
Hey.
Say something else.
Would you please cash this for me?
Would you...
Open your mouth.
Try and make the words more discreet.
Fuck off!
No one's going to believe I went
to some posh-ass school anyway.
Class is an attitude.
It's not about you.
Why don't you imagine
that everybody you meet...
is younger than you are...
like they're 12.
Everyone you meet knows less
about the world than you do.
Would you please cash this for me?
Very good.
Good afternoon,
my name is Gabrielle Martin.
Perfect.
All right, school's over.
Let's go.
Good afternoon, I'm Miss Martin.
I have this check for you to cash.
Good afternoon,
I'm Gabrielle Martin.
I have this check for you to cash.
If you get stopped...
just tell them that you
picked up your old license.
It's just a fine.
Ronald, would you be a darling
and bring the car up for me?
Oh, sure, Miss...
Miss Martin.
Be right with you.
You know I wouldn't let you go...
if I didn't think you could do it.
You just want to live, that's all.
Yes.
I do.
That's why I'm not worried about you.
So.
How do I look?
Gum.
Don't, Ronnie.
My lipstick.
Did a good job, Andy.
I hardly recognized her.
Glad you approve.
Oh, I didn't say that, did I?
So you enjoy yourself up there?
Dressing her up?
Doing her hair?
Hey, And, you can admit it.
She's hot. Right?
She's very sweet.
Come on, And!
You've been checking her out
ever since we got here.
No, I haven't. I...
You sayin' she's a dog?
No, of course I'm not.
So you have been checking her out.
No. She's your girl, Ron...
That's right, And!
That's right.
She's my girl.
And you wanna fuck her.
No, no. It's not true.
You think she's hot?
- And you'd like to fuck her.
- No, Ron.
You think she's hot,
and you'd like...
- to fuck her.
- No!
You think she's hot,
and you'd like...
- to fuck her!
- No, Ron!
You wanna fuck her,
don't ya? Yeah, Andy!
Come on!
You wanna fuck her!
Yes! All right! Yes!
I'm only fucking with you, Andy.
But maybe I'm not.
Next, please.
Next, please!
I've got this check
for you to cash.
I... I've left...
Shit.
It's a lovely piece, that.
Dressed in porcelain in Amalou.
That's 1780.
It's quite unusual. Look.
It's lovely.
Are you after anything
in particular?
No, just browsing.
Of course. Feel free.
Do you live locally?
Yes.
We're just out of town.
Well, look, let me get
you one of my cards.
I have contacts here
and overseas...
so often, if you're after
something specific...
I can source it for you.
But next time, you might want
to bring your partner in...
Or not.
I have this check
for you to cash.
Sure.
Now, your chick...
She's hot.
I hope you don't
mind me saying that.
- No.
- Good.
Because I'd really
like to fuck her.
I bet you she'd be
a goer, too. Huh?
She like it hard and fast?
Am I right?
She like a bit of dirty talk,
you know?
She like it when
you call her a slut?
Just when you're into it?
You know?
Just before she comes?
Give her a bit of, "You slut".
"You bitch".
She'd love that, wouldn't she?
What's she like
in the rumpy department, and?
She a moaner?
Or a screamer?
I bet you she's a screamer.
You're losing her, Ron.
- What?
- She's bored already.
- Haven't you noticed?
- Shut the fuck up.
She's slipping away.
How does that feel?
Knowing that you're...
not... quite...
adequate?
Come on!
If the phone rings out,
you're dead.
- Hello?
- Andrew Shepard.
Frank, yes.
I need to verify some I.D.
Gabrielle Elizabeth Martin.
Yes, it's my fiancée.
Okay. And password.
Restraint.
All right.
- Good.
- Yes.
Thank you. Yes.
We're gonna be doing
this again tomorrow.
Is that all right?
Yes. That's fine.
Want your license back?
We don't have anything larger.
So that's 10, 12, 14...
16, 18...
19, and 20,000.00
Thank you.
Miss?
Excuse me. Miss.
This your car?
It belongs to my fiancé.
The door was unlocked.
I wouldn't do that around here.
Sorry.
Here's my money.
I did it. I actually did it, Andy.
It was extraordinary. They believed
everything that I was saying.
You know, they treated me
like I was someone special!
That's what I'm talkin' about, Andy.
You feel alive, huh?
You did good, baby!
You did good!
I just felt so comfortable.
Just shows, when one makes
a little bit of effort...
with your appearance and whatnot...
and the attitude, darling...
the attitude of those around you
completely changes.
Yeah, well, you can
drop the attitude now.
She's amongst friends now,
isn't she, Andy?
Sorry, darling.
To what attitude do you refer?
The attitude, babe!
The accent, all right?
It's not funny!
I knew you could do it.
You could almost be her.
Gold!
We are celebrating tonight, my friends!
You ever order in, Andy?
- I'm sorry?
- You know.
Whores.
Hoochie mamas.
You getting me?
What?
Six months without a screw?
No wonder you're tropo, mate!
Come on, And. You gotta learn
to live a little, you know?
I mean, look at that.
Now that's a disgrace, man.
You've been on that all night.
No wonder.
Hang on.
I know what you need.
Now where's the ice cream?
In the chest freezer, on the side.
By the fridge.
Can I introduce you
to a titillating sensation?
That's a hundred dollars a bottle, Ron.
There's some cheap stuff
in the fridge...
Fuck the cheap stuff.
We're celebrating, mate!
I give you... the champagne spider.
It's like poetry.
Come on. Give your
Master Tom a good swipe.
I really don't think it's my...
Oh, and you haven't even tried it!
Come on.
Well, I'll be damned.
Isn't that some gourmet shit?
Drink up, lads!
So what's with all
the paintings, mate?
You an art dealer?
I used to be.
I'm more of a collector now.
Right.
With your private income.
That's right.
I was also a dealer.
Dad was a druggie.
Your old man's in mining, right?
Among other things.
Little tension between
you and the old man, is there?
How about your mum?
She died a few years ago.
Sorry to hear it.
Mine's still around.
She breeds dogs.
That's what I'm gonna do, too.
Back.
Now what sort, you reckon?
- I have no idea, Ron.
- Just have a guess.
- I don't know...
- Go on, have a guess!
- I really don't know.
- Have a guess! Play the game!
Play the game.
Rottweilers? Pit bulls?
Poodles, mate.
Miniatures.
That's what I'm using
your money for in Thailand.
I'm gonna start my own kennel.
Look anywhere in Asia now.
What do you see?
Gucci. McDonald's.
Coca-fucking-Cola.
You see, they get to a certain level...
and they all want to be white.
Jesus, Ron!
You shut up, babe! Look.
Mercedes Benz.
Little bloody poodles!
Every little yellow bastard
is gonna want one...
either as a pet...
or on the barbie.
What?
I like it, Ron.
I think it's a very good idea.
I knew you'd get it!
- What's this one?
- It's jazz.
New Orleans-style.
- How do you play it?
- You don't.
It's never been played.
It's a first edition.
What's the point of having a record
if not you're gonna play it?
I just don't think
it's your type of thing.
Put the fucking thing on.
You know nothing about me.
All right? Nothing.
See, I like that. Yeah!
10 to 15 inches.
See, that's your miniatures.
Anything under that is just a toy.
Good water dogs.
What are you laughing at?
- Come on. Get up here.
- Come on, Andy.
- Go on.
- Get up.
Shake your tail feather, Andy!
That's it. Go on.
There he goes.
Come on.
You, too.
Dyin' for a fag.
Never.
Listen to me.
You will never make it to Thailand.
You won't even get a passport.
Ron's got friends
that can help us.
But things are different now.
There's all sorts of security checks.
- You don't know what you're talking about.
- Things have changed, Dale.
Ron has murdered two people.
They're gonna catch up with you.
Ron!
Dale, listen to me.
Listen.
You haven't done anything wrong.
Look at you. You're...
You're beautiful.
You've got your whole life ahead of you.
You could turn yourself in
tomorrow and walk.
Walk to what, Andy?
Back to stripping?
Ron... He loves me
just the way that I am.
But you don't love you...
the way you are.
Boo!
Found this outside, And.
I thought you might have lost it.
Now, you reckon
an art critic did this?
Or have you been up
to something naughty?
She left me.
Crap.
She left me, Ron, all right?
Bullshit!
She walked out
without any of her stuff...
her clothes, her makeup.
Now, ladies and gentlemen of the jury...
you show me a broad
that would do such a thing.
She left me because my father...
paid her a great deal
of money to disappear.
And she did.
They met for lunch,
and I never saw her again.
Fuck me dead.
I thought my old man was harsh.
He always said
she was a gold digger.
I guess she was.
Well, this brought the night...
to a rewarding end, didn't it?
They way he keeps all her stuff...
it's fuckin' sicko.
I think it's romantic...
like Miss Havisham.
Miss who?
Forget it.
I shot your boss's
fucking head off, all right?
I fucked up my whole fucking life.
Dale, have you ever
asked yourself once why?
Because you owed him money, Ron!
I fucked him so you'd have
more time to pay.
Yeah, and I killed him
to get you out of that.
You want to get me out of it?
You could've just paid him.
Just paid him, Ron.
Is that right?
You see...
I seen you talking on, Dale.
And you know what?
I don't care.
Because I know you love me.
Don't you?
Do you love me, Dale?
What do you think?
I got to believe you love me...
because if I don't...
I might as well shoot my head off...
right fucking now.
Do you love me, Dale?
Yes.
Good.
Instead of gawking
at this poor bitch...
why don't you see what's
right in front of your eyes?
- What do you mean?
- What's around her neck?
That must be 50 grand's worth.
I reckon you could get him
to tell you where it is.
You know?
Turn him on a little.
- Make him think you're hot for him.
- Oh, Ron.
What? You did it tonight
and you enjoyed it.
We were just having a bit of fun.
Hey.
I'm not saying fuck him, Dale.
I'm just saying, you know...
do what you did
every night at the club.
Are you too good for that now?
Isn't that what you wanted?
Yeah.
You're right.
I'll just break his fucking legs...
and he's gonna
cough it up soon enough.
You fucking shit.
And that way, you can stay pure!
I'll do it.
That's my girl.
Why are you such an asshole?
We're not like him, Dale.
We're different.
Ron's going to break your legs if you
don't tell me where her jewelry is.
It's in the bank.
How do I get it?
I will tell you on one condition.
You get the money and the jewelry...
and then you call the police
and you disappear.
You must think I'm a bad person.
We've all done bad things
when we're desperate.
I'd be dead already
if it wasn't for you.
- How do I get it?
- Promise.
- Ron will get it out of you.
- Promise me
you'll take the money,
and you will go.
Then I promise.
It's in the safe deposit box
in the bank...
under Gabrielle's name.
The keys are in my pocket.
They're not here.
No.
They're in the music box
in the sunroom.
Fuck this.
Well?
Yep.
Your lipstick should be lighter.
It's fine.
It's not right.
It doesn't matter.
Gabrielle would never wear
that shade with that suit.
As if they care at the bank.
I'll change it.
Okay?
We might as well get it right.
Thank you, Ronald.
Don't forget who you are, Dale.
Bitch.
You think you could
possibly untie me...
so that I could give
Charlie some water?
No!
No, you... you fucker!
You bastard! You ape!
You stupid, dumb ape!
I guess I don't have
to untie you now.
You're never going
to get your money now!
It's just a bird, Andy.
God, I didn't cry that much
when my nana died.
Fuck you.
Sit down.
No.
- Sit down.
- No.
- Sit the fuck down.
- You're gonna kill me anyway.
- Fuck you! Fuck you!
- Sit down!
Fuck you!
Hi, Mr. Shepard.
It's Frank Middleton.
Your fiancée's here
to cash a check.
Mr. Shepard?
All right, Frank.
This will be the last time
that we do this.
Yes, Mr. Shepard.
And your password, please?
Restraint.
Game's over, And...
You don't have to kill me.
I got no choice.
You don't have to do it.
What about if I told you...
that I had done something?
I've done things...
things that I can't
tell the police.
So you have been naughty, have you?
It's about my father.
He fucked her.
What?
My father.
Your father tumbled your fiancée?
That's why he...
he paid her off.
He wouldn't let us get married.
They were having an affair.
That's bad.
I just don't know
if that's bad enough.
I killed him.
I killed my father.
I paid a man
$100,000 in cash.
They made it look like an accident...
on his boat.
He gave me a photograph.
There's proof.
You could take it with you...
and you wouldn't have to kill me.
You would always have it over me.
I'd like to see this photograph.
Miss Martin to see you.
Miss Martin.
Come in.
Just need you to sign here.
Sure.
We've met before, I think.
Have we?
Can't think where.
It'll come to me.
Always does.
Come through.
Let me know when you're ready.
Turn the light on.
This way.
The photo's behind those pipes,
under that brick.
Go get them.
Can you untie me, please?
You see...
I thought we were becoming friends.
But you fucked me over.
So that'll be a no.
Yeah?
Well, I've been fucked over
my whole life.
Shit!
Andy!
Andy! Let me out!
Let me out! Andy!
You having fun yet, Andy?
I know I am!
Right.
Okay, I forgive you.
You have been a bad, bad boy!
Come here!
Oh, Mr. Shepard.
Sergeant Widdens...
what a surprise.
You all right, Mr. Shepard?
Yes, sir.
I've just been... Sorry.
Been cleaning up out the back.
Can I help you?
Well... do you mind
if we come in, sir?
No, actually,
as I said to you yesterday...
I really think it's time
you let us inside, sir.
I appreciate that.
I would like to, but...
to be honest,
I can't have people in my home...
because of my condition.
All right.
We came by because
two very large checks...
have been drawn against your account
in the last two days.
You aware of that?
Yes.
$20,000.00.
Made out to cash.
Yes, that's right.
Are you saying you
came by because the...
the bank contacted you?
They routinely monitor these things...
and they couldn't raise you
on the phone.
Shit.
My fiancée, Gabrielle Martin.
Miss Martin.
Sergeant.
Look at the state of you.
Been cleaning up in the...
in the basement.
Getting ready for the painters.
This place is falling apart.
She's back for one day...
and she's running my life already.
I see.
Sometimes things work out,
don't they?
The cash withdrawals...
it's renovating money.
Just want to make sure
you're all right, sir.
Anyway...
happy renovating.
Me and my old man...
we saw this big fucking crash.
Big semi just went right
over the top of a little Jap job.
There's a girl stuck in the car.
I would've been about 15, I guess.
Car is so dead.
The ambos are on the way.
And my dad, he can't get in there.
So I says, "Hey, Dad.
I can fit, I can get in there".
There's this little gap, right?
I get in.
Fuck me dead, the girl's alive.
I can just see her head,
her body's trapped in the car.
She'd be about 25...
long, curly blonde hair...
pretty.
She's got blood on her forehead...
but she smiles, you know...
this big beautiful smile.
I said, "Are you okay"?
She's like, "Yeah, I'm fine".
So I keep her talking about
her dog and stuff, you know...
until finally, we hear the sirens...
and it's time for me to get out.
And she says to me...
she says...
"Well, Ronnie, my name's Sara".
"When I get out of here...
I'm going to give you
the best night you've ever had".
Which to me, right,
I'm, like, 15...
so that's big news.
So I get out feeling
pretty good, right?
Then finally, the firies...
they have the jaws of life...
and they open the doors...
and her body's not connected...
to her head.
Decapitated, right?
After that, no one
looks me in the eye.
My old man, he just pretends
like it never happened...
like I'm crazy or something.
Well, I knew her name
was really Sara.
Isn't that spooky?
Anyway, Andy,
I'm telling you this story...
because everything I ever had...
has never been quite real.
It's just disappeared, you know...
like steam off a grate.
Except for Dale.
You see, she's real.
I fucking love you.
We're on our way to Thailand, baby!
Tell you what, though,
you had me worried.
I thought the cops
might have picked you up.
Just took longer than I thought.
Now, be careful with this, okay?
It's loaded.
You don't want
to lose me at this point.
So you're just going
to leave him here?
What are you doing, Ron?
Listen, Dale,
it's not a bad way to go.
And pass me the tape, will you?
Ron, you promised.
I know, but that was
more of a little white lie.
You know that he had
his old man bumped?
He's not just a babe
in the wood, Dale.
Yeah, Gabrielle was
"writting" his old man...
so he had him knocked off.
How sick is that?
Now, the tape, Dale!
No!
Don't make me stand here.
Let him go, Ron.
Dale, we had no choice.
We have no choice.
We never did.
I don't want you to kill him.
You'd better make
a fucking choice right now...
because there's gonna be
one dead prick in this room.
- Stop it!
- Him or me, Dale?
Stop it, Ron!
- Stop it!
Think of this
as Dr. Ron's instant phobia cure.
Now she's been in there
about five minutes.
You get out there
and you turn that engine off...
or hell, we'll just pull her
to the house, won't we?
But if not...
well, you'll have to live
with that, won't you?
The man who couldn't walk
across his own backyard...
to save his girl.
Go on, Andy.
Come on, buddy!
Come on, you pathetic prick!
Giddyup there, Andy. Go on.
Come on, Andy. Go on.
That's it!
Go on! That's it, Andy.
Go on, that's it.
That's it.
You're nearly there, Andy.
Come on, And!
Get up!
Don't you quit on me,
Andy, come on!
There we go!
Oops!
- Did I lock it?
- Dale! Dale!
I'd make a bloody good shrink.
Don't you reckon, And?
Dale!
- At least you tried.
- Dale!
Hey, hey.
Fucking love this shit, Andy!
How long you reckon
she's got, buddy?
Three minutes or less?
She's dying, Andy.
You can run like
a bloody rabbit, Andy.
Dr. Ron was spot on,
don't you reckon?
That's because
we're the same, Andy.
Except...
I'm always one step ahead.
Very good, Andy!
Very good!
Come on, Andy!
Is that all you got, Andy?
You can do better...
Put your back into it, Andy.
Do it.
We're just the same, Andrew.
Dale. Dale.
Dale, come on!
Here we go.
You gonna ring the cops?
I have to.
I've got two dead bodies
on my property.
What about me?
I suppose you'll do some time.
You fucking shit.
It's not as if the police
aren't gonna...
work out what happened, Dale.
I mean, what are our options?
I saved your life.
Twice.
Don't you mean three bodies?
Sorry?
What about your dad?
Isn't he buried out here?
Daddy's alive and well...
and living in Melbourne.
Wouldn't say we're exactly
on speaking terms, but...
I didn't kill him.
Say you love me...
like Gabrielle would say it.
"I love you".
I love you.
I don't believe you.
I love you, Andrew.
I love you.
Say you want me, Gabrielle.
I'm Dale, Andy.
Call me Andrew, Gabrielle.
Say you want me.
I'm Dale.
Yes, but say it like
Gabrielle would say it.
Go on, say it.
Yes?
- I want you.
- Yes.
Do you know where she is?
No.
Europe, I think.
What if she comes back?
She won't.
Doesn't she have family?
No, she lost touch with them.
Do you know, I think she
even changed her name.
Don't worry.
She's gone.