( machine gun fire )
( machine gun fire continuing )
There are over
550 million firearms
in worldwide circulation.
That's one firearm for every
12 people on the planet.
The only question is...
how do we arm
the other 11?
( ''For What It's Worth''
playing )
( men shouting indistinctly )
# There's something
happening here #
# What it is
ain't exactly clear #
# There's a man with a gun
over there #
# Telling me I got to beware #
# I think it's time we stop,
children #
# What's that sound? #
# Everybody look
what's going down #
# There's battle lines being drawn #
# Nobody's right #
# lf everybody's wrong #
# Young people
speaking their minds #
# Getting so much resistance
from behind #
# I think it's time we stop
hey, what's that sound? #
# Everybody look
what's going down #
- # What a field day for the heat #
- # Ooh-ooh #
# A thousand people
in the street #
# Singing songs
and a-carrying signs #
# Mostly say,
hooray for our side #
# It's time we stop,
hey, what's that sound? #
# Everybody look
what's going down #
( clamoring )
# Paranoia strikes deep #
# lnto your life it wilI creep #
# It starts when
you're always afraid #
# You step out of line,
the man come and take you away #
# We better stop, children,
what's that sound? #
# Everybody look
what's going down #
# There's battle
lines being drawn #
# Nobody's right #
# lf everybody's wrong #
# Young people speaking
their minds #
# Getting so much resistance
from behind #
# It's time we stop, hey,
what's that sound? #
# Everybody look
what's going down. #
Man:
You don't have to worry.
l'm not gonna telI you
a pack of lies to make me look good.
l'm just gonna telI you
what happened.
- My name is Yuri Orlov.
- ( ''America the Beautiful'' playing )
When I was a boy,
my family came to America,
but not alI the way.
Like most Ukrainians,
we congregated in Brighton Beach.
It reminded us
of the Black Sea.
I soon realized we just swapped
one helI for another.
Even in hell,
an angeI sometimes
makes an appearance.
l'd worshipped Ava Fontaine
since I was 10 years old.
Of course,
she didn't know I existed.
I was starting to think
she had a point.
For the first 20-odd years
of my life,
Little Odessa was to me
what it is to the Q train.
The end of the line.
Oh, I did lie about my name.
It's not really Yuri Orlov.
There have been few occasions
in the 20th Century
when it's been an advantage
to be a Jew.
But in the '7 0s to escape
the Soviet Union,
our family pretended
to be Jewish.
Little about my life
has been kosher ever since.
How's it going, brother?
It's not.
Yuri: That's Vitaly,
my younger brother.
He was a lost as me.
He just didn't know it yet.
Yuri, you're late.
My father took his assumed
identity to heart.
He was more Jewish
than most Jews,
which drove my
Catholic mother crazy.
How many times?
I can't eat shellfish.
- It's trayf.
- You're not Jewish.
I like it.
I like the hat--
to remind us there is
something above us.
I like that.
- l'm going to temple.
- You're not going to temple.
You go to temple
more than the rabbi.
( speaking Russian )
Yuri, don't forget
to check the specials
at the Palace.
Yuri:
Growing up in Little Odessa,
murder was an everyday
part of life.
Russian mobsters had also
migrated from the Soviet Union.
And when they came to America,
their baggage came with them.
There was always some gangster
getting whacked in my neighborhood.
But l'd never seen it
with my own eyes.
I had this knack of showing up
five minutes before something went down,
or five minutes after.
Not that day.
It hit me.
It couldn't have hit me harder
if I was the one who'd been shot.
You go into the restaurant
business because people are always
going to have to eat.
That was the day I realized my destiny
lay in fulfilling another basic human need.
The next Sabbath,
I went to temple with my father.
However, it wasn't God
I was trying to get close to.
Eli, my oldest son Yuri.
My contact at synagogue
landed me my first lsraeli-made
Uzi submachine guns.
The first time you selI a gun
is a lot like the first time you have sex.
You have absolutely no idea
what you're doing.
But it is exciting,
and one way or another,
it's over way too fast.
Gentlemen, the new Uzi
machine pistol--
big firepower
in a smalI package.
This little baby uses
9mm hollowpoints,
20 25-round extendable mags,
rear-flip adjustable sights.
Silencer comes standard.
Excellent recoiI reduction.
Muzzle jump reduced 40%,
60% improved noise suppression.
You could pump a mag
into me right now
and never wake the guy
in the next room.
Of course that would eliminate
your opportunity for repeat business.
Yuri: I did have a naturaI instinct
for smuggling contraband.
Fortunately, back then a video camera
was as big as a bazooka.
Here, l'd been running away
from violence my whole life,
and I should have been
running towards it.
It's in our nature.
The earliest human skeletons
had spearheads in their ribcages.
# AlI right #
# He was a young American #
# Young American,
young American #
# He was a young American... #
Where have you been?
What if we had a customer?
God bless America.
- Mm, mm-hmm. ( gags )
- Yeah?
( speaks Russian )
''Beware of the dog''?
You don't have a dog.
Are you trying to scare people?
No, it's to scare me.
Remind me to be aware
of the dog in me.
The dog that wants
to fuck everything that moves,
wants to fight and kill
weaker dogs.
I guess it's to remind me
to be more human.
lsn't being a dog
part of being human?
What if that's the best part
of you, the dog part?
What if you're really
just a two-legged dog?
You need to see somebody.
It stinks in here.
Yuri: l'd always wanted to do
something big with my life.
I just didn't know what.
Anyhow, I figured if I was
going into the gun trade,
I was going to aim high.
Vitaly, stop fucking around.
I want to talk to you.
You read the newspapers, V?
The newspaper?
It's always the same.
You're right. Every day there's
people shooting each other.
You know what I do
when I see that?
I look to see what guns
they're using,
and I think to myself,
why not my guns?
What, you opening
a gun shop?
Already more of those
in America than McDonald's.
Even with alI the gangsters
around here,
the margins are too low.
- You've worked out the margins?
- Sure.
Forget gang wars.
The reaI money's
in actuaI wars between countries.
Yuri, what the fuck
do you know about guns?
I know which end
l'd rather be on.
I made the first sale.
We're already in business.
Whoa. We?
I need a partner.
I don't know.
Uh, I don't know, Yuri.
Vitaly, l've tasted your borscht.
You're no fucking chef.
I can eat in the restaurant
for free, and I stilI don't eat there.
Fuck you.
We're doing nothing
with our lives.
I mean, this is shit.
This is shit.
That's true.
But maybe doing nothing's
better than doing this.
I need you.
( speaking Russian )
( ''Ride of the Valkyries'' playing )
Sir, sir, may I interest you
in the shoulder-fired SA-7
surface-to-air missile?
It's the older Chinese model.
Not so effective
against modern military aircraft,
but deadly if used
against a commerciaI airliner.
Giving them away at 850.
Yuri: It was the '80s, and the Cold War
was far from thawed.
Most of the deals were
government to government.
It was a mostly private club
with a lifetime club president.
- That's him.
- Who, the big shot?
Simeon Weisz.
Angola, Mozambique,
those Exocet missiles in the Falklands.
He was selling guns
before there was gunpowder.
l'lI be right back.
Mr. Weisz. Mr. Weisz.
It's okay. They're talking.
- May I help?
- Yes, a mutuaI friend, Eli Kurtzman,
from Brighton Beach, import, exports,
said to contact you.
I have a business proposal,
and I thought perhaps
we could discuss it.
I don't think you and l
are in the same business.
You think I just selI guns,
don't you?
I don't. I take sides.
But in the lran-lraq war,
you sold guns to both sides.
Did you ever consider that l
wanted both sides to lose?
Bullets change governments
far surer than votes.
You're in the wrong place,
my young friend.
This is no place
for amateurs.
Yuri: Curious how you always revert
to your native tongue in moments
- of extreme anger and ecstasy.
- ( heavy breathing )
- Oh, you are beautiful.
- ( TVplaying )
What's your name again?
( man on TV speaking
foreign language )
Yuri:
The only option for Vitaly and me
was under the counter gun running.
I got my first break in Lebanon
after the suicide bombing.
But I wasn't the only
locaI kid making good.
When the United States
leaves a war zone,
they generally don't take
their munitions.
It costs more to bring it back
than to buy new stock.
So we selI by the kilo.
They're secondhand weapons,
but they're stilI okay.
How many kilos
would you like?
- 5,000.
- Yuri: I had a flair for languages.
But I soon discovered that
what talks best is dollars,
dinars, drachmas, rubles,
rupees and pounds fucking sterling.
Of course, the US Army
got a piece of the action.
Army salaries were no better
in the '80s than they are today.
And some of the brass,
like Lieutenant ColoneI Southern
needed to raise money
for their own private wars.
Good to make
your acquaintance.
This is bullshit money, V.
This is smalI fucking potatoes.
What do you want to go,
go more legit?
No, more illegal.
What I would give right now
for a plate of cabbage and potatoes.
( machine gun fire )
It's not our fight.
V, come on.
Let's go. Come on.
Yuri: Selling guns is like
selling vacuum cleaners.
You make calls,
pound the pavement, take orders.
I was an equaI opportunity
merchant of death.
I supplied every army
but the Salvation Army.
I sold lsraeli-made Uzis
to Muslims.
I sold communist-made
bullets to fascists.
( speaking Chinese )
I even shipped cargo
to Afghanistan
when they were fighting
my fellow Soviets.
I never sold
to Osama bin Laden.
Not on any moraI grounds. Back then
he was always bouncing checks.
( machine gun fire )
By the mid '80s,
my weapons were represented
in eight of the world's
top 10 war zones.
( cash register chiming )
There's no problem leading
a double life.
It's the triple and quadruples lives
that get you in the end.
Back then I carried
a French, British, lsraeli
and Ukrainian passport
and a student visa for the US.
But that's another story.
I also packed six different briefcases,
depending on who I was
that day and the region
of the world I was visiting.
Without operations like mine,
it would be impossible
for certain countries
to conduct
a respectable war.
I was able to navigate around
those inconvenient little arms embargoes.
There are three basic types
of arms deal.
White being legal,
black being illegal
and my personal
favorite color gray.
Sometimes I made the deals
so convoluted,
it was hard for me to work out
if they were on the level.
To keep authorities in the dark,
I often spoke in code.
Rocket launchers were ''mothers, ''
the rockets-- ''children. ''
The AK-47 assauIt rifle
was the ''angeI king. ''
It's Yuri.
Yeah, well, yeah, Raoul--
Raoul, the angeI king
wilI arrive tomorrow.
Hallelujah to you too.
AlI right.
The point is if l've done
my job right,
an arms embargo should
be practically impossible
- to enforce.
- ( telephone rings )
What?
Okay, just slow the fuck down.
I can't understand you.
What?
What do you mean tipped off?
They know where we are?
Well, where are they?
Well, how long have I got?
Not long,
what does that mean? Shit.
- Do we try to lose them?
- On this?
- Yuri, we have to get off this thing.
- No, no one's going anywhere. Slow.
Dead slow. Buy me time.
Yeah, it's Yuri.
Get that fucking rag down!
I need another handle
for this tub.
Something in our weight class.
You, over the side.
We're changing the name. Now!
Yes, it's gotta check out.
Yuri: The way I look at it.
What's in a name?
Have you got a shorter name?
l'd often change the registration
of the ship or a plane.
But never at such
short notice.
Damn, they're hauling.
What? ''Kono.''
How do you spelI that? K-o-n-o.
Okay, well, that's good.
Kono.
K-o-n-o.
What are we flying?
Dutch. Got it.
V, get me a Dutch flag,
would you?
Faster or l'lI send
your ass in!
Yuri, I don't have Dutch.
- What?
- l've got Belgium.
What the fuck use is that?
He's painting a name
registered in
the fucking Netherlands.
- l've got a French flag.
- So?
Turn it sideways--
it's Dutch. ( laughs )
That's why you're my brother.
AlI right, good.
Everybody look innocent now.
Yuri: They say every man
has his price.
But not every man gets it.
lnterpoI agent Jack Valentine
couldn't be bought,
at least not with money.
For Jack,
glory was the prize.
Yeah, it's the Kono.
It's not the Kristol.
Kono. K-o-n-o.
- It's clean, sir.
- It's clean?
Sure doesn't look clean.
l'm gonna go aboard.
Phone in a sighting
of the KristoI south of Aruba.
Yuri: Even when I was up against
an overzealous agent,
I had a number of methods
for discouraging a search.
I routinely mislabeled
my arms shipments ''farm machinery. ''
And I have yet to meet
the lowly paid customs official
who wilI open a container
marked ''radioactive waste''
to verify its contents,
but my personaI favorite
is the unique combination
of week-old potatoes
and tropicaI heat.
( insects buzzing )
It smells.
Sir, sighting of the Kristol
due north.
Most importantly, I kept a number
of intelligence people
on the payrolI to supply
their colleagues
with counterintelligence.
Let's go.
The second rule of gun-running
is always ensure
you have a foolproof way
to get paid.
Preferably in advance,
ideally to an offshore account.
That's why I chose
my customers so carefully.
Say what you like
about warlords and dictators.
They tend to have
a highly developed sense of order.
They always pay their bills
on time.
( speaking Spanish )
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa...
What the fuck are you doing?
- Fuck you!
( screams )
No, V.
Shit.
The first and most important rule
of gunrunning
is never get shot
with your own merchandise.
You okay?
I think so.
- So what do we do now?
- Let's celebrate.
# lf you wanna hang out,
you've got to take her out #
# Cocaine #
- # lf you wanna get down #
- God.
# Down on the ground #
# Cocaine... #
That narco-guerilla
had his facts right.
After shipping it stateside,
the return on that blow
netted me a heaIthy profit.
It would have been better,
except one kilo never made it back.
Vitaly.
Vit.
To this day, I don't know what
Vitaly was running away from.
Maybe just from Vitaly.
I found him 1 2 days,
2,000 miles
and 1 50 grams later
in a Bolivian boarding house.
Of course, my dream girl
had gotten there before me.
# Cocaine... #
V.
# lf your thing is gone
and you wanna ride on #
# Cocaine... #
- Come on.
- # Don't forget this fact #
# You can't get it back #
# Cocaine #
# She don't lie,
she don't lie, she don't lie #
# Cocaine #
Yuri.
It's my brother Yuri.
He's my big brother.
What the fuck is that?
Ukraine. I was young.
But I remember. Look.
I start in Odessa, right?
And then I work my way
to the Crimean.
You're gonna be dead
before you fucking reach Kiev.
- Come on, we're going home.
- You fuck!
You fucking fuck!
What the fuck
is your problem?
( snorting )
Come on, Vit.
It's so nice to be home.
Yeah, we're-- we're gonna get
you home.
Come on.
( sighs )
Get out of the car.
Vitaly, I need you
to get out of the car.
I promised our parents.
Please.
Vitaly, you're gonna have
a great time. This is a top place.
Two Ford models
checked in last week.
And that cute weathergirl's
been here since July.
Please, please.
Please, Yuri.
( snorting )
You're a good brother.
- Okay.
- You're a good brother, Yuri.
- Okay, alI right.
- Good brother.
AlI right,
get out of the car. Okay.
Get out of the car.
Yuri: From then on,
I was a one-man operation.
I never understood what separated
the recreationaI drug user
from the habitual,
but for the grace of God,
it could have been me snorting
lines as long as the BeIt Parkway.
However, I wasn't entirely
free of the grip of addiction myself.
There she was again.
Ava Fontaine.
ln my neighborhood,
they say ''The good get out. ''
ln our own ways,
we both conquered the world.
( woman singing in French )
You can't force someone
to falI in love with you.
But you can definitely
improve your odds.
It cost me 20 grand
to book her for a fake photo shoot.
Another 1 2 to buy out
the hotel.
It's a popular hotel, huh?
- Ava Fontaine.
- Yuri Orlov.
What brings you to St. Bart's?
Photo shoot.
At least that was the plan.
Guess the photographer
got stuck in Miami.
Hurricane, though there's nothing
on the news.
Those things can come
out of nowhere.
So, the job's been canceled,
and wouldn't you know it, there's no flight
back to New York untiI Tuesday.
You can hitch a ride with me if you like.
l'm leaving tomorrow.
Meanwhile, why don't l
take your picture?
Yuri: ln my experience, some
of the most successfuI relationships
are based on lies and deceit.
Since that's where they
usually end up anyway,
it's a logicaI place to start.
Right there. Right there.
Hold it.
Oh my God!
Yuri: I nearly went broke trying
to convince her I was anything but.
I knew Ava was not the kind
of woman to be seduced
by a ride in a private jet
unless you owned the jet.
This is your plane?
That is my name.
Yuri:
Of course I was lying.
The plane was a rentaI like the car
and even the suit I was standing in.
At the last minute I bribed
the crew for the paint job.
Luckily by the time we landed
Ava wasn't looking anywhere
but in my eyes.
I had no idea.
l'm sorry I didn't recognize you.
Don't apologize.
I put clothes on for a living.
WelI at least you're not
taking them off.
I would be if half the photographers
had their way.
What about you?
l'm in transport.
lnternationaI air freight mostly.
Business is good.
Where are you from?
I was born in Ukraine
but I grew up in Brooklyn.
- No.
- What, you too?
Williamsburg.
Well, here's to a hurricane.
Without it I never
would have met you.
This is no accident, is it, Yuri?
It feels like fate.
I don't believe in fate.
What do you believe in?
ls that a view or is that a view?
That's a view.
( people applauding )
Thank you.
Thank you all.
- MazeI tov.
- Congratulations.
Thanks.
Always remember, son,
there's something above you.
Sure, Dad.
A $40,000 crystaI chandelier.
( laughs )
Make yourselves at home.
Go. Go!
l'm sorry.
Today must be tough.
Be nice to have a couple more guests
from my side of the family.
l'm sure they're watching right now.
Thank you.
But you don't believe that, Yuri.
Remember?
I know you, Yuri.
I know you're not
everything you seem.
Don't worry.
I won't ask a lot of questions.
I don't want to hear you lie.
You take risks.
Just...
promise me you won't risk us.
Yuri: That's the trouble with falling
in love with a dream girl.
They have a habit
of becoming real.
l've never been so glad
to see Vitaly.
- So fucking beautiful!
- Oh!
Brother, brother,
thank you so much
for giving me such
a beautifuI sister.
Yuri: He was out of rehab
and out of his mind.
Dance! Dance! Dance!
We have to dance!
- AlI right.
- It's a wedding. A celebration. To Yuri!
Yuri:
But for once, he rescued me.
I was stilI living
way beyond my means.
Mortgaged to the hiIt, using one
credit card to pay off another.
Anything to keep Ava
in the style to which she had,
thanks largely to me,
become accustomed.
Ava!
Ava this is too much.
Yuri likes to spoiI you.
Yuri: Then suddenly
alI my Christmases came at once.
Nicki, you did it!
Good boy!
Ha ha!
That's my grandson!
Yuri, don't you want to see
what your son is doing?
Yuri: Whoever said
it's better to give than receive
never got a Christmas present
like the one I got
in 1 991 from MikhaiI Gorbachev.
- What the hell's the matter?
- It's over! It's over!
- What's over?
- The Cold-fucking-War!
The Soviet-fucking-Union!
The eviI fucking empire.
Mikhail's saying ''no mas.''
He's throwing in the towel.
It's over!
- Your son is walking.
- That's incredible, honey.
At least there'lI be religious freedom.
Let's hope so.
I think l'lI go back for a visit.
Do you stay in touch
with Uncle Dmitri?
l'm not a fool, Yuri.
I don't think you're going
just to selI Pepsi-Cola.
ls this how you want
to be remembered?
( laughs )
I don't want to be
remembered at all.
lf l'm being remembered
it means l'm dead.
Merry fucking Christmas!
( laughing )
Who is this, Vitaly?
- l'm Angel.
- Her name really is Angel.
She's a fairy.
Let's put her on top
of the Christmas tree.
- Vitaly: I love you!
- Come on.
- I love you all.
- ( Nicki crying )
Take this.
l'm going back to Ukraine.
I miss Odessa.
( inhales )
- I miss you.
Be careful, Yuri.
Those things you selI kill.
lnside.
You're high.
Well, that's true.
Hello, Christian.
( ''Soviet National
Anthem'' playing )
Yuri: During the Cold War
the Red Army stationed
nearly one million troops
in Ukraine
because of it's strategic
military importance.
The day after The WalI came down
the paychecks stopped coming.
( speaking Russian )
There's nothing better
for an arms dealer
than the combination
of disgruntled soldiers
and warehouses fulI of weapons.
I was hoping Major General
Dmitri Volkoff
would open a lot of armory doors
in lots of military bases.
For a start, he was family.
He was a highly decorated hero
of the Red Army
and he was almost
permanently shit-faced.
I can't just selI you
government property, Yuri.
I have to report.
Report to who?
Moscow?
As of last week Moscow's
in a foreign country.
New flag, new boss.
There is no new boss yet.
They're alI too busy squabbling
over who's gonna get
the presidentiaI holiday home
at the Black Sea.
It's beautiful.
The ones who know don't care anymore
and the ones who care don't know.
Show me your inventory.
Yuri:
Those 45 years of mutuaI hatred
between the East and the West
had generated
the highest weapons buildup
in history.
The Soviets had guns coming out
of the demon hole.
Huge stockpiles,
and now no enemy.
How many Kalashnikovs
do you have?
40,000.
ls that a four?
Doesn't look like a four to me.
Looks more like a one.
No, it's a four.
It's whatever we say it is because
no one else wilI know the difference.
10,000 Kalashnikovs
for a battalion.
Your stocks are dangerously
depleted, Dmitri.
You should order more
from the factory.
Someone wilI work it out.
What happens then?
We'lI cut them in.
Yuri: The end of the Cold War
was the beginning
of the hottest time
in arms dealing.
The arms bazaar was open.
guided missiles,
unguided missiles,
mortars, mines,
armored personneI carriers.
Whole tank divisions.
I even landed a squadron
of helicopter gunships--
the most sophisticated
fighting machines,
buiIt for a war with America
that never happened.
Thanks to me, they'd finally
get to fire a shot in anger.
I have a feeling it wasn't exactly
what comrade Lenin
had in mind when he advocated
the redistribution of weaIth.
But I wasn't the only one offering
a crash course in capitalism.
I had rivals.
lnform your commanding officer that
Simeon Weisz is here to meet him.
You don't know who I am, do you?
You're late.
So it appears.
( speaks Russian )
( imitates gunshot )
You look a little lost, Simeon.
ls the world changing too fast?
l'm here, aren't l?
Not alI of you, I think.
You've gotten so rich
selling for the ClA
you can't seem to get that ideology
completely out of your head.
Oh, the Cold War had its uses.
Kept attentions frozen.
Now it's harder to determine
which side one's on.
Things have become more complicated.
No, it's gotten simpler.
There's no place in gunrunning
for politics anymore, Simeon.
I selI to leftists and rightists.
l'd selI to pacifists but they're not
the most regular of customers.
Of course you're not
a true internationalist
untiI you've supplied weapons
to kilI your own countrymen.
This current state of chaos
won't last forever.
There'lI have to be order.
lnstead of cutting
each other's throats,
it may be beneficiaI if we work together.
What do you think?
What do I think?
I think you're the amateur now.
I think you should go with your instincts.
With your first instinct.
l'm the same man who was not
good enough for you before
and l'm just not good enough
for you now.
The problem with gunrunners
going to war...
is that there's no shortage
of ammunition.
Yuri: This was the chaos
that the Old Guard had always feared.
As far as they were concerned I was
giving arms dealers a bad name.
But then they could hardly report me
to the Better Business Bureau.
And Ukraine
wasn't the only former state
with an unpaid army
and stockpiles of guns.
There was Bulgaria, Hungary,
Poland, Belarus,
alI there for the taking.
Of alI the weapons
in the vast Soviet arsenal
nothing was more profitable
than Avtomat Kalashnikova,
modeI of 1 947
more commonly known
as the AK-47 or Kalashnikov.
It's the world's
most popular assauIt rife.
A weapon alI fighters love.
An elegantly simple
9-lb. amalgamation
of forged steeI and plywood.
It doesn't break, jam, or overheat.
It wilI shoot whether it's covered
in mud or filled with sand.
It's so easy even a child
can use it, and they do.
The Soviets put the gun on a coin.
Mozambique put it on their flag.
Since the end of the Cold War
the Kalashnikov has become
the Russian people's greatest export.
After that comes vodka, caviar
and suicidaI novelists.
One thing's for sure.
No one was lining up
to buy their cars.
I thought you were supposed to be
watching out for these people.
How can l?
You keep selling my helicopters.
You are too greedy, Yuri.
I can't hold him forever.
- l've got paperwork.
- Not for the gunships.
You know the penaIty
for sanction-busting.
Selling the military helicopter
is a major violation.
Military helicopter.
It's not a military helicopter.
It's a rescue helicopter.
Get to work, son.
The law is on our side.
AlI right, let me see your papers.
No, no, put that away.
Let's see your papers.
- Yuri Orlov.
- Mr. Orlov.
Always in the wrong place
at the right time.
We've met before.
Off the coast of Columbia.
What was the name of that freighter?
I can't remember.
Was it Kono
or the Kristol?
The crew called
that vesseI a lot of names,
none of them repeatable
in polite company.
- Answer the question.
- The new MP-5.
Would you like a silencer for that?
I need to see your papers.
Dmitri!
the end-user certificate
for this aircraft
states ''Burkina Faso.''
Nice. Very nice.
Did you type this up yourself?
The helicopter is to be used
on humanitarian missions.
- Oh, so you're a humanitarian?
- Oh, absolutely.
( laughs )
This is a military aircraft.
- Not anymore.
- Listen to the nephew.
What can they do with military hardware
but convert it to civilian use?
The only way you could die from this
baby now is if a food drop hits you.
And this stuff over here?
ls that going to Burkina Faso as well?
Ah, but to a different client
at a different address.
Just a coincidence, is that it? Do you
take me for a complete fucking fool?
Not complete, sir.
And while I hesitate to telI you your job,
I must point out
that when shipped separately
the weapons and the aircraft
both comply
with the current lnterpol
trade standards and practices.
We both know that is an obscene
bureaucratic loophole
that's gonna be closed
any goddamn day.
But it's not closed.
And while certain people might
interpret this cargo as suspicious,
thank God we live in a world where
suspicion alone does not constitute crime.
And where men like you
respect the rule of law.
Yuri: I was as guiIty as sin,
but Valentine couldn't prove it.
And he was the rarest breed
of law enforcement officer.
The type who knew
I was breaking the law
but wouldn't break it himself
to bust me.
Valentine wasn't the only one trying
to put me out of business.
My uncle had turned down
a half dozen rival arms dealers.
Sometimes with offers
better than mine.
But to Dmitri, you couldn't
put a price on loyalty.
- What was he doing here?
- He is hoping to beat your offer.
I told him to go have
intercourse with himself.
- But Yuri--
- You need to make more payoffs.
- Too many know.
- Don't worry.
There are more VCRs, cigarettes.
I left them in your new car.
Even your enemy
was admiring that car.
( laughing )
I am the luckiest man alive.
You are.
( phone ringing )
- Hello?
- Ava?
Hi, baby.
You forget what time it is?
l'm sorry, l--
how was that--
your audition?
They're going in another direction.
Direction of someone who can act.
They don't deserve you.
Where are you?
is everything okay?
It was a rough day
at the office.
- Come home.
- Soon.
- How's Nicki?
- He misses you.
We both do.
It's lonely without you here.
You know I don't like nights.
Ever since my parents.
( gunfire )
Yuri, what's that?
A party.
I better go.
Just wanted to call
and hear your voice.
- Kiss Nicki for me.
- I love you.
( diaI tone )
Yuri:
The pillaging didn't die with my uncle.
After The WalI came down
$32 billion dollars
worth of arms were stolen
and resold from Ukraine alone.
One of the greatest heists
of the 20th century.
The primary market was Africa.
1 1 major conflicts
involving 32 countries
in less than a decade.
A gunrunner's wet dream.
At the time,
the West couldn't care less.
They had a white war in what
was left of Yugoslavia.
I did the bulk of my business
in Liberia.
''Land of the Free. ''
Originally established as a homeland
for freed American slaves,
it's been enslaved by one dictator
or another ever since.
The latest was American-educated
self-declared president
Andre Baptiste.
- Mr. Yuri!
- ( engine revs )
l'm Andre Baptiste Jr.
My father would like to meet you.
What an honor.
Thank him, but unfortunately
I have other business.
It's a shame.
It's a very busy schedule.
( laughing )
It is not...
as they say, optional.
My father is easily offended.
My schedule just freed up.
Whoo!
Yuri: President Baptiste
was my best customer
but I was in no hurry to meet him.
He's gotten a reputation
for routinely hacking off the limbs
of those who opposed him.
His seven-year civiI war
has been described as
a relentless campaign
of sadistic wanton violence.
That kind of sums up Andy for me.
( engine revs )
The Glock is interesting.
It's made of a polymer composite.
Many of my clients feeI they can
get through airport security
without setting off a lot
of bells and whistles.
Personally,
I do not recommend that.
On the other hand, if you are looking
for a traditionaI wheeI gun,
there is no substitute for
the six inches of muzzle energy
of the .357 Magnum.
And of course, it wilI never jam.
Why'd you do that?!
What did you say?
WelI now you're gonna have to buy it.
It's a used gun.
( cocking guns )
How can I selI a used gun?
( chuckles )
A used gun.
That's a good one.
( laughs )
You know, there is no discipline
with the youth today.
I try to set an example
but it is difficuIt.
Personally, I blame MTV.
( distant gunfire )
A used gun.
( laughs )
I think you and l,
we can do business.
Yuri: lf I thought
I was scared of Andre Sr.,
I knew I was scared of Andre Jr.
Like father like son.
The guava doesn't fall
too far from the tree.
He was also a cannibal.
They say Andre would eat a victim's
heart while it was stilI beating
to give him superhuman strength.
( gunfire )
Monrovia itself was like
being on another planet.
Planet Monrovia.
From the temperature, it was
obviously a planet close to the sun.
I rarely saw another white man
and I never left town alone.
Outside town was the edge of hell.
I didn't want to even gaze into it.
Andre Jr.:
This is your hotel.
Two stars.
Can you bring me the gun of Rambo?
Part one, two or three?
- l've only seen part one.
- The M-60.
Would you like
the armor piercing bullets?
Please.
My father left a welcoming
present in your room.
Enjoy.
( laughs )
( gunfire )
( man speaking French
on TV)
My God,
she nearly got her head cut off.
When I get to America,
I wilI not live in Brentwood.
Second floor.
Yuri: ln the most AlDS
infested region of the globe,
where one in four is infected,
Andre's idea of a joke
was to put a young lman
and a young Naomi in my bed
and no condom within 100 miles.
# Yes #
# Give me a reason
to love you... #
( clears throat )
# Give me a reason... #
Hello, Mr. Yuri.
Hi.
We'd be happy to make you happy.
Uh...
I can't.
l'd love to,
but I can't.
Don't worry.
We don't have anything.
Oh.
How do you know?
Do we look like it?
What if I have AlDS?
Don't you worry?
- ( distant gunfire )
- ( laughs )
You worry too much.
Why do you worry about something
that can kilI you in 10 years
when there's so many things
that can kilI you today?
Now...
how can we make you happy?
# Give me a reason
to love you... #
- By leaving.
- ( music stops )
( exhales )
Andre:
These are my Kalashnikov Kids,
my Boy Brigades.
I can see what you are thinking,
but we need every man we can get.
Even if they're not men?
A bullet from a 14-year-old
is just as effective
as one from a 40-year-old.
Often more effective.
No one can stop this bath of blood.
It's not bath of blood,
it's bloodbath.
( chuckles )
Thank you,
but I prefer it my way.
I am not going to pay
your asking price.
We are not a rich people.
And besides,
the market is already flooded
with your Kalashnikovs.
Do you realize in some parts
of my country
you can get one
for the price of a chicken?
But you can't just look at the unit price.
You forget ancillary costs.
End-user certificates need
to be forged and notarized.
ShelI companies set up, insurance
purchased, pilots and crews hired.
Not to mention the bribes.
You can't get a nut and boIt out
of the Eastern Bloc without a bribe.
There's one bribe for the nut,
another for the boIt.
Andy, Andy, listen to me.
This is an expensive proposition
Andy?
I am going to pay you in timber.
Or stones.
Well, l'lI take the stones.
It's kind of hard to get a tree trunk
into my hand luggage.
I know you're planning
a new offensive.
lf you can delay a week I can get you
armored personneI carriers.
They'd greatly reduce
your casuaIties
and give you a significant
strategic advantage.
You know, they calI me
the Lord of War,
but perhaps it is you.
It's not Lord of War.
It's Warlord.
Thank you,
but I prefer it my way.
( laughs )
Yuri: Conflict diamonds are
a common currency in West Africa.
Also referred to
as blood diamonds,
since bloodshed is what
they generally finance.
By the late '90s, my weaIth
had caught up
to my lies about my weaIth.
Even surpassed my lies.
I could even afford to become
a patron of the arts.
I can't believe it.
Well, of course
it's wonderful. I just--
I didn't expect it
to happen so soon.
Yes, well, that--
well, that would
be great, too, yeah.
It's wonderful.
Thank you so much.
It's-- Yuri.
Okay, thank you. Bye.
Yuri, that was the dealer on the phone.
I just sold my first painting.
That's fantastic!
( laughing )
Who bought it?
Someone important.
They wanna remain anonymous.
- This is so wonderful.
- Yeah, how was your trip?
You know, same old, same old.
Where's Nicki?
ln bed. l'm sorry.
He couldn't stay up.
- Well, that's best.
- My first painting.
l'm officially an artist.
- This calls for a drink.
- What doesn't?
Hi.
- Yuri, this is, uh, uh...
- Candy.
- Candy, of course.
- Hi.
Any friend of my brother's
is a friend of my brother's.
You have a beautifuI everything.
Yes, he does.
Yes, I do.
- l'm gonna kiss Nicki good night.
- Okay.
How are you, brother?
Oh, you know,
stilI the resident family fuck up.
Yeah, well, I guess
someone has to do it.
Yeah.
Hey, Ava knows, right?
I never want to say anything.
She doesn't have to know.
She understands.
She's a survivor, like me.
Well, she may be a survivor,
but she's not like you.
Really, she doesn't know how
you pay for alI this?
We don't talk about it.
How many car salesmen
talk about their work, huh?
How many cigarette salesmen?
Both their products
kilI more people every year
than mine.
At least mine
has a safety switch.
lf those guys can leave
their work at the office, so can l.
Goddamn, you are good.
You really are.
You almost had me convinced.
Could you, uh...
could you help me out
with some...
Why?
Why what?
- Why, why, why, why?
- I don't know. I don't know.
Why what?
Why are you so fucked up
alI the time?
Because I am.
Yuri: I didn't know how much
Ava really knew
and how much she ignored.
She never questioned how a guy
in the transport business
could afford to give her
1 8-karat diamond earrings.
I guess she didn't really want
to hear the answer.
Mostly, she seemed content
that I was a good provider,
and as far as she
was concerned, loyal.
Despite the other women,
I always made love to Ava
as if she was the only one.
l'm not saying
I didn't have setbacks.
It's not called
''gunrunning'' for nothing.
You gotta be fast
on your feet.
Some revolutions blow over
before the guns even get there.
There's nothing more expensive
for an arms dealer than peace.
Truce?
What do you mean truce?
The guns are already
on their way.
Peace talks.
AlI right, forget it.
l'lI reroute the shipment to the Balkans.
When they say they're gonna
have a war, they keep their word.
Yuri: Of course,
a new breed of gun-runner
requires a new breed
of cop.
Henry, take Park Avenue.
( helicopter whirring )
( horns honk )
Take 'em on a tour
of New Jersey.
( celI phone ringing )
Ava: Yuri...
there are men
going through our garbage cans.
It's probably just some reporters
looking for somebody else.
I have a feeling
they don't work for the tabloids.
Yuri...
is there anything
I should be worried about?
No, nothing.
- Nothing.
- I love you.
I love you too.
Sir.
Yuri: I was now the best
merchant of death alive.
I didn't own my own plane.
I owned a fleet.
Running guns into Liberia,
Sierra Leone or the lvory Coast
at least once a week.
Most trips, I had phony paperwork.
lf the deadline was tight
and I had to cut corners,
I had no paperwork at all.
But I wasn't overly concerned.
There was hardly any radar
over most of Africa,
and even fewer people
to watch it.
Valentine: Charlie, Echo, lndia.
Reroute to Kabala airport
on heading 0-2-9.
Comply immediately.
( celI phone rings )
ColoneI Southern, it's Yuri.
l'm sorry to calI you on this number,
but l've got lnterpol
alI over my ass.
I can't know you right now.
It's not a good time.
Not a good time?
( alarm sounding )
Charlie, Echo, lndia,
comply immediately.
This is your last warning.
Where was the first
fucking warning?
Rock your wings
if you intend to comply.
l'm putting us down.
lf you land, we're alI going away.
I don't have paperwork.
- We're in a flying fucking bomb.
- They're firing bullets at our bullets.
l'm putting us down.
Okay, okay, fuck!
This is Charlie, Echo, lndia.
Request to reroute
to Kabala airport on bearing 0-2-9.
No, not the airport. There, the highway.
It's our only hope.
Are you fucking mad?
A pothole wilI set us off.
You underestimate yourself,
Alexei.
You're the best.
You're the shit, Alexei. You're the shit!
You're the shit!
Yuri: Of course,
Alexei wasn't the best.
He'd come 42nd out of 43
at the Moscow Flight School.
Oh, God, what's he doing?
ls this guy nuts?
I can't land there, sir.
Kabala's only 15 minutes away.
He can't get far.
I want a truck on the tarmac.
( speaks Russian )
( sighs )
We're gonna be okay.
Yuri: Where you going?
As far from the evidence
as we can get.
Wait, there's not gonna be
any evidence.
Come here, come here.
Hey, don't be shy.
Here, look. Free sample.
Help yourself, okay?
Free sample. TelI your friends.
Come here.
You want something? Look.
Want an RPG?
AlI for you. AlI right?
Happy times. Come on.
Help yourselves.
No charge.
Everything goes.
Guns, guns, guns.
Yeah, come on up!
Yeah, having fun now, huh?
Come on.
Guns, guns, guns! Yeah!
Bullets, guns, grenades.
Hooray, yeah, take 'em all.
Take the whole crate.
Go ahead, take the crate.
Everybody, come on.
Guns, grenades, hooray!
Bullets, guns, grenades!
Yeah!
That one's got
your name on it.
You want one, too? Come on.
We got bullets.
Don't forget the bullets.
How can you shoot a gun
if you don't have bullets?
Everything goes for free.
Guns, grenades, RPGs,
bullets, guns, yeah!
Hooray, hooray!
Want some bullets?
Gotta have bullets.
What a cargo crew at
Heathrow Airport does in a day
took a bunch of malnourished
Sierra Leonean locals 10 minutes.
By the time Agent Valentine
got there,
you could find more guns
on a plane fulI of Quakers.
Yuri Orlov.
- Ow, fuck!
- You run from us?
No, Mbizi, no.
Can he run with no legs?
Let me make him disappear, Mr. Valentine.
Around here, people disappear alI the time.
- I can't do that.
- Look where we are.
Who wilI know?
We will.
He's gonna get
what's coming to him.
l'm not as certain.
( coughs )
AlI right, get up.
- What's the charge?
- What are you doing in Sierra Leone?
- l'm on safari.
- Yeah, you're hunting wildebeests
- with a submachine gun?
- Do you also work with the Park Service?
Hunting without a license.
ls that the charge?
Why are we playing games?
You traffic arms.
- Trade.
- Trade, traffic.
You get rich by giving
the poorest people on the planet
the means to continue
killing each other.
Do you know why I do
what I do?
I mean, there are more
prestigious assignments.
Keeping track
of nuclear arsenals.
You'd think that more critical
to world security, but it's not.
No, nine out of 10
war victims today
are killed with assauIt rifles
and smalI arms like yours.
Those nuclear missiles,
they sit in their silos.
Your AK-47, that is the reaI weapon
of mass destruction.
I don't want people dead,
Agent Valentine.
I don't put a gun to anybody's
head and make them shoot.
I admit, a shooting war's
better for business,
but I prefer people to fire
my guns and miss,
just as long as they're firing.
Can I go now?
You've got nothing on me.
Except cuffs.
Since you're so concerned
with the law,
you must know l'm legally permitted
to hold you for 24 hours
without charging you.
You might ask why I would do that.
And I can assure you it's not because
I enjoy your company,
because I don't.
No.
The reason why I wilI delay you
for every second
of the permissible 24 hours
is I am delaying
your deadly trade
and the deaths of your victims.
I don't think of it as taking a day
from you, but giving a day to them.
Some innocent man, woman or child
is going to have
an extra day on this earth
because you're not free.
So, I wilI see you...
in 23 hours
and 55 minutes, huh?
( jeeps start up )
Yuri: Valentine knew
he didn't have to guard me.
There was nowhere to go.
Or maybe he was hoping
the locals would tear me apart.
But they were too busy with the plane.
It's like parking your car in certain
neighborhoods in the Bronx.
You just don't do it.
The way I look at it,
it's the way of Africa,
maybe life.
Everything that comes from the earth
eventually returns.
Even a 40-ton
Atonov-1 2 cargo plane.
A gift for you.
You know,
you've arrived just in time.
I was afraid that he might die
before you got your chance
to kilI him.
This man came here
hoping to take your place.
ls that not so?
No, l'm not here
to supply Mr. Baptiste.
I am here to supply his enemies.
I fear it's a sale
I shalI never complete.
He killed your blood.
Your uncle,
when he tried to kilI you.
- ( whispers ) No.
- No?
You want that I should let him go?
- No, l--
- ''No no, l--''
You do want him dead.
You just...
don't want to have to do it yourself.
So...
we wilI do this together.
This wilI be
a bonding experience.
You know that you can stop this
anytime that you want.
But I don't think that you do.
Just say the word.
Say ''stop.''
( whispers )
Stop.
( laughs )
I wilI get you another room,
my friend.
With a much nicer view.
( African dance music playing )
He ordered you brown-brown,
Mr. Yuri.
- What?
- Brown-brown.
- What is it?
-It's a mixture of cocaine
and gunpowder.
They give it to the young boys
before they do battle.
- They do anything.
- ( groans )
Some other time.
I suggest you try it
at least once, Mr. Yuri.
Why?
Because it's your gunpowder.
( laughs )
AlI right.
Yuri:
Even before that night
I started doing a lot of cocaine
in West Africa.
l'd never tried
brown-brown before.
But then I never killed a man either.
( children shouting )
Here we go.
Come on!
( children cheer )
( laughing )
( groaning )
Oh, I didn't do anything,
did l?
( speaking French )
Wait, are you sick?
SlDA?
AlDS?
Ask the white man.
He wilI know.
Sir, wilI my hand grow back?
( ghostly howling )
- Simeon?
- Remember, Yuri.
Take sides.
Simeon!
- ( groans )
- Don't! He's Andre's.
- Fuck Andre.
- Yeah, fuck Andre.
( gun clicks )
l'm sorry.
they don't usually do that.
( gun clicks )
Well, let me look at it.
Maybe I can fix it
Let me see it.
It's the magazine. Give it to me.
- ( groans )
- Fuck you!
( growling )
Yuri:
I started to feeI l'd been cursed.
The curse of invincibility.
( imitating gunshots )
Nicki, please go to your room.
I don't believe you.
Can you prove any of this?
Mr. Orlov goes to a lot of trouble
to make his business
look legitimate.
Even to you.
Perhaps especially to you.
I don't expect we're gonna find
anything here today.
So what do you want?
I was hoping that you would help me.
I understand that, uh...
your parents died tragically.
The illegaI firearms used
to murder your mother and father
were procured from men
exactly like your husband.
l'd like you to leave.
Okay.
Gentlemen.
( door opens, shuts )
Ava?
Ava. what's wrong?
I can't wear the clothes.
I can't wear the jewelry.
I can't drive the car.
Can't live in this house.
Everything's got blood on it.
Blood on it?
What's the matter with you?
- Don't be so melodramatic.
- Of course l'm melodramatic.
l'm a failed actress, remember?
I told you,
these people, it's political.
They lie.
They're liars.
Look at me. Look. They lie to make
themselves look good, okay?
You can't--
you can't trust them.
It's not just them.
Don't worry.
Your family didn't say anything.
They didn't have to.
I selI people a means
to defend themselves, Ava.
That's all.
Yuri, I see the news.
I see those pictures.
The guns are bigger than the boys.
There is nothing illegaI about what I do.
I don't care if it's legal.
It's wrong.
Please stop.
It makes no difference if I stop.
Someone wilI take my place
the next day.
So let them.
We have enough.
It's not about the money.
Then what is it?
l'm good at it.
I feeI like alI l've done
my whole life is be pretty.
I mean,
alI l've done is be born.
l'm a failed actress,
a failed artist.
l'm not much good as a mother.
Come to think of it,
l'm not even that pretty anymore.
I have failed at everything, Yuri.
But I won't faiI as a human being.
Yuri: My enemies had finally found
a weapon that could hurt me.
For the next six months
I stopped running guns.
- I went legitimate.
- This is an untapped market.
l'm talking over five million cubic meters
of timber in the first year alone.
Over 100 exploitable species.
The oil? Between you and me,
this is the new Texas.
What do you say to over
10,000 barrels a month?
He must be lying.
He's talking.
There's gas reserves off the lvory Coast
that OPEC doesn't know about.
The phone numbers alI check out.
It's alI on the level.
Yuri:
No wonder Valentine was confused.
( church bells ringing )
Thank God
there are stilI legaI ways
to exploit developing countries.
But the only problem
with an honest buck
is they're so hard to make.
The margins are too low.
Too many people are doing it.
Still, l'd promised Ava.
Yuri, the president of Liberia
is on his way up.
He's early.
- l'lI be back in a minute.
- Okay.
What the fuck
are you doing here, Andre?
We are here for peace talks
at the United Nations.
So at the same time you thought
you'd drop in on your arms dealer?
WelI I was beginning to wonder
whether that was stilI your profession.
You know you're a hard man
to get a hold of alI of a sudden.
That is a shame.
My son and l, we were hoping
to do a little shopping
- while we are here in New York.
- You know they're watching you.
Yes, I know they blame me. They blame
me for everything, those hypocrites.
- They're on a hunt for a witch.
- Witch-hunt.
Hostilities have escalated.
They are making it very difficuIt
for me to resupply.
That requires a man
of your rare ingenuity.
I can't help you.
l'm sorry.
I understand.
But you should know this.
Due to our present situation
we are compelled
to be unusually generous.
So see you soon,
Lord of War.
You stilI haven't brought me
the gun of Rambo.
( laughs )
Yuri:
At four and a half months old
a human fetus has a reptile's tail--
a remnant of our evolution.
Maybe that's what I couldn't escape.
You can fight
a lot of enemies and survive.
But if you fight your biology
you wilI always lose.
You guys aren't waiting to say goodbye?
l'm not leaving for another 10 minutes.
- Sorry, Nicki has swim practice.
- Oh, okay.
You know, l'm kind of glad
you're going.
You've been here so long
you're starting to get on my nerves.
This oiI concession should be
wrapped up by Thursday.
l'lI be back for the weekend.
We'lI go somewhere.
- The sea.
- That would be fun.
- Come on.
- Hey.
You trust me, right?
Yuri: She looked me directly
in the eye the way l've looked in the eyes
of a thousand customs officials,
government bureaucrats
and law enforcement agents.
Yes, I trust you.
And she lied without flinching.
- l'lI see you, big guy.
- Bye, Papa.
Yuri:
She learned from the best.
Have a good trip.
# But you don't really care
for music #
# Do you? #
# Baby, l've been here before #
# l've seen this room
and l've walked this floor you know #
- # I used to live alone... #
- That's him.
# Before I knew you #
# And l've seen your flag
on the marble arch #
# And love is not a victory march #
# It's a cold and it's a broken #
# Hallelujah #
# Hallelujah... #
- Where are we going, Mama?
- It's a game, honey.
Like hide and seek?
Yes.
Like hide and seek.
# Maybe there's a God above #
# But alI l've ever learned from love #
# Was how to shoot somebody #
# Who got to you... #
Yuri: I can always sense
when l'm being tailed.
I know what to look for.
But then l've never been tailed
by the woman I love.
# It's not somebody
who's seen the light... #
- ( helicopter circling )
- # It's a cold and it's a broken #
# Hallelujah #
# Hallelujah... #
Yuri:
I can put myself in Ava's place.
She might have understood
if the combination
was the last four digits
of my sociaI security number,
my birthday, even her birthday.
But not Nicolai's.
My son's birthday unlocked what
the government would later describe
as a catalogue of carnage.
Honey, come over here.
Nicki, stay right here.
Come on, Nicki.
( train rattling )
Come to see
how the other half lives?
I miss your borscht.
- Mom and Dad say you're clean.
- Yeah, you too.
You went legit, huh?
That's hard to believe.
That's because it's not true.
Only you know.
l'm leaving tonight on a job.
I want you to come.
I can't.
l've got a girlfriend.
I think she might be the one.
Plus l'm thinking
of opening my own place.
Maybe this trip wilI help.
It's good money.
Yuri...
l've given my word.
No one has to know.
We'lI telI them we're going
for a little R&R.
What do you need me for
alI of a sudden?
West Africa's fucked up.
More than usual.
I can't trust anybody.
I need you to watch my back.
( woman singing
in African language )
Yuri.
Welcome back.
Welcome, both of you.
Welcome to democracy.
Democracy?
What have you been drinking, Andy?
You have not seen the news.
You know, they accuse me
of rigging elections.
But after this,
with your Florida
and your Supreme Court
of kangaroos, now
the US must shut up forever.
( laughs )
How do you do this, Yuri, huh?
How do you do this
when they are watching
alI of my airspace?
- Where there's a wilI there's a weapon.
- ( laughs )
Come on, where's my fucking money?
When it is delivered.
- It is delivered.
- This is not for me.
This is for my neighbors to the west.
Vitaly:
The west?
We're going to Sierra Leone.
Oh yes.
And my son,
Baptiste Jr. wilI go with you
to make the proper introductions.
- We have no trucks.
- You will...
as soon as we get
the food out of them.
The gun of Rambo.
Mr. Yuri, you are a man
of your word.
- So where are we going?
- RUF.
The Freedom Fighters.
- ( laughing )
- ( gunfire )
Yuri: Every faction in Africa calls
themselves by these noble names
Liberation-this,
Patriotic-that,
Democratic Republic
of something-or-other.
Yeah!
( laughing )
I guess they can't own up
to what they usually are--
Federation of Worse Oppressors
Than the Last Bunch of Oppressors.
( whooping )
Often, the most barbaric
atrocities occur
when both combatants proclaim
themselves freedom fighters.
Right, l've got 500 units,
brand new
right out of the box
alI as clean as this.
What have you got?
( woman shouting )
( mob clamoring )
God!
Oh Jesus!
Yuri, I need to talk to you.
- Not now.
- Now!
Excuse me.
What?
- We can't do this deal.
- The fuck we can't.
- What's the matter with you?
- Look. Look over there.
AS soon as we hand over the guns
those people are going to die.
It's not our business.
They killed a boy just now
as young as Nicki.
- What is the holdup?
- There is no holdup.
l'lI be right there.
Vitaly, it's what we always know.
We can't controI what they do.
No no, today we can.
Today we can.
Yuri, they're right there!
What do you think they'lI do
to us if we back out? They'lI kilI us.
And if we go ahead,
what do you think they'lI do to them?
We got to do something.
What is he saying?
It's the, uh, deal.
My brother's not happy with the terms,
but we're working it out. It's nothing.
Right?
It's nothing.
Yeah, nothing.
You're right, Yuri.
You're right.
God, l've got to get my shit together.
Uh, this is not our fight.
Right.
Okay, what's the deal?
300 RPGs,
500 assauIt rifles
and 800 grenades.
I thought it was 1 200 grenades.
Yuri:
I was so caught up in the deal
I never realized what
was going on in Vitaly's head.
I thought it was 1 200 grenades.
Confused.
Yuri: Come to think about it,
maybe I never understood
what was going on in his head.
I beg your pardon.
May I see another stone?
Yuri:
One thing I do understand for certain
is that Vitaly broke
the cardinaI rule of gunrunning.
Never pick up a gun
and join the customers.
What are you doing?
Something for Yuri.
Step away.
Slow.
( grunts )
No, Vit!
( gasps )
Yuri:
Only half the guns were gone
so I was stilI entitled
to half the diamonds.
lf I took them, I was lost.
lf I left them, I was lost.
The massacre played out
exactly how Vitaly predicted.
But then a half dozen other massacres
happened in Sierra Leone that week.
You can't stop them all.
ln my experience,
you can't stop any of them.
( gunfire )
They say ''eviI prevails
when good men faiI to act. ''
What they ought to say
is ''eviI prevails. ''
( gunfire continues )
I now shared
even more in common
with the leader of that country
God seemed to have forsaken.
We saw something in each other
neither one of us liked.
Or maybe we were
just looking in the mirror.
l'd paid a Monrovian doctor $20
to remove the lead
from Vitaly's body
and write a bogus death certificate.
I should have paid more.
l've smuggled millions
of rounds of ammunition
and the bullet that lands me in jail
is found under my dead brother's rib.
Yuri Orlov.
We're with the Bureau of Alcohol,
Tobacco and Firearms.
Let me guess. This isn't about
the alcohoI or the tobacco.
( phone ringing )
- Crimean Restaurant.
- Papa?
Both my sons are dead.
Yuri:
There are only two tragedies in life.
One is not getting what you want.
The other is getting it.
Valentine:
ls this one of yours?
Yuri: Jack Valentine finally had
what he wanted.
Curiously, the death certificate
says he died of heart failure.
Falsifying a death certificate?
That's not going to hold me.
( chuckles )
You're right.
As usual,
you are right.
Have you seen today's paper?
Huh?
Fake end-user certificates.
Cut-out companies,
meticulously catalogued.
There is hardly a warlord,
dictator or despot
anywhere in the world that you're not
on a first-name basis with.
It was your wife,
your trophy wife,
that led us to the prize.
It's not her fauIt.
She's just easier to follow than you are.
- May l?
- Yeah, go ahead.
( chuckles )
Enjoy it.
- What?
- This.
TelI me l'm everything you despise.
That l'm the personification of evil.
That l'm, what, responsible
for the breakdown
of the fabric of society
and world order.
l'm a one-man genocide.
Say everything
you want to say to me now.
'Cause you don't have long.
Are you paying attention?
Or are you delusional?
You have broken
every arms embargo written.
There is enough evidence
here to put you away
for consecutive life sentences.
You are going to spend
the next 10 years of your life
going from a celI to a courtroom
before you even start
serving your time.
I don't think you fully appreciate
the seriousness of your situation.
My family has disowned me.
My wife and son have left me.
My brother's dead.
Trust me,
I fully appreciate
the seriousness
of my situation.
But I promise you,
I won't spend a single second
in a courtroom.
( scoffs )
You are delusional.
I like you, Jack.
Well, maybe not,
but I understand you.
Let me telI you what's gonna happen.
This way you can prepare yourself.
( chuckles )
Okay.
Soon there's gonna be a knock on
that door and you wilI be called outside.
ln the halI there wilI be a man
who outranks you.
First, he'lI compliment you
on the fine job you've done,
that you're making the world
a safer place,
that you're to receive a commendation
and a promotion.
And then he's going to telI you
that I am to be released.
You're going to protest.
You'lI probably threaten
to resign.
But in the end
I wilI be released.
The reason l'lI be released
is the same reason
you think l'lI be convicted.
I do rub shoulders
with some of the most vile,
sadistic men calling
themselves leaders today.
But some of those men
are the enemies of your enemies.
And while the biggest arms dealer
in the world is your boss,
the President of the United States,
who ships more merchandise
in a day than I do in a year...
sometimes it's embarrassing to have
his fingerprints on the guns.
Sometimes he needs
a freelancer like me
to supply forces
he can't be seen supplying.
So...
you calI me evil.
But unfortunately for you,
l'm a necessary evil.
( knock on door )
I would telI you to go to hell,
but I think you're already there.
Pleasure doing business with you.
Yuri: Most people are happy
just to get out of jail.
I expect to be paid to leave.
l'm not a fool.
I know that just because they
needed me that day
didn't mean they wouldn't make me
a scapegoat the next.
But I was back
doing what I do best.
You know who's going
to inherit the Earth?
Arms dealers.
Because everyone else
is too busy killing each other.
That's the secret to survival.
Never go to war.
Especially with yourself.
( score playing )
( woman singing
in African language )