Daddy, it's 7:30!
Daddy, it's 7:30.
Daddy, wake up!
Morning, Daddy.
Come on, wake up.
Wake up. Come on, wake up.
There's your coffee, right there.
Oh, where am I?
Here, I want you to drink this.
Then I want you to take a shower.
Then I want you to get dressed.
There are your clothes, right there.
And then I want you to go to see
the woman about the job, okay?
- Today, you promised.
- I know.
What would I do without you
nagging me all the time?
You really want me to answer that?
God, I've been getting in
kind of late lately.
We haven't had a chance to talk
or anything.
Oh, don't worry about it.
There hasn't been a lot to say.
- Is everything all right with you?
- Yeah.
- Is school good?
- No, but it never is.
- Have you been asked to the prom?
- No.
Not yet.
When was the last time I told you
how beautiful you are?
About yesterday.
- Hey, hey, turn around.
- What?
You know what.
Come here, let me see this outfit.
- And is this your latest creation?
- This is it.
My God, what did that cost you?
Oh, about $15 for the shoes,
secondhand, and I made the rest.
Unbelievable.
I was thinking maybe
that you could do something with this.
- Maybe put some ruffles up here.
- Come on, get up! No, really, I mean it.
This means a lot to me.
Honey, I'm perfectly happy
with what I'm doing.
You're perfectly happy
with part-time work?
No, that's why I'm getting up.
Okay. I'll make you some breakfast.
I'm up!
- Hi, Blane.
- Hi, Kate. How you doing?
- Fine. How are you?
- Good.
Good morning!
Welcome to another day
of higher education.
Hi, Duckie. How are you?
Not all that bad,
considering I'm in this dump.
You know, this is a really
volcanic ensemble you're wearing.
It's really marvelous.
- Volcanic?
- Well, you know, hot, dangerous.
Are you gonna go to class today?
Well, I don't know
if I'm emotionally ready.
- Oh, go for it. It's virtually painless.
- Excuse me.
- I gotta go, okay? I'll see you at lunch.
- Okay, well, listen,
I'll call ahead to the cafeteria
and make a couple of reservations.
- You know, two by the window.
- Sure.
Well, no. You don't like to sit in the sun.
Okay, something else.
Listen, may I admire you again today?
Ladies, ladies, listen,
I may be able to work out a deal
where either one or the both of you
could be pregnant by the holidays.
What do you say?
Some argue that the New Deal
saved the capitalist system.
And as evidence
that the Roosevelt administration
was trying to avoid
excessive governmental power
rather than implant socialism,
in his first act as President,
Mr. Roosevelt enacted
the Emergency Banking Act,
and he refused
to consider nationalization.
Where'd you get your clothes,
five-and-dime store?
Attractive.
Is there a problem, ladies?
- No.
Andie, is there something going on
between you and these ladies?
No, not that I'm aware of.
I'd like to apologize on behalf
of Miss Trombley and Miss Hanson.
These two young ladies will be thinking
of you tonight
as they write a summary of the chapters
that we've just covered.
Great.
- Excuse me.
- Yeah.
There's nothing wrong with me.
I mean, I'm fine.
Can you just forget about the chapter?
Yes?
We'll take the chapter.
Fine, let's go on.
The Emergency Banking Act.
I'll see you guys later.
- Hey, see ya.
- Bye.
Oh, Andie, you look ravishing.
So we graduate in a month.
Now, I want to know when it is
that you and I are gonna get together
and do something.
Try never.
Well, I'm talking about
more than sex here.
No, you're not.
You know, I've liked you for four years,
and you treat me like shit, you know.
I don't understand that.
What's your problem?
Can you get off of my car?
You know, I've been out
with a lot of girls at this school.
I don't see what makes you so different.
I have some taste.
You're a bitch.
You know,
I think you ought to see a doctor,
'cause that condition of yours
could get a lot worse.
Applause, applause, applause.
This is beautiful.
It's so modern.
I mean, is this fab, or what?
It's great.
- I'm very, very good at this.
- I know.
Such a waste that I run
a lowly little retail outlet.
No, not if you're good at it.
I'm good in bed. Should I be a whore?
It's great.
Did you say that you went to your prom?
Yeah, sure.
- Was it terrible?
- It was the worst.
But it's supposed to be,
you know what I mean?
But you have to go, right?
Well, you don't have to.
I mean, it's not a requirement.
I have this girlfriend
who didn't go to hers,
and every once in a while she gets
this really terrible feeling, you know,
like something is missing.
She checks her purse, you know,
she checks her keys,
she counts her kids, she goes crazy,
and then she realizes
that nothing is missing.
She decided it was side effects
from skipping the prom.
I don't know. I mean, part of me says
just go and get it over with.
And this other part of me says
it's a stupid tradition
and what's the point?
Well, you know,
you could say that life itself
is a stupid tradition.
But don't analyze it, just go.
Put that back!
- You missed my eye by an inch!
- Half an inch.
This ain't the public library, light fingers!
I'll get it.
Trax, what do you want?
Tyrone, you blow.
Yeah, I'm working. Leave me alone.
That's thrilling!
I cook for you, I do your laundry,
I sleep with you,
now you want a ride to work.
Please grow up!
Take the bus.
Take a cab.
- How you doing?
- Fine.
Good.
- Can I help you?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Can I get your opinion
on something here?
Maybe.
This any good?
Sticks and stones, Tyrone.
- It's hot. White hot.
- Sticks and stones.
Good, I'll take it.
Okay. Will that be cash or charge?
American Express Platinum Card,
maybe?
Take a bus to the zoo!
Cash.
You know,
every time you go to the john,
you lose IQ points.
It's Walter Mondale.
- And just $7.50 is your change.
- Thanks.
Tyrone, no.
- I don't need a bag.
- No?
No.
I can't do these things for you.
- Thanks. Thanks.
- Enjoy it.
Bondage has no place in my life.
Since when?
Since I spent the night tied up
in the backseat of your car!
- Jena?
- Yeah.
Would you ever consider going out
with somebody that had money?
I don't think it makes a difference.
I mean, it's material.
Simon? Simon.
What would you do
if your father came home a rich man?
Kiss his ass.
- See?
- See what?
- What Simon just said.
- What...
Andie, what are you getting at?
Are you... Are you going out
with a rich guy or something?
- I gotta go.
- Hey, wait! Wait!
- You didn't answer my question.
- No.
- Good.
- Simon, it's been stimulating.
- How long I been coming here?
- I don't know, a couple years.
Okay, so, you know, we're buddies.
We're close, right?
Oh, yeah, oh, yeah. Very, pal.
Okay, so how many times
have you let me in?
I never let you in, you know that.
- So you see what I'm saying?
- I don't know. What are you saying?
What I'm saying is
my girlfriend is in there,
and I'm out here.
Well, she's a girl and she's my friend,
so she's a girlfriend.
But she's in there, and I'm out here!
I mean, you're a sensitive,
sexually potent kind of guy.
You gotta know how that hurts.
Now let me ask you a question,
seriously.
Why does she come here,
knowing I don't let you in?
- Huh? Think about it.
- I don't know.
All right, my advice to you is dump her.
Lose her. You don't need that.
You see what I'm saying?
You see the point I'm trying to make?
Love's a bitch, Duck. Love's a bitch.
- Ain't it the truth.
- Oh, it's the truth.
- High-five.
- All right.
Go for it.
You wanna try a cigarette? Come on.
Oh, the babe, the babe, the babe.
Hey, honey, honey,
let me ask you a personal question.
If you worship the Duck, why don't you
hang out somewhere he could get in?
Good night, Dice Man!
Hey, say hello to the wife and kids,
you know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
You see, the Dice Man is dyslexic.
He gets everything backwards.
- What he meant to say was, like, if I...
- It's okay, Duckie.
Oh, okay. 'Cause you're sure?
Because if he offended you,
I would gladly clean up this parking lot
with his butt.
- No, I'm fine. Don't worry about it.
- Okay. Okay.
- Were you here long?
- No, no. Three, four hours.
You have a good time, at least?
- Oh, good, that's good. Now, what now?
- Bed.
- Yours or mine? Ours?
- Nice try.
Okay.
- Can you at least give me a ride home?
- Yeah, get in.
Can I, like, put my head in your lap?
No, wait, can I rest my head
on your shoulder and let you steer?
- Get in, Duckie.
- Okay.
These houses are amazing, Duck.
Hey, the first million I make,
I buy you one.
I hate this song.
They're so beautiful.
Hey, you want beauty, look in the mirror.
This whole tape is horrible.
I must be going through, like,
a hormone thing,
'cause every song I listen to
is making me sick.
I mean, why can't I find
a decent song here?
- That one's my favorite.
- Are you deaf?
The house.
Oh, yeah, yeah. That's a nice little crib.
I wonder what it's like inside.
Well, what difference does it make?
You know what
the really sad thing is though?
I bet the people that live there
don't think it's half as pretty as I do.
- You know what I mean?
- You know, Andie, I'm just...
They just don't write love songs
like they used to.
It's... I'm...
I'm angry about this, you know?
My evening's shot.
Just drive me home, now.
Hey.
Well, the reason I came over,
I mean, other than I'd been planning
to come by and just say hello,
I wanted to talk to you about Andie.
- Yeah.
- I mean, she's an incredible individual.
I mean, you know that.
I mean, I'm there for her!
Whenever, however, I'm there.
You can rest assured
that she's covered.
I don't want you to worry,
because my only future plans are
to make sure that she's taken care of.
That's nice of you, Phil.
And I'd like to marry her.
Oh, well, not, you know, not today,
but eventually, I figure.
Well, does Andie know
how you feel about this?
No confirmation on that just yet.
I mean, I'm laying the groundwork
and everything, you know.
I'm thinking in terms of housing,
you know, food,
basic needs type of stuff.
But I'm picking my moment.
Yeah, I mean, you understand, right?
Oh, sure. I felt the same way
about somebody myself.
- Oh, a girl?
- A girl.
I loved her and I married her.
And one day she just split.
Oh, wait. This was Andie's mom?
- Yeah.
- Oh.
So I haven't seen her in three years,
you know, and...
But I still love her
just as much as I ever did, you know.
I mean, you can love Andie,
but that doesn't mean
she's gonna love you back.
I mean, it doesn't mean that she won't,
but what I'm trying to say is
you can't make it happen, you know?
It either will or it won't.
It's all in the heart.
Oh, yeah, sure, I... Cardiovascular.
Yeah, I understand. I've been to school.
Yeah.
Well, I got an appointment
with a vacuum cleaner. Gotta go.
Hey, you're on a whole
home improvement jag here, aren't you?
Yeah. Turning the old life around.
Oh, well, hey, more power to you.
If Tina Turner can do it,
Jack Walsh can do it, too.
Well, thanks for taking your time.
I really, you know... I appreciate it.
- My pleasure.
- I'm off like a dirty shirt.
Tina Turner.
Hiya.
We just got these glasses in.
- They're really
- Yeah, I didn't like that album I got
- the other day.
...dumb.
- What?
- The record.
- Oh, the record.
- Yeah, I thought it was a little too...
- Too hip, maybe?
Yeah, a little too hip.
Well...
Think you can recommend something
else a little less political, or something?
- Lionel Richie?
- Nah.
No, well, Teena Marie, Madonna?
Madonna?
- Yeah, Madonna.
- That's awfully deep.
Yeah, very deep,
but she's got such great style.
Yeah, listen...
That's the alarm.
- Can you hold on for a second?
- Sure.
Just... I'll be right back.
Here, read this.
It's really good. Don't lose my...
No, no, no, you can use my...
Hold on.
What is this?
Hi! How's your day?
Baby pumps out
about 300 decibels, huh?
- Did you do this?
- Well, I'm not sure.
I mean,
I was just using your powder room,
and I decided not to disturb you,
so I was going to go out the back door.
But I guess
I must've touched something.
How'd you get in here?
- Are you mad?
- Yes, I'm mad.
There are public bathrooms
all over the place!
I'm not nine, Andie. I know that.
It's just, it's the end of the month.
They're out of toilet-seat covers.
You know what a stickler I am
about personal hygiene, too.
That's ridiculous, Duckie. Why don't you
just stop making excuses?
Blane, what are you doing?
Hey, buddy, what's up?
Nothing, hanging out.
Well, what are you shopping for,
records or something?
I guess.
- Did you find anything?
- No, not really. Not really.
Well, are we gonna shoot some trap,
or what?
'Cause, I mean, if we're gonna shoot,
we gotta shake it, man.
I don't have anyplace to go. I like
coming here, excuse me very much.
It's okay.
I'm sorry for getting mad at you.
I gotta get back out in front, okay?
I'll see you later.
This is a shitty alarm system.
I had to open and close the door
five times before it rang!
That's it, I'm leaving.
I'm not gonna stay here!
No, no way!
Hi, it's 6:05, Duckie Dale.
Give me a call.
6:15, Duckie Dale again. Call me, okay?
Andie, where are you? This is the Duck.
Give me a call, okay?
It's 6:28.
Please call, please, please, please.
This is Duckie. Are you really home
and just not picking up?
'Cause if so,
I feel like a giant asshole here.
It's 6:31. Give me a call, okay, please?
Andie, this is Steve.
Duckie, I'll just talk to you
in the morning, okay? Bye.
What are you doing up?
I didn't wake you up yet.
Well, I'm fixing you breakfast.
One egg, over-medium,
and I fed the dog.
Did Daddy feed you?
- Your egg, Madame.
- Oh, I don't eat eggs, Daddy.
Here, why don't you go in and eat it?
I'll bring you your coffee and juice,
okay?
Okay.
Since when don't you like eggs?
Oh, since about birth.
Don't worry about it.
Hey,
you never told me why you were up.
Well, it's morning.
Oh, you mean, why didn't you have
to drag my ass out of bed?
Okay.
Well, I got a job.
- No.
- Yeah.
Where?
Well, I'll tell you after I start.
- When's that?
- Soon.
I'm so proud of you! You got the job.
- No big deal.
- Yes, it is a big deal.
It's a very big deal.
Listen, I gotta go, okay?
I'm gonna be late for school.
You tell me all about it tonight.
I'm so proud of you.
All right, it'll be real good.
Hi, guys.
- How you doing?
- Fine.
- You?
- Okay.
- And you?
- Well, I just said I was fine.
- Oh, yeah, sorry.
- No, it's okay.
- So is this your first time out here?
- Yeah.
I don't think I'm very popular
out here, either.
Oh, I don't know. You're just fine inside.
I don't know.
I'm not really into all this shit,
you know?
Yeah.
Oh, I really liked your computer trick.
- Clever, huh?
- Terribly clever, yeah, terribly.
- Are you late for something?
- Yeah, I am, as a matter of fact.
But, I mean,
it's no big deal. It's fine.
Listen, do you wanna...
Do you wanna go out Friday?
Yeah.
- Yeah?
- Sure.
- Yeah. Okay.
- 7:00, okay?
- Yeah, that's fine.
Great, great. Well, where do you live?
I'll pick you up.
- Where do you live?
- Oh, no, I'm sorry.
I'm gonna be working on Friday,
so you can just pick me up at the mall.
- Okay.
- Okay?
- Bye.
- See you.
Hey, Blane. How you doing?
Hey, buddy, what's up?
- What are you up to?
- Oh, not much. Going to class.
- Well, I saw you outside.
- So?
So what were you doing?
What are you, my mother?
Come on, I gotta go. I'll see you later.
- Blane, what's going on?
- Nothing.
Well, not nothing.
I mean, I saw you talking to that chick.
What's her name? Eddie or something.
So what do you care?
Listen, my best friend is conversing
with a mutant,
you know, and I'm curious.
I don't think that's any reason
to get defensive.
I'm not defensive.
I just happen to like her, all right?
Listen, all right, it's, you know,
it's your life. It's none of my business.
You really don't think
she's got something?
No.
I really don't, I'm sorry.
You're gonna be late, buddy.
Okay, the Warsaw Pact is a treaty
that was signed by the Soviet Union
and its seven East European
satellites, okay?
And what it did was it...
It established a mutual
defense organization
as a counterweight to NATO.
- Duckie.
- What? What? What? What?
Well, what did I put?
You wrote, "The Warsaw Pact is
the pact that's named after Warsaw."
So a teacher's just gonna know
that you're just bullshitting.
Okay, okay. What about the rest of it?
Well, the Russian Revolution did not
take place in Germany.
- Well, what was Karl Marx then?
- He was a German.
Well, there you go.
Yes, but his being German
doesn't have anything to do
with where
the Russian Revolution occurred.
Okay, okay.
Okay, Duckie,
can I propose something to you
without you getting upset or angry?
- Well, that depends.
- On what?
I don't know, I just said that. Go ahead.
Well, I propose that you're deliberately
flunking your courses
so that you can stay in high school.
Get out of here! Why would I do that?
I don't know, you tell me.
Well, I'm not, so there's nothing to tell.
Well, you know,
you're not always one to face things.
What? Since when?
- What am I not facing?
- The future.
Well, whether or not you face the future,
it happens, right?
You run yourself down.
Why do you do that?
I am not running myself down.
You think I'm running...
I don't think I'm running myself down.
Why? Because of the way I dress?
'Cause I can laugh at myself?
That's called a sense of humor.
You should get one, they're nice.
What are we gonna do next year?
Well, according to you,
I'll still be in high school.
No, I'm serious.
I mean, not a day has passed in, what,
eight years
when I didn't see you
or talk to you at least 20 times.
Well, that's devotion.
I know,
and even though I sometimes get angry,
you know that I secretly love it.
You see, I knew that.
You know,
I hope I'm not the only one in the world
that knows what an incredible person
you are.
Well, at this point in time,
I'm afraid you are, honey.
Okay, I'm gonna get something to drink,
and then we work, okay? You promise?
- Oh, you bet.
- Okay, what do you want?
- Oh, beer, Scotch, juice box, whatever.
- Okay.
Oh, God.
I love this woman.
I love this woman, and I have to tell her.
And if she laughs, she laughs.
And if she doesn't love me,
she doesn't love me.
But if I don't find out...
Oh, I love her too much.
Love is real
Thank you, thank you.
Real is love
You're a wonderful crowd here,
you know that.
Love is living
You're fabulous. I do love you.
I do love you. You're gorgeous.
I love your hair.
Love is feeling
Feeling love
Love is wanting
She's gonna laugh.
Would I blame her?
- Here you go.
- Oh, shit.
Listen, honey, thanks,
but I'm gonna split, you know.
Why? What about your paper?
That's what I'm gonna do,
you see, 'cause...
I mean, if you help me,
thanks a lot, but it'll...
It won't be my work. It'll be bogus.
And you know,
I guess I'll see you in the a.m.
Hey, drinking and driving don't mix.
That's why I ride a bike.
- I got it.
- Over here.
Get it!
So, what's the deal?
Are you going out this weekend?
I don't know. I'm not sure yet.
- Why? What are you gonna do?
- Stay at home.
- Yeah, you gonna study again?
- Probably.
- Would you put that out?
- No.
Well, you study so much,
it makes me ill.
- I just don't see the point.
- You don't?
I don't wanna work in a record store
my whole life.
Yeah, what do you wanna be, a doctor?
Oh, God. Here we go.
Okay, let's go, everybody.
Get in your lines, please. Thank you.
- Fulmeister.
- Here!
Besset!
- Basono!
- Yeah.
- Look at that girl's shoes.
- Goulong!
- Oh, look. Watch out.
- Yorkland!
- Deeds!
- Do we smell bad or something?
- Hey, Benny.
- Fox!
- Penfield!
- I hope they shrivel up and fall off, okay?
What was that, Miss Hoeman?
I said, I hope they shrivel up and fall off.
You hope what shrivels up and falls off?
Her breasts, Miss Dietz.
- Shut up!
- I'm sorry.
- You are out of here, Hoeman.
- Right.
Bye-bye. Bye, girls.
So, do you share
your partner's attitude?
No, I don't.
Eat shit.
Excuse me, Miss Dietz.
You've only got a couple of months left.
You're doing extremely well
in your courses,
and I think your chances of getting
a scholarship are excellent.
I know this, Mr. Donnelly.
- Why are you in here now?
- I don't know.
I guess I just got a little fed up.
- With what?
- The way that we get treated.
Look,
you're getting
a top-notch education here,
and I just don't wanna see
you throw it away.
I'm getting a better education
than I deserve. I'm lucky.
I'm fortunate that the good people
of this community
allow me to attend this school.
Again, you are misunderstanding me.
No, I understand everything,
Mr. Donnelly.
I don't need to have it explained to me.
I live it.
It's just sometimes I get a little upset,
and I lose my temper.
I just don't like to see my friends
getting dumped on
or punished for defending themselves.
Well, we'll just forget about
this whole thing, okay?
Okay.
- What about Jena?
- She's off, too.
Thank you.
Andie,
if you put out signals
that you don't want to belong,
people are gonna make sure
that you don't.
That's a beautiful theory.
Andie, Andie, Andie, listen,
I heard what happened,
and I came as fast as I could.
I cut out of Home Ec and everything.
- Was it really bad?
- No, it was nothing, Duckie.
- Are you upset?
- No, I'm not.
No, yes, yes, you are.
I can tell.
Your eyes get all squinty and everything.
Listen, I know just what to do
to make you feel better.
- I feel fine.
- I wanna take you away this weekend.
Do you fish?
- Okay, then we can go right now.
- I have a class.
Tonight at 7:00,
and I won't take no for an answer.
Try, please.
This woman is suffering inside.
That's all there is to it.
Yo, man, next time, I'll kick your ass!
That'll be that!
I'm just kidding, that's... It's a joke. It's...
How about that stock market?
You know, my broker is E.F. Hutton,
and E.F. Hutton says...
You see, it never works. It never works.
I've never seen that work
in my whole life.
Oh, shit!
So this is what it looks like.
This is great.
Hey, wait a minute.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
You got doors on the stalls.
They're not stopped... Wait a minute!
We don't have none of this stuff
in the boys'...
Wait a minute,
we don't got none of this.
We don't got doors
on the stalls in the boys' room.
We don't have... What is this?
We don't have a candy machine
in the boys' room.
- We don't got none of that. None of that.
- Enough screaming.
- You gotta get out of here.
- I'm sorry. No, I want the principal here.
I want him here this instant.
I want... Now. This instant.
I'll wait. Thank you.
Oh, shit! Why can't I do this?
What have you done?
This... You have to subtotal first.
I tell you this every time.
You never listen.
One more tune, then it's off
to enjoy a terrible relationship.
The furrier next door loves this.
Soft words
They are spoke so gentle, yeah
It makes it easier
Easier to bear
You won't regret it, no, no
Young girls, they don't forget it
Love is their whole
happiness
Yeah
But it's all so easy
All you've gotta do is try
Try a little tenderness
Yeah
All you gotta do is, man
Hold her where you want her
You got to squeeze her,
don't tease her
Never leave her
Get to her
Got to, got to
try a little tenderness
Yeah, yeah, yeah
you've got to
know how to love her, man
Take this advice, man
You got to squeeze her,
don't tease her
Never leave
You got to hold her
And, brother, something else
Try a little tenderness
Yeah, yeah, yeah
You got to, brother
Don't lose her, no, no
You got to love her,
tease her, don't leave her
Got to try, now, now, now
Try, try a little tenderness
Yeah, watch the groove
You got to know what to do, man
Take this advice
You gotta love and squeeze,
don't tease my baby
Love her, Lord
Evening, young ladies.
This is a very good tune.
My mother used to sing this.
This is Otis. I love Otis.
We're closed.
You know what an older woman
does for me?
- Changes your diapers?
- Touche.
No, seriously though,
you're a very smoky alternative,
but this is the Duck Man's love in life.
- Shall we?
- Ever had one of these?
I don't think so.
Come on, let's plow.
Do I offend?
Andie, hon,
listen, it's after 7:00.
Don't waste good lip gloss.
I know, lona.
I mean, I don't mean to be a bitch
or anything,
but I don't think Mr. Wonderful's gonna
happen tonight.
I don't know what I'm doing.
Wishful make-uping.
Come on.
Wait, wait, you babes are, like, talking
a sign language that the old Ducker
here just does not understand.
Now, would you mind filling me in here?
I'm a little confused.
She got stood up, twerp.
Stood up? Wait, how so?
Wait, I'm here!
I mean, is this like one of those
feminine mystique deals or something?
He showed.
Andie?
I'll get that.
Duckie, I'm really sorry.
What is this...
You're gonna go out with this guy?
I mean, is this, you know,
like, a date or something?
Yeah. I mean, you'll like him.
He's not like the other guys, seriously.
No. No way. Andie!
You really piss me off,
you know, 'cause...
'Cause you know they shit all over
everybody, including you.
I just...
I can't believe you'd be this stupid.
Who's shitting on me?
I'm not gonna let anybody shit on me.
He's just... He's gonna use
your ass and throw you away.
God, I would've died for you!
So what am I supposed to do?
He asked me out, and I like him!
If I hate him because he's got...
Just listen to me.
If I hate him because he's got money,
that's the exact same thing
as them hating us because we don't.
Do you understand?
You can't do this and respect yourself.
You can't.
Well, I'll make that decision, all right?
Sure, you can do what you want.
You know, you're talking like that
just because I'm going out with Blane.
Blane? His name is Blane?
That's a major appliance,
that's not a name!
Just because I'm going out with Blane,
doesn't mean I can't be friends with you.
I mean, it doesn't change
the way I feel about you.
Well, that's very nice. I'm glad. Here's...
Here's the point, Andie,
I'm not particularly concerned
with whether or not you like me.
'Cause I live to like you,
and I can't like you anymore.
So when you get your heart splattered
all over hell,
and you're feeling really low and dirty,
don't look to me to help
pump you back up,
'cause...
'Cause maybe for the first time
in your life, I won't be there!
I can't believe
you're actually saying this.
Well, I guess that's just tough shit!
- Sorry.
That guy in the store.
Oh, he was a friend of mine.
I've known him since I was a kid.
He's a really nice guy.
- Yeah?
- Yeah. I like him a lot.
So do you wanna go home and change?
I already did.
- Sorry.
- No, that's okay.
Oh, boy.
So, where are we going?
You up for a party?
Yeah? No? Maybe?
No, I don't think so.
- Why?
- Come on, they're my friends. It's okay.
- That's it, they're your friends.
I wouldn't take you
if I didn't think they'd accept you.
Can't we just go somewhere else?
Hey, Andie, I like you.
I think you like me.
I mean, we both know there's a lot
of bullshit that goes on,
but if you're above it, I'm above it.
You wanna make anything out of this
whatever, we gotta deal with it, right?
Yeah.
Come on, I got as much to lose as you.
We can go out with your friends
if you want.
Go crawl under a rock.
Anything you want. The choice is yours.
We can go hang-gliding.
You like hang-gliding?
- I've never been hang-gliding.
- Well, first for everything.
If it's a bad time, we leave.
- Hi, Blane.
- Hey, Eddie.
We'll see you later.
Come on.
Hey, what's up, bro?
Hey! Aren't you the girl in my art class?
Nice pearls.
- This isn't a dinner party, honey.
- Watch it.
- Hey, Blane, how you doing?
- Hey, Kev, what's up?
Great party, man.
- All right, man.
- Later.
I can't believe I actually associate
with these people, huh?
I can't believe that I'm actually here.
- Pretty bad, yeah?
- Yeah, it's pretty bad.
I'm sorry.
Hey, let's go upstairs, huh?
Come on.
Look, I didn't come here
to get you off, okay?
- That was not my idea.
- Andie.
Come on, that is not what I meant.
I haven't even tried to kiss you, have I?
Look, it's quieter up there, okay.
Come on. These hands will remain
in these pockets, I swear to God.
Come on.
Look at me here.
Come on, I'm utterly defenseless.
And utterly foolish. Come on.
- So what do you think of these carpets?
- Oh, fab.
It's gonna be great.
Oh, hey, Blane.
- Steff.
- How you doing?
- All right.
- Come on in.
No, I'll get another room.
No, no, no, come on in.
I'm just watching some 'toons here.
Who have you got with you here, Blane?
Andie, this is Steff. Steff, Andie.
Oh, well,
it's very nice to meet you, Andie.
Listen, you wanna come in
and sit down?
- Or you want the bed, is that it?
- No.
No. We're fine.
Well, at least come in and have a drink.
Let's go. Can I get you something?
I mean, this is my last serious party
of my high school career.
I hope you guys are gonna
tough it out until Sunday,
at least when my folks get home.
I think this one may just finally kill
the old son of a bitch, Blane.
Another giant step away
from virginity I went.
You are a slut, aren't you, Benny?
Oh, my God.
- Am I having a nightmare?
- We got guests.
I know you. You're in my calculus class.
- Gym.
- Your name's Jim?
Oh, you are worthless, aren't you?
You and your friends gave me
a lot of shit the other day.
- Everybody gives you shit.
- Take it easy, Benny, huh?
Hey, this is Steff's party, Blane.
Don't tell me what to do.
Steff.
I mean, you shouldn't be allowed
to invite just anybody.
- Steff, she's gonna ruin my night.
- Shut up, Benny!
- You're a faggot, Blane.
- All right. Okay. Listen, Benny.
- Listen, why don't we just...
- Where are you going?
Let's just leave them
with the room, okay?
Why?
And we will get you something to eat,
all right?
- Oh, you've got what I want.
- Maybe some ribs or something.
Listen, you guys enjoy yourselves,
and we'll see you later, maybe.
I doubt it.
- You all right?
- Fine.
- You're an asshole.
- All right.
And I don't wanna know what you are.
I'm gonna take her
to throw up somewhere.
- Listen, enjoy yourself, Blane.
- Come here.
They're kind of jerks
when they drink, huh?
- Bad idea.
- Can you just get me out of here now?
Yeah.
Look, I don't want to take you home.
I mean, I'd like to be with you.
If not here, somewhere else.
Anywhere you want.
I'm sorry. What can I say?
I made a mistake.
I over-estimated my friends. I'm sorry.
What, do you wanna hit me?
Yes, I do.
Be my guest.
You wanna know my thing?
If I really have it solid for a girl,
I'll ride by her house on my bike.
I'll do it like 100 times in a day.
And it's really... It's intense.
You ever park?
I'm kind of a drive-by kind of guy.
- Do you want a drink?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
- Coke.
Coke. Coke? Okay.
Give me your address.
I'll put you on my route.
Okay, you're gonna have
to help me out here.
You know, someday that girl's gonna
realize just what she missed.
Come on, don't stop,
give me more! Yeah!
- Hi.
Prince Charming wimp out?
No, no, he's at the bar.
Duckie?
He's sulking.
He's not gonna ride his bike
past your house anymore.
Duckie, you're being a real jerk.
How'd he get in here anyway?
I said he was my kid.
How come you're here?
I've been trying
to figure that out all night.
Can I get a cigarette from you, buddy?
Sorry.
- Mom make this for you?
- Yeah. Gross, huh?
Excuse me.
- Hi.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
- You met lona, didn't you?
- Not formally. Hi. Blane.
And that's Duckie Dale over there
behind the glasses.
- Hi, Duckie.
- Philip F. Dale to you, scum wad.
So, where you guys been?
Oh, a friend of mine was having a party.
Oh, how adorable.
Yeah, it was a little intense.
Oh, wait, wait.
You had an intense party?
No, it was a friend of mine's, I said.
Duckie, shut up.
What's the problem?
This is a classic,
classic piece of work here.
- Duckie, please.
- Phil.
Hey, Phil, I think you're making
Andie uncomfortable.
Why don't you just knock it off?
What's the problem?
I devoted my life to the girl,
and this guy,
he comes in one day
and thinks he knows her.
That's funny. You should give
David Letterman a ring sometime.
I'm sure he'd book you in a minute.
Phil, would you like us to leave?
Yes, very perceptive.
Come on.
And look at the manners on this guy.
This was a treat.
Really, thanks a million.
You're a great couple of kids, really.
You know, I can't believe
I actually felt bad for you tonight,
retarded little dwarf!
See you.
Nice meeting you.
See you later.
- Sorry.
- No problem.
- You're an asshole.
Hey, blow me, butt wad. Coming
from you I take that as a compliment.
Andie! Yo!
You've been replaced.
Gee, I'm sorry.
Well, what now?
I gotta get up early.
Why don't we just forget it?
What, home?
- Hey, you wanna go to my house?
- No, thanks.
You wanna eat?
- No.
- What do you wanna do?
Anything.
Why don't you just drop me off at Trax?
- You know, I can...
- Trax?
It's real close to where I live.
Well, it's late. I'll just drop you home.
You wanna go home, I'll drop you home.
No, but I have something
I have to do there.
Now? Come on, it's late.
You wanna go home, I'll drop you home.
It's fine.
- I don't want you to take me home.
- Okay, let's go out.
- No, I don't want...
- We'll go out anywhere you want,
- anything you wanna do.
- I don't wanna go out.
You don't wanna go out.
You don't wanna go home.
- What do you want to do, Andie?
- I don't want you to take me home.
Wait, I'm missing something.
I'm not a jerk here.
I don't understand what you're saying.
Wait a minute!
- Just go.
- Don't walk away. I'm talking to you.
- Don't. Just... Please!
- Why?
- Don't you understand me?
- No, I don't
- at all, obviously.
- Will you listen to me?
- I don't want you to take me home.
- Okay. Why? What is the problem?
Because I don't want you to see
where I live, okay?
- What?
- I'm sorry, forget it.
It's okay.
Jesus Christ.
I'm really sorry for bumming out
the night for you.
You didn't bum out anything.
I had a great time.
- You liar.
- I was with you. I had a great time.
If I was in a Turkish prison,
I'd have a great time with you.
I don't know.
It's just too weird for me, you know.
- Maybe this shouldn't happen.
- What, you and me?
Well, you know,
maybe it doesn't happen all the time,
but it doesn't mean it isn't right. Right?
Doesn't mean you can't try.
Feel any better
if I asked you to the prom?
I mean, I know the prom's kind of lame,
so if you don't wanna go,
it's really no big deal.
Hey. What?
It happened! He asked me.
- And?
- I accepted!
Well, congratulations.
No more moping around the house
waiting for the telephone to ring.
So you in love?
- Yeah, I think I am.
- Well, who is this guy?
His name is Blane and he's a senior.
He's so beautiful.
He's a richie.
- A whatie?
- A richie.
It's kind of stupid.
It's just his family has a lot of money.
Oh, well, is that a problem?
I don't know. It's just weird, you know.
His friends have a lot of money,
and he has a lot of money.
He drives a BMW.
Just, I don't know. I'm not really sure
if they're gonna accept me.
Well, what does that mean?
I mean, you like him. He likes you.
What his friends think
shouldn't make any difference.
Yeah, but it's not just his friends.
It's my friends, too. It's everybody!
I'm just not real secure about it.
Well, so take the heat.
I mean, you like him. He likes you.
It's worth it.
Is it?
Well, isn't it?
You're right.
I'm just overreacting, aren't I?
Well, not necessarily.
I mean, a good kiss can scramble
anybody's brain.
Look, just don't worry about it,
you know.
And wait and see
how you feel tomorrow.
- Good night, honey.
- Good night, thanks.
That's my baby.
Honey.
Wait a minute.
Could I ask you something?
Yeah.
Yeah, sometimes I feel a little sorry
that I'm the one you have to talk to
about these things.
I'm not.
She couldn't have said it
any better than you.
I mean it.
Good night.
Okay, make my day.
I want all the gory details.
The mingling breath, pounding heart,
the steaming windows.
I want the whole skidoo.
Well, I hate to disappoint you,
but nothing happened.
Nothing?
Well, not nothing. I mean, I kissed him.
- Anywhere interesting?
- Oh, please.
So
does he have
strong lips?
How can you tell?
Do you feel it in your knees?
I felt it everywhere.
Strong lips.
Talk about lips.
I mean, I'm old enough to be his mother,
but when the Duck laid that kiss on me
last night,
I swear to God,
my thighs just went up in flames.
He must practice on melons
or something.
Is this your prom dress?
- Believe it or not.
- No, it's great.
- It's silly.
- It's a great material.
You know, I'm going.
To prom.
Stop it.
No, I am. Last night he asked me,
and I don't know, I said yes.
Seems really weird,
but it might be kind of fun.
You were here for 15 minutes,
and you didn't even tell me!
I really, really wanted to go.
You lucky girl.
Isn't that a dreamy dress?
Lona, I have to go.
Can you just hold it
till this song is over?
But I have to leave.
Oh, why can't we start old
and get younger?
I envy you.
I really envy you!
Lona, you're gonna OD on nostalgia.
I loved The Big Chill.
I love this dress.
- It's a great dress.
- Yeah.
My mother bought it for me.
God, she was so happy.
It was the first and last time
I ever looked normal.
I mean, you know, relatively speaking.
It would've been a fairytale
if my date hadn't been
the only one at the prom
with a wife and two kids.
You wanna try it on?
I bet it'd look great on you.
I mean, your butt is 15 years
younger than mine.
I mean, I used to have a great butt.
I did! I loved my butt!
I wish I had photographs of it.
You wanna try this on?
No, not right now.
Oh, yeah, you got to go. I know. I know.
- I gotta get ready myself.
- You're going out?
Yeah. New guy.
Terrence, owns a pet shop.
We'll see what happens.
Have fun.
- Give Mr. Perfecto a squeeze for me.
- Oh, I will.
Hey, and listen,
if you see your little Duck Man, be kind.
He's nursing
some fairly serious wounds.
- Okay?
- Okay.
- Bye-bye.
- Bye.
Hey, you know, we're going for sushi.
Do you think this is too much?
Bye.
Thought that was very uncool of you
last night, Blane.
- What?
- You mean Andie?
- Yeah, I mean Andie.
What's the big deal? I like her.
Matter of fact, I was pissed off
at you guys for being so nasty to her.
It was way out of order for you
to foist her on the party.
Steff, you hear yourself?
You hear the same asshole shit I hear?
What, do I have to spell it out
for you, Blane?
I guess so.
Nobody appreciates
your sense of humor, you know.
As a matter of fact, everybody is
just about to puke from you.
You know, if you got a hard-on for trash,
don't take care of it around us, pal,
all right?
Right, buddy.
Listen, I don't need a lot of shit on
this one, Blane, all right? I really don't.
Money all that matters to you?
Where the hell does that come from?
Come on, look around you.
Would I treat my parents' house like this
if money was any kind of issue?
Come on, why are you doing this?
You know, why don't you just nail her
and get it over with?
You know, why are you getting involved?
Is there something wrong with that?
I just think it's stupid.
You know, it's pointless.
You know, and your parents,
I think they'll be thrilled.
They have nothing to do with it.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I've seen your mother go to work on you,
Blane. You know, it's vicious.
And when Bill and Joyce
get through with you,
you won't know whether to shit
or go sailing.
Listen, I'm getting really bored
with this conversation, all right, Blane?
You know, if you want your little
piece of low-grade ass, fine, take it.
You know, but if you do,
you're not gonna have a friend.
- Is that right?
- Yeah, that's right.
I mean, if you want to make the choice,
go ahead, make it, all right?
I personally wouldn't trash
a friendship over it.
But, hey, I'm old-fashioned, so...
Why don't you take a shower?
You look like shit.
If two weeks ago, somebody had
told me that I'd be going out with you,
I never would have believed them.
Why? I'm not all that bad.
- No, but...
- What about me and you?
You know, it's so insane
that somebody you've never met,
never talked to, can be your enemy.
Yep.
You shouldn't meet my parents then.
Okay.
Well, I mean, they're not ogres,
but I think they still believe
in arranged marriages.
Corporate families
replaced royal families.
I'm the crowned prince
of McDonnagh Electric.
- It's irrelevant.
- No.
Yeah.
- I could just tell them all to go to hell.
- Tell them to go to hell.
- Everyone, friends, parents.
- All of them.
All of them.
What about you?
If somebody doesn't believe in me,
I can't believe in them.
You don't lie, do you?
I don't have to lie.
This is gonna happen.
Okay, I really want this to happen.
Yeah.
- Can I help you?
- I'm fine, thank you.
Something for the prom?
Just looking.
Yeah, well, if you need anything...
This is trash.
It's very becoming.
Mother, it looks like I should be
standing on top of a wedding cake.
Oh, darling, don't I wish.
And I hate this material.
And by the way,
I cannot stand baby blue.
Well, do you know where he is?
No, I'm sorry,
he didn't tell me where he was going.
Okay, well, then if he calls or comes
home, can you just tell him to call me?
- Who is this, please?
- Andie.
- Who?
- Well, yes, could I have your number?
- Yeah, no, he has the number.
Well, fine, I'll leave him a note, dear.
Okay, thanks, bye.
Where the hell is he?
Don't fall in love, Ace.
You just won't like it.
It's very complicated.
Andie!
- Andie.
- Come in.
- Hi.
- Hi, Daddy.
I brought you something.
What is it?
Oh, just a little something
I picked up for you.
Now, I know it's a little busy,
but I know you can make
something out of it, if you need to.
- Wow.
- Yeah, do you like it?
- It's a beautiful color.
- Yeah.
- It's really pretty.
God, it reminds me
so much of your mom.
You know, she always wore pink,
and she looked so beautiful in it.
- It's okay.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
- Daddy.
- What?
I just want you to know
I really appreciate this.
You know,
I think I can make something out of it.
- Can I ask you something?
- Sure. What?
Where'd you get the money
to pay for this?
Well, it wasn't that much.
I had some money.
From your new job?
Yeah, from my new job.
I came home before work
on Wednesday,
and your car was in the driveway.
You know, you didn't have to lie to me.
- Yes, I did.
- No, you didn't.
Yes, I did. I had a line on something,
and I missed the appointment.
- Oh, why'd you miss the appointment?
- It slipped my mind.
It didn't slip your mind.
You didn't want the job.
You just went to the counselor
because I forced you to. Am I right?
Yeah, what's your point, Andie?
My point is you just didn't go!
You saying I deliberately
missed the appointment?
Yes.
Is this how you feel about me?
- Well, I didn't know this.
- Well, now you do.
Oh, you know everything, now, huh?
You're 18, and you've got a scholarship,
- That's not fair.
...and you're grown up and free,
and I'm just an ignorant son of a bitch
- that never gave you anything.
- Hey, I never asked for anything.
Oh, that's brilliant!
Why can't you just forget her?
It's late. You got school.
No, don't walk out on this!
Will you please just listen to me?
- Please?
- I've already been through this, Andie.
Sure, you go through it every day!
You're still going through it!
Why can't you just realize
that she's gone,
and she's not gonna come back?
She's never coming back!
- Shut up! God damn it!
- Why can't you accept it?
She's just gone! She...
Why can't you accept it?
Because I love her, that's why.
Well, I loved her, too, you know.
She just didn't love us back.
Okay, she tried.
I don't know, she just couldn't handle it.
Yeah, but I knew it.
I knew it all along.
I mean, when I was five, I felt it.
Remember when she didn't come home
that time?
I knew it then. I knew why.
I was 14 and I knew it.
You were 50 and you didn't.
You know, you can't go on
living every day in the past.
She left us, Daddy. We didn't leave her.
There was nothing we could do about it.
It just happened.
Since when is a daughter supposed
to know more than her father?
I've just been a blind fool.
And you're a blind fool
that needs a shave, too, you know that?
And I need a shave.
Well,
you better get to bed. You got school.
And I gotta hit the hay, too,
'cause I got a few things
I gotta do tomorrow, okay?
Okay.
I would've got you some shoes,
but I didn't know your size.
Melanie.
How you doing?
Why haven't you called me?
Oh, I got nailed for the stable thing.
I guess a groom saw us.
It's against club rules.
I called you three times,
and I left messages.
Yeah?
Well, I didn't get them.
My family, they're irresponsible
about that stuff, you know.
I waited for you this morning.
- Yeah? Where?
- Parking lot.
I saw you,
and I thought that you saw me.
No.
What about prom, Blane?
Oh, Andie, I'm having a bad day.
Can we talk later?
No. What about prom?
Come on.
Why don't we just meet after school?
- No! What about prom?
- Andie, come on.
- Just say it.
- What?
Just say it! I want to hear you say it.
Andie, please, all right.
I wanna hear you say it!
A month ago I asked somebody else,
and I forgot.
You're a liar!
You're a filthy, fucking, no-good liar!
You don't have the guts
to tell me the truth!
- Just say it!
- I'm not lying.
- Tell me!
- What?
- What do you wanna hear?
- Just tell me!
- What?
- You're ashamed to be seen with me!
- No, I am not!
- You're ashamed to go out with me!
- I am not.
- You're afraid.
- No, I am...
You're terrified your goddamn
rich friends won't approve!
Just say it! Just tell me the truth!
You don't understand that
it has nothing at all to do with you.
Andie!
Forget about it, man.
It's not worth getting upset over.
Why don't you just take off, Steff?
Please.
Well, listen, any girl that did that to me
I would not be too jazzed
to hold onto, Blane.
It's not worth it, man. I told you
it wasn't gonna work, you know.
The girl was, is
and will always be nada.
You got a problem, friend?
Come on.
All right! All right!
That's nice, huh?
Andie?
- Yeah?
- You're Andie, aren't you?
Yeah, I am. How do you know me?
Well, lona told me. I'm Terrence.
Terry.
Oh, the pet shop. Right?
Yeah, among other things.
She's in the bedroom getting ready.
You might wanna go in there
and tell her to shake her tail feather.
- We're late.
- Okay.
Iona?
Nice to meet you.
- Iona?
- Hi, honey, I'm in here.
Laugh and I'll deck you.
What happened?
Either it's all those drugs
I took in the '60s,
or I am really in love.
What do you think? Honestly.
Honestly, I think you look great.
Oh, I look like a mother.
No. Well, yeah, a little, but that's okay.
You look happy.
I am.
It's weird, but I... Did you meet him?
- Yeah.
He's a yuppie, but he's so nice.
He's employed. He's heterosexual.
I swear to God, I'm so far ahead
of the game, next time you see me
I'll probably be picking out
my china pattern or something.
Hey, are you all right? No, you're not.
- What, did I blow your mind?
- No, that's not it.
Is it boy trouble?
- The worst?
- Way beyond.
He backed out on me.
He said he asked somebody else,
and he forgot about it.
I can't believe it. I can't believe it.
I'm so humiliated.
I could've killed him! I swear!
You know, I just walked right into it.
No, no.
Oh, love is awful, isn't it?
It's okay.
You remember when I...
And when you said that
if I wanted your prom dress
I could have it?
Well, I need it. I want it.
- What for?
- I just need it.
Okay.
It's yours.
Oh, my God. Look at you.
Another first.
Your guy's gonna fall to the floor
when he comes in.
No, he won't.
The hell he's not.
No, he really won't. He's not coming.
- What?
- It's okay.
- I'm gonna go.
- Alone?
Yeah, I'm not sad about it. I'm not hurt.
I mean, you know, I am hurt a little bit.
But I know if I don't do it
I'll just feel a lot worse.
I'm just gonna go in,
walk in, walk out and come home.
You sure?
I just wanna let them know
that they didn't break me.
- Open up.
- Thank you.
You're such trash.
Well, as soon as anybody's ready
to go upstairs and get serious,
just let me know.
We've only been here an hour.
We can go up and come back
down again, Benny, all right.
Did you look at the suite?
It's $300 a night, Benny.
It's not gonna be a palace, okay?
I think we should stay for a while.
We're not gonna see these people
for much longer.
Come on, it's kind of the end, okay?
I don't give a shit what you do.
Damn it.
Oh, my God!
You're here! What happened?
- Well, I guess you're looking at it.
- Oh, wow, you look great.
Thanks, you look stunning, really.
It's breathtaking.
No, and listen, I want you to know,
despite my appearance at this function,
I remain now and will always be
a Duck Man.
May I admire you?
Oh, if you wish.
Let's plow.
Should we dance?
It wouldn't be unheard of.
A little, lingering doubt perhaps, Blane?
You know,
you gotta give her credit though.
I mean, after you dumped her,
she certainly went out and found herself
what I'd have to say is probably
the most interesting date
- that our generation...
- Steff.
You buy everything, Steff.
You couldn't buy her, though.
That's what's killing you, isn't it?
- I don't wanna listen to this.
- Steff.
That's it, Steff.
She thinks you're shit,
and deep down you know she's right.
Hi.
You don't need me to say I'm sorry.
It's done. It's over with. I'm fine.
Oh, well, if that's true, then I'm glad.
It's not true.
It doesn't matter, does it?
You told me
you couldn't believe in somebody
who didn't believe in you.
I believed in you.
I always believed in you.
You just didn't believe in me.
I love you.
Always.
Andie,
he came here alone.
Okay, you're right.
He's not like the others.
If you don't go to him now,
I'm never gonna take you
to another prom ever again,
you hear me?
I mean, this is an incredibly romantic
moment, and you're ruining it for me.
Thanks, Duckie.
Go ahead.
Blane.