Captioning sponsored by
PARAMOUNT
(rock music playing)
¶ Caroline laughs
and it's raining all day ¶
¶ She loves to be
one of the girls ¶
¶ She lives in the place
in the side of our lives ¶
¶ Where nothing
is ever put straight ¶
¶ She turns herself round
and she smiles and she says ¶
¶ "This is it,
that's the end of the joke" ¶
¶ And loses herself
in her dreaming and sleep ¶
¶ And her lovers walk through
in their cloaks ¶
¶ She's... ¶
爸 7點半了!
爸 起床了!
早安 老爸
快點 起床了
起床! 起床!
你的咖啡在桌上
我在哪裡?
來 我要你喝一下這個
然後我要你洗個澡 然後穿好衣服
你的衣服放在那
然後我要你去見那個女面試官 好嗎?
就是今天 你答應過的
我知道
如果沒有妳整天在我身邊嘮叨
我該怎麼辦?
你真得要我回答這問題嗎?
天阿.. 我最近起得越來越晚了
我們最近沒機會聊天互動
這點不用擔心了
反正能聊的東西也不多
你最近一切都還順利嗎?
還行
學校那邊好嗎?
不好 學校從來沒好過
妳被邀請去參加畢業舞會了嗎?
還沒
我上一次跟妳說
我女兒很漂亮是什麼時候?
昨天吧
嘿 嘿 轉過來
怎麼了?
妳知道的
過來點 讓我看看這套服裝
這是妳最新的作品嗎?
嗯
就是它了
我的天呀
這要了妳多少花費?
鞋子的部分大概15美元
二手的剩下的我自己做的
真不敢相信
我在想 也許...
妳可以幫我領子這邊..
也許弄個摺邊什麼的
快點 起床!
別玩了 我說真的
這對我來說很重要
親愛的 我對我的工作感到很高興
你對兼職的工作很高興?
不是
所以我要起床
好拉
我去弄些早餐
我起來了!
嗨 布萊恩
嗨 凱特 妳好嗎?
還不錯 你呢?
我很好
早安!
歡迎又一天來到高等教育
嗨 達奇 你好嗎?
不完全很糟
考慮到這爛地方還有我
你知道嗎 你這套真的是火山的服裝
你穿上它 真的是非常嘆為觀止了
火山的?
這點嘛 你知道的
火熱 危險的
你今天會去教室媽?
這個 我不確定
如果我情緒上準備好的話
拜託 就去吧
實際上不怎麼痛苦的
不好意思
我必須走了 好的
午餐時在見 好
嘿 聽著 我先打給自助餐廳 預定兩個位置
你懂得 靠窗的
當然
哦 對了 不
你不喜歡座的時候曬到太陽
好吧 別的什麼
痾 聽著
我今天可以在稱讚你一次嗎?
女士們 女士們
聽著
我或許有能力做個交易
你們兩個之中的一個可以在假期中懷孕
妳們覺得呢?
有些人覺得《新政》拯救了資本主義
如證據所示 羅斯福政府是在避免..
防止過多的政府權利
也不要以移植社會主義
來作為他當總統的第一把火
羅斯福總統制定的《緊急銀行法》
他拒絕了考慮國有化
你那件衣服哪買的?
廉價商店?
凱特(竊笑):挺有魅力的
妳們有問題嗎
女士們
沒有
凱特:沒
安蒂 妳和這兩位女士之間
有什麼事情嗎?
沒有 我不知道有什麼事情
我代表莊柏琳和韓森兩位小姐道歉
這兩位小姐今晚會想念你們的
因為她們會被留下抄寫
我們剛才討論過的章節摘要
真行!
不好意思
嗯?
我真的沒問題 我很好
我想說
可以請妳忘了抄章節的事嗎?
請說?
我們會留下抄章節的
很好 讓我們繼續上課
《緊急銀行法》
待會見
哦 安蒂 妳看起來真迷人
我們再一個月就要畢業了
所以現在我想知道 什麼時候妳才會
和我再一起然後做些什麼事情?
永遠不會
我說的是指上床以外的事情
別裝了吧
妳知道的  我已經喜歡妳四年了
妳卻還是對我不理不睬
我不 我不懂
妳到底有什麼問題?
你可以離我的車遠點嗎?
你知道嗎 我在這間學校跟很多女孩出去約會過了
我看不出來
你為什麼如此與眾不同?
我還是有些品味的
你真是個婊子
你知道嗎 你應該去看個醫生
不然你的症狀會更嚴重
The '80s
掌聲 掌聲 掌聲..
這裡太美了
這裡太... 新潮了
我是說 這很棒對吧?
妳覺得呢?
很棒
我對這個非常非常在行
我知道
這對經營小間零售批發店
的我來說 可有多浪費
不會 如果妳那麼內行就不算了
我在床上很在行 我應該去當個妓女嗎?
真的太棒了
妳有說了關於妳去妳的畢業舞會嗎?
是阿 沒錯
妳的舞會棒嗎?
那絕對是最糟的畢業舞會
但還是應該去的
妳懂我意思嗎?
就算糟也得去 不是嗎?
這到也不一定
我是指 學校也沒硬性規定
我有個女生朋友
她沒去她的畢業舞會
然後現在她偶爾
都會有一種很糟的感覺
就像遺失了什麼東西
她會檢查她的皮包
檢查她的鑰匙
數她的幾個孩子
她變得神經質
然後她意識到..
沒有東西遺失
她決定把那些當作逃離舞會的副作用
我也不知道該怎麼決定
我內在的天使說:就去吧!
早點結束這一切吧
然後我內心的惡魔就說:
舞會只是個無聊又沒意義的傳統
所以我該聽誰的?
這個嘛 妳知道的...
妳可以說生活本身就是個無聊又沒意義的傳統
不如別想這麼多 就去就對了
把那個放回去!
妳差一吋就射到我眼睛了!
是半吋!
這裡可不是公共圖書館
你這小偷!
我去接
艾歐娜唱片行 你需要什麼?
IONA: Tyrone,
you blow. 泰隆
我在工作
別煩我!
假笑ing
這可真震撼到我了!
我煮給你吃 我洗你的衣服
我跟你上床
現在你要我載你去上班?
拜託 成熟點!
自己去搭巴士!
或是計程車!
妳好嗎?
還不錯
太好了
有什麼我可以幫你的嗎?
嗯 有的
妳可以給我點意見有關這裡的商品嗎?
可以吧
這張碟好聽嗎?
真是個爛招
史蒂夫·勞倫斯 (把它帶回家)
這張碟很熱賣
艾歐娜:別太把我的話當回事了 泰隆
很白熱化
太棒了 我買了
Okay, um, will that be cash
or charge?
American Express Platinum Card,
maybe?
IONA: Take a bus
to the zoo!
Cash.
IONA:
You know...
every time you go to the john,
you lose IQ points.
(whispering):
It's Walter Mondale.
And...
$7:50 is your change.
Thanks.
IONA:
Tyrone... no.
I don't need a bag.
No?
No.
IONA:
I can't do these
things for you.
Thanks.
Enjoy it.
(door opens,
shop bell tinkles)
IONA:
Bondage has no place
in my life.
(bell tinkles, door closes)
Since when?
Since I spent the night tied up
in the backseat of your car!
¶ I stuck my head out
of an empty room ¶
¶ Expectin' nothin'
but the new room view ¶
¶ I swear
I saw the future below me ¶
¶ Spitting in the face of doom
¶ Yes, so I'm sayin' ¶
¶ Tonight ¶
¶ Whoa, tonight
¶ Rudy, come on
and rule it tonight ¶
¶ Tonight ¶
¶ Yeah, tonight
¶ Rudy, come on
and rule it tonight ¶
¶ Tonight ¶
¶ Rudy...
¶ Tonight... ¶
Jena?
Yeah.
Well, would you ever consider
going out
with somebody that had money?
I don't think
it makes a difference.
I mean... it's material.
Simon?
Simon!
What would you do
if your father came
home a rich man?
Kiss his ass.
See?
See what?
What Simon
just said.
What S...
Andie, what are you getting at?
Are you... are you going out
with a rich guy or something?
I got to go.
Hey, wait, wait!
You didn't answer my question.
No!
Good.
Simon, it's been
stimulating.
How long
I been coming here?
I don't know,
a couple years.
Okay, so, you know,
we're buddies.
We're close, right?
Oh, yeah,
oh, yeah.
Very, pal.
Okay, so how many times
have you let me in?
I never let you in.
You know that.
You see, you see
what I'm saying?
I don't know.
What are you saying?
What I'm saying is,
my girlfriend is in there,
and I'm out here.
Well, she's a girl,
and she's my friend,
so she's a girl friend,
but she's in there,
and I'm out here!
I mean, you're a sensitive,
sexually potent
kind of guy.
You got to know how that hurts.
Well, let me ask you
a question seriously.
Why does she come here,
knowing I don't let you in?
Huh? Think
about it.
I don't know.
(laughs)
All right, my advice
to you is, uh...
dump her, lose her.
You don't need that.
You see what
I'm saying?
You see the point
I'm trying to make?
Love's a bitch, Duck.
Love's a bitch.
Ain't it the truth,
ain't it the truth.
Oh, it's
the truth.
High five.
All right.
Go for it.
Hey, want to try
a cigarette? Come on.
Oh, the babe,
the babe, the babe.
Hey, honey, honey, let me
ask you a personal question.
If you worship the Duck,
why don't you hang out somewhere
he could get in, I mean...
Dice, Dice Man, hey!
Say hello to the
wife and kids.
You know what
I'm saying?
Yeah.
You see, the Dice
Man is dyslexic.
He gets everything
backwards.
What he meant to say was,
like, if I worship...
It's okay, Duckie.
Okay, 'cause... you're sure,
because if he offended you,
I would gladly clean
up this parking lot
with his butt.
No, I'm fine.
Don't worry about it.
Okay, okay.
Were you here long?
Nah, nah, three,
four hours.
You have a good
time, at least?
Uh-huh.
Oh, good. That's
good. Now, what now?
Bed.
Yours, or mine?
Ours?
Nice try.
Okay. Can you at least
give me a ride home?
Yeah. Get in.
Aha. Can I, like,
put my head in your lap?
No, wait. Can I rest my head
on your shoulder
and let you steer?
Get in, Duckie.
Okay.
(instrumental
rock music playing)
(tape squealing)
(jazzy instrumental rock
playing)
ANDIE:
These houses are
amazing, Duck.
DUCKIE:
Hey, the first million
I make, I buy you one.
I hate this song.
They're so
beautiful!
(tape squealing)
Hey, you want beauty,
look in the mirror.
(indistinct rock vocal plays)
This whole tape
is horrible.
(tape squealing)
(instrumental rock music plays)
I-I must be going through,
like, a hormone thing,
'cause every song
I listen to is making me sick.
I mean, why can't
I find a decent song here?
That one's my favorite.
Are you deaf?
The house!
Oh, yeah, yeah,
that's, that's...
That's a nice little,
little crib.
Wonder what it's like inside.
Well, what-what difference
does it make?
You know what the really
sad thing is, though?
I bet the people
that live there don't think
it's half as pretty as I do.
You know
what I mean?
You know, Andie, I'm just...
They just don't write love songs
like they used to.
It's... I-I... Oh.
I'm angry about this,
you know?
I... this...
My evening's shot. I...
Just drive me home now.
(computer keyboards clicking)
(woman speaking quietly)
(indistinct,
overlapping chatter)
WOMAN:
That's...
That's right.
(keys clicking,
indistinct chatter)
(sighs)
(keys clicking)
WOMAN:
All right.
(typing)
(beeping)
DUCKIE:
Well, the reason I came over--
I mean, other than I've
been planning to come by
I don't want
you to worry,
because my only future plans
are to make sure
that she's taken care of.
That's nice of you, Phil.
(clears throat)
And I'd like to marry her.
Oh, well, not... you
know, not-not today,
but eventually,
I figure.
Well, does Andie know
how you feel about this?
Uh...
No confirmation
on that just yet.
I mean, I'm-I'm laying
the groundwork and everything.
You know, I'm thinking
in terms of housing,
you know, food,
basic needs type
of stuff, but
I'm picking my moment.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, I mean, you
understand, right?
(chuckles)
Oh, sure.
I felt the same way
about somebody myself.
Oh, a girl?
A girl.
(laughs)
Um, I loved her, and, uh,
I mar... married her.
And, uh, one day she just split.
Oh, wait. This was...
This was Andie's mom?
Yeah.
Oh.
(laughs)
So, uh, I haven't seen her
in, uh, three years, you know,
and, um, but I still love her
just as...
as much as I ever did, you know?
I mean, you can
love Andie,
but that doesn't mean
she's gonna love you back.
what I'm trying to say is,
you can't make it happen,
you know?
It either will, or it won't.
Uh, it's all in the heart.
Oh, y-yeah, sure.
I... Cardiovascular.
Yeah, I-I understand. I-I...
I've been
to school.
(chuckles)
Yeah.
Well, uh, I got an appointment
with a vacuum cleaner.
Got to go.
Hey, you're on a
whole home improvement
jag here, aren't you?
Yup. Turn the old life around.
Yeah. Well, hey,
more power to you.
If Tina Turner can do it,
Jack Walsh can do it, too.
(laughs)
Well,
thanks for taking your time.
I really... You know,
I-I appreciate it.
My pleasure.
I'm off like a dirty shirt.
(chuckles)
(distant train bell clanging)
Tina Turner.
(train bell clanging)
(humming)
(instrumental rock music plays)
(door opening,
shop bell tinkling)
(door closing,
Hiya.
(laughs)
Um, oh, we just got
these glasses in.
They're really, um...
Yeah, I didn't like that album
I got the other day.
...dumb.
What?
The record.
Oh, the record.
Uh, yeah, I thought
it was a little too, uh...
Too hip, maybe?
Yeah, a little too hip.
ANDIE:
Well, um...
BLANE:
Think you can recommend
something else
a little less political
or something?
Lionel Ritchie?
Nah.
(sucks air
through teeth)
No. Uh, well, hmm...
Tina Marie, Madonna?
Madonna?
Yeah, Madonna.
That's awfully deep.
Yeah, very deep.
But she's got
such great style.
Yeah.
Yeah, listen, um...
(burglar alarm ringing)
Um, that's the alarm.
Can you hold
on for a second?
Sure.
Just... I'll, I'll
be right back.
Okay.
Here, read this.
It's really good. Don't...
No, no, no, you can...
Hold on.
What is this?
(alarm continues )
(loudly):
Hi!
How's your day?!
Baby pumps out
about 300 decibels, huh?
(alarm stops)
Did you do this?
Well, I'm not sure.
I mean, I was just using
your powder room,
and I decided not
to disturb you,
so I was going
to go out the back door,
but I guess I must have
touched something.
How'd you
get in here?
Are you mad?
Yes, I'm mad!
There are public bathrooms
all over the place!
I'm not nine, Andie.
I know that.
It's just, it's the end
of the month.
They're out
of toilet seat covers.
(knocking)
DUCKIE:
You know what I stickler
I am about personal hygiene.
It's very
important to me.
ANDIE:
That's ridiculous.
We want you to
stop making...
Blane, what are you doing?
Hey, buddy,
what's up?
Nothing,
hanging out.
Well, what are you shopping
for, records or something?
I guess.
You find anything?
No, not really.
Not really.
Well, are we gonna shoot
some track, or what?
'Cause, I mean, if we're gonna
shoot, we got to shake it, man.
I don't have anyplace
to go.
I like coming here.
Excuse me very much.
It's okay. I'm sorry
for getting mad at you.
I got to get back
out in front, okay?
See you later.
(shop bell tinkling)
(alarm ringing)
This is a shitty
alarm system.
I opened and closed
the door five times
before it rang.
That's it,
I'm leaving.
I'm not going
to stay here.
No, no way!
(door slams)
(sighs)
Uh, hi, it's 6:05.
Duckie Dale. Give me a call.
(answering machine beeps)
Um, 6:15. Duckie Dale again.
Call me, okay?
(beep)
(singsongy):
Andie, where are you?
This is the Duck.
Give me a call, okay?
(beep)
Uh, it's 6:28.
(sighs)
Please call,
please, please, please!
This is Duckie, are you really
home and just not picking up?
'Cause if so, I feel like
a giant asshole here.
It's 6:31, give me a call,
okay, please?
(beep)
(phone rings)
DUCKIE:
Andie, this is...
Duckie, I'll just talk to you
in the morning, okay?
Bye.
(sighs)
(train whistle blowing)
(humming "Santa Lucia")
¶ Prospero il vento
¶ Prospero il vento...
What are you doing up?
I didn't wake you up yet.
Well, I'm fixing
breakfast.
One egg, over-medium,
and I fed the dog.
Oh, did Daddy
feed you, huh?
Your egg, madame.
Oh, I don't eat eggs,
Daddy.
Here, why don't you go in
and eat it.
I'll bring you your coffee
and juice, okay?
Okay.
Since when don't you like eggs?
Oh, since about birth.
Don't worry about it.
Hey, you never told me
why you were up.
Well, it's morning.
Oh, you mean,
why didn't you have to drag
my ass out of bed?
Okay.
Well, I gotta job.
No?!
Yeah.
Where?!
Um, well, I'll tell you
after I start.
When's that?
Soon.
I'm so proud of you!
You got the job.
No big deal.
Yes, it is a big deal.
It's a very big deal.
Listen, I gotta
go, okay?
I'm gonna be late
for school.
You tell me all
about it tonight.
I'm so proud
of you.
All right,
it'll be real good.
Hi, guys.
How you doing?
Fine.
And you?
Okay.
Well, I just said
I was fine.
Oh, yeah. Sorry.
So, is this your
first time out here?
Yeah.
I don't think
I'm very popular out here
either.
Oh, I don't know.
You're just fine inside.
I don't know.
I'm not really into
all their shit, you know.
Yeah.
(softly):
Oh, um, I really liked
your computer trick.
Clever, huh?
Terribly clever, yeah, terribly.
Are you late for something?
Yeah, I am, as a matter of fact.
But I mean, it's no big deal.
Um...
Listen, do you want to...
you want to go out Friday?
Yeah.
Yeah?
Sure.
Yeah? Okay!
Uh, 7:00, okay?
Yeah, that's fine.
Great. Great.
Well, where do you live?
I'll pick you up.
Where do you live?
Oh, I, I...
No, I'm sorry, um,
I'm gonna be working on Friday,
so you can just pick me up
at the mall.
Okay.
Okay?
Bye.
See ya.
Hey, Blane.
How you doing?
Hey, buddy,
what's up?
What are you up to?
Oh, not much.
Going to class.
I thought
I saw you outside.
So?
So, what are you doing?
What are you, my mother?
Come on, I gotta go.
I'll see you later.
Blane, what's going on?
Nothing.
Well, not nothing,
I mean, I saw you talking
to that chick--
what's her name?--
Eddie or something.
So, what do you care?
Listen, my best friend is
conversing with a mutant,
you know, I'm curious.
I don't think that's any reason
to get defensive.
I'm not defensive.
I just happen to like her,
all right?
Listen, all right,
it's you know,,
it's your life,
it's none of my business.
You really don't think
she's got something?
No.
I really don't,
I'm sorry.
You're gonna be late, buddy.
(class bell rings)
Okay, the Warsaw Pact's a treaty
that was signed
by the Soviet Union
and its seven East European
satellites, okay.
And what it did was...
it established a mutual
defense organization
as a counterweight
to NATO.
Duckie!
What?
What? What? What?
Well, what'd I put?
You wrote,
the Warsaw Pact is
the pact that's named
after Warsaw.
Uh-huh.
So, the teacher's just
gonna know
that you're just bullshitting.
Okay, okay,
what about the rest of it?
Well,
the Russian Revolution
did not take place
in Germany.
Ow.
Well, what was Karl Marx, then?
He was a German.
Well, there you go.
Yes, but his being German
doesn't have anything
to do with where
the Russian Revolution occurred.
Okay, okay.
Okay, Duckie, can I propose
something to you
without your getting upset,
or angry?
Well, that depends.
On what?
I don't know,
I just said that.
Go ahead.
Well, I propose
that you're deliberately
flunking your courses
so that you can stay
in high school.
Get out of here!
Why, why, why
would I do that?
I don't know,
you tell me.
Well, I'm not.
So, there's
nothing to tell.
Well, you know, you're not
always one to face things.
What, since when?
What, what am
I not facing?
The future.
Well, whether or not you
face the future, it happens,
right?
You run yourself down.
Why do you do that?
I am not running
myself...
You think I'm
running my...
I don't think I'm
running myself down.
Why b-b-because, because
of the way I dress?
'Cause, 'cause I can
laugh at myself?
That's called a
sense of humor.
You should get one;
they're nice.
What are we gonna do
next year?
Well, according to you, I'll
still be in high school.
No, I'm serious.
I mean, not a day
has passed,
in, what, eight years,
when I didn't see you
or talk to you
at least 20 times.
Well, that's devotion.
I know, and even though
I sometimes get angry,
you know that
I secretly love it.
You see, I knew that.
You know, I hope I'm not
the only one in the world
that knows what an incredible
person you are.
Well, at this point in time,
I'm afraid you are, honey.
Okay, I'm gonna get something
to drink
and then we work,
okay, you promise?
Oh, you bet.
Okay,
what do you want?
Oh, beer, scotch,
juice box, whatever.
Okay.
(sighs)
Oh, God.
I love this woman.
I love this woman
and I have to tell her.
And if she laughs, she laughs.
And if she doesn't love me,
she doesn't love me.
But if... if I don't find out...
Oh, I love her too much.
(sighs)
You're a wonderful crowd here,
you know that.
(panting)
¶ Love is living
(imitates crowd noise)
¶ Feeling love
(laughs)
(dog barking)
¶ Love is wanting
Ah!
She's gonna laugh.
Would I blame her?
Here you go.
Oh, shit.
Honey, thanks, uh,
but I'm gonna split,
you know.
Why?
What about your paper?
Uh, that's, that's what
I'm gonna do, you see,
'cause, I mean,
if you help me, thanks a lot,
Hey, drinking and
driving don't mix.
That's why I
ride a bike.
(sighs)
I got it.
(screams)
JENA:
So, uh, what's the deal?
You going out
this weekend?
I don't know.
I'm not sure yet.
Mm?
Why? What are
you gonna do?
Stay home.
Yeah, you going
to study again?
Probably.
Would you put that out?
(giggling):
No.
Well, you study so much,
it makes me ill.
I just don't
see the point.
You don't?
Mm-mmm.
I don't want to work
in a record store my whole life.
Yeah? What do you
want to be a doctor?
(whistle blows)
Oh, God.
(sighs)
TEACHER:
Okay, let's go,
everybody.
Get in your lines, please,
thank you!
Fulmeister.
Here.
Besset!
Basono!
Goulong.
Oh, look, watch out.
Ooh.
Deeds!
Do we smell bad,
or something?
(whispering):
Hey, Benny.
Fox.
Penfield.
I hope they shrivel
up and fall off.
(whistle blows)
Okay.
What was that, Miss Hoeman?
Um.
(clears throat)
I said, I hope they shrivel up
and fall off.
(lightly laughs)
You hope what shrivels up
and falls off?
Her breasts, Miss Dietz.
(laughs)
Shut up!
I'm sorry.
You are out of here,
Hoeman.
Right.
Bye-bye.
Bye, girls.
So, uh,
do you share
your partner's attitude?
No, I don't.
(under breath):
Eat shit!
Excuse me, Miss Dietz.
You've only got a couple
of months left.
You're doing extremely well
in your courses.
And I think
your chances
of getting a scholarship
are excellent.
I know this, Mr. Donnelly.
Why are you in here now?
I don't know.
I guess I just got
a little fed up.
With what?
The way that we get treated.
Look, uh...
you're getting
a top-notch education here,
and I just don't want
to see you throw it away.
I'm getting a better education
than I deserve.
I'm lucky.
I'm fortunate
that the good people
of this community allow me
to attend this school.
Again,
you are misunderstanding me.
No, I understand everything,
Mr. Donnelly.
I don't need
to have it explained to me.
I live it.
It's just sometimes
I get a little upset
and I lose my temper.
I just don't like to see
my friends getting dumped on
and punished
for defending themselves.
Well, uh, we'll just forget
about this whole thing, okay?
Okay.
What about Jena?
She's off, too.
Thank you.
Andie...
if you put out signals that
you don't want to belong,
people are going to make
sure that you don't.
That's a beautiful theory.
Andie, Andie,
Andie, listen.
I heard what happened and,
and I came as fast as I could.
I cut out of home ec
and everything.
Was, was it really bad?
No, it was nothing.
Are you upset?
No, I'm not.
No-- yes,
yes, you are.
I can tell; your eyes get
all squinty and everything.
Listen, I know just what to
do to make you feel better.
I feel fine.
I want to take you
away this weekend.
Do you fish?
(Andie sighs, class bell rings)
Okay, then we
can go right now.
I have class.
Tonight at 7:00 and I won't
take no for an answer.
Try, please.
This woman is suffering inside.
That's all there is to it.
(banging loudly)
Yo, man, next time
I'll kick your ass.
Dat'll be dat.
Dat'll-- I'm just kidding;
that's-- it's a joke.
How about
that stock market?
My broker is E.F. Hutton, and
E.F. Hutton says...
You see,
it never works.
It never works.
I've never seen that work...
(girls scream)
DUCKIE: Oh, shit!
GIRL:
What's going on out there?
Aah...
So this is what
it looks like.
This is great.
Hey, wait a minute,
wai-w-w-w-wait.
You got doors on the
stalls, they're not stopped.
Wait a minute.
We don't have none of
this stuff in the boys'--
wait a minute, we
don't got none of this.
We don't got doors on the
stalls in the boys' room.
We don't have-- what
is this, what?
We don't have a candy
machine in the boys' room.
We don't got none of that.
GIRL: I'm gonna start screaming
in a minute if you
don't get out of here.
I'm sorry, no, I want
the principal here.
I want him here
this instant.
I want-- now,
I'll wait.
Thank you.
Oh, shit!
Why can't I do this?
What have you done?
This-- you have
to subtotal first.
I tell you this
every time.
You never listen.
One more tune, then it's off to
enjoy a terrible relationship.
(drops needle on record)
The furrier next door
loves this.
¶ Soft words
¶ They are spoke so gentle,
yeah ¶
(loud knocking)
¶ It makes it easier
¶ Easier to bear
(shop bell rings)
(snaps fingers)
¶ You won't regret it, no, no ¶
(mouthing words)
¶ Them young girls,
they don't forget it ¶
¶ Love
¶ Is their whole happiness
¶ Yeah
¶ But it's all so easy ¶
¶ All you got to do is
¶ Try, try a little...
¶ Tenderness
¶ Yeah, oh,
you got to do it, man ¶
¶ Hold her where you want her
¶ Squeeze her, don't tease her ¶
¶ Never leave her
¶ Give to her
¶ Got, got to try
a little tenderness ¶
¶ Yeah, yeah, yeah
¶ You got to know how
to love her, man ¶
¶ You've got to squeeze her,
don't tease her ¶
¶ Never leave
¶ You've got to hold her ¶
¶ Rub her softly
¶ Try a little tenderness,
yeah, yeah, yeah ¶
¶ You got to rub her gently
¶ Don't bruise her, no, no ¶
¶ You got to love her
¶ Tease her,
don't displease her ¶
¶ Got to try, now, now, now
¶ Try...
¶ Try a little tenderness
¶ Yeah...
¶ You got to know what to do,
man ¶
¶ Take this advice
¶ You got to love, squeeze,
don't tease my baby ¶
¶ Love her long...
(music fades out)
(breathing
heavily)
(with accent):
Evening, young ladies.
This is a very
good tune.
My mother used
to sing this.
This is Otis;
I love Otis.
We're closed.
You know what an older
woman does for me?
Changes your diapers?
(without accent:)
Touche.
No, seriously though, you're
a very smoky alternative,
but this is the Duck
Man's love in life.
Shall we?
You ever had one
of these?
I don't think so.
Come on... let's plow.
(with accent):
Do I offend?
Andie, hon.
Listen, it's after 7:00.
Don't waste good lip gloss.
I know, Iona.
I mean, I don't mean
to be a bitch or anything,
but I don't think
Mr. Wonderful is going
to happen tonight.
I don't know
what I'm doing.
Wishful makeupping.
Come on.
Wait, wait.
You babes are, like,
talking a sign language
that the old Ducker here
just does not understand.
Now, would you mind
filling me in here?
I'm a little confused.
She got stood
up, twerp.
Stood up?
Wait, h-how so? Wait, I'm here.
I mean, is this like one of
those feminine mystique deals
or something?
He showed.
Um...
Andie.
I'll get that.
Duckie,
I'm really sorry.
What, is this,
um, you're gonna,
you're gonna go
out with this guy?
I mean, is this, you know,
like, a date, or something?
Yeah.
I mean,
you'll like him.
He's not like the other guys,
seriously.
No, n-no way, Andie!
You really piss me
off, you know, 'cause,
'cause you know they shit all
over everybody, including you.
I just-- I can't believe
you'd be this stupid.
Who's shitting on me?
I'm not gonna let anybody shit
on me.
He's just-- he's gonna use
your ass and throw you away.
God, I would have died for you.
So what am I supposed to do?
He asked me out and I like him.
If I hate him
because he's got mon--
just listen to me-- if I hate
him because he's got money,
that's the exact same thing as
them hating us because we don't.
Do you understand?
You can't do this
and, and respect yourself.
Y-You, you... you can't.
Well, I'll make that decision,
all right?
Sure, you c--
you can do what you want.
You know,
you're talking like that
just because I'm going out
with Blane.
Blane?
His, his name is Blane?
Oh... that's a major appliance,
that's not a name.
Just because I'm going out
with Blane doesn't mean
I can't be friends with you.
I mean, it doesn't change
the way I feel about you.
Oh, that's very nice.
I'm, I'm glad.
Here's... here's the point,
Andie.
I'm n--
I'm not particularly concerned
with whether or not you like me.
'Cause I live to like you
and, and,
and I can't like you anymore.
So, so when you get your heart
splattered all over hell
and, and you're feeling
really low and dirty,
don't, don't look to me
to help pump you back up,
'cause, 'cause, 'cause,
'cause maybe for the first time
in your life, I won't be there.
I can't believe
you're actually saying this.
Well, I guess
that's just tough shit.
Sorry.
(loud thud)
That guy in the store.
Oh, he was
a friend of mine.
I've known him
since I was a kid.
He's a really nice guy.
Yeah?
Yeah, I like him a lot.
So you want to go
home and change?
(laughs quietly)
I already did.
Sorry.
No, that's okay.
Oh, boy.
So, where are we going?
You up for a party?
Yeah? No? Maybe?
No, I don't think so.
Why?
"Why?"
Come on, they're my
friends, it's okay.
That's it;
they're your friends.
I wouldn't take you
if I didn't think
they'd accept you.
Can't we just go
somewhere else?
Hey, Andie,
I like you.
I think you like me.
I mean, we both know there's a
lot of bullshit that goes on,
but if you're above
it, I'm above it.
If we want to make anything
out of this whatever,
we got to deal
with it, right?
Yeah.
Come on, I got as
much to lose as you.
We can go out with your
friends if you want.
Go crawl under a rock.
Anything you want.
The choice is yours.
We can go hang gliding.
You like hang gliding?
I've never been
hang gliding.
Well, first
for everything.
If it's a bad time, we leave.
(thunder rumbling)
¶
MAN (faintly):
It's time for more beer!
Hi, Blane.
Hey, Eddie.
Hey, see
you later.
(music playing,
partyers laughing and chatting)
Hey, what's up, bro?
Hey, aren't you the girl
in my art class?
Nice pearls.
This isn't a dinner party,
honey.
¶ So I keep believing
¶ That you and I
can change the world ¶
¶ I'm going 'round and 'round,
'round again ¶
¶ I say things
that I really shouldn't say ¶
¶ I'm going 'round,
'round again ¶
I can't believe I actually
associate with these people.
I can't believe
that I'm actually here.
Pretty bad, huh?
Yeah, it's pretty bad.
I'm sorry.
Hey, let's go upstairs,
huh?
Look, I didn't come here
to get you off, okay?
That was not my idea.
Andie.
Come on,
that is not what I meant.
I haven't even tried
to kiss you, have I?
Look, it's quieter
up there, okay?
Come on.
These hands will remain in
these pockets, I swear to God.
Come on.
So what do you think
of these carpets, huh?
Utterly fab.
It's going to be good.
Oh, hey, Blane.
Steff.
How're you doing?
All right...
no, I'll get another room.
No, no, no, no, come on in.
I'm watching some tunes here.
So... who you got
with you here, Blane?
Uh, Andie, this is
Steff; Steff, Andie.
I hope you guys are
gonna tough it out
until Sunday,
at least when
my folks get home.
I think this one may
just finally kill the old
son of a bitch, Blane.
Another giant step away
from virginity I went.
You are a slut,
aren't you, Benny?
(sighs):
Oh, my God.
Am I having a nightmare?
We've got guests.
BENNY:
I know you.
You're in my calculus class.
Gym.
Your name's Jim?
You are worthless,
aren't you?
You and your friends gave me
a lot of shit the other day.
Everybody gives you shit.
Take it easy, Benny, huh?
This is Steff's party, Blane.
Don't tell me what to do.
Steff.
I mean, you shouldn't be allowed
to invite just anybody.
Steff, she's going
to ruin my night.
Shut up, Benny!
You're a faggot, Blane.
All right, okay,
listen, Benny...
Why don't we just...
Where are you going?
Let's just leave them
with the room, okay?
Why?
And we will get you
something to eat, all right.
I don't want
to know what you are.
I'm gonna take her
to throw up somewhere.
Listen, enjoy yourself.
They're kind of jerks
when they drink, huh?
Bad idea.
Can you just get me
out of here now?
Yeah.
Look, I don't want
to take you home.
I mean, I'd like
to be with you.
If not here, somewhere else;
anywhere you want.
I'm sorry.
What can I say?
I made a mistake.
I overestimated my friends.
I'm sorry.
What, you want to hit me?
Yes, I do.
I'll do it like...
like a hundred times in a day.
It's really-- it's intense.
You ever park?
I'm kind of a drive-by
kind of guy.
¶ Rave up
¶ 'Cause being down
ain't being a rat's head up ¶
¶ So fool those rats
another time, rave up... ¶
You want a drink?
Yeah.
Yeah?
Coke.
Coke? Coke, okay.
Give me your address.
I'll, I'll put you on my route.
Okay, you're gonna have
to help me out here.
You know, you know, someday
that girl's going to realize
just what she missed.
Come on, don't stop,
give me more!
Yeah!
Hi!
IONA:
Prince Charming whimp out?
No, no, he's
at the bar.
Duckie?
(yawns)
He's sulking.
He's not gonna ride his bike
past your house anymore.
Duckie, you're being
a real jerk.
How'd he get in here anyway?
I said he was my kid.
How come you're here?
I've been trying
to figure that all night.
¶ You lost a lot
when you lost me ¶
Sorry.
Mom make this for you?
Yeah. Gross, huh?
¶ You lost a lot
when you lost me ¶
¶ Six paperback books
and a dime tree ¶
¶ You lost a lot when you lost
me, six paperback books... ¶
Hi.
Here you go.
Thanks. You met Iona,
didn't you?
Not formally.
Hi, Blane.
And, um, that's
Duckie Dale over there
behind the glasses.
Hi, Duckie.
Philip F. Dale to you, scum wad.
So where you guys been?
Oh, a friend of mine
was having a party.
Oh, how adorable.
Yeah, it was a little intense.
DUCKIE:
Oh, wait, wait,
you had an intense party?
No, it was a friend
of mine's, I said.
Duckie... shut up!
What's the problem?
This is a classic,
classic piece of work here.
Duckie, please...
Phil.
BLANE:
Hey, Phil, I think
you're making Andie
uncomfortable.
Why don't you just knock it off?
What's the problem?
I devoted my life to the girl,
and this guy, he comes
in one day and-and-and thinks
he knows her, that's funny.
You should give
David Letterman a ring sometime.
I'm sure he'd book you
in a minute.
Phil, would you
like us to leave?
You know,
that's very perceptive.
Come on.
(laughing):
And look at the manners
on this guy; this was a treat.
Really, thanks a million.
You're a great couple
of kids, really.
You know, I can't believe
I actually felt bad
for you tonight,
retarded, little dwarf.
See you.
Nice meeting you.
See you later.
Sorry.
No problem.
(mockingly):
You're an asshole.
Hey, blow me, butt wad.
Coming from you, I take
it as a compliment.
Andie! Yo!
You been replaced.
Gee, I'm...
I'm sorry.
(electric guitar
instrumental break)
Well, what now?
I gotta get up early.
Why don't we
just forget it.
What, home?
Hey, you want to go
to my house?
No, thanks.
You want to eat?
No.
What do you want to do?
Anything.
Um... why don't you just
drop me off at Trax.
You know,
I can, I can...
Trax?
It's real close
to where I live.
Well, it's late;
I'll just drop you home.
You want to go home,
I'll drop you home.
No, but I have something
I have to do there.
Now? Come on, it's late.
You want to go home,
I'll drop you home, it's fine.
I don't want you
to take me home.
Okay, let's go out.
No, I don't want...
We'll go out,
anywhere you want,
anything you
want to do.
I don't want to go out.
You don't want to go out,
you don't want to go home.
What do you want to do, Andie?
I don't want you
to take me home.
Wait, I'm missing something.
I'm not a jerk here.
I don't understand
what you're saying.
Wait a minute.
Let's go.
Don't walk away.
Wait a minute.
I'm talking to you.
No. Just please, I just
don't want you...
Why?
Don't you understand me?!
No, I don't... at all.
Will you listen to me?
I don't want you
to take me home.
Okay, why?
What is the problem?
Because I don't want you
to see where I live, okay?
What?
I'm sorry, forget it.
It's okay.
(sotto voce):
Jesus Christ.
(keys jangling)
(car starts)
(crickets chirping)
(dogs barking in distance)
I'm really sorry
for bumming out
the night for you.
You didn't bum out anything,
I had a great time.
You liar.
I was with you.
I had a great time.
If I was in a Turkish prison,
I'd have a great time with you.
I don't know, it's just...
It's too weird for me, you know?
Maybe this shouldn't happen.
What, you and me?
Well, you know, maybe it
doesn't happen all the time,
it doesn't mean it
isn't right. Right?
Doesn't mean you can't try.
Would you feel any better
if I asked you to the prom?
I mean, I know the
prom's kind of lame,
so if you don't want to go,
it's really no big deal.
(door squeaking)
(screams)
Hey. What?
It happened!
He asked me.
And?
I accepted!
Well, congratulations.
No more moping around
the house waiting
for the telephone to ring?
So... you in love?
Yeah, I think I am.
Well, who is this guy?
His name is Blane.
And he's a senior,
he's so beautiful.
(both chuckle)
Um, he's a... richie.
A whatie?
A richie, it's kind of stupid.
It's just his family
has a lot of money.
Oh, well, is that a problem?
I don't know, it's just weird.
You know, his friends
have a lot of money,
and he has a lot of money.
He drives a BMW.
I don't know, I'm not really
sure if they're gonna accept me.
Well, what does that mean?
I mean, you like him,
he likes you.
What his friends think shouldn't
make any difference.
Yeah, but it's not just his
friends, it's my friends, too.
It's everybody. I'm just not
real... secure about it.
Well, so take the heat.
I mean, you like him,
he likes you; it's worth it.
Is it?
Well, isn't it?
You're right.
I'm just overreacting,
aren't I?
Oh, not necessarily.
I mean, a good kiss
can scramble
anybody's brain.
Look, just don't worry
about it, you know?
And wait and see
how you feel tomorrow.
Good night, hon.
Good night. Thanks.
That's my baby.
Uh, honey.
Uh, would you-- wait a minute.
Could-could I ask you something?
Yeah.
Uh... sometimes
I feel a little sorry
that, um, I'm the one you have
to talk to about these things.
I'm not.
She couldn't have said it
any better than you.
I mean it.
Good night.
(mid-tempo rock beat playing)
Okay, make my day.
I want all the gory details.
The mingling breath,
the pounding heart,
the steamy windows.
I want the whole scoop.
Well, I hate to
disappoint you,
but nothing happened.
Nothing?
Well, not nothing,
I mean, I kissed him.
Anywhere interesting?
Oh, please.
So...
uh...
does he have strong lips?
How can you tell?
Do you feel it in your knees?
I felt it everywhere.
Strong lips.
(Iona laughs)
Talk about lips.
(laughing)
I mean, I'm old enough
to be his mother,
but when the Duck laid
that kiss on me
last night,
I swear
to God, my thighs just went up
in flames.
He must practice on melons,
or something.
This your prom dress?
(laughs)
Believe it or not.
It's great.
It's silly.
It's great material.
You know, I'm going...
to prom.
Stop it!
(giggling):
Well, I am.
Last night he asked me.
And I don't know, I said yes.
It's really weird.
But it might be kind of fun.
IONA:
You were here
for 15 minutes
and you didn't
even tell me!
ANDIE:
Oh, but I really,
really wanted to go.
(giggles)
You lucky girl.
¶ Cherish is the word I use
to describe... ¶
Isn't that a dreamy dress?
¶ All the feeling
¶ That I have hiding here
for you inside ¶
¶ You don't know
how many times I've wished ¶
¶ That I had told you
¶ You don't know
how many times I've wished ¶
¶ That I could hold you...
Iona, I have to go.
Can you just hold
till this song is over?
But I have to leave.
Oh, why can't we start old
and get younger?
¶ Cherish is the word...
I envy you.
I really envy you!
Iona, you're gonna
O.D. on nostalgia.
I loved
"The Big Chill".
I love this dress.
It's a great dress.
Yeah.
My mother bought it
for me.
God, she was so happy.
It was the first
and last time
I ever looked normal.
I mean, you know,
relatively speaking.
It would have been
a fairy tale
if my date hadn't been
the only one at the prom
with a...
wife and two kids.
You want to try it on?
I bet it'd look great on you.
I mean, your butt is
15 years younger than mine.
I mean, I used to
have a great butt.
I did!
I loved my butt!
I wish I had photographs
of it.
You want to try
this on?
Mm, nah, not right now.
Oh, yeah,
you gotta go, I know.
I know.
I gotta get ready myself.
You're going out?
Yeah.
New guy.
Terrance,
he owns a pet shop.
We'll see
what happens.
(giggles)
Have fun.
Give Mr. Perfecto
a squeeze
for me.
Oh, I will.
if you see your
little Duck Man...
be kind.
He's nursing some
fairly serious wounds.
Okay?
Okay.
Bye-bye.
Bye.
Hey, you know, we're going
for, uh, sushi.
Do you think this is too much?
Bye.
¶ You don't know how many times
I've wished that I... ¶
Thought that was very
uncool of you
last night,
Blane.
What?
You mean Andie?
Yeah, I mean Andie.
What's the big deal, I like her.
As a matter of fact,
I was pissed off at you guys
for being so nasty
to her.
It was way out of order
for you to foist her
on the party.
Steff, do you hear yourself?
You hear the same asshole shit
I hear?
What, do I have to spell it out
for you, Blane?
I guess so.
Nobody appreciates your sense
of humor, you know.
As a matter of fact, everybody
is just about to puke from it.
You know, if you've
got a hard-on
for trash, don't
take care of it
around us, pal,
all right?
Right, buddy.
Listen,
I don't need a lot
of shit on this one, Blane,
all right? I really don't.
Money all that matters to you?
Wh-Where in the hell does
that come from?
Well, look around you, would I
treat my parents house like this
if I, if money was any
kind of issue?
Well, wh-why are
you doing this?
You know, why don't
you just nail her
and get it
over with.
You know, why are
you getting involved?
Is there something wrong
with that?
I just think it's stupid.
You know, it's pointless.
you know, and
your parents,
I think they'll
be thrilled.
They have nothing to do with it.
Really?
Yeah.
I've seen your mother go to work
on you, Blane.
You know, it's vicious!
And when Bill and Joyce
get through with you,
you won't know
whether to shit
or go sailing.
Listen, I, I'm getting really
bored with this conversation.
All right, Blane.
You know, if you want your
little piece of low-grade ass,
fine, take it,
you know,
but if you do,
you're not gonna
have a friend.
Is that right?
Yeah, that's right.
I mean, if you want
to make the choice,
go ahead and make
it, all right?
I, I personally wouldn't trash
a friendship over it,
but... hey,
I'm old-fashioned.
So...
Why don't you take a shower;
you look like shit.
ANDIE:
Two weeks ago,
if somebody told me
that I'd be going out with you,
I never would have
believed them.
BLANE:
Why?
I'm not all that bad.
No, but...
What about me and you?
You know, it's so insane
that somebody
you've never met,
never talked to
can be your enemy.
Mm... yeah.
You shouldn't meet
my parents, then.
(laughs)
Okay.
Well, I mean,
they're not ogres, but...
(both laugh)
I think they still believe
in arranged marriages.
Corporate families replaced
royal families.
I'm the crowned prince
of McDonnough Electric.
It's irrelevant.
No.
Yeah.
I could just tell them all
to go to hell.
Tell them to go to hell.
Everyone, friends,
parents.
All of them.
What about you?
Hmm?
Somebody doesn't
believe in me, I...
I can't believe in them.
You don't lie, do you?
I don't have to lie.
This is gonna happen.
Okay, I really want this
to happen.
Yeah.
(distant train passing)
¶ So, please, please, please
¶ Let me, let me, let me
¶ Let me get what I want...
Can I help you?
I'm fine, thank you.
Something for the prom?
Just looking.
Yeah, well, if you
need anything, uh...
(sighs)
This is trash.
MOTHER:
It's very becoming.
Mother, it looks
like I should be standing on top
of a wedding cake.
Oh, darling,
don't I wish.
And I hate
this material
and by the way, I cannot
stand baby blue.
(phone rings)
(phone continues ringing)
Well, do you know where he is?
WOMAN:
No, I'm sorry,
he didn't tell me
where he was going.
Okay, well, then if he calls
or comes home
can you just tell him
to call me?
Who is this, please?
Andie.
Who?
Andie!
Well, yes,
could I have your number?
Yeah, no, he has the number.
Well, fine,
I'll leave him a note, dear.
Okay, thanks. Bye.
(sighs)
Where in the hell is he?
(dog panting)
(sighs)
Never fall in love, Ace,
you just won't like it.
It's very complicated.
Andie?
Andie!
(knocking on door)
Andie.
Come in.
Hi.
Hi, Daddy.
I brought you
something.
What is it?
Well, it's a little
something I picked up
for you.
¶ Ta-tah.
I know it's a
little busy,
but I know you can make
something out of it.
If you need to.
Wow.
Yeah.
Do you like it?
It's a beautiful color.
Yeah.
It's really pretty.
God, it reminds me so much
of your mom.
You know, she
always wore pink.
And she looked
so beautiful in it.
It's okay.
Okay.
Thank you.
Daddy.
What?
I just want you to know
I really appreciate this.
I think I can make
something out of it.
Can I ask you something?
Sure.
What?
Where'd you get the money
to pay for this?
Well, why, it wasn't that much.
I had some money.
From your new job?
Ah, yeah, from my new job.
(sighs)
I came home before work
on Wednesday
and your car was
in the driveway.
Mm-hmm.
You know,
you didn't have to lie to me.
Yes, I did.
No, you didn't.
I had a line on something
and I missed the
appointment.
Oh, why'd you miss
the appointment?
It slipped my mind.
It didn't slip your mind.
You didn't want the job.
You just went to the counselor
because I forced you to.
Am I right?
Yeah, what's your point, Andie?!
My point is, you just didn't go!
You saying I deliberately missed
the appointment?
Yes.
Is this how you feel about me?
(sighs)
Yes.
Well, I didn't know this.
Well, now you do.
Oh, you know everything,
now, huh?
You're 18
and you got a
scholarship
and, uh,
you're, uh,
That's not fair!
all grown-up and free,
and I'm just an ignorant
son of a bitch who never
gave you anything.
Hey, I never asked
Oh, that's brilliant!
Why can't you just forget her?!
It's late; you got school.
No, don't walk out
on this!
Will you please just
listen to me?!
Please?!
I've already been
through this, Andie!
Sure, you go through
it every day!
You're still
going through it!
Why can't you just
realize that she's gone
and she's not
gonna come back?!
She's never
coming back!
Shut up!
Dad...
Goddamn it!
why can't you
accept it?!
She's just gone!
She...
Why can't you accept it?
Because... I love her.
That's why.
Well, I loved her,
too, you know.
(crying)
She just didn't
love us back.
(sighs)
Okay, she tried.
I don't know.
She just couldn't handle it.
Yeah, but I...
I-I knew it.
I knew it all along.
I mean, when I was five,
I felt it.
Remember when she didn't
come home that time?
I knew it then,
I knew why.
I was 14, and I knew it.
You were 50,
and you didn't.
You know, you can't go on
living every day in the past.
She left us, Daddy.
We didn't leave her.
There was nothing
we could do about it.
It just happened.
(sighs)
Since when is the
daughter supposed
to know more
than her father?
(chuckles)
(sniffles)
I've just been
a blind fool.
(sighs)
And you're a blind fool
that needs a shave, too.
And I need a shave.
(sighs heavily)
Well...
(sighs)
You'd better get to bed.
You got school.
And I got to hit
the hay, too,
'cause I got a few things
that I got to do tomorrow.
Okay?
Okay.
Uh, I would have
got you some shoes,
but I didn't know your size.
(door closes)
(crying)
(sniffles and sighs)
¶
(class bell rings)
How you doing?
(indistinct crowd chatter)
Why haven't
you called me?
Oh, I got nailed for
the stable thing.
I guess a groom saw us.
It's against club rules.
I called you three times,
and I left messages.
Yeah?
Well, I-I didn't
get them. My family,
they're very irresponsible
about that stuff, you know?
I waited for you
this morning.
Yeah? Where?
Parking lot.
I saw you, and I thought
that you saw me.
No.
What about prom, Blane?
(sighs)
Oh, Andie, I'm
having a bad day.
Can we talk later?
No. What about prom?
Come on.
Why don't we just
meet after school?
No! What about prom?!
Andie, come on.
Just say it.
What?
Just say it!
I want to hear you
say it.
BLANE:
Andie, please,
all right?
I want to hear you say it.
A month ago, I asked
somebody else,
and I forgot.
You're a liar!
You're a filthy,
fucking, no-good liar!
You don't have the guts
to tell me the truth!
Just say it!
I'm not lying.
Tell me!
What?
What do you
want to hear?!
Just tell me!
What?!
You're ashamed
to be seen with me!
No, I am not, I am not!
You're ashamed
to go out with me!
You're afraid.
No, I'm...
You're terrified
your Goddamn rich
friends won't approve!
Just say it!
Just tell me the truth!
(exhales deeply)
You don't understand it.
It has nothing at all
to do with you.
Andie!
(footsteps running)
Andie?
Forget about it, man.
It's not worth getting upset
over it, you know?
BLANE:
Ah, why don't you just
take off, Steff, please?
Well, listen, any girl
that did that to me,
I would not be too jazzed
to hold on to, Blane.
It's not worth it, man.
I told you,
it wasn't gonna work, you know.
The girl was, is and
will always be nada.
(door opening)
(footsteps thudding on stairs)
You got a
problem, friend?
(scoffs)
(Duckie yelling)
(grunting and groaning)
(coughing)
(grunts)
Come on.
(blows landing)
(grunting)
All right, all right!
Nice, huh?
¶ She was a showgirl
(gong-sounding doorbell chimes)
¶ With yellow feathers
in her hair ¶
¶ And a dress cut down
to there ¶
(gong chimes)
¶ She would merengue
IONA:
¶ And do the cha-cha
Cha-cha!
Andie?
¶ And while she tried
to be a star... ¶
640,,*Default,641,0000,0000,0000,,Thank you.
1337,,*123,641,0000,0000,0000,,请你出去
Yeah?
You're Andie,
aren't you?
641,,*Default,642,0000,0000,0000,,You know, l won't deny that things
have gotten progressively worse
1338,,*123,642,0000,0000,0000,,你知道吗 我不否认在你不在的这些日子
Yeah, I am.
Uh, how do you know me?
Well, Iona told me.
642,,*Default,643,0000,0000,0000,,during your absence.
1339,,*123,643,0000,0000,0000,,情况越来越糟了
I'm Terrance. Terry.
643,,*Default,644,0000,0000,0000,,The public, the military, everyone,
it seems, is starving.
1340,,*123,644,0000,0000,0000,,公众 军队 每个人似乎都在挨饿
¶ They were young
and they had each other... ¶
Oh, the pet shop, right?
Yeah, among other things.
644,,*Default,645,0000,0000,0000,,Our blood supplies are, well, gone.
1341,,*123,645,0000,0000,0000,,我们的血液供应也 出问题了
She's in the bedroom
getting ready.
You might want to go
in there and tell her
to shake her tail
feather; we're late.
645,,*Default,646,0000,0000,0000,,Ed.
1342,,*123,646,0000,0000,0000,,艾德
Okay.
¶ At the Copa, Copacabana
Iona?
¶ Music and passion
were always the fashion ¶
Nice to meet you.
¶ At the Copa
¶ They fell in love
¶ Copa ¶
IONA:
¶ Copa
¶ Cabana, a yellow feather
¶ She was a show girl
Iona?
IONA:
Hi, honey.
I'm in here.
Laugh, and I'll deck ya.
What happened?
Either it's all those drugs
I took in the '60s,
or I am really in love.
(laughs)
What do you think?
Honestly.
Honestly, I think
you look great.
Oh, I look like a mother.
No. Well,
yeah, a little,
but that's okay.
You look happy.
I am.
It's weird, but I...
Did you meet him?
Yeah.
He's a yuppie,
but he's so nice.
He's employed,
he's heterosexual.
I swear to God,
I'm so far ahead of the game,
next time you see me,
I'll probably be
picking out
my china patterns.
(laughs)
(crying)
Hey, are you all right?
No, you're not.
What...
What, I blow your mind? No?
No, that's not it.
It's boy trouble?
The worst?
Way beyond.
He backed out on me.
He said he asked somebody
else, and he forgot about it.
(crying)
I can't believe it,
I can't believe it.
(sighs)
I'm so humiliated.
I could have killed
him! I swear!
You know, I just
walked right into it.
I know, I know.
(sniffles)
Oh, love is awful,
isn't it? Oh.
It's okay.
(crying)
(sniffling)
(sighs and sniffles)
You remember when I...
and when you said
that-that, um,
if I wanted your prom
dress, I could have it?
Mm-hmm.
Well, I need it.
I want it.
What for?
(sighs)
I just need it.
(sniffles)
Okay.
It's yours.
(rhythmic drumbeat)
673,,*Default,674,0000,0000,0000,,Vampires can never survive.
1370,,*123,674,0000,0000,0000,,吸血鬼不能永远生存
(upbeat music playing)
674,,*Default,675,0000,0000,0000,,That's the truth.
1371,,*123,675,0000,0000,0000,,这才是事实
But you love him.
¶
But I love him.
I do feel like I have to go back
and see what we're willing
to do about that.
Because I would never
forgive myself
¶
Another first.
Your guy's going to fall through
the floor when he comes in.
No, he won't.
The hell he's not.
No, he really won't.
He's not coming.
What?
It's okay.
I'm gonna go.
Alone?
Yeah, I'm not sad about it.
I'm not hurt.
I mean, you know,
I am hurt a little bit,
but I know if I don't do it,
I'll just feel a lot worse.
I'm just gonna go in,
walk in, walk out,
and come home.
You sure?
(sighs)
I just want to let them know
that they didn't break me.
("If You Leave" by Orchestral
Manoeuvres In The Dark playing)
¶ If you leave,
don't leave now ¶
¶ Please don't take
my heart away ¶
¶ Promise me
just one more night ¶
¶ And we'll go
our separate ways ¶
¶ We've always had
time on our sides ¶
¶ Now it's fading fast ¶
Open up.
¶ Every second, every moment
¶ We've got to,
gotta make it last ¶
¶ I touch you once,
I touch you twice ¶
¶ I won't let go at any price ¶
STEFF:
Well, as soon as
anybody's ready to go
upstairs and get serious,
just let me know.
We've only been
here an hour.
Well, we can go up
and come back down
again, Benny, all right?
Did you look
at the suite?
STEFF:
It's 300 bucks
a night, Benny.
It's not gonna be
a palace, okay?
I think we should
stay for a while.
We're not gonna see these
people for much longer.
Come on, it's kind
of the end, okay?
STEFF:
I don't give a
shit what you do.
¶ I'll be running
the other way... ¶
Oh, damn.
My God.
You're here!
What happened?!
Well, uh, guess
you're looking at it.
Oh, wow, you look great.
Thanks, you, uh,
you look stunning.
(giggles)
May I admire you?
Oh, uh, if, if you wish.
Let's plow.
¶
¶ Oh-oh-oh
It wouldn't be unheard of.
¶ Seven years
went under the bridge ¶
¶ Like time standing still...
A little, uh, lingering
doubt perhaps, pal?
You know, you gotta
give her credit, though.
691,,*Default,692,0000,0000,0000,,There can't be a cure.
1388,,*123,692,0000,0000,0000,,他们不能成为解药
I mean, after
you dumped her,
she certainly went out
and found herself what
692,,*Default,693,0000,0000,0000,,l can't let you do it.
1389,,*123,693,0000,0000,0000,,我不会让你那么做的
I'd have to say is
probably the most
693,,*Default,694,0000,0000,0000,,l'm sorry.
1390,,*123,694,0000,0000,0000,,对不起
Steff.
You buy everything, Steff.
You couldn't buy her, though.
That's what's killing
you, isn't it?
Steff.
I don't want to
listen to this.
That's it, Steff.
She thinks you're shit.
And deep down,
you know she's right.
Hi.
You don't need me
to say I'm sorry.
It's done. It's over with.
I'm fine.
¶ You always said...
Oh, well, if that's true,
then I'm glad.
¶ ...we'd meet again ¶
¶ Someday
It's not true.
It doesn't matter, does it?
You told me you couldn't believe
in somebody
who didn't believe in you;
I believed in you.
Always believed in you.
Just didn't believe in me.
I love you.
¶ I need you now
like I needed you then ¶
¶ You always said
we'd meet again ¶
Always.
Andie.
He came here alone.
Okay, you're right.
He's not like the others.
If you don't go to him now,
I'm never gonna take you
to another prom ever
again, you hear me?
I mean, this is
an incredibly romantic moment
and you're ruining it for me.
¶ I touch you twice,
I won't let go at any price ¶
Thanks, Duckie.
Go ahead.
¶ We'd meet again someday... ¶
Blane?
¶ Oh-oh-oh
¶ Oh-oh-oh, oh-oh-oh
¶ If you leave
¶ Oh-oh-oh
¶ Oh, if you leave
¶ Oh-oh-oh, oh-oh-oh
¶ Oh, if you leave...
Captioning sponsored by
PARAMOUNT
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org
¶ Caroline laughs
and it's raining all day ¶
¶ She loves to be
one of the girls ¶
¶ She lives in the place
in the side of our lives ¶
¶ Where nothing
is ever put straight ¶
¶ She turns herself round
and she smiles and she says ¶
¶ "This is it,
that's the end of the joke" ¶
¶ And loses herself
in her dreaming and sleep ¶
¶ And her lovers walk
through in their cloaks ¶
¶ She's... pretty in pink ¶
¶ Isn't she...
pretty in pink? ¶
¶ Isn't she? ¶
¶ All of her lovers
all talk of her notes ¶
¶ And the flowers
that they never sent ¶
¶ And wasn't she easy? ¶
¶ Isn't she pretty in pink? ¶
¶ The one who insists
he was first in the line ¶
¶ Is the last
to remember her name ¶
¶ He's walking around
in this dress that she wore ¶
¶ She is gone,
but the joke's the same ¶
¶ Pretty in pink
¶ Isn't she... ¶
¶ Pretty in pink?
¶ Isn't she? ¶
¶ All the favorite rags
are worn ¶
¶ And other kinds of uniform
¶ But kid, you're already free
like individuality ¶
¶ You are what she wants
to be until tomorrow. ¶