You almost died.
Yes.
Don't do it again.
Previously on "Scandal"...
what do you want?
I want a divorce.
I would like to marry you.
Whatever's wrong, don't say
you're marrying Edison.
You're willing to bring down
the whole Republic
'cause you feel guilty!
And if what we did gets out?
Then it gets out,
and we are brought to justice.
You are not the president.
Hollis Doyle rigged the voting machines.
It's a go.
We all helped cover it up.
Mellie? Cyrus? Olivia?
I told Edison I wouldn't marry him.
I changed my mind about that.
What?
Don't wait for me.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Honey, I'm back.
Do you have it?
It's 7:00 in the morning.
Do you have it or not?
Yes.
You didn't sleep at all
last night. Maybe you should--
don't.
Okay.
What are you doing?
I thought you could use
a little morning pick-me-up.
Mellie--
Shh.
You don't have to do anything.
I'll do all the work.
Mellie...
Ignore it.
Yes?!
Mr. President?
Cyrus, you're in my bathroom.
Yes, sir, Mr. President.
I'm as unhappy about that as you are.
I sent two aides, and neither
had the courage to knock.
Sir?
Hi, Cyrus.
Good morning... ma'am.
A-All set for
the christening tomorrow?
Yes. Thank you. Sir?
You have bad news.
Four Americans have been
kidnapped abroad.
Oh, God.
Oh, God, Oh, God, oh, God.
Mr. Rosen? Police!
Mr. Rosen?
Be right there!
I'm officer Drew.
This is officer Bristol.
Hello. Hi. Uh, I'm sorry.
Took a second to answer the door.
I had to, uh, throw some pants on.
Anyway, what can I do for you?
We got a call
from one of your neighbors.
Said they heard a disturbance
coming from your place.
Really? No, uh...
not that I--
No. I don't--
what kind of disturbance?
A woman screaming.
A fight of some sort.
No. No. Uh, no fight.
Uh...
maybe the TV was on too loud.
I don't hear the TV.
I turned it off
when I heard you knocking.
No one else was here last night
or early this morning?
Just you?
Yep. Yep. Uh-huh.
Just me. I-I live alone.
All right, Mr. Rosen.
Thank you for your time.
I will be sure to keep the TV down.
This tape arrived at our embassy
in Kashfar an hour ago.
"Head up.
Look into the camera."
The guys with the guns are
Kashfar liberation front,
a local terror group
affiliated with Al Qaeda.
Most of them can't even read the koran.
Thugs with an excuse to wreak havoc.
"tell them what you are.
Tell them what agency
you work for."
what do they want?
The release of Moktada Al Far.
Local Leader, picked up
last year, now in Gitmo.
We don't negotiate with
terrorists. They know that.
"speak into the camera, you bitch."
If he's not released in 48 hours,
they say they'll start shooting
these guys, one per day.
What's he saying?
"Speak, you godless American whore.
Tell them who you work for." I work
for the international red cross.
I was delivering medical supplies.
What about the family?
We're waiting on that, sir.
They deserve to know.
What are we waiting for?
It's complicated.
And why is that?
Because they're ours, sir.
Are you saying that they're spies?
They're our top C.I.A. assets
in the region, Mr. President.
You want to tell me how these
two-bit junior Jihadis
got their hands
on legitimate U.S. operatives?
We don't know--
Well, find the hell out!
I'd like a large coffee
and a bran muffin, please.
Okay.
No. Make that banana nut.
Ah, hell, make it a doughnut.
Ooh.
Sorry about that.
Is it okay? Did I, uh...
I short-circuit your life?
My life is
still intact. Thank you.
Good. Well,
how about a doughnut?
The doughnuts here are amazing.
They are the unsung heroes
of the pastry case.
I'm good. Thank you.
Sure.
So, what do you do?
Okay, come on.
Top-Secret
government official?
C.I.A.? N.S.A.?
You know, this place
is like a--
like a "who's who?"
of high-powered D.C.
Once, I saw the vice president
take someone else's latte.
I did.
Not cool.
What do you do?
Me? Nothing.
I sell office supplies.
No, you don't.
Sure, I do. Yeah.
I can get you a great deal
on, uh, protractors in bulk.
Hmm.
I'm a tour guide.
Up on that double-Decker
bus all day.
Did you know there's a typo
in the inaugural address
on the right wall
of the Lincoln memorial?
Mnh.
Mm.
That is a very impressive
fake job you have.
Likewise.
Hello?
David Rosen just called.
He's in trouble.
Her name is Wendy.
Was Wendy.
Wendy Westerberg.
25 years old.
Came to D.C. five years ago
from Allentown to attend G.W.
Dropped out her junior year.
No social network presence.
Where'd she work? So far
zero employment history.
But she lives on Mintwood Place.
Rent's probably about 4 grand a month.
Find out how she swings it.
Did you know her well? A little.
We hung out a few times.
She's a regular at Mcghee's on prospect.
Did you have sex with her?
David, you need to tell me everything.
Your life could depend on it.
Yes, we had sex.
It's the last thing
I remember before--
I didn't kill her.
What's David been up to?
After losing his job
as an A.U.S.A.
And being blackballed
by the justice department
due to a series of embarrassing
high-profile failures,
Mr. Rosen knocked on just
about every door on k street
and the hill looking for work.
When none of those doors opened,
he tried forming
his own firm,
working out of his apartment.
Made business cards and everything. Mm.
I didn't even know they made,
uh, stock this thin.
The phone never rang.
Pupils are dilated.
Also you see how they're
turned inward? Yeah.
My pupils are turned inward?
You got roofied.
I'd say seven, eight hours ago.
No lividity or rigor mortis,
so Wendy here's pretty fresh.
I'd say she died an hour ago, maybe two.
Oh, thank God. Thank God.
I knew I couldn't--
are we moving her?
Moving her?!
If we're moving her, we gotta move now.
Moving her means
the killer might go free.
We're not moving her!
Everybody, hold on.
David, you've been set up.
Professionally, by the looks of it.
Now you tell me you lied to the police.
I panicked. I did.
But I cannot tamper with a crime scene.
We can try to help you sell the truth,
try to explain away
your lies to the cops,
dead woman lying in your bed,
but you have to ask yourself,
will the police believe you?
Will they work overtime
getting to the bottom
of this mystery, or will they
go for the easy arrest?
But moving the body has its own risks.
It's illegal, and it makes it
Harder for the police
to find the real killer,
so tell us what you want.
Either way,
we'll help you fight this.
Do it.
You got her jewelry?
Electronics, too.
Laptop?
No laptop.
She has one.
There's a power cord.
I looked everywhere.
Fine. Break that lamp.
Why? Needs to look like a "B" And "E."
it won't throw off the examiners,
but it'll buy us more time with the cops.
What happens next?
You go to work.
You have a job, right?
Yes, I have a job.
No thanks to any of you.
Who can tell me
the three branches of government?
Anybody?
How about just one?
David's bank statements.
There was only one recent
deposit, for $5,000.
Who's Eugenia Bergman?
David's grandmother.
She paid his rent last month.
We ruined David's life.
So you go to your job
just like nothing ever happened,
because, David...
nothing happened.
What are you looking for?
We need spatter for the sheets,
for the walls.
We need fresh blood.
Here.
You said you wanted to learn cleanup.
This is cleanup.
Wait! Eyes open.
You can't miss.
She's already dead.
It's not her I'm worried about.
You're a natural.
He's in a meeting. There's
nothing on the schedule.
You think I make this
stuff up to amuse you?
Louise, who's he meeting with?
Together we will resolve this crisis.
And may we become
better friends in the process.
I didn't think that was
possible, Mr. Ambassador.
Keep me posted.
You got--Thank you.
You met the ambassador
to Kashfar without me, sir?
I saved you an hour
of your life--
An hour I wasted trying to get
the Kashfaris to step up
and take responsibility
for their own security.
You didn't want me in the meeting.
Can I help you with something?
Is there something we need to discuss?
You tell me, Cy.
I guess not.
I'm in!
Wendy's cell was stolen at the scene,
but I hacked into the cloud.
There's nothing on her finances
yet, but it looks like
she was uploading a bunch
of photos from her phone
almost every night.
Okay, let's see 'em.
Uh, these are a bunch
of pictures of, uh...
men. Lots and lots
of naked--
Hey.
She wasn't a fan of faces.
If she was sleeping with all these guys,
maybe one of them got jealous.
Is that's someone's--
Hairy baby arm? No.
Abby.
Oh, right.
The good news is it doesn't
seem like we have to worry
about any doormen or cabbies.
Bad news?
The bartender at Mcghee's
definitely remembers Wendy and
that she left with David.
Cops will be coming with a warrant.
Well, they won't find anything
at his place.
We were thorough. How long till
they find her at her home?
Well, based on the ambient
temperature in her apartment,
two days, three Max.
I've got Quinn on surveillance.
She's good at it.
So we have at least two days
to Figure out
who all these men are
and if any of them
might have wanted Wendy dead.
She ordered Cable. Wendy
ordered Cable. What?
Cable guy came.
Her neighbor left him in.
So we just went from having
two days to find out
who framed David...
to having two hours.
It's like a puzzle.
A thousand-Piece puzzle.
Of man parts.
We don't have time,
we don't have names.
We don't have numbers.
What do we have?
Location stamps.
Huck can pin the location
where each photo was taken.
We know where they live.
We know their names.
Like this guy here--
Based on the location stamp
of where the photo was taken
and some spring break shots on Facebook,
I'm gonna say he's Chase Coleman,
bike messenger for beltway courier
until six months ago, when
clients' sensitive materials
were leaked to the "times."
Bitch put something in my drink.
Stole my messenger bag.
Next thing I know,
I can't get hired anywhere,
and I'm selling my bike.
Please take one. I have to
get rid of 500 by noon.
Jason Davies.
Photo was snapped at a duplex.
The only other male resident
is a norm dinova, born 1928.
So unless old normy keeps
himself in Amazing shape...
the sad thing is I actually thought
we kinda had something,
and then two weeks
after we start bangin',
my club's all over the frickin' news.
Davies owns the Luna lounge
on 9th street.
They had that big drug bust
the "post" Broke last month.
They've all had some kind of thing.
That guy was connected
to the massage parlor bust.
Ah, this is the guy that had an affair
with his daughter's
best friend--
Congressional Aide, remember?
Wendy wasn't just sleeping
with these guys.
She was digging up dirt, exposing secrets.
But... why?
Yeah. I paid her
for some stories.
I mean, what's a few g's for
seven front-Page bylines, huh?
I am really sorry she's dead.
Good source.
So Wendy--She's some kind
of story whore?
She targets men with access
to sensitive information,
tries to get it out of them through sex.
If that doesn't work, she roofies them,
digs for dirt herself, and sells
it to the highest bidder.
Now we know how she made rent.
Huck says the cops
are at the bar talking to the bartender.
Their next stop is gonna be David.
I'm on it.
So, David, what secret
is she getting from you?
What did she want from you?
What do you think she wanted from me?
That we faked the moon landing?
That a Starbucks tall is really a small?
She wanted defiance, liv.
She wanted to know why
a grand jury had been convened.
What did you tell her?
Nothing.
I didn't get the chance.
Next thing I knew, I was
waking up covered in blood,
framed for her murder.
Because apparently I am the single most
unlucky schmuck...
Or because that's the way you wanted it.
What?
You won.
Defiance is dead, and so am I.
So why isn't it enough
to ruin my career?
Why do you have to throw
the rest of my life
on the fire, too?
Are you actually
suggesting--
Unless you haven't won yet.
Or maybe you didn't win until just now.
Or rather until you planted
a dead girl in my bed.
I'm the last loose end, aren't I?
Lock me up, and you have
nothing more to worry about.
I only have a minute.
He's watching me, liv.
He's not watching you.
The president is watching me.
I feel like every time
I leave to see you,
he knows where I'm going and he
adds another mark against me.
Can we not talk about him?
What did you need?
Did you have David Rosen
framed for murder?
No offense.
None taken.
Why would I have David Rosen
framed for murder?
To put defiance to bed once and for all.
I can't say it's the worst idea
I've ever heard, but no. No?
No. Defiance is over, Liv.
It died with Verna.
I know things are bad
between you and Fitz, but...
I-I'm sorry about
the christening, by the way.
I'll have you in
and out in an hour or two.
You'll barely have to see him.
What?
I think... he knows.
I think he knows what we did.
I'm pretty sure.
Liv, there's no way-- I
haven't slept in ten months.
I have our last conversation
on a loop in my head
all night every night.
I think he knows what we did, Cyrus.
My minute is up.
I have to get back.
Are you--
I'm fine.
Cyrus.
What?
Defiance isn't ever going to be over.
Where are we?
We just ran out of time.
Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh.
You kiss?
You give that monkey a kiss?
Give daddy a kiss?
What do you want?
- is he in there?
- Shh. It's baby time.
He can play with that baby for hours.
I don't know how he does it.
I don't have the patience.
Me, either.
Mellie.
Something has to be done.
He can't keep this up.
What do you propose we do, Cyrus?
I have tried everything.
Right now I'm just trying
to keep him focused and calm
so that he can run the country.
Sometimes I think that baby is
all that's holding him together.
He knows about defiance.
No.
No. This is about Olivia.
Something happened, and they're done,
and he just needs time to adjust.
That's what I thought, too.
But it's been almost a year.
This isn't just about Olivia.
So he's drinking more than usual.
We can handle that.
I am handling that.
He could bathe in scotch for all I care.
That's not the problem.
The problem is, he's not
using me like he's supposed to.
I'm the guard dog, I'm the bad cop,
I'm the Dragon that gets released.
I run the meetings and make the calls
and help him come to decisions.
Except I'm not.
He's isolating himself.
He's shutting me out.
He's running for the country,
for real, on his own.
He doesn't trust us, Mellie.
I've tried talking to him.
Try again.
I will. After I get him through
your daughter's christening.
Whose brilliant Idea was that?
Olivia Pope as godmother?
Mellie...
It's not just my... problem here.
If I'm right, if he knows
about defiance,
it's both of us he doesn't trust.
And if he doesn't trust us
when he gets tired and thirsty
and goes looking for water,
he's going to drink
from someone else's trough.
He needs somewhere to lean,
he's going to lean on someone else.
He's going to start trusting
someone else,
and once that happens,
someone else is going to be
riding our horse across the finish line.
Um... boo!
What do you see? Hmm?
And back to our story that led the hour.
The White House has issued
a statement regarding
the four American Aide workers
who went missing
near Kashfar City yesterday morning.
And while some reports
suggest the Americans
may have been captured by rebel forces,
the White House is denying
those claims, saying--
Any news?
Nothing.
Is David gonna go down for this?
Not if I can help it.
Abby.
Are you--
I'm fine. I'm--I'm fine.
Work helps.
So does exercise--
Stuff that numbs you keeps you
from thinking too much.
Dating also helps, but...
it also helps to remember
that he hates you,
and it helps to try to hate him, too.
And that works for you?
I was talking about you and David.
Someone keeps calling Wendy.
I've been monitoring her
cell phone activity just in case
anything interesting came up,
and today something did--
Four calls, all from the same line.
Can we track the number?
I already did.
They're coming from
the joint chiefs' office.
In the Pentagon.
It's a fishing expedition.
They got nothing--No case.
They're grasping at air.
So you? You do exactly what was
done to you as a A.U.S.A.
Guy comes in with his lawyer, clams up,
flat-out refuses
to play ball.
Probably annoyed you to no end, right?
Now see, that's how we do this.
Say nothing, do nothing,
admit to nothing.
Let me do the talking,
and we'll be fine.
Good. Just like that.
You got it.
These past several months
have been very difficult
for you, haven't they, David?
You don't have to answer that.
I mean, if I were fired,
gosh, I'd be so frustrated.
And not just frustrated, but angry.
The kind of anger that just
sits there and doesn't go away.
Are you angry, David?
You don't have to answer that, either.
In fact, my client doesn't have
to answer any--
Do you remember the case
I was working on
when I got fired, Mike?
We referred to it internally
as defiance.
What are you doing? Defiance is the county
in Ohio that elected our president.
Not by an honest accounting of votes,
the case alleged, but through
an illegal manipulation--
Voting machines.
Okay, I need to, um,
speak with m--
It's a bold claim, and I say "Claim"...
because it never
saw the inside of a courtroom.
You wanna know why?
David, please.
Because I was an idiot.
Are you an idiot, too, Mike?
Your theory of the crime
is that I, David Rosen,
the man whose job you're now occupying,
whose chair you're now sitting in,
your longtime colleague
with extensive legal training
and no prior record whatsoever
picked up a woman at a bar
and then brought her to my place,
where I promptly stabbed her to death.
Because that's what I am--
a stabber.
Give me a knife and I'll stab anything.
Oh, how I love to stab.
Which is why, when I finished
stabbing her in my apartment,
I carried the body to her place
and stabbed it some more.
Why settle for a crime of passion
when a burglary gone wrong
is so easy to stage?
You were the last person
She was seen with.
By a bartender who's routinely drunk
for the last two-Thirds
of his shift.
Trust me, I'm a regular.
Which in evidentiary terms means
you have absolutely nothing.
So if you want to keep this job,
stay in This nice Office,
look out at that beautiful
view of the mall every day
and put yourself on the fast
track to Attorney General,
don't be an idiot.
Leave me alone
and forget this ever happened.
Because only an idiot pursues cases
he stands no chance of winning.
I learned that the hard way.
If I were you,
I'd spare myself that shame.
And since I'm under no legal obligation
to continue this
bizarre and humiliating visit
to my old office...
I'll leave you to it.
Well...
That was fun.
We should, uh, do it again soon.
I expect we will.
I'm looking for a captain Jacob Ballard.
You found him.
You could have just called me...
or run into me accidentally
at the coffee place.
You didn't have to come
all the way down to the Pentagon
just to ask me out.
That's a hike.
She was stabbed to death?
Oh, my God.
Do they know--
Who did it? No.
No idea.
Was she working on a story?
Maybe trying to get
some information from you?
Are you a detective?
No.
'cause you sound like a detective.
I'm not a detective.
Well, then why are you asking me
detective-like questions?
I can't tell you that.
Ahh.
I know Wendy traded in secrets.
Was there anything she had on you,
anything you might have leaked to her?
So even though you're not a detective,
I'm some kind of suspect here?
At this point,
I think everyone
in her phone log is a suspect.
She came to me a month ago
with some information
she wanted to sell.
I didn't take it very seriously
until a couple of days ago
when something I was working on
Suddenly made
that information pertinent.
What were you working on?
My turn.
Classified.
Unlike you, I don't have the choice
about what I can and cannot say.
Were you going to buy
the information she was selling?
I work at intel
for the joint chiefs of staff.
We are not in the business
of paying for information.
Even though she knew
something you didn't?
An assumption I can neither
confirm nor deny.
By the way, shouldn't
the police have her phone log?
How do you have it, too?
I can't tell.
Can't tell me.
Well, since you're not
able to tell me anything,
and I'm not able to tell you anything,
I guess we're done here.
I guess we are.
Unless you'd like
to go out to dinner with me.
Then we can not talk
about all sorts of things.
Sorry.
I don't think so.
You sure?
I can be very unhelpful.
Oh, I'm sure you can.
We can't get human intelligence
on where the hostages are being held.
The guys they grabbed
were our eyes and ears
on the ground there.
But the N.S.A. picked up chatter
from a small city in the northeast
after a recon overflight, we pinpointed
the building where the hostages
are being held.
Degree of confidence? High. These K.L.F.
Guys like to talk.
Send in a S.E.A.L. team.
Mr. President,
can we just take a breath
to consider other options?
It'd be faster to let
the Kashfari military handle it.
I wouldn't trust them to watch my dog.
And no one in Their government
can even know about this.
If I may, s--
Enough.
How soon can we dispatch a team?
They're locked and loaded,
sir, just awaiting your go.
Mr. President, please, a word?
There's a way that this works.
If you pulled me out of the sit room
to give me a civics lesson,
or to tell me I'm ticking--
Your job is to process
all of the various opinions--
Here we go. Should I
get a notebook and pencil?
No, sir. I simply--
Then make your point.
You've been isolating me,
shutting me out.
I've been waiting to address it with
you until-- Make your point, Cyrus.
You can't do this alone.
No one can.
You're my bulldog, my Dragon.
Is that today's rehashed speech?
You're isolating me,
and it's bad business.
It's bad for the country.
It's bad...
for me, Mr. President.
It makes it very hard for me
to do my job.
And my job is simply
to make yours easier,
So, please, will you let-- Are we
done discussing your hurt feelings?
Because I would like to get back
to saving American lives.
Can we do that?
Will you let us?
Yes, Mr. President.
Excellent.
Now, what's your take?
It's my opinion
that it's too early
to send in a s.E.A.L. Team.
We need to be careful.
We need to contain this situation.
Allow the Kashfaris some time
to gather intel on the ground,
so we can be better prepared
when and if the time comes
to pull the trigger on an extraction.
Fine. We'll hold off.
For now.
All right.
Great.
We're done.
Very good, Mr. President.
She was on to
something big--Wendy.
Ahh.
A high-level military
intelligence officer
was desperate to talk to her
the day she died.
He wouldn't tell me why,
which means she was on to something big.
And I'm willing to bet
whatever she was on to
is why she's dead now.
It's why you were framed.
How much do I owe you?
What?
For your services.
Or did you take a commission
when I sold my soul to the devil?
Your troubles aren't over.
Not by a long shot.
But you and I are.
Everything you've ever done
for as long as I've known you
has been tailor-made
to hurt me, so I'm done.
I'm done with you,
I'm done with your people.
So how much, Olivia?
David--
How much?!
You can't afford me.
Mint?
What?
Mint.
You smell like alcohol.
You're Ella's godfather.
We're going to her christening.
You can't smell like alcohol.
You know, don't you?
About defiance.
You feel betrayed, and I am sorry.
It was--There was a decision
made in a moment--
I don't want to discuss it.
You deserve to be president, Fitz.
No, I don't.
But that doesn't matter,
because here I am.
Fitz, if you had been a part of
that conversation-- But I wasn't.
No one asked me, and I said
I don't want to discuss it.
No, you just want to drink.
You're shutting Cyrus out.
He's not stupid.
He knows he's on the outside.
He's your chief of staff.
If you're gonna try to tell me
how to run the country
that you helped steal
for me--
I was going to say you're right.
You're right to shut Cyrus out.
You are right.
It was Cyrus.
Cyrus... pushed
and he plotted and he planned
and he dug his heels in, and he made us.
I wanted you to be president.
I did.
I am unashamed of how much
I wanted the White House for us.
And I can be an animal if I need to be.
I'm proud to rip the flesh off anyone
who comes between me and...
Cyrus... stole the election.
He decided, and he got Liv on board
and Verna and... me.
He got me.
It was Cyrus.
I'm not trying to excuse what I did.
I'm not trying to say
I didn't have a part.
I'm just saying you're right.
To shut him out.
To not trust him.
I think you're right.
Because...
It was Cyrus.
You have me.
You can trust me.
I'm thinking of sending
an extraction team into Kashfar.
I need those guys to come back alive.
I think you should trust your instincts.
I need to know
I'm making the right call.
You are the president.
Any call you make is right.
And if it doesn't work out,
we'll figure out what the next step is.
We can do this.
It's gonna be all right.
Hi, Darling.
Don't worry. The ceremony
will be short and sweet.
They abbreviate for the godless.
Call the secretary.
Tell him to send in
the S.E.A.L. team.
Do it before the ceremony.
I thought we agreed
to take a breath on this.
Take as many breaths as you like,
then recount them in your memoirs.
Call in that S.E.A.L. team.
Now.
Hey, James. How are ya?
How fortunate is baby Ella?
To have such fine examples of leadership
and commitment to our lord and savior.
Ella Margaret Novak Beene...
I baptize you
in the name of the father...
♪ I don't know why I love you ♪
and of the son...
♪ I don't know why ♪
and of the holy spirit.
♪ I love you ♪
amen.
Amen.
Ella won't remember today.
She won't remember
all of you cooing over her.
She won't remember the president
of the United States
holding her.
I hope to God she won't remember
the temper tantrum I threw
when I found out the Japanese peonies
would not arrive in time
for the ceremony.
It is, however, etched
deeply into my memories.
She won't remember, but I hope
all of you will remind her.
Not about the absence of the peonies,
but about how she was
surrounded by love.
To Ella. To family.
Thank you.
♪ With another guy ♪
♪ laugh in my face ♪
♪ lord, how long must I be disgraced ♪
♪ 'cause I love you ♪
♪ Oh, baby, baby, baby ♪
♪ I don't know why I love you ♪
♪ I don't know ♪
♪ you and me, baby, oh ♪
♪ I don't know why I love you, baby ♪
♪ but I love you, baby ♪
♪ Oh, Darling, Darling, Darling ♪
♪ you throw my heart down in the dirt ♪
♪ you made me crawl ♪
♪ on This cold black earth, baby ♪
♪ No, I never ♪
♪ I never knew how much love
could hurt ♪
♪ Oh, till I loved you, baby,
till I loved you, baby ♪
♪ Oh, baby, I can't stop ♪
♪ I can't stop crying,
can't you see? ♪
♪ Ahh, here I'm pleadin' ♪
♪ On my knees, I'm on my knees ♪
♪ won't you help me ♪
♪ help me, please, 'cause I love you ♪
♪ I love you, baby ♪
♪ whoo, sure enough, baby ♪
♪ I don't know, you don't know ♪
♪ we don't know, none of us ♪
♪ Can't do nothing about it ♪
♪ I don't know, baby ♪
♪ I don't know ♪
♪ Ahh, ahh ♪
♪ Oh, baby, sure enough ♪
I made a mistake.
We both did.
It won't happen again.
I was talking about defiance.
That wasn't a mistake.
That was betrayal.
We are done
I may not be able to control
my erections around you,
but that does not mean I want you.
We... are done.
Sir, it's a go. Right now.
First floor secure.
Advancing towards target.
Based on heat-sensored
satellite imagery,
we're expecting anywhere
from five to eight
enemy combatants guarding the hostages
in the northwest corner
of the second floor.
Centcom, we've reached the target.
Alpha, you're a go.
Fire in the hole!
This is it.
Whiskey tango foxtrot!
It's empty!
No hostages.
What the hell?
All clear.
Alpha Bravo ten, awaiting orders.
Tell them to abort.
Centcom, do you copy?
Charlie Mike?
This could be a trap.
Get them out of there now!
Centcom, abort.
Do you copy?
Copy. Relaying order now.
"E" and "E"! Echo Echo, go, go, go!
Move, move!
Stay on your six.
Alpha Bravo, go two.
What the hell just happened?
How did we send a s.E.A.L. Team
to the wrong address?
We didn't.
How did this happen?
Permission to clear
the room, Mr. President?
Go ahead.
Sir... we have a mole.
Damn it.
I'll get the director
of national intelligence
over here right now.
We'll start an internal investigation.
Hold off.
What?
But, sir--
Are you having trouble hearing lately?
When I say "Stand down,"
I mean stand down.
We've got a mole.
I need to think about how to proceed.
Sir--
I need to figure out who I can trust.
Since when do you knock?
I'm sorry.
Really? For which part?
All of it.
Don't be. I'm fine.
David-- I'm fine. Never been better.
Found my calling--
Molding the young minds of America.
Good night, Abby.
What is that?
Wendy's flash drive.
She had just started downloading
my defiance files when she died.
Whoever killed her probably
didn't even know it was there.
Take a look.
Click on the one titled
"Albatross."
There's over 350 pages
of high-Level,
classified military intelligence
on there.
Nuclear missile locations.
Black sites.
The coordinates for
the president's wartime bunkers.
There's six of them in the country,
just in case they ever
ask it on "Jeopardy!"
This is a major security breach.
No civilian should have
their hands on this stuff.
I think this is your something big.
I would love to forget
about this whole thing.
I would love to forget I ever met Wendy.
I'd love to forget I ever met you.
But now... I need you,
because I'd be really
terrible at prison.
That's if I'm lucky enough
to live that long.
You're not just here for you.
I know you, David.
This is about justice.
This is about dusting off the white hat
and putting it back where it belongs.
Baby's asleep.
Thought we could pick up
where we left off yesterday.
No.
Fitz--
No. No.
Come on. It'll be fun.
No. No. Mellie, damn it, I said no!
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Hello?
It's Olivia Pope.
Ah, I thought you might call.
Oh, yeah? Why is that?
Because that's what beautiful women do
when I invite them
to have dinner with me.
You're assuming I called to accept.
I'm a high-ranking
intelligence officer.
They train me to read people.
Where should we go?
Got any ideas?
There's a quiet little
French place on Connecticut
everyone's raving about.
Quiet's not really my thing.
No? I had four brothers and two sisters.
Quiet, uh...
quiet freaks me out.
So what is your thing?
Honestly?
People watching.
It's got its own category on Zagat.
So does late-night dancing,
but I'm guessing
that's not in the cards.
Depends how much wine I drink.
Really?
Well, then maybe we should
go to that French place.
How does, uh... how's 8:00
on Friday sound?
8:00 on Friday
sounds perfect.
Good.
Well, I will see you then, Olivia Pope.
See you then, Captain Ballard.
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/4t727
Help other users to choose the best subtitles