That was a bomb.
No word as to
whether it was an ied
or a specific car bomb.
Over 10 fatalities reported.
Sources within isaf suggest
that isi may be involved.
Did these phones just
go down or did that
fucker hang up on me?
Good thing that x was bodgy
or I'd be flying right now!
I can't hear you, honey.
I need to talk to ed Faber.
Well, then who is
fronting the show?
I can't hear you!
Hey, that's my ass!
Do you have a mother?
Hello!
Fu...
Listen up.
Iraq two is happening.
The network is
stretched thin. All our
talent is going there.
We need people, any
people, to fill the void
in Afghanistan.
And you folks here
are all the unmarried,
childless personnel
in this bureau.
For those of you
who are behind
the scenes, there are
opportunities to be on camera.
Kim, are you going
to be joining in?
The travel or the crying?
Um, hopefully, the travel.
I'll think about it.
The success
of operation mongoose
has overshadowed
the real lesson
to be learned,
that the Taliban are
far from vanquished.
And as the drums of war
beat ever louder in Iraq,
the NATO mission
in Afghanistan grows
increasingly uncertain.
Tanya vanderpoel, outside
lashkar gah, Afghanistan,
vbc world news.
Hey.
I got you! Hey.
Uh, when do you get
back from Houston?
I think on
Tuesday. Why?
Uh, because I'm going
to Afghanistan on Tuesday.
You're going
to Afghanistan on Tuesday?
Yeah.
But you write news copy.
Wait. For how long?
- Like, three months.
- What?
Kim!
Hey!
I can't believe this worked out!
Hey, you want to have a quickie
on the changing table
in the bathroom?
Yeah, I don't think
i could get it up
with that little
koala looking at me.
Also, they're boarding already.
Hey, don't worry.
Just go. Go, go, go.
Oh, shoot, I...
I copied a key
for you, so...
Plants, mail.
Anything else
I'm forgetting?
I think that's it.
This is crazy.
Listen, I think it's impressive.
Starting a new career?
It's gonna be great.
And listen, in three months...
"I'll be back."
No, that's terrible! No.
Don't remember
me like that. No.
Bye. Okay. Okay.
It's not my job.
I'm a producer.
General news. Enron.
These coalminers
in Pennsylvania,
but you probably
didn't see that.
'Cause we got two
wars going on now,
so, uh, I know how
to set up a bgan
and no one will sue if I die
so I got an expedited visa,
like, two days ago,
and I guess now
I'm a war reporter.
Shit dick!
Corkscrew landing.
In case
a missile is fired
at the aircraft!
Kabul international airport.
K.I.A.! "Killed in
action."
Once again, we thank you
for flying with us.
Sorry.
Uh, sorry.
Shit.
No, thank you.
Miss Baker?
I am fahim.
Oh, fahim, hi!
Pleased to meet you.
The car is over here and we go.
She says, uh...
"Welcome to Afghanistan."
Okay, let's go.
Here is your local mobile.
The number is on the back.
Yeah, I ordered
some money last week.
Still in the post.
I'll fix you up next week.
Okay.
Yes, the air
here takes some
getting used to.
It's quite polluted with feces.
Ah, here she is!
How are you, Kim?
Welcome to the Stan.
My name's nic.
I'll be doing
your security.
I'll take your bag.
Fahim. The police are giving
me shit for parking here.
They just want money.
Wait, oh, no. Um,
do you need money?
Because the network
gave me money.
No, keep that on you!
No, no,
no! Kim, please!
Piss off, that's it!
That's it! Hey! Hey!
- I'm sorry. Sorry.
- Piss off!
Remember that we
are at altitude here,
so drink plenty of water
while you acclimatize.
Where did you learn English?
At medical school.
I was a doctor.
Listen, rest up tonight.
Tomorrow, I'll drive you
to the base for your embed.
And just one bag,
but make sure
you pack extra
socks and knickers.
That's like, um,
it's like "panties," yeah?
Mmm-hmm.
So, you've been
embedded before, then?
Not really. We all did
hostile-zone training in 2001.
They taught us to
open our mouths
if we get mortared...
That kind of stuff.
Okay.
G'day, qadar.
The feces smell
all the way to here.
Your room, Kim, is upstairs.
Yeah, they're bloody addicted.
That one melted a laptop
downloading porno.
Jaweed, yes,
he likes to watch
men with donkeys.
Hi.
It's unfortunate.
Kim, this is tall Brian.
Brian hooper.
Tall Brian.
Hi.
I'm your shooter.
So, is there another Brian
around here
somewhere that
you're taller than?
Short Brian.
Works for reuters.
Couldn't one of
you just be "Brian"?
Fair enough.
Didn't think of that.
Also short Brian's dead.
- Oh, fuck. Really?
- Yes.
Anyway, welcome
to the fun house.
Home sweet home.
This is your room.
Is there a shower?
A nation accustomed to war
once again seeks
a return to normality.
And nothing symbolizes that
effort more than this place,
the Kabul zoo.
No, he didn't. The zoo?
Go back to wapping.
You fucking tourist!
Uh, shit. Sorry.
I'm trying to
find the shower?
You're the new girl.
Oh, my god.
Uh... Kim Baker.
Just got here from New York.
I'm Tanya. Oh, my god,
it's so nice to have another
woman in the house!
I love that lippy color.
What is that?
No, they're just really chapped.
Oh, you poor thing.
Can I get you anything?
I'm sorry, I'm freaking out
because I saw your
special about your embed in
korengal, and it was amazing.
Thank you.
That's so sweet.
Where's the shower?
Yes. This way.
Can I ask a favor, Kim?
And absolutely
feel free to say no.
Yeah, sure.
I hate to even bring it up.
I feel so rude
even asking this.
No, it's fine.
Can I fuck your security guys?
What? Oh.
By all means, yeah.
Yeah? I mean,
i wouldn't ask,
it's just that for some reason,
the vbc use
an American contractor
and, I mean, no offense,
but they're all, like,
goatees and "fat-strong."
You know? But the aussies
and kiwis are so hot.
Right. I get it.
Be my guest.
You sure? Don't just
say that to be polite.
No, I wouldn't. I'm not.
Even nic? You don't
want nic for yourself?
Nic?
No. I don't. No.
That's... no, that
would never happen.
So you're good.
Hey! No, Kim,
don't say that.
You could have nic.
In Afghanistan,
you're a serious
piece of ass.
Thank you. That's nice.
Because you're what,
i mean, you're like,
a seven, a six or
seven in New York?
Here, you're a nine.
Borderline ten.
It's called "Kabul cute."
What are you here, like a 15?
Yeah.
Huh.
The thing is, I have a very
serious boyfriend at home,
so, you're good.
All right, well, come talk
to me in two months
when your pussy's
eating your leg.
Shower's that way.
How you doing?
It's bananas here.
It's, um...
My nose is running.
There's shit in the air,
literally.
And
I don't think I can do this.
Do what?
Kim?
I don't think I can do this.
Can you see...
I don't... hello?
Shit.
I'm sorry, colonel,
i can't accept gifts
as a journalist.
Okay.
So lodging, transport,
chow and protection,
that's all you can accept?
I'll do my best
to stay objective.
I don't care if
you can do your job.
I care if my men can.
Are you familiar with
the term "four-ten-four",
miss Baker?
I am not, colonel.
It refers to women
who are fours back home
become tens when they ship out
and when they're
back stateside, they
become fours again.
Are you saying I'm a four?
I'm saying you carry
an orange fucking backpack.
I've seen people
with actual experience
make bad decisions here.
So while you're outside
the wire with my men,
you will in no way
distract them,
understood?
Are you asking me not
to sleep with your soldiers?
No, not "soldiers."
Marines.
You're not here to sleep with
or perform jobs of any
type on my marines.
Clear copy, miss Baker?
Copy that.
Good.
We'll get you out to
a fob as soon as we
find a ride for you.
In the meantime,
captain stern here
will see to it that
you get a wet hootch.
A what?
It's a tent with a shower.
Unless you'd
prefer a dry hootch.
I would not, sir.
Sorry.
Could you just...
State
your name and rank?
Gunnery sergeant
Clinton j. Hurd.
All right. Uh... dang it!
So, do you believe
the afghani people
are happy about
our presence here?
No, Afghans are the people.
Afghanis is the currency.
That's right.
I knew that. Thank you.
What do you believe
your mission to be here?
Ma'am, you got
a sticker on your pants.
It's bugging
the shit out
of me. Ma'am...
Fahim.
What inspired you
to enlist originally?
I'm a big fan of
the movie predator with
Arnold Schwarzenegger.
We're the same height.
Do you think the war
in Iraq has affected
your resources here?
I'm sorry, ma'am,
I'm not authorized to
answer that question.
I'd say we're both
on the wrong side
of persia, ma'am.
Iraq is where you
get some right now.
Here just has shit all.
Are you guys getting
outside the wire much?
Yes, ma'am.
Most days. Uh...
You know, we help out with
community projects and all.
And Wells. Uh...
And sometimes at night
we shoot the big gun,
but, you know,
it's quiet here.
Jesus!
We don't wear ibas on the fob.
I don't even chamber
a round in my weapon
anymore, because,
you know, I figure
accidental discharge is
scarier than the Taliban.
With Iraq, do you feel
like people have forgotten
about Afghanistan?
Oh, well...
Yes, ma'am. I'd say that
surely is the word for it.
This here's a forgotten war.
It's capital f, capital w.
What's your, uh...
Your name and rank?
I'm Lance corporal coughlin,
India company 3-5.
Thank you.
Kim. Your hair.
Thanks, fahim.
Mmm-hmm.
You really are a fixer.
Moon's out.
Hmm.
It's beautiful.
What does that mean?
It means, "oh, what
a terrible event!"
Uh-huh.
Miss Baker.
Colonel hollanek
is coming to
Norton tomorrow
to check on some
of our prt work.
And you and your crew
are clear to tag along.
Great, thanks.
Rolls out at zero-six.
That's 6:00 A.M.
i know that, yeah.
Fire!
Come on, let's go!
Get this shit together!
We gotta move!
Fucking hands out
of your pockets!
You think you're
in the fucking army?
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
What is this?
Uh, that's my supplies.
Camera stuff.
You fucking kidding me?
This is an orange
ruck. No, ma'am.
Not on my vehicle.
The girl at the north face store
said it was,
like, military grade.
Well, where are you
gonna hide it?
Inside a fucking sunset?
I mean, even
the Dutch army
don't wear orange.
Fix it.
How do I fix it?
Rapono!
Got to stay hydrated, ma'am.
Coughlin.
I didn't recognize you.
That's 'cause I'm
in warrior mode.
It makes me taller.
Enjoy the ride, ma'am.
I'm dying to
know who blew up my well.
Working on it, colonel.
That was a nice
fucking well, corporal.
What'd he say?
What's that mean?
He wants to know
if you are the Russians.
The Russians?
Mmm.
No!
No, sir. That was
20 years ago.
And we're here to help.
And I'm black.
If we fix the well,
you can't blow it up.
Kim, I was
talking to some
of the younger men.
They say
the Taliban
came at night.
I don't care. No.
I drank too much water
and I have to pee.
Stop. Stop.
I am engaged
to be married.
Okay, fahim,
i know you like your
women to be, like,
beautiful, mysterious
Ikea bags, okay?
But we urinate, doctor.
Out of our vaginas.
You think you urinate out the...
No. I know it's
a separate thing!
God! Just please help me.
There is nowhere for you to go.
I cannot ask
these men about this.
And I'm not allowed
to talk to the women.
Fine. Forget it. I'll hold it.
Women are tough, right?
Are you okay, ma'am?
- Gosh, damn it, man.
- This is a new one.
I was cursing your
name at 0-stupid-30, but
I'm glad I came out today.
Would you not have
gone on patrol today
if I weren't here?
No, I'd be back in
Norton filling hescos.
Copy that.
We're still 5 Mikes.
It must be one hairy dump.
No, I'm just getting
my pants on.
Damn it, sergeant hurd.
Whatever.
Sorry. Sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
Marine!
Make a hole, Baker.
Move out!
Why are we stopping?
The lead vehicle bottomed out.
Okay!
Heads on a swivel!
Didn't we come this way?
We most surely did.
Contact left!
Stay in the vehicle!
Shit! Hot! Hot bullet things!
Kim, don't get out
of the car! Kim!
Whoa!
Get down behind
the engine block!
Stay there! Stay there!
Kim.
Get back in the car!
No, please, Kim!
Ma'am, I asked you to stay put!
Those assholes
tried to shoot us!
Jesus!
You have got to be shitting me!
You just shot
a javelin at
a fucking car!
That's an $80,000
piece of ordnance!
Can any of you
geniuses tell me the
kelley blue book value
of a 1989 Toyota pickup?
Oorah, Baker. Get some.
I hope you got all
that on film, ma'am.
'Cause that right there,
that's what we do best.
Hearts and minds.
That's the two best places
to shoot somebody.
What?
I told you to stay in the car.
Okay, I'll get back in the car.
The marines don't have
much to say about Iraq.
Their mantra is that
they are focused on
doing the job here.
And even though,
as we saw firsthand,
attacks against
coalition forces are up,
corporal coughlin
told me earlier that
he is still not planning
to lock and load his weapon
when he is out on patrol.
Our own Kim Baker
reporting for us live.
Welcome!
Wow, good job,
Kim! Ruthless!
Bitch, we are going
out tonight! Whoo!
It's okay. It's okay. Here.
It's okay. It's all right.
Why don't I know who you are?
You're what, like, 42?
Sold.
Why have I never heard of you?
Yeah, I haven't done
a lot of overseas reporting.
I've done mostly
domestic reportage.
"Reportage"?
Domestic reportage.
Look, everyone in
the kabubble is
full of shit. It's okay.
Half the accents are fake.
The whole "I'm
ex-special forces" wankers
are flat out lying.
"Reportage"?
Oh, Christ, what is this?
I really shouldn't have
my back to the door.
It's bad tradecraft,
but it's worth it to
talk to you two ladies.
Fuck off.
Ugh.
You got it.
Champagne?
Thank you.
Finish this,
and then we'll go
meet some friends
in wazir akbar Khan.
And I am warning you now,
do not sleep with iain.
Who is iain?
He's a proper asshole.
Shall we?
Yeah.
Is that a cab?
Is your full name Shakira?
'Cause I thought it was
a Colombian nickname.
Why would you think that?
Because of the singer.
No, I know.
I'm kidding. No, it's
arabic for "thankful."
Kim is American
for "white lady."
Actually, "Kim"
means "who" in turkish.
"Who's that white lady?"
It's Kim.
That's so you can
remember my name.
So... this is iain.
Iain, Kim.
Kim. Kim. Kim.
Kim, nice work.
You sit next to the
only two women in a
country the size of Texas
that remind a man
that you're really
only okay looking.
Well, she said
you were an asshole,
but that's really
above and beyond.
Who said that?
Tanya.
No. No. No.
I don't think so.
A lot of women find me
very charming, Kim.
No, not biological women.
Oh, really?
Women who think that an accent
is the same thing
as a personality, maybe.
Oh!
Nae, haud yer wheesht.
Go bile yer heid, ya wee bampot.
I bet you're wetter
than a submarine
with screen doors now.
Oh!
I got that from a pickup book.
Jesus.
Oh, yeah.
Mmm.
So what's your deal?
You got chucked over by some guy
so you think, "forget him.
"I'm gonna go discover
the wonders of the east,
"and I'm gonna
fuck a Scottish guy
and write a book."
I'm Scottish, by the way.
Cheers.
- Cheers.
- Salud.
- To Kim!
Is this your first night out?
Yes.
It is, actually.
That little bastard!
Oh, no, Kim.
You didn't give egg boy
money, did you?
Hey! Egg boy! Hey!
You're a little shitbird!
I hope you get salmonella!
Oh!
I gave him, like, $100!
$100?
What?
I'd give you my eggs for $100.
Where are we going?
A whorehouse.
You're going to love it.
You see that?
It's a brothel
and a Chinese restaurant.
Do you remember this video?
Everybody was drawings.
Me? Oh, no, thank you.
Look, a month ago,
i was writing a story
about corn syrup.
Okay? I was not happy.
I didn't think
there was anything else
out there for me.
Just death.
Then this came along and...
Wenge, do you guys
have regular
access to healthcare?
He called me a fenian bastard.
I fuckin' showed him
what for, kicked
his teeth in, the cunt.
Oi, Tanya?
What's her story?
She has a boyfriend.
And she's unconscious, okay?
Not that either of
those things have ever
stopped you before.
That's not true.
Firstly, I'm afraid
of boyfriends.
Mmm-hmm.
Secondly, I'm a gentleman.
What? According to
no less an authority
than grace mugabe.
I held a door open for her once.
Let me just
have a little peekaboo.
Get out!
Actually, not bad.
- I think I missed one.
- Stop!
Il y a du monde
au balcon. Pas mal.
Kim?
You all right there, mate?
Oh, wouldn't you like to know?
Hey. I'm just talking
about her safety.
Nic here does
security for Kim, iain.
Right, well!
I'm off. Excuse me.
Excused.
Good night.
- Bye, darling!
- Good night.
The best, nic!
Oh, that's Oprah.
Hello.
It's fahim.
Are you ready to go?
Go where, dude?
It's Saturday.
Friday is the only day off
in the islamic week.
We have interviews.
No! That was not made
clear. That's... no.
That's bullshit, fahim. No.
Kim, today we are
meeting Ali massoud sadiq.
I sent research.
He's likely to be
Attorney General.
Please hold.
Please come outside.
This is against
what I believe
as an American.
I am sorry, but we have to go.
Oh, my shoes. Shit.
You wish to interview
me, Mr. ahmadzai?
I do, Mr. sadiq.
Yes, on camera.
Mr. ahmadzai,
I am a person of,
of no consequence.
Well, you soon might be
the second most powerful
person in Afghanistan.
Mr. ahmadzai,
I run a small department
inside the interior ministry.
What possible interest
could I be to the Americans?
Because your ministry
for the prevention of vice
and the encouragement of virtue
sounds a lot like
the Taliban's old
ministry of vice and virtue.
Don't you think?
- Kim Baker.
Mmm-hmm.
When the Taliban was in power,
they enforced their
version of sharia.
One of their edicts
was a rule that
all men must shave
the hair of their pubis.
They would walk
the streets carrying
a small wooden rod,
a dowel,
which they would
roll along the front
of a man's trousers.
If a man's pubic hair
was long enough to
curl around the dowel,
they would beat him.
Now, I ask you,
do I look like a man
to walk the streets
carrying a
hair-of-the-pubis dowel?
No, sir, you do not.
I returned to this
country to save it.
I am a friend of America.
Which is why you should
let me interview you,
so people can understand that.
I like you, Kim.
I like your mouthiness.
That is a word, yes?
It reminds me of
my time living in London.
You make me feel
like a young man
again.
But I do not know you.
How can we
get to know
each other, Kim?
Hmm?
Yes, excellent, Kim!
Put a turban on her,
she'd make
a very handsome boy.
How are you?
You okay there?
What the hell was that?
It's probably
just a wedding
somewhere nearby.
They like to shoot off
guns at weddings here.
You get it, you're from Florida.
Funny.
When was the last
time I saw you?
Since June?
I'm sorry that I didn't
get back last month.
I can be in New York
by Thursday.
I miss you and I want
to see you. And I...
I have...
Oh, not again.
I hate this fucking airport.
Can I bring you guys
anything from New York?
Just bring us back
a six pack, eh?
- This is Kim.
- Kim Baker?
It is sadiq.
Mr. sadiq, hi.
How about an interview
with pacha Khan?
Pacha Khan, the warlord?
Pacha Khan is a businessman.
Would you like that?
Uh, yeah. Yeah. But I'm
on my way to New York
to see my boyfriend.
You will be the first
western journalist
to interview him
since the Soviet war.
Shall we say tomorrow?
Okay, yes, of course.
Thank you.
What?
Back in the car.
Wait here.
It's okay, come.
Hmm.
Okay. Yes.
Yeah?
Okay.
Pacha Khan, thank you
for your kind hospitality.
What?
No.
Oh, Kim. Cheers.
Hi.
What a rush, yeah?
Pacha Khan, yeah.
It's like, adrenaline.
Everyone was...
Good job.
Yeah, it went well.
But, you know, I was...
I was in the...
The New Zealand sas back home.
And today felt
like jumping out
of an airplane.
Or like, you know,
like having sex.
Kim!
Tanya's got scotch.
It won't last long, so...
Nic, you're welcome,
too, you big cunt!
That's a term of
affection, by the way.
You were
supposed to be in
New York, sneaky girl.
Yeah, Chris is
not super pleased.
Chris can suck a fat one.
I'm trying to see if
they put my story up,
but this Internet
connection is the worst!
Oh, goddamn it, jaweed!
Oh, Christ!
- Really?
- Wow.
Although, donkeys aside,
he's a good fixer.
Mmm.
Oh, no, thanks.
Morning shows.
You have something they
want for the mornings?
Maybe. I don't know. Maybe.
Hmm.
That's what I'm trying to see.
You know, I heard
that he has contacts
in the tribals.
Like real Taliban contacts.
- Jaweed?
- Jaweed.
- No fucking way.
- Mmm, apparently.
Would you do that?
Would you go down there?
Yeah, sure, if it
was the right call.
Yeah, but how do you know
if it's the right call?
Fuck, man, I don't know.
That is why we drink, do drugs
and shag strangers
in restaurant bathrooms.
Kim, are you okay?
What's going on?
Oh, shoot. Oh, sorry,
what time is it?
I don't know.
I'm in Seattle.
God, I thought you got shot
at a wedding or something.
Jesus, Kim!
No.
Sorry. So, just real quick...
I want you to come visit me.
In Afghanistan? Really?
I mean, I've got tons of miles.
I could fly you first class.
I have to look at a
calendar. I don't think
I can do it this month.
I'm here until,
like, at least the 15th.
But when I get back maybe...
Who is in your bed, Chris?
What?
No, that's my bag.
Look in the mirror, dipshit.
My god. You motherfucker.
Unbelievable. Unbelievable!
You calm the fuck down!
Listen, you haven't
been home in months.
You forgot my fucking birthday!
Oh, right, it's my
fault. Great, Chris.
You're a genius.
And I kept your stupid
fucking plants alive,
but you let this relationship
wither and die!
Ugh! Did you
have that prepared?
What?
Pussy!
You know what?
Have fun in Seattle.
You should go to the
rock 'n' roll museum.
It sucks.
You'll fit right in.
Are you shitting me?
Fahim.
Let's apply for another embed.
Because I want to
get out of Kabul.
I just need to get out of Kabul.
I need "me time",
exactly. That's...
See? I told you
that o magazine
would increase your
understanding of women.
Hey, you guys
are 3-5, right?
Do you know a corporal coughlin?
No, ma'am.
Sorry, but I've only
been here for
a couple months.
Ma'am, if you set one foot
in front of the other,
there's less chance
you lose both feet
if we hit an ied.
Vides, make ready.
Man, we are
definitely losing
the war
when it comes to
this particular well.
I swear to god,
they blow up another well,
I take another
pair of boots off.
It's like fucking
musical chairs.
Hey, do I have to
buy a dress
for your wedding?
No. Whatever you
wear in Kabul is fine.
Yeah?
Yes.
The only thing I ask
is that you make sure
my friend is there.
Aw, your friend is me.
I get it.
Mount up!
Jesus, stern!
General, excuse me.
Hey. General, do you
have a minute?
Not now, Baker.
It's just...
The Taliban haven't been
destroying the well here.
The women of the village
are destroying it.
Or so they tell me.
We dug that well
several times
for the women
so they don't have
to walk to the river.
But they want to
walk to the river.
It's their only
chance to be social
and gossip and,
you know, hang out.
I think that they
have a bunch of
old Soviet landmines,
and they just prop one up
and throw rocks at it.
Kim, did you ever feel like
you're Manning that tollgate
and the engineer's yelling,
"i got pig iron,
i got pig iron"?
No. I don't know
what that means.
But it's very folksy.
Also, the women, obviously,
they don't want the men
to know about this,
so they are hoping
that you would just refuse
to repair the well this time.
Well, they're in luck.
That's exactly what
i told the mullah, so...
Well done, Baker.
Hooyah, general.
Marines say "oorah."
The Navy says "hooyah."
Don't mix those two up.
Got it.
Have a good...
Have a good ride.
Kim.
Sorry.
You look beautiful!
Oh, my god.
- Oh, my god.
- Oh, no!
Kim!
What the dick?
Why did fahim tell me
i could dress like this?
Well, he didn't
want you to have to
go buy something.
Oh, my god. I only washed
the front of my hair.
Here.
You know what?
I'm going to let you
have one of these.
Thank you.
Now I look great.
Now you're ready.
Now I'm ready to party.
Oh, she likes it.
- Sure.
- Oh, wow. Well...
It was worse than
a unibrow. It went all
the way into his hair.
We all have some reason
for being here.
What's your reason?
What is yours?
I don't have a good one.
I'm just here.
Come on, she just told
her unibrow story.
I just... I don't have one.
Come on.
I was at the gym after work
one night. Stationary bike.
Okay? The same
bike every day.
And I notice this
indentation in the carpet,
it's, like, a foot
in front of my bike.
And I realize that it's from
where my bike used to be.
I have done thousands
of miles on this bike
and I have gone backwards.
I have literally gone backwards.
I just
wanted to blow everything up.
I just wanted out of my job,
writing news scripts for
dumb pretty people to read.
I wanted...
out of having to decide whether
I should just
marry my mildly
depressive boyfriend.
And that's it.
I just... I couldn't
look at that
fucking carpet anymore.
Oh...
Well, that is
officially the most
American white lady
story I've ever heard.
- Shut up.
- It is.
You know what?
Fuck that.
You are a battle-tested
foreign correspondent.
You're a solid Kabul 9.5.
And you are fucking
single, all right?
So that lady back at
the gym, she's dead.
This is your life.
Despite Taliban threats,
election observers
are reporting
high voter turnout,
especially in cities.
A British fighter-bomber
last week
reduced this compound to rubble.
Not to cooperate.
Oh, god. Christ, there's a...
Bahzo! There's a bahzo here!
The surprise visit
from secretary of
defense Donald rumsfeld.
Today, Kabul's first
licensed female driver,
gulbahar yousofy, hits the road.
That sucks.
That sucks for women.
Thank you.
Congratulations
on your promotion,
Mr. Attorney General.
Thank you.
As I said, we could have
done this over the phone.
I'm just looking
for a statement on
sharia in kandahar.
I understand that
you are no longer
with your special friend Chris.
Who told you that?
Very little happens
in Afghanistan
that Ali massoud sadiq
does not know about.
Very little.
May I show you something?
Of course.
You have a bed in your office.
Yes.
There is a bed here now.
So, no comment on
sharia in kandahar or...
No comment.
We are going to
isaf later, yes?
I don't know.
Pressers and
"right of boom" crap.
Who cares?
We need
to enterprise
something. Okay?
We need to get
out of the bubble.
Oh, that hit the net.
The what?
It hit the net.
The invisible net?
Yes.
My point.
Let's go. Bullshit.
You know, Kim, the reason
that your village well
story got traction is
because it wasn't a bang-bang,
it was about women's rights.
It was a brilliant piece, that.
Oh, fucking hell.
We should go to kandahar.
No, too dangerous.
No way. It's a wee bit
fluid down there these days,
security-wise.
Yeah, it might
be a bit much
for you, eh, nic?
You're a bit late to the whole
"kandahar's gone
to shit" party.
You know?
What about the woman thing
where the sharia law is back?
And there was
a firebombing there
the other day.
Yeah, I think
it's worth the risk.
Iain, that's easy for
you to say, mate,
sitting there in your
cozzie taking photos
of the fucking garden.
Look, Nicky,
i know you've been
specially trained
to protect New Zealand from,
what, fucking dolphins?
But I'm not exactly
a war zone virgin, you know?
I was kidnapped by
the aig when they
were still called that.
Why dolphins?
What do dolphins got to
do with New Zealand?
Nothing to do
with it. I'm just...
White pointers and sharks,
but the dolphins
never hurt anyone.
I know they've not
hurt anyone, mate.
I'm just making the point...
I'm not gonna protect my country
from an animal that
hasn't hurt anyone.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Dolphins? What a joke.
I'll come with you
in the car if there's room.
Oh, great,
we're all going
to kandahar!
I can make some calls.
We can take my car.
Kim, if we are
going to kandahar,
you will need to
buy some new clothes.
I can't...
Ah! It's so pretty,
i don't even want to vote.
I'm flipping you the bird
in here right now.
- Is this your car, fahim?
- Yes.
This is a fucking piece of shit.
I think it's very nice.
No one is staring
at me. It's weird.
You are in the blue prison now.
Fahim, what does
the graffiti say?
"No education for woman."
Brian.
Huh?
Fahim, what's going on up there?
The Taliban used to do this.
Execute the radios
and televisions.
Oh, shit!
Get out of the way!
Move on! Move on!
You guys can't go
out there, but I can.
- Kim, come back.
- Kim, wait! Come back.
Kim, now.
We must hurry.
Get in the car!
Get out of here!
That was a men's
park, Kim! Men only!
Fuck!
Bebakhshid, fahim.
Coalition capacity,
priorities and support.
Let's look now at
the 12 first-tier drivers
in the current coin paradigm.
Shit.
Tactical and institutional...
is always in purple,
and noting as such...
Kim Baker.
Sir, do you have a minute?
If I'm
understanding
this briefing,
I have all
the fucking time
in the world.
Okay.
Well, I'm covering
the girls' school
in kandahar that was firebombed
and I'm wondering
if you could give me
something, on background,
just about the security
situation here
and the state of
the war in general.
Yeah, I can give you something:
This war is like
fucking a gorilla.
You keep going till
the gorilla wants to stop.
I think I can paraphrase that.
Knock yourself out.
You know, Afghanistan
produces 90% of the
world's narcotic opiates.
- So they say.
- Mmm.
When I worked in the hospital,
these men, heroin addicts,
would come in with a child.
They'd say,
"oh, my son,
he broke his arm."
And while we were
tending to the child,
the men would
steal our morphine.
And we would wonder
how the arm got
broken to begin with.
What are we
talking about, fahim?
Hmm.
The human body
produces its own heroin.
In fact, when
the fight-or-flight instinct
is activated in
the hypothalamus,
your body releases endorphins,
dopamine and norepinephrine.
That is heroin, cocaine
and amphetamine, all at once.
Okay, great. Are we
having the Afghan version
of this conversation,
where in New York we would have
gotten to the point,
like, five minutes ago?
There is a reason to
believe that a person
can get addicted to
this type of high.
Soldiers, athletes...
War reporters. Got it.
An addict always
needs a greater
and greater dosage.
And then people
make mistakes,
people get hurt.
I get it. You're
a newlywed. I can
probably get them
to go up to $125 a day.
Let us have the
American version of
this conversation.
Okay.
I do not want to
work with you anymore.
No, okay, wait.
Fahim, I know I fucked up.
I do not think you do.
Hear me out.
Kim, no.
I am now married.
I want to have children.
It will not happen again.
It's not gonna...
"I ride after a deer
and find myself
chased by a hog.
"I plot to get what I want
"and I end up in prison.
"I dig pits to trap
others and I fall in.
"I should be
suspicious of
what I want."
I don't know what that means.
You do.
Fahim?
I can't breathe in here.
Time to take a walk.
I have to go outside.
I have to go home.
Shit.
It's the wrong house.
Oh, shit.
Kim?
What the hell are you doing?
Here.
Kim, sip that.
Okay? You all right?
Keep sipping that.
You're all right. It's okay.
It's okay. Hey.
Hey, it's all right.
Oi. Now, that there
was a bit of fun.
Are you mental?
Okay, mate...
I'm not your mate.
I'm gonna ask you again,
are you fucking mental?
Come on, iain,
it's not his fault.
What's your job again? Hmm?
Because if I hadn't
come back to see you lot
because I stole a bottle of sake
from a Japanese travel writer...
Wait, you have sake?
You could've
killed her, "mate!"
Oh, fuck off.
Jesus! What the
fuck?
Dude, what the fuck?
Did you fucking sucker punch me?
You broke my nose.
You fucking American?
Are you a yank?
I'm Canadian, you asshole.
Ugh.
I almost fucked a Canadian?
I'd stay down if i
were you, ya wee cunt.
And that's not
a term of affection.
Fuck that.
Oh, god! Mmm.
Ow!
Wait.
Oh, fuck.
Iain, don't carry me around.
I'm not a fucking baby.
Ah!
Goddamn it.
What the fuck are you doing?
Take it off.
I'm fucking
trying to take it off!
Oh, god, I'm gonna put it
in you so fucking hard,
you're gonna
fucking get it.
Shh. Don't talk.
I want everything in your mouth.
Iain, just shut it.
I'll take you
lying down, come on.
Do you have one of those
weird little penises?
No! This is how
i want to go.
No, I don't want to see myself.
Roll off!
Okay, fuck it.
Oh, god, I fucking...
What are you doing?
I'm just putting my fucking
finger in your mouth.
Shh. No!
Come on, just put
everything in your mouth.
Do you want me to go?
No.
There's aught like a good shag.
Okay, let's try to
be adults here.
I think we were.
Obviously this was just
a kabubble thing, right?
Just a
fun mistake where one
of us had an orgasm.
I mean, we're both
in a really bad place.
And then you
punched nic.
I don't know.
It's endorphins, right?
Nope, that's not what this is.
No, you don't
need to be gallant.
I'm serious.
I fancy you, Kim Baker.
I do.
Of all the dozens of women
in this country, I chose you.
No, you didn't,
because this is not me.
I would never do this.
Precisely. Because
you're not you anymore.
You're in the kabubble.
You said so yourself.
Don't fucking hide.
Kim, you know the frog
in the pot of water?
You raise
the temperature
bit by bit,
the frog doesn't notice?
That's what this place
and that's what this job
does to all of us.
It changes your perception
of what's normal until...
until here we are.
You know the frog boils to death
at the end of that, right?
Nope.
Yeah.
Is that my toothbrush?
Ugh!
What's going on
with my kandahar piece, ed?
Jerry killed it.
Wait, who killed it?
Jerry Taub,
head of the network, Kim.
What happened to Angela?
She left.
She's running a website
for women or something.
Look, I can't sell
Afghanistan in
Monday meetings.
Your war's got chronic
same-shit-different-day-itis.
Great. What am i
even doing here, ed?
I wouldn't ask
that too loudly, Kim.
Though I'd be thrilled to have
you back at your old desk.
That's all I got.
Hey, I heard that nic quit
and you fucked iain!
Whoa, hold on.
Listen, the iain thing
is not a thing, okay?
We have the same
size hands. I can't.
It's just work has been
a little frustrating.
Yeah. I get it.
Because Afghanistan
doesn't rate anymore.
That is bullshit.
You've got to find
your own luck here, babe,
you know that.
What?
What? What is that?
Hey! You're hooking up
Tanya in the tribals?
What the fuck, jaweed?
Her network will pay me triple.
I taught you how to clear
your Internet history, okay?
What has vanderpoel
ever done for you?
Give me a break, man.
Whatever. You owe me.
What else do you have?
You're ghilzai, right?
Do you have any
other connections
to members of
the ghilzai family?
You mean hekmatyar?
Maybe.
Are you fucking
crazy, Kim? Please.
Hey! Nabil! Hey.
Are you still in touch
with that isi guy
who says he knows
who killed Abdul haq?
That guy?
He's dead two years.
Hey.
Oh, for fuck's sake.
Mrs. mackelpie.
Twice?
Two and a half, actually.
Ugh!
I don't remember
what happened last night.
Kabul happened,
my wee froggy in the pot.
Did I not wear
a headscarf?
Where's my phone?
I believe I threw your
mobile in my cupboard.
Why?
Because mid-coitus
you tried to call Tanya
about some bloody
wild goose chase
in the tribals.
I told you about that?
Mmm. Well, it was hard
to understand you
once you asked me
to stuff your knickers
in your mouth.
I'm joking, Kim.
That didn't happen.
Fuck. I am...
I am fucking losing it.
I need a win.
Christ, if you're that hard up,
I'll share my badakhshan
thing with you.
What badakhshan thing?
You know China
won the contract to
mine for gold up there.
They built roads, airport,
housing, all that.
Well, guess whose
responsibility it is
to protect
the investment
of red China
in this restive nation?
American troops, Chinese gold.
Oh, iain, that's really good.
People are gonna get mad.
Just waiting for
my guy to give me
the green light.
You pay for the trip,
I'll share the story
with you. Easy peasy.
Really? Thank you. That's...
I owe you one.
Well, how about a half of one?
And then we can
make it an even three.
Yeah. Or I could
buy you breakfast.
Or a half of one
and we can make
it an even three.
I think breakfast is of
equal monetary value.
My middle name is eoghan.
Which is erse... shut up.
It's erse for Owen.
"Oo-hee"?
Mmm-hmm.
Iain "oo-hee."
Don't bother.
Where is bin laden?
People think he's
in Pakistan, right?
Yeah.
You've got egg in
your beard. Hang on.
Thank you.
Your national animal
is the unicorn.
I think it's romantic.
That is the national animal
of the kingdom I ruled
when I was eight.
Who's your
favorite three stooge?
Um, Larry. Because
he's put upon in a way
that I identify with.
He's the art Garfunkel, right?
Yeah.
So, I thought I might
like to hang out
with you for a bit.
Yeah. Okay. Yeah.
Do you really want to
know what I want to do?
Yeah. Okay.
I'd like to kiss you.
Who knew?
Here's my little man.
No, iain, don't. It's a scam.
Do you think so? Really?
I know it's a scam,
Kim. So what?
He's still
begging in the street.
Hey, abrahaim.
There's my boy.
I knew I'd win you over.
Jesus!
What the fuck, jaweed?
Are they coming or not?
Here they are.
There they are.
4-6800, line six north.
Standing by approval.
We are clear to engage target.
Roger. Clear to
engage target.
It is him. That's my guy.
If we go anywhere,
jaweed, we take our vehicle.
No carpooling.
All right. Okay.
Shit! Shit!
Stay calm.
Splash.
Cease laser. Safe laser.
Laser off. Laser safe.
I'm looking for
someone. Excuse me.
Oh, my god. Tanya.
Hi.
Jesus.
Oy.
Jaweed's dead.
Andy's in surgery.
I know. Iain
talked to Colin.
Jesus!
I know. It's fucked.
You know, Colin was rolling.
What, like, rolling-rolling?
You have tape?
He got the whole fucking thing.
I'm going to go live
with it as soon as
they let me out of here.
Can you fucking believe it?
Hey.
Hi.
Aye.
- How are you?
- You doing all right?
Holy shit!
And as we watch it
again there, Susanna,
you can actually see
the hellfire missile
right before it detonates.
What is going on
with badakhshan?
Ah, snow's killing us.
So unless your network wants
to stump up the money
for the helicopter,
we'll have to wait till
they clear the passes.
Kim, we have a bit
of a situation outside.
Oh.
What?
I just need you
to see something.
Sorry to interrupt.
Did he say what he wanted?
I don't know.
Fuck.
Qadar. Qadar,
it's okay. You can go in.
He just wants to talk to me.
Okay. Okay.
It's okay.
Oh, please, do not cover
your hair on my account.
It's such beautiful hair.
It's like the hide
of a fine horse.
Sadiq, what are you doing here?
I was just going home
from closing a woman brothel
when I told my driver,
"mahboobullah, this is
where my best friend
Kimberly lives!"
But she has been
a bad friend lately.
She does not call.
She does not
invite me to her party.
I'm sorry,
but I didn't think
the Attorney General
of the islamic
Republic of Afghanistan
went to parties at guesthouses.
And why not?
I am still a man, no?
I love music.
I love to dance!
But
even though
you have been
a bad friend,
I want you to be happy.
Do you have a special friend?
Because
I would love to be
your special friend.
Would you like that, Kim?
You're a bad friend.
You are a bad friend.
In America, I would get
a book deal out of this shit!
You can't just do this, okay?
I haven't been on
the air in months!
My best friend
here almost died,
and I am jealous of her!
And I am just...
Fuck this! All of it!
That was a bomb.
Hello! So, wait!
Who is fronting the show?
Tucker? No, I don't
know who that is.
Okay, well, I could go
live for the overnights,
but this is...
"Satellite time?"
No, I have a
dedicated feed.
Since when?
This is Tucker wang.
This is Kim Baker.
Why am I being told that
i don't have a sat hookup?
Because you're on
the hourly plan now.
And either way,
the show is full tonight.
No. Who is your boss?
I want to talk to
this Jerry whatever, Taub.
Okay, look, Jerry has
mentioned Afghanistan
to me once,
and mentioned it to know why
the only good story to come
out of there in a year
was on another network.
What, Tanya's thing?
No, I've got shit like that.
I'm waiting for
the snow to melt!
I want to talk to Jerry.
If I could just get
you to get me a story
that somebody would care about,
it would be fine.
But meanwhile...
Okay, what if i come to New York
and I burst into
Jerry's office?
How about that?
Well, that might look
like I hadn't done my job.
Perfect. See you Wednesday.
Cunt.
Kim.
Kim, look at these dogs.
How does this end?
A bucket of cold water,
i suppose.
No.
Um...
How does this
end?
Uh, I don't really know, Kim.
We grow old together?
Get a cottage in the country?
Raise chickens?
Eat scrambled eggs
off each other?
Look, we're good, aren't we?
We'll always have Kabul.
No, we won't.
We won't "always have" it
because I have to go home.
No, this is home.
I have to go to
New York City
and justify my life
to somebody named Jerry
before he takes
it all away, and I
cannot go back to sitting
at a goddamn desk. I can't.
Aye. Listen...
No one can take
it away from you.
Not all of it.
Whatever happens,
you'll have me.
That's a very nice
thing to say, but...
But what?
Following
a fatal traffic accident
involving a coalition truck,
long simmering frustration
today boiled over
into violence and despair.
They kill us!
They kill us and
they break our hearts!
And I also give this message
to president Hamid karzai:
What the hell is happening here?
Okay, I don't care
who the hell's in there.
I'm Kim Baker.
Go on in, Kim.
Jerry's expecting you.
Well, that's
fucking unsatisfying.
Can I take your bag?
Yes. Please.
Would you care for some water?
Yes.
I should've googled you.
I've been... I've been
using all the wrong
swear words.
Well, I hope
i didn't ruin
your big moment.
Look, geri, I don't know what
Tucker has been telling you.
He said that you're
upset about the air
time you're getting.
That's just wrong,
because this is
not about me.
My frustration is
with our priorities
and what's best for the network.
Isn't deciding what's best
for the network my job?
I'm just saying,
as journalists, we have
an obligation to this story.
And Afghanistan should be
on our air more, period.
With the resources
we have over there,
Afghanistan should
definitely be
on our air more.
But the problem is,
as much as everyone
loves the troops,
they don't actually
want to watch them
on the news anymore.
They just don't.
So I can't give
Afghanistan more air.
Which means I need
to give Afghanistan
fewer resources.
That's what's
best for the network.
Geri...
You have that call now.
I'm not trying to be a bitch.
Okay, let me
pitch you something.
All right, the Chinese
mining concession...
Jesus!
Look, the last person
who got any kind of
bounce out of Afghanistan
was your friend
Tanya vanderpoel.
She's actually
got me over a barrel
thanks to that drone story.
What do you mean,
"over a barrel"?
She's London, Kim.
You're hiring Tanya.
Yes.
I assumed you two
flew here together.
She's here.
I'm sorry, you started
talking to her before
the uav strike?
Is uav a drone?
Hello! Where are you going?
No, I'm only here
for a few days.
Oh, I know.
Oh, fuck.
I don't know what to say to you.
Ducky, I'm sorry.
I fucked up.
Did you go to the tribals
because you were in
a contract negotiation?
Dude, I'm not
stealing your job, okay?
Tanya, this is not
about my fucking job.
We have to make
good calls, right?
And now Andy lost an eye
and jaweed is dead.
Christ, man, we've both
fucking made mistakes!
No. Tell me you
didn't go to the tribals
because of a contract.
You would have done
exactly what I did
if jaweed had gone to you.
No. I'm not you.
Do you remember
your first embed?
You interviewed a young marine?
Coughlin? Yes. What?
Yeah, well, after they
aired your story,
where you used
his soundbite about
not loading his rifle,
they sent him to helmand.
And he got his legs blown off.
So I hear.
See you in Kabul.
I'm not really surprised
she chased the story.
That's what we do.
That's what you do.
I would do it.
Sorry.
Goddamn it, I'm tired.
You booked your return yet?
'Cause you could come through
Glasgow if you wanted.
I'll meet you.
What?
No. What about badakhshan?
Badakhshan, that will keep
because the fucking pass
is still snowed in.
I need that story.
I need a hit, all right?
I need something
so that geri doesn't decide
I'm more useful as
an ottoman in
her fucking office.
What you need, Kim,
is some time
out of the bubble.
You'd better get ready.
I'm fucking
making love to you
to bagpipe versions
of sade songs.
Yeah, okay.
Really? You'll meet
me in Glasgow?
Yeah, I'll meet you in Glasgow.
I'll get the next flight.
Okay.
Bye.
Hey, Antoine.
Where have you come from?
I thought you
were in badakhshan.
I was. Drove
back overnight.
Wait, what?
The pass is open?
Oui. For now.
Cheers.
Oh, Christ.
Mmm-hmm.
Aye, thank you.
Yeah, I get it.
Thank you. Thanks a lot.
Oh, Jesus.
Oh, shit.
Welcome to
Glasgow international airport.
Outside temperature's
18 degrees celsius.
Local time is 15 hours.
There will be
an airline representative
to assist you to your luggage.
Once again, thank you
for flying with us...
Oh, my god.
Leaving a message for Susan.
Woodward,
I'm back in Kabul again.
I'm trying to get
information about
the disappearance
of iain mackelpie,
so if someone at reuters
can please call me back.
Call to let me know
that you've
received this message.
Thank you.
Who kidnaps a Scottish
freelance photographer?
The whole point
of kidnapping is
to get money, right?
As far as I understand,
iain was just in
the wrong place
at the wrong time.
Can this half-assed
country not even do
kidnapping right?
Isaf does not think
this was an
upper-tier organization.
So these men will
probably try to sell
him to someone else.
And then there
will be some talking,
you know.
Oh, my god, fahim.
They're gonna kill him.
No, they will not, Kim,
inshallah.
Now is when you're supposed
to say "i told you so."
Fuck!
Ramadan has ended.
They are slaughtering lambs.
May I speak with him?
The general's busy.
Really, general?
The elliptical?
I have bad knees.
I'm guessing you
didn't come here
for the smell of balls.
Everybody get the fuck out!
They believe that
he may have been sold
to another organization
somewhere in that same region.
That's a pretty big ask, Baker.
There's a real-time
clock on this.
I'm sorry, i can't help you.
You know, it's just a shame that
y'all don't get
credit for all these
high-profile
things that you do.
You know, especially with
seals and delta out there.
I mean, what week
goes by that you don't see
those assholes
on TV, am I right?
And then next
time congress votes
on a Pentagon budget
and there's this pesky little
10% line item for the marines,
next thing you know,
you guys are just
part of the Navy.
Although, sir,
you would look
spectacular
in one of those
pretty white uniforms.
God, you know what?
It's just occurring to me
that, unlike jsoc,
you guys allow reporter embeds.
Which means that
a cameraman could go
on a forecon mission.
Don't you think that would be
great for the corps, sir?
That kind of exposure?
Pretty good for you, too.
Look, we don't go in blind.
We have to know
what we're doing
and where we're going.
It's the way we work.
We're not likely to
get an address, but...
When you have
something concrete,
come back and we'll get kinetic.
Ugh!
Please tell Mr. sadiq
that his "special
friend" is here.
What can I get
for you? Some tea?
The new PlayStation?
No, thank you. I just need
a moment of your time.
Ah.
We still friends, sadiq?
Well, that is up to you, Kim.
Because you once told me
that nothing happens here
that you don't know about.
So you must know about my friend
iain mackelpie
getting kidnapped.
I did hear about this, yes.
Yeah, well, everybody
heard about it,
but a powerful man
such as yourself must
actually know something.
Or your friend pacha Khan
knows something.
Or his friend does.
Of course.
I could make some inquiries,
but I can only do this
for a very special friend.
I have a video that I think
you should watch, sadiq.
You push the little triangle.
You can watch
video on the phone?
What is this?
It looks like
the Attorney General
of the islamic
Republic of Afghanistan
dancing in the street
with a western enemy of islam
at a party where
alcohol was served.
I've never touched
alcohol in my life!
Well, I'm just saying
how it looks.
It's a good idea, right?
It's a great idea!
It's fucking Ace!
Good on ya, Kim!
Let's go, load up!
Let's go, move, move, move!
You drink Tennessee whiskey,
miss Baker?
Yeah.
Outstanding.
Tall Brian? What the fuck?
Hang tight, sir.
I'm gonna get you
that ride.
Thank you.
What happened
to the army, Dr. brydon?
I am the army.
Thank you, Kim.
How are you?
I've had worse kidnappings.
Mackelpie is being
treated for minor injuries.
Again, this incredible footage
was produced
by our very own Kim Baker.
Just incredible.
Way to go, Kim!
If you want to kidnap
someone fucking twice,
you do a Toyota.
Fucking not as
interesting as it got
when they fucking
pulled out a burqa.
It's too fucking long for me!
I don't know who
the woman was
it belonged to.
I'm not fucking 6'2", right?
I'm dragging this
fucking thing along,
thinking
the only consolation is,
at least if I'm a fucking woman,
I'm not gonna get buggered,
you know what I'm saying?
So anyway, I took
a little something,
actually.
I went to
the gift shop at Taliban.
I'm afraid all I could get
was that.
It's a shame you're going.
Hmm?
Well, I hope at least
they're flying you
first class.
Geri doesn't
like me that much.
But she does like me now,
so while I have this juice,
I've got to leverage it
into something better.
Yes!
Yes, wait, Iraq.
I'll come with you.
No, actually, Pakistan.
That's where
the real shooting shit is.
It's like
the wild west out there.
Actually, I told geri
that I want New York or D.C.
No, I did.
No, really, where are you going?
New York or D.C.
Why?
You can still come with me.
Because I think
there's plenty of good work
to be done in the real world,
and the kabubble
is well-established.
Is this about me going
to badakhshan without you?
'Cause you would have done
exactly the same thing.
And, hey, what, i forgive you!
This is not about you.
It's not about badakhshan,
or Glasgow,
or the cottage
with the chickens.
What chickens?
It's okay.
I know you're not gonna come.
I just have to get out of here
before it's too late.
What do you mean?
I started to feel
like this was normal.
You know it's not, right?
Come to New York and get it.
Remember, you're like
a six in Manhattan.
How's your baby?
Which one?
You have two?
Yes.
Irish twins.
No, they are very good.
The younger one, the boy,
he's very strong.
Mmm.
I bet the girl is strong, too.
She's stronger.
So, um,
those men in the hospital,
the addicts...
Any of them ever get better?
Have a happy ending?
In my culture, we would hug.
Hey.
You know,
I miss it. The Stan.
Yeah, I miss it, too.
Actually, I tried to go back
but even the army
wouldn't take me.
I mean, the army!
I mean, that's just hurtful.
Well, I'm very sorry
for what happened to you.
So if there's anything
that you want to say to me,
that's why I'm here.
That's why I came here.
Ma'am,
I lost my legs
because of an ied,
not because of you.
I appreciate that,
but if I hadn't quoted you,
you wouldn't have
been transferred.
No, really, you can say
whatever you want to me.
That's why I'm here.
Okay, well,
then let's say you're right.
It's still not
'cause of you, ma'am.
Some 12-year-old haji
had to plant that bomb.
And, hell, you know,
if bin laden's parents
hadn't have gotten divorced,
maybe none of us would've been
in the Stan to begin with.
And the Taliban, they wouldn't
have even been there for ubl
if brezhnev hadn't have gone
and fouled up Afghanistan
in the first place.
And the British empire. Yeah.
And Kim Baker.
Okay, I deserve that.
Goddamn! Once you got no legs,
everyone takes everything so serious.
I mean, there's only
so much any of us
have any control of,
good or bad.
If you didn't learn
that in Afghanistan, you
were not paying attention.
So, you're not gonna yell at me?
I mean, ma'am...
Kim, you've got to move on.
You're giving yourself
way too much credit.
You embrace the suck,
you move the fuck forward.
What other fucking
choice do we have?
Do I hear swearing over there?
How are you standing there
the one time I curse?
"One time."
I mean...
It's true. He had a good
long run in the military.
Don't cover up for him.
So, Kim, are you
gonna stay for dinner?
Of course she will.
Bye!
Say bye to Kim. Bye, Kim!
Say bye.
Colonel, the Afghan
national army missed
yet another benchmark
for preparedness.
How do you think
that will affect
our draw down in the region?
There needs to be
a revision to the previously
announced draw down
or our future exit strategy.
Thank you, colonel Roberts.
Thank you. My pleasure.
Coming up,
a look at the war on terror
that's close to home
for those of us who cover it.
From London,
I'll be joined
by award-winning
combat photographer,
iain mackelpie.
His new book, conflict zone,
chronicles
a decade spent working
in the middle east
and Afghanistan.
That's when we return.
And we're clear.
Back in 40.
Hi, iain.
Hi. Was I supposed
to say something then
when you introduced me?
Nope.
Nope. Just sit up, smile.
I can't smile.
My face feels weird.
No, you're fine.
You look good.
Thank you for
coming on the show.
No, please.
Thanks for having me.
I got it. Okay, yeah. Got it.
You know, they got me
on this book tour
at the moment.
I'm gonna be in New York
at the end of the month,
if you'd fancy a coffee.
We're back
in five, four, three...