All right.
I want to get on.
To Josh, Chris, Jeff,
right.
Oh, I don't know.
I need to know.
Not nothing like it.
Well, you're always doing
this.
You know, if I look
well, it's a
real meeting
today.
Sort of problem.
So stick a c. No,
I know we've not always seen eye to eye,
but I try not to let personal feelings
get in the way of professional decisions.
Which is why I'm recommending you
for a promotion.
So a vacancy for Chief
Inspector has come up a good one for you.
The job is yours.
Well, thank you very much, sir.
You know, it's about time
you received the recognition you deserve.
Well done, lady. Thank you.
Thank you, sir.
Maybe a few more pennies in the bank.
Do you need to talk that through
with Superintendent McNeill?
But Superintendent McNeill promotions the
Glasgow Force be leaving end of the month
in Glasgow.
Force.
Nice to get back to the old one, Tony.
Well, then again, Lady.
So I would like some time to think
about it.
Well, I'm off to Manchester
for a couple of days.
Give me an answer when I get back.
Mr. Victor LATTMAN. None.
Lord Alexander Lipton.
No, sir. Thomas Pembroke.
Marquess of Bath. Not nothing.
Not a single piece of scandal
on any of them.
Well, the uncle of the Lepton man
has been throwing his money around.
Oh, not to hospitals.
And a fact treatment clause for the poor.
They've been doing this for weeks now.
Well, you hear what they've been up to.
Mrs. Parker pays me to do background
checks
on potential husbands for her niece.
She wants to know if they're suitable.
And I promise, had he defined reasons
why they were unsuitable.
She wishes to marry someone of her own
choosing, and her aunt will.
Need to find someone else
to do the yard digging.
I'm done.
I know it's unethical, but
how do you spend such a sheltered life?
I don't care.
What it takes is boring.
Boring?
They're all seamen with the same families
and the same lives.
There are better uses of my time.
I have a reputation to protect.
Since you are asking for more money.
No. It'd be about professional pride. Why?
I'm much afraid.
You're right.
There are much better uses of our time.
I'm doing as presently.
I tell her to speak to her aunt.
I'm happy to have a word with Mrs.
Parker myself. If the money is right.
Now, that is something
I would love to see.
And Inspector.
Moses.
What does he want?
Well, working the case isn't.
The kind of case.
Tony Waistcoat.
Very smart.
No. Are you aware
how often you change the subject
when you don't
wish to talk about something?
I'm glad you had a favor to ask.
When do you plans?
On this evening.
I was in System's departure
as Barnabas comes to.
There's no way
I can settle that in the home.
Eliza, he's his own anyway.
Never mind that I am.
I need to speak to you about something.
Do you mind if I have a card when we talk?
Kathy Park is calling around
and I'm running late.
Yes, fine.
So, um.
So I was at work this morning.
This isn't going to be about Moses, is it?
No, he's all about Moses.
If you insist on such things. No criminal.
This is about Moses.
I didn't come here to speak to you
about Moses.
All born with bloody pox.
I've.
I've been offered a promotion.
Chief Inspector William
for news.
Congratulations.
The job's in Glasgow.
Oh, I see.
That's a shame.
I don't mind.
Is that what you're going to say?
What else is there to say?
Was in Glasgow.
Allies of.
Scotland. I'm well aware where Glasgow is.
You're not going to take it. So.
How do you know
William? I say this is a friend.
Since I've known you.
You've been offered many different jobs.
Any that are outside of London.
We've always turned. Out. Yes.
And this is a promotion
to Chief Inspector.
As for the job in Nottingham,
I seem to remember
we've had this conversation
on at least three occasions.
And each time
you agonize over the decision
and in the end decide to stay.
My not comfortable here.
Comfortable.
It was a poor choice of words.
For your information, I'm
seriously thinking about taking this job.
And yes, I'm
well aware that I've said that before.
William has
come.
Through and has given me yet
another list of potential husbands.
I'm running out of reasons
whether I'm suitable.
You must speak to her to tell her
you do wish to marry.
It is not that I do not wish to marry.
It's just I do not wish to marry
someone who does not wish to marry me.
They want to marry for love. Yes,
but my aunt thinks I'm fanciful.
Harriet, she says
you do not have the luxury of time.
Oh. Looks to wait for love.
How could she possibly understand?
Everyone is in love with her.
You're a grown woman.
You must stand up for yourself as you try
that.
You'd be surprised
how determined she can be.
As here
you are a lovely young woman.
Any man would be lucky
to have you as that wife.
Sir. Absolutely.
I will tell my aunt I do not wish to wed.
And that is that
Papa left me some money.
Perhaps I could set up my own house.
There may be financial implications,
but as you say, Eliza,
I'm a grown woman and I will find a way.
Do you will?
I will go and see Mr. Norris,
our family accountant.
He will tell me which pass strings
my aunt controls.
So that is a plan.
Is it?
It is. Will you come with me?
I have every faith
that you can do this on your own.
So that is a definite no? Yes.
And you will not change your mind? No.
Thank you for changing your mind.
Must be careful what to say to Mr. Norris.
He's rather enamored with my aunt, right?
Oh, yes. She has many admirers.
She's a very handsome woman.
It's a mystery how she remains alone.
Mr. Norris.
Oh, I hear. You.
He didn't want to come in.
Mr. Norris.
It's Miss Parker. Mr. Norris.
Norris.
That's the police.
No. Hattie.
We must begin about 2 hours
after Dash first and the muscles around
the face and jaw and then it outwards
to the rest of the body.
So it feels very familiar.
Prescott I still remember asking you
to accompany Mrs.
Parker
back to Scotland Yard to give a statement.
So many of us staged.
Why go to all that effort?
Try moving his wrists
completely rigid.
Full rigor mortis takes 14 to 18 hours
to develop, which puts the time of death
at some point last night.
A rough guide?
Of course we can't.
The exact time. For the. Midnight.
I stand corrected.
Ms.. Scholars clearly developed a new
technique unknown to medical science.
It's called Using Your Eyes.
The clock has been stopped.
No, it has stopped.
You do not know. Has been stopped.
Inspector Wellington.
This entire scene
is exactly as it was in the novel.
What novel?
What does? A Midnight by Samuel Barber.
You heard about it? No.
Enlighten me.
For a few years since I read it,
I would swear everything in this room
is precisely as it was in the book.
The Bloodstained Alley.
The knife in the neck.
The arrangement of his hand on the chest.
And the clock stopped at midnight.
You really should read while I replant.
It is not a particular book.
I've not read it either.
Thank you, Detective Fitzroy.
Although I do read
at least one book a week.
At the moment I'm working
through the Russian study with Goncharov.
Make yourself useful.
See if there's a visitor's book
or a list of his appointments.
I know who was last in here.
Miss Scarlet Ford.
Go back to Scotland Yard.
Make a statement.
Then I can be much more. You said.
You just do what I ask.
This is about your job, isn't it?
You're annoyed with what I said.
And I am so often
annoyed with what you've said.
It's hard to keep track.
When I said you were comfortable.
You meant I lacked ambition.
No, of course. Not
only that, your life is arranged
as you like it.
You're settled.
That sounds even more insulting
than comfortable.
I think it's best
if we cease to discuss this.
I will let you know my decision
when I have come to it.
All right. Can I just say no?
I go back to Scotland Yard
and ask for Phelps.
That book.
The one you think the murderer imitated.
You said it was from by Samuel Bedford.
That's right. Why?
The victim was his accountant.
I do not see what the bulk of it.
I'm not hiring you. Just hear me out.
Firstly, I've heard every time I've been
able, I'm a huge fan of his work.
Secondly,
if you don't hire me, how do you like me?
Mr. Norris was a friend of Iran's.
Surely it's better to share information
and resources.
You know, for me, the taxpayers of London.
Oh, you're so selfless, Eliza.
As a person, I must bear.
So is that a yes?
How much is your free?
On second thoughts,
let's forgive the haggling and think that
the first moment you were going to say.
That seems fair.
Good.
Half it.
He could not be distracted
once his mind was focused on a task.
There was nothing that could break
his chain of thought,
not the shattering of the window
downstairs,
not the footsteps in the hallway.
When at last he looked up,
he saw a blade glistening in the moonlight
and felt the cold steel pierce
his heart.
Thus concludes
Chapter three.
Thank you, Mr.
Bedford, for once again
gracing our humble.
Shop with such a wonderful. Reading.
Now, if you would like to form
an orderly queue, Mr.
Bedford will gladly sign
copies of his book
as long as they have been purchased here.
Of course. I.
No, no, no.
Outside, please.
I need to speak to Mr. Baird, bro.
This event is for ticket holders only.
I'm in search of Wellington, Scotland
Yard.
I'm here on piece business.
And yet you brought your wife.
She's not my wife.
I'm a
private detective assisting Scotland Yard
with their inquiries.
I've heard many excuses in my time,
but that.
I, for God's sake,
haven't even read any of his done books.
I have.
I am Mr.
Federer, Samuel's sister.
Is something wrong?
I need to speak to your brother
right away. Yes.
When did this happen?
We believe Mr.
Norris was killed last night.
Can you think of anyone
who might wish to do harm?
They always seem to be
a perfectly decent man.
In truth, I didn't know.
Well, he was a business acquaintance.
We only met a few times a year.
When was the last time?
A few weeks ago.
I couldn't say for sure.
As we mentioned,
we believe the crime scene was arranged
to resemble the murders
in quarter to midnight extra.
You understand that.
I have to ask you about your own movements
last night, sir. Why?
It's a standard question, Samuel.
I ask it of everyone.
I have a sweet Brabham hotel.
I'm staying there
whilst I finish my latest novel.
And were you alone?
You mean apart from the 50 staff
and 300 guests.
Samuel.
My sister and I had dinner
and then I wrote all night.
I'm rather late delivering
my latest novel.
Is it true you once finished a manuscript
in the carriage
on the way to the publishers?
I woeful about deadlines,
but I have no need for Muse or Mood.
I can write any time or any place
you enjoy my novels?
Very much so, yes.
In fact, quarter to midnight
is my favorite.
Oh, I haven't read that
particular one, but
I did enjoy Curse of the Crimson Shadow.
That was not me.
Could do midnight.
It's based on his own life.
He spent years as an unpublished writer
before finally enjoying success.
Writer in the novel was
under pressure to deliver his latest book
and slowly starts going insane.
Believes his two best friends
want to put him in an asylum
so he kills them both.
But like Macbeth,
he is unable to live with the guilt.
You do know the story of.
Yes, Eliza, I know the story of Macbeth.
My apologies.
Anyway,
when the author in the novel was a child,
his parents died of scarlet fever.
As a boy, he witnessed them
laid out in their coffins at home,
each holding a lily.
The clock in his office
about a quarter to midnight,
which is the exact time of two murders
in the book take place,
but on separate nights.
So if someone is not keen to replicate the
book in his post, they could kill again.
It's possible. Yes.
Do we know any more about our victim?
Edward Norris, 52 years old, sir.
Fond memories to respect for the countless
hundred or so clients
that we're busy tracking down.
I'm going to read the book again.
See if there's anything we've missed.
May I suggest you do the same?
Fitzroy?
Everything you have so far. And Norris
and his associates.
Right away, sir.
Oh, and give me a brief synopsis
on the story of Macbeth.
A couple of pages to
you will have it, sir.
When the hurly burly is done,
when the battle's lost.
And one may not one pitch.
Yes, sir.
One. This is Mr.
Bedford's most famous work.
But have you considered
beginning with a loan in Greenwich,
which should be here somewhere?
Yes. I'll read that straight after this.
Miss Willoughby.
Might I recommend that you read it first?
They do make a wonderful pair.
Such vivid prose.
I could recite every line.
I think I'll just start with this one
for Nice.
You know, what am I saying?
I would also recommend the jagged tears
effect.
But perhaps I should just get you
his complete works.
How does that sound? Expensive.
May I ask why you wanted to speak to Mr.
Bedford? I can discuss something for it.
I knew there was something wrong
as soon as he came in.
He usually turns up to readings
in a wonderful mood.
But today he was
rather withdrawn and upset.
And this was before I spoke to him. Yes.
I've never seen him like that before.
I do hope everything is all right.
Would you like in wrapped.
From one.
Of us, skipper.
To concentrate?
I could.
Get. You in
any way.
You felt like you.
As for the Norris case, I.
Did not view down as much of a reader,
but from the sporting past.
You want something, Charlie?
No. Just say now you are.
If there's any news.
In the ten years
we've worked together, I don't think
you've ever bought me a drink.
People change. People do.
You don't like it?
What do you want?
I got sober
talking to you about a promotion.
I was just passing.
Passing. And I was thinking
if you did take it,
you might put in a word for me
to take over from you.
You're not such a sinner.
What was your strong point was it?
I've got a wife and four kids.
Five kids?
Your car full to be sorted.
I know you've had offers in the past
and it back.
But you're not getting any younger
naval officer.
At some point the offers are not coming
and that will be your law.
If you were happy with our.
Things are fine. But if you're not. Yes.
Thank you, Detective.
He could.
Terrible.
Good morning.
Morning.
Did you submit.
Make some progress to the Norris case
and to the evidence?
How did you find me?
Oh, no.
Lucky guess.
You do have something of a set routine.
Beethoven on Monday.
Double track on Tuesday.
Shoes on a Wednesday.
Thursday.
Oh, you've made your point.
Progress has been made.
I need to see the murder weapon.
I read that, of course, midnight.
On Saturday,
along with some of his other work.
There's no reason to out.
Yes. Themes rags to riches are very common
with characters.
Like the lawyer and the London Greenwich.
Man. Not by surprise, unimpressed.
Compliment and sullen one.
That's quite something.
Even for your lighter.
Have you made
your decision is about the job.
As I said, I'll let you know when I have.
Well,
please feel free to discuss it with me.
And let you suffer here.
Thank you.
My intention was not to insult.
Can be rather sensitive
sometimes sensitive.
Unsettle others.
Just because, Bertram, that's. Not.
The case.
Eliza wants to see the murder weapon,
the cat.
And at midnight, it's the same weapon
which made the knife. Yes.
First victim was stabbed in the neck
with our knife.
The second had the same knife
embedded in his neck.
Just how we found Norris.
Which means he may not
be the first victim.
Exactly.
You wrote.
I closed the book last night,
and I just must find publishers
not on the crest.
He's like anything else.
So the killer is following
the plot of the book.
Then the knife belongs
to the first victim.
It's not.
Mr. Bellamy.
Is there a side entrance?
There's no time for that.
Kick it down
because touching touched
nothing.
Let's get to Wellington.
And here.
Just like the novel.
Right down to the time.
James was a good man.
He'd been my publisher for years.
When did you last see him?
At dinner on Thursday night.
How did he seem?
In good spirits.
And you can think of
no one that may wish to do him harm.
I don't know.
My mind is a little foggy.
My brother has been up all night writing.
I tell him to go to bed,
but he never listens.
And that's where you were last night?
In this room, writing?
Yes, all night.
May I ask what happened to your hand?
God sake!
Must you
keep asking these relevant questions?
Samuel? I
slipped in the vault.
Could we finish this later?
I must go and visit James's son.
We prefer you stay here, sir.
Both murders were exactly
as in your novel.
And as you know, there is a third death.
All through my novel takes his own life.
I can assure you
I'm not planning on doing that.
Even so, if someone is determined
to replicate the book, they may wish to do
you harm. Your sister's right,
Mr. Barbara.
I'll arrange police protection for you
in the meantime, if you'd like to go home.
Our homes are being decorated.
I'll stay here. As you wish.
I'll wait here
until an officer arrives with Scarlet.
If you could take this message back
to Scotland Yard for me.
I tracked down the nightfall
to some of it,
but left the hotel last night around
9:00 and didn't return again to dawn.
Midnight.
A killer
who replicates the plot of his own book.
Isn't it more likely
someone's trying to damage his reputation?
Possibly.
There's no book cover than a murderer
who hates in plain sight.
It's like he
was arrested three months ago
for public disorder.
He was arguing with a woman in the street,
and apparently
they threatened to kill each other.
They were arrested for breach
of the peace, but no charges were brought.
So they were cautioned and released.
And Jessica Sweeney.
Is an actress.
Go and speak to them.
I the bodies, the mortuary.
Mr. Covered.
Excuse me, sir. Your carriage is ready.
Thank you, Fitzroy.
On the way back from the mortuary,
I wonder if we might go via Covent Garden.
I very much like to see tickets
for the premiere of Offenbach's
The Tales of Hoffmann.
Perhaps I would do that my own time.
Perhaps you will.
What'll happen to him if I leave?
Well, it's a good job
that you're not going to take the job.
How many times?
I haven't made my decision yet.
Unlike you, I give consideration
to the life that I've built here.
What do you mean?
Unlike me?
Well, if you were offered
the job, you'd think in a heartbeat.
Well, on the day
that women are allowed to be
chief inspectors,
we should have that conversation.
You know what I mean?
If you were offered more money
and high profile cases,
you would jump at the chance.
We're the location.
We're very different people, William.
Oh, meaning
that you have a singular ambition.
And I am a dull and predictable,
beautiful.
Monday shoeshine in a way to school.
Am I?
You do not have to
justify your life to me.
I do.
And you constantly tease me about her.
And I apologize.
Clearly, it's a nerve from.
Where I have come from.
I have done done well to get this far.
We don't all have the luxury
of inheriting a father's business.
I was going to speak to Ms..
Pelosi and I'll have her reporting.
Morning. Eliza.
Eliza, I apologize that
that came out harsher than I expected.
Don't let me keep you waiting.
It's almost time for your 3:00 whiskey,
Sidney.
I'm looking for Miss Fettuccini.
What was the nature of your relationship
with Mr.
Bhadra?
The nature of our relationship?
Yes. Physical. And.
And where did you meet him?
Some party cannot remember whose.
But we do not see each other anymore.
I have a new level.
Younger, much more willing to please.
You know
what happened the night you were arrested?
I had little too much to drink
and went to see him.
And one thing led to another.
You know how these things go.
The police were understanding.
I told them it was Italian person,
not that them from Italy.
Nobody has heard about my country. So.
Italy plays much better.
So you argue
because he finished your relationship.
He sends his little friend
with a diamond necklace.
A parting gift to make me go quietly.
Who is this friend? Norris?
His accountant, I think.
I call him the Grim Reaper.
When you see him, you know it's over.
Cause of death is identical in both cases.
A single puncture
wound to the carotid artery.
The size of the wound indicates
the same weapon.
You to start
making those close encounters.
ST See if he had any visitors.
Fitzroy Phelps
You do the same for the publisher.
Screw your courage to the sticking place
will not fail.
Lady Macbeth.
I have to go with him.
That depends
whether you want to keep your job.
All right.
Off you go.
Fitzroy
word, please.
What we do requires
working as part of a team.
Any detective, above all, needs the trust
and respect of his colleagues,
including Shakespeare.
Sorry, sir.
It was misjudged.
One day
I may not be around and coat for you.
So you need stuffing in. Where you going?
I'm just making the point
with them.
Why let them moan about their job
or their wives or the money
that they lost in the narcs?
Let them moan about me.
I would never let them do that.
The more you are an outsider, the weaker
you will be.
And when they felt they could smell
weakness, no, that doesn't make him a bad
man. It's
just the nature of being a copper.
Tony can be one of the lads.
You sound like my father.
God forbid.
Sorry for the delay.
I was comforting my aunt.
She's in great distress about Mr. Norris.
Well, I have a question about Mr.
Norris.
Samuel Barber said that he and Norris
had a purely professional relationship,
only seeing each other a few times a year.
Really?
I found that strange.
Mr. Norris is always mentioning Mr.
Barber to my aunt.
He made out to respect things
that may not have been true, of course.
He may have been trying to impress
since he was secretly in love with her.
Here we go. 5 minutes
without mentioning your aunt.
Yes, of course. My apologies.
You said Norris and everyone take a seat.
It is my understanding that
they don't get it several times a month.
I missed her.
Norris was always doing this favor
or that for Mr.
Barbara.
I believe that Mr.
Norris recently arranged the purchase
of the house in Knightsbridge.
It was only a few doors down from
I'm about to mention
my aunt, but I believe it is relevant.
Go on.
Mr. Pappas, new house
is on the same street as my aunt's.
The other residents were beside themselves
to have such a well-known
face living among them. Until.
Well,
I am not one to gossip, of course.
But please do.
Mr. Barbara moved in not two months ago.
I seem to be spending a fortune
on my relations.
But then last week,
the strangest thing happened.
Some rude bedbug is up to his neck
in debt.
He's staying a suite at the bathroom.
Not for much longer.
He's facing a hefty bill.
It was money all over town.
That's why the natives took his house
and everything in it.
You had to build this last night.
Doing what?
Trying to get back some piece of furniture
they took from him every day this week.
He's turned up trying to buy it back, but
they want to put it, believe it or not.
Piece of furniture.
Right in this.
I told them it couldn't write it out.
I just told me he had no need
for news on news.
Do right.
Any time any works.
With you on starting this clock?
Security caught him
breaking into the warehouse
last night, roughed him up on.
Spanish hand, as well as
he got contacts in.
I have contacts everywhere.
He got walking out the door.
And seen nothing like that. Before.
It was amazing.
Good evening.
It's actually Fitzroy.
Any possible bets on?
Very good.
Would anyone like a drink?
Oh, they don't serve milk in our.
I'll take that as a no. Oh.
Why don't you go with your mommy, Fitzroy,
so she can clean
you up?
What are you.
Shut your mouth, Phelps.
You want to repeat that?
I didn't think so.
Spoiled brat.
I don't want.
You shouldn't have done that, boy.
We've got 10 minutes to this exchange.
But first things.
All that dear.
It took everything from his house.
Didn't do it, Mr. Trick blows wise.
No wonder he's dead.
Manners, expensive things.
These are for members of Piccadilly.
Here.
Doesn't look like much. It's not.
It must be very attached to it. These are.
Give it back.
Maybe sentimental.
Poker tees.
What?
It one of peppers early novels.
There's a lawyer. Socrates.
The Greek God of silence.
Agent.
How is it that whatever secrets he knows.
Never speak of them.
I'll take them to the grave.
Of course, as secrets are discovered,
learning remains,
which is cool.
Piece of
peppers novels covered in that new work.
And they must be the original manuscripts.
Why keep them.
Hidden
and sent to report?
No, sir.
As Barbara is writing.
And that's not to be disturbed.
What is it.
Hell's going on?
My thoughts. Exactly.
I needed to confirm a suspicion.
There's no time to wait any longer.
Well, the final death in the book
is when the author takes his own life.
He must live among all.
He's not the author. Mr.
for the Knife.
Don't do what he says.
Please. For
the writing desk
that was taken from your brother's home.
That was yours? Yes.
I found manuscripts inside with notes
from the publisher addressed to you.
So it was you who wrote the novels?
Not your brother.
Mother died in the workhouse. A father.
God knows what he went
to. I was determined
to make something of himself,
but he struggled for years
to become a novelist,
didn't have the heart to tell the truth,
but he lacked the talent he knew to.
Deep down,
and he's my older brother,
I would have done anything to help him.
So I did.
I rewrote his story.
I had a flair for it.
By the time I submitted his manuscript
publishers,
there was barely a word of his left.
Why do you put your own name on the cover?
Samuel begged me not to. You?
He cannot have suffered the humiliation.
The spinster sister was the one
putting food on the table and not him.
But after the success of the book
started to rise,
I did ask him
if I could put my name to the next.
That was when
they called the meeting. They
Samuel Bellamy and Norris.
The three of them convinced me
that as a woman,
my wage would be half of that as a man.
They promised that one day
I could write under my own name, but
that was not the right time.
It was never the right time.
Why kill them?
The one benefit
I received from this arrangement
was that I would be well looked after.
I would have a comfortable home security.
But then one day
the bailiffs arrived
and I found out the truth.
Some of those debts were all consuming.
He'd spent every penny of my money.
I'm going to be a nurse,
knew all along, did nothing.
They didn't care.
As long as Oakley's still being written
and they were receiving their money.
Money I was earning for them.
So this was your revenge.
And the world
would know that you were the true author.
I would have my moment of fame and death.
All this time
I brought the shine
for what? For?
To end up a poor spinster
back in a workhouse.
Would you like me to arrange a lift home?
Oh, thank you.
I would sit in myself,
but there are folks that have to finish
for the morning shift.
And send.
All this.
I was polite. This is exhausting.
Isn't it?
Just.
I didn't mean what I said
about your father's business.
I know you haven't been handed
anything to play.
I know how hard you've worked.
But there are times
when you push me too far.
I and it's easy because I'm so comfortable
in our friendship.
I suppose I can be a
little insensitive sometimes.
It's only because I'm envious.
Envious of me.
Not fulfilled in your life.
That's not lack of ambition.
That's something you should celebrate.
You have that rare thing
that most of us don't find in a lifetime.
True contentment.
That's why you're one of the people
I respect most.
When you say one of
Give me saw,
I didn't know you were still here.
What have you done now?
I did as you suggest.
I went for a drink and I tried to fit in.
Perhaps I tried a little too hard.
I could not go home to my father
like this. So
I thought I could sleep here.
I have a spare room.
You can stay there.
Thank you, sir.
Are you.
Going to.
Judge her?
I shouldn't
fight.
I can't let you
come off.
Quick words, sir.
I can see I'm almost done.
How was your trip, sir?
To ask
business or pleasure? Neither.
It was two days.
My wife's family.
So it was time to think.
I trust you realize
they get an opportunity.
This promotion is a have.
And you're right. It's a good opportunity.
But it's not one that's right for me.
I'm so.
I put in a lot of favors
to get you the slutty
chance like this may not come up again.
I won't understand, sir,
but my decision has made
my life here in London.
Well, I hope you would accept the position
so I could avoid this.
So, Fitzroy's
Father,
the police commissioner wants you gone.
Boy's getting worse, not better.
I been trying. He the albatross.
Which is why I told
you to put some distance between yourself
and him till I am sink or swim.
He wouldn't listen to me
at least drowning.
His father wants someone to blame.
So let me be crystal clear.
You're going to take this post in Glasgow.
It's no longer a job for you here.