# "Sayonara"
# "Japanese goodbye"
Just like a bird!
How many did you get, sir?
- Hey, he got two more!
- Old Gruver got two more!
Nice going there, sir.
Let’s try the other lung.
Breathe.
- Breathe.
- Hi, Padre.
- Two more MiGs today, I hear, Lloyd.
- Yeah.
That’s it. You can put it on.
- Well, Ace, you’ve had it.
- Say what?
You’re through flying for a while, anyway.
Oh, no. Nothing wrong with me
a little bottle of beer isn’t gonna fix up.
Give him a bottle of beer
and send him back up.
- Don’t get yourself excited here.
- Don’t get pale. I was just giving you a rib.
But you could use some sleep.
Yeah, I could use
a little nice Korean sleep.
Better than that. You’re going to Japan.
- I’m going to Japan? What for?
- Why not?
Wouldn’t you like to tangle with
one of those beautiful Japanese dolls?
If it’s your prescription, Doc,
I’ll certainly work at it best I can.
You’re going to Kobe.
Kelly has your orders.
What in the world am I gonna do in Kobe?
It’s a special request
of General Webster himself.
Well, then, this has all been prearranged?
Prearranged? Demanded.
Why shouldn’t a three-star general
look out for a four-star general’s son?
Don’t get on my back.
I ain’t buckin’ for favours.
I know you haven’t. I was just kidding.
- See you, Doc. Thanks.
- Can I have a word, Gruver?
Yeah. I’ll bet you I know what the word is.
K- e-l-l-y. Is that true or false?
He’s got permission to go back
and marry that Japanese girl.
I told him - he can’t take her
back to the States.
I explained the law in detail myself.
But there’s no law
which says he can’t marry her,
and he’s appealed to his congressman.
- His congressman?
- I wish you’d talk to him.
After all, he is one of your men, and you’re
the only human being he looks up to.
Listen, I’m gonna tell you something.
That boy don’t look up to anybody.
He has been promoted four times
and busted right back again.
Yeah, my congressman.
Shocking, ain’t it, Major?
Chaplain says don’t marry the girl.
Colonel says don’t marry the girl.
You say don’t marry the girl.
Congressman says “You marry
that girl, Kelly.” What can I do?
I’ll tell you what you can do, boy.
You can go and marry your congressman.
You’d be better off.
Give me coffee.
Yes, sir.
I hear you bagged two more today, Major.
- How was it up there?
- Splendid.
What’s the matter? What happened?
There was a guy with a face
in one of those planes today.
in all the other seven you shot down.
Yeah.
That’s exactly
what I’ve been thinking about.
Well, you can stop thinking.
You got a very well-written contract here.
General Webster’s had you assigned
to the inter-service aviation board,
which means you got
practically nothing to do.
Except, of course, marry the general’s
daughter who arrives in Kobe tomorrow.
- You mean Eileen...?
- That’s right.
- General’s wife and daughter both.
- Don’t fool me now.
I’m not fooling. You’re not supposed
to know anything about it. Big surprise.
Eileen’s coming to Kobe.
Yeah. General Webster arranges it
for you to marry his daughter,
my congressman arranges it
for me to marry my girl.
Generals for the officers,
congressmen for the peasants.
Listen, I’m glad you brought that up, boy.
I think there’s a little bit of difference
that we oughta talk about.
- What do you mean?
- Well, now listen.
I never did show you
a picture of my girl, did I, Kelly?
No.
Well, I’m gonna show you
a picture of a girl.
It happens to be my girl,
but she’s American.
And I want you to take
a long, long look at her,
because I believe that maybe you forgot
what an American girl looks like.
And this girl I’m gonna show to you
is first of all an American girl,
a girl with fine character,
a girl with good background,
good education, good family, good blood.
I’ve known this girl since I was about
that high. Families are very close.
I’ve been engaged to this girl
for a long time, Kelly.
Now, she’s a girl of unusual character.
I’d like you to take a look at her,
a close look,
and tell me what you think
and what your feeling is.
- Kind of beat up, ain’t she?
- I beg your pardon?
No. The beat-up one’s
her mother, you idiot.
Here’s Eileen.
- Now, now...
- Hey.
" She sure does something wicked
to a bathing suit.
She has an enormous capacity
to fulfill a bathing suit. That’s enough.
I’m just showing it to you.
But all kidding aside,
the reason I wanna show you this girl...
You ever seen Katsumi?
- Where’s that?
- It’s not a “where’s that?”
- It’s the girl I’m marrying.
- Oh. Well, no.
I don’t know Japanese names.
That’s all right. Forget it.
- Well?
- Yeah.
Looks like a bright girl.
- She’s a whole lot brighter than me.
- That ain’t too hard to do, you know.
Listen, Kelly, I wanna say
something seriously to you.
Aren’t you taking a risk
in marrying this Japanese girl?
Risks don’t scare me any.
The army and the air force
and the State Department
have ganged up
to keep me from getting married.
Hold on. What do you mean, ganged up?
Here, look at these pamphlets.
”Think it over, Americans.”
”Things you are required to know and do
before marrying Orientals.”
Here’s another piece of garbage.
”But will your family accept her?”
- Will they, Kelly?
- I ain’t got any family.
I haven’t got anything
against this girl of yours.
I haven’t got anything against
the Japanese any more. Not really.
But, you know, when...
I just don’t understand
how a normal, average American...
Let’s put it this way.
I think even your friends are gonna
put you down if you marry this girl.
If the friends I got are that kind, they won’t
be friends of mine much longer.
Major, I’m gonna marry my girl if I have to
give up my American citizenship to do it.
Kelly, you stupid, ignorant slob.
Go ahead and marry this slant-eyed runt
if you want to. It’ll serve you right.
Wait a minute, Major.
Don’t talk to me that way!
I won’t take that
from you or anybody else.
I’m sorry, Kelly.
I’m sorry.
I’m just blowing my stack a little today.
But, boy, I mean it. I...
I wanna tell you, when you tell me
that you’re gonna give up your citizenship
for a girl, any girl,
I think you’re nuts.
- I think you’re crazy.
- I am crazy. I’m in love crazy.
I think you’re gonna cut your throat
and I’d just hate to see you do it.
And I mean that with all sincerity.
Maybe that’s because you don’t feel
as strong about your girl as I do mine.
There’s your orders, Major.
See you on the plane.
OK.
Kelly.
We’re coming in, Major.
There’s the Inland Sea.
Beautiful, ain’t it?
Sure is nice scenery out there.
That’s Kobe over there.
See it, with all the docks?
What you’re looking at, Major,
really is three cities all run together.
There’s Kobe, Osaka and Kyoto.
- They got kabuki there.
- What’s kabuki?
Never heard of kabuki theatre?
All men, no dames.
- That’s gonna be dull, ain’t it?
- I don’t know.
If it’s all dames you want,
I think we’re gonna get there in about...
Yep. Look down there.
See that little park over there with
the lakes around it? That’s Matsubayashi.
- Where?
- Right down in there. See it?
The Matsubayashi girls
are the most famous in Japan.
They sing, they dance,
they act all the parts. No men.
Katsumi knows all the actresses.
She’s a movie fan.
You’re just blowin’ your top about
seeing Katsumi, aren’t you? Carryin’ on...
She’s my girl, Major.
- Well, GG, good to see you.
- So long, Lloyd.
- Lots of luck to you.
- Thank you. Bye-bye.
Lloyd! Lloyd! Here we are.
Lloyd!
- Hey, there!
- Don’t forget to act surprised.
Yeah, hi there! Hot dog!
Won’t he be surprised!
- Major?
- Yeah?
How about being my best man?
Listen, Kelly, I told you
that I’m against this marriage.
It would mean a lot to me.
What do you say, Major?
OK.
Consul’s office. 10 o’clock, Saturday.
Well, come on, honey. Hurry up.
Well, now. Come here, you!
Hi!
Certainly good to see you.
Hi, sir. Nice to see you.
I said “There’s General Webster
but who is that good-looking woman?”
- Tell me about Eileen. How is she?
- She finds Tulsa terribly dull without you.
Well, I wish she could have come along.
Lloyd, you couldn’t expect us
to bring her out here.
You’re registered at the hotel for the first
few nights but stationed here after that.
- I see.
- Let’s go. You get in first.
- You go ahead, Mrs. Webster.
- No, you get in first.
- Go on, get in.
- No, ladies first.
Hi, Lloyd.
You devil.
Come here.
I’m glad to see you, darling.
I forgot what an ugly girl you got here.
She’s not ugly. She’s a beautiful girl.
She’s the ugliest girl I ever saw.
And that dress is terrible.
It just goes in and out. That’s awful.
It’s meant to go in and out. I go in and out.
Well, we’ll talk about that later.
Send Major Gruver’s luggage
up to his room, will you?
That’s beautiful, isn’t it?
- Are there any rules against it?
- No, but it’s understood...
I thought the club would be honored.
Please, Mike, let’s go.
- What’s she doing here?
- Mother!
- Isn’t she with that young officer?
- Kobe’s a recreation centre.
- That’s right.
- It degrades the uniform.
- It’s out-and-out fraternization.
- She’s beautiful.
All the more reason.
Mark?
Colonel Crawford.
- Let’s get outta this clip joint.
- Just a minute, Captain Bailey.
- What’s the trouble?
- I didn’t mean to bother you with this.
Captain Bailey here is wanting
to take her into the club.
General Webster, sir, this young lady
is one of Japan’s most famous dancers.
She’s no ordinary...
Yes, I understand.
Even so, don’t you realize
this club is only for American personnel?
Now, we’ve been pretty easy
about fraternization in this area,
even though there are
strict orders against it.
But when an officer
who should be an example...
Am I to understand, sir,
that you personally
refuse to allow me
to take this young lady into the club?
I understand how you feel, Captain,
and I’m very embarrassed, but I’m sorry.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, "sir."
Don’t you know there’s such a thing
as insolence through manner?
Thank you, "sir."
Come on in, boys. Eileen has to change.
- Eileen’s taking you to the kabuki tonight.
- Good.
We met Mr. Nakamura, the head actor,
and he invited her to come.
Isn’t that where there’s no dames
and the men play all the women’s parts?
That’s right, the way they do at Princeton.
Come on, Mark.
It’s gonna be fun. Come on, baby.
Did you bring your lunch?
”Miss Eileen Webster.” Ah!
- Who’s fightin’ her?
- That’s Nakamura.
- He’s the one I met. He’s very famous.
- Is that Nakamura?
It’s about a lady who turns into a lion.
She gonna turn into a lion right here?
I wanna see that.
I love you, Lloyd. I love you terribly.
I always have and I guess I always will.
I love you, honey.
Awful glad you’re here, too.
Everybody acting
like nobody ever kissed in the world.
She wouldn’t be half so ugly if she didn’t
stick her face in that flour barrel.
She?
Well, whatever.
He had me.
He’s a male actress. It says here
they’ve been trained since childhood
to have the grace of a woman
and yet the power of a man.
Oh, my word.
My lord! That’s my father!
Is he man enough now for you, Lloyd?
Is that the same fellow?
Uh-huh.
It’s all right.
I am sure it must be very difficult
to enjoy theatre
so different from your own.
- We found it fascinating.
- I am glad.
Kabuki’s very old, isn’t it?
Some 300 years.
I find myself becoming intrigued
by everything in Japan.
I should be happy to help you know
my country better, if at any time I can.
You did not enjoy the evening so much,
I fear, Major Gruver.
Oh, yeah. I thought it was a fine play.
I thought maybe you could use a Marilyn
Monroe here and there, you know, to...
Unfortunately, Miss Monroes were barred
from kabuki in the 17th century.
I didn’t mean to sound corny.
I just didn’t know what to say about it.
Please, do not apologize.
I am great admirer of Miss Monroe myself.
That’s two of us. That’s you and me, boy.
No, don’t do it to me. It’s real good.
Thank you very much. Why not?
- Let’s go and see the garden.
- OK, you go on. I’ll take this.
That’s fine, fine cooking. Very good.
Here you are, honey.
- No, thank you.
- Don’t care for any?
- Sit down, darling.
- You look awful pretty.
I’ve been doing a lot of thinking
with you away, Lloyd.
- Answer me one thing.
- What’s that, honey?
Why aren’t we married now?
- Isn’t that a silly question?
- No, not really.
You do a lot of wondering in Tulsa.
Well, I suppose the Korean War
might have a little something to do with it.
Wasn’t Korea maybe convenient, Lloyd?
Convenient?
What I really mean is... do I mean
everything to you as you do to me?
Course you do, honey.
I went to visit your mother
before I came here, there in Richmond.
My mother?
I was appalled at the loneliness
in which she lives,
and the way your father’s content to go off
and leave her walled up
in a circle of friends
while he plunges off to the war.
Hold on a second. You’ve got to
remember my father’s a general, honey.
Besides, my mother
wants to live that way.
- Don’t be ridiculous.
- Don’t tell me that.
No woman wants to live any way except
body and soul with the man she loves.
You’ll never tuck me away
in some little town.
Become the greatest general
in air-force history, but love me too.
But do I love you, baby. I do.
Well, I guess all I’m trying to say is that -
and I really mean this, Lloyd -
if what you want
is a family like our fathers have
and promotion in the air force
and position in society
like our mothers have,
and you marry me because I’m pretty and
smart and have guts and know the ropes...
then I don’t think
you want to marry me, Lloyd.
I’m sorry.
I guess I’ve been thinking too much.
Yeah, I think you have
been thinking too much.
Now...
Now quit it.
OK. I don’t know.
Maybe things’ll turn out after all.
What do you mean, maybe?
Sure, it’s gonna turn out.
It’s just all that nonsense you talk about
every time we get together.
Nonsense? I hadn’t realized
it was nonsense.
Course it is, honey. It’s all very simple.
Now, look here.
I want a wife and a family.
I want a home in America.
And every time I think of a home like that,
I think about it with a woman like you.
A girl with a good army
background like my own...
What do you mean, a girl like me?
I’m not a type. I’m me.
Lloyd, it’s me you’ve got to love.
Haven’t you ever felt like grabbing me and
hauling me off to a shack somewhere?
You know better than that.
Of course I have.
- Then what’s holding you back?
- Eileen, are you ever gonna grow up?
There’s a right time
and a wrong time to do things.
You have responsibilities to other people.
You have a position to fulfill.
- You’re not alone in this world.
- You defend yourself like a fort.
No matter how I defend myself, you gotta
understand I am not in a position
to be hauling my fiancée away
to a shack somewhere like an alley cat.
I wasn’t brought up that way.
You’re going to do everything
expected of you?
I’m certainly gonna try.
I don’t expect you to marry me
just because it’s expected of you.
Sometimes I look at you
and I don’t understand you.
I think sometimes I don’t even know
who you are or what you’re all about.
Maybe you don’t. Maybe you never will.
- …so long as you both shall live?
- I will.
Katsumi, wilt though have this man
to thy wedded husband,
to live together after God’s ordinance
in the holy state of matrimony,
love him, comfort him, honor
and keep him, in sickness and in health,
and forsaking all others keep thee only
unto him, so long as you both shall live?
- She will.
If any man can show just cause why
they may not be lawfully joined together,
let him now speak
or else hereafter for ever hold his peace.
Do you realize
you waive all your legal rights?
I signed all the papers, didn’t I?
You’ll have to look after your wife on
your own. The air force is not responsible.
Yeah, I know. Romantic, ain’t it, Major?
Will you finish this ugly deed
and get it over?
I pronounce you man and wife.
Sign over there.
Just a minute.
That’s it, Mrs. Kelly. Just you and me now.
Where do we sign?
May as well witness this now, Major.
Yeah, all right.
It was a great honor meeting you,
Major Gruver.
Thank you.
Tell me, Consul, are all these ceremonies
conducted like this?
Well, we do our best
to prevent as many as possible.
We make the paperwork so difficult
that a good many of them lose steam.
About how many GIs
have gone through this ceremony?
About... 10,000.
10,000? Well, then,
you let a few slip by you, didn’t you?
A few, yes.
How’s your girl, Major?
Eileen? I haven’t seen her
in a couple of days.
I’ve been moving in,
getting my things arranged.
She’s been hightailing it
with the brass, socializing.
Major, ain’t you gonna kiss the bride?
Sure, I’m gonna kiss the bride.
Yeah. Sure.
Listen, I want you to take good care
of this boy, you hear?
Here’s your ticket, honey. Don’t forget it.
OK, boy.
Thanks, Major. Took a lot of guts
for you to come here today.
Quit.
If you ever need a job done that you West
Point guys ain’t allowed to do yourselves,
I’m your man.
- I’m gonna call on you.
- Come on, let’s get a belt.
- How are you, Lloyd?
- Fine, just fine.
- That’s a pretty dress you got on.
- Thanks.
Lloyd, sit down, son.
All righty.
- Thank you for coming over so promptly.
- That’s all right. I was just darning socks.
Lloyd...
I don’t exactly know how to put this.
It’s a little embarrassing. For me, that is.
You were a witness
at a marriage yesterday between...
one of your men and a Japanese girl.
Yeah, one of the men
from my outfit in Korea.
You realize, of course, there’s an army
policy to discourage all such marriages.
I think they couldn’t have been
discouraged. They’re very much in love.
I dare say. However, you personally
seemed to sanction the marriage...
No, I didn’t mean
to give that impression at all.
I didn’t sanction it.
I tried to talk him out of it before.
But, Lloyd, darling,
you did act as his witness.
Well, as long as
it was gonna be inevitable,
I thought I might as well
try to make it pleasant.
Don’t you see the position
that puts me in?
Since I’m the area commander here...
You didn’t do anything to encourage
this marriage, sir. I did all this on my own.
What do you mean?
On your own, Lloyd, dear?
Everything you do reflects on the general.
After all, he is Eileen’s father.
This places me
in a position of incompetence
when it comes to doing anything
to help my own men.
Let’s stop beating around the bush.
What’s wrong between you and Eileen?
You haven’t been to see her
for several days.
Well... you talked about
being embarrassed, sir, before.
I’m embarrassed too.
- What about?
- About my whole situation here.
I’m a pilot, sir. I was doing a job in Korea.
An unfinished job.
I’m pulled off that job and sent here
and plonked down at a desk
at this inter-service whatever it is.
As far as I can see,
there’s absolutely nothing to do.
All so’s I can be with Eileen.
There’s nothing dishonest about it.
That is, if you plan to get married.
- I think I know how Lloyd feels.
- Do you plan to get married or not?
- Really, dear.
- I’m her mother. I want to know.
Well, Mrs. Webster, as of the moment,
Eileen isn’t too sure about it and I...
We know, Lloyd, dear. There’s evidently
been some slight strain between you two,
but don’t let it become too important.
This is Sunday night. Why don’t you
call her up later and ask her out to dinner?
Well...
Mother, I found the dearest little shop...
- Hi, Lloyd.
- Hello, Eileen.
Lloyd just came in to see you.
Oh?
Listen...
I thought... It’s Sunday night
and I thought maybe
you and I can go out and catch a movie
or something, if you feel like it.
I’m sorry, Lloyd. I’m having dinner
with some friends tonight.
Well, what about tomorrow?
That’s booked too, I’m afraid.
Well, it looks as though
I’m holding pretty tough cards.
What about next week?
Of course, Lloyd. Call me.
OK.
Mrs. Webster, General.
- Goodbye, Lloyd.
- Goodbye, Eileen.
Goodbye, Lloyd.
Eileen, why did you tell him
you were busy tonight?
Because I don’t want to see Lloyd Gruver
when you ask him to see me.
Besides, I do have a date with that young
lieutenant and his wife from Fort Bragg.
A whole bunch of us.
I hope you don’t lose my man for me.
Give me a martini, will you?
No, make it a lemonade.
No, give me a scotch and soda.
- Scotch and soda.
- Scotch and soda, sir.
There’s such a thing as insolence
through manner, you know.
I hate to admit it,
but I guess that’s what I said.
I thought it sounded kinda strange coming
from a guy who shot down nine MiGs.
That’s a kind of reflex action.
I’m a West Point man, you know.
I guess it sneaks out sometimes.
So listen, Captain, what does a fella
do round here after the sun goes down?
Why? You on the loose?
Halfway.
Bring him another.
What part of the south are you from?
Almost any old place
that’s got an army post on it.
I was all set to take the exams
for West Point
and there was a teacher there who
made me take a part in the school play.
They were doing one of
those Hungarian things by Molnár.
You never did hear a Hungarian play
played in a southern accent, did you?
- No, I’m afraid I missed that.
- That’s a shame. I was awful good in it.
Anyhow, I suddenly
didn’t wanna go to West Point
and didn’t wanna have
anything to do with it.
My mother come up to school and...
She said “We expected you to go to
the Point like your father and his father.”
And I told her, I said I had an idea
about a whole different way of life.
What’d she say to that?
She said something like...
if I ever once had that idea,
I shouldn’t let anything stop me.
And she couldn’t come right out
and say “Don’t go to the Point”,
but I knew what she meant.
Then my father flew up from Texas and...
He put you straight, huh?
He just looked at me and said “If you don’t
wanna go to the Point, don’t go.”
”The unhappiest men I know
are those who...
were forced into something
they got no inaptitude for.”
How did he force you to go to the Point?
That’s what I’m telling you.
He didn’t force me.
We just had a little talk and he flew
back to Texas and I went on to the Point.
I see.
Well, I’ll tell you something though, Mike,
I never once had any regrets
about going to the Point.
Except, just lately, I’ve had
some old feeling come back on me.
I don’t know if I wanna go on
in the air force and buck for a star,
get married into the Webster family
and get swallowed up by all that.
I think maybe my old lady was right.
Well, what does it all mean?
The eternal struggle, sex,
New York Yankees.
All right. Quit now. Come on.
- Ain’t that a nice-looking bridge?
- That’s the Bitchi-Bashi.
- Say what?
- The Bitchi-Bashi.
Bashï’s Japanese for bridge. We call
this particular one the Bitchi-Bashi
because there’s so much
lovely stuff that goes over it.
Did you say stuff?
Brother, I said stuff.
Would you care to tell me
what we’re standing in the bushes for?
- Can’t touch it.
- Why not?
These girls that go over there
are the Matsubayashi girls.
They just cross over there on the way
to the theatre from those dormitories.
" That’s right.
Somebody told me about them.
Hey, boy, is there anything
going over there now?
" Hey, come on.
The goods are on display.
Wait for me, buddy.
There’s Fumiko-san,
the one you saw me with.
- Yeah, little one in pink.
- Yeah, that’s the one.
Are you goin’ over to say hello?
In public? A Matsubayashi girl?
Are you nuts?
- You’d take her to the officers’ club.
- That’s for Americans.
Thought I could sneak her in
without her being recognized.
- " What happens if they catch her?
- " Immediate dismissal.
- " No fooling?
- " Yeah.
No Matsubayashi girl is allowed
to have dates of any kind.
You were dating her.
Well, I’m different.
Get outta here.
Like I told President Truman “You was
wrong when you sold the marines short.”
See, I hate to be stuffy about this, but
you air-force men wouldn’t understand.
The marines have got "l’amour," and these
girls, they got fame, wealth, bright lights.
- But they ain’t got "l’amour."
- You got "l’amour."
- What’s going on now?
- Hana-ogi’s coming.
- Who?
- Hana-ogi. She’s the top. Number one.
Come on, let’s go.
How come she’s dressed like that?
Tall ones play men’s parts mostly.
- They play women’s parts too.
- How do you do?
What do you say let’s see the show?
Well, come on, Ace.
- Do you follow the plot?
- Yeah, nothing wrong with the plot.
Are you sure they come back this way?
Just keep yourself in check, son.
Am I nuts
or is she the greatest thing I ever saw?
Whatever you’re thinking, forget it.
You ain’t going anyplace.
Yeah? How’s this for introduction?
She comes along and I just kinda
walk on by and slip my arm around her.
- What do you think of that?
- I think we’d better go.
- Major.
- Hey, Kelly, how are you?
- How’s everything?
- Saw you at the show.
I want you to meet Captain Bailey.
This is Airman Kelly.
- Nice to meet you.
- How do you do, sir?
- How you been, boy?
- Fine.
- Here’s Katsumi.
- Hello there, Katsumi.
- Say something, kid.
- It is fine to see you among us tonight.
She’s speaking better English
than you are, boy.
She’s been taking English lessons
and I’ve been studying a little Japanese.
Let’s hear you go.
I hope he can get rid of it, don’t you?
It means “My feet are cold”.
She always laughs when I say that.
How you been?
How you gettin’ along down there?
Just fine, Major. We got
a wonderful house down by the canal.
Didn’t you tell me Katsumi
knows those Matsubayashi girls?
Sure, she’s a real fan.
I want you to do something for me.
I am trying in the worst way
to meet this Hana-ogi.
And I want you to ask her if she won’t,
you know, kinda introduce me.
She says the rules are very strict
but she’ll ask her.
- She will ask her?
- " Oh, yeah.
Cos I said to Truman
when he came over to the house,
”Harry, don’t ever sell the air force short.”
All right, boy.
Now you gonna see something.
Here comes Fumiko-san.
- Here comes Hana-ogi.
- I know it.
- You ain’t gonna let me down? Go on.
- It’s all right, Major.
How d’you do, Miss Ogi?
You think you made the grade, Ace?
She gave me a nice little look there.
She sure did.
She says that Hana-ogi
will not speak to an American.
Why not?
We shot her brother
and killed her father with our bombs.
I didn’t do it.
Sure you did, Ace. We all did.
Come on.
Come on, Ace.
If they’re so strict with you, how come
you go out with Mike and fool around?
It is very bad of me.
But I cannot help myself.
He’s so tall.
He’s a big boy, all right.
There’s no fooling about that.
But, listen, what I really wanna know is
does this Hana-ogi ever go out on dates,
like you and Mike?
No. She’s number one girl.
Must be special careful.
Well, I want you to do me a favor.
Will you do it? When you go back
to the dormitory tonight,
I want you to tell Hana-ogi that
Major Gruver would like to meet her and...
Wait. Now, wait.
I just wanna talk to her for a little while.
- Will you do that for me?
- Never happen.
Hana-ogi-san never speak men.
And with American never happen.
Well, honey, I am here to tell you
that it’s going to happen.
Pardon me, Miss Ogi.
I wonder if I could have your autograph?
Thank you very much.
How d’you do, Miss Ogi?
Hi, Major. I’ve been looking for you.
Hello, Mr. Kelly.
The wife says to be at the house tonight.
No, I tell you, boy, I have an engagement
this evening with a friend of mine.
Be there, bub. Hana-ogi’s coming. Sir.
- Kelly...
- Be there early.
Kelly.
- Hello.
- " Hello!
You know where Joe Kelly lives?
Over there? You show me, will you?
How do?
- Hi, Ace.
- Kelly, is that you?
- How are you?
- How are you, Ace?
- Nice to see you. Come in the house.
- Let me just take a check here.
- Did she come yet?
- No.
Katsumi.
- OK. What she say?
- Don’t ask me.
Off with the shoes. You don’t
wear shoes in a Japanese house.
Coming off. What about the pants?
- The room on your right.
- Here?
That’s it.
Watch your head, Ace. This is it.
This is all right, boy.
This is cute. This is nice.
Sit down over here, Ace. That’s
the place of honor in a Japanese house.
What’s this thing?
- This is an armrest.
- Armrest?
Be even better
when the rest of the chair gets here.
Hi, Katsumi, darling. How are you?
Yeah.
It is very nice to have you... among us.
It’s very nice to be among you too.
I brought a couple of things
you can stick round the house.
Yeah. Flowers.
You’ve made her very happy, Ace.
Are we gonna eat this or wear it?
This is a little towel that they serve
before a meal or a drink.
- A little refresher for your hands and face.
- That’s a good idea.
Wash ‘em off. OK, clean everywhere.
Do I pass, teacher?
Just dump it in the basket.
Yes, sir.
What’s this, an eye cup?
We got to wash our eyes out too?
No, that’s a cup for sake.
That’s a wine made out of rice.
- Rice? No fooling.
- No fooling.
- I’ll try it.
- Taste it. You’ll see.
- Feels warm.
- We heat it up before we serve it.
Katsumi, here’s to your house.
And, Kelly, very best to you.
- That’s all right, boy. Not bad.
- I told you. It’s wonderful.
- You not gonna have anything?
- I was just gonna say.
There’s kind of a polite thing you do.
You take the cup, you swish it around
in the water and pour some sake for her.
- OK.
- That’s right.
- It means “a little bit”.
- All righty.
Hold on now. Wait. OK.
See? Didn’t hurt.
She’s gonna get me
under the table in five minutes.
She’ll keep pouring all night.
Katsumi, I pour for Gruver-san now.
You excuse me? I finish cooking.
You go ahead, darling.
Go right ahead. Go right ahead.
A present. Whisky.
Whisky?
Listen, boy, she’s just as cute as a bug.
You ain’t gonna lose with her.
See what I mean, Ace?
I’m the happiest guy in the world.
- You wanna see the rest of the house?
- Yeah.
I’ll show you round.
This is the garden. Katsumi,
I’m showing him around the house.
The bathroom is back there. We got extra
rooms here. Would you like to see ‘em?
Yeah.
What you got here, boy?
Oh, lord!
We haven’t done anything with these yet
but maybe someday, if we expand.
It’s really working out for you, isn’t it?
Everything’s perfect, except for
that rat of a colonel I’m assigned to.
You wouldn’t be talking about Crawford?
That’s the guy. He rides every guy
that’s married to a Japanese girl.
Extra duty, everything.
He’s a rough cob, no getting around that.
So what do I care? I come home to my girl
and I forget it. Let’s go.
Wait. I forgot to ask you.
Does this Hana-ogi speak any English?
Those girls sing in a lot of languages.
I guess she’ll be able
to catch your drift, Ace.
You nasty boy, you. Wait a minute.
I just got to take a look at my grass now.
Are we gonna be, all four of us
gonna be together all evening long?
Take it easy, Ace.
You’re gonna blow a fuse.
Well...
Might be.
- Your lumber’s wrong.
- Watch your head, Ace.
Katsumi, you ready?
In here? You gonna have to change...
Kelly.
Hana-ogi-san.
This is a great day for our house.
Major Gruver-san.
How do you do, Miss Ogi?
- Where you going?
- I gotta help Katsumi with the...
It looks as though everybody’s ran off
and left us alone here.
Certainly was nice of you
to come over here this evening, Miss Ogi.
I was just tickled to death
when they told me you were coming over.
I’ll just sit down here.
Well, Miss Ogi.
Let me fix you a little drink.
No, not... Well, OK.
Here’s to you.
It’s good. Don’t tell me. I know you’ve got
to slosh this around in here a little bit
and get the dribble off
and give it right back to you.
Now you take that.
All right.
I was surprised to find
that they make that stuff out of rice.
We have rice back home in America.
We just make rice pudding out of it.
We don’t drink it.
This is the first liquid rice I’ve ran into.
You know, did...
Did anyone ever tell you, Miss Ogi,
that you’re a fine-looking woman?
I mean, really fine.
You’re even better looking offstage
than you are on. That’s the truth.
You get up there and sing,
dance, act, everything.
You’re all-round great.
I wonder where Kelly and Katsumi...
I’m getting kinda hungry again.
Look, Miss Ogi...
I’m not up to Japanese ways of doing
things. Maybe I’m saying the wrong thing.
Maybe my American manners
are embarrassing.
But I figured,
as you came over here tonight,
maybe you were interested
a little bit in meeting me too.
Maybe I’m wrong, but if I’m wrong, then
you got to tell me where we go from here.
Cos I don’t know what to say.
I’m runnin’ out of things to say.
My father was killed by American bomb
dropped on my country.
You have been my enemy.
I have hated Americans.
I have thought they are savages.
There has been nothing
but vengeance in my heart.
Miss Ogi, there were an awful lot
of Americans that were killed too.
I think it would be best
if we forgot about that.
You have been watching me at the bridge.
Watching me dance.
Watching me
as I go back to the dormitory.
But I have been watching you too.
And you have not looked like a savage.
And when Katsumi-san told me
how gently you kissed her
the day she became a bride,
how tenderly you kissed
my sweet little friend,
I realized the hate was of my own making.
That is why I came
to ask you to forgive me
for what I have been feeling.
Gruver-san, will you forgive me?
You make me feel
like an awful fool, Miss Ogi.
I really feel that
I oughta ask you to forgive me
for some of the things that...
I’ve been thinking.
I come from the north of Japan
and my father was a farmer.
There were nine children.
And we were very poor.
There are too many people
in my crowded country.
I took the examination at Matsubayashi
and now I am first dancer of all.
When I’m too old to dance,
I will become head teacher.
My life is planned.
I am dedicated to Matsubayashi,
as you are dedicated
to American military life.
I have never been in love...
but I have dreamed and thought about it...
and waited.
The danger that lies ahead of us,
we must face now.
The danger of discovery for both of us.
The danger of weakness when it is over.
I will never fall in love again.
But I will love you, if that is your desire.
How do you do?
- Miss Webster.
- Hello.
- Mr. Nakamura, how nice of you to come.
- It is a great pleasure.
And may I say that you look
especially beautiful today.
I haven’t been
to this month’s kabuki programme.
I know. You see, I have been waiting.
- Eileen.
- Mother, you remember Mr. Nakamura.
- How do you do, Mrs. Webster?
- Yes, of course.
This party isn’t given especially for you.
You’ve got to circulate around
and cement Japanese-American relations.
That’s exactly what
Mr. Nakamura and I are doing.
Nakamura-san, my little girl wants
your autograph. She admires you so.
- Of course. Will you please excuse me?
- Yes, of course.
Has Lloyd come yet?
How many weeks
are you gonna keep on pretending?
- Lloyd is not coming.
- I’m absolutely furious at him.
How can he ignore the general’s
invitation? I had it delivered to his office.
I’m stuck with that Farrington woman.
Can you help me out?
Uh-oh. There’s Crawford. Whenever
he shows up, there’s always something.
Can I speak to you alone
for a minute, General?
Major, do you have that list with you?
I want to see if the Williams have come.
Yes, they have.
Waiter. Could you leave?
The reason I took this up with you
is because it concerns Major Gruver.
We think he’s hooked
onto a Japanese dame.
I’m sorry, but this thing’s
gotten me all riled up.
Do you realize what it’ll mean
to the enlisted men
if they find out that their big hero,
Ace Gruver, is out with...
I’ve known Major Gruver all his life.
I’m a close friend of his father’s.
- I assure you, you must be wrong.
- He was seen going into that house.
My men have been watching
a troublemaker named Kelly.
- He’s shacked up with another native...
- Kelly’s married to a Japanese girl.
Major Gruver was the best man. It seems
quite natural to me that he’d visit them.
- How am I gonna handle the situation?
- Don’t handle it.
I trust Major Gruver implicitly.
Is it all right with you if I post an order
to keep these officers from being seen
with indigenous personnel?
If they are seen,
there’s something we can do.
All right.
Lloyd.
No one saw you come?
No, there’s no military personnel
around here. Except me.
- We must go to the tea ceremony.
- Yeah, I know.
Good afternoon.
All this getting up and down like to kill me.
He makes such a production
of everything.
The pleasure does not lie in the end itself.
It’s the pleasurable steps to that end.
I see.
- That you, Ace?
- Yeah, Kelly.
- Come on in here.
- I can’t right now.
He’d be surprised you come in this way.
He’d faint.
Just a little lower, Katsumi.
You always seem to be a little above it.
Yeah, that’s it. Yeah, yeah.
Kelly-san, now you get in tub?
OK, all right.
- Is Hana-ogi coming over tonight?
- Yeah, if she can get away.
We gonna cook up some fine St Louis
goulash with a little Memphis greens.
What are you doing tonight after dinner
when Hana-ogi goes back to the theatre?
" Nothing.
How about playing poker
with Katsumi and me?
" I’d be delighted
to take your money, and your pants.
This is the life, ain’t it, Ace?
There you are.
How d’you do?
I got one word for you.
- What is that?
- Food.
# Sayonara
# Japanese goodbye
# Whisper “Sayonara”
# Lover, don’t you cry
# No more we stop to see
# Pretty cherry blossom
# No more we ‘neath the tree
# Looking at the sky
# Sayonara
# Goodbye
That’s the cutest thing I ever saw, honey.
I must go.
Ooh! Good eatin’.
Bye-bye.
Are you going back
to the officers’ quarters tonight?
No, I think I’m gonna just
fool around here.
What will you do all evening?
What am I gonna do?
I’m gonna get some beer, pretzels, girls.
I’m gonna have a little fun for a change.
Good. I don’t like you to be lonely.
Take care.
Come on in, Katsumi.
I’m sorry, Lloyd.
I had to come. It’s important.
Hello, Eileen.
How are you?
Sit down, will you?
I’ll take this stuff out the way.
I was just gettin’ a little...
Sit down here.
How are you?
- They’re after you, Lloyd.
- Who’s after me?
There’s a colonel. His name’s Crawford.
Oh, yeah.
I know him.
He’s the one that’s riding Kelly.
This is Kelly’s house.
Yes, I know.
- You want to hear this, don’t you, Lloyd?
- Yeah, sure. Course I do.
I overheard Colonel Crawford say
that he’s been having this house watched,
hoping to catch Kelly
at something irregular, I suppose.
Anyhow, that’s how I knew where it was.
Well, then they... they’ve seen me
coming in and out of here.
Yes.
I just felt that I had to tell you...
Eileen...
There’s something that I feel that...
I must go, Lloyd. I just wanted to warn you
to be particularly careful about...
About what, honey?
About sticking strictly
to military regulations.
Lloyd, they’ll do anything
to hang something on you,
to keep you in line.
After all, you’re the air force’s
pin-up boy, you know.
Colonel Crawford sounded
as if he was after blood.
- More than anything I could think of...
- I must go now, Lloyd. Good luck.
Wait a minute. Let me help you.
Eileen, I know...
Lloyd, you’ve really thought seriously
about what you’re doing, haven’t you?
Yes, I...
I think I have.
I hope so.
You’ve a brilliant record in the air force.
People depend upon you.
Before you throw all that you’ve worked
for away, be sure. Please be sure.
Eileen, I don’t think if I had a million years
that I could tell you how all this happened.
I’d better go before I lose all my charm.
Do you like this old curious play?
Yeah, I’m beginning to get a kick out of it.
- See the rope between the rocks?
- Yeah.
That is a Shinto sign
showing they are married.
- What, the rocks?
- Yes.
They’ve been together so long, our people
thought it was time they got married.
- They look well together, don’t you think?
- Yeah. Make a handsome little couple.
Do you like my country?
Yeah, was all these funny things here
before when I came through Japan?
Yes.
- Well, hello.
- Hello there, double-double ugly.
To what do we owe
the honor of this visit?
Laundry. Gonna put down the dirties
and pick up the cleans.
I hope you know what you’re doing.
This came in.
Thought you might like to see it.
”This is a routine reminder of
the recent orders issued by Camp Kobe:”
”Any public display of affection
for a Japanese national
by a member of this command
is forbidden.”
”Officers should not even
appear on public streets
accompanied by indigenous
female personnel.”
- Hooray for Christmas.
- This is serious. Everybody got one.
Listen, fool, Hana-ogi and I
are just as careful as we can be.
We never go anyplace where we’re gonna
be seen by anybody that matters.
We don’t even walk down the same street.
We just go out in the country
and fool around.
You’ve never been to the country
around here, have you?
Awful pretty country round here. I mean it.
You know what I saw yesterday?
I saw two rocks that just got married.
- You what?
- I saw two rocks that got married.
- And they looked very happy together too.
- I’ll bet they did.
They did. If you were gonna be smart,
I’ll tell you what you’d do.
You’d get your shoes shined
and go out tonight,
cos tonight is gonna be Tanabata.
OK, what’s Tanabata?
You’re gonna sit there and tell me
you don’t know what Tanabata is?
Yeah.
My word, boy. I’m ashamed of you.
I thought everybody knew
what Tanabata was.
Tanabata is the night of love.
You told me all about it one time.
You were telling me about Harry Truman
and New York Yankees and sex,
and New York Yankees
and Harry Truman and sex.
What have I done
to deserve such happiness?
I have seen this night of Tanabata
come and go many times,
but never before
have I understood what it meant.
Tanabata.
My heart is so full of love for you.
- Miss Webster?
- Yes?
Nakamura-san get your note.
Here is reply.
He wishes if you will have dinner
with him and his guests.
Thank you very much.
They have a rather pleasant
garden here, Miss Webster.
- Would you like to see it?
- Yes, I think I would.
How beautiful.
What are you really afraid of,
Miss Webster?
You don’t think it would enter Major
Gruver’s mind to marry a Japanese girl?
I don’t know.
Then permit me to reassure you.
I think Major Gruver is brave,
but not brave enough to face the censure
that would result from such a marriage.
As for our famous, honored Hana-ogi,
there are many Japanese -
most of them, in fact -
who look upon marriage to an Occidental
with as much distaste
as your people do to one of us.
I do not feel that way,
but then I have had the privilege
of traveling in your country
and knowing some great people there.
And I am especially conscious
at this moment
that beauty is not confined
to any one race.
Do not turn away, Miss Webster.
I am not necessarily making love to you.
I am only stating a very obvious fact.
May I see you again, Miss Webster,
and acquaint you with more Japan?
Of course.
I need to know more, much more,
about everything.
There she is.
Hello, honey.
Are you tired?
No, I just been lying here
thinking about myself.
I can’t believe I’m really here.
It’s hard to believe
me being the same Lloyd Gruver
that came over from Korea
just a little bit ago.
I’ve been thinking
that all my life I’ve been so busy...
snapping to and giving orders
and taking orders
and being a general’s son
and doing the job and all that,
I just never took time
to sit right down and...
you know, think about
what my reason for living is.
And I’ve been spending
some afternoons here just...
bein’ peaceful and easy and thinking.
And I believe for the first time I...
I’m just beginning to understand
what it’s all about,
what I really am and what I really want.
It’s a nice feeling.
Come on in.
Ace, excuse me. I hate to bother you.
- I just got the news.
- You got what news?
- I’m gettin’ shipped back.
- You’re being shipped back where?
Stateside. I’ve been reassigned
to a new duty station.
Well...
- Did you tell Katsumi yet?
- No.
Don’t tell her.
Maybe we can work something out.
What reason did they give you for it?
No reason. But I know what it is.
Every guy on that list
is married to a Japanese girl.
I’m sorry, Major.
There’s nothing you can do.
We’re sending Kelly to the States
Thursday, and that’s that.
What about his wife, Colonel?
She stays here.
He knew he couldn’t take her back
with him when he married her.
- Didn’t you?
- That’s right.
You’d be busting up his home, then.
I’m not busting up anything.
Though I admit Kelly’s been
a pain in my side for quite a while now.
Could you tell me why he didn’t have
the privilege of extending his tour of duty?
Don’t ask me, Major. There are lots
of reasons for these things.
Anyway, it is an order
and there’s nothing you can do about it,
even if you are a four-star general’s son.
Yeah, well...
Would it make any difference if I told you
my wife’s gonna have a baby?
That’s tough, I admit.
Colonel, under these circumstances,
don’t you think that you’d be able to
postpone this for a little while?
Maybe I could be transferred
back to Korea.
No, you’re going home.
All the boys on this list are going home.
- Where is your home?
- That house by the canal.
- I mean your real home.
Yeah, all right.
I’ve taken all the insubordination
from you I intend to.
Now, you listen to me, wise guy.
That house by the canal
is off limits from now on.
Whole street’s off limits.
Do you want a court martial?
Does that mean I could stay in Japan?
You’re shipping outta here on Thursday.
And don’t you try to help him.
Remember that house by the canal
is off limits to all personnel.
Would you tell me just exactly
what you mean by that last remark?
That’s all I’m prepared
to say at the minute.
Except you watch your step.
I don’t know what else to tell you,
General. I’ve known this boy a long time.
If he has to go back without Katsumi,
he’s gonna be in trouble.
That’s about it. That’s it.
- What about his wife?
- I don’t know.
And the baby?
So the army lets them get married and
then forces them to desert their wives.
That’s not fair, Eileen.
A boy away from home
for the first time, lonesome,
often falls in love
with the first girl he touches,
in most cases with a girl from the streets.
It’s up to the service in some measure
to be fathers and mothers to these boys
and try to head off these marriages.
But after they’re married,
why send them home?
He’s being transferred to a new
duty station, along with many others.
Don’t ask me the reasons for changes
of duty. There are thousands of them.
But Lloyd said most of the men on this list
are married to Japanese girls.
- That can’t be just a coincidence.
- Why not? It could easily be.
Frankly, with some of these men,
I think they might welcome the transfer.
Why’s that, sir?
There have been unfortunate aftermaths
to many of these marriages.
Recriminations, regrets.
A boy gets married impulsively, then feels
caught, doesn’t know how to get out of it.
Change of duty gives them both
a chance to think it over, to cool off.
I don’t mean to imply that’s the reason
these men are being transferred but...
well, the whole thing’s a messy business.
General Webster, there is no regret
in the case of Kelly and Katsumi.
You can have my word on that.
Lloyd, three officers came to me today
with identical requests for their men.
It’s not our policy to interfere with
decisions made by commanding officers.
The basic structure of the military service
would collapse if we did things like that.
Your father would understand that,
even if you don’t.
You’re asking me to make an exception of
Kelly when I’ve refused these other men?
I am gonna ask you to do that, sir.
You made an exception of me
when you brought me from Korea.
I’m afraid it’s a hopeless situation, Lloyd.
Well...
That’s the end of Joe Kelly.
You told me yourself that Kelly’s
past record was against him.
I couldn’t even use that.
Why does this mean
so much to you, Lloyd?
Kelly’s from my outfit, Mrs. Webster,
I was his best man,
and I’m planning to marry
a Japanese girl myself.
Come into the other room, Eileen. This is
something for your father to handle.
No, Mrs. Webster. I don’t think
this is anything for anybody to handle.
I’m sorry, Eileen.
Mrs. Webster. Good afternoon.
I don’t think I’ll ever love anyone again
as much as I love Lloyd.
But I’ll tell you something
that’s rather ironic.
I once asked Lloyd
if he ever felt like grabbing me
and hauling me off to a shack somewhere.
That’s just what he’s done, isn’t it?
Only it’s with somebody else.
Don’t go out, Eileen. Stay and talk.
I’m sorry, Mother. There’s only one
person I’d like to talk to at the moment.
And, oddly enough, he’s Japanese.
- Ace, I’ve been waiting for you.
- Kelly, listen.
I just came from General Webster’s
house. There’s a whole big mess there.
- No good, huh?
- No. He didn’t go for it.
Matter of fact, I think
I even messed it up a little.
That figures.
Did you tell Katsumi yet?
I’m chickening out fast.
Besides, she’s got her heart set
on something she planned for us tonight.
Wants us to take the train over to Osaka
and meet the girls at the puppet show.
Why spoil it?
Maybe I’ll tell her late tonight
when we’re alone.
Listen, Kelly, don’t give up on it.
I think there’s gonna be a way out of it.
You think so? I don’t.
- I’ll see you, Ace.
- Kelly-san.
Tell Katsumi we’ll be there with bells.
Were you able to help?
- No.
- How terrible.
I know it’s hard, honey,
but it’s not gonna last long.
The army’s gotta change that law
next year, or the next one.
It just has to be. I’m sure of it.
And, in fact, I’m so sure of it
that I went downtown today
and I signed some papers here that mean
that you and I are gonna get married.
- What’s the matter?
- We never spoke of marriage.
I know we didn’t, darling.
I know we didn’t.
I’ve been going round and round with that
every day for a long time.
I didn’t feel I could
speak about it until now.
But now I can.
Now, of course, I won’t be able
to take you back to America,
but they’re bound to change
that ridiculous law soon.
Until then I’m gonna stay here with you.
I’m not stuck in the air force. I can resign.
Course, I’m not trained to do
anything else, but I’d find something.
We never spoke of marriage.
I know we didn’t, darling,
but we’re speaking of it now.
Do you remember
the first night we talked?
I said there would be danger
of weakness when it is over.
Over? What are you talking about?
I’m tempted. With you, I could become
and woman and a mother,
and I could love you.
That’s right.
Do you think I haven’t thought about it?
Do you think I want to become a lonely
old woman who teaches dancing,
now that I have known you?
But it is no good.
- You must know it too.
- No. I don’t know anything of the kind.
The way you talk about
leaving the air force,
finding some pitiful way of earning living,
just to be here with your Japanese wife.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
I think we’re too far into this thing
to be talking like that.
Matsubayashi has been kind to me, Lloyd.
- I am obligated to them.
- No, you ain’t. No, no.
You are obligated to me.
They are my life.
I would bring shame to them, disgrace.
Lloyd, you know what I mean.
Yeah, I think I’m beginning
to know what you mean.
I think you mean you simply don’t
love me enough to go on through with it.
That’s what you mean, don’t you? Why
don’t you just come on out and say it?
It is not what I mean.
I’m leaving for Tokyo in six days.
Matsubayashi are sending me.
You what?
With another troupe.
They have found out about us.
Any other girl they would have dismissed,
but because they like me,
because they feel I am important to them,
they are being lenient.
Well, I’m not gonna be lenient with you.
I want you to tell me why Matsubayashi
means more to you than I do.
Lloyd, there is something about myself
I have not told you.
I have no right to marry anyone.
My father was very poor.
To save his other children,
he was forced to sell one of his daughters.
The man from
the houses of Yoshiwara came to him.
Because I was the oldest,
he agreed I should go with him.
Your father sold you?
Yes, but I was saved from starting this life
by my best friend, Fumiko-san.
Her father paid money to free me.
Then she brought me to Matsubayashi.
There I not only earned my living,
I brought honor back to my family.
Matsubayashi has been kind to me.
They have trusted me.
I cannot leave them.
I cannot marry anyone.
Don’t you understand?
I don’t know.
I don’t know what to think.
I’ll kill you! You ever do anything like this
and I’ll kill you, you understand?
- Wait a minute. Just take it easy, now.
- Ace, look at this.
- It fell out of her bag.
- What is it?
She was gonna have it done tomorrow,
by that quack doctor down by the docks.
For eight bucks he slashes her eyelids
and sews ‘em back up again.
Lots of these stupid little jerks
have it done. She was gonna surprise me.
Then... then I have good eyes,
I fool everybody.
I look American, like Joe.
Hana-ogi, will you tell that stupid dame
I love her the way she is?
I don’t want her changed. Will you tell her
I love her mouth and her nose
and her ears and her eyes
just the way they are?
Tell her if she ever does
anything like that, I’ll...
I want him be proud of me.
I’m sorry.
If you want him to be proud of you,
quit this stuff.
You’re making him very unhappy.
Tell him you’re not gonna do it any more.
- Tell him that.
- Joe.
I’m so sorry.
We’re gonna forget about that.
I thought we were gonna have a fish fry,
have some fun and dancing and yelling.
And what do I find?
So what’s gonna happen to us?
- Puppet show.
- We had a surprise.
- You like?
- Sure I do. I’ve been looking forward to it.
- Everybody tonight?
- Yeah.
We will be late.
Look.
The lover is leaving the city.
Walk to the wood.
Lloyd, don’t think of anything now.
Watch the play.
It’s a tender story.
When gong sound, it is dawn,
and then she will bind her body.
Bind her body?
So that she will not fall in an ugly position
of dishonor when she dies.
- When she dies?
- Yes.
It is custom for lovers to die together
when they can no longer face life.
It is so beautiful.
Beautiful? They’re gonna die, aren’t they?
They will live in another world
on a beautiful lake,
floating always together.
Like water lily.
Sure.
" Kelly-san! Kelly-san! Kelly-san!
Something about soldiers
going through the house.
- That’s the MPs, boy.
- What happened? What’s wrong?
- What happened?
- Get in the car.
- Please tell me.
- Go to Matsubayashi. I’ll tell you later.
Matsubayashi.
Hey, Ed, look.
Look at that.
- You’re Major Gruver, aren’t you?
- That’s right.
You’ll have to come with us.
General Webster’s orders.
What right do you have
to board up this house?
He won’t be needing it. He’s shipping out.
Joe!
Come on, Major.
You’ll hear from me, Kelly.
Come on, kid.
We’ll get in through the garden.
I got something to tell you.
You were seen in public with her tonight,
violating orders.
This has given me the right
to put you under arrest.
And for your own sake,
I think I better do it.
Well? Have you anything to say?
Just as soon as I’m out of this, I’m gonna
be married and have a house of my own.
I’m afraid not.
I’m sorry, Lloyd, but it’s all settled.
The supervisor of the Matsubayashi
came to see me tonight.
The girl goes to Tokyo and you fly to
Randolph Field the day after tomorrow.
Here are your orders.
Until that time, you’re under house arrest.
You’re not to leave your quarters
until further notice.
I’m doing this because I feel
you’re not responsible at the moment.
After all, I’ve known your father for years.
Well, that’s all.
Mike.
- Did you see her?
- I couldn’t get near the place.
They’ve really clamped down.
I couldn’t even see Fumiko-san.
I’ve got to see her.
I’m being shipped out tomorrow.
- Major Gruver.
- What is it?
- Would you do something for us?
- What do you want?
- Airman Kelly’s disappeared.
- That’s impossible.
- I was with him just last night.
- We know.
A special plane came through and
Colonel Crawford told us to get him on it.
I took him to the airport at 12.50. When
the plane took off, Kelly wasn’t on it.
- We figured you might know where he is.
- His house has been boarded up.
We know.
Neighbors won’t talk to us.
We figure maybe they’re hiding him.
They’ll talk with you, Major.
Would you help us?
Would you give me one good reason
why I should?
We figured we’d give him a break.
We haven’t reported him yet.
If we get him on another plane, we might
not have to turn him in for desertion.
- Desertion?
- Yes, sir.
Well...
- I’ll go with you in a minute.
- Major.
The neighbors won’t talk
if they see an MP.
- I’ll go with him.
- Thank you, sir.
Kelly?
It’s Gruver out here.
I think he’s in there.
Kelly?
I’m goin’ on in.
Kelly? You in there?
Oh, my God!
Oh, my...
Oh...
I’ll call the police, Ace.
Oh, God!
" Sayonara, Kelly-san.
Sayonara, Katsumi-san.
Sayonara, my Lloyd-san.
" Go home! Go home!
Ace, there’s no police around.
We better get outta here.
Hey, look.
Doesn’t look too good, boy.
Come on, take it easy.
We’re gettin’ help, Ace.
- You OK, boy?
- I’m fine. You all right?
Yeah.
I’m gonna... I want you
to take care of everything, will you?
Yeah, I’ll get it.
I’ll see you later.
- Where’s Hana-ogi?
- Hana-ogi is not here.
- I know she’s here.
- She is on her way Tokyo.
- She wasn’t going till next week.
- She went today.
- I don’t believe you.
- Major Gruver! It’s forbidden to go in.
Hana-ogi?
Hana-ogi? Hana-ogi?
- Gruver-san!
- Where’s Hana-ogi?
- She’s gone.
- Where’s her room?
- Listen, where’s her room?
Come here.
Hana-ogi really gone, Major.
I don’t believe you.
Hana-ogi?
I give you my word.
You go now too, Major.
It’s over.
Leave me alone a minute, will you?
The hoodlums who attacked you
weren’t all your Japanese neighbors.
They were troublemakers
sent to your street
to create an incident specifically with you.
If you’re important to those who hate us,
don’t you see
how important you are to us?
Do you understand any of this, Lloyd?
I know how you feel.
It was...
It was dreadful about your friend Kelly
and... and his wife.
It must be hard to take.
And I... I hate to tell you something else,
because it’s almost too grotesque...
almost unforgivable
in your eyes, I imagine.
I got word today that there’s a law
being passed in a month or two
that will make it possible
for men like Kelly
to take their Japanese brides
back to the States.
- That can’t be true, General.
- Well, it happens to be true, Lloyd.
Listen, how do you get the guts
to come here and tell me that?
It takes time to get laws passed, Lloyd.
And a lot of people have died in this world
needlessly waiting for them.
It’s harder to take
when it hits you personally.
Lloyd...
You’re lost. You’re confused.
Don’t you think it’s time you got back
to the mainstream of your life?
Back to your roots,
what you were born for and raised for.
You’ll feel better about everything when
you get back home, back to your work.
I appreciate you coming over, General.
Take me to the airport, Mike.
That must be him.
- Hold it so we can get a picture, General.
- Where would you like me?
Smile, please.
- Bill, isn’t that Ace Gruver?
- Looks like him.
Sir.
Aren’t you Major Gruver? Ace Gruver?
- That’s right.
- We’re from the "Stars and Stripes."
- What are you doing in Tokyo?
- I’m just passing through, boys.
- Just seeing the sights, huh?
- That’s right. I’m in a hurry.
- Do you mind if I excuse myself? Sorry.
- You’re excused.
It’s Gruver! Gruver-san!
Lloyd-san.
Hello.
Hello, Hana-ogi.
I’m goin’ back to America on Friday,
and I probably won’t
get back in Japan again.
And before I go, there was just...
just one thing I wanted to know.
You remember one time you said to me...
that you could love me
and be a wife and a mother?
I remember.
You said that since you’d known me,
you’d been afraid of being
a lonely old woman teaching dancing.
Remember that?
I remember.
Did you mean that
when you said it, Hana-ogi?
I meant it. It is already happening.
Life has gone out of my work, out of me.
Lloyd, please go now.
This will only bring pain and trouble.
Hana-ogi, you and I
are gonna have more trouble
than we ever thought
of having in our whole lives
unless you are absolutely
honest with yourself.
Please, Lloyd,
can’t we talk about this later?
No. There’s isn’t gonna be any later.
There’s only gonna be right now.
Excuse me, mother. Excuse me.
I must return this robe.
I wanna know -
do you love me or don’t you?
Because if you don’t, then I’m gonna
have to find a way to live with it.
- And if you do...
- Please, Lloyd.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
I don’t want you to tell me
anything more or anything less
than you feel
in the very deepest part of you.
Because what you answer to me now
is gonna affect us for the rest of our lives.
Do you love me, Hana-ogi,
or don’t you love me?
I’m so frightened and confused.
I cannot think.
I cannot even understand your thinking.
I’m not thinking. For the first time
in my life I’m not thinking and I don’t care.
But we must do the right thing.
What are you talking about,
the right thing?
We been wasting two good lives
trying to do the right thing -
the right thing for Matsubayashi,
the right thing for my father,
the right thing for the military,
the right thing for Japanese tradition,
the right thing for the great white race.
- But we have duties and obligations.
- We do have duties and obligations.
The first obligation we have
is to love each other,
to become man and wife
and raise some clean, sweet children,
and give them the very best
that we know how.
And if we don’t meet that obligation,
we ain’t gonna be any good to anybody.
We live in different worlds,
come from different races.
Honey, I want you to be my wife.
But what would happen to our children?
What would they be?
They’d be half-Japanese, half-American.
They’d be half-yellow and half-white.
They’d be half you, they’d be half me.
That’s all they’re gonna be.
Hana-ogi, I want you
to come with me now.
I want you to come with me now
down to the American consulate.
Here in Tokyo. We’re gonna start
filling out those papers.
We’ve only got a few days to get
this whole thing done and out of the way.
Will you come?
I’m gonna wait for you outside.
Did I tell you they’d be here?
- Look at this crowd.
- Look who’s here. Our rivals.
You guys heard about it too?
No secrets. No secrets in this country.
Major, what a coincidence.
You got a story for us, sir?
No, as a matter of fact, I don’t.
- You’re not gonna try to deny it, are you?
- Deny what?
The story.
Why won’t you give us the story?
- You’re big news now, sir.
- I don’t know what you’re talking about.
Here’s Hana-ogi. Maybe she’ll talk.
Come on, Hana-ogi.
That’s not fair. What did you say?
It is very difficult for a Japanese woman
to speak in public.
I have never done so.
But perhaps now it is the time.
Major Gruver has asked me
to be his... his wife.
He knows there are many people in
this country who will be disturbed by this.
I know my people will be shocked too.
But I hope they will learn to understand
and someday approve.
We are not afraid,
because we know this is right.
I hope I can continue as a dancer
and I hope when I am old,
I will be able to teach children to dance.
My own children.
Major, the big brass are gonna
yell their heads off.
The Japanese aren’t gonna like it either.
Have you got anything to say to them, sir?
Yeah.
Tell ‘em we said “sayonara”.