You didn't really expect to get away
with a thing like that, did you?
Frankly, officer, I didn't.
Then why try it?
If you don't care about yourself,
think about other people.
Drivin' through traffic
at 50 miles an hour.
Traffic?
You...
Oh.
I'm sorry, officer.
Now, you keep it up and
this'll be the last New Year's
you'll ever see.
Unpleasant thought, isn't it?
Isn't it, though?
Okay, go ahead, but take it easy.
I don't wanna hand out any
tickets tonight unless I have to.
Thanks.
Oh, Mr. MacAllister.
A letter for you, and a happy New Year.
Happy New Year, Mr. MacAllister.
Something wrong, Mr. Boss?
No.
You going to spend New Year Eve alone?
Yeah.
You want Chang to stay,
maybe mix drink, keep you company?
No, just close the
door from the outside.
Chang do something wrong?
You wish him unhappy New Year?
All right.
Happy New Year, Chang.
- Good night.
- No hurry, it's all right.
Chinese New Year not for a long time yet.
Operator?
Police department.
Thank you.
Police department?
My name is George MacAllister.
I live at 150 West 59th.
I just killed...
I just killed a man.
You'll find his body
at Rossmore Apartments,
East 7th,
apartment 14.
What's that?
Yes.
Yeah, he's quite dead.
My dear George,
I should have known sooner
that the hate that you
bore your half-brother
must one day bring you to this point.
Crime and passion are a bad
mixture at best, George.
When the passion is hate,
nothing but evil and violence can result.
It was shortly after Dr.
Mitchell had pronounced
his death sentence on your brother Barry,
giving him only a little
more time to live,
a few months at the most, he said,
and sent him deeper into the seclusion
of that place he called home
and deeper into the dark mood
that seemed to find comfort
only in that unhappy organ music of his.
Your Aunt Margaret was there,
and Barry,
and I, Carlotta Duval.
Stop it, please, please!
Are you ill, Ms. Duval?
Don't you care for my music?
It's, it's your bedtime, that's all.
Why, it's just 8:30.
8:30?
Yes, it's 8:30 outside, but not here.
In this house, it's midnight all the time.
Aren't you being a
little dramatic, Ms. Duval?
Perhaps I am.
Sorry.
Barry's music relaxes him.
Relaxes him?
It's killing him.
Ms. Duval.
Barry, my poor boy.
So it is my music.
I'm sorry, Mr. MacAllister.
That's all right.
But why don't you like it?
I don't like it for
what it's doing to you.
Those depressing dirges you
call music are as ugly as,
as what you're waiting for.
The girl is insane.
No, no, I'm not.
But I will be if I stay here any longer.
Just a moment, Ms. Duval.
It seems you have an opinion of me.
I'd like to hear it.
Yes, yes, I have an opinion of you.
Barry, let her go.
Ms. Duval, you're exciting him.
I warn you.
His pulse is very firm,
and it'll take more than my opinion
to get through that blanket of self-pity
you've thrown around yourself.
Self-pity?
Isn't a dying man entitled even to that?
A dying man?
To be a dying man, you
must first be a living man.
You're not living.
You have already abandoned life.
I'm going to call Dr. Mitchell.
I'll save you the trouble.
I'll call Dr. Mitchell
and ask him to send another nurse tonight.
Hello?
Dr. Mitchell.
Ms. Duval speaking.
Dr. Mitchell, I'm quitting...
Hello, Uncle Joe.
Wrong?
Oh, no.
No, I think Ms. Duval
just wanted to report
that her patient is feeling
exceptionally well tonight.
Quitting?
No, I, I think she wanted
to quit giving me the
brown pills, the big ones.
Can you imagine, Ms. Duval?
He thought you were quitting.
No, Uncle Joe.
No, I think she's very happy here.
And as for myself,
I couldn't get along without her.
She's very happy here.
As for myself,
I couldn't get along without her.
Now do you like my music, Ms. Duval?
It's wonderful.
But why aren't you in bed?
I couldn't sleep.
Then I did upset you.
Yes.
Yes, you did.
I was thinking about you.
There's one thing I didn't
think about you, though.
Of course, I didn't know it then.
It was how lovely you would look
coming down a staircase wearing
just that.
But Mr. MacAllister,
you are not supposed to-
Not supposed to think about
fair ladies and romance, Ms. Duval?
That's exactly what I was thinking about.
Carlotta.
Yes, Mr. MacAllister?
I, uh, know I haven't much to offer you,
except companionship,
money, love.
It's not much to trade for the happiness
I know that you can give me
during whatever time is left.
Carlotta?
Yes?
Will you marry me?
You poor, poor man.
Now you'll never know I,
I would have married you if you
hadn't a penny to your name.
Kitten!
It worked, darling, it worked!
He went for it?
We'll be married Monday.
Great, where's the happy
event going to take place?
In his apartment here in New York?
No, he wants to be married
in the family chapel.
Oh, you're wonderful.
And I love you.
It's about time you said so.
Never doubt it.
It was my lucky day when I met Nurse Duval
at that French hospital.
Nurse Duval.
You know, you were the only
good thing that happened to me
in the whole war.
It was my lucky day, too.
Oh, it's good to be here.
If I could only stay forever.
Poor kitten,
you're tired, aren't you?
No, I'm not tired exactly,
at least not from the work.
It was a strain, darling.
It took such a long time,
I was about ready to propose to him.
Mm-mm, wouldn't have worked.
I know the guy.
I bet when the icy, impersonal Ms. Duval
finally let him have that burst of temper,
he fell off the organ bench.
Practically.
But I'm glad it's over.
I wasn't joking when I told him
I was going insane out there.
I wouldn't mind a wife
who's a little nuts,
as long as she has a few million dollars.
Come on.
This calls for a celebration.
Here, we'll bring to the
future Mrs. MacAllister
To the future which
Mrs. MacAllister, huh?
The Mrs. George MacAllister, of course.
Most certainly not the
wealthy widow MacAllister yet.
Don't, George.
What was that for?
Well, I don't know.
It's just that he doesn't seem so bad.
Well, you better take
another look at him.
But out of respect for your opinion,
I'll send the biggest wreath
I can find to his funeral.
Please don't, it's, it's bad enough
that our happiness depends on that.
Is it our fault that he's got a body
that doesn't wanna stay wrapped
around that penny-pinching,
shriveled up little
soul of his any longer?
No, no, of course not.
And don't be angry with me,
especially not just now,
but I have to leave.
I'm not angry, kitten.
But when am I gonna see you again?
It gets a little lonely up here.
I'll see you as soon as I can,
but see that you stay lonesome for me.
Don't go looking for new company.
Ah, kitten, you know your
Georgie better than that.
I certainly do know my Georgie.
I'm just teasing.
Hey, wait a minute.
Maybe I'm the one that should be worrying,
just a little?
No, darling.
With me, you're my love,
and Barry's my business.
Trust me.
I'll not mix the two.
Only dazedly do I recall
the next few days.
The hours became a solid mold of anxiety,
anxiety over my ability to go through
with what we had planned,
over the normal details attending
marriage to a MacAllister,
and then it was Monday,
the day of the wedding.
And I stood before a mirror dressed
as I had once hoped to be
dressed for another wedding.
All right?
Just as pretty as a picture.
There ain't no other word for it.
Oh, I'm glad.
Now, you'd better go and
help Mr. MacAllister.
Yessum, I sure will.
I'll do just that.
Something old, something new,
something borrowed, something blue.
Something borrowed.
I forgot.
Something borrowed?
You startled me.
Would this be suitable, do you think?
It's quite horrible.
Some might think it'd rather symbolic.
I'm tired of your
insinuations, Ms. MacAllister.
If you have anything to say,
then say it, and be done with it.
I have only one thing to say, Ms. Duval.
Don't marry my nephew.
Your motives are obvious.
I must ask you to leave my room.
I have no desire to remain longer.
After you have repeated
our conversation to Barry,
I imagine he will want
me to move elsewhere.
I'll not repeat it to him.
And you may stay in this
house for as long as you wish.
I'm not afraid of you, Ms. MacAllister.
That is a great mistake. Ms. Duval.
Come in.
Yes, Doctor.
What do you mean by that, "Yes, Doctor"?
Oh.
Quite a bit different from the uniform
I expected you to wear
when I sent you out here.
Haven't I seen Maggie, Ms.
MacAllister, wearing this?
She thought I should wear it.
Something borrowed.
Nasty looking thing.
Well, Ms. Duval, I expect you
know I didn't come up here
to inspect the bride's wedding gown.
I know why you came
up here, Dr. Mitchell.
Ms. MacAllister left no doubt in my mind
that my marriage to Barry
isn't meeting with general approval.
So?
I'll have to give you
the same answer I gave her.
Nothing is going to stop this wedding.
You don't have to be
antagonistic toward me, Carlotta.
I didn't come here to
tell you not to marry him.
I just wanted to tell you something about
this man you're getting.
You see, I've watched him
grow up in this world,
and now, I'm faced with the unhappy task
of supervising his departure from it.
No one can know how I feel about the job.
Thanks, George.
Nice of you to help.
And I thought it was nice of you
to ask me to your wedding.
Oh, but I really wanted you here.
See, I figured that, uh,
if you saw the happy,
eager look on my face,
contentment in my eyes,
might encourage even you to settle down.
Abandon hope, my dear brother.
I consider marriage settling up, not down.
Payment in full for
all the fun you've had.
Oh, then you don't approve
of my getting married?
Oh, now wait a minute.
Settling, I approve.
I just hate to think of your widow.
Practically a stranger getting
all that beautiful money.
Now, look, why don't you be a good guy
and put me back in your will?
Oh, no, no, I wouldn't
think of it, George.
Spoil our lovely relationship.
You see, you're the only relative I have
who isn't waiting for me
to join our ancestors.
Probably because you have
nothing to gain by it.
Uh, yeah, that's possible.
But I certainly would
like to be mentioned.
Oh, you're mentioned.
You get a dollar.
A dollar?
You could at least make a two.
Cab fare to the funeral.
You're making a mess out of that tie.
Let me fix it.
This girl you're marrying, she's
after your money of course.
She's gonna get it, whether
she's after it, or not.
But if you think that's
what she's marrying me for,
you don't know her.
That's right.
But I've known a lot of women in my life.
They're all alike.
"This girl's different, I tell you."
"Her smile when she gives it is"
"an instant of complete happiness."
"The touch of her hands
is a lifetime of pleasure."
"To make her my wife
will be the achievement"
"of all the beautiful
dreams I've ever known."
Oh, no.
Never felt that way about a woman, huh?
No.
And in all apologies for
your flowery description,
there is no such woman.
No?
No.
"My dear Barry, well,
it seems the bullet
"that got me in the leg
was only making a detour,
"and didn't have my name on it after all.
"I," let's see.
Oh, here it is.
Listen carefully.
"She's a nurse."
"This girl is different, I tell you."
"Her smile when she gives it is"
"an instant of complete happiness."
"The touch of her hands
is a lifetime of pleasure."
"To make her my wife
will be the achievement"
"of all the beautiful
dreams I've ever known."
Ever heard those words before, huh?
No.
"As ever, George."
George who?
You, Mr. MacAllister.
Oh, well.
I memorized them.
Thought they were so nice.
Whatever happened to her, George?
I don't know.
Guess she must be kicking
around Paris someplace.
It's too bad you lost track of her.
What was her name now?
I, uh, I don't know.
I don't remember.
Why didn't you marry her?
And what did you do with
the money that I sent you
for that particular purpose?
I, uh, got rolled
over by a roulette wheel
on the way to church.
It's too bad you didn't marry her.
Would've been good for you.
You know, it still might be.
I'm in a magnanimous mood, George.
You find her, and I'll stake
you to any business you name.
If she doesn't wanna leave France,
I'll put you in charge of
our organization over there.
Well, what do you say?
I'll think about it.
Good, good.
Oh, by the way, I had the
office make out a check,
sort of a wedding present in reverse
from me to you.
My, my.
$10,000?
Thanks, I certainly can use it.
That's what I figured.
If getting married puts
you in this kind of mood,
we should do it more often.
I hope you'll take my advice.
About what?
Find that girl and marry her.
Yeah.
I'll see if I can remember her name.
Dearly beloved,
we are gathered together here
in the sight of God and in
the face of this company
to join together this man and
this woman in holy matrimony,
which is an honorable
estate, instituted of God,
signifying unto us the mystical union
that is betwixt Christ and his church,
which holy estate Christ adorned
and beautified with his presence
and first miracle that he
wrought in Cana of Galilee,
and is commended of St. Paul
to be honorable among all men,
and therefore is not by any to
be entered into unadvisedly,
or lightly, but reverently, discreetly,
advisedly, soberly, and in fear of God.
Into this holy estate,
these two persons present
come now to be joined.
If any man can show just cause
why they may not lawfully
be joined together,
let him now speak,
or else hereafter forever hold his peace.
Barry, will thou have this
woman to thy wedded wife,
to live together after God's ordinance
in the holy estate of matrimony?
Will thou love her, comfort her,
honor and keep her in
sickness and in health,
and forsaking all others
keep thee only unto her
so long as ye both shall live?
I will.
The Lord mercifully with
his favor look upon you
and fill you with all
spiritual benediction
and grace that you may so
live together in this life
that in the world to come,
you may have life everlasting.
Amen.
I wish you both much happiness.
- Thank you.
Sorry.
Me too.
Good evening, Mr. MacAllister.
- Any messages?
- No, sir, except your bill.
I have it right here.
This includes the current month.
Well, get that worried
look off your face.
I'm gonna pray it.
You are?
Fine.
Although we never really
worry about your account.
I'll bet you don't.
Who's the guy over there?
I don't know.
Put the receipt in my box, will you?
Thank you, sir.
With me,
darling, you're my love,
and Barry's my business.
Trust me, dear.
Okay, let's have it.
What's on your mind?
What is this, a stick-up?
You know it's no stick-up!
What is it then?
Every time I turn
around, I see your face.
It's my face, I'll
take it where I please.
If you don't want it
messed up, quit trailing me.
If anybody's trailing you, I
don't know anything about it.
I get troubles of my own
that don't include you.
Then what are you
casing my apartment for?
Your apartment?
Is your name Helene?
Do you work at the Chapeau Blanc?
Have I got a yen for you?
Helene?
Helene Anderson?
Yeah.
Oh, you know her, that's your angle.
No, I just heard she
moved into the apartment.
What are you watching her for?
She's a dame that needs watching.
Girlfriend?
Sometimes I wonder.
I've been out of town a while.
Checking up before checking in?
Something like that.
She wouldn't talk to me on the phone.
Just waiting around to find out why.
Oh.
Say, uh...
I'm sorry I jumped you the way I did.
I guess I'm a little nervous.
Nervous?
Yes.
You see, I'm having a little
romantic trouble myself.
Oh.
Now I know how you
feel, I tell you what.
Let's go up to my apartment.
We can have a couple of drinks.
Do us both good.
It's as good a place to wait as any.
Okay.
- Make yourself at home.
- Right.
Nice place you got here.
Thanks.
If I could support a layout like this,
I wouldn't have any worries about Helene.
What'll you have to drink?
Bourbon, you got any?
Yeah.
Helene, I take it, likes nice things.
You ain't kidding.
She likes anything that
costs a lot of dough,
if you know what I mean.
When I got it, she even likes me.
That ain't often.
I don't know what kind
of trouble you're having
with that dame of yours.
Bet she ain't two-timing you.
What makes you so sure?
Her face.
This dame's got class.
That's not the girl.
That's not the one, huh?
No.
That's not the dame I saw coming in here
a couple of days ago,
and once before that?
No.
I haven't seen that
girl since I left Paris.
Oh.
For all I know, she's still there.
French dame, huh?
Yes, that's right.
That autograph,
that thing she wrote on the picture,
it's in English.
Well, what about it?
A lot of people in France write English.
What are you so jumpy about, pal?
I'm not jumpy.
Oh.
What's keeping you from your torch?
Married, huh?
Yes, that's right.
She's married.
Say, Ernie, do me a favor, will you?
Go in the kitchen, and get me some ice.
- Ice?
- Yeah, over there.
Oh.
Wanna call her, huh?
Hello?
George.
What are you calling
for this time of night?
I just wanted to apologize
for running away from the
wedding and reception.
Would you put Barry,
or my brand-new
sister-in-law on the phone?
No.
I'll give them your message.
They've retired.
I see.
Good night, Aunt Maggie.
That's the trouble with having
a girlfriend who's married.
If her man answers, you gotta hang up.
Tell you what, Ernie.
What?
Let's go see Helene.
Helene?
Yes, Ms. Anderson.
You said her name was Helene, didn't you?
Why should you wanna go see her?
You said you didn't know her.
Well, I just feel like going someplace.
I feel as though I owe you
a little entertainment.
Oh.
Come on, I'll
take you both to dinner.
She's working, singing.
All right, we'll go there
and wait 'til she's through.
Between the two of us, we can convince her
that Ernie Hicks is a man of importance.
Oh.
♪ Love me, or leave me ♪
♪ Let me be lonely ♪
♪ You won't believe me ♪
♪ And I love you only ♪
♪ I rather be lonely ♪
♪ Than happy with somebody else ♪
♪ You might find the nighttime ♪
♪ The right time for kissing ♪
♪ But it's my time for just reminiscing ♪
♪ Regrettin' instead of forgettin' ♪
♪ With somebody else ♪
♪ There'll be no one unless
that someone is you ♪
♪ I intend to be independently blue ♪
♪ I want your love ♪
♪ But I don't wanna borrow ♪
♪ To have today and to
give back tomorrow ♪
♪ My love is your love ♪
♪ There's no love for nobody else ♪
♪ Nighttime is my time ♪
♪ 'Cause nighttime ♪
♪ Is the right time ♪
♪ My love is your love ♪
♪ There's no love ♪
♪ For nobody else ♪
Pretty nice, huh?
Very attractive.
The way guys go for her,
you can see why I gotta watch her.
I certainly can't say that I do.
She had a nice big smile for you.
That was for you,
the gold cuff links you're wearing,
and the good stuff in that suit.
She'll tell you the price of both of them
from 50 yards away.
Ernie, you're bitter.
You think she'll join us?
After one gander at you,
there's no doubt about it.
Hello, Ernie.
Gee, I'm glad to see you.
I sure missed you.
Oh, excuse me.
Ms. Anderson, I want
you to meet my friend,
Mr. MacAllister.
How do you do?
Sit down, won't you?
I sure missed you, kid.
You said that already.
Why wouldn't you see me
when I came back to town?
I told you over the phone.
I've been too busy with rehearsals.
I've heard it said about
great singers, Ms. Anderson,
after rehearsals come in the door,
romance flies out of the window.
Or was it vice versa?
Yes, I guess it was vice versa.
I guess.
Anyway, it's nice to have you join us.
Will you have dinner with us?
- Sure, I'd love to.
- Oh, swell.
This time, the dinner's on him.
Next time, it's on me.
Fine, after tonight, I
was going on a diet anyway.
Say, where did he pick you up?
I didn't pick him up, he picked me up.
That's right.
We're gonna have a lot of fun together.
We've got a lot in common,
Mr. MacAllister and I.
What's he talking about?
Oh, you're drunk and I'm hungry.
I think we better let
Mr. MacAllister order.
The menu's printed in French, kid.
He had a French girl in Paris.
How nice.
Oh, you better order some champagne.
Goes good with French food.
Thank you for a very pleasant evening.
It's been fun, especially meeting you.
My pleasure.
Oh, care for a nightcap?
No, thanks, past my bedtime.
I could use one.
It's past my bedtime, too.
Good night, Mr. MacAllister.
Good night.
See you around, Ernie.
Well, I'm gonna walk up, Ernie.
I'll take the elevator.
- Say, Ernie.
- Yeah?
About that news item.
You can understand why I
said it was a different girl.
Sure, sure.
Well, now that she's
married, it's all over,
and, well, you know-
- It's all over?
- Naturally.
Oh.
And I'd appreciate it
if you didn't mention
seeing her come up here to anybody.
Consider it forgotten.
Atta boy, Ernie, thanks.
Here's something.
I think it might help you out with Helene.
Nah, no, no, no.
I wouldn't think of it.
I'll be seeing you.
- Who's there?
- It's me.
Hi, neighbor.
Howdy ma'am.
Long time no see.
Well, I decided I'd
have that nightcap alone,
but when I looked in my bar, no whiskey,
so I just ran up to
borrow a cup of bourbon
from my neighbor.
What are you looking for?
Mice.
Will you drink it here,
or take it with you?
I think I'll drink it here.
Mm, I've been wanting that all evening.
Couldn't wait any longer.
Me too.
Really?
Really.
What are you looking for?
My picture.
Where have you got it?
In the-
No, it's not in the kitchen, either.
It's right there in the desk.
I just left at there 'til
I got, um, a frame for it.
I forgive you.
It's a good thing it was in the drawer
when Ernie was here.
Why didn't you tell me you knew him?
Ernie?
Yes, Ernie.
I forgot.
Of course, you know
he's slightly jealous.
Oh, he gives me a pain.
Say, how did you ever
get mixed up with him?
I don't know, I felt
sorry for him, I guess.
He's nuts about you.
Oh, he is nuts period.
But he's a troublemaker,
and if you take my advice,
you'll brush him fast.
So why do you let him hang around?
I won't, Georgie, if,
if you don't want me to.
I wouldn't take the responsibility.
Just for that, I think I'll
take this and drink it alone.
Good idea, kitten.
But I didn't mean it, George.
I, I don't wanna go.
But-You need your beauty rest.
Good night, kitten, and happy hangover.
Celia, what's so
interesting out those windows?
Mr. and Mrs. MacAllister,
they're down by the sea,
that beautiful old sea on the high cliff.
On the point?
Yessum.
Ain't it wonderful, Ms. Margaret,
the change that's come over
him since he found her?
Ain't it, though?
That love bug sure is a
wonderful little creature.
He sure is.
He's one of God's chosen creatures
that little old love bug.
If you've finished down here,
you'd better start with the bedrooms.
- Yessum.
- And don't forget
to check on the linens.
Yessum.
That little old love
bug is still all right.
Barry, please, not so close.
It frightens me.
Don't worry, I'll be careful.
If the fall down there didn't kill me,
the climb back up would.
Then step back a little.
You love this,
the sea and the cliffs
and the rocks.
Don't you?
I do again, now that you're here.
Say, by the way, you're,
you're not the fisherman's little girl
that used to play over
these rocks with me?
No, why?
You have the same effect on me.
Was she a blonde?
I don't know.
Her hair was always so full of seaweed.
Yeah, we built beautiful,
wonderful air castles,
my little beachcomber and I.
I was going to buy her the whole world,
starting out with a marble
palace, a golden yacht.
But she was a realist,
decided she'd rather
start with a bracelet.
So I went without my
lunch for a whole month
and bought the bracelet.
Mm, I bet she loved it.
She never saw it.
George showed up that summer
and I lost my little beachcomber.
George stole your girl?
Oh, sure, George always stole my girls.
You know, by a peculiar coincidence,
I just happen to have
that bracelet with me.
Wear it, darling.
It's wonderful to regain something
you've loved and lost as a child.
You know what I mean?
Yes, yes, I do.
How?
Because of, because of Henry.
Oh, you had a little boyfriend, huh?
No, French poodle.
I hated the taxi cab that killed him.
No wonder you dislike George
for taking her from you.
Dislike George?
Whatever gave you that idea?
I, I don't know, I thought-
Because he's shiftless and lazy,
plays too much and works too little,
'cause he took my girls away from me?
For that I should dislike him?
Oh, nothing of the sort.
I've always liked George.
He's got a way with him.
Oh, I've always tried to
get him to settle down.
Almost succeeded once.
When was that?
When he was overseas.
Got a bullet in his leg,
fell head over heels
in love with the nurse
that took care of him,
wanted to marry her.
At least, that's what he wrote me.
Of course, I'm always
meddling in George's affairs.
Even on our wedding day,
I offered to set him up
in any business he'd name
if he'd find that girl and marry her.
He wouldn't, I, I suppose.
No, same old George.
Couldn't even remember her name.
Oh, darling, you're getting cold.
Here I am boring you
with a family skeleton.
Come on, I'll take you back to the house.
Oh, Barry, I, I've been thinking about
your New York apartment.
I'd like to fix it up a bit
in case we get to use it more often.
Well, that would be all right, but-
You'd rather I didn't?
Oh, no, of course not.
Go ahead and do it if you'd enjoy it.
I'll have Hammer bring the car.
I told Barry I was going shopping.
Hammer brought me in.
He didn't bring you here?
No, of course not.
I had him let me off at Barry's apartment.
Then I took a cab.
Smart girl.
Know how much I missed you?
What's the matter?
I don't know what's wrong with me.
I, I'm upset
About what?
You don't mean to tell
me that my dear brother
isn't feeling well, I hope?
He's feeling all right,
but, well, George, he told
me some things about you,
and I had to see you.
Oh, I know I'm being foolish.
Tell me I'm being foolish, darling,
that they aren't so,
that I'm just upset because
I got too lonesome for you.
If they bother you,
kitten, they aren't so.
He said you wanted
to marry me in France.
You?
Well, he said a nurse in France.
I knew he meant me.
Well, say that's so.
If I hadn't been broke-
But he sent you money.
So what?
Then he did send you money?
Yeah, he sent a little.
But why didn't we get married?
What did you do with it?
I don't know.
Bought you some posies,
or something, I guess.
It wasn't enough to think about.
But we didn't need much.
Just a little and each other
would have been enough.
Well, look, honey, you're
making something out of nothing.
You are letting him fill your head
with a lot of doubts about me
when you know he hates my guts.
But he doesn't, George.
He likes you.
Look, honey, I've known him
a lot longer than you have.
Doesn't hate you, George.
He doesn't.
All right, kitten.
All right.
Anything you say.
But you gotta let me run the show.
Have I ever steered you wrong?
No.
No, of course not.
Then you gotta trust me.
Will you?
I do, of course I do.
It's just that it's more difficult
than I thought it would be out there.
I know.
It isn't exactly easy in here either,
but you mustn't doubt me.
Forgive me, darling.
I'm just confused.
And I better be going.
You wanna go?
Well, I've got to.
Hi, Georgie.
Look, Ernie,
I'd like to have you stay,
but I've gotta change and go out.
I won't interfere with your dressing.
Have something I wanna talk to you about.
All right, what
do you wanna talk about?
I'm in a hurry.
Going out, huh?
- Yeah.
- Oh.
Well, what is it?
How many bedrooms you got here?
One.
Oh.
Is that your
idea of something important
to talk about?
Thought I might move in with you.
Second thought, my taste is
a little snappier than this.
What makes you think
I'd let you move in with me?
Well, seeing as we're
in business together,
I figured we might as well live together.
Since when are we in business together?
Since your brother's wife parked her car
in front of your brother's
apartment downtown
and took a cab up here.
I wouldn't if I were you, Georgie.
I should've spotted you
for a stinkin' blackmailer
the first time I saw you!
I wasn't a blackmailer then.
You'd almost say it was your idea,
what, with being followed.
That, and Helene.
Helene?
She won't have anything to do with me.
Seems she's got a yen for somebody else.
I can't help you there.
No?
No.
Oh, I think you can.
When I got money, Helene
feels different towards me.
I don't get you.
I offered you some money the other night.
Why didn't you take it?
Small money, Georgie, small money.
You know, the minute I laid eyes on you,
I knew I was in business.
Big business.
That shocks you, doesn't it?
You'd be amazed how
talkative the servants are
out at your brother's place.
Why didn't you tell me he only had
a couple of months to live?
Or maybe less now that he's
married to your Carlotta.
I got too much money
invested in you, Georgie.
Pour me one, too.
My mind was
a welter of confusion
after leaving your
apartment that afternoon.
It was the first time I had
ever really doubted you, George.
But I doubted myself too.
And I was frightened as
I approached the house.
I felt I couldn't possibly
face its occupants,
and to my mind, the very house itself
scowled disapproval of me.
I felt the wind shriek its hatred,
and the ocean, always
angry and threatening,
seemed to be reaching for me,
trying to drag me by force from this place
which Barry loved, and in
which I was an imposter.
I started for the house.
An impasse made me turn,
and then go toward the chapel.
As I stood inside the door,
I looked at the place
where we were married,
Barry and I.
Then I seemed to hear bells.
And a voice.
I pronounce
that they are man and wife.
I knelt there for a long time,
but peace would not come to me.
I'm sure that if I prayed,
my prayers were so confused,
I wondered if even God
could understand them.
I was about to leave, when
there was an awful crash.
At first, I thought the light unearthly,
and then I was hearing our
wedding music in my imagination
as I had heard the bells,
and the words of the minister.
Then I realized the music I was hearing
was coming from the house.
But the sudden peace
and clarity in my mind were not imagined.
You weren't in my thoughts, George,
as I hurried from the chapel.
I went through the doorway
of the house, my house,
and for the first time, it welcomed me.
It was then I knew I had
to tell Barry about myself.
The thought instead of
frightening me brought me comfort.
Please don't stop.
Say, do you know that
the room lit up just now
when you walked in?
Tell me, what's the cause
of this new radiance?
Clear conscience.
A wife with a clear conscience?
I never heard of such a thing.
It's the clear conscience
I'm about to have.
Barry,
you really don't know much
about this new wife of yours.
Doesn't that ever bother you?
No.
Say, what is this, a confession?
Yes.
Well, that probably means
I'll have to bare my lurid past.
No dice.
Please be serious, dear.
Serious about your past?
Just some of it, Barry.
There are some things
you have a right to know.
You may not like me
quite as much, or at all,
but that's a chance I have to take.
I don't think I could
live with myself if I-
Say, you are serious, aren't you?
Yes.
Carlotta,
I know about you.
You know what?
All that I want to know.
All that's important.
You see, darling, every man has a picture
of the woman he loves.
Mine is a picture of a pretty little girl
that grew into a lovely young woman,
put on this earth for the sole purpose
of bringing happiness into
the life of Barry MacAllister.
Humor me, darling.
Let me look at my picture.
See what I see.
But it's not exactly the truth.
Hmm, of course it's not.
You're such a good little girl,
you wanna tell me all about the time
you held hands with the neighbor boy.
Don't do it.
I know it may sound funny to you,
but, well, even that,
just don't do it.
That was Barry.
I looked at him with new eyes then
and in the days that followed.
I even looked in him for all the things
you had found hateful, George,
and I looked in vain.
They weren't there.
All I could find was kindness, gentleness,
and appreciation for the little I gave.
What are you clucking about?
Hotel service,
very bad, very dusty.
Well, you've done
all the dusting up here.
Finish it up and get out, will you?
Yes, sir, all finished.
Wait a minute.
Chang?
Yes, sir?
I wanna give you a bit of advice.
If you ever fall in love,
admit it to yourself right away.
Don't wait until it's almost too late.
Oh, that could not happen to Chang.
Why not?
Haven't you ever been in love?
Oh yes, in love many times,
once with girl.
Hurt too much.
Now, Chang fall in love
only with roast duck,
weekly paycheck, riding streetcars,
and going to movies.
It's a sound idea.
Only it won't help me any.
Confucius have many helpful word
for people in all kind
of trouble, except love.
For them, he have only sympathy.
Chang would not like to be
in love with one so lovely
and so good, as her face
show this one to be.
Why?
The better she is, the harder to lose.
What makes you think I lost her?
Someday, everybody lose everybody.
That is why Chang never fall
in love with girl again.
If she mean all the world
to you and you lose her,
then you have lost the whole world.
If she mean more than life
to you and you lose her,
then you have lost all of life.
But if she mean more than your soul to you
and you lose her,
then you have lost your own soul.
Confucius say that?
Maybe Confucius.
Maybe Walter Winchell.
Chang remember only the words.
I go.
Oh, I'll get it.
Hi, neighbor.
Hello, Helene.
Confucius would be much confused.
You shouldn't have come today.
I'm in a stinkin' mood.
Good, I'll get stinking with you.
I don't mean drunk.
- Oh.
- Just don't feel like
entertaining anybody.
Well, then I'll entertain you.
Come on.
Tell the neighbor lady what
my big baby's sulking about.
I'm not sulking.
I just feel like being alone.
Can't you understand that?
Ooh, you really are in a nasty mood.
But I don't mind.
Oh?
So this is the reason my picture stays
in the desk drawer, hmm?
Don't be silly.
That's only a girl I knew a long time ago.
Don't you be silly.
I read the social columns as
well as the funnies, dear.
This picture isn't as good
as the one in the papers
when she married your brother.
All right, so she's my brother's wife.
What's wrong with that?
"For George, with all my love."
A very chummy family, aren't you?
Get outta here, your little
tramp, before I throw you out.
I'll go,
and I'll remember what you called me, too.
And while you're at it,
remember not to come back.
George, I didn't mean anything.
I want to stay.
Well, I meant it.
Darling, please try to understand.
I was jealous, and, well,
you're the one guy that
never called me a tramp.
Well, beat it if you
don't wanna hear it again
from the same guy.
Oh, you'll be sorry for this, George.
Do you wish to see me?
Yes.
Helene Anderson's the name.
I don't believe we've met before.
No, we haven't.
But we have a, a mutual friend,
and I thought we should know each other.
A mutual friend?
Yeah.
Georgie.
Georgie?
You mean George MacAllister?
I don't mean George Washington.
Perhaps, Ms. Anderson,
you'd better tell me
just why you're here.
Sure, why not?
I just came up to tell you
that Georgie is all yours,
or, or didn't you know we'd
been dividing him up to now?
I still don't know what you mean.
Oh, snap out of it.
I know you're French, but
you've got a pretty firm grip
on this country's language.
It's too bad you don't
know more about the men.
He's a stinker, and you can have him.
Is that plain?
George is my husband's half-brother.
I'm not interested in his personal life.
Half-brother, that's all, hmm?
Yes.
"For George, with
all my love, Carlotta."
Oh, and I hope you forgive me,
I, I broke the glass in the picture.
Oh.
So this is blackmail then?
No, it isn't blackmail.
It's just that I want to
see a few other people
get what's coming to them for a change,
- and I intend to do it, too.
- Carlotta?
Oh, I'm sorry, darling, I
didn't know you had company.
That's all right, dear.
This is Ms. Anderson, my husband.
How do you do, Mr. MacAllister?
How do you do?
She, Helene just learned
where I was living, and-
I figured she'd be very happy to see me.
An old friend, eh?
Fine.
Are you a nurse too, Ms. Anderson?
Why-
You might say that
we've taken care of the same
patients, hmm, Carlotta?
- Yes.
- Good.
I wish more of her friends would come...
What's the matter darling?
Aren't you feeling well?
- You look pale.
- Pale?
Oh, it's your imagination, dear.
Just the same, I
better have Dr. Mitchell
take a look at you the
next time he's here.
Well, I imagine you
girls have a great deal
to talk about, so-
Yes.
Yes, I could talk all day.
Well, I'll be running along then.
Good bye, dear.
Nice meeting you, Ms. Anderson.
Come see Carlotta again real soon.
Please do.
Well, I, I guess I'll
be running along, too.
Ms. Anderson?
Yes?
Thank you.
For telling you about George?
No.
Oh, for not telling him?
Well, why should I?
He's a nice guy.
You ought to take good care of him.
Well, happy, happy.
Hello?
- Hello?
You know who this is?
- Yes.
- Celia!
Just a minute.
Yes, George.
What do you want?
Where have you been?
Why haven't you talked to me?
Why haven't you been in town?
I, I've been busy.
This is dangerous and foolish.
I know it's dangerous,
but I've gotta talk to you.
This is important.
We're in trouble.
You must, Carlotta.
It's important.
Why not this afternoon?
No, it's impossible.
No, I can't.
Celia!
I can't talk anymore.
All right, I'll try.
Yes.
Yes, tomorrow afternoon.
All right.
I promise.
You didn't
ask her for the dough.
Over the phone?
Don't be stupid.
Suppose she can't get the money, or won't.
She can and she will for you.
Especially when she knows
how important it is.
Why do you have to have it now?
Why can't you wait?
It's Helene.
All of a sudden, she's changed.
She came back to me.
Do you understand that?
I told her I was coming into some dough,
an inheritance, I said it was.
She agreed to marry me
right away tomorrow.
Then we take off on our honeymoon.
You better get me that
dough, George, fast.
I'll see what I can do.
I can't promise anything.
Well, maybe I better contact her direct.
Wait!
I'll get it.
Okay, George.
Your call upset me,
but I was certain your plea of trouble
was simply an excuse to see me.
I had no intention of keeping my promise
to visit your apartment the
next day, Christmas Day.
I was determined not to see you again.
I never wanted to.
Come in.
Mm, how pretty you look.
Merry Christmas, darling.
It's not Christmas yet, silly.
It is for you.
I wanna give you your present.
But why don't
you put it under the tree?
I can't wrap packages,
especially this one.
Henry?
Henry!
Barry, you remembered!
Oh, he's a darling!
He seems to think the same about you.
Oh, another thing, darling.
I, I invited George out for
our little Christmas Eve party.
- George?
- He called me at the office,
seemed kind of lonesome, so
being Christmas and everything,
I asked him out.
Merry Xmas, mm-hmm.
And that's a fact.
Thanks.
I know you play, Reverend McDonald.
You must have a number
that'd be appropriate.
I sure have, and it'll be a pleasure.
Good.
You were about to ask your
wife to dance, I presume?
I was?
Uh, I mean, I was.
Excuse me.
Aunt Maggie?
Merry Christmas, George.
Be a merrier Christmas if you
let me dance with your wife.
Aunt Maggie steps on my feet.
You're so gallant, George.
You can step on my feet
for a while, darling.
You've been avoiding me all evening.
I, I couldn't help it.
Carlotta, I've gotta talk to you.
But not here.
All right then.
Up there.
No, don't, please.
No one can see us here.
You said you wanted to talk to me,
that there was trouble.
What, what kind of trouble?
We're being blackmailed.
Blackmailed?
By who?
Oh, by a guy by the
name of Bernie Hicks.
You wouldn't know him.
He saw you coming to my
apartment a couple of times,
started checking.
Checking?
When?
Oh, long time ago.
I thought I could handle it.
I didn't wanna worry you.
I knew it'd be harder
for you to stay out here
if you thought someone was watching us.
Then why tell me now?
Because we are whipped, Carlotta.
Can't you see, when that
blackmailer learned our plan,
we no longer had a plan.
Oh, I've lost the money, that I know.
But I don't wanna lose you too.
What do you want me to do?
Leave here tonight, now.
Leave here?
Why, I...
I can't.
Why can't you?
Are you trying to tell me you love Barry?
Don't you wanna come back to me?
He's wonderful to me.
I, I won't hurt him.
Maybe you won't, but I might.
You're mine, you belong to me,
and you're going to come back to me,
no matter what it takes.
You understand?
Well, what about it?
I'll, let me think.
Oh, there you are.
Darling, some of the guests are leaving.
I know you'd wanna say good night.
Yes, yes, of course.
George was just saying good night, too.
Oh, nonsense.
You're staying over for breakfast with us,
aren't you, old man?
Sure, sure.
I was afraid you weren't
gonna ask me for a moment.
I couldn't
think of going to sleep.
I knew the thoughts that
were going through your head,
and I was afraid of what
you might do to Barry.
The last vestige of my regard for you died
when you told me of the blackmailer,
for you were the only blackmailer, George.
You were trying to blackmail
me into returning to you.
Your words kept hammering in my head.
Maybe you won't, but I might.
You're mine, you belong to me,
and you're going to come back to me,
no matter what it takes.
You understand?
Why aren't you asleep?
Because I'm not sleepy.
Oh, I know you.
You couldn't without kissing
little Georgie good night.
I...
I was nervous and worried.
And you had to kiss little
Georgie good night, didn't you?
Yes, yes, that too.
George, do you still
carry that gun with you?
My little baby?
Why, sure.
Every place I go.
Let me have it.
Why?
I'd like to keep it for you.
Oh, mm-mm.
I'll give it back to you tomorrow.
Really, I will.
Ooh.
You worried about Barry?
I, I just don't want anything
to happen to either of you.
You're in love with him, aren't you?
Oh, George, why don't you go to bed?
I want a straight answer.
Are you in love with him?
Well?
No.
No, George.
That's good.
Because if you had
fallen in love with him,
I don't think baby here
would like it very much.
Oh, but it's silly of me to think
that you could fall in
love with anybody else.
There's no one quite like Georgie.
Don't drink anymore, George.
Please go to bed.
You do wanna come back, don't you?
Sure you do.
The next morning,
my decision had been made.
I suddenly realized
that you would kill him
before you would give me up.
But I was returning to you
without my heart and soul.
I waited until Barry left and
then wrote him a short note.
I couldn't tell him very
much, certainly not the truth,
not after he had said-
You're such a good little girl,
you probably wanna tell me about the time
you held hands with the neighbor boy.
But don't do it.
Oh, I, I know it may sound funny to you,
but, well, even that,
just don't do it.
And so, I blamed my own weakness
as a person unable to find happiness,
and I asked him to forgive
me for running away.
For he is such a good man, Father.
You understand why I must do this to him.
Comfort him, and make him strong and well.
And bless him, Father.
Bless him every minute of every day.
And dear Father,
help me just a little bit, too.
Please.
Please?
Amen.
That was a lovely prayer, Carlotta.
Dr. Mitchell, I, I
didn't know you were here.
Forgive me.
I started to speak and then
I didn't want to interrupt.
But how do you happen to be in here?
Oh, to tell the truth,
I often sit in here
for a moment when I'm out this way.
Nice quiet place to write prescriptions.
Remember my Latin better in church.
Oh, well, I'll leave you alone.
No.
Sit down a minute, please.
I was going to the house.
I wanted to talk to you about Barry.
He isn't worse?
No.
You must've prayed for him
many times before, Carlotta,
because he's much better.
Much better.
I'm so glad, Dr. Mitchell.
Are you?
Of course I am.
Well, that's funny,
because when you were praying
up there a minute ago,
I almost got the impression
you were leaving him, going away.
Why, Carlotta?
I thought you were happy here.
I thought you meant this marriage.
There are reasons, Dr. Mitchell, I...
You don't know.
I can't tell you.
I know you've done
wonders for your husband.
What else don't I know?
Dr. Mitchell, I for many years,
George and I-
I know, I know about you and George.
You do?
Quite a while.
A doctor has to know a bit
about his favorite nurse.
But, but why didn't
you say anything before?
Why?
I considered it.
Yes.
I was just about to speak up
when I looked at Barry's face
and I realized he had found
the medicine he needed.
And, well, I, I love Barry as my own son.
Dr. Mitchell, I, I'm so confused.
You see, I love him, too.
Then why are you going back to George?
He's desperate.
I'm afraid of what he might do to Barry.
Did he threaten you?
Yes.
Ah, he'd carry it out, too.
Well, that leaves just
one thing for you to do.
What?
Uncle Joe's going to
recommend a sea voyage
for his patient with his wife.
Take him away, Carlotta,
for six months, a year,
10 years, if he's having fun.
The Queen Elizabeth sails New Year's Eve.
Be on it.
With Barry?
Is he well enough?
For his honeymoon?
Under your care, it looks as though
he'll outlive the lot of us.
Thank you.
Thank you,
Uncle Joe.
What are you doing here?
I was merely making sure that
Celia had cleaned properly.
I'm taking care of Barry's room.
I thought perhaps you were leaving.
I was never more sure that I'm staying.
Not until it was burning
did my happiness return,
and even then, it was happiness
overshadowed by foreboding.
There was reason for foreboding.
Barry told me later that
you wanted to see him
in his New York apartment
before we sailed,
and that he had agreed to meet you alone.
Then I knew I must burn this letter.
I'm pleading for my husband's life
and our happiness, George.
But even as I write, I seem
to know it will do no good.
There's a great fear in
me of what will happen
when you and Barry meet.
I beg of you, have mercy, George.
Late, kitten.
A little late.
You all right, Mr. MacAllister?
Why you call police?
Homicide Bureau.
I expected you, but not so soon.
He's hurt.
- We should call doctor.
- No.
I'm all right.
We, uh, found that guy.
You were right.
He is quite dead.
Hey.
Can't you see?
He's sick.
You're not kidding.
He's sick, all right.
Got a bullet hole clean through him.
If you wanna ask him any questions,
you better do it here and fast.
I'll call a doctor and an ambulance.
Please, Mr. MacAllister,
you'll be all right.
You tear your coat.
Ah, shut up.
Try to remember, MacAllister.
I hate to make you talk now,
but some things we gotta know.
Why did you kill him?
What was the fight about?
- What happened?
- Homicide.
Send a doctor and an ambulance
over to 150 West 59th.
Yeah, and don't spare the horses.
Uh, try to think,
MacAllister, what happened?
What happened?
I tore my coat.
Yes, I tore my coat.
Although the tear in the
coat had nothing to do
with my errand there tonight.
I wasn't thinking about anything
when I stepped into that corridor
except the job I had come there to do.
He'd crossed me for the last time.
Nice layout.
I got it for Helene.
You're giving me the dough to pay for it.
Money?
I didn't bring any.
I told you tonight was the deadline.
I wasn't kidding.
I know, pal.
But things have happened.
Our plans have changed a bit.
My sense of humor ain't so good tonight.
My plans haven't changed.
Now, quit stalling.
Give me the money now.
I'll have to swim for it.
Mrs. MacAllister and her
husband are sailing tonight
on the Queen Elizabeth.
They'll be gone a long, long time.
Oh.
Where are you going?
To the docks to wish 'em bon voyage.
Bon voyage, Ernie.
Mr. MacAllister?
Mr. Boss?
- Please.
- Yeah, snap out of it.
I got a couple of more questions.
Don't, he's...
Mr. MacAllister's answering
questions elsewhere now.
Excuse me, please.
Mr. and Mrs. MacAllister?
- Yes?
- Telegram, sir.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you, sir.
What is it?
Same old George, he'll never change.
"Unavoidably detained."
"Wish you and Carlotta a happy New Year."
"Love, George."
Happy New Year, darling.
♪ Should old acquaintance be forgot ♪
♪ And never brought to mind ♪
♪ In the days of auld lang syne ♪