POTE: Previously on
"Queen of the South"...
I'm done with this business.
Let's be a family
before the world
tries to tear us apart again.
- Don't!
- (gunshot)
Agh!
CORTEZ: Camila is playing you.
Just 'cause our kids are
engaged to be married,
you don't think
I'll kill the bitch?
(speaking Spanish)
- (grunts)
- (people gasping)
(sobbing)
(people clamoring)
CAMILA: Isabela, it's okay.
You do what you need to do.
You'll get no
interference from me.
We're nearly free of Boaz,
but there is still the
matter of Teresa Mendoza.
Whatever you've done,
you don't need to hide from me.
PECAS: It's Pecas.
Came across a little
something here in Phoenix.
You might be interested.
(tense music)
♪
(soft atmospheric music)
(sighs)
EPIFANIO: Mi
amor, es espactular.
Gracias.
(smooches)
For 25 years together.
And every night I
thank the heavens
that you decided to
marry a baboso like me.
Salud.
EPIFANIO: What's
wrong? You're not drinking.
I found a very... large transfer
in our bank statement today.
You know, just out of curiosity,
how much longer am I gonna
keep paying for your whore?
I couldn't turn away
someone in need.
You can be as generous
as you want with your dick,
just not with my money.
And I'm gonna tell
you something else.
If I ever see...
that you deposit one more cent
to that puta... she's dead.
♪
Your rage and desire for revenge
will be your end, mi vida.
♪
Happy anniversary.
Enjoy your watch.
♪
(cell phone buzzing)
¿Bueno?
BOAZ: (speaking Spanish)
What can I do for you, Boaz?
You know, mi amigo Pecas
picked up Teresa Mendoza
as a favor for me.
I handed them over
to your pinche general.
Still got to collect my bounty.
Say I give you
the family discount.
(speaking Spanish)
CAMILA: Thanks...
but I don't pay
debt to a dead man.
See you on the
other side... suegro.
(tense music)
(sighs)
♪
(door closes)
(man speaking Spanish)
♪
These will be your
accommodations
during your stay back home.
I hope...
that you will find
them up to your...
high standards, Teresa.
I would like to
speak with Camila.
She needs to know
what will happen
if I don't walk out of here.
La gobernadora will see
you when she's ready.
Until then...
- (fence rattling)
- You two can catch up.
♪
(fence rattling)
No, no... ♪
Guero?
No.
Teresa?
(motorcycle engine rumbling)
Where are you?
Hey, look, I'm on my
way to the meeting spot,
but I got a little
bit of heat on me.
Okay, lose them first.
Meet us at the port.
- I love you.
- I love you, too.
(dramatic music)
♪
Se fue, idiota.
CORTEZ: Tell me where she is,
and I'll untie you and
treat you like a king.
Sushi... micheladas...
pedicures... Anything
you want, Guero.
♪
She left you high and dry.
Save yourself.
(spits)
♪
(gun cocks)
(speaking Spanish)
♪
- Ah!
- (groans)
♪
(spits)
Doctor!
Ayúdale.
(speaking Spanish)
♪
(sniffs)
(speaking Spanish)
Tomás.
♪
If it wasn't for that
doctor, I'd be gone by now.
You didn't give up
Marbella to Cortez?
What, and tell him that
was our plan? Hell, no.
Cortez could beat me
for another eight months,
and I wouldn't betray you.
I went to Malta instead.
Should've looked for you.
No, it's good that you didn't.
That's what Camila wanted.
I knew that she'd bring
you here one of these days.
I think I got a plan for us
to try and get out of here.
(poignant music)
You're the only thing
that's kept me alive, Teresa.
♪
I know they did it.
Pecas is the type of man
that doesn't like to be accused.
Well, if La Comisión
didn't take her,
they know who did.
Sometimes the fly needs honey,
sometimes the hammer.
You choose the wrong one,
and you get nothing.
We don't have time.
(door bells jingle)
Pecas!
Where is she?
Can't a guy enjoy his
doughnuts on cheat day?
-I know you have
her. PECAS: Sit down.
Relax. Have a bear
claw. It's on me.
(traditional Mexican
music playing)
(sniffs)
♪
You hit like a little girl.
I delivered Teresa
to my connect.
So she's in Mexico?
Maybe.
Maybe not.
(inhales sharply)
I turned her over to
one of Boaz's guys.
That's all I know.
James... Listen to
your friend, Romeo.
Teresa's a hot boss.
But thinking with
your little pee-pee's
going to get you killed.
Call Boaz... now.
(tense synth music)
- (cell phone ringing)
- The plan didn't work, pendejo!
And now the crazy
perra is after me.
Well, that's what you get for
negotiating with Camila Vargas.
BOAZ: Who the hell
is this? Where's Pecas?
JAMES: This is James.
Pinche Santiago!
You want to get
revenge on Camila,
take away what she wants most.
Help me find Teresa.
BOAZ: If it means hurting
that perra, I'll help you,
but I don't know
where your girl is,
just that Camila's got her.
(speaking Spanish)
♪
We're getting on
a plane to Mexico.
Malta, huh?
I always knew you were
destined for some badass shit.
(chuckles)
Just like a little
cocaine princess.
(chuckles)
It's a long way from
counting money in Culiacán.
Yeah.
I learned cryptocurrency...
Banking without cash.
- No shit.
- (chuckles softly)
Then I made an enemy, so...
we fled to Phoenix.
I bought a winery as
front for the business
and a plane.
I'm learning how to fly.
(inhales deeply)
Oh, Jesus, that's
the kicker right there.
You started to solo yet?
Soon.
I'm gonna be your
first passenger.
- Okay. (Chuckles)
- Can't wait.
(brooding music)
♪
Hello, Teresa.
It's good to see you here.
You like the surprise?
♪
I picked you up...
when this rat left you for dead.
♪
I housed you.
I protected you.
No.
You sent James to kill me.
I hear that he
works for you now.
He followed his
dick right back to you.
And now you share
a house... and a bed.
But he couldn't
protect you from me,
so here we are.
You see, eventually,
we all have to pay for our sins.
♪
You killed Epifanio.
And you allowed me to
watch him die in my arms.
♪
Your need for power
is what got Epifanio killed.
♪
It wasn't me.
I have an employee
who hacked into your
Cayman Islands accounts.
By now, he knows
you've taken me.
He's been instructed to
transfer 10 million pesos
from Sinaloa State
Bank into one of them.
After that, he'll make
the transfer public.
You expect me to
believe that shit?
You know what will happen
when Sinaloa discovers
you're just another
dirty politician.
(exhales softly)
(suspenseful music)
♪
(indistinct shouting)
(breathing heavily)
You're going to watch...
the love of your
life die a slow... ♪
And painful death.
A death of 1,000 cuts.
♪
GUERO: No, no!
- (blade slices)
(Guero yelling)
(haunting music)
♪
(Guero breathing heavily)
And, Teresa...
there's not a damn
thing you can do about it.
♪
It's okay.
I mean, what are the chances
that I could find a house
with an airplane hangar in it?
You moved your
other girlfriend in first.
(soft wistful music)
♪
We got a pool house
around the corner.
We can take afternoon naps.
We can... I mean, we
can do whatever you want.
(chuckles)
Come on, check out the inside.
- I can't believe this.
- Believe it.
Check this out. This
is my favorite part.
It's a bedroom.
I mean, it's not
much now, but...
It's perfect.
♪
Messing with
Camila's accounts...
that was smart.
She wants revenge more
than the power or the money.
It will only buy us time.
Well, that's what we need.
And Cortez... he thinks
he's got it all figured out.
He's got locks on every door
and guards 24-7.
But he can't control everything.
♪
(speaking Spanish)
- (laughs)
- (speaking Spanish)
♪
(breathing heavily)
I have to stay alive.
Shh, shh, shh.
Para Teresa.
♪
(speaking Spanish)
GUERO: The doctor couldn't
watch me suffer anymore.
Now that you're
here, we've got a shot.
Every night...
one of the guards...
he goes out,
and he calls his
mom on the phone,
leaves the other guard alone,
and that's when we strike.
♪
(birds chirping)
(speaking Spanish)
-(door opens)
CORTEZ: Isabela, wait...
I'm in a meeting, Isabela.
I need to speak with you, alone.
It's important.
Is there something you
want to talk to me about?
Some big news?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Kique told me you have Teresa.
His father told him she's here.
(sighs)
Why did I have to
hear it from him?
You promised you'd tell me.
She killed my father.
I deserve to see her today.
I don't think it's a good idea.
That prison is no place for you.
I'm not asking for
your permission.
I know where she is,
and I have the right.
CORTEZ: Isabela,
your mother has said no.
(dark music)
If I spoke to my
mother like that,
I would not be
standing here right now.
My father would kill me.
That disrespect can lead
to serious consequence.
This is between me and my mom.
She's right.
This is family business.
I won't have you
threatening my daughter.
My apologies.
♪
- (door closes)
- (sighs)
You heard my decision.
♪
Isabela... (door closes)
(sighs)
(insects chirping)
(José speaking Spanish)
(dramatic music)
GUERO: He's on the
phone. We need to go now.
♪
- Keep an eye on him.
- Mm-hmm.
♪
(grunting)
Okay.
♪
(Guero breathing heavily)
Oye!
(speaking Spanish)
(Chuy speaking Spanish)
♪
- (groans)
- (lock clicking)
(grunts)
♪
(shouting, grunting)
JOSE: Oye. ¿Qué está pasando?
(gunshot)
♪
(lock rattling)
Come on.
♪
Isabela, put the gun
down. Guero, it's okay.
We got to get out
of here, Teresa, now.
It's okay.
You took my father from me.
The person to blame,
Isabela, is your mother.
Okay?
I will kill you.
♪
(whimpering)
GUERO: There's a car out back.
- Come on, let's go.
♪
CAMILA: That's Isabela's car.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
♪
(tires squealing)
CORTEZ: (speaking Spanish)
♪
(gunshots)
CORTEZ: (speaking Spanish)
♪
- ¿Está bien?
- Sí.
♪
-(pop) GUERO: Shit.
Damn it, the tires.
(engine sputtering)
(dramatic music)
♪
TERESA: You okay?
- Yeah, come on, let's go.
TERESA: (groans) We
need to get you to the doctor.
♪
Tomás's clinic is close.
He'll help me.
♪
(footsteps running)
Isabela... (sniffles)
(sobbing) Teresa got away.
Are you okay? Are you hurt?
- No.
- Come on.
(sobs) I tried to kill her.
(sniffles) And I couldn't.
- I'm so sorry, Mom.
- Shh, shh. Shh. Shh.
(solemn music)
I told you not to come here.
(scoffs) I said I was sorry.
You disrespected me.
There will be serious
consequences.
This wasn't about you.
- I did it for me.
- Really?
You're forbidden
from seeing Kique.
That's crazy. We're
getting married.
Not anymore.
The wedding's off.
Until you learn how to
make better decisions,
I'm making them for you.
♪
I'm doing what's best for you.
You'll thank me one day.
-Come on. ISABELA: No!
♪
You just want me to
spend the rest of my life
by your side...
just as miserable and
alone... as you are.
(music intensifies)
♪
(tires squealing)
(tires screech, engine revs)
CAMILA: Teresa
and Guero nearly took
my daughter from me tonight.
Isabela may hate me now,
but eventually she'll understand
that what I did
was best for her.
No.
It is I who failed you both.
You kept me out of harm's way,
and for that, I'm grateful.
Their escape is not your fault.
I'm just thankful
that Isabela's all right.
Maybe it was meant to be.
I promise you,
I will not relent until I
lay Teresa at your feet
like hunted prey.
♪
I have no doubt
you'll bring her to me.
You're my most loyal soldier.
It's rare when a man
can find a woman
so worthy of his
complete loyalty.
Thank you, General.
♪
Are your soldiers
searching the area?
Teresa and Guero
are fleeing on foot.
They won't get far.
(speaking Spanish)
♪
(speaks Spanish)
(tense music)
♪
- Okay?
- Yeah.
(pounds on door)
- Hi.
- Doctor, I'm sorry.
We didn't have... we didn't
have anywhere else to go.
He won't stop
bleeding. Please help us.
Come inside, come on.
(groaning)
That's a bad cut.
It's close to the artery.
- You're Teresa?
- Yes.
Thank you for helping us.
WOMAN: (speaking Spanish)
- (baby whimpers)
(speaking Spanish)
(baby babbles)
We're leaving as soon as we can.
Is there a phone I can use?
TERESA: Thank you.
(cell phone beeping)
(cell phone buzzing, beeps)
Yeah?
TERESA: It's me.
Teresa.
Are you okay? Where are you?
I'm safe.
I'm in a town just
outside of Culiacán.
I'm with Guero.
I'm with Pote. We
just landed in Sinaloa.
We've got some of Boaz's
men. We've been looking for you.
-Boaz? JAMES:
I'll explain later.
Where exactly are you?
I'm in a clinic in Imala.
- She's in Imala.
- Oh, that's close by.
JAMES: All right,
we're on our way.
Please, hurry.
♪
POTE: Is she okay?
-She's with Guero. POTE: Guero?
I thought that pendejo was dead.
JAMES: I guess not.
♪
How's your hand?
If there's trouble, I
need to count on you.
♪
I'm good... now.
Quit driving like
a pinche viejita...
and go.
(music builds)
Thank you.
(Guero breathing heavily)
(grunts, groans)
(relaxing music playing)
♪
What's this?
We're celebrating.
Hey.
- My birthday is tomorrow.
- I know this.
But I got to make a
run for Epi tomorrow.
♪
I got you a present, though.
What is it?
It's the deed to the house.
It's yours.
♪
No, I can't take this.
This is too much.
No, no, listen, if
anything were to happen,
I want you to have that.
♪
It's getting cold.
TOMAS: You two are lucky
you got here when you did.
Guero's lost a lot of blood.
(scalpel clanks)
I need more gauze.
- I'll be right back.
- Thank you.
Listen, James and
Pote are in Mexico.
They're coming to help us.
So it's true. You and James
are working together again?
- Yeah.
- You didn't have to call him.
We made it this far, didn't we?
- Yeah.
- Just you and me, babe.
- We got this.
- I know.
(pounding on door)
CORTEZ: Doctor,
I need to see you!
Do you have a back door?
Okay.
(tense music)
-Come on. This way?
CORTEZ: Doctor!
- (pounding continues)
- (Cortez speaking Spanish)
♪
TERESA: We need to
hide until James gets here.
Let's go.
(pounding continues)
Doctor, I know you're
in there. Open the door!
♪
(both speaking Spanish)
(breathing heavily)
It seems I might
have injured my wrist.
Maybe something for the pain.
TOMAS: Perhaps
you pulled a muscle.
I can wrap it up just in case.
Was there a problem
in your prison?
Guero escaped.
Someone slipped him this.
You know anything about it?
TOMAS: No.
Could've been one of the guards.
CORTEZ: No.
They're both dead.
Guero and his woman...
killed them both.
Teresa Mendoza, I'm
sure you heard of her.
She murdered our beloved
governor, Epifanio Vargas.
- She did?
- In cold blood...
in front of his wife and child.
Well, I'm sure you'll find them.
(ominous music)
You have, uh,
another patient
here this evening?
♪
TOMAS: Excuse me?
A patient cut herself
making dinner.
Forgot to clean up.
I hope you won't inform the
health department, General.
♪
CORTEZ: Was your wife here
when this other patient came in?
She's visiting her mother
this week with the baby.
I'm here stuck alone, eating
quesadillas three times a day.
♪
What a shame.
All alone... with
your quesadillas.
♪
(grunting)
(tense music)
Should I ask your wife
who else you're hiding?
(speaking Spanish)
♪
- El doctor Tomás...
- (gun cocks)
(breathing shakily)
Such a good, good man.
♪
(gun cocks)
(tense music)
♪
(glass shatters,
tear gas hisses)
(people yelling outside)
- It's James and Pote. Let's go.
- (guns firing)
(dramatic percussive music)
♪
I'm here.
Okay, let's go.
♪
(grunts)
Listen, Cortez will follow us.
You have time to go, okay?
Get as far away as
you can, all right?
Gracias, señor.
(guns firing)
(both breathing heavily)
♪
(man shouting in Spanish)
We have to make
a run for it, okay?
I'll be right next to you.
- Let's go.
- Yeah, go.
♪
Ah! (Groans)
- Are you okay?
- I got hit!
Cover me!
♪
- (explosion)
- (guns click)
♪
Come on, let's get out of here!
We can't leave him.
Come on, help me out.
Vamos!
♪
(guns firing)
(gunshots)
♪
- (groaning)
- (murmuring)
The bullet just grazed
you. It's gonna be okay.
(groans) It hurts like a bitch.
- I know.
- (groaning, chuckles)
(stammers, speaking Spanish)
Hey, James, thanks
for helping us out, man.
Hey, Pote, it's good
to see you, too, man.
Looks like you lost
a little bit of weight.
(speaking Spanish)
Is he coming to Phoenix with us?
Yeah.
All right, we need
another guy at the winery.
And Teresa's been
shopping for planes, so...
we could use another pilot.
Listen, whatever you
guys need, I'm all-in.
(solemn music)
(watch rattling)
♪
EPIFANIO: Camila, don't do this.
And, please, take
your ring back.
I made up my mind.
(soft music)
If you need to expand
the business in Dallas,
I can send Batman
to run the operation.
Batman is not a businessman.
He'll run the entire
organization into the ground.
Camila, I love you,
and I need you by my side
to run the campaign
for governorship.
The people love you.
Having you on my arm will
win me all the votes I need.
♪
You just want to keep
me under your thumb.
I'm not that woman.
I thought you knew that.
You want to throw a
25-year marriage away,
then so be it.
Good luck in Dallas.
I won't be there to protect you.
I don't need you.
I can protect myself.
♪
(scoffs)
Camila, you are
like fire on steel.
You know how to make
the most challenging men
bend to your will.
I speak from experience.
Use that gift.
It might keep you safe.
♪
POTE: There's a Taco Bell.
Does anybody need a chalupa?
No.
How about one of
those tall slushies?
It's like a bump of coke, man.
It'll keep you awake
all the way to Phoenix.
I'm good, thanks. (sniffs)
How about you, Teresita?
I'm good, thank you.
Guero, do you need something?
Guero?
Pote, he's not
breathing. Guero...
-(car beeping)
TERESA: Guero? Guero?
Guero... (somber music)
♪
(wistful guitar music)
Here you go.
- Is it all for me?
- (chuckles)
No, it's for us.
It's your favorite...
Tres leches from that
place that Brenda likes.
♪
- Mmm.
- How is it? (Speaking Spanish)
Mmm.
♪
Hey, so, listen, I know
you've had it rough,
all right, but you don't
have to worry anymore.
Okay, what's mine is yours.
I know you feel weird about
me giving you the house, but...
(speaking Spanish)
♪
Come here.
CORTEZ: Gobernadora.
You don't have to
say it, General, I know.
Teresa's gone.
I'm sorry.
You know, your
devotion... to me...
it's not about power
or about money.
I know that now.
You have become... family.
I really hope that's true.
Please... sit.
Pozole.
I don't cook often,
but that happens to be
one of my specialties.
(dark music)
♪
(speaking Spanish)
You have become
a very good friend
to me, Alberto.
Maybe we can be more.
I mean, I'm still
mourning, and...
I need to take things slow,
if that's okay by you.
Of course.
I'll follow your lead.
♪ Yo vivo para ti
♪ Para ti, para ti
♪ Pensando solo en ti
♪ Solo en ti, solo en ti
♪ Rebuscándote no vez ♪
♪ Me he dejado de querer ♪
♪ Yo me arriesgo
para ti ♪ Para ti, para ti
♪ Nada puede ser sin ti
♪ Yo sin ti, yo sin ti
♪ Eres mi razón de ser
♪ Fantasía de mi edén ♪
♪ Quiéreme ♪ Te
lo ruego ♪ Eres tú
♪ La raíz de mi fuego ♪ Para mí
♪ No hay otro deseo ♪ Que besar
♪ Tu piel de terciopelo
(woman vocalizing)
♪