WE HAVE BUSINESS,
YOU AND I, HMM?
WE HAVE BUSINESS?
THERE IS NO NEED
TO SHOUT BETWEEN US.
WE'LL CONDUCT
OUR BUSINESS
LIKE GENTLEMEN.
NOW TELL ME.
TELL ME.
HERE.
THIS, I THINK,
MUST BE THE PLACE.
GOOD DAY
TO YOU, LAD.
MAY WE HAVE
SOME WATER?
WATER IS FREE.
FREE. FREE, YOU SAY.
AH!
NOT SO. NOT ALWAYS.
EVEN THIS YOU'RE
BUILDING A FENCE AROUND.
YOU CAN HELP ME, SIR.
I'M LOOKING FOR
AN ORIENTAL GENTLEMAN
VERY CLOSE
TO YOUR AGE...
A MAN ABOUT YOUR HEIGHT,
NOT TOO FAR FROM YOUR WIDTH.
WHAT WOULD YOU WANT
WITH SUCH A MAN?
WELL...
WHEN I FIND HIM...
I'LL TELL HIM!
Master Kan: YOUR TREAD
MUST BE LIGHT AND SURE,
AS THOUGH YOUR PATH
WERE UPON RICE PAPER.
IT IS SAID A SHAOLIN PRIEST
CAN WALK THROUGH WALLS.
LOOKED FOR,
HE CANNOT BE SEEN.
LISTENED FOR,
HE CANNOT BE HEARD.
TOUCHED,
HE CANNOT BE FELT.
THIS RICE PAPER
IS THE TEST--
FRAGILE AS THE WINGS
OF THE DRAGONFLY,
CLINGING AS THE COCOON
OF THE SILKWORM.
WHEN YOU CAN
WALK ITS LENGTH
AND LEAVE NO TRACE,
YOU WILL HAVE LEARNED.
UNH!
HA HA HA!
BRAVO, CLARENCE!
AAH!
OOH!
DROP IT. DROP IT.
DROP IT, I SAID!
BLOOD HAS NO PART
IN THIS.
MAGNIFICENT.
MAKING FOOLS
OUT OF MY FOOLS.
IF THE FIGHTING'S
DIRTY,
THESE TWO ARE
WORTH A PLATOON
OF MERCENARIES.
THEY'VE DEFENDED
THEIR DISHONOR
IN SALOONS
FROM SAN FRANCISCO
TO MADAGASCAR,
AND NOBODY EVER DID
WHAT YOU DID
TO THEM BEFORE.
I'LL STAKE
MY LIFE ON IT.
YOU'VE THE BRAND
OF THE TIGER
AND THE DRAGON
ON YOUR ARMS, EH?
YOU ARE
KWAI CHANG CAINE.
AND IF I AM?
I AM BRANDYWINE GAGE,
CAPTAIN GAGE,
ASHORE FROM THE SHIP
PEKING LADY.
RUMP-SPRUNG
AND CALLOUSED
WHERE NO MAN OUGHT
TO BE CALLOUSED.
THIS BRACE
OF SURLY DOGS--
MY FIRST MATE
CLARENCE MURPHY...
AND TRAN CHOU.
HE COULD PEEL A POTATO
AT 20 YARDS
JUST BY HATING IT.
YOU'RE ANGRY, LAD.
THIS SHOULD
MAKE AMENDS.
WHAT IS IT?
MORE THAN YOU EVER
DREAMED ABOUT, LAD.
AH!
KWAI CHANG CAINE,
I'VE A RING FOR YOU,
AND A NAME.
YWANG KYU.
MEAN ANYTHING, EH?
MASTER KYU?
YES?
THERE IS
AN INJURED MAN
AT THE GATES.
ARE YOU THE OLD MAN
WHO HEALS?
I AM HE.
IT IS GONE.
COME.
LET ME SEE IT.
YOU DESERVE IT,
DRUNKEN FOOL.
NO ONE DESERVES PAIN.
AAH! UNH.
ALL WILL BE CARED FOR,
BUT YOU MUST DO
JUST WHAT I TELL YOU.
YOU MAY SEE HIM
TOMORROW.
I HAVE WORK TO DO,
AND SO HAS HE.
WE SHALL DO
WHAT WE CAN.
COME.
YES...I KNOW HIM.
OLD TEACHER
OF YOURS, EH?
YOU HAVE NEWS OF HIM.
HE IS WELL?
HE'S DEAD, LAD.
THE YELLOW HOUSE
IN TOWN, CAINE.
AFTER YOU'VE
READ YOUR LETTER,
COME SEE ME.
"WE, BY THE GRACE
OF HEAVEN, EMPEROR...
"INSTRUCT ALL MEN
TO NOTE THIS, OUR EDICT.
"THE PRIEST
KWAI CHANG CAINE,
"CONDEMNED TO DIE
FOR CRIMES AGAINST OUR
IMPERIAL THRONE, HAS--"
YES?
IT'S ME--ELLIE.
YOU DIDN'T COME
TO SUPPER.
YOU ARE VERY KIND.
YOU'VE CHANGED THINGS
AROUND HERE, CAINE.
I DIDN'T EVEN SEE
WHAT THINGS LOOKED LIKE
AFTER FATHER DIED.
THINGS SEEMED
SO HARD TO GET DONE,
LIKE THAT FENCE.
YOU MAKE IT LOOK LIKE
A WHOLE RANGE CREW'S
BEEN WORKING ON IT.
IT WILL SERVE.
IT'S THE BEST FENCE
IN THE COUNTY.
WHAT DID THOSE FELLOWS
WANT THIS MORNING?
THEY BROUGHT ME THIS.
WHAT IS THAT?
A PARDON...
FROM THE EMPEROR
OF CHINA.
YOUR MEN ARE
SHOOTING AT ME.
BELAY THAT!
THIS IS NONE OF MINE.
STAY DOWN.
CHING, YOU'RE
A BLOODY, BLOODY FOOL!
YOU ALMOST
RUINED EVERYTHING!
YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW IT.
I OUGHT TO HAVE YOU
FLOGGED TILL THE WHIP
CRIES "MERCY."
YOU ARE MY HUSBAND,
AND I BELONG TO YOU,
AND YOU MAY WHIP ME
IF IT PLEASES YOU,
BUT I'LL SHOOT HIM AGAIN
IF I GET A CHANCE.
CHING, YOU...
AH.
KWAI CHANG CAINE?
I AM HERE.
CATCH.
HA HA HA!
THERE WILL BE
NO MORE SHOOTING.
COME IN.
AH, MR. CAINE.
UH.
COME ALONG, THEN.
COME ALONG.
HA HA HA!
I'D LIKE YOU TO MEET
MY MISCHIEVOUS,
MOST DEAR WIFE,
THE LADY CHI CHING.
SHE IS OF THE ROYAL COURT
AND NIECE
TO THE EMPEROR HIMSELF.
CHING, BE A LOVELY GIRL,
WILL YOU,
AND APOLOGIZE
TO MR. CAINE
AS YOU MEET HIM,
EH, MY SWEET?
I WISH TO PLEASE
YOU, MY HUSBAND,
BUT DO NOT ASK ME
TO APOLOGIZE
TO THAT MURDERER.
Man: HE'S JUST KILLED
THE ROYAL NEPHEW!
GET THE GUARD!
Master:
DID YOU KILL HIM?
YES, MY MASTER.
YOU MUST LEAVE
THE COUNTRY.
Gage: THE BOY
YOU KILLED,
THE NEPHEW TO THE EMPEROR--
HE WAS HER BROTHER.
THEY WERE VERY CLOSE.
I...AM SORRY.
THERE, YOU SEE?
HE'S A PROPER GENTLEMAN,
SO I MUST INSIST,
DEAR WIFE, APOLOGIZE.
WE MAY BE BARBARIANS
IN AMERICA,
BUT WE DON'T
GO AROUND SHOOTING
ONE ANOTHER...OFTEN.
I AM SORRY,
KWAI CHANG...
THAT I TRIED
TO SHOOT YOU...
AND MISSED.
I'M AFRAID THAT
WILL HAVE TO DO,
EH, OLD FELLOW?
IT WILL DO.
NOW TO BUSINESS.
CAN I HAVE
MY PISTOL BACK,
PLEASE?
AH, AH, AH, AH.
NO MORE OF THAT.
GIVE IT HERE.
NOW YOU GO THERE
AND SIT DOWN
LIKE A GOOD LITTLE PRINCESS
AND BEHAVE YOURSELF.
SO, KWAI CHANG,
YOU READ
THE EMPEROR'S DECREE.
I DO NOT UNDERSTAND.
HE HAS SWORN
TO SEE ME DIE.
AYE...
AND NOTHING WOULD
PLEASE HIM MORE,
BUT LIKE ALL MEN
GREAT AND SMALL,
TROUBLE CAME TO HIM.
HIS NEWEST BRIDE--
PRETTY LITTLE GIRL--
MU LING,
CAME DOWN WITH
THE BRAIN FEVER,
DON'T YOU SEE?
WELL, HIS MAJESTY
ANNOUNCED
WHOEVER COULD CURE
MU LING
SHOULD HAVE
WHATEVER HE DESIRED.
YOUR OLD SHAMAN
YWANG KYU CAME ALONG
AND CURED HER
RIGHT UP,
AND WHAT HE DESIRED
WAS FORGIVENESS FOR YOU.
THIS IS TRUE?
AS TRUE AS I'M
STANDING HERE.
WELL, THE EMPEROR
WAS OUTRAGED AT FIRST
HAD YWANG KYU
THROWN OUT OF THE PALACE,
BUT THEN...
THEN?
THEN...
THEY STRUCK A BARGAIN.
Gage: AH!
THE EMPEROR INSISTED
THAT ROYAL HONOR
DEMANDED A BEHEADING,
AND THEY SO AGREED.
OF WHAT USE
IS SUCH A PARDON?
WHAT IS PARDONED,
MY HEADLESS BODY?
PLEASE, LISTEN TO ME.
NOT YOUR HEAD, LAD.
A TOKEN,
A SMALL BEHEADING.
THE SMALL FINGER
OF YOUR RIGHT HAND.
THEY AGREED.
THAT'S ALL.
WHY THAT?
OH, WELL, THE EMPEROR
WANTED MORE, BELIEVE ME.
HE'S NOT
A CHARITABLE MAN.
NO, THIS WAS
YWANG KYU'S IDEA.
HE SAID...
THAT YOU
WOULD UNDERSTAND.
Injured man: BECAUSE
I WAS A RASCAL AND A FOOL,
I GAMBLED AWAY
ALL THE MONTH'S RENT
FROM MY TENANTS,
BOUGHT...
WINE FOR EVERYONE,
PAID THE FLOWER GIRLS
FOR THEIR SONG.
THERE WAS NOTHING LEFT.
AT LAST...
THEY GOADED ME INTO IT!
I BET MY FINGER.
MAU THREW THE DICE...
AND I LOST!
IT HURTS, MASTER KYU!
IT HURTS!
AND WHAT
WOULD YOU HAVE WON
IF THE DICE
HAD BEEN OTHERWISE?
4 PIECES OF SILVER.
AS MANY AS I HAVE
FINGERS LEFT!
AND WITH THE 4
PIECES OF SILVER,
YOU WOULD HAVE
BOUGHT MORE WINE
AND FLOWER GIRLS,
WOULD YOU NOT?
THEN PERHAPS
WITH THE FINGER,
YOU HAVE BOUGHT
WISDOM,
AND THAT WOULD
BE WELL WORTH
THE PRICE.
YOU SAY YWANG KYU
IS DEAD?
YES.
COGNAC?
NO. HOW DO YOU
COME BY HIS RING?
GIVEN TO ME
BY THE EMPEROR,
ALONG WITH THE PARCHMENT
I PUT IN YOUR HANDS.
THERE IS SORROW
IN YOU, LAD,
FOR THE DEATH
OF THE OLD MAN,
AND THAT
DOES YOU CREDIT,
BUT YOU AND I
ARE ALIVE,
AND SO I ASK YOU,
ARE YOU READY TO LEAVE?
LEAVE?
AYE, LAD.
LEAVE. GO HOME.
TO CHINA.
MY SHIP LIES
IN THE BAY,
LOADED AND PROVISIONED
FOR THE ORIENT,
AND I AM LIKE
A BEACHED WHALE
IN THIS BARREN LAND,
DYING FOR A SPLASH
OF WATER AND SALT AIR.
WHAT IS TO HOLD YOU?
WHY, YOU, LAD.
IT'S FREE PASSAGE
I'M OFFERING YOU.
WELL, LAD?
FIRST...I MUST DECIDE
IF I WISH TO PAY THE PRICE.
THE PRICE? HA HA!
MMM, THE WAY
THE WORLD IS,
THIS BIDS FAIR TO BE
A BARGAIN FOR YOU.
EVERYTHING
YOU EVER WANTED--
FRIENDS, HOME, FREEDOM.
YOUR GOOD NAME--
AND ALL IT COSTS--
A LITTLE FINGER.
THEN I MUST DECIDE
IF YOU SPEAK THE TRUTH.
Gage: HMM.
NOT TO OFFEND YOU,
CAPTAIN GAGE,
BUT IT WELL MAY BE
YOU MEAN TO BETRAY ME.
WHY SHOULD I DO THAT?
I DO NOT VALUE
MYSELF VERY HIGHLY,
BUT I BELIEVE THE EMPEROR
HAS MUCH TO GIVE
TO A MAN WHO WOULD
BRING ME TO HIM.
OH, LAD,
YOU DON'T KNOW,
AND IT'S NOT
FOR ME TO TRY
AND CONVINCE YOU.
WITH OR WITHOUT YOU,
WE LEAVE TOMORROW
AT NOON.
WE SAIL ONE HOUR
AFTER WE'RE ONBOARD,
AND IT'S ALL THE SAME TO ME
WHETHER YOU'RE ONBOARD OR NOT.
MAY I SPEAK
TO THE LADY?
WHY?
I BELIEVE I MAY
LEARN THE TRUTH.
LAD, THE MINUTE SHE
SETS EYES ON YOU,
SHE FIRES A CANNON
IN YOUR DIRECTION,
AND YOU'RE LOOKING
FOR THE TRUTH
FROM HER?
YES.
WELL...
GO AHEAD, THEN.
TALK TO HER.
IS THIS TRUTH?
AM I PARDONED?
Chi Ching: HOW CAN
YOU BELIEVE ME,
WHATEVER I SAY?
YOU KNOW I HATE YOU.
IF I SAY IT IS TRUE,
THE PARDON MAY BE FALSE.
YOU WILL GO
BACK TO CHINA...
AND DIE.
AND THAT
WOULD PLEASE ME.
AND IF I SAY
IT IS FALSE,
THE PARDON
MAY BE TRUE.
BUT YOU
WILL STAY HERE
AND LIVE AMONG
THOSE BARBARIANS,
BARRED FOREVER FROM
YOUR NATIVE LAND.
AND THAT, TOO,
WOULD PLEASE ME.
YOU HAVE NOT ANSWERED.
THE LETTER YOU HAVE READ
IS AS IT IS,
AND IT WAS WRITTEN
UNDER MY UNCLE'S ORDER.
DO YOU BELIEVE ME?
YES.
WELL, THEN, LAD,
COME ALONG.
I'LL SEE YOU OFF.
YOU WERE MAGNIFICENT.
HOW ARTFULLY YOU PICKED
YOUR WAY AROUND THE TRUTH.
I DID NOT LIE.
MY UNCLE IS
INDEED THE AUTHOR
OF THIS TALE
THE FOOL BELIEVES.
BRANDY,
WOULD THE AMERICAN
EMPEROR DO
SUCH A THING?
LIE? MAKE
A FALSE PROMISE?
MY DEAR CHILD...
GO ASK...
ASK AN INDIAN, EH?
AN EMPEROR...
IS AN EMPEROR,
BY ANY NAME
YOU CALL HIM.
THEN HONOR IS
A CHILDREN'S GAME.
AND WE ARE RICH.
YOU SHOULD HAVE
LET ME SHOOT HIM.
WITH TWICE THE REWARD
OFFERED FOR HIM ALIVE?
IT'S THROWING
MONEY AWAY.
YOU TELL ME THAT
NO CHAIN WILL HOLD
THIS SHAOLIN PRIEST,
NO MAN MAY TAKE HIM,
AND YET YOU BAIT
A TRAP WITH WORDS.
IT'S THE ONLY WAY,
MY PET.
HE'LL WALK ONTO MY SHIP
BECAUSE HE WANTS TO,
AND HE'LL STEP UP TO
THE EMPEROR'S CHOPPING BLOCK
BECAUSE HE PROMISED.
AND IF HE DOES NOT?
HEH, IF HE DOES NOT...
IF HE DOES NOT...
WELL...
IF HE DOES NOT,
WE'LL SHOOT HIM,
EH, LADS?
Injured man: I'VE LOST
TOO MUCH ALREADY! AAH!
THE FIRE HAS
ENTERED THE HAND
THROUGH THE WOUND,
AND THE HAND
IS DEAD ALREADY,
AND IF WE DO NOT
REMOVE THE FIRE,
YOU, TOO, MAY DIE.
DID YOU HEAR ME?
LIU, LIU, I'VE DONE
ALL I COULD,
BUT THE SPIRIT OF
THE FINGER IS CALLING
TO THE HAND,
IF WE DON'T
GIVE IT, THE SPIRIT
WILL BE ANGERED
AND MAY EVEN
DEMAND MORE!
THE SPIRIT?
HAVE YOU SEEN
WAS IT HERE?
IT IS HERE,
AT THE WINDOW!
AAH!
AAH! DRIVE IT AWAY!
DRIVE IT AWAY!
AAH! AAH!
NO, YOU CANNOT
HAVE MY HAND!
HOW CAN I WORK?!
YOU LOOKING FOR THIS?
IT HAD A TEAR IN IT.
I PATCHED IT.
IT HAD NO TEAR.
YES, IT DID,
ON THE BUTTON.
YOU MUST THINK
I'M AN IDIOT.
NO.
I JUST WANTED TO SHOW
MY APPRECIATION.
FOR WHAT?
FOR EVERYTHING YOU'VE
DONE AROUND HERE.
YOU FEED ME,
GIVE ME A PLACE
TO SLEEP.
IT IS AS IT WAS
AGREED.
BUT IT SEEMS
SO CHEAP.
I WANT TO DO SOMETHING
USEFUL FOR YOU.
USEFUL?
COOK, CLEAN, SEW--
ALL THE THINGS
A WOMAN CAN DO.
YOU DO NOT BELIEVE
IN YOURSELF?
OF COURSE I DO.
THEN WHY DO YOU NEED
TO PERFORM FOR ME?
I DON'T WANT YOU
TO THINK THAT I
TAKE YOU FOR GRANTED.
YOU KNOW, THAT PAPER
WITH THE PARDON
FROM THE EMPEROR...
IT MADE ME REALIZE THAT
YOU WEREN'T TIED HERE,
THAT YOU HAVE YOUR OWN LIFE
AND YOUR OWN INTERESTS,
AND WHATEVER THEY ARE,
THEY DON'T CENTER
AROUND THIS RANCH
OR WHAT HAPPENS TO IT.
NOTHING HERE
TO HOLD ME?
ONE WORN-DOWN
LITTLE FARMHOUSE
AND A FEW ACRES
OF LAND...
A FEW HEAD
OF STOCK.
I KNOW WHAT I HAVE.
I KNOW WHAT I AM.
YOU DO NOT KNOW
WHAT YOU ARE.
TELL ME.
YOU ARE...ELLIE.
OH, WHAT'S ELLIE?
A NAME.
A WOMAN.
A PERSON.
THERE ARE A LOT
OF WOMEN IN THE WORLD,
A LOT OF PEOPLE.
BUT ONLY ONE ELLIE.
ALONE...
AND FIGHTING.
FIGHTING FOR WHAT?
YOU LOOK
INTO THE MIRROR,
AND YOU SEE
ONLY YOURSELF.
WHAT ELSE IS THERE?
YOU ARE ALONE...
AND SEPARATE,
BUT YOU ARE ALSO
PART OF THE LAND...
PART OF
THE PEOPLE...
PART OF THE WHOLE.
EVERYTHING IS
WITHIN YOUR REACH.
WHERE DO YOU FIT
IN ALL THIS?
I ALSO AM...
IN PART
OF THE WHOLE.
WITH ME?
WITH YOU.
YET WE'RE APART.
WE ARE JOINED.
ARE WE?
CAINE?
YES?
I'VE NEVER MET
ANYONE LIKE YOU
BEFORE.
ABOUT LAST NIGHT,
THE WAY I CAME IN--
YOU MUST THINK
THAT I--
I THINK
YOU ARE...ELLIE.
YOU'VE DECIDED TO
GO, HAVEN'T YOU?
GO?
BACK TO CHINA.
I DO NOT KNOW.
WELL, THERE'S
NOTHING TO
KEEP YOU HERE.
THERE'S A GREAT DEAL.
THEN WHY GO?
I HAVE
ASKED MYSELF THAT.
THERE IS MUCH HERE
THAT I HAVE LOVED--
LAND...AND PEOPLE.
HALF MY LIFE IS HERE,
AND THROUGH MY FATHER,
MY ROOTS.
BUT CHINA...IS HOME.
WHAT MUST WE SAY
OF THE MIRROR
THAT RECEIVES
TRANQUILITY...
YET REFLECTS
TROUBLEMENT?
THE MIRROR I SPOKE OF
WAS YOU, STUDENT CAINE.
IT IS NOT FOR MYSELF
I AM TROUBLED, MASTER,
BUT FOR THE
SICK MAN, LIU.
IF HE DOES NOT ACCEPT
THE LOSS OF HIS HAND,
HE WILL DIE.
DID NOT YWANG KYU
MAKE THIS CLEAR TO HIM?
YES, MASTER, BUT...
YES?
SHALL WE NOT ACT
IN SPITE OF
THE OBSTINACY
OF THE SICK MAN,
WHEN INACTION
MAY DESTROY HIM?
IS IT YOUR FEELING
THAT YWANG KYU IS NOT
FORCEFUL ENOUGH?
I HAVE ASKED MYSELF
THAT QUESTION.
LOOK TO THE WATER
AT YOUR FEET.
DOES NOT THE SAGE SAY,
"WHAT IS MORE YIELDING
THAN WATER?
"YET BACK
IT COMES AGAIN,
"WEARING DOWN
THE RIGID STRENGTH
"WHICH CANNOT YIELD
TO WITHSTAND.
WHAT IS MORE FORCEFUL
THAN QUIET WATER?"
LOOK AT THEM.
HOW CAN YOU TRUST THEM?
GIDDY-UP.
I'M NOT ASKED
TO TRUST THEM.
STOP HER.
WHOA.
SO...YOU ARE
CAINE'S WOMAN.
MY HUSBAND
SPOKE ABOUT YOU.
I'M THE WOMAN
HE WORKS FOR...OR DID.
HE HAS THEN DECIDED
TO COME WITH US?
YOU'D BETTER
ASK HIM THAT.
SAY, WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
CHI CHING.
CAINE TOLD ME
ABOUT YOU.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
A PRINCESS BEFORE,
BUT YOU LOOK
LIKE ONE.
YOU DO NOT DRESS
LIKE THE OTHER
AMERICAN WOMEN.
WHY IS THAT?
I HAVE TO WORK
FOR A LIVING,
THAT'S WHY.
YOU ARE
A PEASANT, THEN?
I WOULDN'T SAY THAT.
I OWN 100 ACRES OF LAND,
AND I HAVE
NEAR 20 HEAD OF HORSES
AND MANY CATTLE.
THAT IS VERY MUCH.
YEAH, TOO MUCH FOR ME
TO HANDLE MYSELF.
YOU PEOPLE ARE TAKING AWAY
A GOOD HAND
AT A BAD TIME FOR ME.
IT WOULD ALWAYS BE
A BAD TIME FOR YOU
TO TAKE CAINE AWAY.
YOU CARE ABOUT HIM
VERY MUCH.
NOW, WHAT WOULD YOU
KNOW ABOUT THAT?
I'VE SEEN THE WAY
YOU LOOK AT HIM.
I AM A WOMAN, TOO. WHAT I
DON'T UNDERSTAND IS HOW YOU
COULD CARE SO DEEPLY--
WHO SAID I CARED--
SO DEEPLY
ABOUT A MURDERER
AND A CRIMINAL.
I'VE KNOWN A LOT OF MEN,
AND NOT MANY
DECENT MEN AMONG THEM.
THIS MAN CAINE IS
THE DECENTEST, KINDEST
MAN I'VE EVER KNOWN.
WELL, PRIEST,
WHAT HAVE YOU DECIDED?
I HAVE MADE
NO DECISION.
IS IT THAT YOU
DO NOT TRUST ME?
I AM CERTAIN YOU
CANNOT TELL A LIE.
WELL, THEN?
I HAVE RECEIVED
A PARDON FROM
THE EMPEROR.
NOW I NEED A PARDON
FROM HIS NEPHEW,
YOUR BROTHER.
BUT HE IS DEAD.
YOU KILLED HIM.
THAT IS WHY
I ASK HIS PARDON.
HOW CAN YOU ASK PARDON
OF A DEAD MAN?
HAVE YOU NOT
SOMETIMES TALKED
WITH THE DEAD?
YOUR ANCESTORS?
WHAT HAVE THEY
TO DO WITH THIS?
IT IS THE PRINCIPLE
I SPEAK OF.
DO YOU THINK
HE WILL HEAR YOU?
IF HE THINKS ME
WORTHY.
POOR PRIEST.
YOU DO NOT
THINK ME WORTHY?
I THINK
YOU'RE A FOOL.
IS ANYTHING
WRONG, LADY?
WRONG? WHAT
SHOULD BE WRONG?
I DON'T KNOW,
LADY.
SILLY GIRL.
DID I SAY ANYTHING
WAS WRONG?
NO, LADY.
THEN STOP PRATTLING
AND COME AND FIX
MY HAIR.
WELL, LAD,
WHAT'S YOUR ANSWER?
STILL SUSPICIOUS?
I BELIEVE, CAPTAIN,
THAT YOUR WIFE
CAN ONLY SPEAK
THE TRUTH.
WHICH IS AS MUCH TO SAY
THAT I DO NOT?
I MEAN NO OFFENSE.
I WILL NOT SURRENDER
MY FINGER.
LAD, THAT'S NONE OF MY DOING.
I HAVE NO USE
FOR THAT KIND--
DOES THAT MEAN
YOU'RE GOING?
IF YOU HAVE ROOM
FOR ME, I WILL GO.
SPLENDID.
Woman: OH! LADY!
THE DEMON!
Gage: MURPHY, TRAN CHOU!
QUICK! UPSTAIRS!
WHY DID YOU SCREAM?
I COULD NOT HELP
MYSELF, LADY.
TO SCREAMS ERUPT
FROM YOUR BODY,
THEN, AT WILL?
WHEN I SAW
THE DEMON UPON
THE WINDOWSILL--
IT WAS NO DEMON.
BUT, LADY, IT WAS.
DID YOU NOT SEE
ITS EYES?
I SAW.
IT WAS THE EYES
OF A DEMON.
FOOLISH GIRL,
DEMONS ARE FOR CHILDREN.
DON'T YOU KNOW THAT?
IT WAS...
WHAT?
NO MATTER.
TAKE THE BOXES
DOWNSTAIRS.
DO YOU BELIEVE THAT BIRD
WAS THE SPIRIT
OF MY DEAD BROTHER?
DO YOU?
YOU ASK TOO MUCH,
PRIEST.
YOU EXPECT
A MURDERED MAN
TO FORGIVE
HIS MURDERER.
WHO ELSE CAN?
ISN'T IT ENOUGH
TO BE PARDONED
BY THE EMPEROR?
IT IS A GREAT HONOR.
IT IS VERY GENEROUS
OF THE EMPEROR
TO PARDON YOU
IN THAT WAY,
DON'T YOU THINK?
TO FULFILL
A PROMISE.
HE DIDN'T HAVE TO
KEEP HIS PROMISE.
AN EMPEROR DOESN'T
HAVE TO DO ANYTHING.
UNLIKE SEA CAPTAINS'
WIVES, WHO HAVE TO LEARN
THE VIRTUE OF SILENCE.
WE HAVE HIM, LOVE.
WE DO NOT WISH TO
FRIGHTEN HIM AWAY.
YOU SEE, THE TRICK
IS TO GET HIM
IN MOTION.
ONCE UNDERWAY,
HIS MOMENTUM
WILL CARRY HIM
TO THE SHIP,
THEN THERE
IS NOWHERE ELSE
FOR HIM TO GO
BUT TO THE CHOPPING
BLOCK.
YOU SHOULD'VE
LET ME SHOOT HIM.
NO, NO, NO,
MY LOVE.
THAT WOULD
GET IN MY WAY.
YOU'RE A PRINCESS.
DON'T LET
HIS FOOLISHNESS
UNNERVE YOU.
DO NOT CALL IT
FOOLISHNESS.
WHAT IS IT, THEN?
SPIRITS AND DEMONS?
A SPIRIT
IS NOT A DEMON.
AND A CROW
IS NOT A SPIRIT!
AND IT WAS A CROW,
A SIMPLE, UGLY BIRD.
THE LAND
IS FULL OF THEM.
CHI...
ARE WE QUARRELING
OVER A BIRD?
YOU KNOW, MY LOVE,
I WOULD GLADLY
EXCHANGE THIS CROW...
ANYTIME...
FOR MY CROW'S NEST...
AND CHINA.
BUT DO NOT FORGET
HOW MUCH
A GRATEFUL EMPEROR
CAN DO FOR US.
MY LOVE.
KWAI CHANG, YOU
ONLY DECIDED TO COME
WHEN I TOLD YOU
WHO WROTE THE PARDON?
YES.
MY HUSBAND TOLD YOU
THE SAME THING.
DID YOU NOT
BELIEVE HIM?
NO.
YET YOU BELIEVE ME?
YES.
WHY SHOULDN'T
I LIE?
YOU HAVE
NO NEED TO LIE.
BUT I MIGHT LIE.
ENOUGH!
BUT I DIDN'T.
OH, LADY!
THE DEMON!
AAH! MAKE HIM GO!
MAKE HIM GO!
I'LL DO AS YOU SAY!
YOU CAN HAVE MY HAND!
BUT IT MAY BE TOO LATE.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
I DON'T CARE.
TRY THE GODS.
I BEG OF YOU--
GO TELL MASTER KAN,
AND GO TO THE LAUNDRY
AND GET CLEAN RAGS. HURRY.
Gage: KILL IT.
DO NOT SHOOT.
YOU HAVE ORDERS, MAN.
PUT THE BEAST
OUT OF HIS MISERY.
NO. IT IS THE SPIRIT
OF MY DEAD BROTHER.
IT'S THE WART
ON MY GREAT-AUNT'S NOSE.
PUT IT AWAY, MURPHY,
WITH A BULLET DOWN
ITS UGLY GIZZARD.
NO!
DO IT, MAN, NOW.
PLEASE.
Murphy: FINE SHOOTING,
CAPTAIN.
NOT BAD, EH?
HAVEN'T LOST
THE TOUCH.
MURDERER.
YOU KILLED HIM!
USE YOUR HEAD,
PRINCESS.
IF THIS WAS
A SPIRIT,
COULD A BULLET
HAVE BROUGHT
IT DOWN?
BY YOUR OWN
LIKES, MY PET,
THIS WAS NO
ROYAL-BLOODED,
IMPERIAL SPIRIT
TO COME TUMBLING
DOWN LIKE THAT.
NAY, ME LOVE.
AAH!
KWAI CHANG,
IT IS ALL A LIE.
THERE IS NO PARDON.
IF YOU GO BACK TO CHINA,
YOU WILL BE KILLED.
I KNEW YOU WOULD
NOT LIE TO ME.
A CROW,
AFTER ALL.
I AM SORRY.
I WOULD HAVE WISHED
IT WERE TRUE.
THE EMPEROR DID
WRITE THOSE WORDS,
BUT HE DIDN'T MEAN
TO HONOR THEM.
THAT'S WHY I TRIED
TO KILL YOU.
YOU REALIZE, ME BUCKO,
I CANNOT LET YOU GO.
WHY?
AH, I RISKED
MY GOOD NAME
WITH THE EMPEROR
TO WIN HER.
SHE'S PART
OF THE PAYOFF,
DON'T YOU SEE?
AN ADVANCE,
SO TO SPEAK.
I'VE INVESTED
TOO MUCH.
TOO MUCH
BEAUTIFUL PLANNING
TO LOSE IT NOW.
THE OLD MAN'S RING,
THE ARTFUL LITTLE THING
ABOUT THE FINGER.
POTENTIAL, EH?
IT WAS WHY
I BELIEVED YOU.
NO MATTER WHY,
CHANG CAINE.
WE HAVE AN APPOINTMENT
IN PEKING.
PLEASE,
INTO THE COACH.
I WOULD BE FOOLISH
TO DO SO.
BELAY THAT.
THIS IS FOR ME.
Liu: MASTER KYU,
I WAS SO MUCH
TROUBLE FOR YOU.
YOU WERE
MUCH MORE TROUBLE
FOR YOURSELF, LIU.
I SEE NOTHING
TO GIVE THANKS FOR.
I BROUGHT YOU MY HUSBAND,
WHO HAD A HAND AND AN ARM,
AND YOU RETURN TO ME A MAN
WHO IS HALF HIMSELF!
WOMAN, BE STILL.
AND YOU, BOY,
THANKS FOR KEEPING VIGIL
SO LONG WITH ME.
MASTER.
Liu: COME, WOMAN.
MASTER...
WHY WAS THE SPIRIT
NOT SATISFIED
WITH LIU'S HAND?
THE SPIRIT
MIGHT HAVE BEEN,
BUT LIU HIMSELF
HAD NOT DONE
WITH GAMBLING.
HE REFUSED,
AS WE RECALL,
TO LET ME HELP HIM.
I DO NOT UNDERSTAND.
WHAT DID
THE SPIRIT WANT?
THAT WE MAY NOT KNOW,
ONLY WHAT THEY DO.
BUT IT SEEMS CLEAR
THAT THE FINGER
WAS LOST FOOLISHLY,
AND THAT ANGERED
THE SPIRIT OF THE FINGER,
TO BE RIPPED
WANTONLY OFF
WITH SO MANY GOOD YEARS
OF WORK LEFT IN IT.
BUT TO TAKE THE ARM
AND SAVE THE LIFE,
THAT APPEASED THE SPIRIT,
FOR IT WAS A GOOD LOSS.
THE SPIRIT DECIDED
TO LET LIU LIVE.
SOMETIMES WE MUST LOSE
PART OF A GAMBLE
IN ORDER TO WIN
IN THE END.
MASTER, LIU MIGHT
NOT HAVE CONSENTED
TO THE LOSS
OF HIS ARM...
EXCEPT FOR
THE APPEARANCE
OF THE CROW.
YET THE CROW
DID APPEAR.
AND ON THE FLOOR
OF THE SICKROOM,
I FOUND THIS.
LIU BELIEVED
IN HIS DEMONS
BY HIS OWN CHOICE,
NOT BY OURS.
IF THE APPEARANCE
OF ONE OF HIS DEMONS
HELPED HIM MAKE
THE RIGHT CHOICE,
THEN WE CAN ONLY
BE GRATEFUL
FOR THE WAYS
OF PROVIDENCE.
CAN WE NOT?
ALRIGHT, LAD.
IT'S OVER.
THERE IS A TIME
WHEN EVEN AN EMPEROR
MUST BE DISOBEYED.
I AM SATISFIED
THAT THE AFFAIR OF HONOR
BETWEEN US IS OVER.
I'VE NEVER MET
A MAN LIKE YOU.
HA HA HA.
I SWEAR, I ADMIRE YOU
MORE THAN I CAN SAY,
BUT...
WHEW!
I WOULDN'T BE YOU
FOR ANYTHING IN THE WORLD.
WILL THEY BE
IN TROUBLE WHEN
THEY GET HOME?
THE EMPEROR
IS VENGEFUL,
BUT THEY HAVE
EACH OTHER,
AND THEY HAVE
THE SHIP.
Ellie: I GUESS THE FENCE
WILL NEVER BE FINISHED.
I WILL FINISH IT
BEFORE I GO.
DON'T.
YOUR HORSES
WILL STRAY.
LET THEM.
WILL YOU EVER
COME BACK?
LIFE IS LONG.
WILL YOU EVER
BELONG TO ANYONE?
NO MAN CAN
GIVE HIMSELF AWAY.
I WOULD.