The boomslang was stolen
from the zoo last night.
It's extremely dangerous.
Father.
Any news on my grandson?
No change.
He has not woken up.
A father's job is to protect his family.
When Wataru was on that roof...
when he was pushed...
where was his father?
Wataru is lucky.
You never know what horrible fate,
your bad luck has saved you from.
Hope you enjoy the show.
Bullet Train
Thank you for taking
the job on such short notice.
I am ready.
You are getting
the new and improved me.
Since I have been working with Barry,
I am experiencing a calm like...
never before.
Never.
Like, I am less reactive to situations,
I am more accepting
of people's shortcomings.
I was a little uncertain
about coming back to work,
but it's like Barry says.
If you put peace out in the world,
you get peace back.
I think your new
therapist might be forgetting
what you do for a living little ladybug.
Ladybug?
Your new operational name.
Really?
You don't like it?
You like it?
I like it.
Well, if you like it, alright.
I see what you are doing.
Ladybugs are supposed to be lucky.
You don't have bad luck.
Really?
My bad luck is biblical.
I am not even trying to kill
people and someone dies.
That's an exaggeration.
It is? My last job?
The political blackmail photos?
Remember the suicidal bellboy
climbed to the roof of his hotel,
could not take it anymore?
Seems more like
his bad luck than yours.
Hang in there buddy!
And he didn't die.
Ok? You drove him to the hospital.
It's good luck.
All in how you frame it.
Sure.
Gotta say I like it here.
I could live here.
I like the atmosphere,
the people are considerate.
Except for that guy.
Why is this job paying so well?
It was supposed to be Carver's,
but he has got some stomach thing.
Carver?
You know and he doesn't do
snatch and grabs.
I am filling in for Carver?
Yo-You picked me second to Carver?
You said you wanted simple
for your first job back.
Doesn't get simpler.
Shit.
Shit what?
I think I must have lost
the key when that guy bumped into me.
What's the number again?
Five twenty three.
Carver.
What an ego.
I mean, talk about a candidate
for self improvement.
I mean, calling in sick?
I mean, what is that, high school?
I can hear that personal growth.
I know I am being judgmental.
I need to...
work on that, but Jesus...
what a douche bag.
You have the strangest requests,
firecrackers?
I am industrious.
Please tell me you didn't
order the sleeping powder.
Nope.
You almost gave that bodyguard
in Anchorage a heart attack.
I have worked on the dosage.
Take the gun.
Ticket please.
Hai.
Thank you for using our train.
First class is that way.
Hai. Domo.
I am gonna assume
you didn't take the gun?
Barry says every conflict
is an opportunity for a peaceful...
what was it?
And your handler says
some conflicts require a gun.
Shit.
Ok I am on.
Well that's a start.
Hey, this is nice.
Economy?
You know, I am thinking
of starting my own agency.
You know, all simple jobs, all the time.
That's a terrible business plan.
No more sociopaths, no more maniacs.
Just quality people.
Barry says it's time for some change.
I think he is right.
Barry does not know
what you do for a living.
Ok, here we go.
The bullet train has 16 cars.
Ten economy, six first class,
and remember, only one minute
stop at every station.
Bloody fucking hell.
Do you mind?
What is he, fucking blind or something?
Hey, hey, hey. Come on.
Oh, come on nicking.
No it's just...
You don't have to nick the biscuits man.
XXX
Oh no. We alright.
Ok cool. Thank you.
Fucking asshole.
Why did I do that?
It's like I got a compulsion or something.
I have to take it if I see it.
Need to talk to someone.
Serious.
A goldfish biscuit?
I mean, I don't, I don't understand it.
Ok, simple snatch and grab.
What am I snatching and or grabbing?
A briefcase.
Intel says there is
a train sticker on the handle.
Briefcases have owners.
Owners are not simple.
And last update says
the owners will be in economy class.
Owners, plural?
Why didn't you tell me to bring that gun?
I did.
You chose spiritual enlightenment.
Please.
Ticket.
Hold on.
No, no, no.
Receipt.
Shit, I think I dropped my ticket too.
That receipt shows
I bought a ticket though, right?
One stop.
Yep.
Dōmo arigat...
I thought they bowed here.
I PUSHED HIM. FIRST CLASS, SEAT B4
Sorry kid. Excuse me sorry
I am looking for...
You found her.
Oh lemon.
Tangerine.
You are bleeding mate.
Oh mate shit.
Oh shit man.
Oh fuck.
Who the fuck did I kill?
Get a wet one on it or something.
Oh, it's not mine mate.
Oh, it's not yours?
Yeah I don't bleed. I don't bleed.
Oh, in that case,
just leave your jacket open,
let everyone have a good old look.
Yeah, I want everyone to see my tie.
Yeah, yeah.
Fuck is wrong with you?
Pull your coat together
so no one else notices lemon.
I think they will notice
the childish code names first.
But if we are gonna stick with fruit
why not apple or orange?
So, what's in this case?
Are we doing this?
You know what's in the case.
Money.
It's always money.
Tangerines are sophisticated.
Oh, now he is calling a fruit sophisticated.
Yeah, it's cross hybridized with other fruit.
They are adaptable.
Like me.
You said, six cars in economy, say...
30 passengers per car,
guessing two bags per, let's see...
times two and you carry...
Yeah, no fucking way.
I am gonna find one brief...
Wait.
What?
Train sticker on the handle?
Yeah.
Holy shitbox.
And why am I lemon?
Because you are sour.
No one likes lemons.
That's bollocks mate.
Lemonades, lemon drops.
You got a sore throat?
Lemon meringue pie.
When was the last time
you ate a lemon meringue pie?
Lemon drizzle cake.
I am sorry, are you talking about lemons?
I have the case.
Well, that's great.
Is it?
Yes.
What's the catch?
There is no catch.
There is always a catch.
Get off the train.
Quite like lemons, I just hate code names.
Oh, well look at this.
Sleeping beauty.
Wakey-wakey.
Eggs and bakey.
Where am I?
You are safe now.
Your father sent us.
You idiots work for my father?
Oh, easy.
We could deliver you back
to your pops in a box.
Technically we...
are outside contractors.
I am Tangerine.
He is Lemon.
Like the fruit?
You ever watch, Thomas the tank engine?
Here we go.
Hey, you watch something nowadays,
what is it?
Nothing it's twists,
violence, drama, no message.
What's the point?
What are we supposed to learn?
Everything I learned about people
I learned from Thomas.
Oh, yeah? And you bring
your sticker book, did you?
I always bring my stickers with me,
you know that.
Take tangerine here.
He is a Gordon, this blue one.
And Gordon is the strongest,
the most important,
but he doesn't always listen to others.
What's that now?
I mean, some people are Edwards.
Wise, kind.
Some are Henrys.
Hardworking, strong.
Some people are Diesel.
Fuck me!
Those are trouble.
You though...
Yeah you...
seem like a Percy.
Young.
Sweet.
Not all there.
You finished both of you?
Yeah.
Alright, your daddy,
hired us to get you out of the trouble
you got yourself into,
didn't you naughty boy?
Why are you tangerine though?
Oh, it's sophisticated mate.
Oh, fucking hell.
It's not important, is it?
What is important are the 17 dead
bodies we left getting you back
from the triad that kidnapped you
with the plans to ransom you
to your extremely psychotic
fucked up father.
Actually it's 16.
What's that now?
Sixteen kills mate.
No it was 17.
It's... 16.
Lemon, you are starting to get on my tits.
It's 16.
I will smash my fucking head
through a brick wall.
That had help your memory,
because it was 16.
What the fuck is wrong with you man?
It was 17, goddamn it!
I want to fuck strangle you now.
You mind if we do this now?
We will get it sorted.
Oh, don't worry about him.
Could not give a shit.
Go ahead.
One.
Two and three.
Five guys playing poker.
Keep moving!
Big guy.
Yeah big guy.
Ten.
Three assholes with swords.
Fucking get it.
Fuck!
Why do you always bring swords?
Fucking triad.
I mean you would, would not you?
You son of a bitch!
I like swords actually.
Looks like it's time for a Jaffa cake.
How about a wagon wheel?
Oh, that works.
Swing!
Fourteen, fifteen.
And the prick on the motorcycle.
So 16.
You forgot the poor
innocent civilian on the street.
Fuck you.
Hey buddy.
Hey, buddy.
You ok? Oh my...
Shit.
That was not our fault.
That was not our fault. No.
Was not our fault?
Well, what would Thomas
the tank engine say, Lemon?
That's really mean.
He would say,
hey take responsibility mate.
He doesn't sound like that.
Gonna put a little distance
between me and the owners.
Are you nervous?
Yeah, I am nervous.
You sound nervous.
Because I am in fact nervous.
Hey listen,
I am just gonna get off at the next stop.
Oh, let's have a seat then.
Do you know what they call
your Papushka?
Course I fucking do.
The White Death.
Not exactly a fruit.
No. There you go.
There is a story...
Stop me if you have heard it...
Where this woman found herself
in the unfortunate position
of owing your father a tidy sum of money.
Now, the issue was
it took her some time
to acquire this money.
But she did pay it back
five minutes late, didn't she?
Yeah, what did he do?
Cut their arm off.
Fucking hell!
Yeah.
He said she owed him a finger
for every minute.
Anyway, he is not a monster.
He didn't make her sit
through it five times.
He just cut once didn't he?
This is too easy.
You are over thinking it.
You are under thinking it.
It's not a word.
Yes, it is.
Really?
I think it is.
Did you Google it?
Doesn't matter.
What would Barry say?
Barry would say,
a negative outlook
leads to a negative outcome.
How much do you pay him again?
Our job is to keep you safe,
and to recover the briefcase
with the ransom money inside.
And I plan on completing my job
and keeping...
Lemon.
Where is the briefcase?
Oh, I stashed it.
The case lemon.
Go get me the fucking case.
You are a liability, you know?
To my father.
He doesn't need a reason
to kill people like you.
He needs a reason not to.
Does he have one?
That's fucking confusing.
Hello?
Do you have White Death's son?
What, you mean this dickhead
with the silly face tattoos?
Yeah, he is sat right here.
And the briefcase?
Yes, of course,
I have got the case.
You will both deboard at Kyoto station.
Then your business with him
will be concluded.
It was just here.
Well, it's not anymore.
We need to find the person
who took that case.
Maybe you are right.
Maybe my luck is starting to turn.
You.
Yes.
Me.
But you...
are Yuuichi Kimura.
And you came here
to kill me.
My parents call me Malenkiy Prince.
That means little prince.
Obviously, they wanted a boy.
You are going to hear the whole story,
or you will be...
very...
Very sorry.
It's the hospital.
Hang on.
Hi.
Yes, you can see the boy now.
Good.
If you don't hear
from me every ten minutes
or if I don't answer this phone
when you call...
I want you...
to go in there and kill...
I am sorry, what's your boy's name again?
Wataru.
Right.
Kill Wataru.
Aren't we glad we waited?
We got his son.
That was our job.
Our job was to come back with his son,
and his 10 million dollars.
Three words describe
our situation right now.
Do you know what they are?
Deal. Saved his son.
Family is more important than money right?
Do you honestly not know,
who the White Death is?
Yeah.
I know the White Death.
You just told me five minutes ago.
He cuts off arms puts them...
Why do I even bother forwarding you,
the briefings?
I do not know.
The Japanese underworld
used to be ruled
by a man named Minegishi.
Now Minegishi,
was one brutal bastard.
But he was old school, you know?
Tradition and loyalty
was all that mattered to him.
When you were in, you were in.
You were like family.
He treated you like
you were one of his own.
Then out of the blue...
comes this 6 foot fucking
6 geezer from Russia.
Whispers that he was exiled from
the Russian mafia
or that he was ex-KGB.
No one really knows the truth.
But what is known...
is this Russian...
Worked his way up the ranks.
Bit by bit, kill by kill.
And very, very fucking quickly
became one of Minegishi's
closest advisors.
And those loyal to him said,
hold your horses.
This geezer ain't the full ticket.
He ain't to be trusted.
He is dangerous they said.
A modern plague they said.
A White Death.
So, sure enough they were right.
He made his own alliance.
His own gang.
And what did he do?
Stabbed him in the back.
I mean metaphorically.
Blew his fucking brains out didn't he?
He wiped the name Minegishi
off the face of the earth
in one single night.
And made an empire
worthy of the White Death.
So,
let me put this bluntly.
There is this soulless psychotic leader
with the largest criminal
organization on the planet
shoved right inside our fucking ass cheeks.
That motherfucker is definitely a Diesel,
then isn't he?
If you mention Thomas
the tank engine one more time,
I am gonna shoot you in the fucking face.
Ok, ok, if-if he is such a badass,
how come he hired two random operators
Instead of getting his son back himself?
Because if you actually read the briefings,
you would know that he had a wife.
What he had a wife?
Yes.
She was the most important
thing in his life,
and she died.
Drunk driving accident or some shit.
And now he is at the compound
and he ain't left since.
An unnamed locomotive
might say there is a lesson
to be learned.
Listen and he didn't hire
two random operators Lemon.
But no he asked for the best.
He asked for the two responsible
for the Bolivia job.
He asked for pros
who would not fuck up.
Three words Lemon.
We are...
Fucked.
What do you want?
People think that
I am just some young girl.
Someone is future wife or...
Future mother.
But I am not in someone else's story.
You are all in mine.
The fuck does that have to do with me?
You work for the most
feared boss in the city.
The White Death.
Oh, deny it all you want.
But you work for someone
who works for someone else,
et cetera, et cetera,
and it all falls under the same person.
You delivered a briefcase two days ago
to one of the White Death's associates...
And I saw my opportunity.
Follow the case and find the White Death.
Don't know what you think
I can do for you.
Oh, that is my favorite part of the story.
You are going to kill him for me.
How the fuck...
am I going to kill the White Death?
You will see.
Oh, look at that.
We are right on schedule.
Sit back, relax a little bit.
You look so tense.
We rescued his fucking son?
We find the fucker
who took the briefcase,
make things right,
be like it never happened.
Never happened.
You still got that vest on you?
Oh no, vests give you
a false sense of security.
You might like, get shot in the neck.
Yeah, it also stops you from
getting shot in the chest,
but, I guess you missed that
episode of Thomas, did you?
I really must have, because
that sounds dark as shit.
Nut up or shut up bro.
Well so,
slight change of plans.
First his wife, now his son?
That's a lot of white deaths.
I want you to be strong, son.
Do you understand?
Sí.
Be strong.
My heart.
No!
Find me the son of a bitch who did this.
You lucky son of a bitch.
You stabbed me?
You ruined my life.
I don't even know you!
I come here for revenge.
The assassin who killed El Saguaro.
Killed my wife.
But fate made this
a two for one special.
Can we just...
take a timeout here?
Talk this out?
I will never stop coming for you.
What?
Run as far as you like.
I will find you.
Why?
And I will ruin your life
the way you ruined mine.
Dude, I don't even know you!
My heart.
What the...
Really?
Let this be a lesson in the toxicity of anger.
Venezuela,
Uruguay,
Barcelona.
Who are you?
Alright mate, try these.
They are the Momonga glasses.
The fuck is a Momonga?
Comes on after Thomas every Thursday.
Ok.
It's good.
Just like that.
He should look asleep, you know.
There, like that.
Like that? Right.
Wasabi.
We got to make sure he doesn't
step a foot off this train.
You see the case,
deal with whoever has it.
Alright, how do I do that?
Talk to him or like...
talk to him?
I don't know, why don't you tell him
about the story about
how Gordon met Percy
and how Percy is now bleeding
from his fucking eye sockets!
He means kill him.
Fuck. Dammit.
Well, excuse me.
You are fucking excused.
Arigatou.
Konnichiwa.
Joburg.
I am sorry buddy.
Give...
give it!
Shit balls.
That was not a minute.
I missed my stop.
Why?
Because god hates me.
No, she doesn't.
Do you still have the case?
Yeah, I stashed it.
Get off at the next stop.
It sounds so easy when you say it.
Does the name El cigarillo
mean anything to you?
El Saguaro?
The cartel boss?
Yeah, why does that sound so familiar?
He was in the wedding
you infiltrated in Mexico.
Tequila?
You were the cocktail server.
The groom.
I knew I recognized that guy.
I am really good with faces.
Wait, what guy?
Sorry.
Be right back.
The guy who stabbed me.
I spilled wine on his suit.
He is dead now.
You killed the wolf?
It was an accident.
I am really gonna have to process
my part in the incident on Monday.
Shit.
Fuck! No.
Shit, fuck, what?
Remember those two wackos
from the Bolivia job?
Killed all those people?
The twins?
Yeah, I am not so sure they are twins.
Stop it.
Everyone knows they are twins.
Well, one of them is walking
towards me right now.
I think I saw the other on the platform.
Occupied!
Well, now we know who
the owners of the case are.
See, this is exactly what I am talking about.
We have to have a hard
discussion about the caliber
of people we are surrounding ourselves with.
Why are you whispering?
Hello.
The white death would like to know
why you stepped off train.
Wanted some fresh air.
Your orders were to stay on the train.
I didn't realize I was getting a
babysitter to come cut my bollocks.
I am a professional.
We are making sure the case
and his son are perfectly safe.
Can I please go do my job now?
If something has gone wrong...
Oh, very kind of you.
Thank you very much.
Fuck me!
Jesus Christ.
It's very rude, talking on the phone,
on the train.
In Japan.
This rude enough for you, fucking prick?
Shove that fucking hat up your
fucking asshole you hear me?
Fuck this job.
I knew we should have got
an upgrade, fuck all.
I beg your pardon, sorry. I...
Was not aware there was a
young lady present. Apologize.
Yeah, you didn't happen to see someone
come by with a silver briefcase, did you?
There is a little train sticker
by the handle.
Actually, yeah.
A man with black framed glasses had it.
He went that way.
Thank you Love.
That fucking bastard.
Come on.
Hi.
There is a gun under this...
This is the quiet car.
Gotta use your small
inside voice in here son.
There is a gun underneath this table
pointed right at you, so I would...
I can't really hear what you are saying.
There is a gun...
I am just fucking with you mate.
It's been a long time since Johannesburg.
Yeah.
Who the fuck are you?
Really?
You don't remember me?
You look like every white
homeless man I have ever seen.
Ok.
Well, I have something
I believe you are looking...
Really? You don't remember me?
I am sorry mate.
I remember Johannesburg,
but I don't remember you, alright?
You shot me.
I shoot a lot of people.
You shot me twice.
Well, you also have a shoot able face.
I know you are black framed glasses.
The cheeky fucker
who took our briefcase.
Yes.
Yes, I am.
You know, I have done a lot of
personal work since Joburg.
I have forgiven, I have moved on.
I have learned that
with any potential conflict
there is an opportunity for growth,
a path to a peaceful outcome.
Interesting.
Who is that?
I have no idea.
How did you know that was there?
Didn't I mention?
I have always been lucky.
It was then, that I took a long
hard look into the mirror.
And you know what?
Buddy, I didn't like what I saw.
Nope.
Nada.
Until I did.
You know?
Between us now, sits a wall.
But it's an illusion.
For within every wall,
awaits a window...
Oh wait it's...
it's a door.
Real quick...
every day is a fucking headache
with you, innit?
Right.
You and your partner...
Look, I am Lemon, he is Tangerine.
Ok Lemon... like the fruit?
Blessings.
What's your plan here?
Here is the plan.
I give you back your case,
you don't kill me.
You give your case to your employer,
he doesn't kill you.
You are alive, I am alive,
everyone is happy.
Win-win, don't you think?
How do you know...
whoever hired you won't
kill you for failing your job?
Lose-lose. No happy.
Man, I just want to get off this train,
go see a zen garden
and some shit, you know?
I would like to accept your offer.
Great. But then you went
and killed someone.
Didn't you?
How did you know?
Was not exactly subtle.
It was an accident.
Tragic.
That's a...
Bizarre even.
Cool story bro, but...
I think you had your own plans of
getting out of here with that case.
No, no.
Pinning a body on us.
Hoping the White Death is so busy
cutting off our arms instead
of cutting off our fingers.
It's like Thomas
the Tank Engine always says.
Simple is better.
The kids' show?
Yes, the fucking kid, man...
I learned everything
about people from Thomas.
Everything.
Really?
That's how I can read people like
you so well,
and you are Diesel.
I am not Diesel.
You are the dieselest Diesel
that ever fucking dieseled
Not even close.
That I have ever seen in my life man.
Because Diesels bluff, they go too far.
Man, I am trying to get Diesel
out of my life, you know?
If there was a gun under this table yeah,
I would be as dead as that kid over there.
Nope.
You mother fucker.
Have the courage to listen.
Come on Joburg.
No.
Shot number three.
No, no, no. I ain't got
the time or the patience,
let alone the interest.
Fucking hell.
Are you following me?
Stop!
Asshole.
I will call the conductor!
Eat a bag of dicks lady.
I am sorry, I am sorry.
I am, I am working on it.
I am not a Diesel, you are a Diesel.
There is another body here.
Of course there is.
Not my fault and I believe
it's The Son of the White Death.
Did the twins I.D. you?
Did you hear what I said?
White Death. Death. Death.
Snatch and grab my ass.
There is someone else
doing a job on this train.
The twins. We know that.
Again, not twins.
Loonies, but not twins.
They are here for the kid but...
somebody killed the kid.
The guy with the knife.
The wolf.
He said he came here for revenge.
He just happened to run into me,
because of course he did.
Now, get this.
The kid was poisoned in the same way
as El Sbarro was at the wedding.
It's El Saguaro.
The same killer?
Yeah.
I am like MacGyver.
Fuck!
All of Japan is in terror.
Because a poisonous snake was stolen.
Boom slang snakes.
Have a very strong poison.
When they bite...
it can cause internal bleeding...
and bleeding from holes in the body.
Oh shit.
What are you doing?
What's wrong?
Fuck this man.
Fuck Carver.
Shit.
Oh, thank god.
For a minute there...
Jesus Christ, you had a bit of a bosh pal.
Alright.
Five stations to Kyoto.
Better get ticketyboo.
Would you describe me as someone
who lives in perpetual anxiety?
No, no.
Fuck nuts.
And if it was not clear, I meant yes.
The conductor.
I don't have a ticket.
Not sure that's your biggest concern.
You don't understand,
this guy is like crissfucking angel.
He pops up everywhere.
He slows me down, Tangerine catches me,
I am dead.
Dead.
Dead...
Hold on.
Hey bro.
Want to make an easy 200 bucks?
Is this like a...
Like a sex thing?
Nope.
Oh, ok.
I was... I was kidding.
Yeah, what's up?
What do you need bro?
Momomon!
Alright, game is up big boy.
Where is the case?
Tell me and I promise,
I will only shoot you enough...
Is-is this the sex stuff?
Twat!
Shit.
I-I do love an accent.
Come on.
Oops.
Picture it.
Picture what?
Well the man.
Watching your son.
I wonder how he will do it.
Maybe...
a pillow to the face.
Or maybe something clever.
Like an air bubble in the IV.
No, no. You hold onto it.
The innocent young girl act
doesn't really get you very far
if you are holding a loaded gun.
Put it on speaker.
Father.
Yuuichi?
Why did you leave...
the hospital?
Be honest.
Who is there with you?
I found out who pushed Wataru...
off that roof.
Did you go to the authorities?
I wanted to handle it myself.
My son.
You can't control what fate,
has in store for us.
Father.
I am sorry.
We are not finished.
You are going to sit here
and you are going to go through
every combination
until you open up that case.
Kid,
that could take...
No, no. It won't.
I'd start with the low numbers.
Just a thought.
You know...
Fuck me!
There he is.
He-he got by me.
Yeah. Yeah, me too.
Well, I guess our best option now is...
bring the White Death
the man who killed his son.
Yeah, but glasses didn't do it.
I could give a rat's ass.
No I am telling you.
I read him.
He is not the type mate.
I will tell you what, do you like your arms?
You know I like my arms.
You know someone is got
to take the blame, don't they?
That's you or me?
You or me?
Shit, that asshole stole my phone.
You kidding.
And my gun, Lucille.
Oh, come on.
That's my favorite gun.
Son of a bitch.
Fuck about...
Right, what?
Step off the train at the next stop
with the briefcase and the Son.
Well, hang on mate,
didn't we say Kyoto?
You will still depart at Kyoto.
The White Death wants to make sure
you are being honest about situation.
Well, this is a waste of our t...
Alright, alright.
We just have to prove
we have a case we don't have
and a live son instead of a dead one.
What are you thinking?
The old punch and Judy.
You were all told to exit the train.
Yeah?
Well unlike you, I am a professional.
I wanted to make sure
it were not some yakuza trap,
but clearly not it's some
fucking '80s dance off, innit?
Where is your twin?
Tangerine?
I am Tangerine.
Lemon is keepin' the case safe.
And the White Death's son?
Yeah he is there.
Wave to your fucking fans Princess.
He is a fucking happy chappy, isn't he?
But, I have got to pop on the train,
you know, ten seconds left, so Tara.
We will stick to the plan, depart in Kyoto.
Do us a favor,
get the fuck off my back, will you?
Ok.
I mean, that could not have gone better.
Yeah, let's hope they buy it.
We need to find that glasses twat,
like, right to the fuck now.
I am gonna go up, you go down,
double back when you are done.
If you see him, fucking deal with him.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Up is...
That way.
Towards Tokyo.
Right.
Departing trains are always moving down.
And look, be careful.
Something else is going on here.
Yeah?
Yeah, I still feel like
there is a Diesel lurking about.
I swear to god, what did I say?
What did I say?
I said I will fucking
shoot you in...
Shoot me in the face.
That's right.
Yeah.
Thomas still taught me how
to see people, read them for real.
Yeah.
And I am never wrong, am I?
No.
Glasses, he is not our guy.
Ok.
You shoot first...
and come up with the answers later.
I always do.
And Lemon?
Yeah man?
You be careful too.
Oh, man, when this train is a rock in',
don't come a knock in' right?
Seven more minutes,
and I am off this train.
Are you hiding in a bathroom?
Yeah. Have you tried these smart toilets?
They are...
a pleasure to the senses.
If I had one in the chamber, I
would rock this bad boy right now.
Boundaries.
We need boundaries.
Holy shit.
Oh there.
Oh, look at that.
I knew my luck would rub off on you.
Fuck.
What the fuck are you doing?
I am doing the same thing
that I did to the gun in your hand.
I am just making things interesting.
I am hedging my bets, you could say.
Fuck.
If the gun doesn't kill him, the case will.
This thing could have blown up
in my hand at any point.
No. No.
It's inert unless you fire it.
But don't fire it, you know what I mean?
Unlike what I...
put in this...
briefcase here this is very...
Well, this is not inert at all.
This is...
Did you know that there have been
31 attempts on the White Death's life
from within his own organization?
Each one,
he executed with their own weapon.
Do you see what I am getting at here?
Kimura, I brought you here to fail.
You push my son off a roof.
Right.
Bring me to this train,
frame me as an assassin,
here to kill the White Death,
and use my gun
that will blow up in his face?
Very good.
Very, very good.
It's a stupid plan.
It is...
A brilliant plan.
Occupied.
You remember that mob surgeon
that died mid heart operation?
Yeah, he had a stroke, right?
No, that was the official cover.
He was poisoned.
The assassin goes by the name
of the hornet.
Oh, my god!
He used boom slang snake venom.
It congeals the blood, making
you bleed out of every orifice.
If the antidote isn't administered
within 30 seconds, you are dead.
Fun fact.
The same poison that was used on...
El Sagardo.
It's El...
Saguaro.
What is the hornet doing on this train?
Well,
whatever deal was made,
it was not done through
the normal channels.
There is something else going on here.
It's still occupied, lady.
The wolf must have figured out
who the hornet is,
came here for revenge for his wife,
his boss,
came here to whack the hornet.
Oh, my god, did you just say whack?
I did. I am bringing it back.
No, it needs to stay where it was.
If I can figure out who the hornet is,
I can give him to Lemon and Tangerine
so they don't whack me.
Really?
Se... you see what I did there?
You are really proud of yourself,
are not you?
Geez, they are usually so polite here.
Lady, I am so...
That's cool.
Come here...
Bastard!
Come here, you you dirty fucking scum!
You bastard.
Wait wait wait wait wait.
I know who killed the kid.
I could not give a rat's ass.
Where is my fucking case?
Hello.
Yeah.
Excuse me.
Oh, I am so sorry. Excuse me.
Do you want something?
Oh no, thank you.
We are ok.
Oh, I-I would love a bottle of water.
This one we have.
You know what? Do you have...
anything sparkling?
With bubbles?
Hai.
That's the one. Thank y...
Dōmo arigatō.
You are welcome.
Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
Bro, I just remembered I gave all
my money to that guy to wear my...
hat and glasses.
Could you?
How much for the bottle of water Love?
1,000 Yen.
Thank you a lot.
Oh, there. No, you are welcome.
Yeah.
A thousand yen that's...
ten quid for that bottle of water mate.
Thank you a lot.
Tara.
Excuse me.
Dōmo arigatō.
You sure you don't want to talk this out?
Not particularly, no.
Ok.
You fucking bastard!
Fucker!
Come here, you little fuck!
I know who killed the kid.
Yeah?
Where the fuck is he then?
He is on this train.
Oh well, that narrows it down,
then don't it?
Let go! Get off!
You gonna get that?
No.
You probably ought to get that.
It could be important.
Oh, ok, maybe it's important.
Fucking hell.
Come here.
Yeah, what do you want?
The White Death
says to get off at next stop
holding the briefcase
or he will kill everyone on that train.
Ok yeah, I can make it but...
Lemon, he is a little tied up right now.
Both of you this time,
with the case or everyone dies.
Fucking paranoid, this lot.
You don't happen to have
the case on you, do you?
No.
Yeah, I don't think I would reach
Lemon in time anyway.
You still got his phone.
Do you have a gun on you?
Don't like them.
Well...
Game is up mate.
For what it's worth, you seem
like a right fucking asshole
and I am glad you are gonna
fucking die with me.
That's nice.
Just curious.
Yeah?
Do they even know what Lemon looks like?
You two do look like twins?
Yeah ok.
We got the case now what?
You still take the train to Kyoto station.
Yeah.
Ok. We can do that.
Wonderful.
Hey.
Have you opened the case?
No, of course not.
Do you know what? I never asked
for the combination.
You know what I mean?
Keep it safe that way.
Yeah.
So no one gets greedy.
Oh I know, I know.
I am sorry, I am sorry, I am sorry.
I-I have this bad luck thing and
I hit the thing...
oh, is that what you call it?
And it went...
So what the...
what was that?
Why did you even bother trying?
I was trying to sell it.
I was selling it.
Well, I don't think they were in the market
for fucking dildos and pantyhose,
were they?
Ah but...
They were buying it. They...
I had them.
You proved you are
smarter than everyone.
You have won kid.
Please.
Please kid.
Call your man.
I will do what you want.
Just...
Leave my son, alone.
Your son.
Do you know how easy it was
to get him to follow me up onto that roof?
Didn't think it would take you three hours
to even realize your son...
was missing.
You are a terrible father and...
your son...
is going to pay for all the
mistakes that you have made.
You don't know anything...
about life.
How hard it is.
You are just...
Some spoiled girl,
who breaks their toys,
when mommy says she has to pick up.
Sorry.
Pardon me, I don't mean to...
interrupt what's...
going on here but...
you would not happen to have seen...
a tiny white prick with a pair of glasses
come through here, have you?
No.
What about a silver case
with a train sticker
by the handle? You seen that?
It's not ringing any...
Uncle Kkimura, have you seen
a silver briefcase with the train...
Did you say train sticker by the handle?
Yeah. On the handle...
That's...
It had a train sticker.
Unique.
No, I have not seen anything like that.
I think I would remember.
I am s...
Uncle Kimura?
Yeah.
Y... right.
Are you ok? That's...
Oh, yeah. Never shave on a bullet train,
you know what they say.
Well, could not hurt to ask, you know?
I am just gonna keep following him.
Go for it.
Yeah, no, it's alright.
Pardon me, uncle Kimura.
You guys, take care.
Just one thing, though.
Most people...
Most people assume suitcase,
you know, because it's a train,
overnight and all.
But you...
You said briefcase.
I never said briefcase.
I think...
I found my Diesel.
You know what's waiting for us in Kyoto.
We should just get off this train. Now.
If you think I am stepping off
this train without lemon or the case,
you must be mistaken.
Ok. Well, the case
is in the first class lounge.
It's behind the bar, it's in a trash can.
It's yours.
Me,
I am getting off.
I am gonna go find a...
temple and reevaluate
my choices or something.
Oh that sounds very lovely
but here is the deal.
I still need a fall guy.
Shit.
You need a fall guy.
Yeah.
No, I understand.
I-I get it.
It's a bit of a conundrum really,
because you know, I am thinking,
do I hand him back in one piece
or do I chop you up into little pieces
and stuff you inside
a fucking Momomon or not?
That's what's going through
my head right now.
Or...
Oh what?
You got a better idea do you?
You know, before us now is just a wall,
but it's an illusion man.
It's a construct.
You know, because within that wall...
sits a window.
A window of opportunity.
Dammit it's a door.
It's...
Within that wall, is a door.
I am finding it very hard
to follow this story.
My point is, that door is closing.
Now the only question is.
Which one is the Diesel,
which one is the Duck?
The duck?
It's a kids' show.
Thomas the train engine.
Close.
Thomas the tank...
engine.
Please mister.
This...
this man, he kidnapped me,
and he said that he is going,
to hold me for ransom.
I am sorry. I get captivated
by white girl tears.
Bravo.
Common sense tells me
that this old, shaky geezer here
is the one in charge,
but I am really good at reading people,
and something tells me
you are just not fucking right.
So...
let's see here.
I mean, I can't shoot you both.
Then I get no answers.
You know what,
how about this?
I am sure you will love this.
We are gonna play a little game.
If you want to play a game,
put both your hands up.
Perfect. I knew you would like this.
You are gonna close your eyes,
and I am gonna count to three.
And whichever one of you is in charge,
you are gonna raise your hand,
and whichever one isn't,
you point at who is.
Now, if you both raise your hands
or you both point at each other,
I know you are both liars
and the truth ain't in you,
and then I will fucking shoot you both.
Ready?
You you said you could not kill us both.
You would get no answers.
I did say that, didn't I?
Yes.
Sometimes you got to shoot first
and come up with answers later.
One.
Or if I don't answer
this phone when you call...
Two.
Kill Wataru.
Three.
Am I dreaming?
Sorry mate.
Not your lucky day.
I have a wire in, in my bag
and I-I think that we could...
use it to-to lock the door from the outside.
It was so scary.
He said that if I didn't do what he said,
or if I yelled or anything that he would...
do awful, awful things to me.
Then why didn't you use this, then?
Yeah, he kidnapped you and...
gave you his gun to hold, right?
No, no, no.
Easy.
No...
I... please.
I don't know how to use a gun.
I don't know.
Please.
Fuck me. You are fucking...
You are really...
good, you sure you didn't study?
I mean, you are not even afraid
and your lip's quivering.
That's a tear.
That is really authentic, mate, like...
You are the Diesel.
I got to kill you.
Please, I am just a kid. Please.
How do you do that?
I am not! I am not!
It's really unbelievable.
Please. Please.
You...
You are...
I got...
It's fucking...
You stay right there.
Did you?
What the fuck is happening?
Everyone loves lemons.
Fucking die!
I am glad you enjoyed the performance.
How did you do that?
I am not sure.
Just lucky, I guess.
Tell Tangerine that...
Tell Tangerine...
Tangerine...
He is gone.
Tangerine is gone.
Getting off this train.
I am getting that case and that's it.
Hello?
Yuuichi,
where are you?
It looks like Yuuichi lost his...
phone on the bullet train.
You can pick it up
at Kyoto station though.
Kyoto...
There is this find my phone app.
Surprisingly accurate.
Bye.
God, he has got a great walk.
Mr. Wolf.
So you came to kill the hornet.
What happened?
Are you ok?
Fuck, that thing is hot.
Momomon.
Go.
Mom on.
No lea...
Momomon.
The pastry chef.
You stole my snake, bitch.
That was your...
We should really call the authorities
because someone...
Take that punk!
Hey, bitch.
One little prick from this,
you know what happens?
Yes.
Your blood congeals,
clogging your veins.
You bleed out of your fucking eye socket.
I said yes!
Weakass bitch.
Stop.
I am taking that case.
Give it!
I was promised my money.
By who?
Don't know. It was all online.
They said my money was in the case.
What? Someone paid you
to have the kid killed
with his own ransom?
That's dark.
That is dark as...
Stop!
The hornet stings, bitch!
Lady, you can have the case.
Oh, but you have seen my face, bitch.
Thirty seconds before the venom
does its thing.
You bitch.
Oh, shit, man.
Do you have a backup?
What do you think bitch?
Oh shit man.
You don't have another one?
You got to be better prepared.
I am mansplaining,
I am mansplaining again.
I am sorry. It didn't...
Can I get you something?
You don't seem like a religious person.
Water? Would you...
Would you like some water?
No?
You want a blanket?
You want me to hold your hand?
Karma is a bitch.
Talk to me.
It's my bad luck.
It's bad luck on acid.
I-I-I-I got to get off this train.
Do you have the case?
Yes.
Are you lying on the ground
in the fetal position?
I am not on the ground.
You need to get up.
How do you always know what I am doing?
Because I know you.
I could journal.
I should journal.
Ladybug. Ladybug.
Man.
Breathe.
Deep breaths.
We are almost there.
You just need to get up.
Right.
You have been lying to me, my friend.
Well, cat's out of the bag now, innit?
You were responsible
for keeping my son safe.
For keeping my money safe.
You know, I-I don't know a thing
or two about being a parent,
but you know what I would do,
being that it's your son and your money?
I would stop crying about your dead wife,
get off your fucking lazy ass,
come here and finish the job yourself.
But as we are having a bit
of a heart to heart,
got a couple things to tell you.
Your son is a complete bell end
and fucking deserves
to be bleeding out of his eye sockets.
And as for your case,
I have not seen it since Tokyo.
And I hope someone is fucking found it,
put it all on red and having
a fucking wonderful time.
I will meet you at Kyoto station.
Oh, how wonderful.
I can't fucking wait.
I want to look into your eyes
when I kill you and your brother.
My brother.
West Ham have taken it!
West Ham one, Chelsea nil.
Morning rush hour is rolling in quite nicely.
What's your plan, mate?
You gonna fucking waltz up here
and blow my brains out
in front of the whole fucking carriage...
of witnesses?
There is no one left on that train.
I know.
I bought every ticket,
until the end of the line.
Oi.
You.
I know you.
You are that girl, are not you?
Oh, my god.
Yeah, I never forget a face me.
I am so happy to see you.
Please help me.
Oh there is this man
and he was holding me hostage.
He was wearing glasses and...
he killed my uncle.
And he also killed this other man who,
I don't know, he just kept talking about,
Tho-Tho-Thomas the trains and...
Tank engine.
Yeah, right. Exactly.
But he killed both of them,
and then he... he said he was going
to get away with some sort of money.
I don't know.
I am sorry darling I...
I beg your pardon.
I don't know who the fuck you are.
I am just a girl who was
supposed to get off at Nagoya,
and then this man, he...
That was fucking ages ago.
I know, but this man, he just said
that I could be a good backup plan
and that a pretty girl makes a good hostage.
Yeah well, he ain't wrong there
but hey look.
Keep your fucking knickers on, alright?
Please just help me.
Alright, alright. Calm down.
Get off or do what the fuck
you like.
You are free to go. Yeah, yeah.
Thank you.
It's alright. Go on.
Get that way, you are doing anyway.
Are you ok?
Diesel.
The absolutely fucking worst.
Little shitstirrer.
See...
Lemon...
God rest his soul,
was the Don...
and he could read people.
See them for who they really are.
What?
He was right.
There is been a Diesel
running up and down this train,
causing all sorts of fucking havoc.
And it was you the whole fucking time,
you dirty little Diesel!
You made Lemon bleed.
And lemon never bleeds.
Oh, my god mister!
Please help me!
Ladybug.
Please!
Please help me!
Bugger.
You little shit.
Please! What the fuck
are you doing, you bell end?
You...
Sir! Please!
What?
Diesel!
You fucking bell end!
You are a Diesel.
What the fuck?
He said that he was going to kill you
and blame everything on you.
He also said that...
there is someone waiting for us
at Kyoto station.
Someone scary,
who would hurt me.
No one is gonna hurt you.
It's ok.
We are getting off this train.
We make the next stop,
we will be fine.
Ok kid, come...
Kid, come on.
I can't.
My backpack is stuck.
What?
Leave it. Let's go.
We got to go, we got to go.
No. No, I can't.
Right now, young lady!
No.
It's our last chance.
No. No, no, no, please come back.
Kid, please.
I am scared. I don't want
to be alone, please.
I got it.
It's not your fault kid. It's...
it's my luck, not yours.
You got your whole life ahead of you.
Make sure you...
do something that brings
you peace because...
everything else is a...
pain in the ass.
And if you run into a guy named Carver,
he is a dick.
You can tell him I said so.
I...
I took this.
I didn't want to leave it.
The man had it and I thought
you could probably use it
to kill whoever is waiting for us
at the end of the line.
You are not going to let me get hurt.
Be honest.
Who is there with you?
Really?
Right.
Ok fella.
You are creeping me out,
so...
if you don't mind,
could you just find another seat like...
way, way, way down there?
And that way,
I won't have to tell you twice.
No.
You won't.
Let's just move.
Let me grab your bag.
Was that a snake?
Would you know where my son is?
Oh, fuck.
After everything.
You are the person...
who pushed my grandson
off the department store roof.
Why?
Your son.
He was going to help me
kill the White Death
at Kyoto station.
And that was the only way
to get him on this train.
The White Death.
That's right.
But he could not even do that.
So he is dead.
Just a few cars back.
They are both dead.
My grandson was pushed off a roof.
What makes you think
I would leave him unprotected?
My grandson is safe.
And my son is not dead.
Listen,
old man...
The only thing you know
about an old man young lady,
is that he has survived much more,
and much worse,
than you.
I will fucking kill him myself.
Are you alright?
That?
You are not gonna believe
this coincidence but I...
already got a dose of
antivenom in me today, so...
I am good.
Probably.
The girl...
Her intentions with you,
were not honorable.
Yeah.
A blind man could see
you are the one in the dark.
I don't know about a blind man.
She was pretty convincing.
What did you do to her?
I did not need to do anything.
Fate will do what it wills.
Why...
Why do you laugh at fate?
Man...
fate for me is...
just another word for bad luck.
And that...
That follows me around like...
I don't know, something witty.
My handler calls me Ladybug.
She is witty.
Ladybug?
Yeah.
This is very lucky, indeed.
No, she is being ironic.
She...
Never mind.
I am going to tell you a story now.
No I am good.
It's short.
Really I am fine.
No
it's very quick.
No, no.
It's a good story for you, I think.
I am cool.
Here we go.
A long time ago,
I made a promise to myself...
that I would provide for my family
no matter what it cost.
I had risen to a highly coveted position
within the Minegishi crime family.
A man raised up to take my place.
A man from the north.
I asked Minegishi,
not to trust this man.
Minegishi told me...
I had lost my appetite.
He was not wrong.
But neither was I.
I returned home
and I found nothing,
except ash and blood.
The White Death had taken
everything from me.
Almost.
Yuuichi!
Yuuichi.
I went into hiding.
I searched for a way
to strike at the White Death
without endangering what I had left,
but he remained forever out of reach.
I did not think...
fate would ever give me
a chance to make things right.
Do you know what they call
a ladybug in Japan?
Tentōu mushi.
As a boy,
I was told there is a spot on its back
for each of the seven sorrows
of the world.
You see...
Tentōu mushi is not lucky.
It holds all the bad luck
so that others...
may live in peace.
II don't want to hold the seven sorrows.
Everything that's ever happened to you
has led you here.
Fate.
Well, that's a shit deal.
At Kyoto station,
the White Death,
will arrive on this train.
I will finally be allowed
to make things right.
My son is a few cars up.
If you could escort him off this train...
Yeah, I don't see the White Death
letting any of us off this train.
You let me worry about the White Death.
Ok.
Mr. Ladybug?
Your briefcase.
Thank you.
Father.
I don't understand.
It is fate my son.
Wataru?
He is safe.
Well,
he seemed like a decent guy.
He shot me.
Me too.
Twice.
Still, he had another side to him...
Oh, man.
Am I in hell?
Fuck.
Fucking vest man.
Oh, you drank the water.
Where the fuck is my brother?
Man.
You...
You were more like Thomas anyway right?
Fellas.
We need to come up with a plan.
You killed my brother.
You killed my brother, you piece of shit!
Yeah, you, you, you fucking shot me!
I will shoot you in
the fucking throat next time,
Hey!
And your partner Keira Knightley!
Hey! Hey! Fellas!
I will shoot the fuck out of her!
When we are so quick to anger,
we are slow to understand.
Yeah, well, I am fast
to kick your ass though,
I swear to God.
Fucking piece of shit!
I should have put a bullet through
your fucking ass!
When you point a finger
at someone in blame,
there are four fingers pointing back at you.
Three.
That's weird.
Fuck it!
That's it!
You know what I could do!
We before me!
Get off! Get the fuck off me!
You before fucking God!
Gentlemen!
Get off me!
A plum, does not resent the hungry man,
but the farmer, who planted the tree.
He resents the...
Resents the farmer?
So how do plum-plums have
fucking resentments now?
So how can it resent?
Listen.
The White Death is the farmer.
So we...
we are the plums.
We are the plums?
It don't make sense. Why are you
motherfuckers using metaphors?
Look, he shot my fucking brother!
You shot my son!
We prepare together,
or we die alone.
That's all I was trying to say.
The White Death waits for you
with his army of assassins.
Killers from all countries.
But he has no idea
my son and I are on this train.
If fate wills,
I will get my revenge.
I will head for the back
and stop as many as I can.
I will go to the driver car
and get us the fuck out of here.
What are you gonna do,
Joburg?
I am gonna buy us some time.
Daughter.
Father.
Hey...
fellas, I am looking for a Mr. Death.
Got his case here.
Hey easy.
Hurt people hurt people.
I came to see you.
And to make you finally see me.
The real me.
I built myself up
from the nothing you gave me.
All so I could be
the one in front of you today...
my finger on the trigger.
I was the one...
who deserved your attention.
Your love.
I am more like you
than that little fuck up ever was.
Do it.
I came here to kill you.
So kill me.
Kill me like you did all
the others who tried the same.
Do it.
Fucking do it!
Pow!
Pow.
I see you dochka.
I always have.
But you have never
been part of my plan.
We found the American!
What about the others?
They are all dead.
Good news is I... have your case.
Ay, good news,
good news.
Check the case.
Hurry.
Move. Let's go.
Clear the train.
Alright Thomas.
Time for you to start up...
Oh shit, everything is in Japanese.
There is no episode in Japanese.
What the f...
Get on the ground!
Man, I got a bad feeling about this.
We have no idea what's in this case.
Man, what are you talking about?
Why is it always got to be us
that opens this shit?
Just open the goddamn case.
I would like to keep my fucking arms.
Mr. Death, if I may?
The shadow buyer...
who bought all our contracts,
got us all on this this train and me...
the Hornet, Tangerine, Lemon...
That was you right?
Yes, very astute.
I brought you on this train
hoping you would kill each other.
Ok. Well...
If-if I could...
Why?
Why you do what you do?
You know, I have been asking
that very question.
If it's so safe, why didn't he just open it?
What if it's a bomb
and it blows up in our faces?
You think these stupid masks
are gonna protect us?
All these years later...
the burden of your betrayal,
still heavy upon your heads.
Let me relieve you of both.
My wife...
was taken from me.
I heard.
I am so sorry for your loss.
It was a horrible accident...
Horrible.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
No.
Nothing in life is an accident.
It was an assassination attempt on me.
But fate...
fate put two wet work operatives,
twins,
on a job in Bolivia...
Butchering my entire crew.
And I had to go deal with it.
And he didn't hire
two random operators Lemon?
No, he asked for the two responsible
for the Bolivia job.
That is why
it was my wife in the car,
that night,
not me.
Fate put my wife,
in the hospital.
A piece...
of her rib...
piercing her heart.
Only the most skilled cardiovascular surgeon
could save her life.
But two nights earlier,
this surgeon...
was poisoned.
Oh, my god!
Fate.
Fate again.
They said my money was in the case.
Don't want to sound judgmental,
but if you...
hired the hornet,
you had your own kid killed?
Oh, yes.
Ok.
Oh yes I did.
The piece of shit.
That night,
I told her...
Not to leave.
To wait for me.
But she promised,
it was the last time
we would ever bail him,
out of trouble.
I will come.
I will always come for you.
Well,
I suppose...
she was right.
If I had amputated that weakness
out of my life years ago,
she would still be by my side!
Yeah, it helps to process this.
II-I have a good therapist.
I loved my wife very much.
She taught me a valuable lesson.
If you do not control your fate...
It will control you.
So I took control.
I brought them all here to die.
But now there is only one left.
Mr. Carver.
Wh...
Excus... Excuse me?
I am filling in for Carver?
Calling in sick?
Fuck Carver.
The man who murdered my wife.
Bro.
Just open it!
Fine. You happy?
I am not Carver!
He went that way! Come...
Alright.
Oh, shit. Ok.
Oh, shit.
Something is happening.
Excuse me.
Yep.
Kimura.
Why are you here?
Your daughter.
It would seem she pushed,
the wrong grandson off a roof.
Oh children!
You do the best you can
to raise them right.
Cockroach, I do not know
why you are here,
but move out of my way
or you will join your wife.
Our paths were destined
to return to each other.
Ok.
Right.
Fucking slow down mate.
Come on!
Hey, so far so good.
You can stop the train.
About that.
I took the velocity of the train
and divided it by the mass,
and I realized that I don't know
how to fucking drive a bullet train!
Dude, all you do is talk about trains.
Man, Thomas is a metaphor for life,
not how to actually drive...
Get down!
Shit.
I got this!
Stop the train!
What?
English, English, English.
English, English.
Brakes!
We are good! I got it!
No!
Hold on!
We are on the wrong track!
Oi, Joburg!
What?
I am sorry I shot you!
Actually, it was, like, twice!
Sorry?
You shot me twice!
Sorry I shot you twice.
Thanks man!
That shows real growth!
Fuck!
You are not ruled by strength.
You are ruled by fear!
Fear of the one thing deep down
you cannot control!
Fear of fate!
Hey and I am sorry about Tangerine.
Yeah.
But I got another brother now.
Really?
Fuck no!
For old times' sake.
Fuck it.
Fuck!
Oi.
That will be 20.
Let's go.
Oh, mate.
Yeah?
I wanted bubble milk tea.
How about a wagon wheel?
Yeah.
Father.
A father...
protects his family.
Oh, fuck.
About your wife,
I had nothing to do with that.
It's a mistake.
I am not Carver.
I only do snatch and grab jobs.
The Carver, I want the Carver!
I hired the Carver!
Yeah, no, he had a stomach thing man.
I am just filling in.
You are filling in.
For what it's worth,
Carver is a dick.
The most cunning assassin...
maybe the laziest but...
Come on.
Just let it go, bro.
Do not call me bro!
Ok.
Dude, did you see that?
What was that?
Dude.
It's done.
Hey, about this plum.
Shouldn't the plum give up all resentment?
Like...
Oh, my god.
It's my luck...
that delivered...
my father's corpse at my feet.
The narcissism on this chick.
Untreatable.
Now I am...
Ok, wait, wait.
Wait.
What?
What is with this fucked up family?
You need some suggested reading,
if I may.
Surviving borderline personality disorder.
What?
I highly recommend it.
Now I...
I am the White dea...
What was that?
Was that kar... was that Karma?
Farewell.
Tentōu mushi.
Tangerine.
Maria?
Take the gun.
Oh, my god, did you just say whack?
We are almost there.
You just need to get up.
Did you come to rescue me?
Did you need rescuing?
You came to rescue me.
Please don't make me regret it.
Ok, don't. Don't.
What's happening to your face?
Are you, are you crying?
It's a lot to process.
I want you to know,
you are the greatest,
most wonderful,
handler
that I could ever have.
Ever.
Do you think...
maybe there was a little head trauma?
Maybe.
Little bit, yeah.
A little lightheaded.
Yeah.
Need a banana?
Potassium might be good.
Have one in the car.
Hey,
next time, take the gun.
Don't listen to Barry.
Ok?
Simple?
Stop it.
Stop.
You know, I think you were
right about one thing.
Usually am. Come on.
Maybe it is,
just about how we frame it.
Like, maybe there is no bad luck
or good luck.
Maybe we are all just agents of fate.
Nice car.
Yes, it is.
Try not to bleed on it.
Holy mol...
Well...
How do you know it's a bad thing?
Really?
See what I am doing?
I do.
Turning that upside down.
This is working.
Yeah.
Wasabi peas.
Fate obviously didn't want me
to have that banana.
Fate did not want us to get in that car.
Well,
maybe you have
learned something after all.
Fate needs me to find a smart toilet.
I take that back.
Can you hold it?
I am ball pointing.
Walk faster.
Ok. Yeah.
By LESAIGNEUR
Sync & corrections September 2022
I am alive!
I am Ali...
Oh, fuck me.
Fuck me.
Come on, you fucker.
Fuck you!
Tangerines?
Fuck Diesels.
I...
Fuck you, Diesel bitch!
I am the white d...
Final curtain?
Final curtain!
Take a fucking bow!
By LESAIGNEUR
Sync & corrections September 2022