♪ ♪
(alligator growls)
(phone beeping)
(beeping speeds up)
(beeping stops)
(wood cracks loudly)
(gunshots)
(squawking wildly)
♪ Boom, boom, boom, boom ♪
♪ Bang, bang, bang, bang ♪
♪ How, how, how, how ♪
♪ Hey, hey ♪
♪ You gotta come on. ♪
(playing jazzy piano music)
No, thanks, Hoyt.
School night,
it's getting late.
Not my idea.
It's hers.
Apparently,
you got a fan.
Been watching you
play for a while now.
What do you want me to do?
I'll handle it.
Thanks for the drink.
Thought you could use it.
Really? Why's that?
Oh, seem a little tense.
You might want to lighten up
on the keys.
Oh.
Music critic, huh?
You play?
No. I used to sing a little,
though.
Long time ago.
Why'd you stop?
Lost my piano player.
By the way,
I still haven't forgiven you.
For the record...
wasn't just me who ended it.
Besides, 25 years is a
long time to hold a grudge.
26, but who's counting?
(chuckles)
I heard you moved back.
I wondered when we'd
bump into each other.
Forgot nothing happens
in this town
without you knowing about it.
(chuckles)
Yeah.
You look good, Dwayne.
(sighs) You, too, Rita.
By the way,
sorry to hear
about you and Lloyd.
Sorry to hear
about you and Linda.
Divorce sucks, right?
Yeah.
♪ Sometimes you gotta just
move on... ♪
Don't get me wrong, I'm, uh,
I'm glad to see you and all,
but, uh... buying me a drink
at 1:00 in the morning
after all these years?
(chuckles)
Everything all right?
(exhales) No.
No, it's not.
♪ No one else gonna love you
like I do. ♪
♪ ♪
SEBASTIAN:
That's it,
I got to find a new mode
of transportation.
I mean, don't get me wrong, I'm
a moped guy through and through.
But the law of physics
is not in my favor
when there's a huge SUV
riding right up my...
Glass.
Well, yeah, rhymes with "glass,"
but that's not
what I was gonna say it was.
No, no, no. I mean...
this glass.
Check it out.
This isn't
another newbie hazing thing?
Just look at it,
please, will you?
What do you see?
Lipstick.
Looks like Pride had some
company over here last night.
Female company.
Oh, you mean...
Pride? Lady time at work?
Nah, I don't think so.
Hey, is coffee on?
SEBASTIAN:
Hey, Lasalle, tomorrow,
do you think you can swing by
and pick me up, too?
I'm done with my moped, man.
GREGORIO:
Excuse me.
Are you just gonna ignore this?
Ignore what?
Well, Gregorio seems to think
that Pride had a
date last night.
Yes.
Late night, home-cooked meal,
couple of drinks,
lipstick? Hello.
Doesn't even smell like alcohol.
Oh, come on.
Aren't you guys the least
bit curious about this?
No, 'cause whatever "this" is,
it's not what you think.
Our King's not like that.
He wouldn't bring anybody
to the office.
Like what? He lives upstairs.
You're still new, Gregorio,
so you don't know.
You don't know.
SONJA:
What we've learned
is Pride is married
to his work.
Period.
Okay.
All right.
$20 says I'm right.
ALL:
You're on.
(knock at door)
PRIDE:
Got a case.
JAG lawyer Noah Sandler.
Prosecutes highly classified
cases for the Navy.
He's gone missing.
For how long?
The last time
anybody heard from him
was the night before last.
Called a fellow JAG.
Said he had something sensitive
to discuss with her,
but never showed.
Her?
Reserve JAG Devereaux,
also an A.D.A.
She trained Noah.
Gave him his start.
Knows he wouldn't have called
if it wasn't important.
So she thinks
something happened to him?
Yeah, we both do.
Rita and I went to his...
GREGORIO:
Rita?
PRIDE:
Sorry.
JAG Devereaux and I
went to his apartment
last night,
but there were no signs of him
or his car.
Well, still, it's only been
a day and a half.
I mean, NOPD doesn't even take
missing persons cases
for what, 48 hours?
Yeah, well, we're not NOPD.
And this isn't just anybody
we're talking about here.
Sorry. Look, I...
I admit there's nothing
much to go on here yet,
but I've known
Rita a long time.
She's not one to panic easily.
She's concerned.
I told her we'd help.
A friend of yours
is a friend of ours, King.
What's our next move?
Only thing suspicious we found
at JAG Noah's apartment
was there was nothing
on his computer.
Nothing?
Like it had been erased?
Yeah. I want you and Patton
to work on it.
Maybe see if you can restore
what was on it.
Might give us some leads.
Christopher, Percy,
deep dive Noah.
Credit card charges,
phone records,
surveillance cameras.
Anything
that might help us trace
his last known whereabouts.
You got it.
What can I do?
You and I
are going
to Belle Chasse.
Okay.
See if we can figure out which,
if any, of Noah's cases
have something to do
with his disappearance.
Classified cases--
do we have access?
Yeah, we do,
and Rita will meet us there
to help us sort things out.
Okay, then.
Look forward to meeting
this Rita.
Don't get me wrong.
If there's anything I've
learned since I got here,
is you have a definite
nose for justice.
It's just, you know, unusual way
of taking the case, is all.
What are you trying
to get at, Gregorio?
No, nothing.
I'm just saying,
we usually start things
off with an actual crime.
Phone call, a body.
But here, banking a lot on
this Rita friend of yours.
You must have good reason
to trust her instincts.
I do.
Oh.
Keep fishing, New York.
RITA:
Thanks for doing this, Dwayne.
No thanks necessary.
Special Agent Tammy Gregorio,
Assistant District Attorney,
Reserve Naval Commander,
JAG Corps Rita Devereaux.
Lot of titles, I know.
You can call me Rita.
Nice to meet you, Rita.
D.A. get us any access?
Had to go back on active
duty to get it, but yes.
Glad the uniform still fits.
It's been a while.
No, you look great.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Ladies? Yeah.
We find anything in Noah's
case files that might help?
No, nothing yet, unfortunately.
I've gone through all
his current JAG caseload,
but although sensitive,
nothing stands out
as suspicious.
What about his computer?
Has that been erased, too?
No, it seems to be intact.
His last entry
was calendaring the meet
he wanted to have with me
tomorrow morning.
Home computer wiped,
office not?
If Noah's really missing,
could be more of a personal
nature than business.
Gregorio's right.
If there aren't any leads here,
but there were
at his apartment...
Look, you knew him well.
What did he do
with his personal time?
We really haven't had a chance
to catch up
since I moved back here
a couple months ago.
Oh, you lived in New Orleans?
Long time ago, way, way back
when I first met Dwayne.
Looks like Noah was pretty
involved with Fort MacArthur.
GREGORIO:
What's Fort MacArthur?
Private military academy
outside the city.
Town has a long-standing history
with the school.
Takes in troubled juvies
with criminal records.
Place is their last shot
at turning their lives around.
RITA: Just like it
did for Noah.
Academy offered him
structure and direction.
It's why he joined the Navy.
And why he's been
volunteering there ever since.
He likes to give back.
A lot like you, actually.
GREGORIO:
Looks like your friend
was doing more
than volunteering.
Student files, log books,
leave requests,
blueprints
of the school's ground.
I mean, it almost feels like
(phone rings)
he was investigating
something there.
I wonder what.
What you got, Sebastian?
Okay.
We're on our way.
Uh, tell Christopher
we'll meet them there.
Noah's computer
was erased remotely,
but they were able to trace
the IP address to his laptop.
Call me. Good or bad.
Promise.
Noah Sandler's vehicle.
Judging by the tire tracks,
it sat here overnight.
Any sign of Noah?
Not yet.
Any idea what he was doing
all the way out here?
Well, it could have been
gator hunt.
Got the gear.
It's a popular spot, but
you got to have courage.
Meaning?
(sighs) Lake Verret's
not the safest place to hunt.
PRIDE: It's pretty
remote and dangerous.
Nobody usually
comes out here alone.
Found the laptop,
but it's been wiped clean, too.
And according to Sebastian,
it was used to remotely erase
Noah's home computer first.
Noah didn't come all the way
out here to erase computers.
King.
Whoa.
(growling)
Hyah. Get back.
Hyah.
(growling)
Hyah. Get back.
Get back.
Hyah. Yeah.
(hisses)
Get back.
Hyah.
It's probably Noah.
Looks like he's been shot twice.
Which means our missing persons
case just turned into a murder.
SEBASTIAN:
Hey, Doc Wade call you yet?
No, why?
She just finished her
prelim autopsy on JAG Noah.
Turns out you were right.
He was shot twice in the back.
Hunting accident?
I don't think so.
It was a tight pattern,
and both went
right through the heart.
Kill shots.
Question is,
who killed him and why?
Looked like he drove out there
by himself.
Someone lying in wait,
hoping to make it look
like a hunting accident?
Yeah, how'd they know
he'd even be out there?
And why was he there?
Calls your friend Rita,
says he wants to discuss
a sensitive case with her.
Well, it had to be connected
to whatever case
he wanted to talk to her about,
right?
And told her it was important.
Thing is, if Rita hadn't come
to me when she did,
probably never would have found
Noah's body.
Gators would have made sure
of that.
Was probably what the killer
was hoping for.
You and Patton have any luck
figuring out
what was on Noah's computers
before they got erased?
Nada. We even hacked into the
cloud to check the data stream.
Which means whoever it was
went through
an awful lot of trouble
to cover up
whatever Noah was working on.
RITA:
Any word?
You said you would call.
I know. But we just got back,
and I...
I wanted to be sure first.
Sure of what?
Good or bad, you
wanted to know.
It's not good.
Noah was murdered, Rita.
He was shot.
What?
How? Who?
I don't know.
We just started
the investigation.
I assume that...
that you've kept looking.
Any idea what Noah wanted
to talk to you about yet?
What was so important?
I, uh...
I think it had something to do
with Terrence Lewis.
He's one of the cadets
that Noah was mentoring
at the academy.
I started looking more
into Noah's Fort MacArthur
connections after you left.
What's so special
about Lewis?
Uh, Noah had requested
the boy's
juvenile criminal file,
but JAGs can't access
a minor's record
without a court order.
But A.D.A.s can, and
you're thinking that, uh,
he called you, hoping you
could get him the files?
Troubled kid, Terrence Lewis.
Assault, armed robbery,
and it doesn't look like he got
reformed at the academy, either.
Kept getting into trouble,
both in and out
of Fort MacArthur.
If Terrence Lewis knew
Noah was investigating him...
He might have killed
him so he couldn't?
That's a stretch.
I'm just looking
at the facts, Dwayne.
It's what I do.
And I'm sorry, but not every kid
can be reformed.
And Lewis looks like he wasn't.
Violent background,
access to weapons,
and then Noah gets shot to death
before we can even meet?
If that's not probable cause,
I don't know what is.
Don't want to rush
to judgment here.
Especially when it comes
to the kids at the academy.
Suspects are suspects,
regardless of age.
Look, I know that
Noah was your friend.
That's got nothing to do
with this.
It does when you're
not thinking straight
'cause you're loaded for bear.
(exhales)
Might be the first argument
I ever won with you.
I got a good team here, Rita.
They're good at their jobs.
Let us investigate
Terrence Lewis
and whatever connection
the academy may or may
not have had in this,
and I promise we'll find
out who killed Noah.
Okay.
But if you don't, I will.
(guns firing,
drill commands shouted)
(drums playing)
Agent Pride?
General Walsh.
Heard a lot about you.
It's nice to finally meet you.
PRIDE:
You, too, General.
Special Agents Percy
and Lasalle.
Welcome.
Hey, General.
Thank you.
DRILL SERGEANT:
Atten-hut.
WALSH:
So...
what brings NCIS
to Fort MacArthur?
Well, probably best to
discuss in private.
Minors around,
want to handle this as
sensitively as possible.
Understood...
and appreciated.
Especially considering where
most of our cadets come from.
Law tends to assume
the worst about them.
Uh, General Sklahr, who is that?
PRIDE: He was the man who
practically founded this place.
You're familiar?
Hard to grow up in
this town and not be.
All the good he did,
troubled kids he helped.
WALSH: He gave 'em a home,
a second chance.
General Sklahr
was the father figure
most of these boys
didn't have.
That's large shoes to fill.
Proud to have been appointed
to do exactly that.
Although,
easier said than done.
COMMANDING OFFICER:
Halt!
CADETS:
♪ The military live... ♪
So, which of my boys
is in trouble?
Well, not sure
any are yet.
That's why we're here.
Hoping for an assist.
We'd like to talk with one
of your cadets, Terrence Lewis.
Well, so would I.
Private Lewis has been UA
for three weeks now.
Wish I could say
that was unusual.
LASALLE: Lewis
go missing often?
Unfortunately, yes.
We take pride here
in reforming boys,
teaching 'em
to obey orders,
how to commit to something
larger than themselves.
But, we're not
always successful
and I'm afraid
that includes Private Lewis.
You notify NOPD
he was missing?
They don't
have the manpower
to chase down runaways and...
juvies like Lewis
aren't a high priority.
What's he done?
Again, not sure, but, uh...
I'm sorry to say,
JAG Noah Sandler
has been murdered.
And Terrence Lewis
is a person of interest.
(sighs)
Noah, my God.
How, when?
Last night.
And what we know now is:
Noah was investigating Lewis.
And maybe even the academy.
Investigating?
Noah never said anything to me
about it
and he was here all the time.
He mentored lots of boys,
not just Private Lewis.
Is it all right if we speak
with Lewis' commanding officer?
Of course. Uh...
Dorsey,
come in here, please.
Sir?
These are NCIS agents,
Captain Dorsey.
They need to speak
to Commander Cabral ASAP.
Yes, sir. Right this way.
Agent Pride?
This news of Noah's death
is gonna hit the boys hard.
I'd rather they hear it from me,
if that's all right with you.
Yes, sir.
(sighs)
(door opens)
What do we got,
Loretta?
I'm sorry, that was way too much
like Pride.
That was awful.
God, I got to work on that.
I'll work on it,
it's gonna be fine.
Stop trying so hard, Sebastian,
you're doing fine.
I know, I know, I know,
it's just...
still trying to find
my NCIS way, I guess. You know?
Maybe I should
keep the moped.
You here for an update?
I am. Yeah,
inquiring minds want to know.
Especially Pride's.
Well, obviously, an intact body
would have helped,
but from the pattern of the cuts
and abrasions I've seen,
coupled with the lack
of coagulation,
it appears JAG Noah's body
was dragged postmortem.
Because of Tick-Tock Croc?
It's a Peter Pan reference.
Anyway,
the alligator bite pattern
didn't match
the indicated direction
of the cuts, so...
So the killer must have
dragged Noah after he shot him,
closer to the water.
Hoping the alligators
would devour the evidence, yes.
(sighs)
Doesn't really get us any closer
to IDing the killer, though.
Is there any way
that we can, uh,
narrow down what type
of gun was used?
It was definitely
an automatic rifle of some kind.
Based on the...
entry wound,
probably military.
I can't be sure until
you find me the projectiles.
Yeah, well, good luck
with that, right?
A high-powered rifle, bullets
went right through the body,
it's probably buried
back in the bayou somewhere.
Mm-hmm. Sounds like
a field trip to me.
Yeah.
Wait, do you mean me?
You-- you want me to go
back out there
to deadly gator-world?
By myself?
Tick-Tock Croc.
(sighs)
All right.
I'll see you never.
(door opens)
DORSEY:
Platoon, atten-hut!
Good afternoon, sir.
At ease, Commander.
Commander Cabral,
these are NCIS agents.
They need to speak
with you in private.
Of course, sir.
Cole, front and center.
Your command, Lieutenant.
Aye, sir.
Still can't wrap
my head around
how teaching juvies
to shoot M16s
helps reform them.
Well, it's not about that.
It teaches them responsibility.
At least this place
gives them a chance.
Port arms!
How can I be of assistance?
I understand Terrence Lewis
was in your squad,
Commander?
Is in my squad.
Yes, sir.
Although, currently,
Private Lewis is...
UA, I know.
How well do you know him?
General Walsh assigned him
to my squad three months ago.
Hoped I could
straighten him out.
How so?
Permission to speak freely?
We're just looking
for answers.
However you can help.
Private Lewis was
a difficult recruit.
The academy prides itself
on strength through loyalty,
following orders.
Lewis fought it
every step of the way.
So I take it you and Lewis
didn't get along very well.
Lewis didn't get along
with anyone very well.
What about JAG Noah?
JAG...
He's the best, he's always
been there for us.
Lewis, too, but...
But what, son?
Just a few weeks ago,
JAG Noah tried to help Lewis
with some stuff
he was going through.
But Lewis got mad.
Violent, even.
Hit JAG Noah-- hard, too.
That's the last anyone
ever saw of him.
(device beeping slowly)
(loud growl)
What the...?
(beeping)
(beeping rapidly)
Bingo.
Okay.
(beeping steadily)
(beeping rapidly)
Oh, my God!
Judging by the rate
of decomposition,
I'd estimate the boy died
about three weeks ago.
SEBASTIAN:
Same time Lewis went UA.
Cause of death?
WADE: Your missing cadet
was obviously beaten.
Even after all this time,
bruises on his face,
arms, and chest
are still evident.
Yeah, more interesting, though,
is what was used to beat him.
Yes, we recovered
the same substance
found in the epidermis
of the bruises--
lye, glycerin,
potassium hydroxide...
I.e., soap. We even found trace
amounts of it in Lewis' mouth.
Soap?
Soap bashing.
A hazing technique
the military has long condemned.
Except soap didn't break
the boy's parietal bone.
The cause of death was
a sharp blow
to the back of the head,
and I'm still trying
to figure out
exactly what was used.
Hazing gone too far?
If so, JAG Noah may have been
investigating
Terrence Lewis as a victim,
not a juvie.
Somehow figured out
where the body had been dumped,
went to Lake Verret
to investigate,
and then got shot
by whoever killed Lewis.
Well, I hate to say it,
but if more than one cadet
really did haze Lewis,
then it's hard to believe
they're not responsible
for both murders.
We're not gonna jump
to conclusions here, okay?
(phone beeping)
We need to be sure.
Okay, Loretta,
I need to know what exactly
was used to kill Terrence Lewis.
On it.
PRIDE:
Sebastian,
get an ID on those bullets
that killed JAG Noah.
I want to know
what type of weapon
they came from ASAP.
Copy that.
Where you going?
Rita just texted.
I need to try
and slow her down.
Send her up as soon
as she gets here.
Max Cabral,
assault with a deadly weapon.
William Cole,
aggravated assault.
Jamal Povey, attempted rape.
Rita...
Tyler Wilson, armed robbery.
And the list goes on.
I unsealed every cadet's
criminal record
after I heard about
what happened.
I know Noah believed
in these boys, Dwayne.
I know you probably do, too.
But you can't tell me
none of them are
capable of murder.
You can't prejudge them
from their past.
That's not fair.
That's what reform's all about.
This isn't about
reform anymore.
This is about justice.
I agree, but all
I'm saying is
we don't know enough yet.
Well, we know enough to get
a search and arrest warrant
for the entire academy,
which is exactly what
I'm going to do.
And what if you're wrong,
like you were yesterday,
when you thought that
Lewis killed Noah?
Bring all those warrants,
media follows,
makes this headline news,
and Fort MacArthur
gets shut down.
Is that what you want?
No! I want justice,
and you should
want that, too.
They're boys.
They're suspects!
Look, I know everybody
in this town loves you, Dwayne.
They always have because
you always put them first.
Believe me, I know.
This isn't about us, Rita.
I know how you grew up.
I know how you want
to give everyone,
especially the underdogs,
the benefit of the doubt,
but sometimes they
don't deserve it.
We don't know enough yet.
There's too much risk to those
boys and to the academy.
So, Rita, please...
I disagree.
JAG Noah may be
your jurisdiction,
but Terrence Lewis is mine.
I'm getting the arrest warrants.
DRILL SERGEANT:
Hut!
(sighs)
I don't believe this.
Hazing? Murder?
WALSH: If any of this is true,
I've lost total control
of this school.
How certain are you of this?
The bullets that killed Noah
could have come
from one of
the academy's rifles,
so we need to find out
what is true
if we have any hopes
of containing the situation.
And to do that, we need to
test your cadets'
rifles for matches,
and know which students
were off-campus or on leave
during both murders.
I'll get the logs.
(gunshots)
Clear!
Thank you guys
for your cooperation.
Didn't know how
you would act
after finding out
what happened to JAG Noah.
He'd be the first
to counsel calm
and tell us to follow orders,
and that's what I'm doing.
Okay, whose rifle's
up next?
Commander Cabral's.
Let's have it.
(gunshots)
I still don't understand, why
are they checking our guns?
I don't know.
Commander Cabral.
At ease.
General Walsh needs
to see you, Commander.
It's about Private Lewis.
Fide, Honorem, Victoria.
Yes, sir.
Prep the squad for Code 18.
But...
Just do it!
(gunshots)
Christopher?
What is it?
I don't know, but I don't have
a good feeling about this.
Something's definitely up
over there.
One ID shows off premises
at the time of both murders.
Dog tag 2476.
PRIDE: 247...
Lieutenant Commander
Max Cabral.
Max?
Yeah, well, his rifle just
matched the bullets
that killed JAG Noah.
(alarm blaring)
What's that?
It's a lockdown.
But I didn't order it.
Whoa!
What the hell is going on?
I'm protecting the academy.
Hands up!
(sirens wailing)
(alarm blaring)
Let's go, come on.
Down here.
Come on, let's go.
Stop looking back.
Keep going, come on!
You don't know what
you're doing, son.
You're not thinking straight.
What is this supposed to...
Sit down!
CABRAL:
Pull their weapons.
(alarm buzzer continues)
(cell phone ringing)
You should answer that.
Talk to him.
No, don't.
Don't.
We're under strict orders.
Orders?
Orders from who?
Stand watch.
Go! Go! Go!
(indistinct shouting)
No answer?
No. It's weird.
Pride.
Anything?
NOPD and LSP are
evacuating the students.
SWAT's taking position.
Geez-- Dorsey!
Why is SWAT here?
Rita.
She called them. It's procedure
when serving felony warrants,
and in this case,
it's obviously warranted.
Where the hell
are Christopher and Sonja?
NOPD saw a squad of them
take them
into the mess hall at gunpoint.
What?
Students were
blocking the windows.
No one's answering.
Things are getting
out of hand here, General. Fast.
Dorsey!
Sir.
You just spoke to Commander
Cabral, what did he say?
Well, he didn't say anything.
I just told him
you wanted to talk to him
about Lewis,
then he triggered a lockdown.
You don't think Cabral
had anything to do
with this, do you?
No, no, no. Hold on.
All we know right now
is that the bullets
match Cabral's rifle.
That's it.
SEBASTIAN: Right.
Why would he hand us
over his rifle
when we asked for it,
without even hesitating,
if he knew it was gonna
match the murder weapon?
GREGORIO: He wouldn't have
let you test it.
Get ahold of Loretta.
Okay, let's hope
she's got some answers.
We're missing something here.
I'm still trying
to establish communication
and waiting on drones, stand by.
A.D.A. Devereaux.
What's going on? What happened?
The cadets have locked down
the school.
Wait, because of the warrants?
We never got a chance
to serve them.
Now, they're ensconced,
heavily armed
and they've got hostages.
How long till HRT gets here?
(sighs)
15 to 20 minutes,
but based on the situation,
we may not have that long.
I want scopes in every window
and access...
Okay, look, I don't want
this blowing up on us.
We need to find out
what they want first.
It's not up to me, it's up
to them, but the fact is,
is they've taken hostages.
Hey, they'll listen to me.
Let me go in,
talk to Commander Cabral.
I'm his commanding officer,
he'll do whatever I say.
It may be the only
way to save them.
WADE: The lethal blow
to the head on Terrence Lewis
was administered
after the hazing.
How long after?
12, 15 hours.
So, it's not due to the hazing?
Unless Lewis threatened
to tell somebody
after the fact,
and got killed later.
Yeah, there's still
not enough there
to let Commander Cabral
off the hook.
Any idea
what the murder weapon was?
No, but I did find
some curious details.
I found a sliver of wood
in the boy's skull,
not just any wood,
but 200-year-old cedar.
Also, trace amounts of sulfur,
charcoal, saltpeter.
That sounds
like black gunpowder.
Black gunpowder, you mean,
like from the Civil War?
WALSH:
Yeah.
Pride, what is it?
Sebastian,
if somebody swung one
of these old rifles hard enough,
could trace amounts
of black gunpowder...
Get dislodged,
and end up embedded
in the skull? Absolutely.
Any idea where the missing
rifle is, General?
I never even noticed
it was gone.
Who else has access
to the office?
Captain Dorsey.
Where is Dorsey?
CABRAL:
This is not a negotiation.
We don't have a choice,
Lieutenant.
All I'm saying is maybe
we should listen to them.
We didn't do anything wrong.
Lewis is dead because of us!
We were ordered to haze him,
just like we were ordered
to do this.
We didn't kill Lewis any more
than we killed JAG Noah.
You think anyone outside
of here cares about that?
Everything this place
stands for is on the line.
Do you understand?
We follow orders. Period.
But following orders
is what got us into this mess
in the first place.
PRIDE:
Rita!
I'm sorry to say this, Dwayne,
but I think this proves
I was right
about the cadets.
Actually, I think
they're being set up.
I don't think any of
the cadets killed Lewis or Noah.
Based on what?
Have you seen Captain Dorsey?
Dorsey, we just sent him
inside. Why?
(door closes)
Stand down.
You were supposed to contain
the situation, Cadet.
Now I have to clean it up.
With me.
(urgent chatter, guns clicking)
All I'm saying is, the situation
may not be as it appears.
We think Commander Cabral's
being set up by the man
you just let inside.
Cabral is holding two
of your own people hostage.
He's just following orders.
And so am I. My job is clear,
Agent Pride,
and that's to defuse
the situation any way I can.
MAN (over radio): Dugan?
Excuse me.
RITA: This doesn't
make any sense.
If you're right,
and the boys are innocent,
why do this?
Why take hostages?
The whole premise of reform here
is to teach cadets
to obey orders without question,
to put the academy first.
Obviously, Dorsey
took advantage of that.
Wait, you're saying Dorsey
killed Noah and, and Lewis? Why?
SEBASTIAN: Pride.
Talk to me.
The general got me access to
Dorsey's personnel files.
Apparently, he applied
to take over the academy
after the last general died,
but Walsh got it instead.
That's not motivation
for murder.
Well, no.
But the main reason that
he got passed over might be.
See, Dorsey had been
reprimanded several times
for abuse of authority,
including ordering
the hazing of cadets.
So things with Lewis
went too far,
they got out of hand,
JAG Noah figured it out...
And he had to kill him, too.
Still doesn't explain why Cabral
locked down the school.
No, it does.
It does, if he's following
Dorsey's orders.
And if Dorsey's trying
to make Max look guilty...
Where's Gregorio?
PRIDE:
We only got one shot at this.
Got it, Pride.
I just hope we have enough time.
Hey. If you're innocent,
if Max is innocent,
we can prove it,
But not like this.
Besides, even the military's
not supposed to follow orders
if they're illegal,
or criminal...
hey, and neither are you.
Look, if you want
to do what's right?
What is wrong with you?
We can stop this
before it's too late.
You can stop this.
But please,
let us go.
You are an embarrassment
to the uniform.
This is your mess, Commander.
I was following your orders.
My orders were to protect
the academy,
not to put it at risk,
which is exactly
what you've done.
What the hell were you thinking?
You're the one
that started this.
You're the one that told me to
haze Lewis, scare him straight.
But you went too far,
didn't you?
Lewis threatened
to expose it,
but that would've brought down
the very institution
that's kept you
from spending the rest
of your sorry-ass life
in prison.
I didn't kill Lewis!
But I had to!
To protect
the academy
from the same mess.
What about JAG Noah?
Also on you.
After he figured out
what happened,
tracked down Lewis's body,
I had to do something to protect
us all from your screwups!
Loyalty above all else!
Remember that?
That's what
this place stands for.
But that's something
you obviously don't get.
You're a failure,
Cabral,
a failure to yourself,
and this institution.
You should be ashamed
of yourself!
Do I have permission to fire?
You think you got the balls?
Go ahead, pull the trigger!
Shoot me!
No, but I do. Move.
Do it!
Federal agents! Don't move!
Put your hands up!
All clear, all clear.
Nice shot, Gregorio.
I knew you could do it.
See you when you get
back down here.
Copy that.
Just out of curiosity,
how'd you know
that would work?
That that was Dorsey's plan?
I didn't,
but I couldn't figure out
what else he was gonna do.
Backed in the corner,
knew we were onto him,
assumed things would escalate.
So, in other words,
it was just a hunch?
I prefer "educated guess."
(exhales)
(chuckles)
(piano playing)
GREGORIO: Still can't quite
figure him out.
Figure out who? Pride?
Yeah.
What's there to figure out?
He's the man.
I think she's talking
about his personal life.
Oh.
Yeah, but playing piano
is his personal life.
Nah, there's got to be
more to it than that.
He's such a good catch.
I mean, he should be hooked
up with someone, no?
Talking professional curiosity
here, let's just be clear.
Look, King is not in a hurry
to get together
with anyone anytime soon.
SONJA: Yeah.
He's just happy
being King.
SONJA: It's true.
Okay. Well, like I said,
he's a great catch, and
it's just not natural.
You're just cranky that you lost
the bet about Rita.
Bingo.
Exactly! I forgot.
I'm cranky? I'm cranky?
Yeah, you cranky.
Then why is she here?
GREGORIO:
Huh?
I see I made
an impression on you.
Oh, yeah? How's that?
Lighter touch on the keys,
less tense.
All right,
you're pretty confident.
(chuckles)
Uh, not so much.
Certainly not after
I nearly caused a disaster.
You're being too hard
on yourself.
Eh. What else is new?
I should've known better.
I should've remembered.
Never go up against
one of your hunches.
Oh, I don't know, my way
could've gone sideways, too.
Troubled history
those kids had even before
they get to the academy,
hard not to think
that where there's smoke,
there's fire.
Well, certainly
what Captain Dorsey was hoping
to make everybody believe.
D.A. thinks he wasn't
just trying to frame Max,
but also make Walsh look
bad so he could take over.
Almost brought down
the academy instead.
Thanks for putting in
a good word on their behalf.
Oh, it's the least I could do.
After all, those boys
deserve a second chance.
Yeah, I agree with that.
(playing piano)
Yeah, go ahead.
By the way...
(begins playing
"It Had to Be You")
Remember this one?
No-- don't.
Please, don't go there.
What, are you scared?
♪ It had to be you ♪
Uh, wrong key, though.
What?
♪ I wandered around ♪
♪ Finally found
somebody who... ♪
That's perfect.
No, it's too low.
♪ Could make me be true ♪
♪ Could make me be blue ♪
♪ Or even be glad ♪
♪ Just to be sad
thinking of you ♪
Yes!
♪ Some others I've seen ♪
There it is.
Okay.
♪ Might never be mean ♪
May be right.
♪ Might never be cross ♪
BOTH:
♪ Or try to be boss ♪
♪ They wouldn't do ♪
(clears throat)
BOTH:
♪ For nobody else ♪
Pay up.
Let's go.
♪ With all your faults ♪
♪ I love you still ♪
(chuckles)
Thank you.
♪ It had to be you ♪
(laughs)
Too bad you don't take credit.
♪ It had to be you. ♪
Captioning sponsored by
CBS
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org
Uh-oh.