好 下一个是谁
Alright, so who's next?
谁觉得自己可以打败传说中的帮派帮
Who thinks they can take on the legendary CrewCrew?
帮派帮
CrewCrew!
看起来大麻烦还想要更多
Looks like Big Trouble's back for more.
老兄 另一场对战要开始了
Dude, another battle's about to start!
天 这个人每个星期都过来
Man, this dude is back every week.
不 我这次要打败你们所有笨蛋 放beat
Nah, I got y'all fools this time, hit it!
你们最好都看好
You all better watch out,
因为大麻烦现在拿着mic
cause Big Trouble's on the mic now,
我要把你们都击倒
I'll knock all o' your lights out,
你们都被我的句子诅咒 爆炸像个烟花
with my verse, y'all be cursed, blowing up like fireworks.
就这样? 闪彗星 给这个笨蛋看看我们的水平
That's it? Blitz Comet, show this fool how we do.
闪彗星在台上
Blitz Comet on the scene.
你走进我只能拿到奶油玉米
You step to me and you gonna get creamed-corn!
你的嘴超臭 你这个疯子只能做酷的反义词
All up in your teeth, you reek, you're the opposite of chic, ya freak!
你的段子都太旧
Your ryhmes are all antiques.
没人想听都扔到一边
Nobody wants em, they throw em all away.
一开始你的脑子就像在卡壳
Right from the get go like your brain is on delay.
我看你应该去做做检查
Matter of fact yo, you better get a check up.
问问你得医生 为什么你脖子上面那么丑
Go ask your doctor, why you be so ugly from the neck UP?
不好意思
Excuse me.
帕布在干嘛
What is Pops doing?
拥抱多美妙
A hug can be a wonderful thing.
两臂围绕如母亲的翅膀
Two arms wrapped around you like a mother's wing.
但我们忧郁又自私
But we're so selfish when we are blue.
一个拥抱难道不值得另一个拥抱
Doesn't a hug deserve a hug too?
谢谢
Thank you.
哟 他在说什么 等等等 等一下
Yo, whatcha say? Nah, nah, nah, nah, hold on man.
你要加入我们
You trying to step to us?
我只是因为有同好诗人感到激动
I'm just so excited to hear some fellow poets.
我认为我可以加入你们歌颂韵律之美
I thought I come join you in the celebration of rhymes.
不不不不不 你没有在歌颂什么
Nah, nah, nah, nah, you're not celebrating nothin'!
嘿 机器人V 放Beat
Yo V-Tron, turn it up.
吔 帮派帮锁定你 说两次 别忘记
Yeah, CrewCrew's coming at you. Say it twice, don't forget it.
你最好看看我们在干嘛
Y'all better catch up to where we're at.
你太过时 比不上我们酷毙的压韵
You're behind the times. Can't compete with our dope rhymes.
所以你最好离开
So you better say your goodbyes.
我们有佛朗科 闪彗星 机器人V 泽西仔在说唱
We got Francois, Blitz Comet, V-Tron, the Jersey kid,
你知道我们超屌 然后我们有毁灭女
on the beats. You know we rock. Then Demel-Ishun,
说唱界最牛的妞
the dopest girl on the mic.
还有狗A我 我吠叫事实 我的段子既严密又优质
And Alpha-Dog, I bark the truth, my verses be all nice and tight.
所以你知道我们是谁了
So now you know who were are.
帮派帮是比星星还闪亮的帮派
CrewCrew is the crew shining brighter than a quazar.
但是你这个灾难
But your bizarre.
是 就是你 就是个废物
Yes, you sir, are a loser.
所以盖好你的疯圆头带着诗滚回家
So cover up that freakish dome and head back home and take your poems.
嘿 你们 别这样
Oh, dude, come on!
帕布 你还好吗
Pops, are you ok?
尽管我很欣赏他们作诗技巧 但是我不是废物
While I appreciate their poetic skills, I am not a loser.
你对我来说就是个衰人
You look like a loser to me.
是啊
Yeah, why don't you take gramps back home before he starts crying some more?
Loser.
- C'mon, Pops, let's go. - No!
I'll have you know my verses won many a competition!
You don't believe me?
I challenge you to a competition tonight!
You mean a rap battle?
If that's what you're calling it, then yes.
Alright, grandpops.
Crew-Crew never backs down! So it's on.
- You're going down! - You're gonna get yours, buddy!
Alright Pops, we can't let you do this by yourself.
Yeah, those guys are gonna walk all over you!
Plus, we know way more stuff about this than you do.
So Rigby and I will rap with you in the battle.
Really!? Our own crew, good show!
Alright Pops, here's how you battle.
Rigby, show him.
Hey Mordecry, oh I mean Mordecai,
didn't mean to diss you please don't run away and hide,
saw you sobbing at that movie 'A Very Happy Bride',
here I'll pass you a tissue, try to have some male pride!
See Pops, it's easy!
'coz the ladies don't like your sensitive side,
like Margaret for example but I guess it's just implied!
Okay, dude.
She won't get with you, she just won't get with you,
not gonna get with you, never gonna get with you-
- Okay, we get it! - I'm just keeping it real.
Now you try Pops.
But he's just making fun of you!
Exactly! That's what you gotta do!
Now give it a shot.
No, I won't do it!
What!? C'mon, you said you wanted to win!
Being negative and hurting someone's feelings
is no way to win a competition!
The power of poetry lies in expressing the beauty of everything around you!
- What? - You're not making any sense.
Come, I'll show you!
What is this place, this magical field,
it's wide and it's open, nothing's concealed.
It's sceneic and peaceful for us to enjoy,
why this is the park, good show old boy!
Hmhm, not bad!
Yeah!
A place of great beauty for plenty to use,
it inspires us all so go spread the news,
to man woman and child or begging cowboy,
this is the park, good show old boy!
Where's this stuff coming from?
Man, he's getting into it!
The key to this place puts a smile on your face,
it is the people it does employ!
Why this is the park, good show old boy!
Yo, is he for real with that?
Good show old boy?
You're gonna have to do better than that if you wanna beat us tonight.
You big headed loser.
Hmph, go ahead and make snide remarks.
Me and my crew are taping into the power of poetry,
and the beauty of our verses will be sure to knock your socks off.
See you fools tonight,
unless you too afraid to show up.
We'll be there.
Lo-ser.
Their rhymes are clever,
but they don't come from the heart.
As long as we're true to ourselves we can't lose.
Oh look, ice-cream truck!
Dude, this is not good!
We gotta find a way to back out of the battle.
Yeah man, I'm totally with you, those guys are gonna destroy us!
Mordecai and Rigby, look! I have a surprise for you.
Tah-dah! I made matching uniforms for tonight!
Pops, we can't do this.
What do you mean?
Look, we're gonna lose!
No, the power of poetry will d-
Pops, the power of poetry isn't even a thing!
C'mon, Pops, this is dumb.
We should just back out.
Well I don't have that option.
Those gentleman called me a loser and I must set them straight.
Yeah, but what if they're right? Uh, I mean-
Fine, I'll do it your way.
I'll do it your way!
Wait, Pops, that's not what we meant!
Shoot.
Man, I feel kinda bad.
I know, but Pops just doesn't get it!
I mean Skips, you're not all into classical poetry, right?
Eh, haikus, mostly.
Seriously?
Okay, but what're we supposed to do?
If we dess up like idiots and go down to recite poetry against that crew,
we'll be humiliated!
Yeah, losers for life!
I've lost my appetite.
Mordecai, Rigby.
Friends don't let down other friends.
You guys are losers.
He's right.
Man, poetry's powerful stuff.
Your attitude is unappealing,
some would say quite rude.
Your shoes are colorful-
no!
C'mon tough guy, why are you tongue tied?
Watch out everybody looks like grandpa's about to cry!
Whether in righteous storms or the rainiest of days-
Poetry!?
-friends stick with friends through thick and thin always.
Mordecai, Rigby, you came!
We're sorry, Pops, we were acting like fools-
-we hope you can forgive us for being complete tools-
-your poems aren't lame, they're really works of art-
-if we gotta win this battle we gotta do it from the heart!
Oh, thank goodness!
Your way wasn't working at all!
So what up?
Are will battlin' or have y'all smartened up?
Let's do this!
Beauty's in the center of all that you see,
simple yet complex and fully textured.
And beauty be apart of all that you be,
because you are the best rhymers that I've ever heard!
That's pretty cool!
Aww yeah, they're into it!
Aw what!? Uh uh, this is real now.
Why you talking 'bout beauty, man,
don't understand what's that got to do with you, you fool.
You guys are like spoiled hams in a can-super bland,
expiration date's overdue!
The canning of meat is quite a sweet treat,
so thanks for comparing us so.
Your words are inspiring, my dear so concrete,
you really put on quite a show!
Okay, hold up,
you wanna talk words and verse,
but your face is distracting, so ugly it bugs me,
take care of that mess and sweep it under the rug please,
so trust me, you're only taking matters from bad to worse,
so the only solution is to turn around in reverse.
A gift to us, a new perspective on things,
life looking different from where you stand true?
So much to discover so spread your wings
and take flight for a birds eye view!
Okay, things be getting serious,
you guys are delirious, are you hearing this?
Talkin' 'bout positive things, but you ain't got no game,
and it's plain to see, you're strange to me
'coz we be shining like diamonds,
y'all be petty cash, nice mustache-
-conquistador's been wanting it back,
in fact what are you, a rat-a squirrel-
-some kinda fat meerkat who thinks he's rad-
-and look at that-
-your bird friend's dropping words absurd again,
you spit a rhyme that exposes the nerd in him,
if you think Alpha Dog is gonna lie down and let you win,
your head be all inflated I guess just like a giant blimp.
Okay Pops, you got this!
Yeah, you can finish him off!
It's been some time since I've felt this way,
challenged by such worthy opponents.
Your rhyme scheme is good but you're missing a few components.
You may say things that are hurt or some things that will sting,
but for you it's all just posturing.
Look inside and be true to some real feelings
and the world will be yours I'm assuring you.
So I thank you good sirs for this great contest-
-it's certainly been lots of fun,
但是你们说什么都不能打败我
but there's nothing you can say to put me to rest,
所以真的 我已经赢了
so really, I've already won.
我们做到了 我们赢了
We did it, we won!
我们不是废物
We're not losers!
这真是令人兴奋
My, that was exhilarating!
谢谢你们支持我
Thank you for standing by me,
诗歌的力量在友谊面前不算什么
the power of poetry is nothing compared to the power of friendship!
没问题帕布
No problem Pops.
我只是很高兴没有人再叫我们废物了
I'm just glad no-one can call us losers now.
废物们 你们哪里拿的戏服
Hey losers, where'd you get those outfits?
我妈的衣柜
My mom's closet?
我们最好去换一下衣服
We should probably go change clothes.