[Script Info]
; Script generated by Aegisub 3.2.2
; http://www.aegisub.org/
Title: 深影字幕组
Original Script: ShinY
Synch Point: 0
ScriptType: v4.00+
PlayResX: 1920
PlayResY: 1080
Timer: 100.0000
YCbCr Matrix: TV.709

[Aegisub Project Garbage]
Audio File: the.walking.dead.dead.city.s02e01.1080p.web.h264-nhtfs[EZTVx.to]
Video File: the.walking.dead.dead.city.s02e01.1080p.web.h264-nhtfs[EZTVx.to]
Video AR Mode: 4
Video AR Value: 1.777778
Video Zoom Percent: 0.375000
Scroll Position: 7
Active Line: 8
Video Position: 727

[V4+ Styles]
Format: Name, Fontname, Fontsize, PrimaryColour, SecondaryColour, OutlineColour, BackColour, Bold, Italic, Underline, StrikeOut, ScaleX, ScaleY, Spacing, Angle, BorderStyle, Outline, Shadow, Alignment, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Encoding
Style: Default,方正黑体简体,78,&H00FFFFFF,&HF0000000,&H00000000,&H00000000,0,0,0,0,100,100,0,0,1,1.2,0,2,15,15,24,134

[Events]
Format: Layer, Start, End, Style, Name, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Effect, Text
Dialogue: 0,0:00:02.40,0:00:15.00,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fad(400,0)}{\3c&H000000&}{\pos(960,972)}{\fs312}{\fscx0\t(0,500,\fscx850)}{\alpha&H9F&\c&H000000&}{\bord3}{\shad3\blur12}■
Dialogue: 0,0:00:15.00,0:00:15.50,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fad(0,400)}{\3c&H000000&}{\pos(960,972)}{\fs312}{\fscx650\t(0,500,\fscx0)}{\alpha&H9F&\c&H000000&}{\bord3}{\shad3\blur12}■
Dialogue: 0,0:00:00.80,0:00:15.00,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fe134}{\fad(500,500)}{\c&HFFFFFF&}{\pos(960,810)}{\fs60}{\fn方正细倩简体\fsp0}{\bord0}本字幕由{\fs84}{\fn方正综艺简体}{\fe0}{\c&H1DE9FF&} ShinY {\fe134}{\fn方正宋黑简体}{\c&HFFA40C&}深影字幕组{\fscy100}{\fe134}{\fn方正细倩简体}{\c&HFFFFFF&}{\fs60} 原创翻译制作
Dialogue: 0,0:00:01.60,0:00:15.00,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fad(500,500)}{\pos(960,900)}{\fn方正细倩简体}{\fs54}{\b0}{\bord0}{\shad3}{\c&HFFFFFF&}{\3c&H2F2F2F&}{\4c&H000000&}{\fsp0}{\fs60}{\c&HFFFFFF&}长期招募翻译人员若干人，请加QQ群327417194（验证：翻译）
Dialogue: 0,0:00:15.80,0:00:20.30,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fad(400,0)}{\3c&H000000&}{\pos(960,918)}{\fs120}{\fscx10\t(0,500,\fscx1300)}{\fscy120}{\alpha&H9F&\c&H000000&}{\bord3}{\shad3\blur12}■
Dialogue: 0,0:00:20.30,0:00:20.80,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fad(0,400)}{\3c&H000000&}{\pos(960,918)}{\fs120}{\fscx1300\t(0,500,\fscx0)}{\fscy120}{\alpha&H9F&\c&H000000&}{\bord3}{\shad3\blur12}■
Dialogue: 0,0:00:15.80,0:00:20.50,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fad(500,500)}{\pos(960,873)}{\fn方正细倩简体}{\bord0}{\fs60}{\c&H1BE5FF&}翻译：{\fs60} {\c&HFFFFFF&}吃西瓜不吐西瓜皮 221B角落里的花生 星月山 加州小疯紫
Dialogue: 0,0:00:20.80,0:00:30.30,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fad(400,0)}{\3c&H000000&}{\pos(960,918)}{\fs120}{\fscx10\t(0,500,\fscx2200)}{\fscy120}{\alpha&H9F&\c&H000000&}{\bord3}{\shad3\blur12}■
Dialogue: 0,0:00:30.30,0:00:31.00,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fad(0,400)}{\3c&H000000&}{\pos(960,918)}{\fs120}{\fscx2200\t(0,500,\fscx0)}{\fscy120}{\alpha&H9F&\c&H000000&}{\bord3}{\shad3\blur12}■
Dialogue: 0,0:00:20.80,0:00:30.50,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fad(500,500)}{\pos(960,873)}{\fn方正细倩简体}{\bord0}{\fs60}{\c&H1BE5FF&} 校对：{\fs60} {\c&HFFFFFF&} Sisyphus_44 {\fs60} {\c&H1BE5FF&} {\c&H1BE5FF&} 压制：{\fs60}{\c&HFFFFFF&} 认真打滚儿 {\fs60} {\c&H1BE5FF&} {\c&H1BE5FF&} 
Dialogue: 0,0:00:00.00,0:00:12.00,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fscx80}{\an5\t(0,3000,0.5,\fry360)}{\fad(300,0)}{\shad0}{\bord0}{\alpha&H9F&\3c&HFFFFFF&}{\fn@百度综艺简体}{\pos(1770,171)}{\fs90}S{\fs60}hin{\fs90}Y
Dialogue: 0,0:00:00.00,0:00:12.00,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fscx80}{\an5\t(0,4000,0.5,\fry360)}{\fad(300,0)}{\shad0}{\bord0}{\alpha&H9F&\3c&HFFFFFF&}{\pos(1770,120)}深影
Dialogue: 0,0:00:12.00,0:00:15.00,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fscx80}{\an5\t(0,3000,0.5,\fry360)}{\fad(0,300)\1a&HFF&}{\shad0}{\bord0}{\alpha&H9F&\3c&HFFFFFF&}{\fn@百度综艺简体}{\pos(1770,171)}{\fs90}S{\fs60}hin{\fs90}Y
Dialogue: 0,0:00:12.00,0:00:15.00,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fscx80}{\an5\t(0,3000,0.5,\fry270)}{\fad(0,300)\1a&HFF&}{\shad0}{\bord0}{\alpha&H9F&\3c&HFFFFFF&}{\pos(1770,120)}深影
Dialogue: 0,0:00:15.00,0:00:30.00,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fscx80}{\an5}{\fad(0,300)\1a&HFF&}{\shad0}{\bord0}{\alpha&H9F&\3c&HFFFFFF&}{\fn@百度综艺简体}{\pos(1770,171)}{\fs90}S{\fs60}hin{\fs90}Y
Dialogue: 0,0:00:15.00,0:00:30.00,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fscx80}{\an5}{\fad(0,300)\1a&HFF&}{\shad0}{\bord0}{\alpha&H9F&\3c&HFFFFFF&}{\pos(1770,120)}深影
Dialogue: 0,0:00:30.00,0:00:42.00,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fscx80}{\an5\t(0,3000,0.5,\fry360)}{\fad(300,0)}{\shad0}{\bord0}{\alpha&H9F&\3c&HFFFFFF&}{\fn@百度综艺简体}{\pos(1770,171)}{\fs90}S{\fs60}hin{\fs90}Y
Dialogue: 0,0:00:30.00,0:00:42.00,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fscx80}{\an5\t(0,4000,0.5,\fry360)}{\fad(300,0)}{\shad0}{\bord0}{\alpha&H9F&\3c&HFFFFFF&}{\pos(1770,120)}深影
Dialogue: 0,0:00:42.00,0:00:45.00,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fscx80}{\an5\t(0,3000,0.5,\fry360)}{\fad(0,300)\1a&HFF&}{\shad0}{\bord0}{\alpha&H9F&\3c&HFFFFFF&}{\fn@百度综艺简体}{\pos(1770,171)}{\fs90}S{\fs60}hin{\fs90}Y
Dialogue: 0,0:00:42.00,0:00:45.00,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fscx80}{\an5\t(0,3000,0.5,\fry270)}{\fad(0,300)\1a&HFF&}{\shad0}{\bord0}{\alpha&H9F&\3c&HFFFFFF&}{\pos(1770,120)}深影
Dialogue: 0,0:00:45.00,0:01:00.00,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fscx80}{\an5}{\fad(0,300)\1a&HFF&}{\shad0}{\bord0}{\alpha&H9F&\3c&HFFFFFF&}{\fn@百度综艺简体}{\pos(1770,171)}{\fs90}S{\fs60}hin{\fs90}Y
Dialogue: 0,0:00:45.00,0:01:00.00,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fscx80}{\an5}{\fad(0,300)\1a&HFF&}{\shad0}{\bord0}{\alpha&H9F&\3c&HFFFFFF&}{\pos(1770,120)}深影
Dialogue: 0,0:57:42.42,0:57:57.44,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fad(500,500)}{\pos(960,888)}{\fs120}{\fscy100}{\fscx3050}{\alpha&H80&}{\c&HAE6B00&}{\bord0}{\shad0}■
Dialogue: 0,0:57:42.42,0:57:57.44,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fad(500,500)}{\fn微软雅黑\b1\fs72}{\pos(960,864)}{\bord0}{\shad0}{\c&H42F4FF&}更多精彩 请登录深影论坛 sybbs.vip
Dialogue: 0,0:57:42.42,0:57:57.44,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fad(500,500)}{\pos(960,978)}{\fs120}{\fscy100}{\fscx3050}{\alpha&H80&}{\c&H1490FF&}{\bord0}{\shad0}■
Dialogue: 0,0:57:42.42,0:57:57.44,*Default,NTP,0,0,0,,{\fad(500,500)}{\fn微软雅黑\b1\fs72}{\pos(960,954)}{\bord0}{\shad0}{\c&H42F4FF&}深影字幕组微博 weibo.com/syfansub
Dialogue: 0,0:58:02.44,0:58:17.45,Default,,0,0,0,,{\an4\fad(500,500)\shad0\bord0\fscx900\fscy400\blur9\pos(-14.4,843.426)}■
Dialogue: 0,0:58:02.44,0:58:17.45,Default,,0,0,0,,{\p1\an1\1c&H004BED&\alpha80\fad(500,500)\shad0\bord0\fscx363\fscy290\pos(60.574,931.718)}m 0 0 l 0 16 l 15 16 l 15 0 m 2 2 l 13 2 l 13 14 l 2 14 m 5 5 l 11 5 l 11 11 l 5 11 m 18 0 l 18 2 l 22 2 l 22 0 m 0 18 l 9 18 l 9 22 l 11 22 l 11 25 l 13 25 l 13 27 l 15 27 l 15 29 l 13 29 l 13 31 l 15 31 l 15 29 l 20 29 l 20 27 l 15 27 l 15 24 l 13 24 l 13 22 l 15 22 l 15 20 l 13 20 l 13 18 l 15 18 l 15 20 l 18 20 l 18 18 l 20 18 l 20 20 l 22 20 l 22 22 l 20 22 l 20 27 l 22 27 l 22 29 l 20 29 l 20 31 l 18 31 l 18 33 l 20 33 l 20 31 l 22 31 l 22 29 l 24 29 l 24 25 l 29 25 l 29 18 l 35 18 l 35 20 l 38 20 l 38 25 l 36 25 l 36 22 l 33 22 l 33 25 l 31 25 l 31 33 l 29 33 l 29 36 l 27 36 l 27 38 l 24 38 l 24 36 l 27 36 l 27 31 l 29 31 l 29 27 l 26 27 l 26 31 l 25 31 l 24 31 l 24 33 l 22 33 l 22 36 l 18 36 l 18 38 l 13 38 l 13 36 l 16 36 l 16 33 l 5 33 l 5 31 l 2 31 l 2 33 l 0 33 l 0 31 l 2 31 l 2 24 l 0 24 l 0 22 l 2 22 l 2 20 l 0 20 m 4 20 l 4 29 l 11 29 l 11 27 l 7 27 l 7 20 m 0 49 l 15 49 l 15 64 l 0 64 m 2 51 l 2 62 l 13 62 l 13 51 m 5 54 l 5 60 l 11 60 l 11 54 m 49 0 l 49 16 l 64 16 l 64 0 m 51 2 l 62 2 l 62 14 l 51 14 m 54 5 l 60 5 l 60 11 l 54 11 m 0 38 l 2 38 l 2 36 l 11 36 l 11 38 l 13 38 l 13 40 l 16 40 l 16 42 l 18 42 l 18 40 l 20 40 l 20 38 l 22 38 l 22 40 l 20 40 l 20 42 l 18 42 l 18 45 l 16 45 l 16 47 l 13 47 l 13 45 l 16 45 l 16 42 l 13 42 l 13 45 l 9 45 l 9 42 l 13 42 l 13 40 l 11 40 l 11 38 l 9 38 l 9 42 l 7 42 l 7 47 l 4 47 l 4 45 l 2 45 l 2 47 l 0 47 l 0 42 l 2 42 l 2 40 l 7 40 l 7 38 l 2 38 l 2 40 l 0 40 m 18 5 l 18 11 l 20 11 l 20 13 l 18 13 l 18 16 l 20 16 l 20 18 l 22 18 l 22 16 l 24 16 l 24 18 l 26 18 l 26 16 l 29 16 l 29 11 l 26 11 l 26 16 l 24 16 l 24 13 l 22 13 l 22 16 l 20 16 l 20 13 l 22 13 l 22 11 l 26 11 l 26 7 l 29 7 l 29 9 l 33 9 l 33 11 l 33 11 l 31 11 l 31 16 l 33 16 l 33 11 l 38 11 l 38 13 l 36 13 l 36 15 l 38 15 l 38 20 l 40 20 l 40 18 l 44 18 l 44 16 l 46 16 l 46 11 l 44 11 l 44 9 l 46 9 l 46 7 l 44 7 l 44 9 l 42 9 l 42 13 l 44 13 l 44 16 l 42 16 l 42 13 l 40 13 l 40 11 l 38 11 l 38 5 l 33 5 l 33 2 l 40 2 l 40 7 l 42 7 l 42 2 l 44 2 l 44 4 l 46 4 l 46 2 l 44 2 l 44 0 l 31 0 l 31 2 l 29 2 l 29 4 l 24 4 l 24 9 l 22 9 l 22 7 l 20 7 l 20 5 m 40 15 l 38 15 l 38 13 l 40 13 m 18 64 l 18 56 l 20 56 l 20 58 l 22 58 l 22 54 l 20 54 l 20 51 l 22 51 l 22 49 l 18 49 l 18 45 l 20 45 l 20 47 l 24 47 l 24 45 l 22 45 l 22 40 l 27 40 l 27 38 l 29 38 l 29 36 l 31 36 l 31 33 l 33 33 l 33 36 l 31 36 l 31 38 l 29 38 l 29 45 l 33 45 l 33 47 l 29 47 l 29 51 l 24 51 l 24 56 l 27 56 l 27 54 l 29 54 l 29 51 l 31 51 l 31 49 l 33 49 l 33 54 l 31 54 l 31 56 l 29 56 l 29 58 l 33 58 l 33 62 l 36 62 l 36 64 l 31 64 l 31 60 l 29 60 l 29 58 l 27 58 l 27 62 l 22 62 l 22 64 m 40 64 l 40 62 l 42 62 l 42 64 m 40 60 l 42 60 l 42 58 l 40 58 m 36 60 l 36 56 l 33 56 l 33 54 l 36 54 l 36 56 l 38 56 l 38 54 l 40 54 l 40 56 l 38 56 l 38 60 m 44 64 l 44 58 l 46 58 l 46 56 l 44 56 l 44 51 l 42 51 l 42 54 l 40 54 l 40 51 l 35 51 l 35 49 l 40 49 l 40 47 l 38 47 l 38 45 l 35 45 l 35 42 l 33 42 l 33 40 l 31 40 l 31 38 l 33 38 l 33 36 l 38 36 l 38 38 l 35 38 l 35 40 l 38 40 l 38 38 l 40 38 l 40 40 l 38 40 l 38 42 l 40 42 l 40 40 l 42 40 l 42 42 l 44 42 l 44 38 l 40 38 l 40 33 l 36 33 l 36 29 l 33 29 l 33 25 l 36 25 l 36 27 l 38 27 l 38 29 l 42 29 l 42 27 l 40 27 l 40 25 l 47 25 l 47 18 l 49 18 l 49 20 l 54 20 l 54 18 l 60 18 l 60 20 l 56 20 l 56 22 l 56 22 l 51 22 l 51 25 l 47 25 l 47 25 l 47 27 l 49 27 l 49 29 l 47 29 l 47 27 l 44 27 l 44 31 l 49 31 l 49 29 l 51 29 l 51 31 l 49 31 l 49 33 l 51 33 l 51 36 l 49 36 l 49 45 l 51 45 l 51 38 l 53 38 l 53 36 l 55 36 l 55 38 l 53 38 l 53 40 l 58 40 l 58 38 l 60 38 l 60 33 l 56 33 l 56 31 l 60 31 l 60 29 l 56 29 l 56 27 l 53 27 l 53 25 l 58 25 l 58 22 l 62 22 l 62 18 l 64 18 l 64 22 l 62 22 l 62 25 l 64 25 l 64 27 l 62 27 l 62 25 l 58 25 l 58 27 l 60 27 l 60 29 l 64 29 l 64 33 l 62 33 l 62 40 l 60 40 l 60 47 l 64 47 l 64 49 l 62 49 l 62 54 l 64 54 l 64 60 l 62 60 l 62 56 l 60 56 l 60 60 l 62 60 l 62 64 l 60 64 l 60 60 l 58 60 l 58 58 l 53 58 l 53 60 l 58 60 l 58 62 l 51 62 l 51 55 l 49 55 l 49 64 m 27 42 l 24 42 l 24 45 l 27 45 m 27 47 l 24 47 l 24 49 l 27 49 m 44 47 l 42 47 l 42 49 l 44 49 m 58 42 l 55 42 l 55 45 l 58 45 m 58 49 l 58 51 l 55 51 l 55 54 l 60 54 l 60 49 m 46 54 l 53 54 l 53 47 l 46 47 m 49 49 l 49 51 l 51 51 l 51 49 m 42 20 l 42 22 l 44 22 l 44 20
Dialogue: 0,0:52:10.44,0:52:25.45,Default,,0,0,0,,{\fad(500,500)\fn微软雅黑\b1\an1\fs48\1c&H000000&\shad0\bord0\pos(294.384,936.033)}关注深影字幕组\N微信公众号，更\N多影视资讯，等\N你来发现

Dialogue: 0,0:00:05.35,0:00:07.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,《死亡之城》前情提要\NPreviously on Dead City...
Dialogue: 0,0:00:07.09,0:00:09.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我是新巴比伦的执法官 你见过这个男人吗\NI'm a New Babylon marshal. Have you seen this man?
Dialogue: 0,0:00:10.90,0:00:13.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你是我最不想求助的人\NYou're the last person that I wanted to ask for help.
Dialogue: 0,0:00:13.11,0:00:14.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他们绑走了你的孩子\NThey took your kid.
Dialogue: 0,0:00:14.41,0:00:15.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个带走荷歇尔的男人\NThe man who's got Hershel,
Dialogue: 0,0:00:15.87,0:00:17.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,被称为"克罗地亚人"\Nthey call him the Croat.
Dialogue: 0,0:00:15.87,0:00:17.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\an8}克罗地亚人 来自克罗地亚的前救世军成员 多年前与尼更撕破脸后流亡到纽约曼哈顿 组建起延续救世军理念的“兄弟帮”（The Burazi）
Dialogue: 0,0:00:17.12,0:00:19.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我一路追踪他到曼哈顿\NI tracked him all the way up to Manhattan.
Dialogue: 0,0:00:19.34,0:00:20.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,曼哈顿是爆发区之一\NManhattan was one of the epicenters.
Dialogue: 0,0:00:20.78,0:00:23.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,部队摧毁了所有的桥和隧道 想要控制那里\NMilitary destroyed all the bridges and tunnels hoping to contain it.
Dialogue: 0,0:00:23.56,0:00:26.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,死尸是那里最丰富的资源\NDeath is the most abundant resource.
Dialogue: 0,0:00:26.68,0:00:29.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,尸体腐败会产生大量的甲烷\NAs the bodies break down, they produce methane.
Dialogue: 0,0:00:29.06,0:00:30.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嘿 当这些都结束了\NHey, when this is over,
Dialogue: 0,0:00:30.57,0:00:32.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你会帮我照看金妮吗\Nwill you look after Ginny for me?
Dialogue: 0,0:00:32.27,0:00:34.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我杀了你的父亲\NI killed your dad.
Dialogue: 0,0:00:35.19,0:00:37.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是我在一家旅游纪念品店里找到的\NFound this in one of those tourist shops,
Dialogue: 0,0:00:37.07,0:00:38.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我觉得你也许可以把它给荷歇尔\NI thought maybe you could give it to Hershel.
Dialogue: 0,0:00:38.85,0:00:40.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他需要有人推他一把\NHe needed a little push...
Dialogue: 0,0:00:40.14,0:00:41.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,妈妈\NMom!
Dialogue: 0,0:00:41.14,0:00:43.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是你把他带回家了\NBut you brought him home.
Dialogue: 0,0:00:43.16,0:00:45.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你被尼更迷住了 对他做的事也着了迷\NYou're obsessed with Negan, with what he did.
Dialogue: 0,0:00:45.29,0:00:46.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这不是真的\NThat is not true!
Dialogue: 0,0:00:46.39,0:00:47.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是你从不懂我\NBut you never see me.
Dialogue: 0,0:00:47.63,0:00:48.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还有其他人\NThere are others.
Dialogue: 0,0:00:48.81,0:00:51.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果能联合他们 那我们将坚不可摧\NIf we could unite them, we'll be indomitable.
Dialogue: 0,0:00:51.37,0:00:52.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我为什么要帮你\NWhy would I help you?
Dialogue: 0,0:00:52.98,0:00:55.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我和之前那位客人聊了很多\NMy former guest and I had a lot of talks.
Dialogue: 0,0:00:55.94,0:00:58.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,最终我让他走了 换了你来\NI eventually let him go in exchange for you.
Dialogue: 0,0:00:58.73,0:01:01.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是我保留了他的一小部分\NBut I kept a little piece of him
Dialogue: 0,0:01:01.43,0:01:04.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,并且我可以随时回去拿更多\Nand I can always go back for more.
Dialogue: 0,0:03:12.71,0:03:21.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\an8}无线电城音乐厅
Dialogue: 0,0:04:03.00,0:04:07.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,行尸走肉：死亡之城 第二季 第一集
Dialogue: 0,0:04:11.02,0:04:12.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等等\NWait...
Dialogue: 0,0:04:12.98,0:04:15.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,从头顶 记得吗\NOverhand, remember?
Dialogue: 0,0:04:15.07,0:04:17.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,会打得更准 转速更高\NIt's more accurate. More spin.
Dialogue: 0,0:04:26.15,0:04:29.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没事的 熟能生巧 你可以的\NIt's okay. You'll get it. Okay.
Dialogue: 0,0:04:41.76,0:04:44.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你被荆棘划伤了\NYou get scraped by the brambles?
Dialogue: 0,0:04:44.23,0:04:45.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我没事\NI'm fine.
Dialogue: 0,0:05:46.27,0:05:47.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你确定吗\NYou sure about this?
Dialogue: 0,0:05:47.81,0:05:51.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,凯西想要张书桌 我也用不着了 就给她吧\NCasey wanted a desk for her room and I don't use it anymore, so.
Dialogue: 0,0:05:51.11,0:05:52.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好吧\NAll right.
Dialogue: 0,0:05:54.91,0:05:57.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也许能找到些你的旧衣服捐给她的兄弟们\NProbably got some old clothes you can donate to her brothers.
Dialogue: 0,0:06:33.68,0:06:36.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你这件灯芯绒夹克好像已经穿不下了\NLooks like you outgrew the corduroy jacket.
Dialogue: 0,0:06:36.21,0:06:37.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,行 带着它吧\NSure. Take it.
Dialogue: 0,0:06:40.92,0:06:44.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,其实 我觉得有点累了\NActually, I'm feeling kinda tired.
Dialogue: 0,0:06:45.13,0:06:47.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也许我们能明天或者改天再去\NMaybe we can take it down tomorrow or something.
Dialogue: 0,0:06:47.91,0:06:49.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,当然\NOf course.
Dialogue: 0,0:07:17.81,0:07:19.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们之间的暗号\NOur signal.
Dialogue: 0,0:07:21.74,0:07:23.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在你小时候 以防我们走散了\NWhen you were little, in case we got separated,
Dialogue: 0,0:07:23.69,0:07:25.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,通过它我能确保你没事\Nso I'd know that you were okay.
Dialogue: 0,0:07:26.18,0:07:28.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你还记得是怎么开始的吗\NDo you remember how it started?
Dialogue: 0,0:07:28.22,0:07:29.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你五六岁的时候\NYou were five or six.
Dialogue: 0,0:07:29.96,0:07:33.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们在路上 营地在查尔斯顿的北边\NWe were on the road, camping just north of Charleston.
Dialogue: 0,0:07:35.09,0:07:39.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我醒来时 听到了外面传来脚踩树叶的声音\NI woke up, heard feet crunching on leaves outside.
Dialogue: 0,0:07:40.01,0:07:42.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后我发现你的毯子是空的\NThen I noticed your blanket was empty.
Dialogue: 0,0:07:42.53,0:07:45.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以我起身 拔出了我的刀\NSo I got up, pulled my knife out,
Dialogue: 0,0:07:45.71,0:07:48.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,朝声音传来的方向走去\Nstarted toward the sound.
Dialogue: 0,0:07:48.37,0:07:51.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,突然之间 一个家伙从灌木丛的后面冲过来\NThen all of a sudden, this creature came running from behind the bushes.
Dialogue: 0,0:07:51.99,0:07:53.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一个小小的声音响起\NAnd a little voice said,
Dialogue: 0,0:07:54.54,0:07:57.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看 妈妈 我找到了\N"Look, Mom! I got it".
Dialogue: 0,0:07:59.38,0:08:01.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你捧起双手\NAnd you had your hands cupped together,
Dialogue: 0,0:08:01.95,0:08:04.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后摊开给我看\Nand you opened them up to show me...
Dialogue: 0,0:08:04.63,0:08:06.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一只萤火虫\NA lightning bug.
Dialogue: 0,0:08:06.30,0:08:08.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是啊 一只萤火虫\NYeah, a lightning bug.
Dialogue: 0,0:08:56.16,0:08:57.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你还有剩菜吗\NYou got any leftovers?
Dialogue: 0,0:09:00.71,0:09:01.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我有什么好处\NWhat's in it for me?
Dialogue: 0,0:09:01.93,0:09:03.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个嘛 我能给你的是\NWell, what's in it for you is
Dialogue: 0,0:09:03.29,0:09:05.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你不用吃整盘的蟑螂\Nyou don't have to eat a plate of cockroaches.
Dialogue: 0,0:09:06.67,0:09:10.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,或者我用这个跟你交易\NOr I can trade you for this
Dialogue: 0,0:09:11.17,0:09:14.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一桶我精心制作的排泄物\Nlovely bucket of my very own piss and shit.
Dialogue: 0,0:09:14.19,0:09:17.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,呃 我看到那桶了\NYeah. I uh... I have had my eye on that bucket
Dialogue: 0,0:09:17.48,0:09:18.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,从几个月前就注意到了\Nfor the past couple of months.
Dialogue: 0,0:09:18.76,0:09:20.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我知道你看到了\NI know you have.
Dialogue: 0,0:09:20.68,0:09:23.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是 我还是想要那条破毯子\NBut, I think I'll hold out for that ratty blanket.
Dialogue: 0,0:09:39.09,0:09:40.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,谢谢你\NThank you.
Dialogue: 0,0:09:47.70,0:09:50.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一年前你说过\NYou said a year ago that
Dialogue: 0,0:09:50.23,0:09:53.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我会求着你要那些蟑螂\NI would be begging for cockroaches.
Dialogue: 0,0:09:56.36,0:09:57.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,上帝啊\NChrist.
Dialogue: 0,0:10:02.07,0:10:03.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看起来怎么样\NHow's it looking?
Dialogue: 0,0:10:51.10,0:10:52.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,打开它\NUnlock it.
Dialogue: 0,0:11:16.20,0:11:20.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看见你这样我真难过\NIt pains me to see you like this.
Dialogue: 0,0:11:23.83,0:11:25.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,时间不多了 尼更\NTime has run out, Negan.
Dialogue: 0,0:11:26.67,0:11:28.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她会说的\NShe's going to talk,
Dialogue: 0,0:11:29.71,0:11:31.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你要好好听着\Nand you need to listen now.
Dialogue: 0,0:11:32.56,0:11:34.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你准备好听了吗\NAre you ready to listen?
Dialogue: 0,0:11:36.00,0:11:37.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个男孩怎么样\NWhat about the boy?
Dialogue: 0,0:11:39.47,0:11:42.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你知道的 我自己想过这事\NYou know, I have been thinking about that myself.
Dialogue: 0,0:11:42.51,0:11:45.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你看 他回家了 他安全了\NYou see, he is home. He's safe.
Dialogue: 0,0:11:45.43,0:11:47.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为了找到他\NAnd in order to get to him,
Dialogue: 0,0:11:47.04,0:11:49.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你需要找到他的妈妈\Nyou would have to go through his mom.
Dialogue: 0,0:11:49.74,0:11:52.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我不确定你是否记得 但是\NWho, I'm not sure that if you recall, but,
Dialogue: 0,0:11:52.39,0:11:55.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她要是狠起来\Nshe is a mama bear
Dialogue: 0,0:11:55.00,0:11:57.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就像一只先开膛破肚\Nthat would tear out your throat with her teeth
Dialogue: 0,0:11:57.97,0:12:01.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,再咬断你喉咙的母熊\Nright after she gutted you with her claws.
Dialogue: 0,0:12:01.81,0:12:05.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对 这些就是我所想到的\NYeah, that's what I've been thinking about.
Dialogue: 0,0:12:05.88,0:12:09.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嘿 别担心 我很好\NHey, don't you worry about me. I'm good.
Dialogue: 0,0:12:09.32,0:12:12.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看看这个 我有张超棒的床\NLook at this. I got this nice bed.
Dialogue: 0,0:12:12.76,0:12:17.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我有独立卫生间 美味的食物\NI got a private toilet. Gourmet meals.
Dialogue: 0,0:12:21.72,0:12:24.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,唔 这正是我喜欢的\NMm, it's just how I like it,
Dialogue: 0,0:12:24.76,0:12:26.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,外酥里嫩\Ncrunchy on the outside and soft in the middle.
Dialogue: 0,0:12:37.93,0:12:43.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这样的话 我担心事态会升级\NIn that case, i fear things will have to escalate.
Dialogue: 0,0:13:47.58,0:13:48.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们得回去\NWe need to get back.
Dialogue: 0,0:14:12.90,0:14:18.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\an8} 欢迎来到新巴比伦联邦成员: 砖墙区 成立于P.D.I 纪元17年 布鲁里奇领地
Dialogue: 0,0:14:21.37,0:14:23.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果各位不记得我了\NIf you all don't remember me from admission day,
Dialogue: 0,0:14:23.98,0:14:25.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我是查理·伯德\NI'm Charlie Byrd,
Dialogue: 0,0:14:26.09,0:14:28.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,新巴比伦联邦总督\Ngovernor of The New Babylon Federation.
Dialogue: 0,0:14:28.46,0:14:29.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也就是你们的总督\NYour governor.
Dialogue: 0,0:14:30.91,0:14:32.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我可以继续闲扯 但是\NI could ramble on, but,
Dialogue: 0,0:14:33.13,0:14:35.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我觉得你们更想听另一位杰出人士的讲话\NI got a feeling you'd rather hear from someone
Dialogue: 0,0:14:35.04,0:14:37.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个男人声名远播\Nwhose reputation precedes him,
Dialogue: 0,0:14:38.09,0:14:42.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,去过遥远大陆 有过重大发现\Na man who traveled to a distant land, made huge discoveries.
Dialogue: 0,0:14:42.93,0:14:44.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果这还不够 那么\NAnd as if that weren't enough,
Dialogue: 0,0:14:44.91,0:14:48.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他追踪到了臭名昭著的亡命之徒 尼更\Ntracked down the notorious outlaw, Negan,
Dialogue: 0,0:14:48.13,0:14:49.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,并带他回来接受审判\Nand brought him to justice.
Dialogue: 0,0:14:52.89,0:14:54.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,谢谢您 总督\NThank you, Governor.
Dialogue: 0,0:14:57.93,0:15:00.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,时至今日 我觉得可以这么说\NLooking around today, I think it's fair to say,
Dialogue: 0,0:15:01.30,0:15:03.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们不再只是侥幸存活\Nwe're no longer just lucky to be alive.
Dialogue: 0,0:15:05.35,0:15:06.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们在生活着\NWe're living.
Dialogue: 0,0:15:08.70,0:15:10.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,正在拿回我们所失去的一切\NGetting back what we lost.
Dialogue: 0,0:15:12.98,0:15:14.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但我们的工作并未结束\NBut our work isn't done.
Dialogue: 0,0:15:15.63,0:15:17.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,曾经有这样一个地方\NThere was a place once.
Dialogue: 0,0:15:17.80,0:15:19.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,建筑林立 密密麻麻\NFull of so many buildings, so packed together,
Dialogue: 0,0:15:19.96,0:15:22.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你几乎看不到天空从哪里开始\Nyou could barely see where the sky started.
Dialogue: 0,0:15:22.21,0:15:23.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,它是战略要港\NA strategic port.
Dialogue: 0,0:15:24.98,0:15:26.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是音乐中心\NThe center of music,
Dialogue: 0,0:15:27.27,0:15:31.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有美食 艺术 还有贸易\Nfood, art, and commerce.
Dialogue: 0,0:15:31.83,0:15:35.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这座城市向世界宣告 我们在这里\NA city that announced to the world, we are here.
Dialogue: 0,0:15:35.22,0:15:37.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,人类在这里\NHumanity is here.
Dialogue: 0,0:15:37.85,0:15:39.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如今这里只剩下残垣断壁\NAll that's left today are crumbling buildings
Dialogue: 0,0:15:39.98,0:15:41.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和数以百万的亡魂\Nand a million dead souls.
Dialogue: 0,0:15:41.62,0:15:44.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,无法无天的野人在此横行\NIt's been overrun by lawless barbarians.
Dialogue: 0,0:15:44.54,0:15:47.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么我们为什么还要去那里 我们有何目的\NSo what's our interest in it? Why would we go there?
Dialogue: 0,0:15:49.87,0:15:53.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为了夺回它 现在还不算太迟\NTo bring it back. It's not too late.
Dialogue: 0,0:15:53.83,0:15:58.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,曼哈顿可以重燃并传播希望\NManhattan can once again inspire and spread hope,
Dialogue: 0,0:15:58.34,0:16:01.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,成为文明的堡垒\Nand serve as a bastion for civilization.
Dialogue: 0,0:16:03.17,0:16:06.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,听着 我不会撒谎 这并非易事\NNow, look... I'm not gonna lie, it's not gonna be easy.
Dialogue: 0,0:16:06.21,0:16:09.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这就是我们在城市间奔波的原因\NWhich is why we've been going from town to town,
Dialogue: 0,0:16:09.08,0:16:11.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,征召士兵执行探索任务\Ndrafting soldiers for an exploratory mission,
Dialogue: 0,0:16:11.55,0:16:14.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为这是联邦条约赋予的权利\Nas is the federation's right by treaty.
Dialogue: 0,0:16:15.38,0:16:17.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你们害怕 我理解\NYou're scared. I get it.
Dialogue: 0,0:16:18.31,0:16:20.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但听着 这是一场战役\NBut look, this is a fight.
Dialogue: 0,0:16:21.58,0:16:23.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是值得为之战斗的使命\NThis is a mission worth fighting...
Dialogue: 0,0:16:37.27,0:16:39.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,离开这 金妮\NGo! Ginny.
Dialogue: 0,0:16:47.29,0:16:49.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说出你的名字和城市\NState your name and town.
Dialogue: 0,0:16:49.39,0:16:53.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,杰森·奥内尔 来自马格德堡\NJason Ornell. Madgeburg.
Dialogue: 0,0:16:53.52,0:16:55.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,陈述你的罪行\NState your crime.
Dialogue: 0,0:17:01.89,0:17:04.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在抵达马格德堡之后 奥内尔先生\NAfter arrival at Madgeburg, Mr. Ornell
Dialogue: 0,0:17:04.91,0:17:09.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可耻地选择了逃跑 而非直面征兵\Nchose to shamefully flee rather than face conscription.
Dialogue: 0,0:17:11.48,0:17:13.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他在森林中被捕\NHe was apprehended in the forest.
Dialogue: 0,0:17:16.59,0:17:19.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,第52条 第8节\NCode 52, section 8.
Dialogue: 0,0:17:19.32,0:17:22.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,若拒绝或者逃避注册\N"Refusal or evasion of registration
Dialogue: 0,0:17:22.41,0:17:26.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,进入新巴比伦联邦军队\Ninto the armed forces of The New Babylon Federation
Dialogue: 0,0:17:26.16,0:17:30.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,应处以公开处决\Nshall be punishable by public execution".
Dialogue: 0,0:18:22.03,0:18:24.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们在大陆的耳目\NOur eyes and ears on the mainland
Dialogue: 0,0:18:24.16,0:18:28.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,截获了聚居地之间的通信\Nhave intercepted messages between the colonies.
Dialogue: 0,0:18:28.64,0:18:31.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,会有一次探索行动\NThere is to be an exploratory mission
Dialogue: 0,0:18:31.92,0:18:35.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,随之便是大规模入侵\Nfollowed by a massive land invasion,
Dialogue: 0,0:18:35.43,0:18:40.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因此 我们必须组建好一支自己的军队迎战\Nso we must be ready with an army of our own.
Dialogue: 0,0:18:40.88,0:18:42.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为达到这个目的\NTo that end,
Dialogue: 0,0:18:43.22,0:18:48.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,上城区是由三个组织控制的\Nuptown is controlled by three groups.
Dialogue: 0,0:18:48.49,0:18:51.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他们十分残暴且领地意识极强\NThey are ferocious and territorial.
Dialogue: 0,0:18:53.00,0:18:56.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而这座公园位于他们之间\NAnd the park sits between them,
Dialogue: 0,0:18:56.08,0:18:57.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,作为缓冲地带\Nacting like a buffer.
Dialogue: 0,0:18:57.73,0:18:59.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,无人区\NNo man's land.
Dialogue: 0,0:18:59.04,0:19:02.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错 因为没人能活着走出那里\NYeah, because no man comes out alive.
Dialogue: 0,0:19:04.09,0:19:07.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果我们结盟\NIf we can form an alliance,
Dialogue: 0,0:19:07.70,0:19:10.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,把所有人都拉拢到我们这边\Nbring everyone onto our side,
Dialogue: 0,0:19:10.83,0:19:13.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,届时新巴比伦将不再有机会\Nthen New Babylon won't stand a chance.
Dialogue: 0,0:19:14.38,0:19:18.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,目前 这些组织每月接头一次\NNow, the groups interface once a month,
Dialogue: 0,0:19:19.60,0:19:23.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在这个广场上进行街头交易\Nat this plaza for a form of street trade.
Dialogue: 0,0:19:23.15,0:19:25.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,赌体彩\NGambling on sport.
Dialogue: 0,0:19:25.28,0:19:27.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他们有自己的农贸市场\NGot your own farmer's market.
Dialogue: 0,0:19:27.22,0:19:28.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是啊\NYeah.
Dialogue: 0,0:19:28.47,0:19:31.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是一个名为勃鲁盖尔的男人的智慧结晶\NIt was a brainchild of a man named Bruegel.
Dialogue: 0,0:19:31.92,0:19:34.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不出所料 他从这些交易中\NAnd unsurprisingly, he has accumulated
Dialogue: 0,0:19:34.38,0:19:37.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,积累了大量财富\Na good deal of wealth from this, this trade,
Dialogue: 0,0:19:37.37,0:19:40.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有武器 食物 装甲 还有住所\Nweapons and food, armor, shelter.
Dialogue: 0,0:19:40.25,0:19:44.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他就是个耍蛇的\NHe's a snake, snake charmer.
Dialogue: 0,0:19:44.86,0:19:46.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有三寸不烂之舌\NSilver-tongued...
Dialogue: 0,0:19:49.23,0:19:50.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好吧\NWell...
Dialogue: 0,0:19:50.70,0:19:52.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他们下一次会面就在今晚\NThe next meeting is tonight.
Dialogue: 0,0:19:53.60,0:19:55.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我之后请他们去教堂\NI've invited them to the church afterwards
Dialogue: 0,0:19:55.91,0:19:58.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,再夜间小酌一下\Nfor a little nightcap.
Dialogue: 0,0:19:58.66,0:20:02.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我只能帮到这了\NMy overtures have gotten us as far as they can go.
Dialogue: 0,0:20:02.80,0:20:05.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,现在需要一个领头的\NWhat's required now is leadership.
Dialogue: 0,0:20:05.93,0:20:07.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,来鼓舞士气\NInspire them.
Dialogue: 0,0:20:07.93,0:20:09.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,上点手段\NManipulate.
Dialogue: 0,0:20:10.03,0:20:11.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,给点颜色\NTerrorize.
Dialogue: 0,0:20:11.55,0:20:13.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,逢场作戏\NPut on a show.
Dialogue: 0,0:20:13.25,0:20:16.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不管怎样 先把他们拉入伙再说\NWhatever it takes to get them on board.
Dialogue: 0,0:20:19.66,0:20:21.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,合你的口味吗\NIs it to your liking?
Dialogue: 0,0:20:21.93,0:20:23.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你爱喝金酒 是吧\NYou're a gin man, right?
Dialogue: 0,0:20:23.67,0:20:25.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,确实是\NI am, indeed.
Dialogue: 0,0:20:26.74,0:20:28.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有个问题\NHere's the thing, I...
Dialogue: 0,0:20:28.17,0:20:31.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我感觉我们几个月前已经聊过这个话题了\NI feel like we had this conversation a couple of months ago.
Dialogue: 0,0:20:32.46,0:20:34.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我还是一样的态度\NMy answer's still the same.
Dialogue: 0,0:20:35.88,0:20:37.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没他妈门\NHell no.
Dialogue: 0,0:20:42.44,0:20:44.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你自己已经见识到\NYou yourself have seen
Dialogue: 0,0:20:44.79,0:20:47.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,新巴比伦的本事了\Nwhat New Babylon is capable of.
Dialogue: 0,0:20:48.89,0:20:52.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如达玛所说 现在天赐良机于我们\NAs Dama says, we have been given a gift.
Dialogue: 0,0:20:53.89,0:20:57.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,旧世界 它就是充斥着痛苦和不公\NThe old world, it was a place of suffering and injustice, yes.
Dialogue: 0,0:20:57.98,0:21:00.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是我们的过去已经翻篇了\NBut our past has been erased.
Dialogue: 0,0:21:01.45,0:21:02.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有了甲烷\NWith the methane,
Dialogue: 0,0:21:01.45,0:21:02.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\an8}甲烷是天然气的主要成分 通常作燃料
Dialogue: 0,0:21:05.10,0:21:07.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们就可以妙手回春\Nwe can bring the city back
Dialogue: 0,0:21:07.69,0:21:10.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,让这座这座城市重现生机\Nin wondrous new ways.
Dialogue: 0,0:21:10.47,0:21:12.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,教堂可以成为发电厂\NA church can be a power plant.
Dialogue: 0,0:21:12.96,0:21:16.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,体育老师可以指挥一支军队\NA gym teacher can command an army.
Dialogue: 0,0:21:22.38,0:21:25.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这酒对我来说有点太花哨了\NThis is a little too fancy for my taste.
Dialogue: 0,0:21:28.73,0:21:31.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是心意我领了\NBut I do appreciate the gesture.
Dialogue: 0,0:21:38.82,0:21:43.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你知道吗 我们的人在外面找你的时候\NYou know, when our people were out searching for you,
Dialogue: 0,0:21:43.65,0:21:46.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他们听说在田纳西州有个地方\Nthey heard whispers of a settlement in Tennessee
Dialogue: 0,0:21:46.56,0:21:49.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,住着个女人和一个小孩\Nthat was home to a woman and child.
Dialogue: 0,0:21:49.03,0:21:54.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我没记错的话 叫安妮和乔舒亚\NAnnie and Joshua, if I'm not mistaken.
Dialogue: 0,0:21:56.24,0:22:00.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你也知道 他们的车本来是开往密苏里的\NTheir wagon train was meant for Missouri, as you know,
Dialogue: 0,0:21:56.24,0:22:00.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\an8}密苏里州位于美国中西部
Dialogue: 0,0:22:00.16,0:22:03.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,毕竟是你亲自给司机付的钱\Nconsidering you yourself paid the driver.
Dialogue: 0,0:22:03.22,0:22:06.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是密西西比河涨大水 他们不得已改道去了孟菲斯\NBut a flooded Mississippi rerouted them to Memphis.
Dialogue: 0,0:22:03.22,0:22:06.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\an8}密西西比河位于美国中西部 是北美洲最长河流 孟菲斯是田纳西州最大城市
Dialogue: 0,0:22:07.80,0:22:11.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我讨厌破坏惊喜\NI hate spoiling the surprise,
Dialogue: 0,0:22:11.01,0:22:14.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是既然他们已经在去那个岛的路上的话\Nbut now that they're en route to the island,
Dialogue: 0,0:22:14.01,0:22:17.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我想你应该要做好准备了\NI suppose you'd want to make your preparations.
Dialogue: 0,0:22:27.47,0:22:29.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,至少在曼哈顿 还有一线希望\NAt least with Manhattan, there's a chance.
Dialogue: 0,0:22:30.00,0:22:31.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,- 我们都不知道... - 不\N- We don't know for sure... - No.
Dialogue: 0,0:22:31.61,0:22:34.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,反正都是判死刑\NNo, it's a death sentence either way.
Dialogue: 0,0:22:34.43,0:22:37.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他们带去曼哈顿的人 我们再也见不到了\NAnyone they take to Manhattan, we'll never see them again.
Dialogue: 0,0:22:37.35,0:22:39.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是旧世界的中心\NIt was the capital of the old world.
Dialogue: 0,0:22:40.61,0:22:43.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,坐拥各种博物馆 剧院和教堂\NHome to museums, theaters, churches.
Dialogue: 0,0:22:44.66,0:22:48.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大道就像大草原一样宽广开阔\NAvenues as wide and open as a prairie plain.
Dialogue: 0,0:22:48.84,0:22:53.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且一切很快都会恢复如初\NAnd will all soon be restored just as sublime as it once was.
Dialogue: 0,0:22:56.72,0:22:58.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你笑什么\NExcuse me?
Dialogue: 0,0:22:58.10,0:23:01.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没什么 就是你说的那些完全是放狗屁\NNothing. It's just everything you're saying is total bullshit.
Dialogue: 0,0:23:01.17,0:23:04.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好啊 我花了几年时间把课本\NWell, considering I've spent years poring over old textbooks,
Dialogue: 0,0:23:04.87,0:23:06.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,地图 还有期刊都翻烂了\Nmaps and periodicals,
Dialogue: 0,0:23:06.37,0:23:10.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我觉得我不至于就只是放了个屁吧\NI would think that what I'm saying is not total bullshit.
Dialogue: 0,0:23:10.33,0:23:11.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你又没去过那里\NBut you haven't been there.
Dialogue: 0,0:23:13.21,0:23:15.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等等 难道你... 什么...\NWait, you've... What's it...
Dialogue: 0,0:23:15.13,0:23:17.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那里全是僵尸\NIt's full of walkers.
Dialogue: 0,0:23:17.17,0:23:18.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,比你吃过的盐还多\NMore than you've ever seen before.
Dialogue: 0,0:23:18.70,0:23:20.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还有 那些博物馆和教堂\NAnd... and those museums and churches,
Dialogue: 0,0:23:20.55,0:23:22.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不是被抢就是被炸了\Nthey've all been looted or blown up.
Dialogue: 0,0:23:22.44,0:23:26.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有座桥 在楼房之间高高挂起\NThere's this one bridge, high up between the buildings,
Dialogue: 0,0:23:26.40,0:23:28.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,开始要倒了 但它自己又稳住了\Nit started to fall, but then it caught itself
Dialogue: 0,0:23:28.37,0:23:30.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后就扭成一团 就像是...\Nand got all twisted, so it's like uh...
Dialogue: 0,0:23:31.58,0:23:33.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,给我 我画给你看\NHere, I'll show you.
Dialogue: 0,0:23:53.03,0:23:55.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不可同日而语啊\NIt's better now than it ever was.
Dialogue: 0,0:23:56.65,0:23:58.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我可以留着吗\NCan I keep this?
Dialogue: 0,0:23:58.43,0:23:59.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,啊 可以 当然\NUh, yeah, sure.
Dialogue: 0,0:24:09.82,0:24:11.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为什么不等吃完晚饭再聊这个\NWhy don't we pick this up after dinner?
Dialogue: 0,0:24:20.79,0:24:22.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是你的儿子啊\NSo that's your son.
Dialogue: 0,0:24:23.59,0:24:25.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是我的儿子\NThat's my son.
Dialogue: 0,0:24:29.81,0:24:31.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有一阵子了\NIt's been a while.
Dialogue: 0,0:24:31.55,0:24:34.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是啊 恭喜啊 顺便一提\NYeah. Congratulations, by the way.
Dialogue: 0,0:24:35.12,0:24:37.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,追踪臭名昭著的法外狂徒 尼更 \NTracking down the notorious outlaw, Negan,
Dialogue: 0,0:24:37.38,0:24:39.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还取了他的性命\Nand shooting him dead.
Dialogue: 0,0:24:39.17,0:24:41.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我那么说都是为了保护他\NI only said that to protect him.
Dialogue: 0,0:24:41.88,0:24:44.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他在哪 他怎么了\NWhere is he? What happened to him?
Dialogue: 0,0:24:44.13,0:24:46.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,据我所知 他还在岛上\NStill on the island for all I know.
Dialogue: 0,0:24:48.05,0:24:49.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你想要什么\NWhat do you want?
Dialogue: 0,0:24:49.59,0:24:51.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我要引荐你征兵入伍\NI'm gonna recommend your conscription.
Dialogue: 0,0:24:52.21,0:24:54.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我觉得你对这次任务很有价值\NI think you could be an asset to the mission.
Dialogue: 0,0:24:54.31,0:24:55.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你有经验\NYou've been there.
Dialogue: 0,0:24:55.68,0:24:57.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还从克罗地亚人那带回了你儿子\NYou got your son back from the Croat.
Dialogue: 0,0:24:57.27,0:24:59.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你知道他的软肋 他是怎么操作的\NYou know his weaknesses, how he operates.
Dialogue: 0,0:24:59.67,0:25:02.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我猜你全都搞明白了\NYou've got it all figured out, I guess.
Dialogue: 0,0:25:02.15,0:25:04.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我知道你对新巴比伦的感觉\NI know how you feel about New Babylon.
Dialogue: 0,0:25:04.58,0:25:06.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,- 我自己也有一肚子问题 - 为什么是现在\N- I've got my doubts, too. - Why now?
Dialogue: 0,0:25:06.37,0:25:09.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为什么你突然间就想重振曼哈顿\NWhy all of a sudden do you wanna bring back Manhattan?
Dialogue: 0,0:25:12.03,0:25:13.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你想要甲烷\NYou want the methane.
Dialogue: 0,0:25:14.54,0:25:17.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我看到飞蛾了 你快没有乙醇了\NI've seen the moths. You're running out of ethanol.
Dialogue: 0,0:25:18.77,0:25:20.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,它们已经散布在南方各个角落了\NThey've spread all over the south.
Dialogue: 0,0:25:20.73,0:25:23.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在玉米里产卵 让它从里面烂掉\NLaying eggs in the corn, rotting it from the inside.
Dialogue: 0,0:25:23.73,0:25:25.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没甲烷我们也能活\NWe can survive without it.
Dialogue: 0,0:25:25.08,0:25:27.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,新巴比伦不行 但我无所谓\NNew Babylon can't, which is just fine by me.
Dialogue: 0,0:25:27.07,0:25:28.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是真的\NIt's true.
Dialogue: 0,0:25:28.83,0:25:31.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果我们能接管他们的甲烷业务\NIf we can take over their methane operation,
Dialogue: 0,0:25:31.70,0:25:34.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那就能拥有取之不尽的资源了\Nit's ready to go, practically unlimited.
Dialogue: 0,0:25:34.53,0:25:36.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可以给电网供能\NIt'll fuel power grids.
Dialogue: 0,0:25:36.75,0:25:38.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,把技术和药品还给我们\NGive us back technology and medicine.
Dialogue: 0,0:25:38.98,0:25:41.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就不会还有人死于流感感染\NPeople wouldn't have to die of infection or the flu.
Dialogue: 0,0:25:41.24,0:25:43.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且我不仅是在为我的人考虑\NAnd I'm not just talking about my people.
Dialogue: 0,0:25:43.71,0:25:45.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还有你的人\NYour people.
Dialogue: 0,0:25:45.32,0:25:46.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所有人\NEveryone.
Dialogue: 0,0:25:46.97,0:25:48.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是如果我们得不到甲烷\NBut if we don't get that methane,
Dialogue: 0,0:25:48.32,0:25:50.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果新巴比伦陷落\Nif New Babylon falls,
Dialogue: 0,0:25:51.37,0:25:53.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们付出的代价就太大了\Nwe've lost too much.
Dialogue: 0,0:25:54.46,0:25:56.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们为什么要重蹈覆辙呢\NWhy would we put ourselves through that again?
Dialogue: 0,0:25:56.81,0:25:58.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们现在是一根绳上的蚂蚱\NWe're in this together.
Dialogue: 0,0:25:58.20,0:25:59.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是吗\NAre we?
Dialogue: 0,0:26:01.60,0:26:04.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你的妻子在哪 你的女儿又在哪\NWhere's your wife then? Where are your daughters?
Dialogue: 0,0:26:04.68,0:26:06.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她们为什么不来曼哈顿\NWhy aren't they coming to Manhattan?
Dialogue: 0,0:26:06.47,0:26:08.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还探索任务 是吧\NExploratory mission, huh?
Dialogue: 0,0:26:08.69,0:26:11.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为我们只是第一波应征入伍的\N'Cause we're just the first wave, the conscripts,
Dialogue: 0,0:26:11.66,0:26:13.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就他妈是一群小白鼠\Njust a bunch of fucking guinea pigs.
Dialogue: 0,0:26:13.45,0:26:14.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我提醒你 \NI'll remind you that 
Dialogue: 0,0:26:14.49,0:26:16.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,- 你可是联邦的条约成员 - 被你逼的 \Nyou're treaty-bound members of the federation... - Which you forced us into, 
Dialogue: 0,0:26:16.57,0:26:19.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,- 你断绝了我们所有的贸易伙伴... - 即使你看不出 \N- cut off all of our trading partners... - Even if you can't see 
Dialogue: 0,0:26:19.37,0:26:21.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,- 这对你我都是有利的 - 我又没赞成...\N- it's in your interest as much as mine... - Not that I voted for it...
Dialogue: 0,0:26:21.51,0:26:21.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你来了\NYou're coming.
Dialogue: 0,0:26:21.97,0:26:25.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,- 是这样吗 执法官 - 上校 现在是上校了\N- Is that right, Marshal? - Colonel. It's Colonel now.
Dialogue: 0,0:26:27.36,0:26:30.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果我受约束 那么我有责任\NIf I'm treaty bound, then it'd be my duty
Dialogue: 0,0:26:30.67,0:26:34.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,告知你的上级 尼更发生什么事了\Nto inform your superiors what really happened to Negan.
Dialogue: 0,0:26:43.12,0:26:44.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果我去岛上\NIf I come to the island,
Dialogue: 0,0:26:45.36,0:26:48.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你们就不能强行征召其他砖墙区的人 除非他们愿意\Nno one else from the Bricks gets drafted that doesn't want to.
Dialogue: 0,0:26:49.73,0:26:51.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那我只能卖给总督了\NI'd have to sell it to the governor.
Dialogue: 0,0:26:53.63,0:26:54.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,随你便\NGet selling.
Dialogue: 0,0:27:10.16,0:27:12.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原谅我 神父 我有罪...\NForgive me, Father, for I have sinned...
Dialogue: 0,0:27:13.71,0:27:16.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,罪孽深重 罪大恶极 罪不可赦\NAnd sinned, and sinned, and sinned.
Dialogue: 0,0:27:24.02,0:27:28.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,很抱歉你老婆孩子也卷进来了\NI'm sorry your wife and son got dragged into this.
Dialogue: 0,0:27:29.16,0:27:31.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但我觉得与其把这视作一种威胁\NBut think of it as less a threat to your family 
Dialogue: 0,0:27:31.79,0:27:36.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不如当作你的家人加入我们大家庭的欢迎仪式 不好吗\Nand more a chance to welcome them into our larger family, huh?
Dialogue: 0,0:27:37.74,0:27:39.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嘿\NHey...
Dialogue: 0,0:27:40.70,0:27:42.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,给你个惊喜\NI have a surprise for you.
Dialogue: 0,0:27:47.40,0:27:48.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么样\NHuh?
Dialogue: 0,0:27:49.52,0:27:52.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,跟原版露希尔一样\NJust like the original Lucille.
Dialogue: 0,0:27:49.52,0:27:52.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\an8}露希尔是尼更的主要武器 缠着铁丝的棒球棒
Dialogue: 0,0:27:54.51,0:27:59.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过 怎么说呢 我加了点料\NAlthough I have added some, shall we say, improvements.
Dialogue: 0,0:28:04.87,0:28:06.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我懂了\NI understand.
Dialogue: 0,0:28:07.78,0:28:09.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,休息时间长了\NAfter a long break,
Dialogue: 0,0:28:09.22,0:28:11.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,表演者要再次登台的话\Nwhen a performer takes the stage again,
Dialogue: 0,0:28:11.39,0:28:13.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就要尝试新鲜东西\Nhe wants to try out new material.
Dialogue: 0,0:28:13.69,0:28:15.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但到头来\NBut in the end,
Dialogue: 0,0:28:16.04,0:28:20.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,观众真正想要的只是热门歌曲\Nall the audience really wants are the greatest hits.
Dialogue: 0,0:28:23.13,0:28:26.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们得走了 到时间了\NWe have to go. It's time.
Dialogue: 0,0:29:34.18,0:29:35.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,, 拿下他\NGet him!
Dialogue: 0,0:29:43.68,0:29:46.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是个大屁股僵尸\NThat is one big-ass walker.
Dialogue: 0,0:29:46.87,0:29:48.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,该死的 农贸市场\NGoddamn, farmer's market.
Dialogue: 0,0:29:55.54,0:29:56.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不 站起来\NNo! Get up!
Dialogue: 0,0:30:51.60,0:30:53.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,纳尔瓦埃斯少校\NMajor Narvaez,
Dialogue: 0,0:30:53.14,0:30:55.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我读到曼哈顿的电网在1888年暴雪过后\NI read that Manhattan's power grid was run underground
Dialogue: 0,0:30:55.89,0:30:57.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就被埋到地下去了\Nafter the blizzard of 1888.
Dialogue: 0,0:30:57.79,0:31:01.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也就是说它可能在城市毁灭中存留了下来\NWhich means that it's probably survived the destruction of the city.
Dialogue: 0,0:31:01.07,0:31:04.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我想多了 但有没有可能...\NI'm getting ahead of myself, but is it possible...
Dialogue: 0,0:31:04.03,0:31:06.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你不是还要写日记吗\NDon't you have some journaling to do?
Dialogue: 0,0:31:06.83,0:31:08.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她就是嫉妒 皮尔斯先生\NShe's just jealous, Mr. Pierce.
Dialogue: 0,0:31:08.99,0:31:11.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你一路上记录的历史\NThe history you'll be recording along the way,
Dialogue: 0,0:31:11.08,0:31:14.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,发现 还有荣耀的故事\Nthe tales of discovery and glory,
Dialogue: 0,0:31:14.08,0:31:16.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,都将是我们最大的胜利\Nthey'll be our biggest victory of all.
Dialogue: 0,0:31:16.22,0:31:17.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说到这个\NSpeaking of which...
Dialogue: 0,0:31:20.66,0:31:25.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这些只在庆祝我们满载而归的时候才抽\NOnly to be smoked in celebration when we get what we're after.
Dialogue: 0,0:31:33.28,0:31:35.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你有想过我们之前聊的事吗\NHave you given any thought to what we talked about earlier?
Dialogue: 0,0:31:36.80,0:31:38.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个砖墙区的女人吗\NThat Bricks woman?
Dialogue: 0,0:31:39.37,0:31:40.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她有那么重要吗\NIs she really that important?
Dialogue: 0,0:31:40.69,0:31:42.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她就是我在岛上遇到的女人\NShe's the woman I met on the island.
Dialogue: 0,0:31:43.59,0:31:46.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她单枪匹马从克罗地亚人手里救回儿子\NShe single-handedly rescued her son from the Croat.
Dialogue: 0,0:31:46.03,0:31:47.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那就直接征召她\NSo let's just draft her.
Dialogue: 0,0:31:47.47,0:31:48.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可以试试\NWe could try.
Dialogue: 0,0:31:50.13,0:31:52.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可人家放话了 除非踏过她的尸体\NOver her dead body, as she put it.
Dialogue: 0,0:31:52.66,0:31:55.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要么我们带着优厚条件让她自愿加入\NEither we bring her on incentivized alive,
Dialogue: 0,0:31:55.47,0:31:57.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要么就再失良机\Nor we throw away yet another opportunity.
Dialogue: 0,0:31:57.52,0:32:00.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,据我统计 我们这有二十名精壮士兵\NBy my count, we have 20 able-bodied soldiers here.
Dialogue: 0,0:32:01.39,0:32:03.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个女人值二十个士兵吗\NIs this woman worth 20 soldiers?
Dialogue: 0,0:32:03.32,0:32:04.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我觉得值\NI think she is.
Dialogue: 0,0:32:06.70,0:32:08.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那就让她自己证明吧\NSo then let her prove it.
Dialogue: 0,0:32:10.53,0:32:12.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这办法可行\NI think that's smart.
Dialogue: 0,0:32:13.58,0:32:15.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那就对这女人做个战力评估\NWe'll conduct an assessment of the woman.
Dialogue: 0,0:32:19.85,0:32:21.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为什么一定是你去\NWhy does it have to be you?
Dialogue: 0,0:32:21.41,0:32:23.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为这是唯一可行的方法\NBecause that's the only way that this works.
Dialogue: 0,0:32:23.51,0:32:25.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可你连其他办法都没试过\NYeah, but you didn't try to find another way.
Dialogue: 0,0:32:25.25,0:32:26.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,直接就...\NYou just...
Dialogue: 0,0:32:26.81,0:32:28.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,简直像是你自己想去\NIt's almost like you wanna go.
Dialogue: 0,0:32:28.04,0:32:29.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我不想去\NI don't wanna go.
Dialogue: 0,0:32:29.29,0:32:31.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我这么做是为了你 为了砖墙区\NI'm doing it for you, for the Bricks.
Dialogue: 0,0:32:31.29,0:32:33.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,荷歇... 荷歇尔\NHersh... Hershel.
Dialogue: 0,0:33:14.68,0:33:15.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不 不 不\NNo, no, no.
Dialogue: 0,0:33:20.02,0:33:23.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,若你真想代替岛上这二十个应征兵\NIf you plan on taking the place of 20 conscripts on the island,
Dialogue: 0,0:33:24.08,0:33:26.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你要对付的 可就不是士兵了\Nit won't be soldiers you'll be fighting.
Dialogue: 0,0:33:47.55,0:33:49.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我也是刚刚才得知\NI only just found out.
Dialogue: 0,0:33:49.52,0:33:54.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,志愿应征者上前到围场集合\NAnyone intending to enlist, step up to the corral.
Dialogue: 0,0:33:59.19,0:34:01.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,金妮 你不能进去\NGinny, you're not going in there.
Dialogue: 0,0:34:02.50,0:34:04.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等等 我们不能...\NWait, hold on. We can't...
Dialogue: 0,0:34:04.08,0:34:06.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,- 有什么问题 - 她还只是个孩子\N- What's the problem? - She's just a kid.
Dialogue: 0,0:34:06.34,0:34:07.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,孩子就不能战斗了\NAnd kids can't fight?
Dialogue: 0,0:34:07.78,0:34:09.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这和我们当初说好的不一样\NThis isn't what we decided.
Dialogue: 0,0:34:09.37,0:34:11.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没人会被强征入伍\NNo one gets drafted involuntarily.
Dialogue: 0,0:34:11.39,0:34:12.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这才是我们谈好的条件\NThat was the deal.
Dialogue: 0,0:34:18.06,0:34:19.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,别让我说第二遍\NDon't make me say it again.
Dialogue: 0,0:34:21.18,0:34:22.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好吗\NPlease.
Dialogue: 0,0:34:31.54,0:34:32.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不 金妮 我说了...\NNo, Ginny! I said...
Dialogue: 0,0:34:32.94,0:34:34.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,该死的\NGoddammit.
Dialogue: 0,0:35:13.71,0:35:14.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,金妮\NGinny.
Dialogue: 0,0:35:16.67,0:35:17.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,金妮\NGinny!
Dialogue: 0,0:37:13.75,0:37:15.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,磨蹭啥呢 到底开不开始\NWe gonna start this shit or what?
Dialogue: 0,0:38:09.59,0:38:11.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,感谢各位到场\NThank you all for coming.
Dialogue: 0,0:38:13.42,0:38:16.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,据我所知 你们对彼此恨之入骨\NFrom what I gather, y'all hate each other's guts.
Dialogue: 0,0:38:17.07,0:38:18.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说实话 我懂\NI gotta say, I get it.
Dialogue: 0,0:38:18.94,0:38:23.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我才走进门 就已经看你们不顺眼了\NI just walked in the door and I already hate your guts.
Dialogue: 0,0:38:25.73,0:38:27.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但瞧瞧 咱们这群人\NAnd yet, here we are,
Dialogue: 0,0:38:27.73,0:38:30.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,居然能齐聚在上帝的地盘上\Nall together in God's house.
Dialogue: 0,0:38:31.56,0:38:33.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说真的 我挺意外没人被...\NI gotta say, I was a little surprised that nobody got...
Dialogue: 0,0:38:33.96,0:38:35.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,天打雷劈\NI don't know, struck by lightning,
Dialogue: 0,0:38:35.74,0:38:37.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,或者燃成灰烬\Nor burst into flames.
Dialogue: 0,0:38:37.35,0:38:42.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,毕竟 咱们可都是行走的罪孽化身啊\NI mean, after all, we are the walking manifestation of sin.
Dialogue: 0,0:38:43.02,0:38:44.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但重点是\NBut here's the thing.
Dialogue: 0,0:38:44.62,0:38:49.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为啥把这帮杂碎凑在一块\NWhy bring this motley group of shitheads together?
Dialogue: 0,0:38:49.43,0:38:51.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这他妈的意义何在\NI mean, what is the fucking point?
Dialogue: 0,0:38:56.60,0:38:58.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有人认得这玩意儿吗\NAnybody recognize this?
Dialogue: 0,0:39:01.12,0:39:02.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是警徽\NIt's a badge.
Dialogue: 0,0:39:03.51,0:39:05.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,执法者的徽章\NA lawman's badge.
Dialogue: 0,0:39:06.30,0:39:08.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还记得法律是什么吗\NDo you remember the law?
Dialogue: 0,0:39:08.89,0:39:10.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,虽然那都是老黄历了\NI mean, I know it's been a minute.
Dialogue: 0,0:39:11.30,0:39:14.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,来自新巴比伦联邦\NFrom The New Babylon Federation.
Dialogue: 0,0:39:14.13,0:39:16.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,当初有个蠢货追捕我时把它弄丢了\NSee, I got this badge
Dialogue: 0,0:39:17.22,0:39:20.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后被我捡到了\Nwhen the asshat that was chasing me down lost it.
Dialogue: 0,0:39:20.53,0:39:24.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错 我曾经是个通缉犯\NThat is correct. I was once a wanted man.
Dialogue: 0,0:39:26.58,0:39:30.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,被条子追得走投无路 才逃到这破岛来\NLawman chased me down, so I came here.
Dialogue: 0,0:39:30.33,0:39:34.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,选择这个岛是因为我听说 这里无法无天\NI came here because I hear this island's got no laws.
Dialogue: 0,0:39:34.35,0:39:35.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,算你说对了 贱人\NGot that right, bitch.
Dialogue: 0,0:39:38.11,0:39:41.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,问题是 你们打算继续这样下去吗\NThe question is, are you gonna keep it that way?
Dialogue: 0,0:39:42.26,0:39:44.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要知道 这徽章的来处\NYou see, where this badge came from,
Dialogue: 0,0:39:45.03,0:39:46.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是有成百上千个这样的家伙\Nthere's a hell of a lot more of 'em.
Dialogue: 0,0:39:46.90,0:39:51.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而他们 此时此刻 正在杀来的路上\NAnd they are coming here right now as we speak.
Dialogue: 0,0:39:51.92,0:39:55.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,听着 新巴比伦那帮人已经听说\NSee, New Babylon, they found out about your
Dialogue: 0,0:39:55.81,0:39:59.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你们这儿无法无天的好日子了\Nkick-ass, bad-ass way of life.
Dialogue: 0,0:39:59.26,0:40:01.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对他们来说 这 就是个问题\NAnd to them, that's a problem.
Dialogue: 0,0:40:02.09,0:40:06.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,新巴比伦的解决之道 就是他们的法律\NFor New Babylon, the solution to that problem is their laws.
Dialogue: 0,0:40:07.67,0:40:11.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以 加入我们\NSo you join us,
Dialogue: 0,0:40:11.23,0:40:13.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,放下恩怨\Nyou put aside your differences,
Dialogue: 0,0:40:14.59,0:40:16.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一起战斗\Nand we fight.
Dialogue: 0,0:40:16.12,0:40:17.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们才能把新巴比伦…\NWe keep New Babylon...
Dialogue: 0,0:40:17.56,0:40:21.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,♪主啊 求降临♪\NKumbaya, my Lord Kumbaya
Dialogue: 0,0:40:27.18,0:40:28.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你是哪位\NAnd you are?
Dialogue: 0,0:40:30.51,0:40:32.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,赫里斯托斯\NChristos.
Dialogue: 0,0:40:32.60,0:40:36.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,赫里斯托斯 赫里斯托斯 很酷的名字\NChristos? Christos. Very cool name.
Dialogue: 0,0:40:37.22,0:40:39.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这么着吧 赫里斯托斯 能不能把问答环节留到\NHere's the deal, Christos, I'm wondering if we can save
Dialogue: 0,0:40:39.43,0:40:41.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,比如说 结束之后\Nthe Q and A until... I don't know, afterwards.
Dialogue: 0,0:40:41.94,0:40:43.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要是我们不想入伙呢\NWhat if we don't wanna join you?
Dialogue: 0,0:40:43.35,0:40:44.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是\NYeah.
Dialogue: 0,0:40:46.61,0:40:47.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯\NHmm?
Dialogue: 0,0:40:48.53,0:40:52.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要是我们不想放下恩怨呢\NWhat if we don't want to uh, put aside our differences?
Dialogue: 0,0:40:53.05,0:40:55.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是啊\NYeah.
Dialogue: 0,0:40:55.14,0:40:56.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大家都冷静一下行吗\NWhy don't we all just take a breath?
Dialogue: 0,0:40:56.62,0:40:59.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要是我们就喜欢现状呢\NWhat if we like things just the way they are?
Dialogue: 0,0:41:00.92,0:41:03.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且我们压根不想鸟别人的破事\NAnd we don't give a fuck about someone else's problem.
Dialogue: 0,0:41:03.74,0:41:05.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是啊\NYes!
Dialogue: 0,0:41:06.02,0:41:07.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯\NHmm?
Dialogue: 0,0:41:09.59,0:41:13.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不知道这老太婆在指望什么\NNow I don't know what the old lady was hoping for,
Dialogue: 0,0:41:14.12,0:41:18.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但老子绝不会给这个\Nbut there is no way I am bending the knee
Dialogue: 0,0:41:18.00,0:41:21.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,皱皮老杂毛下跪\Nto some skinny fucking bitch-ass old man.
Dialogue: 0,0:41:23.35,0:41:25.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,哪他妈冒出来的家伙\NWho's come here out of fucking nowhere
Dialogue: 0,0:41:25.87,0:41:28.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真以为能忽悠我们\Nthinking he can sell us on some bullshit!
Dialogue: 0,0:41:33.52,0:41:36.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真要打 我们也知道该干爆谁的狗头\N'Cause if we're fighting, I think we know whose ass we're fucking up.
Dialogue: 0,0:41:37.79,0:41:39.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说得好 够种\NDamn right! Damn right!
Dialogue: 0,0:41:47.29,0:41:49.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是我的责任 我认栽\NThis is my fault. It is.
Dialogue: 0,0:41:49.56,0:41:50.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,责任我全扛\NI'm gonna take all the blame for it,
Dialogue: 0,0:41:50.91,0:41:54.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但我们之间是不是 有点小误会\Nbut I think we're having a little bit of a misunderstanding.
Dialogue: 0,0:41:55.12,0:41:59.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我不是来唱团结赞歌的\NI am not asking for any kumbaya.
Dialogue: 0,0:41:55.12,0:41:59.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\an8}团结赞歌 是一首传统民歌歌词 后演变为象征团结 情感共鸣与精神连接的符号
Dialogue: 0,0:41:59.64,0:42:01.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我不是牧师\NYou see, I am not a preacher.
Dialogue: 0,0:42:01.72,0:42:04.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你们也他妈配不上信徒二字\NAnd you sure as shit ain't no congregation.
Dialogue: 0,0:42:06.23,0:42:07.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但你们必须打这一仗\NBut you are gonna fight.
Dialogue: 0,0:42:07.81,0:42:09.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也不是为了什么共同利益\NAnd not for the common good.
Dialogue: 0,0:42:09.49,0:42:12.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我完全不在乎共同利益\NI could give a rat's ass about the common good.
Dialogue: 0,0:42:12.42,0:42:14.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不 你们必须得打\NNo, you are gonna fight...
Dialogue: 0,0:42:17.14,0:42:19.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为这是老子的命令\NYou're gonna fight because I say so.
Dialogue: 0,0:42:26.21,0:42:28.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,把这该死的玩意从我面前拿开\NGet that fucking thing out of my face.
Dialogue: 0,0:42:28.68,0:42:30.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,休想\NNah.
Dialogue: 0,0:42:31.15,0:42:33.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,把这该死的玩意...\NGet that fuckin' thing...
Dialogue: 0,0:42:52.14,0:42:55.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,甲烷 我们有 而你们没有\NMethane... We got it. You don't.
Dialogue: 0,0:42:55.44,0:42:57.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们掌控着霓虹灯 超酷座驾\NWe got the bright lights, the cool cars,
Dialogue: 0,0:42:57.62,0:43:01.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,顶级武器 我们还掌控炸弹\Nthe awesome weapons. We got bombs.
Dialogue: 0,0:43:02.40,0:43:04.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,明白吗 强权\NYou see, power,
Dialogue: 0,0:43:06.56,0:43:08.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是真理\Nequals power.
Dialogue: 0,0:43:08.75,0:43:10.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,道理就这么简单\NIt's as simple as that.
Dialogue: 0,0:43:11.63,0:43:13.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果不加入我们...\NSo if you ain't with us...
Dialogue: 0,0:43:14.53,0:43:17.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,恐怕会有惊喜等着你们\NI guess you're in for a bit of a shock.
Dialogue: 0,0:43:19.49,0:43:22.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以你们不如内部讨论一下\NSo why don't y'all talk amongst yourselves.
Dialogue: 0,0:43:22.42,0:43:23.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,想一想\NThink about it.
Dialogue: 0,0:43:23.90,0:43:25.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过帮我个小忙 行吗\NBut do me a favor, yeah?
Dialogue: 0,0:43:26.90,0:43:28.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,别苦思冥想\NDon't think too hard.
Dialogue: 0,0:43:58.00,0:44:01.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\an8} 无线电城
Dialogue: 0,0:44:19.17,0:44:20.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我的罗盘 得拿回来\NI need my compass.
Dialogue: 0,0:44:20.39,0:44:21.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为什么 出什么事了\NWhy? What's going on?
Dialogue: 0,0:44:21.83,0:44:24.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她以为自己能去曼哈顿 痴心妄想\NShe thinks she's coming to Manhattan and she's not.
Dialogue: 0,0:44:29.27,0:44:30.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们仨\NThe three of us,
Dialogue: 0,0:44:32.01,0:44:34.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,都知道回那里意味着什么\Nwe know what it means to go back there.
Dialogue: 0,0:44:35.19,0:44:36.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我担心你\NI'm worried about you.
Dialogue: 0,0:44:37.28,0:44:38.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好吗\NOkay?
Dialogue: 0,0:44:40.08,0:44:41.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我向他保证过\NI made him a promise.
Dialogue: 0,0:44:41.93,0:44:44.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,发誓会护你周全\NI swore that I would look out for you.
Dialogue: 0,0:44:47.37,0:44:49.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是为了尼更吗 所以你才要去\NIs this about Negan? Is that why you wanna go?
Dialogue: 0,0:44:51.32,0:44:54.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,- 我不会放你走 - 你不是我亲妈\N- I can't let you. - You're not my mother.
Dialogue: 0,0:44:56.48,0:44:58.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你对我来说什么都不是\NYou're not anything to me.
Dialogue: 0,0:45:09.73,0:45:11.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,- 我也要去 - 你胡说什么呢\N- I'm going, too. - What are you talking about?
Dialogue: 0,0:45:11.60,0:45:13.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我和你一起\NI'm coming with you.
Dialogue: 0,0:45:13.31,0:45:15.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,- 不行 - 金妮可以走 我就不能\N- No. - Ginny can go, but I can't?
Dialogue: 0,0:45:15.21,0:45:17.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对 因为你是我儿子\NYeah, because you're my son.
Dialogue: 0,0:45:17.23,0:45:19.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而我之所以去 纯粹是不得已\NAnd, I'm only going because I have to.
Dialogue: 0,0:45:19.29,0:45:21.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,或许你也是为他才去的\NOr maybe you're going for him, too.
Dialogue: 0,0:45:21.35,0:45:22.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是因为良心过不去吗\NWhat is it 'cause you feel bad?
Dialogue: 0,0:45:22.67,0:45:24.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为扔下他而感到自责吗\NYou feel guilty 'cause you left him there?
Dialogue: 0,0:45:24.38,0:45:25.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你在说什么啊\NWhat are you talking about?
Dialogue: 0,0:45:25.54,0:45:27.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,或许还是因为以前那些事\NOr is it still about everything from before?
Dialogue: 0,0:45:27.45,0:45:28.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我还以为这事早翻篇了\NI mean, I thought we were past that.
Dialogue: 0,0:45:28.80,0:45:29.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我以为都结束了\NI thought we finished it.
Dialogue: 0,0:45:29.81,0:45:31.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这可是你说的啊 结束了\NThat's what you said, it was finished!
Dialogue: 0,0:45:31.98,0:45:33.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我以为我们在变好\NI thought we were getting better,
Dialogue: 0,0:45:33.49,0:45:35.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但你死活不肯放下\Nbut you just keep holding on.
Dialogue: 0,0:45:35.41,0:45:37.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这和尼更没关系\NThis has nothing to do with Negan.
Dialogue: 0,0:45:40.08,0:45:42.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为什么要这样\NWhy are you doing this?
Dialogue: 0,0:45:42.09,0:45:44.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为什么要回去\NWhy do you wanna go back?
Dialogue: 0,0:45:44.82,0:45:46.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在经历那么多之后\NAfter everything that happened?
Dialogue: 0,0:45:49.39,0:45:50.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为什么\NWhy?
Dialogue: 0,0:45:58.04,0:45:59.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你翻了我的东西\NYou went through my things?
Dialogue: 0,0:46:01.06,0:46:02.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你这些画是什么意思\NWhat do these mean to you?
Dialogue: 0,0:46:03.88,0:46:04.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没什么\NNothing.
Dialogue: 0,0:46:04.89,0:46:06.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你在那里遭遇了什么吗\NDid something happen to you there?
Dialogue: 0,0:46:06.73,0:46:08.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,除了被绑架之外\NOther than being kidnapped?
Dialogue: 0,0:46:09.28,0:46:11.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这座城市勾了你的魂\NDoes the city have some kind of pull on you?
Dialogue: 0,0:46:12.42,0:46:13.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没啊\NNo.
Dialogue: 0,0:46:16.79,0:46:18.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这女人是谁\NWho is this woman?
Dialogue: 0,0:46:19.73,0:46:20.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我不认识\NI don't know.
Dialogue: 0,0:46:20.78,0:46:22.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在哪块广告牌上瞥见过\NI saw her face on some billboard or something.
Dialogue: 0,0:46:24.33,0:46:26.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我没骗你 妈 只是随手画的\NI'm not lying, Mom. They're just drawings.
Dialogue: 0,0:46:30.22,0:46:32.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我不是想分开\NI don't wanna be apart.
Dialogue: 0,0:46:32.44,0:46:33.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我只是...\NI just...
Dialogue: 0,0:46:34.71,0:46:36.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我不想让你离开\NI don't want you to go.
Dialogue: 0,0:46:50.59,0:46:51.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你知道 其实我...\NYou know, I...
Dialogue: 0,0:46:53.24,0:46:55.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我基本不了解我妈妈\NI didn't... I didn't know my mom.
Dialogue: 0,0:46:58.55,0:47:02.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在一起时间不长 也不算亲近\NI mean, not for very long and not very well. 
Dialogue: 0,0:47:05.36,0:47:07.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等我把和爸爸的关系处理好后\NBy the time I got things right with my dad,
Dialogue: 0,0:47:07.71,0:47:09.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我已经是大人了\NI was all grown up.
Dialogue: 0,0:47:09.95,0:47:11.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且有了自己的生活\NAnd I had my own life.
Dialogue: 0,0:47:21.05,0:47:23.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我想说的就是\NAll I'm trying to say
Dialogue: 0,0:47:23.14,0:47:27.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,过去几个月陪伴你的时光\Nis that these last few months with you
Dialogue: 0,0:47:28.16,0:47:30.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对我来说意味着一切	\Nhave meant the world to me.
Dialogue: 0,0:47:31.19,0:47:32.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就像你说的\NAnd it's like you said,
Dialogue: 0,0:47:33.80,0:47:35.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们终于变好了\Nwe're finally getting better.
Dialogue: 0,0:47:36.72,0:47:38.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们终于能够放下过去\NWe're finally moving past...
Dialogue: 0,0:47:40.08,0:47:41.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,放下一切\Nall of it.
Dialogue: 0,0:47:41.94,0:47:45.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以我必须去 这样你才能在这里\NThat's why I have to go,so that you don't have to.
Dialogue: 0,0:47:46.47,0:47:48.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,保护我们在这里拥有的一切\NSo I can protect what we have here.
Dialogue: 0,0:47:49.56,0:47:52.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我会快去快回\NI'm gonna go. I'm gonna come right back.
Dialogue: 0,0:47:53.04,0:47:55.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,继续我们未完成的事\NAnd we are gonna pick up right where we left off.
Dialogue: 0,0:47:55.95,0:47:57.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好吗\NOkay?
Dialogue: 0,0:47:58.13,0:47:59.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好的\NOkay.
Dialogue: 0,0:49:40.10,0:49:42.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今天没有东西给你吃\NGuess you won't be eating today.
Dialogue: 0,0:49:53.90,0:49:55.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是别担心\NBut don't worry...
Dialogue: 0,0:49:57.47,0:49:59.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不会太久的\NIt won't be long.
Dialogue: 0,0:50:03.27,0:50:04.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你很快就会适应\NYou'll get there.
Dialogue: 0,0:50:57.43,0:50:59.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你最近很受关注\NYou've been getting a lot of attention.
Dialogue: 0,0:51:00.23,0:51:01.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有些事情我必须完成\NThere's something I gotta do.
Dialogue: 0,0:51:02.05,0:51:04.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你知道他能做出来什么\NYou know what he's capable of.
Dialogue: 0,0:51:06.58,0:51:08.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们收到了信号\NWe received the signal.
Dialogue: 0,0:51:08.33,0:51:11.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,新巴比伦人攻破了岛屿\NThe new Babylonians breached the island.
Dialogue: 0,0:51:11.11,0:51:12.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果士兵们死了 我会找到他们\NIf the soldiers are dead,I'll find them.
Dialogue: 0,0:51:13.75,0:51:15.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果他们没死 那我就了结了他们\NIf they're not, I'll finish them off.
Dialogue: 0,0:51:15.48,0:51:16.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,狩猎愉快\NHappy hunting!
Dialogue: 0,0:51:20.89,0:51:22.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们只赢了一场战役\NWe've only won a battle,
Dialogue: 0,0:51:22.29,0:51:23.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不是整个战争\Nnot the war.
Dialogue: 0,0:51:23.42,0:51:25.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们需要强大的军队\NWe need our army.
Dialogue: 0,0:51:26.08,0:51:28.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,权力真是有趣\NPower is a funny thing.
Dialogue: 0,0:51:28.39,0:51:30.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,能使你充满能量\NIt fuels you.
Dialogue: 0,0:51:30.25,0:51:32.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们得亲自去取甲烷\NWe have to get the methane ourselves.
Dialogue: 0,0:51:33.52,0:51:36.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我要你把尼更带过来\NI want you to bring Negan here.
Dialogue: 0,0:51:38.68,0:51:41.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我要把他们排成排 然后都杀了\NI'm gonna line them all up and kill them all.
Dialogue: 0,0:51:41.23,0:51:42.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嘣\NBoom!
Dialogue: 0,0:51:45.66,0:51:48.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这对你来说是场游戏吗\NWas this a game to you?!
Dialogue: 0,0:51:58.75,0:52:00.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我之所以去 纯粹是不得已\NI'm only going because I have to.
Dialogue: 0,0:52:00.57,0:52:02.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,或者说你也是为了才他去的\NOr maybe you're going for him, too.
Dialogue: 0,0:52:02.78,0:52:04.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是因为良心过不去吗\NWas it because you feel bad,
Dialogue: 0,0:52:04.09,0:52:05.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为当初把他抛在那里愧疚吗\Nyou feel guilty, 'cause you left him there?
Dialogue: 0,0:52:05.65,0:52:08.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这和尼更没关系\NThis has nothing to do with Negan.
Dialogue: 0,0:52:09.95,0:52:11.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,第一季结尾时\NWhen we came to the end of season one,
Dialogue: 0,0:52:11.53,0:52:13.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,玛纪对荷歇尔保证\NMaggie had made a promise to Hershel
Dialogue: 0,0:52:13.36,0:52:15.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们会放下过去\Nthat we were going to put the past behind us
Dialogue: 0,0:52:15.53,0:52:16.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,努力向前看 \Nand find a way to move on 
Dialogue: 0,0:52:16.86,0:52:19.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,治愈以前留下的伤痛\Nand heal all these things that had come before.
Dialogue: 0,0:52:19.08,0:52:21.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,当我们看到角色们再次登场时\NAnd pretty early on, when we see the characters again,
Dialogue: 0,0:52:21.54,0:52:25.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这份保证已经面临了巨大的挑战\Nwe're going to see this promise already challenged in a big way.
Dialogue: 0,0:52:25.02,0:52:28.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,荷歇尔和他母亲的关系非常复杂\NHershel's relationship with his mother is a very complicated one.
Dialogue: 0,0:52:28.86,0:52:32.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,母亲一直放不下\NThe fact that his mother is always obsessed
Dialogue: 0,0:52:32.12,0:52:33.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他的杀父仇人\Nwith his father's murderer
Dialogue: 0,0:52:33.85,0:52:36.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,却也不愿杀掉他的杀父仇人\Nand also not willing to kill his father's murderer.
Dialogue: 0,0:52:36.61,0:52:38.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我认为这是他很大的心结\NI think that is a huge issue for him.
Dialogue: 0,0:52:38.12,0:52:41.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我会快去快回\NI'm gonna go. I'm gonna come right back,
Dialogue: 0,0:52:41.36,0:52:43.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,继续未完成的事\Nand we are gonna pick up right where we left off.
Dialogue: 0,0:52:43.73,0:52:45.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好的\NOkay.
Dialogue: 0,0:52:45.08,0:52:49.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我觉得她只是太急切于抹平所有的创伤\NI think she's just sort of desperately trying to erase all the trauma,
Dialogue: 0,0:52:49.87,0:52:51.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所有阻碍她的伤痛\Neverything that's kind of gotten in the way
Dialogue: 0,0:52:51.33,0:52:52.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,并试图说服自己\Nand trying to tell herself,
Dialogue: 0,0:52:52.72,0:52:55.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这里是家 一切都会好起来的\N"This is home, and we're okay, and everything's gonna be okay".
Dialogue: 0,0:52:55.15,0:52:58.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她在努力创造家的感觉\NShe's trying to create a kind of sense of family and home,
Dialogue: 0,0:52:58.97,0:53:00.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,尽对金妮的责任\Nand being there for Ginny too.
Dialogue: 0,0:53:00.76,0:53:03.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今年玛纪的主要动力 \NWhat's primarily motivating Maggie this year 
Dialogue: 0,0:53:03.19,0:53:06.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是努力坚守 她对儿子的承诺\Nis to try to hold on to something that she owes her son and promised her son
Dialogue: 0,0:53:06.61,0:53:10.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,并且应对剧中出现的挑战\Nwhile navigating the kind of challenges that we know come up in this show.
Dialogue: 0,0:53:11.11,0:53:12.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,啊\NAah!
Dialogue: 0,0:53:18.90,0:53:21.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一开始 尼更在牢房里\NInitially, when we meet Negan, he's in the cell.
Dialogue: 0,0:53:21.74,0:53:23.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,某种程度上 他看上去就像在说\NI think on some level, he's like,
Dialogue: 0,0:53:23.24,0:53:25.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这就是我应该呆的地方\N"This is where I want to be. This is where I should be".
Dialogue: 0,0:53:25.25,0:53:27.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他有屎尿桶 有床\NYou know, he's got his pot, he's got his bed,
Dialogue: 0,0:53:27.63,0:53:29.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还有他的蟑螂饭\Nhe's got his cockroaches.
Dialogue: 0,0:53:29.08,0:53:30.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还有剩下的吗\NGot any leftovers?
Dialogue: 0,0:53:34.43,0:53:36.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,啊 又是蟑螂饭\NUh, yeah, I got the cockroaches again.
Dialogue: 0,0:53:36.20,0:53:37.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就这么说吧\NHere's the deal.
Dialogue: 0,0:53:37.20,0:53:39.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,吃一盘子蟑螂\NUh, eating a plate of cockroaches
Dialogue: 0,0:53:39.64,0:53:41.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对于一个高度近视来说\Nwhen you're blind and your character
Dialogue: 0,0:53:41.66,0:53:45.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,尤其是你的角色还不戴眼镜 确实不太容易\Ndoesn't get to wear glasses is a problem.
Dialogue: 0,0:53:46.63,0:53:48.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他们说 哦杰夫 这个是...\NAnd they were like, "Oh, Jeff, this one's, like, filled...
Dialogue: 0,0:53:48.97,0:53:50.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是巧克力馅的\NThis is like a chocolate thing, and this one's filled
Dialogue: 0,0:53:50.96,0:53:53.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个是蛋奶酱馅的之类的\Nwith, like, uh, custard or something".
Dialogue: 0,0:53:53.43,0:53:55.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,麦基说 詹姆斯我需要你\NMikey said, "James, I really need you
Dialogue: 0,0:53:55.63,0:53:57.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,做一个超级多汁的蟑螂\Nto make a very overloaded,
Dialogue: 0,0:53:57.95,0:54:01.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,给杰夫瑞  一个就行\Njuicy roach for Jeffrey. Just one".
Dialogue: 0,0:54:01.59,0:54:05.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,哦确实是我让詹姆斯·罗森塔尔\NWell, y-y... yes, I did tell James Rosenthal
Dialogue: 0,0:54:05.61,0:54:07.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,制作一个超级多汁的蟑螂\Nto make an extra juicy cockroach
Dialogue: 0,0:54:07.62,0:54:09.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为我想看蟑螂爆浆的样子\N'cause I wanted to see it shoot out of his mouth.
Dialogue: 0,0:54:09.83,0:54:11.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我一边吃一边就想\NAnd I kept eating these things and going,
Dialogue: 0,0:54:11.96,0:54:13.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这根本不是巧克力\N"That's not chocolate".
Dialogue: 0,0:54:13.17,0:54:14.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他是我的好朋友\NAnd, you know, he's a good friend of mine,
Dialogue: 0,0:54:14.87,0:54:16.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以会配合的对吧\Nso you got to around a little bit, right?
Dialogue: 0,0:54:16.74,0:54:20.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可没人告诉我盘子里一半是真的蟑螂\NUm, no one told me that half the plate was real cockroaches.
Dialogue: 0,0:54:23.18,0:54:26.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,哦 口味正合我意\NOh. Just how I like it.
Dialogue: 0,0:54:26.64,0:54:29.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我大概已经吃了十到二十个蟑螂\NAnd so I probably ate 10 to 20 real cockroaches before
Dialogue: 0,0:54:29.74,0:54:32.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,直到发现盘里有真蟑螂\NI even found out there was real cockroaches on the plate.
Dialogue: 0,0:54:32.28,0:54:34.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对 我也尝了 非常恶心\NYeah. So I put one in my mouth, too, and it was disgusting,
Dialogue: 0,0:54:34.91,0:54:36.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是 好歹烤过了\Nbut, you know - but they are baked
Dialogue: 0,0:54:36.79,0:54:38.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,加工了 至少能吃\Nand cooked, and they are edible.
Dialogue: 0,0:54:38.77,0:54:41.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在世界上别的地方 确实有人吃蟑螂\NAnd in other places of the world, they eat cockroaches.
Dialogue: 0,0:54:41.55,0:54:43.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我说 我不能  你们\NI'm like, I can't... You guys, it's just
Dialogue: 0,0:54:43.69,0:54:45.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,吃这玩意我真不在行\Nlike a brown thumb to me.
Dialogue: 0,0:54:45.71,0:54:47.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我要吃了\N"I'm gonna eat it".
Dialogue: 0,0:54:47.55,0:54:49.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真混蛋啊\NJust  ass 
Dialogue: 0,0:54:49.29,0:54:51.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们剧组就这样 混蛋\NThat's what my crew is. Just ass 
Dialogue: 0,0:54:53.69,0:54:56.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们的人在找你时\NWhen our people were out searching for you,
Dialogue: 0,0:54:56.59,0:54:59.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,听说田纳西有个安置点\Nthey heard whispers of a settlement in Tennessee
Dialogue: 0,0:54:59.60,0:55:02.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,住着一个带着孩子的女人\Nthat was home to a woman and child.
Dialogue: 0,0:55:02.12,0:55:06.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没记错的话 叫安妮和乔舒亚\NAnnie and Joshua, if I'm not mistaken.
Dialogue: 0,0:55:07.39,0:55:09.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你知道吗 尼更这个角色做了一件事\NYou know, the one thing that Negan has done,
Dialogue: 0,0:55:09.44,0:55:12.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而这也是让我一直穿着皮衣的唯一原因\Nand the only reason that I'm still wearing the leather jacket
Dialogue: 0,0:55:12.24,0:55:15.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那就是他一直在进化\Nis because that he has continued to evolve.
Dialogue: 0,0:55:15.05,0:55:16.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在这一季里\NAnd I think that this season,
Dialogue: 0,0:55:16.76,0:55:19.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,尼更会陷入\NNegan finds himself in a bit of a predicament
Dialogue: 0,0:55:19.21,0:55:21.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,前所未有的困局中\Nthat he's certainly never been in.
Dialogue: 0,0:55:23.84,0:55:27.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他在被人利用 他也深知这一点\NI think he's being used, and he knows he's being used.
Dialogue: 0,0:55:27.07,0:55:29.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但尼更总能抢先一步\NBut Negan is always kind of a step ahead.
Dialogue: 0,0:55:29.47,0:55:31.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,了解全部的局势\NHe knows what's going on.
Dialogue: 0,0:55:31.01,0:55:34.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以 他要策划人生中最大的骗局\NSo, for him, it's about pulling off the biggest scam of his life
Dialogue: 0,0:55:34.64,0:55:36.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,来让他的家人活下来\Nto keep his family alive.
Dialogue: 0,0:55:36.18,0:55:40.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看他如何在这场游戏中如何试图领先\NSo watching him figure out how to get ahead in the game
Dialogue: 0,0:55:40.74,0:55:43.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是这季的一个有意思的看点\Nhas been an interesting story this year.
Dialogue: 0,0:55:48.74,0:55:51.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我知道这一季将会是\NI knew that this season was going to be a season
Dialogue: 0,0:55:51.06,0:55:53.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,熟悉的尼更在各种意义上回归的一季\Nwhere the old Negan comes back, in all ways,
Dialogue: 0,0:55:53.92,0:55:56.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,回归怎么能少得了露希尔\Nso he couldn't have come back without Lucille.
Dialogue: 0,0:56:00.73,0:56:03.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们想给它带来些新意\NWe wanted to give it something new, a new layer there,
Dialogue: 0,0:56:03.59,0:56:06.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,比如是缠着铁丝\Nand if it was a bat that could be electrified
Dialogue: 0,0:56:06.24,0:56:08.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还带电的球棒 我们的道具组\Nwith the barbed wire,and our props department,
Dialogue: 0,0:56:08.63,0:56:10.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,做得非常逼真可信\Nthey made it believable and real,
Dialogue: 0,0:56:10.51,0:56:13.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他们研究了一些背后的科学原理\Nand they figured out the sort of technology and science behind it.
Dialogue: 0,0:56:13.36,0:56:15.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是露希尔2.0版本\NThis is Lucille 2.0.
Dialogue: 0,0:56:15.04,0:56:17.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,做一个大概要四小时\NTakes me about four hours to build one of these.
Dialogue: 0,0:56:17.26,0:56:18.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,很高兴杰夫瑞喜欢\NI'm happy if Jeffrey loves it.
Dialogue: 0,0:56:18.77,0:56:20.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他都不想和这球棒分开 真的\NHe doesn't like to be separated from it, seriously.
Dialogue: 0,0:56:20.93,0:56:22.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在拍戏间隔时候我都不撒手\NI don't let go of it between takes.
Dialogue: 0,0:56:22.52,0:56:23.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,总有人跑过来问\NSo there are people who always rush up,
Dialogue: 0,0:56:24.00,0:56:25.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,-杰夫用我们帮你拿露希尔吗  - 不用 我来吧\N-"Jeff, can we take Lucille?" - "No, I got it".
Dialogue: 0,0:56:25.85,0:56:28.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我当演员这么多年从没遇到过\NI've never had a prop in my life as an actor
Dialogue: 0,0:56:28.78,0:56:31.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,让我感觉天生属于我的道具\Nthat felt so innately mine
Dialogue: 0,0:56:31.21,0:56:33.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,仿佛是角色的一部分\Nand feels like an extension of the character.
Dialogue: 0,0:56:33.87,0:56:35.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,长时间以来\NAnd I think, for so long,
Dialogue: 0,0:56:35.90,0:56:38.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们都在推开过去那个尼更\Nwe have kind of pushed away that Negan.
Dialogue: 0,0:56:38.42,0:56:42.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,现在回到那个角色 既亲切自如\NSo to come back to that,one, it felt like I was home,
Dialogue: 0,0:56:42.93,0:56:46.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也有充足的理由\Nbut it felt like a very goodvreason to be at home
Dialogue: 0,0:56:46.46,0:56:47.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,让她回归\Nand to have her back.
Dialogue: 0,0:56:47.89,0:56:50.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我个人 超级喜欢她\NAnd me personally, I adore her.
Dialogue: 0,0:56:50.48,0:56:53.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我今年纹了一个露希尔的纹身\NI mean, I got a tattoo this year, and it says "Lucille".
Dialogue: 0,0:56:53.67,0:56:57.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我老婆演过露希尔\NUm, and it helps that my wife played Lucille,
Dialogue: 0,0:56:57.64,0:56:59.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过纹这个 主要是为了球棒哈哈\Nbut really, it's the bat.
Dialogue: 0,0:57:05.83,0:57:09.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,第二季会有更多的纽约场景\NSeason two, fans can look forward to a lot more New York.
Dialogue: 0,0:57:09.53,0:57:12.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们会转移到中城区\NWe're gonna be moving north, into Midtown.
Dialogue: 0,0:57:12.15,0:57:15.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我对继续这两个我们认识已久的角色的故事\NI am excited always to continue this story
Dialogue: 0,0:57:15.52,0:57:17.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而感到非常激动\Nof the two characters that we've known for so long
Dialogue: 0,0:57:17.91,0:57:21.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,并且用独特的方式\Nand finding a way to continue the story in an original manner
Dialogue: 0,0:57:21.26,0:57:27.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,深度挖掘他们之间的关系\Nand dig deeper into the issues that they have with each other
Dialogue: 0,0:57:27.07,0:57:29.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和在末世中求生的主题\Nand survival and all of it.
Dialogue: 0,0:57:30.72,0:57:33.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,本季最让我期待的\NThe thing I'm most excited about for this season
Dialogue: 0,0:57:33.61,0:57:35.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是观众们能看到我们做的一切\Nis for everyone to see what we've done.
Dialogue: 0,0:57:35.97,0:57:39.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,, 非常非常感谢大家的支持\NI'm just, like, really humbled and grateful.
