(COWS LOWING)
(SIGHS WITH RELIEF)
(ZIPPING FLY)
(MAN SNORING)
Good morning,
Mr. Basset.
This is your
wake-up call.
Please move your ass.
(SNORING CONTINUES)
Stampede!
Stampede, Earl!
Get out of the way!
(PANTING)
You dumb shit.
(LAUGHING)
I was in
a stampede once.
Three hundred head going
hell-bent for the horizon.
Now, exactly
how many cows
are required for
a stampede, Earl?
I mean, is it like
three or more?
Is there
a minimum speed?
I wish a stampede
up your ass.
No breakfast?
I did it yesterday.
It was bologna and beans.
No. it was eggs.
I did eggs, over easy.
The hell you did.
Bologna and beans.
It's your turn.
Well, I guess
when I'm your age,
I'll forget
what I eat, too.
Oh, God damn it!
I ask you, is this a job
for intelligent men?
Show me one.
I'll ask him.
I mean, if we were
real serious about money,
we'd quit being
hired hands...
Handymen, Earl.
We are handymen.
Yeah, yeah. We
should quit this job and
find ourselves
some real employment.
Are you gonna give up
all this personal freedom?
I don't know.
(VALENTINE LAUGHING)
VALENTINE: Freeway!
So, what's on
the agenda for today?
It's garbage day.
Oh, man! Already?
Hey, what's Nestor
paying us?
50 bucks. And that's 47
bucks more than we got.
Burt and Heather's place
is closer.
Let's do their linoleum today
and do the garbage tomorrow.
Nestor's not home tomorrow.
Now, look, we don't dig
today, we don't get paid today.
Now, damn it, Valentine,
you never plan ahead.
You never take
the long view.
I mean, here it is Monday, and
I'm already thinking of Wednesday.
It is Monday, right?
VALENTINE: Hey,
who the hell's that?
That's not what's-his-name,
the grad student?
No. He graduated.
Must be the new one.
The new one?
That's supposed
to be a girl.
(VALENTINE WHOOPING)
You will have long,
blonde hair,
big, green eyes,
world-class breasts,
ass that won't quit and
legs that go all the way up!
Hi! I'm Rhonda.
Rhonda LeBeck.
I'm up here
for the semester.
Yeah, geography.
Geology.
Yeah, well,
actually seismology.
Earthquakes.
And you two must
be Val and Earl.
I've heard all about you.
We deny everything.
(RHONDA GIGGLING)
Hey, listen,
I've got a question for you.
Do you know if anybody's
doing any drilling or blasting
or anything like that?
(LAUGHS)
Around here?
No, ma'am.
Well, I'm supposed to monitor
the seismographs.
You know,
they measure vibrations.
Vibrations
in the ground.
Yeah.
Well, I've been getting
some really strange readings.
I mean, the school's had these
machines up here for three years,
and we've never recorded
anything like this.
Well, we'll ask around. You know,
see if anyone's heard anything.
Thanks.
God, I hope
they're not broken.
I might have to bag
the whole semester.
Anyway, sorry to bother you.
No problem.
Nice meeting you. Hope
you get it all sorted out.
You know, if you wanted,
we could take a look at those
seismographs for her
if you want.
What the hell do we know
about seismographs?
Nothing.
It sure might be a slick
way to get to know her.
Why?
Damn it, Valentine.
You don't go for any gal
unless she fits
that stupid list of yours
from top to bottom.
Well, sure!
- Yeah, and it's dumber than my hind end.
I mean, like that
Bobby Lynn Dexter.
Tammy Lynn Baxter.
It don't matter. They're
all the same, dead weight.
"Ooh! I broke a nail!"
Makes my skin crawl.
Well, I'm a victim
of circumstance.
I thought you call it
your pecker.
Hey, pizza face!
Melvin?
Melvin! You touch
that truck and die.
Oh, man,
I'm really shaking.
Thanks, Walter.
Look, these are
hollow points,
but they're not
Hydrashok hollow points.
Excuse me, I thought
bullets were bullets.
Hi, guys.
What you been doing?
We ran into that new college
student, that Rona.
Rhonda. Yeah, she's
having trouble with her, uh,
uh, things.
You know,
those college kids
turn up oil or uranium
or something out there.
Next thing the feds
will be at our door.
"Sorry. Time to move.
Eminent domain."
Down, honey. Down.
Yeah, Burt.
The way you worry,
you'll have a heart attack before you
get a chance to survive World War Ill.
We'll see.
(WHIRRING)
Hey, guys, listen.
Bearing going out.
What do you think?
- Could be.
Catch you later, Chang.
We got a schedule to keep.
Oh, yeah.
See, we plan ahead.
That way we don't do anything
right now. Earl explained it to me.
(RUMBLING)
(FLIES BUZZING)
Cocktail?
You bet.
(EXHALES)
Well, I'll tell you.
Nobody handles garbage
better than we do.
Yep.
Oh, come on, Earl.
Now this is low.
We have got to set our sights
a little bit higher.
Hey, Melvin, why don't
you give us a hand?
Most of this shit
is yours anyway.
Listen, run down to the store and
pick me up a six-pack. I'll pay for it.
Son, beer is for adults.
You know, not having a plan is
what keeps us doing jobs like this.
Just doing jobs like this
is you dragging your feet.
Are you gonna stand there
and tell me, in broad daylight,
that I'm the reason
we're still in Perfection?
You know how close I am to
leaving this place right now?
I'll call that little bluff.
- How close?
(TANK RUMBLING)
Shit!
- God damn!
(BOTH SHOUTING)
Jesus Christ!
God damn!
Don't forget the TV.
EARL: Hey, what's that
vacuum cleaner for, man?
I like this
vacuum cleaner.
Hell, you never use it.
Well, it's good
for parts.
And, besides, maybe
we'll hire a maid.
Now had you thought
about that, Earl?
Get in the truck.
Guys!
Hey, guys, wait!
Hi.
Sorry, Nancy.
We're not delivering
firewood anymore.
We're heading for
Bixby permanent.
Oh, sure.
Oh, my God.
You really are!
Hey, Mindy,
what's the count?
Six hundred and forty.
Guys, look,
I don't need firewood.
I have this big
order to fill,
and I have to build
my new pottery kiln.
Come on, it'll be at
least a month's work.
I'll throw in lunches.
And beer.
(VALENTINE WHOOPING)
VALENTINE: I can't believe
we said no to free beer.
We did it! We did it! We faced
temptation and did not bend!
God damn!
Praise the Lord!
Now there's nothing,
and I mean nothing,
between us and
Bixby but nothing!
Yeah!
- Yeah!
(EARL WHOOPING)
Hey, look at that guy!
Oh, that's one job
I'd never do.
Working around
electricity.
Hey, hold up.
That's Edgar Deems.
Come on.
No. He only wears
that one damn jacket.
That's him,
I'm telling you.
Man, oh, man, he sure
must've been drunk this time.
Edgar, get your
butt down from there!
(SIGHS)
Well, shit.
We can't leave him
up there.
(CHUCKLES)
Thank you, Edgar.
You owe me on this one,
you damned old boozehound.
One of these days, you're
gonna have to get your ass
on a wagon
and stay there.
Jesus! It's not like I don't
have better things to do
than to climb towers and
drag your hairy ass down.
Jesus Christ!
VALENTINE: Was it
a heart attack, Doctor?
No.
He died of dehydration.
Thirst.
Well, that doesn't
make any sense.
That takes a couple
of days, doesn't it?
Maybe even three or four.
You mean he sat up there
three or four days?
He sat up there and
just died of thirst?
(SHEEP BLEATING)
(BLEATING EXCITEDLY)
Hmm.
(SCREAMING)
You reckon he hated
Perfection more than us?
Do you suppose he
wanted to kill himself?
Come on. Somebody
must've chased him up there.
What, you mean someone who
ain't scared of a Winchester rifle?
Then what'd they do?
Camp out down below
and just wait for him to die?
What the hell?
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(EXHALES)
What the shit?
Hey, Fred!
Hey, there, old Fred!
Fred!
EARL: This is weird.
VALENTINE:
This is real weird.
(SHOUTS)
Jesus!
What the hell's
going on?
I mean, what the
hell is going on?
(VALENTINE BREATHING HEAVILY)
Everybody get the hell
out of here!
There's a killer
on the loose!
What?
- A murderer, man! A real psycho!
(STAMMERING)
He's cutting people's heads off.
I'm not kidding!
They're pulling
our chain.
Yeah.
(SCREECHING)
What?
Shit.
(SCREAMS)
Howard! Howard!
Carmine?
(CARMINE SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
Who could be doing it?
I'm not accusing anybody.
I'm just saying, some
of my cattle are missing.
Are you serious?
Old Fred's dead?
Dude, something
like that.
Come on, you're
bullshitting me, right, pal?
What happened to Fred?
No worse than Edgar.
What happened to Edgar?
- You won't believe it.
Here, I need one
of those candy bars.
I don't believe this.
The phone is dead.
Walter, your phone
is dead!
I didn't do it.
Nestor,
what's happening?
NESTOR: Somebody
killed old Fred.
MIGUEL: What should we do?
- What's going on?
Now, look, Val,
you gotta get to Bixby,
and you gotta get
the police up here.
And you gotta step on it.
Consider it stepped on.
Man, we decided
to leave this place
just one damn day
too late, you know?
Well, there's sure as hell
nothing to stop us now.
Everybody we know between
here and Bixby is already dead.
Look out!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
ls there some higher
force at work here?
I mean, are we asking
too much of life?
Where the hell
are these guys?
What are they doing?
Blasting?
(SHOUTING) Hey!
Where are you guys? It's not
like there's another road, asshole!
Val! Val!
(FLIES BUZZING)
Jesus!
I don't believe this!
You're hung up.
I am not!
(ENGINE STALLING)
(ENGINE STARTS)
You're hung up,
I tell you!
You're gonna burn
the clutch!
You know, you could
break an axle like that.
Could you shut up?
Hey, I don't need to
spend the night out here.
Crybaby.
HEATHER: Could it have been coyotes?
NESTOR: No way.
MIGUEL: No.
Coyotes didn't kill Fred.
Hey, it's Val and Earl.
They shouldn't
be here already.
Thought you two
were in Bixby by now.
You are never
gonna believe this.
Mom!
Oh, my God!
HEATHER:
Oh, Burt, be careful.
MELVIN: Unreal.
Where'd you get it?
I didn't know
we had it.
It's disgusting.
Some kind of snake?
Looks more like
an eel to me.
Eels live in the water,
don't they?
Big mother slug, maybe.
Don't touch!
Relax. It's dead.
(GROANS)
Hey, it must've grabbed us!
That's why the truck stalled out.
Next time I tell you
I'm not hung up...
Hey, wait.
This stalled out your truck?
It'd have to be one
strong son of a bitch.
Stinks, too.
I'll give you boys
$5 for this.
$20.
Okay, $10!
$15.
Okay, $15.
Damn right, $15.
I don't believe you guys.
Could be a snake!
Some kind of mutation.
Yeah.
Whatever it is,
just one of these couldn't eat up
Fred and his whole flock of sheep.
So you think there are
more of them out there?
I'm dead. Let's put this
stuff up in the morning.
No.
We have to go to Bixby
in the morning.
The cinder blocks are in.
Oh, the cinder blocks.
Oh, my God!
Just keep looking
at that beautiful sky.
That's the sky that's gonna be over
our roof every night when we're done.
What if we don't
finish the roof?
Then we can look at
the sky all the time. Huh?
(LAUGHING)
Oh, that damn thing.
Maybe it's time we buy
a new generator, huh?
It's gone!
What do you mean,
it's gone?
You sure this is
where it was?
It was right here!
There's the cord.
Hold this.
Yeah, maybe the
ground caved in.
There's a lot of mines
and stuff around here.
Well, don't then.
You don't wanna fall in.
(ROARS)
Let's go.
God, what is that stink?
(ROARS)
You hear that?
Come on. Come on,
let's just go.
Let's go back to town or
something. Please, Jim!
Maybe it's a geological thing or
something like natural gas or a geyser.
They stink like that.
Remember in Yellowstone?
Jim!
- Something's got me!
(SCREAMING)
No, Jim, no!
Something's got me
down here!
(CRACKING)
Oh, Jim!
Oh, God! Oh, God!
Get something! Get something!
Get me out of here!
(SCREAMING)
Jim!
Something's got me.
Oh, God!
Please get me out!
Help me!
(SCREAMING STOPS)
Jim!
(ROARING)
(SCREAMS)
(SCREECHES)
(COUNTRY MUSIC
PLAYING ON RADIO)
Oh, my God.
(RUMBLING)
(HORN HONKING)
(WORM SCREECHING)
(SCREAMING)
WALTER: Mindy, smile.
NANCY: Come on, honey.
Don't look so afraid.
It's not gonna hurt you.
I promise.
WALTER: Mindy, look up. Smile.
- Come on.
Hold it.
Melvin, get out of there!
Old Chang, slick as snot,
and I ain't lying.
15 lousy bucks.
A man who plans ahead...
Look, we arm ourselves, we
set perimeters, we stand guard.
Any of those snake things show
up here, we make them extinct.
All right!
Come on, Burt,
get serious.
Yeah! You make it
sound like a war.
What have you people
got against being prepared?
Where's the sugar?
- Rambo.
Wait a minute.
Walter's got a CB radio.
Why aren't you calling
somebody in Bixby? The police...
No. We can't reach outside the
valley because of the mountains.
Melvin, you're next. Come
on. Sit down, look scared.
- Okay.
MELVIN: Yeah.
The phone's out. The
road's out. We're on our own.
You two are just
loving it, aren't you?
Come on, Nancy. Let's don't
get personal about this thing!
We gotta do something.
Hell, yes!
We are completely
cut off.
We got the cliffs
to the north.
Mountains to the east
and the west.
That's why Heather and me
settled here in the first place.
Geographic isolation.
Well, there's gotta be
some way we can get help.
For God's sake,
this isn't the moon!
What are you gonna do,
walk the 38 miles to Bixby?
Hey, there's
Walter's saddle horses.
That's it.
You're welcome to them.
Somebody could
ride to Bixby.
That's not bad.
Who's best on a horse?
Walter, they
better be fast.
We don't wanna be stuck
on a couple of canners.
Those snake things
couldn't travel that fast.
Shit, for all you know,
they could fly.
Here, what do you want?
This colt or Edgar's old rifle?
Rifle.
Hey, Earl. Here's some
Swiss cheese and some bullets.
Thanks, Walter.
You guys all set?
Well, ready as
we'll ever be.
Heather and I are
gonna drive around.
We'll see if we can
find that college girl,
tell her to get her
ass back into town.
Good idea. We'll swing
by the doctor's place
and see if they went
into Bixby or not.
HEATHER:
Hey, wait a minute, guys.
Y'all gonna have
to take something
that packs more of
a punch than that 30-30.
Why don't you take
one of our Browning Autos?
Or better than that, why don't
you just take my Model 70?
It's .375 H&H mag.
EARL: Thanks, Heather.
Well, I hope we
don't need to use it.
(MELVIN SCREAMING)
It's got me!
(LAUGHING)
- Melvin!
NANCY: Grow up!
Damn it, Melvin!
He's only kidding.
You came that close.
Too close.
No more games.
Melvin, one of these days
somebody's gonna kick your ass.
(COUNTRY MUSIC
PLAYING ON RADIO)
Doctor?
Man, I hate
this shit.
Wait a minute.
The car's gone. We just
missed them, that's all.
Where the hell's the goddamn
golden oldie coming from?
What the hell's this?
You got me.
Okay, here's the plan. We
don't even stop. We ride like hell.
Tonight we'll keep right on
going. We'll walk the horses.
That is the plan.
I mean, God damn, what
the hell are those things?
And how could they bury
a whole station wagon?
Why would they do it?
(HORSE WHINNYING)
Come on, boy!
Come on, git, git!
Walter wouldn't know
a decent horse
if it came up and
bit him in the ass.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute. They
got wind of something they don't like.
Git.
Something's
going on here.
VALENTINE: I don't see
anything anywhere!
(WHINNYING)
(EXCLAIMING)
Hey! Hey, you okay?
Yeah, yeah.
What about my horse?
What in the name of...
That's how
they get you.
They're under
the goddamn ground.
Well, what the hell
are they?
Sons of bitches!
(RUMBLING)
Must be a million
of them!
(SCREECHING)
Nope. Just one.
Come on.
He's gaining on us!
Look!
We can make it!
(BOTH YELLING)
(WORM SQUEALING)
(BOTH PANTING)
Stupid son of a bitch.
It knocked itself cold.
Cold, my ass!
He's dead.
We killed it.
We killed it!
Fuck you!
(LAUGHS)
(EXCLAIMS)
Hey, guys.
What's going on?
Did you notice anything
weird a minute ago?
I mean, it just...
What's that?
EARL: All right, together.
One, two, three.
(GASPS)
Jesus Christ!
Does it smell like that
'cause it's dead?
I don't see any eyes.
Must be totally subterranean.
And those tentacles.
Yeah.
You know, I think they
shoot right out of its mouth,
and they hook you
and pull you right in.
Good thing we stopped it
before it killed anybody else.
Look, this is important,
you know.
This is like...
Well, let's just say it.
This is probably the biggest
zoological discovery of the century.
VALENTINE: Hey!
Hey, check this out.
I found the ass end.
(GRUNTS)
Jesus, we really
caught something here.
Wow!
- Man!
That's one big mother.
This must be the old boy had your
seismos working overtime.
Yeah.
Yeah, it must push
itself along with these.
All of them
pushing at once.
That's why it
moved so fast.
I mean, this thing had sensors
tripping all over the place. No...
Hey, Rhonda, you ever heard
of anything like this before?
Oh, sure, Earl. Everybody
knows about them.
We just didn't tell you.
Oh, hell, man, no one
ever saw anything like this!
We're really
onto something here.
I'll tell you
one damn thing,
old Chang don't get his slick
mitts on this for no measly 15 bucks.
- You got that right.
(WHOOPS)
All right, here's the
plan. We need a flatbed.
Yeah, right,
with a winch.
Yeah, five-ton maybe.
No, no, no,
don't wanna winch it.
Don't wanna winch it.
It'd tear it all up.
All right, a crane?
Yeah, a crane
with lifting straps.
Hey. Hey, shut up.
The way I figure it, there
are three more of these things.
What?
Three more?
I've got seismographs
all over this valley.
Now if you compare
the different readings.
Here's one at
2:00 yesterday.
But here's one
three miles away
at the exact same time.
Now that's two.
But here...
- Yeah, yeah. We'll take your word for it.
Yeah, where's
your truck?
Just beyond that hill.
(SCREAMING)
What? What?
(PANTING)
Damn prairie
dog burrow.
Little sons
of bitches.
(SEISMOGRAPH SCRATCHING)
Psst! Psst!
EARL: This way!
Up on that rock!
(SCREECHING)
EARL: Looks like the one
that grabbed our truck.
Where the hell's
your truck?
It's right over there.
Oh, man, I don't think
we can make that.
EARL: At least
he can't climb.
Oh, man!
Live ones smell
worse than the dead ones.
(RUMBLING)
Phew!
I got it. I got it.
They're mutations
caused by radiation.
Or no, no, no.
The government built them.
Big surprise
for the Russians.
Well, there's nothing like them
in the fossil record. I'm sure.
Okay, so they predate
the fossil record.
That would make them
a couple billion years old.
And we've just never
seen one till now.
Right.
I vote for outer space.
No way these are local boys.
Well, haven't seen
a sign for hours.
Must be long gone.
Yeah, must be.
Hey, why don't you take
a little stroll and find out?
(SIGHS)
We gotta do something.
"We gotta do something."
I don't know why "we" always
has to be "me" every damn time.
We, we, we. What do I look
like? An expert on worms?
Watch it, Valentine, it's
got a good six-foot reach.
Thank you, Earl.
Son of a bitch!
Son of a goddamn bitch!
Pardon my French.
Shit! It's been waiting
here all this time?
I mean, how's it know
we're still here?
Well, it's got
no eyes, right?
Sure as hell can't
smell us underground.
I say it's
been listening.
Of course!
It senses
seismic vibration.
It can hear
every move we make,
especially on this rock,
it's a perfect conductor.
That means we're stuck.
That pisses me off!
EARL: Well, I hate to be crude, but
I gotta take care of some business.
VALENTINE: Me, too.
RHONDA: Same here.
(FLY UNZIPPING)
(VALENTINE SIGHS WITH RELIEF)
Thanks.
No problem. Anytime.
Well, what's the plan?
I think the first
thing we gotta do
is see if old stumpy's
still out there.
Can I borrow
that shovel?
Yeah.
(ROARS)
Doesn't he have
a home to go to?
That's why Edgar never
got down off that damn tower.
I think
I have an idea.
You know,
we're gonna have to come
up with some sort of plan,
he's just gonna
wait us to death.
Yeah, well, I was...
- Why don't we just make a run for it?
We outran him yesterday.
Run for it?
Running's not a plan.
Now running's what you do
when a plan fails.
Valentine, you're not even
trying to think of a plan.
Well, it ain't like we got
a hell of a lot of options.
There's always options. We
just gotta think of them, that's all.
All right, well, why
don't you start thinking?
Why in the hell do I always
have to do all the thinking?
Who died and
made you Einstein?
You guys know
how to pole vault?
(GRUNTS)
We just stay
where he can't get us,
on these
residual boulders.
My truck's parked
right next to one.
Stay on those
residual boulders!
That Tammy Lynn Baxter,
she do much pole vaulting?
Shit!
That's pretty good.
That slimebag ain't gonna give
us much time once we hit that truck.
I say we all
jump together.
Right.
(STAMMERING) Wait.
Okay, ready.
One, two, three!
(RUMBLING)
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Watch it, Val!
(WORM SCREECHING)
Move! Move!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Could somebody,
perhaps, help me?
WALTER: Burt! Heather!
- No! No! No!
The snake things are just
their tongues or something.
These animals are huge!
I'm sorry. I'm having a
real difficult time with this.
WALTER: Come on,
you guys, answer.
Come back.
- Hey, Walter.
Where's Burt and Heather?
I can't reach them.
I guess they're still
driving around somewhere.
Hey, Rhonda, what's the
name you call those things?
Huh? Where do they come from?
I don't know.
You're a scientist,
aren't you?
Yeah, aren't you supposed
to have a theory or something?
Look, these creatures
are absolutely unprecedented.
Yeah. But where do
they come from?
Yeah!
It doesn't matter
where they come from.
No name? Ha!
We discovered them,
we should name them!
Walter, forget
the damn name!
Now me and Earl think we
better get the hell out of this valley.
Hang on, Val.
Let's not go off half-cocked.
Yeah. Well, somebody's
bound to come check on us,
Once they see the road is
out and the lines are down.
Yeah, that's
how it works.
(FLIES BUZZING)
Or "suckoids." "Oids."
Oids. I like snakeoids.
One of them comes near me, and I'll
just hit him with a five-pound pickax.
No. You don't
understand, Nestor.
They come up from underneath
the ground and they grab you.
They sense the slightest
vibration through the ground.
Even footsteps.
That's how they hunt.
Hey, so like we don't
vibrate, right?
Maybe they won't even
come through here.
Maybe they'll
leave us alone!
NESTOR: Chain saw.
That's what I'll use.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Wake up!
Now, look!
You see, they're
headed right for us.
Look, they trapped
Edgar here.
Grabbed old Fred
right here.
Nailed those two poor
suckers on the road,
and the doctor's place
is right here!
Now this valley is just
one long smorgasbord.
We have got to get out.
I'm gonna
go get Mindy.
Oh, she's okay. I saw her
playing down the street.
That's what I like,
"Graboids"! That's it, graboids!
Jesus, Walter.
We're gonna be sorry
if we don't give it a name.
Okay, Val, you say
let's get out of here.
So where are we
supposed to go?
Well, Rhonda's got
an idea about that.
Yeah, see, they move very easily
through the Pleistocene alluvials.
The dirt.
The loose soil that
covers the valley floor.
But they can't
move through rock.
So I think we should
head west to the mountains.
She means up
the old jeep trail.
If those mountains are solid
granite, we'd be safe there.
And we could hike along them
all the way to Bixby if we...
(MELVIN SCREAMING)
(MELVIN LAUGHING)
I scared you, didn't I?
You little ass wipe.
You don't knock it off, you're
gonna be shitting this basketball.
Pardon my French.
Mindy!
EARL: It's gonna take us days
to get back with help with Nestor.
We're not gonna
leave you alone.
(MELVIN SCREAMING)
Damn it!
I'm gonna kick his ass!
I'm gonna help you.
Melvin!
Where is that
little shit stain?
(WHIMPERING)
Melvin, get your...
Get inside!
Run! Come on!
Come on, get in!
Jesus Christ, Walter,
you got a gun?
No! What are we gonna do?
Be quiet, quiet, quiet!
Where is he?
(RUMBLING)
(WHISPERING) Now remember,
no noise, no vibrations.
(POGO STICK BOUNCING)
Oh, no, Mindy.
Stop, stop.
MIGUEL: Mindy, get off
the pogo stick.
VALENTINE; Mindy!
WALTER: Get her, Val!
- Mindy, come back!
RHONDA; Mindy!
Oh!
(SCREAMING)
NANCY: Mindy.
Quiet. Quiet.
Don't move.
(RUMBLING)
Mindy, get back.
Get back.
VALENTINE: Run!
Get in the house!
(RUMBLING)
We gotta get him off.
It'll suck that truck down.
Go back for Christ's sake!
Jesus, here comes
another one!
Run! Come on! Come on!
(SCREAMS)
(SHRIEKS)
(YELLS)
Get out of your pants!
Look out!
(GRUNTING)
Run!
EARL: Run! Don't look back.
Come on! Come on!
(RHONDA GASPS IN PAIN)
Sorry.
Rhonda, here.
Oh, thank you.
So, what are
we gonna do?
You know, how long
till they go away?
They got
the patience of Job.
They sit and goddamn wait till they
hear something that sounds like lunch.
We gotta have a plan.
I got a plan.
You and Val drive the
truck up to the mountain,
walk to Bixby,
get some help.
Walter, those
scumsuckers ate our radials.
Well, you can
take my truck.
No, we need a major
four-wheel drive
just to get up
that jeep trail.
That trail's
all messed up.
(REFRIGERATOR WHIRRING)
WALTER: Turn it Off.
Pull it back.
I got it.
(WHIRRING STOPS)
(GROANS)
Give me your hand!
(GROANS IN DISGUST)
Son of a bitch.
Son of a bitch!
Come on, let's go!
The roof!
Come on!
EARL: Jump, Rho!
You can do it!
No, I can't! I can't!
Rhonda! Don't stop.
Keep moving!
Oh, my God.
Hey!
You Okay?
MELVIN: Hey, what's going
on? Where are you guys?
What's up, man? What the
hell are you doing up there?
Melvin, shut
the hell up.
Get up on your roof.
- No way!
(SHOUTING IN FEAR)
Nestor?
Nancy, get up
on your roofs.
Up on your roofs! They
come through the floor!
I don't know.
I can't believe it.
No tracks.
No sign. No spoor.
You'd think after
eating all those sheep
they'd have to
take a dump some place.
Yeah. I don't
understand it.
ON C.B. RADIO: Yo, Walter.
This is Burt. Come back.
Walter? Anybody copy?
I'm waiting.
Walter, you there?
Come back!
Okay, I got it.
Yo, who's minding the store,
for God's sake?
Burt, listen. We found out
what's been killing people.
Say "over."
- Over.
Negative copy on that,
Walter. Check your frequency.
I'm on 22. Come back.
Burt, can you
hear me now? Over.
Val, is that you? What're
you doing back already?
Hey, Burt, something real
weird is going on over there.
They're up on
top of the roof.
Hey, I think they're
going for Burt's.
Oh, man,
they're going!
Burt, get out of your
basement. Take your radio.
You and Heather
get up on your roof.
We'll talk later.
Okay? Over.
Up on the roof? Val,
what are you talking about?
Damn it, Burt. Just listen
to him. Something's wrong.
Burt, Jesus Christ!
Get up on your roof!
The things!
They're under the ground.
They're bigger than we
thought. They're huge.
They're coming right after you
guys. They're coming right now!
We don't see
anything, Val.
What the hell are you
talking about? Over.
Burt, they're under the ground.
They're under the ground.
They can dig like
a son of a bitch.
Big monsters!
Underground! Now get out!
Hurry!
(RUMBLING)
Jesus Christ!
(RADIO CUTS OUT)
(DISTANT GUNSHOTS)
(SHOUTS)
Burt, come on.
Magazine!
- Here!
(GRUNTING)
(SQUEALS)
Here!
Broke into the wrong goddamn
rec room didn't you, you bastard?
We killed it! You got that? We killed
that motherhumper! Come back.
Well, roger that, Burt.
And congratulations.
Be advised, however,
there are two more.
Repeat, two more
motherhumpers.
Burt got one!
He killed one!
Way to go, dude!
All right!
Yes! Yes!
Well, I guess we don't get to make
fun of Burt's lifestyle anymore, huh?
Say, Burt?
Any chance you can get
the other two? Come back.
Yeah. One second, pal.
You didn't get penetration
even with the elephant gun.
Shit!
Good Lord!
Val, we can't get them.
I never figured on having
to shoot through dirt.
The best goddamn bullet
stop there is. Come back.
Let me see that.
Burt, listen.
Forget shooting them.
Tell me this. Can
you get to your truck?
Over.
- No problem.
Good, 'cause you have the
only truck in the valley
that can get up
that jeep trail.
Now listen.
Here's the plan.
You and Heather
go for help.
You get to the mountains
and keep going...
Guys! You guys!
Come over.
- Hang on a sec.
He's up to something.
VALENTINE: Well, if it
isn't our old pal, stumpy.
Bastard.
Hey, Rhonda. What do you
think it's trying to do now?
Why do you keep asking me?
What the...
Gee! Wow.
What the hell was that?
BURT: Breaker there, Earl. What
did you want us to do? Come back.
Hang on, Burt. This
bastard's trying something new.
(RUMBLING)
Over.
(WORM GROWLING)
They wasn't
making no noise.
Why is he
bothering them for?
Well, it's like it's studying the
buildings, trying to figure them out.
They can feel our vibrations
but they can't find us.
Looks to me like they're
coming up with a plan.
VALENTINE:
Watch it, Nestor!
Jesus!
Shit! Enough!
(SCREAMS)
VALENTINE: Get off the
ground, Nestor! Get moving!
MIGUEL: Get out of there!
Get off the ground!
EARL: Move it! Move it!
(EXCLAIMING IN FEAR)
VALENTINE: No, Nestor.
That's no good.
Come on,
you gotta get higher.
(NESTOR SCREAMING)
No way! No way, man!
No! You guys
gotta do something!
You gotta do something!
VALENTINE ON C.B.:
Burt, Heather?
Yeah, you got us, Val.
Come on back. Over.
Listen, we're in
deep shit over here.
We'll have to
change that plan.
Burt, cut it out!
I think I scared him.
No use going for help.
We'd be dead long before
you'd ever get back.
Okay, Val, we're with you. Just
tell us what you wanna do. Over.
Yeah, well, this one's gonna
tear this town out from under us.
We're all gonna have to
get out of here together, now.
Okay, Val.
We're coming after everybody.
Just hang tight. Over.
Look.
(CAR ALARM SOUNDS)
Val, you're gonna have to
forget about the truck.
Yeah, we got you, Heather.
Now, look. The
situation hasn't changed.
We still have to make it to solid
rock. There's gotta be some way.
Like what?
There's nothing left that can
make it to those mountains.
Hey, Val. Quiet, man.
It doesn't matter now.
They know we're here.
Oh, shit! We need a
helicopter is what we need.
Or a goddamn tank!
Wait a minute.
The Cat!
Could we take the Cat?
Oh, Jesus.
It's slower than hell.
Yeah, but it weighs
better than 30 tons.
There's no way they
could lift 30 tons.
Could they? I mean...
But we can't all
fit on the bulldozer.
No.
No, but we could
drag something, though.
We could pull a car
behind it. I don't know.
Hell, that old semitrailer.
Its tires are flat.
Doesn't matter.
That Cat can
pull anything.
Well, all right.
We just roll on
out of here.
We've got a plan!
Of course, that's a
hell of a long walk.
Listen, they only respond
to vibration, right?
Well, couldn't we
distract them somehow?
Yeah. Good.
Something to keep
them busy, like a decoy.
Hey, Melvin,
you wanna make a buck?
Eat it!
How about the tractor?
Walter's little tractor?
Start him up.
Let him go out
by himself.
Let those things follow him
all over if they like that noise.
Not bad.
What do you think?
(RUMBLING)
Ground's getting closer, Earl.
- Yeah.
I say we go with
Miguel's plan.
Just hold on, Nancy!
I'm making the run
for the Cat.
Like hell you are.
Get real, Earl.
I'm faster than you.
But I'm best at
driving the Cat.
Not while I'm around.
Look, damn it!
Now listen to me.
I'm older
and I'm wiser.
Yeah? Well,
you're half right.
Damn! I lost.
Guess I'll have to do it.
I won.
I pick who does it.
Ready when
you are, Miguel.
(ENGINE STARTING)
There he is.
There he goes!
He's chasing it.
It's going.
This one's going, too!
Good luck, shithead.
Don't worry about me,
jerk-off.
Shit!
You suicidal
son of a bitch.
(EXCLAIMS)
Keep going!
EARL: Oh, my God!
Oh, my God!
Come on!
They're gonna get him!
Val, stop! They're
coming! Be quiet!
Don't move!
It worked.
They can't find him.
We gotta...
We gotta make some noise.
A lot of noise!
Hey, you sorry sons of
bitches! Come and get my ass!
Over here, you slime bucket!
Come get me!
(ALL SHOUTING)
MELVIN: Come on. What
are you, scared? Come on.
Hey, what's she doing?
(RHONDA GRUNTS)
That did it, girl!
God damn good thinking.
(GRUNTS)
(WHOOPS)
You okay?
- Yeah.
Here goes.
Here.
- Yeah.
God damn!
Armored transport.
Burt! Heather!
Let's get going!
Let's move it.
VALENTINE: Burt! Heather!
Come on, let's go, you two.
We're headed for the mountains.
If that's how we're doing it,
we're going prepared.
We can't hold still long.
These things are damn smart.
They're getting
smarter by the minute.
That's fine.
We've got some new
things to teach them.
(TRACK SQUEALS)
(ALL SHOUTING)
You see that?
They're doing it again.
They try it every time I stop!
Come on, now.
Jesus Christ! We're
only going nine miles.
Yeah, well, those things are gonna be
on our ass every foot of the way, right?
NANCY: Just hurry! Burt, Heather,
what are you doing up there?
MIGUEL: Can't you see
we're sinking?
Get in the trailer!
What do you think?
Max firepower or this?
I go for penetration.
The .458, shooting solids.
Less ammo to carry.
Come on, Burt.
Move it!
Watch these ammo boxes!
EARL: Come on, Burt!
NANCY: Heather, hurry!
Tell them to come on!
Okay, now!
Now! Come on! Come on!
Hey, give me a gun.
I'll take one.
I wouldn't give you a gun
if it was World War Ill.
Food for five years.
A thousand gallons of gas,
air filtration,
water filtration,
Geiger counter,
bomb shelter.
Underground
goddamn monsters!
Yo, there we go!
Solid rock.
(EXCLAIMING)
Any sign of them?
Maybe they just
gave up, you know?
Hey, what's that?
Damn it! What the hell
are they doing?
I don't care
what they're doing
As long as they're
doing it way over there.
Wait, wait!
Look out!
Mindy!
Mommy!
- Everybody stay here.
Burt, you okay?
- I'm okay.
MINDY: Are they gonna
get us? What happened?
Burt, you sure
you're okay?
Yeah.
MIGUEL: Earl,
what happened?
NANCY: What happened?
They dug a trap.
I can't believe this.
All right.
Here.
(GUNS CONTINUE FIRING)
Let me have my gun.
Hungry? Eat this!
Everybody down!
(WORM SCREECHING)
There they are!
EARL: Did you get one?
BURT: I don't know.
No, there's still
two of them.
Look, there're two
different dust trails.
VALENTINE: Sure made them
think twice though.
What the hell's in
those things, Burt?
A few household chemicals
in the proper proportion.
Here they come.
They're coming back!
We'll have to make
a run for those rocks.
I don't know, Val. That's
a hell of a long way.
Yeah, man,
they'll get us!
They're sure as hell
gonna get us if we stay here.
Hey, Burt! You have
any more of those bombs?
We've got you
covered, Rhonda.
Well, what if we throw one that
way, the way that we wanna go?
Then when it explodes, I
mean, if it drives them away,
we run like
goddamn bastards.
Pardon my French.
(RUMBLING)
What if they don't get
scared? What if they don't run?
I don't think it does
scare them. It hurts them.
They're so sensitive
to sound, they gotta run.
Oh, hell,
she's got my vote!
That's it! We're
making a run for it!
We're going
for the rocks.
I don't know, man.
They're too fast.
You can't outrun them.
No way!
Yo, Melvin. This'll
make them think twice.
Everybody ready to run?
BURT: Heads down!
(WORM SCREECHING)
RHONDA: It worked!
There they go!
All right, let's go!
MIGUEL: Move.
EARL: There you go.
Here. Come on, Burt.
Oh, fuck.
(GUN CLICKS)
Oh, Burt, you asshole!
(GRUNTS)
Mommy!
Mindy, get up.
Get up.
(ALL SHOUTING EXCITEDLY)
Get up here!
I'm with you, honey.
Go, go, go!
Burt, you asshole! There's
no bullets in this gun.
Got you moving,
didn't it?
So, now what?
Could we make it to the
mountains, use Burt's explosives?
No way.
We'd need 50
of those bombs.
Well, that's it.
We're not getting
off this rock.
Well, we're not gonna
pole vault out of here.
That's for damn sure.
Wait a minute.
What're y'all
talking about?
It's like you're
giving up or something.
They'll just wait out there till we're
dead. That's exactly what they do.
Wait!
For Christ sake, we could've
made a stand at our place.
We had food, water.
You can't fight
them like that.
BURT: So you two screw-ups
hauled us way the hell out here?
Hey, why don't you just
back off, string bean?
You know, we could've left
your worthless ass on the roof!
I wish you had,
fearless leader.
Who the hell put you two in charge?
- Don't push me!
EARL: Just back off, Burt.
- Just don't goddamn push me!
If them graboids
don't kill him, I will.
What?
They'd have torn your place
out from under you in half an hour.
Come on. Come on.
Just let it go. Let it
go. Forget about it.
(MUTTERING)
I know he does. He
thinks he knows everything.
(SIGHS)
If it comes to starvation,
I know what I'm doing.
Take one of these,
walk right out there with the
fuse lit and let them take me down.
Boom.
Good Lord, honey.
Now that's not
a bad idea.
(CHUCKLING)
No, no.
It gives me an idea.
Going fishing like.
There's one.
Straight out in front.
Let's see if we can
keep him right there.
All right,
how much we need?
I don't know.
They're pretty quick.
Fifteen seconds
at least.
Which kind of fuse
is that?
Cannon fuse.
What the hell
you use if for?
My cannon.
You guys
watch yourselves.
Right out there
about 30...
Oh, man. You're not
gonna do your lasso thing?
Just 'cause you're
no good with a rope.
All right, get back!
Come on, baby.
Take it.
Take the bait!
Yeah! All right!
Look at it!
Yeah!
(ALL CHEERING)
VALENTINE: All right!
RHONDA:
Okay, one to go.
Damn! Where
the hell is he?
Hope he didn't wise up.
RHONDA: There.
Look who it is.
Give me that thing.
This son of a bitch is mine.
There it goes!
All right, get back!
I got it.
Come on. Come on.
Come on,
lunchtime, snot head.
All right, get down!
Shit!
Oh, my God! It's...
Get back! Get back!
Run!
Get up, come on!
What are you doing
out there?
(SCREECHING)
Okay, let's make
some noise.
Try to distract him.
Come on, everybody.
(ALL SHOUTING)
Fresh meat!
Wait, wait, wait.
This one's not
falling for it.
This one ain't dumb.
He's trying to trick us.
Use your bomb.
It's our last one.
What else you
gonna use it for?
So what if we
make it to the rocks?
We'll be dead in
three days anyway.
Well, I wanna live
for the three days.
BURT: What the hell?
What's the matter?
Use the bomb,
for God sakes!
MIGUEL: Throw
that bomb, man!
Scare him away!
Throw the bomb!
This bastard ain't
smarter than us.
For Christ's sake, Val!
I'm gonna go for it.
Go for what?
What are you doing?
I got a goddamn plan!
Where the hell is it?
I've got it!
EARL: This better be
one hell of a great plan!
Get ready!
Light it, man! Light it!
Not yet. Not yet!
Come on.
What are you waiting for?
Go!
Come on! Come on!
Too far!
You threw it behind him.
Run, Val! Run!
Yeah!
Can you fly, you sucker?
Can you fly?
Well, it just suddenly
hit me, you know.
Stampede.
(CHUCKLING)
(OTHERS CHEERING)
BURT: Way to go!
Way to go, Val!
Now, the second we hit Bixby,
we start making some phone calls.
I mean, we could make
some real money on this thing.
We could get in
People magazine.
People? Hell!
National Geographic.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Smile.
Burt loaned me
his camera.
Yeah. He gave us
these tires, too.
It's all pretty
exciting, huh?
There's gonna be major
research, and I'm gonna be in on it.
The first thing to do is take some
pictures of that one we dug up.
Yeah. Yeah.
Pictures seem
like a good idea.
Yeah, well,
thanks for everything,
you know,
saving my life and stuff.
You're welcome.
Maybe I'll see you sometime?
Uh-huh.
Well, see you.
I know. I know!
I'm working up to it.
What am I doing?
I mean, what's a woman like
her want with a guy like me?
She's going
for her damn Ph.D.
Rhonda?
Yeah?
Well, I just
wanted to...